Chloe! Hey!
What are you doing?
Someone could have seen you!
You've got to be a good
hider otherwise
the bad guys will find you.
Sorry, Dad.
I'm Eleanor Reed.
Age 7.
I live at 726 Monroe Street.
My birthday...
Mhm...
Is March 9th
10th.
March 10th.
Can I stir?
Yeah, but keep practicing.
That's my Mom, Nancy Reed.
Her birthday is August 10th.
Is she really going to love me?
That's why we're paying her.
That's my sister Harper.
Harper.
Her birthday's June 13th.
She snores.
Where'd you get that?
I thought we were
going with puppies.
It's true Dad.
She snores.
Good job, Chloe.
That is something a
sister would say.
Partners?
Partners.
What's the plan if
I don't come back?
I go to my closet.
Yeah?
And then what?
If I run out of food I
go across the street,
tell Steve and Nancy that I'm
Eleanor Reed and I give them
the whole shebang if
they take care of me.
Let's go over the old
classics, shall we? A.
A is for Apple.
Apple is a red fruit that
you eat and it is delicious.
You ever seen a green one?
- Yes.
- Okay, good.
What's B?
B is for baseball.
A game played between
two teams with 9 players
who run in circles around
a diamond-shaped field.
Chloe what's your
favourite sport?
I've never played a sport.
Bang!
You're dead.
That's not fair!
You never asked me that before.
If you don't know the answer to
something you just make it up.
You go...
huh?
I don't know!
I love all sports.
That's lying.
Yes.
You need to lie to be normal.
How much money do you
think is right there?
Well these are hundred dollar
bills so like a couple thousand?
More than that.
No, I'm not sure myself.
Okay I raise ten.
Can we have ice cream
after dinner?
You know we don't
have any ice cream.
When are you going?
Not for a while.
I was hitting the store
too much.
I can't wait until I'm normal.
Are you going to call
my ten or not?
You're bluffing.
Try me.
All in.
I missed the river.
You win.
You're getting good
under pressure.
Staying calm.
That's good.
Did Mom's eyes bleed too?
Are my eyes going
to bleed someday?
I hope not.
But if they do you're going
to let me know, right?
Right.
You're going to say, 'hey Dad
my eyes are bleeding,
what the heck?'
Yeah
Alright now collect your
million dollar jackpot
Alright
Make sure you get
the ones in the back.
I did!
Oh well, last time I checked...
Oof, there are knots
in your hair.
Ow!
Alright.
Time for breathing.
Close your eyes,
nice deep breaths.
In.
Exhale.
You're not normal!
It's not funny.
It's not funny, Chloe.
You need to practice this.
You looked funny.
You gotta practice this.
It's important.
And if I don't I'll
go to the mountain?
What are you talking about?
Nothing.
I never taught you
about the mountain
so you must have talked
to someone.
Did you go outside?
No
Did you go through Daddy's
junk mail?
Is that where you learned about
the mountain?
No.
Chloe, Chloe, Chloe.
This is not a game
right now okay?
You can never lie to me.
I'm not lying.
You're never mean to me, Mommy.
Go away ghost.
Go away.
You imagined it.
Ghosts aren't real.
Stay with me.
I'm scared.
Okay but I can't fall
asleep again.
Too much time goes by outside
when I'm asleep.
I can only protect you
when I'm awake.
Mr. Snowcone.
Whoa.
Harper. Bring me ice cream.
Please.
Bring me ice cream.
Please, please, please,
please, please.
Bring me ice cream.
Harper.
Hello?
Hi.
I brought you ice cream.
Is it chocolate?
Yes.
Hey!
What are you doing here?
Huh?
I brought Chloe some ice cream.
How do you know her name?
Huh? Huh?
Harper?
What are you doing here?
You know better than to knock
on strangers' doors.
I am sorry about that.
I don't know why she came
over here.
No, not at all. Not at all.
Alright. Bye-bye now.
Is this your daughter?
Oh we should go.
Gotta go.
Hi.
Hi I'm Nancy.
You're beautiful.
Oh my goodness
she's a sweetheart.
And she looks so normal.
Eleanor, go back inside.
Come on Eleanor, go back inside.
Harper called you Chloe.
Was that Nancy, for real?
How did she know your real name?
Have you been going outside?
No.
No, Dad! The closet
is too scary!
You know the punishment
for breaking the rules.
Time out.
I almost got ice cream.
You opened the door.
You almost got us killed.
Vroom, vroom. Vroom, vroom!
I'm an ice cream truck and
I give kids ice cream
all around the world.
Vroom, vroom.
Oh no!
There's a giant!
There's Harper.
She likes chocolate ice cream.
What are you doing
in my room, Chloe?
Shh you can't call me that.
I'm supposed to be Eleanor.
Will you play a game with
me before Dad wakes up?
You are so annoying.
Why do you always wake me up
in the middle of the night?
We can play at the park
like normal people.
You're allowed to play outside
with other kids?
Aren't you scared the bad guys
will want to kill you?
No.
Everybody does it.
It's fine.
It's not fair that you have
a Mom and I don't.
Will you pretend to be my Mom?
Ew.
Why are you so weird?
That's gross.
Come on.
No.
Be my Mom. Be my Mom.
Be my Mom.
Okay fine. I'll be your Mom.
Say you love me.
I love you.
Mom.
I want to go outside.
Am I allowed?
Yes you can go outside.
Thanks Mom.
Now let's cuddle and sleep.
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
Mom said I could go outside.
Chloe.
She said I could go
to the ice cream truck.
Want to know what's
in an ice cream truck?
What?
Frozen kid bodies.
Not true.
They kill kids and then
they freeze them to eat later.
I want to go anyway.
You're not normal enough yet.
You'll die if you go outside.
It's not fair.
Harper gets to go to
the park and I don't.
If I get you ice cream will you
shut up about this?
Yes.
I'll get you a whole bucket
if you never open that
door ever again.
I promise.
Will you get it for me today?
Fine. I need new
supplies anyway.
Yay!
Thank you Daddy!
Hide!
They might have followed me.
Daddy are you okay?
It's okay.
Most of this is their blood.
Whose blood?
What happened?
Don't worry.
I'll be alright.
Just gotta be more careful.
I can't be leaving the house
for stupid, non-essential-
You forgot the ice cream.
What? Don't you realize
I almost just died?
I'm going to the grocery myself.
Chloe.
You see what happens
when we go outside?
When am I going to live
with Nancy?
Change of plan.
What?
Yeah.
We have to stay hidden.
Till when?
Till when?!
Well lookie here!
What can I do for you,
young woman?
Are we safe?
Safe?
Safe from what?
The people who want to kill us.
Nobody's going to kill you
if I'm around.
Can I have ice cream?
Sure!
But what flavour, Chloe?
Chocolate.
Wow, a hundred bucks.
You can buy a shitload of
ice cream for a hundred bucks.
Is that a lot?
What do you mean is it a lot?
You could buy any flavour
you wanted with that.
Really?
Yeah.
Come around back.
Come inside.
Taste any flavour you want.
I'm not allowed.
Oh, come on.
Hey.
You never have to do what
your Dad tells you again.
Come on up.
Take a look around.
Are there frozen kid bodies
in there?
It's an ice cream truck.
Come on. I gotta go.
There's other kids that have
to have ice cream too, you know!
But I'd love to have a big
girl like you helping me out.
You could actually make
some of the ice cream.
Here.
Lookie here.
Are you going to the park?
That's exactly where I'm going!
So come on.
Is that a bad guy or a good guy?
What do you think?
He bleeds like my Dad.
Well no, they just put that
on him.
That's like makeup.
That's just because they want to
scare the hell out of everybody.
You ever bleed from your eye
like that?
No.
You're not lying to me, are you?
That's too bad.
Woo!
Push me!
So Chloe, can you
do anything special?
Higher!
How about when you're scared?
Anything weird ever happen?
Even!
Higher!
I want to touch the sky.
I want to touch outside
of the universe!
Okay real high!
Okay out of the universe
here you go!
Maybe you can fly!
Go higher!
Wait no! Stop pushing!
Higher!
Stop! That's too high!
Now jump!
I'm scared!
Jump!
Stop!
Let me go!
Have some courage.
Come on Chloe.
Jump out of the swing!
I'm scared!
Come on, jump out!
Come on!
Show some courage!
I'm scared.
What do you mean
you're scared? It's okay.
Don't you under-
Come here. It's okay.
Ow!
What's the matter?
Does that hurt?
Yes!
Does it make you mad?
Now what happens when
you really get mad?
I take deep breaths
to calm down.
Is there anything that you can
do that other people can't do?
Well I've never met
any other people.
Well, you know what's happening?
Your Dad is turning you
into a pussy.
You can't do that.
You gotta be strong
like your Mom was.
You knew my Mom?
Everybody knew your Mom.
Your Mom was famous.
What's famous?
Famous means she had
special gifts just like you.
And everybody who knew her
was scared to death of her,
except the people who loved her.
And then she died?
You may not know this but
in a land far away from here
there is big evil dark mountain.
I've heard of the mountain.
Yeah, well your Mom and
I went to that mountain
together, and we tried to
destroy it, and just as we...
Hey.
What's going on here?
Everything okay little girl?
It's okay bud.
Actually we're getting ready
to leave.
Come on.
I want to go home.
Do you know this man?
No.
She's my granddaughter.
Is this your grandpa?
No.
She jokes like that
all the time.
Shut up for a sec.
Let me see your eyes.
Why?
You know why.
Oh my God.
Who is that?
He's a bad man.
He's going to kill us.
Hey I'm not done talking to you.
Yeah.
No, it's cool bud.
You know the people that want
to kill us?
That's him.
That's him!
- Shut up!
- No!
Don't kill us!
I'm not going to hurt you,
sweetheart.
Just come here.
You don't need to point
the gun at us!
We're leaving.
Hey!
He killed your mother!
Step away from the girl!
Make him go away.
I said shut up.
Get rid of him!
Now!
Go away!
Let me see your eyes, old man.
Look I said come here now, kid!
Go away!
Go away! Go away!
You are a very special girl
and you and I
are going to do big things
together.
Now let's go home.
Come on.
All officers on alert.
Abnormal child reported
at Peachtree Park.
ADF has been notified.
Repeat. All officers on alert.
You did good.
Very good.
Who is that?
That's your Mommy.
My daughter.
She looks like an angel.
Yeah she sure does.
Just like you.
I have a dream to get her back.
I'm going to get her back.
But she's dead.
Well, sometimes angels can come
back to Earth.
Can I have it?
No.
It's the only picture I have
of her and I'd like to keep it
so I can look at her every day.
Oh come on don't give me
those eyes.
Here, take it back.
It's a rental.
Just don't get boogers and all
that crap out of your nose
and stuff on it, okay?
Okay.
When am I going
to see you again?
When the time is right.
You see, your Dad
has to be asleep.
So I have a present for you.
When you hear the music
from my truck,
you put this in Dad's food
and he'll go out.
Like magic?
That's exactly right.
That's what it is.
It is magic.
Take it.
And you know what else?
You, madam, are not going
to have to hide much longer.
Chloe?
Chloe? Chloe!
Chloe!
There you are.
Did you hear me calling you?
Huh?
You scared me.
I'm sorry I didn't get you
any ice cream.
I'll go out and I'll get you
some tomorrow.
I don't care about ice cream.
Can I colour too?
No.
You're a liar.
What?
You lied about the bad people.
They won't hurt me.
What are you talking about?
I'm going to go live with Nancy.
Wait Chloe.
I want a Mom!
You had a Mom.
You are not going
to be like her.
She died because
she broke the rules.
She didn't break the rules.
She was special.
And I'm special.
Don't say that again, okay?
I'm special. I'm special!
I'm special!
I'm special I can feel it!
You're not special!
Don't say that again okay?
I hate you.
You're not my Dad anymore.
Baby I'm sorry.
I'm just trying to protect you.
You're a liar.
I'm not lying to you.
I'm so sorry.
Get out of my room!
Get out!
Get out! Get out of my room!
I hate you!
I wish I had a Mom.
You're so beautiful.
Hello?
Ghost?
Who are you?
Chloe.
Chloe?
No.
What are they giving me?
You're really my Mom?
Chloe.
Chloe. Chloe.
No.
You're not real.
You sick assholes!
Get this kid out of here before
I rip her throat out!
I'll kill you all!
Dad?
And that's why you came
to town today,
because of reports of
a full-blooded minor.
Is that correct?
Yes, there was an interesting
report.
As you know, Abnormal minors are
my particular area of interest.
I can't help but notice you use
the term 'Abnormal'
as opposed to the more
widely-used 'Freaks' -
is that a political statement?
I believe it's important for
the ADF to try to normalize
relations with the
Abnormal community.
Abnormal community?
By definition, any Freaks who
are running loose are illegal.
Declaring a group
of people illegal
doesn't make them go away.
It makes them go underground.
They're forced to defend
themselves to survive.
Well to your point, the Amnesty
Act gave Freaks
an opportunity to peacefully
relocate to Madoc Mountain.
So, the ones who continue
to hide in our cities,
they're breaking the law,
are they not?
I believe in relocation
and termination.
Abnormals are dangerous and
we can't let them live free.
But I don't believe they are
born evil.
Everyone knows
their abilities increase
generation by generation.
Their children are defined
as living weapons
of mass destruction.
Isn't culling them as children
the most humane approach?
But I just
I mean the last time Freak
children were loose,
we lost Dallas.
Just imagine if we could raise
an abnormal child ourselves.
Teach him or her how to be good.
With guidance,
a child like that would be a
powerful tool in our arsenal.
I can't wait to live
with you Harper.
And have a normal family.
We're really going
to be sisters.
Your Mom is going to love me.
Harper?
What are you doing here?
This is my room.
No it's my room.
Who the hell let you in here?
I'm going to live with you now.
Who in the world is this?
She's a weirdo who lives across
the street.
I'm not a weirdo.
I know how to be normal.
Are you friends with a Freak?
She's not my friend.
I'm not a freak.
She's just messed up in the head
because she doesn't have a Mom.
She's such a freak.
Freak! Freak!
Freak!
I'm not a freak!
Freak! Freak!
And I do have a Mom!
And she's a ghost
and she's famous
and she lives in my closet!
Freak! Freak! Freak!
See!
Mommy don't be scared.
It's alright.
The girls aren't here anymore.
Go away. You're not real.
You're not real.
It's okay Mommy.
Don't be scared.
Oh my God.
I missed you.
You're alive.
I thought you were dead.
I'm not dead Mommy.
You are.
How long have I been gone?
It's only been a few months
and you were a baby
and now you're...
how did you get so big?
Chloe how did you get in here?
I opened the door.
Chloe where are you?
In my closet.
Is your Dad there?
Where is he?
He's sleeping.
He's always tired.
Why do you live in my closet?
I don't, Chloe.
I want to be with you
all the time.
Oh I wouldn't want you
to be here with me.
Because you're dead.
I'm ready for my new mom.
But Dad says I can't have her.
Your new mom?
Nancy.
She lives across the
street and she makes cookies.
You tell your Dad,
you tell your Dad that he should
move on, okay?
And baby I'm so sorry that
I can't be there with you.
But I'm not going
to be coming back, okay?
And you should have a new mom.
You should have a new mom, okay?
We're coming for you soon bitch!
What are you doing down here?
I saw Mom.
She lives in my closet.
This is my alone time.
She said I should get a new mom.
She said you should move on.
Stop making stuff up.
I'm going to live with Nancy.
I can be normal.
Stop! Chloe!
What's gotten into you?
I wish you would die.
Someday they will kill me.
You'll be on your own and
you'll regret saying that.
I'm sorry Daddy.
I made you special juice.
Thanks.
I'm sorry too.
Partners?
What's this?
Are you trying to poison me?
Chloe! Chloe!
Chloe!
What the hell is this?
Where the hell did you get this?
After everything
I've done for you?
Stop yelling!
- Go to sleep! Go to sleep!
- How could you do this to me Chloe?
What are you thinking?
I'm the only person
keeping you alive, Chloe!
- Go to sleep! Go to sleep!
- Why'd you do this?!
- Chloe! Why did you do this?
Whoa. Where are you going?
Oh my God.
Here. Whenever you feel you cry
you must wipe away that tear.
It's a dead giveaway.
Okay? What's that?
To get my new mom.
Your new mom?
What are you talking about,
your new mom?
Nancy Reed.
Oh come on.
I got a better idea than that.
What?
Real mom.
Get in the truck.
Now!
It's getting close.
Should be here in a few minutes.
Now... showtime.
I don't want to be here.
When we go inside you
don't say anything.
Why?
Just don't open your mouth.
You're scaring me.
Did your Dad ever tell you
the story of the unicorns?
Well, in a forest very
nearby there was
a whole big family of unicorns.
Then one night a pack of
snarling wolves came
into the forest and grabbed
the Mommy unicorn
and took her away.
And the Daddy unicorn who had
a weapon right here
chose not to use it.
He wanted to hide.
He wanted to be a peaceful
unicorn.
Well, the next night the wolves
came back
and they ate the Daddy unicorn.
Then what happened?
The baby?
She's left alone.
Doesn't know what to do.
She knows that she's supposed
to hide
because that's what the Dad did.
And so she thought if I do that
then I can live peacefully
in the forest.
But you know what happened?
There are no more
fucking unicorns.
Hiding is out.
That's her.
In the booth.
Excuse me, Agent Ray?
Uh, could I have a word
with you for a minute?
Sorry I don't have time
right now, Father.
I have something to tell you
and I need to tell it to you,
um, privately.
Watch the door.
May we?
Please.
My name is Father Tom Finnegan
and you and I share
a common dream.
What dream is that?
Well, this little soul here
needs your protection.
And we need you to take us
to Madoc Mountain.
Seven years ago a newborn was
laid on the steps of my church
with a note - a prayer -
to keep her safe.
I knew right then I might have
an Abnormal.
Why do you think that?
Well it was right
at the beginning
of the relocation riots.
You remember that.
They were rounding up
every Freak they could find.
I had suspicions but I raised
her all by myself.
Look at me.
Do you mind, Father?
Please.
You just admitted
to a federal crime.
I know what I did ma'am.
But I also know if I raised her
in the light of the Lord
and taught her to love that she
might never be a Freak at all.
I'm not a freak.
I'm normal.
Um, it's okay.
She's not going to hurt you.
You don't need to pretend.
I'm not pretending.
What's your name, sweetie?
I'm Eleanor Reed.
I'm seven and a half
and I like baseball.
My dad is Steven Reed.
He likes fishing but he's not
very good at it.
You can give it up.
You don't have to do it.
I just told ya.
I'm not gonna tell you two
or three times every time.
Her Dad?
She doesn't have any parents.
I raised her by myself.
I do so!
My mom is Nancy Reed.
Her birthday is August 10th.
Cut it out!
I'm going to have
to make a call.
But before you do,
there is one condition.
You have a condition.
Forgive me, but
I have to stay in her life.
So I can continue
to nurture her.
Therefore you gotta take
both of us to Madoc Mountain.
I'm not going anywhere with her.
I'm not a freak!
Hey! Come back here!
You scared her.
Not your fault.
Copy that. On our way.
Don't ever do that to me again.
Never wimp out on me.
Why are you doing this?
You have no idea how hard
it was for me to get
that bitch's schedule!
I'm not a freak!
I'm normal!
Oh no, no, it's cool.
I didn't hear anything.
Hey maybe you're a Freak,
maybe you're not a Freak.
I don't care.
That's not my business.
It's okay, it's okay,
it's okay, it's okay.
What are you afraid of?
Nothing.
Um, could I borrow your pen?
Yes, of course.
Absolutely.
No! No!
His eye is bleeding!
- Fire!
- Stop!
That's not the guy!
Hold your fire!
We gotta disappear.
Goddamnit!
Shit!
Is that man going to be okay?
No he's dead!
That's what happens when they
find a special person like us.
You're dead!
Period.
You know they always fed us this
crap about Madoc Mountain
was gonna be a new home for us
and a place where we
could be independent.
It's a goddamn death trap.
Why did you want to live there?
We didn't want to live there.
We had to get inside it and
the only way to get inside was
to pretend we wanted
to go there.
I'll be goddamned if I'm gonna
let anybody including you
get in the way of me
saving my daughter.
But she's dead.
I don't understand.
Well you don't really have
to understand.
You're seven years old
for Christ's sake and you,
you have to allow me to teach
you to use your powers now!
I don't wanna!
I'm giving Nancy the whole
shebang to take care of me.
No you're not.
You're not giving
her that money.
We're going home
to my apartment.
Take me home.
What?
Take me home!
TAKE ME HOME!
Get out of my goddamn head!
Take me back.
Now.
Alright I'll take you back.
Jesus Christ.
Goddamnit!
Get out of the truck Chloe!
Stay there.
Don't you worry.
I'll take care of this.
Daddy!
Grandpa stabbed a guy!
And we also met a real bad guy!
- But she was a girl-
- Get in the house.
Looking good, Henry.
You're coming with me.
Chloe!
No Daddy!
I don't want to go back
to the house!
I looked everywhere for a week.
I want to go to Nancy's house!
I can't handle you anymore.
No Daddy let me go!
What do I have to do
to make you listen?
Let me go!
Let me down!
Chloe!
You're special too Daddy?
I tried so hard to protect you.
I created a time bubble around
our house to keep you safe.
It worked as long as I could
stay awake.
For the rest of the world it's
only been a couple of months
since they killed Mom
and we started hiding.
But for us inside the
house you grew up years.
Everything is changing so fast.
I wish I could stop time
permanently
but I can't keep you in
the bubble forever.
I'm ready.
What are you doing here?
Is everything okay?
This has to happen now Steve.
Um you know we're actually right
in the middle of dinner.
I brought dessert.
Okay.
Okay, yes.
Come on in. Come on in.
Honey we have guests.
Eleanor.
Mom why is she here?
I'm Eleanor Reed.
I'm seven and a half
and I like baseball.
Sweetie are you hungry?
Come on sit down.
I'll get you some food.
Uh, okay.
Are you joining us too?
- No.
You were supposed to give us
more notice.
It's only been a month.
We haven't even told Harper yet.
After today you've never going
to see me again.
You'll get one of these
every month
as long as you don't call
the ADF.
Please take good care of her.
Okay.
I'm Eleanor.
My birthday is March 9th and
I live at 726 Monroe Street.
That's where we live.
Harper.
How would you feel if
Eleanor stayed with us
for a little while?
Her?
Yes!
No! No, she's weird.
Harper, sweetie.
Why are you being like this?
I see her in my room at night.
She makes me do things.
- What kind of things?
- That's impossible.
- What do you mean, Harper?
- She's never left the house until today.
She crashed my slumber party.
Okay?
She forces me to...
She's just a regular kid!
She's a freak!
Okay.
Alright, you know what-
She makes me hug her
and kiss her at night.
What?
Maybe we need some
more time to decide.
Okay Nancy, just-
Please.
I just think we need to-
We can't afford
to say no, Nancy.
Yes we can afford. Yes we can.
That is our daughter-
I knew he was a freak
but not her.
Honey, honey, honey...
No! Don't tell me to.
- Don't say it.
- Can we calm down for one sec?
Just calm down for one second,
please!
Eleanor, you're fine, right?
Everything's alright.
You're my Dad, Steven.
You like to fish but
you're not very good at it.
Uh...
Tell me you love me.
Um...
Sure.
Love you.
Do you love me Mom?
You know what, I'm - I'm sorry.
This is all a bit sudden.
I just need a little bit
more time.
I think it's time for you to go
and we'll discuss this later.
I just need a little bit
more time.
No our deal-
Tell me you love me.
Our deal was that she was
basically normal.
No!
We had a deal.
When you think about it-
Our deal was that she was
not a freak!
Tell me you love me.
I think you should both go
so it doesn't get out of hand,
just, please.
Tell me you love me!
Nancy can we think about
this for one second?
Tell me you love me!
I love you. I love you.
I love you.
I love you sweetie. I love you.
You're my sweet little girl.
Let me go.
She got into my head.
Get out!
- Get out of here!
- Just keep the money!
Get out or I'm calling 911!
Get out of here!
- Just keep the money.
- I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I'm so sorry.
Sorry Daddy
What the hell is going on?
I don't want you to get mad.
When did this start?
You were supposed to tell me
when your eyes started bleeding.
What did she do now?
Shut up Alan!
What do you mean, shut up Alan?
No! Please!
I can't trust you anymore to
follow the rules and stay safe.
You can't do that to people.
I promise I'll listen to you.
I won't go outside.
How long have you known?
What the hell do you think
you're gonna do?
Lock her up forever?
I'm keeping her safe from you.
Oh for Christ's sake.
In a shitbag like this?
You're not awake all the time
like you say you are.
Don't start with your bullshit.
She happens to be exactly what
we've been waiting for asshole!
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Shhh.
Up in the sky
birds sing a song
between the clouds
they sing their love.
You'll always be
here with me, right?
Of course, sweetheart.
Even after they kill me.
I'll be right here.
Right here.
Okay?
But you're already dead.
I'm not yet, honey.
Not yet.
Don't fucking touch me!
Don't!
Looks like you pissed off
somebody upstairs
so finally you are going to pay.
No!
Chloe!
Help!
Help me Chloe!
I said stay in the closet!
They're taking Mom away!
Your mom's dead!
She's not dead, yet!
Let me out! Let me out!
You have to follow the rules!
We have to save Mom!
Please let me out!
This is for your own good!
I'm trying to keep you safe!
Let me out!
Daddy please!
I'm sorry!
Let me out! Let me out!
Let me out!
If you don't let me out
I'm going to kill you!
Chloe?
Chloe? Chloe!
Chloe! Stop!
Chloe stop, stop, stop!
No, no!
I'm sorry love.
I'm so sorry.
I shouldn't have done that.
Are you okay?
Say something.
Hey. Hey.
She's coming back.
Hey.
I'm sorry.
It's my fault.
I was just scared.
I shouldn't have done that
to you.
Where's Mom?
What did you see there?
Don't start.
What do you mean?
If she had a vision of Mary
I gotta know it.
How could she have a vision
of Mary if Mary's dead?
Alan?
She's not dead yet.
She's in the mountain.
What?
Look.
When I found out that she
wasn't dead it was too late
because you'd already taken
off with the kid.
Jesus Christ!
I thought she was dead.
You left her there!
No! I barely got out myself!
And you know what-
They're going to kill her.
She needs help.
Dad!
Yeah of course I blame you!
You forced my wife to go
on a suicide mission!
She's my daughter!
You left her there.
It may have only been a few
months for you Alan
but I've been in this house
for 7 fucking years!
Well that's your problem!
You're fucking nuts!
You can't go crazy on me.
We need to be partners.
Maybe we can get her out.
I have tried again and again
and again while you're in here
digging around and
taping up mail slots
or whatever the
hell you're doing.
I'm not talking about one
of your ridiculous ideas.
The only way you're going to get
in there is if they let you in.
And the only way they will let
you in is with her.
Oh, Chloe is going to have
nothing to do with this.
No! Chloe is gonna do it!
Dad!
Are you insane?!
- I'm not insane!
- Grandpa!
I'm telling the truth! You've
never accepted the truth.
There's only one way in there
and that's with her.
Face it.
She gets us in!
Which gets Mary out!
Dad!
What?
A wolf is here.
And when we do we get
the reward?
When we verify their status.
You'll be well taken care of.
Okay, and you'll take them
to Madoc Mountain?
I can't have them coming
back here.
They'll know it was me.
Madoc isn't set up to handle
Abnormal children.
Too risky.
Besides since Mary Louis
tried to blow the place up
a few months ago they've
kept it mostly empty.
And suspects only make it there
if they don't resist.
And they usually resist.
Good.
That little Freak does things
to my daughter at night.
You can't hide this little girl
on your own anymore.
I gotta help.
Come on to my place.
I got it all figured out.
No.
Well then go out there and
take care of all of your shit!
I don't kill anymore.
Well I suggest that this might
be the perfect time
to get over that phobia
because if this man orders
a strike we're done.
We're dust.
You got that?
Hello?
Sir is everything okay?
No!
Chloe! No! No! No!
No! No!
She's a bleeder!
Stop resisting!
Open fire!
Look what you've done.
What I've done?
Chloe saved us.
She saved us!
Come here honey.
Get out!
No!
Alan!
Let me go!
Let her go!
Let me down!
Where are you, you
invisible asshole?
Let her go!
Let me go!
Let me down!
Chloe!
If I ever see you again
I'll kill you,
you piece of shit!
Mommy. Mommy. Mommy.
Mommy.
Mommy?
Chloe?
Is that you?
Mommy?
Where are you?
Are they killing you now Mommy?
Mary.
Henry?
I'm so scared.
Device is armed.
Ready to begin procedure
immediately.
Go ahead.
Do it.
I didn't - I didn't know
you were alive.
I never would have left.
I'm so sorry.
No.
It's all my fault.
Don't do that.
Just promise me you won't
let them touch Chloe.
Promise me you won't let
them get away with this!
Oh my God.
Chloe.
I love you, okay?
Mommy loves you so much.
Don't forget that.
Mommy loves you so much, okay?
Chloe?
I love you, okay?
- Mommy loves you so much.
- What are you doing with that?
Hey!
Goddamnit you can't
do this to her!
Chloe!
We need your help!
Get away from her!
Damnit!
Don't do it!!!
No, no, no...
Is something wrong?
What are you doing?
No, no, no!
Stop it!
No! No!
I love you too, Mommy.
Chloe?
Oh my god.
Shit!
Shit.
Now, no, no, you gotta
hold still for a minute.
Just like that.
Doesn't hurt, does it?
We need to leave.
Now.
You froze everyone.
I'm already too drained.
I can't hold this for long,
okay?
Then bring it back to normal.
Then they'll get in!
She wants to start a prison
break from the inside.
But she can't do it if everyone
is frozen!
We need to get out of here.
I don't want to hide anymore.
Chloe.
Listen to me.
The bad people are outside.
If anything happens
to the agent out there,
we are never getting out
of here alive.
I can save Mom.
It's our last chance.
Talk to the lady outside.
Just pretend you're normal.
What?
Like you taught me.
I hate to be the one
to break it to you
but you really look like shit
Thanks.
Here. Hydrogen peroxide.
It'll clear your eyes.
You know something else?
I got your back.
And I've got a blue shirt
that matches your eyes.
Wow.
My eyes are green Alan.
They are?
But thanks.
Hi.
Is everything okay?
Sorry to bother you.
I'm Special Agent Cecilia Ray.
ADF.
ADF?
There are freaks around?
They're under our control.
Can I ask you some questions?
I was just leaving actually.
I have an appointment downtown.
It's important.
Can I come inside?
Any weapons in the house?
No.
None that I know of.
Squatters have been in
and out so I don't know
what they get up to.
Take your glasses off.
So you don't live here?
Huh?
Oh, no.
I'm just the owner.
You know I bought it with six
other condemned shitholes.
I get in there and I tear them
down and I build them up.
If you're in the market
let me know.
I found all this stuff here
this morning
and I came to check it out.
Looks like there could have
been a child here.
You don't think they were
Freaks do you?
Could be.
Abnormals are known to hide in
abandoned properties like this.
Disgusting animals.
Are you a father?
Yeah.
Yes I am.
Boy or girl?
Boy.
If you knew he'd be killed on
site wouldn't you do anything
you could to keep him safe?
Yeah.
I guess I would.
I'd love to meet him.
Little devil's in summer camp.
Chloe.
What do we do now Mom?
I need to get outside.
I can't defend myself
until I get outside.
Can you help?
Yes Mommy but we have
to be quiet
because the bad people
are here too.
Okay but Chloe, listen to me,
there's not enough room for me
to use my powers
underground here
so we have to get out
before they sound the alarm
because if it goes off I will
never be able to escape.
You understand?
Yes.
Okay, come on.
So uh...
what happened across the street?
The Reed family.
Turns out they were Abnormals.
Oh Jesus.
There goes my sale price.
I never, you know,
thought this neighbourhood
would have Freaks in it.
Makes sense though I guess.
How so?
Eh well you know, when I was
checking out this street
I saw them.
They were strange, you know.
Accusing their neighbours
of stuff,
lying all the time, random
piles of money around the house.
And you didn't report them?
I didn't think they were Freaks.
Just thought they were assholes
but I guess you
really can't tell.
They look just like us, right?
Anyways I really need to get
to this appointment so...
Sit.
Down.
What?
I know who you are.
Excuse me?
This house according
to city records
was foreclosed six months ago.
Western Trust Bank owns it.
Yeah, no, I'm actually
a developer;
I work with the bank.
Henry.
That's not the name of
the bank that owns it.
And I can still smell
the peroxide on your face.
Henry.
You are Henry Louis right?
Your wife is Mary
and I'm pretty sure
your daughter is upstairs.
Look.
It seems to me at this point
you have two options.
One.
You can try to kill me at which
point my colleagues
will hellfire the house
and we will all die.
There's a Reaper 10,000 feet
above us right now.
Option two, and the reason
I came in here alone,
was to convince you that
you can help Eleanor.
Or Chloe.
Whatever her name is.
I'm listening.
Hey Rob.
Did you see the game?
Dodgers are in, man.
Playoffs this year.
Baseball is my favourite sport.
Yeah.
Yeah, me too, Rob.
I'm a parent too.
I know you want the best
for Chloe.
If half of what your neighbours
say is true about her,
she's remarkable.
And very valuable to us.
Valuable?
Valuable as a weapon.
No, no, no, no.
As a symbol.
With us she'd be safe and
with the right training
she could even do some good
in the world.
Wouldn't you want that?
Will I ever get to see
her again?
I want to be honest with you so
that you know you can trust me.
You will be killed.
You will sacrifice
your life for hers.
But I mean, you've already
been doing that, haven't you?
I never wanted the world
to turn her into a Freak.
She's just a girl.
I know exactly what you mean.
And you?
Won't you put the gun down
and do what's best
for your granddaughter?
A hellfire missile takes 60
seconds from launch to strike.
And he and I both know
that in that 60 seconds
we can do a goddamn
bunch of damage.
Alan.
Calm down.
We need more time to think.
Dr. Daulby didn't radio
in after procedure.
Can you go to the
execution chamber
and see if he's in there?
Copy that. On my way.
Mommy?
They're gonna find out.
Chloe?
No!
Chloe!
Oh shit!
Nobody move.
You're not gonna shoot me.
Hold the hellfire.
I'm coming out with the girl.
No, Chloe! No! No! Chloe!
No! Come on!
Oh my God.
You're freeing her.
Such a waste.
Oh, no.
Chloe. No, no.
Don't do this.
Don't you dare!
Don't you want a normal life?
Grandpa!
I'm fine.
Just go to your Mom.
Let's go get it done.
Agent Ray.
Agent Ray, come in!
Agent Ray. We heard gunfire.
Agent Ray, do you copy?
Let's try to slow them down.
I have your agent hostage.
Move away from the house.
Keep going.
Okay sir.
Let's just try to calm down.
I just want to talk
to Agent Ray alright.
You better get away
from my house
or I'm going to melt all your
brains with my Freak powers!
Okay no problem sir.
We're moving back.
I just want to make sure
my friend's okay.
Dad!
I can't help Mom
when she's frozen!
Just a second honey!
Launch hellfire!
Stay back! Stay back!
Let's go! Let's go!
Move it! Move it! Move it!
Chloe, can you hear me?
I need you!
Chloe! I need you!
Chloe, get up! I need
to get outside!
Chloe please get up,
you can do this.
You can do it Chloe.
Chloe can you hear me?
Open the door!
They're going to kill me!
I need you!
You know where to find me mommy?
Yeah, I can feel you.
Daddy?
Dad?
Wake up!
Dad!
Can you hear me?
Hey.
I'm so proud of you.
I love you so much!
And I am so sorry.
You are special.
Partners?
Partners.
No!
Please come back.
Come back.
No.
Please come back.
Wake up.
Wake up, wake up, wake up!
Come back, come back, come back.
Oh shit!
Mom?
Chloe!
Are you okay?
Listen to me.
I will protect you
from now on, okay?
And we'll find a new place
to hide.
No.
I don't want to hide anymore.
I'm sorry baby, but we have to.
We have to.
We can live wherever we want.
And if anyone bothers us, we
know how to make them stop.
Okay.
You ready?
Yeah?
Hold on.