FRED JÜSSI
THE BEAUTY OF BEING
A FILM BY JAAN TOOTSEN
I'm no researcher or a scientist.
Rather, I'm an observer.
And I've focused on relationships,
as constituents of a whole.
This beauty
has captivated me.
And sharing this beauty,
or experiences of it, with others
suits me best.
I sought a more intimate contact
with this world through education,
so I studied biology.
Recording the sounds of nature
as well as nature photography
have been a means of perception.
And they've been very enriching.
It broadens your world.
I discovered a whole new world
once I started living
via my ears. It's surprising!
I can't tell how much photography
has enriched my perception of
colour and form. And light!
My comprehension of light.
What is this light we live in?
Such a mundane thing.
But as you delve into it and as it
gains importance in your work,
new layers begin
to reveal themselves.
Awareness is important.
All we need is all around us.
And some things are just given.
For example, we're all given
a course to follow.
This course is yours alone.
The course is important.
As for the destination...
It might sound odd,
but I'm one of those people
who doesn't have goals in life.
Nor principles.
Not that I'm depraved
or wholly unambitious,
but I trust my course.
And if you trust it,
if you hold true to your course
and follow the chime of this inner
sound that you're compelled to hear,
you'll surely reach
your destination.
And I've experienced that as that
unseen or unknown destination nears,
the clearer
it shows itself.
And when you're finally there,
you'll exclaim with surprise,
'Ah, so that's where I was headed!
I've reached my goal.'
When I speak of silence
as the shaper of a person,
I'm thinking of the profound effect
silence has had on my relations with
nature,
people,
music,
visual arts,
poetry...
Because silence is inherent
in all these realms, and many others.
Either directly
or indirectly.
Thus, I think of silence
as a natural resource.
Being your own companion,
accepting yourself,
learning to live with yourself
is no easy feat.
That's why, I've noticed,
people are afraid of silence.
Silence has
its own measure.
Make no mistake, I'm not saying
silence is some ultimate bliss.
That all is fine
so long as it's silent.
No, silence has its measure.
And it's different for all people.
One has to bear it,
while another needs it...
It depends on
one's nature, I guess.
You might see
a glade of cowslips.
Or marsh-marigolds growing
on a riverbank, in springtime.
Or an underbrush
covered with liverleafs
and later aglow
with thimbleweeds.
But finding what's truly yours
in all that glory takes time.
That's how
a relationship grows.
These bonds are the main asset
when you're your own company.
Some might say they're
alone when they're out.
In a forest or at a seaside,
in a meadow or a marsh...
But really,
I'm not alone.
There's so much talk of
hard work and success...
'Grow your business!
Grow yourself!'
So that you end up
with no time for yourself.
You have to have
time for yourself.
You can't let others organise your
weekends and evenings and mornings,
and whatever else...
You need time
for idling!
We've been taught
to work hard.
Now we ought to be taught
to slack off.
That is, to rest.
Sometimes you have to be
sinfully slothful and by yourself.
In April 1983
I recorded a nocturnal bird.
I recorded its songs and the silence
dwelling in the pauses between them.
It sounds as if I did so in a church
because it sang its nightly song
in a forest of tall pine trees.
Like pillars supporting arches.
That is, treetops
merging overhead.
I managed to send a copy of that
recording from the USSR to England,
since I had some great contacts
at the BBC Natural History Unit.
Surprisingly, I received a letter
of gratitude urging me to send them
silence from
a coniferous forest.
That was my first encounter
with silence as a commodity.
I like listening to water.
It's a peculiar pleasure.
I even have my own
spots for doing it.
You sit down by a river and start
catching different tones in its flow.
It runs fast in some places,
over rocks. Lazily in others.
Over a fallen tree, say.
There are higher and lower sounds.
It's fascinating
to listen to!
The cosmos
that surrounds us,
that is so awe-inspiring
and so admired by us,
so secret and mystical...
It's actually a continuum!
It continues... All it has,
I have – within myself.
Like a droplet of water
from snowmelt or rain...
It's hanging on a branch
and when you take a closer look,
you see the whole landscape in it:
the upturned forest, flower fields...
Whatever it may show you,
tiny though it is.
Everything's in it.
And I, too, am such a droplet!
I'm no churchgoer.
Though I like visiting them,
whether home or abroad,
to sit awhile and
listen and look, and take it all in.
But my church
is the forest.
And as for my religiosity,
if I can even call it that,
it has everything to do
with the forest, the trees...
I find it unfathomable
that people don't appreciate
or love living trees...
I've never understood it.
Come summer, I like to go out
and gaze at clouds passing by...
For us northerners, summer is
a time to recharge, rest and settle.
Cicadas and grasshoppers chirping
adds a lot to the experience.
A blowfly or a bumblebee
might pass through.
And there you are,
gazing at clouds.
Fully immersed
in doing nothing!
Just idling,
quite literally.
But it's like
a purification.
Looking at the clouds,
at the sky,
I enter a realm
of no notions.
In it, there's no good or bad,
no big or small.
No thoughts even...
I've noticed, on these occasions
I'm not thinking at all.
It's a 'state of mind', yet it's also
a realm without such concepts.
Gandhi has said that the world
has enough for everyone's need,
but not enough
for everyone's greed.
That, it cannot sustain.
My time here
is almost up.
And I've often thought
I'm glad, in a way,
that I don't have to witness
how our GDP is further 'raised'.
Traversing boglands
is not easy.
Viktor Masing has said that
the fact one can't hurry in a bog
is reason enough
to visit one.
This is something
our oldest landscape can teach us.
It was a very quiet,
moonlit night.
A lone dog
was barking far off.
You can reach
a very peculiar
state of mind
in complete silence.
Away from the
clamour of the world
and wandering
around in a forest...
That moonlight contains all the
moonlit nights of my conscious life.
Suddenly, they all
spring to life.
And so you
stand there, and look...
Not at the moon so much,
but at what it does to the landscape.
How it changes a forest,
or a river valley...
Or the grass, fence pickets,
a chimney on a roof, its shingles.
I remember, in early childhood
I was often terribly ill.
And a few times,
I had a vision.
It was only many years later
that I met a very wise old woman.
And we had many talks
on different topics
I've not discussed
with anyone else.
I described my vision to her.
Though it's hard to convey visually.
She looked at me and I asked her
if she knew what I had experienced.
'I do,' she said.
'That was death.'
'It neared.
But didn't take you.'
Though I recall feeling dread
before that vision, as a child,
I didn't know it had anything to do
with the fear of death.
And I haven't given much heed
to grand ideas about the afterlife
and all that.
I know nothing of my birth,
or what this world was like
before I came about.
Similarly, I know nothing
of leaving this world.
I've no point
of reference even!
So I haven't bothered to think
where I go and what comes next.
Juhan Liiv has said that
poetry is like wind,
but without wind,
the earth would stink.
At times I spend hours
listening to the wind.
Especially in a pine forest.
When the flaking bark
vibrates in the wind.
It makes this music.
You can hear a whole symphony in it.
Wind makes no sound by itself.
But you can hear it as it enters
an old windmill or a chimney flue
and rattles the stove door
as you're making a fire.
And what the wind does to the sea
is familiar to every Estonian.
Wind... can be a sign of danger
but also a great companion.
A very calming companion.
Like sounds of the sea,
wind sounds can be
very calming.
There was a time when
I went out to hear birdsong.
And finally I reached
an age and a period in my life
where I go out
to hear living silence.
It's a great pleasure.
A lot can be said about the level
of culture of a land or a people
by how highly it regards and
cares for its natural resources.
How well-studied and known they are,
'resources' in the broadest sense,
how well-preserved they are...
It's purely a matter of culture.
I spent last Christmas
in the forest.
I've been alone
since my wife died.
And I had little desire to go
visit someone as usual.
To be someone's guest,
sit at a table and...
well...
play at celebrating Christmas,
as insolent as it may sound.
But I felt things might
turn out that way,
if I couldn't spend Christmas
by myself – and by my campfire.
By the smell of its smoke.
I need it!
Just as some need oxygen to live,
I need my fire and its smell.
It's one of my
favourite aromas.
It's some innate need
that stems from one's nature.
And if you're at all able to follow
your nature, then please do.
Though a person who does
doesn't have it easy
once they've
recognised their nature.
It means you have to remain
true to yourself in all situations.
Which isn't
always possible.
But whenever possible,
try and follow your nature.