Subtitles by explosiveskull
You know, Steph, it's not
like I haven't tried, okay?
I never know how you're
gonna react to anything.
I... I... Every single day
is a different emotion,
I come home to a
different situation,
something I have to deal with.
Something that is oppressive.
That's just mentally draining.
Over the past eight months,
I began to realize that,
dating you
has been harder on me
mentally, spiritually,
and every other kind of way that
I could possibly have imagined.
I started smoking.
You can't tell me you had
nothing to do with that.
I never cheated on you.
I know you didn't.
I know.
But there's more to it
than that.
You're an awful person.
Honestly, I mean, I... Your
friends must fucking lie to you
because no one is telling
you the truth.
I'm the one who has to deal
with it every single day. Me.
Your... your mood swings,
your attitudes,
you're being manipulative,
you're selfish.
You treat all your
friends like shit.
That's not true.
You know how you
are with people.
You know that, and...
if I don't get out now,
you're gonna ruin me,
like you ruined all of them.
You said that we were the same.
How could you be
so mean to me?
Stephanie, do you ever think the reason
we don't work is because we are the same?
Same person.
We're both
extremely fucked up.
I'm just gonna nip it in the bud
and tell you how I feel right now,
it's what I'm doing.
And honestly, I think you should, if
anything, you should respect me for that.
Shit.
Can I get my stuff?
I got somewhere I gotta be.
Yeah.
I'll get your stuff.
Thanks.
Hey, would you...
would you relax?
Yes, I know.
I'm doing it now.
Yeah, and in ten minutes
this crazy bitch will be
in the fucking rear-view
mirror, just relax.
Yeah, I know.
I never called you a piece
on the side, so shut up.
Yeah.
Yeah, I love you.
What the fuck?
Are you fucking crazy?
We were perfect together,
Chad.
We could have been
so much more.
Hey! What's up?
I... I really need you.
Okay.
Yeah?
I need you to drop whatever
you're doing and get over here.
What happened?
Something bad, okay?
I just need you.
I'll be there as soon as I can.
Good.
Hey, I like what you
did with your hair.
It's kind of different
and awesome, you know?
Or not.
Okay, Stephanie,
what do you want us to do?
Where should we go?
As far away as possible.
Are we really gonna do this?
Yeah.
Okay.
Are you sure
we're out far enough?
I still see lights out there.
It's the desert,
we're miles away.
Hey.
It's okay.
I told you to fucking
cut the lights.
I left them on so you could... so you
could see what you're doing, okay?
I left them on so you could see what you're doing.
- Son of a bitch.
- What the heck?
Come on,
everything's gonna be fine.
- Come on, let's...
- Don't touch me right now.
Really?
Carrie, come take care
of your friend.
Sorry.
Fuck!
What the fuck?
Fuck it.
What?
- What?
- Don't want to say.
Good for you.
- Are you kidding me?
- No.
I told you to fucking cut
the lights.
Son of a bitch!
Didn't think the battery was gonna die from
leaving the light on for, like, two seconds.
So, uh, what I'm gonna do is, I'm
just gonna hike up to the road,
and I'll hitchhike so...
we can get another car
over here, okay?
No. That's the worst idea.
It's not a bad idea. I mean,
we're just gonna be stuck...
Dave's the idea guy.
Yeah, the idea guy that got our car dead
and now we're in the middle of nowhere.
It's not a bad idea, okay?
They're not going to allow four
people to hitchhike with them, so...
- We shouldn't leave the car...
- No, we... Yeah,
- we're gonna stay together.
- No, Steph. Why don't...
No, no one's staying together,
we can stay here with the car
and some of us can go find
somebody else to jump the car.
No, we're gonna
all stay together...
And stay here? Just hang out,
wait for the body to rot?
No, we're gonna
go together and get a car
and then come back here
and get rid of this mess.
- And just leave the car here?
- Okay?
Together. We are not leaving
each others' sights.
- We can't leave the car
- Great.
We'll come back and jump
the car and we'll go, okay?
Jeb, let's just go.
Okay.
Great. Let's go.
Do you need a light?
Thank you very much.
Just go.
- It's a good idea, Jeb.
- Here we go.
The sooner we get this done, the
sooner we can stop complaining
and go back to our normal lives.
Let's go.
I know this is messed up,
but this isn't... this isn't her,
this is just an off day.
- An off day?
- Yeah.
An off day? Carrie,
she just buried a body.
I mean, it's not like that
happens all the time.
Jeb, she is my friend.
She's my best friend.
I mean, we have to support her.
I get that you two are close,
I can accept that.
But look, I don't know her shit,
and neither do you. Okay?
I mean, I don't know. All I know is
that she's usually not like this
and she's the only person who's
ever really been there for me.
- She...
- Oh, okay.
Okay, before I met you,
she was the only person.
The only person
who cared about me.
Please can we just trust her?
Please?
Fine. All right.
If you want to stay here,
that's what we're doing, okay?
But just know,
that I am here for you.
Not her.
All right?
And the minute that bitch tries
to throw you under the bus,
I'm gonna park it on top
of her. You got it?
Got it.
Good.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Come on.
What happened?
What do you mean?
You know,
between you and...
Mister Perfect.
Um, none of your business...
that's what happened.
Well, I think that because maybe the fact
that I'm helping you quite a bit here,
that I deserve to get some
kind of information.
Just the slightest
information, at all.
I just don't want
to talk about it.
Come on, you know I'm not
gonna tell anyone.
I mean, I'm here helping
you out.
We're on the same team.
You don't need to know anything.
If you were in my position,
you'd do the same thing.
So you can
just leave it alone.
Okay, fine, whatever. Just...
No, it's not whatever,
you just drop it.
Stephanie treats Dave
like a puppy.
Yeah, well, he's been warned
and he still does it anyway.
You gotta be nicer to me. I'm not...
I'm not like this other guy.
It's not fair.
What are we gonna do?
I don't know.
I mean, she's not even
acknowledging it.
She's not saying anything.
Hey, if you have something to say,
why don't you say it to my face?
Take it easy, all right?
I think that we should make
some kind of plan.
Okay, when I figure it out,
I'll let you know.
Okay, well, we're waiting,
so any minute now would be nice.
Steph, we can figure out some kind of plan
together before we go back and get a car.
I'm figuring it out, so until
then, shut the hell up!
- Stephanie, we need an alibi, okay?
- Great.
Hear her out. Come on.
Okay, do you have any ideas?
'Cause right now,
you're just complaining.
Yeah. Yeah, I think I do.
You think you do, or you do?
Okay, what if we never left
your house, right?
What if, um,
we were still there?
Having a party or something,
you know, drinking.
We could take pictures to commemorate
whatever we're celebrating.
We can pretend that we were,
I mean, all together.
That's a good idea.
- At your house.
- That's a great idea.
- So...
- Do you still have those beers?
Yeah, it's... gonna...
Brilliant, okay, that's
actually a really good idea.
- Really?
- Yeah, yeah, it's great.
- One for you.
- It's really good.
Who's got a camera?
- I do... I have my phone,
- Yeah great.
You want it now? Okay.
- Yeah.
- Turn off your lights.
- Okay.
- Hide the flashlights.
No lights, and, um,
just get our faces.
Yeah, okay.
- Um.
No, like, Joshua tree's
in the background.
Okay, everybody in? You guys,
come in closer, Dave.
Okay, one, two, ah!
- Yeah? Again?
- One more.
- You want to do a silly face?
- Yeah.
Okay, one, two,
we're having a party.
We're having a party? Yeah,
this is a great party.
- That's my party face.
- Brilliant.
- All right, perfect.
- It was actually a really good idea.
- Let's go.
- It was brilliant.
- You think so?
- It was really good.
- Yeah, okay.
- You remember, like, three years ago?
When I wasn't in your life? I doubt you
would have had an idea as great as that.
Hmm, probably not.
Steph, can we... can we
just take a break? I just...
We've been walking forever,
I'm just exhausted.
Wait, you're just gonna sit here
in the middle of the desert?
Yeah, it's... We're tired.
Come on, it's... Oh my God,
I'm so tired and cold and we
don't have any water. Just...
- Fine.
- just five minutes.
Fine.
Oh, should we get the boys?
No, they will be fine.
All right,
so I just have to ask,
how did you wind up
chasing after that?
Whatever you think of her, she's
actually pretty awesome, okay?
Really, 'cause awesome people
don't murder their boyfriends.
All right? She could have keyed
his car or burned his clothes,
murder kinda takes it to
a different level.
She's spontaneous.
Why are you always
standing up for her?
Okay, I understand this is an awful
situation but she's bringing us together
and she's keeping us safe. And I
know you only see her in, like, a...
a bad light,
but she's more than that.
You sound like a cult follower.
Jeb, I love that girl.
- I love her.
- Oh.
I know she's crazy but she
goes after what she wants.
- And I'm a part of that.
- Yes! Dave, you are.
You're being used.
All girls are manipulative, Jeb.
And sometimes it's far worse
than this.
You don't want more?
Of course I want more,
but that's...
You know, I'm just trying to
hold on to what I have.
So you just showed
up one day and said,
"Oh, hey,
I'll worship you.
Pick me."
Yep, you're right, Jeb.
You got it right on the nose.
You know something? I've know Carrie
a lot longer than I've known Steph.
My Carrie?
Yeah, we were really close.
But then she introduced
me to Steph,
and then I fell for her.
And she's, yeah...
Oh, well that's a love story
of epic proportions.
I didn't know that.
But you know, then the whole
Stephanie thing happened.
No, I don't know.
She even told me to not, uh, pursue Stephanie,
saying I was going to ruin everything.
Yeah, but you did...
you did it anyway.
- Jeb, I know you think I'm this loser.
- Mm-hmm.
But the real question is,
why was Carrie so upset that I
was pursuing Steph and not her?
I don't know,
maybe it's because she knew
Steph was a trainwreck.
She was trying to protect
you from that.
Because that's what
good friends do.
Oh, thanks, you know, friends don't
let friends pursue true happiness.
No, you see, I was thinking, friends don't
let friends pursue bad relationships
that ultimately
lead to murder.
Or maybe you
missed that class.
Why are you here, Jeb?
I'm not gonna let Carrie run around in
the desert by herself with Stephanie.
You know, uh, the two of 'em
are more alike than you think.
Carrie is nothing
like that sociopath.
Oh, yes, she is.
They are really close friends
and they rub off on each other.
I would be careful.
- Be careful?
- Yup, careful.
Yeah, well you fuckers
deserve one another.
Okay, I'm gonna get
us out of here,
and you're right,
this... this is a chance
for a fresh start.
So, I was thinking,
remember in high school when
we'd have all those sleepovers
and they were really fun?
I was thinking that we should
move in together.
Like, we always talked about making
it happen but we never made it happen
and now this could be our
chance.
We could go out to clubs and have
parties, and late night movies.
It would be so much fun.
Steph, I can't.
You can't?
Why because of that asshole Jeb?
Don't say that,
he's my boyfriend.
You depend way too much on him.
He is a guy.
He will either hurt you,
or leave you, or both.
I am here to protect you from
those assholes,
one day he's gonna be gone,
and then you will be
left with just me,
so you might as well
get used to it now.
Because I am the only one who is there to pick
up the pieces when your life falls apart.
I know.
Steph, uh, I, um, I...
Oh, my god, spit it out.
You know that drives me crazy.
I just wanted to say that
I'm sorry Chad hurt you.
Oh. Thanks.
I never understood why
you were with him.
He never treated you right.
I saw the marks no matter how
hard you tried to cover them up.
And the rumors that he was seeing
other girls and he just...
He made you so unhappy.
I always thought that you
deserved better.
Dave, he loves you.
I mean, he would do
anything for you.
And then there are days that...
you treat him so bad.
As bad as Chad treated you.
I mean, why?
I don't... I don't get it.
Sometimes people do things that
don't make sense.
Okay, Dave is good.
He's funny and he's caring,
and he would do whatever
I say with a smile.
Um, I love him,
I do.
But I will destroy him.
That's not true.
I deserved Chad.
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
How did you kill him?
I strangled him.
Uh, no, I mean...
I know physically, like, how you
killed him, I mean, um...
What does it feel like
to take a life?
Was it hard?
Power.
There is nothing like it.
In that moment I felt...
powerful.
So much anger built up.
I was unstoppable.
You know, it sounds weird,
but I hope you get to experience
that for yourself one day.
Me? I...
I don't think I could.
Oh, you can do it, Carrie.
I mean, you are stronger
than you think you are.
I even felt a little
bit guilty, but...
every regretful thought
that I have
about killing that piece
of shit goes away
because I know I did what I needed
to do in that moment to survive.
And I would do it again
in a heartbeat.
You think something's
out there?
Hey, hey, what happened?
Uh.
Oh, geez.
Are you okay?
It's just a little prick.
Yeah, I'll say it is.
Get the hell out of my hand.
I'm sorry.
It's Joshua tree, it's just a piece of cactus.
You're fine.
Great, okay, break's over.
The sooner we get out of this
man-eating desert the better.
Dave, you should have
printed out a memo.
Yeah, next murder, I expect a full
breakdown of indigenous species,
plant life, oh, and, um,
restaurants.
Please, that would be
awesome next time.
I hope there's not a next time.
Yep.
Do you hear that?
Hello?
There's a footstep...
there's a footstep out there.
Okay, there's something
out there!
I swear to God.
Did you not hear that?
Keep your cool, come on, just got
a little bit more ways to go.
Shut up,
there's someone there.
What the fuck?
- What?
What the fuck happened?
- Holy shit!
- What the fuck?
Oh, fuck.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Oh, my God.
What the fuck happened?
No! Hey, hey! Shh! Don't fucking
do that shit, come on.
- I knew this would happen.
- No.
- I got you, okay.
- Jeb, how is this... how is this possible?
We're back where we started, how
is that even happening? I don't...
Hey, it's all right.
Just stay here, okay?
Everything's gonna be fine,
all right?
Hey, everything's gonna be okay,
all right? Hold this.
This is all your fucking fault.
How is this my fault,
Stephanie?
We all went together like
it was your plan.
- Okay?
- Fucking retarded.
Everything's fine,
everyone's okay.
- What if I had fucking been here?
- How is this my...
What do you think would have
happened to me if you left me here?
- Okay, good...
- Or Carrie and Jeb,
what do you think
would have happened to them?
- How is this my fault?
- Are you kidding me?
I'm just helping you out,
Stephanie.
Yeah, a lot you've done.
The car's dead. This is
amazing, you've helped so much,
I'm so happy that you're here
right now.
Everything's fine.
Everyone's okay.
Nobody's okay, we're in the middle
of nowhere with a dead fucking car!
I haven't seen one
of these in forever.
That is not mine.
Why is that here?
Let's see what's
on this bad boy.
Guys, that's us.
What the fuck?
Someone's been fucking
watching us.
I can't, I can't.
Every single one of us.
Our faces.
Fucking shit.
Carrie.
Oh, no.
Oh, fuck.
What the fuck is he, man?
Oh, fuck, dude.
Fuck.
We shouldn't have come here.
Because of the Joshua tree.
What about the Joshua tree?
It only grows in two places,
two places in the whole world.
Jerusalem, which is
the gateway to Heaven,
and here,
which is the
gateway to Hell.
And I think that
we're being punished
because we did something
terrible
and that's why we're here.
And I think that we're
not gonna make it.
We don't
deserve to keep going,
because we brought him here.
And we're all going to Hell.
It's over.
We're all gonna die.
We're gonna die.
This is bullshit, this has
nothing to do with a tree.
No.
It doesn't matter.
There are two options,
either he's out there,
heading towards the road,
licking his wounds,
just swearing off
crazy bitches forever,
or he's here,
just plotting his revenge.
For what Stephanie
did to him.
Then it's settled,
we leave him here to rot.
Over there.
Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure.
- Come out you motherfu...
- Stephanie, stop.
I don't think you're
getting this,
I'm not just gonna sit here and wait
for some asshole to toy with me.
If he wants a fight he can come
out here and I will give him one.
Can we just calm down?
It's probably just an animal.
You think?
Yeah, I mean, it doesn't sound
like it's coming for us.
Does it?
Well, yeah,
it's like a squirrel.
Yeah.
Okay, well,
nothing has changed.
We still need to get
to the main road and...
Wait, where's the camera?
You left a camera
showing all of us
bury a dead body
in the front seat
of your truck!
What the hell?
Okay.
We all know how important
that camera is, right?
So you know what
you need to do.
Is anyone gonna come with me?
Oh, no, no.
We all know that you
fucked this up,
so you need to fix it.
We will wait right here.
We'll be right here, Dave.
It's not that far.
I'm pretty sure you can get
there and back in 20 minutes.
All right, fine, but you
have to hold my jacket.
So I can do it,
just like I do everything else.
How far do you think it is
to the road?
No idea.
Wait, Jeb has no idea
about something?
I never thought that
would happen.
Okay, you manipulative bitch,
you just sent Dave out alone,
because you were too lazy
to do it yourself.
It has nothing to do
with being too lazy.
I'm sorry. It has everything to do with your
sick and twisted need to control someone,
which in this moment,
you needed stroked.
So you thought,
"I have an idea,
I'll send Dave out into the
darkness alone for my pleasure."
You know, you're a whole
different kind of monster...
Okay, I'm going to tell you
something right now, I hate you.
You think you're so much
better than everyone else,
and you flaunt it around
the rest of us.
I can't wait until Carrie wakes
up and sees you for what you are.
And what is that?
A spineless loser by day
and sick pervert by night.
The only reason we are in
this hell right now is
because you thought a break up
was just a little too cliché.
I will take being a spineless
loser over being a soulless cunt.
Jeb!
You suck, you know that?
She's going to use you
all the time.
Yeah, I think I left that open,
right?
Yeah, that's how I left it.
Okay, um....
Just need the camera,
and head back
and everything will be fine.
Okay.
Oh, fuck.
Of course it's not here. Of
course, that's what happens.
I brought my gat with me.
It holds twelve bullets.
Bullets are expensive these days
but not... not like I'm
planning on not using them.
I got this awesome, uh,
apache ax thing,
that I used on the last
motherfuckers that messed with us!
Run! It's coming!
Run!
It's coming!
Just sort of waiting
for him to come back.
I don't even know if
he's gonna come back.
Are you a psychiatrist?
Do you have a degree?
- Yeah, I'm a psychiatrist.
- What do you have a degree in?
Yes, I have a PhD in fuck you.
Run! Run!
I think we're okay.
No. Jeb! No!
Yes, Carrie, we have to go.
Look, Carrie, I'm sorry,
she was gonna hurt you,
and I'm not gonna
let that happen.
She's a monster and I'm
gonna protect you from that.
All right?
Everything I'm doing,
from here on,
is just for you,
for us.
I'm sorry.
All right?
And look,
she murdered someone.
Carrie, she invited him into her
house and she murdered him...
No, she was defending herself.
Is that what she told you?
That she was defending herself?
Then I guess, uh, he was
attacking her with his back,
because she murdered him
from behind, Carrie.
That makes self-defense very
difficult to prove.
No.
You sound just like her.
Come on,
I did this for you because you
refuse to help yourself, all right?
I love you,
I'm the one that loves you.
Do you not understand that?
All right? I love you.
But I'm getting us
the fuck out of here.
Let's move.
Hey, you okay?
No.
Why do you do that?
Do what?
You don't let me touch you.
I just don't like being touched.
You never give me a chance.
What are you talking about?
You know what I'm fucking
talking about.
I've been here through
everything with you
and you just treat me
like a house boy.
I always thought of you
as my friend.
I want more.
Can't you just be okay
with what we have?
No! I can't, Steph.
I have to see you with
all these guys
and I have to pretend
I'm okay with it.
You rub it in my face
and I have to be cool?
You think I wanted this?
No girl wants a friend who's
constantly trying to screw her.
It sucks.
But you put yourself
in this position.
I did this to myself, Steph?
Are you... are you serious?
Really?
Did you ever think that maybe...
I was trying to save you
from something worse?
Like what?
What are you doing here, Dave?
I mean, this isn't
a camping trip.
I screwed up.
Don't you think that
that could have been you?
I wish it was.
You don't mean that.
I have been here through
everything with you
and this hurts so much.
I'm sorry.
It's not my fault.
You need to understand that
nothing will ever happen bet...
Fuck! My lip! Oh, fuck!
Oh, you bitch.
You didn't have to do that.
Fuck!
Ugh!
Uh, you bit my lip...
You didn't have to do that.
Oh, my God!
Ah!
Dave!
Where is he?
- I don't know, something took him.
- What's happened to him?
I don't know,
something took him!
He tried to hurt me!
Dave did?
He tried to hurt me, Carrie.
Something came out
and dragged him away.
So you fucking killed him.
No, I didn't.
Something came out here
and dragged him away.
So all this blood?
That's just your blood,
right?
'Cause it couldn't be Dave's blood
if something else took him.
Screw you, Jeb,
I am telling the truth.
Then where did he go?
We're getting out of here.
Yeah, that's the
best idea you've had all night.
I don't think you're
understanding me.
You're not coming with us.
Really?
That's how this is
gonna go down?
Years of friendship
ruined over a boy.
I'm sorry, Steph.
You did this to yourself.
No, don't you apologize to me.
I've been trying to warn you
about him from the beginning.
He is going to hurt you, Carrie.
He might try to give off that
nice guys finish last routine
but he is just as much
a monster as I am.
I wasn't lying when
I said you should be careful.
That is not true,
don't say that.
She's not falling for it
anymore, Stephanie.
You're on your own.
Like it, Steph.
You're just as bad as she is!
Carrie!
Your kind,
and now you're all the same.
Do it.
Please, I don't want to.
Please,
I don't want to.
Do it!
Do it or I will!
I just wanted her to love me.
I just wanted her
to love me.
Do it!
I just wanted her
to love me!
I just wanted
her to love me!
Love me.
Whoever you are,
I hope you're happy.
Because you ruined my life.
Now what have you seen?
You caused me so much pain.
Look what you did to me!
Look at me!
Please, sit down, Carrie.
I'm not really
happy right now.
I'm sad.
Tell me about your friend Dave.
What's he like?
- Again?
- Shut up, Carrie.
Do you like your friends?
Yeah.
Why are you even talking
to this idiot?
You want to tell me about Dave?
Dave...
nice.
He's in love with Stephanie.
Well, what about Stephanie?
Is she nice to you?
Stop talking.
Stephanie can be nice.
She doesn't really
like to be.
She thinks that people take
advantage of girls who are nice.
Does Stephanie like Jeb?
I wish she did.
God, you're gonna
ruin everything.
She hates Jeb.
They're gonna lock us up
and they know what we did.
They know we're responsible.
...because I like him.
Do you think that
Stephanie would ever hurt Jeb?
I hope not.
I should go...
I... I... I need to...
I need to go.
Do you think that
Stephanie would hurt you?
No! I... She's my friend,
she wouldn't do that.
But could she hurt you?
Carrie,
you stupid fucking bitch!
If you say anything,
I swear to God...
She's my friend.
All friends can hurt you
if they really wanted to.
You were my only friend.
Now you're just like
everybody else.
Carrie,
I'm gonna find you.
I'm gonna find you
and I'm gonna make you hurt
for what you did to me.
I'm gonna make you bleed.
I'm gonna find you.
Is that you Dave?
Who is that?
Who's there?
It's okay.
Don't be afraid.
Oh, my God.
We thought you were dead.
I don't know what I am.
We did this to you?
No.
I tried to leave her,
she's so much worse
than I realized.
I am so sorry, Chad.
You... have to stop her.
I can't, she's...
She's a killer.
Hey.
It's okay.
It's gonna be okay.
She's only strong when
you follow her.
She needs you to follow her.
It's gonna be okay,
okay?
It'll be okay.
I promise.
Friendship is the truest bond.
A spear against my friend is a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend is
a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend
is a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend is
a dagger in your spine.
I never thought
you'd have it in you.
- Steph?
- That was fantastic.
I'd like to think
I played a little part in that,
I mean, I have been
nurturing you for yours.
He hurt you, didn't he?
Yeah, he did, but he was mine
to hurt back and now he's gone.
No, I...
I did this for you.
Oh, I know you did,
sweetie,
and I couldn't be
more proud.
So what do we do now?
Whatever we want.
I mean, you proved
yourself tonight.
You proved that you can do way
more than I gave you credit for.
Well, Steph,
I don't know what I would
have done without you.
♪ My best friend ♪
You started to
one up me tonight.
♪ She's so awesome!
And I love her! ♪
And the thing that comes after
one-upping me...
♪ And she's a bad bitch ♪
is not needing me at all.
♪ My best... ♪
Why'd you have to change?
Why? Why? Why?
No one can survive losing
this much blood.
Carrie!
A spear against my
friend is a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend
is a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend is
a dagger in your spine.
What about Stephanie?
A spear against my
friend is a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend is
a dagger in your spine.
Do you think
Stephanie would hurt you?
A spear against my
friend is a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend is
a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend
is a dagger in your spine.
A spear against my friend is
a dagger in your spine.
What's Dave like?
Tell me about your friend.
Could she hurt you?
No.
I... She's my friend,
she wouldn't do that.
Wait!
They're all dead.
Dave, Carrie.
Well, we're alive.
And you think we're going
to make it out of this?
Everything that happened
here is because of you!
You dragged us into this
and you're going
to die here,
with us.
Wake up.
All right, good.
You're okay.
You're safe.
You're safe, it's okay.
It's remarkable.
From the last hour's
experiments, it's clear,
that Miss Thompson has completely broken
free from any psychological barriers,
that hold acute
personalities independent.
What we've accomplished
here is the first steps
in finding a psychological cure for
the most aggressive mental illnesses.
It looks like you've
made it back.
Do you think the
process worked, Doctor?
There's no doubt in
my mind it worked.
But it's too early to tell
what benefit it's had on her.
Carrie,
I know it's gonna take you
some time to process this.
And it's not gonna be easy,
but I assure you,
that it will get easier
when you see...
Chad, and Dave, and Jeb,
and Stephanie
for what they are.
I understand this is
not gonna be easy.
You've lived with these
people for some time.
But it's time.
It's time to break free.
What would you like me to
put in the report, Doctor?
Yes.
As of today,
I believe we've successfully
eradicated half the personalities
that Carrie had created.
At this moment we can't
tell whether,
they're lying dormant,
or gone completely.
My professional opinion would be
that she was able to
break down the less
aggressive personalities.
Furthermore, the personality
that calls herself Stephanie,
was able to remain.
I feel that a strong
anti-psychotic
and sedative regiment
should reduce the chances
of that personality becoming...
violent.
Is there anything else?
I believe we must continue
this course of action.
If there's any chance
of Miss Thompson
ever leaving this institution,
but I believe she has it
in her to succeed.
What... happened?
Where am I?
I hope you can hear me,
Stephanie.
The next time Carrie comes
to me for treatment,
I'm going to rip you
out of her
like the cancer you are.
I know you can hear me,
Stephanie.
Say something.
And there was silence.
Is that her tongue?
Get a nurse!
Get the nurse!
I am the only one who
is there to pick up the pieces
when your life falls apart.
Subtitles by explosiveskull