Executive Producer: Kuroi Kazuo
Producer: Nabeshima Hisao, Oobayashi Kyouko
Directed by Oobayashi Nobuhiko
Based on a novel by Yamanaka Hisashi
( "I'm Her And She's Me" )
For fans of  25 years ago and -
Children of the future.
Tenkousei ( Transfer Student )
Sayonara Anata ( Good-bye to You )
Back then,
I don't think I knew who I was.
I'm sorry for dragging you out all the way out here.
You're probably thinking it's nothing but mountains.
No, not really.
Onomichi, where you grew up,
was a small but lively port city.
Compared to that, my hometown is a small town in the mountains.
I vaguely remember it. I went to kindergarten here.
You're right.
Shinshuu (Nagano area) is also your home.
It's dad's too.
Don't talk about your dad.
I just want you to be happy here.
You make it sound so easy.
Divorce of his parents,
is very traumatizing for a boy in his puberty.
Why are you tormenting me?
I'm more hurt by it than anyone else!
Was that from Akemi?
Yeah.
Why didn't you reply?
Trying to forget eases the pain of breaking up, right?
I knew you two were in that kind of relationship!
Is that the cell phone strap your dad bought for you?
What, does it hurt your feelings that I'm still keeping it?
As if I get hurt so easily!
- Really?
- Really.
I'm hungry.
You just ate lunch when we transferred in Nagoya.
A boy in puberty
gets hungry before he gets traumatized.
I wish a mother of a boy in his growth spurt would at least know that!
Who do you think you're talking to?
Shinshuu, City of Nagano
Good morning.
North Zenkouji Junior High School
Class 3-D
- All rise. Class 3-D
Bow.
Good morning.
Morning.
Sit down.
As Yamamoto's grandfather said,
traditional standing greetings are the best.
I will now introduce you to a new classmate.
He's Saitou Kazuo.
Saitou moved here from Onomichi, Hiroshima Prefecture.
Do you all know where Onomichi is?
It's a lively city by the Seto Inland Sea.
But you used to live right here in Nagano when you were little, right?
Yes.
Is that you, Kazuo?
Right, you're Kazuo.
You're that Kazuo!
Kazumi...
Remember we were sleeping, and you wet the bed!
Kazuo and Kazumi?
Are you brother and sister with similar names?
No, no way!
Brother and sister!
Quiet down, everyone!
You and Kazumi are childhood friends?
That's great! You already have a friend then.
That's not how it is.
How can that be? I said I'll marry you when we grow up,
and even kissed you!
I said no!
I'm sure he's Kazuo from my kindergarten class.
He has to be.
Same family name, just Kazumi's "mi" changed to "o",
so people always asked if we were brother and sister!
Is that another one of your wild imaginations?
No, no. This is real,
This is the truth.
Then, you two were very close?
You just said you kissed him...
That's like a greeting between kids.
My first real kiss was with you, Hiroshi.
During summer break, after that campfire!
Don't talk about that here...
You haven't kissed me since.
Kazumi!
You kissed Saitou while sleeping with him?
He kissed you and wet his bed...
then what did you two do?
We had a nap.
His underwear was wet,
so my mom made him wear mine!
Then he went back home, and tried to pee in the toilet,
but couldn't get his wee-wee out,
so he panicked, screaming "my wee-wee is gone!"
It's true, his mom told me.
Kazumi...
- And after we took a bath together...
Stop it already.
What's the matter, Hiroshi?
So, the kindergarten is the setting of your fairy tale this time?
You really have a wild imagination!
But Kazuo's wee-wee was really...
Enough already!
- You were listening?
- I was!
I'll never forget the pain of my thing being pulled as you screamed "I want one too!"
I knew it was you.
I knew it was you!
Stop telling everyone about something that happened so long ago...
Oh, he's Hiroshi.
Yamamoto Hiroshi.
He's the class president, and my boyfriend.
I'm Yamamoto Hiroshi.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Saitou Kazuo, nice to meet you.
By the way, Saitou...
this Saitou sometimes slip into the world of her imagination.
In other words, her imagination is quite wild.
So, Saitou Kazuo,
don't let her confuse you about what really happened.
Kazumi, I'll let you borrow this book.
I think you should read more advanced books.
"The Sickness Unto Death...
Kierkegaard"?
One of your grandfather's books?
Yes, it's about the World and God, reality and imagination,
and the inevitability of inauthentic despair.
You will find the meaning to life.
What's with him?
He's the exact definition of the word "pompous"!
Ow, what did you do that for?
But who's "Kierkegaard"?
Then, it happened after school that day.
Hey, Kazuo.
You moved to Onomichi because of your dad's work, right?
Did you move for the same reason this time too?
Who cares? It's all in the past.
But I'm curious.
Is your family still in the udon noodle business?
Not udon, it's soba noodle!
I can't believe you forgot!
You used to love my grandpa's soba.
Really? It wasn't a udon restaurant?
I'm really good at making udon, you know!
( Udon: Thick noodles made of wheat )
Udon is made from nothing but wheat.
That's why it tastes so good!
So? Soba is good for your health.
( Soba: Thin noodles made of buckwheat )
Plenty of vitamin B1 in the noodle,
and the soup contains lots of protein and rutin.
It prevents aging.
Look, it's Kazumi. Completely absorbed by her imagination again!
Masae...
- You two sure seem to get along well.
Yuka...
Wait, Kazuo!
Should I tell Yamamoto Hiroshi?
Hiroshi is a philosophy nerd,
so he's got a big brain,
but nothing down there!
Kazuo, wait!
Kazuo!!
Please, OK? Grandpa?
I just called home to let them know you're coming over to eat soba.
Who let you decide?
What, are you in a position to argue with me?
What?
I haven't told anyone about that secret.
Secret? What secret?
That you killed my grandma.
Huh?
Once upon a time, Kazuo and Kazumi came home from kindergarten,
and saw a fly entering grandma's mouth.
Incredibly, Kazuo suddenly started spraying insecticide into grandma's mouth!
Pshhh, pshhh!
And so, the fly and grandma were both exterminated.
- Mother? The end.
Kazuo, Kazuo!
Don't run.
You can't escape.
My home is this way.
Hey! You forgot our restaurant too?
Huh?
This is my home, where you wet the bed.
Why are you talking about wetting a bed in front of a restaurant?!
Oh, wow.
That little bed-wetting Kazuo has grown up!
Bed-wetter!
You wore Kazumi's underwear home, right?
Panties!
I don't remember that...
It happened so long ago, he wouldn't remember.
Yes...
But Kazuo back then was so funny...
Kazumi! Don't go around embarrassing the man.
But...
Embarrassing man!
Want to eat some? I remember you used to like soba.
Kazuo has turned into a udon enthusiast.
Udon?
How did that happen?
They don't have a good soba shop in Onomichi?
Actually, there was a good udon shop.
Udon and soba are both kneaded with water.
I know, Kazumi.
Why don't you take Kazuo to the Spring of Sabishira?
It might bring back memories.
The Spring of Sabishira?
- Sa-Bi-Shi-Ra?
It's a spring where we get the water for our soba.
Don't you remember going there when we were kids?
No... sorry.
Then, go take him there, Kazumi.
We'll have delicious soba prepared when you get back.
You're the one who's supposed to treat me to soba.
( Old Japanese tradition: the new arrival makes soba for neighbors. )
Shall we go? Into the world of our story?
OK.
Be careful!
We'll be back soon.
I'm glad she's playing outside.
Unlike me, she totally lacks masculinity!
Masculinity!
This way, Kazuo.
Huh? Oh.
How big is your family?
Let's see... my dad, mom,
grandpa, and an older brother.
But my brother is working in Tokyo,
and we're taking care of his only daughter, Kazuko.
Her mom passed away.
Then, it's a family of 6, including you.
Yes, since you killed my grandma.
What? Hold on...
The Spring of Sabishira.
Is your family just you and both of your parents?
No, it's a family of 2.
This way,
it's up there.
Do you remember anything?
No.
Male's Gate and Female's Gate.
You're a boy, so...
this way.
Kazuo, the water here is really great!
That's also why our soba tastes great.
I see.
You really don't remember?
My grandpa took us here
many times when we were little.
I remember very clearly while you don't remember at all.
Isn't that unfair?
I wonder why?
Maybe I was trying hard to forget about you.
Because you'd miss me if you remember? Or...
because you wanted to forget about killing my grandma?
My mind went blank.
I went home...
without knowing what just happened.
( Notice of store closure... )
Kazuo, did you just get back?
It's so hot in here.
You!
Me?
Ow.
Gone...
It's gone!
Why are you making so much noise, Kazuo?
Who are you?
- Mom...
- Mom?
Kazuo! He brought a weird girl home on the moving day?
Half-naked too... what are you doing?!
Where are you, Kazuo?
I'm Kazuo...
I don't know who you are, but...
Aren't you ashamed of being naked like that?
What have you been doing with my Kazuo?!
What have I been doing?
I went to the Spring of Sabishira with Kazumi and...
Kazumi? Is that...
That Kazumi from the Saitou soba restaurant?
You're Kazumi?
But why aren't you wearing anything?
It's not like that...
Anyway, do something about your appearance!
Now tell me, where's Kazuo?
Where?
Wait, Kazumi!
Where are you going, dressed like that?
What's on earth is this?
Kazumi?
Just tell me, what happened to Kazumi?
Is she safe?
I'm telling you mommy, I'm Kazumi!
He probably bumped his head against a rock!
Grandpa!
Idiot, look how pathetic you're making me look!
Stop crying like a wuss!
It's me, Kazumi's body!
This one's Kazumi too!
Get off me!
Kazumi, why are you dressed like that?
Geez, Kazumi.
Your mom is scary despite her appearance!
That... that's not true!
You're still saying things like that?!
Mom, don't hit me!
Don't scar a girl before she finds a man!
Exactly, grandpa is right, old lady.
"Old lady"?!
- Old lady?
Mom, stop it!
This is hopeless!
Wait, Kazumi!
Bag, take your bag!
This is hopeless!
Get on.
Not like that! Open your legs.
Hold on.
What a ridiculous double ride!
Wait, that's against the law!
Wait!
Hey, put your hands down.
It hurts when someone grabs my boobs.
Perv! You played with my breasts, didn't you?
"My breasts"?
Well, they may belong to you,
but they're on me right now.
You can have them back if you want!
But in exchange, give me back my nuts!
You scum, idiot, pervert!
Knock it off!
And what's with this appearance?
My panties are clearly showing!
Fine, sorry about that!
But... what now?
My mom was telling me to go home,
but I don't even know where you live!
Right...
Anyway, just for today...
I'll be you, and you'll be me.
There's nothing else we can do.
Let's walk.
We're not kids.
Whether it's dream or reality,
let's just think it through.
My home is this way.
What are we going to do?
Let's discuss it inside.
We've got to do something about this.
Where have you been hiding for so long?
It's not like that, mom.
This is Kazumi, and I'm Kazuo!
This girl is still not making any sense.
Stop trying to seduce my Kazuo!
What's wrong, Kazuo?
No! This is Kazumi!
I'm sorry, Kazumi. Please leave for today.
Hang in there!
This is yours, isn't it?
Go home already!
Excuse me... I mean, I'm home.
Thank you for waiting.
Where have you been?
I told you to enter from the back during this time.
We have customers here!
Hurry and eat dinner.
Why did you bring back the dipper?
Tell grandpa to take this back tomorrow.
OK.
- Welcome home.
- Thanks.
Auntie ate mine!
Call me sis.
I'm the only child.
You don't even like oyster mushrooms.
It's first come, first serve today!
Kazumi, get me the rice.
Your mom is busy cleaning up the restaurant.
Fine...
Another bowl!
What's wrong, Kazumi?
No appetite today?
No...
Her stomach is growling!
I finally finished cleaning up!
Kazumi...
I'm glad you can eat oyster mushrooms, but...
you're a girl! Where are your manners?
Go back to your own seat.
That way, auntie!
Come on...
Sake...
For me too.
I'm home!
I talked to our landlord after greeting the neighbors.
She happens to be a quite a talker!
I ended up having a long chat with her.
This bar used to be very popular in the past,
but they got beaten by new competition nearby.
"An old woman like me can't keep up with the trends",
she said with a smile.
Look, she gave me some persimmon!
Sorry I'm late, you must be hungry.
Should we just order some noodles?
Where did you get this?
I made it.
You did? By yourself?
Yes.
Feeling depressed will only make me even sadder.
Sorry for using the food without asking you.
What? You always take the food without asking!
I asked the landlord to leave her old appliances here.
Oh, yes... right.
By the way, what do you have to be depressed about?
About Akemi?
Or that weird Kazumi?
Who's Akemi?
You miss her after all!
You must be doing all this because you're worried about me.
No, I'm just trying to imitate other people's cooking.
Really? But sometimes it tastes horrible when you do that!
Wow, it tastes great!
What's gotten into you, Kazuo?
- Is it good?
- Yes!
Then I'm relieved.
- By the way...
- Yes?
Daddy... I mean,
When's dad coming home?
Kazuo, are you still saying that to hurt my feelings?
No, um, err...
You're being so difficult lately.
You even brought some weird girl home.
All this stress...
it's a great diet!
Let's eat. I'm happy my son cooked for me.
Thank you for the meal.
- Thank you for the meal.
Ah, TV!
What are you doing, I turned it on.
This is my TV time.
I don't care.
Kazumi, it's not your turn.
You guys actually have a rule like that?
- What's gotten into you?
Never mind.
Don't worry, I'll do the dishes.
Hey, Kazuo, you can watch the bar's TV.
TV?
What's it called? That classical music show you watch every week.
You know, the one you used to watch with Akemi.
She must be the reason you started learning piano.
Akemi is good at everything,
good mannered. I really liked her.
I hope you'll make a friend like her in this school too.
Right... but I'll clean these.
Oh? But you don't have to worry about me.
Doing something is better than nothing.
Actually, I need to use the bathroom first...
Huh? You don't have to ask me.
Oh, right.
Well then...
Don't read books in there!
I'm using it soon too.
Geez, where did he pick up that strange habit?
"The Sickness Unto Death"?
"Kierkegaard", what a weird name.
I thought this would relax me, but it's the complete opposite!
Auntie, are you done yet?
Kazumi, how long are you going to be in there?
Diarrhea?
What's that?
What's with you?
When did you start reading books in the bathroom?
When? I have for a long time...
Whatever, hurry and use it.
I'm also waiting for the bathroom.
Kazumi, show me that book.
I'll go after you.
- You can go before me...
Where's the phone?
What's wrong with you, Kazuo?
The phone is over there.
He's strange tonight.
Why are you just sitting there, Kazumi?
Hurry and clean up, then make tea for everyone.
And what's with this disturbing book?
Something Unto Death?
I have to make tea?
Of course! And what's with the boy talk?
(Girl Talk:) I have to make tea?
- Yes.
Don't worry about the tea, get the phone.
Damn, what a busy house.
What are you doing? Get the phone!
Right, phone...
She must have bumped her head too.
I'll make tea!
Where's the phone...
Oh, here it is.
Hello?
It's me, Kazumi.
I know that, it's my own voice.
Kazuo, there's an emergency with your body.
Emergency?
The shape... suddenly changed!
Shape? What shape?
Where you pee from...
Idiot! Don't play with that!
But... I only wiped it with toilet paper after going...
It started to change shape.
Idiot, who wipes that with paper?
Just swing it a couple of times and put it back in!
Don't do funny stuff to it!
I got it.
But you have to use the paper.
Fine.
Hey, how's it going at your end?
Ain't so bad, I guess.
You can't talk like that!
Anyway, what about you?
Everything going well?
I cooked something, and we ate together, but...
your mom seemed to be surprised at how fast I ate.
Really...
You know how I have a big family.
If you don't eat quickly...
There will be none left.
I know what you mean. It took a while to grab the food.
You have to eat properly
It's my body.
But I'm a bit relieved.
You're calm enough to cook.
I'll try to think of something about our situation.
- That and...
- Yes?
Did you see a cell phone in my pocket?
There was.
But it's all wet, so the memory is all gone.
It doesn't matter.
But the strap...
Oh, this? The piano-shaped one?
Can you keep it somewhere safe?
Is it a gift from someone important?
This Akemi person?
No, it's from my pops.
From your father?
Well then, I'm going to hang up.
Take care.
You too.
Bye.
What, again?
What, you still have something to say?
It's Kazumi... right?
Oh, ah... Yes.
It's me, Hiroshi.
Oh, Hiroshi is that...
class president, Kazumi's boyfriend, show-off, Yamamoto Hiroshi?
What's the matter? You're acting strange today, Kazumi.
I'm not acting strange, damn it.
(Girl Talk:) I mean... I'm not strange.
There's definitely something wrong.
I called your cell phone many times, but it wouldn't connect, so I called your home.
Oh, my cell... It's in my home...
Huh?
(Girl talk:) It was soaked in water.
Soaked?
- I went to the Spring of Sabishira.
You know, I took the transfer student, Kazuo there.
Then I fell in the water.
Really? I hope you're not hurt.
Duh, that's why I'm home.
Right... I don't mean to be rude,
but is this another one of your stories?
Huh, uh, um...
(Unnatural girl Talk:) This is truth it is.
(Girl Talk:) Kazuo is very strong.
(Girl Talk:) He saved me.
Something's definitely wrong.
I'm coming over right now.
No, no, don't come!
- Please don't come!
- But...
Don't worry, I'm just tired.
Maybe that's why I'm a bit nervous.
So you don't need to come tonight.
I see...
Then... rest well.
Do you think you can come to school tomorrow?
I think so.
Bye, good night.
Who was it?
Such a long call.
It was Hiroshi.
You've had a long day, go to sleep.
Don't forget to greet grandma before going to sleep.
Ask her to heal your head.
Grandma's still alive?
What is she talking about?
That's a tough book.
Tie your sash properly!
This way, go.
Pray that you'll feel better tomorrow.
I'm sleeping here?!
What? You have your own room.
Now, give her a greeting.
( Random chanting... )
Kazuo, are you asleep?
No, what is it?
I ironed your uniform.
Oh, thanks!
I'll also iron that weird Kazumi's uniform.
I found her cell phone too, but it's broken.
But return it tomorrow.
Who knows how that crazy girl will react?
Really, I can't believe she turned out to be such an annoying kid.
Ah! Hot, hot, hot!
Kazuo.
Oh, you're here?
Are you crazy? You can't wear that to school.
I've brought your uniform.
Your mom washed it for you.
Here's your precious cell phone strap,
and my broken cell phone.
I can't get the buttons on!
What are you doing? Wear a bra underneath!
People can see my breasts!
Calm down.
Over there, in the top drawer.
What's that?
- Don't touch that!
Help me with this.
Good morning, Kazumi.
How are you feeling?
You? What are you doing?
Mom, I always tell you to knock before entering my room!
What about you?
Entering a girl's room this early in the morning?
Uh, I came to bring his cell phone strap and uniform.
She came because she was worried I suddenly turned into a girl.
You don't have to get all mad.
Who do you think you're talking to?
And why aren't you wearing anything?
What did you do that for, old lady?!
- Kazuo, stop!
What did you just call me?
Why are you here in my daughter's room?
Do you think this is appropriate?
Honey!
This is inappropriate too!
What's going on?!
Your skirt is on backwards.
Oops.
Are the folks in your home going to be alright?
They're fine. It happens all the time.
Oh.
You may be good at these things,
but I'm not used to living in an unrealistic situation like this.
What's wrong?
I'm starting to want to kill myself.
Whoa, don't be absurd!
What will happen to me if you died?
Your body belongs to me.
I know that.
Good morning.
Let's just go to the school.
(Girl Talk:) Let's go.
(Girl Talk:) Yes.
(Boy Talk:) I mean, Yes.
Is that correct?
Ah! I missed breakfast!
I'm hungry.
- Kazumi and...
- Kazuo!
All rise,
bow.
Good morning.
Morning!
Sit down.
For today's music lesson...
Let's enjoy...
a piano performance first!
Yay!
Saitou.
Yes.
Oh, I wasn't calling you, Kazumi.
It's Saitou Kazuo.
Saitou Kazuo actually happens to be
a great piano player from Onomichi.
Isn't that right?
Don't be shy.
Well then, Kazuo. Go ahead.
Come on, Kazuo.
The piano is waiting for you.
Kazuo, you can do it!
What's wrong, Kazuo?
You're good at piano, right?
Come on, Kazuo. Like a hero from Kazumi's fairy tale...
Play the piano like a prince!
(Boy Talk:) What are you doing?
Just spread your fingers, hit the keys and it'll make sound!
Do-re-mi or Flea Waltz, or whatever, just play you idiot!
(Girl Talk:) How can you expect me
to actually play the piano all of a sudden?
This is all your fault
for learning piano without telling me.
Idiot!
Oh, crap!
Kazuo!
Time-out for a sec.
Kazumi, wait! Don't kill yourself!
Watch over the class.
Quiet down.
Hey...
Wait.
Hey, Kazumi.
What's the matter?
It's not fair. Piano is not a part of my fairy tale.
But Akemi taught me...
Hey there!
What's going on here?
Kazumi, I thought I heard you scream
"don't kill yourself"...
What's going on?
Kazuo.
It's not like a boy to be crying like that.
What exactly is the problem?
Hey, Kazuo.
Stop that.
Stop, you idiot!
Oh, crap!
Are you alright, teacher?
What the hell? Move it!
Ow, move it.
Don't look!
Take your head out of my skirt!
It's all dark, I can't see anything.
But that was kind of hot.
Geez, that hurt.
Hiroshi?
Oh my god!
I'm glad it wasn't anything serious.
I don't know what I would do if it left scars.
Hiroshi didn't even help, he was just staring.
Hiroshi likes watching doesn't he?
I want to get back into this body.
Cute boy and girl.
The short days of autumn are sad, aren't they?
Young girl, you have a small frame,
but a nice proportion.
Why don't you take my hand and come with me?
Someone,
someone help!
Why are you screaming?
I have nothing to do with you.
Go away!
Stop!
What are you doing?
What a creepy kid, go away!
Kazumi!
You OK? Why you...
Hurry, let's go.
I can't breathe...
Open your legs.
- It's too embarrassing.
Just do it!
- Is that better?
- A bit...
Let's get away while he's still down.
Here's a bonus!
Autumn days... are painful...
Actually, Saitou and Saitou were...
about to engage in red entertainment...
Pinku entertainment, you mean.
Yes, pinku entertainment when...
the president of Educational Committee's grandson came to warn them...
One of the Saitou kicked his...
important place!
You fool!
Anyway, my son's...
that place is internally bleeding.
He had to take a leave of absence from university too.
How will you take responsibility for this?
He's a university student?
Excuse me, my child is a girl.
There is no way a girl can do something like that to a big university student.
I'm sure Kazuo was the one who did it.
Saitou? Did you do it?
Well...
Kazuo, tell me. What happened?
That bastard was staring at me with a really dirty look!
If we didn't get him,
he would've rubbed this whole body, took off my panties, and...
Kazumi! Stop it already!
But...
In any case, I believe Kazuo was simply trying
to protect Kazumi from being assaulted.
And Mr. Committee,
your grandson kicked Kazuo's nuts first.
Watch your language!
It's true! That's why we kicked him back.
I guess it's self-defense.
That's hard to believe...
President Imada.
Let's just say we've both suffered damage.
Our students may have been partially responsible, but
if this gets out to the public,
it will affect your grandson's future career.
Of course it will!
If the public found out a university student
got beaten by a junior high girl... Right?
Thanks, mom.
That's not your mom.
They bought you a new cell phone?
Yeah, your mom said I'm strange lately,
so she bought it for me so she can contact me anytime.
Oh, my mom said that?
Oh, crap! It's that kid Hiroshi!
Let me see!
"I called your home, and they told me you've got a new cell phone."
I'm really worried about your abnormal behavior
ever since Kazuo transferred to our school.
Is there anything I can do to help?
"Or am I no longer needed by you?"
Hiroshi...
I'll type it for you. What do you want to say?
I'm sorry for making you worry.
It's not that I no longer need you.
No, in fact, I think I need you most by my side right now, star-mark.
But please give me a bit more time.
Please don't forget, star-mark,
you're the most important person to me, OK, 3 question marks.
Then, I want you to remember this, star-mark.
I am always by your side.
I'll die just for you, star-mark.
OK?
"I'll die just for you"?
That line sounds like a big lie, huh?
Ow, what the hell?
"Thank you,"
I think I will be able to tell you everything one day.
Please look after me from a distance until then.
"Goodbye."
You have to be the one holding this cell phone.
Oh, right.
I promise I'll contact you if he sends mail again.
Thanks.
There is a petition to have Zenkouji shrine nominated as a World Heritage Site...
Why are you lying around like that?
You're acting like a boy!
Kazumi, you weren't like this until that boy transferred here.
That's why, I want you to stop hanging around with Kazuo for a while.
What? But...
That's what we've decided.
I also discussed this with Kazuo's mom.
She told me you were wandering around their home naked.
Turn off the TV when you're not watching.
But that was because I fell in the water...
In any case, you two are bad influences on each other.
Listen, I know you can't help it inside the school,
but once you get out of the school, you're forbidden to hang around Kazuo.
Forbidden.
You, give her an earful as a father too!
What do you say, Kazumi?
Want to make some soba again?
Honey?
Soba? Kazumi can make soba?
It's true making soba is a man's job,
but I'm an incompetent apprentice of your grandfather's.
He always teases me that you're better at making soba than me.
I guess it's what they call "the talent skipped a generation"
But I like the soba you make.
Thank you, you're the only person who tells me that.
What do you say, Kazumi?
Want to give it a try?
OK, it's same as udon, right?
Yeah... huh?
Oh, Kazumi. Want to give it a try?
Yes.
Raise your arms.
You're good to go.
It's same as udon, just as I thought.
- Here you go.
- Got it.
Ka... Kazumi?! What are you doing?!
What's wrong?
Huh? Am I doing it wrong?
Auntie, you look awesome!
Dad, dad?
- Are you alright?
- No...
Is this all my fault?
Why is the restaurant closed?
Welcome.
What's wrong with you, Kazumi?
I'm not a customer.
Welcome home, dad!
This is for you. - "Dad"?
You're Kazumi's older brother?
Mom told me you're acting strange lately, so I came to see how you're doing.
It seems she was right.
Are you practicing for the school play?
Kouichi, Kouichi! She made soba with her feet!
With her feet?!
Is that true, Kazumi?
Well, that's what we do for udon.
That's why her dad and grandpa both fell into a state of shock.
I see...
But I guess you're trying to make soba your way.
Huh?
That's a great thing.
I wasn't interested in making soba,
so I ran off to Tokyo, but
it seems you like making soba.
You might even become a pioneer of female soba masters.
To achieve your goal... do whatever you need to, even with your feet!
You have my support.
- Kouichi...
Honey!
OK.
You're pretty understanding, bro!
Understanding!
Well then, I still have homework to do.
I'm going back to my room.
Kazumi, wait.
Help me clean the restaurant.
I'll help out too.
Me too!
Kazumi, are you alright?
Yeah, I just felt a bit dizzy.
Don't worry.
It should still be a while until your next period.
Period? I'm going to have periods?
Of course you will.
Give me a time-out. I'll go downstairs in a while.
See? She's acting strangely.
You might be right.
Strange.
Do you see a pretty pouch in the drawer?
My sanitary pads are inside.
What am I going to do?
Your mom tells me I can't see you anymore.
Your mother told me the same thing.
Don't panic during your period.
It only happens once a month.
Oh, right. Our field trip is coming up.
I'll show you how to use them then.
Field trip?
Oh, it's your first time.
It's our school's annual event.
The entire class stays overnight somewhere.
This year it's at Shimao Hot Spring.
I don't care where we're going anymore.
I feel so tired tonight.
As if I'm sick.
You're just not used to it.
It's not a sickness.
Well, at least now the over-energetic Saitou Kazumi can finally calm down for a bit.
I guess it worked out for the best.
Hello? Hello?
Are you listening to me, Kazuo?
Yeah, I'm listening. I really don't feel very good.
I'm going to hang up now, good night.
Oh, good night..
Kazuo, can I come in?
Yes.
I see swimsuit in the list of things to bring for the field trip...
You're actually going to swim in this weather?
Oh, we wear it for the hot spring.
Swimsuit for the hot spring?
Yes, that's what we've always done in our school.
"What we've always done"?
Uh, that's what I heard from my friends.
Oh. I've heard kids nowadays aren't used to shared baths,
so they wear swimsuits for hot springs.
You used to share baths naked?
Oh, I almost forgot. We have to buy you a new swimsuit.
The old one was getting a bit small, right?
Uh... I think so.
Saitou, what do you think of the mountains in Shinshuu?
It's your first time, right? Aren't they beautiful?
Yes.
Saitou? What's wrong?
You don't seem as energetic as usual.
She's fine. Kazumi is a quiet girl, isn't she?
You think?
Are you alright, Saitou?
I think this is the first time I've seen you get car sick.
I'm having my period.
Idiot!
Kazuo!
I got mine on! Let's go!
Can you help me with mine?
- Sure.
Yuuka, have your breasts gotten bigger again?
Kazumi, are you alright?
Gently tap her behind her neck.
Saitou,
Maybe you should rest up in your room.
No, I'm fine.
Ah... but maybe I should.
Girls at your age have delicate bodies.
Right, yes.
Hey? Kazumi?
You can play piano?
Uh... no.
I can tell from your finger's movements.
But.. why have you never told me?
It's a secret, but I used to play piano too.
Used to?
Because I quit.
How come?
Because I broke up with the person who loved piano.
- For such a reason?
- It's fine!
Learning and quitting piano...
is all for the person you love.
What kind of tunes did you like?
Schumann's Novelletten.
Oh, mom bought you a new pair of swim pants, huh?
Perv!
You must have gotten the nosebleed from
watching girls change and got too excited.
Well, it's a gold mine!
Geez!
Ow!
What an overreaction!
- What's wrong?
- It's nothing.
What are you doing? Perv!
Kazuo?
I'll carry her, you get the teacher.
Hang on, help is coming.
Hiroshi... you're making me blush.
She's fine now.
Her complexion has improved a lot too.
I'll stay by her.
All of you, return to your rooms.
It's better to give her some quiet time.
OK.
Let's go.
Hang in there!
Dinner's at 6PM.
Take care.
Bye.
Saitou,
I need to talk to you.
Uh, OK.
It's almost dinner time.
Kazumi.
Yes?
Oh, uh...
I know that you're Kazumi.
Isn't that right?
You and Saitou Kazuo switched bodies somehow.
That's the only explanation I can think of,
by observing you two.
But... how did you know?
It's love.
Love?
Love is philosophy.
Even if it cannot be scientifically explained,
it can be by the philosophy of love.
Hiroshi...
The person I love is...
You, Kazumi.
Me?
Me, inside me?
I can't stop loving you.
And even if the Kazumi I love is shaped like a man,
I can accept that.
Because I love your soul.
Hiroshi.
Kazumi, Kazumi.
Suddenly...
I can't see you anymore
Starting tomorrow
I won't be able to see you again
I won't be able to
See you again
Even if I prayed for it
What's the matter?
I would've even understood it if you said
"Your forehead is cute" or
"I like the shape of your jaw."
But how can you possibly see my soul?
You're in love with your own soul.
Not mine, not Kazumi's.
Even if it was, it's the ideal me in your mind.
That's not the real me.
Not this Kazumi.
I'm not philosophical like you.
You will become a wind
Become an invisible wind
To your most sought after place
You will become a wind and reach
Don't laugh and say I'm strange
It's slightly embarrassing
You can see through everything
That's why
I'm leaving you now...
Kaneko, Kawahara,
Kita,
Kuroda,
Kobayashi,
Saitou, Saitou Kazumi?
Yes.
Not you.
Saitou Kazumi is... absent.
Sakui,
Sawada,
Shiina...
Kazumi is sleeping.
She's acting strange, more than usual!
I can't let you see her even if you come all this way to visit.
So, please. Leave.
Let's go, Kazuko.
Kazumi.
Hiroshi.
My mom won't let me see Kazuo.
I've never had to sleep in because of my period.
I'm really worried about what's happening to my body.
OK.
I'll go visit.
I promised to do anything for you.
Please do that for me.
I'm sure my mom will let you see me.
- Yes.
Sorry for making you worry.
I'm fine,
but Kazumi is worried about your body.
Kazumi is...
Does that mean Kazumi told you?
No.
Kazumi's stories are always very imaginative,
and although they were amusing,
I've always thought them to be slightly immature.
But I noticed...
That song you sang most recently...
The song...
It came naturally to me.
That song was like one of Kazumi's stories.
It sounded as if Kazumi had made it.
You may be right
It felt as if I was her when I was singing it.
Hiroshi, thank you for visiting.
Please keep her company.
Come on, talk about something.
Would you like some snacks?
Yes, thank you.
It reminds me of the time when my dad used to hold me.
We're not equipped to treat her here.
I will recommend you to a hospital in Nagano.
Please consult with an expert from there.
It's such a difficult disease to treat?
- Yes...
I will arrange a full medical examination in 2 or 3 days.
Please be prepared to stay in the hospital.
OK.
She has a very rare illness.
We have also never encountered it before in our hospital.
And the treatment?
You can cure it, right?
- About that...
Director, they are the parents of the patient.
Oh, you're that...
Committee president!
You're a doctor in this hospital?
Yes...
Does that mean, that lively girl...
Doctor, you can cure Kazumi's illness, right?
Dr. Mizutani, you still haven't...?
No.
Sir, with the current medical technology,
you're daughter's illness can't...
What?
It can't be cured?
But...
Are you just saying that because of our history?
You're just saying that to scare us, right?
It's nothing more than a light anemia,
and you're trying to make her suffer.
Isn't that right?
Madam,
I'm a doctor.
I would never lie or joke to a patient's family!
But...
But she's still only 15!
Honey...
she's only 15...
15...
Doctor,
how long...
How long does Kazumi have?
I cannot guarantee it,
but most likely...
2 to 3 months.
That...
that can't be...
We will do all we can.
But the support of family and friends
will be more reassuring than anything else.
I know it must be tough,
but let's give it our best.
- Hi.
- Committee president?
Thanks to you giving my grandson a beating,
we found out more and more of his wrongdoings.
He had been skipping university,
and hanging around with trouble-making friends of his.
See, told you it was that punk's fault.
You're right!
That severe injury turned out to be a good lesson for him!
I think he's learnt his lesson.
It's all thanks to you.
So I am indebted to you.
I'll do my best in your treatment.
You're going to grab my boobs
and say it's an examination, aren't you?
You got me!
Well, I might have to touch a little.
Anyway, can you do something about this kindergarten-like room?
It's bringing back the memory of getting my wee-wee pulled.
Oops, she already took mine.
Patients 15 and under are considered pediatrics...
But I'll move you to an adult's room.
OK. Fine, I'll let you touch my boobs.
It seems like you're a nice person.
Well, thank you.
Let's try to get along.
Let's give it our best.
OK.
It can't be cured?
Does that mean I'm going to die?
Kazumi's body will die...
What about Kazuo?
What will happen to Kazuo?
Kazumi's body will die,
that means Kazuo inside will also die.
That's the most logical conclusion.
I can't live on if Kazuo dies.
What should I do,
What should I do?
Keep still.
Here, it's from Kazuko to "auntie".
Sorry to trouble you, Hiroshi.
Dr. Mizutani.
Who's that boy?
Oh, he stares at Saitou's room from there every day,
but it seems he caused some trouble in the past.
Her family members won't give him permission to visit.
Hold this.
You're Saitou, right?
Yes.
Why are you here.
You can't see her.
Madam, if you're avoiding him because of that incident,
I'll apologize on his behalf.
I want him to talk to Kazumi.
I can't allow that.
Chie, let him visit.
But honey...
Doesn't Kazumi need the support of as many friends as possible?
Let him visit her.
Will you see Kazumi for us?
Kazuo?
It's me.
Come on, now.
Oh, right.
It's Kazumi.
My mind is dull.
It's the medicine's side effect.
What exactly happened?
I don't know.
It just turned out this way.
Forgive me.
How did this happen,
Kazuo?
I don't know.
It feels like I was suddenly thrown into a whole different world.
Kazuo, is there anything I can do for you?
You're me, so I'll do anything for you.
Tell me if you need anything.
Don't push yourself too hard.
- I'm fine.
- But...
that's my body.
I should be the one lying down there.
Why are you sick instead?
It can't be helped.
We've switched.
I'm you right now.
I'm the one who got sick.
But...
Do you remember that kid Hiroshi saying that corny line?
"I'll die just for you".
What a joke.
But I guess he's a nice guy.
"I'll die just for you", huh?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Kazuo.
Why are you apologizing?
Is there anything you want,
or person you want to see?
Person I want to see?
Of course it's...
I know...
Of course.
You want to see your mom.
I thought I said you're not allowed to see Kazumi.
But she really wants to see you.
Why does she want to see me?
She said because you took care of her...
I never took care of her.
I don't see a reason for me to see Kazumi either.
You just want to use me to see her,
isn't that right?
That's not fair, mom!
That's 378 yen. Thank you.
Anyway, Kazuo.
I got a phone call from Akemi.
She's coming here to visit you in the winter break.
Akemi's coming?
I know you want to see her.
You'll completely forget about Kazumi once she's here.
Do you know how I can contact her?
What? Have you forgotten
how to contact your own girlfriend?
Yeah...
my old cell phone got soaked in water.
Kazuo!
Are you Yoshino Akemi?
Oh, you really are Kazuo.
Well, I guess it's Kazuo's body.
So that's not a surprise.
So, you understood what I explained in the email?
Vaguely,
but it's obvious when I see you in person.
You're not Kazuo.
I see,
you can also tell.
Nice to meet you,
I'm Saitou Kazumi.
He's Yamamoto Hiroshi from my class.
Nice to meet you,
I'm Yamamoto Hiroshi.
Ah, so you're my rival in love.
I guess so.
I cried for a whole night after you told me Kazuo might die.
I kept crying,
and played Schumann's Traumerei,
the piece I always played with Kazuo, through the night.
But it won't change anything.
So I thought I have to make his last wish come true.
That I have my own duty.
Am I just trying to satisfy myself?
I'm only here because Akemi asked me,
but why do I have to come along?
Come on, mom.
It's true, I knew her when she was in kindergarten, but...
I hope I won't cry.
It's better if you cry!
Hello, Kazumi.
I'm Yoshino Akemi.
Akemi...
I've brought Kazuo's mom too.
Kazuo and Hiroshi asked me to bring her.
Mom...
Go ahead.
Kazumi,
it's been a long time.
You were so energetic...
Mom...
How are you doing with Kazuo?
Huh? Uh, yes.
But he also doesn't seem to be very energetic lately.
Oh.
But...
please get along
Kazuo hates being lonely.
OK.
We get along very well.
He's my son, after all.
Right...
He's your son.
She's Akemi.
Kazuo's friend.
She came all the way from Onomichi to see him.
I've heard from Kazuo...
about everything, all of it.
Everything, all of it?
Yes, everything, all of it.
That's why I brought his mom here today.
I see, that explains it.
Thank you, Akemi.
What are you two talking about?
About something important,
between me and Kazuo.
I'm glad...
I got to see Kazuo's mom.
Really?
It's kind of strange...
but I'm glad I could be of help.
Then, I'll say a couple more strange things...
Take care, mom.
And also...
You should fall in love with someone too.
Geez, Kazumi!
You're not making any sense as usual.
Mom...
Kazuo's...
I'm sorry Kazuo is always causing trouble.
Not at all.
You came all the way here to visit?
It felt as if I was talking to my own child while I was with her.
I'm sorry.
You have my condolences.
I am grateful for your heartfelt visit.
Grateful.
Auntie?
Kazumi is young,
so she can endure our treatment.
She may even regain her strength temporarily.
But after that short period of time...
It's best to ask her what she wants to do,
who she wants to see, while she still can.
Ah! Dad.
Kazuko.
Brother.
Yes?
Bro...
What is it?
How did Kazuko's mom die?
What?
Sorry for asking a strange question.
No problem,
Kazumi.
I don't know the answer to that question either.
Why Yuriko went shopping by herself on that day,
that afternoon,
and had to be hit by a car...
By a drunk driver, no less.
But you know,
I know very well what she lived for.
It's Kazuko.
Kazuko is here because we loved each other.
Kazumi.
No one knows why people die.
Maybe it's fate.
But you decide what you're living for.
I guess that's why we fall in love.
That's why, you have to live.
Live your own way.
Give it a try.
Brother.
I'm glad I'm your sister.
Try to live, sis.
Are you feeling well today?
Yeah, I feel well on some days.
Doesn't last long though.
- I see.
Can you open the curtains?
I want to see the sky.
Sure.
We're pretty high up...
Kazumi.
What?
There's somewhere I want to go to.
You want to go somewhere?
Let's go then.
Do you think we can?
Where, Kazuo?
Let's just go!
Let's go.
From the emergency stairs.
Come, hurry.
Over there.
- Akemi.
- Huh?
Kazumi.
I can walk from here.
Kazuo...
Are you alright?
I'm alright.
Kazuo, are you really alright?
Kazuo?
Sorry for the trouble.
Hurry up!
I'll get disowned if my father finds out about this.
That's better than having your attempted rape exposed.
What you're doing is called blackmail!
I'll give you a kiss as a reward.
Yeah!
Why is this happening to me...
Hey, Hiroshi.
Yes?
What's "The Sickness Unto Death" about?
- It's about despair.
- Despair?
Despair destroys people.
What about hope then?
"It is too difficult to understand, I don't know",
my grandpa said.
Your grandpa?
He kept reading that book until he died at 94,
"I am counting on you to figure out the rest".
I wonder if hope lies in what's left.
Is this far enough?
Yes, thanks.
Geez, kids these days!
I'm not involved anymore.
You're responsible for yourselves.
Thanks.
What about that kiss?
I don't want it!
The arrival of winter sure is sad!
This is as far as we'll go.
Yes.
Aren't we going together?
You two go together.
You two are protagonists of the same story.
I'm sure there are many things you two want to discuss alone.
Akemi...
Kazuo,
we didn't get to talk too much,
but I'll never forget you.
I'm going to quit piano.
That way I can treasure the memories of us together.
Thank you, Akemi.
Hiroshi...
Be careful.
Call the ambulance immediately if something goes wrong.
Yes.
And so, Kazuo and Kazumi
walked the divine path.
They walked endlessly through the buckwheat field
We're also all alone now.
Two walking the divine path, two lost love.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
Might as well share the same umbrella,
and write our own story.
Yes,
but you won't surpass Kazumi. I'm certain.
Kazuo either, huh?
Hey Kazuo.
I lied to you about one thing.
What is it?
That you killed my grandma.
Let's not mention her.
I think this is happening to me because of her curse.
No, it's not.
Grandma was already dead when it happened.
From a heart attack.
We saw her while my mom went to get the doctor.
You were lying to me the whole time?
I'm sorry, Kazuo.
But I only lied to you because
I wanted you to be a special person in my story.
I know that now.
A special person, huh?
But meanwhile, you were trying to forget about me.
That's also because I wanted to make you a special person.
OK, let's get going soon.
OK.
Where are you kids going?
Want to come with us?
We're performing in a hot spring inn.
What about you?
Uh, yes.
We're planning to go there too.
How lucky.
Kazuo?!
Oh? Then let's make it a nice trip.
Yes.
Are you sure, boss? I think they're runaways.
You can only be reckless when you're young.
You've done the same thing, haven't you?
I'm 2 tens and a five...
A young man.
But they seem like junior high students.
Fool, they have a reason they can't tell others.
The girl seems to be sick too.
Let's take care of them.
Yes, sir.
You haven't had breakfast yet, have you?
Eat this.
Thank you, we'll have it.
Wow, you can become an actor.
Huh?
People are born with certain qualities.
I'm playing a female role after years of training,
but you're born with the quality needed for female roles in Kabuki.
Would you like to enter this career?
Uh, no... I...
That suits him! It might be perfect for him!
Stop it!
That movement!
You're like a pro. Don't you agree, boss?
What, you want to make him your successor?
Thank you so much for coming.
I slay you!
I live for love!
I wonder if she's already asleep?
Hey, are you asleep?
No.
Can I go to your room?
I can't seem to fall asleep.
Yes, sure.
Kazumi.
Yes?
Can I join you?
What?
Don't worry, I won't try anything funny.
OK.
Then...
can I hug you?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Something's happening to me.
What's wrong?
You must know.
You're a boy.
I'm sorry, Kazuo.
I may not be able to control myself.
You may be right...
Hey...
Can I?
No, we can't!
Kazuo...
This is your body, after all.
And I'm in your body.
We can't do it like this.
But...
Let's forget about it, OK?
I don't know about complicated things like Hiroshi,
I want to be myself when...
When we...
And if I got pregnant...
I won't last for that.
You're right.
Let's get better first.
Yeah.
I've never seen my own face from this close before.
Then, show me.
Let me see myself.
Huh?
I'll never see my own body again.
So, please.
I want to take a last look at my own body.
Let me say farewell to my body.
OK.
It's beautiful.
See, our heartbeats
are in sync like a single metronome.
You're right.
Goodbye, me.
I will die for you.
I'm starving.
Do you have an appetite?
Yeah, it seems like my body is in a good condition today.
I'll find something to eat.
Yes, they seem like junior high students.
Our boss is a nice man, so he can't help it.
But they'll just get us into trouble.
Let's get rid of them before that happens.
We're fine now.
- Hey...
- What is it?
Let's go home.
Yeah.
Our moms must be worried.
More importantly,
You'll get really sick at this rate.
I guess.
But before that...
What?
I want to see the Spring of Sabishira.
The Spring of Sabishira?
My dream was to
turn my story into a song, and sing it.
But I don't have musical talent like you.
You're already singing your song.
At least, that's what I think.
Is this where you wanted to get off?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
See ya.
Take care.
I'm sorry.
I'll walk.
You sure?
Yeah,
I told you I'm in a good condition today.
OK.
See?
Watch out!
I'm fine.
I can walk with your support.
OK.
Let's climb together then.
But... which gate will we enter from?
Male's Gate and Female's Gate...
makes no difference to us now.
We've arrived.
Are you alright, Kazuo?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
I'm feeling good today.
Kazuo.
What is it?
When you die, I'll die too.
Huh?
I'll take my own life if you die!
Don't be stupid!
Why do you have to die?
Because... because I...
You have to live.
You have to live in my place.
Kazumi,
I'm starting to understand.
Hiroshi's words,
were supposed to be "I'll live just for you".
And I might just get cured, once I drink from the Spring of Sabishira.
Right, yes!
I'm sure you'll be cured.
Let's drink together.
From the Spring of Sabishira.
Hey, don't say you'll die!
You have to live, Kazumi!
Ah...
It's Kazuo.
Of course! I'm Kazuo, and you're...
Oh crap, our clothes switched again.
Kazumi...
Hey, slap me. Am I dreaming?
Get ahold of yourself!
It hurts, it hurts!
Kazumi.
We've switched back!
Back to our own bodies!
- Kazumi...
I love you.
I really love you, Kazuo.
I love you more than anyone else.
For you, Kazuo,
I don't mind dying.
I don't mind.
I can die for you.
Wait...
Aren't you cold?
I'm fine.
Let me stay here for a while longer.
Two of us together.
I'm sorry.
We shouldn't have come to the Spring of Sabishira.
I was going to die for you.
No, I wanted to live for you.
Hey, Kazuo.
What?
It turned out for the best.
This is natural.
I will die as myself.
That's why you have to live as yourself.
OK?
Please,
promise me.
OK.
It's alright.
I'm filled with hope right now.
You see,
My body remembers.
The fingers you played piano with.
We didn't just switch.
We're already two as one.
Kazuo.
Hey, sing that song for me.
That song,
it was your song.
I mean, I don't know how to sing.
And I can't just come up with a song like that.
That song can't even be sung without your voice.
You're right.
Then let's sing.
Two songs as one.
Yeah.
Two stories as one.
You will become a wind
Become an invisible wind
To your most most sought after place,
You will become a wind and reach
Don't laugh and say I'm strange
It's slightly embarrassing
You can see through everything
That's why I'm leaving you now
- Here you go, dad.
- Thanks.
Honey, dad.
Kazuo brought flowers.
Oh, he's here?
Did you come for soba, Kazuo?
Yes.
Good.
I'll make great soba for you.
Kazumi was good at making soba.
She was a far better craftsman than her dad.
Did you know,
buckwheat grows in sterile land too harsh for other crops.
People who lived in such lands
made noodles from low quality flour,
and ate them to survive.
That's why, soba is in no way a tasty food.
But it's our job to figure out how to make it delicious.
I see.
That Kazumi,
she made soba in a strange way a while back.
Right?
Yes, she did.
- Shall we try it?
- No way!
It's Kazumi's way.
And it's for Kazuo.
Let's do it.
OK...
Can you let me do it?
Really? You want to try it?
- Yes.
OK. You try it.
That's a nice masculine sight.
Darn it!
It feels like Kazumi is back!
These are your change of clothes.
Wear a fresh pair of underwear everyday!
I know! I'm not a kid anymore.
I won't wet my bed either.
Did you pack your new cell phone?
Call me right away when you get there.
Don't let it soak in water again!
Fine, fine!
You're so annoying.
Your speech became so rude immediately after Kazumi passed away.
It just returned to normal.
True, now that you mention it.
But why Onomichi, of all places?
Because there's no sea in Nagano.
Sea?
When I grow up a bit more, I want to cross the sea,
and journey through foreign countries.
There are many different stories of the sea.
I want to visit them all.
Will that make you lonely, mom?
I won't be lonely.
You've finally found what you want to do with your life.
It makes me very happy.
But...
you're obviously staying in his place, right?
You know, mom.
You may be estranged from him,
but he's still a father to me.
Just as you will always be my mom.
He will always be my dad.
You're right, but still...
Oh well, at least you can play piano again.
I've already said goodbye to piano.
Anyway, they say blood is thicker than water.
I mean, I'm only here because you two did it!
Kazuo!
How can say something like that to your own parent?!
Mom, want to go to Onomichi with me?
Actually, I'm thinking of running this bar.
I'm still young!
Plus, I'm a beauty, right?
You're not supposed to say it yourself.
But without a doubt, you're a beauty.
Maybe you'll even fall in love with someone.
A good luck charm.
Do you want me to walk you to the station?
No, I'll go by myself.
Oh.
Ah, it's snowing.
Well then, have a safe trip.
Study hard.
OK.
It snowed a little that morning.
It was like "once upon a time" in a fairy tale.
Snow is fitting for farewells.
Happy end...
Or will it be one?
Hello, Akemi?
I just left home.
I'm just going to take a detour before heading for the station.
I think I will arrive on time.
So, how did it go between you and Hiroshi?
About that... Hiroshi is acting strangely.
He just emailed me a while ago,
"Your forehead is cute, I like the shape of your jaw."
As if he doesn't care about what's inside.
Are we really talking about that Mr. Kierkegaard?
Anyway, I can't wait to eat your udon.
Please make a good bowl for me.
I'm walking over snow right now.
It feels like I'm making udon.
Kazuo...
( Grave of Saitou Kazumi )
Goodbye, me.
Goodbye.
Goodbye to you.
Extremely rare, but there is a disease that develops during puberty.
Saitou Kazumi died before she had grown up.
She will continue to live as a child.
To not forget
Is harder than I thought
But don't be upset
Just smile when you recall me
So, take care.
Take care, everyone.
Goodbye, the child in me.
This is how I became myself.
And...
Goodbye to you
We'll never meet again
Starting today, you'll be by my side
Smile back when I recall you
Smile by my side
( Everyone lives to leave their stories behind )
( A person's lifespan is limited, but a story lasts forever )
( Children of the future, are you living to your fullest? )
S
Su
Sub
Subs
Subs b
Subs by
Subs by N
Subs by Ne
Subs by Nec
Subs by Necc
Subs by Necco
Renbutsu Misako as Kazumi
Morita Naoyuki as Kazuo
Shimizu Misa as Kazuo's Mother
Atsuki Takurou as Hiroshi
Terashima Saki as Akemi
Ishida Hikari as The Teacher
Taguchi Tomoroo as Kazumi's Father
Kotegawa Yuuko as Kazumi's Mother
Inuzuka Hiroshi as Kazumi's Grandfather
Kubozuka Shunsuke as Kazumi's Brother
Nagato Hiroyuki as The Doctor
Theme song: "Sayonara no Uta" by Terao Saho
Music by: Yamashita Kousuke
Based on the novel "I'm Her And She's Me" by Yamanaka Hisashi
Sreenplay by: Yamauchi Kenji
Directed by Oobayashi Nobuhiko