(ominous music)
- Looking for someone, son?
- I've come to fetch my brother.
- Yeah.
- All right Mitchell, your year's up.
- [Mitchell] It didn't
seen like more than ten.
- You're lucky it wasn't the rope.
- It looks like the citizens
out there still have ideas.
They don't like gunfighters,
especially drifters and strangers.
We'll take care of them for now.
The next time you have to
come through this town, don't.
All right, give him his gun.
Don't put it on till
you've got out of town.
Wait here.
What do you men want?
- You know what we want.
- You'll have to call it.
- Sure, we'll call it, Brock Mitchell.
- All right, now you'll listen to me.
- Oh, we listen to you what!
You'll have your own way
when he gunned Frank Wilson,
- Wilson was always trouble,
he asked for it.
- Frank Wilson was one of our boys.
- Wilson, forced Mitchell to draw.
I know his reputation wanted
to prove he was faster
than Mitchell.
Wilson lost.
- Yeah, Wilson lost,
because we let you take Mitchell
when you promised they'd get justice.
- But you've crossed us.
Well, we've waited now
we'll see who gets justice.
- Mitchell's done his years.
Under the circumstances that was justice.
Now he leaves town, safe.
Anybody has any other ideas
they come up against me first.
- Hi Brock.
Brought you the colt.
Remember him?
- He's grown some.
- Move.
- Bye sheriff.
Sometime I'd like you to be my guest.
- Remember, if you ever come
through this town here again,
I might not be here,
but they will.
(suspenseful music)
- The railroad will be laying new tracks
starting next month.
Nobody but us and ours ranch,
and Riley's out there to supply beef
for a couple of thousand workers.
- How'd you keep all this
going after pop died?
- Well, I always figured, I
hoped one day you'd be back.
Had to have someplace
for you to come back to.
So Mr. Van Steeden at the
bank gave me a loan of 5,000
on our place,
and now with the railroad contract,
it'll be easy to pay off the bank
and plenty leftover.
- You're a very great, Trace.
- The best.
Come on, let's hustle.
Norris and Riley are meeting us in town.
Phelps, the railroad agent is coming in
on the afternoon stage with the contracts.
One thing.
- Yeah.
Chad Deezy is in town.
- I thought he had his loggers in Fisco.
He came back after you and
his brother had the showdown.
Now that around that
he just wait patiently
for you to come back.
Please, keep hope, Brock,
don't let him push you.
- I am to hang onto my skinny chance.
- Yeah.
(suspenseful music)
(horses neighing)
- Mitchell, I wanna talk you.
(suspenseful music)
I got word from the sheriff in Buckhorn
you were heading this way.
Also from every Sheriff's on
every town you had pass through
from there to here.
- It's nice of them to look out for me.
- All men look out for each other.
I bet time are out of
bounds to you, Mitchell.
I'm telling you right now
I don't like your being
here and Showdown Creek.
- I don't like you not
liking me being here.
This is my home.
- Got no cause to run you
out of town at least not now,
but you take one step out of line,
I'm gonna make you move.
I am to keep this a law abiding town.
I'm not gonna let you repeat
what you did two years ago,
- Sim Deasy drew on me.
- Have you made him draw?
Maybe there was another reason.
- It had nothing to do with your daughter.
- Come on.
- I said my say.
- Yeah, that's how it was, Trace.
Everybody believes I gun Sim Deasy,
because he was seeing Ginny, even Ginny.
That's why I left.
- This aint going to be easy,
but hold on,
just hold on.
- Don't worry.
I'll hold on.
- Glad to see you back home, Brock.
- Thank you, Mr. Norris.
Glad to be here.
Guess Tracy filled you in on the beef deal
with the railroad.
- I think I'd let you
men give him the details.
- Stage will be in half an hour
we better get right to it.
- Now here's the way it cuts,
new track road runs nearest power places.
Nobody else can handle supply,
there will be plenty in
the contract for all of us.
- The road will want plenty
of beef for the men, grading,
digging, and laying the track.
- And Norris and me will
put in the supply joint deal
while they're building the
60 miles south of town.
- And you and Tracy run the supply
for 30 miles north of town.
It cuts to 130 each for
the 90 mile stretch.
- And where there's no cutthroat deals,
we don't drive the price up or down,
and we'll all get a fair
shake of the business.
Deal?
- What do you say, Brock?
- I say I couldn't have
made a better deal myself.
- Ah, I figured we could
settle it friendly,
like we used to with your dad.
- All right, we're all agreed.
Nothing to do now,
but sit here and wait for the
stage to bring Mr. Phelps.
- Is that the railroad agent?
- Yeah.
We see him together,
deal with him together.
There'll be no long woven.
- No one is gonna try
to cut anyone else out.
- Never hurts though to
have all things understood.
Roy, drinks for the boys.
- No thanks, Tracy and I have an errand.
We'll be back on the stage gets in.
- We'll be here.
- They didn't mean anything.
- Nobody means anything.
- You know how they are,
old timers, trusting the
good book and not much else.
Still play poker with two decks
and three guns on the table.
Anything they said wasn't meant personal.
- No, it wasn't meant personal for you.
(door shuts)
- Welcome home, Brock.
- Very glad to see you.
- Thank you.
- He looks pretty good,
doesn't he, Mr. Van Steeden.
- Brock, always look good to me.
Sit down.
Have a cigar, new shipment.
- No, thank you, sir.
- Half the people I know tell me
tobacco is good for the nerves.
The other half telling me it's bad.
Weight on both side.
I guess I know what's worrying you, boys,
worrying me a little too.
- Trace told me about the loan.
It was very kind of you, sir.
- Kindness had nothing to do with it.
I'm a banker using depositors' money.
Your land was good security.
Your note comes due in three days.
I put it the directors for an extension
in case you needed it.
The answer was no.
I think you'd be able to meet it.
- We'll know in about an hour.
- Railroad deal?
- The agents coming in
on the afternoon stage.
- Think you'll be able
to close the contract?
- Well, I hope so,
we're pooling with Norris
and Riley on the deal.
- Smart business.
- They're certain we'll have
the deal roped and tied.
- Even if you're able
to reach the agreement
with the agent tonight,
the contract will have to go to Washington
for final signature.
Now that'll take time more
than you've got to spare.
- Well, can you get the
bank directors to hold off
till the contract is signed?
- I'm getting strong
opposition to this note,
uncommonly strong.
Tell you what?
Try to get a letter or some
sort of written assurance
on the deal from the agent.
Bring it to me,
and I'll personally
assume the responsibility
to give you the extension.
- If anything happens, you
will be left holding the bag.
You were running that risk?
- That's what we're
really here for, Brock.
We passed by this way only once.
We get the chance to run the risk
for a different way of future
life for a boy we like,
we should be grateful to be
given that chance to help.
Anyway, you've had your fling,
I think you'll handle your
responsibilities like a man.
- Thanks for your confidence.
- There is one thing
you always should know.
Someone's pressing to buy
up your note for cash.
- Who?
- Chad Deasy.
He also happens to be on
the board of directors,
that's the opposition to the extension.
Now, you know what you're up against.
- Mm-hmm.
And you?
- I don't like it.
I don't like it because I
know what's pressing Deasy
and it isn't a legitimate business.
- You'd like nothing better
than to get the whip hand over me.
- There's nothing I'd like
less than to give it to him.
- Even by sticking your
own neck out to prevent it?
- Like I said,
we pass by this way only once.
Good luck.
- I dunno, Trace.
I have a feeling this isn't gonna work.
- What are you talking about?
- Chad Deasy, he isn't gonna let it rest.
He's gonna push to a showdown.
One way or another, Deasy is
gonna push me to a showdown.
- Listen, there's nothing he can do
unless you let him.
He's no gun,
so he isn't gonna force you to draw.
There's nothing he can do about our note
once the railroad agent gets here,
just sit tight.
Another couple of hours,
we'll be heading back to the ranch.
Sit tight.
- I heard you were in town, Mitchell.
In fact, I heard you were
heading this way two days ago,
and so I got me an imported
bodyguard from the COllins.
Meet Miley Sutton.
This is Brock Mitchell,
and he's got the reputation
of being the fastest gun
in the territory.
He'd rather gunfight than eat,
so that's what you may
have to come up against.
He likes to specialize in killing Deasys.
He's already gotten my brother Sim,
so watch him.
That's what I'm paying you for.
- Deasy.
- Watch him like you'd watch a Sidewinder.
He's just as quick and just as tricky.
- I killed Sim in a fair fight.
After he'd killed a
drunken 20 year old kid
he bullied into drawing on him.
I've never heard you cry about that kid.
- I wasn't his brother.
The only thing that matters to me
is that Sim was my brother.
- Your brother dropped that kid
then turned his gun on me for no reason.
- No, you yelled,
he turned and you shot.
You wanted him to turn on you,
because of Ginny Clay.
- Brock?
- The next time he makes a move
like that gun him, you hear?
You're my body guard,
and you've got a right to
gun him down like a dog.
- Don't ever get between
me and a gun again.
- I had to.
That's Deasy's play from now on
to get you to draw against his hired gun.
I had to save your skinny chance for you.
(peaceful piano music)
- You had me thinking brothers.
Yeah, it looks like I
got the best of the deal.
- Hello Brock.
- Ginny.
- I heard you were back.
- Yes.
- Oh, this is Mr. Tom Williams.
Tracy and Brock Mitchell.
- Brock Mitchel?
- How do you do you do?
- How do you do, sir?
- Well.
- Well?
- You're looking very well, Brock.
- Thank you.
You look wonderful.
- How have you been?
- Oh fine Brock, just fine.
- That's good.
Do you spend-
- Do you spend-
(suspenseful music)
Well, bye Brock.
Nice seeing you again.
- Goodbye Ginny.
(suspenseful music)
- I was just thinking
maybe after we get settled,
there is no reason why you
shouldn't you and Ginny.
- The way her father feels
about me, I don't know.
(dogs barking)
I don't know.
- Here she comes.
This is it!
(jolly suspenseful music)
(horses galloping)
(dogs barking)
- Mr. Phelps.
- What?
- Are you Mr. Phelps, from Washington?
- No.
- Alabam.
- Hi Tracy,
- You carry a passenger name of Phelps
coming on from Washington,
making connections with
your coach at Gunstock.
- Phelps, Washington?
- A railroad man.
- Oh yeah, that's the fellow.
- Did you see him?
- Yep.
Gunstock.
- He was supposed
to ride in with you.
- That's right.
- Where is he?
- Like I said Gunstock.
- And did you speak to him?
- Yep.
- Why did he say?
- Staying on at Gunstock.
- Is that all?
- Nope, he said had some
business to attend to there.
- He sent a message?
- To who?
- Them, Trace.
- No message, except he had
to stay over for business.
- Yeah, well, nothing we can do about it.
We just have to wait for him.
- You think there's any doubt
about them coming through.
- No, I don't think so.
More than likely he'll be
here by tomorrow stage.
Well, might as well get
ourselves a couple of rooms
at the hotel.
- You figured to stay
over in town for tonight.
- Too hard to ride back at the ranch,
and back to town again tomorrow.
- Well, maybe Brock and I
will go back to our place.
- Might be better for you
and Brock to stay on in town
where we can see you.
It might be a good idea to talk some more
about the deal after dinner.
- Yeah, we'll stay here,
where you can see me.
- Fair enough.
- I think we've gotta stroll
down the hotel and register.
- There isn't anything else we can do?
Let's check in.
(jolly piano music)
Whiskey.
- Yeah.
- I repeat it's the end of any town
when it lets killers roam it's streets,
and peaceful citizens
have to hire bodyguards
to protect themselves.
No, man is safe.
Well, women and children.
If we permit gunfighters to
come and go as they please.
- Let's go.
- Finish your drink.
- How about some Chinese
food across the street?
- No, we'll have our drinks
and dinner here, right here.
- [Chad] I don't know what
that sheriff was thinking of.
If he's afraid of gunfighters,
can't handle the situation let him say so.
Plenty of men in this town are
ready to protect their own.
- Mr. Mitchell.
Mr. Mitchell, good evening?
- Yeah, good evening.
- I just, well,
I want you to know that I-
- What's on your mind?
- Ms. Ginny Clay, sir.
She doesn't mean anything.
I mean, I don't mean anything to her, sir.
- What?
- Well, I just happened to be out there.
I promised her father I'd see
that she got home all right, sir,
and I want you to know that I
didn't mean to cut in on you.
- What are you trying to say?
- I promise I'll never see her again,
and I want to apologize to you, sir.
- No, that you don't have to,
it doesn't mean anything to me.
- I'm sorry, I never-
- I not gonna hurt you.
- You are, you are.
- Don't ever talk to me like that again.
Don't ever come begging
to me, you hear me?
- Please sir, I'll never
see her again I promise.
- Mad dog killer.
(people chattering)
(suspenseful music)
- No lights.
I'm afraid, Tracy.
- Afraid of what?
- Myself.
I'm afraid of what's happening to me.
I'm thinking wrong.
- Brock.
I'm listening.
- I'm beginning to
think everyone hates me,
plotting against me,
and they think I have
no friend but my gun.
- There's me and Van Steeden.
I think there's Ginny too.
- Yeah.
You remember that summer when you, Ginny,
and I were playing at the Creek?
Well, maybe hip high and you ran away,
and got lost in the foot hills.
- Two days and nights,
and you didn't sleep till I was found.
- Yeah.
You tried to tell me
then what it was like,
being out there alone in the nights.
You tried to tell me what
that dark alone feeling.
and the lost feeling was like.
I thought I knew what you were saying,
but I didn't,
I didn't know it all.
I know now I can't find a road, Trace.
I wanna come back to people.
I wanna open up my arms up to them.
I want them to take my
hand when I hold it out,
not look for the gun in it.
I want people to look at me
again with that warm feeling
that I belong.
Yeah, that I belong.
(somber piano music)
I do belong.
(piano music)
- I'll run over and tell Van Steeden
Mr. Phelps would be in town today.
Meet you at the Queen.
- Okay.
- Mr. Mitchell, why did you do it?
- Ma'am?
- Driving my boy out of town,
beating him, and threatening him.
- Your boy?
- Only a boy.
Only 20 years old.
Told him you'd gun him down
if he didn't leave town.
You warned him not to see that girl again.
- No.
No, it isn't true.
- How could you do such a thing?
- Ginny?
Please listen to me.
- Let me pass.
- I swear it isn't true.
- I thought it was all just talk
until I heard Mrs. Williams version.
- No, it didn't happen like that.
- You threatened him.
- That's a lie.
- Everybody there heard it.
- I was only trying to help.
- You come as a client or as a gun?
But you finally found
me without a bodyguard.
You know, I never carry a gun,
so it should be easy for you.
- You know you don't need a bodyguard.
We both know why you're doing this.
- Doing what?
- You're playing a tight game,
close to the vest.
But you might've make one
raise too much and be cold.
You know a man can only be
pushed and baited so far.
- Call me, that's what I'm counting on.
- He's in the business
last night with a kid
at the Mountain Queen,
now I'm down in the
street with his mother.
- You know I don't think
it's all just happened
out with the blue.
- And that's where you are
fishing out in the blue.
You're spinning, you're reeling.
You're dizzy, Mitchell.
You're losing your grip and you know it,
that's the difference between us.
I know how to wait it out, you don't.
- Yeah, and that's the
risk you're running.
- Let me lay it out for you.
You killed my brother,
before I'm through with you,
you'd wish it was the other way around.
I'm going to make you a mop
for every trigger, happy punk.
I'm gonna push you off
the land, out of town,
into the saddle,
onto the trail with nothing
but your roll and gun.
There won't be a town of a
thousand miles where the sheriff
won't be waiting for,.
Won't be at town and a thousand miles
where you'll be able to rest your head.
- I've learned to take
the shots as they come.
- Saddle bum, just rolling and rolling
till you reach that spot
where the faster shot is waiting for you,
and you catch that final
bullet between the eyes.
That's the way it's going to
be and nothing can stop me.
Only one thing worries
me that you go quietly
into some dark corner right now,
and put a bullet in your head
to save yourself all
that grief and misery.
That's the one thing I
can't stop you from doing.
- I know Deasy,
you figure you've got a
legitimate burn against me.
All right, but by trying
to drive me off the ranch
you're hurting an
innocent kid, my brother.
There was another innocent kid
who was hurt.
He happened to be my brother,
but I'll make a deal with you,
I'll leave Tracy be,
even see that he gets a year's
extension on his bank note.
All you got to do is to sign this,
and get out of town.
Very simple as to clear
and clean admission
that you killed Sim,
deliberately, 'cause you were jealous.
After you'd warned him to
stay away from Ginny Clay.
- Hold it.
Raise them.
Raise.
What do we do with them, Mr. Deasy?
- It looks like we got
everything in our hands now,
doesn't it?
Notorious gunfighter, half
the town saw him come up
to the office of the man
who's brother he gunned.
He put the gun to me,
but just in time my bodyguard.
Yeah, he's a lawyer.
My professional opinion,
I'd say that was self-defense,
clean and clear.
Wouldn't you, Sutton?
- Anything you say, Mr. Deasy.
- Yes, I think that would
hold it up in any court.
Of course I had other plans for Mitchell,
but this sure is one way
of a little bit temptation.
What do you say, Sutton?
- Well, no telling how long
did it drag on otherwise?
And I got a job waiting for me in Durango.
All right, fella, pick it up.
- Making you look good for the law, huh?
- No hard feelings.
Just another job to me.
But pick it up or I'll club you blind.
(Gun fires)
(punch thuds)
- Hold it.
(window crushes)
Now, there're a dozen witnesses down there
that will swear that they
saw my gun fly out the window
after one shot,
and they'll find that bullet in the wall.
Shoot now and they'll know you
did it when I was in armed.
- Maybe another time, Mitchell.
Another place.
- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm afraid you're right.
- You're all right, you didn't?
- No, nothing happened.
- I was just coming out of the bank
when I heard the shot then
your gun came sailing out.
What happened?
- Anybody hurt up there?
- No.
- Come to my office.
All right, what happened?
- [Brock] Oh, Sutton Drew,
and I knocked the gun out of his hand.
The shot went wild.
- Then what?
- Then I threw my gun out the window.
That's the way it happened.
- You have trouble, Mitchell.
Ever since you came back
nothing but trouble.
- Yeah, but I'm not asking for.
- Just seems to grow
around you like wheat.
Well, last night,
you had threatened young Tom Williams,
scared him out of town.
A whole bar room full
of people saw you do it.
We both know the reason why.
- You put me in a tough spot,
and I'm trying hard to
think only as it's sheriff.
I think of what's good for this town.
I got a lot of reasons I'm
trying to keep out of my mind.
Yeah.
We know what those reasons are.
That's why I'm bending over
backwards trying to be fair.
But just one more thing, Mitchell,
just one more thing.
(suspenseful music)
- Anything else?
- Brock's trying.
He's trying real hard to settle down.
He needs help.
(suspenseful music)
(jolly music)
(dogs barking)
(suspenseful music)
He didn't show?
- No.
- Alabama, you see Mr. Phelps in Gunstock?
- Nope.
- Did he say anything?
Probably just held over on
railroad business there.
He'll be here tomorrow for sure.
- We haven't much time, Trace.
- We just wait it out.
- Maybe one of us ought
to ride over to Gunstock.
- That's a good idea.
It's a hard ride,
but Brock can make it there
and back by nightfall.
- Well, I don't know.
- Why not?
Let's find out how we
stand with Mr. Phelps.
- Might not look too good
to push him like that.
- That's right.
You think we're all so anxious
likely to drive our price down,
right Norris?
- That's the way I figured.
- Look, our notes due at
the bank tomorrow night.
- Then let's wait till tomorrow night.
- We have to know where we stand.
It makes sense to me to ride
out a Gunstock and find out.
You don't trust me.
- It isn't a question of trust.
We're in this together
and agreed there'd be no lone wolfing.
- Anybody could ride who wants you.
- No, you don't go to
Seatumbs and Gunstock.
- I don't see how I can be stopped.
- You'll go and Norris and me
pull out of the deal with you.
Your ranch can handle the contract alone.
And we train Norris and me,
we might be able to make
the stretch for service
in the road,
so make up your mind.
- Let Trace go.
- No, this kind of deal
wouldn't look right
to send a kid like Tracy.
- You better keep your
brother in line, Tracy.
We like you, but he's trouble.
Just keep him in line.
- Brock?
- Don't worry, Trace.
I'll stay.
I won't cause you any more trouble.
(ambient music)
(horse neighs)
Hey, it doesn't seem too
long ago that you, Trace,
and I used to-
- Yes, seems like only yesterday.
A lot of water's trend
down this Creek fit.
- [Brock] Where did it all go gone?
- Gone, I thought.
- [Brock] Yeah, a lot has
happened to both of us.
- I'd rather not talk about it, Brock.
- Maybe talking about it will help us find
where it all went.
- [Ginny] Will it?
- It was good between us once, very good.
- Brock?
- Yes, Ginny.
- A river can't run the other way, ever.
- Maybe that's what I'm
trying to do with my life,
run he river backwards.
But ever since I've
trouble with Sim Deasy,
the river just seemed to pick me up,
and roll me away.
No, time to swim, fight, or even breathe.
You know, it doesn't seem possible
that a feeling between two
people could stopped cold
than the time it takes
a bullet to leave a gun.
- Do you think it's been easy for me?
- [Brock] Then why all this?
- You know why.
- No, Ginny, all I know is
that without ever see me again,
you believe what you were told
that I killed a man deliberately.
- [Ginny] Well, you forced me
to believe it, you went away.
- Look, I had never killed a man before.
And that night when you wouldn't see me,
you could've stopped me, Ginny.
All you had to say was,
"I stand with Brock,"
but no, you turned the other way,
- Please Brock.
I...
- Ginny.
All right, it's done.
I don't wanna hurt you or myself
trying to roll the river back.
Just one thing,
I was forced to shoot Sim Deasy,
and I never threatened Tom Williams.
Do you believe me?
(suspenseful music)
(horse gallops)
- Anytime that hot shot once
wants to slow down with me,
he knows where he can find me.
I'd even give him the draw.
Well, there's the big man now.
And what do you know?
Look, man, no guns.
A gunless gunfighter like
gunless gutless wonder.
- Brock, we better go.
- No.
- Pretty tricky, you know.
Now where do you think he hides his guns?
Under his hat?
Maybe he's got some sort
of new weapons, huh?
Hey you!
I mean you, gunless.
You got some kind of new weapon, huh?
Name it.
I'll meet you with anything you call,
even feather pillows at 10 paces.
Well, it's better pillars,
you're gonna have to give me a break.
Let me throw mine, first.
No wonder of the age.
The gunless gutless wonder.
Scares women and children out of town.
Oh now, I hurt his feelings.
I ain't been fair.
All right, gutless, reach for it.
Reach.
(Sutton blows)
(people chattering)
(gun fires)
(punch thuds)
(punches thudding)
(bottle shattering)
- [Man] Come on!
- Brock!
(punch thuds)
- [Man] Just get up now!
- Brock, stop it!
(horse neighs)
Brock, stop it!
Stop!
You...
all of you.
You did this to him,
pushing him.
Baiting him.
Sniffing at him like an animal.
Making an animal of them.
All he wanted was to...
all he wanted was to...
- [Brock] Is he dead?
- No.
- I wanted him dead.
It's no good, Trace,
a killer, an animal.
I'm like an animal.
- No, you're not.
They're right.
So many people they must be right.
- No, don't let them be right.
- I couldn't stop.
I wanted to sink my teeth into his throat.
Clay is right,
I am trouble.
It grows around me like weeds,
every one I touch.
I shouldn't have come back.
I'm leaving.
(somber piano music)
- All right, you leave again.
but not without me.
You think I tried to keep
the ranch going for myself,
I don't want it without you.
I don't want any part of
that loneliness anymore.
You hit the trail,
I hit it with you.
You live in the saddle, the
saddle boom I live it with you.
You can't run away from it anymore, Brock.
I'm tired of holding the fort by myself.
(suspenseful music)
- Fix my face.
I can't look like this
when Phelps gets to town.
Hey, easy!
(sheep bleating)
- Howdy?
- Morning.
- You come the price I'm cuttings.
- No.
- No?
I don't know where them clothes
are supposed to come from.
You sure you aint a fellow named McCots?
- No, I'm look-
- No, funny.
We've been waiting for this fella to,
are you sure you aint
a fella named McCots.
- Listen, I'm sure I'm
not a fella named McCots,
and I didn't come for the cutting.
I'm looking for Mrs. Williams,
is she around?
- Yeah, she's up by the barn.
- Thanks.
- I sure don't know what we're
gonna do with them cuttings.
(sheep bleating)
(dogs barking)
- Morning.
- Your face, how?
- I guess it's all part of what happened
between us yesterday.
- I don't understand.
- People accusing me of
running people out of town.
Mrs. Williams, you know I
didn't threaten your boy.
Now if he left town
there was another reason.
- I'm sorry, Mr. Mitchell.
I'm very busy just now and.
- Mrs. Williams, I must talk to you.
I don't think you realize
how important this is to me.
- I've got nothing to talk
to you about, nothing.
I didn't ask you to come here,
and I want you to go.
Please, just go away.
- I think I understand how you feel.
Sometimes they're forced to
do things one way or another,
that we're ashamed of later.
It isn't easy to speak the truth
once the lie starts,
one lie leads to another until
we get in deeper and deeper,
and well it looks like
there's no other way,
but to go on with it,
no matter who it hurts,
that's what's happening to you.
- I've got problems enough on my own.
Gotta get on with my work.
Got a living to make.
- And I have a life to make.
(Mrs. Williams sobs)
I'm sorry, I better be going.
- Oh, forgive me.
Please, forgive me.
- It was Deasy, wasn't it?
- Yeah, he came to town and
said he tear up the notes
if we would, (sobs) we would.
- I don't blame you Mrs. Williams.
I know what Chad Deasy can do.
- I begged Tom not to do it,
but he wouldn't listen.
Said we were in deep
trouble about those notes,
and he meant well.
- Mrs Williams, thank you.
It took a lot of curries to tell me this.
I only wish I could help you.
There is one thing I can do though,
keep this quiet.
I don't care much what people think now,
except one person.
I'd like you to tell her the truth.
- Just tell me what you want me to do.
- Thank you.
I'll be back.
(horse galloping)
(dog barks)
(Brock knocks)
(door opens)
Hello, Ginny.
- Your face?
- Yeah.
Ginny, I know how you feel about me.
- Please Brock, there's
no use talking about it.
- I don't intend to.
But there's one thing
that's very important to me.
- What is it Brock?
- Ride with me,
it won't take long.
after that I promise I
won't trouble you anymore.
- Wait for me.
(suspenseful music)
- And Chad Deasy, he said
he'd tear up the note
if Tom would leave town.
I hate to admit it,
but I finally agreed,
and promised Mr. Deasy I'd
make a scene on the street
to embarrass Mr. Mitchell.
You never threatened Tom, I know that.
I just wish I hadn't let myself to.
Please forgive me.
- Thank you Mrs. Williams.
(peaceful guitar music)
Well, that's about it.
I just want you to know.
(suspenseful music)
- What'd you run off
to while I was asleep?
You've been gone almost all day.
- I had to find out something.
It's all right now.
- I see the stage got in early.
Phelps didn't show. huh?
- Let's go see Van Steeden now,
maybe he can come up with an idea.
- All right.
- The stages in.
- I heard.
- Mo railroad agent.
- I also heard.
- Is that all you have to say?
- You come to my office,
I didn't come to yours.
- Oh, there's no reason for us
to play cute with each other.
Mitchell can pick up his note,
and his chances of getting
the money are very, very slim.
- That's the bank's business.
- And the depositors of which I happen
to be one of the largest and a director.
- Well, you should have
bought my offer, Mitchell.
At least you've done for your kid brother.
Very well, headstrong,
Always too late for the headstrong.
- Mitchell's note is
mot due until sundown.
Tell them there's nothing to talk about.
How then you'll have to, excuse me.
These gentlemen are waiting to see me.
- It doesn't take much in these parts
to be called a gentlemen,
even if you're a bankrupt.
Oh, well I guess I can wait till tonight.
I'm a patient, man.
If I have to, I can even wait
till there's a new banker.
I'll see you after
business hours, tonight.
- It's like my trouble wits are beginning
to trip you up too.
- I can handle myself.
- That'd be a good thing
, Brock, for the community
if someone can finally handle Deasy.
No, no, no, don't be getting any ideas.
- No worries, sir, I'm past that.
- I shouldn't have said that, but that,
well boys, it doesn't look too good.
You just saw for yourselves
what I'm up against.
If you can't get some assurance
on that railroad contract
by sundown, we're late.
Now one of you better hustle
up the Gunstock and see Phelps.
- You know how Norris and
Riley feel about that.
If they pull out on us,
well, we haven't got any chance at all.
- None, unless somebody
gets a note from Phelps,
and now I think Tracy and I see things
even clearer than you
what this thing means.
It isn't just saving the land.
It isn't just foreclosing
on a piece of property.
It's foreclosing on a man's life.
- It isn't easy to join
the human race again.
Once you've been drummed out, we'll try.
- You rode out of town this morning.
- I didn't ride to Gunstock
if that's what you mean.
- No, now let's not fly off the handle.
We're all under a strain.
Riley didn't mean nothing.
- You only made that nothing pretty plain.
- Sit down and talk this out.
No profit for anyone
yapping at each other.
- All right, let's put it on the line.
You men don't trust me,
but you know and respect, trace.
- That's for sure.
- Well, this beef deal means more to Trace
than it does to me.
- To us.
- Our bank note's due tonight.
If one of us doesn't get
to Phillips before that
then Tracy's lost his ranch,
and he's gambling everything on this deal.
- And Brock's gambling more
than a hunk of property.
You both know that.
- Go on, we're listening.
- You men can sit and wait out,
but we can't.
Let Trace ride the Gunstock.
He can make it there and back by then.
He can see Phelps and get a note from him,
and we'll catch you in
for a piece of our share.
- Okay, Trace,
- Whatever you say, Brock.
- Agreed?
- Where will you be while
Tracy's up to Gunstock?
- Where you can both see me every minute.
- Agreed, and share Stan pack.
- Agreed.
- We better get priding.
- Where are you going?
- To help Trace saddle up.
- He's a big boy.
- You just stay with us, Brock
till Tracy gets back to town,
that way you won't get lonely.
- Order yourself some food.
He went off without
breakfast this morning.
- I don't know what you mean.
(tense music)
(horse galloping)
- Mr. Phelps?
- Yes.
What can I do for you?
- I'd like to talk to you, sir?
- (laughs) Sure, sit down here.
- Thank you, sir.
- Something to drink?
- No, thank you, sir.
I'm Tracey Mitchell, Mr. Phelps.
- Mitchell?
- From showdown Creek.
- Well, I haven't seen in
the past, Mr. Mitchell,
I'd expected you to be
well, a little older.
- Well, the boss of our
ranch is my brother, Brock.
He's older and very dependable.
- Yes, I'm sure.
Well, son, I'm glad you got here sooner,
Norris and Riley with you?
- Sooner?
- Well, I didn't expect you
until the last day of the week.
I didn't mind waiting though
since I had business here in Gunstock.
That it was very thoughtful of you men
to save me the trip to Showdown Creek.
- But we've been waiting for you, sir.
- Waiting for me?
- In Showdown Creek.
- For how long?
- Three days now, sir.
- But that's when I got
the letter three days ago,
said you were coming up
here to save me the trip
to Showdown Creek.
- What is that, sir?
- Got a letter from the attorney
representing you as syndicate.
Here.
A Mr. Chad Deasy.
(suspenseful music)
(horse galloping)
(gun fires)
(horse neighs)
- Well.
- Mm, getting late.
- Maybe the kids staying over
in Gunstock for the night.
- No.
- Any word from Tracy.
- Getting late.
- I know.
- I just saw Deasy.
Squatting like a vulture.
Just waiting.
(horse galloping)
Any ideas, Brock?
- No, he knows the notes due tonight.
He should have been here long ago.
- Here's my check for the Mitchell note.
Time's not up yet.
I'm a patient man,
but you're beginning to try me.
There's not one chance for
Mitchell and you know it.
- What makes you so sure?
- I'll be in my office at six.
Just make certain that you
show up there right on time.
- I'm really worried, Brock.
- Yes, so am I.
(door closes)
(horse neighs)
- Brock!
(Tracy thuds)
- I saw Phelps.
- Don't talk, Trace.
Get the doctor.
Then I hid the letter Phelps gave me
under some rock.
- Tracy, please don't talk.
- I got to tell you now,
Sutton bushwhacked me.
He left me for dead.
I made it back to the rocks got letters.
Letters that...
Deasy wrote Phelps
told him to wait.
Other letter Phelps gave me
assurance of deal
to give to Van Steed.
- Trace, hold on.
Trace, you leave me alone.
You hear me?
Don't cover him!
Leave us alone.
- I wouldn't go in now.
- Chad Deasy had your brother killed.
I killed Deasy's brother and Tracy.
- No, Brock.
- The bullet that went
through Deasy's body,
my blood, it never stopped
until it found Trace
and killed him.
- My father is the law.
But the law is and always justice, Brock.
You didn't murder Sim Deasy.
I know that now,
but Tracy was murdered.
Tracy never harmed anyone.
He never even carried a gun.
They murdered him, Brock,
and if you don't settle this yourself,
you desert your own brother.
You can let Trace's life go for nothing,
and I couldn't love a man who would.
- I can't touch a gun again.
- Pay me off.
- Did you get the letter?
- No letter, but the job is done.
- What do you mean?
- The job's done, finished.
Now pay me off.
- the letter.
- No, one's gonna find out
anything until tomorrow.
- Find out what?
- Tracy Mitchell is dead.
I had to gun him.
- You killed him?
- Yeah.
Now pay me off.
- You killed him.
- My pay!
- Brock Mitchell's brother.
- Yeah, I killed Brock Mitchell's brother.
- Brock Mitchell, you killed his brother.
- Now you want the credit?
All right, you say you killed him.
I won't argue with you.
- You don't understand Mitchell.
He'll come after me.
- Just be polite to him.
- He'll kill me.
You can't leave me.
You gotta protect me.
He'll come after you too,
he'll kill you too.
- I'll be long gone by
the time he finds out.
- You are my bodyguard,
you've got to protect me.
- Let go!
- You can't leave me here alone.
Let go of me.
(punch thuds)
(door opens)
- All right Sutton, we're not slow,
keep your hands up.
Hold it.
No, gun play.
Go down to Parkman building,
we want to take him alive.
- But.
- Wait a minute.
- Hey Kim, Herbert, cover him.
Hey, Herbert?
Get back.
(tense suspenseful music)
(gun fires)
(tense music)
(guns firing)
Hold your fire!
- What's the matter?
You run out of bullets?
Okay, this is the way it's gonna be.
I'm getting on my horse,
the girls getting on with me.
We're leaving this town,
and nobody's gonna stop us.
(suspenseful music)
all right, little one.
(belt thuds)
- [Man] Hold it!
- Sutton, let the girl go.
Sutton, I'm asking you as a father,
let my girl go!
(door closes)
- Well, the gunless gutless Wonder.
(tense music)
- Wait!
You're my bodyguard,
I paid you, you can't leave me.
I'll ruin you.
- Get off.
(guns firing)
- My bodyguard, I'll ruin you.
I'll ruin all of you.
Sutton bomb that's what
I'll make out of you.
(slap thuds)
(guns firing)
(horse neighs)
(suspenseful music)
Don't shoot.
- There's nothing more
that gun can do to you,
or for you.
(suspenseful music)
(horse gallops)
(ominous music)
(upbeat music)