My man's a boxer.
You're going to get me beat up.
Sit down, girl.
She's scared of getting beat up.
It's going to start soon.
Let's play!
People want music.
We'll play and then we'll leave.
Why is there no music today?
Fuel…
No, no. Stan.
Start!
Good evening.
How are you?
- Fine.
I like it when you all drink.
You all have to drink, like me.
Wait.
Are you an intern here?
Shiny
Graduate
Hands off.
Watch out, OK.
Give me four skewers.
I am Tabu!
Tabu Fatu!
Hang on.
Thanks to you I'm going to drink and eat.
Stop it, I'm working.
Bring me my feeding bottle!
He's already drunk!
He's well over his limit.
Sing, mama. Sing.
Yesterday, I met a woman.
Like nothing you've ever seen!
Imagine a mix of wonders!
The mountains,
the lakes, the trees,
vegetables, spices, salt.
It's killing me!
If a man loves you,
love yourself.
God needs only the soul.
The body will rot.
We're in the middle of a battle.
Stop lying.
So, what would you think
of this diamond ring?
You've hooked your prey.
Even night has two sides.
So does your mama.
You're drunk.
Go home!
- Who do you take me for?
Get out!
Wait. It's coming!
A terrible rape!
Children kill. Even small kids.
Never!
You're arguing over false issues!
People don't speak their minds.
Who knows what they think?
Whoever dares!
I'll send him back up his mother's ass!
His whore of a mother!
What are you A terrible?
Who do you think you are?
Calm down, calm down…
Hit him!
How dare you?
You're paying for this.
Leave him…
He went too far!
Leave him, leave him.
Tabu, Tabu?
Bandit?
Go find me someone to mend my fridge.
Bandit!
Where's the repair man?
- There is no-one else.
What are you doing here?
- You're the one who called for me.
Come in.
You mend fridges?
Has it got a motor?
It's the fan.
What do you mean, the fan?
Not even two weeks.
I paid 60000 francs
to buy a motor.
Your colleague said it was the motor.
60000 francs,
less than two weeks ago!
And now you say it's the fan!
First, he's not my colleague.
Second, it's not his fault,
this time, it's the fan.
Your sure it's a problem with the fan?
Sure?
I shouldn't have listened to that crook.
I wanted to get a new fridge,
but he told me not to.
To wait for him
to come back and mend it.
How much for the fan?
Give me 30000 francs
plus my work.
How much?
30000 francs?
That's $100
for an old machine I…
OK!
I'll buy a new one for you.
A new one?
Give me $250
and I'll get you a new fridge.
I can't.
I can give you 100.
Give me 150.
I give you 150
and you bring me a new fridge?
Give me 150.
I'll find a good one.
The other guy told me the same thing.
The liar.
I should never have listened to him.
You repair men, all crooks!
He lied about the motor,
when it was something else.
It's my own fault. Too gullible.
Do this, don't do that.
Do that? That's not right.
What am I going to do?
I'm going to go bankrupt.
My hard-earned money…
Just give it to him…
Find me a robust fridge.
A good one.
Not like this one.
Let it be strong!
DRC!
Hello?
Yes, it's me.
The hospital?
He's my son.
Papa.
- Yes, mama.
I got a call, my child was in an accident.
At what time?
I don't know. They just called me.
Go that way.
Mama!
I'm looking for Samo.
- Samo?
I got a call.
- Which pavilion?
11.
- 11? I'll show you.
Pavilion 11
When you get to that corner,
go all the way to the end.
They'll tell you where pavilion 11 is.
Mama, where is 11?
- 11 is just there.
Samo.
Calm down, dear.
The nurse is there.
She's there.
Nurse!
Yes?
You've got to move him.
He can't stay like that.
Who?
- My son. What happened to him?
It was a road accident.
An accident?
But how did it happen?
Motorbike, I think.
A motorbike accident, this bad?
- Calm down, mama.
Wait for the doctor, we'll know more.
Who brought him here?
When?
The police…
- And they left him in that state?
We'll look after him.
He's got to go to another room.
He can't stay here like this!
We'll move him, but it'll cost more.
I'll pay!
- Not now.
Calm down.
Wait for the doctor,
he'll sort everything out.
Listen to me, calm down.
Let's wait for the doctor.
Mama, give me two loaves.
Hurry, please.
What's the problem? I've just got here.
Listen to me first.
His left leg is broken.
It's an open fracture
and there's a lot of bleeding.
But we can mend it.
What's needed?
He needs an operation.
- Then operate him.
It will cost you a lot of money.
I work.
Money isn't a problem.
Tell me how much it's going to cost.
For the operation,
it's 600 to 700000 Congolese francs.
But it's not just the operation.
He'll need more care and treatment.
In all it will cost
one million Congolese francs.
- Operate, papa!
Do it!
- Yes, yes…
But first we need pan payment.
As soon as you've paid,
we will start with the operation.
But first you should buy
the necessary medicines.
What medicines must I buy?
I don't know.
I've prepared a prescription.
See the nurse.
Does the nurse…?
Go that way.
You'll find her in her office.
That way?
- Yes, that way.
My child.
I'm going to the pharmacy.
Give me your prescription.
So that I can help you.
You're exhausted.
Mama.
Leave it.
How will you pay?
Drink some water.
Do you want to eat?
Shall I give you some food?
Do you want some water?
Mama, are you asleep?
Should we take him to another room?
Yes.
Did you buy the medicines?
Where is the woman who was here?
I don't know. Do you know her?
Did you give her money?
Papa?
Where is the woman who was there?
- I don't know her.
Your wife, she was sitting there.
I don't know her.
Why did you do that?
You still want us
to take him to another room?
Leave it. You'll pay the cashier.
Buy the medicine.
He needs it.
Change his room.
Papa, come and help.
We'll put him over there.
Don't drink too much tonight.
I want your instrument to work.
Give me your hat.
Hey! What's up with you?
Take the hat and come with me.
Have you seen our singer?
Her son needs an operation.
She's looking for money.
He's collecting donations,
little by little.
Whatever is left, you can give it to her.
There!
Like that!
You 're crazy!
I'm happy!
You're like lightning!
You sorcerer!
Pay me!
And keep owing me!
Like that!
Thank you!
We've been summoned.
I was told
that
our colleague,
Félicité… her son,
had a terrible accident.
So, I ask you,
without forcing anyone,
to find it in your heart to help her.
Well, we all have our problems.
And if we all come here with them,
none of us will eat.
We all contribute for funerals.
But, by the grace of God,
the child is still alive.
I don't want it said
that it was me who refused.
I just want everyone to be aware
of what is being asked.
Let each person give
what they are able to.
But do not put me
in judgment before God.
That's not right.
I never ask.
Mama…
"If you lack money, have friends".
Dieudo has spoken well, but…
Félicité is right too.
She hadn't asked for anything.
What we've been told is upsetting.
It has provoked much argument.
But we must help her.
OK, so, let he who has a little money
and the heart to give,
give something.
God will return it to you.
Even if Félicité is like she is,
she was created this way,
but everybody changes.
How did you get in?
Marry me, mama,
your life will improve.
If you forget me,
I will strangle your little neck.
You are tiny to me.
Félicité…
You are beautiful.
Like the leaves of brambles.
When they laugh,
nobody sees them.
Félicité…
Look at me
and let your heart quiver.
You are beautiful, mama.
Like the leaves of brambles.
When they laugh,
nobody sees them.
Like when you laugh.
Do you want someone to take you?
Who? You?
No.
How much will I have to pay?
Just the petrol.
When you're done,
leave the keys at the shop.
Is it you or someone else?
How did you let yourself go like this?
You used to be a presentable woman.
Your mother used to tell me…
That she was
always worried for you.
I told her:
"Your daughter is brave."
She answered:
"She is too tough for her own good".
How did you end up this ugly?
I need your help.
You were dead, you know?
You were only one or two years old.
You died.
You became very ill and died.
We put you in a coffin.
The priests were called for the burial.
And then you woke up.
That's why we changed your name.
Your name was Kapinga.
We rechristened you Félicité,
"Our Joy".
We never told you
so that you wouldn't leave again.
Nobody will help me.
You've come at the wrong time.
I have nothing.
Give me what you can.
Papa, I've come for my money.
How about a "Hello" first!
- Hello, I've come for what you owe me.
This is a bad time.
- I don't have any time.
Are you going to pay me or not?
You know the situation.
Wait, wait…
Wait!
Agent Faustin.
My 50000 francs.
But, I told you that…
- Sir!
You're coming to the station!
You know who I am?!
Get your hands off!
Walk, I said. We're going
Don't lay your hands on me.
Do you know me?
Pay now!
I'm going to your superiors!
You don't know me!
You! Get out of my sight.
You're fired!
Get those little legs out of here!
Pay the money!
Understood?
Mama, give me that money!
Take your money!
Don't ever come back here!
You dare bring the police here?!
Get out! Leave!
Get out!
I'm not giving you anything!
Wait,
I'll give you what you came for…
Olivine, come here!
Take my child. Sell her!
To pay off your debt.
Sell the child for your money.
What's going on?
That's no way to act!
- No, no, no…
Go and sell her!
Let her take the child, papa.
She can sell her to get her money back.
She dares bring the police here.
Get out!
You owe her the money.
Stay calm.
Move back, Sir.
Work it out
- Mama, move back. Move back!
The State will…
Take this money. Take it and leave.
Get your hands off me!
Is that a way to behave?
It's the last time.
Look at her eyes!
Hey, mama.
What are you giving me here?
Mama.
It's 120000 short.
I know.
OK…
I'll subtract the cost of the room.
What's left,
I'll keep as an advance.
The day you pay we'll operate your boy.
Papa?
- Yes?
Listen, mama…
If you want,
we can put him with all the others.
It will be less expensive.
What do you say?
- No.
You want him over there?
- Yes.
We can change his room.
No!
Leave him there.
I'll be back tonight to pay the rest.
OK, fine.
Here.
Samo is at the hospital.
He needs an operation.
He had a motorbike accident.
You got rid of me.
Give me some money.
Who showed you where I live?
It's not for me, it's for the kid.
Give me some money. I'll leave.
Whose motorbike was he on?
Does he go to school?
You see!
You've raised a thug!
But he's your son.
You wanted to be a strong woman!
With lessons to give to the whole world!
This isn't about you and me.
So what are you doing here?
It's for your child.
You don't know what to do.
You're less cocky now!
The price of pride!
Give me the money.
I'll leave.
You've raised a thug
in your own home!
You puffed out your chest!
The strong woman!
Fooling yourself!
Look at you now.
You don't know where to turn.
You're useless!
Get out!
Give me some money.
Out!
Get out!
- I'm not leaving.
What do you want?
I'm looking for the boss.
Hello, mama.
- Hello.
You're looking for the boss?
- Yes.
He didn't say he was expecting
anyone this morning.
But he told me to come.
He always warns me
if somebody is coming.
Do you know his whole family?
- No, but he didn't say anything.
But you know me?
- No, it's the first time I see you.
Why would I have come here?
I don't know. I'll ask him.
- He asked me to come.
You don't know his whole family!
No, wait here.
- You don't know who I am.
Madame, wait, I have to ask the boss
before letting you in.
You think I'm a mad woman?
- You can't just enter like that.
You can't just enter.
Wait for me to ask.
You're going to get me into trouble.
You'll get me fired.
The boss won't like it.
Wait while I ask the boss.
Hello boss.
- Hello.
There's someone here for you.
For me?
- Yes.
Your little sister.
Hello, mama.
Hello, papa.
Do we know each other?
No.
Papa, I'm here to ask for your help.
My son had a motorbike accident.
He's in hospital.
He needs an operation.
I have no money.
I've come to ask for your help.
Help me, I am your sister.
Judith.
- Boss.
Next time you let someone
in off the street,
you're fired.
Forgive me, Boss.
Mama.
How did you get in?
I stand before you as a singer.
I get by alone.
I've come to you,
but I'm not someone who begs.
I've come to ask for your help.
If you don't help me
my son will lose his leg.
I have nowhere else to go.
Judith.
- Boss.
Is mama here?
She's gone out, boss.
Auguste!
Get her out of here. Now.
- Papa.
You need to leave!
- Help me, papa.
Let's go.
- Have mercy, papa.
Mama, let's go!
Mama.
- Papa.
Get back here! Leave!
Papa, please help me.
- Come here. Get out!
Papa, don't leave me like this.
Let go of me!
Out!
Get her out. People will think
we're killing someone.
Out! Out!
- I'm dying!
Help! I'm dying!
Let go of me!
Get out!
Come here, you. Out.
Get out.
- Let go of me!
Out. Out.
- I'm dying!
Stop. Leave her.
Leave her be.
I'm giving you this money out of pity.
If you come back, we will kill you.
Judith.
- Boss.
Give it to her.
Let's go, mama.
And don't come back here.
Your going to get me sacked.
Doctor!
I have the money.
Stay calm.
Mama, wait there, I'm coming.
I have to tell you something.
Quiet now… Be calm.
Try to calm down.
No.That's not it.
Listen to me first.
After you left, his leg got much worse.
He lost a lot more blood.
We've just amputated the leg.
We absolutely had to, otherwise…
Listen.
Otherwise he would be dead.
So…
No, first, listen to me.
Listen.
Everything will be alright.
God will watch over him.
The fan isn't working.
I'm going to get you another one.
A fan.
Can you come with me to get Samo?
Somebody will have to carry him.
No problem.
You really have to look after his leg.
It's not the end of the world.
What matters most,
is that he is still alive.
That's what really matters to us.
You've got to follow his treatment.
His pills… you really must
make sure he takes them.
You will need to help the boy.
Especially with his crutches…
So that he doesn't start
having problems with the other leg.
Careful, watch out for the wound.
You see that robot, Félicité?
That robot was built here in the Congo.
Our Congo will go a long way!
Just like me, Tabu.
One day, you will be amazed
to see me on the TV,
literally standing on the moon.
Literally standing on the moon.
Jumping from star to star,
from one to the other,
like those guys on their motorbikes…
Because I am great, me, Tabu!
I am greater than all the stars.
The stars are nothing to me.
Are you with me?
The stars are tiny to me.
Yes, mama?
Félicité.
Mama, your troubles touched our hearts.
Everything is in the hands of God.
Without God,
we may have lost the child.
Hang in there, my friend.
All this was God's will.
- Yes, God's will.
The child has been saved.
Let us Give thanks to God.
Be brave.
- Hang in there.
Mama, I rejoice
that you are among us.
Believe. God's will shall be done.
Be brave.
May God watch over you
and give you strength.
Look for God's presence.
He will help the boy recover.
Be strong in prayer.
Be strong.
Thank you mama. God watches over us.
Thank you, mothers,
for coming to visit us.
But please leave us now.
We need some peace and quiet.
Thank you for the love you have shown us.
Thank you, papa. Stay with God.
Thank you, mama.
May God be with you.
- Thank you
By the grace of God,
may the child recover.
Thank you, all of you.
Please let us rest a bit.
Thank you. Be well.
- Thank you.
Aren't you going to sing, Félicité?
Sing!
Félicité I?
Hello.
- Hello.
Sing, sing, sing!
Don't stay alone.
We need to be able
to run this campus.
But you, scoundrels,
why don't you give up?
Friend, we are going to behead this woman.
She has shown us no respect.
She will get a beating.
Hit her!
Mama!
But… I… told… you…
that… these… children…
had… become… witches…
during childhood.
But… no-one… helped… them…
It's working.
This time, it's working.
Idiot!
The transformer.
Are you going to eat?
Eat!
Must the sun come up?
Night has no brother,
no father, no mother.
Oh good Sleep.
Come and reward those who love the Night.
Only the crazy do not know her.
They do not know
the precious taste of your fruit's juices.
They do not see that you come
from ancient times.
And that you approach us closely.
You have the keys
of the doors to paradise.
Haven't you got a 12V transformer?
- Transformer? I've got a 6V.
Multiply it.
2 wires here, 2 wires there.
Depends how you power the device.
I need a 12.
Thieves! Thieves!!
Stop them!
Catch them!
Hit them!
Tie them up!
Hit him!
Calm down. Calm down!
Wait.
I know you well.
I know your real name, mama.
My needle.
You wounded my heart.
Let me go.
I never stay in the same place.
Remove the thorns from your heart.
Because your heart
is made for my hands.
What nonsense.
- Sorry.
What are you doing?
- I'm sorry.
Barman!
Bring them all flavours,
it's my round.
You've drunk up your money
from yesterday and today.
I'll pay for my own beer.
Idiot!
What are you saying, your?
I see you have money tonight.
Been working a lot, have you?
Where did you find that money?
Tabu!
I'm telling you now,
don't get on my nerves!
Do you hear me?
Idiot.
What are you drinking?
You have no money.
Just get out, leave.
You're crazy.
- OK. Fine.
That guy's crazy. Move back!
OK!
If you have money,
buy us a bottle of whisky.
Barman!
Bring them two bottles of whisky.
On my tab.
I told you…
Today is different.
It's a special clientele.
If you don't behave,
I'll kick you out.
You hear me?
You cause too much trouble.
Go and sleep it off.
You're right.
I'm not paying for anything.
If you like,
go and serve yourself from the till.
On my tab!
People like you sponge
off other people…
Off people like me,
for the whores you're with.
Can you also talk?
Sorry. Excuse me.
Is your mother here?
You are from a people with dignity
We are more beautiful than heroes.
We are the truth.
We are more beautiful
than lies.
You're old enough to get angry.
Get angry!
Everything has to be done
over and over again.
More.
I'll be with you.
Because I am your soldier.
More.
You will be brave.
Because you don't have a choice.
The night will help you.
If you lack money, drink water.
Those without money, live in suffering.
Ah, me, Tabu!
If I get fucked up,
it's none of your business.
Ah, the world!
Oh, life is beautiful!
- …Life is…
Careful.
Have pity on me, my love
Have pity on me, my heart
I work hard night and day
to offer you happiness
Every morning, early, I wake…
You sing badly.
Félicité.
Girl of legendary beauty.
On this day,
you have destroyed this world.
Beyond,
look at the pleasure of the sky.
I let myself go.
You can't sing.
Entirely for you.
You sing badly. Please stop.
I'm not your wife.
I won't allow you to.
I am nobody's husband.
Your face, mama.
My God, like an armoured car.
It's working.
Switch on the TV.
Switch on the TV!
- No.
I'm switching it on!
Switch on the TV.
I came back only for your eyes.
Love me.
But don't ask me for anything.
I really like your way…
of being.
If you're like this
things can work between us.
Don't come here every day.
What do you think I came for?
For your good looks?
So why did you come?
I was nearby.
It's not on your route.
I just popped in to say hello.
Like that, for no particular reason?
Have you ever seen manioc leaves
and a goat left in the same place?
So then, why did you come?
I just wanted to tell you…
I saw you in the forest.
You are the one I was looking for.
You were looking for me?
Who would I be looking for in the forest?
Here I am.