FOEGI IS A BASTARD
Excuse me, please let me through.
His pulse is weak.
Hurry up.
Can you hear me?
Answer me!
I was instantly attracted to him.
His music totally fascinated me.
When I heard him on the radio for the first time,
I couldn't believe that this was a Swiss group.
And when I saw him, I instantly understood.
Foegi was a star.
I had never seen anyone like him.
And to imagine that one day I would be so close to him.
The Doors.
Cat Stevens.
Van Morrison.
Bob Dillon.
Velvet Underground.
Neil Diamond.
Really, Reto, you're so out of line.
Why that?
- That guy gives me the creeps.
- That's a matter of taste.
Exactly this is your problem: no taste.
And Van Morrison?
Between Van Morrison and Neil Diamond
there's a world of difference.
There's no way to compare the two.
Instead of reading teen magazines
you'd better smoke a joint.
There's Schaefer.
Okay, let's go!
Instead of messing with everything, you could help me.
Wind up the cables, for example.
I was not that good at winding up cables,
but they took me along to their concert in Basle as a roadie.
Has anyone brought something to drink?
Isn't there anything to drink?
I don't believe it!
It's stifling hot
and there's nothing to drink!
- Is this supposed to be a joke?
- What, the hat?
- Well, it's cute.
- Marc Bolan!
Marc Bolan?
It's more like the Queen of England.
Hey, Waede, music!
I have to rewind the tape first.
Wait, take this tape.
- It's CCR.
- American pop shit.
Not American pop!
Hey, give the tape to me.
Do you know how late it is?
- 3:15 am.
- Three in the morning. Where have you been?
- In Basle.
- In Basle?
Are you kidding me?
Do you think I'd accept that my son travels to Basle just like that?
Listen!
You're living under my roof.
I have a right to know where you spend the whole night.
- Anything else you have to say?
- Yes, you bet I have!
I didn't sleep one second the whole night.
Fritz left because he was fed up with my worries about you.
And you think it's normal just to disappear and return quietly at 3 am.
Fritz is your friend, not mine.
I don't give a shit about his boat.
We're better off without him.
If it doesn't suit you, I'll move out.
Got it?
You want to go?
May I ask where?
And on what are you going to live?
Dear Foegi,
I don't even know if you know my name.
I've been helping backstage at your concert in Basle.
I didn't dare to speak to you, so I'm writing you now.
I've been following The Minks for a long time.
I see all your concerts and think you're an amazing singer.
But I'm no ordinary fan like the others.
I admire you not only because you're famous.
You create your own music without bothering what others think.
I heard you're gay, but that's okay for me.
I love you, Beni.
Hello?
One moment.
Beni.
For you. Someone named Foegi.
Hello?
It's open!
- Hello.
- Did I wake you up?
- Yes.
- Sorry.
- That's okay.
- Do you always get up so early?
- No, just today.
Is there a cigarette left?
Listen, I'm completely wasted.
Lie down here if you want.
- Can I have one?
- Sure.
I didn't smoke at your age.
I was a good boy.
- I just started smoking...
- That's okay. I was just kidding.
I really liked your letter.
- Honestly?
- Yes.
I had never thought you would call me.
- Why not?
- You have so many fans.
- But they are not like you.
- Why?
You said so in your letter.
Yes.
You're beautiful!
I have to go to the toilet.
It's at the left side.
- Are you okay?
- I feel dizzy.
It's your breathing.
I see.
Too much oxygen in your brain.
You breathe like an ox when we fuck.
- Must be because I love you.
- Really?
Don't laugh.
I'm serious.
Yes, Beni.
I know.
He doesn't get it. Listens to The Lords,
Melanie, Neil Diamond, and other bullshit.
- You liked the Lords too.
- That's ages ago.
- It isn't that long ago.
- It seems so to me.
I had never smoked pot yet
and jacked off every night
when I still heard that shit.
That's precisely Reto's problem.
He's stuck there and doesn't notice.
Since I met you,
I realized a lot of things.
Come on.
Light that joint.
Oh, sorry.
Hello, Toebe.
Did it work out?
- Yes.
- And the van?
Ritch's brother will lend it to us.
Well, I'll go to the kitchen.
What's with him?
One for Foegi.
A little bit for Toebe,
and one for Beni.
What's that?
Are these trips?
Why didn't you tell me?
I am also interested in this.
Are you?
Have you already taken one?
No, Beni, not yet.
Why not taste one?
No, not today.
- Why not?
- Because...
Because of what?
Because... not now.
Okay?
- But I've never tried one.
- Don't touch it!
- I said not now, understood?
- Yeah.
Did you hear about The Alligators?
They managed to play the opening act of Eric Burton's tour in Germany.
Yeah, we all know about that.
It's because they have a manager
and he gets them all these good gigs.
Of course, that's what such a guy is for.
So where's the problem?
He's right.
What's this paranoia good for?
Music is business.
Let's face it.
We can't keep asking my brother for the car forever.
One day he will say: "That's it, boys!
Unload the car and get lost!"
- And than it's over for us.
- Here, have a drink.
No thanks. I don't need one.
- Come on!
- No!
Why not?
Because I can't play when I'm drunk.
The Alligators only play when they are completely stoned.
That's their secret.
Come on!
It will help you to keep things in perspective.
Shit! Look at me.
You spilled it all over me.
What a jerk!
You think it's funny, huh?
Got a cigarette?
Fire?
Did you see the movie with the giant pods?
Body Snatchers.
They gobble up your identity,
your feelings.
No, not like that.
You catch the virus the moment you're born.
It grows very slowly.
It depends on the person.
After 30 it get's difficult.
At 40 it's over.
Guys at 40 are the desert.
No more emotions,
they only produce.
No more generosity,
no heart...
Nothing but sacrifices.
A life full of sacrifices.
- What about women?
- Same thing.
With a few exceptions,
but for those Valium was invented.
- What about me?
- You? You'll kick the bucket before.
Aren't you sleeping?
Come!
Hey... Toebe!
What is it?
Have you seen Beni?
- What? Beni?
- Yes.
I don't know where he is.
Come on, let's go.
- Now?
- Yes.
He's not here.
He'll come.
It's alright, Toebe.
Go to bed.
I'm completely finished.
Is it okay if I sleep here?
Sure.
Get yourself a blanket.
Ah, there you are.
I'm sorry.
Where have you been?
I hitched a ride,
but got stuck in Baden.
There I had to wait for the first train.
Come to bed.
Do you still love me?
Of course I still love you.
You know, Foegi, I'm not like you.
I don't want to be jealous,
but I couldn't stand to see you with him.
I was scared.
And now you aren't scared anymore?
No.
Are you awake?
Is everything okay?
In winter, things didn't go well for The Minks.
Ritch was right.
It's hard without a manager.
But Foegi wanted to stay independent.
So he resorted to dealing drugs and travelled to Lebanon to buy cheap hashish.
- Hello, Beni.
- How do you do?
Cool, man. Long time here?
We're up there.
No, I just arrived.
- Well? Any news from Foegi?
- Yes, he sent me a card.
What's bothering you?
I've gone crazy since he left.
Come on!
It's only two weeks.
I know...
But I miss him so much.
I'm worried that something might happen,
that he could get caught or something.
Don't worry, he is too smart for that.
They'll never catch him.
Hey, Beni-freak!
Has Foegi not sent a sample yet?
Hello, Ritch.
Listen, Ritch.
Beni isn't feeling too good.
If you want to avoid a double suicide, leave us alone.
Do you have a light?
It's cold, huh?
Haven't I seen you at the Odeon?
Yes, I was there.
You kept staring at me.
Yes, that's true.
You were there yesterday too,
and you didn't look so well.
- And I saw you twice last week.
- That's possible.
I've been noticing you for a long time.
I even dream of you.
Won't you have a drink with me?
- I just want to go home.
- Only one beer,
or whatever you prefer.
Hello, Beni.
How's life?
I was completely stoned.
All I wanted was to go home.
Then he started talking to me and I went with him.
He gave me 50 francs.
- Are you angry?
- No.
I can't stand it when you're not here.
I can't live without you.
If you had been away a little longer,
I don't know what I had done.
What's the matter?
- I understand. You're angry.
- I'm not.
You know, in Beirut
I wasn't feeling too good either.
Why?
I realized that I was getting old.
Are you crazy?
You're not old at all.
I realized that this can't go on much longer.
Listen, Foegi.
Tell me clearly if you're fed up with me.
I know I'm not very interesting, but I'd do anything for you.
If you want, I'll get you some super guys.
Stop hallucinating.
It has nothing to do with you.
You know that I can't stand old people.
They're walking corpses.
I'd rather put an end to it before.
You want to commit suicide, is it that?
If you do, I'll do the same.
Come on, Beni, take it easy.
I've bought orange soda.
And cigarettes.
Thanks.
I've bought this too.
It's brand-new and very practical.
You just have to put it in the oven.
What oven?
If you don't feel like it, Ritch,
just say so.
Tell me what to play.
I have no idea what I'm supposed to play.
Tell me.
I don't know what you want.
You don't know what I want?
What a shame.
We've been playing together for so long.
So what do you want?
Do you at least know what you want yourself, huh?
Come on, tell us!
You must have a reason for being here.
Or do you just have nothing better to do?
Did you fail to find someone to screw today?
Enough, Foegi,
this won't get us anywhere.
I just want to know, that's all.
You're unfair.
Am I?
Do you want me to rub your back?
Foegi!
Do you think Ritch will quit?
You were a little rude,
but you did the right thing.
He's been slacking off lately.
Really?
Yes.
I mean, you didn't go to Lebanon and made all that money to continue as before.
Listen, Beni,
stop talking bullshit and leave me alone.
Why?
What did I say this time?
We must return to the stage, give concerts.
Then the feeling will come back again.
- Leave us alone.
- Then I'll play Pinball.
Okay.
We are a live band.
You always said so.
The people love our music.
And now that we are loaded...
To hell with the people.
Forget it, Toebe.
You can see there's no point in it.
Why drag on with something that's already dead?
- When did you have your relapse?
- That has nothing to do with it.
- Are you sure?
- Leave me alone with that.
I'm just fed up.
Foegi.
Foegi!
You don't love me anymore.
You just don't love me anymore.
- Foegi!
- Leave me alone!
Don't be like that.
Please.
Say something.
What do you want me to do? Tell me!
Will you stop that!
Stop it!
Enough of that! Okay!
Come on, get out!
Leave me alone!
No!
Do you want coffee?
No.
Then I don't want either.
Get lost.
Listen, Beni, you're getting on my nerves.
But I didn' do anything.
You crawl around like a slave.
It's totally nerv-destroying.
The two of us, that was only a fling!
Now get out!
Can you give me two grams?
Got something?
Can I exchange hash for this?
100 francs and a piece.
How much longer do you plan to play the dog?
Eat!
"Eat", I said!
- Can I order another one?
- Go ahead.
And tell them to bring me a beer.
And cigarettes.
Hello, Beni, how are you?
Do you have a little time?
- No, I'm here with a friend.
- I see.
- Who is that?
- Wirsling.
Who?
- The guy who picked me up when you were in Lebanon.
- And what did he want?
He asked if I had time.
Hi!
Hello.
Am Foegi, a friend of Beni.
- Can I take a seat?
- Sure.
- Beni told me you're a psychiatrist.
- Right.
That must be interesting.
Sometimes it is.
Cold showers, electric shocks,
that sounds attractive.
- The methods have changed a bit lately.
- Is that so?
- Never heard of gentle psychiatry?
- No, but it sounds good.
Does it mean you're locked up without feeling pain?
Listen, Foegi...
Thanks.
my profession is by far not as monstrous as you seem to think.
Sorry, it's nothing personal.
Anyway, I'm not in a hurry to visit your facility.
Well, I've got some things to do.
Couldn't you keep this gentleman company?
- You don't mind, do you?
- That is for Beni to decide.
At the Odeon, in two hours.
- Let me...
- No, it's on me.
This is a bit... I mean,
you don't have to stay if you don't want.
No, it's fine.
Would you like anything to drink?
For whom is this piece?
Faster, faster, faster!
Come on and get it!
Get it, get it!
No, not on the bed!
Get down!
Come on.
Come on now.
If you're good, you can have it.
But only if you're good.
Show Foegi what a good dog you are.
Yes, that's good.
That's a good dog.
You want it?
Easy.
Good dog.
Foegi saw to it that I cultivated my connections with wealthy men.
I was walking the streets now and very much in demand.
At that time, it was all over with The Minks.
But Foegi didn't care since I earned enough money for both of us.
Hi.
The architect called.
You have an appointment for tomorrow.
- Have you been swimming?
- Yes.
How many rounds did you swim?
10.
You should do 15.
Build up your muscles.
I'm in the other room.
Sometimes I didn't speak a word
all day long exept "yes" and "no".
I felt a new happiness.
Not being responsible for anything anymore.
There were no words in my head,
only eyes, a mouth,
and the dream of a sleeping dog.
That must be Wirsling.
But you'll stay here tonight.
No, I must go.
There is also a physical strength.
Do you see it?
The almost erotic expression of this painting.
This conception was of course a challenge
to the conservative and mannierist style of that epoch.
Like a freeze-frame in a movie.
Beni?
What's wrong?
Don't you feel well?
It's the vodka.
Come and lie down.
You're not eating?
No, I'm not hungry.
- What's the matter, Beni?
- Nothing. I'm fine.
What drugs did you take?
Heroin?
Stop it, Bruno!
I've said I'm fine.
I took some acid and had a bad trip, that's all.
That guy is bad for you.
I'm serious.
Listen to me.
I've made you a proposal.
It still stands.
I can get you an apartment.
And I'll ask Robert to let you work at his gallery if you want.
Would I have to let him paw me as well?
That was nasty, Beni.
- Is that you, Beni?
- Yes.
Poor Toebe.
We had completely forgotten and never taken care of him.
He used to say The Minks were the most important part of his life.
Now we know that he meant what he said.
He left me a letter.
You see, he did it.
He really did it, you understand?
What do we do now?
We have to call someone.
I did not know he would go so far.
I wasn't really sad,
rather baffled that someone who always had been around suddenly was gone.
And I felt guilty because Foegi had withdrawn from Toebe because of me.
I accepted a job as a model.
All those old gay geezers started to get on my nerves.
So I tried something more serious.
Well, serious...
Hello?
Hello, Mr. Schaefer.
Yes.
Which time?
7 pm?
Shall I wear anything special?
Okay, very well.
See you then.
I didn't hear you come.
Have you seen my dope?
I put it here this morning.
- I took it.
- What!
Are you crazy?
Why did you take my dope?
What do you mean by "my dope"?
I paid for it.
Can you roll me a joint?
Do it yourself.
I have to take care of the laundry.
Beni,
bring me a beer!
Hurry up, I'm thirsty!
Would you mind bringing me a beer?
What are you sitting there?
See, that's what I want.
I met Reto today.
He asked me what I was doing currently.
What should I have told him?
Do you even remember Reto?
My classmate.
I had a wonderful day.
Schaefer gave me a blowjob.
It was great.
What's wrong with you?
Mick Jagger is dead.
What?
They talked about it on TV.
Are you brain fucking me?
You're such a slob.
Look at yourself!
You make me sick.
Do you realize how low you've sunk?
But you don't give a damn, huh?
What?
Get lost if it doesn't suit you.
And what will become of you then?
I didn't ask you for a thing!
Fuck off! Get lost!
Did I ask you to do the cleaning?
You can't do it.
You can't do it yourself.
You can't even take care of yourself.
You can't do anything!
Look at this place!
It stinks, it sucks!
It sucks and stinks!
Calm down!
Just look at yourself!
Look at yourself!
Enough of this!
I've had enough of this!
Just go on and smash up the whole place.
Fuck you!
Beni.
Where did you put "The Beggars Banquet"?
Damned...
Beni.
Come on, have a drink with me.
Come on.
Beni, sit.
Sit, I said.
I said, sit!
- You're so kind.
- It's alright.
You're really a nice guy.
I love you very much, you know?
Do you know that?
I love you more than anyone else.
I'm so sorry.
I can understand that you don't love me anymore.
But I still love you.
No.
I've treated you so badly.
It's alright.
All I want is to be with you.
Everything else doesn't matter.
I've treated you so badly.
There was no alternative for us but to leave Zurich.
But for Foegi it wasn't just a vacation.
He would never return to Switzerland.
Foegi!
- Won't you go swimming with me?
- I feel like playing a little.
- Okay, I'm off then. See you.
- See you.
- Do you mind that they're here?
- No.
I read in a newspaper article
that in 2004 a meteorite will explode on Earth.
All life on Earth will be wiped out.
We won't be here anymore.
It was a scientist who found this out.
So we will all perish.
Is this really a fact?
Yes, because it will impact with a tremendous force.
Well, if it's like this,
we have to enjoy our life to the fullest.
There was no need to talk about it.
I knew what was going on in his head.
He had already made up his mind.
That's why he was so relaxed and content.
But I was afraid of dying.
Hello.
Come.
Do you think this is enough?
Yes, it's first-class stuff.
Wait.
Hold the spoon a little higher.
That's right.
If only I was not so afraid of needles...
Give it to me.
Don't be afraid.
You have great veins.
I have to pee.
Make a fist.
Like this?
Yes, that's right.
Excuse me, please let me through.
His pulse is weak.
Hurry up.
Foegi didn't make it,
but I pulled through.
Maybe because I didn't want to die
or because I was younger and healthier.
Perhaps Foegi gave me a smaller dose.
I don't know.
I felt very tired,
as if I had not slept for 100 years.
I thought I could never catch up on all the lost sleep.
But this fatigue was also a relief.
Maybe because of the medication they had given me at hospital
I felt lighter and emptier.
In this emptiness was sadness
but also consolation.
And of course I asked myself over and over again and still do:
If I had loved him more and differently,
perhaps he wouldn't have died.
Should our paths cross again, Foegi,
I'll try harder to love you so that nothing can separate us.
I swear, next time I'll be stronger.
Next time...