♪ Gets, gets better, better
♪ Our summer out west,
our summer of sex
♪ Our summer just gets better
♪ Our summer out west,
our summer of sex
♪ Our summer
just gets better, better
♪ I don't need no weekend
telling me when to begin, ah
♪ You stay upstairs
until I call you down for dinner
♪ Single ladies want a ring
on it, I shake a finger
♪ Let it be, I'll call you Paul
♪ Paul, you call me Linda
♪ Single ladies want a ring on it, ah
♪ I shake a finger, I shake a finger
♪ All the single ladies want a ring
♪ I shake a finger
♪ We're just having fun
if you got to order in
♪ Our summer out west,
our summer of sex
♪ Our summer just gets better
♪ Our summer out west,
our summer of sex
♪ Our summer
just gets, gets better, better
♪ Better, better, ah
♪ Better, better
♪ Our summer of sex,
we get so wet about the weather
♪ She tell you no cos
she want avoid a commitment
♪ She resists, but you persist,
and I suggest her sister
♪ She's a go-getter, she say no, never
♪ She's a go-getter, she never say no
♪ The sign says open,
doesn't ever say closed
♪ I put a twenty on her,
she's good to go
♪ I bet you get her, she say no, never
♪ Our summer out west,
our summer of sex
♪ Our summer just gets better
♪ Our summer out west,
our summer of sex
♪ Our summer
just gets, gets better, better
Ever notice how in high school
there's just something
about being first?
Like that girl who's always
first to raise her hand
or that first kid to own
every new cutting-edge iThingy?
There's so much pressure to be
a trend-setter, a pioneer.
Well, not me.
Tanner Daniels was just like any
other average comic-book geek,
more than content to fly under the radar
and leave the trailblazing
to the others.
After all, of the many firsts
my peers were vying for,
one still remained
conspicuously up for grabs.
Never in the history
of North Gateway High
had any student admitted out loud
to being an honest-to-goodness,
card-carrying, proud,
or even slightly modest, homosexual,
including me and my best friend, Brent.
Explain this to me again.
How will being the first out kid
in school make you instantly popular?
It's simple. All the teen
and tween rags agree.
The hottest new trend
sweeping schools worldwide
is the GBF.
- GBF?
- Gay best friend.
Every celeb has one,
so every teen girl needs one.
And pretty soon, all three
prom-queen front-runners
will be battling it out
for my attention.
♪ H
♪ E
♪ R
Three powerful cliques
controlled North Gateway High,
and the queen bitch from each
ruled our school
from nearly every direction.
Caprice Winters dominated
as queen of drama,
all three kinds of choir,
and our school's loose network
of minority students.
Then there was 'Shley Osgoode,
short for "Ashley",
which was about as edgy as she got.
With her perpetually sunny
Mormon disposition,
'Shley ruled all wearers of
shiny gold crosses and goody-two-shoes.
But neither could hold a candle
to Fawcett Brooks.
By far the hottest girl in school
and empress of the rich and popular,
Fawcett loved fads and hated fatties.
Her trademark golden tresses
had won her "best hair"
three years in a row,
an unprecedented achievement
because you're supposed to be
a senior to win.
Like neighbouring warlords
in a third-world country,
they maintained
an uneasy balance of power,
friendly but always vigilant
of anything that could upset the truce
and create all-out social warfare.
So, I'm thinking prom
for maximum effect.
That way, no matter
who wins king or queen,
all anyone will remember is me.
Why not send out a mass text
and be done with it?
"FYI, I like guys.
Now let's never speak of this again."
Tanner, you cannot come out
via text. That is so gay.
Well, you can count me out.
Or in, I guess.
How very early 2000s of you.
I'm so not surprised.
Glenn is more likely
to come out than Tanner,
and he is our token vagina enthusiast.
Damn straight. Literally.
Look, it's not a matter of if
I'm coming out. Of course I am.
It's the "when" I'm still working on.
I just can't believe that you'd be happy
being some vapid whore's
sexless accessory.
Why do you think this plan will work?
Oh, you know I've been doing
my reconnaissance.
Ready? OK!
Fawcett's the obvious
prom-queen front-runner,
but since mega-hottie Hamilton Smith
dumped her last week,
she's vulnerable,
and she'll be looking for an edge.
- Whoo!
- Any edge.
What the hell was that?
You were totally out of sync.
It's that time of the month, ladies.
Please. Their "must-have" list
is so five minutes ago.
- Let's hear it.
- This month's are,
totally bedazzled vintage totes,
chunky cashmere ironic shrugs.
Been there, worn that.
- Distressed jeggings.
- Cute!
I practically invented them.
- Cold langu.
- And a GBF.
- It stands for...
- I know what it stands for.
I can't help it that the school
is devoid of the gay.
If there were some,
they'd obvi worship me.
I mean, look at this.
No, totally. They'd worship you.
Look at you. You're beautiful.
OK, so, Fawcett might fall
for it, but what makes you think
a super-Chris like 'Shley Osgoode
would want a GBF?
'Shley is Mormon. Their shtick
is being relentlessly nice to you
until you give up and throw on
a pair of their magic underwear.
They smile to your face
and Prop-8 you in the back.
I can't believe our godless peers
read this blasphemy.
- They're trying to make sin seem in.
- I don't know.
Don't you ever think
it would be neat to meet one?
- Like a real, live gay?
- What?
We could bring him to youth group
or take him out
for milkshakes or something.
If we're all super-duper nice to him,
maybe he'd realise that the only person
he should be gay for is Jesus.
'Shley, you can't
just befriend these people.
They're out to steal
our brothers, boyfriends, our gerbils,
all as part of a secret agenda to spread
their gaybies all over America.
Gay babies?
No! Like... Like gay rabies.
Bitch!
'Shley will try
to befriend me and convert me,
and that'll make Fawcett
want me even more.
So, what about Caprice?
Miss Caprice cannot stand
not being the centre of attention.
You all saw her mostly
plagiarised musical mash-up
of Mean Girls last spring.
♪ Mean girls
♪ Mean plastic girls
♪ I'm coming to get you
wherever you turn
♪ I'm writing your name
in the book of burn
- That could've been kind of brilliant.
- But it wasn't.
Caprice needs a gay visionary
to shepherd her career
towards iconic diva-dom.
I hope everything
goes according to plan.
You won't forget us when
you're in a new social stratosphere?
No promises. Oh, my God!
Is that the new one?
Oh, sweet, dude!
And I still carry the last
flip phone on the planet.
We are so downloading Guydar.
- What the hell is Guydar?
- Where have you been?
It's the new app that lets
gay guys find other gay guys
through state-of-the-art,
globally positioned technology.
- She knows.
- I only know about it
because Brent here tried
to download it onto my phone.
Yeah, and hetero buzzkill here
totally cock-blocked me.
I'm not soiling my pristine phone
with some slutty gay hookup app.
Tanner,
we're not gonna do anything.
We're just gonna see if there are
any other gay guys in this town
and find out how many cubic feet
away they are from us. It's science.
And it's about to change our lives.
Which was actually true,
but not in the way we imagined.
But it isn't fair, Ms Hoegel.
I'm sorry, Soledad,
but the school board was clear.
Now, we can't have
a gay/straight alliance
without an actual gay member.
Just because we're all straight
doesn't mean that there
aren't gay kids at this school.
My future GBF is just waiting
to come out of the closet
and tell me how fierce I am.
Please, Ms H, this club is all I have.
Is this about helping queer
and questioning kids or yourself?
It's all for the gays!
They need to at least know
this group exists.
What if Viola here
came out as a lesbian?
- Hey! I'm strictly dickly, yo.
- Just take one for the team.
- Now, Soledad!
- Braxton has two mommies.
That has got to count for something.
And both Mrs Cooper-Cullins
were so helpful
in organising last month's
vegan bake sale.
Moms say hi, by the way.
Hi, Moms.
But it's simply not enough, I'm afraid.
Please, Ms Hoegel,
just buy me a few more weeks.
I will find a real-life gay, even if
I have to drag the little teen queen
out of the closet myself.
Soledad, I don't want you conducting
some sort of a gay witch-hunt.
- No, of course not, Ms Hoegel.
- Give it time.
One day you will meet
the gay of your dreams,
and it will be the happiest,
most fulfilling day of your life.
Then it's all downhill from there.
Hi, there, Soledad. Or whatever.
You're prez of the school's
currently gay-less GSA, right?
- Yeah, something like that.
- Couldn't help but overhear your dilem.
I might have an idea
that could help you out. Keep up.
The wi-fi password is "Lilo".
- Oh, hey, guys. Where's the fire?
- Oh! Hi, Mom.
Erm, we just got this really
tough math assignment, so...
Oh. Math.
It's gonna be, like,
a really tough nut to bust.
T-T-Y-L!
Later, Mrs Van Camp.
Be safe! W-With your math.
Your mom totally knows
and also thinks we're doing it.
Why don't you just tell her?
She's so smug,
dropping her little hints.
I'm not gonna give her the satisfaction.
Maybe when she gets the balls to ask me.
Maybe she's just respecting
your privacy.
She wants to milk this
for all the drama it's worth.
Trust. I am her son, after all.
Do we have to listen
to this heinous pop dance crap?
Shut up. You know you love it.
♪ Why should I be a victim of this love?
♪ Why should I feel so ashamed?
Knock, knock!
What? What do you want?
- Everybody decent?
- Yeah, Mom.
- No, I'm serious.
- Yes, we're decent!
Oh, God. OK, good.
Whew! Just checking. Oh, O-M-G!
This be my jam. Whoo!
You boys have any poppers? A popper
would really hit the spot right now.
Mom, erm, yeah, this dance party
is invitation only, so...
I simply came up to tell you boys
that I won't be back up here
for at least one hour or so. Relax.
Do your thing. Get crazy.
- Thanks.
- I'm good with it.
Thank you. Alright. Bye!
Now that we've banished the beast,
let's download that app
and find us some mens.
What if we see someone we know on there
or someone finds my phone?
It's my ass on the line.
Tan, please, if I don't at least
get my makeout on before college,
I'll be playing sexual
catch-up for years.
I just want to find out if there are
any other gay guys out there
that, you know, aren't you.
You know, no offence.
OK, fine.
But we're gonna need
a profile picture first. Say "cheese".
Cheddar!
Let me see it.
No.
Hey!
Relax. You'll just be another headless
torso in a sea of low self-esteem.
PS, your abs ain't too bad,
Mr Four-Pack.
Really?
Let's see what the filthy gays
of North Gateway think of them.
You sure this is a good idea?
Was Drake on Degrassi?
The answer is yes.
Bad-ass rapper Drake
was on a wholesome Canadian
after-school soap opera. Never forget.
We had little luck chatting up
dudes on Guydar that night,
but the next day, Soledad and her swarm
of blossoming fruit flies
were preparing to put the app
to much better use.
OK, ladies,
somewhere in this school,
there's a sexually confused boy with
no one to turn to and nowhere to go.
So we must hunt him down...
to help him, of course.
According to a very knowledgeable source
on what's in style, this Guydar thing
is all the rage with the gays,
especially the closet cases.
We all got our faux-mo avatars ready?
Yep. Mine's of Robert Pattinson's
air-brushed torso.
- That's what they like, right?
- Totally.
And you've got Zac Efron. Perfect.
Persephone's rocking Adam Lambert.
Oh, great. I think we got
all our bases covered.
Let the manhunt begin!
- Oh, shit!
- What was that?
Oh, erm, nothing.
Just stating the obvious in here.
Ew. Let's go.
Shit. Shit, shit, shit.
Tanner! Hand it over.
You'll get it back
at the end of the day.
Shit.
Come on, come on, come on! Shit!
Montag.
Dienstag.
Mittwoch.
- Mittwoch.
- Donnerstag.
What's up, bitch?
- Herr Brent?
- Ein moment, Frau Burkhardt.
Oh, scheisse!
Ooh, I got one! 4Packboy95.
He's 400 feet away.
- I got him, too! This way!
- Yeah!
Give me your phone now! Now!
Oh, my God, Brent!
You're obsessed with that stupid app.
You don't understand. Soledad
and her gaggle of junior hacks
are using Guydar
to track gays at the school.
Oh, my God. Slatsky took
my phone in third period.
It's still signed on.
I am not taking the fall for this!
Time for the big, dramatic coming-out
you've always wanted.
No, no! This is not how I planned it.
Prom is months away!
It's coming from in here.
- We are here to help.
- Come on, guys.
- What do you think you're doing?
- Who do these hairless abs belong to?
The signal's from the front
of the classroom.
- You have two seconds to...
- From right around Mr Slatsky's desk?
- Mr Slatsky?
You're married to a lady,
and these are clearly not your abs.
This is false advertising.
What are you talking about?
Wait! It's not Mr Slatsky's.
- Tanner, I don't think you should...
- This is your cellphone, correct?
I-I guess it is.
You're the secret gay.
But you're not even that fabulous.
I... guess I am...
Not fabulous, but gay.
I'm gay, I guess.
Oh, we've got one!
Our very own homosexual!
I have to tweet this right now.
We did it! I'm so excited! Oh, my God!
What are you looking at, fag-off?
What, are you...?
What, are you checking out my... balls?
You trying to check out my balls?
Tanner! Wait! Wait! I'm your friend!
Leave him alone,
you desperate psycho bitch.
Whoa. That was really mean.
- Are you a psycho and are you a bitch?
- I am his best friend.
I couldn't believe it.
I'd been so careful for 17 years.
I learned how to clear
the internet history when I was 11.
One stupid slip-up
had cost me everything,
and I had one person to blame.
Hey, girl, hey.
"Hey"? That's all you have to say?
I'm sorry. I-I freaked.
It happened so fast.
You were the one
who wanted to come out!
I can't believe
you let me take the fall!
Shh, please. Look,
maybe you can turn this around.
You know, pretend it was a joke.
You can't "no homo" this, Brent.
I'm basically a dead man, and what
kills me is you're the queeny one.
The least you can do is come out and
take your share of the daily beatings.
I can't. It would be,
you know, pathetic,
like I'm copying you or something.
You know what? I blame myself.
All I ever do is go with the flow,
your flow, 99 percent of the time.
Oh, please, We both know
you love being the sidekick.
So, I'm the sidekick?
Wow. Well, at least now I realise
all you care about is yourself,
you self-absorbed,
gutless little faggot!
- Tanner Daniels!
- Christ, Tanner. I said I'm sorry.
Sorry, Mrs Van Camp,
but I'm allowed to use that word,
seeing as how I am one.
Just like your son.
Tanner, you had no right.
Well, what do you care?
You know she knows.
It was a total dick move,
and I immediately regretted it,
but it was too late.
Like Lex Luthor and Clark Kent
or Professor X and Magneto,
Brent and I went from best friends
to archenemies in a matter of seconds.
Hey, Tanner. How was school, honey?
Er, hey, Shannon, Dad.
It was uneventful. Lacking events.
Why, you didn't hear anything, did you?
No. What would we
have heard about, Tanner?
Nothing, of course, because
of the whole nothing thing.
Honey, that's great. Are you hungry?
I made my world-famous
homemade gluten-free popsicles.
They are delicious.
Oh, I hope you made them
extra thick and fruity,
just the way Tanner likes them.
What? Er, I mean, right.
Thanks for freezing juice on a stick
for me, Shannon, but I'm good.
Maybe you'll have one later.
- Maybe I'll have one right now.
- Ooh.
What flavour did you make?
- Cherry.
- Ohh.
The next day, I tried to keep
an even lower profile than usual,
but my power to go unnoticed
had been completely neutralised.
Hey. Remember me?
Hey, Sophe. Sorry I haven't
texted/called you back.
I'm just really overwhelmed right now.
Look, I know you're pissed at Brent,
and, honestly, I would be, too.
But what he did was an accident.
- What you did with his mom was...
- Wait. Really? Wow.
Of all people, I never expected
you to take his side.
He outed me to the entire school.
And plus, his mom already knew.
It wasn't your job to tell her.
You know that.
You know what, Sophe?
I have bigger things to worry about
than Brent's psycho momma drama.
Well, hey, there, Tan-Tan.
You know, I used to think
you were a little fag.
I didn't realise you were
actually a full-fledged homo!
That doesn't even make sense.
Oh, yeah? Oh, yeah?
You calling me stupid?
You calling me stupid and gay?
Hamilton, take your hands off him.
Back off, babe. We're history,
which means you don't tell me
what to do any more.
History. Now,
that's an appropriate word
because that's what
your sex life is gonna be
if you don't leave him alone.
After all, I know things.
Tiny little pinky-sized details.
Touch him again, and you won't be able
to get as much as a half-ass handjob
from some flag-twirling
colour guard skank.
Bitch, you wouldn't dare.
Try me.
- You OK, babes?
- I'm... fine.
- I'm Fawcett.
- Yeah, I know.
You doing anything after school?
Want to go sip extra-large
low-fat iced coffees
and talk shit about people?
Hey, there, you. I like coffee, too.
I'll come with.
- Ooh! I like decaf.
- How nice for you both.
Well, er, we could all go... together?
Fine. Whatevs. Let's.
So...
So, you're a gay now.
Er, not now. I mean, I've always been.
Just now everybody knows.
Are you gonna audition
for the spring musical?
We're doing The Wiz and we need
as many minorities as we can get.
I'm not much for the whole singing
or dancing or being on stage thing.
You sure you're a 'mo?
What gay stuff do you, like, like?
Erm, I'm into comics.
Like Kathy Griffin? She's hilar.
Er, no, like comic books.
That's not gay. That's just lame.
You don't even sound
like the ones on Bravo.
- Say the word "fierce".
- Ooh.
Yeah, I don't really say that word.
Maybe it's like Caprice. She's black,
but she doesn't talk like them.
- Excuse me?
- Well, not all the time.
It's like when we call you a Mormon
but forget the second M.
What about those other losers
you eat lunch with?
They seem way gayer than you.
Oh, no, no, no, no. I heard Brent
is, like, super hetero.
That's why they're all fighting.
That Glenn, though,
he is way too cute to be straight.
Er, Glenn is so not gay. Trust me.
I would know
cos I've got that gaydar thing, right?
But even that Sophie girl,
she's always seemed like
a mucho muncher supreme to me.
I don't think so. I mean,
she hates all the guys at this school,
but she hates all the girls, too.
Well, Tanner, I just want you to know
that I'm totally fine
with your homosexiness.
I mean, it is a sin and all,
but we Mormons
pretty much think everything's a sin,
including those caffeinated beverages.
If you're all gonna burn in hell,
you may as well have a nice time
being queer and stuff while you're here.
Well, that's at least consistent
of you, 'Shley.
I have an amazeballs idea.
This Saturday, why don't you
and me come back here,
and we can totally gay you over?
Oh, and I know all the stylists
at Heroine salon.
I'm sure they can give you something
butchy and Rihanna-esque.
I think he just needs a trim, sweetie,
not a full-blown weave.
These are clips, boo.
Erm, I have a gift card
to Banana Republic that's half full.
Well, perf. I guess
we'll see you both there.
None of them wanted to share
the school's newest
limited-edition status symbol,
and if that meant pretending
to play nice with each other, game on.
That weekend, I quickly discovered
that if I was going to accept
the protection of the in crowd,
- I had some major catching-up to do.
- Where have you been?
I thought we were meeting
at the food court.
- That was, like, four texts ago.
- Come on!
My texts-per-minute average
was extremely subpar.
I had about 200 completely unacceptable
photos of myself tagged on Facebook.
Ooh. Fat face. De-tag.
De-tag. De-tag. De-tag!
Oh, my God. De-friend
whoever put that one up!
And I was about three months behind
on all of the latest abbreves.
- Incredsies.
- Fug, in the good way.
Oh! This one is tally feroshe-balls.
- Feroshe-balls?
- That's what we're calling it.
Here, sweetie.
One, two, three.
♪ Anything can happen
Oh, my God.
Praising the leather god.
♪ Anything can happen
♪ Anything can
How do we look together?
I love it!
It was a straight-up
makeover-montage situation,
and all I could think of
was how much Brent
would have lived for every second of it.
♪ I guess we thought
that's just what humans do
With Brent, Sophie and Glenn,
it was always so easy.
I never worked so hard
just to have friends.
But without Fawcett
and the other clique queens
watching my back, I was a sitting duck.
♪ But now I've seen it through
Good morning, ladies.
So, you speak to traitor,
excuse me, I mean Tanner,
this weekend?
Well, no, actually. I called him,
like, 50 times, and no responses.
You two really need to work it out.
I mean, it's like...
Er, ladies?
♪ I know it's gonna be
♪ Oh, yeah
♪ I don't think I need you
He united them. I can't believe this.
I can't believe how tight his pants are.
And is he wearing bronzer?
He's spray-Tanner now.
Before, I could move through
the school unnoticed, invisible.
But as the GBF, well,
I was kind of indestructible.
The up-close view of 'Topher,
'Shley's hot Mormon boyfriend,
wasn't bad, either.
For once, I was actually
kind of enjoying the spotlight.
What do you think you're doing
with that... that ho... ho...
Ho Ho? This is a Twinkie.
Homosexual.
I'm talking about that other twinkie,
your new apparent BFF.
Tanner? He's super nice, actually.
Like, not pure evil at all, really.
I mean, maybe we're wrong.
'Shley, this is not God's plan.
I think that means time out.
This is part of
the polygamists' plot, isn't it?
The pastor always said
it's a slippery slope.
First come the gays.
Then next thing we know,
you people will want multiple
sister-wife prom dates.
Well, I'm taking a stand.
Consider this my resignation
from the O-M-G Club.
I can't be a part of a group
whose leader is in league
with sodomites.
What's a sodomite?
I think it's like dust mite,
but with sod.
Oh.
In times of crisis, I turn to Lilo.
I mean, I know he's angry at me,
but, like... how could he do this?
Tanner's just doing his best
trying not to get his ass kicked.
- I mean, aren't we all?
- I'm not letting him off that easy.
This literally could not get any worse.
Actually, it can.
You know how the paper
has its prom-court preview issue
coming up?
- Yeah.
- I got a proof.
Tanner is the undisputed front-runner
for prom king this year.
And it's... it's not even close, really.
What offends me more than anything
is the hypocrisy and sexism of it all.
If I were to come out as a lesbian,
would I suddenly be a top candidate
for prom queen? I think not.
Congratulations, Your Majesty.
This has got to be a joke.
It's no joke. You're pretty much a lock.
You've got all our votes.
And the votes of our various
minions and mini-mes.
As for queen, they've got us
in a three-way.
- Tie, that is.
- Most kids are undecided.
They're waiting for you
to tell them what to think.
Me?
Everyone knows that 'mos are always way
ahead of what's hot and what's so not.
On a completely unrelated topic,
I made you a batch of my famous yum-yum
double-fudge brownies last night.
'Shley, are you special?
Gays don't do carbs.
Yeah, a carb to a 'mo
is like sunlight to a vampire.
Carbs make gay people sparkle?
I'm thinking maybe we should hang out
just the two of us tonight,
sans C and 'Shley.
Will they be cool with that?
Those bitches can suck it.
I'm so over sharing you.
Psst.
Psst. Hey.
Soledad. Remember me?
How could I forget?
This is an A and gay conversation,
so kindly see your next Tuesday
out of it.
Erm, well, Tanner,
I just wanted to let you know
that there's a GSA meeting
after school, so I thought...
He doesn't want to join
your fag-hag training club.
That is a highly inflammatory term.
I mean, Soledad, you did out me
to the entire school.
Think of the other gay kids
at this school
that are still languishing
in the closet.
You could be a real role model
for them.
That's not my problem.
Hey! So, we heard a vicious rumour
that Fawcett's snagged you
all to herself after school.
Word travels fast.
If that's how we're gonna play it,
I'm calling you Friday
for one-on-one audition prep.
We'll turn the shiz out of The WiZ.
Thursday, you're all mine.
'Topher and I will cook you din-din.
Fawcett had made her move,
but the other queens
weren't going down without a fight.
Friday night is Cameron Woods's party.
We'll all be there,
including 'Shley for some reason.
I'm bringing enough diet caffeine-free
ginger ale for everybody.
Wow. Well, I guess
my week's planned out, then.
Hm-hmm. we've so got you booked, bitch.
Boom.
Wow. This really works.
Or did you prefer the other one?
I'm really not very good at this.
Tanner, I don't actually think that gays
have a heightened sense of fashion.
I'm just asking you
to look at two options
and choose the one you prefer.
I like the one from before.
Those kind of give you '90s mom ass.
Ah, thank you! That is just the kind
of bitchy gay insight I'm looking for.
So, the bitchier I am,
the more you'll like me?
Exactly. But don't push it.
- You sure have a lot of stuff.
- I know. Don't you love?
I kind of have a thing for labels.
Chanel, Versace,
gay, fiercely fabulous.
- Like you and your comic strips.
- Books.
Whatevs. I'd much rather say hello
to a new handbag
than a friend or boyfriend.
And they're much easier to return.
Is that why you and Hamilton broke up?
Now, he is someone who doesn't
understand the value of a label.
Somehow me being his girlfriend
meant the whole cheerleading squad
suddenly became
his own personal hookup harem.
- Gross.
- But now I've got you, bitch.
Seriously, though.
I feel like I can be myself around you.
You're not trying to screw me
like a guy.
You're not threatened by me
like every other girl in school.
I guess that's the appeal
of this whole GBF thing.
I'm not sure what I get out of it.
Duh! You get to hang out with me.
OK, erm...
I could help you with
your chemistry homework.
- You're getting a C, right?
- Hmm.
I'm actually kind of brills
when it comes to science-y stuff.
- Really?
- Can you keep a secret?
OK, my hair
is only 99.9 percent flawless.
I mix all of my own hair serums
and conditioners in here.
I'll have my own hair-care line one day
on, like, QVC or something,
finally make it big.
That's when I realised
Fawcett was more than just popular.
She was actually kind of cool.
Conversions. This is easy.
I know you and Tanner had a falling-out,
but you're taking it kind of literally.
Yeah, well, my life is over. So, thanks.
Oh, come on, man. I mean,
you still got the two of us.
For about ten minutes.
I never RSVP to a nonstop pity party.
So, I'm bound to eternity
in Loserland with you two. Great.
That's a little harsh.
And here I thought we were
all doing pretty OK,
but I guess we aren't sparkly enough
or have enough synthetic
hair extensions for you.
Sophie, you know what I meant.
No. You know what?
Why don't we take a few days apart.
Maybe without a couple of losers
like us hanging around,
you'll ascend
to your proper social station.
Just be careful, though,
because we might not be here
to bandage you up next time you fall.
- Come on, Glenn.
- Sophie!
Erm, yeah. Take it easy, bro.
Glenn. Come on.
We were gonna watch The Voice.
As the wheels
seemed to be coming off
my old friend group, the next day,
I was third-wheeling it, Mormon-style.
Wow. This is a whole lot
of meat, 'Shley.
Well, that's what you like,
isn't it? Meat.
Huh?
No carbs. I remembered.
Oh, right. Er, mmm!
Meats with... sides of meats.
Erm, may I use the restroom?
Whoa! What are you doing?
Girl-talk time. So, what do you think?
Think about what?
'Topher. Do you think
he's bored with our relationship?
- I feel like he's bored.
- Erm, I don't know.
I'm worried because we don't,
you know...
- So I need some tips.
- Tips?
You gays are supposed to be experts
in man pleasing. So, spill.
- Er...
- Should I give him a BJ?
- A what?
- Or an HJ?
Or how about an RJ?
Er... I don't even know
what an RJ could possibly be.
Me neither.
I was hoping you would.
- Are Mormons even allowed to...?
- What about backdoor?
- Oh, my God!
- Tanner, honey.
Please do not take the Lord's name
in vain in my house.
Sorry. I actually did have to pee.
Could we, er, talk later?
Fine, but you owe me girl-talk time,
mister, OK?
Oh, Tanner, I am so, so sorry.
'Topher reminded me I have a Junior
Republicans meeting in 20 minutes.
Do you mind if 'Tophie takes you home?
Erm, s-sure, I guess.
'Topher, this isn't my house.
- I know. I just wanted to talk.
- OK.
I've caught you checking me out.
Please don't beat me up!
It won't happen again!
Whoa, dude. Whew! Relax.
I find it kind of flattering.
So, what do you like most about me, huh?
What's my sexiest quality?
Oh, I get it. You're one
of those straight guys
who likes to flirt with gay guys
for your own amusement.
- No, that's actually not...
- Contrary to what you might believe,
we homos don't all sit around
pining for straight boys, OK?
Some of us like the idea of a guy
actually being turned on by us.
Does this feel straight to you?
Erm, it does, actually.
You Mormons
are a horny, repressed people!
You have no idea.
Wait! This is wrong. You're with 'Shley.
Dude, in two years,
I'm gonna go on my mission.
In four years, I'll probably be married
with a bunch of redheaded rugrats
running around.
So, why don't you just sit back...
. .relax,
and let me get this out of my system?
Ooh.
- You OK?
- Er, th-thanks. I'll walk.
So, I have some news for you.
- It's pretty maj.
- What?
I may have snatched you a prom date.
His name is Christian.
He went to theatre camp with me
last summer.
He's a tenor, a college boy,
and he's British.
- Love it?
- He sounds great.
I'm just not sure if this
whole prom thing is for me.
OK. You're losing yourself.
Come with Momma.
Take a look, Tanner. This is
every prom king and queen since 1983.
You notice anything?
Not the most diverse selection.
Huh. All white, all straight,
all jocks and pom-pom wranglers.
Tanner, we could be the ones
to change all that.
You could be the first
openly gay prom king
and enjoy a hot date to boot,
and I can be the first queen
who's actually deserving
of any notoriety.
So, what do you say?
I get you laid. You get me crowned.
You can lose that virginity
before you snatch up that diploma.
Just because you know
another gay guy doesn't mean...
Whoa!
He's very attractive. Those lips.
Hm-hmm. That's what we call
some high-speed DSLs.
So?
I'll... think about it.
Perf! I'm gonna invite him
to Cameron's tonight
so you two can get to know each other.
- Crap. I forgot that was tonight.
- Relax. It's gonna be V low key.
Everyone can relax.
The people who matter have arrived.
- I'm gonna go see if Christian's here.
- Ooh, there are Christians here?
Get your gay game face on.
After tonight, you'll have
the prom date of your dreams.
So, Caprice reeled you in some mangina,
huh? Well played.
I guess. I mean, I don't even know
if he'll like me.
Sounds like you need
some liquid courage. Follow me.
Oh, come on. You call this an ensemble?
Get it together, girl.
Do not call me that.
What? Why?
I meant, like, gurl with a U. Gurl!
Not like you're a... Oh, OK.
Erm, so, hey, why don't we dust this off
and you take me to the mall
and pick me out some eye shadow,
just like the old days.
You're so good with colour.
I don't think I'm leaving the house
till college, but, thanks.
Oh, boo.
Listen, I get it. I really do.
With what happened with Tanner,
I know that you didn't get to come out
to me in the way that you wanted to.
We didn't get to have our extra-special
mother-son lifetime movie moment.
I know that.
You don't want to go out tonight, right?
I got a plan B!
Did you know that Webflix
has an entire gay and lesbian section?
Blew my mind. OK, Milk. I got Milk.
It's about a gay mayor.
Boys Don't Cry. Now, this is
a girl that wants to be a boy.
That's a tricky one.
Brokeback Mountain. That's the cowboys.
And something called Shortballs?
Oh, Shortbus. Shortbus.
So, which one do you want
to pop in first, huh?
Probably the cowboys, right?
That one's safe.
Someone drank
all my ginger ales.
Hey, do you know if there's
caffeine/alcohol in a Chica Loca?
No, 'Shley, of course not.
Chug away.
- This was a bad idea.
- There is no getting cold feet now.
We have got to rescue Tanner
from those gay-snatching fashion Nazis.
Divide and conquer.
Hey, sexy. Don't think me presumptuous
when I say "bottoms up".
This tastes like ass.
- Hm-hmm. Perfect for you.
- Funny.
- Loosen up.
- I hear that's helpful.
There you go.
Look, don't let Caprice pressure you.
If you're really that nervous,
then blow off blowing what's his name
and come to prom as my arm candy.
It might be kind of cool to, like,
actually go on a date or something.
PS, this one can has over 600 calories.
I thought carbs
were like gay kryptonite.
Alcohol is the one exception. Duh.
Now down it, bitch.
Whoo!
It's freezing cold out there.
Heath! Don't stand on your pride.
Get in the tent with Jake,
for crying out loud.
Good. Get in there. Snuggle up.
Snuggle up for warmth. There you go.
Oh. Looks like they're waking back up.
Oh-oh. Here we go.
Game on.
You know, I do sense an affection there.
I mean, you really do feel
they care about one another.
Oh, my. Well, yeah.
I guess necessity
is the mother of invention.
I mean...
It's funny. I guess back then
they didn't even need to use protection.
You know, I'm gonna get a drink.
They could have made something out of
some kind of lamb skin or something,
but there probably wasn't time for that.
A few hours
and a lot of drinks later,
I was getting all
the frequently asked questions.
So, with straight guys,
there's ass men and tit men.
But what's the gay equivalent?
Like, ball men?
When you're getting gay with a guy,
how do you decide
who's the girl and who's the boy?
Not an expert,
but I think you're both the boy.
That's kind of the point.
- Just Wiki that shit, freak.
- Leave him alone.
Come on, slut. You owe me a dance.
♪ You do your body work
♪ I feel my pulse working overtime
- Oh, my God!
- Sorry.
Oh. Sorry.
Oh, you guys, I found you! Hi!
- 'Shley.
- Hi.
Hi and bye.
Is it just me, or is she,
like, the worst Mormon ever?
It's so not just you. She's cray-cray.
Hey! You! Gaysian boy, come here.
Ew! Get out!
We're having gay-guy/girl gab time.
- Seriously?
- Oh, my God.
There's a beanbag
in the other room. Let's go.
- Sorry about this.
- I can't wait.
- Really sorry.
- Bitch.
So, your friend Tanner
won't tell me anything about the Js.
The who?
The HJs and the BJs,
pretty much any of the Js.
But I've got an idea.
You are gonna show me how.
And it's not gonna count
because you're like supes gay-mosexual.
- Er, yeah, right.
- Shh!
Just pretend I'm, like, some
super-hot guy, like David Archuleta.
David Archuleta? David, don't you worry.
I'm gonna teach you all about
the HJs and the BJs
and the Jay-Zs and the JJ Abrams.
No, wait. Hold on.
You're drunk, plus, you're Mormon,
which totally exacerbates
the whole being-drunk thing.
- Exacerbates. That's a funny word.
- Yeah.
Yeah, anyway, I'm... I'm not even...
- What?
- Gay.
Prove it, Gaysian.
Look who I found!
Sorry. Oh, hi.
You must be...
Christian. Hello, Tanner.
Even better in real life, right?
- Even better with beer goggles.
- Don't touch me.
Damn, you are pretty.
I mean handsome.
I mean pretty handsome.
- Whassup, bro?
- He's usually less special.
Do you want a glass of water
or something, mate?
Oh, hi, there. I hate to break up
this little... whatever this is,
but I need to talk to Tanner.
Tanner can't talk right now.
He and Christian want private moment.
Caprice, we got off on the wrong foot.
Yo, 'Topher, welcome to the casa.
Thank you. Hey, is Tanner here?
I mean 'Shley.
Is 'Shley here?
She's my girlfriend. Love her.
- Yeah. She's in the back.
- OK.
Hey, Glenn.
Oh, my God. Ew, 'Shley.
Glenn, you really are straight?
No, no, he's totes not.
So it doesn't count. Right?
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Caprice, watch your mouth, please.
I could say the same for you, whoremon.
- I think I have to barf.
- I'll hold your hair.
Hey, T. Remember me?
I just ripped it off. I just had to.
Tan-pon, I heard you bulimed cuisine
all over a Mormon.
I thought I told you
to always drink on an empty stomach.
I'm gonna go. I'm kind of over
being the party's gay mascot
and of publicly humiliating myself
in front of potential dates.
- You want Mindie to drive you?
- Don't worry. I'm totally sober.
No, thanks. I'll walk.
OK. Call me tomorrow.
Kisses. Mwah!
Oh, my God, you totally made out
with your gay bestie.
No!
Oh, erm...
I... am... drunk.
Me, too.
What are you doing
in front of my house?
I have no clue.
Since I basically have no friends left,
my mom decided to have
a queer-movie marathon.
But when we got to Heath and Jake
grunting in a tent,
I started drinking heavily.
- You walked all the way over here?
- Hm-hmm.
I had this idea that I'd make
this grand entrance at the party
and make a huge scene,
but this is as far as I got.
Oopsie.
It's not fair!
You get to be belle of the ball,
and I'm stuck home with mommy dearest.
I'd trade places with you in a second.
- Just... Just do me a favour.
- Hmm?
When you win prom king,
you'll make a big speech
about, you know, everything that
you've learned, you know, very Lohan.
Not really my style, but... we'll see.
Sorry. Still picturing you
watching Brokeback with your mom.
It's not funny!
I'm gonna have to emancipate
or something. She's driving me crazy.
She's just being supportive.
Maybe everyone secretly wants a GBF,
even moms.
Right now I would just settle for,
like, a BF.
You mean like a best friend
or, like, boyfriend?
Either/or.
Or both.
Wait. What?
Oh, my God, no, no.
Did we...? We didn't, right?
- You don't know?
- Do you?
No, no, no. We... We came in,
and we just... We were drunk.
We passed out, I think.
- Right. That sounds right.
- Yeah.
Closet! Now!
- Seriously?
- Gah!
Honey, what was that?
Nothing. I'm just cleaning up in here.
Yeah, it does smell
kind of musky in here.
So, I've got bubbling cinnabons
in the microwave
and some chocolate milk for you.
Super. I'll be right there.
Come on.
- Thanks for that.
- I'm sorry. I'm just not ready.
I don't even know what
I'm doing here. God.
- Wait!
- What?
Could you, er, just go that way?
So, first you want
to put me back in the closet,
and now you want me
to jump out your window?
- Yes.
- Real nice, Tanner.
- I'll make it up to you. I swear.
- Yeah, whatever. It's fine. I get it.
♪ I don't wanna be alright
♪ I don't wanna feel just OK
♪ I wanna see everything
♪ I wanna go everywhere
♪ I wanna settle down
♪ Hey, lover
The next Monday,
I still couldn't shake my hangover
or what happened between Brent and me.
I mean, what was I thinking?
♪ I don't wanna simplify it
Hey, T. Amazing news.
Christian's willing to forget
about your projectile vomit
and general schwastedness
this weekend.
He's still willing to go
to the prom with you.
- Really? Still?
- Believe it, bitch.
You being the only decent-looking,
age-appropriate gay guy
in a 20-mile radius
has given him a convenient case
of boner-induced amnesia.
- He really thinks I'm decent-looking?
- Yeah. Just one condition.
Lay off the cosmo-tini-ritas
on prom night, OK?
- That definitely won't be a problem.
- Yay!
This is gonna be so homo-dorable!
Come on, Tan-tut.
Thank you so much.
I'd like to get two tickets to prom.
Oh, OK, then.
Just write down
the name of your date here
- and also her school if she...
- He.
Erm, excuse me?
- He. He.
- Something funny?
No, "he" as in "him".
Pronouns that describe my date,
who is a dude.
Yikes. Sorry.
To get the couple's special,
you need to be a traditional
boy/girl pairing.
- You want me to fight this bitch?
- Sorry, but that's the policy.
Tanner, I just want you to know
that I share your outrage.
- What are we gonna do about this?
- We?
I thought you could use the GSA's help
to right this blatant discrimination.
That's why our group exists.
Please come to our meeting after school.
Thanks, Solehag,
but we can fight out own battles.
This isn't over.
It's just outrageous.
I mean, what is this, 2008?
OK, that's 20. Give me 20 more.
You want to stay a four-pack queer
forever? Let's go!
McKenzie has a different take
on the love-thy-neighbour thing.
And apparently you can't get
enough of that neighbour lovin'.
McKenzie Price is deceased socially
at this school.
I've already got the Facebook post
composed.
But that defeats the purpose.
I think I'm gonna go
to the GSA meeting after school.
No. Soledad and her little group?
It'll totally downgrade your rep.
Those busted bitches were the ones
that dragged you out of the closet.
Remember? You know what my advice is?
Just buy the stag tickets
and get the F over it.
Don't say you're seriously
considering this.
What have I got to lose?
I mean, they outed me,
but at least their intentions
were kind of noble, I guess.
And let me just say, if you guys
really claim to be my friends,
you could focus a little less
on how much I match your outfit
on any given day
and show some concern
for my freaking equal rights!
PS, are my arms looking
Michelle Obama toned or Madonna scary?
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Have you heard about Tanner?
What? What did... I didn't...
What did you hear?
Apparently he totally threw down
with McKenzie Price over prom.
He was all,
"I'm taking a dude as my date."
She was all, "Not on my watch."
He was all, "We'll see about that,
you c-word-face mofo ho."
Hold that, Wonton.
Tanner wants to ask a guy to prom?
Yeah. I have no idea who, though.
Hey, maybe he met someone.
- No one I can think of.
- Me neither.
See ya.
First order of business, GSA-ers,
I'd like to introduce
our first actually gay member,
Tanner Daniels! Whoo!
Welcome, bro dude.
Good to have another member
with a member representing.
Right. Well, I'm just here because
I was trying to buy prom tickets, and...
And he couldn't
because of our school's unjust,
totally outdated prom-date policies.
So, what are we
gonna do about this?
We?
Yeah. I am joining the GSA
to support my GBF. Move.
- Sorry. I'm sorry.
- Erm...
Fawcett, thank you,
but, erm, we're at capacity,
so we don't really...
Soledad, the GSA is open
to anyone who wants to join.
But, Ms Hoegel,
this is my thing, you know?
She has things, lots of things,
and she's trying to take my... my, er...
- She's...
- Are you quite done?
- Can we please...
- Just one moment.
I've noticed some disturbing trends
in this school as of late.
It seems that many of you girls
are treating Tanner
as more of a prize to be won
than an actual person.
Ms Hoegel, that's ridiculous. Right, T?
Listen, girls. I get the appeal.
Now, I myself had
a gay best friend once and...
Oh, we were room-mates
for many fruitful years.
But now he's no longer with us.
- Oh.
- Oh, damn.
What? Where'd he go?
He obvi died of the hivs, dumb-ass.
Oh, God, no! He moved to San Diego
with a leather queen.
I meant myself and my cat...
Anderson Coo-purr.
Oh, my God.
We're very happy, Mr Coo-purr and I.
What do we do about this prom situation?
If you can't take your boy toy to prom,
I will lead a school-wide boycott,
and if they don't meet my,
I mean our, demands,
then I will just host
my own cooler alterna-prom.
Fawcett, you'd do that?
I mean, prom's your night.
You're a shoo-in for prom queen.
Come on. What's the point of being queen
when I don't have a fabulous king
to share it with?
You know, Soledad, you have done
such a great job with this group,
but I think it's time that some things
actually changed around this school.
Who's with me?
Whoo!
- Hey, Tanner, looking good.
- Hey. Thanks.
WTF, T? I secure you
a date with the hottest teen homo
in the Tri-State area, and that jizz bin
still gets your endorsement?
What? But I didn't ever... What?
"Tanner Daniels endorsed Fawcett Brooks
yesterday at the GSA meeting."
"The new power BFs known as..."
T-Fawce. Cute, isn't it?
You really think another bland blonde
like her deserves the crown, Tanner?
Well, at least she stands up
for my... my rights or whatever.
This hack-tivist doesn't give
a flying fairy about gay rights.
She just did it to gain
the advantage with you.
Like you did with that
male-bait Christian?
Whatever! At least I tried
to bribe him with sex.
I treated him like an actual human being
and not some asexual,
neutered purse puppy.
I've had enough bad-dinner-theatre
dramatics for one day.
- We've got a revolution to plan.
- Do not come for my craft, bitch!
Do not come for my bitch, bitch!
Yeah, it sounds great.
Right. Promise. No drinks for me.
See you then, dude.
- Hey.
- What's up?
Not much.
You're making
quite the stank over prom,
joining the GSA,
endorsing your new bestie.
I didn't endorse anyone.
I just... It's not fair.
We should be treated like everyone else.
We? I mean, you got to ask me first.
What are you talking about?
You and me. Prom.
Er...
Caprice set up this thing
with her friend. I just...
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Who said anything
about us going to prom together?
Just that...
No, I was saying, like,
if you wanted a friend to go with,
but, like, obviously you got
that, you know, taken care of, so...
You know, I hope your Prince Charming
gives you everything you want.
And also crabs.
I got your Facebook message.
Why are you wearing sunglasses?
Does your vocal coach know you smoke?
Look, we all know you're gayer
than a very special episode of Glee.
I am not!
What's your point?
Well, I need a minion,
and you need a diva to worship.
With Tanner and Fawcett
heading up this fey prom,
that leaves an opportunity
for me to be the queen of the real one.
So, how would you like to be
my date, maybe even my king?
Alright, if you still need convincing,
check out a pic of Tanner's prom date.
He can do better, but I'm in.
Hi, there. Caprice, you said you had
something you wanted to talk about?
I do.
- Love your cloak.
- Thanks.
Support traditional prom-going values.
Buy tickets to the official
school-sanctioned prom.
Attend the prom by students,
for all students.
Can I have one, please?
No.
Sorry. You're not on our list
of approved students.
What?
This being an indie operation,
we've got very limited space.
I'm sure Caprice's
old-fashioned loser dance
has plenty of tickets available.
Thank you.
Fawcett, what the hell was that?
Tan, if we want to pull off this
whole gay-inclusive-prom thing,
we're gonna have to keep it
kind of exclusive.
Look, I didn't make up these rules,
but a fugly prom is a failed prom.
So wrong.
You smell great.
Thank you.
I told you. This is crazy.
It's like freaking high-school
Game of Thrones out here or something.
Sorry, Ellen Jr, but you can't take
your poor man's Portia to this dance.
Try the pro-sodomy prom.
You do know that oral
counts as sodomy, right?
So, with the amount of going
down that goes down at prom,
you might want to rethink
the concept. Right, Brent?
By the way, did they change
the official prom song
to Trapped In the Closet just for you?
Nice try, lies-bian,
but I know for a fact
that my boo Brent
is as straight as they come.
Like Kanye or Diddy or Tyler Perry.
Whatev...
. .er. Whatever.
The full word. I said it all.
'Tophie,
I want to go to cool prom.
Hey, 'Shley, you know Caprice calls you
a ginger-snatch behind your back, right?
- She does?
- Well, Fawcett said your religion
is just Scientology without
birth control or famous people.
Well, you know what?
F you both.
She'll be fine.
And we'll take two tickets to
the 100 percent totally ungay prom.
Thank you.
Hmm. Cute shorts.
And you.
I hear you and Spigot here
are denying certain
less-than-favourable people tickets.
Relax, So-fat. You and Memoirs
Of a Gauy Nerd are allowed to come.
I'm giving you a temporary pass
to the cool kids' table.
We wouldn't come
if you paid us, Fawcett.
Or should I say fascist?
- It's your social funeral, sweetie.
- I'll start mourning now.
So-fat! I mean, Sophie! Damn it! Wait!
You know what? You both
have become so much more
than these bitches' sexless accessories.
You've become full-blown tools,
in every sense of the word.
Oh.
Tanner. Tanner.
Tanner! Tanner!
Tanner! What is your deal?
I can't do this any more!
Excuse me? The last I checked,
this was all for you.
Is it?
I actually started to believe
that you were my friend.
But what is this, really?
Am I just some tool to you,
a wrench so that you can screw
over Caprice and 'Shley?
Wrenches don't screw things.
God, you are gay.
But you're right.
Look, at first I just wanted
to keep you to myself.
After Hamilton dumped me...
Yeah, it's true, he dumped me.
I thought I needed you
by my side to win.
But it's different now.
I really like hanging out with you...
for real.
Then why create a separate prom?
You're gonna win queen no matter what.
Don't be so sure.
I took a peek at the polling data.
I rule with the popular kids,
but the other 90 percent,
the rest of the school,
just think I'm a soulless bitch.
I mean, they'd rather vote for 'Shley.
At least she's nice.
Caprice, she's got talent.
What have I got?
- You have me.
- Really?
You're more than what people see
on the surface,
and you're the only one
who stood up for me
when it really mattered,
so let's make a compromise.
You let everyone come
to the alterna-prom,
and I'll make sure
that you get that crown. Deal?
Yeah.
Thanks, all of you, for helping
to keep our prom gayness-free.
So, I'm thinking, activity-wise,
how about a promise-ring booth?
So charming. Love it.
Promise rings for prom. Cute.
I've got
a bit of a different plan.
Listen up, ladies.
Tanner and Fawcett are poaching all the
cool kids for their little pansy prom.
If we don't act quick, we won't have
enough people for a decent hokey pokey.
What we need to do
is start prom-oting prom.
You feel me?
- Amazing.
- Whoo! Yeah!
Hmm. Don't you think this might
be a bit over the top, Brent?
I'm just fighting flamers
with flame.
- Hey.
- Oh, my God!
Relax, dude. I just wanted to tell you
how much I admire your passion.
You're really... organised.
When I heard about Tanner going to prom
with that other dude,
I was totally grossed out, too.
Right, bro? I mean, like,
two dudes, like...
- Ugh. Ick.
- Yeah.
So, erm, do you want to feel
how straight I am?
Come again?
Is this actually happening
or is this a dream?
I just changed my sheets yesterday.
- No, it's real, bro.
- Oh, my God.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
How did you know?
- I mean, did Tanner tell you?
- No, dude, I figured it out myself.
Tanner won't even look at me
since I tried to get with him.
Wait. What am I doing?
No, no way, no.
I cannot have Tanner's
rejected sloppy seconds.
I have too much self-respect.
Now, if you'll excuse me, I have
some anti-gay prom posters to finish.
So close. Goddamn it!
I am so sorry.
"Prom is short for promenade,
not prom-n-Aids."
No one but Brent
could come up with a pun
that simultaneously lame
and offensive.
I told you, he has officially lost it.
What the shit were you thinking?
This language is unacceptable!
Principal Crowe, as a devout Mormon,
I think the signs are all totally true
and appropriate.
Oh, in what universe
would "boutonnieres, not butt sex"
be appropriate for a prom slogan?
Yeah, and "no tossing salads"?
I got cafeteria ladies coming in here
asking me if I changed the menu!
I've got news organisations
calling me, not to mention the ACLU.
- Facebook!
- People are tweeting about this!
We... We weren't thinking.
Well, I'm particularly disappointed
in you, Mr Van Camp.
I expected more of you.
I was thinking about suspending you all.
Instead I'm just gonna cancel prom.
Wait, no! You can't do that!
Wait! That'll turn us
into social pariahs.
That's not fair.
You're not cancelling their prom.
That prom is out
of Crowe's jurisdiction.
Its organisers
haven't been promoting hate.
Get out of here before I change
my mind about the suspensions.
- Terrific restraint.
- Thank you.
Well, Tanner, looks like
we've now got the only game in town.
Though, Brent, I have to
give you some props.
Those signs were pretty hilar.
Later, later.
Sorry.
Onward, Christian soldiers.
They want to cancel our prom?
Then we will organise a protest
of their deviant dance of debauchery.
She's right, B.
The whole me-being-prom-queen ship
has sailed.
But take it from an actress,
if we can't be in the spotlight,
we can sure make
one hell of a scene.
Family values!
Family values! Family...
'Tophie, how could you?
Those signs that you made
were just so, so mean.
Babe, I was just trying
to protect our relationship.
Congratulations.
You just did the opposite.
We are so done-zo.
Hmm.
- How's it going, guys?
- Oh, fantastic.
We've devised a genius way
to take Tan Lines down a few notches.
And knock Fawce-slut off her horse high.
OK, while you crazy Christians
are outside protesting,
Caprice and I will infiltrate the prom
in killer ensembles.
James Bond. Hello.
The moment that Tanner and Fawcett
are crowned king and queen,
we douse them with this.
It'll be very Stephen King's Carrie
meets Mariah Carey's Glitter.
Tanner will hate it.
In fourth grade, I accidentally spilled
glitter on him in arts and crafts.
He didn't talk to me for a month.
It's the longest he and I
have ever gone without speaking,
you know, until now.
And Fawcett will be picking it out of
her prized goldilocks for months.
With any luck, she'll have to
shave it back like Britney.
Yeah! I love it!
- Great scheming, guys.
- Thanks.
I'm so glad we're friends now, Caprice.
I've always wanted an SBF.
An SBF?
Sassy black friend. Duh.
As Brent and Caprice plotted,
I realised I had my own
unfinished business to take care of.
Hey. I mean, hey.
I've got something to say.
Tanner, honey, what is it?
You need a snack.
No, Shannon, I'm not hungry.
I, erm... I've got something
to tell you both,
and I don't care if you like it or not.
- Tanner?
- Honey, what is it?
I, erm...
So, I'm not actually going to the prom
with Fawcett tomorrow.
I mean, she's driving me,
but I've got another date.
A boy. I like boys.
Well, I mean, not boys.
Like, gross. Men. Like, men.
Like, men my own age.
And so did Abraham Lincoln.
I read that somewhere.
And he was, like,
the best Republican ever,
so you should probably say something
before I keep saying more things.
Tanner, we know.
Y-You what?
We know.
And it's OK.
Although your claims
about Abraham Lincoln
I don't think
are entirely substantiated.
Tanner, sweetie,
you haven't been completely consistent
in clearing the internet history.
We've seen... some stuff.
Word. We have seen some stuff.
I mean, who knew that that even...
Anyway, so, you're 100 percent
completely allergic to the lady parts.
That's fine!
- Who cares?
- It's OK.
I-I could be bi.
Yeah, right!
Of course you can.
OK, well, erm,
so, good, I guess, then.
I'm... I'm gonna... I'm gonna go.
Tanner, honey, do you need a snack?
You're skinny.
He could be bi. Coastal.
Prom! Let's do this!
Oh, that's cute.
Oh, that's so prom. Yes.
- Girl, you look great.
- Hey, girl.
- I was talking to my son.
- Thank you.
Ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's do this.
♪ Don't you think it's time
♪ For you and me to make some history?
- ♪ Tell me now what you say
- Cheese!
♪ We can take anything
Caprice, I'm impressed.
I mean, you look very convincing.
♪ When times are hard,
we'll smile and say
♪ We're not afraid of anything
♪ Cos we feel young and wild
♪ I believe
Darling, can I just...? I just want...
Listen, I just wanted to say
that I don't know what, you know,
all this is and I don't...
Whatever...
Whatever you want to call yourself.
I mean, the bottom line is
your mom loves you very much,
like crazy a lot, like to the point
where it's really kind of ridiculous.
It's almost embarrassing. A lot.
So, please just know that, darling.
Thanks. I love you, too.
Oh, gosh, honey. Thank you so much.
Here, I don't want... I don't want
to smudge your makeup.
. .Shall surely be put to death!
Prepare ye... for the infidels.
Finally. Where have you been?
And why are you wearing that?
You're baling on me
to go after that latter-day skank.
'Shley dumped 'Topher
and needs a GBF to escort her to prom.
She still seems to think that I'm gay,
despite our little dry-humping session.
The indignities and humiliations
a guy will go through
just for some Mormon ginge-muff.
You really are a flaming heterosexual.
Guilty! Seriously, Sophe,
can you do me a huge favour
and cover prom for the Gazette?
- No.
- Come on! Please.
You, of all people, know that
this insanity needs to be documented.
And, er, well,
I might have my hands full.
I am not paying Aqua-valve one cent
to get into her sham of a dance.
Comped press passes.
Fine, but I'm only going
if there are appetisers.
Yes!
- Don't hug me.
- Come on.
Aww!
- You're doing it again.
- What?
That noise girls make when
they see two gay guys together.
Yeah, it's the same
annoying sound people make
when they see cute animals
dressed in human clothes.
Ew, gross. Barf. Is that better?
Much.
You're all gonna burn!
Think of your soul you're defiling!
Ever read the Bible?
"Do not lie with a man as one lies
with a woman. It is an abomination."
- Abomination!
- You're all going to hell!
That's right, bitches. I'm upstaging
you all with double the 'mo.
And this one's imported.
Take my picture!
Please take my picture!
Caprice. Brent. Funny seeing you here.
Welcome.
We've seen the error of our ways.
We can't wait to see you both crowned.
You guys really deserve it. Truly.
See, guys? It all worked out.
We all have our very own GBF.
Actually, we're not all GBFs.
Right.
Brent's 100 percent grade-A hetero.
Sure he is.
Well, hey, there, prom date.
Hey.
So, is this not the lamest thing ever?
I didn't know we were gonna be
your girlfriend's matching corsages.
I know, right?
Sorry about that.
Do you want to get out of here?
I know a place where we could...
get to know each other.
Yeah, that sounds awesome.
I just feel like I should really
stay here for Fawcett's sake.
- Tanner.
- She's like...
- . .really fragile.
- Tanner.
- And... Hmm?
I get it. You're not there yet.
So, if you don't mind,
I'm... I'm gonna bounce.
OK.
- Night.
- Sure.
". .For this is how the nations I am
driving out before you became defiled."
Nice!
"I came to punish
and it has vomited out its inhabitants."
See ya.
What are you doing?
I feel a monster stress zit coming on.
You know when you can feel it coming
and there's nothing you can do
to stop it?
Let me look.
OK, well, I do see it.
The good news is
it won't surface for a few hours.
Thanks.
But if things run late with Posh Spice,
he might have to learn
to love you, zits and all.
Not gonna happen. He baled.
I guess I spent all this time
being a GBF
and never actually learned
how to be a real, live gay.
Well, it sounds to me
like he doesn't deserve you.
I just miss you guys so much.
I can't believe I ditched you.
I don't know what happened to me.
I just got scared.
Not to mention blinded by the flash
of bleached teeth and hair?
Tanner?
Our crowning moment
is only minutes away.
Great tunes, great tunes.
OK, hello there, ladies and gentlemen,
and, er, everything in between.
This is it, babes. This is our moment.
T-Fawce is gonna dominate.
This is it, our moment.
T-Fawce is gonna eat it.
We make a good team, B.
It is my pleasure to announce
this year's prom king and queen
of North Gateway's first "LGBTQA
and every other letter you
can think of" inclusive prom.
So, without further ado...
. .our trailblazing couple is...
. .T-Fawce!
Tanner and Fawcett!
Wow.
Congratulations. Well deserved.
Let me know when you think
they're in position.
- Congratulations.
- We love you, Tanner.
Thank you. Oh, my goodness.
This is such a surprise.
- Fawcett, I want to say something.
- OK.
You're fierce!
This is for you.
- Wait. Give him a second.
- We love you, T-Fawce!
Look, er, thanks, everyone,
for making me king of this gay prom.
Oh, my God, he's doing it.
He's going full Lohan.
I don't want to be king of the gay prom
or be a gay best friend
or get gay-married.
I just want to go to prom,
be a friend,
get married, maybe.
You all see me more
as an object or a symbol.
I guess I've been guilty of that myself.
I used my friends
as shields to hide behind.
I had friends who cared about me...
. .whether I was gay or whatever.
And I had a best friend
who I shared everything with.
And all I want is...
I mean, I'd give anything
to just be his loyal sidekick again.
Thank you very much.
Well, that's just sweeter
than a pug in a sundress.
Oh, no!
Oh, my God!
Hmm!
Brent! Jesus, are you OK?
Thought you could upstage me
with a classic "what I learned" speech?
Amateur!
So, Brent burst
out of the closet
in an explosion of glitter,
just like he always wanted,
and I got my best friend back.
- Caprice, mission accomplished?
- Er, not yet.
OK, y'all made your point. I made mine.
Now we all have a choice.
You can stay out here,
bored out of your minds
and freezing your asses off
with this crazy bitch.
Or you can come inside and dance
your asses off with this crazy bitch.
Do you really want to go heaven
if it's filled with nothing
but psychos like her?
That's what I thought.
OK, let's go.
Suit yourselves! Run toward damnation!
I'll see you all in hell!
I mean, I won't see you
cos I won't be there,
but there's probably, like,
a window or something
where people in heaven
can look down to people in hell!
And I'll see you through
that hell window... thing!
That sucks, man.
How about an HJ?
♪ Drop that beat, bitch
♪ My gay best friend
♪ He's on the go
♪ We hit the club
♪ We drop it low
♪ He always gets
So, I went down in history
as the first kid in our school
to come out,
but I definitely wasn't the last
because, as it turns out,
the closet and high school
are kind of the same thing.
They're both something
you can't wait to escape
but are scared to death
of what lies beyond.
They both make you kind of insane,
cause you to take on a secret identity
or make you confused
or mean...
or crazy horny, even.
- Sweet Joseph Smith, you are sexy.
- You, too.
You're out, right?
For a face like yours, I'll out myself
to the entire Mormon Tabernacle Choir.
When you're in,
every little thing
just seems like the hugest deal,
but once you're out, well,
you wonder why
you ever made such a fuss.
And while things still suck
every once in a while,
when you finally leave
both the closet and high school,
everything just kind of... sucks less.
- So, now that you're out...
- I am?
What about us?
- Us?
- Hm-hmm.
- Well, I just...
- I was...
What? No, you go first.
- I was thinking...
- Hm-hmm.
- . .You know, if we ended up together...
- Which we totally would
if this were a classic
high-school movie.
Right, and, you know, but we
don't get to kiss as the credits roll.
Well, we got to,
you know, keep going.
Maybe we'd last a few months.
- Right.
- A year.
And then what?
Then we go to college
and then I cheat on you
and it's awkward and I lose you forever.
So, what you're saying is,
instead of satisfying
our teenage horniness...
Instead of risking having you as my BF,
I'd rather keep you forever as my BFF.
Go F yourself.
So, after Brent
had made his gayness official,
'Shley and Glenn won cutest couple
when he came out as irrefutably straight
and she came out as a total rice queen.
But it took us a bit longer
to convince Fawcett to come out
as a chemistry nerd
with a secret nice streak.
Oh, my God!
Sophie won a scholarship
to Sarah Lawrence
after she published
a well-regarded analysis
of the adolescent propensity
for self-perpetuated objectification.
And Brent and Caprice
were voted most dramatic,
which, let's face it, is basically
short-hand for gayest and bitchiest.
As for me, I didn't win
any senior superlatives.
With all the new outings going on,
my sex life, or lack thereof,
was once again
the least interesting thing about me.
I wasn't an accessory or a sidekick.
I was just me.
And I couldn't have been gayer about it.
And I mean that
in the old-timey, happy way,
not the gay way,
but... yeah, that, too.
♪ In the darkness
I will be waiting for you
Pop dance crap!
Oh, shut up.
You know you love that crap.
You have a ladybug in your hair.
Looks like they're waking back up.
- You want to hang out?
- Yeah. Should I just...?
Yeah, just have a seat.
Hmm, sits well.
She did... You... You...
OK, do it again.
You're not wearing underwear, are you?
No.
I think they do care
about each other, though.
That's the nice thing.
Yeah!
You could be like my sister wife.
I like just "gay". He's gay.
Yo, bro.
Necessity is the mother
of invention, right?
Little...
. .spitting.
Now give me booty bump, booty bump.
Oh. Oh, boy, that's firm.
Not surprised.
I can't wait to go home. I miss you.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Drama!
You checking out my ba...
I like the colours.
I really think hipster goth
is coming back.
No, it's not. Let's go.
I just bought these!
- What flavours did you make?
- Cherry, of course.
Mmm. Black or bing?
You know I like the black ones.
He could be bi.
Lingual.
But then we'd have
a Spanish-speaking son.
Who the hell wants that?
- Bi is confusing.
- I don't get it.
- I'm glad he's gay.
- Yo no comprendo bi.
- Yeah.
- How about a Pop-Tart?
- Do you want a Pop-Tart?
- Yes, I would like a Pop-Tart.
- I'll get you a Pop-Tart.
- Thank you, love.
♪ Traditional prom
- It's always my day.
- Wait! I wouldn't lift up that high.
- Oh, my Britney.
- Is that what they call it these days?
My sunglasses
are supposed to be on.
Tweets! People are tweet... tweeting.
Or how about an arch J?
Not arch.
What's an arch J?
"Can think of" inclusive prom,
so... sorry!
With that...
He can't deal with it.
Heath is freaking.
That's sad.
Are you coming back?
♪ H
♪ E
♪ R
♪ Oh, I'm such a lady
♪ But now I wanna get freaky
♪ I'm feeling naughty, am I crazy?
♪ Oh, I just want to be bad
♪ Pass me my glass
♪ The fangs are out tonight
♪ Who am I gonna bite?
♪ H... my hips
♪ E... emotion
♪ R... the rhythm
♪ All the parts of her
♪ H... my hips
♪ E... emotion
♪ R... the rhythm
♪ All the parts of her