23.976
Sweet dreams are made of this
Who am I to disagree?
Travel the world and the Seven Seas
Everybody looking for something
Some of them want to use you
Some of them want to get used by you
Some of them want to abuse you
Some of them want to be abused.
Some of them want to use you
Some of them want to get used by you
Some of them want to abuse you
Some of them want to be abused...
Put the fucking team back in!
Turn me around.
Shit!
Subz done manually by majtjk0ng
Good run, Kable.
- My name is Tillman.
- Whatever your name is,
- you got to the save point fast.
- Who the fuck cares?
No one is getting out of here alive.
I am. I'm gonna make it out.
Sure you will.
They said you got 3 battles left
before you get out.
Bob!
Alright, let me handle this.
- Do we have the interview or don't we?
- Yes
We are a cunt-hair close.
Look I'm not going to blow the
3 Asian Wars for 'close'.
With all do respect, Bob,
nobody cares about dead Orientals.
- They care about Ken Castle.
- Can I hear from Gina, please?
Okay, Bob...
Bob, are you aware that Castle has clocked
exactly one media appearance date,
and that was Walter's last interview
before she died nine fucking years ago!
Stop menstruating and just tell me
whether we fucking have it?
We fucking, have it.
Good!
Palindromes
Okay, focus.
Let's get lunch.
Iranian, Sushi, or Mexican?
Uh, no.
Burger, chili fries?
I could freak a burger.
We live in Society.
We visit Society.
I mean, which one,...
.. which one's more real?
Really?
I mean, which one's really real?
Know what I mean?
You're watching
Gina Parker Smith
A live 'World Link Tonight' exclusive!
This motherfucker is
off the charts.
You realize he could
buy the network.
Yeah, why would he?
The son-of-a-bitch pulls in
650 millions pay-per-views
for one single broadcast.
Going live in...
5... 4... 3... 2... 1...
First, there was "Society".
The ultimate SIM environment,
where players don't control
virtual animated characters,
but actual,
living, breathing, human beings.
They walked them. They talked them.
They juiced them. They rocked them.
Rickity-dickity-doo.
We had that on t-shirts
back in 2010.
The creation of reclusive genius
Ken Castle...
"Who is Ken Castle?"
"Society" took the
world by storm,
becoming the #1 guilty pleasure of billions.
You can get paid to be controlled,
or you can pay to control.
And generating one of the
world's largest private fortunes,
.. surpassing Bill Gates
practically, over night.
Nine months ago,
Castle availed a new simulation.
One that would take gaming to
new heights of thrilling excess...
.. and controversy.
SLAYERS
Slayers.
If "Society" let us
live through others,
"Slayers" would let us
die through others.
Slayers gives the gamer full
control of a flesh & blood human being,
in full scale kill or be killed combat.
And when we say "flesh and blood"
We mean, flesh...
and blood.
www. frendz4m. com
Slayers.
Slayers!
Why isn't it murder?
Gina, when was the last time you saw
somebody volunteer to be murdered?
I'm sure you know that every last one
of our Slayers is a bonified death row inmate.
Each one offered the chance to participate
as an alternative to their sentence.
You stay alive for 30 sessions,
you get set free.
That's not a bad goddamn deal.
And has any of these men or women have
actually survived long enough to be set free?
Well I'd remind the audience that Slayers
was put together with a full cooperation
and approval, of the United States
Federal government.
That the revenue that produces...
is responsible for funding
our entire prison system...
keeping the bad guys
behind bars.
And that the Prop. was voted
for by a cock-solid 68% of the American public.
In an election tainted by
a suspected digital fraud.
Let's talk about the
so called "Genericons",..
.. sent into the Slayers' environment,
With a set of pre programmed actions,
with no one controlling them,
.. and no way to react.
Their chances of survival are next to nil.
There's plenty of men and women in prison
who can never cut it as Slayers
shouldn't they be given the same chance
to roll the dice for a ticket out?
Besides they only need to survive
one session.
Right.
So Mr. Castle,
how the hell does it work?
It begins with a single nano cell
planted in the motor cortex of the brain.
This cell can replicate,
replacing the cells around it
with perfect copies.
And these copied cells contain
remote access functionality.
Therefore nano plus cortex,
equals a "nanex".
Isn't it true, that every human
that undergoes this procedure,
will have a distinct "IP" address,
like a mobile device...
- or a notebook computer?
- Similar, yeah.
But control is strictly localized
to the parameters of
our gaming environment.
You take "Society" for instance.
Once a cast member has left the workplace
they're completely free...
from the control and
monitoring of their player.
Oh well, that's a relief!
For some, maybe.
For some...
Don't you suspect a good many folks
wouldn't mind or need a bit of controlling?
Someone else making
all the decisions for you?
No tough choices?
No responsibilities?
- Think about it.
- We will, Mr. Castle.
We will!
The Gina Parker Smith Show!
Sponsored by...
SLAYERS
Good little talk?
Oh, shit!
My pleasure!
Can I just tell you, I cannot wait
until the next Slayers,
I mean, Kable has been unbelievable!
His arms are just so...
well I know they're terrible!
What the hell was that?
Ken Castle wants you to believe that
we are living in a better, safer world.
- His a liar! Mind controlling his Slayers...
- Mr. Castle, we have no idea where this is...
We will all be his dogs if we allowed
this evolution to continue.
That's a goddamn hoot!
This is nuts, it's like the signal is generating
simultaneously from six countries.
Bypass overload. Reroute to
the backup servers please, now.
Now!
Uh, Mr. Castle, we can't stop every
virus that sneaks in.
You might want to let my home boys
take a look at your firewall.
We're on it. They'll be off
the air momentarily.
So sorry.
What about you, sugar?
I wonder if I might breach your
firewall one of these days?
You're bad!
He's good!
Hit him!
Fuck him up!
Get down!
Get the fuck down!
Get down! Get down!
Kable!
My name is Tillman.
Yeah yeah. Tillsman, Tillsman
They said your name was Tillsman.
You're just sitting, eh?.
Sitting and looking, just looking and sitting...
Just like me, man.
Keeping my wholes down,
you gotta keep your whole's down...
Everyday I do it, and then
everybody snaps, breaks...
starts to crack up, you know,
because you don't know if
you're going to live
a day or two or die.
Anybody but you, right?
27 battles, huh? Three to go...
Nobody has ever done it.
No man has ever come that close.
No one has even got 10 games
without getting their brain shot...
Everybody but Kable. Kable, because
he's sitting and looking, huh man?
You're gotta plan in your head.
You got a mission.
You never break.
You never snap.
You never say shit either, but you
take care of your business, don't you?
Niggers can get spooked by that kind of
single mindness, you know what I mean?
Cause you're spooky.
You spook me.
Whatcha in for?
You want to get back to them.
It's all you think about.
It's the only thing that keeps you alive.
Who's talking?
Sign it.
What?
Sign it. Please Tillman.
My son David is your biggest fan.
He prays for you.
I need to prove it's authentic.
Makes it worth more.
Why would anyone want my name?
You don't even know what's
going on out there, do you?
All medical personal
report to central process.
Damn, gotta go.
- No, wait! Wait!
How did you get this picture?
Have you seen them?
Sweat baby sweat baby
sex is a Texas drought.
Me and you do the kind of stuff
only Prince would sing about
So put your hands down my pants
and I bet you'll feel nuts
Yes I'm Siskel,
yes I'm Ebert
and you're getting
two thumbs up
Come quicker than FedEx never reach an apex,
just like Coca-Cola stock you are inclined,
To make me rise an hour early
just like Daylight Savings Time
You and me baby
ain't nothin' but mammals
So let's do it like they do
on the Discovery Channell. Do it again now.
You and me baby ain't nothin' but mammals
So let's do it
like they do on the Discovery Channel
Gettin' horny now
Hey.
Hi.
- Hi.
So what's your damage?
You know, just hanging out.
Just looking to meet people.
...meet people.
Lucky you. You met me.
- I'm Nika.
- I'm Dale. I like your fur.
- Do you wanna go somewhere?
We are somewhere.
Ken Castle... Is a liar.
Liar!
Fuck!
A new video prank by
the subversive group Humanz...
caused a nation wide
stir today.
All contact between "Society" city, and
an estimated 3 quarters of a million players
were shut down for 3 hours
while Castle technicians
worked to remove what they described
as a "satellite infection"...
These pranks, at first,
attributed to rogue isolated hackers
are now suspected to be the work of
an elaborate and sophisticated,
network of programming cells,
spread around several countries.
Experts estimate that the service interruption
will end up costing Castle
billions in lost revenue.
Well don't cry for Castle,
he can cover this with
change in his couch cushions.
On a personal note,
that shit was fucked up.
Yeah it was.
I literally pissed myself.
Sounds like fun.
Seriously, these Humanz cock suckers,
they're are out of control.
- Sandra.
- Quiet.
- My name is Sandra.
- Stop talking.
They can't say
I didn't try...
Fuck yeah!
We're all going to die!
Oh God!
Let me out of here!
I'm not supposed to be here!
Who are they?
Who the fuck are they?
Who the fuck is playing us, man?
Shut up, fish.
Gay, gay, gay, tardily gay.
- Swarmers.
The latest innovation
from Browning,
this self detonating cartridge...
offers the widest
and deadliest spray available...
from a full tracking, cornering coordinates.
- Daddy like it.
- Simon!
Fan girl, stop hacking me.
You suck Simon. You're going to get
my boyfriend killed...
before he can get out of jail and
before he can fill me up with his hot seed!
Simon!
I just wanna play you.
- Forget about that star fucker.
- Shut up bitch!
So when am I going to get to meet you,
for like, real?
What's that?
What's up looser?
Mum says: Go to college,
move the fuck out, and...
And, oh yeah! You're a sick retard!
You're pathetic.
You smell like Jeffrey Dahmer.
- Wanna make out?
- You wish.
I can't wait until they
cut you out, Simian.
Your balls bitch.
- Simon?
- Maybe.
Oh my God! Is really you!
- Nice.
- Do you want to see our tits, Simon?
Yes, yes I do.
Now that we have your attention, here's
an offer that you can't refuse.
- Here we go.
- 50 million euros...
for control of Kable.
instant transfer to the account
of your choice.
Kable is not for sale,
thank you.
Baby, make it a hundred...
It's been real!
What the fuck?
If you want to talk to Kable,
we can show you how.
Look at it.
The new face of Slayers.
Pure, crystalized horror,
two stories high and
bathed in bloody red.
He is what they want.
They love Kable.
They do now,
but when they watch their hero die
right in front of their eye balls...
so sharp and vivid...
if feels like it could've reach out and
touch the wet flesh.
They're going to change their point of view
and be seduced by the power...
.. the violence, the dominance.
It's human nature.
Kable's made it through 28 battles.
Every player in the game
is trying to take him out.
Yeah, Kable is a perfect soldier,
He's a tactical killing computer.
His only vulnerability is
the nanex itself. The...
delay between Simon's commands
and Kable's ability to execute.
So why should this one be any different?
Who controls him?
No one.
Get it out of me!
What the hell happened
to this one?
Looks like he escaped.
Hi girls. Back to your Jazzercise.
That's Hackman,
Hackman, Hackman, knack man.
They say he killed a
whole bunch of people, man.
Killed himself all kinds of people.
And then one day, he just walks up
and turns himself in...
like he wants to be inside
or some crazy shit like that.
You know what I'm saying?
So it's going to be all
kinds of Slayers, man.
As long as you got motherfuckers like
that running around killing...
Kable! Let's go!
Upgrades, come on.
Why don't you upgrade
a brother man?
Why don't you shut the fuck up?!
Shut the fuck up. Shut the fuck up.
Fucking, shut the fuck up.
- Who wimps?
- What?
Who wimps,
The player or the slayer?
I am the hand.
Someone, somewhere else is the eye.
It's tripped out, man.
Sometimes, they take over...
completely, they...
move you around like a robot.
- But that don't work so good.
- Why?
The delay.
Yeah the ping.
They talk about that.
About how long it takes the
Slayer to respond to the command.
Whatever they call it,
the slice of a second out there,
is the difference between living and dying.
When that trigger pulls...
.. it's just me.
Hey, Kable.
Look.
I just killed someone.
This is the blood.
Look.
He's back here.
Wanna see?
You know your head ain't on straight.
I'm going to kill you too,
on Sunday.
Yeah, probably.
That's why they put me here.
I got no strings.
I got no strings,
so I have fun.
I'm not tied up to anyone.
They got strings,
but you can see,
there are no strings on me.
You go two whores, Kable.
- What the fuck did you say?
- On the outside.
I'm sorry,
I meant your pretty girls.
So you want to get back to them.
But I'm going to visit them first.
Alright.
Kable.
Kable, dude. It's me.
It's me.
Who?
Simon, I'm playing you.
- How come I can hear you?
- Well, it's a mod.
Gamers can't talk to cons.
I know.
It's fucking unbelievable.
This is amazing.
Cool yeah?
No it's not cool.
Pay attention to the fucking game!
Okay, okay.
I got it, I got it.
What are you, 12?
I'm 17 actually,
thank you.
This is unbelievable.
How am I not dead yet?
Cause I'm a badass,
motherfucker.
Shit!
Freak, you shouldn't be here.
- Gibs.
- What?
Like giblets -Kibbles and Bits -
Chunks - Pieces everywhere.
These are real humans fucker.
Death row, psychos... so what?
They had it coming anyway, right?
I guess that goes for me too.
Yeah, but you're different.
Different, how?
I don't know, because
you're my psych.
Damn new area.
Think about it Kable, all the shit
we've been through together,
what an epic run, man.
It's gonna suck to see it end.
Are you fucking kidding me?
Oh yeah, I get that for you it's different.
This way.
- There's nothing there.
- Trust me, kid.
It's restricted area. It's beyond
the borders of the game
I couldn't put you there if I tried.
Warning.
Access denied.
Shit.
Bye, Kable.
Come on.
This kid's going to get me killed.
Dude I'm right here, man.
I can hear you.
Listen to me.
I don't know who's behind it or why,
but I was supposed to die tonight.
Lucky for us,
I can beat them...
but not with you controlling me.
What the hell are you talking about?
Turn me lose, kid.
You want to win? Turn me lose.
Find a way.
Bastard.
So Ms Roth. Says here you're
applying for custody of your daughter?
Delia, her name is Delia.
Spouse incarcerated. Life, without the possibility of parole.
- You use your maiden name?
- Uh-huh.
My husband... he's...
it's not entirely true
regarding his sentence.
In fact,
he's due to be released soon.
Ms. Roth,
your husband was charged and con...
He was charged and convicted
of first degree murder.
I can't hardly
consider his release,
if it were to happen at all..
I don't think it would be a good thing.
So it's says you're an actor?
I don't know that I've
seen you in anything.
I work in "Society".
It's a job.
Ms. Roth, your child has been exceedingly well placed.
The new family is very wealthy,
She will never want for anything.
Now I can understand that
you love your daughter.
Probably very much. But do you really
think she would be better off...
with...
people like you?
Yes, I do.
I'm her mother.
We will give your application on
the consideration of merits.
www. frendz4m. com
Do you like the software?
Software?
The walkie talkie, player.
No shit.
You're the guy from the TV,
the Humanz.
That's right, baby.
You think about
what the brother said?
To what brother do you refer,
brother?
Kable wants the freedom to ass kick.
Do shit his way.
- Are you going to give it to him?
- You were listening?
We see and hear everything...
everything that goes on inside
that so called game.
Alright then,
Kable said we got lucky...
They were gunning for us.
What's that all about?
Kable got a past,
he knows things.
Things you don't even know.
- What things?
- Things that Castle is afraid of.
As long as your boy stays on the inside,
Castle knows he can keep him quiet.
But if he ever got out... Castle
would never let that happen.
There's one battle left,
I think I can handle my own business,
thank you very much.
You're not hearing me.
This is not something you can control.
They're gonna kill his ass, Simon.
In the eyes of the world,
and then what?
You're just another poor
little rich honky.
No cable, no pussy, no shit.
Look man, this... this is too heavy. I don't
even know what the hell are you talking about.
- I just play games, man. Games.
- That's right.
It is a game.
You want to win, don't you?
Yeah, I intend to.
Then you need to cut your
strings puppet master.
Imagine a slayer that don't got
to wait to be told what to do.
No ping, you dig?
That would be cheating.
A mod.
That's all it would be.
You know why?
Because the game's got to evolve.
- You feel me?
- I do.
I do feel you my,
giant brother.
Well then,
let's rock baby.
Tillman...
he knows you talked to him.
Your player.
Who are you?
A friend.
I don't have any.
Listen to me.
Simon is going to give you what you want.
What you asked him for.
How do you know that?
I know something else.
Whether or not he's controlling you,
you will never reach the save point.
Castle won't allow it.
We'll see.
No, you have to escape.
Your wife and your
daughter need you, Tillman.
If you want to get out and see
the people in the picture...
you will have to find another way.
I need you to get me something.
What? Tell me.
Drunk.
What have you got there?
Kable, what the hell is that?
Put it down.
Put it down!
Fuck face!
Throw the bottle in the trash!
Oh, I see it was a great idea
turning you loose.
- What happened?
- You happened!
You wanted control,
you got it.
What's the matter with you, Kable?
Kill something!
This is unbelievable.
Kable, listen.
This is the last game
you're going to end up dead and I'm
going to look like a total asshole...
if you don't pull your balls together, man!
Damn it!
Kable, what the hell are you doing?
Aw, what the hell?
That's just gross, bro.
Go, go, go, go!
I'm not your fucking cheerleader!