--casualties have been medevacked.
Live from Shibuya.
I can see many cars ablaze
at Shibuya Crossing.
The destruction is like a war zone.
--the area is closed off.
The cause remains unknown.
Kurono!
Your suit!
Don't.
Someone has to.
But you can't!
I have to!
Who else will?
Kurono!
Kurono.
How's Pop?
He's alive!
Good...
Kurono? Please...
Kurono! Kurono!
No! I don't want to go!
Kurono!
See my shiny and wavy hair.
Enrich your hair.
NEWSFLASH
OSAKA IS IN A STATE OF EMERGENCY
What's going on in Osaka?
Maybe it's monsters, like in Shibuya?
-OSAKA'S IN A STATE OF EMERGENCY.
-YOU OKAY?
LIKE THE KILLINGS IN TOKYO.
It contains super rich
hyaluronic acid, Akatsuki.
-IS IT THE U.S. MILITARY?
-IT'S MASSACRE!
Ayumu, I'm in Shinjuku.
I'll catch a train.
You're late. What have you been doing?
I'm sorry.
Do you remember what today is?
What is it?
He has a knife!
Police!
There!
Where are you hurt?
You'll be okay.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, AYUMU
Am I alive?
Hey, you--
Are you in shock?
I got...
stabbed.
You were?
I dropped dead from a stroke.
Reika here was in a car accident.
Reika...
The star?
Oh, yeah. She's a big deal, right?
I'm a bit out of touch,
but I saw her in a TV ad.
What was it? Shampoo...
Oh, please. Who cares?
Aren't you her fan, Nishi?
I know you schoolboys...
Shut up, Baldy.
What's your name?
Masaru Kato.
My name is Suzuki.
Nice to meet you.
What's going on?
Explain!
It's hard to believe,
but we all died before.
What...?
You told me the same thing.
It makes no sense to me!
Rise and shine
It's a new morning for us
A morning of new hope
Breathe in
A chest full of joy
Look up at the clear, blue sky!
Listen to the radio
What's this?
The summer breeze
It is so wholesome
Breathe in and exercise now
To the count of one, two and three
Your old lives have ended.
I will decide how to use your new lives.
That's the way the cookie crumbles.
Go now and finish off this guy.
Nurarihyon.
HE KICKS ASS. HE WON'T GIVE UP.
KILL HIM IN GIVEN TIME.
Oh, no. He looks tough!
What is this thing?
This black orb is... Gantz.
Gantz?
I don't know why,
but that's what everyone calls it.
What the hell?
Are these toy guns?
"Kato-cha, LOL." Is this mine?
You two first-timers
had better get dressed now.
Don't tell me what to do, Baldy!
Morons like him always die first.
What's that, punk?
You're just a stupid gamer.
You have an attitude, school kid.
I'm talking to you, punk!
-Nishi!
-Don't!
I told you.
Nishi!
He would have only dragged us down.
This guy looks useless, too.
Are you okay?
Put on the gear, Kato!
Who are you?
We're stuck playing
an endless survival game.
A survival game?
You must have seen it on the news.
You know the monster in Shibuya...?
We fight the monsters.
You mean,
you're the ones in the black suits?
In the previous game,
our toughest members
were eliminated unfortunately.
We lost our leader.
Gantz, beam me out of here.
Hurry up, Kato!
Quickly, please!
Put it on!
Are you okay?
Wait a minute...
DOTONBORI
We're...
This is Osaka!
But we're always sent to Tokyo!
She's out of range, moron.
Are you okay?
You guys are useless.
Sorry, I totally panicked.
What's going on?
Explain it to me.
Fuck off.
What's going on? What is she?
-Why us?
-Wait, Nishi!
I'll tell him.
Why do we have to fight them?
And who are they?
We don't know.
We only know one thing.
We have to kill all the enemies
before our time runs out.
What if we don't?
Then...
We'd all die.
But...
For real.
We'd no longer exist in the world.
That's the Gantz rules.
What do you mean, rules?
Oh, no!
Impossible!
Come here.
This way.
Kato, go ahead and shoot!
Kato!
I'm okay?
The suit protected you. Come on!
Who did it?
-He's lying!
-Are you?
Who are they?
You have a Tokyo accent.
Are you the Osaka team?
Osaka team?
So, there are more?
How come you don't know that?
This is his first game.
A novice, a kid, a middle-aged man,
and a woman.
How pathetic.
Ouch!
Is he okay?
As long as you're still alive,
you'll get back all your limbs
when the stage is cleared.
What...?
How about that tough guy
who's called Kuro or something?
He's dead.
Wait a minute!
It's Reika!
Man! Look at the jugs on her!
Shit!
Hey, the Tokyo team's not bad.
More of them!
Here we go!
You just sit and watch, wimps.
Reika, watch us finish them off.
Then we can swap numbers.
Come on, George!
There are so many of them!
I'll go for the right side.
How about you?
They're enjoying this...
That's worth points. I'll have it.
How about that, Reika?
The Osaka team is tough.
What's that weapon and the bike thing?
You can get superior weapons
if you score 100 points.
One hundred points...?
After defeating the enemies,
we're teleported back to the room
to get scored.
100-POINT MENU
If you get 100, you win the game.
Gantz gives you three bonus options.
Like what?
Like superior weapons.
Or resurrect a dead teammate.
You can bring them back?
Apparently. I've never done it.
And the third option?
3. HAVE YOUR MEMORY WIPED AND QUIT.
Graduation.
You'll be free!
Free?
Score 100 points
and you can leave this all behind.
You'll forget all about the Gantz games
and go back to your regular life.
Anyway, it's good, isn't it?
We won't have to do anything.
The Osaka guys will wipe out the monsters.
I'll let them have the small ones,
and I'll take the Boss at the end.
Nishi's strategy is to hide and wait
for the strongest one at the end.
Killing the Boss scores you
a lot of points.
Help!
We have to help those people.
Come on, Suzuki.
We should avoid any unnecessary risks.
Suzuki!
-But isn't that what you do?
-Well...
Not without our leader...
Come on!
We're not tough enough
to protect other people.
We can leave it to the Osaka team...
so that we can just concentrate
on surviving, okay?
Kato, wait! Kato!
If you must go, keep this.
Someone's waiting for your call.
There are still some pay phones around.
Make sure that you don't die.
It's good.
All the sauce we want!
Do you see that there?
Yeah...
It's no Biriken statue.
He's spooky.
The Kato residence.
Hello?
Ayumu, it's me.
Where have you been?
I've been calling you.
Sorry.
I was called into work.
On a night like this?
With what's happening in Osaka?
What's happening there?
Some monsters are running wild in Osaka.
Really?
I had no idea.
How is that even possible?
Anyway, just come home.
Sorry.
It'll be a while.
Okay, see you later.
Ayumu.
What?
I will come home.
I know that!
I'll eat first, then go to bed.
It's here!
Damn it!
Hi there!
You with the Tokyo team?
Right.
I'm Anzu Yamasaki,
from the Osaka team. And you?
I'm Masaru Kato.
How old are you? I'm 23.
Seventeen.
A high-school boy! You're just a kid.
I've been watching you.
I got really curious about...
what you were doing.
I'm sure I'm wrong, but...
Did you just save that family?
What were you really doing?
Well...
I saved the family.
Oh, my God, it's impossible!
I did.
No! No one does that.
But I did!
Would you just watch someone get killed?
Phony Alien!
Are you upset?
I'll help people.
Quit it.
You hypocrite.
Don't follow me.
Lighten up. I love watching weirdos.
You're funny.
I know you won't last long.
I just remembered.
I saw a kid hiding with some old people.
I hope they're okay.
Where are they?
You're such a show-off!
Don't cry or the monsters will get us.
We're finished. It's just like hell.
It's okay if I die...
but not the boy.
His life's just begun.
I want to take him to his parents.
Get away from it!
You run! I'll take care of it!
Honey!
There they are.
Are you okay? I'll save you!
Back away!
Run!
No. I'll save them!
No way. You can't beat him!
I'll save them.
Don't you dare!
I know you're scared.
You'll die, you blockhead!
Stop! He'll seriously kill you!
You idiot!
He can die if he wants to.
He's just a hopeless moron...
He is kind of cute though.
Is there anything I can do, boy?
Just move away.
Idiots like that are rare.
One of a kind...
Get back!
What's this?
Maybe I'm scared...
...to see him die.
How can I beat him?
What an idiot!
Damn it!
Excuse me!
Now what?
Hey!
Are you okay?
Hey, are you okay?
Is there a doctor or a paramedic?
Someone call an ambulance!
Major roads are swarming with citizens.
Experts say that the creatures
are not of this Earth
but of alien origin.
You're gonna save more people?
Yeah.
Why are you acting like such a hero?
Leave it alone.
I'm just curious about your upbringing.
What do your parents do?
My parents?
Dad was a firefighter.
He died with Mom in a car accident.
When I was in junior high.
Any siblings?
A brother, 10.
Is he in an orphanage?
I work so we can live in an apartment.
If you don't survive,
your brother would be left alone.
Right.
I live with my 3-year-old son.
You're a mom?
Yeah. Do I look too young?
Hey! Just say "yes"
whenever you're asked that.
Anyway, we're both in a similar situation.
We can't afford to die.
Never.
Right.
We can't die.
Military personnel have been deployed
all across the city.
We have an update on the mysterious people
in black suits.
This footage was just uploaded
to a video site.
A young man in black fought
to protect an old couple and a child.
THEY EXIST!
-I'M IMPRESSED.
-GO, OSAKA!
-SEE THE NEWS?
-IS IT REAL?
-THE TV SAYS SO.
-GO, BLACK SUIT!
Go now!
Thank you.
-Use the big gun!
-Not yet!
I'll do it.
There's something crazy about them...
Guys like them always survive.
That dark-skinned one...
We call him George.
His real name is Shimaki.
He's won three bonuses.
The tall skinhead is Nobuo Muroya.
We call him Nobuyan.
He's won four times.
He's a megalomaniac.
And he's a reckless...
self-appointed leader.
But...
there's one more.
Really?
Hachiro Oka, a seven-time bonus winner.
He's somewhere.
He cloaks himself and goes into hiding.
Good...
I hope Kato is doing okay.
What's wrong?
If Kurono was alive,
would he have saved people like Kato?
I'm sure he would have.
We can resurrect Kurono if we score 100.
We don't have a chance.
But, Suzuki...
We can hardly take care of ourselves.
Oh, no!
There's one in Japan?
Is it on our side?
The Boss creature should be 100 points.
One hundred points for one creature?
Yeah, 100 for one.
The monsters on the tower look badass.
Killing one won't get 100 points.
Oka says it's happened before.
Really?
It was before our time.
Before we went to the room.
Everyone died except Oka.
Oka killed the Boss monster.
By himself!
He's a monster himself!
Oh, God.
What's that?
It's way out of our league.
Freeze! Put your hands up!
Wait!
Don't shoot!
Kato!
You in the black suits! Who are you with?
-I'll shoot!
-Wait!
-We're agents.
-State your unit.
Our unit is...
Gantz.
Gantz?
He's in even more trouble!
-Show your ID!
-We don't have any.
But it's true!
-I'll shoot!
-No!
Wait a minute.
Fire!
Run, all of you!
Watch Suzuki!
Come and get me!
No way.
Well?
Hey.
You're shitting me.
It's not dead.
Is it a 100?
I'll do him.
You'll be flatter than paper
when I'm through.
Pretty tough, aren't you?
You cockroach.
Stop playing!
You fuck!
You goddamn motherfucker!
Fucking help!
Boo-hoo, can't you take care of yourself?
I bet you shit your pants, Muroya.
Fuck...
He's dead.
No way!
So, you're their boss?
That old man?
Gotcha!
What the...?
What is this?
What is it?
I've caught you!
This can't be true!
They're both dead!
What's your plan?
I'll do whatever I can.
You'll die!
Think of your brother!
That's why it has to be done.
Otherwise...
we'll all die.
But how?
Hey! Hey! Don't be stupid!
She just dodges it!
She's too quick.
All together!
She was hit.
A hit to the head has no effect!
Cover me.
Ayumu, I promise you.
I'll come home!
I got the Boss!
You almost blew us all up!
Big deal! I went for his arm anyway.
We made it...
We beat the Osaka team.
No...
What the heck?
Oh, God!
Run.
Run!
We lost...
Look at its head.
-It's Oka.
-Oka?
Hachiro Oka!
He got it!
Still bleeding.
Hey, can you hear me?
Kato, look at that!
It's alive.
Shit!
Oka...
So, if you live to the end of the game,
you'll recover?
Well, yes...
If Oka beats him quickly,
it will help.
It's too powerful!
I don't even know how it attacked me.
Oka can do it.
He'll beat it!
He's won seven times.
Hachiro Oka.
You're deluded
if you think you can beat me, sucker!
What you don't know is,
I played Ping-Pong in college!
I also took karate lessons...
by correspondence!
Amazing.
Did he win...?
You want to die?
It's not over. Can't you see?
I find this fascinating.
Very fascinating.
I think I got it.
I've got it. Here I go!
He'll lose...
Come on, boy!
Oka, no!
Eat this!
Only intuitive attacks work on him.
Is it over? Did he die?
Not yet.
-No?
-What do you mean?
Only surprise attacks work. I'll go cloak.
You should finish him off now!
No, it's risky.
Damn it...
It is risky.
I know.
But...
someone's got to do it.
Kato!
Suzuki! Why did you...?
Your brother...
He's waiting for you.
Suzuki! Suzuki!
Reika.
Watch Suzuki.
But it's...
too late.
We can save him.
What about you?
I'll do it.
I'll finish the game.
-Kato!
-Don't!
Where's that other guy?
He was fun to play with.
Stay here. I'll kill you later.
Hey, are you okay?
-What now?
-We can run and leave it to Oka!
And if he loses?
But...
We have to think of a way to win!
It's impossible.
We can't die.
We both have someone waiting for us.
That's why I'm going.
I have to!
I have to! Who else will?
You're right.
We have to.
Reika.
How can we beat that thing?
Oka said it must be a surprise attack.
How do we surprise him?
Maybe we can snipe him.
Good idea.
I'll be a decoy. When he approaches,
shoot him from a distance.
Are you out of your mind?!
We have no choice.
Are you sure we want to snipe him?
Ayumu.
What's wrong?
Listen.
I have to say this before I go.
You...
You mean a lot to me.
Please don't die.
Do not die, okay?
I don't intend to.
You mean it?
You really mean it?
Yes.
I won't give up,
even if the odds are against me.
Promise me.
If you survive,
the four of us can live together.
You, your brother, me, and my boy.
All right? Make a promise.
Come on!
Just say "yes" when you're asked that.
Yes.
It's a promise.
Don't break it!
I'll protect you.
I won't let you die!
Watch me get a bull's-eye on that thing!
I will make it home.
For sure.
What the...?
They're not in position yet...
Wait.
Let me ask you.
Why are we...
killing each other?
Do you feel that you're in God's presence?
God?
God is the absolute power.
You're God...
are you?
This world has many.
I'm merely one of them.
There is no defying that fact.
I hit him!
We'll live together!
I'll end this!
Die!
I got it.
I see.
I can finish him off!
He's just shooting blind.
Kato!
I got the Big Boss.
It's over.
It's really over.
But I...
I was of no help.
Me neither.
Kato did everything.
Where is he?
Oh, no!
I guess he's dead.
No...
He did so much...
Gantz.
Score me.
Live from Osaka.
With no explosions,
the Dotonbori area is very quiet.
EAT BY YOURSELF.
There's no sign of the creatures.
Soldiers are assessing the situation.
We only returned because of Kato...
Kato!
I...
You survived.
Oh, God!
I'm so happy.
You barely made it.
It's time to score your points.
Jugs, six points.
Baldy, two points.
Nishi, 12 points.
It's your turn, Kato.
Kato-cha, LOL, 100 points.
-Shit!
-Amazing!
You cleared it!
Did I...?
Bonus menu.
One, weapon.
Two, resurrection. Three, freedom.
2. RESURRECT A DEAD PLAYER.
3. HAVE YOUR MEMORY WIPED AND QUIT.
Choose three and you're free.
And go back to living
with your brother like before.
I'm happy for you.
Kato.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Have a nice life.
Hey...?
I didn't die...
Oh, that fool...
That hypocrite!
KATO-CHA (LOL) 100 POINTS
You think she was resurrected?
But why, Kato?
What about your brother?
You'll have to join the game again.
You could die.
But I made her a promise.
That's lame.
I can leave?
My brother's waiting at home!
You didn't tell Kato
that he used to fight with us.
Your brother's waiting.
Choose three.
Kei...
If I had, he'd fight to resurrect
everyone who'd ever died in the game.
You're right.
I choose three. Free me.
I never thought he'd be back!
He hasn't changed a bit.
Every time it's the same for him.
He risks his life for others.
Kurono was like that, too.
I'll do the same.
One day...
I'll get Kurono back.
I'm home!
Subtitle translation by
Dean Shimauchi