Call the strippers.
[man 2] Okay.
[man 1] Get him two of those blondies.
[man 2] Don't need you to remind me
about calling the ladies.
[Simple-Chun] Tell your boss to hurry up.
Not being on time,
how the fuck is he a boss?
[man 1] As you know,
our boss is quite busy.
Just wait a bit longer.
Let me ask Pretty-Pan to call him
Pretty-Pan!
Call the boss to see where he's at.
[Pretty-Pan] He's almost here.
Boss, just a bit longer.
Almost here.
I got ladies waiting for me,
I'm leaving if he isn't here soon.
Boss Chun, I got a question for you.
I heard you guys got some
new chicks in from Vietnam.
When do we get to play with them?
When?
Come on, say something!
Don't be so stingy.
Boss is here.
[car door closes]
[Qing] Boss.
[all] Boss.
[spits]
Why the fuck would you ask me
to come to this shit-hole?
What the fuck are you doing?
-What the fuck are you doing?
-[Simple-Chun crying]
[Simple-Chun groaning]
You're quite an unpopular fella,
aren't you?
-Why don't you just retire?
-Retire, my ass!
Just because you said so?
Who the fuck am I, then?
Even if I agree to retire,
my brother wouldn't easily agree to that.
Fuck. [groaning]
[cell phone ringing]
[man] President.
-[groaning]
-Boss.
-[Simple-Chun groaning]
-President is on the phone.
[sighs]
Boss.
[President on phone] What the hell
do you think you're doing?
Did you forget who is in charge?
Nah, it's not like that, boss.
[President] Remember, his father
was like a brother to me.
Let the man go!
Fine, I'll take care of it.
What?
I'm the fuckin' chosen one.
You're just a little bitch to me.
[screaming]
[Simple-Chun] Fuck you! Fuck you!
[groaning]
Boss, are you all right?
All right? I'm dying here.
"All right," my ass!
Can you walk?
[Ren] Boss...
"Boss," why don't you be the boss, then?
Boss,
I don't get it, why worry about it?
Everyone wants a piece of North Town.
-I'm just taking it over for the family.
-Impossible.
What do you mean impossible?
That pig, I can easily
have him taken care of.
So long as I am still alive,
this will never happen!
You know I have sworn to Hada's grave.
That was only a half a year ago.
Have you forgotten already?
Huh?
At this rate, do you know
how many innocents
will be involved because of you?
How many more of our boys
must sacrifice their lives?
[sighs]
Ren,
remember why we joined the family.
After all, what we all want
is a peaceful life.
Now that you don't have any needs,
a wife, a child, a career,
isn't this the peaceful life you wanted?
What more do you want?
A word of advice, control your ambition.
-Lou, let's go.
-Hmm.
Boss, what now?
We are the big dogs,
not somebody's bitches.
Shut the fuck up.
You have a problem with my boss?
No, I wouldn't dare.
[dishes clattering]
[door closes]
[Ren's wife] You're back.
I'm back.
Are you hungry? Want some porridge?
Nah, you go ahead.
How about some chicken soup?
[sighs] Sure, why not?
Mmm.
What's this?
Our child's school agenda.
I thought you were the one
who signed her homework.
I want you to see it.
Her teacher says
she did a great job on her writing.
She's very smart,
though she constantly asks,
why bother studying at all?
What about it?
She's just like me when I was young.
[people chattering]
Hurry, roll it.
Reveal it, Boss, let's do it!
Po, are you sure you're going to do this?
Boss, there's no such thing
as mercy on the table.
Hit it while it's still hot!
All in!
[laughing]
Fine.
All in, with extra.
[all groaning]
Wait, wait, l have something to say.
This is how much I already won today,
and if I win one more round,
boys, each of us is going
to get a blondie tonight, all on me!
[laughing]
Now you're getting cocky, huh?
Roll it.
[grunts]
[all] Deal.
[Big-C] Qing.
Big-C.
Big-Ren.
[laughing]
Po.
What's up, Big-C?
I've got shit luck so far, come,
bring me some fortune.
Heard what happened with North Town.
President wasn't happy about it.
[groans]
He has his ways of doing things.
Don't worry too much about it.
Nah, he is my boss after all,
I can understand.
Huh?
Big?
Bigger the better.
Oh. Oh!
I think it's a big one.
-The biggest one?
-Huh.
Show it! [shouting]
Now that boss has Big-C on his side,
how is it fair for us?
Now who's your daddy?
[Po] Come on, have some mercy.
Qing.
Go get Big-C his share for this month.
Okay.
Bro, come join me later.
[laughing]
Gotcha.
Hurry, now it's my turn.
[line ringing]
[cell phone vibrating]
Hello, who is this?
Hey, brother, it's me.
Long time no see.
Hey, brother, long time no see.
Why called me all of sudden? What's up?
Got time to hang out? I'm at Room 18.
Sure, I'll be right there.
Domination!
[man] Boss, boss.
It's your turn.
Is there a rule that says
I must play it right away?
But I'm dominating this round.
Dominating, my ass.
Last time I checked, I was still the boss.
[laughing]
Boss, let me come with you.
Nah, stay and enjoy your food.
[cell phone beeping]
-Hey.
-[gasps]
My brother.
Long time no see.
What have you been up to? Huh?
Some plans are in motion.
-Hey.
-What's up?
I heard about your failed attempt
to acquire North Town.
Ah.
Let's not talk about it.
It has been a while,
let's go grab a drink together.
[gun cocks]
What the fuck are you doing?
Put that away!
[people screaming]
Are you mad?
Why the fuck would you do that?
At least tell me beforehand.
Hurry, let's get out of here!
[police siren blaring]
I've decided that I wanted to meet
some important people in there.
Today, I'm just here to say "Hi"
and tell you about it.
If that is your wish.
I have nothing much left for you.
Here, take this lucky 7 for good luck.
[police officer] On the ground,
put down your weapon!
On the ground, put down your weapon!
Hey!
Once I have all the turfs in Taipei,
I will come back and find you.
-[grunts]
-Get up.
Hey.
Wait for me.
Get up now.
THREE YEARS LATER...
[people chattering]
[all] ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
Thank you.
[all cheering]
I wish you all success.
[all singing]
[all cheering]
President.
My boss, Yung, couldn't make it today.
However, he specifically asked me
to wish you good fortune on his behalf.
-May you live long.
-Thank you.
Fung, cheers to you.
[Fung] Ren.
Please greet Yung on my behalf.
Your new friend?
[laughing]
-Cheers.
Thank you.
Come visit us sometimes.
[Fung] Of course.
[singing in Mandarin]
President, I'm Po.
Happy birthday to you.
Cheers.
President, may I have the honor
of singing "Gold and Silver" with you?
"Gold and Silver"?
Life is treating you too well, huh?
Girl, pick a family song for us.
What is the song of the family?
Good question.
The "Song of Sorrow."
That's it, the "Song of Sorrow."
Come, sing.
-[announcer] Music!
-Dumbass.
That was too obvious.
-[music playing]
-You're such a brown-noser.
I was doing it for Boss-Ren.
Well, I fucked up.
President is singing it now.
Good job.
Wow, Big-Chao, nice M6.
Isn't she pretty?
Nice, nice.
Can't smoke in there.
Gotcha.
Don't dent the car.
Or I'll break your legs! You got it?
Yeah, yeah, I got it.
-Big-Chao.
-Now what?
What about tips?
Get outta here, go!
-[car door closes]
-Dumbass.
[engine revving]
Don't dent the car.
Or I'll break your legs!
[laughing]
What the fuck is wrong with him?
Hey.
Who are those two?
They are from Jian Corp.
The "Pharma" business people,
they're rich as fuck.
All of them drive lambos.
For real? Damn.
Hey.
Tips.
Wow, thanks, Big-Chao.
There you go, my man.
Freeze!
I'm just here for my car.
Get out of here.
[man chattering on TV]
-Boss.
-Hmm?
Those two who called you before,
they're here.
[music playing on tablet]
So, what is it? Hurry up.
I don't have time to waste on you two.
Boss Chun!
My boss tried to meet with you
so many times.
Why didn't you ever reply?
[music stops]
What the fuck are you talking about?
Huh?
You guys are doing
the "Pharmacy" business.
That is a business for worthless junkies.
-[laughing]
-I am the fuckin' chosen one.
Do I look like a worthless junkie to you?
[screaming]
-Freeze! Hands up.
-What the hell?
-I said freeze.
-Fuck off, bitch!
My hand!
[groaning]
[Syko] Fuck, I'm not your bitch.
[in English] I have to call you back.
What the fuck did you bring me here for?
Those were your final words?
Still refuse to cooperate, I see.
Fuck you, I don't want your dirty money.
Let me tell you something.
If you kill me,
don't even think
about leaving this building.
Oh, well.
Your parents might have given you
the wrong name.
However, the nickname is right on.
Simple-Chun.
What about you?
[Syko laughing]
[Simple-Chun] My boys won't betray me.
-[Syko laughing]
-You motherfuckin' junkies.
You motherfuckin' junkies.
[phone ringing]
You will all pay!
Hey.
My brother, it is me.
I am back.
The turf you failed
to acquire three years ago?
I have taken it over for you.
[people chattering]
Ready?
Let's do it.
Six and a pair.
[screaming]
What the fuck are you doing? Let me go!
Let go!
[screaming]
-[glass shattering]
-[horn honking]
[horn honking]
That's it.
That's it for today?
Hey, dipshit, you should spend
more time with your fiancée.
You're lucky,
all I have left is my grandmother.
So what? Isn't that great?
This headache is killing me!
Hey, that prescription
you take for your PMS,
does it even work?
It definitely works for my PMS.
As for your hangover,
I doubt it.
Mmm.
Hey, dipshit!
Stop hounding the lady.
Po, come help us out.
Oh.
I'll take one to see what will happen.
It doesn't seem to work.
-It's not a fetish.
-Not a fetish?
I'm looking for the tenderness sensation.
Like your mom?
[Po] That woman last night
wore lacy stuff.
So I was between her legs, right?
As I looked up, those two big ones
were pressing my face down.
Do you have any idea how big they were?
Yeah, right.
[man] He likes to go for big boobs
when he is drunk.
[Po] Nah, I'm not shitting you.
However, I think those are fake.
Because for a skinny chick
to have a pair that size naturally,
-no fuckin' way.
-Oh.
I wasn't even drunk!
All right,
that's enough bullshit for the day.
-Drink up.
-Cheers.
I'm done for now.
Since you're a pussy, drink soup.
[laughing]
That's cool. I'll be the pussy, then.
[newscaster on TV]
The new electronic buses
now come with the Hello Kitty design
and have already taken
the local residents by storm.
Breaking news.
Last night in Taipei Zhongshan district,
a man died falling off a building.
The deceased person
was a known gang leader in the area.
The police investigation found that
the deceased was tortured before he died
and had his fingers cut off.
The police believe this could be a murder.
A witness saw
men in black clothing
leaving the building.
After investigating, police learned that
the famous Jian Corp might be involved.
After having a short meeting
with the Jian Corp president,
Jian Corp stated that
they are not related
to the deceased in any way.
Police currently have
a couple of suspects under investigation,
especially those who had finance exchange
history with the deceased.
Meanwhile, the investigation continues
-as more questions remain unanswered.
-[gong sounding]
Coming up next is our weather report.
[gong continues sounding]
[man] Please prepare the next one.
Mr. Gui, step forward.
Commence with three bows to the deceased.
First bow.
Second bow.
Third bow.
Appreciation to the participants.
Sorry for your loss.
Thank you, Uncle Gui.
I'm so sorry.
[man] Once again, appreciation
for Gui's participation.
Coming up next, Jian Corp.
Jian Corp.
Step forward.
First bow.
Second bow.
Third bow.
Madam, this is Jian.
He is a great friend of Boss Chun.
I'm sorry for your loss.
Madam, please accept this.
Accept it, accept it.
Please do let me know
if there's anything I can do to help.
-Please.
-[whispering] Traitorous asshole.
-Thank you.
-[man] Once again,
appreciation
for Jian Corp's participation.
Please, have a seat.
-Take the President home.
-Yes, Boss.
Brother.
-Brother, long time no see.
-Brother.
Did I look good up there?
I see you're doing well for yourself
and your boys.
Remember?
Three years ago,
you were the only one there for me.
Now that everything is going so well,
I also want you to do well.
Ren.
When I said I want you to do well,
I wasn't kidding.
This 40-foot cargo container
is worth over 800 million,
and it already has customs clearance.
This is just one of many.
Take a look.
These are all mine!
Ren.
You've always been a brother to me,
let me be frank with you.
Based on what you have right now,
seven clubs, five pubs,
four massage parlors...
Correct?
And this, this is what I have now.
Since I am able to operate
at such a scale,
trust me when I say,
let us use your turf to move the goods.
You and your boys will no longer
have any trouble making easy money.
Well?
You must be kidding me.
When it comes to fights,
I never turn down any of them.
But international business like this?
This isn't my cup of tea.
Do you look down upon my business,
or do you look down upon me?
Uh...
Brother,
there's never "too much wealth."
However, what really matters
is how the money is made.
This is beyond my capacity.
Brother, don't think too much of it.
That's fine.
I know that you respect the old man.
He has his moral code.
But he'll come around.
We'll talk more later.
I'm hungry now.
Braised pork over rice.
Let's get some braised pork over rice
from that same old place.
Do you still go there?
Remember that girl who used to work there?
[laughing]
[people chattering]
[footsteps approaching]
[woman] Ren.
Madam.
Don't stay for too long,
remember your heart condition.
Get up.
Yes, your highness.
[chuckles]
The wife is the real boss around here.
Remember, her words are law.
Yes, sir.
Take care.
-So many people.
-Yeah,
the more, the merrier.
Where is Chao?
Isn't he coming?
Chao?
He's probably busy today.
He's a grown-ass man,
no need to worry about him.
He's coming later.
Tell him to be more mature like you.
He's always like a kid.
Tell Chao.
It's his grandfather's anniversary
in two days.
Remind him to take me there.
I can't even find him.
Okay, I'll remind him.
Come, let's get something to eat.
Sure.
Watch your step.
Po.
Let's go, kiddo.
-Remember to say hi to everyone.
-Sure.
Where is Chao now?
Why would I know?
He called me this morning
to pick up his grandmother.
Then he disappeared himself.
Let me call him.
Okay, go ahead.
Panda.
[violin music playing on record player]
Whoo!
Come on!
Cut the shit.
[door bell buzzing]
[men chattering]
Muy bien. Muy bien.
[in English] I'm calling you because, uh,
my boss wanted me to tell you
that he's very happy,
and we're looking forward
to our next transaction.
Sí, sí.
Ooh! [laughing]
Boss, the man is here.
Sir.
I'm Chao from North Fort,
one of Ren's boys.
[in Mandarin] What do you want?
Say it.
I'm here for the goods.
-Let me ask you a question.
-Hmm?
Do you think supplying drugs
is a dirty business?
Dirty?
Why? It's just business.
However, Ren doesn't think so.
He thinks drugs are beneath him.
He thinks he has no need for money.
Therefore, he doesn't know you are here.
He forbade you from dealing with drugs,
didn't you know that?
Chao, isn't it?
Hmm.
Hey!
-What is this about?
-[grunting]
[violin continues playing
on record player]
-[thudding]
-[grunting]
[Syko laughing]
Po!
Chao's grandmother
is asking who is getting married.
-Grandma, it's Pretty-Pan.
-Grandma, it's me!
-Pretty-Pan is getting married.
-[laughing]
-You're all invited.
-Please join us that day.
This is a good day.
Toast to it, cheers!
Congratulations!
♪ As we hold our hands,
our hearts connect instantly ♪
♪ As I look at her,
that cutie looks right back ♪
♪ As we parted ways,
I wondered who that beauty was ♪
Hey! There aren't any prawns in the pond!
Here's more.
[Jian continues singing]
Still aren't any!
Wait here, keep the engine running.
Move!
♪ And with the same heaven above us,
we share the blessing of this world ♪
[vocalizing]
[laughing] Ren,
remember this song?
Come, sing with me.
[vocalizing]
♪ We live in this world,
there is love and there is hate ♪
♪ As a family,
why must we harm each other? ♪
♪ Of all the unnecessary death ♪
♪ who is the one responsible for it? ♪
♪ Of those who remain,
whose rage is still burning? ♪
♪ Hey-ho, Hey-ho
Such is the wrath under heaven ♪
[exclaiming]
[Syko laughing]
My brother.
Now that I am here,
isn't it the time for you
to return my boy to me?
Before I do that,
I must explain what happened.
You
refuse to do business with me.
However, your boy, Chao...
Chao, isn't it?
He came to deal with me behind your back.
Isn't that a shame?
Therefore, I have punished him for you.
[snaps fingers]
Fuck you, who do you think you are?
-Qing.
-[chuckles]
[voice breaking] Boss, I am sorry.
Panda, take care of him.
-Chao.
-Are you all right?
Brother.
Fine,
consider this as my fault.
You had to do my job for me.
Sorry about that.
[chuckles] We've been brothers
for so many years,
there's no need to apologize.
To be frank,
though you as the boss
have no need for money,
your boys are eager anyway.
So I already have
a plan for you and your boys.
Imagine if I let you have
the North Town now.
And have all your boys run the place
while distributing the products.
We're going to be rich as fuck.
Brother,
so you're saying if I refuse to cooperate,
then I'll end up like Simple-Chun.
You will have me
"taken care of" as well, right?
Don't say that.
There's no need to turn a brother of yours
into your worst enemy.
Do you remember?
The lucky 7 you gave me?
I believe
now you will need that luck more than me.
[cell phone vibrating]
[Biao] Boss.
Phone call for you.
Oh.
[sighs]
Hey, what's up?
Oh!
What?
One second.
Sit for a bit. I'll be back.
Hey.
Jian.
When you were planning
for everything three years ago,
did you anticipate the current situation?
[mouthing]
Let's go.
[Biao] Hey.
Where do you think you're going?
So what now?
Hey, we're not done yet.
Done? You're fuckin' done!
-Ooh. [laughs]
-[Qing] Bring it on, if you dare.
[woman screaming]
Hang in there!
Where are you now?
Weren't you almost here?
[grunting]
[tires screeching]
Hurry the fuck up!
What's going on now?
Boss, just go.
Qing.
Boss, get out!
Get out of here!
Qing.
Let go of me.
Go.
Go now.
Chao.
[gun firing]
Chao!
Get out of here, Boss!
Chao.
Chao!
How the fuck?
Why are we still here? Let's fuck them up!
I'm going to kill them all.
Qing.
Get everything ready.
Move! Get ready!
[all chattering]
Boss.
One second.
I am being reasonable.
But are they being reasonable?
Boss.
I remember everything you taught me,
and I understand all of it.
But you know me, Boss.
My boy took a bullet for me,
and now he is dead.
If it wasn't for him, I wouldn't be here,
and we wouldn't have
this conversation right now.
Can you understand, boss?
So we're just going to
let them get away with this?
Boss.
Is it President again?
But the one who died is...
[panting]
Take care of it.
Understood.
So we really have to wait here all night?
Should just leave it
to the boys to handle it.
Chao was our brother,
we will avenge him ourselves.
Chao.
This is all for you.
This is a little present from us.
Today is the anniversary of your passing.
However, your grandson, Chao, isn't here.
[sighs] Chao is such a nice kid.
But he's always out there somewhere,
you can never find him.
[inaudible]
[engine revving]
[dance music playing on car radio]
[music stops]
-Here he comes.
-Ah.
[clears throat]
Big-Syko.
[dance music playing on speakers]
[woman moaning]
[thunder rumbling]
[grunting]
[screaming] This is fun.
[grunts]
[laughing] Wow!
So much fun!
[grunting]
Hey, that's enough.
-[screaming]
-That's enough.
Let's go now.
Enough. Get up.
-Let's go.
-That's enough.
Syko!
Get out of here.
-This is really fun.
-[man] Crazy bitch!
Come on, Syko, let's go home.
[laughing]
Hey, Boss is here.
[all] Boss.
What the fuck is going on?
So now you're the fuckin' boss?
Who told you to start
the conflict with them?
Boss, didn't you tell me
to take care of it?
I told you to take care of Chao's funeral!
Fuckin' great, now President wants me
to take care of you.
What the fuck am I supposed to do?
It's President again.
Fuck it, I'm hungry now, let's eat first.
Braised pork over rice, please.
[chuckles]
May I have one more...
-One for me as well.
-[Ren] Are you guys okay?
Make it two.
Nothing, it's fine.
Cheers.
Damn.
[machines whirring]
Big-Biao. Big-Biao.
[man] Big-Biao.
-[cell phone vibrating]
-Hey.
Hey, it's me.
[Jian on phone] Wire three million
to Syko-boy's family.
Yes, sir.
[Jian] Tell them not to say a word.
Understood.
Boss.
Let's do this.
North Fort is a piece of shit.
Smash all of it.
Wreck this place!
It's definitely Jian Corp.
Cut the shit, it's war time!
[man] Ready?
-[all] Ready.
-Let's go.
[all shouting]
[people chattering]
[people screaming]
Fuck off.
Fuck 'em up.
Where is your boss now?
[phone beeps]
Everyone's here?
Tie up your red bands.
Make sure you don't hit one of our own.
[all] Yes, sir.
Let's do this.
[cell phone vibrating]
[inaudible]
[man answering phone]
[man chattering on phone]
Boss, I have someone to deal with.
Be smart about it.
Go.
[all yelling]
[police officer] Fang.
Pan.
Hey. Pan, is that you?
What the fuck are you looking at?
Fuck you, piece of shit.
-Come at me.
-Hey! Hey!
Enough.
[police officer] Meh, sir.
These trouble makers.
Those gangs.
Fuck you, shut the fuck up.
Enough, sit down.
Are you done?
How old are you?
Because I'm already sick
and tired of this shit.
Sir.
It's definitely them.
Don't tell me how to do my job.
You'll see.
Your president never taught you
how to behave?
Do you solve
all your problems with violence?
[thudding]
-[Panda groaning]
-[man] So you think you're untouchable?
What now?
[Panda crying]
[laughing] Everywhere.
[coughing]
[Panda panting]
Know this.
You're already standing in your own grave.
If you are willing
to take out your own boss,
then you're free to go.
[laughing]
Are you out of your mind? Or was it me?
Get me down, I fuckin' dare you.
I'm going to fuck you up.
Motherfucker.
Fuck.
Get me down.
[laughing]
♪ Burn, baby, burn ♪
♪ Burning ♪
Get me down.
[coughing]
Get me down. [screaming]
[woman laughing]
♪ Burning! ♪
-[siren blaring]
-[man] Fuck you, come back here.
Hurry up!
[man chattering on police radio]
[sighs]
There was a big mess out there last night.
Was it necessary?
Why would you bring this upon yourself?
What for?
I'm here today to deliver you a warning.
The higher up is now
paying attention to the situation.
If you keep this up,
I will have to do my job.
Right? Let me handle this.
I'll leave it to you, then.
It's about time.
[Ren] See you.
What is going on now?
What is this about?
Say something!
[sighs]
Boss.
I understand.
You have your reasons to stay silent.
Now that two of our boys died.
Your boys,
my brothers,
if I don't do something right now,
how am I supposed to avenge them?
Qing.
Boss!
I'll handle it well.
Handle what?
You the boss now?
Here, take my position
and let me take orders from you.
Somebody killed my boys.
Is it because I failed as a boss,
or are you getting too ambitious?
Ren, I don't understand.
I thought Jian and you were like brothers.
How did it all come to this?
Brothers, so what?
People change.
Like everything else.
Back then, it was about loyalty.
Now, it's about profit.
I sincerely hope everyone will be okay.
Especially you.
Mr. Jian, now that both sides
are in conflict,
the situation has not improved.
Instead, it has gotten worse.
Her highness is not happy about it.
The conflict between
North Fort and North Town,
that was all part of my plan.
This is the perfect time
for me to take control of them,
one by one.
If you're unable to contain the situation,
I will have to step in to do my job.
Oh, great Lord Guan, the God of War,
I, Ren of the North Fort,
humbly ask for your favor.
There is a wicked organization, Jian Corp.
I believe it has to be destroyed
in order to bring peace back
to the region.
Therefore, I brought my followers to you.
May you choose
the right person for the upcoming task.
May the chosen one
return safely to the family.
[people chattering]
Excuse me.
Where have you been?
My son had a fever,
took him to the doctor.
Meh, you're not that important anyway.
-It's me.
-Boss.
Just let me do this.
Rules are rules.
Chu.
Raise the incense.
[sighs]
Oh, great Lord Guan,
the revered God of War,
I, Po of the North Fort,
thank you for this opportunity
to serve the people of North Fort.
May you watch over me
as I carry out the mission,
and please bring me back safely.
[Po] Easy, take it easy.
Just keep calm.
What are you doing?
Calling Big-Qing for backup.
Do you know how long
I have been waiting for this?
[gun cocking]
I'm going.
Hey.
What?
Take care of yourself.
Tell you what, no matter what,
remember, wait for me.
I got this!
[rattling]
What is going on?
What happened?
[Jian] Hey!
Looking for me?
Make an appointment next time.
[man] Hey, over here!
You're back.
Why so sudden this time?
Have you packed everything?
Hey!
[breathes deeply]
-I'm leaving.
-Hey!
How long is it going to be this time?
I don't know.
Don't know.
You don't know?
Is it nice over there?
Not bad.
Try not to worry too much.
So I might be back before I know it?
[boat horn tooting]
It's about time, the boat is here.
[Qing] Captain, all good?
Yeah.
Big-Qing, how long before I can come back?
About 20 years.
[exclaiming]
Big-Qing, about my fiancée and my son...
I know.
Make sure you don't call here.
Take good care of yourself.
[cell phone vibrating]
Hey.
Where the hell are you?
[groans]
[knocking on door]
Fuck you.
What the fuck now, what the fuck now.
Pretty-Pan.
Do you know what happened to him?
What happened?
What about him?
-Tell me!
-You don't know?
You don't know?
Fuckin' say it one more time!
Why the fuck are you here?
I chickened out.
Chickened out?
Why didn't you just call me?
Don't you have my number?
I couldn't do it!
Why didn't you call me?
Don't you have my number?
[sobbing] I didn't know this would happen.
I didn't know this would happen.
I didn't want to.
There were five of us!
Huh?
Now two of our brothers are already dead!
How could I know this would happen?
He was the youngest,
and now he is gone too.
Is this how you treat your brothers?
Why would he do it for me?
I told him to wait for me in the car.
If you did shoot that motherfucker,
this wouldn't have happened,
was it really that difficult?
Do you really think I'm that brave?
It's all because of you.
Because you were always there
to back me up.
I thought I was always fearless
when you were around.
How would I know what would happen
when you aren't there?
I really had no idea.
[sniffling]
Stop it.
-Fuck, fuck.
-Please stop it.
-I'm begging you, please stop.
What the fuck is wrong with me?
What am I supposed to do?
Please stop this,
it pains me as well.
When I was chosen,
I really had no idea what to do.
I waited until now to call you
because I really had no idea what to do.
Please tell me what I am supposed to do.
[sobbing]
Please don't do this, I beg you.
[both crying]
What have I done?
You tell me, then!
What am I supposed to do?
Tell me, then!
I really don't know.
Please, I don't know anymore.
-Boss.
-Mm.
Pretty-Pan.
Have you taken good care of him?
I have.
I've asked brothers from the other side
to help him settle in.
A man can't help but go with the tide.
[chuckles]
I'll handle this myself.
Lou.
-Give them a call.
-Yes, sir.
-Set up a meeting for me.
-Mmm.
[car approaching]
-[President] Brother.
-[Yung laughing]
Thanks for coming.
You wanted to see me.
I'd crawl my way here if I had to.
-[laughing]
-Thank you, thank you.
[car approaching]
Boss.
Secretary is here.
-Mr. Secretary.
This is brother Yung.
-Welcome.
-President Gui.
Thanks for coming.
It's my pleasure.
-Thank you, once again.
-It's a pleasure.
Senator, thank you for coming.
[chattering]
President.
[President] Thank you,
thank you all for coming.
I am honored to be among you.
For the good of this community,
I humbly ask for advice from all of you.
Thus, we can settle our differences.
[clapping]
Mr. Liu.
Perhaps you have some suggestions?
President, you
are like a great father
trying to be the peacemaker for Ren and I.
I am so touched.
Really touched.
My heart...
President,
you're not young anymore.
Times have changed.
Why don't you just take a back seat, hmm?
Young man, mind your manners.
President.
Your dog is trying
to take a bite out of me.
You can't just hold on
to his leash forever.
Besides,
he is already beyond your control.
[all shouting]
[gun clicks]
Go on, keep going.
Why don't you guys keep going?
I could use a boost to my career.
[people chattering]
President, Yung, I'll take my leave.
My apologies.
Congressman, this way.
[coughs]
Son of a bitch.
I've never seen anyone
more disrespectful than that little shit.
Boss, let me drive you home.
Let Qing do it,
I want to have a few words with him.
[coughing]
Qing.
Do you know what it means to be Gatao?
In the early days of Taiwan,
there were many Gataos,
and they were not gangsters.
They were a bunch of passionate young men
with a sense of justice.
They wanted to protect
the interests of local people,
and they fought the outsiders.
As time went by,
they gained many followers
and became forces to be reckoned with.
That's how they won the hearts of people
and became the local leaders.
That is the real Gatao.
Now that North Fort
is such a prosperous place,
people are able to live their lives
in peace because of us.
You can't always solve problems
with violence.
Instead, you have to use your virtues.
Understand?
Therefore,
you shouldn't continue
to provoke Ren, your boss.
Instead, you should support him.
Bring stability to our Gatao.
President,
I hear everything you're telling me,
and I understand all of it.
However, it is others
who brought this onto us.
I know!
[panting]
No matter how much anger
you have right now,
I want you to swallow all of it.
I... [panting]
President?
The medicine...
Where is your medicine?
[panting]
[gasping]
[President collapses]
[clattering]
[Qing whimpering]
[Lou] President is talking to Qing.
[woman] Gui! Gui!
Gui!
Ambulance, call the ambulance!
[ambulance siren blaring]
The fuck are you doing over there?
What's going on? Say something.
Qing.
Fuck.
That was my boss!
My boss!
Fuck!
[thunder rumbling]
Boss, let me drive you back.
Chu, where is the car?
Boss, it's that way.
[Pretty-Pan] Boss, Qing.
Have you ever regretted taking this path?
After I came here,
I asked this question myself constantly.
I just wanted to be with you guys.
Like a family.
These days, I can't do anything,
but get drunk.
[inaudible]
I have no future.
I miss you guys.
I miss Panda, I miss Chao.
-It's Pretty-Pan.
-Grandma, it's me.
Pretty-Pan is getting married.
-I can fire three times and...
-Hit five targets!
So you were there?
Hey, dipshit, you should spend
more time with your fiancée.
[Pretty-Pan] Honey, remember the day
I promised you and our son a family.
Sorry, I failed to keep my promise.
Please forgive me.
Boss Ren, where are you going today?
Home.
[Pretty-Pan] I really want to go back.
Boss, Big-Qing, thank you.
I will never forget you.
However, 20 years is too long for me.
My heart couldn't take it.
It's too empty without all of you.
Honey, promise me, take care of our son.
Don't let him grow up like me.
Tell him his father loves him very much.
Boss, Big-Qing, I'm going home.
Please take care of my family.
And take care of yourself.
Home.
I am coming home.
[screaming]
[Qing] Pan, you're home.
I told him to leave.
He wouldn't
because he said
he had brothers like you.
You were his family.
How come they're the ones who died?
Why?
How come it wasn't you?
Qing.
The Big-Qing.
You promised me,
you promised you would bring him back.
You promised me.
This isn't what you promised,
not like this.
Why?
Leave! Please, get out! [crying]
[boy crying]
[cell phone ringing]
Brother, it's me, Ren.
This is the last time
I'm calling you as a brother.
This phone call is just a heads-up.
Now it's just between you and me.
You and me. Understood?
Chu, Chu!
Yes, Boss.
-Tell Qing to come back.
-[Chu] Yes, Boss.
[door closes]
[door opens]
Sweetheart.
Let me answer the question
you had for your teacher.
The reason why you have to study hard
is so that you can have
a proper career when you grow up.
So you don't have to be like me,
constantly living on the edge.
Honey,
I'll be back in a bit.
[Ren's wife sniffles]
[door opens and closes]
[sobbing]
Big-Qing is back.
What the fuck is going on?
Boss only told me to call you back.
What's going on?
I don't know.
-[wind howling]
-[dog barking]
[gun firing on mobile game]
Where is your boss?
Ren, come.
Join me.
Come, help yourself.
This braised pork over rice
is from our favorite joint
when we were young.
The owner, she had a daughter, remember?
During that time,
I had nothing.
Tried so hard to impress her.
Now, I have everything,
and she's already married.
Such is life.
You're right, people do change.
Even this braised pork over rice
doesn't taste the same anymore.
The whole world is changing.
If you don't change,
what makes you different from a caveman?
Jian, I still have
the same question for you.
When you were planning
for everything three years ago,
did you anticipate the current situation?
Ren, do you know
who I envy the most?
It is you.
Without spending a single dime,
you've got a whole gang of brothers
backing you up.
As for me,
look at me,
the amount of money I spent,
yet, I have no one I can trust.
This situation,
it wasn't that I didn't think it through.
It's just that I didn't expect
it would end like this.
Then we have nothing left to say.
Hey.
Why are you here?
[man] Boss.
Ren, don't take this the wrong way.
Let me ask you again, why are you here?
-Huh?
-Boss!
It's about time, they're taking over.
[breathes deeply]
Ren.
This world is not
what we can decide anymore.
[gun cocks]
It seems you never get the point.
It's not perfect, but acceptable.
I warned you.
In the end, you still let everything
get out of control.
Out of control?
Everything is according to my plan.
Both North Fort
and North Town are now gone.
Jian Corp has already taken
the majority of Taipei.
The northern Taiwan underground
is now under my command.
Isn't this what you asked me to do?
Your command?
You're still missing the point.
What we wanted was stability.
All you do is cause trouble.
Tell me,
how am I supposed to keep my job?
Her highness has made her decision.
Our cooperation ends here.
Hey.
Let me tell you something.
Nobody tells me what to do.
Nobody dares to tell me what to do.
Hmm.
[gun cocking]
So?
You're going to kill me now?
I learned all of this from you guys.
[guns firing]
Ren, it's me.
Boss, I'm here.
All this fun, and you didn't invite me?
Watch out! Boss.
Use this one.
Boss, Qing is here.
-[gun firing]
-[grunts]
Po! Po!
[grunting]
Just die!
Boss.
Qing, are you all right?
I'm good.
[police sirens blaring in distance]
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
Po, you all right?
Clumsy as always.
You aren't drunk again, are you?
I got shot by the big one.
[exclaims]
Po, you all right?
Should be fine.
[thunder rumbling]
[man chattering]
[man] Next.
[chattering]
-Boss.
-Hmm.
Doing all right in there?
Not bad.
Got many friends looking after me,
they send you their regards.
How is Po?
Where is he?
[Qing chuckles]
He got into a fight with someone.
Fight? Again?
If he doesn't shape up,
he won't be calling us "brothers" again.
I'll tell him.
Boss, what about him?
Don't know.
I haven't heard of him since then.
No worries.
Boss.
I'm sorry for causing you all the trouble.
Dumbass, don't be silly.
Make the best use of your time in there.
You will be back before you know it,
you hear?
Yes, thank you, Boss.
Send me a letter if you need anything.
[both chattering]
Boss.
-Ask Chu if he also needs anything.
-No problem.
[pop music playing on speakers]
Here.
Pull now.
Hold right there.
That's him!
-[woman screaming]
-[crashing]
[men shouting]
Fuck you!
[groaning]
[groans]
Hey, thanks, a little present from me.
Nah, don't worry about it.
We're from the same school.
You're such a badass.
What are you going to do after graduation?
I am from North Fort. My boss is Big-Gui.
I am going to take over
the underground for him.
What about you?
Wanna join me?
I'll probably
continue my studies.
I am Ren, what's your name?
I'm Jian.
[gun firing]
[wind howling]
[Jian] What is the song of the family?
The "Song of Sorrow."
This is it, the "Song of Sorrow".
♪ I was born with the wrong sign ♪
♪ While others are fortunate,
I had to live underground ♪
♪ As if the birds outside
are crying for me ♪
♪ I had no choice
but to go with the tide ♪
♪ Though having fun on the surface
I feel hollow inside ♪
♪ Only alcohol can sustain me these days ♪
♪ Unable to face my past ♪
♪ Yet don't have the courage
to take a different path ♪
[all cheering]