Three more to go in our
final qualifier tonight,
and it's hidden taking control.
Close behind is
Slegger and Williams,
double wide and three and four,
now all bunched up
heading to the
front straight away.
Side by side, rim to rim,
takes a high line,
Bill needs to go slow.
Slides into one and two.
There's the white,
one more time,
wants the future spot,
so does Snider.
Still, holding onto
the lead is Hinton.
Here we go, here we go,
back into the straight away.
It's game on, and the
turns are leading.
Now four, into the finish line.
It's gonna be Hinton and Snider
in tonight's feature,
coming up next.
GEARHEADS
Subrip: Pix
And here we go, it's race time.
Powering in to an early
lead in tonight's feature
is Walter,
who got a another full house
here inside of our town.
Thanks again for filling
up those bleachers
every Friday night.
Here comes Bobby Dunlap
Senior on the high line,
into turn four, he
overtakes Walter,
opening up some distance.
Nobody hangs onto
a lead like Dunlap.
He's in his rocking chair now.
Still in second,
it's Walter, double
wide out of turn four.
We have Phillips and Baker.
It's Bobby Dunlap Senior,
made them all choke on
that red dust once again.
He has his mechanic Lucas here.
Been almost unbeatable since
18 and a half years ago.
Seems nobody can build a car
like that, their car good.
Running high now
down to the low line,
old Bobby D's been turning
left and doing all right,
so if he thinks there's
a groove way down there,
maybe he's right.
Two to go.
What's going
on with the 55?
He's spinning loose.
Real loose.
Does the steering
wheel even work?
He out of control.
Hit the brakes, Bobby.
Get the fire trucks over there.
Bobby!
Bobby.
Bobby Junior.
I know you're down there.
Deputy Clarke.
Fishin'
What do you say
we go for a ride?
Look, Bobby.
I told you before,
if you missed another day
the school is gonna
come down on you.
I ain't goin'
to summer school.
Well, I understand.
But maybe a different learning
environment is what you need.
It's called work study.
Luke?
There's no way man.
There ain't no way.
Bobby, Bobby.
He's the only one who
even returned my call.
It's eight bucks an hour.
Don't tell those
global warmies.
This baby burns a
full gallon of gas
just turning over.
Can I help you, sir?
Sir?
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Is there any specials today?
Hey.
I was steaks today,
and everybody picked
up their to goes.
What do you call this?
I call it free.
Here.
Put a bunch of mustard on it.
Won't even taste
the burned parts.
The burned parts?
Look at that.
Dude.
That chick is
hillbilly white trash.
I'm gonna make her mine.
Ho ho.
Check this out.
Well if the whole trailer park
didn't come down here today.
So say hello?
Let's tune him up.
Another smart-ass t-shirt.
Probably burns the flag too.
Hey pal.
Sorry about the whole eye thing.
You know, I heard you
were talking all kinds
of mess about me, so
I had to represent.
So what?
You all like, what?
Straight up gangsters
or something?
You know what?
That's it.
Hey, hey hey.
Calm down, calm down.
Listen, man.
I came down here to
apologize to you.
I just found out
that you didn't even do it.
I made the extra effort
to come and find you.
I swear.
What do ya say?
See, was that so hard, man?
Now listen, pal.
You see that girl over there.
Do you know her?
Naw, I've never
seen her before.
She's white trash,
just like you.
Shut up, Dale.
I'm trying to talk
to my friend here.
So what's her deal?
She got a name?
Dude, you really
wanna know her name?
Go read her name tag.
You hear this guy?
Listen up, buddy boy.
That little shiner
is nothing compared
to what's coming.
I will own your ass.
Nice seeing ya, fellas.
It's just dancing,
but with less clothes.
Bobby, is that you?
No, I'm not gonna tell you
this again, Jamie Monroe.
What you do with your
body is your business,
and I will never
judge you for it,
but there is no way I
am ever gonna do that.
Hold on one second.
Come on, girl.
Don't be shy.
Later.
There's a
whole lot of money down here.
More than you'll make
selling chickens.
So when did you
say I can start?
I hear they had to wake
you up off the bar last week.
Must've been over served.
I got a friend
coming in to work.
I told you I could get somebody.
You ain't drinkin' no more?
Ain't drinkin' any less.
School sent me over.
Told me to give you that.
All right.
I need these parts.
Tools are here,
parts go in there.
Okay, but how
do I know what...
All right then.
Darling, you ready?
Honey, don't do that.
You'll ruin your makeup.
Come on.
It'll be fine.
You're lookin' real hot.
They'll love you.
I don't know.
I don't know if I
can do this, Jamie.
Of course you can.
Just smile and make
'em feel special.
I gotta go work the floor
while they still love me.
So hot.
You're gonna make a ton of
cash of of them mill boys.
Here you go, boys.
Well, thank you, sweetheart.
You're welcome.
So why ain't you up there?
Jeez.
Mind your manners, boy.
Apologize to the lady now.
That, that's all right.
Someone's gotta keep
bringing the beers.
Welcome
ladies and gentleman,
and thank you for making
it down to the speedway.
The cars are warm and
the drivers are ready.
It's now time to get
onto our time trials.
The last group is
coming off the track,
and that's it for our hot laps.
We have many generations
with us tonight,
in the true tradition
of dirt track racing.
Come on, Travis.
We should leave her alone.
She doesn't know what
she's missing out on.
She should be serving me,
not greasy burgers
and burnt toast.
So that Dunlap,
he's been working with that
whack job up at the junk yard.
Is that right?
So he didn't say a word?
Barely two.
Crazy drunk if you ask me.
Bobby Junior, why
won't you talk to me?
What do you want me to say?
I gotta get to work.
See ya.
What are you doing
creeping around here?
I say you here,
I figured I'd come say hey.
Yeah?
Yeah, just got a
new lift kit in my truck,
and I thought maybe
you and I could
go for a drive sometime.
That is if you're single.
I'll think about it.
You think about it.
And here
we go, it's race time.
Powering into an early lead
in tonight's feature is Walter.
We've got another full
house here in Solder town.
Thanks again for filling
up those bleachers
every Friday night.
Here comes Bobby Dunlap
Senior on the high line,
into turn four, he
overtakes Walter,
opening up some distance.
Nobody hangs onto
a lead like Dunlap.
He and his mechanic Lucas here,
he's been almost unbeatable
since 18 years ago.
Seems nobody can
build a car like that.
Riding high, and now
bound to the low line,
old Bobby D's been turning
left and doing all right,
so if he thinks there's
a groove way down there,
well, maybe he's right.
Checkered flag!
Really racking up
them points now.
He's definitely in contention
for the Martin Cup once again.
Okay, I'll see
you tomorrow night.
Thanks, Higgy.
Hey.
You're doing a good job.
I need 16 15 inch tires
with the rim separate.
Okay.
Do you got an impact
wrench or something?
It's out of sorts.
You've got to be joking.
All right.
Hey there, Daisy Duke.
I got a big race tomorrow night.
Yeah?
Yeah, I think you
need to be there.
Is that right?
That's right.
Caution
lights are down.
Here we go, only three more
for the checkered flag.
Tilman powers into the hotline.
The number 27 won't let...
Coming out of turn four, on
the front, straight away.
There's the light.
One more time.
Tilman on back straight away,
now in the final turn.
Checkered flag!
He's gonna beat Travis
Tilman in victory lane
for the fifth time this summer.
Really racking up
them points now.
He's definitely in contention
for the Martin cup once again.
What's up?
Well, I'm gonna need you
to move them cars up there,
to down there.
Yeah, but...
You'll figure it out.
Lucas.
Hey, Lucas.
Come on, man.
I can't do this.
I don't drive.
Can't you just tow 'em?
I will own your ass.
Lucas.
Come on, man.
I can't do this.
I don't drive.
That Travis Tilman
sure doesn't like to lose.
While other drivers may
not like his aggressive,
sometimes dangerous style,
he certainly knows how
to rack up the victories.
Hey.
You see me out there?
I sure did.
You see me win?
I did.
Should we go celebrate?
Let's go.
There you are.
Here, hold this.
What is this?
See...
Motion creates electricity.
Electricity creates motion.
And it all starts with
magnetism from the poles.
It's all in there.
Yeah, this
baby's a beaut.
440, dual exhaust,
heated seats.
Can't beat that with a bet.
How's it run without nitrous?
Inhalation, compression.
Ignition, exhaust.
Art.
Pardon me.
Mastery of hand.
Confidence of stroke.
What the?
How can you stand so
close to those speakers?
I said how can you
stand so close to those...
It's the only way
to take it, buddy.
Yeah, well, it
almost blew me over.
Woo yes, sound
waves will do that.
They push things around.
And if you're looking
for maximum heavyocity...
Damn, I ain't never heard
no car sound like that.
Yeah, you can tune 'em
up, you can tune 'em down
any which way.
Just like a motor.
Woo!
Humbuckers and horse power,
now that's what
I'm talking about.
Woo.
So what in the heck you
doin' here so early?
It's two o'clock.
What, in the afternoon?
Man.
I must've got
accidentally drunk.
I'll put the coffee on.
Yeah, it's Friday night.
You ain't goin' nowhere
'till that whole
paycheck is gone.
Congratulations.
New guy pays all night.
Hell yeah, I'm
fixin' to get wilder
than a filler goat
tonight, boys.
Woo.
Lucas.
Higgy.
New girl in town?
Naw, it's Jamie's friend.
Chill.
Sick of the farm I guess.
Another round?
Save it for the dancers, sir.
How 'bout a lap dance?
Get off of me!
Get out of here now.
So, when did your sister start
working at the strip club?
What do you mean?
You know it can get
pretty rough in there.
What happened?
What, are you gonna pick
her up on your handle bars?
I'll meet you outside.
Hey.
Hey, you out of your mind?
Bobby, what are
you doin' here?
Yeah, I could ask
you the same thing.
I work here.
Are you all right?
Since when are you driving?
What are you doing
working at that place?
You saw that sheriff's notice.
We can't make that kind of money
working at the corner store.
Lucas told me what
happened tonight.
Who were they?
Bobby, I ain't strippin'
if that's what your thinkin'.
I didn't need that
image in my head.
Shut up.
Look, I just...
I just don't wanna
lose the house.
Yeah, me neither.
So you know Lucas?
Yeah, he was Daddy's
mechanic and partner.
Don't you remember?
I was five when Dad died.
He and Daddy would be
in that garage for hours,
and their heads buried
under the hood of some car.
He don't act like he knows me.
Hey, you're back?
Everything all right
with your sister?
Hey now, you're gonna
damage the equipment.
Did you have that machine
hooked up to my Daddy's car?
Is that how he died?
Look, it's not
that simple, Bobby.
Hey now.
It's time I told ya.
Now, that night
your Daddy and I,
we were testing out a theory.
Hey, but we lost control.
Hey.
You know what gets me?
Is you never told me.
You never said a damn word.
Bobby, your Daddy
and I had a plan.
We just didn't know
how far it would go.
Bobby!
My family
owns all of this.
The lake looks
beautiful to me.
So do you.
Travis.
C'mon, you know you want it.
Travis, stop it.
Travis stop it!
Don't.
Don't you wanna
be with a winner?
Where are you goin'?
Where are you goin', Mae?
That night,
your Daddy and I,
we were testing out a theory.
We were manipulating
time and space.
Hey, but we lost control.
Is that how he died?
Look, it's
not that simple, Bobby.
Bobby Dunlap
Junior's car has left the track
in a crash eerily similar to
the one that claimed the life
of his father 12 years ago.
We regret to inform you
that Bobby Dunlap Junior
did not survive the crash.
Bases loaded,
bottom of the ninth,
two outs, here comes the pitch,
he got all of that one.
Home run, baby!
That was awesome.
Hey.
Can I help you?
Can we talk?
Please.
What do you got there?
Travis, what are
you doing here?
Why haven't you
been returning my calls?
Don't you remember?
Why you bringing that up?
We need to talk.
Are you okay?
Ain't like hitting girls, is it?
You picked the wrong day, man.
Are you all right?
I almost had him, you know.
I saw that.
Come on, let's go get some ice.
You sure this is his place?
Yeah, that's it right there.
That redneck sucker
punched the wrong guy.
Yeah, he got you good.
Shut up, Dale.
Help me find a way inside.
Yo, this don't
look like his room.
Might be his sister's.
This might get
us a little profit.
Maybe even a new
exhaust manifold.
Bingo.
They took it all.
Bobby Junior.
I heard what happened.
Yeah, they took all the
money Michelle had saved.
I know you're totally
against the idea
of racing and everything,
but, the prize is
10,000 dollars.
It's worth a shot.
This is what
it's all about, folks.
Passing down the tradition
through your family
and your good buddies.
Dirt track racing
is real racing.
Home grown, served up
right here at the speedway.
Lucas.
Hey Lucas.
Hey...
About before...
Me too.
For everything, Bobby.
Sorry.
Beautiful.
This place in the morning.
Hey Lucas...
Can you do me a favor?
Can you teach me how to race?
I've been waitin'
for you to ask.
You ready?
Now, until you crash
or hit the wall,
a man never truly
understands racin'.
A good driver has
concern for the wall,
but he pushes past it.
A complete racer has
respect, but no fear.
All right.
Good talk.
Hell, we got all day.
That dog will hunt.
Pretty sight, ain't it?
Yeah, Lucas, this
may sound crazy, but,
I swear I can hear music.
You feel it right down
to the bone, don't ya?
The rhythm of them cylinders,
it's like a symphony.
When you start driving with
your ears, not just your eyes,
you begin to understand
what you're doing here,
what you're all about.
Took your Daddy a
lot longer than that
to hear that orchestra play.
All right, watch out
for snakes and spiders.
It's like your
Daddy used to say,
if you're not doing something
with what you learn,
you ain't worth a damn.
It's your Daddy's old backup.
I reckon he'd want
you to have it.
Damn, I don't
know what to say.
Hey Michelle.
Looks like I got a ride.
Do you know this guy?
Yeah, that's my brother.
He's a cutie ain't he?
Don't even think about it.
Okay, okay.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah,
this is the place.
Eenie meenie miney, hose.
My goodness.
What happened?
Well, I stepped out.
Lucas, what
happened to the car?
Somebody broke in.
They sure knew what
they were doin'.
Why would anybody
wanna do this?
Bad ethics.
Can we fix it?
Whoever it was, wasn't just
trying to mess up the paint.
The race is in
less than a week.
Well, that doesn't give
us much time now, does it?
Hey, hand me that
wrench, would ya?
Lucas.
Yeah?
What if I don't win?
Well...
You never know.
I mean, you've
seen me out there.
I ain't the fastest,
and I definitely ain't
the most experienced.
Well, none of that
is gonna matter none.
You mean none of
that's gonna matter.
Well, you got somethin'
none of them got.
Like what?
You're gonna say I have
heart or spirit or something.
No, more important.
You got your Daddy's blood,
and I swear that
man had motor oil
coursin' through his veins.
What if that ain't enough?
Well, it's what you got.
You're not gonna do
something to the car, are you?
You don't have to
worry about any of this.
You just keep your
wheels on the track.
This is my path.
Ain't this excitin'?
Welcome to the show.
Yep.
The rumors are true.
You're paintin' again.
Where are you off to?
I was gonna see Bobby,
see if Bobby needed
help with his project.
I thought he was
finished with that.
Hopefully today he will be.
Where's Bobby?
He got called up
for his time trials.
Should be finishing
up about now.
I missed it?
Yeah, he got bumped
up on the list.
Wait, here he comes.
Well, how'd you do?
Made the cut.
That's great.
How'd Tilman do?
He's up now.
Well, don't worry about him.
You'll see him soon enough.
Don't forget to
come on down to the midway.
Under the bleachers,
you get your racing
gear, good food,
and an ice cold drink.
Lots of flavors not be missed...
Careful now.
Don't wanna over tighten it.
It seemed like it
was running a bit,
retching the heat.
Yeah, that oughta do it.
Now start 'up.
Right on pitch!
You should really pull
out of those turns now.
You come a long way,
and
I'm proud of ya.
Thanks, Luke.
Yeah, well...
Check them tires, I'm
gonna go grab a beer.
And
by the way, folks,
don't forget to
stop by the Via W,
women's auxiliary bake sale
by the concession stand.
They're selling
mouth-watering cheery,
and apple crumble pies
made from scratch and
ready for the table.
All proceeds go to disabled
veterans in the local VA.
This is a great cause
run by some great ladies,
so let's get out there
and show your support
for the veterans.
God bless ya, and
God bless America.
Knock 'em dead, Bobby Junior.
I will.
Thanks, Mae.
For everything, I mean,
you've been amazing.
I'm just happy I could help.
Racers,
please lead your cars...
I gotta...
You'll do great.
All right, drivers.
This'll be a 25 lap race.
The first one to cross
the finish line wins.
We'll be running in
Durrow rules tonight boys.
That means nothing stops
unless you flip over
or catch on fire.
At that point, a yellow
flag will come out,
a truck will push
you off the track.
Prize tonight's 10,000.
Let's have a good race, boys.
You picked the
wrong horse, Mae.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
The kid's a natural.
What'd he say?
Here we go, the
big race final.
Three time champion of
this 10,000 dollar race.
He always
And get this, driving
in the 55 car,
is newcomer, Bobby
Dunlap Junior.
Dunlap looks past the past,
but doesn't
Bobby Junior is the son
of the great track legend,
Bobby Dunlap Senior,
and just as surprising,
seeing his old equipment
man, Lucas, here,
who seems to have
come out of retirement
to get behind this young racer.
Good luck, Bobby Junior,
you're certainly gonna need it.
Racing may be Bobby Junior's...
This is the first time
we see what this kid has
what it takes to capture
the checkered flag.
Tilman's trying to
pick up the final lead
for the Martin Cup.
Here we go.
Turn green, turn
force into a file.
Up to the high line.
Dunlap, he's gonna
take the low line,
turning one and two.
He's gonna power away now.
Tilman, he's gonna try to
build up some momentum.
He's been on the high
line to make 'em up.
Bobby Dunlap Junior has made
his way through the path,
he's maneuvered
into second place.
Challenging Tillman, we've
got lots of decent showman
going on right now.
These drivers want that 10,000
dollars something fierce.
Travis Tilman and Bobby Junior
battling it out man to man,
machine to machine,
this could come down
to the final stretch.
He turns one and two,
Dunlap looks to make
a move down low,
slips underneath
into three and four.
If he flunks it, he's gonna
have to take it from Tilman,
who's trying going on.
The back, straight away,
making a run for it.
White flag, one more
time, it's game on now.
It's Tilman and Dunlap.
Tilman gonna take the high line,
Bobby Junior's gonna
take the low line
into three and four.
He slams the door on Tilman.
Here we go, it's
Tilman and Dunlap.
Dunlap powers into
a lead out of four,
now on the front, straight
away, it's Dunlap.
Dunlap for the win,
and Bobby Junior
takes the checkered flag.
And the Dunlap legacy
has been passed on
to the next generation.
Bobby Junior, we'll see
you in victory lane.
Michelle!
Woo!
Thank you, thank you.
Thanks.
Man.
Yeah.
Bobby,
It's clear to me that
you are exactly the man
your father would
have wanted you to be.
Your Daddy would be proud,
just like I am.
Enclosed is the key to the shop.
You'll find the title and
other paperwork laid out
on the desk.
It's yours now.
I got some traveling to do.
A journey that you've
helped me to brave.
'Cause the truth is, well,
the truth is different
for each man, ain't it?
But I reckon maybe that's
what we do on this earth.
We search for truth, and
if we're lucky, we find it
in who we are, and what we do.
I was fortunate to meet
you and your Daddy.
If I see him first, well,
I'll be sure to say hello.
Good luck to you, Bobby.
Your friend, Lucas.