Tolga! Tolga!
Tolga man! Get up! It's 7.30 already.
Hnnn...
C'mon man. Get up!
If you really put your mint to it,
you can wake early the next day.
That was the 9 o' clock news.
We hope to see you again at 10.
What have you done, man?
It's already late.
What can I do? It said 7.30.
C'mon, move, man.
The projects I did before were
always ignored because of that guy Salim.
Now for the first
time an opportunity to...
...make a presentation to
the big boss happens...
and I'm late for that too.
Is it possible?
Excuse me, where's the Galata tower?
Ask someone else, you maniac.
C'mon I can't waste time on you.
Come here you. Come here. Animal.
That guy was a Turk.
Shall I tell you something?
With this luck we'll be
caught on the bridge.
Don't be ridiculous.
Are you busy?
Get in.
Oh man. We should've
turned right there.
We missed the turning.
We'll have to go round now.
Don't cut in. Idiot.
Don't stop. Don't you understand.
For God's sake.
Let's get on with it.
We're in a hurry.
Wait. Stop. Don't man.
What's he doing?
Hey man. Just leave it.
C'mon. Let's go...
Oh man I've dropped
the flash disc.
My presentation is on it.
My life is on that disc.
Tolga, where've you dropped it?
I don't know, man.
I hope it's at home. Damn.
One of my girls has got one. Let's go
back and get it if you want. T'S 4 GB too.
Turn just here man. Turn.
Got it, found it. What happened man?
Where's the taxi?
The taxi? He's running
on a meter. It reached...
...10 lira. I paid him
and sent him on his way.
What are we gonna do?
Hhhh.
C'mon. Move.
There you go. Perfect. Just my luck.
I've told you before.
No luck. I just have that
kind of luck. Whatever I do...
...born unlucky. Oh for
chrissakes. Damn it, shit!
Give me my pass.
Take it.
You see it's my luck, man.
Everything in my life's like that.
You go... go and be in love
with the boss's daughter...
...as if there isn't
another girl in the world.
Haven't you been eyeing her up, man?
No, my son. I mean, in fact... At the
company we looked at each other, that's all.
One time she smiled. She
may just've been eyeing me...
...up secretly. I can't be sure.
Maybe she was just looking.
We can't really call that chance.
It's something else completely.
Even the team I support is in the amateur
league now. 'Sthat seem familiar to you?
You've really lost it man.
Look at me You haven't woken up yet.
When we get off, go and wash
your face and get it together.
If you want to beat your run
of bad luck it's in your hands.
Do your gig to the boss and win him over.
You said Ebru will be there.
Break your run of bad luck man, break it.
Tolga.
Give me that!
Hayati my man.
How're you doing?
On the way to the man, I said go and wash
your face and he flew into the sea.
Haha. Very funny.
Quickly.
What?
Tolga.
Salim's calling.
What's that psycho got to do with me?
Here, take it. You speak.
I dropped my phone in the sea.
Hello, Mr. Salim. Excuse me.
Excuse me. I'm a bit late...
Can't you see the sign? Rude boy.
Who d'you think you are?
And you educated 'n' all.
If you can't think for yourself,
think of others.
You'll see.
Hey man, can't you see the sign? It's
forbidden to speak on the 'phone.
Mr. Salim. Sir, I'm on the
bus right now...
and it's forbidden to speak here, so you
speak and I will listen, sir.
Driver. I'll get off the bus
at a convenient spot.
It couldn't have been more
convenient, in fact.
Is this the last stop?
This is the last stop for everyone.
We're not too late, are we?
Mr. Salim will kill me.
OK man, see you later.
Take it easy. Good luck.
- You too man.
- See you.
Enter.
Tolga, what do you think we do here?
Salim, good morning.
Everyone's waiting for you,
where've you been?
A small thing happened on the...
What do you think you're wearing?
And why don't you answer the phone?
My phone, well, it fell into the sea.
Where's your presentation?
It fell in too
and everything got wet but
but I've got a flash disk.
I hope it will work.
Will it?
Let me look, give it here.
You go to the conference room
check the preparation, see if there's
anything you need.
After the meeting drop by here, you
need to sign a few documents.
OK, sir.
C'mon, what are you waiting for?
Quickly. Move.
Standing there like a lemon.
Everything OK?
I don't think there's a problem.
Thanks.
OK, let's start, please.
Of course, sir.
First of all welcome to everyone.
Err. The Alacity Project.
Petrol has been found in various
areas of Turkey,
mostly in the South Eastern region
and there is some production there.
The South Eastern region.
Batman. Mardin.
Let's keep it short please.
Make it clear.
Right away. One second.
The petrol reserves in the Aegean region
according to my research in the area.
I focussed on the Alacity vicinity.
Excue me I'm a bit nervous- err
moving on swiftly -
if we, as a company,
invest in this region...
err - the Alacity region -
err -while I was coming here
I dropped my flash disk in the sea.
I don't know how these
changes happened - err.
Here's something the region's best - err
- where's this come from?
Now, Mr Salim, you know,
there's real potential in...
...this Alacity region and
there is serious proof...
One second. This is Alacity but
where've these come from?
Now, Mr. Salim, Alacity,
Mr. Salim, you know
that the Alacity region...
...has been well researched
and there are details...
Mr. Timur, the final contracts.
I can't tell you how
sorry I am about wasting...
...your precious time
this morning sir.
I shouldn't have trusted that boy
to make a presentation to you.
With your permission I'd like
to speak to the accountant...
...and secure that young
man's formal notice.
Don't you think deciding to throw
that young man out is a bit heavy?
Mr. Timur, sir, in business life this
sort of thing is intolerable.
I don't really think it's a good idea but
that youth is just at the beginning.
For young people to learn,
sometimes it's better...
...to make difficult decisions,
for their own good.
Take it easy.
Tolga.
Tolga, ah Tolga. I can't tell you
how sorry I am.
You didn't deserve this.
I really tried to keep you but the boss...
Now what will you do?
Sometimes this is what happens
in business life. I hope...
...from now on things will
go how you want them to.
Oh. Tolga, before you
got drop by for a moment...
...I need you to sign a
few papers for me.
Meto, my man, when you read
this I will be far away.
If I can't succeed at yet another
bit of bad luck, very far away.
I have no hope left even for
my big, secret love. Damn my...
...bad luck, living with bad
luck I prefer not to live.
Damn my bad luck.
Damn my bad luck!
Good jump huh!
Wow. So it's like this.
Hi. The Gates ha.
No, no, no. Entry procedure. The situation
and friends are a bit different there.
Actually, there's no reason for formality.
I mean I should go straight to hell.
After such an unfortunate life
I'm not expecting anything else actually.
What a supercool guy you are.
Hm. What?
Look human. D'you know
what your real problem is?
You put all your responsiblity in
the hands of chance and fate.
You learn nothing.
You don't fight it.
You don't take the responsibility for
anythinga dn immediately leave it to God.
At a time like this mutiny
in the face of destiny...
...might be good, don't you think?
Mutiny? In this case,
which I've never been in...
...I don't know where
to put myself.
With my help. I'm concerned
with things of the world.
D'you know what
I've lived with all my life?
Did I fail your registration?
I'm the registrar.
Look. This was the
first time I fell in love.
What happened to me? Bad luck, wasn't it?
My presentation, my getting fired,
making a fool of myself in
front of the girl and once...
...again being able to see
her. What was all that then?
Look, in time
you will find out.
What's the point of throwing yourself
of a skyscraper? What's that, man?
Could you have
lived with that life?
OK. If you'd lived d'you
know what would've happened?
If only you knew what you missed.
OK. So now I should be
sorry about that then?
O, forget it. I prefer to hand myself over to
this than going on living that unlucky life.
Nope, this guy doesn't get it.
He doesn't.
D'you know what the
best punishment could be?
Showing you where you could've
been in five years time.
If you can do that, bring it on.
Bring it on he says.
O God. My god.
Just one day from morning to night.
Then you come back here at midnight.
But don't tell anyone
our little secret.
The minute you do you
come back here right away.
Ok.
Will you beam me down?
O, for Chrissakes!
Hello sir.
Welcome sir.
Good morning.
Good morning sir.
Where've you been man?
I've been looking for you all morning.
Meto.
It's incredible that
on a busy day like...
...today you're not to be
found anywhere, Tolga.
We've got tons of stuff to do. Even
your secretary has come to me for help.
How you think you can manage I don't know.
C'mon then let's get on with it.
C'mon man. Still here? Move.
Take it easy.
Thanks.
Welcome, Mr. Tolga.
Ruya, let's get on with it.
We're all a bit tense today.
Here's your programme for today.
First I postponed your holographic
conference with the Australians.
That's great.
The president wanted to see
you and is waiting for you to call.
Who?
The president.
With me?
Tolga. I can't get involved in that. Enough.
Let's postpone that too.
The financial director is stil waiting for
your approval of the new payments.
UNESCO want to give you
an award for your most...
...recent charitable
contribution and await a date.
That's for tomorrow too.
I don't need to remind you that it's
your wife's birthday party this evening.
And your father-in-law, Mr. Timur is
waiting for news from you about lunch.
My wife and my father-in-law.
That's all for today.
Have a nice day, sir.
Man, this, man.
Tolga, are you OK?
I'm fine, fine.
Have a look at this.
This is last week's.
And this.
This is the other day.
This really is a strange day for me.
Seems like I've forgotten everything.
Let's go and see a doctor.
No, no. I'm saying, look at what
we've been through recently.
Recently - meaning? We won
last month's tender for land.
Then we opened a second oil well.
We went together why d'you ask me that?
Petrol. I knew that.
What did you know?
Ha, forget it. Look. Look.
What if we talk about life a bit.
Oh. You wanted me to find
a ticket for the European...
...final and your brother
got the best box for you.
No, not things like that man.
What did you say?
The European final?
The Championship League.
The final?
Yes.
Oh! Talk about me a little.
Man, for god's sake, what are you saying?
What d'you want to know?
I mean the last three to five years-
tell me that, how'd I get here?
Oooh.
I mean, Ebru, me, our kids, our marriage,
how'd that happen?
Give me a summary.
Man, you haven't been well since
this morning. Let's go to the doctor.
I'm exhausted.
D'you know Tolga, I never had the
slightest doubt about you.
It brings me great satisfaction that we've
come to this point and I wasn't wrong.
Thank you, sir.
By the way, are all the preparations
for Ebru's birthday party ready?
Birthday party?
Of course, of course.
Ready? Everything's ready.
It makes me very happy to see my daughter
and my grandchildren so happy.
God never gave me a boy but...
Hold on. Don't rebel!
No, no. That's not what I wanted to say.
God didn't give me a boy but he gave me
a son-in-law like you. So I'm blessed.
Thank you, sir. Go on just like that.
Excuse me?
I mean, to feel blessed is nice,
to give thanks.
I'm going to wash my hands,
you get the bill.
Excuse me sir, what did you want?
I just wanted the bill.
Of course sir.
There you are.
Your retina payment has been approved.
What's that then?
Thank you, sir.
If Turkey has become the
third largest economy in...
...the world, it's not
because of the government
but more to do with our debt to the success
of the Alacity and Adana projects.
Those are reckoned to
be among the best...
...quality and richest petrol
reserves in the world.
Of course. Turkey's destiny changed
because of those oil reserves.
Is it easy to become a major
world force overnight?
But I don't think we should belittle
what the government has done.
The problem in the South
East has finished, inflation...
...wiped out, unemployment
around the zero mark.
Our president showed
great leadership over our...
...petrol reserves
at the G-9 summit.
...the G-9 summit is another thing...
- G-9. Phew!
But if our president hadn't
stopped the other eight...
...countries and we say if it wasn't
easy to get to this point now...
And now we join our sports
service for the sports news.
Because today is an important
day in football,
- after our national football team.
- Following the World Cup championship.
World Cup?
The eyes of world football are
focussed on two teams in...
the League Championship match between
Galatasaray and Fenerbahce.
Whoa! It's really true. Man, I wonder what
happened to my poor team?
Everyone left the amateur league. Only
they remained. They won't get out.
They're shutting down the
third amateur league.
How's it going, bud?
You? What are you doing here?
I brought a message from the chief
angel and thought I'd take a look.
You were trying to get
information from people.
I suggest you don't go there.
What can I do? Hey man. It's not that.
Everything's turned upside down.
What am I gonna do at home?
You mean when you see Ebru?
Yea.
That's your problem. You've
got til midnight. Use your time well.
Cinderella.
Help me just a bit.
Bye bud.
Asistan angel. Look. What was I gonna say?
Are you on overtime?
Do they insure you up there? It's amazing.
There you go. Work from nine to five and...
What's that?
Are you talking to a genie?
Come on. Shall we go?
Fine, see you this evening.
See you later, sir.
Here you are, sir.
Excuse me?
Are you alright, sir?
I'm fine.
Will you get in?
Get in?
Do you want to drive again today, sir?
Really?
Sir?
There's probably a lot of traffic,
no, you drive, you...
Where are we going, sir?
Straight on. Straight home, I mean.
My wife, my kids, my home.
Where else?
I want to ask you something.
Yes, sir.
What am I like?
A good man, sir.
You're just saying that,
because I'm the boss. But I'm...
...really asking. Forget about
all that driver boss stuff.
As a plain man I'm asking. What am I like?
I won't be angry, really.
In as far as I know,
you are a normal man, sir.
As a father, a husband.
I'm a good man.
God bless you sir, a good man.
A good man, a good man.
Excuse me. I mean as a
man what do I do outside?
What do I drink? Eat? What
am I like? Give me a clue?
Are you feeling unwell sir if you like
shall w ego down to the water.
I'm fine Im a good guy.
You are a good man sir.
I'm a good man ok.
Wow wow.
Welcome home sir.
Thanks.
Dad.
My girl.
What did you buy mummy for her birthday?
Present? Right. Errrr
Don't worry sir it's arrived.
Wheres your mummy?
At the hairdressers.
Dad? How did you meet mummy?
Your mummy. We used to do
the same things that's how we met.
Then?
Then? We saw each other and fell in
love and got married.
Have you forgotten?
What's the matter? Whats up?
You havent callled me daffodil today.
You always say it.
Are you sure? My darling you are
always my daffodil my darling daffodil.
My darling.
Your mummys arrived. I'm going
to see her and then come back.
Hi, how's it going?
Everything's ready. Were just waiting
for the catering company to come.
OK, that's fine. Let me
know when they arrive.
Aha, my darling. How are you?
Fantastic. My love.
How's my hair?
Lovely.
I wonder if I'd put it up would it
have been better?
Up? That would've been lovely too.
That way's lovely too.
Liar.
Truly.
D'you want to see the dress
I've got for this evening?
OK.
C'mon then.
Hold on a minute darling.
As soon as i saw it in the
window i said that's the one.
Look dyou like it?
What d'you think?
It's lovely but...
But?
I want to see it on you.
Youll have to wait til this
evening for that my darling.
This evening? I want to tell
you someting. Listen.
Sometimes we don't have ot
wait til the evening right?
D'you want to do
something naughty?
Naughty? Maybe...
I think you must
wait until tonight.
But why?
I want you to be impatient.
What for?
Because I do. OK.
No, it's not.
Darling, Is there anything wrong?
Yes.
Ma'am, the catering company's
arrived and you wanted me to tell you.
OK. I'm coming.
They're waiting downstairs.
OK. I'm coming now.
Darling. Let go. I have to go downstairs.
Unfortunately.
Darling.
Many happy returns
of the day. Like 1001 nights.
Are you ready for a wonderful holiday?
Here are your reservations.
Baghdad. Thank you very much.
Darling.
Happy birthday my darling daughter.
Thank you for everything!
This is from me.
A 1960 Mustang.
I don't believe it.
My dearest here you are.
I'm really nervous.
Son-in-law.
I think it's my turn.
Happy birthday darling.
Darling, wasn't this Granny's necklace?
Yes it was. Her favourite one.
She had to sell it during the war.
We saw it in an auction
catalogue recently.
Tolga wanted to do this
as a surprise for you.
Me?
Darling I cant believe
you. You cant possibly...
...know how important
this is for me.
This necklace was very
important for Granny and...
...she always wanted it
to stay in the family.
Darling. You're wonderful.
Thank you very much.
Before my grandmother died
she spoke to me and said:
Everybody creates their own luck.
Your luck will be that you find a man
who loves you very mcuh.
She said: One day when you feel like you're
the luckiest woman in the world
...you will, in fact, have met the
man you were looking for.
Come with me.
Where?
Nothings gonna happen. Come.
What?
Come on.
Ohh. It's lovely.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Yes, yes. Lovely.
Come on.
What come on?
Aren't we going to look inside?
At this time? In the dark? No way.
Come on.
Wait a minute.
What are you doing?
You said the evening.
What are you waiting for?
When i said evening i meant later?
O, don't do that.
Darling are you mad?
With all these people?
What will happen?
Now we're out of the crowd.
Ye-e-s.
And weve got this
opportunity to go upstairs.
You've gone mad baby. When
there are so many people outside.
So? Guests. Today is today
and tomorrow is tomorrow.
We are all guests in this world arent we?
Here today gone tomorrow. I think so anyway.
Why cant you wait? Why now?
Cant you wait another hour or two?
I cant wait.
Why?
I cant wait. Don't ask why. Isnt this
more exciting? While there are guests.
Cold weather. We go to
the bedroom. Inside.
I don't know.
You got me.
I'll take the keys.
What are you saying?
Slowly, wait.
My love, wait.
Hurry up. Nobody will notice,
don't worry.
Ive been looking for you everywhere.
Where've you been?
I've got lots of old
friends I want you to meet.
Come on. Hurry. Lets go.
The US economy is on
the up. It's easy to say.
The threat of terror is finished.
You can see what's happening in Europe.
Whatever we do they're all amazed
by the Turkish American alliance.
Even if we are a superpower we can't
manage the whole burden ourselves.
True.
Excuse me.
Of course.
He's absolutely right. C'mon now guys,
forget about business. Let's have some fun.
Cinderella.
So, human. How was it?
Did you like it?
If you'd given me five or ten minutes
more would it have killed you?
Don't be ironic, human.
Where's that cool pose now?
I died too soon.
You threw yourself off.
That's a kind of bad luck.
The first part of life finished with a
suicide and bad luck. Look to the rest.
Listen to that.
You stil don't understand.
I'm unlucky, unlucky and you hand over
your flash disc to Mr. Salim.
You say your watch is broken and it's
been saying 7.30 for a week.
Haven't you got a cell phone?
Set the alarm and get up.
When you get in a taxi
you look at the driver and...
...see what he's like, thief
or not? What's he like?
You just get in, whatever.
What were you doing only two nights before
your presentation?
What's that?
Goooooaaal!
You pick up a hairdryer
when your hair is wet...
...it's lucky you
weren't struck dead.
Yes, you're lucky you. And if you hadn't died
when you jumped off that building
I wouldn't have seen the state youdve got to.
If you hadn't died I'd've seen you.
Look. I wasn't aware of that.
Maybe you're right.
And he said this stuff
like I'd rather be here than...
...living that unlucky,
ill-starred life and all that.
I'm really sorry.
That's great.
Now it's time to ask you what good deeds
you did and count your sins.
An I'm sure if you gave me
another chance.
I could prove that I've changed.
What kind of chance?
I mean I'm not talking abut five years time.
Don't misunderstand.
Theres the suicide.
If I could go back to just before that,
that would be enough for me.
Of course, OK.
When I said a just before that,
I meant before I fell.
I gather you misunderstood.
Look, bud. Are you serious?
Sometimes people die in
hospital and the doctors...
...give them an electric
shock on their chest
and they say they went to the
other side and came baack.
Could you do something like that?
My friend. Are we playing ping-pong here?
Go to the other side and what have you.
Doctors do that.
Nothing to do with us.
Have you seen the light at the
end of the tunnel yet?
No...
Well.
Really man, what's all this?
I dunno.
Look, I promise I won't think
things like that again.
I'll be responsible for everything I do
and I won't curse my bad luck.
Please.
But, if you do the opposite in the future
youll be back here in a flash. Watch out.
OK.
OK. But after this what you do
with your life is your affair.
What you've seen five years
into the future is no guarantee.
What you do and where you
get to I don't know. It's up to you.
It's always like that.
I accept.
Tolga! Tolga!
Don't do it man!
- OK! OK! I'm not gonna jump.
- Stop! Stop! Youll fall. Be careful.
OK! OK! Quiet! I won't jump.
I'm here. Finished.
Lets go.
What are you doing then?
Everybody creates their own luck in life.
I believe that now.
What happened to you on the roof? Did you
get too much oxygen? I don't get it, man.
Look man, I'm just gonna
get it together. I will do my...
...resentation again and get
my job back. I'm serious.
Go for it. That's you. Go on.
Now, I'm going out this door
and I'll start a brand new life.
New luck, new hope, a new life. You won't
believe what's gonna happen.
Tolga!
What an unlucky guy you are.
Don't say that Meto. If only
I'd looked left and right.
I got away lightly
from this accident.
A couple of scratches and a broken
bone or two. Stuff happens.
Tolga, you never said
anything like that before.
It sounds like someone else is talking
in the room. What did they give you, man?
Meto, this situation is
nothing for me. I'm gonna get...
...my job back.
Did you bring my laptop?
Yes, Ibrought it. I did.
Excuse me, sorry.
I'll just check my projects again.
Please copy all the things from Salim's
computer and bring them to me.
OK, man. I'll deal with it.
Can I come in?
Yes, Miss Ebru.
What are you saying?
Get out.
Go.
Get well soon.
Thank you.
I'm really sorry.
We were all shocked.
At the same time my father wishes
to convey his condolences.
Thank you.
However much I'm the Personel Director,
that's not why I'm here.
Actually I didnt even know youd been fired.
Everything happened at once I guess.
Yes, a bit like that.
By the way, the company will pick
up all your hospital bills.
Actually, theres no need for any of that.
I mean, theres no need
for you to feel guilty.
It's just about
my carelessness.
You cant be serious.
What happened at the
presentation in the morning...
...then getting thrown out of work.
I was going to the company by
boat and arrived at Uskudar
When i fell in the water
and I had a flash disk...
...in my pocket and that fell in too.
Then I came to the office and
started my presentation.
Ahh. What's this Picture id never seen.
Nothing.
I just remembered the pictures.
If theres anything you need at all.
No. Thanks, really.
Don't forget really. O, once more.
Get well soon.
C'mon Meto.
But weve been planning a holiday for weeks.
Ive even got my clothes ready.
What can I do, baby. The
guy had a traffic accident...
...and I had to get him
to sign those documents.
Just because of your
stupid mistake we cant...
...go on holiday again. I
really cant believe it.
It's not a mistake, baby. Not a mistake.
Just the opposite.
You know I have to make sure that this
bogus company is in his name.
That way we avoid all the
legal responsibility.
Now the shares hav erisen
in value and we with...
...just one signature can put
the company in our name.
The idiot hasn't a clue.
Can you really do it?
It's always talk, talk with you!
You leave that to me.
Waiting in the wings is athe Alacity Project
and that's where the real money is.
Now we're going on a
holiday to Amsterdam...
...but later we'll go on
a world tour. Together.
I'm going to the hospital now
to get his signature.
Don't worry everything's
going to be fine.
OK.
Ah! Tolga. Ah!
I cant explain what I felt
when I heard the screech of...
...brakes and ran to the
window to see the horror.
You really upset everyone
and we're all very sorry.
The phone's ringing.
Won't you answer it?
Oh. Ah. Hold on a second.
I'll help you.
Tolga, listen man, listen. Man,
I went to that psycho's room
He's got a computer, you know, full of your
presentations he didnt like.
That guy's using you.
He's a thief, a rogue.
And listen to this, as if that wasn't enough,
he's gonna steal your Alacity Project.
He's complete bastard.
You're absolutely right.
Yes. Of course.
Mr. Salim. Sorry for the trouble.
My dear Tolga.
That's what pals are for.
Sometimes that happens.
What are you talking
about? I don't get you.
The guy's a thief and
using you. A thief. A thief.
I love you too. Say hi to everyone.
Take care. See you soon.
Of course when all your friends heard about
your accident they wanted to speak to you.
No, no theres definitely something wrong.
While I'm here, I mentioned
there were a couple...
...of formalities which
need your signature.
Now is not the time for signatures.
No, it's not important now.
A couple of signatures.
We'll just sign these two now.
No, it's not the time now.
Lets do it like this. Theres
that unfinished presentation.
I'll come over to the
office and finish it off...
...then we'll talk about
the signatures.
OK. Understood.
When then?
As soon as I'm up.
As soon as you're up. OK.
Whatever you want.
D'you need anything?
No.
OK. Theres a couple of meetings...
...I have to go to, my dear
Tolga. Get well soon.
Bastard.
Was it easy to copy?
A cinch. Like taking candy from a baby.
Look man, these are the files that were on
that bastard Salim's computer.
There it is, the Alacity Project.
Can you see?
So that's why that bastard is trying to
get me to sign so often.
Man, there are guys like that who try tor ip
you off. And he's one of them.
So Ebru coming all this way to sweet talk me
and appear so kind was in fact her reason.
Shit, they created a company.
So you've finally opened your eyes.
I sure have. Look, I could reach
those heights like that.
What? What heights?
If I'm just their tool.
But Ebru. Our children.
Meto. I'm really confused, man.
That's for sure. What are
you saying? I dont get it.
Ebru, kids. What are you
saying? Are you alright?
Ahh. Ebru.
Don't blame her. Maybe
she's not guilty at all.
Doesn't even know.
I don't know.
It's completely up to me.
I'm not like that. I don't want...
...a life or riches like that.
If it's like that - forget it.
What riches? We have nothing.
You're talking about riches.
What are you saying? They must be giving
you something here. Must be.
Thank you for sparing me
a little of your precious time
But I guess a few words arent important for
a few million dollars of your dirty Money.
Getting straight to the point I
want you to know that I won't return...
...the share of the bogus
company you formed in my name
in order to avoid tax and legal problems.
I have all the regions here.
For example these are my projects...
...which weren't liked but
they've all been viewed.
Hmm.
Don't you find this
a bit strange, Mr. Salim?
Yes sir, a bit strange.
Now then, apart from you as
company project director...
...who could know about new projects
and do something like this?
Err. I don't know Mr. Timur. It means
someone's in need of a lot of money.
If that was me my presence here would
probably have no meaning.
If that's the case you accept
that those projects you...
...claimed you threw in the
bin are worth something then.
No, sir I...
What? If the projects are valuable
why weren't they presented to us?
If they're worthless how can someone
else make use of them?
Difficult questions, Mr. Salim?
It's terrible when theres
no place to hide.
Mr. Timur, look, all these err,
an explanation is very... some projects.
Now to you, young man.
This, err, bogus company...
...these shares, you can do
what you want with them.
As part of our corporate policy
we do not claim the right...
...to a company which doesn't belong to us,
even if it's in our name.
You mean, now.
What's that? You think our
corporation is a game?
I never planned to be
part of a bogus company...
...but what with one
ting and another...
If you're sincere about
what you say and...
...if there is a need for
a new project manager...
I will make you a proposal. If you
accept that place is yours.
O my god. Am I dead again?
Now what?
Is this like counter strike?
How many more lives?
He's pretty cool.
Just as I'm getting mylife
together I die and rise again.
What happened?
Why are you here again?
Look here you. Because
you've seen what's going to...
...happen in five years time you
couldve chosen the easy route.
Then we wouldve had to take
you back again with us.
But you've surprised both of us.
Life is presented to you as a gift.
Live it well or that life can be
taken away from you.
Enjoy the choices you make human.
Ah! Thank you.
You're welcome.
Filiz, has Ebru arrived?
No, she hasn't.
She didnt say anything.
What's between Tolga and Ebru?
I don't know.
Look Filiz. You brought Ebru up
and sacrificed yourself for her.
You havent married or
had children. As a woman...
...you know her well.
But I want to know.
Actually she doesn't say much to me now...
but...
...if you really want to
know
our girl's in love.
Ebru.
Yes.
Last night I had a lovely dream.
Tell me about it.
A little girl approaches from far away,
a child with tiny little hands...
so sweet, cherry-red lips and with
her a perfect beauty.
Long- haired like a fairy.
And that's her mother.
Just like you.
And with them theres a man.
The happiest man in the world.
His smile's a bit like mine.
In fact he is me.
And there are the in-laws.
They're really happy to. I
didnt quite get why there...
...we happy. And aunts
and uncles-also happy.
Whya re you happy?
I'm not really asking.
One of teh aunt's
has a child - Unal.
You know-she says. How can I know?
I havent seen him for ten years.
Yes, my love. The dream.
What happens in the end?
- What? - A lovely big family
but what happens in the end?
Ebru.
Yes.
I want the dream to be real.
How?
Will you marry me?
Yes.
When ever I think about the wedding
I run out of breath.
Thank god that Tolga is doing
most of the work.
How are you, Tolga?
Hello, sir.
Or should I start to say 'groom'.
You know best, sir.
Now, dear Tolga. There seem to be some
problems with the Alacity project.
The investors have suddenly said that
they find the price too high.
You know the project well and
I can't trust anybody else.
Just as we're talking about
weddings and honeymoons
you will have to be out of the
office for a long time.
I'm saying, first solve this problem.
Don't worry, sir.
I'll see to it.
Finish it quickly.
This position suits you - ha!
Thanks.
Tolga. Look at that.
Arent those our investors?
What kind of a man are you?
What kind of a guy is that?
Damn it.
You seem pretty sturdy. Bravo.
Nothing to do with it.
Call it tense.
So it's just to relax then.
Actually you don't need a
massage to relax. It would...
...relax you just to get
mad and curse your fate.
You.
My name isnt on the invitation list.
How rude.
What are you doing here?
Look, if you remeber, we made an
agreement with you, human.
Damn it.
Oh. That. Itjust slipped out.
I guess my tongue is guilty I mean.
But, why not?
It's just that one thing happened after
another. What can I do? I'm really sorry.
Theres no point apologising to me.
What's gonna happen now then?
I used my initiative and brough you here.
And so it's my job to take you back.
Take me back?
But, just as I was getting
ready to marry, it's not fair.
Theres nothing we can do human.
But look, everything happened at once.
I was in such a bad state that...
Isnt thatjust like life really? The whole
point of you making decisions, free will.
So what's gonna happen now then?
Will I suddenly disappear?
No, no. It's not like that at all.
Look; what we showed you before was
what could happen in the future.
Now, it's different.
- Ah, something better will happen.
- Yes.
- What?
- You really die.
A gas bottle explodes, a train crash,
a rock falling, a bear escapes, we'll see.
What?
He didnt express it very well.
Whereas you have a lot of choices...
and we will give you three days
to say goodbye to the world.
What a bonus.
C'mon get up.
Welcome make yourself at home.
Don't feel like strangers anymore.
I can see don't worry. But don't
feel like you're staying long.
Look, there are millions
of people in the world.
Why was I the only
one given a chance?
I don't know. I mean
theres Edison and Napoleon...
...there's Einstein. Why
didnt they come back?
Human, lots of people
are happy about...
...where they are and as the
years go by none return.
Don't make fun of me. I'm curious really.
How dyou know? Can you tell
the people around you?
No. What about it?
None were like you.
I'd never thought of that.
Weren't you ever paranoid
that everyone in the world...
...was created for you and they
were all playing a role for you?
So you're saying that
everyone has their own...
...separate world. Is that
it? What are you saying?
Weve got a lot of work to do with you.
People. I really don't
understand them.
This feeling of supporting a team,
being in love, with a team.
For example a man comes to us whose
team was playing away and was knifed.
At home, hungry kids. We tell
him you had a fight to the...
...death and he says: 'I'd die for
my team'. As if he wasn't dead.
I'd really die for my local team too.
My son. Even the players
change teams for money.
You grow up living and breathing a team.
What is it about you?
They're professional.
You don't get money from it.
During the season the
prayer lines are jammed.
Please god, what about a
goal, what about a goal now...
...this and that, you know,
not this, not that, a goal.
That's a waste of time.
My team went down, you know.
The angels didnt protect them.
Words. Are we football middlemen
that we can protect your team?
If you played with the ball like a man
and didnt fall over. I'll strike you down.
Can you cripple someone?
I didnt mean that.
I meant I'll hit you.
I think maybe we've
become too familiar...
...and it's time to put
some distance between us.
Ah, so it's like that
then now, is it? I get it.
Darling we're home.
O dear Ebru.
What do I say to Ebru?
Can everyone see you?
Can they see me?
Are you only visible to me,
I mean, or to everyone? Ssh.
Am i Casper? Of course
everyone can see me.
Smile play the part.
Hi, I thought I'd get used to our
house and use my keys.
Of course you should use them sweetie.
This is your home.
I'll introduce you.
Ebru, my fiancee. Filiz, Ebru's aunt,
big sister, everything. Right?
- Right?
- Uhuh.
Oh. My uncle.
Your uncle?
Yes, my uncle.
Darling, you told me you
had no relatives.
I don't, still don't. My dead aunts
husband. No blood ties.
Welcome, pleased to meet you.
What's your name?
Here we are at the best bit. Err. Killer.
Kill-er.
One word.
Killer. A terrible name that's difficult
to say. What kind of a name is that?
It's best if we go to the kitchen.
Early in the morning the designer
and the lighting people are coming.
I want to make a plan with Filiz.
It's going to be lovely, lovely.
Not long to wait.
See you later darling.
Filiz.
Ive never seen such a weirdo.
People get up. Do something.
I don't know. Is he from the circus?
Strange clothes.
D'you have to do that? I mean,
dyou have to take me back?
Look, human. We made an
agreement with you, right?
The best thing for you to do is forget
the other alternatives. Less painful.
But Ebru.
She's so happy.
I mean, I think.
You find the love of your life but
two days before the wedding...
Put yourself in her shoes.
Ha, I know this. Lying down, sleeping.
It's great.
Listen to me. Where am I going to
sleep tonight?
Where are Ebru and Filiz?
Dunno. In the kitchen maybe.
What's that then?
Angels.
Angels?
They don't look much like
that over there, right?
My son, theres no such thing as
an angel with wings. Very hard to use.
Tolga? I'm suddenly feeling
very odd, dyou know?
Look man, I don't wanna go there.
It's really not the right time.
That's irrelevant.
I feel really hungry.
What did you eat this morning?
Nothing, really.
Tell me, I don't know.
Those angels really arent bad at all.
Apart from the wings.
Ebru, for gods sake say something.
What's this?
Filiz don't upset yourself.
Don't interfere it's rude.
Slow down, uncle. It's not a race.
No sir, not a race. He eats like a horse.
It's as if theres been a famine.
Havent you got anything better to do?
Sticking your nose in my business.
Never mind. Lets stop this now.
Lets talk about our honeymoon.
The Maldives, Dubai,
Miami, the Bahamas.
Theres no need to go so far. Theres Mersin.
You'll find heaven and hell there.
What dyou say my dear Tolga?
To put it bluntly I want to
go somewhere I havent seen...
...or been to before. We're
thinking of somewhere abroad.
What dyou say to Tibet you two?
The way to Nirvana. Haha!
That's all rubbish. Tibet, Miami.
I think the best would be Baghdad. Baghdad.
Baghdad. Heaven. Hell.
When it comes to your time I'll
show you heaven and hell from above.
How about if we close this subject?
What a strange woman Filiz
is. Fluff. Over at mine they...
...make that type squawk.
Squawk.
O if I get her on my watch. Will you eat?
Won't you? Will you?
Butchers meat and a sheeps life.
Dyou know what I'm going through?
Look at what I'm thinking
and your obsession.
Look human, my son. Don't
twist this around making...
...it a private matter
between you and me.
The root of it is, I'm an ambassador.
Ebru spent the whole evening thinking about
her dreams of living together.
And I know they will never be real.
And desptie that she's so happy.
She spends all her time
thinking about the future...
...living with me and would
mutiny too, if she knew.
Then like me she will leave a life unlived.
No, I mustnt allow that.
I want to ask you a question.
Ask me darling.
This is the eve of our
wedding but some things have...
...happened really quickly,
have you ever thought that?
Yes, a bit, went a bit quick,
but I'm not complaining about it.
I don't know. After we
are married, I mean,
maybe you'll regret it. Maybe
something else. I don't know.
Is that what you're thinking?
No, no. I'm asking
about you. I don't know.
That's life. Everything's
possible. If you want...
Tolga.
I'm going to tell you something.
Maybe it's only been a little while.
But we want someting really good,
do you realise?
I love you.
OK.
I've got a strange feeling.
Im listless but neither
hungry nor tired, dyou know?
Inside I'm all excited but theres
really nothing to be excited about.
A strange feeling.
Does it ever happen to you?
For example, someone really,
really irritates you deep down...
...but at the same time you
really want to see them.
Like that woman, you know.
Filiz.
For example, we're totally out
of tune with each other you know
but I really want to see her.
What's that then?
I don't know how to say this.
Ebru?
Yes darling.
You've become the dream
I cant have I guess.
When you reach a goal the
other dreams fade away.
This love is over for me.
Hows that? Nothing can change so quickly
in a few days, can it?
Tolga, you're not like that at all.
How dyou know whether I'm
that kind of person or not?
Maybe I'm a bad guy. Maybe
I'm not the Tolga you know.
Yesterday, was that the thing you
were trying to explain to me?
You mean, everything we've done
was a waste of time for you, is that it?
What happened to your dream?
Your dream.
That picture of a happy family?
Tolga, cant you say anything else?
Look. This is to do with me.
It's my problem. About me.
Believe me. Youll find someone
who loves you more than me.
Don't try to cheer me up.
I'm doing it for you.
Go away - Please - Go away.
I'm ready. We can go.
Actually, thereve been some
changes to the program.
You mean?
In fact, it's great to be alive.
Wonderful.
You humans learn the value
of life once you've lost it.
Because I know what it's worth
I will start life one step ahead.
Meaning?
You still don't get it.
Now look, it's like this.
Since I taught you to value life
and because I taught you
how to behave responsibly I
was given a reward.
I'm staying here too.
Sooo...
You don't have to go either.
Wheres Ebru?
Upstairs, but she doesn't
want to be disturbed.
What are you doing here?
- Give me five minutes, listen.
- Get out of here.
Give me five minutes, please.
Get out of here. I don't want to
listen to you anymore.
Theres been a huge mistake.
All mixed up. I mean difficult.
What's that?
Or am I still a dream for you.
But it's not what you imagine.
Look. You are the most
important thing in my life.
I'm a childs toy, that's all. You were
frightened of marrying me.
That's the only explanation
for it. Because you...
...were uncertain of your
love form e. Get it?
You lost me. Ah! What have I done.
And now you're trying to win me back again.
Before I proposed to you
I told you I had a dream.
You. Me. Our kids.
Actually, it wasn't a dream.
The angels showed me our
life in several years time.
The angels? Sooo... Then what?
Don't mess with me. Please. I told
you this morning that I wanted to leave you.
The angels, this time,
wanted things to go like this.
The angels. Tolga? Do you really
expect me to believe that nonsense?
Yes. I'm waiting for you to believe it.
Because, thanks to those
angels I found out about...
...the things your granny
said to you years ago.
Everyone makes their own luck. Your greatest
luck will be a man who loves you.
When you fel you are the
happiest woman in the world,
you will have found the man
you've been looking for.
That. How could you know that?
I've never told anyone that.
How did you find out?
Your luck is me.
FIVE YEARS later
Aha-a-a. How long has it been?
I've tried to talk him out of it.
For goodness sake, leave him alone Filiz.
Let the man eat.
No, this huge man will die of cholesterol.
I'm frightened of that.
It's nothing.
Yes, nothing.
Like your dad.
Uncle, not so fast.
D'you see what I see?
No, I cant. What dyou see?
Look.
What's the ice-man doing here?
I don't know, man.
I looked at the date of when
Filiz was going to die but...
...I didnt look at my own.
I might die too now.
Look at that guy dressed
like Nicholas Cage.
I hope he hasn't come to get me.
Don't say that, killer. Is this the time?
Turn round. Turn.
Ha! Ha! What?
What are you doing here?
I came to the party.
Oh good. Why?
Chief. After you left nobody
took your place.
I'm saying can you hand that over to me?
I'll take your place.
Of course, my dear.
Have what you want.
Of course. Take my hat. You can have
whatever you want. You can go now.
Darling, who's our guest?
Won't you introduce us?
C'mon do tell.
Hey, killer.
Err. Unal.
You know. I told you.
Unal.
Unal. Ebru.
Unal's gone.
That Unal?
O, that's Unal. He was a kid.
He's grown up now.
And me.