A Japan-Mongolia co-production
commemorating the 800th anniversary
of the founding of Mongolia
Haruki Kadokawa & Ryuhei Chiba
present
GENGHIS KHAN
To the Ends of the Earth and Sea
The Mongolian clans
had formed into tribes.
Tayichi'ut, Tatar,
Merkit, Mongol, Kerait.
The tribes were many,
and constantly at war.
Shall we rest?
Let's go as far as we can before dark.
This is still Mongol land.
Chiled!
They're coming back!
It's me they want!
Have no fear!
I'll protect you.
No!
You must live...
to take me back.
Hoelun!
I'll come for you!
Wait for me!
I am Yesukhei Baghatur. Mongol,
Chief of the Borjigin clan.
You will come to my camp.
Stop crying!
I am but newly wed.
Why must I be stolen away?
My husband will come
to take me back.
There will be war.
I welcome it. I'm always ready
to scatter the Merkit.
But tell me... what is your name?
I am Hoelun, wife to Yege Chiled
of the Merkit.
'Hoelun'...
Now you are my wife.
I'll treat you well.
One day I would take revenge.
I swore that in my heart.
Nine months had passed
since Yesukhei had taken me.
The baby's coming! Stop!
You'll be fine.
It won't be long now.
That's right...
In this land of the Mongols,
the tribes were always at war.
Men defeated in battle were killed...
and the women seized as spoils.
Chief!
He's the leader.
He killed many of u s.
A brave enemy.
What's your name?
Temujin.
Temujin Uge.
'Temujin'... I won't forget that name.
Chief!
The baby's born!
It's a boy!
It is? A boy?
'Temujin'?
That will be his name?
Yes.
It's a good name.
The name of a brave enemy
I killed.
That Tatar chief?
Yes.
'Temujin'...
Temujin, son of Yesukhei Baghatur.
Temujin was named for
an enemy chief his father had slain.
He was born to a blood-drenched
destiny of slaughter.
Rest well.
What fate is yours?!
When he was 14, Temujin went
with his father in search of a bride.
In those years
I had borne four more children.
I had also raised two more
born of a different mother.
My first husband, who had sworn
to take me back, never appeared.
Suddenly, many years
had gone by.
Father, look how far Mt Burhan is.
Tomorrow it will be out of sight.
Nevertheless...
its spirit will watch over us.
The first Mongol was born there.
His destiny given by the gods.
The Blue Wolf.
'The Blue Wolf'?
Yes.
He crossed the great lake,
and made the White Deer his wife.
Batachikan was their child.
Through generations
his blood is ours.
Temujin...
yours, too.
His blood flows in me, too?
A drink called 'wine',
from beyond the Uyghur lands.
Do you like it?
Many are the rarities of a land
that prospers on trade.
And where are you bound?
I am in search of a wife
for my son.
We will look among his mother's kin,
the Olkhunut.
My daughter Borte.
I dreamed last night.
You did?
A white hawk struck the sun and moon.
Then perched on my arm.
I'd just finished telling Borte
a White hawk was a good omen.
Had I not?
Father!
That's the third time
you've said that today!
But now I understand.
The white hawk announced
you would visit with your son.
It's so quiet...
It seems there's no war here.
Have you been in battle?
Not yet.
But I want to, soon, and avenge
the wrongs done to my tribe.
Borte!
Hello.
Who's he?
My affianced.
He is?
I am Jamuqa of the Jadirat,
childhood friend to Borte.
I am Temujin of the Mongols.
I'll be here for a while.
I greet you.
Shall we compete with the bow?
The bow?
What skill!
None of us can shoot like that.
My ancestors are Mongol. Too.
Let us vow friendship.
A vow?
All right.
As of today we are friends
bound closer than brothers.
I will never betray you.
I will treasure your friendship.
While I have life,
there is friendship between us.
I so swear!
I want to make the Mongols
into one nation.
'Nation'?
What's that?
All the tribes united in one.
Can that be done?
Look.
The land of Jin.
One khan rules it all.
One?
But they're enemies.
Think about it. Temujin.
We've always been nomads,
at war with each other.
If we keep doing that,
the Mongols will be destroyed.
Someone has to unite us
into a rich land of peace.
I see...
You think about things like that...
Temujin!
Munrik! Didn't you go home
with my father?
Temujin...
I'm sorry. The Tatars
have poisoned your father.
Poisoned?
How is he?
He's dead!
My father...
Murdered?!
Temujin arrived back
five days after the funeral.
Talgutei of the Tayichi'ut
had announced himself...
Yesukhei's successor.
He was taking the clan
and leaving.
Nothing keeps us here!
Follow the Onon River
to new pastures!
Go, and do not stop your horses!
What's going on?!
Why?
Why are you leaving?
Where are you going?
What's happened?
Why are you going?!
We mustn't leave here!
Hurry!
He's a traitor!
Go back!
Temujin!
Withdraw!
Talgutei! You betray
my father Yesukhei!
Silence, boy!
You are no Mongol.
In your blood is the filth of Merkit.
Are you mad?
I am son to Yesukhei Baghatur!
None recognizes you as heir.
Your mother lay with a Merkit.
Who would follow one born
of such a woman?
Temujin!
Temujin, no!
Talgutei!
Neither I nor the clan of Yesukhei
will forget this treachery!
Nor I your Merkit blood!
Left behind by the tribe...
we had to forage for our food.
Hey!
What are you doing?!
We divide the game with the rest.
That's the rule!
I don't take orders from a Merkit!
What?!
Temujin...
your mother was pregnant by a Merkit
when she was taken.
The child was you!
Belgutei! Your sword!
Draw!
Come at me!
Well?
Scared?
See? You are Merkit scum!
Bekhter!
No, Temujin!
Please!
Bekhter, while you're here,
we will not be united.
The family will fall apart,
and we won't survive.
So I will kill you.
Bekhter!
Run! They'll kill you!
Not him.
Just you.
You two...
what have you done?!
Temujin!
Qasar!
A brother who shared your blood...
one of your few allies...
you've killed him!
Perhaps he would drive us apart...
but still!
It wasn't only that.
He...
insulted you.
Insulted me?
So I killed him.
He showed no mercy...
to one who disobeyed,
or one who betrayed.
That...
never changed in all his life.
These walls won't hold long
if the Tayichi'ut attack.
I know. They're to buy time for
the women and children to get clear.
None of the Borjigin like
how Talgutei runs things.
They'll all come back.
Just like I did.
Munrik, I'm grateful you brought
your people with you.
We've been robbed!
Horse thieves!
Horse thieves?!
How many?
How many head?
Eight. While I wasn't looking.
They can't have gone far.
It wasn't just one man. I'll go.
Brother! I'll go instead.
We can't fight without horses.
I'll get them back.
Steal my horses, will you?
Horse thief!
Wait! It's not how you think!
Then how is it?
The thieves passed here this morning.
I've had horses stolen before,
so I went out to scare them away.
They took off and left those horses.
They're yours...
Yes. I'll have them back.
Take them!
Just lower your bow, p lease.
Are you Temujin?
How did you know?
Word gets around.
The Tayichi'ut betrayed you,
and you don't have many men.
We're few in number,
but we fear no one.
Good. There are still ways to fight
when you are few.
Take your horses.
I will thank you in good time.
Now I need every horse I have.
I'll wait. There are many ways
to show gratitude.
I'll look forward to it.
I am Bo'orchu.
'Bo'orchu'? I won't forget.
The next year,
to collect his bride...
Temujin went after seven years
to Dei Seichun of the Onggirat.
Temujin!
You're alive!
I heard you had been killed
by the Tayichi'ut.
For seven years
we heard nothing.
Borte was passing marriage age.
I arranged for another groom.
I'm sorry.
My father was killed,
my clan scattered...
I never forgot her.
And now you've come...
Who will she marry?
Jamuqa. He asked for her.
Jamuqa?
I see...
Jamuqa...
Temujin!
I came when I heard you were here.
Jamuqa!
It's been years!
Congratulations.
You've seen Borte?
No. I'm leaving now.
Make her happy.
Temujin, I don't want this
to end our friendship.
Let's have Borte decide
which of us she wants.
Borte...
which of us do you choose?
We leave it to you.
Speak.
Well, Borte?
Temujin, or me?
Borte, are you sure?
Are you really sure?
You chose me!
You're beautiful.
Temujin, I've betrayed you
in my heart.
You have?
It's true my father wished it...
but I decided...
I'd be Jamuqa's wife.
I betrayed the one who said
he would come for me.
Borte, I am the one at fault.
With my father dead...
betrayed by the Tayichi'ut...
thinking only of keeping
my family and clan alive...
I left you without word of me
for seven years.
You didn't know
if I was alive or dead.
Who can blame you?
Borte...
forgive me.
You must forgive me.
I should not have lost faith
in you.
But Temujin,
you have betrayed me as well.
I have?
Yes.
Why were you leaving without seeing me?
Because you were to be married
to Jamuqa, my sworn friend.
He would have made you happy.
Why did you not raise your voice
and cry out, 'Borte is my wife!'
'This must not be!'
This is the same
lack of faith as mine.
The same betrayal.
It pained me.
Borte...
I'll make up for it.
On my life,
I will make up for my betrayal.
You won't be hurt again.
I promise.
Mother...
this is Borte.
I greet you. Mother.
You've come far.
My younger brothers...
and sister Temulen.
Hello, Temulen.
Come this way.
You help with her luggage.
Temujin!
Well! Bo'orchu!
You've brought a pretty wife!
Welcome!
I came while you were gone.
To collect my reward.
What would you like?
Let me join you. I want to be more
than chief of a small clan.
Is that all?
I grant it gladly.
I want someone who sees things
differently from me.
You'll be perfect.
This is where you will live.
It has all the household things.
I hope you'll like it.
It will be fine, Mother.
Borte...
will one who has lacked for nothing
be able to stand poverty like ours?
Not just poverty.
Constant threat of attack,
I'm also told.
But beside the pain of being apart
for seven years...
that is nothing.
Thank you.
While there are more of us
than there were...
and life is better...
the Tayichi'ut, the Tatars,
or the Merkit...
would overwhelm us
with a real attack...
He will protect us.
I will never suffer again.
He promised me that.
My heart is at ease.
Two years later, seeking ties
with Toghrul, Khan of the Kerait...
Temujin set off bearing tribute.
You are Temujin?
I have heard your name.
It is an honor to meet you.
And what brings you here today?
When my father Yesukhei died.
He said in his will...
that I should seek the aid
of Toghrul Khan.
Yesukhei Baghatur
was my sworn friend.
Today, honoring my pledge
to my father...
I bring a treasure of my house,
a robe of black sable...
and present it to you
in his name.
A robe...
of black sable?
Well!
A gift indeed!
How do you come to have
such a thing as this?
My wife brought it as dowry.
I see...
Temujin!
Sire!
Support me, and be loyal.
And for my part.
I will keep you safe.
And then. That fall...
Grant us...
the blessings...
of nature.
What's that noise?
Temujin! Wake up!
Everyone!
I hear horses!
Listen...
take Mother and hide in the woods.
Husband!
Just stay calm
and do what we've planned.
The enemy!
To arms!
The Tayichi'ut!
It's the Tayichi'ut!
Don't panic!
They're still a distance away!
Stay calm and get ready to leave!
Tolui!
How many?
Five or six hundred.
Chief!
They're Tayichi'ut!
Brother!
Five or six hundred of them.
We proceed as planned.
We're only 50.
We can't meet them head-on.
Delay them with small groups.
Munrik...
Have the women ride into the hills.
Carts for those who can't ride.
No baggage.
The enemy!
They're coming!
Borte?
Where's Borte?
I'll call her.
Ma'am!
You must leave!
We cannot retreat with you here.
Borte's not here.
I'll send her on another cart.
Take them away.
Chief! They're not Tayichi'ut.
They're Merkit!
Retreat!
Burn everything!
Wreck it all!
Mother!
The attackers were Merkit.
Merkit?
They came from
the wrong direction.
And the bows are different.
So he came...
Mother!
Temujin!
You're safe?
Good.
Is everyone all right?
We did not lose a man!
Against a force ten times ours.
That is a miracle.
Rejoice!
Temujin!
Isn't Borte with you?
Borte?
She's not here?
Coaquchin said
she was already gone.
She's not here...
I see...
That's what they wanted.
I'll go find her!
No! Stop!
Stand back!
You'll get killed!
Move!
Brother!
Without our Chief, we are lost!
Move!
Chief!
Temujin!
So it's true...
that Father took you
from the Merkit?
So after 20 years...
this is their revenge?
Since I was small,
I've been told I was of Merkit seed.
But I didn't believe it.
Mother, I want you to tell me.
Am I of Merkit blood? Or...
Enough!
You shame Mother!
Tell me.
Am I not Father's child?
No more!
Why raise this now?
Elder Brother though you are...
you will not speak of it again!
Temujin...
it is you who must prove
you are son to Yesukhei Baghatur.
Not me.
Your father never once
spoke to me of doubt...
about your birth.
He believed that one day
you would prove...
yours was the blood of the Blue Wolf.
Mother...
Qasar...
this tragedy must not be repeated.
Join with Temujin...
and bring Borte back
as soon as you can.
Father...
tell me.
What am I?
Does your blood not flow in me?
With no way to strike back,
six months went by.
Borte is my wife.
I will take her back.
I understand how you feel...
but we are 300 to their 3,000.
We cannot win.
Seek help from Toghrul.
Brother, send a messenger
to Jamuqa as well.
Chief, you cannot leave her there
for too long.
After a year. Or two,
if she bears Merkit children...
she cannot return.
We must decide now, Chief.
Go to Toghrul and Jamuqa.
Thank you.
I am pleased.
I will take command.
Is that agreed?
Yes.
We should attack by night,
with you on the right flank, Sire.
Of course.
We will attack from the hills behind.
Temujin, you take the front.
Sire...
will you lend me 500 of your men?
300 is not enough
for a frontal attack.
Fine.
Take my best men.
In return, I will take
seven parts of the spoils...
Jamuqa two...
and you will content yourself
with one.
Only two parts? I withdraw!
Wait!
I need nothing.
It is only with your help
I can strike at the Merkit.
I beg your indulgence.
Charge!
Where is Borte?!
Borte!
Forward!
Temujin!
We know which way she's gone!
Borte!
It's Temujin!
How many men?
About ten!
Leave her! Withdraw!
Borte!
After them!
Borte?
Is that you?
What's wrong?
Have you forgotten me?
I'm your husband.
Husband...
I've missed you.
Bring her.
Cart and all!
Temujin...
this happens to Mongol women.
Let it pass.
We've got him!
On your feet!
This is Chiled! He took Lady Borte.
Yesukhei Baghatur
took Hoelun from me!
This was my revenge!
You?
Damn you!
He's dead!
He's dead.
The victory celebration
went on for three days and nights.
Look at you!
We're all here, and still alive!
Chief! Sit with us and drink!
I will.
Bo'orchu!
To your courage
and quick thinking in battle.
Blessings on you!
Belgutei.
To your skill with the sword.
Qasar,
there is no archer like you.
Blessings on you!
Munrik!
Guardian of my house!
For your generosity and wisdom...
blessings on you!
Jelme!
For your arrowheads and spears
that fell our enemies...
I thank Tengri.
Blessings on you!
A son is born!
He's sure to kill this child.
I won't let him.
It's me.
Borte, give me the child.
To do what?
Will you embrace this child?
Don't be a fool!
A Merkit child? I'll kill it.
What makes you so sure
it's a Merkit child?
Anyway, it's a girl.
Will you kill even a girl?
A girl?
I heard it was a boy.
Is this true?
Then I will spare her.
But I never want to set eyes on her.
But if...
it were a boy?
'If'?
So it is a boy...
Then it dies.
Give it to me.
A child is a blessing from Tengri.
You must not kill it.
I'm not killing a child.
I'm killing a Merkit.
Temujin, a newborn child
has not sinned.
Do you lack the generosity
to raise it as your own?
Your father was not that way.
If he had killed you
as a Merkit child...
you would not be here.
It is women who suffer most
from this cycle of rape and revenge.
Would you also then
take away Borte's child, Temujin?
I do not blame Borte.
I let her be taken.
While I lead this tribe...
no woman will be taken as spoils
ever again.
Then accept the child.
Give him a name.
Husband. Please.
Give this child a name.
'Jochi'.
Yes.
His name will be 'Jochi'.
'Jochi'?
'Outsider'.
Born an outsider...
The poor child!
I don't care what he's called.
At least now he will live.
Isn't that so...
Jochi?
War leaves great scars
on the defeated.
And the victorious tribe
grows ever stronger.
The name 'Temujin the Mighty'
spread far and wide...
and every year more clans
flocked to him.
Toghrul Khan, I am honored
you have come so far.
A fine camp!
Temujin, you have come far.
A messenger has come from
the court of Jin.
They are delayed in
their conquest of the Tatars.
They ask my help.
Temujin, will you
strike at the Tatars with me?
The name 'Jin' alone
makes me tremble with rage.
But Temujin,
the Tatars are the enemy...
who poisoned your father.
Close your eyes to Jin
and join me against the Tatars.
And by vanquishing the Tatars...
great treasure will be ours!
Toghrul Khan...
why do you ask me...
and not Jamuqa?
Because of your spirit.
Temujin, I will pay well
for your strength.
Now...
the time has come to smite...
our eternal enemies, the Tatars!
They betrayed our second Khan
to Jin...
killed our third...
and poisoned our fourth,
my father.
While the Tatars remain.
Our forefathers will not sleep.
Are you with me?!
Let us unite...
annihilate the Tatars
and put our ancestors to rest!
The strategy used
put the army of Jin at the front...
while Temujin and Toghrul
attacked the Tatars from behind.
After ten days of fighting...
the Tatars were all but destroyed.
Chief... the Khan returns.
Well! Temujin!
We're celebrating with some hunting.
I am glad to hear it.
I will take my army
and return home...
dealing with Tatar stragglers
along the way.
Oh?
You're leaving?
Come with me.
Temujin...
In this war I have seen
how powerful you are.
Right now you could
defeat Jamuqa with ease.
Jamuqa?
Temujin, crush Jamuqa now.
Or one day he will attack you.
Never!
We are friends pledged to a vow.
What vow?
To unite the Mongols.
That is our dream.
Jamuqa is not dreaming
that dream.
All he is capable of
is wishing himself the greatest.
In any event,
you and Jamuqa...
cannot go forward together.
I am also in his debt
for my wife, Borte.
I cannot fight my sworn friend.
Excuse me.
Brother!
Yes, Teichal?
I'm just leaving.
A word first.
What is it?
I'm surprised you're so calm.
Calm? About what?
Temujin has joined with Toghrul,
and left you out.
Let him die fighting who he wishes.
The Mongols do not need two khans.
Exactly.
He wishes to leave you aside...
and rule himself.
Impossible!
He is a man who goes to war
over one lone woman.
Women are for pleasure...
or for bearing children.
There's always another.
A king cannot have feelings.
Temujin loves Borte.
Your vow of friendship
trips you up as well.
That vow did not come from trust.
It came from fear of betrayal.
It was a child's game.
Chief! There are riders ahead.
Tatars?
Merkit stragglers. I think.
Whoever they are, crush them!
Wait!
A woman?
Name?
State your name!
Kill me.
I don't kill women.
I have lost.
Kill me. I am a soldier.
Enough. Take off that armor
and relax.
Don't touch me!
You will not have me.
Men are all the same.
They violate women,
and make them bear children.
My father and brother are dead.
I am head of my house.
I will suffer woman's grief no more.
I see...
What can you do?
Fight in battle.