As the elders explain it,
every story begins and ends
at the crossing of two paths.
So, for some, this story begins
on the shores of France.
Two men, once enemies, whose
paths first  crossed in battle,
now face different roads
in their journey as friends.
Tarik.
This won't be the same without you.
What will I do with myself
when you're not praying five times a day?
Do exactly the same thing you
would do when I was praying.
That's impossible. 'Cause I
was stealing your food.
Come with me to England.
Come with me to Spain. We'll
find El Cabillo together.
We'll continue our adventures.
I can't. The only adventure
I seek at the moment
are two head of cattle
and an acre of farmland.
Always the hopeless romantic.
Hey.
I hate it when you do that!
Others said it began the same day
with the escape of Father Bernard.
I was going to tie your feet together,
but I want to see you kick!
The shepherd on the run from his flock.
But most say it began right here in England
with the disappearance of Princess Lunna
on the eve of her wedding.
Come here!
Would you look at this?
I'm busy.
Come here. You really need to see this.
Maybe the old rope trick.
The old rope trick.
Praise God, my son.
You saved my, my...
You are a Moor!
So, Tarik headed off to
Spain in search for adventure
and the legendary mercenary El Cabillo.
Whilst George rowed him to England.
The word of God warms the soul,
but good wine warms the belly.
No.
I have to ask you, uh, about, uh...
How did a Christian knight
befriend a Muslim Moor?
That's quite simple, really.
Tried to cut my head off.
I was in Jerusalem, in the
ruins of a small building
with two Arab men. One was dead.
The other was mortally wounded.
I was kneeling over the man
when Tarik came into the building.
And why didn't he kill you?
Because he realized I wasn't
trying to kill the man.
I was giving him water
to ease his suffering.
The man was Tarik's own brother.
So, uh, what are your plans now?
Hopefully find a quiet place to settle down.
Perhaps find a wife.
But first, I have family to visit.
Here in the forest, men search
for the missing Princess.
None more so than Lord de Gurney.
For he had much to lose.
The King had given him the Princess's hand,
and once wed, he would have
the power and riches he coveted.
Whether the Princess loved him or not,
he would marry her and rule the kingdom.
But no one thought "dragon."
They had long since become legend.
But looking back, this story really began
when George returned to the village of Loar,
and our paths crossed for the first time.
Are you lost, sir? And where is your horse?
I'm not lost, and I have no horse.
I'm here to find Sir Robert.
He'll be old now.
He's still there, and he's
still old. I'm Wryn.
George.
Very pleased to meet you, Wryn.
Sir Robert?
Oh, I'll take you to him.
Thank you, kind sir.
You be careful with that lance, boy.
Hello? Is there anybody home?
My eyes may be weak, but even after 15 years
I know the voice of my own
son! Come here, my boy!
I never gave up hope. I knew you'd come back.
So often I dreamt I was there,
fighting alongside of you!
Sir Robert, may we come in?
Yes, yes, come in. My son,
the hero. Prepare a feast.
Shall we cook him first
or eat him on the hoof?
I don't know, Bulchar,
he looks a little tough.
He might need a little tenderizing.
So you are the famous El Cabillo.
I was hoping you could teach me something.
If you're looking
for a teacher, you've
made a very poor choice.
I only have 4 lessons, and sadly
my students always seem to fail.
Get this man a weapon.
This better be worth my while.
Lesson number 1 – Always
expect the unexpected.
And I thought this was going to be easy.
Oh, it's gonna be easy all right.
Lesson number 2 - Never take
your eyes off your opponent.
Lesson number 3 – Never
underestimate your opponent.
Well, Moor, that's the best you got?
Our lessons are almost over.
Lesson number 4.
Always cheat.
Best stick with your bow, son.
Is it true that the Muslims eat the
heart and liver of the knights they kill?
No, no. They only eat the heart.
The liver they feed to the horses.
Give them no mind, Wryn.
I wish I'd been there with you.
What's that?
It's a curious thing, isn't it?
It was given to me by a Muslim friend.
A Muslim friend? Surely your jest.
No, Father.
It looks like the Devil's pitchfork.
Then that's what I should call it. A pitch.
Where will adventure take you next, my son?
Well, Father. I... I want to settle down.
Nonsense! Settle down!
You've got two perfectly good legs.
My blood running through your
veins. The blood of conquest!
Oh, Father. I was thinking of
trying to find some land.
Perhaps north of the Grampians.
Still a hopeless romantic.
You'd be wiser to go East. Fewer brigands.
And no dragons.
You're still telling tall stories
of dragons, Father, huh?
Not tall stories. Facts. Dragons.
The most fearsome creatures
whoever walked this earth.
And there's still one out
there. As you know by this...
The lance.
The other end of it is still stuck
fast inside of her, yes?
Aye. And one day, lad, you'll
go bring that half back to me.
I think you may finally
be ready for this gift.
Something I've been saving for you.
A dragon horn.
Made from a claw from its foot.
Makes a sound only a dragon can hear.
And you saw this dragon, Sir Robert,
with your own two eyes?
With my own two legs, to be more precise.
Whatever you say, Father.
I appreciate this gift.
But my days of conquest are over.
To England!
Gently, gently. All right,
put it down. There we go.
Now, when you arrive in Crail, find
King Edgaar. He's a good man.
Edgaar will recognize that dragon
horn I gave you and know I sent you.
Will he have some land?
If that's what you seek. But I
know what lies inside you.
Here. Farewell, mother.
George.
Goodbye, Father.
Fare ye well. All of you.
Come!
If anyone here were half the man I am,
we might still have a princess.
Okay. Come on, everyone. There's
another way round we can go.
Ouch!
He could chop my firewood.
See the two-headed goats.
Just one tin Sovereign.
Oh!
see what you think about that.
Nothing like a drop of ale to wash
the dust of the road from your throat.
You're right there, sir. I'll
Tell You something, too.
The finest ale this side of the
Grampians. Thank you.
Could you tell me where I
might find King Edgaar?
The King? Uh, well,
normally he'd be, he'd be right
over there enjoying a drink.
The King, here?
Oh, yes. Yes, yes, yes.
When I say my ale is fit
for a king, I mean it.
I was told he may have
some land he could sell.
I'm afraid you've had a long journey,
And it may have been wasted.
You see, the thing is, three days ago
the King got word that his
daughter disappeared.
Not been out of the house. I doubt
he will be 'til she's found.
It's a bad business.
I have some time to kill.
Anyone wanting to buy land around here,
must have a fair few coins in his purse.
Not as many as you think, friend.
My friends here would all
like another tankard of ale.
Let's just check those coins
again. See if we can't...
I don't think you want any trouble.
I wouldn't mind some.
Be very careful what you wish for.
Lord de Gurney!
I suggest you remember your place.
Batley, my Lord. He put me up
to it. It was all his big idea.
Get out of here.
Lord de Gurney.
George of Loack.
I can arrange a meeting with the
King if you like. After you.
Thank you, my Lord.
What news, Lord de Gurney?
None yet, sire. But my men
and I will continue to search.
Was there no sign of her at all?
No, Sire.
But I am convinced it was the Picts.
Picts? Those savages!
They could do anything to
her. Anything at all!
Mark my words, sire. I will
get her back unharmed.
She is your daughter, but she's
also my betrothed.
Then I will join you. For Princess
Lunna I'd follow the Devil himself.
Sire, I fear it might be
a little too dangerous...
Any man who joins in the search
for my daughter has my blessing.
Um, perhaps, my liege, I
may be of some assistance.
My Lord, may I introduce Sir...
My Lord, if I may be so bold.
This is my introduction.
The dragon horn!
How did you come by this? Is Sir Robert dead?
Oh, no. No, my good Lord. He's old but well.
And prays for your good health and long life.
Come here. Come closer.
I'd know those eyes anywhere. You must be...
George. Yes, I'm son of Sir Robert.
Nothing could delight me more than to
know that the son of my old comrade in arms
is joining the search. There is a
reward, you know. Money is no object.
No, my Lord, I seek only one thing.
Just a small parcel of land. Enough for
a cottage, a garden, two head of cattle.
Your modesty touches me.
Do you think it's too late?
Sire, I'm sure she's fine.
I'll wager there isn't a Pict
within a day's ride of her.
It must be the horses.
So, we took the better half a day
to get around a tree, did we?
If I had a coin for every time you were
late, I could pave this country in gold.
I'm sorry, sir. It took a little
Longer than we thought.
We have no time for chitchat, D'Arcy.
We have to make camp by daybreak.
Let's see what England has to offer us.
Let's go!
Would you care for some liquorice?
Thank you.
It must be an acquired taste.
And has the Princess Lunna
acquired the taste?
I do believe she has.
Then you're destined to be together.
Is there a princess in your life?
No.
No. All the women I've come across
are more trouble than they're worth.
Then you most certainly
have not met my Lunna.
She is as gentle and agreeable as a lamb.
I should look forward to
making her acquaintance.
Oh!
Dismount.
I have scoured these woods for
tracks, and I found none.
So, the Picts have wings?
No, they have boats.
They came from the water while the
Princess was in the lake.
And they will never suspect
we have them, too.
We do?
I see nothing but trees.
And from trees come boats.
All right, you men dismount.
Fell the timber here.
You men from here rear-ward, take your
horses and drag the poles to the lake.
And you, give me another roll of liquorice.
Care for another, George?
No, no. You keep it for yourself, my Lord.
Stand aside.
Yes, my Lord.
Shall we?
Garth? Appears we may have some company.
George, take this with you.
This is getting us nowhere.
Having fun?
Can I borrow this?
Thank you.
Elm's gone looking for trouble.
Can you look after these?
I don't need you. Just your ax.
Ax and you shall receive.
No! Come back! My sword!
You all right, Elm?
I surely had them on the run.
No, you nearly got yourself killed.
You're lucky I saw you leave.
Not that lucky, I'm afraid.
Come on.
Come on. Now get up!
Get out of here!
Whoever you are, we consider you a friend.
Please, show yourself.
I know this young archer.
Wryn!
If you don't show yourself,
I'll slice up your liver
and have it for dinner.
You wouldn't really eat my liver, would you?
I've half a mind to do exactly
that. Now come down here.
What are you doing here?
You looked like you could use some help.
We were in a bit of a bind.
I'm Wryn from Loar.
Elmendorf of Crail. Good to
meet you, young Wryn.
I've heard of Loar.
Do you mind?
Now we have to take this child back to Loar.
You can't take me back.
You need me. I saved your life.
The boy does have a point.
Have you both taken leave of your senses?
This journey is far too dangerous
to be undertaken by a child.
We can take him as far as the
abbey of Saint Germain. Near Torgyle.
Well, you leave us little choice now.
Wonderful! Let's get back to the camp
and we'll retrieve the cart
and Princess Lunna's things,
and then I won't have to ride
that infernal horse any longer.
Come on.
I swear, I swear. We haven't
got anything of value here.
Your eyes tell me you're lying.
My mouth's telling the truth.
Honestly, we've got nothing!
Go on.
No, no, please! Don't hang me upside down!
Get nose bleeds.
I can smell a lie like horses
smell water. Do it!
No, no! Look...
Even the King's daughter's disappeared.
She was the only valuable thing we had.
Wait.
A Princess?
Yeah.
A ransom?
Yeah, a great big ransom. Apparently,
a knight's gone looking for her.
He didn't want the reward. All
he wanted was... What was it?
Oh, yeah. A little parcel of
land and two head of cattle.
What a fool, eh? You'd take the
money, wouldn't you?
Let's find the Princess. String him up.
What? No, that's no fair!
No! I'm getting a nose bleeding.
I knew I would. I told them!
George!
Those Picts weren't so tough after all.
I'm sure they didn't fare any better
against Lord de Gurney, either.
What is that?
How old is it?
Ten days.
Yuk!
Maybe a fortnight.
Anything wrong?
No, no.
Just thinking we need to move on.
We'll stop here.
The sky is clearing. Be
able to see the stars soon.
My father once said if I was worthy enough,
they'd name one of those after me.
What's that? Over there.
It's a fire.
We should break camp.
Wryn, what are you doing? Stay here.
Stay here.
Oy!
Useless.
Try that again, and there's
another one where that came from.
Get away from that.
No, you get away!
Princess Lunna, thank God you're
safe! You've no idea wha...
Princess Lunna?
This is the little lamb we've come to find?
Oh, Elm, I knew you'd come.
Subdue this fool. This one.
Holding the sword which is too large for him.
No, no, no, Princess, you don't understand.
Your father sent this fool.
This gentleman, Sir George, to find you.
Oh.
Very well, but no one
is going to harm this egg.
What kind of egg is that?
It's a dragon's egg. And its name is Smite.
May I touch it?
Wryn! You stay put.
I'm getting you out of here, and
then I'm gonna destroy that thing.
You're not getting me anywhere. I was
doing perfectly well until you showed up.
Really?
Because you look very cold
and extremely hungry to me.
I've got something for you.
Wryn, come and help me.
Sh! Don't speak to me.
I wasn't planning on it.
If you came to kill a dragon,
you came to the wrong place.
I came to find you.
Where there's a baby, there's a mother.
Adelaide died.
Adelaide?
That's what I called her.
She had a terrible wound.
Two days ago, she just crawled off
into the lake and didn't come back.
Smite may be the last dragon God ever
creates, and I intend to protect him.
Oh!
So, you are hungry.
Perhaps.
I might just have something for you.
I'd eat anything.
Ugh!
It's liquorice. Garth told me...
Garth? He doesn't know the
first thing about me.
That's the worst substance I've ever eaten.
Very well put.
Lunna, I brought some of your things
from the campsite. There you are.
And I've brought you a
Special piece of venison.
Oh, Elm, you always were so thoughtful.
Wryn, thank you.
Hey.
You scared me.
Sorry.
It's gonna be a long day tomorrow.
Better get some rest.
Elm.
You know we can't let it live, don't you?
I don't suppose we...
No.
I'll do the dirty work.
Mmm.
Tell me Wryn,
do you hope one day to be a
hired killer like Sir George?
I'd like to be a knight if that's
what you're asking. It sounds like fun.
Nothing fun about killing,
Wryn. It's very dirty.
Deeply unpleasant.
And not something I recommend
to anyone at all.
What about you, George?
Aren't you so in the business of killing?
I hardly call it a business.
My father must be paying you a fortune.
If you can call an acre of land and
two head of cattle a fortune, then yes.
How curious. A knight who doesn't seek fame,
a mercenary who doesn't seek fortune.
Why did you follow this path?
I had no choice.
My path was set down
for me before I was born.
You don't have a choice now?
No, I have a duty.
A duty of honor.
To honor my father, to honor my oath.
Perhaps that doesn't make much sense
to a spoiled little Princess.
Most of us can't be quite as
frivolous as we might like.
But I suppose that, too,
for a girl like you,
is rather difficult to understand.
Then I don't suppose you
understand me at all.
Elm, are you sure we can't
push the cart up the hill?
I'm afraid not. It's far too steep.
Then you must promise me to be very careful.
I promise.
Should we clear a path in there?
Oh, no! Not now!
I hope nothing happens to it.
I've never seen a real dragon.
Oh, no! Don't you dare!
As the daughter of the King, for the last
time I order you not to harm this egg! Ugh!
That's twice! I cannot believe
you've done that again!
Enough is enough.
One day you'll thank me for this.
I'm not leaving without Smite.
The riders are coming.
I'm not leaving without him!
Oh! Hang it all!
All right. All right.
But if that thing slows us down,
I swear to you, you'll be the only
one in England wearing dragon skin shoes!
Understood?
Yeah.
Why me?
Elm?
Elm, are you alright?
George?
George? Watch out for the trees!
Ohh...
Darling, are you all right?
I think I'm fine. Thank you.
My little sweetheart.
You brought the egg right to the cart.
Thank you, Elm.
It would be nice if someone else noticed.
All right. You've got to get
Smite into the cart.
The cart happens to be full of your dresses.
Now it'll fit.
I suppose we'd better get the egg.
Uh-huh.
Let's go.
Ah!
Wryn, have you ever seen one of these?
Wow! It's better than a bucket of water.
Torgyle's about a day's ride from here.
They'll run us down long before then.
Thanks to that, we're going
slower than a snail's pace.
Maybe we should head towards the mountains.
We have to stay near the
lake in case it hatches.
And that might be soon.
Smells like a princess.
An interesting relic. It
could be worth something.
I'll tell you when I've sold it.
We're going north.
Mountain path.
Lake path.
Which way?
We need to buy some time.
We can't tell which way
they went. Should we split up?
We have to.
Take four men and... Wait. There.
Very clumsy. They make this too easy!
It's that sound again.
He's not going to stay in there much longer.
This blanket isn't big enough.
I don't suppose we could use your...
No, I don't suppose we could.
What is this?
They took the lake road.
Come on!
I still can't believe you're here.
What's this. Have you kidnapped the King?
Cousin, calm down.
Concentrate. Say "rabbits and radishes."
It works.
She's all right. Let her go.
I was trying to say
that you're smothering me.
Sorry. I couldn't risk being heard.
What is that?
Dear cousin, we have a small problem.
It's a big problem. It's a small dragon.
That's about to hatch.
It's a dragon's egg.
Sister Angela?
Is it you causing all this commotion?
And who, may I ask, are your visitors?
Mother Margaret, this is my beloved
cousin, the Princess Lunna.
Oh, my good Lord. What
in heaven's name is that?
It's a dragon's egg, Mother Superior.
What? But... Wh... How is that possible?
I thought they'd been extinct
for hundreds of years.
It may be the last of its kind.
I feel compelled to take it to safety
where it can be no harm to anyone.
And where may that be?
I understand her point, Mother, but
I fear there is no such place.
It's my belief that this
egg should be destroyed.
I'm afraid I agree with you, sir.
Sister Angela, your friends
are very welcome here,
but that creature, whatever
it is, certainly is not.
See that it is dispatched
as soon as possible.
Please, Mother Margaret.
It's for the best. Only God
knows what havoc it will cause
when it hatches. Now, sir.
Actually,
I am of a different opinion.
I don't believe my eyes!
You know each other?
We did some boating together at one time.
Now these are your friends?
Mother Margaret and I met many, many,
many years ago.
One "many" would've been quite sufficient.
And so, this is your path
to peace and tranquility?
I got a little sidetracked.
It would've been a little less dangerous
if I'd gone after El Cabillo with Tarik.
Mother Margaret,
something is not evil just because
we don't understand it.
Besides, the Princess has a unique understanding of Creation.
I, for one, am going to listen to her.
But, Father Bernard.
And as someone else who has a big heart,
I think you should listen to her, as well.
Very well. On your own head be it.
But no one else, except for those
of us here, can know about it.
It must hidden in the stables 'til
morning, and it must be gone by then.
It will be. I promise.
Oh, oh. Forgive me, Mother.
That's quite all right, child.
Restraint is a virtue only
thrust upon the elderly.
May God be with you.
Wryn.
Sir?
Your poor tunic, it's ruined.
We can find something more appropriate
for you when we get inside.
He's a rather handsome
escort, isn't he, cousin?
I don't know what you mean.
What?
Um, the tie of my dress...
Would you just...
Yes, of course.
Just tuck it in here?
Princess Lunna, they told
me you'd arrived safely.
My Lord.
My Lord de Gurney. Good to see you again.
George.
Where did your adventures take you?
Most likely on the same
roads that you've traveled.
I see you've caught the prize.
It's really not important who
found her. Just that she's safe.
Now we can take her back to
her father together.
Aren't you forgetting something, George?
Forgetting what?
Our little secret.
Oh, no. No, it's really
not what you're thinking.
Could you excuse us while we have a word?
Do not let me interfere.
Thank you. A word.
I'm not giving that egg.
You'd think they were married,
the way they're carrying on.
Lunna?
Lunna!
I am so relieved that you
returned to me safe and sound.
Are you relieved that I'm safe?
Or are you relieved we can finally
move forward with your plans?
That you're safe, of course! Why?
Don't you even wonder what happened to me?
I'd a lot of time to think while
I was away, and I've come to a conclusion.
I will not marry you.
You can't be serious.
Your father promised me your hand.
I don't love you. I never did.
Lunna,
this is not only about love.
This is about the solvency of our kingdom.
When I marry, it will be about love.
This is about him, isn't it?
I made my decision long before I met George.
You just weren't listening.
Elm?
When will they be wed?
Lunna and Garth? Soon, very soon.
George, there's something you must know.
Since the Crusades, our kingdom
has suffered a great deal.
Kind Edgaar felt the need
for a strong successor.
Someone who may not be as benevolent as he.
One who could unify our people.
Garth is that man.
And the King asked his daughter
to marry him. She agreed.
Because, unlike what you thought,
she's not selfish and spoiled.
And preserving this egg, well,
it's the first thing she's ever done
that she wasn't told to do.
It is about time.
Sorry, sir.
There's been a development
that I had not counted on.
So I must expedite my plan.
The troops are camped about half a
day's ride from here. What can I do?
I need you to get the troops
to Dunmeade by midmorning.
I will meet you there with the priest.
And when he's performed the ceremony,
we can move on the old King.
Now, I have some work to do here,
so you'll bring the men.
And, D'Arcy, do not be late.
Yes, sir.
Utter a word, and it'll be your last.
Put these on.
Mo...
What in Heaven...
Come on!
It's Lord de Gurney. He's taken
Princess Lunna and Father Bernard.
I think they were tied.
Where?
To the horse.
No. Where did he take them?
The road to Dunmeade.
I'll get the cart.
I'm not taking it. It'll slow us down.
I'm the servant of the Princess.
I vowed to protect her.
All right, all right!
You protect the egg. I'll
rescue the Princess.
Now, go, go!
You'd better try and secure it.
It won't sit still.
Well, do something.
I did it.
Elm!
We'll take him with us.
No, no!
Let me go!
This is not what I had
in mind for our wedding.
But since you would not cooperate,
this is where it's going to be.
Now, move.
You see, that's not consent. I won't do it.
Oh, really?
Kill me if you want. I don't fear death.
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here today...
Yah!
Do you, Garth de...
I do.
Do you, Princess...
She does.
I swear you'll regret this. I don't
love you. I don't even like you.
I agreed to our engagement
only to serve my father.
And a proud father he'll be.
He'll go to the grave knowing his
Kingdom is in good hands.
Come on!
Once we're wed, I will be King,
and you will be my...
Well, George, just in time.
We need a witness.
The only witnessing I'll be
doing is your certain death!
Unless you unhand her.
I'll not only unhand her. I'll
"un-arm" her, "un-leg" her,
and possibly behead her.
Unless you put down that sword.
Now, let's continue, priest. I've had
enough of these rude interruptions.
The riders! The riders,
they're not far behind me.
Captain D'Arcy's arrived on time.
These aren't your men. They've
been chasing us for days.
A bunch of very ugly looking mercenaries.
The kind that take no prisoners.
No.
What kind of fool do you take me for?
Do you think I'm stupid enough to believe that there's a group of mercenaries outside?
Why not? There's an egg the size
of a cow at your feet.
Think about it. When have your men
ever been on time, huh?
They'll kill us all.
All right. Come on, then.
Elm.
I speak for the one who makes God tremble.
Surrender the girl, and live. Refuse,
and die. Start with the boy.
That is hardly a threat. Who cares
if one more peasant boy dies?
Princess, up on the wall.
Father, you go with her.
So, you are the great El Cabillo, huh?
Terrorizer of sheep and chickens.
Wryn, go.
What are you doing in this dreadful
place? Are you crazy?
Risking your life for that skinny girl.
She's got no meat on her bones.
What did I tell you about that?
Back up.
No. Elm!
He's a friend.
And you thought you'd never see me again.
You are El Cabillo?
I became El Cabillo.
How?
I'll show you. Fight me.
It's a curious arrangement.
Whoever beats El Cabillo,
becomes the next El Cabillo.
You killed him?
Come here.
Do you remember lesson number 5?
5? He got that far, did he?
This is a friend of yours?
The best.
Tarik, this is Elmendorf and Wryn.
Oh, and this is Princess Lunna of Crail.
Princess.
Wait a minute.
And I am Lord de Gurney.
My Lord.
Of all people, you showing up here.
I don't know why. When I heard of
a knight who went to save a princess
for an acre of land, two cows, I thought,
"Who would be fool enough to do that?"
I could only think of one person.
Please, let us dispense
with the family reunion.
If those men out there are yours,
then why are they still battle ready?
I have the situation under control.
Under control.
There's nothing here worth dying for.
We'll turn to the South.
I think there is.
You're defying me?
The men are ready for a new leader.
Bulchar, Bulchar.
Under control? You call that under control?
Now we will see what you're made
of. Let's get on with it.
Come here.
Nice horsey.
Wryn, stay here.
Father?
He's alive.
Father!
This isn't blood. This is burgundy.
But there is a big, big hole here.
Come on!
Close the door.
What in the name of Allah...
It's an egg.
A very special egg.
It's under our protection.
Arrows!
Come on.
Elmendorf!
Ready? Go!
There, that should hold them.
Uh-oh.
Be careful.
Already has its teeth.
You see? What did I tell you?
Maybe it's allergic to you.
Gently. Don't go near its mouth.
Smite!
Soldiers. Get them!
Wryn, blow the horn.
We make a good team.
We did.
We can again. Rule with me, George.
I'd rather eat liquorice. Thank you.
Then so be it.
Not so fast.
Try again.
It's working.
Smite!
George!
The trouble with you, Princess,
is you'll always need rescuing.
Hold that.
If you need help, just ask.
I'm so sorry.
Sorry, sir.
Who are you with?
No, who are you with?
Wrong answer. Come on!
Could you please hold my sword?
Thank you.
I'm an inn keeper. I'll give
You free ale for a year.
You are a very good team, aren't you?
Sister!
He's not... He's not going down.
My God, Elm!
Wasn't meant to turn out like this.
I'm tired.
But knowing there's
someone to watch over you
makes this a little easier.
Wryn, I can think of no one
more worthy to take my place
as guardian of the King's household.
You'll grow into it.
Adelaide.
Father!
Oh, my child.
I'm sorry I've caused you so much worry.
Where's George?
George?
George!
Something's fallen against it.
The lance.
It was no fairy tale.
Huh?
Holy Father.
Forgive me for what I am compelled to do.
I will try to make this
as painless as possible.
Oh...
Please, George, you didn't.
To George, the dragon slayer!
You saved us all. You're
Truly a saint, George.
God was on our side today.
I think Allah doesn't pick sides
when men are killing each other, Sister.
I believe that you're right, Tarik.
He was a good man.
A very good man.
I don't think I'll ever be
able to take his place.
It's such a big ring.
I'll stay with you until you grow into it.
You will?
I'll teach you everything I know.
My lance!
Father.
After all these years.
Forgive me.
I'm so sorry I ever doubted you.
Oh, my, boy.
Only you deserve to use this now.
Thank you.
Lunna?
Take my horse.
Good luck.
I may need it.
A perfect fit. I can do this.
Be calm, young knight.
This is a battle George must face alone.
Come on! Come on!
Lunna, keep riding.
Come here!
There is something you should
know about me, George.
I am not a good loser.
You were right to be afraid of me.
George? George?
George! George?
Ouch, ouch!
You didn't kill her!
I can't believe you did that for me.
I did it because of you.
Your absurd ideas,
your unique understanding of creation
began to make sense to me.
No one knows what a hero you really are.
No one can know about this.
If people should find out
that they're still alive,
they'll stop at nothing to kill them.
This must be a secret.
A secret between them...
...and us.
What're you going to do with that?
No one must ever find this.
George?
I heard there was a unicorn
near Glastonebury.
Oh, no, no. No unicorns, no sea monsters.
And certainly no more dragons.
We could just check on it.
It's on the way!
Get your horse.
Action!
You're a Moor.
Yes, I am. Been one for years.
And a big one at that.
You're a Moor.
I am a Moor. My mother was a Moor.
"B" camera.
Three, two, one.
Action!
The only thing I'll be witnessing
is your certain death if less...
Still running. Keep rolling.
Okay. Can we concentrate
now, please? Here we go.
Action!
The only thing I'll be witnessing is
your certain death until... I'm sorry.
Action!
Your absurd ideas.
Your unique understanding... Sorry.
What is wrong with you?
The horse doing a turd. It was in
my peripheral vision. I'm really sorry.
I could pave this entire country with gold.
I'm sorry, sir? It took a little
longer than we thought.
Action!
Still now, please.
No one must ever find this.
Idiot.
Have you both lost leave of your senses?
Sorry.
What news, my Lord?
None yet, your...
My... I'm sorry.
So relieved that you've...
It's an egg...
Action!
I can arrange an introduction...
Can I just say "a meeting"?
I can arrange a meeting
or an introduction with the King if you like.
Lord de Gurney.
George of Littea.
That's it. I can't take any more
Off than this without help.