The disturbing images and speeches in this
film were broadcast uncensored. So it is not suitable for children.
- Come on, we need to shoot!
- I want to stay a little behind...
- Give me the camera so I'll shoot
- No no! You go...
-Slowly Ceyhun...
- Slowly please
- The sound is coming from somewhere around here.
- There is a sound! There is a sound!
- Fuck your mother!
- Ceyhun, this has gotten out of hand. I'm not in anymore! I turn off the camera.
- Hello, I'm Ceyhun. Actually, it was as if I was greeting myself. Because I will not post this video. This will be my digital diary.
- I will do a research for my master thesis. And that research will usually consist of videos.
- Some parts will also consist of video and audio recordings in this way. Maybe I can add some of these videos to my thesis.
- But mostly these videos will stay with me.
- What will my thesis be about? My thesis is about social fears and myths.
- I am investigating the effect of paranormal events that some people believe in, on people who do not believe in paranormal events.
-I will also do research on what looks like paranormal phenomena.
- Unfortunately, it will not be a very unbiased study. because I don't believe in such things and I know that they all have a scientific explanation.
- I want to reveal which scientific situation people think of as a paranormal event.
- I did some research on this subject. I found places on the internet that said don't go here.
- I want to ask questions and interview the people living there about why we shouldn't go in here.
- For these interviews, two of my classmates will help me.
- Murat will shoot with the camera. Kuzey will also help me with interviews.
- In my internet research, I discovered a village called ILICA with terrible rumors and the nearby woodland.
- No one can go out after dark!
- I'm going to go there and talk to the people who live there.
- ( The village has been raided by jinns! )
- I will ask why and why they are afraid.
- Rumors have it that voices are heard, shadows roam and lights are seen from the wooded area at night.
- The interesting thing is that people who have never been there also believe these rumors.
- In fact, this is the main point I want to focus on!
- Because if people psychologically believe in paranormal events, they believe the rumors containing this belief more quickly.
- In this way, people become selective in perception. And they perceive many things as real.
- That's why they think the rumors in this village are true.
- This will be the case I will approach first in my research.
- Secondly, there are scientific studies showing that some electromagnetic perturbations show such hallucinations.
- Magnetic waves delivered to the forebrain can cause hallucinations.
- We know that some sound frequencies that humans cannot hear trigger hallucinations.
- Some chemicals may be intense in the area we are researching.
-there may be carbon monoxide or formaldehyde in that area.
These can also cause hallucinations.
- In the regions where these paranormal events take place, such things can happen frequently.
- I don't have the technical equipment to measure them. So I'll just try to find visual evidence.
- I think a shadow or sound seen there must have misled and frightened people.
- To reveal the truth, I will stay overnight with my friends in the forbidden area. And we will record what we see there with the camera.
- While researching on the internet, I learned that a horror movie was shot in that feared area.
- And I watched this movie (The Torment of Jin). I even talked to Onur Aldoğan, the director of this movie.
- The director did a lot more research on this scary area than I did before making the movie.
- We talked about whether strange events happened during the filming.
- The people living there. They didn't want a movie to be made. They were afraid that they would awaken evil.
-According to what his director told us, the film crew was also impressed by what was said and began to fear even the smallest sounds in the forest.
- Anyway, I will not be able to shoot as professionally as that director. I'll just record what's going on with a camera and try to arouse curiosity.
- Sometimes I will interview the villagers and the people living there. Of course, if they accept it.
- I'm ending my first shoot here. My friend Murat will record the next on video. And if you're ready, now I'm showing you my home situation behind the scenes. :)
- Yes, friends, I started recording the camera.
- We're close already. What is this? Suddenly there was fog.
- You have to be crazy to come here.
- We're cultured people, but look at the bullshit we've come and researched.
- Ceyhun, can I tell you something?
- Of course
- If you hadn't helped me earlier, I wouldn't have come here for you alive.  :)
- Everything is mutual.
- He brought me by force.
- Tell the truth, did Ceyhun pay you to come here?
- Of course, I will ask Ceyhun a small fee in return for my coming here. :)
- Can you look at the navigation? Are we here?
-The navigation doesn't show them. We will find out by asking.
- Only if you are aware there is no one...
- There really is no one to ask directions.
- Could it be because of those dogs? I'll close the windows so they don't jump in.
- Dogs do nothing.
- Sorry, there is a forested area around here, do you know where it is? :)
- The dog could have spoken and said we don't like strangers here. I expected this.
- Let's find someone around here and ask the way. The glass fogged up and it bothered me.
- Turn on the car air conditioner.
- It's on, but it doesn't work.
- Wait a minute, someone is sitting in the garden. Let me ask them.
- Hello. We were going to go into the forest, but which way should we go?
- What will you do in the forest?
- We need to shoot a video for my thesis.
- You have to go that way, but what kind of thesis is that? What will you do there?
- I am preparing a psychological thesis. There was a forest here and people were afraid of the rumors. I will research this for my thesis.
- Nonsense. It means that these stories have reached universities. There is nothing there. They are afraid of false stories that were made up fifty years ago.
- The people living here made up scary stories so that the young people wouldn't go to the woods to have sex, drink alcohol or use drugs.
- In fact, we came here to investigate where and how exactly what you are talking about originated.
-  The people living here made up such horrible stories so that foreign people and young people would not go there and do things against the rules because the forest area is a bit desolate. In short, all the stories told are lies.
- Then there is nothing there?
- I'm telling you. There is nothing there!
- We went in search of adventure when we were younger. But don't worry there is nothing.
- Do not go in vain for research. The phone doesn't even pick up there anyway. You get lost. Pig, wolf, dog everything is there. You're afraid dude.
- Then you come too.
- Ok but what are you going to do to be right there?
-  We will only shoot a video, but we want to spend the night there.
- Forget about me, there is Özgür here, he knows the place well and can guide you if you want ?
- Let's go ahead, we'll ask for your help if needed. Can we find you here?
- Okay, so it's okay to bother to interview you when we're done?
- Okey okey.
- Of course, when you come, we'll have coffee together.
- This shop is closed but I guess you are sitting inside?
- Yes, we turn off the lights and sit in front of the door with friends.
- Let me ask you something, we didn't see anyone on the way on our way. I wonder why?
- In this town, after a certain time, everyone goes home, it's not too soon.
- We were surprised that it was too early.
- Don't think of this place like city centers. Here, everyone goes home at a certain time and spends time at home. There's nothing to do anyway.
- We understand. Thank you so much.
- Come back from here now. You will go for about a kilometer. There you will see the sign. Go inside from there. But as I said, the phone does not pick up. Let your parents know if they're curious. :)
- Okay. Thank you so much dude.
- There's definitely a dope party in the forrest! :)
- How much the man likes to talk... Our heads are swollen! :)
- It's your fault. You asked so many questions and you didn't stop. :)
- How do I know that the man will talk so much? He kept talking! Like the mayor of this town!  It's like the man forced everyone into their homes. And he's sitting alone in front of his shop, mentally ill.  :)
- I think all the villagers are drinking in the forest. :)
-  I think everyone is avoiding this guy. :) If you ask me, why are people so scared in this town? I would point this guy out as an answer. :)
- Are there too many dogs? interesting...
- I am ready
- is this here?
- I don't know, you have to ask Ceyhun.
- Yes here. Did you get your flashlight?
- What is this place?
- Yes welcome to my channel.
- Don't be fooled, let's shoot a video and go.
-You are right, the university committee will examine it.
- We came to the village where the famous horror events took place.
- It would be cooler if you turned on your flashlights.
- I didn't turn it on so that the light wouldn't reflect on the camera.
- Okay, done. Hold it left and right so I can adjust.
-  There are some things that people who live here are afraid of!
- If you make fun of it like that, we're going to have to cut this footage. You can't give these video recordings to the committee.
- Let's see what people are afraid of, we wanted to see. We will spend a night here.
- The cameras will be with us. Since the invention of the camera, such supernatural phenomena have not been seen very often.
- Let's see if we can capture supernatural events with our cameras. We will spend a night here...
- Only dog ​​barking sounds in the distance
- I hope it's just a dog...
- All I want right now is that the dogs don't bite us.
- Lets go...
- There are just too many bugs around. One of them just landed on my head.
- This stick won't work against the insect, but still, let's have it with us.
- We forgot to take the insecticide.
- Ok.
- Does the camera keep recording?
- Yes.
- Then I'll turn on the flashlight again.
- We rely on pesticides and look for jin. :)
- In ancient European and Christian stories, they used to scare vampires with garlic. We also use insecticide for Jinns.  :)
- It's like there's a road there...
- Are you sure it's the road?
- I am not. so let's follow.
- They entered the mysterious path.
- Here you go...
- Guys, let's move slowly, because I carry both a camera and a light.
- Ceyhun, you can't pay for my effort just by buying me a meal. :)
- Doesn't it mean anything to you that your friend got high marks and completed his thesis?
- Yeah it doesn't mean anything to me I came here for the food you're going to treat me :)
- I need to give a nice speech about why we're here. Let's find a better and free space for this above.
- Have you been up before?
- No, it's my first time here with you.
- Ceyhun; Wherever there is nonsense you find and you always bring us after you.
- But rumor has it we came, you know...
- And here we uncovered the lies. Didn't people come here? Look, people come and sit and hang out.
- Look, they lit a fire over there, too.
- They obviously made up stories so that other people wouldn't come.
- They do not want this place where they are comfortable to be known.
- If it were me, I would make up stories and not want to be disturbed.
- Let's find a nice background to shoot.
- Can you point the flashlight over there? The woodland goes quite down and forward... It looks mysterious.
- Yeah nice... You can come with your girlfriend. :)
- An elite venue :)
- Make your first date with your girlfriends here. :)
- Yes, we came here, but what are we going to shoot? I know you called me just because I can use the camera.
- Ceyhun called you because you could use the camera, but I don't understand why he called me. :)
- I wanted to take advantage of your muscle strength. :)
- If I didn't have a camera, I wouldn't be here either. :)
- Let's start like this... First of all, let me put that stick down.
- Why did you take the stick anyway?
- Just in case. We are in the forest area, I wanted to take precautions. You come before me now and shine a light on me. I will talk to the camera.
- But you don't get into the frame, let the camera only record me.
- Hold light on your face. Keep the light in the background. I will shoot with my own camera light.
- As a matter of fact, it will be much better if you turn off the lights.
- three, two, one recording...
- Hello, I'm Ceyhun. We are in Ilıcaklar village. It's now 02:22 am
- People are very afraid to come here because of the terrible rumors in this village.
- My research focus is to capture images of how these stories affect people.
- I know there is nothing to be afraid of here. But still, I've come to understand why people are so afraid of it.
- Three friends are going to spend the night here.
- Let's see what will happen to us. We will try to understand what are the events that affect the villagers in their daily lives.
- Later in this video, we will have discussions and comments on this subject.
- what are you doing? This video will be given to the university committee.
- Nothing happens, you cut the video from here.
- Well, your voice and image overlapped.
- Do you realize that you did something very stupid? Bad things have already started to happen to us, thanks to you.
- That's what the villagers are afraid of. :)
- You're the fat and bespectacled you of our bro team. That's why you should be afraid first. :)
- So am I going to die first? :)
- Where are we going, what are we doing bro
- What do we know. Let's go wherever we're going.
- I think we should go this way. Maybe we can see something.
- Should we lie and pretend we saw something and were scared? :)
- I think what I just did will work very well for this issue.
- If we add that nonsense you do to the video and present it as a thesis, you will be famous.
- I think I'll take you on video from the front. Keep the lanterns on. It gets more scary and cinematic.
- So where are the Jins?
- You've become like ghostbusters, it's ridiculous that we're here anyway...
- By the way, do you remember which way we came?
- I remember.
- Don't do silly things.
- I regret bringing you here.
- Don't touch! it's the holy stone!
- Okay, that's enough, don't make fun of it, we already know that there is nothing and everything is a lie.
- You must also respect the fears of the villagers.
- What will it gain us if I respect that?
- Our purpose here is to understand why they are afraid anyway. Let us do our job.
- I think it's all nonsense!
- Why did you choose such a stupid topic for your thesis?
- Unfortunately, only these topics remained for the thesis.
- What kind of a thesis teacher do you have, he asks you for such a ridiculous subject.
- In fact, the subject of my thesis; about fears and their effects on everyday life. I changed the subject a little more to make it interesting.
- So you came up with this nonsense topic...
- The moon is beautiful.
- I think you are trying to turn the video into a romantic movie.
- Actually, what we're looking for here right now is a sound, a shadow, a movement...
- Because people are more prone to be afraid of things they can't make sense of.
- The minds try to complete the things that people cannot make sense of with the things they see.
- What are you doing bro?
- You continue.
- How can we go on so you can be serious?
- Ok, don't worry, you record video from the beginning.
- I'm already being silly. I don't even know what I'm saying.
- Anyway, we'll collect them later in the interview section. I'm going to make something up now.
- Can you get out of the frame, let me talk alone.
- What we are looking for is a voice, a shadow, or an illusion. Let's see what the villagers are afraid of.
- One minute, there was a sound.
- Where from?
- Did you see it too?
- Is it a dog?
- Something has escaped. I couldn't understand what was running away.
- Wait a minute. The camera was recording. Let's watch the footage.
- You saw it! just like a human...
- No... It is the shadow reflected from the tree.
- Look, when you hit the light of the lantern from this angle, doesn't it reflect like a human shadow?
- Look, that's what it looks like when reflected from here.
- Ceyhun! Guys, don't talk nonsense! Don't shout, be quiet. That thing was just like a human...
- I think it was the shadow...
- After all, who will be here at night but us?
- If you're here, there may be others.
- Well, if there is someone, why run away?
- Okay, there was someone and he ran away.
- And if you look where to go, there is no way.
- Right...
- But you saw it and heard the sound it made while running. What was that thing?
- Maybe it was an animal...
- Ceyhun, keep the flashlight forward, quick.
- Dude, look like there's someone there.
- Where?
- Shall we turn off the lights?
- No, then we can't see anything.
- Hello?
- It could be the villagers.
- I just heard a gunshot coming from far away.
- It's a tree branch!
- I almost pissed myself out of fear.
- No, what we saw was not a tree branch. Let's take another look at the video we took.
- We shoot video in the dark. Shadows can look like many things.
- Ok, I kept quiet... When we get home, we'll see it on the big screen. But I'm still a little scared.
- It was a tree branch.
- Damn it, everything we see is a tree branch?
- Look then. The shadow of Kuzeys hand also looks like something.
- Nonsense...
- We started the video shoot with the subject of why the villagers are afraid. But we started to fear everything. Actually, as a thesis, it is enough to give the videos that we shot...
- In my opinion, give what we shot on this video as a thesis. We were afraid, you say why the villagers should not be afraid. Let's finish tonight, let's finish shooting.
- What happened now? Are you scared?
- Yes what happend?
- Did you understand that?
- There's a big difference between what you are in the car and what you are now. You're scared.
- What does it matter?
- Look, do you see? Are you scared or not? We can all get scared for a moment.
- Bro, I'm telling you again. In the footage we captured on camera, a man is running away.
- OK, I saw it too. If it already exists, I think it will appear soon.
- Could it be an animal?
- Will it be an animal? He was like a human.
- Ceyhun! Ceyhun! Stop! The fire is burning ahead.
- Calm down, you scared me.
- Okay, that's the guy who ran away from us, that's the one who lit the fire.
- Is there someone by the fire?
- Yes yes there is someone there! hold the light. Look dude! There is someone!
- Don't shine a light on the man, let's go and talk.
- Shall we not disturb?
- We have already come to the man... Sorry?
- Dressed in black. whoa!
- What is he doing there?
- Dude what is this?
- Hello there?
- Human, of course. What else?
- Ceyhun, stop, don't go!
- Hello?
- Fuck! Fuck!
- Fuck!
- Kuzey! Stop stop! Stop!
- Sprained my foot! Sprained my foot
-Fuck! fuck!  Stop! Stop!
- Did you see?
- I saw, I saw!
- Let's go to the car!
- Stop bro! I recorded it on camera.
- Which way?
- Please let's go to the car! Where is the car?
- OK, turn off the camera.
- Wait bro, I think I injured my foot.
- Please let's go to the car!
- Where is the car?
- Are your feet okay?
- My foot looks fine
- Where did we come from? Where did we come from bro?
- Phone not picking up? Let's take a look at the map, shall we?
- Phone line not working...
- No signal?
- No signal...
- Lets go...
- Dude one minute... I heard a voice...
- I swear I heard a voice.
- Where did that sound come from?
- The sound came from nearby...
- I've been like this for two weeks.
- I was startled by every sound and everything.
- I can only sleep for 1 hour a day. Waking up from time to time of course...
- I don't know what I'm seeing... But on the other hand, I'm aware of what I'm seeing.
- Actually, I've been trying to prepare this video for two weeks, but I couldn't talk, I couldn't get my head together...
- I want to try one more time.
- I've been researching like crazy... I'm trying to find out what we're going through.
- We reached the car that night...
- Murat sprained his ankle.
- We saw that thing again several times with the camera off.
- We still couldn't figure out what that thing was...
- That thing's body looked human, but I couldn't see its face clearly...
- There was something like black cloth that he draped over it...  But I couldn't understand what it was.
- That thing's face looked human-like, but more brightly wounded...
- It was as if his skin was torn and shedding ...
- its eyes were very bright, not exactly like human eyes...
- It was like it was on fire...
- I couldn't quite see the mouth of that thing, but it was like smokeless fire...
- Unfortunately, because we escaped, when we look at the videos we shot that night, we can see that thing for a very short time...
- I actually went there to videotape it, but without success.
- After what happened...
- After that incident, I got discouraged and even thought of canceling my thesis altogether. But I will not cancel. Because I have reasons...
- My friend Kuzey insisted that I finish this thesis and even stopped meeting with me...
- He said he was going to see a psychologist...
- Now he won't answer my phones either.
- We researched a little more with Murat.
- I told my wife what had happened and she didn't believe me.
- And I was in a situation like this...
- I can't make people believe me because of what I've seen. Everyone treats me just like I was before I started my thesis.
- In short, I became like the people on the subjects in my thesis.
- I really think that what I saw is not real, but there are camera recordings and two more of my friends saw it with me!
- Like I said, all three of us saw the same thing there.
- We talked about if we all saw the same thing. We opened the images and yes what we saw was that horrible thing...
- I've been watching and researching these images like crazy over and over again... But everything shows the same thing...
- People told me...
- People told me if you're scared, go to the police. They said someone scared you or made a joke.
- Honestly, I've considered all these possibilities.
- I wondered if the villagers, who didn't want us to go there, played this game to scare us. But what I saw was something else, I know that!
- If it's the villagers who scare us, I really congratulate you, it's a great plan... They managed to scare us.
- But the thing there was moving very fast… One moment it was there, the next it was here.
- And that's in the footage.
- I'm trying to stop those moments especially on the computer.
- But it doesn't look very clear in the videos because it moves so fast.
- Maybe you'll call me retarded, but I want to take another shot! Because I'm obsessed with this situation!
- I don't want to call that thing Jin like the villagers. But they say there are Jins out there.
- I'm going to call that thing Jin for now. But I believe that thing there is not from this dimension.
- Why is this creature in that area? Is a dimensional door opening and appearing? Why did it appear to us? I have thousands of questions in my mind.
- And I don't want to leave the questions behind.
- Of course, people call me stupid because of this thought...
- What can I do when I go to the police station? Are the cops going to arrest something they haven't seen?
- It's no use calling the cops!
- They think I'm crazy...
- I showed the videos to a few people and they said it's not real.
- Some youtubers wanted to buy my video. They thought they could make good money out of it.
- No one took it seriously except youtubers.
- I am 30 years old and because of this event that I saw 2 weeks ago, I started to question my whole belief system. I started believing in something I didn't believe in. This is exactly what I want to go after.
- No one believes me when I tell or show images. I want to find images that they can believe in.
- Because I didn't believe anyone either.
- Now it's the other way around and no one believes me. This bothers me a lot.
- Kuzey is gone.
- We went to an imam with Murat...
- My relationship with my wife is not good right now...
- It bothered me a lot that my wife didn't believe me.
- It bothered me a lot that she thought I was crazy.
- We're staying in separate places now and won't be seeing each other for a while.
- I'll talk to her again after I clear my head
- It bothered me a lot that she didn't believe me and left the house...
- I'm gonna videotape that creature. I'll make my wife and everyone else believe me...
- I keep researching like crazy.
- I reached out to someone else who saw that creature in the same area. I even noticed something interesting, let me show you that.
- This video was shot at the same place. He says he saw the creature I was running from.
- I've seen something like this over there that goes by so fast.
- The creature I saw there is very similar to the creatures in this video and photographs.
- I've seen images like this on the internet before, but it's interesting how similar they are to what I saw.
- Both of these images were taken at the same location as mine.
- I contacted the owner of these images.
- I invited her to do my research, but he said she didn't want to be involved.
- I'm investigating for another place right now. I will make a separate video about it later.
- I found another interesting story around Kocaeli.
- I'm startled by every sound now.
- There was a house in this village. But the interesting thing is that nobody wants to tell this story.
- Everyone knew the other stories and they were very popular.
- But they don't want to talk about this story. I just learned that there is a terrible house in that village.
- And I learned that that house has been empty for 50-60 years.
- I know something bad happened to the family that lived there, but I never found out what it was.
- I was able to reach someone who knows about these places through a friend of mine.
- When I asked about the story in that house, he certainly did not want to tell. I said why I was researching this, I told what I had been through.
- Then I offered some money. It was very difficult to convince. He said he would take me all the way to the house, that he would not interfere with anything and that I should not enter the house.
- I think they have invaded the house. And these jins are also haunting those who enter the house.
- I've been searching like crazy for these things I've seen and...
- I think if these jins were going to hurt us, they would have hurt us in the forest anyway.
- They have not harmed us and I have good intentions towards them. I will not disturb them.
- My aim is to announce it to the world with all the evidence if they are real.
- Before we go to that village and home, we will meet with a hodja.
- We'll set off in the morning...
- Let's see what happens...
- Ceyhun, we came this far with your word, but I'm afraid.
- I'm also very afraid.
- I do not think that the amulet written by Hodja will protect me.
- But our intentions are not bad...
- No wait a minute!
- No, I don't trust our good intentions! What if the jins we meet are malicious?
- In short, let's not bother those jins too much.
- I think the same as you. I just want people to see these jins if they exist. Because I know very well what I saw.
- By the way, navigation led us here. If you see someone on the side of the road, let's stop. Look carefully.
- I think we are in a close place, but there is not much internet around here.
- Someone is sitting over there. If we can't find it, we'll ask. Let's go a little further. I think there's a sign over there.
- By the way, navigation led us here. If you see someone on the side of the road, let's stop. Look carefully.
- Look, someone's waiting over there.
- Yes this is he.
- If that person is not the person we are looking for. Let's phone him. A car is coming from behind, be careful while turning.
- Shall I come back from here?
- Let's ask this guy.
- Hello
- You are Mr. Rifat, aren't you?
- Yes, you must be Ceyhun Bey?
- Ok son, I'm hanging up the phone, my guests have arrived.
- Welcome.
- Hello. We talked to you on the phone.
- Yes
- What will we do now? Is our destination too far away?
- This is our village.
- Okay, so get in the car and let's go together.
- Do you have a place in the car?
- Yes, there is, we just need to move the bags to the side.
- The back is full...
- Yes, we came prepared because we were shooting.
- Welcome to our village.
- We're glad to be here.
- By the way, you know we're going to take a video recording. Do you mind if we record you on camera?
- No, it won't be a problem for me.
- Let's not record the people living in the village on camera. They don't want this.
- I guess there aren't many people out at this hour anyway...
- There are mostly young people walking around the village at these hours...
- You can stop the vehicle at a suitable place.
- I also stop the camera recording.
- Is the camera recording?
- Yes recording .
- We will record everything with the camera. For your information.
- Ok.
- We'll walk home from here together, and you'll tell us the story of the house.
- So let's start walking.
- Ok.
- What we do is this
- I actually don't believe in supernatural things.
- Together with Murat, we explore what people fear. And we are trying to understand the facts.
- Then I was afraid of something too.
- But unfortunately, even if I show people the camera footage I have, they don't believe me.
- I know very well what I saw there. I even ran away.
- Later on, I started to research these kinds of events more broadly.
- And I read and found terrible things about this village. There was a terrible house in this village and I met you to tell me about the events here.
- To tell the truth, I believe what happened in that house. But I haven't seen it myself.
- From what I've heard around me, there are many stories about this horrible house.
- Has it happened to people you know?
- Yes, people I know. but i didn't see anything i just heard the stories.
- But I even have relatives who became stutters or paralyzed after their experiences.
- How many people live in this village?
- There are thirty houses in this village
- So everyone knows the story of that house.
- They are already very old stories... I have an uncle.
- He stutters...
- The reason my uncle stuttered was because he walked into that house alone when he was little.
- So did you ever enter that scary house?
- No.
- You never entered.
- I am afraid because I believe and I do not enter.
- Let me tell you the story of the house.
- Please tell.
- A family lived in that house.
- But they lived a long time ago, 70 years ago.
- The father in that family was a bad person... he had connections with the jins.
- Do you mean the man used Jins and their powers with malicious intent?
- Yes.
- As I said, he has a connection with jins.
- The villagers called her the hodja of the Jinn.
- In the stories it is said that this man used jins for good and evil.
- He has used jins many times against the villagers and the people living around.
- So how did he use jins? when someone wants something?
- Yes, definitely.
- He usually used jins for money when he was asked for help.
- They even came to him to find treasure.
- It means that there are also those who look for it... So is there anyone who comes for the love spell?
- Friends, the car is coming from behind, let it pass the road, we will continue later.