Captioning made possible by
lions gate entertainment
I'll tell you,
Bobby, it's bullshit.
Total bullshit.
I don't know.
What I do, is it art?
I don't know what it is.
It must be something
inside me.
Something's missing.
I don't know.
You know, Bobby...
I don't really believe in
all the inner child stuff
that people talk about now.
I think it's
all crap, really.
But every now and then,
I like to give
the little kid a piece
of candy just in case.
Seriously...
It's depressing as hell.
I know enough to know
that I'm depressed.
Who's responsible?
When did this happen?
I don't know.
Where is he?
Bobby, you're too kind.
You're much too kind.
I don't know
if I'm a genius.
Is he gonna come out?
I don't know.
Did he shave?
I think you know and I know
what it is that I do.
We both know it.
That I'm empty.
I'm a fucking
dancing squirrel.
I'm totally vacant.
Ok, ok.
I'm no artist.
I'm a chimp.
Anyway, Bobby.
Thanks very much, Bobby,
for having me on your show.
I really love your show,
and I hope you ask me back.
Nice to see
you again, buddy.
Bobby?
What?!
Hey, boy scout,
how are you?
Give me a credit card.
You don't have
a credit card?
Yeah, I have a...
I'm not using
a platinum card
on this door.
Now, give me
a goddamn credit card.
This is fucking serious.
Here.
Thank you.
10 bucks
you can't do it.
Are you kidding?
You have no idea
who I am.
Used to be a nice kid,
Jennifer, but now...
Why are you here?
Where are your, um...
Where are your clothes?
Tell me why you're here.
Hey, come on, come on.
You know why I'm here.
It's a big night, millions
of viewers, you know?
Going live without
a net, you know?
Just like Johnny.
Johnny got
to tape at 4:00.
Fuck him. Fuck him.
He's a dinosaur.
Fuck Leno,
fuck Letterman.
Boy, you're the one.
You're the one.
You got guts.
Do me a favor,
will you?
You just put on
your clothes here.
We're gonna put on
your clothes,
and we're gonna
get out there,
kick some ass.
I need a little
inspiration, Mitch.
I need to feel like I’m
having something to say.
Say anything you want.
Here, you want something
to say, say this...
This is called
a monologue.
I didn't mean
the Ally McBeal jokes,
Mitch.
I'm talking about...
Saying something
that I'm inspired by.
I know, I know, I know.
I know what you're saying.
I also know that
we got 5 minutes
and you're going on live.
Do you understand that?
I also know that
the most beautiful...
Bloodsucker in the universe
is on the show.
Your show, not O’Brien,
not Letterman.
Bishop live.Tonight.
So your clothes, you see.
Clothes are important.
Because tonight, you are
Bobby the vampire slayer.
And I am telling you, Bobby,
you fuck this up and it is...
It is suicide.
So come on, let's stick
a stake in this bitch
and let's go out
and make
midnight with Bobby bishop
history.
It is silver bullet time.
My name is Kevin, Mitch.
Did you know that?
No. That's great.
Thank you for sharing.
And now,
coming all the way
from sunny Los Angeles,
California,
live, I repeat, live
from downtown L.A.,
it's midnight
with Bobby bishop.
Tonight, Bobby's guests
are the supermodel
and soon to be major
motion picture star,
Bridget bower!
The music of Tito Puente!
Television icon
Jerry mathers!
And, of course,
the midnight rockers!
Heeeere's America's
favorite baby blues,
Bobby bishop!
Loser.
Put on HBO.
Sex and the city is on.
No, Louis, no. You know I’m
trying not to watch it. No.
Sarah Jessica Parker's
so cute!
I'm not putting it on.
Beautiful people
always hump each other.
Exactly.
I'm not putting it on.
Not the ugly beautiful.
Always beautiful beautiful.
Yes!
Hey, I'm trying
to do a show here!
Sorry.
Hello?
Hi. I'm in here.
What's up?
Nothing.
Anyway,
what kind of name...
Hey, what's this?
It's Chinese.
Hello...
Mmm. All right.
Ok.
Hi.
Hey.
Ooh. Ooh, Chinese.
Yeah, well, you know.
Who's on?
I don't know.
I just turned it on.
Put on Letterman.
You put on
Letterman.
I'm gonna
go wash my face.
Let's get outta here.
We'll be right back.
And we're out.
Christ. Hey, Al, you're
such a fucking idiot.
Back in 2, boss.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Al the genius.
Hey, hey, hey,
how you feeling?
Like shit.
No.
Is it me
or is it them?
Listen, they're...
They're tourists.
The band leader
is a real fuckup.
You're doing great.
You're kicking ass.
No, they're bullshit.
For god's sake,
you're sweating.
I'm fine. I'm fine.
Will you guys get
the fuck away from me?
He wants you away.
I said 3 times.
He shouldn't have to say it
more than 3 times.
Just back off.
I'm dying here.
This is live, Mitch.
Here's the crazy
headlines, Bobby.
This shit again.
Third one's
the funniest.
Barbershop chicken.
You, hey,
hey, get out.
Whatever you want.
You want a bullshit show.
Now, listen to me.I'll do a bullshit show.
You are a star.
Ok, good. Enough.
Brightest star
in the galaxy.
Mmm-ah. I love you.
In 5, 4, 3, 2, 1.
We're back.
Hello. Welcome back.
Bobby bishop...
Bridget?
Mitchell banks.
Big fan.
Cell is on the back.
Thank you.
Oh, big night.
Live TV.
Yep.
Bobby is my boy.
He's a big fan.
He's very nice.
He's shorter in person.
Well, when you get
to know him,
he's 10 feet tall,
and he's a big heart.
And...
Are you happy?
Back off, Mitchell.
Hey, look, Napoleon.
Don't listen to him,
kitten.
He touch you?
Ron, are you still
pissed off about
that Luke Perry thing?
I like Bobby.
He's sweet.
He looks like
Charlie Manson.
Ok, ladies and gentlemen.
My first guest has
the best personality
in the whole world.
Right.
And she can dance.
Oh, boy, can she dance.
And she's very pretty.
Ok, now I got
your attention.
Ladies and gentlemen,
supermodel
and super person,
Bridget bower.
Does Lily have a little
crush on Bobby bishop?
No.
I think he's funny.
He's a total moron.
Those are, uh...
Terrific shoes.
Thank you.
Nice shoes.
Ok, Bridget.
Isn't she beautiful?
Thank you so much
for coming, Bridget.
Thank you
for having me.
Bridget...
Yeah, that would be
a tall order, Bridget.
You know, we have
the same initials,
Bridget and I.
We do, I guess.
Yes. Yes, we do.
I'd like
to fuck you so much.
What?
What'd he say?
What'd he say?What'd he say?
Holy shit.
I bet you get fucked
all the time, right?
What?
Go to commercial.
Get us out.
Are we out?
You're probably tired
of fucking, right?
You probably get tired
of fucking.
What'd I do?
What a freak.
Ok, we're out.
You're finished, ass-face.
Bridget, sweetheart,
he will pay with his blood,
I swear to god.
What did I do?
What'd I say?
Hey. Hey, get out.
Here. I'm finished.
Like you weren't thinking
the same thing.
Not only did
he use profanity,
but he did so in a lewd
and lascivious manner.
I mean, we're talking...
We're talking breaking
F.C.C. Regulations,
we're talking
sexual harassment.
Rosie O'Donnell
is gonna crucify him.
What an idiot.
Stay right here.
Don't move.
He said it out loud.
He did.
I'm just saying,
I know I heard it,
but it was in my head.
You're crazy.
Yeah, how were we supposed
to know what's in your head?
Waves, man.
Keith, you...
You should not be allowed
to watch TV anymore.
I can't really be certain
that I said it.
Hello?
Hey, did you see it?
I'm speechless.
In Manhattan.
It's unpublished?
Same last name. Uh...
Try Linda Charles.
It's actually
kind of sad.
Kind of sad?
It's tragic...
What they're doing
to these poor animals.
Wait. What are
you watching?
Discovery.
What are you watching?
Bobby bishop.
Oh, who's on?
Um, forget it.
Let me call you tomorrow.
Ok. Put on 31.
Ok. Bye.
Who was that?
Oh, Cindy.
Oh, yeah?
What does she think
of your knight
in shining armor?
Shut up.
She didn't even watch it.
She didn't?
Mm-mmm.
Hello? Hello?
Stupid cocksucker.
You fuck.
Oh, you fuck, you fuck.
Hello, Mitch.
Mmm.
Say, can I ask you
a question?
What the fuck,
uh, Bob?
Listen, um,
who's your biggest fan?
My mother.
Uh-huh. Aside from
that Saint of a woman,
who's your biggest fan?
I don't think I have
any other fans.
What happened
to your eye?
What happened?
Loyalty.
A sterling character.
What happened?
Bridget bower.
Bridget bower hit you?
No, no, I wish.
No, her bratty
little agent attacked me.
I'm sorry
about that, Mitch.
No, don't be sorry.It's my fault.
No, no.
Don't be sorry.
I respect
what you did.
I don't...I don't
necessarily understand it,
but I respect that you're
an artist, you made a choice.
I dig that.
But, you know,
you're also a...
You're a talk show host.
You're the voice
of America.
There are rules.
I mean,
I...I...I dig it.
I was thinking it myself.
But what the fuck, Bob?
What? I don't know.
What'd I say?
I say something wrong?
No.
My head was pounding,
hey.
It just slipped out.
Hey, I saw her tits.
I saw that.
I dig that.
Your head was pounding.
But what was going on?
I mean, could you not
see the cue cards?
The cue cards were there.
Was your vision blurred?
W-W-Were you ad-libbing?
If you were riffing,
I get that.
But help me.
Help me, baby.
Help Mitchell
help Bobby.
I can't help you.
I don't know why.
I don't know
why I did it.
why I said it.
I don't know.
All I know is
I think Rosie O'Donnell
is gonna crucify me.
Oh, no. Now, uh...
Now, you just listen
to me. Don't stress.
I got it.
Don't stress.
Don't...
Just give me
a second.
Don't anybody
fucking panic.
Ok. Ok.
Here's what we do.
No, Mitch. Come on.
No, no.
Just listen to me.
Mitch, Mitch.Here's what we do.
I'm tired...
Ok, I got it.
Listen to me.
We get, like...
We get...We...
We find a well.
You get that?
Mitch...
No, stay with me.
Just listen. Listen to me.
Listen to me. Listen to me.
Stay with me.
Aren't you
a little tired now?
Let's just let it go.
We find, like,
a puppy or...
A baby.
And we...
We drop the thing
in the well.
You got that?
I'm confused.
All right, then.
Just hold on,
hold on, hold on.
The puppy
or the baby?
Here's the deal.
The kid's puppy runs
out into the freeway
as you're
driving home.
And you're dodging.
Dodging cars
left and right,
right and left.
And the puppy,
it starts barking.
Do you understand?
Barking.
It starts barking
its fucking
puppy head off.
I get it, I get it.
So I see the puppy.
It is just barking.
Right.
And it alerts you
to the tragedy,
and it takes you
back to the well,
and you can
just go fuck
Rosie O'Donnell.
You can fuck
Rosie O'Donnell,
because you...
You're
a fucking hero.
I'm supposed
to get in the well?
No, you don't get
in the well.
Why would you get
in the well?
You...
Boss?
Entertainment tonight's
here.
Tell 'em
he's a fucking hero.
Oh, and, uh, Joanie?
Um, find us a baby.
Come on.
Quick, quick.
I can't take this.
I'm gonna go
to New York.
You deal with it.
Um...
Ok. Why are you...
Why are you going
to New York?
Come on. Pick it up.
Pick it up. Pick it up.
Pick it up, pick it up,
pick it up, pick it up.
Hey, Keith!
No smoking out here.
Yeah, uh, hold on.
Keith, no smoking
outside the lounge.
Are you in the lounge?
I'm on the phone.
You're in the hallway.
Put it out.
Thank you.
Come on, pick it up.
I'm on the phone!
Hang it up.
Pick it up.
Oh, god!
Hang it up.
Pick it up.
Fuck.
Keith, nobody likes
a litterbug.
Pick it up.
Come on, pick it up.
Thank you.
Uh, oh, uh,
your sister's here.
There you are.
Hi, kid.
I'm very sad today.
Why, sunshine?
I don't know.
Just...Very sad.
Oh. I bought you cigarettes
and starbursts.
Yay! Treats!
Oh...mmm.
Thank you.
Hey, slim,
you got a smoke?
Yeah.
Here. Keep 'em.
Oh, thanks.
You got a light?
Here.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I don't want to talk about
Sarah Jessica Parker anymore.
Ok. Sorry.
I mean, I don't why you
have HBO in here anyway.
But she's so scrunchy.
She's like
a little corn muffin.
Keith.
What?!
All right. Remember
when you told me
to tell you when
you're being unstable?
Yes.
You're being unstable.
Ok. Sorry.
All right.
How's dick?
Mark is fine.
He says, "hi."
How's mom?
She's all right.
She's a little worried
about the job thing.
She's stopped coming
to visit me.
She said she felt
a weird vibe.
I'm, like, "mom,
you're in a mental
institution."
Well, she didn't mean it.
She's a little kooky. Hmm.
Mmm.
Ok, I saw it.
Ok. So then, that
was out loud then.
Oh, it was definitely
out loud.
Wow.
What?
What's going on?
What, what, what?
What...nothing.
You know
something.
I do not.
Yes, you do.
What do I know?
I don't know.
Something.
I...I don't.
What is it?Keith, you're paranoid.
Did you talk
to him?
No!
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
Maybe he was sending you
some kind of signal.
By telling a model
he wants to fuck her?
I don't think so.
Are you sure you
didn't talk to him?
Yes, Keith.
I have not spoken
to Kevin moss in years.
But did you talk
to Bobby bishop?
They're
the same person, idiot!
I didn't...
Look...
Eat one of those.
Yes.
Hi.
Hey.
Can I have, um,
a pack of viceroy?
Don't touch
the fucking bag.
Turn around.
Hey.
I can't believe it.
Bobby bishop.
Right.
You got it.
Can you give me
a break?
You don't fucking
remember me?
I think so. Yeah.
Oh, yeah?
I think
I remember you.
Yeah?
What's my name?
Um...
Brian Maher, huh?
You got that?
You're Brian Maher.
Fucking superstar,
right?
Forget all the little
people, right?
What do you mean?
I remember you.
I remember you
when you were
fucking Kevin, man.
We were in
the same class.
When you were still Kevin.You really know me.
Now you're getting it.
Did we go to school
together?
Yeah, that's right.
Mr. Ripton's
western civ...
I remember you.You remember me?
Yeah, you were
a good guy.
You were my favorite.
Fuck you.
You were a fucking
douche bag, but hey...
Oh, come on.
You're a big shot now.
Bobby bishop.
Who was that girl,
though? Deleila, um...
Lily.
Lily!
My girlfriend, Lily.
Yeah, she was nice.
Did you know her brother
went fucking nuts?
Keith?
Keith.
Keith went nuts?
Yeah.
He fucking
put banana peels
all over his naked body,
ran through
a fucking museum
screaming, "don't slip!"
Can you fucking
imagine that?
That's crazy.
Yeah.
You look good.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, you look good.
Can I get a pack
of cigarettes here
and just go?
Yeah, yeah.
Ok, can I...Keep that.
And matches. Thank you.
Take care.
Yeah, be well.
Ok.
Talk to you.
UN-fucking-believable.
Hey, you got
a card, man?
Yeah. Shit, man.
Yeah, stay in touch.
Ok.
I'd love to get down
with you.
Yeah.
Be well, huh?
Would you untape me,
please?
You know,
I should be mad at her
for smuggling in contraband,
but, well, she's pretty.
And I'll tell her.
I mean, she got
all the looks
in the family,
you know?
Come on, my arms
are falling asleep.
Not until group.
You know, um...
I know famous people.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, I...No, really.
I know famous people.
Tony newly does
not impress me.
You would freak out
if you know who
I'm thinking of.
I mean,
you would freak.
If you knew who I know.
I'll just leave it at that.
Hello.
Hey, how are you,
baby doll?
I'm weird, Mitch.
Very, very weird.
Come on,
you're not weird.
You're, uh...
You're creative.
What do you want?
What about
that girl's mother?
You find her?
No. Nobody's home.
No mother.
I need a favor.
Anything, Bobby, baby.
We're gonna beat this
thing called depression.
Lily's brother's
in a mental ward.
I need you
to find him.
His name is, uh,
Keith Charles.
Ok, I’m
writing it down.
Did you write it down?
All right, I'll get
my people on it.
It's done.
Oh, listen, Bob?
They love the
"I want to fuck you"
line in the reporter.
Right. Whatever.
Just find him, all right?
Mom!
Mom?
Can you spare
a dime?
Spare some change?
Mom?
Lily. Oh, my angel.
Give me a kiss.
Mom, what are you doing?
Come on, you're filthy.
What are doing out here?
I'm practicing.
You're practicing?
Come on. Get up.
Come on.
All right,
take it easy.
Oh, god.
Oh, please.
You want a smoke?
Since when
are you smoking?
Whose is this?
Where'd you get it?
Oh, this sweet lady.
She covered me with
it Saturday night.
Look at me.
You're doing this
at night?
No, not last night.
You're sleeping out
on the streets?
So you slept out here, mom?
Come on.
No, no, not last night.
Last night my back
was just killing me.
Yes, uh, operator.
Um, how are you?
Great.
Listen, in Manhattan?
What is the most popular
mental hospital?
Ok, listen to me.
I just found out some
very serious information.
Ok.
This is wicked shit.
Very hush-hush.
Ok.
Let me get
some starbursts.
No way.
Ok, forget it.
Ok, fine.
Give me all
the yellow ones.
No, I'll give you
strawberry.
What's
going on here?
Nothing.
Nothing, Louis.
Take off.
No. Tell me what's
so secret.
Nothing.
Not a thing.
Take a walk.
I'll leave...
If you give me
some starbursts.
Forget it. You can stay.
Keep your mouth shut.
Ok.
Barry just told me
that he happens to
be very good friends
with Matthew Broderick's
dogwalker.
No way!
I'd fuck
Matthew Broderick's dog.
Focus.
Why did he
tell you this?
I got him a date.
I don't get it.
Matthew Brodericks's dog is
50% Sarah Jessica Parker's
dog.
Oh.
I don't get it.
I saw Keith today.
How is he?
He's fine. You know.
Is he still in
that dreadful place?
Yes, mother.
I won't go there, though.
That place has bad Karma.
Yeah, he told me.
Where did you get this?
Give me one
of those smokies.
Why are you smoking?
It's tough out there.
Mom, come on.
You're not homeless.
I could be.
Yeah, we all could be,
but you're not.
I just want
to make sure
that I can hack it
out there.
Oh, come on, mom.
Everything's gonna be fine.
How do you know? You're
not old and unemployed.
You don't know
what it's like.
You're all Keith's age
out there.
This isn't a joke,
you know?
You're not gonna be able
to survive out there.
I met this nice
little black man
who said he'd keep
an eye on me
if I gave him
some gum.
You met a man?
This little fella.
3 feet nothing,
but so sweet.
And tough as nails.
Is he the one
who gave you this?
Oh, no.
That was a white guy.
What white guy?
Nothin'.
No machine?
Yeah. Give me
another number.
I'm going
back to "a".
Just pick
another number.
Oh, here's one.
Adams, Ann.
212...
Well, obviously
it's 212.
Well, it could
be 718...Crabby.
Keith,
you got
a visitor.
Yeah. I'm on
the phone.
Come on.
Let's go.
Move it.
718.
Brooklyn.
It's a Manhattan
directory!
It is.
Nathan, you were
here to assist us.
Mom, was he taller than me?
I don't know,
I was in position.
In position?
What does that mean?
When you beg...
You should be
sitting below
eye level,
or else whitey
gets scared.
Whitey?
Arthur told me that.
Arthur?
My little
black protector.
Mom, where's the new one?
Try the bottom.
Ok. Is this him?
No.
It's not?Do you want a bagel?
This is not the guy
who gave you the lighter?
They're frozen.
I don't want a bagel.
Sorry. I don't know...
I don't know
what's wrong with me.
You know who he
reminded me of?
Who?
Kevin moss.
Ok, let's cut
to the chase.
Oh...whoa.
Keith.
How ya doin'?
Tip-top. So, uh,
Barry filled you in?
All right?
You know the deal
is very hush-hush,
so, uh,
let's get started.
Wow. What's goin' on?
Lab? Retriever?
What?
I don't know
what you're talkin' about.
Maybe some kind
of smaller dog?
A spaniel?
Maybe it's a golden?
Right? A golden?
I think you, uh,
I think you're confusing me
with somebody else, Keith.
I, uh...
No! No! No! Don't!
I shouldn't see
your face.
Ok. Ok.
It's me. It's me.
Do that again.
Do that...
It's Kevin.
Holy shit!
Keith. Keith. Keith.
Holy fucking shit!
Wow!Keith. Keith.
Bobby bishop!
Shh! Don't say it!
Shh.
Are you in my head,
or what?
Come on, Keith. It's me.
It's Kevin.
Let me ask you something.
Are you really crazy?
Crazy?
No.
Would you not
speak for me?
Would you just
be quiet, please?
I'm trying to talk
to somebody.
I didn't mean
to get in the way.
I want...
Pudding. I want...
No, I'm kidding.
I'm fine.
I'm just joking around.
Kidding around.
Hey! We got a guy
in here who thinks
he's you.
Really? Maybe he can
take over my show.
Hey, do you know
Sarah Jessica Parker?
Uh, she was
on the show once,
but I don't...We're not
friends or anything.
Ok, that
sex in the city show?
It just...It kills me.
So, you have HBO in here?
What kind of dog
do you think she has?
I don't know.
Like a poodle, maybe.
A little poodle.
Listen...
Uh...
I don't feel so good.
I feel really empty.
And...I need your help.
I knew it.
Can you do me favor?
301 east 64th street.
That's where she is?
Thanks a lot.
301...
East 64th street.
64th street.
Apartment 16.
Number 16.
Double "d".
♪ Southeast exit
16 dd?
7a.
301.
♪ Southeast exit
♪ 7a
I'm sorry.
301...
I'm kidding.
301 east 64th street?
Uh, 440 Hudson street.
It's not 301
east 64th street?
440 Hudson street.
Don't write it.
I'm sorry.
I'm kidding.
I am crazy, you know.
So there's that.
Please, Keith?
I just want
to talk to her.
Please?
I'm really sorry...
About everything.
321 west 83rd street,
apartment 4.
Are you telling me
the right number?
321 west 83rd?
Apartment 4.
Can you give me
her phone number?
I think it's better
to see her.
Ok.
I'm a bit nervous.
I hope...
I hope she remembers me.
You should
go see her.
Thanks.
I knew you would help me.
Hey.
He saw your mother?
Yeah, but he
didn't know it was her.
How do you know
it's his?
'Cause, look at it.
B.b....that's so cheesy.
Give it back.
Bobby bishop.
This is crazy.
I know.
How did your mother
get Bobby bishop's
lighter
without him knowing
she was your mother?
She was dressed
as a homeless person.
Oh.
She doesn't
even smoke.
No, that's the whole point.
She started today.
See how weird?
What am I doing, man?
I'm nuts.
See what I'm doing? I'm nuts.
You think she's
gonna remember me? No way.
No way.
She never liked me.
Fuck it.
♪ Yeah
♪ dancin'
♪ my baby's a lady
♪ Oh
♪ dancin'
♪ my baby's a lady
♪ we have
a chance, yeah ♪
♪ my baby's a lady
whew! Oh.
That song...Kicks!
This is so dumb, man.
This girl's never
gonna remember me.
Oh, shit.
Who the fuck is that?
Oh, my god.
Who the fuck?
Oh, shit.
I can't believe
I came to visit you.
Nathan, you're not
Bobby bishop.
Keith,
be nice.
He's taller
in person, right?
I did mention
you, though.
I told him we had
a nut in here
who thinks he's him.
You didn't use
the word nut, did you?
Hello?
You know, baby,
maybe you should
write down your feelings
for this woman.
You're used to
working with cards.
Very funny, Mitch.
Call me. It's Keith.
It's very,
very important
that you call me.
Also, what kind
of dog do you think
Sarah Jessica has?
Call me.
Be more of a psycho.
Hey, tell him
to stop giving
my number out
to psycho ward
attendants.
I got some
creepy messages
from a Barry.
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
What?
It's Kevin.
Who?
Bobby bishop.
I'm gonna be sick.
It's ok.
Oh, my god.
Ok, I'm going
to do something.
No, don't, please.
Don't do anything.
Let's mess
with him
a little bit.
No. No.
Just listen.
Go to Lenny's
on Amsterdam.
I'll meet you.
Just go.
If I'm not there
in 5 minutes,
order something.
Yah!
Ha!
Aah!
So, a...
Bob?
What's goin' on?
Don't think you
can come back
so easy, TV boy.
We know
who you are and
what you want.
Kevin.what do I want?
What do I want?
The girl was a model.
Who's a model?
Jesus,
this neighborhood
is so fucked.
Just leave
us alone!
Hey!
Ladies room!
What happened?
Ladies room.
No time. Come on.
Hello?
Hey, Bob.
Aw, man!
Bob?
I can't take this.
Excuse me, did you see
a woman with black hair...
Just came in here?
Black hair. Long hair.
Straight hair.
I don't know.
Fuckin' jerk.
Did anybody...Excuse me.
Anybody see a woman
with black hair?
She just came in here.
I think we're
safe here.
What did you
say to him?
I just told him
to step off.
He won't
come in here.
This is
the ladies room.
We're ok.
He told a model
on live television
he wants to fuck her.
You don't think he's gonna
come into the ladies room?
No one saw her?
No one saw a girl
with black hair?
Did you see a girl
Come on.
Where...did you see
a girl with black hair?
She was just in here.
Ladies room.
Thank you. Thank you.
Hello?
I'm peeing.
I'll just wait
over here then.
This is
harassment.
You attacked me.
I'm looking for
Lily Charles.
Why?
I need to find her.
Can you help me find Lily?
I'm not feeling good.
I'm...I really would like
to find her and talk to her.
You know, for
a talk show host,
you're not
too articulate.
Ok. Ok. You're funny.
You're funny.
Ok? You're a pro.
Come on my show.
You can tell your jokes.
Hi.
I'm trying
to eat vegetarian.
So, um...
I'll have the meatloaf.
Is she in there?
Lily?
She is
different now.
I'm different, too.
I'm a lot different now.
Hold on.
I'm reading
something
on the wall.
Oh, "crock...
Of...Shit."
Great. Insult me.
Come on.
You're not even peeing.
Can I come in there?
I am peeing.Open the door.
I am peeing.
You hear it?
No, I don't hear it.
I bet you she's
still amazing,
like before.
I'd really like
to be amazed again.
Fuck you!
You need to be
amazed again?!
I knew it. I knew
you were in there.
Drop dead you TV
cheesy motherfucker.
Can you come
with me outside?
Just outside?
All right!
You! Out!
Let's go.
It's just,
it's my wife there.
Lily, can you just
come outside for a second?
What are you
doing there?
You look great.
Come on.
What are you doing?
You look
really nice.
Have some dignity.
Let's go. Come on.
Just come
outside for
a second?
Boy, did she
look great.
Didn't you think
she looked great?
I hear ya.
Let's go, pal.
Really beautiful.
Oh, uh...
Holy shit.
That was Bobby bishop.
He looks like shit.
Ok, everyone knew
the movie stunk.
So I looked at him
right in the eyes,
and I said,
"Jean Claude,
the movie stinks."
Right?
The movie stinks.
And since then,
he won't talk
to me again.
So I said, "ok,
great. Don't put him
on the show.."
This is going
to Lulu, right?
Ok...dear, sweet...
Lulu.
L-u-l-u, right?
Love...no offense...
Bobby...bishop.
Here ya go.
And your
girlfriend's Ann.
Hey!
Hey! I'm in here.
I'll be right there.
I'm just gonna
get some water.
Where were you today?
I was out
visiting my mom.
Oh. How is crazy lady?
She's fine.
Her and Keith
should room together.
I saw him today, too.
Sounds like
you had a crazy day.
Jeez.
Don't.
Sorry.
What'd you eat?
I just, uh,
got the meatloaf
at Lenny's.
Jeez! Are
you all right?
What the...
Jeez.
I'm sorry.
It's so stupid.
I got it.
Yes.
So, um,
guess who I saw?
Who?
Oh, just
your boyfriend.
Bobby bishop.
Ow!
God. You know what?
I got it.
I'll do it.
You just wash
your finger, ok?
Jeez.
You know, so I’m
at Lenny's, right?
And fucking Bobby,
Bobby bishop
walks in the door.
Did you say
anything to him?
I spit at him.
You spit at him.
Totally, yeah.
And people,
like, went nuts.
They were, like,
clapping, and they
stood up, and...
What an
asshole.
I know.
What an asshole
thing to do.
What?
I can't believe
you would spit at him.
Asshole?
I'm an asshole?
He's, like,
the biggest pervert
known to mankind.
He's not a pervert.
Are you joking?
He fucking asked
Bridget bower
to have sex with him
on television.
Bridget bower is a whore.
She's a...Wow,
whoa, whaa.
Jeez, you know?
Just...
We're arguing about
a talk show host.
No, we're not arguing
about a talk show host.
We're arguing
because you are an asshole.
All right? I'm gonna
take a bath.
I'm an asshole.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
I haven't eaten.
I'm an asshole?
Did you buzz today earlier?
So, you see, I'm empty.
I'm broken.
Go away!
I can't believe that
you're mad about this.
Come on.
Just beat it.
It's like...You're acting
like you know the guy.
Fine. Psycho.
Pretty in pink
is a much better
love story than mannequin.
It is not.
Rich guy falls for girl
from wrong side of the tracks.
Finds taboo love.
What can be
more taboo
than a guy
who falls for
a life-sized doll?
I used to sleep
with a doll.
Uh, hey!
Hey! What's
going on? Hey!
Hey!
Hey, the board feels
late-night TV's
a bad influence.
We're crazy.
Hey, I'm trying.
I'm trying, guys.
If days
of the week
had a color,
what would
Tuesday be?
Sky blue.
Navy.
No, uh...Dark brown.
Like
a chocolate.
Bobby! Mr. Bishop!
What happened?
Any comment?
Did you know you can
pay bail with visa?
I didn't know that.
Did you know that?
No.
That's crazy.
Talk show host Bobby bishop
in trouble again.
Arrested and in love
in New York City.
Only on news 6 at 11:00.
Hello?
Mark. Hi. How are you?
Hey, how ya doin'?
She's in the tub.
Oh, you're not
watching TV, are you?
Yeah. Why?
Put on 31. Quick.
All right.
Take it easy.
Hold on.
Uh, ok. Great.
I'm not really
into pandas, though.
Ok? Bye.
No, Mark. Shit!
Hello?
Uh, I'm sorry.
I need to talk to Lily.
Uh, what channel
are you watching?
I'm on, uh...
Why am I telling you
what channel I'm on?
She's in the tub.
God.
What a dick.
What a dick!
Oh...
Ok, hold on
a second.
Lily!
What?
Cindy's on the phone.
She says it's important.
For her to be
an asshole. Now.
All right...
I'm gonna
open the door.
open the door
just a crack, ok?
And I want you to
pass me the phone.
Come on.
I'm serious.
All right.
Hello?
It's right here.
Oop. Whoa. There it is.
Oh, there's the phone!
Oh, she's got the phone.
Hey, what's up?
You've got to get Mark
away from the TV.
He's been arrested.
Oh, my god. Arrested?
Oh, my god.
Just listen to me, woman!
Get him away from the TV!
The popular late night
talk show host,
famous for
making lewd comments
to Bridget bower,
has been
bit by the love bug.
Oh! Oh!
Make love to me.
Baby, what the fuck
did you just do?!
No. No. Come here.
Why did you do that?
I don't know.
Are you
fucking insane?
The television!
I know. Fuck me. Hmm?
What?
I can't help it.Baby...
Love got me busted.
And her name is Lily.
Hey, Lily.
Anyway, New York's got
the best pizza in the world.
Oh, Kevin.
What'd you say?
What?
You just said Kevin.
No, I did not.Yeah, you did.
No, I didn't.
I said Mark.
How the fuck could
I mistake Kevin for Mark?
Nobody's Kevin.
Come on.
You know what?
Forget it.
I'm so over this.
I don't fucking care.
Kevin?! Jesus, man.
Unbelievable.
Hi. What...What happened?
What'd they say?
He's fucking
in love with you.
Oh, where's Mark?
Oh, my god.
He's in the bathroom.
Keith. Keith.
Keith. Keith!
Barry, man.
What the hell?
He's here.
Who's here?
I'm talking
to Keith.
Go to sleep.
Who's here?
Him.
Go to sleep!
Pooch in the city.
Who's here?
Called Cindy.
She hasn't
called me
back yet.
Call again.
They love that.
That's a good
job, Nathan.
Go to sleep.
Oh, Nathan,
you've got to...
Hey, do not
talk to me like that!
Who the fuck
is Kevin?!
What are you eating?
I'm eating
wheat thins.
Well, stop it!
What?!
Those are my crackers!
I'm not kidding! Come on!
You are fucking insane!
What are...
Will you open
the fucking door?!
No. You will not
talk to me
like that.
You're...Jesus Christ!
Your whole family
is fucking insane!
God!
Hey, come on.
Give me a break, please.
Hey.
Hi. Yeah.
Thank you.
Hi. How ya doin'?
So you, you...
You hold the key
to the pooch
in the city.
Yes, I walk the dog.
That's what I do.
How do I know?
I'm tellin' ya.
Barry?
How...how...
How do I know
that it's
a pure bred
and not a mutt?
It...it is a mutt.
It's a mix.
No, he...
I think
what he means
is that how
do we know it's
Sarah Jessica's?
No. No. No. Listen.
I walk
Matthew Broderick's dog.
That's all I guarantee.
You guys wanna call it
Sarah Jessica's dog?
Go ahead.
Look, that's your deal.
Ok. 2,000
for the puppy.
Did you tell him
it was a puppy?
No, I said
it was a dog.
Dog. Dog. Dog.
It's not a puppy.
Dog! Dog!
2,000 for the dog.
I mean, it's a dog.
Hey, sugar.
Want a date?
Thanks.
Nice shoes.
Who are you?
I know you.
Thanks for
watching the show.
Thank you.
Thanks for
watching the show.
Holy shit.
Kevin Michael moss.
Right.
Karen Malory.
Fourth period English.
You don't remember?
8.
Look. Look.
Look in my eyes.
Ok.
I'm crazy.
He's crazy.
You know what's crazy?
I'm gonna lose my job.
Ok? 10.
8.
Please, tell him.
Please.
Guys, I gotta
get back.
It's cold.
8.
How about 9?
Barry. Barry.
Get it together.
How about 9?
8. I could buy
a Baldwin dog
for 10.
Mrs. Suchman's
class.
I remember.
There you go.
You were 6 foot tall
in second grade.
I remember you.
Fuckin' a.
We played
football together.
You tackled me once.
You almost
killed me.
I remember you.
Nice to see you.
Yeah.
Good seeing you,
too, honey.
Look it.
Back to mess with
the bitch's brain.
Why don't you
stop swinging
that dick around?
Poor Lily.
I didn't swing nothin'.
I haven't done a thing.
I haven't been
swinging anything.
I haven't done
one thing wrong.
You know her brother
went nuts.
I know the brother.
Yeah, I know her brother.
I know him.
I brought him candy today.
I know all about him.
Believe me,
I know what I'm doing.
What I'm doing.
What's he doin'?
I think he's
haggling with her.
Take some money.
If you're not
gonna let her be...
And shut up.
Wait, look.
See how easy?
I'm gonna pay you
to shut up.
Don't fuck
with the bitch,
unless you fuck her
like a champion.
Good hustle.
You're not gonna
make me shut up.
Take it. Here. $100.
And you don't insult me anymore.
Fuck you.
Fuck your money.
Shove it up
your fucking ass.
All you have to do
is shut your big, fat mouth.
She's a good girl.
Remember big Karen?
Big Karen now grew up
and has a big mouth.
Scrawny
motherfucker.
Scrawny Bobby.
Here, take the money.
Fuck you!
Yes, I did.
I screwed
Bobby bishop.
I gave him
a blowjob.
Yes, I did.
My name is Sundey,
with an "e".
Hey, Marco Polo.
Hey.
What's the matter
with you?
Why do you
look so sad?
I'm not sad.
It's such
a good song.
It is a good song.
You wanna have
a drink with me?
Sure.
Bradley? Can we
have another...
Cosmo.
Cosmopolitan for
sad sack over here.
I am not sad.
You look sad.
Come on. Cheer up.
Oh, my...
Oh.
Come on.
Just do it. Do it.
I don't feel good.
You'll feel better.
I haven't worked out
in, like, a week.
You look good to me.
I'm totally bloated.
My stomach is, like...
I'm, like, chubby.
I am. Stop.
Come on.
Let the music
free your soul.
Ok? Come on!
I'm too fat.
Come on, bitch.
Get up.
Let's work.
Right now.
Off your chair.
On the bar.
Do your dance.
No.
Come on.
Hello?
Hey. You got
fucking arrested. Genius.
Yes, a ladies room.
Big fucking deal.
What the fuck am I doing?
What am I doing?
God, I swear so much
these days.
Hey, uh, listen. Variety
loved the "I wanna
fuck you" bit.
Yeah, we got 'em
by the balls.
We're a hit.
We're...
Hey, we're going live
in New York City.
What?
You're going live.
Don't come
to New York, Mitch.
to New York.
I love you.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Come on, Mitch.
Don't come.
Don't come
to New York.
Do not come
Don't come
to New York, Mitch.
♪ You set me on fire
♪ 'cause you're filled
with desire ♪
Jesus Christ!
♪ You draw my emotions
♪ I can feel your desire
♪ feel it comin',
feel it comin' ♪
♪ dancin'
aah!
♪ Dancin' with desire
♪ dancin',
gettin' me higher ♪
Lily! Lily!
Come on!
Let me in!
Stop.
Ah, come on.
You're as cute
as a fucking bug,
you know that?
Stop it.
You're so cute,
I could eat you up.
Don't fuck with me.
Oh, she's goin'
with the fuckin'
left hook.
Lily!
No, I gotta go.
I gotta go see Lily.
She's so pissed.
Mark, you're gay.
Ok? She knows it.
It's over.
Gay. What is gay,
really?
Lily! Lily!
Hey, Lily!
Come on.
Lily!
Lily, don't
disappear.
Why?! Why?!
Because you're the only one
who can disappear?
You are in my fucking
living room 5 nights a week.
Don't talk to me
about disappearing.
4 nights.
We repeated
on Monday.
I know that, because
I even watched that.
That's how fucking
pathetic I am.
The show's good.
The least you can do,
if you're gonna leave me,
is leave me.
You don't have to become
a part of pop culture!
In my fucking living room
5 nights a week!
Excuse me.
Excuse me for
being successful.
That's what I did.
I've become a part
of pop culture. Lily!
Hey!
All right, I’m...
You know what somebody
gave me for my birthday?
What? What?
One of those birthdays
that you didn't even
fucking call me for.
Lily.you wanna know?
Here! Look!
A midnight with Bobby bishop
coffee mug!
Listen, cut it out.
Cut it out.
Cut it out?
What kind of jerk
would give a mug for...
This is lighter.
Hey, you know what this is?
Won't hurt ya!
That is a beach towel.
Not a normal one.
A Bobby bishop beach towel.
I didn't even know
we made these.
Well, you do.
You make 'em.
And guess what?
I loved it!
I loved it when my cousin
Jenny goes to California.
"Oh, we saw
the Bobby bishop show.
He's so cute!"
All right. Lily...
Fuck you!
Hey, come on.
I'm sorry.
Come on downstairs.
You're waking up
the whole
neighborhood.
I don't give a fuck
about the neighborhood.
For once...
When did you get
this new vocabulary?
You know where it's from?
Where did I get it?
My new attitude?
What the fuck?
You never
said things
like that, ever.
I never had the opportunity
to say it to you before
because you left!
Do you have any idea
what it's like?
Do you know what it's like
to be in a relationship,
to live with someone,
and not be able to tell them
that the guy on channel 7
is your boyfriend?
That is your ex-boyfriend?
Do you know
what that's like?
I'm like a fucking...
I'm a spectacle.
I'm an idiot!
I'm a loser!
You're not a loser.
What are you...
Come on! I did
everything for you!
I helped you!
I loved you!
I loved you, too.
We were a couple.
I thought
you were funny.
I am funny.
I rearranged
my living room furniture
so we could play talk show.
You know? I'll be ed,
and you be Johnny.
I was a better Johnny.
You tried Johnny once,
you were terrible.
No, you weren't funny
as Johnny! You weren't!
Johnny wasn't...
Hey, guess what?
I was funny!
I don't remember you
ever being funny.
No offense, but you
were not that funny.
You were fun,
but you were not
that funny.
Ok? Now,
will you come down
and let's talk?
You know what
wasn't funny?
What?
Don't bring that up.
I wasn't going to
bring it up.
I don't wanna
talk about that
now, please.
I know, it must
be painful for you
to send me a fucking check.
That must have been hard.
You think I had
no feelings about that?
You think I had feelings
when I read
that you're
dating Sheryl crow?
I can't believe this.
I can't believe we're
arguing about a tabloid.
I never met Sheryl crow.
You fucked me up
when you got famous!
I'm gay.
No shit!
I'm Bobby.
Yeah, I know
who you are.
Don't shake his...
But I didn't
know who you...
Who is this?
I hate your fucking
show by the way.
It sucks.
Who is this?!
This is riff.I'm gay, too.
Riff?!
Who is this,
I'd like to know?
You know exactly
who that is!
I'm Bobby.
I love
your show.
Who is he?
I don't understand?
Who's your fucking
little friend?
Is that your boyfriend,
is that your affair,
is that your lover?
He's a friend
of mine, ok?
We're just having
fun, that's all. Ok?
That Bridget bower
is a slut.
Would you shut up
about Bridget bower?
Thanks.
Oh, "thanks."
Bobby, shut...
All right, you didn't
have any idea
about what was
going on? I mean,
come on, be honest.
No, I didn't.
I thought you were
kind of strange,
but, no, I didn't.
Hey, maybe
you're strange, ok?
Hey, maybe you should
shut the fuck up!
Shut up!
What is this?
What is
your life?
You know what,
you know, I'll...
I'll just come back
next week, and I'll
get my stuff.
Come back and get
your fucking cock rings.
Look what you did,
you asshole!
What I did?
I made them gay?
Lily? Lily?
I'm kidding.
Read my speech.
"I'm here,
and I'm not leaving.
"I want to be
a whole person.
"With you, I was
"I was stupid,
but I was whole.
"I'm not going.
I'm smarter now."
I'm not gonna make
the same mistake, Lily.
the same mistake.
It's my girlfriend's
house.
Let's go, Romeo.
It's my girlfriend's house.
We're just having
a conversation.
She's up there. Lily!
Step over
to the car.
Lily!
Damn.
Come on, come on, guys.
It's my girlfriend's
house.
Come on,
inside the car.
Lily!
I'm sick. I'm sick
with love. Lily!
Get well soon.
Lily! Lily!
Lily!
God bless him.
Anybody home?
Mmhh. No.
Check this out.
The hooker's cute, huh?
Mom, it's me!
Who's me?
Me! Your...Mom, come on,
open the door.
Hey.
Mom...hey, hey,
what happened?
Mom?
What are you doing?
Hey!
Mom, what are
you doing?
What you do mean
what am I doing?
Sit down. I'm tired.
Hey...
What?
Oh, my god.
My roots, I know,
my roots.
No, mom,
what happened
to your face?
Nothing, nothing.
I...I slipped in the tub.
Oh, that is
bullshit, mother.
Come on, we're gonna
go to Lenox Hill.
No, I don't want
to go to the hospital.
Mom, I mean it...
Nooo!
Ok, ok.
No.
Ok.
All right, mom.
It's ok, I'm sorry.
Ok.
Sorry.
I'm gonna get you
a diet Pepsi, ok?
Yeah. No ice.
No ice.
Here,
why don't you...
Why don't you
have a cigarette?
I lost my lighter.
No, no, no,
I have it.
Here you go.
I did not touch her.
What's my horoscope?
You did a good job.
Thank you.
You're
the best manager
a bum like me
could've ever
hoped for, Mitch.
All right, stop now.
Come on.
Who's
our first guest?
Matthew Broderick.
Don't start.
He's a fine actor,
a fine actor.
It'll be fine.
You did a good job.
Thank you.
Ok, can we go,
can we go?
Can we go?
Mom, what happened
to your little
protector?
Arthur?
Yeah.
He left.
What do you mean
he left?
Left, gone.
They never come back.
Oh, my god...
Did you have sex
with this guy?
Give me
another cigarette.
No! Mom, look at me,
look at me.
Did you have sex
with him? No, no!
Where? Here?
No.
Where!
In the park.
It was beautiful.
Mom, you could've
been murdered.
Linda, you could
have aids.
Oh, stop it, will you?
Arthur was good.
We used a glove.
I'm gonna take you
to the hospital.
A glove?
Ok.
Ahem.
Yeah.
Starbursts.
Uh...lots of 'em.
Over and out.
Ok, around 4:00
or 5:00.
All right,
thank you.
Everything cool?
Yeah.
Hey, mom,
you want a bagel?
No, honey.
You know, I really
should run over
to St. Paul's before
I miss out on grub.
Heh. Nobody says
grub anymore,
mom.
What is grub?
Hey, how you doing?
What are you looking at?
Did you really
blow that hooker?
No.
No?
No! You would believe
that I would do that?
No, I did not,
I did not,
I did not blow her,
and she did not blow me.
We didn't blow each other.
No blowing.
She was...
No, I don't do that.
I'm not like that.
Ok.
Ugh.
Good man.
All right, here.
I got the stuff.
Oh, yeah.
Got the stuff.
Did I come through?Thanks.
Did you ever see bag
that big of that stuff?
Look, uh...
There's somebody
that I'd like you
to say hello to.
Come on, Keith.
I got a lot on my mind.
Just...just
for a second.
It'd be
a big thrill.
I do this all the time,
I hate it, I hate it.
That's what everybody says,
they say the same thing.
"It's just
this one person."
Bob, come on!
"It would mean
so much to them."
One person. One person.
Yeah, ok, great.
Hold on.
Ugh.
Bobby bishop...
Bobby bishop.
How you doing?
What's your name?
What's your name?What's your name?
I'm Bobby bishop.
Who is this guy?Who is this guy?
I don't get it.I don't get it.
He thinks he's you.
Say hi.
Oh, I see.
He thinks he's me.
All right, enough.All right, enough.
Cut it out.Cut it out.
Anyway, nice to meet
you. Bobby bishop.
Nice to meet you.Nice to meet you.
Thanks for watching
the show.
Cut it out.Cut it out.
All right, enough,
I get it, I get it.
I said I got it. Keith?
Keith?
Ok, we met. Good-bye.
Whuu!
Ahh! Get rid of him.Get rid of him.
Get him out of here.Get him out of here.
Get him out of here. Get him out of here.
Cut it out!
Cut it out.
All right, enough.
I get the joke.
Go, go away!
Thank you. Good night,
thank you.
Keith, get him out of here.
Get out of my sight,
you fucking nut.
Heh heh.
Keith, I mean,
come on.
Thank you.
What was that?
Some wacko?
Thank you.
Ok, the guy's
a fucking nut.
No. Nooo!
No! No way!
No fucking way!
Why is everybody
yelling?
Lily, you're doing
everything right.
It doesn't feel like
it, but you are.
Ok. How are my eyes?
You're beautiful.
They're fine.
Here,
blow your nose.
Ok. Ok.
I'm...I'm gonna go
see Keith.
Ok, I'll wait.
I don't care if his dog
is missing.
What do I care?
Hey, listen,
he promised
to do the show,
he is doing
the fucking show!
No.
No. I don't care
if his dog is dead.
How do you like that?
"I'm gay. I'm gay."
And he's got lipstick
on and the whole thing,
and it was Mark,
it was him.
"I'm gay?"
Lily's dating gay.
The little one loved me.
Mark hated me.
Woof.
Real gay.
Hey, Keith,
your sister's here.
Woof!
Keith, I'm not here,
I'm not here.
Right. Yes.
Bring her in.
Excuse me.
That's my guy.
Bobby.
You watch television?
Do you watch television?
That's my...That's
Bobby bishop.
Late night with...
Mm-hmm.
Do you do film?
Because you have
a beautiful structure
to your face.
A struc...
What's wrong with you?
You...you...
Just...get out
of my face.
Asshole.
Hey, go fuck yourself,
you know?
I'm just trying to make,
you know, conversation.
Go fuck...Go fuck
yourself.
I don't need
that shit.
When was he here?
The other day.
I don't want to
talk about him.
Did you see
the paper?
Yeah.
I don't want to
talk about it.
Look, Lily...
He didn't do that.
What?
The paper.
Lily, he wouldn't
do that.
I don't know that.
Look, he's crazy,
but I told you
it was a sign.
No, having a breakdown
on TV is not a sign.
Lily...
Hmm?
He loves you.
No, he loves Bobby.
No, he loves you.
And you love him.
I can see it.
You cannot.
Lily, Bobby's been
here for 2 days,
and you look
totally different.
I do?
Your eyes,
for the first time
in years,
they sparkle.
You deserve to be
loved, Lily.
Really loved.
I don't know.
I'm out there,
and it is weird,
and it's hard.
I know.
No, no, no,
you don't know.
I remember.
Bobby's out there.
No, no, no, Bobby
is not out there.
Bobby is in TV land.
I don't have people.
I don't have...I can't...
Run a repeat
of last Tuesday
if I can't handle
this one.
I don't have shrinks,
I don't have handlers.
I can't go searching
for some girl
that I used to know
out of the blue.
I mean, I'm alone.
I worry about me.
And between you
and Linda and Mark...
And then all of a sudden,
Bobby bishop.
God.
I'm sorry.
No, don't be sorry,
don't be sorry.
Just please don't
tell me that it's easy.
Ok?
And that goes for you,
too, moron.
I should take
your starbursts back.
No, no!
Lily, Lily!
No, no! Fuck you!
Fuck both of you.
Keith, I'm sorry, I didn't
mean it with you.
You, I mean it!
Fuck you!
Hey, Lily.
No, no, see, I'm not
some Hollywood diva.
I know, I know.
I'm a real
fucking person.
I do my own hair!
I like your hair.
Yeah, your hair
looks good. You...
Stop it!
The world does not
revolve around you
when you're in it!
What's that mean?
I don't think
the world revolves
around me.
She looks good.
She looked good.
Let's go.
What's wrong?
I just got ambushed.
Oh, don't read
the paper today.
Shit!
Ugh!
Kitten? What happened?
Just leave me alone!
Damn.
I just banged
my head.
Let's go
do the show.
Let's do
the show.
There you go.
Yes, sir!
Wow, wow, wow!
Look at this!
Killer! Rebirth!
It's just TV, Mitch.
That's what
I'm talking about.
I'm talking about TV.
I'm talking about big show!
What happened
to Broderick's dog?
Broderick's dog.
That's important.
To me.
I'm on that.
Get on it, Mitch.
I'm...
Where you going now,
killer?
Hi, Linda.
Hiya, honey.
It's good to see you.
Yeah.
How's the vibe?
Not too bad.
Good.
Listen, Keith,
I don't want...
What?
To cramp your style.
Heh! You're not gonna
cramp my style.
Well, you know,
I know you have
a girlfriend.
Mom, I don't have
Oh, I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Your special friend.
Mom, I don't have
a special friend.
It's only natural,
you know,
that a mother
would want to meet
her son's gal.
And I'm sure this...
This little
Sarah Jessica
would like to meet
the mother
of her Beau.
Mom...
Sarah Jessica and I...
Broke up.
Oh, honey.
She gave you
the gate?
What's the gate?
My baby's
growing up.
Listen, we got
a problem.
It's not
a big problem...
Can you keep
rubbing?
It's a talent thing.
All right?
You with me?
Yeah, I heard you.
Ok, we got a problem.
What else is new?
Don't ask
question number 3
to guest number 1.
Who's guest
number 1?
Broderick.and what's number 3?
Hal linden. Not who's number 3.
What's the question
number 3?
Yeah, for number 1.
What's the question
number 3 for number 1?
How's your dog?How's your dog?
What?
Oh, I get
what you mean.
Don't...don't ask...Ok.
How's your dog?
People love
celebrity pets,
you see.
That's
all of it?
That's all of it.
That's a hell of
a price to pay
for a dog.
What are we
gonna name it?
It totally
depends on its
personality.
We're not
getting a puppy.
I'm sure it
already has a name.
Well,
you can't give it
another name.
It'll get confused.
We might like
its name.
We're not naming,
we're napping.
Dognapping.
Exactly.
Did you find
the dog yet?
It doesn't matter.
We can't...It's gone.
Ok, fine. I won't
ask him the question.
Good.
Don't ask him,
"how's your dog?"
Please.
Find his dog.
Put up signs,
do something.
I'm working on it.
You keep saying
you're working
on it.
You want makeup
back in here? Makeup!
Send her in,
send her in.
Ok, all right.
Ok.
"Hey, Matthew,
how's your dog?"
No, no, no.
Just kidding, Mitch,
just kidding.
Look good, feel good.
Take care of him.
Mitch, you know
I got that pounding
feeling again.
Anything could happen.
Here you go, Angy.
Nice and toasty.
These are
delicious bagels,
Mrs. Charles.
Thank you.
Angy, Keith, Nathan:
You're welcome,
boys.
See, I put
the butter on
before
I toast them.
Scrumptious.
I'm gonna go get
a diet Pepsi.
Can I get
anybody anything?
Uh-uh.
Easy, easy, easy.
2 minutes to showtime.
Going live
in 2 minutes.
Band, crew, and talent,
take your places.
Almost time.
You want to watch?
Why do they call it
midnight with Bobby
bishop
when it comes on
at 11:30?
It's cute.
Hey, Ronnie!
Scumbag.
Oh, come on, Ron,
white flag, white flag.
Your boy
better be good.
I brought my gun.
And no dog,
or we're gone.
Hmm.
Ruff.
And now,
ladies and gentlemen,
live, it's midnight
with New York City's
favorite John...
Bobby bishop!
Kevin moss.
Can I speak with you?
Bobby's on.
Got him.
Oh!
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Where do you think
you're going?
Oh...
Mom, this is
my friend Barry.
We're going out
for a little
while.
Nice to meet you,
Mrs. Charles.
Hello, Barry.
Well, don't you boys
stay out too late, now.
We won't.
You promise me.
I promise.
Feel this.
And here he is,
Bobby bishop!
Bobby! Bobby! Bobby! Bobby!
Now before we begin
the show,
first off, right away,
this is very
important to me.
Uh...
I never got a blow job
from that hooker.
What he say?
He didn't just say that.
No blow job.
That's
what I thought
he said.
You can't say
blow job on TV.
Why would
I say that?
This...
Right here...
This is not living.
I want to spend my life
with somebody,
not a bunch
of fucking idiots
who waited in line
for hours
to see this stupid
fucking talk show.
My whole life,
this is what I wanted.
To be right here
in this spot,
in front of this audience,
on this show,
with my theme song.
That's what I wanted.
Because I thought
when I got here
that everything
would be ok.
I would be happy.
This would make me happy.
And once I got here...
I would be able
to start living.
That's what I thought.
But I wasted my life.
I had somebody
who adored me,
and she was
the greatest audience
in the whole world.
And we didn't
need any applause sign
to be happy.
Ok.
I realize
this is not funny.
This is not funny
for anybody.
I'm not being funny.
I'm not that funny.
I'm just a guy.
Just a simple guy.
And, uh, you know what?
Fuck the network.
Fuck all the ratings.
And fuck you.
My name is Kevin.
I'm Kevin.
Uh...
Nice to meet you.
We're outta here.
What a crazy talk show.
Fuck the network!
I'm not Bobby, I'm Kevin.
I'm empty, I'm Kevin,
I'm Kevin! No more show!
I'm Kevin. Nice to meet me,
nice to meet me.
I'm Kevin, I'm Kevin!
Fuck the network!
Fuck you!
I'm Kevin, I'm Kevin!
Little Kevin moss,
all grown up.
Heh heh heh!
Oh, Kevin,
you got so hairy.
Ow, ow, ow!
That hurt!
Did you get it?
Are you fu...No,
I didn't get it.
Give me
a fucking break.
Of course
I fucking got...
What do you think
I was just doing?
You know, the dog
took a shit in the car.
The dog took a shit
in the car? Well...
Fine! Who...
Ok, ok, ok. Can we
go right now?
Please, please,
please?
Thank you.
Hey!
Hey, hey!
I can't believe
he did it!
I can't believe it!
Hey.
Rockefeller center.
Uh, 83rd
and Columbus
as fast as you can.
Big tip, big tip,
big tip.
Yes, yes, yes!
You're the big girl!
Yes, you are!
Who's a cute puppy?
Go, go! No, no!
Thank you.
♪ Lily, Lily, Lily
Lily? Lily!
Lily, Lily!
Where's Lily?
Your show is awful.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Can I speak
to Lily, please?
She went to find you.
She went to find me?
Go!
All right,
thank you,
thank you.
Go!
Thank you.
Where's Bobby?Uh...Lena?
Lily.
Lily, Lily!
Yeah, he's not
here. He, uh...
He went. He went
to find you.
Lot of teeth.
Go around this guy.
Ok, 83rd
and Columbus.
Keith, hurry up!
I'm gonna lose
my job!
Keith!
Will you just give me
a second here?
This is a very
upset dog.
Come on,
that thing is making
a ton of noise.
I know this, Barry.
Get it together.
I'm sorry.It's ok, it's ok.
Ok, now get Louis started
on the ransom note.
Bring back a jar
of peanut butter,
creamy. Go!
Oh, shit!
Boys? Boys...
What in the world
do you think
you're doing here?
Hey, mom.
Keith, I'm very
disappointed in you.
Whoa! Jesus!
Jesus, that was
fucking close!
Should we stop?
No, no, no!
Fucking...Oh,
fucking cab drivers!
God damn it!
Bobby!
Thank you. Thanks
for watching the show.
Bobby!
Kevin!
Hey!
Hey, you ok?
I don't know. It's
like it's stuck.
Hello.
Hi.
Um, I need to
speak to a, uh,
crazy person you have
here named Nathan.
Nathan.
Nathan, yes.
Nathan. Ok.
This way.
Thank you.
Did you see
the show?
Did you see it?
Sorry, I missed it.
Oh, you didn't
see the show?
No.
Lily...
What
I said things to you
on the show.
What did you say?
Things. I can't
explain it now.
What kind of things?
Nice things. I said
things for you.
Like what?
Nice things.
How could you
miss the show?
Did you see
the show?
I saw it.
I want you
to love me again.
Can you love me
again, please?
I can like you
a whole bunch.
No. Can you
love me again?
Ok, now here's
the deal.
We're gonna ask you
to do a monologue.
You think you can
remember a monologue?
Yeah?
Yeah.
Good. Give him
the monologue.
Hey, listen to me.
Ok, I want to tell you
something.
I have seen talent.
Ok, that's all I want
to say. Let's go.
You gotta go something
with his hair.
His hair sucks.
I think earth tones.
Can someone get
the door, please?
Could someone get
Jesus Christ!
Mmm.
Oh, Bobby.
What'd you call me?
Kevin.
Let's just look at it.
I've never seen
that much money.
Oh, ok, all right.
Hold on,
just hold on.
Fine.
Ok. Ok, ok,
ok, ok, ok, ok, ok.
Oh, look.
Oh, my god.
Treats.
You're an idiot.
Fuck me.
Captioning made possible by
lions gate entertainment
captioned by the national
captioning institute
...Www.Ncicap.Org...