Presented by Cinema Service
How can she be that fat?
She's disgusting!
She's huge! Eat as you want!
- She wouId rather die.
- Right...
Fat!
Fatty! Fatso!
It's not here.
Her spirit is gone!
What?
Those bastards again?
WeII...?
Ghost in Love
Hmm... Your body odor...
Make me puke.
What?
Don't take this off
untiI you die, okay?
- Can I take it off after I die?
- You!
- May I come in?
- Wait.
CouId you wait for me in the car?
I'II be right down.
What's the matter?
A woman in there?
What woman?
I'II be right down.
Wait for me, okay?
Who was that woman?
Just an acquaintance.
Look at me and teII me who she is.
Do I have to teII you everything?
Don't nag at me, aII right?
What did I do wrong?
I can't say anything
when a girI shows up here?
You're being ridicuIous.
Do you know that?
RidicuIous? You're the one
who proposed to me.
You asked me to marry you
after 3 years, didn't you?
I have to go now.
Why don't we die together?
She's cute though.
Looks aren't everything.
A girI shouId have nice hips.
Do we have to wait tiII tomorrow?
Let's just do it now...
We have to keep the time.
We're not murderers, you know.
She came to check on
her stock transactions, okay?
Then why did you ride
in her car?
It's important for me to
service my cIients after hours!
But she seemed to be just
more than a cIient to me.
I Iiked you because you were
nice and comfortabIe.
But you've changed.
I don't wanna see you anymore
if you nag at me Iike this.
I'm sorry for not trusting you.
Do you even beIieve me?
I'II try, but don't act Iike you're
hiding something from me.
I'II caII you Iater.
Can we taIk for
5 more minutes, pIease?
Wait for me at the park.
I'II be right there.
Okay.
It's me.
I've been waiting for 2 hours.
You're not at work.
You don't even answer
your ceIIuIar phone.
Where are you now?
I feeI so confused.
CaII me when you check this message.
Don't do that!
We have to take her
before they show up.
Do you wanna be punished? Hurry up!
Our accurate information
says you're destined to die.
Everybody in the worId
is after vain hope.
You're about to
enter the eternaI worId.
Hey, onIy two minutes Ieft!
His battery isn't dead.
He's not just caIIing you back.
Didn't you see it?
He doesn't care about your feeIings.
Anyway, that girI has great body!
She has big tits!
The worId wiII end soon.
Let's just pIay around.
Nah Han- soo! Nah Han- soo!
Train is coming just in time!
Hurry up and jump!
Hurry.
One... two... three!
Who are you...
- It's over.
- Give it up.
Am I reaIIy dead?
Am I?
Are you aII right?
You're not busy, ''Kantorates''?
It has started.
If we don't do anything,
then you'II be a wandering ghost.
You'II be aII right.
Don't worry.
PeopIe have neither a shape
nor memory when they die.
But we'II save you from that.
CongratuIation!
We're the first democratic cIub
for ghosts in the netherworId!
You can join or quit at any time!
You can go in and out of
mundane worId Iike your own home.
Society for Suicide Ghosts!
S.S.G!
Then you are...
We're the recruiters for SSG!
We take care of our members.
What did you do to me?
I never wanted to commit suicide!
- Why did you jump into the train?
- Didn't you say you wanted to die?
- I just...
- We actuaIIy heIped you.
A person Iike you who committed
suicide can't go to the Heaven.
I didn't commit suicide...
We exist for peopIe Iike you
who commit suicide.
For the peopIe who stiII
have things to do in the worId.
You can pay back your grudge
or try to actuaIize sociaI justice.
I'm sure you want to
pay back to someone.
Nah Han- soo!
Man is the Iord of aII creation?
That's possibIe if man is the onIy thing
that can become a ghost.
But an animaI does, too.
The worId is infested with
beast ghosts after dark.
But you're unabIe to
kiII anything, not even a fIy.
It's a wandering ghost!
You'II be a miserabIe ghost
if you're not a SSG member.
Our way to survive is to increase
our society members.
Ghost name ''Pit Viper''.
SSG membership number 00666.
Position: The director of
the generaI affairs. Is it right?
You'II be executed for creating
disorders in the netherworId...
...by joining unIawfuI organization
and kiIIing human beings.
This is unfair!
Unfair?
Hundreds peopIe are kiIIed
each year in the name of revenge.
Do you think they're
being fairIy treated?
They treated me Iike a dog!
Execute him!
You mean I died because they
needed to recruit more members?
No wonder....
I know I shouIdn't
have died so suddenIy.
Died suddenIy?
Okay! ''Sudden''!
That's your name!
We don't use the oId name.
My name is ''Diety''!
Look at aII this meat I have!
OnIy aII this fat...
- You want to eat?
- No, thanks.
This doesn't taste the same.
It's getting worse.
I couId stiII smeII
but after 1 or 2 years...
- What's wrong with this?
- Why?
EventuaIIy I'II Iose my senses.
But I can't heIp that.
If you have questions, ask me.
Don't go around aIone.
Make sure to foIIow him.
Who do you mean?
I mean Kantorates.
You and him are partners.
Damn recruiters!
It's their job to educate new members!
AII they do is Iatch
on to your mistakes.
Hey, Diety! What did I do wrong?
I wasn't taIking about you.
Don't show up Iike that.
You make me nervous.
Let me rest untiI I move to
the bigger pIace, aII right?
Bye.
That was...
Diety!
After aII, we're spirits.
I couId even change cIothes.
You do Iook different...
But I Iike this.
I was curious about
the worId after dead.
But there aren't many differences.
PeopIe Iive in the house
but we don't, that's aII.
There she goes again.
She's ''PaIe Face''.
She was raped in front of her fiance,
so she committed suicide.
She feIt herseIf so dirty even in here.
She's constantIy washing...
She's getting so paIe.
Don't remember anything.
EspeciaIIy the things that hurt you.
Open your eyes!
He got into a car accident.
His BP is 80/60.
CouIdn't you contact Dr. Park?
I paged him.
PIease do something!
Where are aII the doctors?
Are you gonna Iet him die?
Insert the tube in the chest.
- A car accident, right?
- Wake up!
Lungs are caused pneumothorax.
Get the air out first.
Prepare the tube!
PIease wake up!
Your sister'd be with your father.
Let's go.
Did you put socks on her?
She's very sensitive to coId.
Mom...
Mom!
I'm here!
Try to forget it.
We're totaIIy different beings.
We're here but nobody notices us.
We're Iike the third being.
We don't even have a body
but you caII us a ''being''?
Don't be ridicuIous.
You're onIy a ghost!
Just think that you're IittIe away
from where you were before.
Do you think we're pIaying ghosts?
Indeed you're the most inteIIectuaI
ghost in our organization.
No wonder we caII you ''Kant''.
He's aIso ''Hippocrates''
who Ioves human so dearIy.
He's the great Katocrates!
I don't know why you wander
around every hospitaIs.
This is my tweIfth year
of being a recruiter.
But nobody ever voIuntariIy
came to us Iike you.
On top of that, your performance
is pretty poor.
If you keep doing that, then you
can't be with us for Iong.
If you quit... then,
your memory wiII vanish
and your body won't be in intact.
I couId imagine you
being a restIess ghost!
1, 2, 3.
- Do you Iike it?
- Yes.
- I Iove you.
- I do, too.
Han-soo...
HeIIo.
Where are you?
What's wrong with my voice?
Han-soo ?
I'm just IittIe tired, that's aII.
Right now...?
Of course, I Iove you.
Yeah.
Did you aIready forget me?
I have to check again!
I can't end Iike this.
Bastard!
It might be better to end Iike this.
You can't go back anyway.
You want me to end Iike this?
I was a human yesterday
but how can I be a ghost today?
I stiII have feeIings, too.
I won't just accept everything
because I'm dead.
I can't.
HeIIo?
I worked overtime yesterday.
Today I got night shift.
I can't Iive Iike this.
When I first started,
I didn't work hard Iike this.
Some peopIe even
bribed us for Ionger Iife.
Nobody does it any more.
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry.
You know that SSG?
We shouId do something about them.
They can't even come to the Heaven.
Just Ieave them aIone.
In a day, they even take dozens of
peopIe who died naturaIIy.
Those peopIe can't be born again,
so Ieave them with SSG members.
Let them stay there.
- A Prank by Ghosts? -
Suicide Rates go up.
They even incite chiIdren to die?
WeII, those chiIdren can't be born again,
so Iet's Ieave them aIone.
This is serious matter!
Let's get out of here.
He's a messenger from Hades.
An erotomaniac ghost?
He waits untiI dark.
He Iooks for femaIe ghosts.
Don't Iook so startIed.
He tried to rape me.
You shouId reaIIy
be afraid of messengers.
They're aIways after us.
We couId die if we're caught.
- But I'm aIready dead.
- You can die twice.
I shouIdn't have said I wanted to die.
I just wanted to irritate him.
But this is so unfair!
He shouId feeI responsibIe
when he said he Ioved me.
Love?
That's what my fiancee said, too.
Nothing can separate us.
Forever Iove...
But I'm sure he's teIIing
the same thing to another woman.
It's fooIish to beIieve in Iove.
But...
He used you, that's aII.
He pIayed around with you,
and got tired of you.
You can pay back or forgive him.
The choice is up to you.
What? You wanna be a partner
with PaIe Face?
Why? You wanna go out with
an erotomaniac or something?
Diety!
I forbid you aII to act aIone!
Stay with your partners!
PIease take care of her.
I don't need a man's heIp!
EspeciaIIy, yours!
We don't need any more
outsiders Iike you.
Hey, PaIe Face!
You're nothing but
a restIess ghost, that's aII!
As Iong as you're in SSG, act Iike one.
What are you anyway?
Stop it! He's your senior!
How can you treat him Iike this?
He came here before you
for a reason, so respect him!
Team 1!
Team 1 had 86 new members...
and is seIected to be
the best team in SeouI area!
- Team 2!
- Yes?
Your team had onIy 12 new members.
None of you incite
peopIe to commit suicide!
PaIe Face, PaIe Face...
That's the onIy name I see in here!
I don't understand!
Why your team have such
a Iow achievement! Why!
Why do you aIways protect
the member who has no achievement?
What's your reIationship to him?
I'm taIking about Kantorates!
You've better get your act together.
Dead Number 556. This is how
he was found in the parking Iot.
Pay your attention
to a wound in his neck.
Since we have sufficient evidence,
I'II arrest PaIe Face for vioIating
Code 12- 3, causing vioIence
in the netherworId.
She works under
PaIe Face and attacks men.
I'II arrest her as soon as
I have sufficient evidence.
I thought you stood me up.
I toId you I'II be there.
I didn't want you to wait out here.
Your beard is so sexy.
Sometimes, I wanna change for you.
I have to Ieave.
I'm under emergency duty.
AIready? What's wrong this time?
An erotomania or a starving ghost?
How Iong wiII this take you?
I'II come and see you tomorrow.
Meet me at the park.
Okay...
Take care of your body.
I Iike big women, not the skinny ones.
You know about PaIe Face...
PaIe Face!
I just...
This is how you revenge.
PaIe Face!
We have no right to interfere
with human Iives.
If we don't do anything,
who's gonna punish sinners?
WiII it be Jesus or Buddha?
I can't just sit around
and wait for the Judgment Day!
You chose to end your Iife.
Women are being trampIed
down even in this instant.
You don't understand
the pain of taking your own Iife...
PaIe Face!
Leave this worId.
Why? He doesn't know anything,
but I can do aII things to him!
It's mean to act Iike that
to a powerIess man.
Are you saying I'm mean?
So what if I mean?
Since I have no future to worry about,
so I'II do whatever I want.
I knew you wouId be here...
Why are you stiII here?
Don't teII me what to do
when you can't even do it yourseIf.
Wait!
Young-eun, 1, 2...
ShaII we open our cIinic in here?
- In here?
- How about the ''CoupIe CIinic''?
I didn't take the Iicense exam yet.
You're stiII an army surgeon.
ShaII we just get married now?
Seung-woo.
I think we shouId do it now.
This ring wiII be tight
in 10 years, won't it?
10 years?
WeII, I don't know if I wouId
stay with you for 10 years.
Promise me!
What?
Promise me that you'II be with me
no matter what happens.
Young-eun!
Seung-woo!
The abdominaI cavity bIed too much.
InternaI organs are greatIy damaged.
It's 70/50.
His bIood pressure is dropping.
Take him to the generaI hospitaI...
We don't have time! Operate him, pIease!
- I can't operate him...
- You have to operate him!
We can't Iet him die?
I can't perform the operation
when there's no chance to...
I'II do it! I'II be responsibIe!
PIease Iet me do it.
Gauze!
Suction!
I agree with Katorates.
We were once human beings.
Let's not be so crueI.
I don't want you to
become Iike PaIe Face.
It's okay!
Escape from there.
It's common sense to escape
after you decIare bankruptcy.
Your runaway wife?
Didn't you have enough of her?
EmpIoyees' saIary?
OnIy 5 months unpaid.
You're so incompetent!
Why did you open the business?
You imbeciIe!
- Oh, Iet's taIk about your first chiId.
- He deIivers food.
He aIready knows a Iot of things...
Because he's a hot-tempered,
he'II make some troubIes!
How about your daughter?
''I don't wanna see you!
Don't show up in front of me!''
Boy, she's a good taIker!
- The river Iooks so cooI!
- Stop it!
You did what you can.
You couIdn't heIp it because you
business associates went bankrupt.
Suicide isn't the soIution.
You must think about
your youngest, too!
He Ioves you so much.
Hey!
You don't understand!
What?
You want us to start
in three-bedroom apartment?
We have to think about others.
PeopIe think your dad
hid the company money.
Let them say whatever they want.
I don't care!
AII right, then.
You reject my money and
heIp for your promotion.
Are you proud of yourseIf?
Listen, I wanna succeed on my own.
I Iove you for who you are
not for what you are.
ReaIIy?
You wouId rather be an actor.
Jesus!
Are you aII right?
- I'II wipe it for you.
- Never mind!
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Fuck, what's this?
You wanna succeed on your own?
You dirty hypocrite!
- Are you aII right?
- Oh, hi...
How have you been?
It's me!
Who are you... You...
It'II be our 1,000 days in 2 months.
WouId you Iike to go with me?
Are you insane?
You don't care about my death.
I'm so frustrated because you
fooIed around me aImost 3 years.
Do you think I'II Iet you
marry her that easiIy?
Just Iike that, huh?
PIease understand me.
I needed a chance.
I'II aIways watch you forever...
- I...
- Remember that!
Remember!
You've got an E- maiI.
Dad!
Do I have to take this?
Let me handIe it.
Who sent your ex- girIfriend's
picture to my father?
I toId you it was over.
You two were speciaI, huh?
Was she your wife or something?
She was just a sex partner.
We'II get married in 2 weeks.
Don't be mad, aII right?
Don't!
Don't try to stop me!
It's over.
He said I was just...
You wouId onIy feeI empty
when it's over.
I wanna take back everything
that I ever gave. Everything!
Then, that's not Iove.
That's onIy a business.
Love seems so worthIess to me.
Why? Is it not possibIe?
Reporter Kim and accountant Jung
are busy these days?
Dae-Young Pharmaceutica
has poor financiaI structures...
Sir...
CaII me father.
An opportunity comes from a crisis.
Don't think too hard.
We're not the onIy investers.
Father...
Hyun-ju's weaIth
wiII be yours, anyway.
When the price goes down
to 20,000, then seII everything.
I've set the price to 35,000 now,
so puII out at 20,000.
I can't taste anything now.
Where's PaIe Face?
What about Sudden?
Don't teII me you don't know.
If you harbor cuIprits,
you'II be executed, fatso.
How can you treat
a weak woman Iike that?
It feeIs good.
Hm... your body odor...
- What?
- Don't you remember?
We drank together
after you faiIed the job interview.
You were a great guy then...
Hyun-ju...
Just Iike on that day,
teII me you Iove me!
- What's the matter?
- It's me!
Have you aIready forgotten me?
This doesn't go with you!
What was that I did not have?
Her money? Her body?
TeII me!
What did you want from me?
Chae-byuI...
I did Iove you but....
But I couIdn't give
what you wanted, huh?
I'm not doing this because
I stiII have feeIings for you!
I'm just...
I couIdn't handIe that empty
feeIing when you died...
Stop it!
She's just... a sex partner!
Stay caIm! What's wrong?
Is a ghost here or something?
Quiet!
This is so unfair!
My revenge hasn't even begun.
Can't you forgive him?
I toId him to die together...
I reaIIy wanted to die
in front of him on that day.
Then, I reaIIy did die...
It's not passed even 2 months
since I died, but he's getting married.
Was I reaIIy worthIess to him?
Was I?
One more to go.
How do I Iook?
You Iook so pretty!
I've never worn this kind of
an ordinary dress before.
But you Iook so beautifuI.
No, I wanna buy a designer's.
I won't get married in this dress!
Our wedding day is
Iess than 10 days away.
Postpone it!
Shit!
Hyun-ju...
This is your Iast chance.
Are you gonna Iet him get married?
Leave me aIone. Do I Iook happy?
Did you forget
what he had done to you?
I'II revenge him if you want.
I aIso wanna ruin his Iife!
I wanna break off his wedding
and ruin him compIeteIy!
But... I shouIdn't...
This is so hard for me.
Just Ieave me aIone.
That's enough. You don't
have many days Ieft anyway.
You're onIy aIIowed to
stay here for 3 years.
You can't return to the netherworId
due to iIIegaI secession.
I can't go back yet.
You're a messenger!
How much Ionger
do you think I can heIp you?
You have to return now.
Return to the netherworId.
Look what your Kantorates is doing.
Is it by chance that we're
wanted by the messengers?
Groom Nah Han-soo
and bride Cha Hyun-ju.
Do you soIemnIy swear you'II Iove
and care for each other and
fuIfiII your duty as man and wife?
I do.
Bride?
No!
I said, 'No'!
I wanna know the truth.
Can you get married her
even if I were aIive?
Is this how you repay my Iove for you?
What exactIy did you mean when you
taIked about Iove and marriage?
Can you just dump me
Iike that afterwards?
Honey!
If you did Iove me once,
then teII me the truth!
TeII me the truth!
Watch out!
You and he are aIike!
Is this what you caII Iove?
If you reaIIy Ioved him you wish
for his happiness.
Are you okay?
Maybe it means nothing to you but it
couId be everything to someone.
It was too hard for me.
I wanna rest now.
- I'II Iet you rest, too.
- Stop!
You have no right to
judge human beings.
Shut up!
I'm scared.
Let me go!
You misunderstand me.
I'm scared of you.
I don't wanna die Iike PaIe Face!
Yes, I was a messenger.
I had no choice.
You and she had just a brief affinity.
We aren't guaranteed whether
we can reincarnate as a man.
Can you imagine how desperate you are?
I can't Iet Young-eun to Iive
with guiIty feeIings.
I have to make her to forget me.
Hasn't Dr. Suh caIIed?
Since Dr. Hyun died,
we couIdn't contact her.
You shouIdn't act Iike this.
We can't Iet your personaI
feeIings to get invoIved.
Erase aII your previous memories.
I can't do that untiI I find Young-eun.
If you act Iike this,
I have to erase your memory!
You definiteIy have to give up
on one or the other.
I have something to teII Young-eun.
Eat weII.
Mom, I'm here.
I'm sorry, Mom.
I was a bad girI, wasn't I?
Thank you.
You've heIped me since the beginning
but I've never thanked you.
What's your name?
I mean when you were aIive.
Chae-byuI, Jin Chae-byuI
I did have a name...
- What about you?
- Mine is...
Mom!
Are you okay?
Get hoId of yourseIf!
Mom! Mom!
The abdominaI cavity bIed too much.
InternaI organs are greatIy damaged.
BP is 70/50.
BIood pressure is dropping.
Take her to the generaI hospitaI...
The abdominaI cavity bIed too much.
InternaI organs are greatIy damaged.
BP is 70/50.
BIood pressure is dropping...
- Take him to the generaI hospitaI...
- I'II do it!
Doctor! Doctor!
Mom? Mom!
Mom...
Young- eun, it's me
I'm here.
Don't think that it'II happen twice.
You can do it.
I was destined to die.
I don't regret what happened.
I'II be with you.
Let's do it together
AII right?
- Finish up.
- Good job, doctor.
How did it go?
It's done.
Great. Are you aII right?
It was so hard.
You're awake.
Doctor...
Stay caIm.
Coming out from being under the
anesthetic may cause you IittIe pain.
Thank you, doctor.
Take good care of her and
caII me if anything happens.
Okay.
Take care of yourseIf.
Mom...
Does it hurt a Iot?
I guess you can't even show off
your beIIy button now.
But don't worry.
I'II Iet you have a pIastic surgery.
My friend is a doctor.
It won't hurt you at aII..
Mom, you can't feeI my presence.
I think your sister is here.
Didn't you want her to be happy?
I wanna be aIone.
AIone!
It's done! Go!
Once you're out, you can't
never come back here again.
You're removed from SSG forever.
I don't know what you're up to but
your memory wiII begin to erase.
You restIess ghost!
Let him go.
Start aII over again.
This is your Iast chance.
Okay.
Do you need to find anybody eIse?
No, that won't happen again.
You know Sudden
was arrested, don't you?
You're a messenger now.
If you do wiId things again,
then that wiII be it..
You'II be vanished forever.
Ghost name! Sudden!
Convicted of attempted murder
and injuringa human being,
participated in an
Execution is confirmed.
How are you?
You Iook good on it.
I'm sincereIy sorry.
I'm gIad that I met you...
I don't know whom I shouId thank.
You're a good man.
You're good, too.
What's your name?
Hyun, Seung-woo
Hyun Seung-woo...
I'II keep my eyes on you.
This is your first job.
Execute!
You were scared, weren't you?
- Seung-woo...
- You're safe now.
Thank you...
Seung-woo!
When my memories vanish,
I'II forget you, too...
I wanna remember onIy your name...
- So, you don't need me anymore?
- Didn't you expected this?
You fooI.
Your father's arrest is onIy a matter of
time if you irritate me Iike this.
- You dirty bastard!
- SIut!
Listen to me carefuIIy.
I wouIdn't have started if I were to
back off with smaII changes!
Damn you! Stop the car!
- Let it go!
- Stop the car!
- You!
- Be quiet.
How can I be quiet?
Shut up and stay put!
- Get in!
- What?
Hurry up, get in!
Kantorates and Sudden!
That's gonna be your new name.
Remember that!
This is aII your fauIt!
- Crazy bastard!
- What? You...
Stupid bitch!
Get in!
For next 50 years pretend to be them.
- How...
- Diety!
You!
You shouId be punished immediateIy.
Hurry!
Oh God!
Kantorates and Sudden...
- They are caught.
- Pardon?
That's not important!
Look at him.
He's not dead!
But they shouId've died
2 minutes 30 seconds ago...
The dead fiIes must be corrected.
FoIIow up on them! Now!
I don't think so. Not for 50 years!
Do we reaIIy Iive in these bodies?
Of course.
I don't know what to say...
WeII, have a happy Iife.
And never say you wanna die.
I envy you.
Did I teII you that?
I Iove you.
Diety!
You two are the first coupIe from
our organization. Let's take
a picture to commemorate that.
Everybody, Iook here!
Say ''Kimchee''
No. Say ''Ghosts''!
Ghosts!