The legend of Mae Nak
is a tale of true love...
...and is a tale that Thai people have
been telling for many generations.
Because one day the Ghost of
Mae Nak will return again...
...so she can find her true love.
The true love that once was.
Her spirit will never die.
Hey who's there?
It's very late to be knocking...
Who are you? Stop banging!
What are you doing?
Stop banging now!
Stop it! Just stop banging!
Hello. Good morning sir this is
your wake up call.
Nak! Oh I am so glad to hear
your voice. I had another nightmare.
-Mak are you okay?
-Yeah I'm fine. Just a bad dream.
-What do you mean?
-Well this one was...
Well tell me when I see you.
-Okay. Mak loves Nak.
-Nak loves Mak.
Going to work now?
No Father, I'm meeting Nak.
Here, what about your breakfast?
It's okay,
I'll have breakfast with Nak.
We're going to see a house.
They serve breakfast at this house?
No Mother. We'll probably get
something to eat beforehand.
Mother? Father?
Did you hear something last night?
No. nothing.
No. Why?
It must have been nothing. See you.
Nak! Not here. It's too public.
I haven't seen you in twelve hours.
This time I saw her.
Saw what?
This woman.
What woman?
In my nightmare. Her smile was black.
She had no teeth. No gums.
Just shiny black.
It was very real. Very scary.
Well from next week I'll be
sharing the bed with you.
So this woman will have to smile at me
first before she can scare you again.
Maybe a change of home
will improve things.
Let's hope that this Estate Agent
is as true as the words in his ad.
For sale:. Two bedroom house
with kitchen and bathroom
in Phrakanong district.
Needs some attention but...
Yes read on!
...ideal for newly wedded couple.
Asking price 300,000 Baht.
Contact Angel Estates.
It seems too good to be true.
I like the last part best:
"suitable for Newly Wedded Couple"
That'll be us.
You must be the
ten o'clock appointment.
Come on inside.
Sit down.
We've come about the property.
Not so fast! No so fast.
I knew you two would be
coming here today.
Now tell me about yourselves.
Well I'm Mak.
This is Nak, my fiancee.
We are getting married next Saturday.
Excellent. How wonderful.
So that must mean you are interested
in my little house in Phrakanong?
Well. I'm afraid it's sold already.
But you said we are the only ones...
...because we were first to call you.
Just kidding!
I just needed to see
your level of interest.
But I should warn you.
This house does need a few repairs.
Do you want to see it now?
If possible.
Let me find the key then.
What do they mean? These symbols.
They protect me.
Protect you from what?
The key used to be here...
These are so beautiful.
Ah! Here it is.
Phrakanong! You will never find
such a beautiful mix of people
in the whole of Bangkok.
See you're not far from the Skytrain.
Now we have to walk for
a little bit... Just over here.
So who lived in this house before?
There's been several owners.
They don't seem to stay long.
It's been empty for a few years.
You said it is an old house?
It's a very old house.
Probably the oldest in the area.
How old?
Over one hundred years old.
This is going to be
an exciting new area to live in.
They will build condominiums. Soon
all this will change for the better.
The key.
Like I said it's old.
But it's beautiful.
At the back is the bedroom
and bathroom. Simple but cosy.
We want the house Mr.Angel.
Yes! We'll buy the house.
I knew you two would be ideal
for this place.
So let's begin the paperwork,
shall we?
I'm afraid the garden is a bit wild.
But a little work will fix it.
Sorry. I left my bag inside.
Mak! Come on. I've got to go to work.
They only gave me the morning off.
Hey. They look nice and rich.
Yes, rich for the picking.
Mak, call me at work.
Let me know that it's confirmed.
No wait and call me at home tonight.
No, no. Call me at work!
Here's the contract for the Phrakanong
house. You sign your name here.
Hello, I'm calling about
the Phrakanong house...
advertised in the
newspaper yesterday...
Please call me back urgently...
Yes hello! I'm calling about
buying the house in Phrakanong...
Leave it too long,
and you might be too late.
But maybe I should speak
to a lawyer first.
The house is not going anywhere.
It's been there
for over one hundred years.
Sign it.
Well done!
This house has been waiting
for you for a long time.
Hello.
It's ours.
Contract signed and sealed!
Really? Oh Mak I know it's so right.
-Nak loves Mak. -Mak loves Nak...
and needs more change!
Excuse me.
Could I look at this one please.
Can I see it?
What is it?
It's very old. One hundred...
The price to you..One hundred!
I'll take this one.
Look after it.
It's very fragile.
It will bring you good luck.
Nak!
-Hi Noi.
-Look these arrived for you.
Mak's such a romantic.
-Did Mak send these? -I don't know.
Have a look at the card.
So tell me. Did you get it?
So did you get it?
Yes we did. Noi it's so perfect.
Sounds so romantic...
-But it needs a little work.
-What does it look like?
Beautiful. Like in a fairy tale.
It's an old traditional house...
-But the wedding is so soon.
-I hope we can get it ready in time.
-Don't worry. Noi and I will help you.
-That's great!
Don't worry. Chai and Noi will help.
Let's talk later.
Matching furniture. That's nice.
-I don't like the colour.
-It's good that it isn't for your home.
Look! There's the king size bed for
that first romantic hot sweaty night.
-I bet it won't be their first
hot and sweaty night. -Why?
Young people have
no control these days.
Hello Mr. Preecha.
This is Mr.Angel.
You're the lawyer for Mr Mak who signed
the contract for the Phrakanong house?
I'd like to make an appointment to
meet you to discuss the contract...
Driver stop here please.
I've got to get up early
to see Master Tring.
-Which Master Tring? -Our Fortune
Teller for the wedding plans.
Why don't you ask him
about me and Chai?
I don't believe a word he says. I'm
doing this for my Mom and Grandma.
Oh, C'mon! It's tradition.
I'm doing it just for you.
I gotta go now.
Bye bye.
Mak. Is that you Mak?
Nak, What's happened?
Have you seen a ghost?
Grandma, you know
I don't believe in ghosts.
Mom, I'm leaving.
Kong!
Nak, aren't you scared
walking through this cemetery?
I don't mind. I've been
walking through this way many years.
By the way, Did you get my flowers?
I'm in a rush Kong.
I don't have time to talk.
And stop sending me flowers!
Don't do it Nak. Do you know
you'll make a big mistake!
Kong, What are you saying?
Don't marry him. You can't do it.
Kong, I don't care what you think.
I am going to marry Mak. I love Mak!
But I love you Nak.
Good morning, Master Tring.
My Mom and Grandma asked me
to tell you that...
we've done everything
you have suggested for the wedding.
Actually, it's not my suggestion.
But what the
astrological readings inform us.
We must live by them.
And they will guide us to happiness
and a fulfilling future.
My Mom and Grandma hope that you'll
attend our reception and blessing.
I'll do my best for you, Nak.
Thank you.
Master Tring.
Your first morning reading
is waiting.
Come on then.
I'll leave now.
Wait!
Master Tring would like
completion of payment today.
Yes.
What is this?
There should be another two hundred?
Are you sure?
Oh I thought my Mom said...?
I don't know what your mom said
but there's two hundred Baht missing.
I'm sorry.
I'm so happy for Mak and Nak.
They look so good together.
It's true love.
And when are we going to...
This present is for both of them.
Thank you. Please go inside.
Mr. Preecha!
I'm so glad that you're here.
Here's to you
and your wonderful wife.
Mak, Mr. Preecha tells me that the
Phrakanong house is a real bargain.
Well it's a good job we have a great
lawyer like Mr Preecha to help us.
Noi, my feet are aching.
-So how is the cake?
-It's yummy.
Look.
Nak, there's your fortune teller.
But he's brought that
seedy housekeeper with him.
He wasn't invited.
Noi, look he's stealing food!
It's a great honour to be able
to attend the wedding of my niece
who I love very much.
And wish both of you to be happy,
prosperous and have children soon.
And to be wealthy.
Thank you all.
Thank you everyone
for being here today.
I know that Nak and I are so happy
that this day has finally arrived.
And is the start of
our new life together...
And we are going to share our life
together, no matter what happens.
So I raise my glass to everyone.
And especially to Nak
who I love very much.
I promise I'll love and look after
her for the rest of my life.
Cheers! Cheers! Cheers!
Nak you scared me!
What are you eating?
Grandma gave it to me.
It was once a very beautiful look
to have many years ago.
Kiss me Mak and taste some...
Let me see how you look.
It's probably not good for teeth...
here wash your mouth
and drink some water.
Nak!
What is it Mak?
I'm okay. Just got a fright.
What was it? Can you tell me?
Nothing Nak... Let's sleep.
So how are you my Husband?
I'm fine. And how are you my Wife?
I'm fine too.
And did you sleep well my Husband?
Yes my wife...I did...
Oh look what my Grandma gave me.
It's a leaf. Couples used to
chew it many years ago.
But it makes your teeth
and gums shiny black.
Oh you know about it. It was sign of
beauty once. Now we have the opposite.
I guess it's just tradition
to give it.
Nak, I like your teeth white.
Your Father would have loved
your wedding day Nak.
I guess Mr. Preecha will go through
all the paperwork within this week.
Well let me know
if you need more help.
Yes Father.
Let's hope it gets done before
you go on holiday next Saturday.
Krabi is such a beautiful place.
Nak, I don't know if you remember
but Mak's Father and l...
went there 3 years ago.
to celebrate our
25th wedding anniversary.
Well a toast to
Mak and Nak's wedding.
And may they return to Krabi in 25 years
to celebrate their wedding anniversary.
Cheers!
Mak what are you doing...
You'll fall.
Now I get to carry my bride,
my new wife, over the threshold.
Nak!
I'm sure I locked it...
I think someone has broken in.
Our stuff is missing.
Look! Our wedding gifts
have been stolen too.
What did the police say?
There's not much they can do.
Except wait and see if
any of the gifts turn up.
The thieves will probably try and
sell our stuff on the street.
Then we'd have to prove
they were ours.
It's a pity.
They took my wedding suit.
It had a wedding gift
I bought for Nak in it.
It was an antique brooch.
I would like to get that back.
Will you be okay
staying here tonight?
Yes we'll be fine.
This is our house.
What about the neighbours.
Didn't they see anything?
Nothing. Police spoke to them
but no one saw anything.
That's crazy!
You've only got to fart where I live
and a neighbour will come around
to have a good sniff.
Look it's a clock-radio.
I could use this.
We're keeping nothing Tick.
We've gotta' get rid of everything.
We can't be found with any of it.
Why?
That newly married couple
are connected to the police.
We will be in big trouble
if they catch us.
Hey! Stop! Stop!
Mak. I'm here Mak...
It's Nak next to you.
Can you hear me? Mak
Mak...wake up and talk to me.
I'm here Mak.
Can you hear me?
Nak, Doctor has got something to...
Are you Nak?
I'm Doctor Grid.
You must be Mak's wife.
What happened? Why is he like this?
We know he was in a hit and run
accident. It has left Mak in a coma.
Coma? When will he wake up?
It's hard to tell at this stage. We
are monitoring him for any responses.
Mak's parent just arrived.
Doctor I'll go with you.
Find Mae Nak.
You must find Mae Nak.
Doctor, Mak spoke to me. He spoke!
Are you sure that Mak spoke to you?
The monitor shows no response at all.
He's been stable...no change at all.
You have to rest.
You have to keep your strength
so you can be with Mak.
You've been at his bedside all day.
You haven't eaten much...
nothing at all.
I've made a congee for you...
eat some.
Here...eat Nak.
Grandma! Mak said something to me
this morning in hospital.
Are you sure he spoke to you?
The Doctor said there was no change.
Yes, he did!
He told me to find Mae Nak.
To find Mae Nak?
But Mae Nak...is a Ghost!
Ghost! What do you mean a Ghost?
What I am going to tell you
is the story of Mae Nak.
Over a hundred years ago,
there was a young woman called Nak.
Nak married a young man named Mak.
They were very much in love.
And their marriage
was a true commitment...
They were inseparable. Because they
loved each other very much.
And they were blessed with
conception of a child.
But then the dream was broken...
her Mak had to go to war...
Mak was seriously injured.
The monks helped him recover.
Soon Mak was ready to return
to his true love...his Nak.
They were together again as a family.
But then Mak noticed that
things had changed.
Neighbours they knew so well had gone.
People would not stop at their house.
Mak then went home to tell Nak.
The villagers told him she died in
childbirth, and she was now a ghost!
That night the GHOST OF MAE NAK
had her revenge on the village.
The dead were the people that
tried to take Mak away from Nak.
She would not let them.
She cursed them and stopped them.
The villagers awake Mak to face
the truth about his young wife.
That she is dead and he has been living
with a ghost who has struck revenge.
on those who tried to
come between her and Mak...
There in the grave was the
decaying body of the young Mae Nak.
Mak's wife and true love...
and next to her their dead child.
The Higher Dignitary performed
an exorcism on Nak and her child.
They were made to rest in peace.
Mae Nak no longer sought revenge
on those who tried to stop
her love between her and her Mak.
Grandma, why did
Mae Nak want revenge?
She wanted to keep the true love she had.
Her love for her Mak was so overwhelming.
It became her obsession,
turned to anger and finally revenge.
You're late Tick!
Where have you been?
The scrap guy is waiting for you.
I know! I know! I had to go
the long way round.
Police are everywhere.
So you need to get to the scrap yard
as soon as possible.
I'm scared Tock!
Call me when it's done.
Murderer! Thief!
Who is this?
Who are you?
Where have you been?
I've been waiting for you.
You're late.
Here's your money.
You can go. I'll do this myself.
Now all the tests show that Mak is
physically normal.
But he is still in his coma.
He has no response at all.
We are going to do
a brain scan today.
Hopefully that will pinpoint
a cause for his state.
Mak's Father told me that
you have got something to tell me?
It's about Mr. Angel the Prakanong house
Estate Agent, who sold the house to you.
But now...
I'm afraid he is dead!
He was meant to come to our
wedding reception. Poor Mr.Angel.
Well actually, Mr.Angel was about to
create problems for you and Mak.
Recently, I received
a phone call from him.
Saying that he was going to double
the price of the Prakanong house.
Then I checked the contract
that Mak's signed.
It was there in the small print...
that he could increase the price
of the house after one week,
and that it was legal to do so.
Actually, his intention
was never to sell it.
Prakanong House was the
ONLY property Mr.Angel had.
He used it for his
real estate company registration.
And he used it to exploit money
from young newly married couples.
Couples like you and Mak.
Why would Mr.Angel do that?
Greed. What other reasons are there?
Maybe he went too far
for this time...
You are very lucky Nak.
You and Mak own
a very special property.
If you look at the map.
That is Bangkok today.
This map shows the same area
but over hundred years ago.
What I discovered when I was
investigating the contract...
is that Prakanong house
is the oldest house on the map.
Its foundations have been there
for over a hundred years.
Rumour has it that it is also
a land told in legend...
It is said that the Ghost of Mae Nak
used to live there.
You can buy it if you're gonna
look at it that close!
Where did you get this?
This was stolen from my house!
Hey Tock! Come here Tock!
I'll call the police!
Call the police?
Take your hands out of the pocket
or I'll cut it off!
Look she's taken something!
Mak I went to see our Estate Lawyer,
Mr.Preecha, about the house.
He had good news to tell.
The house is finally ours Mak.
Mak look! I found something.
I found the brooch
you brought for me.
It's so beautiful Mak.
It feels so strange.
Very cold.
Mak, feel it.
Mak did you see that?
It was me and you. Our first kiss.
Mak do you remember?
You are lucky Master Tring
will see you at such short notice.
It must be important?
I am saddened to hear about your Mak.
But he is strong.
I'm sure he'll be okay.
I'll read his chart for him
and we will see a positive future.
Master Tring I must ask you
about another concern.
Before Mak had his accident,
Mak told me that
he was having nightmares.
And he was being haunted
by a vision of a ghost woman.
And when he was in hospital,
he spoke to me from his sleep.
He said "Find Mae Nak!"
Mae Nak? Mae Nak is a ghost.
Yes. My Grandma told me her story.
This is why I come to see you.
To give me an answer.
What did they do to her?
The Higher Dignitary at that time...
put a stop to Mae Nak's
curses and vengeance.
He exorcised her to rest in peace.
The Higher Dignitary removed a
piece of bone from Mae Nak's skull.
He now had Nak's spirit
held in the bone.
Her grave was filled in and forgotten...
Unmarked, lost in the woods and in time.
The bone was made into a brooch that
the Dignitary wore until his last day.
What happened to the brooch then?
Legend has it that the brooch
was lost in time.
It is still out there...
But holding Nak's spirit inside.
Nak what is this!
I knew it, I sensed something strong
and evil when you entered the house.
Is this the girdle brooch
made from the bones of Mae Nak!
Take it out! Take it out!
Master! Master!
Master. What is wrong? Master!
What happened?
I ask what happened?
Get out! I can deal with this!
Master! Master! Master!
Master is well now but needs rest.
I don't understand what happened.
His strong visions overpower him
controlling his body and mind.
He explained to me about
the object you have.
This object is very very valuable.
And must be handled carefully.
It's extremely powerful
and can cause you great harm.
So it's true?
This belongs to Mae Nak!
Yes, it is.
Master has asked that I take...
you to a Higher Dignitary
to discuss the outcome of the brooch.
Master does not want it to fall
into wrong hands.
It will be very dangerous
for you to keep.
Come let's go now.
Where are you going? Wait!
Yes! Yes! That's good price.
Very good.
I tell you my friend
you won't be disappointed.
I'll be with you soon.
Have the money ready!
Mak loves Nak.
Nak loves Mak.
Our love forever and ever and ever.
Nobody comes here anymore.
It used to be a nursery
for young children.
But they had to close it.
Because of the children
seeing the GHOSTS.
It was a burial ground
many many years ago.
A burial ground?
Kong
Nak
So, what's back there?
What do you want Kong?
I'm sorry to hear
about Mak's accident.
I called your Mom to say I er'...
couldn't come to your wedding.
Then she told me about Mak.
I was shocked Nak.
Are you okay?
I kept thinking back to
when your Father died,
and you come to me.
I'm here for you Nak.
Look Kong! You were not
invited to my wedding.
And you have no right
to call my Mom.
I told you leave me alone!
Don't you understand?
If Mak doesn't survive, if he dies,
then you will be alone.
But I'll still be here for you.
Forget Mak.
We can make a fresh start Nak?
Get off!
Our love forever and ever and ever.
NAK
Mak's Mother and Father have arranged
for a Monk to come and pray for Mak.
It will give him strength.
Noi. Chai.
I need your help.
I want to explain something to you.
I believe that the old nursery
is the burial place of Mae Nak.
Somehow she connected
with Mak through his dreams
and was trying to
tell him something.
Tell him something?
I think she wants to be at peace.
We have to return what is hers.
And how do we do that?
We dig.
We dig and find
the remains of Mae Nak.
Nak are you sure
no one owns this place?
I've checked. We're okay.
But I think we should
speak to the Police first.
And tell them what?
That we are digging for a ghost!
There!
We have to dig here!
Why there Nak?
Why do we have to dig there?
Okay! But if we don't find anything
after 30 minutes, then we go home.
Okay, but now we have to dig.
Some water for you Chai?
C'Mon Chai you've done enough.
Let's go home now...Chai?
Gotta' dig!
The ground's so hard...
Gotta keep digging!
The ground is so...
This is a bone!
It was a baby!
Why is it buried here?
Now we HAVE to call the Police!
No we can't...Not now...
we need to keep digging.
Nak, this needs a serious police
investigation. We have to call them.
Hello Mom! What is it?
Yes I'm with Chai and Noi.
We'll be there right away.
Something serious has happened to Mak.
We've got to go to the hospital now.
Let's go now.
What's about this?
Let's find something to cover it.
Nak
What have you been doing?
We've been working on the house.
This is the brain scan of Mak.
We are concerned that there
may be injuries to the brain.
Such as a hemorrhage,
that we cannot detect.
So we are going to do
intensive tests.
It will show signs
of damage to the brain.
We are treating this as an emergency
procedure and we want to start tonight.
We are worried that Mak's brain...
might be permanently damaged...
Mak! No!
Mak
Can you hear me Mak?
Mae Nak!
I was worried about you Nak.
I had to call the police.
Don't worry Nak I told them I'll
help you. Come back to my place.
Nak!
Noi Chai
I found Mae Nak. I found her!
Mak? How is he?
He was taken away.
Doctors cannot help him.
Where is Mak?
They took him away.
No! Nak!
Look! I found Mae Nak.
I gave you...what you wanted...
No!
Grandma
I don't understand.
Why doesn't Mae Nak release my Mak?
Why Grandma?
I will take you
to someone who can help.
Legend says that
the spirit of Mae Nak...
was very revengeful on those
who tried to stop her love.
She will do them great harm.
How are you feeling Nak?
Much better now thanks.
It was a difficult night
for us all last night.
Where is Mak now?
He is in safe hands now.
He was taken to a monastery
where they will help him.
The monks will remove the spirit
that possesses him.
We have given them
our permission for an exorcism.
Mrs.Grimm?
Are you there?
I have brought my granddaughter
Nak here. She needs your help.
Who is it?
Can't you remember my voice?
Yes. Come in, come inside.
How wonderful it is to have you
visit us with your grandmother.
So you must be Nak?
I remember you when you
were a little girl.
And I remember her grandmother
when she was a young girl.
Oh don't talk about
such ancient times.
May I touch your face Nak?
It's how Mrs.Grimm sees you.
Yes, of course.
There now I can see you Nak.
You are very beautiful.
Now let's find out how
we can help you young Nak.
Come inside the house.
Mrs.Grimm is tuning
into the spirit world.
She has been a spiritualist
all her life.
Oh I nearly forget...This may help.
Nak was holding it all last night.
Ah! Wonderful!
Let Mrs.Grimm hold it. It may help.
You are surrounded by pure love,
young Nak.
The presence that
this belongs to...
is reaching out to you
through this pure love.
The presence is a woman.
A woman who is not at peace.
Who cannot rest.
The presence is with us.
She's here with us.
We sense that you are with us here.
Will you talk to us? Yes or no?
Will you communicate with us?
Yes or no?
Will you come through to us?
We are here to help you.
What is your name?
Will you speak to us?
Yes or no?
Yes.
What is your name?
Do we know you?
Are you connected to us?
Yes or no?
No.
What is your name?
Nak.
Mae Nak.
Is there someone here
you wish to communicate with?
Nak.
Will you speak to Nak?
Yes or no?
Will you tell us why
you are not at rest?
Speak to Nak.
Nak is with us here.
What do you want of Nak?
Nak. Help me.
Help me.
Why do you feel no peace?
What help do you need?
Speak to Nak. Nak is with us.
Release me.
Release me. Release me!
Release me. Release me.
Release me!
The spirit of Mae Nak has been
awoken by the true love
that you and your Mak
have for each other.
It is the love that
she once had and misses deeply.
I did everything I could.
I searched until I found her.
And you must continue young Nak.
But what does she want?
You must return
what belongs to Mae Nak.
Nak, I must warn you that
your Mak is in great danger.
Your grandmother told me about the
exorcism they plan to do on Mak tonight.
They will do him great harm.
You must stop them Nak.
Nak, what are you doing here?
Chai, I need your help.
I need to go to the Police morgue.
Come on Nak. You're going to create
serious problems for yourself.
Please Chai you must help me.
This will be the last time I promise.
Look Nak this whole thing has
caused a strain between Noi and l.
Noi is worried I may lose my job.
Chai, I just need you to help me get
inside the Police morgue, that's all.
I have to help Mak.
Mak is in good hands now.
The monks are taking care of him.
You'll make things worse for him.
Chai you must help me.
If you don't help me Chai
you could be in danger too.
Mae Nak can do strange things.
Stop it. Enough talk about ghosts
and bones and such crazy nonsense!
Nak!
Touch this.
If you don't help me you'll be
in great danger Chai.
Mae Nak won't let anyone stop her.
Happy now?
Okay Nak I'm going to
drive you home.
And then I'll have some explaining
to Noi because I'll be late and...
I work in the pay-roll department.
I need to collect the job sheets.
They were meant to be sent over today.
So I came over myself.On my way home.
You guys need to get
paid this month right?
-Okay.
-Thanks.
Quickly Nak. Get under here.
You might need
this flashlight inside.
Hey where are you taking that?
It was blocking the entrance.
I'm just returning it.
Returning it?
Returning it where?
That's my job.
Hello? Yeah. Where are you?
I can't come. I'm working tonight.
Have a guess who I'm with.
That man who got
sliced in two by glass.
It's been mad busy all week.
We've got that train guy in too.
Lost his head. Clean off.
Some other guy got burnt alive.
Hang on. The other phone's ringing.
I gotta' go. See you tomorrow.
Our love for ever and ever.
And look after each other forever.
I've done everything
you want me to do.
Now you give back Mak to me.
Give my Mak back to me!
Mak!
Mae Nak can rest in peace now.
This is what she wanted us
to help her with.
They say that this temple is also
the resting place of her Mak.
He is telling you that we will
burn the coffin tonight.
This will complete
the religious ceremony.
Everything's all done now.
Now you'll be happy together.
Nak, come and look at this photo.
Mak.
Come and be with me Mak.
No! I'm not your Mak.
Don't you remember me Mak?
Where is Nak?
Where is my wife?
Mae Nak...
I'm not your Mak.
Give me back my wife.
Please Mae Nak!
Chai...I need to borrow your car.
No time to explain!
Help me please!
Mak!
Please help me!
Mak
Help me. There's somebody in here!
Mak! Help me.
Nak!