Filming begins on Disneynature's
cinematic release, Born in China.
Disneynature's most ambitious film yet.
This is a country that holds
many wildlife secrets.
Home to a remarkable number
of rarely-seen animals
and remote wildernesses that only
a handful of film crews
have been fortunate enough
to get access to.
The film will capture the landscapes of
China and the creatures that live here.
Iconic animals will be filmed
as they raise their families
through their first months of life.
But the greatest challenge of all
is an attempt to accomplish
the near-impossible.
An international team of filmmakers
are about to embark on a mission
to try and film the intimate story
of a snow leopard family,
one of the most beautiful and elusive
creatures on the planet,
in a feat never achieved before.
That's a big cat. Damn.
I'm climbing the mountain
to see if there's any track.
Film crew nil. Cat one.
Hey, we'll just go again tomorrow.
We'll try again tomorrow.
The snow leopard team are three days
into a 10-day, 2,000-mile journey
to their high-altitude filming location.
Just getting there
is a formidable adventure.
The team leave from Beijing,
the capital of China.
The first leg of the journey involves
flying to Yushu,
their first high-altitude stop at over
12,000 feet above sea level.
The remaining 250 miles by road,
up to over 16,000 feet,
will take a week
and will be much trickier.
Now at over 13,000 feet, the team
hit the road to their final destination.
But after every 1,600 feet gained
in altitude,
they must rest for 24 hours
to keep altitude sickness at bay.
Traveling over 16,000 feet
is an expedition
that must be taken seriously.
Altitude sickness can be deadly.
We just passed 4,600 meters
and the air is definitely getting
thinner up here.
I can feel it when I get out of the car
and run around a little bit.
I think we're doing all right, though.
But we definitely need to keep an eye
on how everyone's reacting
to the elevation here.
Shane is the team's
director of photography.
Used to tough adventures in mountains
and a brilliant animal tracker,
he's dreamt of having the chance
to film snow leopards for years.
Is it normal for people to get sick
when they come up here?
If somebody come from the lower place
then they get a headache.
And very difficult to eat food
and then difficult to walk.
If you stay then maybe you can die.
Sonam is a local guide and mechanic,
his humor infectious to the team.
They journey on,
the long road made no easier
by repeated stops.
We just had a puncture on the road.
The road is getting a bit bumpier.
Ed is one of the team's field directors.
He's managed wildlife film crews
in remote regions all over the world.
The stones are obviously
quite sharp up here.
It's just one more reminder
as we go to our final destination
that we have to be very careful.
And we rely completely
on the equipment that we've got
and the decisions that we make.
Yeah, I worry about the film crew.
If they get sick,
it might get very serious.
Dondrub is a Buddhist monk
who's traveled extensively in this area.
He's one of the few people
to have seen snow leopards
in this part of China.
It's hard to recover from cold
in high altitude.
We have a doctor with us
and we have a lot of medicines.
We have also an oxygen tank,
which would be very helpful
if anyone gets sick.
Finally, after 2,000 miles
and nearly two weeks of flights,
adapting to the altitude
and isolated roads,
the crew arrives
in snow leopard territory.
Just around the next few corners
will be our camp site.
They are the first international
film crew ever
to reach this remote location.
Ten days to get here,
to acclimate to the elevation,
but we made it.
Sanjiangyuan, in northwest China,
the heart of China's
snow leopard habitat,
is chosen as the filming location.
At almost 400,000 square kilometers,
it protects not only snow leopards
but is also the starting point
for three of the world's mightiest rivers,
the Yangtze, Yellow and Mekong.
The world's highest wetland provides
water for more than a billion people.
A truly vast landscape
almost the size of California,
dwarfing the entire British Isles
and home to the largest nature reserve
in China.
This is a remote, daunting location,
but China has about 60% of the total
snow leopard habitat on Earth
and the largest number of wild
snow leopards on the planet.
But getting more than a brief glimpse
of these ghosts of the mountains
is all but impossible.
Due to their extreme altitude
and remote home,
few film crews have taken on
the challenge.
No one has achieved the hours
of footage needed to make a movie.
The cats are just too hard to find.
To succeed,
this team will need endurance,
dedication and perseverance
in spades.
Their mission,
not just to film snow leopards,
but to capture what life is like
for a family of them
and tell their story
for the very first time.
Here's our little part of the world.
I've never worked in a place where
the mountains don't have names,
the rivers apparently
don't even have names.
Amongst this vast landscape,
the team find the perfect base
next to a monastery.
Everyone is excited about
the adventure ahead.
Living a couple hundred kilometers
from the nearest city,
a two-day round trip means
meticulous planning
for the crew to survive.
Without a working generator,
there would be no power.
Whenever possible,
natural resources are used.
The team find a spring
where they can source water
for cooking and drinking.
A toilet is dug in the frozen earth.
Stoves and coal are brought in
to keep everyone warm.
When the coal gets wet,
piles of yak dung are used.
It's amazing how reliant you become
on the fire up here.
The warmth and... It's the first moment
it's gone out and everyone's distraught.
Need to get this fire going.
Staying in a house with no insulated
walls when the outside temperature
is almost minus 20 is as cold
as living in a domestic freezer.
Although very basic living conditions,
they are hugely appreciated by
an international team
working in one of the highest
and harshest locations on Earth.
-It's to the right.
-Exactly.
The snow leopard challenge is on.
The team get up in the freezing
darkness before dawn.
With little proof of exactly
where the snow leopards are,
they set out to look for any evidence
they can of a big cat.
When searching for any predator,
finding its prey is a great first step.
There are at least five groups
of blue sheep
with between 10 and 40
individuals in each herd.
I think that's quite a lot of prey
for a snow leopard,
if it did decide to live around here.
But they're still so hard to find.
Brown cat in a brown landscape.
It's very difficult.
Ben is one of the team's field directors.
He's worked all over China,
from its highest mountains
to remotest forests.
It's probably extremely likely that
there's one watching me now.
But I'm not going to be able to see it.
Slightly unnerving.
Yeah, and it's cold.
And it's 16,000 feet up.
This might be a great habitat
for snow leopards,
but finding them, let alone filming them,
is a whole new challenge.
Up here in the thin air, where it's
exhausting just to walk 10 yards,
excitement quickly turns to realization.
It's a sobering reminder
of the enormity of the task ahead.
There are lots of signs from
the various wild animals around here,
some of which will be snow leopards.
And then scattered around are
bones, skulls of blue sheep,
the prey of the snow leopard.
So there's lots of signs here.
And so, although we haven't seen
a snow leopard in the flesh,
we've seen almost everything but.
To make any success of this,
the film crew has to try and get
the local yak herders
that live here on their side.
Yak are the equivalent of cattle,
essential to human life here.
The herders are masters
of their environment,
and living here year around,
they are a good source for any scraps
of information there might be
about the cats.
The perfect chance to break the ice
comes soon after arriving at camp.
Well, we found a baby yak beside
the road in a very dangerous place,
probably about to get eaten
by predators,
and we tracked down the owners.
Yeah.
For its human owner,
the yak is beyond value.
They're a source of food, drink,
clothes and shoes.
So important are they, the families
here give them individual names
like they do their children.
It's very cute.
Amazingly, just minutes before,
we saw a golden eagle
eating a young baby animal.
We saw foxes in the area.
So, I'm very happy
that this guy survived.
He wouldn't have lasted much longer.
Plus it's hailing, it's cold,
and he needs to go home.
So we roll up to this house
and tell them we want one of them
to come with us, jump in.
We can't communicate with them.
And the result is, our baby yak is saved.
The crew have reunited this family
with their most prized possession.
So the baby yak is back with his family,
it's in a warm place.
And our treat is getting to see these
amazing people in their home.
And they gave us yak tea and some
great bread and some meat.
And it's a big ol' time.
This act of kindness will go a long way
to cement relations
with the locals who have snow leopard
experiences to share.
With these stories fresh in their minds,
it's time for the team
to bring out the technology.
In remote regions
where helicopters can't reach,
drones are a great way of filming
vast landscapes from the air.
Shane has spent many months
designing and building this drone,
specifically adapted
to fly at extreme altitude.
It also offers the team further clues as
to where the snow leopards might be.
Any well-worn paths or caves
could be visited by the cats
and will be easier to spot from the air.
With a much better idea
of the lay of the land,
the team turn to their next bit
of technology,
camera traps.
Yeah, it's based on the Panasonic GH4,
the new 4K SLRs.
All the electronics for controlling
the triggers,
picking up the signals from the
sensors, are in the lid here and...
I love the color.
And how many of these do we have?
Yeah, we've got eight. So, we can
spread these far and wide
and hopefully cover a lot of ground
with them.
Dave is a remote camera trap expert.
He helped design the cameras
that will go into the field.
It's a huge landscape. How do we know
where to put them, I guess is the...
Yeah, if you just looked at the math,
you'd give up
'cause even the smaller territories
of a female are, you know,
40 kilometers at a minimum.
And you need to find the exact place,
probably within a foot,
to have that cat in that kind of range.
And, of course, the males have
territories that are
three or four times that size.
But don't look at it that way
because they are somewhat
predictable and they'll funnel through
these valleys and work the bases
of cliffs, so I think you can do it.
Yeah.
These state of the art 4K camera traps
could be left in the field for days
to hopefully capture images of
snow leopards without disturbing them.
So we found this... What looks like
a great place for a camera trap.
You can see how nice it is.
Animal trails come here between
the frozen river and the rock there.
Reckon it's gonna be a good place
for a camera trap,
but the problem is this river.
It was frozen a week ago
and is now already melting,
as you can see from the heat.
James, we're gonna have to work out
how to cross it.
Yeah.
-You wanna go first?
-Sure.
Let's go.
He's going first.
James, the team's field assistant,
is a bit more confident
about any potential risks than Ben.
Jump up and down.
Okay?
All right, we're gonna go for it.
Don't break, ice.
Please, please.
There's actually some
snow leopard hair in here,
so this must be a real important scent
post for them coming through here.
I mean, there's a couple in here.
They may even be fresh,
so this is gonna be an exciting spot.
We'll set it up
and come back in a few days,
see if we can get our ghost on camera.
So at the moment we're just trying to
set the focus in such a way
that as the light conditions change,
the focus point remains
somewhere relevant in the image
so that hopefully when our leopard
comes through the shot,
he'll be nice and sharp
and we'll get
a really good image of him.
These are our sensors,
they're passive infrared.
There's a little infrared beam
that comes out of here.
And hopefully as soon as the leopard
walks past it,
this will send a signal to the trap
and set our cameras recording.
-Happy with that?
-Yeah.
Great.
It's hazardous work,
not helped by unpredictable
and dangerous weather.
Jacky, a member of the camera team,
needs to set this camera trap quick.
Up here at over 16,000 feet,
electrical storms appear
out of nowhere.
Getting caught in them
can be life-threatening.
During a storm,
lightning can strike at
any time and anywhere up here.
And out in the open, three miles up,
Jacky could get hit.
That was scary. Oh, God.
Over the next few weeks,
the team put all their time and energy
placing the camera traps
in a desperate bid to find out
where the snow leopard territories are
in this vast landscape.
The equivalent of searching
for a needle in a haystack.
Every few days, the camera trap
recordings are retrieved...
-Do you want to sit in the hot seat?
-No, go for it, Ed.
Okay, well, let's...
...to see if there are any hits.
-Actually a pretty nice image.
-Yeah.
But no snow leopards are spotted.
You'd think a few weeks,
a cat would walk by.
The camera traps were checked
and rechecked endlessly.
Then one day...
The team's first snow leopard
on camera.
Great.
And it's not just one,
another cat follows behind.
-All right.
-Sweet.
Snow leopards are mainly
solitary creatures.
To film one is astonishing.
For it to have company, incredible.
It's definitive proof the cats are here.
There's now a real sense of the team
being able to get into position
to film the cats on the main camera.
Do you guys wanna
drive around to the west?
Might want to drive around to the west.
To get everyone searching
as much as possible,
a snow leopard spotting
competition begins.
Dondrub, six points.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Mine.
That's my point.
One point for spotting a snow leopard,
two points for if you actually film it.
Sonam, two points.
There are two snow leopards,
so we split two points.
-Thank you very much.
-So you get a point each.
He thought he saw something
and then I saw two snow leopards.
-Yes.
-Congratulations.
The team are now clearly bonding
in their mission to get snow leopards
on the main camera.
Okay, thank you, everybody.
-Thank you.
-No points.
I love to track these cats.
But most of the time the cats here
are either on rocks,
where they leave no tracks,
or they're on this grass,
where they also leave no tracks.
So our only opportunity really for
tracking is when we have snow.
And this place does not get
a lot of snow
and it usually melts off fairly quickly.
So that means the animals don't have
a lot of time to leave tracks.
But we have had some really good
tracking situations
and honestly, that's one of
my greatest thrills.
Fresh snow, fresh tracks and you know
there's a cat at the other end of that.
Bingo.
And with some snow on the ground,
the tracking skills of the team
become crucial.
Beautiful snow leopard tracks.
Beautiful.
Look at this.
That's a big cat. Damn.
Yeah, that's a male.
This is the perfect spot,
a little overhang
so they can spray here and scent mark
and then the rain won't wash it away.
It'll last longer.
I assume that's why they do it
in all these overhangs,
seem to be the perfect place.
So there are times I've been on the
cat tracks and I see it go into
really thick cover
where I couldn't tell...
Thick rocks where you couldn't...
It's a possibility
of surprising the animal.
And in that case, I don't track them
because the last thing I wanna do
is have these animals paranoid
that we're sneaking up on them.
But for now the cats remain hidden,
largely thanks to their
incredible camouflage.
If the military were trying
to design camouflage,
they could really learn a lot
from snow leopards.
I don't know how to describe
a snow leopard
other than it almost seems to occupy
like a negative space.
You don't look for an animal,
you look for something that's just
not completely like the background.
It's just incredible camouflage.
And even their underpart is lighter,
so when they're sitting on a hill
and looking down,
it looks more like the sky.
Biggest thing is believing
that they're there,
and then you look through binoculars
and spotting scopes
until your eyes bleed,
and maybe you actually see one.
It's really surprised me
how often we'll find a cat,
we'll have it in the spotting scope,
some of the locals come by
and they'll want to have a look.
And even though they know it's
in the spotting scope,
they can't see it.
It just does not get any better
than their camouflage
and their ability to hide.
Weeks have passed
with no luck
since the camera trap success.
But then the team receives news
from one of the locals.
Signs of predator activity
close to precious livestock.
And it might be snow leopard.
It's another chance
for the filming team to help out
and tap into more local knowledge.
We are headed to
Dorje's house to try to help them out.
They've had... Four nights in a row,
they've had problems
with snow leopards sneaking in.
And they've taken two of their lambs
and I think one goat.
We have some remote cameras in here
so, hopefully we can
determine exactly what it is.
They don't know
that it's a snow leopard.
They haven't seen it.
Could be a wolf or a fox,
it could be a bear.
The Himalaya blue bear
is one of the rarest
bear subspecies on Earth.
Bears break into most of these houses.
His winter house
was sort of destroyed.
They've learned that they can
find food in these houses,
so they just destroy them,
and it's really...
Getting more and more tension
between the locals
and the animals that live here.
We're trying to help them out.
They've been very helpful to us
and we're hoping to return a favor.
It's Dorje himself.
The family have just suffered
another loss.
What time did the cat come?
4:00, something.
Dog, dog, dog, dog. It's running.
A dog. Not the likely culprit.
Let's try the other camera.
See if there's anything on that one.
No. They escaped us as well.
Well, should we keep trying?
He thinks the snow leopards walk
and attacking every time one way.
-The same way?
-Yes, same way every time.
So he'd like to put...
You find some tracks.
-Okay.
-So he can...
-He can put one there.
-Okay.
Shane heads out
to place the camera traps again.
I think the cat...
They had fresh tracks here yesterday,
so it might be going up this crack.
It feels like a nice...
Maybe sneak route out,
that the dogs wouldn't follow right away.
Give it a try.
Okay.
Let me look at the angle.
That looks good.
So when it walks across...
The team have done
all they can for now.
Just a few days later, they return.
The camera traps have been triggered
many more times.
So we have 60 files.
Hopefully, some of those are
snow leopard.
Straight away, a snow leopard.
So, here's some good evidence.
There's definitely a snow leopard
in this region.
Unfortunately, at the moment,
he's preying on
these poor folks' livestock.
The team continue
their relentless mission
to get footage on the main cameras.
Some of them
resorting to wacky humor
in a bid to get any information they can.
The view's nice.
Only thing we need...
Get the snow leopard.
That'll make this even better.
With endless perseverance
and endurance,
the team continue on, until...
You see it?
Hey, Dondrub.
-Ask Hu to tell me if she moves.
-Okay.
She's walking,
she's walking towards the left.
Dondrub, the rock star,
just spotted a snow leopard up there.
Allowed some great filming opportunity.
That's me.
Very good eyes.
As the weeks pass,
both the crew and snow leopards
get used to each other's presence.
The cats are becoming
more and more filmable.
The team even film
four snow leopards
hanging out together.
A unique opportunity.
And the successes keep coming.
One day, the team get into
an even better spot.
A few days ago, I had an opportunity
to follow a cat that was hunting,
and I was within about 50 meters.
The sheep saw me.
They knew I was there.
They're not worried about me.
They have become used to us,
because we've respected
their space as well.
The cat knew I was there.
I can move where I need to,
to line up a shot.
And everybody's tolerating it.
And I'm not interfering
with what's going on.
I'm part of this.
And I have to say, it's one of the
greatest honors I've had,
you know, with these animals.
It was a real special moment for me.
One of the sheep spot the cat
just in time.
It leaves to hunt another day.
But the cats are behaving naturally.
For the team, it's confirmation
of the trust that the snow leopards
now have with them.
All are in high spirits.
Coming down is much easier
than climbing up.
With so much success,
the snow leopard spotting
competition heats up again.
Zhang is the best.
Five, 10, 15, 20, 33.
Thirty-three?
And the second is Hu, the driver.
Chinese driver. Beijing. Nineteen.
So now he's going to third position.
Eighteen.
The team have overcome one hurdle
by getting the cats onside.
Now they're ready for the ultimate,
filming a snow leopard family.
If they can find them,
the cubs will have just emerged
from their den
and their mother will be very wary.
So it's back to the
remote camera traps.
After months in the field,
the grueling process
has to begin again.
But the team now have the advantage
of knowing the best spots
to place the cameras.
Is there anything?
Nothing on these ones.
We have no footage of
snow leopards in here.
It's not an easy cat to trap.
But we won't give up.
And then, news from camp
of an intriguing hit
on one of the camera traps.
-Cubs? Oh, man.
-Yeah!
That's nice.
-Got to be the cub.
-Yeah.
But is it a snow leopard cub?
We don't know.
We need confirmation.
It needs to back up.
Yeah.
Oh, no. Camera got knocked over.
The team wait anxiously.
We know that there's
a cub-like thing there.
Sweetness.
It's a video of one minute.
Now we got...
That's a leopard.
-That's a leopard cub.
-Yep.
Finally, the confirmation
they're waiting for.
That was cute.
-We got two of them.
-Yeah, there's two.
That's sweet.
And you were thinking there were none.
I thought there were none.
Come on. Give me some good ones.
The camera traps have paid off.
Yeah.
Over the next few weeks,
the hits keep coming.
Rare shots of a young,
wild snow leopard family
playing completely undisturbed
in their stunning natural home.
The crew finally have their stars.
They now need to get close enough
to film the snow leopard family
on the main cameras.
Hours and hours are spent
scoping and hiking the mountains,
until 90 days after arriving at camp...
I'll never forget the day that we
first found the snow leopard cubs.
I mean, our whole goal
was to find a mother with cubs.
We'd been out here for three months
and I looked up on a mountain
and just a little bit of mist
blew through.
It was just enough to give
a hint of a silhouette
to the cat on the mountain
when she wasn't actually on the skyline.
The cat...
It was just a brief glimpse.
It was a gift, honestly.
And I looked through the binoculars
and I was sure I could see
two little things at her feet, too,
and I thought,
"It just can't be. It can't be."
And it looked like a place where if we
tried to get close to them
and let her see us,
she'd probably run away.
So it was one of the few times
where I thought we really had to
hide from this cat.
So I judged what's
the best way to use the land,
how to get in close.
And I really didn't get to see the mother
most of the day
because all I did was stick the lens
of the camera above a rock
and I was actually down.
But, sure enough, it was.
It was a mother with cubs.
These shots are the first time
that such young snow leopard cubs
have ever been filmed in the wild.
It's a remarkable and unique
achievement for the team
after 12 grueling weeks in the field.
Of course, I mean,
I was just giddy all day long.
To see these cubs,
to see them, you know,
playing with the mother,
biting her tail, pulling her ears,
and to see her patience
and great care with the cubs...
125 meters or so,
she knew something wasn't right.
She could see that lens.
But she was just comfortable enough,
'cause we didn't move at all
and she got used to that lens,
you know, peering over the rock,
that they went on about their business.
It was just such an amazing day.
A snow leopard...
The team now
have the amazing chance
to follow a wild snow leopard family.
Two adorable cubs, just months old.
-Two cats?
-I can only see one from here.
And a mother, doing all she can
to keep her family safe.
Snow leopard with baby,
they sleep whole night.
Whole day, today.
They moved and then, okay,
when I looked down on the ridge
at 50 meters,
little bit of snow filtering down,
I can see the cubs curled together,
I can see half of the mom,
and I wanted to take a picture badly,
but I said, "No."
'Cause if they see me,
I'll lose their trust
and they'll be gone.
Over the next few weeks,
the crew capture unique footage
of the snow leopard family.
But as the weather warms,
the cats become harder to find.
A complete lack of fresh snow
making it even harder
for the film crew
to track the snow leopard family.
Weeks pass without a single sighting.
We haven't found
the mother snow leopard
for so long.
And now, I'm climbing.
Climbing the mountain
to see if there is any track
of her and her cubs.
It's really difficult for us
to climb the mountains around here.
The elevation is just too high.
If our mandate was to film
any snow leopards,
it would be challenging enough.
But we're trying to film
one needle in this haystack.
And our star is gone. She's taken off.
We don't have a clue where she is.
You know, their average home range
is 40 square kilometers.
And we don't know which side of that.
It could be left, right, north, south.
We've had all sorts of things
during this.
Crazy weather,
extreme attitude,
and trying to film an animal that's
basically a ghost.
I'm working up here
at 16,000 feet for months on end.
I think he... I think he gave up.
You know, it does test
the nerves and the emotions.
Jeez.
And then things get even worse.
The octocopter
started spinning in circles,
which means you have
no directional control.
I saw smoke, the fire went up the...
Up the food chain, so to speak.
And then it just shot off at
a great rate of speed.
I didn't know if I'd ever see it again.
It was flying over there,
into snow leopard country.
But I saw the...
I saw the fireball
when it hit the ground, so...
I mean, this is probably
an all-time low for me.
I haven't seen our star,
the mother and cubs, in ages.
Helicopter's crashed.
Camera traps aren't working.
Snow leopards are gone.
So...
We're at a low point, for sure.
Nowhere to go but up.
I really feel for Shane.
Shane has been
working on that octocopter
in his garage for months
and months and months.
He's spent
a lot of hard work,
fine-tuning,
making sure that it can fly.
And within seconds today,
all of that work
has gone down the pan.
It must be very hard for him to take.
I feel very gutted for him.
We are at least two days away
from any help.
And in terms of technical help,
like a helicopter,
probably two weeks.
It's just a really hard place to work.
The team make a very brave decision.
The last month, we've had no luck,
we've had no snow.
We arrived here with fresh snow
and I thought, it was, you know,
a wildlife cameraman's dream.
We haven't had any snow
in about five weeks,
so it's turned into
a bit of a nightmare, actually.
I think we've seen the mother six times.
That's a hard way to make a film.
The plan now
is to monitor the conditions
and come back if we get snow
and if the female and cubs return.
Otherwise, there's not much point.
I'm going to let the fire
just die by itself.
We've been doing it for two months.
I guess it'll...
Sad day.
The crew are at a crucial point.
So much has been achieved,
but they know
the story is far from complete.
They're desperately hoping to return,
but they need snow
to stand any chance
of finding
the snow leopard family again.
Two months later, the team return
to a much snowier scene.
We're now headed toward a
mother snow leopard and cubs.
And I couldn't be more excited.
The team has been out here.
They've been seeing
them somewhat regularly.
And I'm thrilled at the opportunity.
We have some snow
on the ground now,
so we should be able to track them
and see them more easily.
Conditions are perfect.
So now we're getting some fresh snow.
I hope we get
another couple inches tonight.
Ideally, it stops about midnight.
Then we have, you know,
eight hours for animals
to lay down tracks.
And tomorrow,
they're much more visible
and much easier to track.
So this is perfect for us.
I'm very excited.
Having an egg sandwich.
It's just kind of
the default breakfast because,
you know, vegetables for breakfast
don't really work for me.
But eggs do.
Eggs saved my life here, actually.
Think you're gonna be all right?
You'll find the road?
Yeah, we'll try to find the road.
Tsultrim,
one of the team's
local guides and drivers,
confident enough in his knowledge
to get the team
wherever they need to be.
So I guess we'll carry on
to try and find mum and cubs.
Correct?
Copy.
The other half of the team
are the first to spot them.
I think that might be the mother.
Yeah.
The team are back
with the snow leopard family.
The film crew's knowledge
of this remote location
and their trusting relationship
with the cats
is paying off.
To everyone's relief,
the family look in great health.
We're not in this
to film on any given day.
We're in this for the long haul.
To try and stay with these cats,
learn what they're doing.
When we started, I mean, the cats,
they would see us and...
You know, if...
If they were close, they were gone.
And now, they've learned that...
That they can trust us, you know.
We haven't done anything
to violate their trust.
Even at the expense of some shots
that we'd like to get on a given day,
it's like,
"No, take your time, be patient."
And hopefully it'll pay off,
and I think it really has now.
As the filming progresses,
the team follow the family
as often as they can
and gain more insight into how
this population of snow leopards
survive here.
They're absolute masters,
but not only is it
the right color and shape
to blend with the environment,
but their movements are.
If I'm going around looking for
a deer, for example, or a sheep
and I surprise one, it runs away
and you see it, you know it's there.
But a cat? You know, no.
And I've watched this so many times.
When they see something
they don't like,
they'll go in a reverse stalk.
So they can still see what they want.
They'll creep back up over the horizon
and take off.
And you never see them.
So, you know, they're just
masters at using the terrain.
They move so slowly.
They turn
and have a head look this way.
And then that way.
Never do they move rapid enough
for something to catch that movement.
But even with these skills,
life for the top predator here
is extremely tough.
It's a wildlife cameraman's dream,
having a chase
come right to camera.
It's just... How can it go wrong?
There are 62 sheep for this cat to hunt
and it sits there.
Jeez.
I don't know what that cat wants but...
It looked perfect to me
but obviously not to him.
Got a snow leopard sneaking up
on blue sheep.
It doesn't get any better than this.
There's no way that cat can sneak
on those sheep.
It's wide open.
So, we wait.
Tough life of a snow leopard,
that's for sure.
You know, you...
We've seen 'em be close to sheep,
close to food so many times
but it just doesn't seem to happen.
I can't imagine what it's
like to wander around.
We can see their belly, they're skinny,
they're obviously very hungry,
very motivated.
But it's just hard to get a meal out here.
A fact the snow leopard mom
knows only too well.
The team now have a unique
and incredible understanding
of this remote area
and the wildlife that lives here.
Most of the time,
we don't spot the cats.
Other animals spot the cats
and lead them to us.
The lammergeiers have been
the biggest help for me.
They're beautiful,
elegant, soaring bird here that lives off
the snow leopard kills.
And the vultures, occasionally,
when we see them on the ground,
or landing near a kill,
then often they're waiting
for the snow leopard to leave and...
And that's our cue,
so, there's lots of things
that are leading us to snow leopards.
Sometimes we just get lucky
and see them.
The skyline is a good place
to pick 'em up.
But basically this whole team
has become
so dialed in now
that it's really amazing to see.
Just get this call on the radio and boom,
there's another cat, off we go.
Sure enough, in the sky above,
a vulture reveals
the location of a carcass.
The snow leopard mom finally
has an easy meal for her and the cubs.
She calls them in.
But only one is brave enough
to venture into the open.
Mom looks to the other cub
to encourage it down
but it's too timid.
She's going to have to fetch instead.
Mom now has two cubs alone.
She's torn between which to go to.
She heads up to protect the timid one,
leaving the other cub out in the open,
unaware of the danger he's in.
This is not good.
She's calling for the other cub.
It's not good.
It's really sad and hard to watch this,
she's calling and calling.
The other cub seems to try and
go to the mother to comfort her.
-It's not good.
-Where's the other cub?
I don't know where the other cub is.
Unfortunately, the other cub stayed
near the carcass,
which could be a bad move
'cause we know there are other cats
moving around and other predators.
I don't know why
it stayed by that carcass.
I hope it's in a cave somewhere.
I really wanna leave right now
'cause I don't want our presence
to keep the mother from coming back
and searching for that cub,
so, it's time to go.
I'd like to see how this resolves
but it's not right.
I'm worried for that little guy.
Let's get outta here.
As of tonight,
he's not reunited with his mother,
the mother was calling
and looking for him,
but I hope he's all right, hope he's okay.
Scary world out there
for such a little guy.
After a nervous night,
the team head out at dawn
in the hope of finding
the family together.
-You found them?
-Found them.
That's great.
The freshest tracks
went around the corner
and I was very tempted to follow them
but I thought, no, if I do that,
I'll probably bump them out
and frighten them away.
-Yeah.
-So I took a big circle around to look...
And sure enough, look right in that cave
and here's a set of eyes
and ears poking out.
Man, that's great.
The snow leopard family,
back together.
Her family is still intact,
and life's good, it's good news, though.
The remote snow leopard
location of Sanjiangyuan,
a beacon of hope for the survival
of the endangered snow leopard.
A wilderness
that offers them some protection.
And they do need help.
Across their vast Asian range,
the impact of climate change,
habitat loss
and conflict with humans
could threaten their very existence.
Snow leopards seem to be
doing pretty well here,
but the future is not guaranteed.
They survive because
the locals are tolerant.
And if anything should happen
to change that,
I think it would be very hard
for these snow leopards
and probably those across the range.
So, it's very encouraging to see
how well it's working now,
but it's a pretty fragile balance here.
A balance helped
by the presence here
of some very special human guardians.
In this vast region,
the cats are watched over
by hundreds of Buddhist monasteries.
The monks practice love, respect
and a compassion for all living beings,
resulting in the protection
of all life here.
Half of the monasteries in this region
are found very close
to snow leopard habitat,
and conservation organizations
are working with monks
to teach them how to monitor
and protect wildlife.
The snow leopard in its habitat
is considered sacred.
The monks serve as wildlife guardians
not only for snow leopards
but for all life here.
The numerous and scattered
monasteries serving
as conservation stations.
The endangered snow leopard
has surprising allies
in unexpected places.
The crew have enjoyed a privileged
and rare insight
into the life of snow leopards in China.
I do feel very privileged
to come to a place like this.
There's only a handful of filmmakers
that have had the magical opportunity
to work with snow leopards.
Much of this success
due to the local team.
Good luck for your film.
These people are certainly
some of the toughest people
I've ever encountered
anywhere in the world,
and fortunately, they had
the endurance that was required
to make this film a reality,
and the persistence,
and the dedication...
We couldn't have worked
with a more wonderful local crew.
A multicultural team
who spent more than
250 days in the field
defying the odds to successfully
capture the first-ever footage
of a young, wild snow leopard family.
It's something I'll treasure
for the rest of my life, I have no doubt.
For Shane and the team,
it's time to go home.
The footage they've captured in one
of China's greatest wildernesses
reveals much
about the elusive snow leopard,
a ghost in the mountains.
A cat that fires our imagination
perhaps more than any other on Earth.