Kitty! It's late,
time to hit the hay.
I just want to play
a little longer, mommy.
Come, let me sing you to sleep.
No, I don't want it,
I only want to hear it from Papa.
Mom, go back to your room, please.
Go to sleep, honey!
Easy peasy, fresh meat ready.
Mr. Há, did you hear something?
It's like something hit the train.
Follow me, we have
fresh meat ready to serve.
What do you mean by "fresh meat"?
It's the cattle from people around here,
they get lost...
and then hit by a train.
We call this... "BINGO".
How can we eat all that meat?
Don't worry.
Just make jerky out of them.
Don't you see
what am I carrying this bucket for?
Aren't we going a little too far?
Damn! That must be a strong hit.
See? It flew all the way here.
Pretty sure it's beef!
Look!
What's wrong?
Have you never seen bloody flesh before?
It's not that.
That meat looked so gross.
Come on, it's nothing.
Now what?
Can you keep going?
- Yes, I can.
- Okay.
Calm down,
what's the point of shaking like that?
I'm not shaking.
Looks like there's someone ahead of us.
How can he get there before us?
It's quite far from the neighborhood.
I don't like this feeling.
'Cause you are a newbie.
You get used to it soon.
Dude, what you're looking for
in this dark?
Need some light?
Can't I just collect my flesh in peace?
The piece I'm looking for
is right in your bucket.
Give it back, please.
Help me, mommy!
Wait for me.
GHOST FATHER
My daughter's just only 4 years old.
But I am often away,
so I'm looking for a nanny
to look after her.
I'll offer you a reasonable check,
25$ per day.
No one pays you more than that.
But... you have to stay here.
How can you entrust
everything to me like that?
You haven't known me yet.
I trust the one introduced you,
also... I trust my instinct.
Now you can go home and prepare,
then come back here.
I'll introduce you to my daughter.
I think Kitty will love you so much.
Ok, I'll be back this evening.
So weird.
No idea when did
my phone screen break
It's terribly annoy texting like this...
By the way, I've got a new job
Can I come over to see you tonight?
Your rental this month alone is $100.
And $15 utility bills.
Good evening, Mrs. Landlady.
Well, aren't you a good husband today?
Just my daily duty.
Why are you collecting rent so late?
I'm not going to collect yours,
I went to Ms. Nhi's.
Really?
Geez! She hasn't
submitted her part for 2 months long.
So frustrated!
Have you seen Ms. Nhi lately?
I haven't seen her, like... about a week.
Her room is always dark.
When she returns this time,
I'll strip her rental.
Such familiarity breeds contempt!
Honey, sound like
someone is on the roof?
Nonsense, maybe it's just a cat.
It's freaking freezing outside,
nobody's that crazy.
Who's that?
Well...
It's me, Van Nhi.
It's late...
Why didn't you call when you came?
I've come for a while...
But I only want to hear you play.
Then what brought you here
looking for me?
It's... nothing.
This is the movie room,
use it as you wish.
Yes.
And this is your room.
For now, I've arranged for you to stay here
while taking care of this house.
Wow, you give me the whole room?
- Don't you like that?
- I love it!
It's way better than my rental room.
Your computer looks so nice.
This room used to be my private office
so it's quite fully equipped.
Oh, so many movies here.
Did you collect all?
Yes, it was my hobby.
When my husband and I were living abroad.
Feel free to watch, if you like.
Just put them back when you're done.
Thank you very much.
Follow me.
Yes.
This is my room,
and that is Kitty's room.
You let Kitty sleep alone?
Yes.
She was taught to sleep alone
in her room at an early age.
And the unlit room over there.
Whose is that?
My husband's room.
So...
Nhi... you should only know,
do not open that door no matter what,
and don't question either.
That's my request.
Okay, I know.
Then, let's go see Kitty,
she's been waiting for you.
She's got a present to welcome you.
Kitty.
Kitty, nanny Nhi comes to see you.
I've got a phone call, come on in.
Hello, Thanh's here...
Kitty.
Oh, you're playing hide and seek with me.
What's your secret gift?
It's so lovely.
I got you, Kitty.
Where are you, Kitty?
Hello, miss Nhi.
Who did the No-Face makeup for you?
My mom.
- Did she?
- Yes.
You wanna go to bed?
- Do you like the "No-Face" ghost?
- I love it.
From tomorrow,
I will take you to school.
- And I'll play with you, okay?
- Okay.
Don't climb on the rooftop again,
It's too dangerous.
Who are you?
The one who cares about you.
Are you a thief or something?
Want me to carry you in?
Why are you always late?
You all look sleepy as hell.
Do I have to let you home
for more sleep?
What are you standing here for!
What a shame! Look at what time it is.
The final exam is almost tomorrow,
and you still behave like that.
Back to the book!
For someone to stand in the public,
language is one of the crucial elements
As it's always said,
speaking leads to answering.
Once you master languages...
Miss Nhi, let's buy some flowers here,
please.
What kind of flower?
My papa loves these flowers.
- Ok, let's go.
- Yes.
Kitty goes inside.
Hello Kitty.
Hello Ms. Chinh.
Are you Kitty's new nanny?
Yes, how do you know?
Kitty's family is my regular customer.
Does Kitty like this flower?
She and her dad do.
They come here to buy
every afterschool.
It's Forget-me-not flowers.
Make me a bouquet.
One moment, please. I'll wrap it for you.
How much is it?
1$ only.
Give me, give me.
Here you are, Kitty.
These flowers will wither fast,
just come here and get some more.
Sure.
- Bye bye, Kitty.
- Bye.
See you.
- Do you like arranging flowers?
- Yes, I do.
I'll make it a beautiful vase of flowers
for you, okay?
- No, not for me.
- Why?
Those flowers are for my papa.
♪ Oh er yee yo... ♪
♪ The rough road I'll be by your side ♪
♪ You'll walk the school to be wise ♪
♪ I'll walk you safe through this life ♪
Go to sleep, Kitty.
- Miss Nhi...
- What?
You sing too bad!!
Just sleep, dear.
Miss Nhi, please go back to your room.
So papa may return and sing to me.
♪ In the autumn wind, ♪
♪ I'll sing you to sleep ♪
♪ All the long night hours ♪
♪ I'll stay wide awake ♪
♪ Oh my sweet lady ♪
♪ Oh my sweet love ♪
♪ How I'm missing you now ♪
♪ My child, please don't cry ♪
♪ My child, sleep the night ♪
♪ Oh my precious child ♪
♪ Oh my precious child... ♪
Teacher, it seems like
someone's stalking me.
Maybe you're busy now.
I don't bother you anymore.
Do you believe
there are ghosts in this school?
I think there are ghosts here.
I have a strange feeling lately.
Are you serious? Don't scare us.
We fear ghosts so much.
Does it look like I'm kidding?
Then so be it.
No need to get agitated.
Let's have some milk tea after school,
okay?
Okay.
Here you go, Kitty.
- See you next time.
- Thank you.
Who's that?
Who's there?
You have beautiful hair, Kitty.
Which one do you love more,
Dad or Mom?
I love dad.
Really?
Does he come back to lullaby you at night?
Yes, he does.
- Really?
- Yes.
Does he really comes
to sing you to sleep?
Once upon a time, there was a girl
called Little Red Riding Hood.
One day, she wandered into the forest...
and bumped into a wolf.
What are you staring at, Kitty?
Miss Nhi, there's someone in the tent.
There's no one there.
It's looking at me.
- Let me catch it for you.
- Okay.
Just stay here. I'll catch it.
Let me see...
Is there someone in here?
Who were you talking to on the bed?
♪ My child, please don't cry ♪
♪ My child, sleep the night ♪
♪ Oh my precious child ♪
♪ Oh my precious child... ♪
- Kitty.
- Yes?
Does Papa sing you to sleep every night?
Yes, he does.
So... which song is that?
- Autumn's Wind.
- Oh, "Autumn's Wind" lullaby.
So where is your papa,
I haven't met him?
He's got to work.
So... after lullabying you,
he go back to work immediately?
Yes.
I wanna ask you something...
but please don't laugh.
What's that serious matter?
Have you got a Facebook account?
No, I haven't.
The social network can help you to
make friends from everywhere.
Even the school guard and janitor have.
Why don't you?
I'm too busy. And well...
I don't know how.
So easy... let me do it for you, ok?
No, thanks...
I don't wanna become addicted,
and spend all my day
on the phone and social networks.
Okay, I got it.
Teacher, can you take a selfie with me?
- Selfie again?
- Yes.
Say cheese!
Smile, please?
Have you seen your new picture yet?
Looks... yummy!
It's occupied.
I said... occupied!
What the hell...!
Someone is stalking me...
It secretly took my pictures
while I was sleeping
Here... yummy noodles for you.
Let me feed you!
- I feed myself.
- Ok.
Kitty is such a good girl.
- Is it good?
- Yes, it is.
Where did you get these photos?
Who are you?
Why did you do this to me?
You will know who I am, soon.
I really hate that girl.
She thinks she's a superstar or something.
What an arrogant bitch!
She just need a coat to
become a real coat-frock.
She's nothing special to my eyes.
If she's as rich as you,
maybe no one can stand her.
Why do you guys hate her like that?
For no reason, we just like to.
What are you staring at me for?
Never seen anyone
washing hands after having a dump?
Hello Kitty!
How old are you?
- Hello, hello.
- I'm four.
You are four years old?
What are you doing, pretty Kitty?
I'm making braids for Barbie.
Hm... so handy!
Let me give you a kiss!
Who is the prettiest girl here?
Go to sleep, honey.
Mommy's back, auntie Nhi!
Kitty... be careful!
Mom's home... Welcome home!
My honey! Missed me yet?
I miss you so much!
Good evening, Ms. Thanh.
These flowers are nice, right, mom?
Yes, nice.
Have you finished your work?
Not yet. But I have to be back home
as I promised you.
- Have you well behaved with her?
- Yes, I have.
- Do you like auntie Nhi?
- Yes, I do.
Good! Come here!
I'll sleep with you tonight, honey.
Have some fruit, Ms. Thanh.
There's something strange in the house.
What's wrong?
I think there's a thief.
No thief dares to be around here.
No thief... so it must be a bandit?
This area's safe. Don't worry!
Now you're here. So I don't have to
stay here tonight, right?
I'll sleep with Kitty tonight.
But... just keep staying here.
And taking care of Kitty
a few more days.
Because I must be back to work tomorrow.
Okay.
But... you even work on Saturday?
And one more thing.
Lately, I heard someone singing
in the house.
Must have been Kitty's.
No... it was a man's voice.
Maybe...
Maybe... that was Kitty's father?
We are in our own way.
How could that happen?
What do you mean?
That wasn't Kitty's father.
But... Kitty was so sure about that.
Kitty... Was Papa back home
and sing you to sleep?
No, he wasn't.
Have some fruits.
Who's that?
Is that you, Ms. Thanh?
You scared me.
You made me think of...
What's wrong, Ms. Thanh?
Ms. Thanh.
I'm sorry for what I said
in the evening...
Just get back to your room.
I wanna be alone.
Ms. Thanh...
there's something strange
that I haven't told you.
What's wrong this time, tell me?
Since I moved in,
my phone's suddenly had a lot of
weird photos.
I'm sure that I didn't take those.
Only Kitty and me at home.
So then who did this?
Look at these!
This,
this,
and this also.
Most of them are sexual photos of me.
See? This one too...
I think Kitty took them.
She loves to play on the phone.
In my phone, lots and lots
of photos of me that she took.
I don't think so...
She's too young to use the phone.
No, you're wrong...
She used it far better than me.
But...
What do you mean
by keeping saying that, Nhi?
Only three people in the house,
I'm off to work all the time.
Just you with Kitty.
Who else if it's not Kitty?
OK, let me show you.
Kitty!
Come here!
Come to mommy.
Can you take a picture
for Miss Nhi and me?
- Okay
- Okay, hold the phone.
We're sitting here!
1... 2... 3!
That's good, honey!
Look at it!
See?
Feel better?
If there's something else,
text me.
You are going to learn about
the concept of "Rest" in music.
Rest is the length
of a sound absence,
the interval of silence
in pieces of music.
A Rest is also a material
in composing musical structure.
The length of the pause
is indicated by the Rest symbols.
Go on and read.
In our school library, there are a lot
more good books for your reference.
Such a mess!
You jerk...
Who's there?
Who's that?
Is that you, Mr. Minh?
It's me.
Where the others?
They've all gone!
Come here!
Why are you still here?
And you?
Fermata is also used
alongside with rests.
Half rest can be used
when silencing a whole beat length,
Seems like I am...
making all of you
fall asleep on my lecture today?
No, I'm not...
Teacher, are you busy?
Why don't you reply?
Teacher, do you like popcorn?
No, thank you.
I wanna ask you something.
Please don't get mad at me.
Have you been married?
It's late... you should go home!
You have to travel a few days.
Could I move in
to take care of the house for you?
It's impossible, Nhi.
Because this is my friend's house,
not mine.
When I finish my work,
I'll leave this town right away.
Please understand that.
So you will quit teaching at university?
I think so.
Nhi...
From now on, please don't ever
ask about my family.
That's a very sad story.
I don't want to mention.
Understand for me, please!
♪ In the autumn wind, ♪
♪ I'll sing you to sleep ♪
♪ All the long night hours ♪
♪ I'll stay wide awake ♪
♪ Oh my sweet lady ♪
♪ How I'm missing you now ♪
Oops...
Let me check it.
Are you hurt?
Miss Nhi...
- What's wrong?
- The Boogeyman's in the closet.
What Boogeyman?
His hand scared me from that closet.
Be careful when you open,
of he'll take you.
Where's the Boogeyman?
I just saw his hand.
There's nothing there.
I did see his hand clearly.
Now you get back to your dolls...
I have work to do.
Okay.
Kitty!
Why aren't you in your room sleeping?
What are you here for?
The Boogeyman's upstairs.
I'm scared...
There is no Boogeyman.
Let me bring you back to bed.
No, I don't want to.
- Stay with me then, ok?
- Ok.
Can you go home tonight, Ms. Thanh?
I need to tell you something.
Miss Nhi, you've got a phone call.
Someone's calling, miss Nhi.
Ok, I heard that.
What's so urgent?
Something happened with Kitty?
Kitty is ok.
Kitty's fine, then I have no worry.
But I don't feel well.
Kitty!
It's late, I'll get you some milk
then we head to bed, okay?
- Okay
- Good girl!
Miss Nhi...
Kitty, I'm preparing your milk.
No need to come over here.
Miss, there's a boogeyman upstairs.
What boogeyman again?
Go upstairs to your bed now.
Miss Nhi...
Can I sleep with you?
Come on in.
♪ In the autumn wind, ♪
♪ I'll sing you to sleep ♪
♪ All the long night hours ♪
♪ I'll stay wide awake ♪
♪ Oh my sweet lady ♪
♪ Oh my sweet love ♪
♪ How I'm missing you now ♪
♪ My child, please don't cry ♪
♪ My child, sleep the night ♪
♪ Oh my precious child ♪
♪ Oh my precious child... ♪
Since you were away,
I've been seeing you in my dream.
But it's strange that...
in my dreams, you were a ghost.
Lol, what if...?
Ms. Thanh,
you think who took these photos?
I really feel worried and afraid now.
What are you afraid of?
I think...
The most fearful creature
in the world is human.
All other fears are just imagination.
No.
The most frightening things are
those that we don't know.
Are you hiding something from me?
What should I be hiding?
Like... the secret room that
you don't allow me to step in.
When I was cleaning the house
a few days ago,
I saw a branch of "Forget Me Not"
in front of that door.
I think the mysteries in the house
all came from that secret room.
If you keep on silent like this,
I can't stay here any longer.
I'm sorry.
Nhi.
Where are you going, miss Nhi?
Are you leaving me?
Miss Nhi...
Kitty!
So you're still determined to leave?
Yes.
Because since I came here,
weird things keep happening...
that I can not explain.
I hope that you understand.
Kitty will really miss you.
She's crying upstairs
wondering why you want to leave
I know.
Actually, during the couple of days here,
I have grown feelings for her.
But... as long as I stay in this house,
I can only feel worry and fear.
I am...
I got it.
Your salary.
Thank you for your time here,
helping me to take good care of Kitty.
Thank you very much.
Perhaps I should leave
without saying goodbye to Kitty.
Please forgive me.
Well...
Here's the coat that you lent me.
Thank you for your caring and attention.
I should go.
Please keep it as a gift.
Thank you, but I gotta go.
Where are you going, miss Nhi?
Are you leaving me?
Miss Nhi...
Please don't leave me, I'll be sad.
Stay here with me, please.
Miss Nhi...
The heck...
What's about her stuff?
Rest assure, I packed them all
nice and tight in the carton boxes.
How about we go down
and check for the last time?
- Sure.
- Please follow me.
It's dark down there,
let me walk you over to her room.
Here it is.
The door isn't locked, feel free.
Thank you.
There's a big box.
I will have some worker
to move them all out tomorrow.
Is that OK?
- Ok, no problem.
- Okay.
One more thing. How much
did she owe you for her rental?
Two months.
Oh, no no...
You want to pay the rental?
Please teacher...
I'll tell you what.
I'm also feeling sad about
what happened to her.
How can I charge a person
that passed away?
So you don't know what happened?
I totally don't know,
I've just come back.
Van Nhi's passed away.
It's been a week.
How did that happen?
Someone found her body near the railway.
She was hit by a train.
Poor her. There's still no one come
to bring her home.
Poor thing...
Do you know where she lived?
- She knows.
- Yes, I know.
Just go to the uphill street Dao Duy Tu,
and ask for madame Tam Hoang's lodgings.
Please accept this money,
consider me as her family
paying the bill on her behalf.
It's your business anyway...
You should keep the money,
so she says rest in peace.
I can't do that.
Since she pass away,
My heart was so broken,
I can't focus my mind.
'Cause I used to
think bad about her.
I feel very regretful now.
So... how about this?
You keep this money...
and buy some votive papers, candles,
fruits...
Help me to make an offering for her.
- Yes, I think it would be better.
- Thank you.
What a pity! Passing away at such an age.
It surprised me also.
I had just met her a week ago.
I heard she didn't have any relatives.
I can only count on you
to take good care of her.
Don't worry, I'll do it.
- It's late, I'll see you.
- Thank you, goodnight.
Teacher...!
Do you believe
there are ghosts in this school?
I think there are ghosts here.
I've been feeling strange lately.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Is someone in there?
Just us only...
What are you staring at me for?
Never seen anyone
washing hands after having a dump?
There are really ghosts in here!
What brought you here
looking for me?
A WEEK BEFORE...
It's... nothing,
I just want to say goodbye.
Goodbye?
Where are you going...?
Van Nhi!
Please don't leave me, I'll be sad.
Stay here with me, please.
Kitty. Ms. Thanh.
Kitty. Ms. Thanh!
Kitty...
Today is the last day
for our family to stay in this house.
After tomorrow,
all of this will soon become memories.
In the next few days,
it will belong to someone else.
To our family, sunny days, happiness...
seems like none,
But full of memories...
of pain and loss.
Since the day you and Kitty...
left me forever.
In the next few days,
I'll leave town for a while.
So I will bring you and Kitty...
to another sacred place.
I hope you two will forgive me.
Kitty,
please forgive your Papa.
Tonight,
I will stay here
with you and Kitty.
In the autumn wind,
I'll sing you to sleep
All the long night hours
I'll stay wide awake
Oh my sweet lady
Oh my sweet love
How I'm missing you now
My child, please don't cry
My child, sleep the night
Oh my precious child
Oh my precious child...
Who are you,
why keep following me?
I'm Quang,
but you don't need
to know that anyway.
I like you, so I follow you.
It just that we were once
belong to two different worlds.
And now...!
I don't know how,
and when I died?
You've followed me since then,
you probably know, right?
Sure.
That was the when you went back
from Mr. Minh's place.
You were focusing on your phone
without noticing the train coming.
I had to pick up
every piece of your flesh.
Those who suffer sudden death
usually don't believe that they're dead.
I was once like that too.
But... that's not important now,
Only living people care about
how they die...
but for the lost spirits like us...
Being dead or alive is not a matter.
And those contacting me
on the social network?
They're all the same as us.
Only ghosts can see each other.
Hi, beautiful ghost.
Nice to see you in this world...
Let send her a welcome clip.
Where's the bone-breaking freak?
I know he's into you,
Me too!
Now, come down here and join us.
The social network in hell...
so much fun.
Honey, took you long enough
to come down here.
Pretty like you is a treasure here.
Even I can not make
the second-best in hell.
You must be number one.
Remember me?
I sell "Forget Me Not" flowers
to you and Kitty every day.
Nice to see you... in hell.
Why did Papa leave me, mom?
Will Papa never lullaby me?
'Cause he's so busy.
So for now...
He will be away from us for a while.
No, I don't want it.
First, miss Nhi left me,
and now Papa too.
When he's done,
Papa will be back with us right away.
Miss Nhi doesn't leave you either.
Just a few minutes,
and I'll take you to her, okay?
Okay, mom.
Good girl.
And now Kitty...
Say goodbye to Papa.
Goodbye Papa.
Remember when you are done working,
please come back to me and mom.