I've never seen anything like it, Mayor.
Not in 35 years of law enforcement.
I think we` got a serial killer on our hands!
Call me back when you get this message.
You know, Tony, I know a guy at Work & Income,
might be able to help you.
Work and Income?!
Go to hell, "Mayor Broody."
I’m not being Mayor Broody right now.
Just your friend.
Jack.
You know I’m no good to anyone.
I’m washed up.
I’m through!
Now what kind of talk is that?
Hell, you’ve got more naval experience
than anyone in this country.
I don’t think anyone wants my naval experience, Jack.
Don’t feed the fish.
Please.
Ghost Shark can’t hurt you anymore, Tony.
Certainly not here.
- You don’t know that!
- Look, that happened a long time ago.
We defeated him.
You’re safe.
You don’t know that.
Still going to your meetings?
Fuck you, Jack!
Stale coffee and a circle-jerk
isn’t my idea of a night out.
Those people are there to help you.
You think anyone can help me, Jack?
I’m a lost soul in a sea full of shit.
- Tony, I...
- I can't even remember what life was like before that goddamn ghost shark.
None of us can, Tony.
None of us can.
What do you want?
Mayor Broody, they say there’s a killer
on the loose. Will you make a statement?
- That’s preposterous.
- But Mayor, they say he drowns his victims!
The police will make a statement later this afternoon.
Now, if you don’t mind…
But Mayor, is this going to affect your campaign for another term
in the forthcoming election?
- Get the fuck out of my face!
Fuck!
Commissioner Goldfarb speaking.
Two more deaths, already?
Ira, tell those boys in your office
to start doing their damn jobs.
We’re trying as hard as we can, Jack,
but we’re stumped!
Aren’t you guys forensic professionals?
Run some tests or something!
We have! But we don’t know what to
make of the results!
Nobody’s ever seen anything like it.
Wait a minute. What are you talking about?
How did they die?
Just like the others, Mayor:
DROWNED!
And what state were they in
when you found them?
That’s the bizarre thing.
It was like they’d been dead for weeks!
Mayor Broody?
Listen, Ira.
These details can’t get out, okay?
This is strictly between us.
What’s going on, Mayor?
Ira, do you remember when we first met?
I told you I’d seen some strange things.
But I didn’t say what things, or how strange.
I can’t keep it a secret any longer.
Back when I lived in Port Isabel…
The city was attacked by a great white shark…
…from beyond the grave.
- Mayor, what are you—
- I know it sounds ridiculous…
…but frankly, we don’t have time
for incredulity right now.
Everyone in Port Isabel died that summer.
- Tony!
After what we did, I didn’t think there was
any way Ghost Shark could’ve survived.
But it looks like he’s back.
I need you all over this, Ira!
We need expert assistance, and fast.
- “Expert assistance?”
What am I supposed to do, look in the yellow pa—
I don’t care what you have to do!
Find someone who’s qualified.
I don’t care how many dirty favours it takes.
I’m already on it, Mayor.
Help me, Tommy!
Tommy, help me!
Help me please, Tommy, help me!
Emily!
Please, Tommy!
Tommy, please!
God damn ghost shaaaaaaarrrrrrr-
What do you mean, New Zealand?
Mayor Broody has done a fabulous job of governing
our beautiful city of Auckland for the past 3 years.
But he belongs to an old school of politics.
A school that doesn’t serve modern,
forward thinking individuals like you or me.
Mayor Broody is last year’s news.
This October, when you’re voting for your new mayor, hey!
Give the new guy a go.
Vote for me, Marco Guerra, and you’re voting
for a new and better tomorrow.
Ahhh, what a douche-dick.
Hey asshole! Wanna turn that shit up?
You’re stuck in the past, man. Move on.
The safety of my people
has always been my primary concern.
What was it you said in that council meeting?
Prosperity comes second?
Who doesn’t want prosperity? Am I right?
Well, the forthcoming International Water Convention
promises to bring a boatload of tourist trade
plus jobs, obviously, to build
the main concourse and aquadome.
And what about this serial killer?
The Freeman’s Bay Drowner?
Is that all you people care about?
We’ve had four murders so far,
and your police department has refused
to give any official details.
So much for “the safety of the people,” huh?
- I assure you, Commissioner Goldfarb and his team
are working around the clock to see that
whoever or whatever it is is brought to justice.
What’s so complicated about solving a murder
in this day and age?
- Significantly more than you might think.
Hey! Jack!
You know I meant no offense in there, right?
Yeah, I know. Gotcha.
Gotta do what you gotta do.
Politics.
Exactly.
I’m going home - are we still on
for lunch tomorrow?
Oh, you betcha!
See you tomorrow.
- Look forward to it, brother.
Oh - give my regards to your little girl!
I will! Goodnight!
Thank you. That’s probably
the best steak I’ve ever had.
I’m glad we did this.
- Me too.
I really should get out more. It’s…
It’s so pathetic.
Yeah.
What are you up to after this?
Why?
Broody here. What you got?
I got a professional in.
They call him the Ghost Shark Hunter.
They say he hasn’t bathed in nine years!
He’s here?
- I’m lookin’ at him right now!
I’m on my way.
Oh!
God, you scared the bejeezus out of me.
Sorry.
Jack Broody. Mayor of the Auckland supercity.
You must be the ghost shark hunter.
Is Ira here?
This your wife?
Gimme that!
So, um…
Ira tells me you haven’t bathed for nine years.
Do the ladies go for that?
Let’s not piss around the pool, mayor.
Right.
Let’s back up the boat here a bit.
How exactly does one become
an “expert ghost shark hunter”?
I mean, really - how many could there be?
Want me to count ‘em for you?
- Well, yeah.
- One.
- I mean, no.
- Two.
Three.
- What?
Four.
Five.
Six.
Six?
THOUSAND!
And that’s only the ones on record.
And you’ve been hunting them all these years?
Oh god, Tony.
There’s somebody I’d like you to meet.
C’mon, you stupid fish.
Hey Jack.
Who’ve you brought with you this time?
Another god damn therapist?
Tony, this is Tom Logan. He’s a…
…ghost shark hunter.
Ghost shark hunter? Ghost shark hunter?!
Jack, what’s a ghost shark hunter doing here?
You know about this serial killer?
The Freeman’s Bay Drowner.
Son of a bitch!
I’m afraid so.
- No!
No! No!
We killed him, Jack!
We killed him! He was dead! I saw him!
God damn it, Jack.
What are we gonna do?!
- Tony, please!
It wasn’t the only ghost shark.
What?!
Apparently there’s…
Thousands.
Thousands?!
Jesus Christ, Jack.
He can swim through water.
He can swim through ice!
God damn motherfucker can even swim through steam!
- I’m sure Mr. Logan is aware of that.
- Oh, so you’re a big professional ghost shark hunter, huh?
That’s why Mr. Logan is here. To kill this thing.
He flew in this morning.
- You come here by plane?
Yeah.
Smart kid.
We gotta get on to it.
Be safe. Okay?
Ghost Shark’s gonna kill you.
He’s gonna kill us all!
We’re all doomed!
Auckland is doomed. Doomed, I tell ya!
He’s gonna swim through and get us all.
Throw us all in the drink!
We’re all doomed!
Tony was a Navy commander.
Managed to kill one of those bastards.
Damn near killed himself in the attempt.
Logan, I’ll be straight with you.
I don’t like to waste time.
How long will it take for you to
make this damn thing dead?
Permanently?
Name your price. Whatever you want.
Money. Women.
Real estate.
Drugs.
Weapons. You want somebody out of jail?
I can do it.
Thought you said you didn’t like to waste time.
So you’ll do it?
I’ll think about it.
Tommy.
Tommy?
- I’m not listening to you.
You know, they’re kinda like us.
- What?
- Dandelions.
- Oh yeah? - Yeah!
I mean, the seeds of a dandelion
can travel hundreds of miles if the winds are right.
They’re like tiny parachutes searching for a new home,
and sometimes,
if the winds allow it,
they find a new dandelion to land beside,
and grow.
- Tommy, I…
- Emily Morgan?
Will you marry me?
Tommy, I love you.
But I live in New Zealand.
I’m going back there next week. I can’t.
- Then take me with you.
- Really?
- Really!
Tommy, of course I’ll marry you!
Let’s get packing.
Tommy!
What are you doing here?
- I just want to talk to you.
- Who’s that?
- Nobody, dear.
- I just need to explain.
- I want you to leave.
- But I -
- I said I want you to leave.
You! I know you!
You’re the boy who’s gonna marry our Emily!
Gerald, why don’t you go and get Thomas a drink?
I’m sure he must be thirsty.
Pick you for a bourbon man, am I right?
It’ll take him fifteen minutes
to find the liquor cabinet.
- Please.
- And by that time he’ll have forgotten you were even here. - Look!
I’m sorry about Emily.
- You’re apologising?!
- I didn’t kill her!
How dare you?
Emily’s dead and there’s not a thing you can do about it!
You want to make it right, do you, Thomas?
Well go back to your own country
and your own family
And stop causing this one any more pain!
I have no family.
Dad, when’s lunch going to be ready?
Shouldn’t be too long.
It’s just about done.
Dad?
But seriously, Mayor…
What are your plans for the
International Water Convention?
You know, Marco,
I’ve been thinking about that.
I think I’m gonna cancel.
Jack, you can’t be serious.
I am serious, Marco.
We’ve got a serial killer on the loose
who drowns people.
Think about it. At a water convention?
It’d be like a fat kid
at a free cake bakery.
But Mayor!
If you cancel the International Water Convention
The economic impact will be devastating.
I know, but think about —
Sorry, what’s your little girl’s name again?
- Mart—
Got a minute mayor?
- Tom, what are you doing in here?
‘Cause I’m about ready to
get my god damn feet wet.
Jack, who the hell is this guy?
- He’s no one.
So you’re just gonna let him barge in?
- No, look –
Tom, I’m in the middle of a meeting.
Steppin’ on your toes, Mayor?
- No –
‘Cause I’d hate to step on your toes.
Okay, what the hell is going on, man?
This is Tom Logan. He’s, uh…
…an advisor.
- I see.
So?
Tom…
Anything you need. Just…
God damn it, Tom,
I’m in the middle of a meeting!
Well.
Now that we’re all…
Nice and cosy.
So, Jack…
What exactly is he advising you on?
Water safety.
Oh my God!
It was a close call, Ira.
Marco almost found out about Ghost Shark.
Marco?
- Jack!
If you value our friendship,
You’d better start talking,
or I swear to God—
Marco, take it easy.
You want me to take it easy, Jack?
You don’t know what I’ve seen!
- Logan, no!
If you follow me again, I’ll tie a fish around
your balls and feed your dick to a sea lion.
You! You sent your lapdog to spy on me?
Hey! I’m nobody’s lapdog.
You think I’m a coward?
If I was gonna spy on you, I’d do it myself.
Jack, it doesn’t matter who followed whom!
He conjured some sort of…
…shark ghost!
- Ghost Shark! - What?
Marco, there’s something I haven’t told you.
It’s not a serial killer on the loose.
What we have on our hands…
…is a Ghost Shark.
An undead beast that feeds on the souls
of those of us who dare to walk on the land.
So cancelling the
International Water Convention…
Was it because of this shark ghost?
Ghost Shark.
Is there a way to get rid of a Ghost Shark?
There is one way.
What are you implying?
I thought you said you’d killed
thousands of these things.
Sure. Ghost hammerheads, ghost makos…
…even ghost ghost sharks.
But this is a ghost Great White.
Like the one in Port Isabel.
You’ve seen one of these before.
You killed the Port Isabel
Great White Ghost Shark?
Marco, could you wait outside, please?
Marco!
Sure, Jack.
No problem.
What I’m about to tell you…
…never leaves this office,
do you understand?
Back in Port Isabel…
Tony!
Christ, I can’t even bring myself to say it.
- I heard about this.
You set off a nuclear bomb.
You killed thousands.
We had to make a call!
Tony had access to a submarine.
The gutters were clogged
with the ghost shark-mangled dead.
Please don’t tell me we have to do that again.
Not here.
Hate to break it to you, Mayor…
Nuke didn’t kill Ghost Shark.
- What?
All those people…
- It was an electromagnetic pulse.
Side effect of the blast.
Sends your Ghost Shark right back to Hades.
Oh God…
We do have another option.
An explosively pumped flux compression generator.
Generates an EMP without any of the fallout.
I can build one myself.
No, Logan.
An EMP would cut power to half the city.
Not half the city, Mayor; all of it.
No, Logan. Think of all the elderly
and sick on life support.
Without power, people will die.
Without an EMP, everyone will die!
- No!
I won’t sanction it.
Not even if there’s a god damn
Ghost Shark on the loose.
Not this time!
Then I’ll call the florist.
What do you mean, a florist?
For the flower arrangements.
For the funeral.
Because you’re gonna die.
Logan…
I understand your concern.
But I– - Love to stay and suck
your dick a little longer, Mayor…
But it’s kinda hard when your dick’s
turned into a pussy.
- Hey!
- Get out of my way.
So Jack…
What are you gonna do?
Go! Go! Yes! Come on!
- We interrupt your regular programming…
- What the fuck?
…to bring you this message from your mayor.
Change the channel.
It’s on every channel!
Unbelievable.
Beers. More beers. Hey!
You get ‘em. More beers!
When England are winning, you’ll be getting the beers.
Auckland is under siege from a
supernatural beast
known as Ghost Shark.
He is unmerciful.
He is unfeeling.
But he is not unstoppable.
It is with a heavy heart
that I have to announce my intention...
Fuckin’ pick up!
…to detonate an electromagnetic device
in the city.
It is the only way we can defeat
this Ghost Shark.
But it means we will have to come together,
as a people, to prepare.
Even now, our vital services are
preparing backup generators.
We would ask that you turn off as much
electrical equipment as possible.
If you leave the city…
…do it in a calm and orderly fashion.
And for God’s sake…
…stay out of the water.
The people of this city are a good people.
And I think... – No.
I know that Auckland will prevail.
So good luck, citizens.
You’re going to need it.
Two hundred straight in…
Two-fifty up the arse.
I just need to be held.
I can do that.
Tommy?
Emily.
You can call me whatever you want.
I miss you so much.
I miss you too.
I miss your voice.
Me too.
Can I kiss you?
What?
No…
It doesn’t work like that.
I love you, Emily.
No! It doesn’t work like that.
I love you, Emily!
What’s the matter with you?
Just leave.
You’re fucking crazy.
I said, leave.
Take a shower, you dick.
Tom!
Son!
You can’t blame yourself.
I didn’t even get to say goodbye.
Son, I know you’re grieving.
But that’s how Ghost Sharks are.
The only wake they leave is one of
death, anguish, and broken dreams.
God damn Ghost Shark.
You know,
I talk about Ghost Sharks and
people think I’m crazy.
But when you’re looking into the cold,
dead eyes of a Ghost Shark…
Your definition of crazy begins to change.
I can’t keep hunting them forever, Tom.
You’ve gotta finish what I started.
How do you even kill a Ghost Shark?
To kill a Great White Ghost Shark like this?
Only way to kill him
is with an electromagnetic pulse.
But you know what you really need, Tom?
Love.
It’ll take you to some dark places, sure,
but it’ll always bring you back.
Citizens are scrambling to be ready
for a power outage
after Mayor Broody today made
a bizarre series of statements
centring around the apparent presence
of a Ghost Shark in Auckland,
and culminating in the announcement of a plan
to detonate an electromagnetic pulse
to destroy it.
We’re now joined live by renowned
paranormal expert Dr. Paul Benson.
Good evening, Paul.
- Glad to be here.
How concerned should the average citizen be
about this Ghost Shark we’ve been warned about?
Very concerned, Rachel.
These are the ghosts of the millions of sharks
killed by the shark fin trade every year.
They combine the unpredictability
and thirst for vengeance of a ghost
with the ferocity and killer instinct
of a shark.
Basically the most dangerous creatures
on the planet.
That was Dr. Paul Benson.
But you can’t base your opinions
on those of one scientist,
so we sent David Farrier to the streets
to capture some of your thoughts.
What are your thoughts on Ghost Shark?
Ghost Shark?
I’ve never seen a Ghost Shark.
I think it’s a crock of shit.
It’s just another series of lies
from the mayor.
I think you’d have to be a moron
to believe something like that.
I mean, an EMP?
I think Broody’s really lost it this time.
So while Mayor Broody continues to worry
about a ghost shark,
the people of this city don’t seem too bothered.
Back to you in the studio.
- Turn that shit off!
What’s wrong with a little
investigative journalism?
Don’t tell me you believe in Ghost Shark.
I don’t need to believe.
I’ve seen Ghost Shark.
Okay, whatever.
Ghost Shark.
You got a problem, asshole?
Look mate, I work for the TV.
Oh, well that’s okay then.
If you work for the TV,
it’s almost a prerequisite.
Whatever.
Oh, that’s it.
Run away!
Hey!
Just leave me alone, man.
I’m talking to you, you bastard!
Mate, I said piss off.
It’s for your own good. Your own safety!
Okay then, tell me everything you know
about Ghost Shark.
You wanna know about Ghost Shark?
You really wanna know?
Son of a bitch killed my wife.
Killed my babies!
You ever think it might’ve been
their own fucking fault?
What did you say about my family?
Mate, I was joking.
What did you say?!
- I was joking!
God damn Ghost Shark!
Oh no.
Oh God. Oh Jesus Christ!
Come on. Wake up.
Get up, you bastard. Come on!
Wake up! Wake up!
God damn Ghost Shark!
Hey, you alright?
Fuck off!
Jack.
Jack, I fucked up.
I killed a man!
No. Fuck.
Jack.
You know how you said
you’d support me through anything?
Oh, fuck. No.
No. Fuck. Fuck!
Thank you.
God damn Ghost Shark!
Tony’s gone.
What do we do, Tom?
You know what we need to do.
- We’re not ready yet!
You think Ghost Shark gives a fuck
about your timetable?
We need this EMP right now, Mayor!
You don’t understand.
I can’t have that blood on my hands.
Not again!
You wanna hear about blood, Mayor?
- Oh please.
I coulda lived in this beautiful country
with a beautiful bride,
but a Ghost Great White killed her, Mayor.
Snatched her away from me.
And this is the closest I’ve come
to my retribution.
You don’t understand.
Without the backup generators up and running,
I can’t condone that kind of action.
And what about inaction?
What?
- From a certain point of view…
…you let Tony die.
Now you listen to me.
I don’t care what kinda Ghost Shark
hunter you are.
I would never let Tony Palantine
come to any harm.
And don’t you dare suggest it!
He’s still dead.
I know.
You don’t have to remind me.
I don’t want the people of this city
to end up like Tony.
This is no time to quibble over ethics.
I don’t know how I’m gonna live with this,
but I’m gonna have to learn how to.
You ready to detonate?
Meet me at the dock in an hour.
Don’t be late.
Come on, Martina.
We’ve gotta get a move on.
Coming, Daddy.
Why can’t Mrs Stevenson look after me?
I just don’t want to let you out of
my sight, okay?
But I want to stay with Mrs Stevenson.
Come here. Just give Daddy a hug.
Look…
I know I haven’t been around much lately.
There’s no excuse for that.
I’ve been busy campaigning
and I’ve neglected the most important thing
in the world to me.
What’s that?
You, my little pumpkin pooch.
Will you forgive me?
I think Mummy would’ve been proud of you.
Come on Martina. We’ve gotta go.
Where are we going?
Out of the city.
Come on, you son of a bitch.
Can we stop for lollies?
Sorry, Martina. No candy until we get
out of Auckland.
But why not?
Because I said so.
It’s bad for your health, and —
Jack?
Martina.
You’ve got to stay here, understand?
God damn it Marco, what are you doing here?
I was leaving the city. What are
you doing here?
The backup generators aren’t online yet.
You fucking idiot!
Just don’t use language like that!
My daughter’s in the car.
What were you thinking?
You shouldn’t have brought her here,
it’s dangerous!
At least here I can keep an eye on her.
She’s my reason for living.
For doing everything that I do!
Hi, my darling.
Cute.
You!
I told you what I’d do!
Get ready, gentlemen.
Martina!
No. No!
No, Marco!
No!
The breeze served us admirably.
We skimmed before it like a bird,
the coast of the island flashing by
and the view changing every minute.
Soon, we were past –
Mom?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Just a little longer, Tommy.
Come on!
The people are gonna be angry.
We can hide in my office.
Stop crying, little girl!
Ghost Shark can swim through tears.
Chaos across Auckland continues, due to
this morning’s complete power failure.
Although many areas have had
electricity restored,
thousands of families are still without power
and several deaths have been repor—
Hello, Jack.
Your time has come.
We’ve been watching you closely
and we do not approve.
You tried to sell us
on the delusion of a Ghost Shark
and innocent lives have been lost
as a result.
So you can run, Jack.
Yes, you can even hide.
But the People of a Free Auckland
will find you.
And when we do?
We will kill you.
What are you doing?
- Got it!
Who is it?
Routine inspection, sir.
Just need to check your fire alarms and
make sure everything’s still functional.
What?
It’s locked.
You unlock this door, or I’ll
skin you from head to motherfucking toe,
you bastard!
Don’t go.
I know he’s here. I have to find him.
Look around you, Tommy.
Who do you see?
Do you see Ghost Shark?
I only see you.
Exactly.
So come be with me.
Just relax.
Forget about your old life.
Join me.
You’re not Emily.
Well done, slow-swimmer.
Are you beginning to understand?
What is there to understand?
What your world is doing to ours!
For millions of years, we have
hunted our oceans.
But you cut off our fins
and throw us back in the water.
If we can’t swim, we die!
You know, I never thought it’d come to this.
Open this god damn door!
Trapped in my own office.
I’m scared.
I’m scared too.
Get the drill.
Don’t worry.
It’s me they’re after.
I’m not a nice person.
In fact, I’m a coward.
I say “it’s for the greater good.”
“It’s for the good of the people.”
But what does that even mean?
It’s all a lie.
And I’m a liar.
A selfish old bastard
without a bucket to shit in.
I mean, what does that say about a man?
I’m glad you’re here, Jack.
Well, Martina.
When they get in here,
make your dad proud.
Be brave.
Gotcha.
- Look, what is it that you want?
What are your demands?
Demands?
Fucker thinks we’ve got demands.
- Cut his throat, Jules!
I don’t understand.
What I did was for the good of the people!
It was for your own good. No one else’s.
But you don’t understand.
A Ghost Shark demands extreme measures.
A Ghost Shark demands –
- I agree.
A Ghost Shark does demand extreme measures.
Hand me my knife.
So.
Do you recognise this place, slow-swimmer?
This is the last place I saw Emily alive.
Did she scream for help, Tommy?
Did she scream?
I never got to say goodbye.
It’s okay, Tommy.
Just accept your fate.
It’ll be quick.
It always is.
You’re right.
What?
- You wanna kill me? Then kill me.
Just give me a few more seconds with her.
Whatever you need.
What are you doing?
You’re a shark.
If you can’t move…
You die.
No. No.
Goodbye, Emily.
What happened to your shirt?
Long story.
And Ghost Shark?
I said, long story.
I hope it has a happy ending.
Hey little girl.
What’s your name?
- Martina.
Well, Martina,
you’re safe now.
What’ll you do now?
I don’t know.
I know a guy at Work and Income.
Be seeing you, Mayor.
It’s been an honour.
Where is he going?
Mayor Broody?
But you know what you really need, Tom?
Love.
It’ll take you to some dark places, sure…
…but it’ll always bring you back.