Everybody seems to be ready.
Are you ready?
For the first time
in three years,
the greatest rock 'n 'roll band
in the world, the Rolling Stones!
- The Rolling Stones!!
We're gonna have a look at you.
We're gonna see
how beautifulyou are.
Whoo!! All right!
Oh, New York City, you talk a lot.
Let's have a look at you.
Let's have a look at New York City.
Whoo!
Well, all right!
Welcome to the breakfast show.
Whoo!
Yeah!
Thank you. Whoo!
Thank you.
We're just gonna wake up.
Well, all right!
Charlie's good tonight,
isn't he?
I think you really--
you really dressed up tonight.
Aren't they?
We'd like to see how you look.
Can we see how they look?
Let's have a look how they look.
Come on.
Oh, we just want
to see how they look.
Ohhh, we couldn't see you!
We couldn't see you.
It's really hard
to see this together, isn't it?
It will take time.
- What?
- Eight weeks.
Eight weeks.
Do you think you can
do it that quick?
This gives us the freedom.
All you guys watching us.
We may only be on you
for a minute,
then go to almost anything.
This is Stefan Ponek,
KSAN Radio, San Francisco.
Well, the Rolling Stones' tour
of the United States is over.
They wound it up with a free
concert at the Altamont Speedway
for more than 300,000 people.
There were four births, four deaths
and an awful lot of scuffles reported.
We received word that someone
was stabbed to death...
in front of the stage
by a member of the Hell's Angels.
Nothing's confirmed on that.
We were there.
We didn't see it,
but we did see a lot.
We want to know what you saw.
Our phones are open.
We'd like to hear from you. What
was the Altamont free concert like?
The Angels did as they saw best
in the difficult situation.
As far as I'm concerned,
they were people who were here...
who tried to help
in their own way.
- Right? You know?
- Hmm. Right.
If people didn't dig it,
I'm sorry.
That was Sam Cutler, one of the
organizers of the free concert.
I think we've got one of
the Hell's Angels on the line.
Sonny Barger.
Have I got that right, Sonny?
- Yeah.
- Okay, what's up?
I didn't go there
to police nothing, man.
I ain't no cop. I ain't never
gonna pretend to be a cop.
And this Mick Jagger, like--
put it all on the Angels, man.
Like, he used us for dupes, man.
And as far as I'm concerned,
we were the biggest suckers for
that idiot that I can ever see.
And you know what?
They told me...
if I could sit
on the edge of the stage...
so nobody would climb
over me, you know,
I could drink beer
until the show was over.
That's what I went there to do.
But you know what?
When they started messing over
our bikes, they started it.
I don't know if you think
we pay $50 for them things...
or steal them
or pay a lot for them or what.
Ain't nobody
gonna kick my motorcycle.
And they might think because they're
in a crowd of 300,000 people...
that they can do it
and get away with it.
But when you're standing there,
looking at something that's your life,
and everything you've got
is invested in that thing,
and you love that thing better
than anything in the world,
and you see a guy kick it,
you know who he is.
You're gonna get him.
And you know what? They got got.
I am not no peace creep
by any sense of the word.
And you can call them people
flower children and this and that.
Some of them people
was loaded on some drugs...
that it's just too bad
we wasn't loaded on...
because they come running up the hill,
yelling "Aaaah" and jump on somebody.
And it wasn't even always
jumping on Angels.
But when they jumped
on an Angel, they got hurt.
Well done, Sonny.
I think I remember him.
Do you?
No, I'm not certain.
I don't really remember
what he looked like.
There was a couple of them
before we went on.
They were really very nice, you know?
A couple of them guys.
It's just, uh--
I don't know.
I mean, the way they cleared the path,
for instance, was incredible.
Were you there? Was you in the party
that had to be led to the stage?
- My goodness.
- I saw what they did, yeah.
That was insane.
What did they do?
Well, it's just the way
they did it, you know?
It's very, very--
'Cause before that,
I didn't really think there
was anything going on, you know?
Really. I didn't hear anything
'cause we were right at the side.
Oh, dear, what a shame!
KSAN Radio here. The violence
at Altamont was completely unexpected.
The Rolling Stones had performed
for overflow audiences...
without incident in major cities
across the United States.
Okay, roll it.
Whoo! Yeah!
Thank you.
Well, all right.
Well, all right!
Whoo!
Are you any more satisfied
as far as your career goes?
Do you mean sexually
or, or philosophically?
- Both.
- Yeah, we're more satisfied
now sexually, aren't--
How about philosophically
and financially?
Financially dissatisfied,
uh, you know.
Uh, sexually satisfied,
philosophically trying.
- Rubbish.
- There's a question here on the right.
I read in one of the papers
that you'll be giving...
a free concert in San Francisco.
We are doing a free concert
in San Francisco.
- When?
- On December 6.
And, uh, the location is not
Golden Gate Park, unfortunately,
but it's somewhere adjacent
to it which is a bit larger.
It's creating sort of
a microcosmic society, you know,
which sets the example
to the rest ofAmerica...
as to how one can behave
in large gatherings.
This is Mel Belli,
the lawyer in San Francisco.
Uh, I'm-I'm talking
for the Rolling Stones.
We've got their managers
and their principals here.
I've just heard that you've
offered them your speedway...
for their performance
on Saturday, is that right?
- That is correct.
- This is an open phone
so we can all talk on it.
What I'm trying to find out
is what we can do to do this concert.
For the last 36 hours, I've stood
my organization on its ear, Mr. Belli.
I don't know anything about this.
I'm coming in late and trying
to straighten something out.
So tell me exactly
what it is without--
Yeah. My first area
of policy concern:
I do not want this gesture...
on the part of Mr. Jagger...
to cost me five cents.
If a blade of grass is torn down,
they are going
to build it up again, you know?
I was involved in Woodstock.
I've represented rock groups,
and I've been involved,
both as an attorney and
as an executive, with festivals.
No matter what anybody tells
you, they're a pain in the ass.
Don't turn me into a proctologist.
Just tell me what I can do here.
Well, somebody tell me why I should
want to get this concert going.
Are you trying to make it
so they can't do this?
No, I want it to happen,
but I'm not prepared to rebuild
my goddamn racetrack.
Will you come up and see
if you can work with me on this thing?
I'd love to work with you, Mr. Belli,
but are you working with Mr. Jagger?
I haven't met Mr. Jagger.
I've only met these other people here.
- Have you met Mr. Schneider?
- Yes, he's right here in the office.
All right, fine.
He knows what happened
at our meeting this afternoon.
Then call me back
and with the thought...
see if you could come up
tomorrow morning.
- You and I can see what we
can do with this damn thing.
- Okay.
All right, call me back.
There's no way to do the concert
except in that location.
As it stands now, you're gonna have
at least 100,000 kids there by Saturday.
You don 't have any alternative.
The only thing you can do...
is to do an affidavit,
temporary restraining order
and talk to one of the judges.
So that brings us down to this.
Um, I'll call one
of the judges right now.
That's your only chance of
forcing these people to do it.
Now, don't scare off from these people.
If I were advising them,
I'd tell them to hide out.
Because right when they're coming out,
you'll-- sh-ta-boom!
- Yeah, but it doesn't
come in till the solo.
- I know, I know.
- What is that?
- What?
- Stickin' out of your pocket.
- Cousin Minnie says,
"How delicious!"
I'm taking it home for Robert.
Y'all come back now, ya hear?
That's one more song.
That should be it.
I found it. I found it.
Anybody in?
Is my local groupie in?
Hello, darling.
How are you?
When are the bags
coming up, Ronnie?
Stew's gotta get 46 pieces up.
We're gonna do--
We're gonna do a slow blues
for you now, people.
You like that?
I like it.
This thing is going on.
The Chronicle is coming out
with a story that it's off.
- This has been building up
for a long time.
- Well, it's off and on.
Everybody wants a piece of the pie.
All right, let's see
if we can get some facts...
to build together
on an affidavit here.
So we'll have that available and then
a very short order to show cause.
The sheriff wants to know who's going
to go to the bathroom and where.
They've got a nice little
bucolic community there--
They know practically when
every john is flushed...
and the orderly habits of the bathroom
of all of their, uh, voters.
Dick Carter's on the line.
He's offering us
the speedway at Altamont.
Hello, Dick.
This is Mel Belli for the Stones.
If they were to perform
in the speedway,
is the speedway open
so that they can be seen...
from the people that can't get in?
I'm sure we can work something out.
I want the publicity.
You want the publicity?
Well, you take the publicity.
The Rolling Stones don't want any money.
It's for charity.
- So I'll take the money.
- All right.
All right.
Well, why don't I do this?
Why don't I talk
with these people here...
and then I'll get back with you...
and then if we
have to sign anything up...
and if you need any insurance,
which I'm sure you will want,
and all the rest of that stuff,
I'll work with you in the morning.
- Okay.
- I'll call you back later,
after I talk with them, Dick.
Bye. He's offered
the Altamont Speedway.
- There's not enough room.
- There's not time to move it.
We got to tear down
a stage and the scaffolding.
The phones are in. The generators
are there. Everything is left to go.
It's anticipated that the amount of kids
now traveling across country--
you may have anywhere
from 5,000 to 20,000 kids...
starting to arrive sometime tomorrow.
They're all lining up at the airports
from as far away as New York.
- Now? You gotta be kidding.
- You have no idea what goes on here.
It's an amazing phenomenon.
It's like the lemmings of the sea.
- Mike Lang is on the line.
- Yeah, Mike?
John says that he doesn't think
you can make it overthere
at the Altamont Speedway.
- Do you want to talk directly to Mike?
- Yeah.
Mike, I got the impression
from everybody where you are...
that there was no way
of moving to that speedway.
We can do it.
Nobody wants to,
but if we have to, we can.
Just a quick question.
You were at Woodstock, and
you've now been to Altamont?
- Right.
- How does it stack up?
Do you have the room?
I think we have the room, sure.
I think we can hold as many
people as want to come.
Can you change locations that fast?
We had a much bigger
operation to change at Woodstock.
I don't think we'll have much problem.
We're just dealing with a free concert.
That's what we want to present.
And I think that's what the Stones
are up to. They want to play here.
Is this going to be Woodstock West?
Well, it's going to be San Francisco.
Do you have any special feelings
about this kind of a concert?
This spontaneous, free--
Well, it's not so much--
I don't think it's a complete concert.
The concert is just--
I think it's an excuse.
You know, because,
like, the thing is,
it's just like everyone coming
and having a good time.
The concert's like
the proscenium of a theater.
It's like an excuse for everyone to just
sort of, you know, get together...
and, like, talk to each other
and sleep with each other...
ball each other
and get very stoned...
and just have a nice night out
and a good day, you know?
- I mean, do you understand?
- I do.
It's not just like getting
up there and seeing...
the Grateful Airplane
and the Rolling, Rolling Dead.
And now, Ike and Tina Turner.
Thank you.
I don't know what they paid
for them-- the costumes--
but is there any way--
Good. It's nice to have
a chick occasionally.
Far out.
Sorry you had to wait.
Whoo!
Oh, yeah!
Thank you kindly.
I think I busted a button
on my trousers.
Hope they don't fall down.
It's that jumping around.
I'll have to do it up again.
Whoo! You don't want my trousers
to fall down now, do you?
We're gonna--
We're gonna kiss you good-bye.
And we leave you
to kiss each other good-bye.
- Hello?
- Yes, Mel?
- Yes, we still have you.
- I got you in an echo.
Think you can pick it up?
I'm practicing. I'm going on first
before the Rolling Stones.
Can we get you to pick up
the phone like before?
Well, what it is now, we're waiting
for Mr. Carter to come in.
But I've just had
a letter read to me...
where he said
that he very definitely...
wants the Stones
and the concert there.
So, as of this minute, we're
intending that the show go on.
They have 200,
300 people working...
and it's going to be
quite a problem to get the thing
set up at the Altamont Speedway.
But it will be,
and it will start at 10:00.
Now, that's where we stand.
I'm waiting for Mr. Carter now.
Uh, let me ask and see.
Are the Rolling Stones all in town?
- Not yet. They're coming tonight.
- They're coming in tonight.
But everybody's ready,
and they're all set to go.
That's where we are.
Is this Mr. Carter?
Sheriff, Mr. Carter just came in.
Now, could we talk a little bit?
I can put this on the box
so that we can all hear.
And I think, to start,
Mr. Carter has expressed...
his willingness to have this
on his private property over there.
But the question is of this
narrow road to come in there.
Do you foresee
any problems on that?
Well, that basically is
the Highway Patrol's problem,
and they foresee problems.
How many cars can Mr. Carter
park on his property?
150 cars per acre?
150 cars per acre times 80 acres.
- How many?
- 150 times 80.
- 12,000.
- 12,000 automobiles.
Well, up in Tallalamee County,
they estimated they had 80,000 cars.
What are we
going to do with them?
There's much open area
around there.
I can probably arrange
with other landowners.
There's one adjoining me
that has 2,000 acres.
Yes, well, we have
some of the adjoining landowners
complaining before it's even granted.
If there's 50,000 cars that Mr. Carter
can 't park, we're in trouble.
8:38 now at KFRC.
This is Frank Terry, and let me repeat:
The Rolling Stones'
free concert is going to be on
tomorrow at Altamont Speedway.
Apparently, it's one of the most
difficult things to give a free concert.
As you all know, the concert
was originally scheduled
for Golden Gate Park...
and then
at the Sears Point Raceway.
Many, many volunteers
went out to Sears Point...
in trucks, cars, trailers,
everything,
packed up all the gear out there
and took it to the Altamont Speedway...
where they are right now,
in the cold, 30-degree weather,
setting up the stage,
setting up the generators...
the sound equipment
and the facilities for the people.
We're gonna end it now.
Good-bye.
Yeah!
Well, all right!
We got to go!
They hit Mick. Somebody hit him.
- Come on over.
- I hate you!
Keith!
Do you think he'll be coming out?
Oh, Mickey, Mickey,
Mickey, Mickey.
I can't function. I've been
on the scaffolding almost all night.
I can't close my hands. They're formed
to the shape of the scaffolding.
You people that are hanging
on that scaffolding,
you're rendering that scaffold
unsafe by climbing on it.
Those scaffoldings are not built
to take very heavy weight.
So if we could have
some sort of reason,
whatever that might be,
we'd be very pleased.
Arthur, in between moving
around, always turn that off.
Turn it off and turn it on.
Look, you've got to be very cool
with that little thing.
Even though it's supposed to be
electrically correct, man,
you got to really
think right around it.
Are you gonna hear
some music today?
Hey, you want me to just
leave this in here?
No.
Hashish.
L.S.D.
Psilocybin.
Hashish.
Make them comfortable.
Even this parking situation back here,
it's all wrong, but
that's the way the kids park.
For once, we're just
gonna let it happen.
For experimental purposes.
You know what I mean?
So be as easy on this
as we can.
It won't hurt the Stones
in any way.
Wow!
Wow, but I wanna be smart,
but you're just so far out.
Because... yeah!
They should be back when they
discover we're not with them.
Since we've got the beer
and the food, they'll find us.
Well, a guy's freaking out
over at the tent there--
So, tough shit.
What do you mean, tough shit?
The guy's really freaking out.
Keep-Keep your--
No, I don't mean tough shit.
What I mean is that...
if you lay successive
numbers of bums on this crowd,
by the time 6:00 comes around,
they're gonna be in a real mood.
I'm not prepared to stand
here laying bum trips--
Up at Woodstock this was done,
and you were there, and you know.
And announcements were made.
We're just sort of
getting there, basically.
If we make it.
I've been falling a lot lately.
Let's go this way.
Whoa! When did this happen?
There's already a doctor over there.
A chick's having a baby.
She's having a baby.
Contributions
to Panther Defense Fund.
to the Panther Defense Fund.
They're trying to either
wipe out the Panther party...
by jailing all the members
and wiping them out economically,
financially, or violently
through killing them.
After all, they're just--
they're just Negroes, you know?
Need that cannon pretty bad.
We just had our first baby born
at Carter's Altamont Speedway.
Yeah, right, yes.
- Just had our first baby born.
- Oh, wow.
Okay so far.
Everything's all right.
- We have a helicopter standing by.
- Can we get a mike?
If the press will push this:
Dick Carter's Altamont Speedway,
not just Altamont Speedway.
This cat right over here.
He just told me to do it, man.
No, well, I'm sorry.
Nobody else goes there except me.
I'd really like you to get off
the stage, baby, please.
Okay, well, I can dig that.
- Thanks very much.
- Uh-huh.
The American Red Cross has asked
us to secure these supplies.
If anyone has any
of these things to contribute.
We need Ace bandages.
Ace bandages,
gauze and sponges.
If you have any of that equipment,
please bring it to the medical tent...
or to the Golden Gate Chapter
Disaster Service Red Cross truck.
Excuse me.
Which way is the stage?
Around the corner?
You mean that way?
I think we're in pretty good
shape, though, right now.
We're in chaos backstage.
We'll never get--
That's gonna have to be cleared,
'cause the group's gotta come in.
What we need to do is start
getting some blokes together--
The essence of it,
as far as I'm concerned,
is this is where the work has gotta go.
- Right.
- Sling them all out.
No fucking about. We've had enough
of being polite. Get out, go away.
- I've asked. I know.
- So if you could help us,
that would be groovy.
- Sure.
- All these people, you know?
I want to see Mick Jagger,
goddamn it. No!
Can I say just one thing
before you take her off?
- Just let me say one thing.
- I will not!
Hey, before you go away, man.
Don't tell me what to say, okay?
You look after your job, baby,
and I'll look after mine.
You're trying to stop me.
I'm trying to ask you--
Will you ask all these
people that are milling around
if they'd move to the side, man.
He wants to listen to you.
- You want a bong?
- She wants to get fucked.
That's the way!
You don't belong here, man.
- Let me have some of that.
- I wanna get up on stage.
The organizers,
who number about 20 people,
would really like
to thank the hundreds of people
who came out here last night...
and worked all night to get this on.
Thanks to everybody who helped.
And I'd like to point out
to everybody here...
that this can be the greatest
party of 1969 that we've had.
Let's have a party,
and let's have a good time.
The Flying Burrito Brothers!
Please stop hurting each other.
You don't have to.
Take him out the other side!
Hey, man, quit crowding.
Just back off.
We need a doctor under
the left-hand scaffold...
as soon as possible, please.
They're not gonna play music
till we get a doctor.
Somebody help.
Somebody's hurt!
Marianne Faithfull is here.
You feel like signing a few albums?
Let me have that album.
Where's that album?
Thank you.
Well, I'm not stepping outside.
- I don't blame you.
- I am. I want to.
-Just sign this.
- But I can't get very far.
Sign this, please.
Sign this one too.
Hey, what about the free records
and all the rest of the shit?
There are a number of people
on and around this stage
who should not be here.
Consequently-- Consequently,
the musicians on this stage...
are playing with something like
200 people breathing down their necks.
Now, can I please ask that
everyone leaves the stage...
and, as I say, we'll go back to
playing music and nothing else.
The Jefferson Airplane.
Jefferson Airplane.
Easy!
Easy.
Easy. Easy.
Please be quiet.
Yeah, it's all right.
It's kind of weird up here.
Hey, man, I'd like to mention
that the Hell's Angels...
just smashed Marty Balin in the face
and knocked him out for a bit.
I'd like to thank you for that.
There's other ways--
Hey, wait. Is this on?
- You're talkin' to me,
I'm gonna talk to you.
- I'm not talking to you.
You're talking to my people.
Let me tell you what's happenin'.
You is what happenin'!
Hey! Oh!
- No! No!
- Watch it. Hold it.
- No, stop it!
- You know what's happening?
- What's happening?
- We're partying like you.
No! No!
Um, you know,
that's really stupid.
Hey, man, you guys
don't have to stay on the stage.
They're not gonna hassle us.
- Hey.
- They're not really that--
That's really not worth it.
You don't hassle
with anybody in particular.
You gotta keep your bodies
off each other unless you intend love.
People get weird, and you need people
like the Angels to keep people in line.
But the Angels also--
You know, you don't bust
people in the head for nothing.
So both sides are, uh,
fucking up temporarily.
Let's not keep fuckin' up!
- Oh, that's what the story is here?
- Yeah.
- Oh, bummer.
- Really bad. I mean, like, it's scary.
- Who's doing all the beating?
- Hell's Angels.
- Hell's Angels
are beating on musicians?
- Marty got beat up.
- A fight on the stage.
- Doesn't seem right, man.
It's really weird, man.
It's really weird.
- Oh, man! Really?
- There's lots of people.
Get that cleared!
Let's get it!
Oh, babies.
There's so many of you.
Just be cool down in front
and don't push around.
Just keep still.
Keep together.
Oh, yeah.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, Keith, Keith, Keith!
Keith, will you cool it,
and I'll try and stop it.
Hey, hey, people.
Sisters.
Brothers and sisters.
Brothers and sisters, come on now.
That means everybody just cool out!
Will you cool out, everybody?
- A fight broke out.
- I know. I'm hip.
Everybody be cool now.
Come on.
All right?
How are we doing over there?
Can we still make it
down the front?
Is there anyone there
that's hurt? Huh?
Everyone all right?
Okay?
All right, I think we are cool.
We can do--
We're always having--
Something very funny happens
when we start that number.
I need to get down with it now.
All right!
Uh, people, who's fighting, what for?
Who's fighting, and what for?
Why are we fighting?
We don't want to fight.
Come on!
Do we want--
Who wants to fight?
Who is it?
Hey, you know, I mean--
Every other scene
has been cool. Let--
Look, that guy there,
if he doesn't stop it, man--
Listen, either those cats
cool it, or we don't play.
- Come on.
- You gonna stop?
We need a doctor!
If you don't cool it,
you ain't gonna hear no music!
Now, you wanna all
go home or what?
We need doctors
down here now, please.
Can we have a doctor
down here now to the front?
I-I cannot see what's going on.
I just know that every time...
we get to a number,
something happens.
I don't know what's
going on, who's doing what.
It's just a scuffle.
All I can ask you,
San Francisco,
is like the whole thing.
Like, this could be
the most beautiful evening...
we've had for this winter,
you know, and we've really--
Why don't-- Don't fuck it up, man.
Come on, let's get it together.
I can't do any more
than just ask you,
beg you, just
to keep it together.
You can do it.
It's within your power.
Everyone, Hell's Angels, everybody,
let's just keep ourselves together.
You know, if we are all one,
let's show we're all one.
- Preach it, brother!
- Up on the scaffold. Urgently, man.
There's one thing
horrible that we need.
Sam, we need an ambulance.
We need a doctor
by that scaffold there.
If there's a doctor,
can he get to there?
Okay, here we go. We're gonna--
I don't know what we're doing.
When we get to really the end
and we all want to go absolutely crazy,
and, like,jump on each other,
then we'll stand up again.
You know what I mean?
Everyone keep-- sit down.
I mean, just keep cool,
and let's just relax.
Let's just get into the groove.
Come on, we can get it together.
Come on. Sit down.
Hey, man, look. We're splitting.
If those cats can't--
If you people-- We're splitting
if those cats don't stop beating
everybody up in sight.
I want them out of the way, man.
I don't like you--
A guy's got a gun out here,
and he's shooting at the stage.
- It's one guy.
- He's got a gun.
Hey, people.
Come on, let's be cool.
People, please.
There's no reason to hassle anybody.
Please don't permit it.
If you move back and sit down,
we can continue and we will continue.
Can you roll back
on that, David?
Sure.
Did you see
what was happening there?
No, you couldn't see anything.
Well, it was another scuffle.
There's the Angel
right there, with a knife.
- Where's the gun?
- I'll roll it back.
You'll see it against
the girl's crocheted dress.
Right there, isn't it?
Oh, it's so horrible.
Is there an officer?
Is there a policeman here?
- What happened here, anyway?
- Man, he pulled out a gun.
- He did?
- Yes, the Hell's Angels
took the gun away from him.
One of them has it now.
He showed it to me.
And they proceeded to put him down
on the ground and started kicking him.
And he has a couple of stab wounds
in his back and one over his ear.
We tried to keep him alive,
but when we got here, the doctor
checked him out and that was it.
We pronounced him dead at about 6:20.
We have a request from the state police.
- I don't want him to die!
Don't let him die, please!
- He won't die!
Now, they're gonna do
everything in their power.
- But they can't hear his heart.
- Now, don't worry about it.
Don't worry about it.
- They're gonna put him
in this whirlybird and take--
- I have to go with him.
Get back, please.
Yeah!
Whoo!
Bye, bye, bye, bye!
Oh, yeah!
Come on in!
All right.
See you all.