GALAXY
It's the engine.
The brake?
Be careful.
I think it's the plug.
- Plug.
- Must be the plug.
The plug is dirty. It's wet.
- Not the plug. The cam.
- Plug. Pla... Prav...
- Pravda.
- Pravda?
No. It's Pravda.
Pravda. Pravda.
Pravda.
This can't move anymore?
- Pravda?
- Yes! Soviet.
Must be the plug!
He's a correspondent for Pravda.
Pravda.
It wasn't me.
I didn't do it!
The plug was really dirty!
I didn't mean any harm!
If there's a chance,
I'll pay you back.
But you...
You don't want
to be involved with me.
I'm always watching you.
You ghost!
Please...
Please, don't delve any deeper.
Who... who told you to do this?
Who told you to do this!
What do you know about me?
You're only doing...
what he expected you to do.
Are you...
Always playing such dirty tricks?
Stop...
Please...
Sorry.
That must hurt a lot.
If you get ahold of yourself,
We'll meet again
when you get back.
But...
We'll always pass each other by.
So I want to chase you.
Perhaps...
that wasn't you.
Right in front of you...
All the time for 20 years...
All the time...
Someone's walking before
you like a white shadow...
That's right.
It's the "you" from that time.
From that time.
Me... from "that time"?
Do you know me?
Back then,
Before you became yourself,
When you couldn't take a
step forward or backward...
I'm you from that time.
Excuse me...
A while ago, you...
Me?
No. Never mind.
What did I do?
Never mind.
Beyond the bright sky,
From farther than
the rays of sun,
I came to be by your side.
At that time...
A long long time ago...
You left.
Separated from me.
Leaving me behind.
Sleepless nights...
Beyond the darkness.
That was the first time?
Yes.
You're lying.
Aren't you here?
Unbelievable.
That it was decided so easily.
- Unbelievable.
- Wait. He's coming.
What should I do?
- Long time ago...
- You, you...
- The present "you" is no good.
- What should I do?
My "he" is coming.
He is coming!
What should I do?
Crickets chirping...
Iris leaves...
This darkness
and that darkness...
Taking photos of pines...
Pierced by the blade...
of the setting sun...
Why did you...
leave that kid?
Too late! Coward!
Even if you jump,
It makes no difference.
Please understand.
I must go back to
the me of that time.
What time?
When?
For what?
That time.
Where?
Where are you?
Come out.
Come here.
I want to meet
the me that I killed.
Meet him again!
Meet me!
Am I...
In a dream?
Or is it real?
What to do with her?
Do I know?
She's going to die.
You and she,
Stop saying bad things.
Go back!
Release me!
I came, because you wanted me to.
Bastard!
Oh, so you know me?
I can understand that.
Listen.
Be more specific.
You want to go against time?
Or go back to the past?
Or go into your dreams?
My...
He's really your incarnation.
But he's not the chap you think.
You think you can hide it
from me?
He's me.
Really?
Now he's really you.
He...
Wants to tell me
that he's my dream.
My world...
And all that cultivated me,
Belong to him.
Precisely.
Then what are you?
I am me!
And me?
You're just a fungus!
That lives in my toes
and give me athlete's foot!
You can only rise a bit
by the sun rays.
Do you know your car
fell off the highway?
Look at her!
She loves you from her heart.
You enjoy hurting yourself.
What's she gonna think?
What do you know?
I don't care.
I'm OK with the way I am now.
I'm going to...
Where he is!
But where?
It's not your fault.
But please leave me alone.
That's enough!
I'm going to you!
You're just dreaming...
You're just walking around me.
It's the frame of your mind.
Don't you understand?
You are yourself.
Look within yourself.
Don't look outside yourself!
You are yourself.
Look within yourself.
You're lost in the darkness
of yourself. Poor man!
"Don't look outside yourself?"
Only seeking yourself?
What is this?
That's why I don't trust you.
What a dirty trick!
That's not what I wanted.
You've always treated him badly.
You've no right to scold me.
If he's so dear to you,
why didn't you treat him well?
Why didn't I?
You've mixed up your nature
with your dream.
It's already too late
to cling to this man.
Shut up!
Hurry then.
You're not finished yet.
You can't give up
on yourself that easily.
You think you've realized
something important.
Soon you'll see
how scary you are!
Don't be stupid.
Go back at once.
After you die,
nothing would be started.
You want to do
something irreparable.
No, you've done nothing but
irreparable things.
You want to bury him.
You're really missing the point.
You're my dream.
You're my whole future.
I was wrong the whole time.
I pursue you to make
myself independent.
All right?
Shall we decide this here?
Bastard!
You want to die?
Or you don't?
You want to go to your next life?
Or go back to the past?
Can you have your own dream?
Let's go over everything.
And do what you like.
Your past is all karma.
All linked up in a string.
I'll show you!
It's you from that time.
Which do you choose?
You're my dream.
My world... My dreams.
You are yourself.
Look within yourself.
Make myself independent...
Can you have your own dream?
Goddamn monk!
Get off me!
Mirror...
Mirror!
Not here...
Where is it?
Mirror!
Please. Come here again.
I want to know
what you meant by...
"The thing in the distant past", and
"The thing that belongs to me".
I...
Don't mind dying.
I killed you.
Many times.
I don't know my world.
That's scary.
But I...
I'm not giving up.
It's boring to be alive.
Terribly boring.
But I have you.
I can meet you.
Somehow I'll go back to my wife.
Go back to the car that's
fallen off the highway, and live.
Do I really have to do that?
You're here!
The monk was right,
"You are yourself,"
"Don't look outside yourself."
You're wrong.
I don't know anything.
That's just his talk.
But...
You're me!
Your existence...
that's my dream, right?
Really.
It really is!
Before he died the monk said,
"That guy, he doesn't
have his own dream.
"That's why he's very frustrated."
Frustrated?
You're frustrated that
you don't have your dream.
You must be joking!
I have a lot of dreams!
Hey.
The monk isn't dead.
Because you've been lying,
He put on an act
to stop your lying.
And he's my dad.
My dad.
Your dad.
I'll be frank.
I appear before you to make
you tidy up your memory.
Dad wants to know if
you're living in your dreams.
Because you're so unconcerned
about your memory.
Don't be so sad.
I like you.
You have such a tough life.
Your dream is still
a blank page.
Nothing was written on it.
That's why I'm so free.
Dad went back to the Underworld.
He said you can find
your memory in your dreams.
But... can you?
You can't, right?
That's the person you are.
That's the person I am.
Must be the plug!
It's dirty!
Plug! Pravda!
Pravda? Pravda!
THE END