GREAT INVENTIONS
So... this...
She is the muse,
the muse of great inventions.
I put it at the beginning of the book
Because women are at the origin
of all great inventions.
It doesn't sound very smart because
muses never invent anything.
They suggest, then
they use and then they smash everything.
On the other hand, every invention
Is a crime against nature.
And when it comes to invention,
you always have to look for...
looking for a woman!
Galileo, for example, when he
invented himself that the earth was round,
He did so because he had been observing
the stars for a long time.
And from a certain age on,
When looking at the stars,
there is always a sentimental reason.
And Newton's apple,
from which tree do you think it fell,
If not from the tree
Of the garden of Eden?
Newton's apple
and Eve's apple are
The same apple, the same crime,
And thus the same sin.
Well, Professor Norman's N734,
my boss,
is the same thing,
originally there was a woman.
True, you don't know what N734 is,
but I will introduce it to you.
Professor Norman, my boss,
has been tinkering with test tubes for three years.
Things were not going well.
He had the lousy mood of an inventor
who hasn't invented anything in a long time.
And then there were ants.
Gross ants.
POCKET LOVE
Maubru...
Maubru.
Yes?
Experiment 3267.
Solution 503.
Ant, family 804, land.
Result?
Null.
Maubru.
Yes?
Open the door.
Here! Good! Let's go, let's go!
This way, this way, straight to you.
Now lay it down. Very good!
Ah, you have ruined my pedal!
But, but.
what does it mean, dear colleague?
As simple as drinking
a glass of water.
Here is the amount
of energy expended,
There the amount of carbon dioxide
released. Here the oxygen.
No, no, no, no...
I mean, what does it mean
the intrusion of his
material into my laboratory?
Is he getting married soon?
I don't see the connection.
Honeymoon!
I am not going to leave all
this valuable space unused.
So I store.
I do not intend to make any
trip, and even if I do,
I wouldn't let you have my
workshop as a warehouse.
Mobru, the counter!
No, Mr. Professor.
It's class time.
Oh the lesson!
Clear it all out!
As early as 1907,
Dr. André Nepveu,
known by the pseudonym
Luc Durtain's literary name,
proved that it is possible to
to freeze at minus 12 degrees...
eyes of fish, rabbit and bird.
Hey, Jerome is looking good.
A toad petrified by the cold,
to such an extent that it is difficult to
to break it with a hammer,
resumes life as soon as it is
brought to normal temperature.
- 500 francs not wearing glasses.
- What?
- For your notes.
- 500 is not enough.
And my belt.
Gone!
No! No!
In 1950.
I won, give me the belt!
- Home.
- No, now!
His body was hard
like metal...
It is his girlfriend who
makes him wear glasses.
They don't need them.
Have you ever seen his girlfriend?
Don't distract me.
...because the temperature
continues to rise.
Is he your boyfriend?
It's not bad, huh?
Is he really a scientist?
Father guaranteed it to me.
His favorite student,
he practically raised him.
Raised well.
Father says if we take care of it
care of it, it can win the Pavlov Prize.
And the Pavlov is the first
step toward the Nobel Prize.
Handsome, intelligent, affectionate...
and obedient.
The opposite of your ex-husband.
Hey, did you know that he remarried?
Really?
Yes, with a hideous redhead.
A movie guy.
From the movies?
Good for him.
Instead you have to be on guard.
With those eyes there...
Don't worry.
Men should
work only with men
and should not
ever travel alone.
That's why I was compelled
to go to this event.
Are you going to stay here then?
Yes. Mom and dad
are staying upstairs.
Thanks to the internal ladder, I can
go up and down without having to go outside.
I can have dinner with
Mother if I want to.
For now Jerome is not staying here,
so I will furnish as I please.
Why? Don't you like it?
I like it!
But why are you staying in this hole?
Your place in Paris
Do you think I enjoy
being in the province?
I'm just waiting for
for the right opportunity.
Jerome is so busy in the lab
and I don't want to rush him.
Again?
An American pastor, Basile
Luyet of Saint Louis University,
defined a state of
thermodynamically stable configuration...
- How is it going with Monette?
- He may be doing better.
His mother painted in
white a step on the stairs.
Prohibition of entry. Understand?
Do you think you are in the Middle Ages?
...heating degree.
Monette.
Hey, Jean-Loup is calling you.
Can't you see that I'm busy?
Slower!
Apart from the scientific prizes,
what's in it for him?
Glory!
Is that all?
Daughter of a professor and granddaughter
Of a scientist, you will be wife...
And you are the daughter of a
soda vendor and you will be...
Shut up, you idiot!
I was thinking.
Pull.
Your Jerome...
Are you sure he will win the prize....
Pavlov?
Why not?
With the connections my father has....
Good.
Our brand needs
needs some visibility
"Juvacola. Are you tired?
Juvacola and the tiredness goes away!"
It works great!
Too much so.
The most envious competitors have
started a campaign against Juvacola.
They imply that it excites young people,
that it keeps them from sleeping.
But it is true!
It is true,
but there is no need to emphasize it.
If an unchallenged scientist
directed a research center
dedicated to improving the human race
human through carbonated beverages,
as the Juvacola,
one would silence
silence the envious.
And when Jérôme
wins his prize,
Will it be like winning
your Juvacola as well?
Yeah!
Yes, but wait a minute!
If I give you my scientist,
what do you give me in return?
I need to talk to Raymond and he
with the board of directors.
But if they agree,
a solution can be found.
How much does your Jerome earn?
So it earns...
Actually, I don't know.
Well, he will earn 10 times more.
10 times more?
Get everything ready for tomorrow.
Professor.
Have you frozen
something in the lab?
What about the cold-blooded animals?
The turtles?
- Have you read Goldsmith's article?
- Not yet.
He is insane.
He needs to be watched.
Sir, are you looking for an assistant? I am
qualified! Sir, please say yes.
- Yes.
- Oh, thank you.
- Am I coming tomorrow?
- Tomorrow in my workshop.
- 6:00 p.m.?
- Yes.
Oh, thank you, thank you!
Girl, look at me!
I am a genius!
You are talking to the assistant to
Professor Norman. I start tomorrow.
Hypocrite!
You said you didn't care!
Don't you understand that it is a damnation?
What if gangsters used it to make a
disappear an atomic scientist...?
- Are you coming?
- No, I have to work.
- I will help you.
- Like the other day, with your hands?
Who are those beautiful women?
I don't know, they don't look like mothers.
Maybe they are teachers' wives.
You are formidable! I recognized
one! That's Norman's girlfriend!
Good.
I want to go play tennis.
It is boring.
- I want to make my friends toil.
- I will not get tired!
Jerome.
My fiancé...
This is my friend Anne-Lise,
I told you about her.
She and her husband have a
booth at the exposition. Wonderful!
I hope you will give us the pleasure
of coming to the opening.
Excuse me, sir...
I was unable to
find in the laboratory
the book on particles
colloids in the protoplasm.
He talked about it in the course.
The author seems to me to be Mechnikov?
No, no, not at all.
His name is Colignon.
One of my students...
Jean-Loup Prade.
Good morning.
Shall we go?
Who is that beautiful girl?
I don't know ... probably
one of my students...
Ah...
Good. F 23 AX, B series.
Good morning.
Now F 23 AZ.
But no, you imbecile!
You gave me the Series A.
- Oh...excuse me, miss!
- No problem, sir.
Can I help you?
I am the one who should help her.
I'm afraid I don't understand.
I am his assistant.
What did Bataillon do?
- What does he think he is doing?
- I don't know.
I already have an assistant.
- No.
- Yes! Now he's going to see it. Maubru!
He will not come.
And why shouldn't he come?
I let it go.
I will replace it.
Impossible. In what?
In all.
Maubru.
- Finally!
- Again?
- But I have to go in!
- Not now!
I don't know you, miss.
But, sir, he had told me.
I don't know your level of
knowledge in biology,
And all I can say to her
Is that I don't need her.
Very good. I don't have much to
tell you, except that you are a liar.
Why liar?
Because yesterday he told me to come!
Me? But when did I ever?
At this point, I don't want to
even work with her anymore....
- Well, are you finished?
- No, no, no, no!
- Does it close the door again?
- Yes!
If I get rid of him, will he keep me?
Look, Miss.
What does he have to risk?
All right, try it.
- What do you wish for, professor?
- I, here...
So, boss?
For me, that's fine.
Give me the second copy to sign.
So do we agree?
Jerome will work for 2-3 months
in one of our workshops here,
Then we will find a pretext
to move him to Paris.
I recommend that before
the beginning of the school year.
It will be all right.
Louisette, call the
advertising office in Paris
And have it announced to the press....
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Wait till I warn Jerome first.
Haven't you talked to him about it yet?
What if he refuses?
He will not refuse.
Louisette,
call Paris...
- The day after tomorrow.
You didn't even
mention the conditions?
Jerome does not understand the
numbers under a million.
2 quadrillion 4 trillion
673 million 274 632.
Can I go?
Yes. Have a good evening.
Hey, stop it!
How restless you are . . .
- Shall we go skating?
- I'm not done yet!
- At this time?
- The experiment is still in progress.
- A very diligent young lady!
- So what?
So should I leave?
- Yes.
Here,
take Atom and come back in an hour.
Pass me the data,
they should be ready.
Was he your boyfriend?
No, boss.
Just a classmate.
Thank you. He is not even a friend.
He is nobody in short.
If you want, go with him,
I can finish by myself.
No, boss.
I'm passionate about this work.
Yes, I'm sure I will be passionate about it....
But I would like to understand...
What?
If you don't mind explaining, it's the
ant thing that I don't understand.
With larger animals,
yes, but with ants....
All right-do you remember my
course on freezing?
You will remember that toads and fish became
frozen and hardened like stones,
But once they warmed up they
resumed life as if nothing had happened.
Ants freeze at zero
absolute kelvin, or -273 degrees,
have revived normally.
Has a person ever been
frozen in a laboratory?
No, no, do you volunteer?
All scientists
dream of freezing life.
My idea is to
replace the cold
with a product that has a similar effect
similar on living cells.
Instead of freezing them, I coagulate them.
So I slow down life at will.
Here is a drop
containing live protozoa.
Here's another one,
where they are all dead.
And here finally, the one where life
Is suspended, thanks to my product.
My N734
Should act in the same way
on ant cells.
I'll take an ant...
But where is it?
That is exactly what I would like to know.
Do you see anything there?
Have you seen it?
Excuse me... That was not my intention.
So? Do they keep
disappear these ants?
Yeah.
Do you suffer so much that you don't eat?
Put yourself in my place.
It's my job.
Look... you are free to
to do whatever you want, but ...
If I were you, I would leave it alone.
Something tells me you are on the
wrong path. Female intuition.
Let's go.
Put on the dress quickly.
Is it that way?
Yes, in your room.
There, in the cardboard boxes.
You know what...?
What?
The Bonjeans have
offered coffee service.
Baroness Edmond has an ice bucket
for ice made of jewels.
Just think, there will be 400 covers!
The cultural attaché will come on purpose
from Paris. Are you listening to me?
Did you find it?
Did you hurt yourself?
Hurry up, mother's guests
will arrive in 15 minutes.
Here it is!
How does Anne-Lise look to you?
I like.
I am glad because
he gave us the most beautiful gift.
Huh? What gift?
Location.
I already have it.
No. You have a job.
What difference does it make?
A working man's wife
wears a fur coat of
rabbit instead of mink.
Take Mom for example...
his dinner costs the same as
three days of vacation.
Since she has been married, she has been using the furniture
she received from her mother-in-law.
Don't worry!
You'll get the mink when I find
The secret to slowing down life.
No. I also like it from rabbit.
Well, if I don't find the slowdown
Of life, I have my super vitamin.
A rabbit takes
3 kilograms in two days.
Nobody wants to get fat!
People want just the opposite.
Listen,
Anne-Lise is giving us an unhoped-for opportunity.
Give dad your resignation
And in a month's time,
You go into private industry, okay?
The dogs, the carp!
The rabbits, the doves, the mice!
Is this a description of Noah's Ark?
It is not acquiring the results.
Turn everything off.
But how,
six weeks of observations...
Turn everything off.
Do we start from scratch?
No, we're stopping!
So do we release them all?
Momo, Bertrand, Jules,
Zoe, Gustave, Caroline, Alfred...
Are they the calendar saints?
I have given names to all of them...
except for these who were born yesterday.
I'm leaving!
I'm leaving the laboratory!
I will have a new, much better one.
Unlimited credit.
But it is wonderful!
Nothing to be sad about!
Unlimited credit, but no Momo,
no Arthur or Caroline.
All research
Will revolve around the improvement
of humanity through gazoses and tonics.
Like the Juvacola?
Exactly.
"Juvacola-super.
And that's why you leave your job?
With the results obtained...
734 changes to my formula and
only so many disappearing ants!
Professor, can I go?
My train is in 27 minutes.
Where are you going?
Professor, do you remember that I have a leave of absence
of 15 days? I'm going to my grandmother's.
Go.
Thank you, professor.
Is there no chance...?
None.
It would take a miracle.
All right, I'll take it all out.
Don't worry, Atom.
Did he want a miracle?
It worked.
Yes! It worked! It worked!
The ants were
too small to see.
She never wears her
glasses when she needs them.
Calm down, we understand the method.
Maybe there is no method.
She is always observing
It is necessary to observe,
to gain experience.
I don't talk about the experiences.
It is not always important
that the calculations are right.
Chance also plays a role.
What if Newton had not
dropped the apple on his nose?
His apple is my little Atom.
My little Atom...
No, no, no ... you are my apple ...
Hmm... Good. Let's go in order!
Or maybe it's better to
make some messes.
Another ant and
another vial of N734.
Here.
Ants, ants,
ants, the whole anthill!
Ah,
my experience is worthless.
Female intuition...
Always late!
We don't go to your father.
Why?
Ah! Why did you decide
to sell knick-knacks?
Much better!
Meaning?
But how?
My N734 solution works.
This was a real rabbit. And this one
Was a real guinea pig.
The indefinite conservation
Of matter. Here it is.
The ants have not disappeared.
They turned to stone,
decreasing in size!
Are you saying that
these are real animals?
But yes!
But it's disgusting!
This cannot
be serious!
Because of these ridiculous little things,
you wanted to change our plans?
For what purpose then?
You have invented a new way
To kill poor animals.
This is nothing to brag about.
And of course, you don't know how to revive them?
Don't you?
But.
Okay, let's go.
Father is waiting for us.
I told him you had resigned.
He felt sorry for you,
But of course, the happiness of
his daughter comes first.
Aren't you thirsty? Go ahead, drink up.
That's it!
Did you see how easy it was?
One always thinks one is
to be indispensable
And instead they are happy
when one leaves.
Especially that colleague of yours
who can take over your laboratory.
Perhaps your method can
be used in the industry of
chimney linings.
Obviously it will be very expensive, but ...
Perhaps I can revive them.
The research takes time.
How long did it take before
your beasts became petrified?
3 years.
You have 15 days to
try to revive them.
Next, preparations for the
wedding. Then, 15 days in Paris.
You are going to Juvacola on August 1.
In the meantime, you can have fun here.
Chief, look!
Yeah ... you have fun ...
I don't think I know her.
Who is this lovely young lady?
Monette...
Monette Landry,
assistant professor Norman.
Sorry for the interruption.
No, no, not at all!
No interruption.
I came for Monette. If the
Mr. Norman is finished with her...
No, we are not finished!
I thought you didn't know her.
She is pretty...
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Very nice. Even too much so.
Your colleagues are envious
And they will start gossiping.
Father will suffer so much....
I am not jealous, I want the
best for your career... Hey!
Mr. Prade,
the young lady needs to be with
my fiancé,
would you mind accompanying me?
With pleasure.
Let's leave the scientists
to their own work.
Can I take the dog with me?
No.
The dog.
It is moving.
Do you think so?
It seems to me. Shall we open?
No. Two more minutes.
What are you doing?
I promise St. Lazarus to
Return the collar I stole.
Why St. Lazarus?
He is the patron saint of the resurrected.
Nothing.
Maybe you stole two collars.
Damn!
This was my last hope.
And our last day.
Don't cry. I will find you
A much better leader than I am.
There is no one better than you.
I have been waiting for it for 15 days....
15 days?
Yes.
Ever since I realized that
you don't love your girlfriend.
You keep crying though...
Of joy.
But what...?
What?
Quick, quick, come here.
No no!
We need to figure out what's going on!
I am afraid!
The tears! The tears! Water
Salted in the proportion of 0.033!
Come on, cry now!
Cry!
I can't!
Yes, of course. Always the same story!
When it is not necessary,
you cry, and when it is needed.
You are a monster!
For you, tears are
only 0.033 saline solution!
My tears are pain!
I am in pain!
Brava! Brava.
Brava. Cry! Cry! Cry!
Come on.
Come on!
Again!
It does not work.
Maybe it only works with ants?
I don't think so.
Probably, you have to immerse it
completely in the solution.
Do you want me to cry so much?
Here it is. It's 198 grams.
Damn!
It is not enough that it is covered.
The volume of salt water
Must be greater than the size
of the living animal's body.
Oh no! No, no!
Phone.
Let it ring.
Answer.
No. Let me...
Go!
Hello?
What? Ah, is that you?
No, no, honey.
What do you mean, "honey?"
No, no, I worked.
If I experiment, it is
because I trust in success.
No, I would rather not kill
beasts and have dinner with you.
Eh, it's quite dangerous.
It could all blow up.
Do you know what you should do?
Eat some chocolates and
go to bed without waiting for me
And later, when I get home,
I will say good night to you
What do you mean if I'm alone here?
Of course, I am alone.
At this time then.
All right, see you soon.
What is it?
My fiancée.
No, it is not.
She is my fiancée, my
fiancée reduced to an equation.
It's simple.
Do you know the arithmetic of passion?
What about that philosopher? Jeremy Bentham?
What were you doing in the classroom?
I used to draw the professor.
Ah, good. Great!
So, the philosopher Jeremy...
Bentham.
He invented the arithmetic of the passions.
For example, if you are offered
a trip to Italy
And you don't know what to do,
make two columns.
In the one on the right,
take notes on what you
like and left the opposite.
Therefore, the grades will be
proportionate to your pleasure.
For example, right...
The things I like.
Yes. So.
"Change of scenery - 8.
"Enrichment of
experience and culture" - 8.5.
"Traveling in sleeping car together" - 10.
10...
"Buying new clothes" - 9.
9...
"Seeing Capri" - 7.
"Buying new hats..."
- 7... Wait a minute!
- 8.5. - 8.5...
"Visiting museums" - 8.
Oh. 2.
2. Well, that's enough.
Now in the second column
mark what you don't like.
Nothing. With you I like everything.
- Do you want to learn or not?
- Yes.
Do the additions and
decide whether to make the trip
based on the column
that has the highest total.
Same thing with my girlfriend.
I write on the right what makes her
angry, on the left what calms her down.
Two additions, one subtraction.
And depending on the outcome,
I am calm, firm or lovely.
And are you often forced
to be lovely?
Oh, it's not that terrible at all,
thanks to my kindness...
Your kindness is exaggerated.
Edith is waiting for me to
drop by to say good night to her.
- Shut up, Atom!
- Who's there?
Open up! Why have you locked yourself in?
Who is it? Is it you?
It is not so terrible...
It's me, Edith!
I know you are not alone! Open!
I'm sure that
girl is with you! Open up now!
I can't now!
Open up, quickly!
I am just finishing an experiment!
An experiment! I can imagine what
kind of experiment you are doing!
Can you hear me? Open or I'll break down the door!
Here, here, here, here I come!
I warn you, I'm going to scream!
You are wasting time.
I will scream so loud that
the whole neighborhood will hear!
Jerome! Open!
I'm going to scream!
If you don't open on 3, I'll scream!
I'm starting to count! One!
Two!
I'm coming!
Jerome, open now!
What are you doing?
Where is she?
- She who?
- He said, "Shut up, Atom."
Shut up, Atom!
You see for yourself...
I must conclude,
my dear Edith,
that you are not the
ideal for a researcher.
I, I am the one who will make you
win the Pavlov Prize!
You confuse rewards and results.
Awards mean nothing. What
that matters are their motivations.
I will take care of the Pavlov Prize.
No, no, from now on
I will take care of everything.
First of all,
tomorrow I will withdraw my resignation
And I will not leave my workshop.
And I will tell Madame Juvacola
That she can croak. That's it!
Do you realize that you are
you are ruining my life?
If I ruin your life, you are free
to take back your word.
And now, good night.
I need to work.
And alone!
So.
Aren't we done yet?
No.
And you don't say good night?
Good night.
I did not hear.
Good.
Here! No, to the right!
Bataillon!
Pay attention and follow along!
Aren't you up yet?
No, no, the box there and
the plant on the porch.
But what's going on?
How what happens.
Items are delivered.
When the utensils arrive
from the kitchen, Solange will clean everything.
Aren't you going to the workshop?
There is not much to do.
- Your breakfast, sir.
- Thank you.
Mom and dad are waiting for me.
If you want, meet me at 1:30?
I have to run.
I have a thousand things to do. Bye!
Hello.
Solange!
Sir?
Salt! So much salt!
Table salt?
Yes, table salt
And a kitchen scale.
All right, sir.
Someone will now take
will take a bath.
Here, sir.
Well thank you.
Is that all we have?
There is enough for a week.
You need to have a supply
of salt for at least a month!
What if we run out of it?
Come on, go get me some salt.
Find me the salt! Please!
Yes, sir.
Solange, what's going on?
Madam, the gentleman scolded me
about the salt. I run to bring it to him.
Enter.
Here, sir.
Ah, thank you. Thank you, you can go.
Solange! There is no water!
The plumbing system is
under repair, monsieur.
Ouch, what a house!
Maubru.
I need a large vessel.
Professor,
do you think I got a tan?
I want a big vessel!
This big?
As large as possible.
The biggest one has it
Mr. Bataillon.
Maubru.
Wish?
I... I was admiring the
his bath in the cistern.
It is neither a toilet nor a cistern!
This is the "Aquadinamometer
Bataillon model."
Would you like to lend it to me?
The experiment he interrupted
will last until 2 a.m.
Also, I don't lend my
Bataillon aquadynamometer to anyone
Until I have it patented.
And even after the patent,
I will not lend it to you!
Throw everything in the trash.
Too bad. They were beautiful.
25 cubic decimeters with 0.033 solution...
If the tank is larger, I will add
7.85 grams -- plus 10 cubes....
LE BISON BATHROOMS
It is strictly forbidden to introduce
into the tank products brought from home.
If you want bath salts,
he can purchase it at the checkout.
That's fine, I'll take it.
Made to order only.
Delivery in three weeks.
Hey! Taxi!
No jokes, huh?
Jerome,
swear that you will love me forever.
How should I know?
In that case,
how do you think I could trust it?
Trust who? Me?
No, about me.
If I'm not sure forever,
then what's the point of loving you today?
Perhaps to be happy.
Do you think it's easy to be happy?
It is very, very difficult.
Also particularly long.
I've been waiting for you for 30 hours.
But...!
30 hours! Maybe you are starving?
Why should I?
But 30 hours. 30 hours you haven't eaten.
Aren't you hungry?
No.
Yes, yes, yes, yes...
What is it? Do I look bad?
No, no.
Breathe. Breathe.
Breathe! Breathe deep!
You crush me.
Your hand.
Don't you like it?
I like it, I like it.
How do I look?
I don't know.
How does he look?
Good.
Are you going to x-ray me
next time?
Next time I will get you
the pressure before and after.
And tomorrow I will start drafting my
my communication to the Academy.
Back from class?
Yes,
"study of aquatic mammals."
Is this a joke?
No, I wouldn't dare.
I have responsibilities!
Therefore, I need to know...
...everything, miss?
18.30 - I leave the faculty,
8 p.m. - I have dinner with a childhood friend,
10 p.m. - Let's go to the movies.
Midnight, at her place.
At her house? Is she a girl?
And finally, today at noon
we were at the beach.
Monette. Where have you been?
Mr. Prade,
forget the white step!
I have to change.
Wait...!
Mr. Prade, the white step!
Excuse me, miss.
- Where are you coming from?
- Can't you see it?
- And before that?
- I had breakfast.
- Where? Were you alone?
- At the Grand Dukes'. I was not alone.
Ah, you were with him. The Don Juan
of the Amphitheater, the future Nobel laureate.
How about you? How is the beautiful Edith?
Who were you with at the end?
- With my uncle.
- What?
Yes, with my uncle.
Now leave me alone.
If you think I'm running after you ...
I don't think it, I see it.
To the two of us, I heard it all!
Perfect, are you spying on me now?
Not out here, come in.
You have no childhood friends or an uncle.
Confession.
I don't want to tell lies.
Then tell the truth.
No one has ever made my
my heart beat faster.
Is it that exciting?
Rockin'!
Good. I'm listening.
You're not going to tell anyone?
I never say anything.
Look, the day before yesterday, Juliette
told me, in secret,
that she was in love
with her Uncle Gilbert.
Did I tell you? No.
Then what?
Well, I love a man.
And he loves me.
We spent the night together.
We had breakfast in the countryside.
We took a bath.
We were soaked.
- I don't believe you, it's not possible.
- But it's true!
But if it is true, what is exciting about it?
Oh, Professor.
This dog barks day and night.
Mr. Bataillon threatens
to press charges.
Go and buy me
cigarettes before they close.
Good.
So.
Chief, where is the dog?
What dog?
So where did you spend the night?
With whom? It's not Jean-Loup.
A new one?
Did you ever tell me about him?
There may be reasons
why I never talked about it.
Is the police looking for him?
My story takes place
internationally.
International...?
International...
I got it!
It is about an atomic scientist
And the spies are trying
to steal his formulas.
Did you meet secretly...
And you changed your
clothes to throw them off!
You always understand everything, you.
Good evening.
Father called twice,
The Institute of Physiology three times,
Maubru relentlessly.
If you don't want to tell me where
you spend your days,
That's fine, but at least tell me what
I have to answer the phone, right?
This morning, as I was having
breakfast with my future mother-in-law,
I found the Yellow Pages open
under "Investigation and Surveillance."
She is doing the same as with her first husband,
from whom she obtained a divorce.
What do you suspect?
All of it!
In the lab...
He heard your voice the other night.
Yesterday, looking for salt throughout the
house, it did not have a natural air.
I disappeared for the whole day.
In the end, I suggested to her
to take back her word.
Did you?
Yes.
Within the framework of the arithmetic
Of the passions?
No, alas!
That was my mistake.
Do you still love her?
No, no...
But I have known her since she was a child.
It is his father who has
taught me everything.
When he got divorced,
she asked me to... console her...
I couldn't say no.
And does she love you?
No, Edith does not love me.
She loves marriage.
In every quarrel,
you take back your word.
But if I want to break up with her,
she refuses.
You don't know women.
Sorry to hear about your father....
I don't know either...
Go get me the cigarettes.
All right, if I'm in the way...
Care will have to be taken now.
Here it is impossible.
Well, in the city it will be even worse.
The students, the parents.
Not to mention my colleagues!
What if we don't do them?
What?
Transformations
in statue with N734.
It is out of the question!
After my report
to the Academy of Sciences,
The whole world will know about N734.
Then don't do it!
But think what benefits
N734 would bring to the world.
One million people
on the same plane.
No housing problems.
1,000, 2,000, 3,000 people
would sleep in one room.
The bathrooms will be
crowded the next morning!
Entire herds could
be sent in postal packages.
Entire nations could
be turned into toy soldiers,
If only they would put
N734 into the water pipes.
No, no, its use will be regulated
in international conferences.
Start regulating yourself.
That would be wonderful for us.
Suppose you go
to a conference abroad,
And that you take me with
you in your pocket.
Evening revive me.
The next morning, a good
cup of N734 for breakfast,
And poof!
I spend the day in your pocket.
But thinking about it, you could
turn into a statue yourself.
No, it is impossible.
Why not?
Because I can't afford
To disappear all night long.
Good. Then I will sacrifice myself.
Do you know who suffers when
you are in my pocket? Me.
- But how...?
- You will sleep-alive.
Yesterday I discovered what it means to .
to truly love.
When you part from a girl
whom one loves, one suffers to think that
someone hurts her,
invite her to dance
And she will start lying to him because
he begins to like her....
And when you're in my pockets,
it's much worse.
You are all mine.
Don't leave me, don't betray me.
You are so perfect.
But when you're not there.
My poor love!
It is good to see you in pain.
It also makes you more beautiful.
How can one resist?
All right, I will destroy the
draft of my report.
Oh, yes, yes, yes!
We find a deserted place.
A deserted place...
A deserted place?
The lapidary museum!
It is always empty there.
Me and my first love
kissed each other there.
It is evident.
Well, in the museum.
So on Friday, I will finish class
at 4:05 p.m. and at 4:20 p.m. I will be at the museum.
You will arrive 10 minutes early.
You will already be transformed.
Why first?
Because if he sees us
together a policeman, he will understand.
Perfect! You will find me behind the
fountain of St. Victor's Abbey.
This is a lapidary museum
and its archaeological garden,
contains artifacts from
from excavations in this region.
Here is the spiral column and the
fountain of the Abbey of San Vittore,
Near the walls of the ancient city.
Do not stray too far!
The Parisians entered through this door.
We are now going to see
a series of votive altars...
You will realize that we are no longer
in the realm of assumptions anymore.
So what do you infer from this?
He cheats on you with a girl
Who has a waistline of 50 centimeters.
50? It will be at least 60.
But that is not the question.
I would like to know when, how,
where and with whom he is seeing.
There is little that can be done.
There is only one way, make him follow.
Listen.
I found on the directory a small
"Eye of the Lynx" agency
which has as its specialty...
A knitted floral specialty...
Oh, honey!
Today is like my holiday.
Blue...  is its color.
Yes ... I see ... its color ... Yes.
I hope it's your size.
This will be fine.
Then see you soon, ma'am.
I'll be back later. Good evening.
That's it.
Jeanne! Jeanne!
Where are you? Where are you?
Oh my God, how scary!
A sinister man followed me
followed me all the way!
Look, this is no laughing matter.
You've lost all my stuff.
Edith took them.
My belt is
too big for her.
And my scarf is lost.
Ah, it's a tragedy!
It is true, though.
You know, if you're not going to be nice to me,
If you won't be nice to me,
I will go to an antique dealer I know.
He is very kind.
I will drink N734, he will sell me and
I will go around the world sleeping.
A century or two will pass,
I will end up in the sea - and poof!
And you will be far away.
All right, I promise:
next time I will take a
suitcase to put all your things in.
And we will change the meeting place.
I will transform at the first station
Of the buses. There is never anyone there.
What are you doing all alone?
Don't you have a mom? Huh?
Come on, go to your mom. Go!
Mirelle! Come and eat!
I am bathing
to my dolls!
Mom! Mom! My doll! Mom,
my doll! Where did she go?
Mom! Mom! Hurry! Mom,
hurry! Mom! My doll!
Your doll has nothing.
No, I dipped her and she
become a lady!
Come on!
There! My doll!
My doll!
Here she is, your doll!
Don't make me angry! Let's go!
Mom, an elephant!
There is no ele...
Who do you think
Stole this elephant?
What elephant?
Read.
Oh! He didn't tell me that!
Who.
Do you know who stole the elephant?
Uh, I have a suspicion.
You have to tell the police.
Are you crazy? Listen to me...
Do you love me? You don't want to put me
in the middle of this, do you?
You read too many spy books!
- Hello girls!
- Good morning...
- Shall we have a drink?
- I'm not thirsty.
- Strawberry ice cream?
- Yes! - No, I don't want to.
I have forgiven you,
why are you pouting?
I don't have to make it up to you and
I have no reason to be kind.
All right, I won't keep up with you.
I know,
you are too busy to forgive.
Here, look: real mobilization.
Stay here.
Why did you revive the elephant?
Me, no!
Look!
Ah, yes, I remember now.
It was when I was angry and I
told Maubru to throw everything away.
But all the drains
flows into the sea!
Busy as usual?
I think I know the young lady.
I will send you my notes by mail.
Good evening.
Good evening...
Why did you come looking for me?
On a whim. And then, Anne-Lise
Would like to have a conversation with you.
Just a little
business conversation.
Go with Anne-Lise,
we will see you at home.
Good luck!
Goodbye!
You are so interesting...
Interesting?
But if I didn't say anything.
Even when you don't say anything,
you are interesting.
Tell me all about yourself.
I thought you were interested in that
little girl, what's her name. Monette.
Monette? She is a little girl.
She doesn't understand me.
I am a dreamer.
A dreamer?
This is a bad thing. You will learn
That life is a war to be won.
Yes, my general!
But don't you ever take leave?
No.
Ah, I see. You are afraid that
your boyfriend will find me here.
He is talking business
with Anne-Lise.
It will keep him stuck
for at least two hours.
So?
Is it him?
No!
Telegram for Mr. Norman.
Hello.
Is it serious?
Come on, I'm bored!
I'LL BE WAITING FOR YOU AT THE HUNTING MUSEUM AT 6 O'CLOCK.
PROFESSOR ATOM
I feel lonely!
I am afraid!
Do you know Professor Atomo?
A professor, no.
I know a dog. Monette's dog.
Professor Atomo...
Professor Atom!
Stop it!
It's almost 6 o'clock, go home!
But it is now 5:35 p.m.!
No, no, no, no,
Jerome might come back. Go!
But you said it was stuck.
Women cannot be
reliance on women.
It is so true!
6 O'CLOCK HUNTING MUSEUM
NEAR THE RHINOS
I'M WAITING FOR YOU - THE COLDNESS OF THE
STONE IS A LEGEND. I BURN
Monette.
I should have guessed that.
Good evening Jerome.
Telegram for you.
Hello.
The hunting museum, please.
Yes, I would like to talk to the janitor.
What?
Will you only open at 8 a.m. tomorrow morning?
What about the cleaners?
Ah, they will not arrive until 6 o'clock....
Who do I ask if they find anything?
To the head of security?
Many thanks.
No, sir.
He was misinformed.
Contact the prefecture.
For lost items,
no earlier than 3 days.
No, sir, we don't deal with
these things. Just ask Section B.
He contacted the wrong office,
sir.
You need to make a complaint
to the police station.
If it's his professor, it changes everything.
I am reserved, very reserved!
Ah! Otherwise I would have
things to say about this girl!
He shows up once in a while.
He must have a double life.
When did you last see her?
Monday or Tuesday.
Four days ago.
It is becoming a habit.
Please call me when you come back.
Thank you. Good evening, ma'am.
Atomic espionage? Come, come!
Sit down and wait.
- Are you the atomic spy?
- Not me, my best friend.
Is he reporting it?
He is in mortal danger!
Professor Norman is
involved in this story.
Norman.
Commissioner, you should see the
guy I've been questioning for an hour.
- Who is he.
- A biology professor, Norman.
On the disappearance
Miss Landry.
It is a case without interest.
It is a simple escape.
I thought so, too.
But he looks so strange that
I wonder if he's not involved.
Okay.
Maybe. I wouldn't be surprised if
He had strangled the girl.
After the classic rape.
- Commissioner Andre.
- Jerome Norman.
She knows my son. He is following
his course... Francois Andre.
Curly blondie.
His father's portrait.
Ah, yes, yes, yes...
I heard about yesterday's misunderstanding,
a mistake for which I wanted to
apologize in person.
Don't worry.
After all, we are almost colleagues.
We both do research.
This case...
is of no interest.
The girl must be living the perfect
romance with a rogue
Or she will be found in a few
days in a ditch, torn to pieces.
The police find out everything.
Do you feel ill?
So, professor...?
No, no, excuse me,
it's hot in here.
But he is trembling.
But no, no, not at all.
I'll take care of it.
Julien, go get some cognac.
No, no, no, you are very kind.
But I am better now, thank you!
Commissioner, you told me that the
police always find out everything, right?
Everything. Are you looking for something?
Yes, Monette. She is my assistant,
Ms. Landry.
Commissioner, I ask you to find it!
Was she a collaborator
so valuable?
Please, Commissioner,
don't talk about her in the past tense.
I -- I love her so much.
I thought I had
read the other day
the announcement of his marriage
to another person.
Yes but it is Miss.
Monette Landry that I'm going to marry.
I asked my fiancée
to dissolve the promise.
Did she refuse?
Yes. In order not to quarrel
With his family,
I stopped living with
them and decided to wait
the first opportunity that would
advantage with my fiancée.
He has a very violent character.
At this time he had
clandestine meetings...
- ...with Ms. Landry?
- Yes.
In short, he is insinuating
That his fiancée might have
have made her rival disappear?
Not at all!
Then it is you who killed her!
Let's face it.
She had a lover who was pushing her to marry her.
His fiancée
threatened a scandal,
he felt obliged
by his parents,
Therefore, he killed the girl.
But-but-but it's not true!
Then explain this disappearance!
I -- I can't.
When did you last see
Miss Landry the last time?
4 a.m. Monday at the university.
What did he do next?
I had a business interview
with a friend of my girlfriend's.
What time was it?
Eh... 5 p.m.
What's next?
- I went back to the lab afterwards.
- Did anyone see her?
No, the lab assistant
finished work at 6 p.m.
In short, he has no
alibi between 5 p.m. and 8 p.m.
Let's continue!
Since he does not want to help us,
I am obliged despite myself
To put her under arrest.
Do you have anything to say?
Can I notify the dean?
Here it is.
Hello. I would like to speak to
Dean Geran, please.
Yes, who is this?
Is that you, Edith?
Yes, where are you, honey?
I'm not going home tonight.
They arrested me.
Arrested? Why?
I am accused of the
disappearance of my assistant.
Stay where you are. Coming.
How-what do you mean come? Edith.
Good morning, Mr. Commissioner.
Edith Geran, the girlfriend.
Oh, my poor darling.
I did it as fast as I could.
Oh, very nice! What is it?
Ashtray.
The murder weapon.
Fascinating.
Well, so do I, Commissioner,
I have something to tell you,
which will thrill you.
To make a long story short, my darling,
the commissioner accuses you
Of a childish tryst
between you and your assistant.
Look, Edith, this is not the time.
I have come to provide them,
Mr. Commissioner,
proof that my fiancé is
innocent of the crime he is accused of.
This is because of a little thing
that can be found here. Here it is.
Here is the result of
a small survey.
I like the certainty. I had some
doubts, and I realized that between certainty
and doubts there is a difference
of 3,000 francs per day.
Those 3,000 francs demanded
by the agency Eye of the Lynx,
of your colleagues, Mr.
Commissioner, to supervise someone.
From 4 p.m. June 25
the agency Eye of the Lynx
watches over my fiancé.
From these papers I will read you an
excerpt from their first report.
On June 25 at 4 p.m., Prof.
Norman was joined
by our client who met him
met him in the university courtyard.
After a very brief conversation
with a young blonde woman,
takes a cab, which takes him
takes him to the research laboratory.
After realizing that there is no
there is no other way to leave the premises,
We lurk in front of the door.
Afterwards, the professor leaves to go to
his house, where he stays all evening.
The reading of these
documents is tedious.
You can read them yourself,
commissioner.
He will observe that as of
4 p.m. June 25,
When Miss, what's her name,
Monette was still alive,
My fiancé never saw her again.
Consequently, he did not rape her,
did not kidnap her, did not kill her.
That's it.
Commissioner, we found
a rhinoceros in the old harbor!
How did you know
that June 26 was
the day of my last
meeting with Monette?
Because the report mentioned it.
And did you continue to spy on me, knowing
That I had never seen you again?
I was too amused
to read that you visited
the police station,
the lost and found, the antique dealer!
Perfect!
Is this your thanks
For getting you out of prison!
I was wondering how long it would take you
to think about the ads.
"Big reward to the person who finds
the figurine of a naked woman..."
Then do you know?
Honey, you have no secrets from me.
I should have figured it out.
You were the one who took it.
Where is it!
Let go of me! You're hurting me!
Where is it?
I took it to the bank!
Then let's go there now! Now!
It is too late. The banks are
already closed. And listen carefully...
I will never give you back that
statuette. Do you hear me? Never!
You are committing a crime.
Oh, yeah? And where is the body?
You are stealing a girl's life!
She stole my fiancé!
I will give her back her life when
I get my fiancé back.
Ah, all right...
Come on, dictate your terms.
First, we will get away
from this little charmer.
Anne-lise and her husband invited us
to spend the vacations in America.
And what are we going to do there?
We are going to get married.
On our return,
we will move to Paris.
How, and why?
We will work together at Juvacola.
I will become an advertising executive.
After one year, hopefully,
I will send the figurine to mom with
your CPR instructions.
And... what if I refuse?
I am the mistress of the situation.
In that case, I would leave.
And your figurine...
Good. I accept.
Here it is...
I finally recognize you.
This girl has had
a hateful influence on you.
You know, I was so sure
to bring you back into the fold
that I have prepared a
bottle of champagne.
I am glad that
you said yes.
It would have been very unpleasant to do
what I had decided to do.
What had you decided?
The moment my
ship had left port,
I would have thrown the figurine into the sea.
To us!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9...
Where are the others?
What others?
Two dark bags
and the three black suitcases.
The gentleman's? The gentleman
took them back five minutes ago.
Isn't he going with you?
It is not possible!
Do you have my bag, Mom?
Yes, but I don't understand it.
You don't have to understand.
If Jerome wants to take it from you, don't
let him do so for any reason.
Ah...
I'm not leaving.
I have changed my mind.
But my dear, everything has been arranged
For your departure. You are expected!
And then you signed a contract.
Edith did it.
She signed the contract.
My husband will sue you! You have
making fun of us! Raymond! Raymond!
Do you know what you are doing? As soon as we
we set sail, the statuette will go overboard.
I don't like to travel.
And you won't, you wouldn't dare to throw it
Into this terrible salt sea.
We shall see!
I bet not.
And I bet it does.
You break my heart.
I love to do that.
Edith, give it back to me.
No!
Don't you have anything else to say?
Have you thought it through?
Perfect!
My bag...
Haven't you changed your mind?
Quick! Follow that ship!
But he goes to America.
I'll stop you first.
Drop it!
Let it fall! Let it fall! Let it fall!
Allow me, miss!
Thank you. But aren't you Alberic
Cahuzac? But yes, I recognize her!
Oh, you were at my conference?
Of course. I subscribe to all
Alliance Française events.
Aren't we going too far?
Go ahead. I will give you double.
I was afraid that the topic
was a little difficult
for ears
so fascinating.
But no!
"The influence of epic myth
on Roman literature."
Nothing more interesting.
But what does it do!
Faster! Faster!
Hey, hey, if we continue,
I will break my engine.
Will you allow me to look at it?
It is a lovely object.
One could fall in love
with this little object.
No, no, it's not a big deal.
Wait, wait...
- Oh no!
- I am desolated!
Finally!
Do you often schedule
appointments on the high seas?
This is the first and last time.
Translated from French audio by ErTenebra