* spoke to me
* I can't believe it,
but she spoke to me *
I'm Josh.
How are you
this evening?
* close to me
* I never thought
I'd get her close to me *
[Woman]
Don't be shy. All
my friends are...
* now the moon and the sun
belong to me *
* all my wildest hopes,
my crazy dreams *
[Man]
They seem more
like reality.
* fantasy
* this girl fulfills
my every fantasy *
Loving from a man.
* she must be
* specially designed
by heaven just for me *
* just for me
* friends that gather,
they see mystery *
* I look at her,
and I see a masterpiece *
* she spoke to me
* I can't believe it,
but she spoke to me *
* spoke to me
* I can't believe it,
but she spoke to me *
* if she hurts me
* I'll take it all
with open arms, you see *
* 'cause like a track
under a subway train *
* she could roll
all over me *
* and I'd still
feel the same *
* 'cause today is the day
she spoke to me *
* I can't believe it,
but she spoke to me *
* close to me
* I never thought
I'd get her close to me *
[Woman]
I'm stuck in some
groovy wet dream.
* ooh ooh
[Man]
I'm digging the scene.
* yeah, baby
[Woman whispering]
Oh, yeah.
That was so nice.
* 1, 2
* 1, 2, 3, unh
[Man]
O.K., begin.
The only reason I have
consented to doing this
Is because I wish
to clear to my name.
Not that I care
what people think,
But enough is enough.
Hold on.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hold on a minute.
Yeah, well, can I finish
my monologue, please?
We're looking for
the latest and the hottest.
O.K.?
You know, we're looking for
the beauty of Halle Berry,
The sexiness
of jada pinkett,
The... the soaring voice
of Whitney.
Can you sing?
Yes, I can.
Don't talk.
Listen.
O.K.
We're looking for the range
of Angela bassett.
We're looking
for the total game.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
O.K. This thing... this movie
is going to be big.
Bigger than big.
Huge.
The greatest romantic
African-American film
ever made,
Directed by me,
of course,
Told from
the point of view
Of an African-American
woman.
We got Denzel, Wesley,
fish.
They're all signed up
to play supporting roles.
What we need...
What are you
looking at?
Because when you said
their names as supporting...
Don't talk.
Listen.
O.K.
Now, this total package
that I'm looking for,
We know... i know...
She's out there.
And I'll know her
when I see her.
Now you can talk.
Thank you.
Ooh, let's see,
where do I start?
Um...
I've been studying
for several years.
I went to nyu.
Mm-hmm.
Done a little off-Broadway,
A little episodic
television.
I can sing,
I can dance,
And I can act,
so if you pick me,
You can't go wrong.
Let me stop being shy.
I just need a break.
A break. That's
what I need, a break.
So, if you let me
finish my monologue,
Then I can do the sides...
Not now.
But I'd read
the sides after.
First things first.
Um, stand up.
Okey-dokey.
O.K.
Hug the camera.
I want you
to turn around.
Uh, wrong way.
Oops. Sorry.
Yeah. That's it.
Slowly.
And slowly.
Keep it turning.
The person we're looking for
needs to ooze sexuality.
Very good.
Bravo, bravo.
You may sit
right back down.
All right.
O.K., now if you would just,
uh, unbutton your blouse
So we can see
your breasts.
What?
Could you unbutton
your blouse
So we can see
your breasts?
Is that required
of the role?
I mean, nobody told me
I was going to have
to take my top off.
Didn't Murray
tell you that?
No, he did not
tell me that.
Well, he fuckin'
should've.
O.K., look.
This is kind
of embarrassing.
O.K., um...
Yes, it's required
of the role.
It's a major part
All right, and, uh...
We're not trying
to be weird here,
But we're just
professionals.
Hey, you know what?
I have a picture.
I can go get it
At the house
and bring it back...
This topless
little number...
Whoa. Hold it.
Whoa, whoa.
We got 75 fuckin'
other girls to see
here, o.K.?
I'm sorry.
I don't mean
to be abusive,
But what's it
going to be?
Can you do it or not?
Come on, honey.
We don't have time.
Just take
your clothes off.
All right, all right.
It's cool. It's cool.
Everything's cool.
* they turn me on
* I don't care
where we go *
Yeah.
* I don't care
what we do *
Yeah, that's it.
* I don't care
That's great.
* just take me with you
O.K. Now, freeze.
Don't move.
Don't talk.
I can't do this.
You can't do this?
You can't do what?
What the hell's
going on here?
What is happening?
[Assistant]
I'm sorry.
I mean, where do you
find these girls?
Hey, look, come here.
Aw, shit!
* I don't care
where we go *
what we do *
Let her go!
Bring the next actress
in here.
She better fucking know
what she is getting into.
Then get me
a fucking cup of coffee!
What in the fuck
is your problem?
Why didn't you
tell me?
If I would've told you,
you would've never went.
How did it go,
knock 'em dead?
I have never
been so humiliated
in all my life!
Cut the sturm and drang.
You want to be
an actress, a star,
you showed them your tits!
So what!
Big fucking deal,
all right?
Sharon stone
spread her legs,
And look what happened.
When I saw that,
I said to myself,
"that's a star."
He didn't ask you
to have intercourse
with him, did he?
No.
Did you get the part?
I walked out.
You walked out on qt?
The hottest director
in Hollywood.
I get you seen by qt,
And you bolt!
[Inhales]
You know, maybe you and me
should go in another
direction.
Maybe somebody
could do better by you.
Listen, the money
that you owe me,
keep it, all right?
This is too much
aggravation.
You know, with my asthma
and everything like that,
it's not working out.
It's not worth it
for me, o.K.?
You're absolutely right.
It's not working out,
But that money
that I owe you, I'm
going to pay you back.
You better pay me back.
Let me tell you something.
I respect you.
You're a beautiful person.
You're talented.
I wish you well, o.K.?
Peace. Out. O.K., bye.
Talk to you later.
Who's on the phone?
Who's on the line?
Qt. Qt! Q! Q!
Free computer seminars!
Learn how to work a computer
in just two short hours.
Would you like a computer
seminar survey, sir?
Thank you so much,
Ma'am?
Excuse me.
Computer seminar?
Thank you so much.
Learn how to work a computer
in just two short hours.
Thank you.
Man of the future.
[Rock music plays]
The only reason...
I've consented
to doing this...
Is because I wish
to clear my name.
Oy, God.
Oy oy oy,
oy oy oy oy.
What?
Oh, God.
What do you mean what?
Where is the pain?
[Mocking her delivery]
Come on!
It needs a bottom!
Where's the bottom?
What's this shallow shit?
A bottom!
I can't think.
Aah!
Drop into the pain!
Drop...
Into...
The pain.
Drop into the pain.
I can't think straight.
Acting is about doing
and feelings!
Drop into the pain!
Now...
Let's add a sensorial
element of shit.
The pain stinks.
Ooh, it stinks.
It stinks.
Smell it.
There you go.
Now, right through there...
Right through there,
speak.
The only reason...
[Mocking]
The only reason.
The only reason,
the only reason!
Look.
Look, nothing!
I went to an interview,
big Hollywood interview,
And this
asshole tells me
to take off my shirt.
So what!
So...
What!
Grow up!
Grow up now!
What are you
talking about?
I'm talking about
you growing up.
I'm talking about you
facing the reality
of this business!
Which is?
Which is...
Taking off your top,
baby.
That has nothing
to do with the work.
You've taught me
about the work.
It has plenty
to do with the work.
That's the business,
honeybunch.
Make it art!
Turn it into
something special!
Do you get it?
Yes, I get it.
You get it?
Yes.
So are we going
to grow up?
Yes, we are.
Oh, we are?
Well, I'm going to
help you grow up.
Now, if you would pay me,
You would show
that you have respect
for your art form.
I'm working three
and four jobs
to pay...
Working three
and four jobs for what?
To pay you.
Oh, to pay me.
Yes.
I have to tell you,
I can no longer
carry you.
That's it.
That's all I have to say.
I'm not going to say
another word.
That's it.
Finish.
Complete.
Over. Grow up.
O.K.
Respect your art.
Learn to respect
your art.
O.K. I will.
I hope you do.
Would you like a flyer?
Right now I don't
have the time.
Computer seminar?
How you doing?
I'm fine, thank you.
Tired as all hell,
but I'm fine.
Computer seminar?
Would you...
I'm with them
already.
Computer seminar?
Sure, why not?
Thank you, sir.
Talk with
the beautiful lady.
Thank you.
Why you give me
a different color?
I'm sorry.
Would you like yellow?
No. It's o.K.
Excuse me, sir.
Would you be interested
in comput...
I'll take it.
All right, people,
It's 90 motherfucking
degrees out here!
So please don't act
like it's cold.
Now, my director
is not happy
With the background action!
That means I'm not
motherfucking happy!
So if I see anybody
that looks like they cold,
I'm sending your motherfucking
monkey ass home!
And you know
what that means.
No check!
What's wrong with you,
little lady?
May I use
the ladies' room, please?
Excuse me?
I have to use it bad.
I really have to go.
Please?
No, you can't use
the bathroom.
No breaks.
We're ready to shoot.
And I don't give
a fuck about s.A.G.
Motherfuck the s.A.G.
Rep.
You can pee when I say
you can pee. Capisce?
Yes, sir.
All right, people,
turn your monkey ass
around!
* housequake, there's
a brand-new groove
goin' round *
* housequake
* in your funky town
* and the kick drum
is the fault *
* you gotta rock
this mother, say uh *
* uh
* you gotta rock
this mother, say uh *
* say uh
* we're gonna show you
what to do *
* you put your foot down
on the two *
* you jump up on the one
* now you're having fun
* you're doin'
* the housequake
* question
* does anybody know
about the quake? *
* bullshit
* you can't get on
* until you make
the house shake *
* now everybody clap
your hands, come on *
* let's jam, y'all
* let's jam
* don't wait
for your neighbor *
* green eggs and ham
* doing the housequake
* there's a brand-new groove
goin' round *
* in your city,
in your town *
* housequake
* and the kick drum
is the fault *
* housequake
* you gotta rock
this mother *
* housequake
Hey there, sexy,
You've just reached
The hottest
live talk line around...
970-wow!
Where the talk
is always hot and cheap.
The cost of this call
is $1.95 a minute,
Plus a $5.00 connection fee.
Specialty calls
are priced accordingly.
Hi. I'm here
for an appointment.
[Woman]
If you don't want
to play with me...
That's o.K.
Or you're under the age
of 18, please hang up now,
But if you're ready,
willing, and able,
Stay on the line
And get your hands on
the fantasy girl
of your dreams.
Hi. Have you
called here before?
Can I have
your name?
The next time
you call in,
All you need
is your phone number
and four-digit i.D.
Excuse me.
I'm here...
All right. I'm going
to hook you up
To one of our
lovely ladies now.
O.K. Hold the line.
I'm sorry.
Uh, I have
an appointment,
And I don't know
which direction to...
Oh, I'll take you.
Come on.
Lil?
Hmm?
Your appointment's here.
[Woman]
Bend over!
Hi. Come on in
and sit down, baby.
How you doing?
I'm just fine,
thank you.
How you doing?
I'm good.
I hear this is a place
Where a girl can make
lots of cash.
You over 18?
Of course I am.
A young voice.
That's good.
You're not local.
I'm from queens,
born and raised.
And you're an actress?
[Laughing]
Yes, ma'am,
I'm an actress.
It's good work,
when I can find it.
"That falling feeling."
Hmm.
How many letters
is it?
Seven.
That falling feeling.
Um...
That's vertigo.
All right.
That works.
You like men?
Yes, I love men.
My luck's for shit
with them,
But I love them.
So I said to myself,
If you can't get it
in real life,
You might as well
get it on the job.
Right?
Right.
You're a dominatrix.
Dominatrix?
Dominatrix.
Finish it.
Uh...
I would probably
have...
Blond hair.
Long blond hair,
Uh...
38 cs...
Yeah, I'd have some
nice, healthy jugs
With big,
perky nipples.
There.
All right. Come on.
That's good.
Very good.
Can't promise you
anything,
But I'll put in
a good word, o.K.?
Yes.
Keep your fingers
crossed.
Thank you.
All right.
Speak into this.
What do you want me
to say?
A fantasy chat.
Go ahead.
The tape is rolling.
O.K.
Um...
Hi there.
I'm so happy
that you called.
Um, what's your name?
Mike! Oh, hi, Mike.
Do you want to play?
That's great.
Thanks.
Yeah, yeah. We'll
give this a listen
And let
you know, huh?
Are you interested
in any peep show
stuff?
Peep show?
You sex them up
on the phone.
Here's your coffee.
Yeah, thanks.
Good luck, honey.
They get to watch you
jiggle.
I mean, there's no
physical contact
whatsoever.
Mm-hmm.
There's a little, uh,
a little nudity.
But the money's
a lot better.
Listen. Believe me
when I tell you
something.
This is nice,
clean work.
No, thank you.
No. No.
You ever married?
Yeah, uh, but it's over.
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, no, really.
You don't have
to be sorry.
See, he was
a kleptomaniac.
On top of that,
he was weird,
But I don't want
to talk about that.
Any experience?
No experience,
right?
Right.
We have
a training session.
We could
show you the ropes.
I mean,
it's not a problem.
We're going to be seeing
a lot of ladies.
I don't think
that this is for me,
This kind of stuff.
The peep show thing.
All right, all right.
Suit yourself.
Something comes up,
I'll give you a ring.
O.K.
Nice meeting you.
Take care.
So you, um,
you own this place?
Yeah.
You like it?
Oh, yes, it's...
It's lovely.
So, every girl
works a shift.
You've got three shifts
to choose from.
You choose the one
that suits you best.
Some shifts are busier
than others.
You get paid
by the call.
Bonus if a guy
requests you.
Can I hold your puppy.
Hi, little pup-pup.
Guys call us up,
and they tell us
what they want.
You dig?
I dig.
Toilet training,
bestiality,
Foot fetishes,
butt plugs,
Bisexuality, three-ways,
five-ways, six-ways,
Yadda yadda yadda.
The mistress-slave routine.
¿Comprende?
Comprende.
You know what?
I can do this.
Mm-hmm.
I can see myself
just working it.
Can I ask you
a personal question?
Sure.
Is your clit pierced?
Nope. Nope.
Ah, never mind.
Anyway, shitting's
really big right now.
Don't ask me why.
Could be the stock market.
I don't know.
They pay by charge card.
They call us, we call you,
you call them,
And you chat until...
They come.
It can get a little
freaky sometimes.
If a girl's at home,
You know,
anything goes.
Not like the office girls.
This is the hot spot.
Could we back up
for a minute?
You said at home?
I call
from my house?
Collect.
Is that a problem?
Currently, i... i
share a phone.
It's a hall phone.
But you know what?
I'm thinking...
This home stuff,
It's, um...
It'll be too heavy
for starting out.
I think
I need something
a little smoother.
I...
Right... Well,
the hall phone
would be a problem.
Listen. I'm going
to give you one of my cards,
And I want you
to give me a call
When you get
a private line.
And some cojones.
Listen, you got
good pipes.
Cantaloupes.
Pears.
Oranges.
Granny smiths.
What else?
Oh, now.
Red delicious.
We haven't had red
delicious in a while.
Ain't that pretty?
Yeah.
Stealing
is wrong, right?
Shh.
Hey, where'd
you get...
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Where you go!
Hey!
Stop!
You go stop him!
[Car horn honks]
[Tires screech]
Stop him!
[Ring]
I got it!
Hello.
Uh, yeah.
Hold the line, o.K.?
Jimmy.
What?
Telephone!
Hello.
[Asian accent]
Jimmy no live here.
So how's
business going?
Business
is kind of slow,
But see this card
right here?
I see it.
In 20 years
it'll be worth
A thousand times
what it goes for now.
I got 2,000 of them.
It's better than stocks.
Really?
All you do
is wait 20 years?
I'll be
a multimillionaire.
in a position
to lend you money.
And in the meantime?
I'm a broke
motherfucker.
Shit.
Me and you, both.
So what's happening
with your callbacks?
I need you
to come over later
And help me do something.
Right, right, right.
Change the subject
as usual.
I'm just asking
a simple question.
You can say
yes or no.
Yes or no.
So, you and him
ever thinking about
getting back together?
Nope. Hair.
I told you once
if I told you
a thousand times,
I don't like him.
He didn't
do me right,
treat me right.
There you go.
Hair.
Thank you.
What you've got to do
is hold the back
So we get it on right.
Pull it down.
There you go.
There it is.
Oh, it's a trip
having to pound
the pavement again
Getting this job,
But so far
everybody's
been great.
Somebody's
got to hire me, huh?
I hope so.
The money's good,
so I figure
I'll be out of here
four months, Max.
Are you going to let me
tighten you up?
Good money
if you're good,
And I'm going to
be great.
Eyes.
Thank you.
Can I just
tighten you up?
Oh, please, Jimmy.
Know what?
Huh?
You ought to get back
with your ex
And let him
rob you a bank.
That's not funny.
It's funny to me.
He stole my heart,
Jimmy.
Steal it back.
Mouth.
Can I ask you a favor?
Uh-huh.
[Imitating landlord]
You must pay rent.
But I don't have the rent.
Who is this?
Dorothy dandridge.
You know what,
Jimmy?
What's that?
I'm sorry,
but I ain't got it.
Why don't you sell
some of your rare
autographs?
You can't hook me up?
You don't have
the money?
And now,
for my first role.
Dorothy dandridge
in Carmen Jones.
I'll pay you back.
It's a damn good
dandridge, isn't it?
Blow on 'em, sugar.
Makes 'em dry faster.
You can turn off
the heat now.
You're some
harmonica player.
Where you going now?
You just went
for a walk.
I'm not some bird
in a cage.
I don't like
being cooped up.
Carmen,
I don't like it
When you leave me
alone.
Hey, there, army boy.
Zip me up.
You ain't going
nowhere.
You're staying here
where you belong,
with me.
Maybe you ain't got
the message yet.
Carmen's one gal
nobody puts on a leash.
No man's going to tell me
when to come and go.
I got to be free,
or I don't stay at all.
You'll never get
away from me.
I'll follow you
down the river
and across the sea,
To hell
or up to heaven.
[Train passing]
'Cause it's not
just sex, o.K.?
You're their friend.
They're lonely,
they're divorced,
Their wives aren't into
what they're into.
They may be giants
in the corporate world
Who are cross-dressers.
Ooh.
Cross-dresser.
Girl 19.
That's a man
who likes women's
clothing for himself.
Or vice-versa.
Cross-dressers
in their private lives,
Giants in
the corporate world.
You are the ones...
Who listen.
Got to listen. Yes?
You're the one
who appreciates them.
You're the ones
who doesn't judge them.
You want them
to like you, ladies,
'Cause if they like you,
they call back.
If they call back a lot...
You make
lots of cash.
Hey.
Yeah.
Girl 6.
Yes.
Who's your transsexual?
My transsexual
is, um...
Esmerelda.
Whopper dick.
Uh, always ready
to please.
Dark hair.
Light green eyes.
Pre-op.
What's that?
It's before
the surgery.
And my mistress...
I don't know
who my mistress
is going to be yet.
I think
I'll call her
April, maybe.
Sweet?
And my girl
next door...
Well, my girl
next door is
going to be lovely.
Wait a second.
Lovely?
Yes, darling.
Lovely brown.
That's cute.
Thank you.
What's lovely like?
Lovely's got dark
hair, dark eyes.
She's hot, but
she's kind of shy.
Kind of freaky.
You know the type.
I don't know
what you're
talking about.
Oh, yeah.
Big freak.
All right, ladies,
unless they request,
All of you girls are...
Huh? That's the deal.
Additional characters
can include black girls,
Puerto rican girls,
Asian girls...
The whole
ethnic gamut. Huh?
Also foreign girls.
French and English accents,
Et cetera, et cetera,
et cetera.
Girl 75.
You got a call
coming in
on line 17.
Monitor tells you
it's a domination
fantasy.
Yes? All right.
I want you
to pick up
and listen.
Hello. This is
mistress Marlene.
I heard you've been
a naughty boy.
Now pull down your pants
and bend over my knees.
You're going to
get spanked.
Yes. One spank
for touching my panties,
Two spanks for
putting your fingers
near my clitoris,
And three spanks
for putting your fingers
deep into my love hole.
Oh, yes. One more spank.
The ultra-spank
for letting your dick drip.
Didn't I tell you
not to let your dick drip?
Now stand up and thank me
for punishing you.
Dick drip.
Very good, 75.
I think a dick drip
is a good way
to end the day.
What do you think?
All right,
ladies, listen.
This job can be
a lot of fun.
You can make
a lot of money,
And you're safe here.
Very safe.
All right.
See you all tomorrow.
Bye.
Lil, the boss, o.K.?
I'm a telecommunications
sales representative.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm girl 75.
I'm girl 12.
Hol a. Girl 4.
Telecommunications
sales representative.
I'm girl 29.
I'm girl 39,
Better known as
black mistress Tina.
Girl 19.
I'm a telecommunications
sales representative.
4-2.
Girl 58.
Hi there. 6 is for sex.
[Moaning]
Oh, yeah, baby.
Girl 6.
Hello.
It's just me.
Something
will come up
in a minute.
We're going to
start you off
slow.
Nothing
too wild.
O.K.
First call's
like a first date.
Just be yourself.
O.K.
I'll keep it simple.
I'll send you
someone fabulous.
Thank you.
Hello.
Hello there.
Anybody home?
Hi there.
How are you doing
this evening?
Horny. Thought
I'd lost you.
Ha. No.
I'm right here,
baby, um,
Where you calling
from this...
to-tonight?
Houston. Houston, Texas.
Oh, my God. It's hot
down there, huh?
Yes, ma'am, it is.
Hot and sticky.
What's your name?
Lovely.
Oh.
What's yours?
Steve. What do you
look like?
Oh, um, I've got
dark hair...
Uh-huh.
And, uh,
dark eyes...
Yeah.
And I have a really
great figure.
Oh, you got big ones,
don't you?
Oh, yeah.
I've got 38 ds...
Double-d.
Don't you be fibbing now.
I was hoping you had 'em,
'cause I like big tits.
Big like Texas.
Like hakeem olajuwon.
Well, I've got these
big silver-dollar nipples...
Uh-huh.
And they're
really sensitive.
I have a 25-inch
waist
And, uh,
35-inch hips...
And, oh, yeah,
Stephen,
I have
a deep throat.
Hot damn,
you're perfect.
You know
what I did today?
No. What?
I made a million dollars.
How'd you do that?
I bought a little
nice old lot.
And you made
a million dollars?
Yes, ma'am.
That sounds
really complicated.
Well, I will
explain it to you.
Say company "a"
is a hammer.
And company "b"
is a diamond,
Say a big, hard, pricey rock.
Now, I take company "a,"
And I smash company "b."
Ooh.
Oh, and I take all them
little diamond chips,
And I sell them
at a jacked-up price.
Wow.
And viola, señorita,
I got one million dineros.
Ooh, I'm getting
excited
Just thinking
about it.
I bet I could hump you
any time I wanted to,
couldn't I?
Ooh, yes,
you could, baby,
'Cause I'm
always horny.
I would really
like that.
Yes, ma'am.
I bet you would.
Are you single?
No, ma'am.
I'm married.
Mmm, well, uh,
does your wife know
you're calling me?
No, ma'am.
She does not.
Are you single?
Yes.
Well, then you can do
anything you want to.
On, no. I...
I'm jealous.
I'm only here
for you, Stephen.
Chow time.
Shh. Get me
a flower, Ron.
One of the corsages
out of the fridge.
The food's
going to get cold.
We'll be there.
[Muttering in spanish]
I want you to jiggle
them big teats for me.
Oh, are you nice
and hard for me?
Yes, ma'am, I am.
Are you touching
yourself?
Yes, ma'am, I am.
O.K., so now
I'll tell you.
I've got, uh,
a tight white
t-shirt on.
Uh-huh.
And a little
white skirt.
Would you
jiggle them titties
up and down for me?
O.K.
Bounce them
up and down for me.
O.K., I'm bouncing,
Stephen.
Oh, yeah.
I'm bouncing
right now, Stephen.
I'm on your lap,
And I'm bouncing
my titties
up and down.
These teats
are moving up
and down, Stephen.
Ohh, ohh!
Oooohh!
Ahhhhhh!
Oh, you are a gift
on this earth.
Ah-ha, thanks, honey.
[Hangs up phone]
Girl 6.
Congratulations.
Thank you. I mean,
he just came.
His name was Stephen,
and he just... ahh!
He hung up happy.
Good job.
Now how you feel?
Fine. My mouth's
a little...
All right, here.
Have some soda.
All right.
Now, miss girl 6,
We have for you...
Voila.
Ohh.
You broke your cherry.
All right, all right.
Come on, y'all.
Back to work.
There we go.
Congratulations, baby.
He came.
[Woman]
Oh, yes, Dr. farber.
I love it
when you put me
in those stirrups
And examine me
with your speculum.
Oh, yes.
[Woman]
Big girl, big pussy.
Slim girl, all pussy.
[Beeping]
Hi there.
I'm so glad
you called.
I'm calling from
my beach house,
housewife.
Let's start
in the kitchen.
There's whipped cream
in the refrigerator.
I've been
on my feet all day,
And now I'm on
my hands and knees
Cleaning
the kitchen floor.
I sure would like
to take a break
So I can talk to you.
You're scrubbing
the floor?
Mm-hmm.
Don't stop
scrubbing.
If you don't mind,
we'll talk while you work.
I'm making slow,
soapy circles
On the linoleum
with my scrub brush.
What color's
the linoleum?
Yellow.
It's yellow
with little daisies.
Slow, soapy circles
On my hands and knees.
Where are your kids?
They're taking their naps.
I'm pushing
your dress up
from behind.
I'm going to
mount you
Snoopy-doggy-
dog-style,
housewife.
Ohh.
Don't stop
scrubbing.
Uh-uh.
I'm mounting you
now, housewife.
Got a lot of work
to do.
Don't stop
scrubbing.
[Moaning]
Don't stop
scrubbing.
A woman's work
is never done.
Oh, you're so right.
I hate that grimy buildup.
With no bra on,
you know?
I go shopping
at the a&p like that.
I'd be the
stock boy,
And I would grab
your p-p-produce.
Mm-hmm.
I went shopping
yesterday.
What did you buy?
Soup.
Asparagus...
Oyster crackers,
you know?
For the soup.
Did you get
lamb chops?
With mint jelly.
[Panting]
Beverages.
Arugula...
[Panting]
Dip...
Instant oatmeal.
Whew,
instant oatmeal?
Quick grits.
Quick... quick
grits?
Popcorn.
P-p-p-popcorn?
[Moaning]
Thank you.
Hello.
Hi.
Who am I
speaking with?
This is lovely.
Lesley?
Mm-hmm.
Wait. Lesley
or lovely.
Lovely.
Hi, lovely.
Hi.
My name is Bob.
Bob?
Yeah.
Where you calling
from, Bob?
I'm calling
from Tucson.
Tucson?
You know where that is?
Yeah. Is it, uh...
what's it like
down there?
Dry heat.
Dry heat. Mmm.
I was just, um,
wondering if,
You know, is, uh
is... is there a rule,
Like, does it
have to be a sex talk?
Oh, no, no, no, Bob.
It's whatever
you like.
We can talk
about anything.
We can talk...
Anything?
Anything.
I'm here for you.
Feeling like talking
about my mother, actually.
What's your
mother's name?
My mom, uh,
her name is Ruth.
Ruth?
And, uh, the thing...
My mother's dying of...
She's dying of cancer now,
And, uh, I just
wanted to hear...
I wanted to say that
to hear how that sounded.
Is your mother alive still?
Yes, she is.
Do you tell her
that you love her?
Yeah. I tell her
I love her.
I never, um, I never use
those words with my parents.
That's the thing.
I never said
"I love you" to her,
And I'm agonizing now.
What do you think?
Well, you know, Bob,
life is about
choices,
And I think that
whatever choice
you decide to make
Will be
the right choice.
I'm out here,
and I'm thinking,
And I just, uh,
I just really
needed to talk,
And I'm glad...
I'm really glad that, uh,
That I dialed
your number.
I'm glad you dialed
my number as well.
You doing all right?
I got my first
request tonight.
Yeah? Congratulations.
I'm sure it won't
be your last.
You need to give yourself
an activity of some sort...
A magazine,
a book, something,
Or you're going to
get hooked, girl.
No.
I'm concentrating.
Concentrating?
Mm-hmm.
Well, you coming
with them?
Please.
You sure about that?
I'm positive.
All right.
I got to go.
Take it easy,
all right?
Later.
How much are grapes?
I'll take a pound
of your grapes.
$3.00.
$3.00?
Bet.
One month down,
three to go.
How much longer are
you going to do this
phone bone stuff?
Well, to be
perfectly honest,
Jimmy, I don't know.
You don't know?
I don't know, 'cause
I'm starting to like it.
Like it?
Yeah. My endurance
has picked up,
And I've become
extremely popular.
You like this stuff,
huh?
It's a lot of fun.
My boss lil says
she ain't never seen
nothing like it.
We had 38 phone calls
last night.
17 requests
were for moi.
17 guys
requested you?
Yeah. That's, like,
what, 50%, right?
They wanted me.
I don't know.
Look at you
eating your food.
You haven't
blessed it.
I'm hungry.
I know, but let's
make a toast.
I'm excited
about this.
All right.
To phone bone.
Phone bone.
Mmm.
Amen.
He needed me
real bad, too.
I was mistress April.
This guy was
really into pain.
He wanted me
to keep counting
As he plucked
his pubic hairs out
one by one
With a monkey wrench.
With
a monkey wrench?
A monkey wrench.
What happened
to tweezers?
I could just
picture that.
1, ow!
2, ow! Ow!
3, ouch!
4, it hurts
so good.
Come on.
That's sick.
That's not sick.
It's sick.
The man got off.
It's still
sick anyway.
Plus I got my minutes.
Three requests
because he had to
call back three times.
I'm telling you,
he needed it bad.
Ooh, a pilot called...
From a cockpit.
Cockpit fuck fantasy,
33,000 feet
in the air
With brigitte,
my busty blonde.
A pilot called you
from his cockpit?
Mm-hmm.
No wonder planes
be falling
Out of the sky
left and right.
You want
some more wine?
No.
That's all right.
Come on, Jimmy.
No, come on, baby.
That's all right.
Oh, you remember
Bob from Tucson?
Bob regular?
Yeah, yeah. Well,
we're vibing, right?
He loves to talk to me
about his mother.
When was the last time
you had an audition?
He likes to talk to me
about his mother
Because she's got cancer
And they were
never really close.
Now they seem to be
torn, you know?
So, what does
this have to do with
your acting career?
What happened
to that?
I'm still an actress, Jimmy.
How are you acting?
What?
You're not on stage,
not on camera.
You're on the phone.
How are you acting,
talking on the phone?
It is acting.
Some perverts,
how's that acting?
They're not perverts,
Jimmy, o.K.?
They're normal
people, right?
Baby, let me
tell you something.
You can continue
to live in that
little fantasy world
With the baseball cards
and the autograph bullshit,
Whatever the fuck
it is you do.
But me, I got to eat,
and I got to pay my rent.
Phone sex is acting.
Now, if you don't
like it,
You can step.
Fuck you.
I got Willie mays'
and Hank Aaron's
autograph
On a baseball card.
They're in
the hall of fame.
Is there a phone sex
hall of fame?
Is there
an equivalent
of cooperstown
For the phone sex
hall of fame?
You bugging.
You drank too much.
You're trippin'.
You wish you had
hammerin' Hank's
autograph.
That's a goddamn lie.
I wouldn't be able
to pay my rent.
Phone sex
is where I am.
I'm paying my bills.
It's an investment.
I'm not going
to sell while
it's short money.
I'll sell them
for more
in the long haul.
Get a life, man.
I ain't paying your rent.
What the fuck is
somebody pulling
out pubic hair
With a fucking
monkey wrench?
It doesn't matter.
It's paying me.
I'll hop my ass on a plane,
go to Hollywood,
and live out my dreams.
What'll you do?
You're going to
collect autographs
And take the next person
that moves in
And make them
pay your rent.
Springtime is usually
that time of the year
When children are outdoors
enjoying their young lives.
Sometimes, however,
joy is not what they get.
Carol.
In Harlem tonight,
there is tragedy.
After-school play
has turned into
a most deadly game.
Nita Hicks
is on the scene.
Nita.
Thank you, Carol.
It started out as
an after-school game
Between two little girls
In this high-rise
apartment building
At 1470 Amsterdam Avenue.
What started out as a game
has played itself out
Into a family's
worst nightmare.
It all started in this
hallway at this door
That the girls' game of tag
led to tragedy.
Witnesses are telling us
that 8-year-old Angela king
Was running down
the sixth-floor hallway
When she leaned
against this elevator door.
The elevator, however,
was not on the sixth floor.
In fact, it was up
on the 18th floor.
And that elevator door
should have been secure.
It was not.
It gave way.
8-year-old Angela king
Fell through the empty
elevator shaft,
Falling six floors
down into the basement.
Angela was rushed
to Harlem hospital,
But officials
are telling me now
That she has been
transferred
To Manhattan's
mount sinai.
The little girl
is suffering
From multiple
skull fractures.
She is in
intensive care.
She is listed
in critical condition.
Right now, I'm in the home
of Martha may Jones,
Who is Angela's aunt.
Yes. I'm her
mother's sister.
I don't know.
Her mama's
at the hospital
with her now.
She's a good
little girl.
She was good
in school.
She did her work.
She always had
a nice smile
on her face.
[Girls laughing]
O.K., o.K., well...
Christine and Martin,
have things been any hotter
Since you guys called
last week?
Sheila, it's so good
to hear your voice.
Listen, Sheila,
I want to live
my fantasy one time
Of a menage a trois
With Christine
and your friend Rosita.
Rosita?
I can't believe him.
That's my best
friend, Sheila.
I don't believe you.
Martin and Christine,
we go through this
With you guys
every week, o.K.?
Now, tonight,
let's try to have
A really
hot sexual experience.
Well, why does
he have to have
another woman?
Right. Right.
He doesn't
really love me.
I love you.
No, you don't.
That's not love.
Listen. What's wrong?
You don't know
what love is.
What's wrong for a man
wanting his wife
and his wife's friend
To lick his dick
at the same time?
Oh, that's
what you want?
How would you like it
if julio was
licking me, huh?
Julio?
Yeah, julio. And besides,
he's my friend,
And I talk to him.
And he says that's
not normal, all right?
[Speaking spanish]
If you do it
with me,
I do it with him.
Oh, do you want julio?
Why don't we get
julio in on this?
[Man]
I got rolexes
Coming out my ass,
all right?
You make me come,
I'll buy you a rolex.
That's worth a rolex.
That's worth me coming.
Now, Martin, I want you to
talk to her really gently.
Soothe her, coax her.
She's your wife.
You love her.
He doesn't
know how to soothe
or coax nobody
Because
he likes it hard
all the time.
That's his problem.
He's always rough
with me.
She's so frigid,
Sheila.
She's so ice cold.
Don't say that.
I am not cold.
Frigid, my ass.
Every time my dick
gets next to you,
it shrivels up.
Stop it.
Don't talk
like that.
I go from condoms to
earmuffs on my dick.
You know the reason
why I have such
a hard time?
Because
he only likes it
from behind.
He never wants
to look at me.
I like to look
into his eyes.
He always does that.
Baby, the doggy style...
That's the thing now.
That's what's in.
In? In, my ass, o.K.?
Hey, you're up, 6.
It's Bob regular.
See ya.
O.K.
Bob?
Hey, baby,
how are you?
I'm fine.
I miss you.
You're not going
to believe where
I'm calling you from.
Oh, let's see.
Your car?
How do you know that?
'Cause I can tell.
You hear me
all right?
Yeah, I can.
Hello?
Hello.
Hello, lovely.
Yes, Bob.
Hey, baby.
So, um, how's
your mom doing?
My mom is not
doing so good.
I'm just driving back
from the hospital now.
I'll tell you
something.
Cancer is
a very bad thing.
It is a beast.
How are you
holding up?
I'm doing...
I'm doing o.K.
I just feel like I'm wasting
my time, you know?
Just a big waste
of time out here.
No point.
Well, you know, Bob,
relationships change.
Not this relationship,
honey.
No, ma'am.
No, thank you.
Look at
you and me.
When we first
started out,
It was just
for the sex.
Now every time
I call you, baby,
All we talk about
is my mother.
But the sex is still
red hot, baby.
Tell you what,
I want you to hang on.
I'm going to pull
this car over.
Just hang on for me.
I'm back, baby.
Bob.
Yes, lovely.
Can I share
something with you?
Shoot.
Well, I just...
I just want you
to know
That
the relationship
we share...
You know, talking
about your mom
and everything,
Is really, really
special to me.
And I just
want you to know
That I'm always
here for you,
Day or night.
I mean, anytime.
So don't hesitate
to call me.
I mean, this much time
doesn't have to elapse
Before we connect
again, o.K.?
Lovely,
I got to go.
I'll talk
to you later.
Is that
a problem?
Oh, no, no, no, no,
that's no problem,
No problem at all.
Lovely, I'll call you soon.
O.K.
Remember, lovely
is always going
to be here.
I'll talk to you
later, Bob.
Bye-bye.
And some matches, too.
Tell me.
You like skiing?
Not really.
No.
How about,
um, fishing?
It's o.K.
Yeah.
Who is he?
Who, he?
He's a black bastard.
No offense. No offense,
please, huh?
I want to ask you
something.
Shoot.
I'd like to
take you fishing.
I have this friend
who's got a cabin
on a lake.
You, me, cabin,
rowboat for two, huh?
How much?
You, uh..
Work upstairs?
How much are
the cigarettes?
Give me your number.
I'll call you.
We'll talk
sometimes.
What is the matter
with that, huh?
Get your fucking hands
off me.
Give me some sex.
Come on.
I close the shop,
go in the back.
Stop!
O.K., o.K.
Don't do that.
O.K.,
but you know what?
Hey, I'm a rich man.
You know
what I'm saying?
I own this shit.
Yeah.
You won't have
to do this work.
Now, come on.
Fishing. Huh?
Or no fishing?
Listen,
you beautiful woman.
Lucky woman.
You could be
my wife.
I am talking
matrimony over here.
You know
what I'm saying?
Why don't you just fuck off?
Leave me alone.
Put the cigarettes
in the bag with the matches.
Tell me how
much they cost.
That's all you
can do for me.
* if we cannot
make believe *
* maybe we can
make some time *
* lots of pity
you and me *
* erotic city,
come alive *
* we can fuck
until the dawn *
* making love to...
We're in the girls'
bathroom, right?
And everybody else
is in class.
I'm going to push you
right into the stall
And put my hand up that
catholic-school skirt.
Ooh.
[Man]
That's good.
I'm so big over here.
I'm, like, deformed.
Oh, Melissa,
unbutton that blouse.
O.K.
Come on,
come on, missy.
Show them to me.
Yeah. Show them
to me, too.
Oh, missy.
Your titties
are so big.
Oh, my God.
I'm going
to explode.
Yes!
This is when
I jump out and say,
"What do you two girls
think you're doing?"
Oh, my God,
Cindy.
It's Mr. blue,
the custodian.
I pull out my big kielbasa,
and I say,
"Look at my big old kielbasa.
"We're going to have
to work out a bargain,
"Or I'm taking a walk
to the principal's office.
"Why don't you little
naughty girls get down
"And maybe give
Mr. big Jim
And the twins
a little kiss?"
Come on, get up there
nice and close.
Ooh, yeah, Mr. blue.
Oh, the kielbasa's
so big.
Oh, my God.
I love kielbasa.
Give me a hit
of your cigarette?
Yeah, sure.
Mmm.
Guess what?
Hmm.
Bob from Tucson?
Yeah?
He wants to meet me
in person.
I gave him
my phone number.
You what?
You know you're
not supposed
to do that.
Look,
don't get hooked
on this shit.
It's just talk.
It's a job.
I know, but he's
got a great voice.
Look,
I don't care.
Did I ever tell
you about...
Yes, you did.
And I don't want
to hear it again.
Give me my cigarette back.
Take it.
I got nothing
to say to you.
Better watch it.
Oh, shit, Jimmy.
Hanging out,
huh?
No, no.
I'm getting some milk.
Want something?
No.
Later.
All right.
What are you
doing here?
I just wanted to bring you
a little something.
No, I didn't steal it.
This old man
gave it to me.
He used to dream
that once he became
a famous actor,
He would get to marry
a beautiful movie star.
He'd say, if you want
something really bad,
You will get a picture of it,
hang it on the wall,
And look at it
every day.
And since you're
into acting and all,
I figured this
could help you out.
I hope you like it.
Oh, I love this.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
No problem.
Can I come up
for a while?
No, you cannot.
But thank you
for the magazine,
o.K.?
And you take care
of yourself.
When a late-breaking story
hits the news,
Other stories
get pushed aside,
As was the case
of a story
That we covered
four months ago...
A story about
a little girl named Angela,
Who has one birthday wish.
That wish is to spend time
with a very special lady.
It was a little story,
But one that made
such a big difference
That we decided
to come back here today
And follow up on it.
That's exactly
what we're doing
With the help of our
very special guest here.
This lady is a movie star
extraordinaire.
She is caring,
compassionate.
She cares
about the community.
This is Halle Berry.
Thank you.
I really can't think
of a better way
to spend today.
Little Angela's
birthday has touched
Millions of people
around the city,
But it inspired
11,000 people
To respond with
get-well wishes.
If I can be
a part of making
her day special,
I'm happy
to be here.
Sultan of SWAT?
Yeah, girl.
Do you have me on
the speakerphone?
Yeah, I got you on
the speakerphone.
Now, I want you
to remember,
Approaching a girl
Is just like
approaching home plate.
Ha ha ha.
Ha ha.
I hear you, baby.
I'm, uh...
I'm a little
nervous.
You know,
them night games,
Night games
kind of make me
kind of nervous.
Oh, baby,
come on now,
Don't be nervous.
You have to remember,
you're no scrub.
Oh, baby,
you said that right.
Do you have your
hitter's eye on?
I can see the
rotation on the
seams of the ball
Like Ted Williams.
Ooh.
Well, I'm on
the pitcher's mound.
Yeah, baby.
I got my pitcher's stance,
And I've got
that left leg cocked.
Just like
I like it, baby.
Tell you
what you do,
And give me that
high leg kick like,
uh, Juan marichel.
Whoo.
Here it comes, baby...
A big, fat, juicy one
straight down the middle.
Shoo.
[Thwack]
Out of here.
You could kiss
that baby goodbye.
[Imitates crowd roar]
Whoo.
I love you, girl.
6 for sex,
darling.
Don't I look pretty
With my long blond hair
and big blue eyes?
Don't I look pretty?
I'm getting
on the bus now.
You can smell my hair
as I walk past you.
You're watching my ass
As I walk
to the back of the bus.
I'm walking.
And you want me.
I'm turning around now.
I'm sitting down now.
I'm crossing my legs now,
And you're watching me.
My flower bed
is all wet now, lover.
Listen to my flower bed.
[Moaning]
Now take my boots off.
Yes, yes.
Now rip my stockings off
with your teeth.
Oh, yes!
Don't my feet
look pretty?
Now touch them.
Tickle them.
[Giggling]
Oh, yes, yes.
Oh, yes.
Faster, faster, faster.
Yes!
Don't I look pretty?
* eatin' my dinner
in a fancy restaurant *
Hi.
Working?
Ooh, what a surprise.
You went in,
I figured
you'd come out.
I didn't know
you had a brain.
Got anybody new?
Yeah. I got this guy
named Bob regular.
He's fabulous.
You should meet him.
I would like
to meet him.
Bob regular.
What kind of name
is that?
I got to run.
You got to eat.
We can go eat
at Sylvia's.
I'm sorry, but
I got other plans.
All right,
tomorrow.
Hmm?
Friday.
Friday's fine.
Good.
Friday's good.
Good Friday.
One of my all-time
favorite characters
Is foxy brown.
Right on.
Power to the people.
Talk to me fast,
baby.
I got five
heavy-tripping,
Jive turkeys
on my tail.
Check it out, mama.
The boss man want us
to meet him in Paris.
There's a 4:30 plane.
I'm just across town.
I'll pick you up.
I'm here, baby.
Stay black and beautiful,
my sister.
Right on.
Power to the people.
Put the phone down, lady.
You surrounded.
What's wrong?
Who's there?
Hold them off
until I get there.
I'm on my way.
Come on, mama.
Don't make me ask again.
Put the phone down.
You're looking for an
ass-kicking now, mama.
Yeah, baby.
[Groaning]
Damn, woman.
You's a bad...
Shut your mouth!
I'm just talking
about my sister.
Can you dig it?
Step aside, little mama.
Don't you know
the black woman
Is the mother
of civilization?
You didn't have to
shoot them, stupid.
Let's go to Paris.
Hello, lovely.
It's Bob.
Where you been?
I've been busy.
Thought you'd be glad
to hear my voice.
I am.
It's just, um...
It's funny hearing
your voice, that's all.
How's your mom doing?
Listen, I'm
going to be coming
to the big apple
For one day only
to close up
a big deal.
I got a little free
time around 2:00.
Let's do
something crazy.
I'm working
a double shift tomorrow.
Come on. Let's do
something crazy.
Let's go
to coney island,
have some hot dogs,
Make love
under the boardwalk,
Just like
the song says.
I'm working, Bob.
Take a vacation,
girl.
Please? I really
want to see you.
Say yes.
All right.
One hot dog.
One Nathan's
hot dog.
And nothing else.
O.K., nothing else.
Tomorrow at 2:00.
Yes, I'll see you
at 2:00.
Bye-bye.
All right, baby.
* oh, yeah
* I keep your picture
* beside my bed
* and I still remember
* everything you said
* I always thought
our love *
* was so right
* only those was wrong
* I always thought
you'd be by my side, mama *
* now you're gone
* what do I know, baby?
* what we had was good
* how come
you don't call me *
* anymore, yeah?
* I still light the fire
* on a rainy night
* I still like it better
* when you're
holdin' me tight *
* everybody said
* everybody said that
we should never part *
* oh, yeah
* tell me,
baby, baby, baby *
* why
* why do you wanna go
and break my heart? *
* all I know, baby
* what we had was good
* how... how come
you don't call me *
* call me anymore, yeah?
* why don't you
call me now? *
Bob regular.
Bob.
* sometimes it feels like
* I'm gonna die
Bob!
* you gotta try
* down on my knees,
beggin' you please *
* please
* why can't you call me
sometime, baby? *
* it's just
one lousy dime, baby *
* why can't you call me
sometime, baby? *
* no, no, no
* why on earth
* can't you just pick up
the phone? Yeah *
* you know I don't like
to be alone *
* why?
6, where you been?
You late, honey.
Don't make this
a habit.
O.K.?
It is so unprofessional.
Hand me those files
over there.
Coming in here late
all the time.
I'm tired of this shit.
I'm going to start
cracking down.
How are you feeling?
All right?
What's wrong with her?
I don't know.
Now, tell me you're
a little wet slut.
I'm a little wet slut.
Louder.
Then I'm going to
tie you up real good.
Have we talked before?
Your voice sounds
familiar to me.
No.
What's your name,
sweetheart?
Jack spratt.
What's your name?
Mrs. spratt.
Bullshit.
No, really.
My name is lovely spratt.
Bullshit.
Who are you?
I'm whoever you
want me to be, baby.
No, you're not.
You're not anybody.
You ain't even nobody.
You ain't even shit,
baby doll.
[Disconnect]
I cut him off, o.K.?
O.K.
Look, you do not
have to be polite.
I wasn't being polite.
Yeah, well,
whatever. Don't be.
Don't encourage
them, o.K.?
Mm-hmm.
Now, why would
you do a thing
like that to me?
I just want to talk
to you. That's all.
You don't have to be shy
with me, girl 6.
I'll be good
from now on.
I'll be very nice
to you, o.K.?
[Click]
Your daughter looked
as if she was making
a miraculous recovery.
I mean, all
of us were hoping
she'd be released,
And released
from the hospital
very soon.
We sent it up to Jesus.
It's in
the lord's hands now.
She used to talk about
Wanting of those, um...
Power ranger dolls
for her birthday,
And the pink ranger
is the girl.
And she had her eye
on the pink one,
But I don't know now.
We're here live right now
At Manhattan's
mount sinai hospital
Right outside
the emergency room.
We've just been talking
with hospital officials
Trying to get an update
on the Angela king story.
She's the 8-year-old
little girl
Who fell down
an elevator shaft,
A story that has riveted
this city
And changed
some safety policies.
We have just found out
that Angela king
Is still listed
in critical condition.
We ask our viewers
send your prayers.
Hi. Let's go.
Where were you?
Come on,
we got to go this way
'Cause I don't want
nobody to see me with you.
Damn.
You miss me?
No.
I miss you.
How are you doing?
I'm doing fine.
My usual
criminal activity.
I still haven't used a gun,
don't intend to,
And I don't go into
people's houses.
I only take from those
Who got more
than they need.
That's still my speed.
You know, supermarkets,
The woolworth's, Macy's,
Korean delis.
I only take
what I can use...
Clothes, food,
Your basic fruits
and vegetables,
Meats,
chickens, beef,
Porks, cold cuts,
rice, cereal, milk.
Damn. You
still smell good.
We had some fun,
didn't we, huh?
Here you go,
enjoy your pie.
Thanks, man.
You're welcome.
I try to eat balanced.
I still got
my sweet tooth,
you know,
But I still got
my bad habits, too.
Basically good,
but...
Bad habits.
How is everybody?
Moms doesn't
like me living
at home anymore.
I told her
I'd seen you.
She says an ex-wife
is a sign.
Oh, did she?
Mm-hmm.
You're the only
true love I got.
You know that.
Really? Well, um...
I'm going to be
leaving town soon,
As soon as I'm able...
For good.
I'm going to California.
But, um...
You do that, uh...
That freelance
typing thing.
Temp work, right?
Wrong.
I'm into phone sex.
No shit.
Yeah.
What, you?
Why not me?
Have you ever
called one before?
Hell no.
I like touch.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Call me.
Ring, ring.
Come on.
Ring.
All right.
Come on, call me.
Ahem.
Ring.
Ring, God damn it.
Hello.
Hey.
My name is lovely.
What's yours?
Joe schbotnick.
Ooh, Joe.
You have a really
sexy voice.
Where are you
calling from?
Death row.
Ooh, death row.
That means you are
a dangerous man, Joe.
That's right.
Fuckin'-a, man.
Would you like to know
what I look like?
Sure. Fire away.
I've got blond hair,
Deep, dark, sensuous eyes,
I'm 5'6",
And my best features
Are my big breasts.
They're 40 double-d.
Oh, bitchin'.
40 double-ds! Dude!
Ooh...
I'm a deep throat, Joe.
Oh, you want some
of this, baby?
Mmm...
Fuckin'-a, man.
God damn.
And I want you
so bad, sweet daddy.
You like that,
Mr. Joe schbotnick?
Mmm-mmm-mmm-mmm-
mmm-mmm-mmm.
Damn.
I didn't know you
were such a freak.
I always was.
You just never
brought it out in me.
I just never brought
it out in you.
You heard me.
Let me show you something.
What?
A little shortcut.
I know you're playing.
You're always playing.
Come on, come on,
come on.
What?
Baby girl,
what a pretty hand.
Oh, how sweet.
What are you doing?
Would you stop it?
Wait a minute.
What do you think
you're doing?
Don't put my hands
down your pants.
What's wrong with you?
What do you expect,
talking to me like that?
I was just playing
with you.
I don't play like that,
all right?
Don't step up on me
like that, o.K.?
I should kick my own ass
for even going out with you.
You're right. I'm sorry.
You're damn straight,
you're sorry.
So take your sorry ass home
to your mama.
You're right.
Shit.
[Cat screeches]
Aah!
Oh, my God!
You see it?
I see it! I see it!
He spared
no expense, lil.
no expense.
No expense.
Well, show everybody.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
It's gorgeous.
Aah!
Oh, wait...
Wait a minute.
Where's miss 6?
Working, working,
working.
Hello.
I got this
special fantasy.
Can I tell you?
Tell me.
Hey.
* in France there
lived a man who died
of a big disease *
* with a little name
* by chance, his girlfriend
came across a needle *
* and soon she did the same
All right, sexy 6.
It's back
to the salt mines.
* is being in a gang
called the disciples *
* high on crack,
toting a machine gun... *
You're like
this hot co-ed.
You know,
head cheerleader,
And I am the principal
of the school.
Ooh. Yeah.
Yeah, you see,
everybody's been worried
Because you're just too,
too hot,
And you turn
everybody on too much.
Ooh, yeah, because
I get them hard,
And it's, like,
so distracting.
Are you, uh...
Hard right now?
I sure am, baby.
Now, see,
I'm the principal,
And I have to
discipline you.
Yes, Mr. principal.
Unzip my pants
and take it out.
You just
took my hand
And shoved it
down your thing.
Tell me how much
you need it. Tell me.
I'm so wet.
I need it.
That's good.
Beg for it, sweetheart.
Oh, please
give it to me,
Mr. principal,
Because I'm so...
I'm so...
I'm so bad,
Mr. principal.
Yeah, that's good.
Ooh, give it
to me, please.
You want some more?
Huh?
You want some more,
Mr. principal?
No, no. That's good.
That's good.
Thanks a lot.
I enjoyed that.
Hey.
6...
You all right?
Do I look all right?
No. You look like shit.
Come on down
from that sink.
I'm sending you home, baby.
You're burned out.
75 got you smoking
that shit.
Look, lil,
I am chill.
I am cool.
I am fine.
Look, hey, hey, hey.
Come here.
I know what
I'm talking about,
o.K., baby?
I've been
through this.
You need some rest.
Yeah?
So, what are you
trying to tell me,
I'm on leave?
Yeah, you on leave.
You go somewhere,
recharge your batteries.
You come back,
you're good as new.
Get some sun, all right?
The islands maybe. Yeah?
Mmm.
I need this job, lil.
I know you need
the job, 6,
But I'm not changing
my mind, o.K.?
Now, go on home.
Go ahead.
Is that job
still available?
Why the change of heart?
I got my own phone.
Still got those pipes?
Yes, I do.
Good. When do you
want to start?
As soon as possible.
* hot thing
* barely 21...
If you do decide
to accept this mission,
You must realize
That your own private line
is essential.
I suggest getting
an unlisted phone number
That is inaccessible
to caller i.D.
Choose a phone
with a lightweight receiver.
I suggest getting a headset.
That way your hands
are kept free.
While office-bound
fantasy girls are restricted
By what they can say,
A fantasy girl
who works out of the home,
A home girl,
Can experience complete
and total freedom.
You can invite your caller
To fully experience
his deepest,
Darkest...
Strangest...
Wildest desires.
No inhibitions...
No restrictions.
Total freedom.
No taboos.
Yeah.
Are you ready, baby?
Huh?
Are you ready for me now?
I'm ready for you.
Ooh... Explode for me.
Oh...
Do it...
Till you're satisfied.
Oh...
Ooh...
Oh, yeah.
Oh.
I loved watching the jeffersons
and good times,
Especially Thelma.
Baby, can I, can I?
But my parents are home.
Weesie!
Give me that phone!
Daddy!
This is the man
of the house,
And you better
get another girl
to wipe your feet with.
Not our daughter.
This is my house!
George!
Look here, honey,
Your mother and I want you
to have an active social life,
But when
some sicko calls...
Listen here, baby.
You got to listen
to your father.
But, ma!
How was I supposed
to know he was a sicko?
All he kept saying was,
"can I come over?
Can I come in?"
"Can I come over"?
"Can I come..."
Ooh!
[Telephone rings]
Son, you're trying
my patience.
Why can't I
speak to her?
O.K. She'll
be right here.
George.
George, what you
going to do, George?
Don't you go
in there, George!
George, what are
you doing, George?
Don't be throwing
that stuff out here,
George!
Where is Florence
when you need her?
Step back.
Don't shoot him,
daddy!
Aah!
God! You cut me!
He killed him!
Aah ha ha!
George, that's the 10th
phone this month!
[Soul music playing]
Oh, he's going
into that slide.
Be careful when
you do that, baby!
The chicken stew!
Aah!
Whoo!
Come on, George.
Work it, baby.
Do that lean-back, baby.
Do that lean-back.
Aah!
Whoo!
[Knock on door]
Shit.
[Knocking]
Who is it?
Banging on my door like
they've lost their mind.
[Knocking]
Oh, sh...
You deaf?
I've been banging
on this door
for an hour.
I have been busy.
That's what
I'm talking about.
What did you
do to your ex?
You got that guy crazy.
He wants
to get back with you.
I don't go backwards.
I only go forwards.
The man's been crazy.
I owe you money.
I don't got a job,
But damn you
and damn that phone.
We're not even
friends anymore.
We don't even talk.
It's just like this...
I get paid to talk now.
I don't have time to be
bullshitting with you.
Me and you talking
is bullshit?
It's bullshit.
Normal conversation
is bullshit?
with you is bullshit.
So what's this, then?
It's a letter.
Mind your own business.
From who?
One of my callers.
"Dear, miss lovely,
I'm such a baby,
"And it's hard for me
to go to sleep at night.
"I'm hungry.
"Mommy, please squirt
some of your warm
breast milk
"Into a bowl
of frosted flakes.
They're great?
Signed... love,
Tony the tiger."
Who's this?
Put it back, Jimmy.
Put it back.
Sexual deviant.
This ain't reality.
It is reality.
It is my reality.
I know what's real
and what's not,
Whether you want
to believe it or not.
Do you?
Miss lovely,
you get off
on this stuff?
Huh? Huh?
* you've always been
the first in line *
* nobody will
ever love you *
* as much as I do
Hey, behave yourself.
Ha ha.
Heh heh heh.
So, um, you still want
to take me fishing?
I don't fish.
You going to play me
like that?
Play with you?
Yeah. I thought you
wanted to get married.
Married?
This is my wife.
Sangi,
who is this woman?
Who is this woman?
I'll tell you.
This woman
is a prostitute
With, mind you,
stolen cigarettes.
Call the cops.
Take them and get out.
Call the cops!
You're standing...
don't shout at me!
Take your cigarettes.
Get out of here.
Come on, you thief.
Get out!
[Speaking hindi]
Yeah.
I get sick
of this nonsense
week after week.
It's always the same
with those girls
upstairs,
Those bloody
phone sex girls.
Phone sex girls?
Yes.
Don't you dare
come near me again,
You useless donkey!
I'm phoning
your bloody mother!
Phone, phone.
Ha ha ha.
* got my future
all planned out *
* bye, girl
* listen, don't talk
to strangers *
* don't forget to say
your prayers at night *
* remember,
God who made you *
* one day will make
everything go right *
Hey. Hey.
Ronnie, I don't know this man.
Homey,
can I help you?
No, you can't.
[Door closes]
Let's go.
I just thought
she was somebody I knew.
Yeah, well, she's not.
Let's go.
Sorry if I caused you any
kind of inconvenience, man.
[Ronnie speaking spanish]
Don't take it personal.
She doesn't speak to me,
either.
I guess
she's working, huh?
Yeah.
I hear her sometimes
through the door.
I haven't seen her
in weeks.
She gave me her number...
It's unlisted...
But she told me not
to give it to you.
Besides,
she screens her calls
and don't call back.
I miss her, man.
If you could get her
to call me...
I don't know.
I'll give her
the message.
* hmm hmm hmm
[Beep]
Hey, honey,
It's me calling
from command central.
Can you take three
of Niki's regs today?
She's got the flu.
Call me back asap.
Wake up. Call me back.
Ciao.
[Beep]
Yo, yo, yo,
this is Jimmy.
You never
call me back, girl.
I never see you.
What's up with that?
[Beep]
Hi, baby doll.
This is your lover calling.
I'm surprised
you're not home.
I usually don't
leave messages,
And I don't really
like machines.
I much prefer human beings.
I think whoever invented
the answering machine
should be shot.
How can we continue
this romance
If you're not home
waiting for me?
Bye, baby doll.
Hello, love.
It's Mr. snuff.
I know.
Uh, listen,
I want to ask you
a question...
Are you ugly?
No. I'm beautiful.
The reason
I ask you that
Is because I was
watching Oprah
the other day,
And they had
the program
on phone sex,
And every one
of those girls
was ugly.
So I'm asking you,
are you ugly?
No. I'm absolutely,
Positively gorgeous.
You're beautiful?
Yes, I'm beautiful.
That doesn't
make sense.
How can a slut
be beautiful?
The Mona Lisa's
beautiful.
The statue of liberty's
The grand canyon,
the first day of spring,
The new-fallen snow,
that's beauty,
But a slut...
Is just slutty, right?
You know?
Yes.
Did you miss me?
Kind of.
I missed you.
You know, I really
opened up to you.
I've opened my heart
up to you.
I trust you.
You do?
I do, absolutely.
And now it's time
for the good part.
I'm scared.
I'll be quick,
And you'll be
much happier
when it's over.
O.K.
You're not happy
now, are you?
No.
You're not happy
because you're
a fuck slut, right?
Right.
So say that.
I'm a fuck slut.
No, no. "I'm not
happy because..."
Say it.
I'm not happy...
Because I'm
a fuck slut.
That's right.
There you go.
But you're going
to be much happier
When everything
is said and done.
Now, this is what
we're going to do.
We're going to put
your head in the bag.
We're going to tie it
nice and tight.
nice and snug.
And then I'm going to give you
the fuck of your life.
I'll do that for you.
And then it's lights out.
Oh, no.
Lights completely out.
Why are you
doing this to me?
That's none
of your fucking business.
But you have to
make it my business
Because I want
to love you.
Don't you contradict me.
I don't need anything
from you, you understand?
Yes.
Are you ready? O.K.
Good. We're going to spice
things up, all right?
Mm-hmm.
I'm going to come
to your apartment,
And we're going to do this
for real. How does that sound?
Oh, baby, please,
let's do it like this.
Don't you fucking perform.
I'm not.
Don't you fucking
perform for me.
I don't want
that bullshit.
O.K.? I do
the performing.
I'm not performing for you.
Then what are you doing?
I just want to...
I just want to love you.
No, no, I don't want
your love.
I don't need your love.
I have enough love.
I have plenty,
believe me.
I have a mother.
I have friends.
I don't want your love.
Oh, come on,
give it to me.
Please.
Bullshit.
I live
very close to you.
I'm going
to come over there,
And I'll be there
in a few minutes.
I'll get that bag
tied around your head,
watch you struggle.
But you don't know
where I live.
No?
213 east 5th street,
apartment number 5.
* ghettos
to the left of us *
* flowers to the right
* there'll be...
Hello?
Hi there, um...
This is lovely.
I just got another
wild card. Ha ha.
Can you do me a favor
And send me somebody
who's, um,
Really sweet right now?
All right, sit tight.
I'll call you right back.
O.K.
Bye-bye.
* we all have
our own problems *
[Ring]
Hello?
Hey, I'm out
on the corner.
I was wondering
if you needed anything.
Maybe some haagen-dazs?
Or how about a dozen
of those long-stemmed red roses
That you love so much?
Look, why don't you
just leave me alone?
[Ring]
Hello?
Well, guess what.
They're out of the green bags,
but I got the blue,
And they're
the see-through kind,
Is that good?
You know what, um...
That sounds really,
really good, baby.
I think you should get
those green baggies
and come on over
Because I got something
for your ass,
you sick motherfucker!
I'm going to kill you
if you come over here!
That's what I want to hear.
I swear to God
I'm going to kill you!
Why you been holding
out on me like that?
[Shouting]
Why'd you hold out
on me?
Come over!
That's right.
[Ring]
Jimmy!
What?
Open the door.
Hold on, hold on.
You got to
let me in, Jimmy.
Look at you.
Please let me
spend the night.
Yes.
Phone bone stuff?
Come on. You look
pitiful. Pitiful.
Jimmy?
What?
You asleep?
Yes.
Guess what.
What?
I'm going to go
to Los Angeles.
I thought L.A.
was falling into
the pacific ocean.
No, I just think
that it's, um...
You know, it's time
that I started
Pursuing my acting thing,
you know?
You mean it
this time, huh?
Yeah.
Well, if that's what
you want to do...
I'm all for it.
I'm happy for you.
Thank you.
You know, I've been...
Trying to tell you...
If I ever saw you...
That, uh,
I finally broke down
And sold off some
of my memorabilia
collection.
Really?
Yup.
It was hard to do,
but, uh...
I can't wait 20 years.
I got to eat now.
I got to pay the rent.
Especially since
you're moving.
Who am I going
to borrow money from?
Ha ha ha.
Some other fool,
I guess. Ha ha.
I got something for you,
I want to give you.
This is a tops,
Mint condition
1964 baseball card,
Signed by Hank Aaron
and Willie mays,
Both hall of famers.
Hank Aaron's
hit more home runs
Than anybody
in major league baseball,
More than babe Ruth.
It's for you.
Signed by both.
So remember me
by that, all right?
Give me a kiss.
All right.
I will.
Don't sell that.
No matter
how low you get,
Don't ever
sell that one.
Say hey,
Willie mays...
The greatest ball player
that ever lived.
[Woman chattering]
Asked Jesus,
"Who is the greatest
in the kingdom of heaven?"
It says in the Bible
Jesus called
a little child onto him
And set the child
in the middle of them.
Hi.
I decided to bring this
to you in person.
Angela, look at that.
That's for you.
What you going to say
to the lady?
Thank you.
Oh, you're welcome,
honey.
Say God bless you.
God bless you.
God bless you, too.
Can I have a kiss?
Thank you
for the money.
God will bless you, miss.
Thank you.
Hey.
I heard your girl
Angie got out.
Thought we could
celebrate.
You been calling
my house?
I would,
but you're unlisted.
I just wanted
a normal conversation.
All right.
I'm going to L.A.
where it's safe.
How in the hell
is L.A. safe?
It's safer than here.
Plus I got to get
my acting thing
going again.
You can't act
in New York?
No. There's
too much history.
Oh, Judy.
I'm going
to miss you, Judy.
Judy.
I always did
like the way
you called me that.
* Tracy died
* soon after
a long-fought
civil war *
* just after
hal wiped away
his last tear *
Taxi!
About time.
Yes!
Driver, drive. Drive!
Where are you going?
To cali!
Jfk. Make sure
she gets there safe.
What time's
your flight?
In an hour.
Peace.
Bye, Judy.
* sometimes it snows
* in April
Miss brown.
He's so sorry
to keep you waiting.
He and your agents
had to work out
a few minor details.
This is, of course,
not a reading.
It's more like
a meeting.
He just wants
to go over specifics,
catch up.
Yes, of course, darling.
* all good things,
they say *
* never last
* springtime was always
my favorite *
* time of year
* a time for lovers
* holding hands
in the rain *
* now springtime
only reminds me of... *
* Tracy's tears
Welcome to Hollywood,
lovely.
Glad you could make it.
How have you been, doll?
I've been fine,
thank you.
So let's have
a look at you.
Mm-hmm.
Good enough to eat.
O.K. Here we go.
Rob, you, uh, you going
to shoot her the line?
Yeah.
And when you
answer him, honey,
I want you to turn
your head... Real slow.
Then we're going to kiss.
O.K.
And then...
Well...
O.K., rob.
Delivery.
Come in.
O.K., now we're
going to kiss.
Good, good.
Now let your top
open up.
Come on, come on.
We need to see
your tits, honey.
Keep the kiss going,
please.
Rob, help her.
We don't have all year,
sweetheart.
Mmm. Mmm.
Please don't do that.
Stop.
Don't do that.
Rob, that's o.K.
Look, I've got other ladies
waiting to audition.
I don't have all day, lovely.
O.K. Whenever
you're ready,
Let's see
what you've got.
The only reason I've
consented to doing this
Is because I wish
to clear my name,
Not because I care
about what people think,
But enough is enough.
And if it helps
some people in the end,
That's fine, too.
Some people
call me a freak.
I hate that word
Because I don't believe
in labels.
I consider myself
to be normal,
Whatever normal is.
But... What you going
to do, huh?
That was the deal.
Mm-hmm.
Good. Very good.
O.K.
Ooh, ooh, look, there was
no offense here, o.K.?
I'm just trying to be free.
No restrictions.
That's what
the role required.
Hmm.
No offense taken.
Oops.
* but all good things,
they say *
* never last
* all good things,
they say *
* never last
* and love isn't love
* till it's past
* 1, 2
* 1, 2, 3
* girl 6
[Telephone rings]
Oh, yeah.
[Ring]
* yeah,
hey, hey, hey *
* girl 6
[Girl]
Hi there.
What's your name?
* girl 6
Oh, yeah.
I've got dark hair.
I have a really
great figure.
* girl 6
Oh, yeah.
* ooh, yeah, yeah
* girl 6
* all the way
from the ghetto *
* my little butt
could sway *
Ah-ah-ah.
* tears you get
through the level *
* no price
too big to pay *
Yes!
* she keeps her pride
in a bucket *
* next to the milky way
* hey, hey
* girl 6
* what do you
wanna hear? *
* girl 6
* listen to your fears
Oh, yeah.
* laughing and tears
* girl 6
* I can make it
* as long
as you're with me *
* God, you're pathetic
* you can call this day
Ooh, yeah.
* you can talk
your sh... *
Shut up, already!
* no matter how lame
Tame.
* the eagle's landing
* on the claim to fame
* she got your number
* you all the same
* you know
it's all good *
* with your bucket
* heaven's only
a phone call away *
* hey, hey
* girl 6
* what do you
want to be, girl? *
* girl 6
* listen to your fears
Oh, yeah.
* laughing and tears
* girl 6
* I can make it
* as long
as you are near *
* girl 6
So good.
Oh, yeah.
* what's the end
to the way out? *
* way out where?
* how do we get
directions *
* to December
in surround? *
* what does
this stuff do? *
* and do not tease
all she dreams about *
* girl 6 in doubt
* hey, hey, hey, hey,
hey, hey, yeah *
Jimmy watching the game,
and I be uptight.
That boy is a damn fool.
Under pressure divas.
* hey, hey, yeah
* girl 6
I've been
on my feet all day.
* girl 6
I'm down on my hands
and knees.
* girl 6
Aah!
* what do you want
to hear? *
* girl 6
* can you listen
to my fears? *
* girl 6
* whoo
* come on, baby
* girl 6
* I can make it
* as long
as you are near *
* girl 6
* I can make it
* what do you want
to hear? *
* girl 6
* I can make it
* what do you want
to hear? *
* girl 6
* I can make it
* what do you want
to hear? *
* girl 6
* I can make it
* as long
as you are near *
* girl 6
* yeah, yeah, yeah