THE CULTURES AND PEOPLE DEPICTED
IN THIS FILM ARE FICTITIOUS.
PLEASE BE RESPECTFUL WHEN TRAVELING
TO THE LOCATIONS USED IN THIS FILM,
AND RESPECT THE RULES AND
CULTURES OF THE COMMUNITIES.
Sometimes, you think
you've got it together.
you're on top of the world.
That life is in the palm of your
hands. But the truth is, it's not.
And when you realize that, you will
find yourself falling to pieces.
But you can pull
yourself together again.
Slowly but surely. Otherwise,
you'd never get yourself back.
Here's my fare, mister.
And, yes, you will
make mistakes.
And you will move through life
like you are drifting
through an endless dream.
Every second you
devote to family,
every waking moment,
all of it, joyless
and meaningless.
But then, one day, you
will meet that one person
who has the power to
wake you from your slumber.
Will you let them?
Did you enjoy
your birthday, Niko?
Actually,
it's not my birthday today.
Well…
Wait…
Are you even single?
Tell me the truth.
Of course. I'm 22 years old,
single, and at your service.
- Wait!
- Keep it down, madam.
Manuel likes you, by the way.
Him.
You know what?
Oh my God,
I can't…
My youngest kid is
a year older than you.
I'm old enough to
be your grandma!
You're one beautiful,
sexy grandma.
Let me guess how old you are.
As I said, I'm old enough
to be your grandma.
Doesn't matter. You're still
one beautiful, sexy grandma.
You know what?
I don't care.
I like you.
And that's all that matters.
How about you?
Did you enjoy it?
I like you too.
Let me.
All right.
You're as light as
a Kawasaki Ninja.
I can't imagine… Seven
years without sex?
I guess.
I was just waiting
for the right man.
Looks like you've found him.
Was it worth the wait?
You know what?
Honestly…
I feel safe with you.
And this,
I've always wanted this
because my husband
never made me feel this way.
He was cold.
He had no time for me.
He was always
heading off somewhere.
I thought I was the problem.
Honestly,
I've never felt this
good until now.
All I ever did was go along
with whatever he wanted.
That's just how it was.
That's funny though.
You keep insisting we shouldn't
text each other after this.
Can you really forget about me?
Wait.
Niko, no…
Stay here.
Just stay here.
I didn't do too badly, right?
- Mom?
- Oh, it's you.
The prayer meeting
ended later than usual?
Yeah.
I was going to wear that.
Can you lend me a denim skirt?
- It's over there.
- Okay.
By the way, Ma.
The delivery guy called.
He said the delivery
would be made later today?
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- Thanks.
- Sure.
Damn it, Gloria.
I told you to buy a new lamp!
I only come home once a month.
Am I asking too much of you?
You really are useless
around the house.
I forgot, okay?
I'm sorry.
I forgot all about it because I got
busy, and my pottery wheel broke.
- Okay?
- Seriously?
Do you even remember anything?
I thought it was just your
eyesight that was going bad.
Apparently, it's
something worse.
I wasted so much
money on that operation.
Hey. You're the reason that I got
a tumor in the first place, okay?
For nine years,
all I ever did was...
- All right, that's enough.
- You had a kid with her!
Don't you ever shut up?
I give you money, so
I'm doing my part, okay?
The only reason you got your
dignity back was because of me.
The bank fired you,
and you deserved it.
Because you're useless!
You can't do anything right.
Was I wrong for
trusting my client?
- What do you want me to do?
- Nothing.
Because I expect
nothing from you.
Here.
Go to the mall and
buy a new lamp.
On second thought,
just text me once you've
picked out something.
I'll pay for it there.
Goodness. Mike's never
going to change, is he?
If he was as hot as he is
hot-hotheaded, I probably wouldn't mind.
Do you want to get him back?
Not at all. I'm not
playing wife number two.
So, do you miss him?
Wow! I thought he'd be the
first and last man in your life.
He was my first, yes, but I
hope he won't be my last!
- I mean, you know what happened, right?
- I know!
Well, you seem to have
come to terms with this.
Look, I just don't
want to be so…
You know, I put a lot of
effort into staying positive.
The thing is, I just
want to be happy.
…for what he did
with his secretary.
Then you're officially
back on the market.
You have to put in
some work, okay?
Look, just go for it.
- Your biological clock's ticking.
- I know! Oh my God!
When was the last
time you had sex?
I don't even remember.
But you know what?
It doesn't matter.
I'm perfectly fine without it.
- Remittance?
- Yes.
Account number, please.
Is it good to go? Thanks.
Mom?
Did you get the money?
I'm not going back
home this weekend.
Right, his birthday's coming up.
Could you buy some
chocolate croissants for him?
Maybe six of them.
You'll get five. 500, yeah.
Yes, of course. You have
nothing to worry about.
It won't take long.
Hurry up, okay?
You've got one hour, okay?
- Hey, you're here.
- Thanks, man.
Did Salazar notice?
No, you came back just in time.
All right.
- Can you help me, mister?
- What is it?
- I'm looking for lamps.
- Wait here, please.
- Hey?
- What?
You have a customer.
Wait.
He's our best salesman.
He will show you around.
You owe me one, okay?
Hello. May I know
what you're looking for?
Light.
Wow, is that so?
I need a lamp for a table.
- Okay.
- Do you have a long one?
You know, one with…
A neck.
And a head on top.
A light, I mean.
How about this?
Niko's the best salesman here.
You can learn a lot from him.
He's got this. Believe me.
He's sold five
already. Me? Nada.
That's because
you're slacking off.
Get back to work.
That one's nice.
Are you taking it?
Can I come back for it later?
Absolutely. I'll
take care of it.
Don't worry.
Can I get your number?
All right.
My husband will stop by later.
If he is happy with
this, he'll take it. Okay?
Got it.
No problem.
Food's here!
Oh, wow.
- What do you think?
- Just stay here, okay?
- I can't.
- But Sam cooked for us.
And Mom's birthday is
coming up soon. Mine too.
Someone's driving me to Manila.
- I can't keep him waiting.
- Please?
- Fine, how about…
- okay.
Here. Go buy yourself
a T-shirt, okay?
Very funny, Dad.
You need to cover up a bit.
Yeah?
- Can you give me money too?
- What?
- Come on.
- Give me a break.
- Your eldest son deserves the best.
- All right. Here.
- Oh, brother.
- Just relax, Mike.
What's the rush?
- Well, you know me.
- Have something to eat first.
No, it's fine.
Gloria. Here.
This should be
enough for everything.
Just take it.
Did you see the lamp
your mom picked out?
It's pretty ugly, isn't it?
You want to come
with me to Manila?
- Come on, Dad.
- Okay.
I have to go now.
- Take care.
- Thanks.
- Bye, Pa.
- Bye.
This is good!
Wait, is that my phone?
I think so.
Who's this?
- How is it?
- It's good.
It's me, Niko, the
hardware shop salesman.
Looks like your husband didn't
like the lamp you picked out.
He told me
that, well,
you didn't have good taste.
Yeah, I know. He
told me already.
But you picked out a good one.
Why don't you drop
by the store again?
We'll pick a good one this time.
I'm sure we'll find something.
Okay, thanks.
Thanks. Bye.
Come on, let's eat!
- Jibs.
- Yeah?
What are you doing here?
I drove her here. Again.
Issa.
I missed you so much.
You have no idea, babe.
Issa, you have to go home.
You have to go home.
All right, let's go back home.
Come on, babe.
Come on.
Help me out here.
- Watch her head.
- Yeah.
Oh, Issa.
I'll leave you to it, Jibs.
Make sure she gets home safely.
Lea?
- Thank you.
- No problem.
- To you and Brenda.
- Don't mention it.
Thank you for
this. I appreciate it.
It's no big deal, okay?
I love you, Glory.
- You know what?
- What?
You're really lucky.
Because you've managed to
overcome all your problems.
It was amazing to see
you get right back up.
You bounced back
like they were nothing.
You've led a colorful
life, and you're so blessed.
Are you happy right now?
Well…
I have no money.
I've lost my husband.
My career.
Everything I've
worked so hard for
is gone.
I've got nothing left because
I've made so many bad decisions.
Oh, come on, Glory.
Yes, you lost your job. But at least
you have the life skills to make it.
And you're in good health right
now. That's all that matters. Okay?
And you raised your kids well.
They love you so much.
Brenda and I do too.
You will bounce back
completely. I know you will.
Glory.
I'm just really
trying my best, Lea.
You know what, honestly?
The only thing I
want for my birthday
is to have someone beside me.
Yes.
- Right?
- Of course.
I want to have someone to
wake up with every morning.
Me too.
Okay.
HOW ARE YOU?
NIKO WHO?
FROM THE HARDWARE
SHOP, REMEMBER?
I HAVEN'T FORGOTTEN YOU.
YOU WERE THE ONE WHO
HELPED ME OUT LAST TIME?
I DON'T EVEN REMEMBER
WHAT YOU LOOK LIKE.
LET'S MEET. YOU WON'T
FORGET ME THIS TIME.
HAVE YOU HAD BREAKFAST YET?
NOT YET, AND MY HANDS
ARE ALL DIRTY RIGHT NOW.
YOU'RE INTO FARMING? MY
PARENTS ARE FARMERS TOO.
NO, I DON'T DO FARMING. I
MAKE AND SELL POTTERY.
YOU MAKE POTS?
SO, YOU'RE AN ARTIST?
SORT OF, YEAH.
I'M NOT FAMILIAR WITH ARTSY TYPES.
YOU MUST MAKE LOTS OF MONEY.
Just somebody.
ACTUALLY, I'M JOBLESS.
YOU DON'T LOOK IT AT ALL.
YOU'RE REALLY PRETTY TOO.
Come on, you're always texting.
OH, ENOUGH WITH THE FLATTERY.
I GOT LUCKY THAT DAY, YOU KNOW?
I SOLD TWO MORE AFTER YOU LEFT.
LET'S MEET, MY TREAT! WHAT'S
YOUR FAVORITE DINING SPOT?
VIZCO'S. THEIR SWEETS
ARE JUST PERFECT.
I HAVEN'T EATEN THERE…
MY BIRTHDAY'S COMING
UP TOO. SO, VIZCO'S IT IS?
She said yes!
Good on you, man!
- Are you good, sir?
- Yeah.
All right, I'll take care of it.
Congrats, man.
Oh my gosh…
Here's my fare, mister.
Oh, it's you, Glory.
It's been a long time.
Have you heard?
They'll be holding prayer meetings
on Thursdays starting next month.
Can you keep me
updated on that, Carol?
Where are you off to?
You look even lovelier now.
I'm meeting up with a
friend at Session Road.
Come again?
- I have to buy something.
- I see.
All right, then.
Excuse me, mister. I'm
getting off here, please.
- I forgot something.
- I see.
- See you, then.
- Yeah.
- Bye, take care.
- You too. Bye.
It's me, Niko.
Remember me now?
Come on, our table's this way.
Here.
You look different.
Busted. You said you didn't
remember what I looked like.
No, I mean...
So, how can I look different?
Well, you actually
look like Keanu Reeves.
This looks good.
Let's eat.
It's my first time here.
Mine too.
I thought this was
your favorite place?
It's my first time
doing this, I mean.
Same here.
I can't afford to
eat here, that's why.
Well, I only come here
on special occasions.
My birthday's special?
As you said, we're here, so…
Yes, sure, it's special.
Hey, I'm not into flattery.
But I do practice the seven
key steps to successful selling.
How do you know that?
From what branch are you?
Oh my God, that
was a long time ago.
I'd only just
graduated back then.
How about you?
Here at Session Road.
I didn't finish the
course though.
So, do I make a good salesman?
Definitely.
You're really good at this.
I need to go to the restroom.
- Is that okay?
- Yeah, no problem.
Did you see that
cute guy earlier?
Yeah, he was so hot! I wish
I'd been the one serving him!
The woman he's with is prettier.
Yeah, but she's old.
You're right.
I'll serve him some water later.
Good idea!
Wait, I have to go.
Can we…
Go somewhere else?
Somewhere where
no one can see me?
Sure. Wait.
One more for takeout, please.
And could I have the bill?
Are you okay?
Why didn't you
put the helmet on?
- I get it.
- No, it's not that!
It's just,
I'm just not used to
riding motorcycles.
Look.
Your hands are really cold!
You were driving too fast!
Come on.
You smell good.
You really do.
It's good, right?
You eat like a pig.
I think we can finish this.
We can't do this anymore, okay?
Are you on a diet?
If you are, then stop.
You don't need it at all.
I'm serious, okay? Niko…
I'm ser...
It's good, right?
This is wrong, Niko. It's...
This is wrong, okay? Niko!
- Delicious.
- This is wrong.
You're right.
Is this okay?
I'm listening.
What?
When I have something
important to talk about,
I put on my best clothes.
That's what Grandma taught me.
Well?
Go on.
I'm a married woman.
I know.
But you don't love him.
Does he love you?
Do you like me?
You're beautiful.
I'm being serious, Niko!
Come on.
We can't do this again.
Once I leave this place,
don't text me ever again.
Can I be serious for a minute?
I don't like where
this is going.
I want to be with you, Glory.
Is that okay with you?
Well?
I'm scared.
I thought it was settled?
Look.
He might beat you up.
It's okay
because I can take him on.
You're a married woman, Glory.
This is asking for trouble.
That's what I
thought at first too.
I told myself
that after that night,
it would be over.
But he was so persistent.
He was so caring, Lea.
He was so nice.
He's a great guy.
You're seriously gushing
over this short-term fling?
Over a guy who's half our age?
Come on! I would never
hook up with Bryan!
He's my godson.
So, why hook up with a guy
the same age as your godson?
You're not playing auntie
to him, too, are you?
What if you get pregnant?
Oh my God! I'm too
old to get pregnant!
You're too old for him.
I told you to get back
into the dating pool,
but not with a
guy half your age!
I'm not dating guys my age.
They're all married
anyway, okay?
Date single guys your age.
Lea, I'm not looking
for a relationship.
It just happened.
If I hadn't pushed myself
or taken the chance…
If he hadn't been so persistent…
He's not like
other guys his age.
He's completely different.
It's called sex drive, Glory.
Know what? I've been
worried about you lately.
I even told Raffy
I was that worried.
Anyway, I have to go.
Hands off Bryan, okay?
I'm warning you.
I have to go now. Please let me
know if Joey's coming over tonight.
Because I let you do
that when I'm here, right?
I hope we're clear on this.
- Yes, Mom.
- Okay, I really have to go.
Wait a sec, where are you going?
We booked Marina for a
mani-pedi session, right?
Can we just do that
tomorrow? Please?
But we have a group project
tomorrow. It's due soon.
Anyway, I really have to go now.
You know what Mom's like.
Mom didn't see you, right?
Babe…
Hello, is your mom
there? It's me, Carol.
Can I talk to her?
She's not here. She left early.
She said she was going
to a prayer meeting.
That's odd. We're not
holding one until next month.
We haven't been
active for six months.
Anyway, I just wanted to ask if she'll be
coming with me to the wake of a friend.
Just tell her I called, okay?
You smell good.
Of course, because
I was expecting you.
Let me.
Let's eat?
I shredded the
chicken just for you.
Wow. You did this just for me?
This is too much. We're
not eating fish, okay?
But thank you. It was
really sweet of you.
Eat up.
Grandma taught me to take
good care of the people I love.
You know,
everyone's talking about us.
Who? The neighbors?
Why does it matter?
I don't care about
them or what they think.
But I can't help it,
you know? I mean…
I'm a private person, you know?
And I only trust very
few people with my life.
Is there something to
be embarrassed about?
Not this again.
You know what they think of us.
People think these
kinds of relationships
only happen because
of one of three reasons.
Money, good sex, or a
guy needing a mother figure.
They're wrong.
First and foremost,
it's about connection.
And it doesn't hurt that
you're hot for your age.
You're pulling my leg.
Just eat.
You do this all the time!
Did I just ruin your
dramatic moment?
I know you've got it bad for
me. That's why you're doing this.
- Good one!
- I know you do!
You've got a witty
comeback this time!
And that's why I love you.
Nice one!
Is that it?
Well?
Lame.
- Super lame.
- Am I?
Lame, huh?
Can I?
G?
Promise me, okay?
That this will be the last
time you bring this up.
Look, even if we
were the same age,
if we didn't get along,
we'd still break up.
Just ignore them. What
they think doesn't matter.
We have each other.
That's all that matters.
You want to live together?
Wait.
I'm giving you this.
I don't have much,
but I made more
than usual last time.
My boss is pretty
happy with my work.
This money is proof
of all my hard work.
By the way,
I just talked to the caretaker.
He's moving overseas,
and he's leaving
this place to me.
We have a place of our own now.
We won't have to worry
about rent anymore.
G…
I love you.
I will always be yours.
And this place?
This is yours too.
This place is proof
of just how much you mean to me.
Of just how much I love you.
I love you too.
I have to talk to my kids.
Why are you...
Who is he? Why is he here?
Mia, what's the meaning of this?
Get out!
Now, you go back to
your room and get dressed!
You and I are going to talk!
Now, Mia!
I'm really sorry, Mom.
What happened, Mia?
Who was that guy?
Well?
My boyfriend.
Since when? Why do I
know nothing about this?
Do you even know
what you're doing?
What if you get pregnant, Mia?
Is he willing to
take responsibility?
Answer me, Mia!
We love each other.
That's all that matters.
He was the only
one who stood by me
when I was having a hard
time completing my thesis.
Giro was the only one who gave me
strength when I felt like giving up!
My God, Mia.
You could have told
us about your situation.
How? Who would
even listen to me?
Sam's busy with his band!
And you?
You're always away
at prayer meetings.
I just miss you so much, Mom.
I've really missed this, Mom.
We're thinking of
moving in together.
So much for prayer meetings.
But it's true.
- Carol called earlier.
- And?
She told me the prayer meetings have
been on hold for six months already.
Can't you and Dad
patch things up?
Mia, please.
You know what he put me through.
He has a second family now.
I didn't tell you right away…
Because I didn't think
I'd fall for someone again.
Are you with a woman?
I'm with a man.
But he's much younger than me.
But he takes good care of me.
My friend, Ryan…
The thing is, I have friends
who go for older women.
It happens. How
young is young though?
Do you love him?
Niko's a great guy.
I just want you to be happy.
Does he have a job?
- Yes.
- Would he be open to living here?
I mean, I could go
jamming with him.
…If we don't live together.
You know your
dad won't like this.
I got your back, Mom.
What?
- You're doing it wrong.
- What?
Then show me.
Who taught you that?
Let me guess. Your grandma?
I'm getting these
out of the way.
Oh, you!
- Here we go.
- All right.
You're doing it wrong.
This is how Grandma taught me to make it.
You need to secure the ends tightly, okay?
See? There you go.
- Let me see.
- That's how you do it.
Hello, Mia.
Your Mom told me
that this is your favorite.
Here.
It's not poison, I swear.
All right.
- I hope you like it.
- It's pretty tender.
- It's good.
- Really?
Niko, come on.
Glory, this is
Nelson. My boyfriend.
Nice to meet you, Nelson.
I'm Glory.
Go join them.
Go on.
I feel so young!
I learned from
the best, of course!
Thanks, Glory.
You know what? I do
Kegel exercises every day.
Can we have two, please?
- Quiet.
- I have an announcement.
Niko has been
promoted to supervisor.
Nice one.
- You can go back next week.
- Thank you.
I'm like a grandma,
scrubbing your back.
You're the only granny who
can scrub my back like this.
Shut up.
You better, or else!
Can I have a hug?
Oh no! Hold on!
How long have you been there?
- You look hot.
- You're pretty hot too.
You're all sweaty.
But you still smell good.
- What's your secret?
- I won't tell you.
And why not?
You smell good.
Stay there.
Oh God!
This is my first time
doing this, okay?
You know what, G?
You're the best
girlfriend I've ever had.
Well, that's because I
do everything you say.
- No, you don't.
- Yes, I do.
And you can teach
an old dog new tricks.
Okay, that's mean! I've
been nothing but nice to you!
But
you're the sweetest,
and
the most beautiful,
and the nicest.
And you always smell great.
You lucky man.
Aren't you glad you met me?
Now…
That look.
I love that about you.
Because that look you're
giving me right now?
That's how I know you
love me. I can feel it.
Why didn't you file
for an annulment?
It's expensive, and
Mike won't pay for it.
He says it's a waste of money.
I can help you with that.
How much would it cost?
Like,
how many lamps, cell phones,
or spare parts
do I have to sell before I
can finally call you mine?
Do you want to get married?
Yes!
I want to marry you.
I love you so much, Niko.
More than you'll ever know.
But…
Can we put our wedding
plans off for now?
Just until we're
financially stable?
Niko.
Look at me.
Let's not rush into this.
I want to know if my
business is sustainable.
If my business looks like it will
do well for the foreseeable future,
we can save up for that.
I'm not going anywhere, Niko.
I'm really sorry.
The owner's brother is
thinking of closing the store.
Don't worry, we still have
two months' worth of salaries.
I can recommend you to a friend.
He works at an
insurance company. Well?
Personally, I think
you'd get the job.
Think about it, okay?
- Excuse me.
- Thanks, sir.
Long day at work?
I'm sorry, Mia.
Niko's visiting his family,
and I'm going with him.
- I'll make it up to you next week, okay?
- Why can't you spare a day for me?
He's with you six days a week!
Thank you, but you
didn't have to. Really.
I'm only visiting
family, anyway.
You're supposed to
be with the kids today.
I talked to Mia already.
You need me here.
I guess saving up
will have to wait.
It's not your fault. Things
happen, you know?
You don't have to worry
about that right now, okay?
- I'm always here for you.
- I still have two months.
I'm sure I'll think
of something.
I know you will.
I believe in you.
- How are you all doing?
- Pretty good.
- Niko!
- Hello.
- How have you been?
- Hello!
I missed you!
- This is Glory.
- Hi.
Where's Grandma?
- She's downstairs.
- All right, thanks.
How old is your aunt?
- Fifty, I think. Why?
- Oh God…
I shouldn't have taken
her hand in greeting!
We're the same age!
It's fine, Glory. You look
much younger, anyway.
Grandma!
How are you?
You weren't here
for Bok's birthday.
I was too tired
from work, I'm sorry.
Wait, I'll introduce
you to my girlfriend.
- Hello.
- G…
This my grandma.
She's the one who raised me.
Every single thing you like about
me is all thanks to Grandma.
Your father wants
to see you, Niko.
I'll be back in a bit, Grandma.
What are you doing, Grandma?
This?
I'm sorting threads
so that tomorrow I
can start weaving.
Dear,
we don't have much.
The only wealth we have is our family,
the ties that bind us together.
I hope you treasure
family as much as we do.
Grandma.
I'll be visiting Dad, okay?
They just got
back from the field.
He's a bit upset that
I went straight here.
Sure, go ahead.
- We'll be back in a bit.
- All right.
- Come on, G.
- Have you had pinikpikan before?
They slaughtered a chicken,
so we're having that now.
I've had that dish
before in Baguio…
How long have you been together?
More than a couple
of months already.
Glory is special to me.
You'll get used to
things here in no time.
It's really nice
here, very quiet.
In these parts, young
people obey their elders.
You hear that, G? Over
here, we obey our elders.
But this one right here, oh!
Grandma always scolds him
because he drinks too much.
- No, I don't.
- Yes, you do.
How do you like it here?
It's nice.
I need to tell you something.
No PDA allowed here, okay?
Why?
Well, it's not
exactly forbidden, but
they don't approve of it either.
Why?
Why, why, why.
We'll talk about it later.
Excuse me.
You drank too much.
Try some pinikpikan.
- My husband made that.
- It's good.
How did your husband court you?
He didn't. It was
love at first sight.
Thank you.
How about you? Have
you experienced that?
It's time you do!
Your husband's a great cook.
No wonder you fell for him.
Yes, he is. He's a
skilled farmer too.
More importantly, he also helps out
with the household chores. And...
If you ask me,
I think it's better to have a family
with someone from our community.
But if that's not possible,
just make sure you
raise your family well,
and keep our traditions alive.
Now, dear,
I hope you can give
me plenty of grandkids.
Will you?
I don't think you're that
much older than Niko.
You should start planning now.
I can't wait to have
grandchildren too.
How many grandkids
do you want, Mom?
- Four!
- Excuse me.
- More?
- No, thank you.
Yes.
Excuse me, sorry.
You won't be able to make it.
She's overwhelmed.
Right?
You're sleeping in this room.
Are you mad at me, G?
Did I do something wrong?
I was up all night
chasing mosquitoes away.
- I was knocking on the window. Why didn...
- I didn't want to.
I know you're crazy about me.
Especially not in
front of your family.
No one would have known.
I would have.
I'm a mother, too, okay?
It won't happen again.
I'm getting off here.
God…
- You scared me!
- That's enough.
Why are you here?
Why do you think?
I know we had a
misunderstanding,
but you shouldn't have left me!
I said I was sorry, okay?
I waited for you at home!
"If you leave, make sure you come
back." That's what Grandma taught me!
You forgot about
that, obviously.
I was worried sick about you, G!
I couldn't even sleep!
So I came here.
- Why did you...
- Because I can't face you right now, Niko!
We can make love all we want,
but that will not change the
fact that I can't have a child!
We can't have a child.
Do you understand?
I'm fine with that.
I knew that from the
moment we got together.
I will always love you.
Child or no child.
Come home, please...
How about we adopt a kid, G?
My uncle was infertile, so
he and his wife adopted a kid.
It turned out well
for them in the end.
We'll see.
How about we adopt a
boy? A little Niko, if you will.
Let's call him Baldemor.
Baldemor? That's pretty unusual.
Right? It's the name
of one of our ancestors.
I see. Okay,
let's call him that.
Mom!
Hey, bro. Sorry about
this. Is Mom up yet?
Mia eloped with her boyfriend.
I'll take responsibility
for our kid.
My uncle told my Mom
about this, actually.
He told me Mom's coming
back home for the wedding.
We're planning to get
married in three months.
A simple wedding will be fine.
Mia?
What now?
Giro and I have
talked about this.
We're thinking of living together
at his place in the interim.
By the way, what did Dad say?
He'll be back by the end of the
month. He will talk to you then.
I'll get our stuff
ready. Excuse me.
Go on.
- Thank you.
- Thank you. Are you Mia's brother?
No, sir.
- I'll go help Mia.
- All right.
Do you love him?
I can't imagine
life without him.
Now,
you'll be the one making
your own decisions.
But can I just
ask for one thing?
Can you wait until
your father comes back?
Can you please
talk to him first?
I'll tell Giro.
Things happened so fast.
You'll be getting
married in three months.
And a few months after that,
you'll be a mother.
It's just so soon, Mia.
I wish you had taken your time.
But no matter what happens…
I will always be
here for you, Mia.
I'm your mother, and I love you.
I love you very much.
Hey there, handsome.
How was the wedding?
It was so romantic.
Even with the simple ceremony, I was
in tears. I've never felt so old.
- You'll be a grandma soon, that's why.
- Come off it, Niko!
Come here, my
beautiful, sexy grandma.
Man, you're heavy.
What are you thinking now?
Oh! I needed that.
That feels good.
Mike was there, right?
Yeah.
We sat next to each other.
We were pretty civil.
He didn't nag me or anything.
As long as Mike is around,
I can never truly
be part of your life.
Can we go back to my hometown?
What?
Mia has just got married.
Joey has a girlfriend.
Sam's married too.
Maybe life would be
better for us back home.
At least until I find a new job.
What is this really about, Niko?
I feel that I can be a
better husband back home.
Living here is expensive.
But my business is doing well.
My pottery shop just got a
lot of pre-orders. For my pots...
See? This is what I mean.
You've shouldered
everything this month.
I'm not okay with that, G.
Not at all.
I've made my decision.
Are you coming with me?
Do you just go along
with everything Niko says?
You're a married man.
Can you imagine life
without your wife by our side?
It's a small community,
but it's nice out here.
What's that?
Over here, everyone is family.
We're all involved
in each other's lives.
You can't hide anything here.
Like they say…
Here's your order.
And everyone is always
ready to lend a helping hand.
Auntie!
- Coffee?
- Thank you.
But that also means everyone
has an opinion about you.
Come on.
Now, that shouldn't stop
you from living your life.
You think so?
- I'll go get a coffee.
- All right.
Thanks.
Niko's been drinking all day.
Sorry about last night, G.
You drink a lot, Niko.
And I don't like it.
You were binge drinking.
Did you think I wouldn't
find out about it?
Is something wrong, Niko?
Maybe it's because…
Ever since we moved here,
all we've done is work.
We barely have any
time for each other, Glory.
We're together every day,
but we're always working.
Isn't that what you
wanted for both of us?
I agreed to this.
I adjusted for your sake.
- That was the plan, right?
- The plan was to save.
So that we can
finally be together.
G, tell me.
Are you still happy with me?
Niko!
- Someone's here to visit Glory.
- Who is it?
The neighbor thought
it was her boyfriend.
- Niko, he asked me… You know him?
- Sam!
He's Glory's son.
Your son was here earlier?
I didn't know you had a child.
I have three kids.
I hope you don't mind me asking,
but how old are you?
Grandma.
I don't think it...
It's not that!
I welcomed you into our family.
Now, I will never
dictate Niko's happiness.
But for you to hide the
fact that you have a son?
That you have a husband?
You should have
told me the truth!
Grandma,
I already told Mom and Dad.
Glory should've
told me this herself!
You chose to be here.
So, you should give us
the same respect
that we give you.
Why did you hide this from me?
I love Niko.
I don't want to lose him.
I know that
others do not approve
of our relationship.
But I'm hoping that we can prove to
them just how much we love each other.
It just happened.
I didn't choose to
love him. I just do.
But what he made me feel…
I've never felt that
way about anyone else.
My husband used to beat me up.
He cheated on me. He
hid that fact for nine years.
Choosing to rebuild our marriage
was one of the worst
decisions I ever made.
Back then, I thought.
I had nothing else to live for.
But when Niko came into my life…
Suddenly, I found
a reason to live.
I know that nothing in
this world will last forever.
Niko and I may
not end up together.
And I might not get
to grow old with him.
But I don't want to
live a life of regret.
That's why I chose
him, to be with him.
I've never felt as alive
since meeting him.
Am I wrong for
wanting to be happy?
Are you sure
your husband won't
come after my grandson?
He won't. I'll make sure of it.
I raised Nikolas.
Even when he was young, I knew he would
grow up to be a very bright young man.
Maybe that's why
Nikolas chose you.
Maybe that's why he
admires you so much.
Even back then,
I wanted him to be a good father
and carry on our traditions.
I wanted him to be with a woman
who could give him a family.
I just have one thing
to ask of you, Glory.
If you truly love him,
then you will let him become
the man he is meant to be!
You've lived a
long life already.
You already found
your place in this world.
You are a mother
yourself, Glory.
Your children need you
more than Nikolas does!
What happened?
You left without a word.
I felt dizzy, that's all.
You and Grandma fought.
Let's go home, Niko.
Let's go home, please.
Go home where?
- Back home, or back to Baguio?
- Anywhere but here!
Niko, please…
Anywhere but here.
Did they say anything?
You should have
just ignored them!
I can't do that!
They will never change
their minds about us!
You have to be strong,
Glory. For the both of us.
Why we're leaving,
why it came to this…
I just don't want to explain
things to Grandma anymore.
We cannot make people
change their minds about us.
Should we keep letting what other
people say about us control our lives?
I'm sick of hearing
what they think of us too!
But at least I have family here!
You will never go against
your grandma's wishes.
I know that.
Glory, please.
Grandma is the oldest
member of our clan.
And we should keep
our traditions alive.
I'm worried about her, Grandma.
She hasn't responded to
any of my calls and texts.
Niko,
she's a grown woman.
She can take care of herself.
Okay?
You have your whole
life ahead of you.
Those who leave…
Must make sure
they come back home.
If she truly loves you,
she will come back.
Wow! Glory, congratulations!
Come here!
Wow, you look so much alike!
Doesn't he?
Hey! Sam is here!
Sam!
Here they are! Hello. Mom!
Hello, Sam!
I've missed you, bro!
- Make a silly face!
- A silly face now?
Glory!
Look at this!
Isn't it nice?
You forgot the bag, Sam!
Where's...
Lito, can you
help him with that?
Be careful.
Come on.
That's it!
Come here, little one.