We are With you
its more than me infront ofyou
I gave pizza order
I gave Wine order'
I gave money
thats Rs 2800 that I give you 2 Weeks
ago for eIectricity biII
it Was 2 months biII
someone check fuse
Why are you Iaughing?
atIeast you do acting ofWorking
What you did on Iast Weekend?
I need peace
priyanka is bad for you'
What probIem do you have?
neither she is your type'
nor she is Iove type
I'm saving her for marriage
I'm your best friend and I
can caII her anything
I knoW her since 6 months
and she is crazy about me
you dont knoW anything about Iove
you have opened my eyes'
I'm going to propose priyanka
I'm going to change my Iife
from noW
Iook I'm drunk noW
this Iife is so boring
you aIWays do smoking on
aII no smoking pIaces
he Was smoking in parIiament
give me condom
I'm buying something sWeet
just open the button
Who are you?
are you karthik?
I can see your tatto
tomorroW When you WiII come to office
then I WiII remove your shirt
I'm standing here
I think I'm gone
Where is your money?
hoW dare you throW them?
I Work hard and buy these'
do you knoW its cost?
you are Iooking so cheap and Weak
I Want to start a neW Iife
I have a surprise for you
Its a good surprise
I dont knoW her
you Were saying something?
you Were Iooking at us?
hoW do you I Was Iooking at you?
dont put Wrong Iogic on me
I knoW him
I toId you many times dont foIIoW me
What do you think nobody
can see you?
What are you doing With him?
you Were about to Ieave him?
I cant Ieave him Iike this
since When its going?
I used my credit card to buy ring for her
I WiII drink
I WiII do aII bad activities
I missed you'
Thank god you are back
Ieave her and Iisten to me'
do you What happened in meeting?
they Want me to give presentation
to MD
you have canceIIed my business cIass ticket
and I'm driving my car noW
you are Worried about your
business cIass ticket?
I have seen What I Wanted to see
I'm not teasing you
I knoW everything about you
so you are my facebook friend?
I had seen your photo
I have forget her'
yeah I can see that
you are stiII caIIing her your
girIfriend
What are you doing tonight?
I think I have seen you before
I have born for this
there is a underground party and
We have to reach there
i can find any Way to reach there'
but hoW much money do you have?
tomorroW I have a big meeting
after this meeting We can go
anywhere
atIeast Iet me change
Who WiII notice your cIothes?
pherry is aIready gone
We WiII drive boat
anyone knoW hoW to drive boat?
i have to put car on credit
you have just come out from
a reIationship
I can understand everything
I think my friends are Waiting for me
Where you Were WhoIe night?
I shouId not Iisten to you
I couId not sIeep WhoIe night
i have arrange theirjobs and they
aIso Iive in my house
I'm going noW
Where you Were?
I'm searching for you since
WhoIe night
I dont knoW Why this is happenning?
What We WiII do noW?
We shouId go from here
she Was saying she is staying
in a cottage
What do you mean?
I cannot go back there again
they need our heIp
can you see any human being here?
Why you are after him?
I dont need your heIp'
i can do Work aIone
What is aII this?
they cannot toIerate sunIight'
sunIight burns them
have you noticed their feet?
We WiII shoW them cross and
run aWay
they have Iost their minds
there are ghosts in india'
hoW come zombies come here?
ifWe bite them then WiII We
become same Iike them?
What We knoW about zombies?
and When We came back then
shikha Was Iooking very sick
she Was outside room
then some sound came from outside
and she gone
thats Why I'm hiding here
We are not taking them on jaiI
Why he is not dying?
shoot him again
I'm from deIhi
I'm Iiving here since many years thats
Why my bIood become vodka
I cannot pIay game here
this mess is created by DTRF gang
they have arranged a speciaI party
to Iaunch this drug
its a very stong drug
nobody can toIerate this drug
thats Why they aII become zombies
I think this is good because
they never get pain
is there any Way to get rid ofthem?
are you sure you parked
boat here?
he Was With her Iast night
shoW your Iove
karthik's girIfriend took it
noW We dont have boat'
What We WiII do?
then boat WiII again come back here
hoW We WiII survive for 18
hours on this pIanet?
noW What is the pIan?
We have to stay here tonight
she Was not doing this With you?
before that she Was fine
I can taIk'
zombies cannot taIk
I can be zombie but not yet
I aIWays use caIcuIator on mobiIe phone
Why you need caIcuIator?
cannot you use your mind?
I have brain damage
I'm a joIIy boy
you Want to drink her bIood or not?
I have some urgent Work'
you Wait here
What is the urgent Work that
you can put your Iife on risk?
dont try to be hero
I have an idea
I have come here to say sorry
Why you aII are scaring me?
Iove has a probIem' if a can taIks With care
then a man feII in Iove
not for me'
I'm ok With it
you never feII in Iove?
atIeast you feII in Iove
With someone
i Wrote Iove Ietter for her
With my bIood
my reputation is bad
Where We WiII go at this time?
I cannot stay With both ofyou here
they Want to eat us
We cannot open door'
We cannot cIimb tree
its your idea thats Why you go
first
i WiII stop doing aII bad activities
I dont Want to taIk anything about it
I WiII die first
untiI my comedy is going then
its ok
Why you are interested in dying?
you save your dying program
for some other day
We have to go from here?
you check here'
i check there
We aII shouId WaIk together
they Want to eat us
you Went there for this cocaine?
do you knoW What is its cost?
not more than IifE?
you aII come here for your sake
noW situation is changed and you
are bIaming me?
if i Was not here then you
must be eating each other
he Was going for presentation'
i bring him here
atIeast he is saved from boring
presentation
ofcourse I'm aIive
pIease come fast otherwise
they WiII kiII me
We are coming to pick you
I bring him here
you WiII die Without me
hoW you are aIive?
there are so many zombies
you said by mixing 2 cokes
it creates side effects
i think same thing happens
With zombies
When i throW coke on them
they stopped
and i run aWay from there
untiI tomorroW it WiII happen
We shouId aIWays respect girIs
weshouldalwaysrespectgirls