I've often dreamed of ringing
in the New Year with my dad.
But I never imagined
it could end up like this.
After seeing what was going on
And understanding it
Now she acts as if nothing happened
I don't know
I don't understand how
Neither how nor why
My ego opened a wound
That you must be aware of
You see? I'm right
I've waited long enough for this talk
It catches my attention
That you've chosen this moment
To confess to me
That you thought I was heartless
We both know it
Each to their own game
I don't know if it was fate or our paths
That brought us together
We both know it
We are what we do
And there's no hatred
That can't be changed with love
Love, love, love
NETFLIX PRESENTS
This place is fantastic!
It looks exactly like the pictures online.
I love it!
Excuse me, Miss, you have to wait in line
like the rest of the guests.
What kind of service is this?
Mom!
What's going on?
Where have you brought me?
To a regular place where you wait in line
like everybody else.
I'm sorry. Excuse us.
Please, don't start making a fuss
about everything.
I don't want to be kicked out of the hotel
like in Paris.
Friendy, easy. I mean, relax.
We are in an amazing hotel with your mom.
We're going to have a great time. Relax!
I just wanted to be treated like I should.
No, no!
That's Crash! And Lady Ant!
And Kayky, the Brazilian singer!
I love him!
-He can't see me like this. I'm a mess!
-Toco Para Vos are here too.
I can't believe it! This is too much!
It's amazing!
I told you! It was obvious!
We are in one of the best hotels
with the most trendy and top celebrities,
such as Jesse &amp; Joy,
who, surely, are throwing a private party.
This will be my best ever New Year's.
Wanna know why?
-Why?
-Because Mía isn't here.
Friends forever
We know what it feels like
Hey,
you could've told your sister
to bring her whole wardrobe.
You know her.
She changes her clothes 15 times a day.
Fortunately, my mom...
brought just one.
We'll need another cart.
Just one? We'll need 27 more!
Wait. Hold on.
You do, since this belongs
to your mom and sister.
Okay, I get it.
I'm spending New Year's
with the clowns Nicoleto and Juan Marulo.
I'll be back.
Who's texting you so much?
Is it Mía?
And why do you care?
I don't, but I'm sure Álvaro does.
I am friends with Mía.
Álvaro and Mía are siblings.
No, they aren't, Juanma. And you know it.
They are to Mercedes.
She's stubborn.
She doesn't want them to be close.
But this won't change
how Álvaro feels about Mía.
What's going on with Mía?
Nothing, this just looks exactly
like Mía's suitcase.
-Yeah.
-You think I'm stupid?
No, but now that I think of it...
You have a lot of suitcases
and I just have two.
Álvaro, listen to me.
Why don't you use this trip
as a chance to distance yourself from Mía?
And to relax. We're on vacation!
You're right. Mía isn't here.
-Let's go in.
-Yes.
Hey.
Wait for me!
We're here! Finally!
-Hello, vacation!
-Safe and sound!
A ticket to happiness!
My baby!
-We're here.
-Mr. Achával.
-Welcome. I'm the hotel manager.
-Thank you.
-Nice to meet you.
-First of all, I wanted to apologize.
You booked our other hotel
and we had to cancel.
-We had to close it due to the storm.
-That's right.
So we had to reaccommodate our guests.
Don't worry, it's exactly the same for us.
It took you an entire day
to bring the suitcases.
Yes, your employees are very slow.
-Do you want us to carry you, too?
-Don't give her any ideas, please.
Calm down, please.
Let's start our vacation peacefully.
Is that possible? Thanks.
I'm worried about Lupe.
She's tense.
What do you expect?
Her father took his new daughter
on vacation.
Don't put it like that.
Why do you complicate things with Ramiro?
Your rooms are ready, so you don't need
to check in at the reception desk.
That's great.
And, please, enjoy your stay here.
-We will!
-Thank you!
We're throwing a big New Year's Eve party
for our guests.
New house, new daughter, new girlfriend.
-Girlfriend?
-What?
-What do you know?
-You said it. I know nothing.
That would be the last straw.
A new girlfriend
and he wants to keep what's mine.
No, look. You got to keep the house,
you're negotiating about the school.
Yeah, we'll see. He's capable of anything.
I can't believe we're spending
our first New Year together.
-Neither can I.
-And you let me invite Zoe!
You're the best dad ever!
-My darling!
-Yes, Ramiro, you're great.
Thanks for inviting me.
I promise to be a good girl.
It makes me very glad
seeing you both like this. Happy.
I know this isn't easy for you.
Don't worry. We came here
to have a good time and to relax,
so let's just worry about that.
-Okay?
-Perfect.
Got everything?
-Wait, my backpack!
-All right.
Mía!
How long did he hide
that he had another daughter?
How long?
Wasn't it the other way around?
It doesn't matter.
We're here with the kids
to welcome the New Year
peacefully and happily.
You're right. We're far away from Ramiro.
Kids, let's go, please.
Wow! It's amazing!
-A margarita, sir.
-Oh, thank you.
-And fruit juice for the girls. Enjoy it.
-Thanks!
This is the coolest!
I love this place, Zoe!
And it will be even more fun
when Simón arrives.
-Great.
-Did he say he was here?
Yes, he has a vacation job here.
Why are you smiling?
Who is it? Álvaro?
-Juanma.
-What? I can't believe it.
Stop. We won't talk about Juanma
or Álvaro during our vacation.
Let's focus on New Year's Eve
and having fun
with my dad and my best friend.
-Let's go.
-Okay.
You're wearing every possible color.
I need to light up the beach.
-I'm starving.
-Yes, I could eat an elephant.
-Have you seen Lupe?
-No, I haven't seen Mía.
-You're so annoying.
-You mean Lupe, right?
Yes, Lupe.
But you said Mía.
You're talking to her again.
And what if I am?
Does that bother you?
Stop it, guys. Can we have some peace?
Let's go to the beach to relax.
Is it here?
-It's here!
-Yes! Breakfast, finally!
But...
I'm not seeing any food.
No, Agustina, Jesse &amp; Joy were here,
on this very spot,
with this palm tree, under this sun.
-Let me see.
-They even swam!
Are you serious?
That picture is old! It's from yesterday!
I can't believe it.
The flight was endless,
I'm hungry, and we are here
because of an old picture?
Are you listening to yourself?
Jesse &amp; Joy were here!
What's more important than that?
Oh, no.
You were obsessed with Mía
all year long,
and now you're obsessed with Joy.
I can't believe it! I'm going to eat!
I knew I should have brought Sofía
instead of you.
Look, Sofía wouldn't have come
because she needed a break from you.
Agustina!
Simón told you he was here?
I can't find him anywhere.
I don't see him either.
What's wrong, Zoe?
-You look like you've seen a ghost.
-Worse.
I hate mascot costumes.
They make me feel like boxing.
Don't exaggerate!
Make him go away!
Calm down, Zoe.
-And he's provoking me!
-Zoe!
No! Zoe!
-Simón!
-Yes, it's me!
-Hi, girls! Tudo bem?
-Hi, Simón!
How are you?
Zoe, you're still afraid of mascots
like when we were kids.
-You scared me! It's not funny.
-You're crazy.
Now that we're together,
this is going to be
the best New Year ever!
Yes!
So peaceful!
And relaxation. This is heaven, my friend.
Sometimes you need to get away
to get some quiet.
-Yes.
-Hi, guys.
-Hello.
-Good morning.
Why the long faces?
Don't you realize you're in paradise?
This place is great, Dad!
We've just seen the pool, and it's huge!
And we heard people talking about
the New Year's Eve party
and Giulia Be is singing!
-That's great!
-Thank you for bringing us here.
Did you eat something bad?
You're unbearable.
Juanma ate a clown this morning.
Let's leave clowns out of it.
I've been afraid of them since--
Don't you get tired of fighting every day?
-We just arrived!
-Let them be.
If they want to ruin their summer,
it's their problem.
Nothing will keep me
from smiling like this.
-Good morning.
-Hi!
-Are you hungry?
-Yes.
-Hi, Simón!
-Bom dia. Tudo bem?
What are you doing here?
Aren't you the mascot?
I'm multitasking.
I'm the mascot, I'm a waiter...
And I teach aqua dance lessons.
You're multi-functional.
I hope you can find some time
for your friends.
Of course.
-Shall we have breakfast?
-Yes, let's go.
Coffee or milk?
Aqua dance?
Is this the cheese you like, honey?
-Yes, I want some.
-There.
It's all tasty. I don't know what to eat.
Well, let's eat!
You can't begin to imagine
how much I needed this vacation, sweetie.
With nobody to disturb us.
A vacation from Mía, basically.
Nothing will get between us
in this haven of happiness.
Those are delicious.
You!
What are you doing here?
You took a flight
to ruin New Year's Eve for me?
-I didn't know you were here.
-Yeah, right.
-If you picked up your phone...
-Now it's my fault?
-It's nobody's fault.
-What?
You stole my dad
and now you want to steal my trip.
Lupe! Come on!
Defending your new daughter, as usual.
-Hi, Ramiro.
-Hi, Álvaro.
Álvaro!
She's your sister.
-She's not, Mom!
-Yes, she is.
Do not cross the security perimeter.
What are you talking about?
Ramiro, pack your things
and go, please.
No way!
It's New Year's Eve tomorrow.
Besides, this place is huge.
We won't bump into one another.
Leave immediately!
Calm down, Lu.
If we all do our part,
there shouldn't be any trouble.
Okay, perfect.
We are leaving then.
-What?
-No! They should leave!
All right, then.
Okay.
We're staying, but with one condition.
You two... keep your distance.
I don't want you close to Mía, Álvaro.
Otherwise,
we'll be on the next plane out of here.
-What are you saying, Mom?
-A plane!
-I can't believe this.
-Neither can I!
You have a great talent
for screwing things up, Mía.
-Lupe, don't go!
-Mía, wait.
Hey, what did your mom say?
If you get close to her...
-A plane.
-I have to talk to her.
-No, not now.
-Please, Álvaro.
She's mad. Give her time.
Mía!
Hi!
Nobody wants to ruin your New Year.
Sure. Why would you bother?
You've ruined my whole life.
-It doesn't have to be this way.
-No.
-It would be great if you weren't here.
-But here I am.
Yes, here, at school, in GO!
Where else do you want to be?
And on the stage, right?
But that doesn't bother you that much.
Do you remember the song we were writing?
I finished it.
-I don't care. Leave me alone.
-Listen.
I told you I don't care. Leave!
You're so annoying!
Sun, sand and sea
It could be a dream
But here we are
I don't want to hear it.
What has been good is a memory now
And what has been bad
Will teach us.
Even though we're different
Like oil and water
I know that if we're together
We are more
You supplement everything I need
And what you lack
I can give it to you
You're like me
Because you know what you want
You want like me
When you know what you want
If we talk, it isn't that bad
We don't need to talk
If there's nothing to discuss
You're like me
Because you know what you want
You want like me
When you know what you want
If we talk, it isn't that bad
We don't need to talk
If there's nothing to discuss
I know sometimes you want me to stay away
Really far away.
But in that moment
I want to hug you
If you could only see the way I see you
You'd be afraid
And fear makes you fail
I know we're different
-Hot and cold
-North and south, east and west
-Our paths can't cross
-Black and white, fire and snow
But we're the same in the end
You're like me
Because you know what you want
You want like me
When you know what you want
If we talk, it isn't that bad
We don't need to talk
If there's nothing to discuss
Okay, Mía, don't be cheesy now.
We are sisters.
Well, half sisters, but sisters in music.
I know you feel that magical connection
we have when we sing together.
That's true. But I can't stand you.
Friends?
Not enemies. But only for the time being.
That's a new start.
Could you do something for me?
Of course.
Pack your things and leave.
This won't end well.
Excuse me.
-Is Lupe here?
-Yes.
Good.
What are you doing here?
We need to talk, daughter.
No, we don't.
And stop calling me "daughter."
Is this how it's going to be from now on?
Now you have another daughter
who you love more.
You're spending New Year's Eve with her.
You didn't want to come with us.
You mean with "you."
There's no "us" anymore.
Please, Lupe, honey.
I know this is hard for you.
-For everyone.
-You don't know what I'm going through.
Come on, baby.
Don't call me that. I'm not five anymore.
And if someone hears you,
I'll be embarrassed.
You'll always be my baby girl.
The one with the most beautiful eyes
in the world.
With shiny hair.
Do you remember
the liters of imaginary tea
that we drank dressed as ladies?
Do you remember?
And all the routines you made me dance?
Sweetie...
we'll always be us, you know?
I know.
But I need time to digest this.
It's not easy.
I know.
We all need some time.
All of us.
I love you, honey.
What are you doing here?
I'm talking to my daughter, Mercedes.
-Sleep well, darling.
-Thanks, Dad.
-Good night.
-You too.
Sweetie.
Are you okay?
Yes, thank you.
-Come here. Help.
-What is it?
The paparazzi, there.
-Would you hug me?
-Yes.
There they are!
Thank you! You saved my life.
Aren't you...
-Meri from Toco Para Vos?
-Yes.
And you?
-Juanma. There's a song I love.
-Which one?
-I love it.
-You have a great voice.
-Thanks.
-I know you from somewhere.
I don't think so.
Aren't you in the group
from the final of Nationals?
GO! Yes, we got second place.
-I watched it online. You're amazing.
-Thanks.
I love that song that goes...
I'm not afraid to love
Love is stronger
-I can't believe it.
-Yes, I love it.
I don't know how to thank you for this.
Don't worry. Just call me
if you need a fake boyfriend.
-I sure will.
-Meri! Are you okay?
Yes, Jairo, thanks to Juanma.
-You saved us, brother.
-Hi.
I'm Jairo.
PR for the guys and other bands.
The party!
-Should we invite him?
-Yes!
We're having a private party today
with Jesse &amp; Joy.
-At the beach. You can come if you want.
-We'll be playing there.
-Cool! Sure.
-Hand me your phone.
-I'm saving my number.
-Great.
And the party information.
-Great. Thanks.
-Bring whoever you want.
-See you there!
-Bye!
No!
Thanks for scaring me.
I'm sorry.
I just wanted to make you smile.
What a mess, right?
Yes, but let's have a peaceful New Year,
please.
That's the only thing I want.
And I'd like to know what will happen
with us when we go back.
What are you two doing?
If Mercedes catches you...
Don't be mean.
-Mercedes!
-Could you just stop it?
No, she's really coming! Get down!
Juanma.
Have you seen Álvaro?
No.
Me neither.
Please tell him
that I left his sunblock on the chair.
Okay, I'll tell him.
I'll look around.
You look gorgeous under the sun.
You should...
Should I? Really?
Yes, come on.
Is she gone?
She left a while ago.
I can't believe this.
Ramiro is talking to a woman.
That's the person I'll be fighting
for my possessions.
Ramiro's little girlfriend.
Girlfriend? He met her five minutes ago.
She's the windsurf instructor.
Flor, can you see her
as Lupe and Álvaro's stepmother?
No.
This is absurd.
After me, Ramiro should be with a more...
Sane, sensible, and rational woman?
Let me listen.
Ramiro! We hadn't seen you here.
No, we hadn't seen you
or that girl you're talking to.
We're discussing
if she's your new girlfriend or what--
Oh, this place is wonderful.
It has some lovely flora and fauna.
-Mature ladies...
-What?
Distinguished ladies
playing hide and seek.
Or are you following me?
Come on, Ramiro!
Quite the contrary,
I think you're looking for an excuse to--
To captivate women who teach water sports.
Come on.
Couldn't we call a truce?
Please.
-We'll talk when we're back home.
-Okay.
Bye!
Honestly, my friend,
you have such bad luck.
To end up at the same hotel
as Álvaro, Lupe, and Mercedes.
Zoe, I can't believe how good you are
at cheering me up.
Wow! Your phone is blowing up!
It's Juanma. He's invited me
to Jesse &amp; Joy's party.
We're going to Jesse &amp; Joy's party!
Awesome, my friend.
Oh, right. He's only invited you.
Yes. And you can't say a word
to anyone, okay?
Are you texting Mía?
Álvaro, my mom does let me talk to her.
Okay?
Álvaro or Juanma?
Álvaro, Juanma, Álvaro.
We could use this for a song.
Yes!
They're driving me nuts!
I'm turning it off and going to ask my dad
if I can go to the party.
Sure, he'll let you!
Why wouldn't he?
I can think of a million reasons.
Zoe, you're infecting me
with such bad vibes today.
It's not funny.
-What did you do? She's not replying.
-What's wrong? Are you jealous?
Yes, you are.
Look, guys.
I sense some tension here.
Let's relax, okay?
We can go to the spa or the gym...
No, not the gym. It has a boxing ring.
I'm going for a walk.
Okay.
I'm sure he's going to see Mía.
Hey, Álvaro,
you're obsessed with Mía.
If she's in love with you,
you'll end up together.
Juanma won't stop you. Nobody will.
You've done everything but chase her
in a costume, so your mom can't see you.
Sweetie! I was about to call you.
They're showing one of my favorite
musicals at the hotel cinema.
It's a classic. You'll love it.
And I was about to tell you
that I've been invited to a party today.
A party? Here at the hotel?
No, it's a private party at the beach
thrown by Jesse &amp; Joy!
A private party somewhere I don't know
outside the hotel?
Honestly, I don't know.
I guess you're all going together.
You, Simón and Zoe?
No. This time it's just me and Juanma.
Honey, I understand you're excited,
but what you're asking for is crazy.
-Dad!
-Honey...
Am I not old enough to go to a party?
I'm just asking you
to have a little bit of trust in me.
This is not about trust.
You're asking to go
to a party somewhere I don't know
and full of strangers.
Besides, tomorrow it's the hotel party
and we're welcoming the New Year
together for the first time.
Come on, Dad!
Mía, please. End of discussion.
I know...
Would you like some water?
Okay.
Well, it looks like
you're having a hard time.
You can't imagine
how much I needed this massage.
Where's Mía?
-Speak of the devil.
-I need your help!
Look, it's okay if you want to see Álvaro,
but leave us out of it.
This is not about him.
I want to go to Jesse &amp; Joy's party
but my dad won't let me.
-Trouble!
-No, no.
Not only are we not invited,
but she also wants to get us in trouble.
-For her.
-No, no.
But I also know you're the best friends
in the world
and that you'll help me go to this party.
That's a yes. I'm getting changed! Bye!
You said yes, Zoe?
Trouble, trouble.
Isn't that Lupe and Agus?
Yes, that's right.
I was so calm without you guys here!
And now I have to put
that horrible mascot costume back on.
Bye, Zoe.
Wait! I can't keep up.
You see?
The only thing I see here, Lupe,
is that you are the problem.
Can't you see
she keeps taking what's mine?
Don't you get it?
And what's yours this time?
Jesse &amp; Joy's party.
Jesse &amp; Joy's party, exactly. Not yours.
Agustina, my place is at that party.
Okay.
Let me remind you of something.
You can't always get what you want.
Simón, we need to find Mía urgently.
Where are you?
Hey, come here, ugly mascot.
Come here. We need to tell Mía
that Lupe knows she's going
to Jesse &amp; Joy's party with Juanma.
The last thing we need now, Simón,
is for--
-For Álvaro to find out, right?
-No, no.
-Got it, Zoe.
-Come here, Álvaro!
One, two, three, four...
Hi!
Are you okay, Juanma?
Yes, you just look gorgeous.
-Yes, but we're friends.
-I know.
And as your friend,
I'm gonna ask you a favor.
Close your eyes.
Trust me. Close your eyes.
Open them.
No!
I rented a limo!
No! Let's go now!
Excuse me, could you get me
a taxi, a horse, anything?
-Thanks.
-I won't go on a horse.
You're not going anywhere.
You're the one who's not going anywhere.
I'll have to tell Mom, and you...
Plane.
Do I have a choice?
Wait, Lupe. If he won't take us,
we can go on foot.
It was just a suggestion.
I'll go change. I'll be right back.
Wait, I have a question.
Obviously we're the guests of honor
at this party.
Always worrying about details.
Is it a detail to know how on earth
we can get into Jesse &amp; Joy's party?
Relax!
We're getting in
if it's the last thing I do.
And?
Nothing. She's not answering.
It must be really noisy at the party.
Can we talk, Mía?
What do we do?
-Get into bed.
-No, you do it.
No, Simón! You!
No. Let's play rock-paper-scissors.
Rock, paper, scissors.
-To bed, Mía.
-Okay, I'm going.
Open up!
-Hi, Ramiro.
-I need to speak to my daughter.
-Yes, but we are--
-Thank you very much.
Sweetie.
Can we talk, honey?
What are you doing under there?
Don't be ridiculous.
Maybe give her some time.
-Mía, listen to me.
-No.
Are you okay?
Let's move on.
All right?
And let's think about the future.
Let's think about
our first New Year's Eve together.
It's going to be amazing.
Okay.
-Talk to her.
-I will.
Advice from a friend is more effective.
Sure.
-Come here.
-That was close, Zoe!
-Yes. Come on.
-Text Mía right now.
I'm on it, Simón.
Wow, this place is amazing!
-Toco Para Vos are playing. I love them!
-I told you.
Hey!
-How you doing, man?
-What's up?
-Enjoy the party.
-Thanks.
That was Kayky. I love him!
And best of all,
Jesse &amp; Joy are playing next!
I love it! Let's go dance!
Hi all! Welcome to my party.
I hope you have fun.
And now let's hear it for my sister Joy.
I can't believe Jesse &amp; Joy
are playing in front of us.
-It's amazing.
-I told you you had to come.
Let's keep dancing.
-I'll go get us something to drink.
-Okay.
-Here we are.
-The party's in there.
How do we get in?
Crash is about to arrive.
Let her in, please.
She's playing in a few minutes.
Okay.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
I'm thinking what I'm thinking.
I came up with it.
I don't need accomplices.
I'm awesome.
-Hi. Don't you know who I am?
-No.
-Crash.
-I'm not doing this.
I'm playing soon and you won't let me in?
You'll ruin the party
and Jesse &amp; Joy will get mad.
Who are they?
My assistant and my stylist.
Hi!
I'm sorry about that.
Thank you.
Thanks.
They'll figure it out. You're both crazy.
You're always such a killjoy.
That won't get you anywhere.
It's only because I have a mad friend.
Are you okay with this?
Don't ask me. I'm just the stylist, Agus.
-See you.
-What?
Copy that. Crash is here.
Her stylist.
Nico!
-No! Come here.
-Where are you going? Don't move.
No! I see trouble coming
and I need some peace.
You won't find it here.
-Try a different hotel.
-What happened?
Álvaro went to the party
with Juanma and Mía.
-No!
-Yes.
How did he find out?
-Zoe--
-It's a long story. What do we do now?
-I'll go back to work.
-No.
Mercedes and Ramiro
can't find out about this.
-Yes, absolutely.
-Yes.
Guys!
What's wrong?
Have you seen an alien?
-I haven't seen Álvaro. Have you?
-No, neither have I.
How did you know
I was going to ask about him?
Because I have mind powers.
I see things.
Great, use them to tell me
why he's not answering his phone.
I saw him dressed as a mascot
and he found out everything.
-Everything?
-And he rushed to the party.
What?
It's just that Simón has to dance today
at the pool party.
That's it!
And your son is pretty funny, right?
He wanted to play a joke on Simón,
so he hid his costume.
-My costume!
-Now we can't find it.
That costume! Well, if you see him,
tell him I'm looking for him.
-Right...
-Away.
Right away.
This is the best party I've ever been to.
I told you you'd have fun.
Don't look at me like that.
-Like what?
-Like that.
Like this?
What if I break my promise?
Watch out!
-I'm sorry.
-No!
Are you okay?
I'm... soaking wet.
No...
No! What happened?
Nothing. It was that guy...
You helped me at the hotel.
-I'll get you clean clothes. Follow me.
-I'll wait here.
-Mía! What are you doing here?
-What are you doing here?
Juanma brought you here
and left you alone? That's not cool.
Why don't we dance together then?
It's great music.
Don't be so boring!
Even though we think it's crazy...
Let's do what your mom says.
It's the only way to keep the peace.
Even though it's hard for me...
I say no.
And what if I say yes?
If I tell you I can't do it?
That it's harder than scoring
without looking at the hoop?
We'll have to try.
What? Is it easy for you?
I don't buy it.
Mía, are you dating Juanma?
What?
You text each other, you come
to this party together... I don't know.
Juanma is my friend.
Just like you.
-Any news, Nico?
-No.
It's impossible.
Álvaro is not answering.
Mercedes keeps looking for him.
I don't know how to hide this.
With anything but the mascot costume.
Excuse me, guys.
Mía won't come down to eat?
-No, she's resting.
-She fell asleep.
I'll go get her.
-Okay.
-You won't find her.
All right, so, when Ramiro comes back,
we tell him that Mía was here
and left again, okay?
-Perfect.
-Yes, you're a genius!
-Great idea.
-Mercedes is coming.
-Álvaro!
-Where?
-Listen, I needed to ask you something.
What?
Do you know what time
they're screening that UFO movie?
Nicolás, do I look like
an alien movie person?
But it's a musical!
-You love musicals!
-Where is he?
He went that way.
-Where?
-He went that way, but he did this.
And now, I really don't know where he is.
Guys, it's time to call Lupe.
-Hi, Nico. What's up?
-Where are you?
At Jesse &amp; Joy's private party...
Who's this?
-Zoe. Don't hang up.
-It's Zoe.
What do you need?
Do you know where Álvaro is?
No, and I don't see him around here.
Why am I talking to you? Bye.
Look who's coming.
No, I can explain it.
It was just a mix-up.
Crash, they're waiting for you.
Crash.
I need your help.
Give this to the DJ. It's my track.
-Yes, I'll do it for you, pop star.
-I have her.
-Thank you.
-Excuse me.
-Where do you think you're going?
-I'm singing. It's late, let me in.
Who are you?
Crash.
I've just let her in.
How is that possible?
-What's going on?
-He says he already let Crash in.
No, you're mistaken.
I'm sorry, but she can't come in.
Don't worry.
Let me make a phone call. We'll fix this.
Hi! How are you?
You know who I am
I don't need an introduction
You speak badly of me
You say I'm the worst
But in the end you want to be just like me
One, two, three
They say I'm cold
And extremely conceited
That I wouldn't be here
If it weren't for my parents
That I'm selfish and boring
That I only have two friends
That I'm not cool anymore
And that my outfit is dull
You get together to criticize me
But I know you want to copy me
I know you look at my Instagram stories
You know them by heart
I know who I am no matter what they say
Those who criticize me
Have no choice
Love me or hate me, I'm beyond compare
You'll apologize even if you don't want to
In the end, you want to be just like me
Your envy is what makes me go on
I don't waste any time
I know what I want
No hater can stop me
I know where I'm going
In the end, you want to be just like me
Your envy is what makes me go on
I don't waste any time
I know what I want
No hater can stop me
I know where I'm going
Is that Lupe?
How did she get in?
It's a long story.
-And full of lies probably.
-Yes, that too.
You want to be like me
Bravo, Lu!
Can we talk now, Mía?
No, please.
But I say yes. Please, come with me.
Let's go.
Any news, Nico?
No. I don't know what to do.
Look, Lupe hasn't seen them,
nobody answers the phone,
Juanma, Álvaro, and Mía together...
This is a mess!
Are you there, Álvaro?
It's Mercedes.
What should we do?
-Hold on.
-What do we do?
Go into the bedroom. Come on.
The costume.
Hide the costume.
-Okay.
I know!
Pretend you're Álvaro. Put that away
and get into the bathroom, quickly!
The bathroom!
Son!
Yes, I'm coming, Mercedes!
What do I do?
Hide in the shower!
In the shower? Okay.
-Yes, here.
-This is insane!
-What if she comes in?
-She won't if her son is showering.
Oh, right. What? Showering?
-That's right.
-No, I'm not showering!
No!
Thanks! I'll sign an autograph
and we'll take some pictures.
They loved me. Do you love me?
I love you! You were great!
-Congratulations!
-Thank you.
I'm terrific, very talented.
-What's wrong? They wanted one more song.
-No, no.
Take this off.
You pretended to be me
to sing in my place?
-Hi.
-Where's my son?
-Well, if I explain it, you'll laugh.
-No, don't.
Your explanations don't explain a thing.
Where's Álvaro?
In the shower.
Are you there, son?
Yes!
That's it, he's taking a shower.
Your son is so--
Son...
Grandma Vilma sends her regards.
Send her a kiss from me.
There's no Grandma Vilma in our family.
Who's in there?
Well... No, wait--
Álvaro!
Hi, Mercedes!
Dear Headmistress, how are you?
Tudo bem?
Could you pass me a towel?
Where's my son?
He's at Jesse &amp; Joy's party.
I can explain.
And who are you?
Her stylist. I mean, her PR--
No, she's my assistant.
It was a mistake,
I didn't mean to impersonate you.
It was just a mix-up.
-Come with me, please.
-Agustina.
Hi? Mercedes?
Oh, no.
Please, don't start.
I don't know what to do
To get you out of my mind
I don't know.
Every time I see you go by
All right.
I lose track of the minutes, the hours
Days go by with the sun
I feel how my heart dances
I don't want to lose you
I want to be with you
Tell me that you love me
Sing the song
If you say yes
I say no
If I say no
I say yes
Nothing can come between us
I knew it when I met you
I say no.
You're the star of all my dreams
I don't know how to hide it anymore
Here I am
-Here you are
-You're not going anywhere
It's not like you promised me the moon
Or dried the seas up
I don't want to lose you
I want to be with you
Tell me that you love me
Sing the song
If you say yes
I say no
If I say no
I say yes
Nothing can come between us
I knew it when I met you
What a lovely song.
What a lovely shirt you're wearing.
This? It was you, right?
What are you talking about?
-A waiter got me all wet.
-No!
You got wet?
Yes, and when I come back,
I find you playing the ukulele.
Yes, I borrowed it from the guys.
-And we started singing.
-Please, don't start arguing.
We are not arguing. He started it.
-Aren't you ashamed?
-Of what?
-You think Mía likes you. Is that it?
-No, she likes you, right?
We were singing and you appeared.
Where's Mía?
You're selfish
and you always blame other people.
And what about you?
Always the best, like no other.
You never judge yourself.
Can we talk, Mía?
Can't you just leave her alone?
Just for a second.
I can't stand this anymore.
I want to be relaxing at the hotel
and thinking about
the New Year's Eve party.
Now you want to leave because of him?
What did I do?
-It's your fault.
-My fault?
Yes!
-Mercedes!
-No!
Hide in there!
Hide!
Forget it, Mom. You've looked for him
everywhere. Can we go?
They have to be somewhere.
Let's wait for them at the hotel.
Can we leave?
Yes, I think that's best.
Your father will learn
what kind of daughter he has.
Let's go.
Don't move.
Let's see.
-Is she there?
-Has she left?
-Let's see.
-Is she gone?
-Madam.
-What? I'm no madam.
May I take a picture with your daughter?
She sang great.
He's my fan!
I want to be in the picture, I'm her PR.
I can't believe it.
Is she gone or not?
-Look.
-No.
-The boat is moving.
Is it?
Hold on.
Wait.
-No!
-What?
-Look!
-No.
How will we get back now?
Juanma, grab the oars.
What oars?
No, this is not over yet.
Mercedes won't stop
until Álvaro and Mía show up.
But can we just relax for a second
until she shows up?
Okay, let's go to Mía's room then
just to check.
This is insane.
Mía hasn't gone anywhere.
She's in her room.
-I saw her.
-Let's check.
-He's coming.
-Is Mía in her room?
-Is she there or not?
-Yes, she is.
-Why did you say that?
-Because I'm weak.
-I know.
-What do we do now?
Got it. I left the window open.
I'll get in the bed.
You distract them.
-Okay. I always get the worst part.
-Good luck.
-Can you calm down?
-Where are you hiding, Álvaro?
She needs to rest, Mercedes.
Simón, get out of my way. Álvaro!
-Son!
-Don't strain yourself!
Mercedes!
Mía.
Is it time for breakfast?
What are you doing here, Mía?
Where would she be if not here?
In her bed.
But you told me--
That Álvaro was at Jesse &amp; Joy's party.
I didn't say that Mía was with him.
Don't say a word, Ramiro.
What's going on? What's all that yelling?
Where on earth have you been?
At Jesse &amp; Joy's party.
Didn't Nico tell you?
Please, Mercedes, leave us alone.
Please.
-Mía! My dear friend!
-Hi!
-You're fine.
-Yes, I am.
You may fool Mercedes,
but you won't fool me.
We're going to have a talk.
Mercedes.
Ramiro and his new daughter
managed to ruin the New Year for me.
I should have left
the moment I saw them here.
What happened?
The same as always.
Ramiro defends Mía.
What about Lupe?
We just forget about her?
That's why she acts the way she does.
She feels uncared for.
Are you taking care of her?
When will you tell her the truth?
Are you taking Ramiro's side?
It's not about taking sides.
You and Ramiro are the ones
with the problems. Solve them.
The kids don't deserve
to spend the New Year like this.
Come on.
Don't tell me. Mía asked you to come.
We're doing everything wrong.
Everything.
Have you ever considered what she wants,
what she needs?
I think she needs some peace.
She's not enjoying this.
-Me neither.
-You think I am?
You know what?
I think that you and I have
quite a lot in common.
The thing is...
we started off on the wrong foot.
Yeah.
How about we start over?
We can try.
Everything looks so pretty!
-This place is so amazing.
-Yes.
Yes, but we're spending
New Year's Eve separated.
You know how Mercedes is.
You can't change that.
The important thing here
is that we are together, the three of us.
And you're the best friends in the world.
Yes, the ones who cover for you
when you sneak off to a party
in the middle of nowhere
with Juanma and Álvaro.
I'm sorry, Dad.
It was unfair of me.
I shouldn't have lied to you.
And I shouldn't have gone
without permission.
I'm sorry.
Let me take a look at you.
You look gorgeous.
Now, let's enjoy our first New Year's Eve
together.
All right?
I love you.
Nico, can you ask Álvaro
to pass the salt?
Tell him to get it himself.
Can't you leave me alone just for today?
We're kidding!
I prefer it when you're fighting.
Juanma, thank you
for everything you did.
Álvaro,
you're the best.
No, you are.
No, you are!
Okay, I'm the best.
Where are you going?
To say hi to Ramiro.
And you should say hi to your dad.
Shall we?
You should come too, Mom.
Shall we, Agus?
Álvaro is right.
We can't start the new year this way.
Let's go.
So nice!
It's a great game.
I'd like to make a toast.
I've always dreamed
of a New Year's Eve like this.
With my family.
We're having a great time.
And I can't help thinking
that we lived this year to the fullest.
And the most important thing
is that we learned to love one another.
I'm sure that in this new year
that's beginning,
we'll make our dreams come true.
-Well said.
-Yes!
I'll drink to that, too.
-That's great.
-Awesome.
-Fantastic.
-Cheers!
-What time is it?
-Ten seconds to midnight!
Ten, nine,
eight, seven, six,
five, four,
three, two, one!
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year, Dad.
Happy New Year, honey. I love you.
My dear daughter.
Son.
My friend!
Happy New Year!
I love you, guys.
My name is Giulia Be
and I have a surprise for you.
The best group of the moment: GO!
Let's go to the beach!
Let's go!
Three, two, one!
I want you to want to toast with me
I want to celebrate that we're alive
I want to be happy
I want to be here
-Dance, dance with me
-I'm telling you
Look at your footprint on the sand
Let the sea take the bad things
Everything will pass
Good things will come
The sun will come up in the morning
As always
It feels good
When we are all here together
Come, let's dance
Let's turn it on
Turn up the volume
Three, two, one, go!
I want you to want to toast with me
I want to celebrate that we're alive
I want to be happy
I want to be here
Dance, dance with me
I want you to want to toast with me
I want to celebrate that we're alive
I want to be happy
I want to be here
Dance, dance with me
A new year
A blank page
I'll start from scratch
And learn from my failures
I'm stronger now
The music keeps going
I want you to come with me
So you know how it feels
-I want to be happy
-I want to be here
I want all our dreams to come true
I know they will
Let the music unite us
And bring out the best in you
I'm telling you
It's time to do things my own way
No more grief or sorrow
Everything will pass
Good things will come
We'll celebrate until night falls
Follow my flow
Feel the dembow
-It's a song
-Three, two, one, go!
Come and dance with me
Music is passion
Feel the drums beating in your heart
It's a strong beat
Don't deny it
You already feel it
Your heart is beating hard
I want you to want to toast with me
I want to celebrate that we're alive
I want to be happy
I want to be here
Dance, dance with me
I want you to want to toast with me
I want to celebrate that we're alive
I want to be happy
I want to be here
Dance, dance with me
I want you to want to toast with me
I want to celebrate that we're alive
I want to be happy
I want to be here
Dance, dance with me
Like I said at the start,
I've often dreamed
of a New Year like this.
With my father,
with my friends,
and surrounded by music.
But now, just you and I know
what could happen.
We both know it
Each to their own game
I don't know if it was fate or our paths
That brought us together
We both know it
We are what we do
And there's no hatred
That can't be changed with love
Love, love, love
We both know it
Each to their own game
I don't know if it was fate or our paths
That brought us together
We both know it
We are what we do
And there's no hatred
That can't be changed with love
Love, love, love