That was tough, the coronary ostia were
damaged too. Well done, professor !
- Thank you, Fratta.
- I was wondering...
maybe next time,
under your supervision...
if you want, I could...
- I don't want. Rosa ?
- Yes, professor ?
Have you found a spot
for the patient in the ICU ?
I'll do it now.
It shouldn't be me to remind you,
try to be more professional if you can.
- Well ?
- Line's busy.
Go ask in person, a good walk
could help you burn a few kilos.
How did it go, professor ?
It was a complex operation,
but a successful one.
The patient is still sedated,
but his heart's responding well.
Thanks, Professor De Luca,
you're a miracle worker.
Miracles don't exist,
I'm an excellent surgeon. Goodbye.
- Hello, darling.
- Hello.
Xenia, can't you see
it's nearly empty ?
Mum, please, I'm watching
something important !
Sorry, Bianca.
You take this,
I'll take care of the wine.
Sorry, Carla,
but I haven't eaten all day.
- Help yourself.
- Really tasty though.
We have a new entry here !
That's right ! You noticed then ?
I adopted her last week.
This is Zinza, from Burkina Faso.
Poor thing, not only an orphan,
she's ugly too !
Dinner's in half an hour.
The Plain of Castelluccio
is so amazing.
So peaceful...
- And the lentils !
- Delicious !
- Carla ?
- No, no wine, you know I don't.
You feel at one with the Universe.
Have you ever been, Dad ?
- No.
- Take Mum, she'd love it there.
Andrea, how's it going
with the respiratory diseases ?
Pretty tough.
Tommaso, aren't you friends
with Professor Savarese ?
I don't want to hear
that kind of talk.
Do you want me to call him and say:
"My son hasn't studied
but pass him anyway
because we're friends" ?
We didn't bring them up
with those values.
I didn't mean it like that,
I meant...
Excuse me.
Andrea's very clever,
he'll make us proud.
Right, sweetie ?
Talking about being proud...
did you know Gianni
wrapped up a great sale today ?
Stop it !
- He'd like to...
- If he doesn't want to tell us...
Okay, I'll tell you.
100 square metres,
unauthorized veranda,
fourth floor, no elevator !
Hear that ?
Well done, my love.
I'll get it, Xenia !
Sorry, that's Furio. I have to go.
Drive carefully.
- Hello, Andrea.
- Hey, Furio !
- Have you told your parents yet ?
- Not yet.
Why not ?
Do Bianca and the wimp have to eat
here every night ?
- You know she can't cook.
- I've no idea what she can do !
Don't be like that !
I saw this documentary
about amoebas.
And some ofthem
are a lot more active than she is.
Listen, about Andrea...
what do you think ?
Why ?
What do you mean ?
I don't know, he's been odd lately.
He's always been peculiar.
As a kid he'd spend all day
counting ambulances going by !
Yes, and we took him
to a neurologist.
What exactly do you mean...
by odd ?
Different.
Well, he's probably got a girlfriend.
Good for him ! !
Then why is he
with Furio every night ?
They get on well.
Precisely !
What do you mean ?
Let's see if you get it...
He's gay ?
I think so.
- Oh God ! Now what ?
- What ?
Are we still discriminating against
one's sexual orientation ? Come on !
No, of course not !
I totally agree with you.
It might sound like a cliché...
but love is what counts.
You're a big softie then ?
Good night.
Rosa, can't you keep up ?
Go on a diet !
I won't operate you
if you have a heart attack.
Good morning !
- How are you feeling ?
- So and so.
- How did you sleep ?
- I was a bit breathless.
Did you expect to run
the New York marathon ?
Right.
Continue the treatment
and add 5 mg of Triatec.
- Goodbye.
- Professor, while you're here...
I've had this pain
for the last two days...
I'm sorry to hear that.
They think I'm their GP !
Did this have to happen right now...
with all the problems we already have ?
- Hello, Carla.
- Tommaso !
- He says he wants to talk to us.
- Who ?
Andrea ! He wants to make
an announcement to the family !
This is it then.
- What shall we do ?
- We have to keep calm. Where is he ?
In his bedroom.
He's waiting for you to get back.
- Bianca and the wretch ?
- At home, they don't know anything.
We'll have to warn them, so they won't
say anything that might hurt him.
- Will you do it ?
- Okay.
Is dinner ready ?
So I just wanted to warn you,
because tonight Andrea's probably
going to tell us he's gay.
Tommaso, I'm so sorry.
What are you doing ?
What's he doing ?
I don't know what to say,
that's terrible news.
No, it's wonderful news !
There's nothing wrong with it.
You're right, but I wouldn't
take it so well.
Dad's right, it's good news.
Dolce and Gabbana's parents
probably weren't happy at first...
- But they made them so proud !
- Bianca, it's an illness !
I know, but there are advantages
of being sick !
Like Dustin Hoffman in that film,
he's a spastic but a genius at cards.
- "The Graduate" ?
- No !
- "Tootsie" ?
- No, come on !
And that short, handsome actor
who's a Jehovah's witness.
- Are you sure I've seen it ?
- That's enough !
Let's go in there now...
and when Andrea makes
his announcement, we'll hug him
and say:
"We're all with you." Okay ?
- "Rain Man".
- That's the one !
I'd like Xenia to be here too.
Xenia's cooking artichokes...
That's no problem, Carla.
If Andrea wants
Xenia to be here too...
In fact, it's only right. After
all these years, she's family too.
- What's up ?
- Come here, Xenia.
Andrea's got something important
to tell us.
Forgive me, I'm a little nervous,
it's hard to find the words.
Darling, everyone here loves you.
Right ?
- Right.
- Hell yeah.
- I hope I won't disappoint you.
- You won't !
Love is all that matters,
as Dad says.
Let's hear him out, Carla !
You're right, Mum.
Love is all that matters.
And my decision
was guided by love.
I have lived a meaningless life
for so long.
I felt I lacked something
and thought: "What's wrong with me ?
Why am I so unhappy ?"
Then one day I met someone
who gave meaning to everything.
And this person is Jesus.
I've decided to become a priest.
I'll go and peel the artichokes.
What do you think, Dad ?
What do I think ?
I'm think that if you're happy...
Dad's happy for you.
What about you, Mum ?
Mum is too, very.
Do we still give him a hug ?
We're all with you.
We're all with you
I have to go now.
We'll talk about it tomorrow.
Of course.
But thanks again...
I love you all.
Better than what we thought...
No !
Are you crazy ?
My son, a priest ?
You must be joking !
God doesn't exist...
and even if he did...
which I sincerely doubt...
why throw your life away
being a priest ?
It's an anachronistic profession,
it's like being a chimney sweep !
A knife grinder !
A bagpipe player !
I don't want a son
who's a bagpipe player !
- Calm down, Tommaso...
- But what with calm down, Tommaso ?
We're talking about
the Catholic Church here !
The most obscurantist institution
that ever existed
on the face ofthe Earth.
Anyhow but the Vatican owns
the best real estate.
Enough.
I'm going to bed.
Dad, wait !
What about the artichokes ?
Good night !
- Xenia ?
- Yes, professor ?
Do you call this an ironed shirt ?
- Is that a trick question ?
- Listen, Xenia...
I've always respected you,
and I've always said that
what Pizarro did to the Incas
was one of the bleakest hours
of history.
But I'm a stickler
for well-ironed shirts. Thank you.
I wouldn't have any coffee
if I were you.
- Carla, we have to do something.
- What ?
I don't know.
Do you want your son to be a priest ?
- If it's what he wants.
- It's madness.
Then tell him.
What if he thinks
I don't like the idea ?
- Why, do you like it ?
- You don't get it !
I can't force him to change his mind,
I have to do it gradually.
I have to make him see reason.
- You talk to him.
- Me ?
I'm always at work,
you have nothing to do.
- Do it when you come home from work.
- No, no, no !
You talk to him.
Instead of adopting other people's
kids, look after your own.
I've had enough,
three years and not one incision !
When will I learn ?
That's enough !
I'll give him a piece of my mind
next time I see him !
Rosa !
Good morning, professor !
Sorry, professor.
Go on, stuff yourself !
When you've finished
guzzling carbohydrates,
bring me Mazzanti's case sheet.
Yes, professor.
Another thing: I don't want
to see her on my ward again.
She provides the patients
with spiritual help !
Don't talk heresy, the patients
have all the help they need.
Is that clear ? I don't want
her around when I'm here.
I'm curious about something,
you become a priest... then what ?
What do you mean ?
I mean, do you go freelance...
do you open your own parish...
Let's say it's more
like a franchising.
Sorry, I'm not well informed
about church business.
Maybe you could explain it to me...
Dad says I never look
into things properly.
You can start by reading
the Gospels.
The Gospel.
There's only one.
No, there are four.
Give me one,
I don't want to overdo it.
- May I ?
- Come in, Mum.
How's everything ?
Much better now.
- Do you feel like talking ?
- Of course.
You gave us some wonderful news...
but we weren't expecting it,
you do realize that ?
Mum, I'm happy.
I can't explain it, but I've finally
found the right path in life.
It's terrible not to have a purpose,
I don't know how you do it.
- Me ?
- Yes.
I've seen you, Mum.
I feel sorry for you.
You pretend to be happy and carefree
but you're depressed.
You're always alone,
doing pointless things.
It's as though
you've given up trying.
Have I hurt you ?
Don't be silly, of course not !
>
Bertocchi, I can't talk right now.
I'm with someone.
I'll call you back. Thank you.
Well ?
Have you been drinking ?
No !
Did you talk to Andrea ?
Tommaso, my life has no meaning.
>
"All the ends of the earth
will remember.
And all the families of the Gentiles
will adore in his sight,
for the kingdom belongs to the Lord,
and he will have dominion,
in his sight they will fall down,
all those who descend to the ground."
- What is it, Dad ? Be quick !
- I need to talk to you.
- You know your brother...
- Andrea ?
You've only got one !
Focus, Bianca !
I need your help.
Do you know what's going on ?
Right now ?
I've downloaded "Jesus of Nazareth",
it's so exciting !
- Zeffirelli's film ?
- Don't tell me how it ends !
Why are you watching it ?
Andrea lent me the Gospels,
but I couldn't get into it.
Sorry, they're leading him to Pilate.
Come on !
Oh God, poor thing !
- Good morning.
- Hello, how can I help you ?
Tommaso, how nice to see you !
I'll take care ofthis.
Come here !
You'd never guess
but she has a degree in Psychology.
Yes, I got that impression.
I'm glad you've come by.
At last !
Would you like a coffee,
tea, cocktail snack...
No, nothing, thanks.
Listen, Gianni,
I'll get straight to the point.
Over the years you may have
thought that I despised you.
- No !
- And you'd be right !
But I've got a problem,
and I don't know who to turn to.
Tommaso, I'm here to help,
anything you need, you know...
It's Andrea.
This vocation of his makes no sense.
I think he's just a bit confused.
I don't know what to do.
Let's go over everything...
In the past has Andrea...
ever shown any interest
in religious matters, like the Pope ?
Padre Pio ?
The Nativity scene ?
- Nuns ?
- No, never.
So it's a recent thing. I reckon
he's keeping bad company.
Do you know
what Andrea does at night ?
Where he goes ?
Who he hangs out with ?
>
Tommaso, you and I need to talk.
Go ahead !
I don't know if you've noticed,
but I've not been happy lately.
Can we turn the TV off, please ?
Tell me.
The other day I realized
I cannot carry on this way.
I'm going out, bye !
Bye, Andrea.
The kids have grown up,
you have your work, which you love,
but what do I have ?
It's as though no one's interested
in what I do or say !
I'm ready !
That's enough !
Enough, or I'll get big-headed
and want to be Pope !
Right, last time we got to
the multiplication
of the loaves and fishes.
Location: the splendid
Lake Tiberias.
Cast: you know the leading man,
he never changes, Jesus,
the disciples,
and a crowd of people,
but not ordinary people,
people of every kind,
mutilated, crippled, blind, paralytic,
in short, a funny crowd.
And they were hungry to boot !
And Jesus said: "Let's feed them,
we can't let them go hungry."
But the disciples were
embarrassed and said:
"All we have left are five loaves
and two fishes.
If we'd known before,
we'd have gone for grocery !"
What a cool priest !
So Jesus said: "That's no problem,
leave it to me."
What can I tell you ?
There's not much difference
between us and those wretches.
Think about it,
we are lacking something too.
Maybe not an arm or a leg...
but sometimes it's worse
not to have any hope or dreams.
So, if you are hungry
like those poor wretches,
then take my advice...
give Jesus a try.
Taste his words,
the way my friend Andrea did.
And you will realize
you'll want for nothing.
It's late, I need some sleep.
See you next time.
Bye, and thanks.
I don't like this Father Pietro.
The way he moves and talks...
he's like a guru.
And he's brainwashed my son.
Find something out,
then I can talk to Andrea
and put a stop to it.
The police chief is a friend of mine,
but I don't want to ask him.
Don't worry, Tommaso.
Pizzuti is a very discreet person.
I can vouch for him,
he's worked for me for years.
Bankruptcies, repossessions...
a real sleuth.
I'm just doing my job.
Forgive me, it's an important call.
Dr. Finocchiaro, good morning !
How is Mr. Lucci ?
BARE OWNERSHIP SALES
What ? Much better ?
He was on his deathbed yesterday !
You're puzzled about it too....
All right, doctor. Keep me posted.
The age is right. Fingers crossed.
Where were we ?
What's up ? Are you crazy ?
I was thinking about our happy
memories in the last ten years.
- And ?
- I couldn't think of a single one !
You've ruined my life !
What's happened ?
He doesn't know !
He never does.
What is there to know ?
You are a selfish and horrible man !
I was a fantastic person
when we met.
- Look what you've done to me !
- Will you calm down, please ?
Yes, we mustn't lose face.
That's all that matters to you !
You've become so middle class !
Worse than those people
we despised when we were 20 !
I don't want to stay
with a man like that.
Enough !
- What are you doing ?
- Leave me alone.
- Where are you going ?
- To live in Xenia's room.
Professor, please make up,
it's a very tiny room.
Well ?
You were right. Fr. Pietro
is a very shady character.
Did you find something out ?
Not here.
Not bad, eh ?
Explain them to me.
Look at this.
What do you see ?
- He's posting a letter.
- That's right.
But the question is: who to ?
Who to ?
I don't know yet,
but it seems a good lead.
And this one ?
Have you ever seen a priest
using a cashpoint ?
I haven't.
This is the most interesting one.
You may say: "So what ?
He's going into a pharmacy."
But you can buy
a lot in a pharmacy.
Medicine, shampoo, but also...
syringes !
- Get out of here, Pizzuti !
- But we're getting somewhere...
- Get out !
- Let me explain...
Out !
Could you give me an advance ?
I'm broke...
Out !
- Photogenic, isn't he ?
- Is that him ?
That's him, that's him !
"Pietro Pellegrini,
several charges of robbery,
scams and aggravated fraud.
He discovered the faith
through the prison chaplain.
He went straight to the seminary
when he left jail.
Why are you interested
in this priest ?
It's a long story,
I'll tell you some other time.
Stefania and I are having
a house warming on Saturday.
- Tell Carla, we'll see you there.
- Yes.
Isn't it strange that a
man like him would drop everything
and become a priest ?
Yes, it is strange, but until
proved otherwise he's clean.
Yes, until proved otherwise...
Thank you.
Sorry for the late notice
but I'm going away tomorrow.
For two weeks.
- Where are you going ?
- Camaldoli Hermitage.
A retreat for young men
who want to be priests.
I thought you had an exam next week ?
Yes, Dad...
but seeing I can't do both things,
I've been thinking
of dropping out of med school.
- What's wrong ?
- Dad !
- Darling !
- Tommaso, look at the little birdie !
Look at the birdie !
Have a sip, Dad.
I'm okay now.
Don't worry.
No one was worried.
Andrea, what's this hermitage like ?
Like a holiday farm ?
- No, it's a monastery !
- Great ! I'd love to go there.
Let's go one weekend.
- Do they have wifi ?
- I don't know.
Fr. Pietro's organized it,
he's a priest friend.
A very special person.
- Really ?
- Yes, he helps everyone.
Whatever problem you have,
financial, family, he'll help you !
That's nice !
I'm very fond of him.
It's thanks to him
I found my vocation.
Come in, Dad.
Listen, Andrea...
we haven't discussed
this matter yet...
but I think it's time I told you
what I think of your vocation.
I already know.
- You do ?
- Yes.
I am so happy to have your support.
I was afraid you wouldn't approve,
but you've been great.
As usual !
I feel like crying.
That makes two of us.
>
Darling, I'll go and get a glass...
Well, how did it go ?
Terrible.
I have to make the most
ofthese next two weeks
to prove that this priest
is a rogue.
- How will you do that ?
- I don't know.
I need an idea.
Shall I call Pizzuti ?
Was that a no ?
That evening, when Jesus finished
praying, he went to his disciples
and they... they were fast asleep !
You're laughing because you think
we're better than them.
But we're not.
We think we are awake
because we eat, work, chat, and
fill our lives with pointless things.
But the truth is we are sleeping too.
And we don't realize it.
But we'll discuss that next week.
Go to bed now, good night.
Thanks.
- Fr. Pietro ?
- Yes ?
I'm desperate, I'm unemployed...
- Bye, Fr. Pietro !
- Later. Say hello to Cesarone.
- You were saying ?
- Forgive me...
I'm desperate, I'm unemployed,
I have problems at home...
- I have a retarded brother...
- How are you, professor ?
- I'll be right back.
- Do you come here too ?
Fratta, you don't know me,
you've never seen me, okay ?
- But, professor...
- If you tell anyone...
I'll have you kicked out
of the hospital, so be warned.
- Okay.
- Have a good evening.
Having problems ?
No, no.
Yes !
Yes, lots of them.
I'm desperate, I'm unemployed,
I support my retarded brother,
my wife had a nervous breakdown
and beats me.
- Nothing else ?
- I want to kill myself.
- I'm not surprised.
- I need some spiritual solace.
I want us to get to know
each other better.
What's your name ?
You can't even remember ?
It's with all these problems...
Mauro !
Mauro, go and get some sleep,
it's late !
- I said I want to kill myself.
- Right now ?
- No...
- No !
Okay, come and see me tomorrow,
we'll have a chat.
Via del Crepaccio, 12.
See ya !
- Sorry, did it hit you ?
- No...
This is the church
my mother used to come to.
I lived nearby when I was a kid,
so I'm doing it up,
bit by bit,
when I'm not in my parish.
- Can you paint ?
- No.
Too bad, you could've
given me a hand.
What was your name again ?
Mauro !
You need to take
something for your memory !
You worry me.
- How are you feeling today ?
- Bad.
Terrible.
It's getting worse.
I think of suicide every day.
Don't, life is not yours,
you can't do as you like !
I know, but I'm broke.
I don't know where to turn,
I'm willing to do anything.
Even steal.
What do you say ?
What can I say ?
I'm desperate...
what would you do if you were me ?
Just a sec.
Federico !
Darn it... Never mind,
we'll meet Saturday.
Remember the clams !
Bye, buddy.
But you don't look that desperate,
that suit must be worth 1,200.
This ?
No, it's second-hand.
I got it from charity.
Good, that chair's still wet !
- Want a bite ? It's good.
- No, thanks.
How long have you been a priest ?
Ten years, late-onset vocation.
- What's it like being a priest ?
- Working on Sundays sucks...
I'm just kidding !
How come you know
how much this suit costs ?
I used to like smart clothes once...
- What did you do before ?
- Lots of things.
- For example ?
- Various jobs...
- Such as ?
- Are you a cop ?
Me ? Of course not !
All right...
I don't remember seeing you
at the meetings.
- Have you been coming long ?
- No.
No, it was my first time.
- They spoke so highly of you...
- Who did ?
Never mind.
You don't even remember
your own name...
- Are you a believer though ?
- Yes ! Very much so !
Then take my advice and pray.
It's essential to pray,
you must never tire of praying.
- Are you busy right now ?
- No.
- Let's go and pray together.
- Don't you have to paint the church ?
Don't worry, I'll do it later.
Come on !
Darn it...
Next week we want to organize
a joint meeting...
with representatives
of some high schools
to prepare a report to send
to the Ministry of Education.
I'll let you know.
But now we have the solidarity
of a former student.
I'll let her speak.
Thank you.
Hello, everyone, my name's Carla.
It feels strange to be back
in this school
after all these years.
My children attended
this school too...
or rather one ofthem,
the other chose a different school...
Okay then...
I am here today
to express my solidarity
and support,
but also to give you
some heartfelt advice.
Student collectives are fine,
so are meetings,
and joint reports, but they are
sometimes not enough.
Because there are people
who just won't listen.
If you think someone's interested
in you for what you are,
and what you have inside,
you're wrong.
No one's listening to you,
they don't care.
It's as though you don't exist.
So show them you exist,
but do it now,
because soon it will be too late,
and you'll regret it all your life.
No more talk, let's take action !
Let's occupy !
Rosa, that's mine.
See who it is.
Hurry up.
It says "priest".
Come closer.
Hello ?
Come straight here,
Via delle Sette Chiese, 101.
>
Knock it off,
you've got nothing to do.
>
- Found you a little job.
What kind ?
A friend of mine wants someone bright.
You said you'd do anything...
>
- Well ?
I'm coming.
Fratta, I have to go.
Can you take over here ?
Me ?
Remember to replace the valve,
or the patient won't survive
the operation.
Good luck !
Fr. Pietro ?
- About time !
- I waited ages for the bus.
Said doesn't trust people he doesn't
know, but I persuaded him.
But don't show me up.
By the way, are you
any good with a knife ?
Not too bad, why ?
- Who's next ?
- Me.
Two euros with potatoes.
- Two euros precisely ?
- Two euros.
Have faith, Said.
Does he think
he's performing surgery ?
79 !
Can I have a piece with mushrooms ?
Not the edge,
it's always a bit burnt.
And not the middle,
it doesn't look very cooked,
I'll get indigestion.
No, I'll have it
with courgettes instead.
I hope you've put more salt
in it today.
What are you doing ?
Cheese and tomato will be fine.
Here's the knife, cut your own.
I ask a friend for a favour,
I find you a job,
which isn't easy right now,
and you walk out ?
I know, but there was
an emergency at home...
Pietro !
Take a walk, I'm busy.
Hello, Fr. Pietro.
- Got the money ?
- Yes, but I wanted to ask...
- Hand it over !
- Why are you so aggressive ?
- You do this every week !
- Wait.
- What is it ?
- I didn't get as much this week.
Make this last all week.
- Go now.
- This ?
Go home, take my advice.
- Who was that ?
- A friend.
- What did he want ?
- What do you care ?
I was just curious.
- What happened at home ?
- An emergency. You know how it is.
Burnt out wife, retarded brother...
Yes, I wouldn't have turned down
that job otherwise.
You can't carry on like this.
I know, so tell me what I should do.
Tell me !
Okay, I tell you what...
I'll come to your place on Friday
and meet them.
- To my home ?
- Yes. What's your address ?
What did you say ?
That I'd send him a text
when I remembered.
Brilliant !
I couldn't invite him
to my penthouse in Prati.
Can you find me a dreary,
dingy apartment ?
It's not easy,
I deal in luxury real estate.
Does it have to be very dingy ?
Absolutely.
Then my place is perfect.
Tommaso, forgive me.
It is worth all this trouble ?
For your own sake,
you're a well-known surgeon,
what if people find out ?
This criminal has brainwashed
my son !
And it's all a cover.
He's got this money racket going.
I need to show my son
he's a rogue.
We'll use Pizzuti's home,
you can be my retarded brother,
that shouldn't be too hard...
- I could be a handicapped relative.
- No need.
Your secretary can be my wife.
Patrizia, who's not here right now...
- She's in a clinic.
- I'm sorry about that. An accident ?
- No, liposuction on her buttocks.
- Darn it !
- It's a routine op.
- Who cares !
Where will I find another wife ?
- There's no sugar in it.
- No, drink it.
I don't want to interrupt
your coffee break.
I said drink it !
Listen, Rosa, I need to ask you
a little favor.
- For friendship's sake.
- Yes, professor.
I can't explain it
to you right now,
but I will clarify everything later.
On Friday afternoon,
for a couple of hours,
I want you to pretend
to be my wife.
What do you mean ?
I... how can I ?
No, I don't feel up to it.
What must I do ?
I've told you,
pretend to be my wife.
But be a little aggressive.
In fact, to be honest,
you have to ill-treat me.
What time are we meeting ?
- Where are you going, Dad ?
- I have to go out.
Andrea will be back
from his retreat soon.
It would be nice if we were all here
for a family prayer.
- Do it with your mother.
- She's at the student's union.
Where ? No, never mind.
Come on, Dad, stay here !
We'll recite the rosary
while we wait !
- What's with the dead smell ?
- Quiet !
- And you live here, Pizzuti ?
- Yes.
Well, I'm staying with
my ex-wife right now.
A small problem with the courts,
but it'll be sorted out soon.
This way.
What did I tell you ?
It's perfect !
It's a bit stuffy,
let's open the windows...
We'd better not.
You know how it is, the neighbours...
People can be mean.
Rosa, there are some teacups
over there.
I'll grab a couple of shirts
and underpants before I go.
Tommaso, I've been working
on the retarded brother act.
- I have another version too...
- No, the first one's fine.
Rosa, understand
what you have to do ?
- Yes, professor.
- No, don't call me that !
Today I'm Mauro, your husband
and you have to ill-treat me.
- I'll try, but I'm not sure I...
- You have to !
I'll be off.
Here are the keys.
Thanks, Pizzuti, you're the best.
You're welcome.
- Who's that now ?
- Probably the municipal police !
My damn neighbour must've called them.
- It's okay, it's Fr. Pietro.
- What will you do now ?
Open it, don't worry.
Leave it to me.
What are you doing ?
- May I ?
- Fr. Pietro !
- Welcome.
- Thanks.
Let me introduce my family.
- This is my wife Rosa.
- Hello.
My brother Gianni.
Yes.
And this is...
- Pizzuti ! His brother-in-law.
- Nice to meet you.
A little floral gift, madam.
Thank you ! Look and learn !
This asshole never buys me presents !
This way, everyone.
Let's sit down.
How are you, Gianni ?
Fine ! How long
has he been like this ?
- He was born that way.
- But he's improved lately.
- Biscuit ?
- No, thanks.
Yes, all he thinks about
is eating, the pig !
Easy, violence doesn't pay.
Sorry, I got worked up.
Isn't Gianni drinking ?
I'll help him. Drink up, dear boy.
It's a little hot.
- Am I doing okay, professor ?
- Yes, maybe just a little less...
I'm very happy to be here
with you today.
Mauro has told me all about you,
I know times are hard,
but Mauro's a good man and with
God's help we'll find him a job.
Ajob !? He's a lazy asshole...
Madam, no...
Mauro, you were right,
you're in deep trouble.
Listen, Pietro, I'll tell you again...
if you've anything that needs doing,
even if it's illegal...
- Not again ! I'm a priest !
- I know that...
but how many priests... you know ?
What ? Go and have a rest,
you're tired.
I have to go now,
but do me a favour...
- When you feel down, and desperate...
- Pray.
No, call me, any time you want.
I'm here for you.
You must never lose hope.
All right.
Bye.
Is Andrea in his room ?
Thanks.
- Welcome back !
- Hi.
- I've missed you.
- Me too.
Dad, I want to introduce you
to a friend of mine.
This is the famous Fr. Pietro.
- This is my father, Tommaso.
- Hello.
You look more like a Mauro to me.
- I don't get it...
- Fr. Pietro likes to joke.
- So does your father.
- No, Dad's serious.
- He's a famous heart surgeon.
- So he earns a fortune.
Even doctors are struggling.
Dad, can I finish talking
to Fr. Pietro ?
Of course.
I have a lot of things
to tell Andrea, too.
- You can tell him next time maybe.
- No !
Go, you're a busy heart surgeon !
- Beverages ?
- No.
- Soft drink ?
- I'll get it.
Go on !
- I'll see to it.
- Thanks.
Tommaso, I need your help now.
I don't know what to do about Bianca.
She's really into Catholicism.
She insists we can't have sex
if it's not for procreation purposes.
Can you imagine ?
What shall I do ?
It's a physical necessity for me !
Perhaps you could talk to her.
- I'll see you out.
- No need.
Will you talk to her ?
Was that a yes ?
Nice house !
Aren't you feeling well ?
What a view !
All of Rome at your feet.
- What did you tell Andrea ?
- Nothing, I can keep a secret.
Professional ethics.
Thank you.
But I want you to tell me something...
Why ?
Because it's inadmissible
that my son, who has a brilliant
medical career ahead of him,
should throw it all away
for something that doesn't exist,
just because someone
has brainwashed him.
- I've brainwashed him ?
- Yes !
Before he met you,
Andrea never wanted to be a priest.
- How do you know ?
- He's easily influenced.
He's a child !
- You've often influenced him !
- I'm his father, I'm allowed to.
Yes ! And for once when Andrea
makes up his own mind,
his father disappears and Mauro
and all his problems appear.
All right...
I apologize for tricking you.
Sorry.
Good man.
Repentance is praiseworthy.
But not enough.
In confession, first we have
repentance, then penance.
How many Hail Marys ?
No, that's too easy !
What do you mean ?
You know all the restoration work
at the church ? I need a volunteer.
You must be joking.
No.
- You can forget it.
- That's too bad.
What will Andrea think
when he finds out his father,
the intelligent, democratic,
and tolerant man he praises to me...
is actually a hypocrite ?
You get the idea !
You will help me out
for a whole month.
Then you can go your own way.
Right, I'll count to three,
we'll lift it up
and hang it up there.
One, two...
Why not call
one of your fanatic followers ?
We can manage, come on !
One, two...
I'll pay for it to get done,
consider it a donation.
You priests are good at taking
money... everyone knows that.
One, two...
It annoys me on a symbolic level.
So are you trying to say
you're too old for this ?
One...
two...
Easy now, one step at a time.
Lift your feet up,
it won't hurt as much.
- Try tilting your pelvis.
- Oh please...
It helps, trust me.
Slowly now.
Rest, deep breath.
Wait !
- Sorry...
- Is that better ?
- No.
- Good, come on !
A few steps more...
It's more a psychological pain.
What ? This is a disc hernia.
L-4, L-5, I know !
Okay, now concentrate,
this is the hard bit.
Try and lean forward
and I'll push you in.
- Don't push me.
- Slowly does it, from behind.
Rotate your hip...
There we go !
You should be happy
to have this pain.
It means the Lord
is putting you to the test.
Go fuck...
Bye-bye.
What's up ?
I don't see why you're doing this,
you already have a parish.
I'm doing it for my mother,
I caused her so much sorrow.
- If she could see me as a priest...
- But where do I fit in ?
It's for your sake too.
In fact, you should be thanking me...
Listen, priest...
I don't have to thank anyone.
While you pretend to save people
with your prayers,
blessings and incense...
I really do save people !
And they thank me for it,
every day !
Is that clear ?
What a nasty temper !
But remember,
even if you do save people,
you are still a human being.
Perhaps you thought you were God,
but you're not, sorry.
Death comes
when you least expect it,
"like a thief in the night"
as Saint Paul put it.
Have you read his Letters ?
Read his First Letter
to the Corinthians.
- Give me a break.
- "For who regards you as superior ?
What do you have
that wasn't given to you ?"
>
I didn't have any palpitations
last night.
Perhaps I'm getting better,
doctor.
I don't believe it !
No !
It's a tragedy !
Where are you going ?
Tell me the truth, am I dying ?
Thank you, darling.
- Carla, we need to talk.
- I have nothing to say to you.
- We can't carry on like this.
- Gianni's finding me a place.
Now get out.
- Listen, Carla...
- Get out !
What is it, Tommaso ?
- Nothing.
- You look miserable.
- Is anything wrong ?
- No, not at all.
I'm here for you.
Listen, seeing you're here,
why don't you talk to Andrea ?
- He's not cut out to be a priest.
- I don't agree with you.
I think it's the right job for him,
he's smart, he'll go far.
- Wouldn't you like a bishop son ?
- Pietro, please !
It's well paid !
Fr. Pietro !
Hold this.
- What do you want ?
- I've brought you the money.
- Hurry up then.
- Here.
- Just this once.
- Thanks.
- Be good.
- I love you.
- Say hi to your wife for me.
- I will. Bye.
Let's go and clean the brushes.
That's Mimmo, a decent guy
but obsessed with video poker.
So I mind his wage and give
him some money now and then.
Give me back my pizza.
Professor, can you sign
Mrs. Mariani's discharge ?
Thank you.
- What have I done ?
- Have you changed your hairstyle ?
Yes. I shouldn't have ?
It suits you.
Thank you.
- Is Andrea not here ?
- He's at the priest's meeting.
By the way, that business
about Bianca and Catholicism...
It's okay now,
she's into the Orient now.
She saw some tantra videos
on Youtube, and...
Tommaso, our sex life
has really taken off again,
we're going whole hog !
Please, I'm eating !
So ?
No luck, she says she's not hungry.
I'm worried, she's getting
more and more depressed.
Don't worry, you know
what she's like.
Why, do you know
what she's like, Dad ?
You don't, or she wouldn't
be in this state now.
Come on, Bianca, eat up !
He thinks he knows everything !
With that air of superiority,
always judging people.
Because he's the best !
No way...
All we needed was you
spouting this rubbish !
Of course, I'm stupid !
You've always thought that,
but you had Andrea to make up for it.
You've always despised me, Dad.
You've always despised us both.
My husband might not be a genius
or the most handsome
but at least he never judges me
the way you have,
ever since I was a child.
And I have always tried
not to let you down.
I remember when I was a child,
you would force me to listen to
Guccini, De Gregori, De André !
Making a 7-year-old
listen to De André...
is really mean !
In fact, I want to tell you
something else
that will really hurt you.
I like Gigi D'Alessio !
Yes, you heard me !
Because he's great, he moves me,
makes me feel better !
I'm going home.
What's come over her ?
Tommaso, forgive me...
Good night.
At the Saviour's command
and formed by divine teaching,
we dare to say:
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name,
thy kingdom come,
thy will be done
on earth, as it is in heaven.
Looking for me in church now ?
What's wrong, Tommaso ?
Nothing, what could be wrong ?
Do you never feel lonely ?
No, never, because
I am never on my own.
And neither are you, because of...
Not your imaginary friend again !
Come with me.
When I'm feeling down,
I come here.
I discovered this place
one morning, many years ago,
after I was released from jail.
Yes, I've been in jail.
And not just once !
There's lots you don't know about me !
I might tell you one day.
We're friends now.
I didn't know what to do,
so I sat here.
- And what did you think about ?
- Nothing...
Nothing at all.
I was on my own here.
No desires, no expectations,
no fears.
Just this.
Then suddenly,
in a fraction of a second
it all became clear.
Three days later I entered
the seminary, and here I am.
Between you and me, do you
really believe there is a God ?
- Who do you think God is ?
- I don't know, you're the expert.
You know those hot summer mornings
when it's really stuffy,
you open a window
and cool air caresses your face ?
- That's a breeze.
- No, it's God.
And when the clouds
take on those strange shapes,
a horse, a face, a carrot...
and you keep staring at them...
- That too is God.
- Who's in church then ?
Do you think God is happy
to be cooped up in one place ?
It's not enough, is it ?
See that pear ?
Inevitably,
that pear will fall one day.
Bet you think it's due to gravity.
No, it's God !
You're starting to get the idea.
- Darling, what's wrong ?
- I don't know.
- I'm always tired.
- You're okay, don't worry.
- Let me feel your pulse.
- What are you doing ?
Slight tachycardia.
Let me look at your eye.
Keep still !
Nothing serious, don't worry.
But go to the pharmacy...
and ask for these tablets.
Take three a day after meals
for a week.
And just to be on the safe side,
have a full check-up done,
okay ?
Here.
- Do you want some more pizza ?
- If you insist.
- Boy !
- Here I am !
- Two more cheese slices.
- Coming up.
Said, two cheese slices.
Come on !
The service is rubbish,
but the pizza's good.
>
I was about to call you.
Have a seat.
- A drop of wine ?
- No.
Just a sip.
Try it.
I made it,
it was one of your favourites.
How is it ?
So so...
What's with all this ?
I wanted us to have an evening
all to ourselves.
You're so beautiful, Carla.
Tommaso, stop it,
you're scaring me.
It's the truth.
Are you courting me ?
Perhaps.
You've started taking
the antidepressants again.
No.
It's just an excuse really.
I'm more interested in after dinner.
I've finished then.
Don't you want the main dish ?
Pot roast cooked in Barolo wine.
Did you make it ?
I'd better not then.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- No.
- What do you mean ?
- The month is up, you're free.
We have to remove the stains
from the floors, move the pews...
I'll take care of that,
you go home !
- I won't see you again ?
- You can come to Mass on Sunday.
Then I won't see you again !
Watch out !
Listen, let's grab a bite at Said's.
- I have to work tonight.
- I can't, I have a meeting.
But if you've nothing to do,
go and talk to Andrea.
- About what ?
- You know what.
If you're convinced it's not for him,
you have to tell him.
I don't know
what to tell him anymore.
Tell him whatever you want,
just talk to him.
The time has come, right ?
Look at this bougainvillea !
Andrea ?
Oh, I'm sorry !
Dad !
- Dad...
- It's okay.
- No, let me explain.
- You don't need to.
Yes, I do.
So much has happened recently.
During the weeks
at the spiritual retreat...
I started to have some doubts
and I thought perhaps
I wasn't cut out for priesthood.
I know I should have
told you before, but
I was embarrassed
because I'd changed my mind.
There's nothing wrong
with changing your mind.
- I do it a lot myself.
- Is that so ?
I thought you were the man
of absolute certainties.
I thought that too.
But no...
- So no priest for a son ?
- No !
- Who's going to tell Fr. Pietro ?
- He already knows.
- What ?
- I told him when he came here.
So he's known all this time ?
He convinced me to change paths
because I was too unsure.
And then I met Alessia
at his meetings,
the girl you...
Okay, I have to go. We're going
to Fr. Pietro's meeting later.
- Bye, Dad.
- Go on.
The bastard !
- Hello, darling.
- Hello.
How long will it be ?
I'm due at the hospital.
- Five minutes.
- Good.
I'll go and get changed.
- Excuse me, professor.
- Yes.
I got the CT scan results.
- Well ?
- He has a frontal-parietal hematoma,
with considerable shift.
I have to operate immediately.
De Luca, I'll be honest with you...
it'd take a miracle.
Do you want to observe ?
Sandro, I have to go.
Will you look after the ward ?
Of course.
- Well, Dad ?
- The neurosurgeon's a friend of mine.
He's very good,
he'll do all he can.
But how is he ?
Not well.
He's not well.
Call me when you get news.
- Where are you going ?
- I have to do something.