Charlotte is off
to a violent start in 2019
with more homicides in
the first month of a year
than we've seen in decades.
Homicide's not taking a break
this holiday weekend.
It's unfortunate.
In three days,
three people killed
in three separate crimes in Charlotte.
First, a person shot to death
in a luxury apartment complex
in the heart of uptown.
Then a body discovered in
a grocery store parking lot
in University City,
and now,
a man shot and killed in a motel room.
Right after the teen was killed,
shots rang out at the crime scene,
Sending police, passersby,
even our own news crew
ducking for cover.
Four people killed in four
shootings this weekend alone.
Out with new crime stats.
Overall violent crime is up 11%.
You can see homicide's up
the most, a whopping 230%.
Police say most of the
incidents involve teens,
oftentime repeat offenders
who are responsible.
Officers say many times victims
are not always willing to
help put the crooks behind
bars before it's too late.
A call coming in at 5:43 am
for a shooting on Ohaus
Court in north Charlotte.
I heard six rounds go off.
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
Police say the gunfire
came from outside the house.
Violent crime in Charlotte,
well, we found out today what
everyone has already known.
Numbers of violent crimes,
including homicides
way up in the Queen City.
Homicides.
Oh my God.
Now up to 35 this year.
All of a sudden I just heard gunfire.
Many of them still unsolved.
If you a man and you did it,
be a man and man up and say you did it.
I just want justice.
These killings
keeping Charlotte on a
record-breaking road,
on track to have one of
the deadliest years ever.
Shit.
Man, fuck.
Never nothin' in this bitch!
Yo Chez.
Yo, yo, yo, what's good?
Bro, I'm fucked up.
Man, I'm fucked up too.
Boy you have no idea, bro.
I'm right there, right
there with you, bro.
What's good?
Talk to me.
Look I might got a way though, man.
I'm trying to figure
something out right now.
Man I gotta go pay and
go holla at these people.
Bra, I'm so with it, bro.
I'm so with it bro man.
I got bills, baby mamas,
everything right now, bro.
Man, I'm not too far away bro,
just around the way, bro.
I'm taking a shit.
After I'm done taking a shit
I can be right to you bro.
Yeah man.
Yo, but you know, I say I'm
coming, I'm one call away.
Say no more.
What's good, nigga?
Yo, I'm going outside!
Yo, what's good baby?
What you got going on, nigga?
Talkin' to me what, all right man.
Shit real man.
I'm telling you boy.
Shit, bro, I'm trying to
make something happen man,
but we gotta make ways.
It's tough.
I can't do this.
I told you there was people
I had to holla at man
and ain't none of those
mother fuckers coming through.
Yeah like what you mean?
What you got going on?
And I'm I'm I'm hurting bro.
Zero dollars to my
mother fucking name, bro.
I already know man.
Something gotta shake.
But shit the people that
I had that little move
bustin' coming through.
Man, that shit got fucked up, man.
They ain't even got dem,
it's fucked up.
I can't even put words on that shit, man.
I was even trying to with the little bitch
from the strip club.
Just so I can hit that bitch.
Shit, nigga, ain't nothin'
looking good, right now, man.
So what you're trying to tell me
is you done pull every finesse page
out the finesse book.
Come on, man.
It's gotta, we gotta make
something shake, bro.
Bills, babies, my budget.
I ain't even got no budget.
My calendar set on zero.
Shit, nigga, you?
Mother fucker I'm hungrier
than a mother fucker, nigga.
I had to walk my ass all the way over here
and I'm a 455 pound gorilla, nigga.
You thought this shit was easy, nigga?
This shit for real out this mother fucker.
I'm saying, it's not
funny, but it's funny, bro.
Nigga, nah, nah, not funny at all,
but we gotta make something shake.
Yo, what's up bro?
Yo.
See what is hitting fool?
Shit nigga, nigga's
trying come up on something.
Everybody fucked up.
I ain't got nothing in my
pocket but lint and buttons.
Man that shit crazy,
but still be messing with
young boy around the way.
Who?
Yeah, the little negro,
I fuck with his daddy.
Whenever he's in town.
I can go over there when he town
but he going back and forth
from that truck over here.
Oh yeah.
Is this something I gotta kill everybody
type of shit?
Is this some tie a mother
fucker for ransom type shit?
Quick in and out.
- Oh this some in and out.
- Yeah.
So give me the details on that though.
So what we gonna do?
Shit it's quick.
It's simple, in and out.
Smash and grab, get the bag.
Shit, if that shit as
easy as you say it is,
shit I'm trying to hit
this mother fucker now.
Say no more man.
I'm ready.
Do me a favor.
Go in your crib and get me some trash.
Aight, I got this.
Give me a minute.
Why do I always gotta do this?
Bro you're three people bigger than me.
Say some shit like that again.
You got the tools?
Man get the fuck over.
Go nigga.
Aw shit bingo.
Hurry the fuck up man!
Get out of here!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Whoa.
Nah, you gotta let shit breathe.
Man get the fuck.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Oh my damn.
Shit.
It's real, it's real,
it's real, it's real.
Oh my God.
This is what we got to do
and we gonna do the right thing.
Of course we're gonna
do the right thing.
We're gonna do the right thing.
Baby mama needs this.
Oh shit.
Oh my God.
I know somebody.
You know somebody?
Yeah.
Man, put that shit the fuck back.
Listen, we don't know nothing.
You don't know nobody.
You don't know where the fuck you got,
nigga put this down.
Damn boy we done came the fuck up.
Oh my.
Nigga, I can't mother fucking wait boy.
Eight of them things whole.
I really needed this shit bro.
And I got five mother
fucking kids nigga.
I'm dead serious bro,
this is like a situation
solved right here, bro.
I ain't even gonna lie.
My only question is who the fuck
we gonna get this shit off to?
I know somebody.
Who?
Chick out by the forest.
Talking about the girl with the mo hawk?
Tattoos on her head.
Yeah, be yelling and shit?
I don't really dealing with women.
They good money bro.
Yeah they good money.
As long as you make sure
that thing go together.
I mean, we in this shit together bro.
I ain't fucking with it.
Shit, since you talking so
highly about this bitch,
you might as well call her ass up.
Man, say no more.
Say no more.
No procrastinating on this money.
Hello?
Yo what's up sis?
This Chez.
Yo what's up?
Boy I got a stupid ass deal.
For real?
About eight of them
things for a steal though?
How much you want for 'em?
Shit like 25.
25 thousand?
I give you 21.
That's too much.
Huh?
168 thousand for all eight of 'em.
Man, we could do that.
We can do that.
Aight, you know where I'm at.
I'm at the spot.
Come on through.
Gonna slide through right now.
Right now, right now.
Hell yeah, I still don't
trust that bitch though.
Fuck that, we gotta get this money.
We straight.
Come in.
What's up?
What's up, what's up sis?
What's up, sis?
I know it ain't your birthday
but a nigga bring you
some mother fucking cake.
Eh let me see this.
Yeah, this that thing right here.
So why it's all four of 'em?
Come on now.
LG been in this game longer than me.
Feel that mother fucker man.
It's two in each one of them bitches.
Aight bet.
Nice doing business with you.
Put this shit out here on the streets.
Came the fuck off
168 nigga.
That's 84 thousand a piece.
Nigga I can count.
I knew exactly what it is.
I'm trying to say I can buy
everything wit this bitch.
Everything.
You can definitely do
what you was supposed to do.
'Cause you definitely
got some shit to do, man.
I just told y'all girl's
was gonna come through,
didn't I though?
I still don't fuck
with that bitch though.
'Cause you a hater.
Put my face on the front
of a hundred dollar bill.
Fuck all that shit.
What's up with Marco?
Where that nigga?
Man, he already on the way.
Good 'cause I need that other thing.
And he got the other thing.
Yeah we need to call them twins soon.
Oh yeah.
Shit trying to do something
freaky for a thousand.
Let me borrow that.
My shit back with interest though nigga.
Fuck it, you can borrow.
Fuck all that shit nigga.
Who dat?
It's gotta be cold outside you know?
Who is it?
Marco.
Yeah.
Just the man I wanted to see.
Wassup bro?
Wassup baby?
I got something for you.
That's that thing.
I love this big bitch.
Street stopper nigga.
Okay.
Some more combat shit.
God damn weapon of mass
destruction out this bitch.
Let me get this.
That's what I'm talking about.
I be pointing that mother fucker bro.
Move that mother fucker bro.
This mother fucker right here nigga.
This ain't nothing bro.
I thought I told you
to put that shit up.
It's up.
How much you want for it?
You know what we talked
about on the phone, man.
1015?
So I guess it's 1515 for both?
12.
Hit me with the 12.
Hell yeah my nigga.
Nice doing business with you.
This shit ain't got no bullets.
Boy you ain't know?
Nigga I'm from Charlotte.
Nigga we don't sell them like that.
I appreciate y'all.
Take it easy bro.
I told you to put that shit up.
I fucked up.
Sup my nigga?
Damn my boy.
You already ready.
What the niggas working with in there?
Man, them niggas had 100, 150 thousand.
For real?
No I'm dead serious.
I just sold some ass
with no bullets in there.
Oh nigga, I got to go get that.
Sweet.
So what you gonna do?
Go down the street?
I'ma pull down the street nigga.
Aight.
Then we gonna hit.
Aight I'm fitting to head in real quick.
I'm gonna knock on the door
and act like they want some more.
Then they open the door, I'm in there.
I don't even care.
You can use my name and then hit that.
I don't even give a fuck.
Okay that's a bet.
Marco said y'all might
need some more weed!
Yeah hold on homie.
Give me one second.
What the fuck?
Come on nigga.
Fuck that shit bitch.
Get in nigga, fuck!
Make sure you hold them people back.
See what we going on here again.
Look like a dead nigga.
Get your picture?
Multiple shots man.
They fucked this nigga up bro.
You know your nigga mother
fucker want for some bullshit.
Nigga, that nigga tried
to get us fucked up nigga.
Bullshit too right?
I could have sworn I
heard that mother fucker
say Marco name.
Ain't no swear to it.
He did say that nigga
mother fucking name, nigga.
Look at this shit, bro.
This nigga tried to knock a ligament off.
The fuck nigga?
Mother fucker pretty too.
Man fuck all that shit nigga.
The fuck is?
Street sweeper?
I swear to God, that
shit gonna be on the news.
Yeah, yeah, head shot that nigga.
Fuck that.
Look, it's on the news now.
Man turn that shit up.
Turn that shit up.
Yeah look that shit crazy.
What, they do that shit quick as fuck.
NBC Charlotte.
A man is dead after an overnight
shooting in west Charlotte.
CMPD was called
out to Jones Street,
that's near Roselle Fairy
and, just before midnight.
They spent hours on the scene
looking for evidence.
God damn man.
Never be able to go to the spot no more.
Beside them as well.
She joins us now live
from CMPD headquarters.
So, what can you tell us?
You know we have to get
rid of the guns right?
Yeah you right.
You gonna have to get rid of yours man.
Huh?
Yeah, yours.
I'm serious as fuck bro.
This mother fucker been with
me through hard times nigga.
I'm not getting rid of my gun.
Didn't I tell you to put that
little mother fucker up bro?
It seemed to me you
ain't been doing nothing
but shooting babies, toddlers and animals.
Shit that don't shoot back.
You know the nigga, Scuffles?
Jumps, Chumps?
I done got them, got
with this mother fucker.
Barely.
Barely?
Yeah, that's 'cause you was holding it.
Anyway, she stays.
Yours need to go.
Dead ass serious.
Come on.
Only a stupid mother
fucker want to hold on
to the mother fucking gun he
just killed somebody with.
I don't like giving my
shit up to mother fuckers
but fuck it.
Got new guns any God damn way.
That one too.
That was his gun.
Stupid.
God damn.
Here just take the clip.
Aw fuck man!
What's up bro?
What's good with you?
I was just about to close
this mother fucker up too.
Let me holler at you real quick.
Aight, what it do?
Came to holler at you
'cause I just ran across a sweet lead.
Oh word?
Yeah, for real.
These little niggas,
they ain't even know
what the fuck they have.
I bought eight of 'em.
Are they clean?
They're straight drop.
They got that jump man?
I'm talking about Michael Jordan.
At the pot?
At the pot.
Yeah, that's why I brought you two of 'em
so you can do what you do.
Boy, I got it right here in the bag.
Oh word?
Oh yeah, gonna make that shit jump.
Yeah.
I took six of 'em, made
'em come back to 12.
You can pull whatever you want on there
and have more than
I'm talking about you can
whip, whip, whip, whip,
step on money.
So that wild lady.
That why I fuck with.
Cut me up
and then we gonna get to it.
Aight let's get to it then.
Good God mercy.
Need that though.
Yeah, so how's business
been going around here?
Shit, shit going real
smooth around here,
you know what I'm saying.
Keep a nigga out of the way.
Yeah that why I'm trying
to see what we can do
so we can take some of this good money
and open up more businesses
around here in the neighborhood.
Oh yeah.
We can do that.
Gotta have this revenue.
We definitely got to get
into this shit right there.
That's the God damn thang.
Nobody got the good shit
like that 'around here.
I'm telling you.
They gonna love it.
Yeah, that straight drop top.
Mama gonna make that jump, understand me.
I got some pee wees who
tear the block up anyway
with that shit, you know what I'm saying?
Shit this gonna be it right here sis.
I'll put you in the game, hold up,
I'll put you in the game right there.
You know what I'm saying.
God damn shit.
Aight, well here you go.
This all you.
Okay.
Nice doing business with you.
Hey I'm gonna see what this shit do.
I'ma hit the kitchen tonight now.
God damn let you know
if they ain't jumpin',
it ain't jumpin' you know I'm
God damn on your nit though.
Guarantee you gonna love it.
You gonna love it.
Oh yeah.
Good God almighty.
That's that fish.
God, boy we on now.
Good God almighty boy.
This shit going down.
God damn boy.
Got time for one more bro?
Shit boy I'm closed right now my nigga.
Shit sign say open.
My bad bro.
I'ma God damn set that shit straight.
I should turn that shit out.
Come in here holla at me tomorrow though.
What time?
Shit come through 'round about 6:30.
Aight bet I got you.
Aight.
We had that bitch up last night.
Shit everybody was in
there, you shoulda seen it.
Man I'm talking about that
nigga put a VIP hood bound bro.
Man look at that nigga
on that God damn scooter.
What the hell he doing?
That nigga up to something.
He gonna work somebody.
What it do, bro?
Oh shit!
What up, what up?
One of y'all got a car on y'all?
Car?
Talking about for that scooter?
I ain't paying for no God damn
scooter with no car nigga.
Shit what you pay for it though?
What you mean what I pay for it nigga?
You know damn well I don't need that shit.
That nigga pull up on a scooter bro.
Nigga pull up on a scooter nigga.
Pull me to the spot right now.
What is it, fish scale?
Pressure.
Pressure?
Let me see.
Take a little hit.
What's up, what's up man?
What's going on?
What's going on with you?
I thought you wasn't here.
Look at this little nigga right here.
Man he say he got something to show us.
Open the bag nigga.
Hold on one second.
Didn't take you that
long to open it up outside.
There was just two of y'all.
You ain't gotta act like that.
Okay.
Didn't you say a mother
fucker broke in your shit?
Yeah, this here.
That's yours right there?
Get that bag.
Beat that nigga ass.
He broke in my shit.
Yeah nigga so you gonna tell me
what the fuck going on nigga.
You going tell me where the fuck
the rest of that shit at nigga.
Either you gonna start talking
or nigga gonna put a hole in your ass.
Man this all the fuck you got nigga?
This ain't all the money right here nigga.
This little bit of change?
Where the rest of my
mother fucking shit at?
I had 10 mother fucking
bricks in my trunk nigga.
Call that nigga right now nigga!
Call her!
Steal my mother fucking shit nigga.
Think you're gonna get away with that.
That's family nigga.
Like I was telling you bro,
I'm fixing to have this
whole strip mall God damn
spit ash nigga.
You already know how this shit go.
I gotta take this.
I'ma holler at you though.
Okay, alrighty.
Fo sho.
Yo, yo, yo, yo.
It's Chez bro.
I need you to meet me up the strip.
No give him the address!
You better tell him
where the fuck you at.
I don't know the fucking address.
822 Moretz nigga.
Oh hell no.
Nigga where the fuck you at?
822 Moretz, come now, now.
And bring my shit!
How the fuck?
Money bro.
Or hide your mother
fucking family nigga.
I'm on my way bro.
Nigga, I'm on my way.
Fuck!
Oh you think you're a
mother fucking gangsta nigga?
You think you're a mother
fucking gangsta nigga?
See I knew from the jump you
wasn't with that gangsta shit,
little bitch.
Little bitch ain't with that shit.
Nigga, how long before
he get here nigga?
That's him right there.
Come in!
Oh hell no!
Nigga, don't move, nigga.
Don't move, nigga.
Don't mother fucking move nigga.
Don't make a mother fucking move nigga.
Don't make a mother fucking move.
Where the fuck my money at?
Don't move nigga.
Set your big ass on fire.
Put that briefcase on the counter.
Put it right there nigga.
Get that right there big boy.
Get that.
What you mean nigga?
You got a scrap nigga.
If he move, hit him,
if he move, hit him.
Nigga, move around here nigga.
Get your mother fucking
ass on around here nigga.
Get in line here nigga.
Tie that nigga.
Stay right there.
Keep it on him.
It's all there.
Nigga don't say nothin'.
Is he short?
It look like they short.
'Cause I smoke him.
Is you short two dollars?
Don't shoot him, don't shoot him.
From what he got
and he got,
got extra two bricks that
his boy had and tried.
Extra bricks?
Ain't no extra brick.
Nigga, he ain't have one.
He had two bricks nigga.
I was gonna tell you.
We gonna talk about that later.
It's all there.
He had two bricks on yo ass nigga.
From what I know, from what
I know about the business man,
it's all there, right there
from my business dealing.
Is he short?
Don't kill him 'cause look
how much money he brought back.
Is he short?
He's short but they gonna make that up.
They gonna make that up for us.
Yeah, we gonna put these niggas to work.
Can I get up now?
Nah nigga.
Stay where the fuck you at.
Don't ask no questions.
Talk to him big brother.
Now I'm gonna give you 10 more
and I need y'all to move
them mother fuckers.
Think y'all can handle that?
Hell yeah I can handle that.
Yeah we can trust the nigga.
What you gonna do to them if they don't?
I'm gonna shoot you, stab you, stab you
and shoot you nigga.
Shoot me, stab me?
That's some penitentiary ass shit nigga.
We shooting out this bitch.
I'll stab you nigga.
Know what I mean?
And once you get out,
that ain't all on you.
Keep talking nigga and
I'ma shoot you, stab you,
stab you and shoot you nigga.
So, do we got a deal nigga?
To pay off your mother fucking debt
or all the rest that you owe.
You like 20, 25 bands short.
Is y'all gonna pay off that debt?
We got it.
No problem.
We definitely got it.
Nigga, this is some bullshit man.
Shit.
'Cause of you nigga we
getting fucked up nigga.
What you mean 'cause of me?
'Cause it's true nigga.
We lost every mother fucking thing nigga.
Every mother, I should,
I love you so mother fucking
much that's reason why
I ain't gonna put my hands on you.
You heard what the man said.
He got us.
Man, he got us!
No he got you nigga.
You on your own mother fucking own nigga.
I'm not fucking with you no more bro.
Ain't no loyalty with you.
Real shit nigga.
It's over.
Fuck you then.
I better not see your
ass around no more either.
Where your badge at?
Come in.
Where your damn badge at?
Tell that mother fucker
to put his badge on.
You keep that badge on at all times.
What leads y'all got
for me on these cases?
Like I keep saying, man,
must be running the sugar shack joint.
See two little girls in there.
They bought the liquor.
By the time it was time to apprehend him,
he was already going out the back door.
So, you're telling me his fat ass
like the ghost just disappeared?
That fat mother fucker quick!
Catch his fat ass.
So y'all
Man ask Mr. coffee and donuts over here.
What you got on everybody else?
What you got on Chez man?
I've seen Chez make a friend quick.
So he's playing chess with us?
Only thing is,
only thing I really know
is about Muscle
And that's it.
You ain't got nothing on KB?
I heard she been selling
loud over there off of
God damn fifth and third.
Bitch talk loud.
What you got on Mr. Bank roll fam though?
You got anything on him?
Nothing but he's crazy.
I'm gonna tell you what I detected.
He likes bitches.
Get some bitches together.
We don't have enough money.
We broke.
Is there any way we
can talk about a budget
on what we're trying to get done?
A budget?
At least 50 thousand.
They're killing everybody in my city,
pushing all these drugs,
making my city Merklin
Bird mother fucking county.
You know what I'm detecting with y'all?
I'm detecting a whole bunch of bullshit.
So, if y'all don't get
me no evidence soon,
y'all gonna get back to
pushing that damn pen
and you gonna get back
to writing citations.
Do y'all detect that shit,
detectives?
Nice, nice.
But you know what ain't
hearing that bullshit?
Ask God you got there?
Find out what these mother
fuckers in the streets doing.
And how to break these cases.
That's what you need to
put in the God damn song.
But you know what you can do?
What's that Captain?
Get the hell out of my office.
What the hell are you doing?
Put down my God damn juice!
God damn Captain, I can't get the juice?
You don't deserve juice!
Put down my God damn juice and
get the hell out my office!
All right Captain.
You too, coffee and donut.
I got everything, fish
gear, come shop with me.
Yeah, prices low.
Stack 'em deep, sell 'em cheap.
Y'all already know me.
What's going on?
What's up bro?
How you doing?
You got five grams.
Yeah I want 500 for those.
Everything hitting on my end.
How the fuck's this make you feel?
Turn the fuck around right
now, the fuck around.
Keep your mouth shut, don't look at me.
Fuck going on man?
Oh what's this, what's this?
That ain't mine.
Turn the fuck around.
What is this?
Hey!
Did I say you could fucking talk?
Listen to me, we may be able
to work this out all right?
I may be able to let this
slide under the table.
What you're gonna do is
you're gonna give me some information.
All right, I'll let you
get the fuck out of here.
So you'll telling me if I
give a little information.
Am I speaking fucking Chinese here?
I already told you what I wanted.
Aight bet.
Man I heard there was a body man
about last week, on Jones and
Roosevelt I think they said,
Jones and Roosevelt.
Okay what was that about last week?
Yeah about last week man.
Hell yeah about last week yo.
You know who did it?
Yo man, I heard it was Chez
and Greers who did that man.
That's what I heard.
That's all I know though.
All right I heard about that
too, I heard about that too.
All right, all right,
what we're gonna do is
give you this fucking stuff back
and you're gonna get the fuck out of here.
Gonna take this, take it, okay?
Take your stupid ass fucking gun, okay?
If I ever see you around
here any time fucking soon,
we're gonna have fucking
problems understand?
All right say no more.
Now get the fuck out of here.
Appreciate that, appreciate that.
Fucking piece of shit.
What's up little nigga?
Yo what's up?
Yo your thing good man.
I need you to come through the spot
and holler at me.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah you know the
address that I text you.
I got it in the phone.
But listen though, listen
though, listen though.
Yo your mans Bankroll Ziggy
bro, what's up with him bro?
You need to check that nigga.
Say what?
Man I'ma holla at him man.
You know what I mean.
That just how he is, he don't trust you.
He always on my ass.
The other day was just
saying like he knew you
from somewhere that you
did some fucked up shit.
Know what I mean?
That just how he is.
But you know, I'ma holla
at him about it though.
So you know what I mean,
just come on through
and pick that on up.
You feel me?
I'm on my way.
Bet.
Yeah Bankroll just go back,
back there where you left off, yeah
and we gonna start back right there.
I'm gonna punch you in.
What's up man?
Who you here for?
Muscle.
All right, wait right there for me.
Hey Muscle, somebody out here for you.
Oh tell him to come in.
What's up?
What's up little nigga?
What's up RJ?
You ready to get back to work?
Yeah.
Okay.
Bankroll, bring that out.
What's up little nigga?
What's good?
I see you finally made it back.
Couple steps.
You ready to do the right thing now?
Hey look here,
this 10 of them things right?
Hold up nigga, don't put
your hands on this box yet.
It's 10 of them things.
Yeah.
You make sure when you bring this back,
everything all there
'cause if it ain't all there,
and Muscle call me, you
already know what I'ma do.
What I'ma do to you nigga?
Say it nigga.
What I'ma do to you?
You want me to say it?
Say it nigga.
Stab you, shoot you,
shoot you, stab you.
Nah nigga.
Say it.
Shoot you, stab you.
I'ma shoot you, stab you,
stab you, then shoot you nigga.
That's what I'ma do.
Fuck.
You make sure it's all there.
Good God almighty that
bitch locking up already.
Woo, God damn.
This mother fucking pump.
This shit got me sweating like
a mother fucker in here boy.
God damn.
Yo.
Yo what's good with you?
What's up sis?
I'm glad you called me
'cause that shit you had,
that shit was that fire.
They loving that.
I need to come holla at
you right now matter fact.
For real?
I'm around the corner.
Aight.
You know where I'm at.
I'm at the yo.
Come through.
Bet.
What's up with you?
Hey what's up?
What's up bro?
Come on in.
I got some shit I need
to holla at you about yo.
Aight what you talking about?
I got eight more of them mother fuckers.
Eight of them?
Hell no, that's too much.
I'm still working with
the same shit right now.
Well look, get two of
them from me for 21 apiece.
21, I give you 18.
Be six, 36.
Matter of fact, where the hell
you getting all this shit from anyway?
Man, you know that big
black mother fucker, Muscle?
Talking about Muscle who
be getting all the money?
Fuck him!
He beat.
You know it's gonna be a
problem fucking with that nigga.
Fuck him, fuck that
light skin mother fucker
with the braids, Bankroll
Ziggy, fuck all them.
You God damn put it in my hand,
we gonna God damn take care of it.
We gonna make it happen.
You know I got your back.
I'm gonna get the two for 18 apiece.
That's 36.
Aight.
And I leave six.
I know you good for it.
Aight, here you go.
Bet.
I counted already, it's all there.
I already had it planned out.
So that mean I ain't gotta count it.
You ain't gotta count it.
Yo what's good Muscle?
Yo what's up with you homie?
Now, look nigga, Chez
bring that through to you?
Nah, I ain't heard from him.
Yeah I gave him something
to bring through to you.
For real?
You know what I mean,
I told him half of it
was yours.
Oh what?
Well you need to call him
and see what's up with him.
All right yeah let me
call him real quick man.
Let me check that out real quick.
I ain't got nothing from nobody.
Hit me back and let me know what's up.
Aight say no more.
Bet.
It's the same every year.
He always leaves it to the last minute.
God damn mother fucker's giving you shit
for me nigga.
You ain't even hit me back.
Fuck kind of shit this nigga on man?
Yo Greers.
Yo what's up?
Yeah man, Muscle told me he
gave you something for me bro.
Got something for you?
Nigga I thought you said you
wasn't fucking with me no more.
You know what?
Fuck?
Fuck you, fuck Muscle
and fuck Bankroll Ziggy.
Nigga what?
Everybody beat nigga.
Oh yeah?
Nigga it is what it is nigga.
Aight say no more nigga.
I hold court nigga fuck.
This nigga got me fucked up.
This nigga feeling his
mother fucking self.
What he talking about I'm beat?
What?
Damn this nigga stay getting me fucked up.
Yo he calling back now.
Yo what's up with you?
What's good Muscle?
Hey check this out.
Nigga Chez talking real crazy bro.
That nigga talking
about fuck me, fuck you,
fuck Bankroll Ziggy.
Say what?
Man nigga you playing.
This nigga got my shit
and he's saying I ain't getting nothing.
We beat.
Oh he talking real reckless
like that out his mouth?
Yeah.
Oh he must think it's a game then.
Well I'm gonna call Bankroll
and put Bankroll on that real quick.
You God damn right we
fixing to get that back.
You know where he at don't you?
I know exactly where he got
the God damn push that shit
because there's only one person.
Aight well as long as
you know where he at,
shit it's all good baby.
Yeah say no more.
Man nigga I told you your bitch ass
ain't want to war with me.
My little nigga Chez got
some mother fucking big nuts.
Let me call Bankroll.
Shut the fuck up.
Take that dick.
You like that?
Yo.
Bankroll.
Bankroll what's up nigga?
What's up big bro?
What the fuck this nigga doing?
Bankroll!
Say what?
Hey man, that little
nigga Chez said fuck me,
fuck you and we beat nigga.
He did what?
Hold up, hold up, get the fuck off me.
That nigga talking reckless
out his mouth like that.
What you doing?
Don't fuck with me.
Yeah, yeah bro.
Man come over to the
spot and holler at me man.
Come on baby.
Okay I'm on the mother
fucking way right now.
Aight bet.
That's what's up man.
I'm on my way.
Aight.
Hey look here, when I'm
taking care of business
with my mother fucking brother,
don't be reaching for
no mother fucking phone
talking about come on,
get this God damn pussy.
I'm having business right now.
This pussy better than
what's going on on that phone.
Nah it ain't better than
a nigga getting smoked.
When a nigga done violated
and did some bullshit,
nigga smoking ain't better than that.
Okay.
Now bring your ass back over.
Stay like that 'til I get back.
I go to funerals.
Only time I go to church.
I won't go to a funeral
unless it's a nigga I killed.
I'ma shoot you, stab you,
stab you, then shoot you.
Yeah man, I appreciate
you coming through.
I got them things right here
I told you I was going to give you,
but before I give them to you,
you're going to have
to prove your loyalty.
I was supposed to do that?
That nigga Chez, you need
to take Bankroll over there
where he at so he can handle
his business with that nigga.
That sound fair.
Aight bet.
Hey hold up bro.
What the fuck is you doing?
Nah, I want you to drive
and you going to take me
where the fuck that nigga at.
Get these God damn keys nigga.
You drive.
And don't be going fast in my shit.
Come on man.
This shit's.
Man, get in the mother fucking car, man.
Bro, I can't fit in
this mother fucking car.
Nigga, what the fuck you
mean you can't fit in the car?
Squeeze in the car.
Take me where the fuck that nigga at.
All that mother fucking talking nigga.
I'm through talking.
Hey yo bro.
Man, take me where the
fuck this nigga at man.
Before we pull out, I
gotta ask you this question
'cause it's been eating me up
all mother fucking night man.
Nigga, anything I do to bug you, nigga,
it need to bug you.
What's on your mind, nigga?
What's up with the suit?
What you just left church or something?
Nigga I just left a funeral,
that's what's up with the suit.
A funeral?
A funeral, nigga I just left a funeral.
Oh you mean a funeral?
You know what the fuck I mean nigga.
Where the dead people lay.
Nah my bad bro bro.
I send my condolences bro.
Nah don't send me no mother
fucking condolences nigga.
I just left the funeral
of the nigga I killed.
Nigga you killed?
Yeah nigga, I wanted to
make sure they were dead.
What type of shit you on?
Fuck you mean nigga?
I wanted to make that he was dead
and I wanted to see the any
of these mother fucking people
had some smoke or wanted some beef
or any of them issues.
I don't go to church
unless I go to a funeral.
I don't go to a funeral unless
the nigga that I killed.
Now take me where the
fuck this nigga at nigga.
You's a twisted mother
fucker but here we go.
And don't drive fast in my shit nigga
because I'ma shoot you, stab you,
stab you, then shoot you nigga.
Take me where the fuck this nigga at.
Fuck.
You don't play with Muscle.
Okay, what's up white boy?
I've been waiting on you.
Yeah how you doing?
Let's just get down straight
to the business all right?
Okay, what information you got for me?
The cat that I talked to him,
he said he got nothing on
you besides the fact that
word's been going around
that you've been running
a little after hours spot.
What's going on with that?
I'm gonna have to stop that
shit, you know what I mean?
'Cause if that making it hot then
I can't even do that no more.
You ain't got no other information?
Nope, everything's good.
All right, okay, well I'm gonna go ahead
and take care.
How much I pay, I normally
pay you about three grand?
Yeah.
All right well I'm gonna go ahead
and up that and give you about five
'cause you been bringing
me some good information.
You know what I mean?
Okay.
You got that and you just
put that in your pocket
and you take care
and I appreciate it.
Let me know if they got
anything else on me.
I will but you also gotta
do stuff on your side too
- as well.
- Aight.
All right?
That's a bet.
All right, take it easy.
You acting all scary and shit nigga.
Scary?
Man, you got me fucked up.
Set out to prove your loyalty.
Now for some strange reason right,
nigga I like you nigga.
I like you nigga.
Yeah you pretty cool in
your own damn weird way.
Pretty cool?
Nah, nigga I ain't cool.
Yo, you always gotta be so
mother fucking serious man?
Loosen up.
Nah nigga.
God damn.
Hey yo, look, look, I told you.
That's them?
Nah, nah, nah, nah.
Is that them?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Nigga is that them?
That's all I want to know.
That's them, that's them.
Cut the lights off.
Cut the lights man.
Slow down nigga.
What the fuck you driving fast?
Slow down.
I told you don't be
acting all scary and shit.
Now slow down.
Oh shit!
Mother fucker I told them
I gonna shoot you, stab you,
stab you, then shoot you.
Stab and shoot what the fuck?
Come on nigga!
Nigga come on!
Man fuck that hat.
Come on nigga!
I'm about to whoop your
ass like we used to do
in.
I have five on the two.
Hey sis, you remember
that shit you gave me right?
Yeah.
That shit was A1.
That
Told you bro.
Appreciate it.
We be sweating to every God damn thin.
You wouldn't even believe what happened.
What happened?
That nigga came back with
eight more of them things.
Eight more?
Yeah.
Good God almighty.
You know little Chez man
from down there in Greenville?
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
That God damn Chez fell out though.
Not no more that nigga.
He back.
Back, good crack.
And you wouldn't even believe
who he got that shit from.
Who the fuck he got it from?
Muscle.
Muscle?
Yeah he took that nigga's shit.
That shit is crazy.
Yeah, I told that nigga we got his bag.
Fuck, shit we got
Shit, I'm ready.
Big shot right here.
I had to bet right.
Oh yeah.
I told you I was gonna whoop
your ass like we used to do
Hey you better not fuck
with my mother fucking money.
Speaking of the devil,
here goes this nigga Chez
calling right now.
Chez, what's up with you bro?
Say what?
For real?
Telling a mother fucking lie.
Aight, aight, we won't talk
about that on no phone.
I see you when I see you.
Aight.
There it is.
Yo what's going on?
Man you wouldn't even
believe what the fuck
just happened.
What happened?
That nigga Muscle just fucked
up our mother fucking spot.
They what?
He went over there, shot up our shit.
Man y'all go straighten that shit man.
Oh we got what they want.
Man get them niggas.
Live in the Queen City,
you've probably driven by this area
near South Boulevard and Tyvola.
CMPD telling us one man has been
pronounced dead on the scene.
Tonight we are asking police
what led up to the homicide,
how the victim died,
and if there's a suspect on the run.
Muscle went all the
fuck way out on this one.
Hell yeah nigga.
I'm gonna get money.
Gotta God damn step it up a little more
to prove my loyalty nigga.
I'm trying to get all the way in the game.
I just got to figure out who the fuck
I can move this shit to
that's gonna God damn
make a difference.
I know who.
Yeah call my nigga Steezy.
He'll know what to do.
He'll take me to the nice market.
Time to turn up on these mother fuckers.
What's up Auntie?
What's up with you nephew?
Yeah I got some shit popping off, man.
I need you to meet me over at the spot.
I don't even want to talk about it
over the phone.
Aight I'm on my way.
Aight.
Hell yeah nephew fixing to come through.
Fixing to have him handle that shit ASAP.
Yeah bro.
You know where them niggas be at?
Hell yeah.
They got a spot out the south side.
All right.
Well, my nephew on the way over here.
So you can take them over there
so y'all niggas can go handle that.
Bet.
Nigga you wanna find out
where the fuck they at bro.
'Cause if you don't,
you about to fall all
the way the fuck out bro.
Straight up.
Didn't you just hear me
tell this mother fucker
where they at man.
Auntie what's going on?
What's up nephew?
What's all that yellow
tape shit out there?
That's why I called you over here
'cause that nigga Muscle,
he done fucked up our shit.
So he fixing to take y'all over there
so y'all can handle that shit.
Oh shit, I'm ready, let's go.
Straight up.
Somebody gonna die tonight.
Man we need to hurry up so we can find
these mother fuckers so we
can slide on they bitch ass.
I don't give a fuck man.
I ain't killing no mother
fucking innocent God damn people.
Nigga what?
The east side like a straight bitch.
These niggas shot and stabbed
and shot your mother fucker
cousin, you talking about
Man, both of y'all shut the fuck up.
We fixing to pull up
and God damn bun these
bitch ass niggas man.
I'm ready, you ready?
Hell yeah I'm mother fucking ready.
There go them niggas right there.
See they hanging out
right here stealing man.
Same spot where a nigga just got killed.
Niggas don't care bro.
We'll deal with that in a minute
but before we get to that,
I need to let you in on something.
I don't need you to do
that shit that you did
in the Captain's office again.
What you talking about,
the coffee and donuts?
The coffee and donuts, that rap shit,
don't do none of that shit bro.
It's that right there, them jokes.
There's a time and a place for everything
and that's not the place
nor was that the time.
You right, you right.
If you want him to take us serious,
we gotta take ourselves serious.
You right man.
All I wanted to be was a cop.
And that's what I
need you to be is a cop.
Playing jokes and acting
like everything is a game
is gonna end us in a situation
that we don't want to be in
which is beating the streets.
You right.
Let's get out here and deal
with these clowns out here
and figure out what's going on
and try to solve this case
before the Captain really get in our shit.
I say we start with
this nigga right here.
Aight let's do it.
Bet.
Damn boy you know a
nigga got shot over here?
I heard that nigga got shot and stabbed.
Shot and stabbed?
Shot and stabbed.
Damn boy, they go the police boy.
I'm gone.
Freeze, freeze!
What you doing out here?
Just chillin' man.
What's going on?
Man, why them boys run?
You know somebody just got killed out here
the other night.
You just hanging out?
I heard about it but
I ain't do that shit.
I don't know nothing about that.
You got any drugs, any
guns, any weapons on you?
I ain't trying to get stabbed
Spread 'em, spread 'em, spread 'em good.
This mother fucker got a screwdriver.
What he doing?
Fixing bicycles with it?
Turn your ass around.
What are you doing with a screwdriver?
I coulda got stabbed with this.
What's your name?
You don't know nothing
about these murders?
I heard about it but
I ain't do that shit.
What the fuck you doing out here?
Sir I'm chilling.
I can't chill out this mother fucker?
Get your ass out of this piece.
Hey, hey, hey!
Get your screwdriver.
Fix your bicycle.
Sick of this shit.
We gotta catch this mother fucker.
Peace God, what's the signs with you?
Peace God, how you doing?
Blessed today?
Yeah we blessed today.
Add three more ciphers to that.
Peace God.
You did the knowledge and
that situation that we built
on the past day?
All right listen,
you know and understand right
now you got to pull back
from everything that you're doing.
I do got to step back and
put somebody else in the plate.
But I'm thinking about
leaving it all alone, man.
You know what I mean
'cause there's too much
stuff going on right now.
Listen, God, you got to
know and understand one thing.
You know that flag that you
wearing right there, man?
That's a universal flag
when and what it stand for.
Also right about now you
got to see that's here.
So all that master cipher,
that's going to come in some way,
some form of fashion, you got
too much hustle on your body.
Do you understand what I'm saying?
You also got a queen that stand by you.
You can pull back and
let your team go forward.
You understand what I'm saying?
You got to know and understand
like today's mathematics
wisdom sight for all
being a born of wisdom.
So do this wisdom is wise
words spoken by a wise man,
but down dealing with supreme
alphabet that's wisdom,
cipher that shows the proof,
the truth in the square.
And you are that man
that's within that square.
So you hold all that in
your palm of your hands.
You feel me?
Aight man, the ball in your court,
but you got to make
some type of move ASAP.
Yeah, God, one more thing I
wanted to build on your with.
No nephew, boy?
Why what's up?
He got a show coming up,
but he got to go to the
radio station tomorrow,
but I need you to DJ for me at the show.
Let's say less man,
you know I'm gonna be right there
doing what I gotta do, man.
I'ma put that divine justice down for it.
Say less peace God.
Come in.
What's happening Captain?
Aight, where your partner
at Detective Coffee and Donut?
I just dropped him off at the house.
He was sick,
throwing up all over the place.
So, I just came up here to figure out
where we at and let you
know what we've got.
Oh I guess he ate something out there
at the Sugar Shack huh?
I don't know.
Them pieces of bad butt.
Tom Bone been heard about
slinging that bone around,
but he'd been throwing
it at the wrong bitches.
Some rabid bitches.
I don't know nothing about that.
Okay.
Trying to figure out what's
going on up here, Captain.
All right, well I'm gonna let you know.
Well, Officer Dan been doing a little more
than what y'all been doing.
He came through and let me know these two,
they got something to do with that murder
over there in Lakeview on Jones Street.
You think they got anything
to do with that stabbing
that happened over there?
I don't know nothing about no stabbing.
'Cause they dropping bodies
after body, after body.
That's why I need y'all to
do some real detective work.
Bring them in for questioning
and that way we can figure
out what's really going on.
Aight.
Look at 'em.
How about these guys over here?
We got anything else on them
other than what we've given you?
Ain't got a word.
What the hell y'all brought me on them?
Not a God damn thing.
You know what you can do?
Talk to me Captain.
Get the hell out my office
'til you bring me something
on them.
Get the hell out.
Don't let the doorknob hit you
where the good Lord should have split you.
Next we gonna get into this new record.
Man Ongo, tell 'em about it man.
Talk to me.
Man, Ongo, the song,
man, me and my little bro,
little Zay Hustle man,
Zay, that's my artist,
he ain't here right now,
you know what I'm saying?
He's up in New York making a lot of moves.
So, me and him came up with the song man
and just something we
threw on the internet
and it took off with a mind of its own,
you know what I'm saying?
Then I got Trefina Cox
in the building with me.
She support me, video vixen,
you know what I'm saying.
Shug Chassey, that's actually your name,
Shug Chassey.
I had to stand up for the youth man
coming after me man.
Bro got to man.
Right you know it's a lot
of stuff out there you know,
a lot of artists don't
know how to go about doing,
you know what I'm saying?
So the generation before me,
they made no way for me.
So I had to make a way for me
and the generation coming after me.
Time waits for no man.
Time waits for no woman.
Right.
Boy Chasey, boy in the building on go.
You know it.
If you won't go, make some
mother fucking noise, man.
If you got a birthday in here tonight,
make some mother fucking noise, man.
Hey you know what, any time
I go to South Carolina,
my niggas fuck with me.
Shout out to South
Carolina in the building.
Miss New York, what it do baby?
Happy birthday, baby.
Hey I got my nigga Bankroll
Ziggy in the building man.
Hey free rhyme a little man.
Where my little brother Ziggy at man?
This nigga ain't picking up.
Yo.
Yo, yo, yo, yo, yo.
What up, Steezy?
Yo what's up nigga?
What's happening boy, what happening?
Hey look, check this out, man.
I got something on my hands, man,
you might need to take a look at.
Very profitable.
Oh word.
Well you know where I'm at.
I'm behind the store.
Aight.
Where I'm always at.
Aight say no more.
I'll be there.
I know where you're talking, aight.
Aight, I got you.
Aight.