[Jet's "Cold Hard Bitch"
playing]
Got to leave town
got another appointment
Spent all my rent
girl you know enjoyed it
Yeah
Ain't going to hang around
till there's nobody dancing
I don't want to hold hands
And talk about
our little plans
All right
cold hard bitch
just a kiss on the lips
And was on my knees
I'm waiting give me
cold hard bitch...
[Dirtmits's "Get On"]
...You're stuck here in the middle
and you got it
Stuck in the middle
You're stuck here
in the middle
And you got it
Yeah
Yeah yeah
I'm an adult now. Whoo!
Deep throat.
Deep throat. Let's go!
Whoo!
Whoo-hoo. Yeah!
Ahh.
I'm going to college! Whoo!
Evening, fellas.
Nick! Buddy, let's go.
Hey, hey, hey.
Come on.
Guys, I can't. Told you, I can't.
Chug-a-lug! Chug-a-lug!
Put me down!
Oh, man, it's in my nose!
You whacking
with condoms now?
Dude, you're
supposed to use them,
not collect them all.
They're not hockey cards.
Unless...
Shut up, man.
Dude, you are tapping ass tonight.
Yeah!
Wait. No, no. Not looking like that,
You're not. You'll be fine.
Just remember -
it's like porn.
You got four positions,
three minutes each,
then go forthe face.
- No, not the face.
- Yeah, the face, man.
Monkeys been doing it
for decades.
Plus chicks like it.
It's an exfoliant.
See you guys around.
Wish me luck.
Good luck, Nick.
Hey, keep the wrapper.
What?
You know, like, as a memento
or souvenir or something.
Put it in a book or...
What?
I'll be over here.
Now, it's just a feeling,
and it's hard...
to know why, but...
I think you've got
exactly what I'm looking for,
and I could use you
just as soon as possible.
Thanks, Mr. Swackhammer.
I'll call you first thing
in the morning.
- Yeah, you do that.
- Trish!
Nick, hey.
There you are.
Um, this is...
[cell phone rings]
Please hold.
Go forthe Hammer.
No way.
I've been
looking foryou.
Are you drunk?
Nick, we had a deal.
Some guy
just spilled beer on me.
I'm serious.
Trish, come on.
It's the last day of high school.
You don't want to leave a virgin
any more than I do.
All right, Nick.
You've earned it.
We both have.
Follow me.
Oh, no. Oh, no.
Yeah
Make some noise!
[Grunting and moaning]
[Kyprios's "Sex" playing]
[Laughing]
Wow!
- Was that all right?
- Are you kidding?
That was the best
two and half minutes of my life.
Really?
Oh, wow.
Can't believe
we waited so long to do this.
I've got to make up
for lost time.
We're going to have to do this
a lot.
Okay.
Thattaboy. Thattaboy.
Yeah.
Oh, shit.
No. Oh, crap.
Whoo!
Yourfriends
are a bunch of idiots.
Hey, buddy,
something's wrong
with this picture.
Yeah, Nick's having sex
and we're not.
Come on. Operation Poontang!
[Laughs]
Right now
know you're thinking of me
Sex
I'm anywhere
that you want me to be
Sex
And want you to
think that I'm love
On your left, son.
What's this for?
Whoo.
It's a piercing chair.
Oh, god.
You guys are
doing piercings now?
Yeah, we're diversifying.
Look. They call it the javelin.
You want one
on the house?
Drink up.
Yin yang huo.
Horny goat weed.
After a rough night of sex,
it's just the thing.
Excuse me?
Oh, don't be coy, Nick.
Everybody knows.
Our little boy
finally lost his virginity.
Such a shame it was
with the spawn of Lucifer.
What?
Who?
Oh, speak of the devil.
Hey, Nick.
Trish.
Jerry, Toni.
I was wondering where you went.
Had tae-kwon-do class
this morning.
Ah!
That's right.
Yeah, get up...
[Both]: Before noon.
Yourfolks should try it
sometime.
Yeah.
Look, I had
a really good time
last night.
Oh, god, so did I.
Oh, hey, you look great today.
Thank you.
What's with the bags?
Actually, that's what I want
to talk to you about.
I won't live on this island
forever, Nick.
My major's in communications.
This is good for me.
The whole summer?
I mean, Trish, what about us?
What about our plans?
Nick, thousands of girls
apply forthis thing.
He said I'm his first choice.
You met this guy
yesterday.
Hey, Trish.
It's go time, kid.
Your Eager Beaver awaits.
Back off, Swackhammer,
we're having a moment.
Look, my resume
could use experience.
If you cared for me,
you'll tell me to go.
Okay.
We're going to stay faithful,
right?
I'll try.
You'll try?
Come on, Nick.
It's not like we're engaged.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Um...
[propeller whirring]
Yo, Trish, let's go!
Be smart.
You don't want to end up
like your parents.
[Gob's "Break" playing]
Whoo!
Well you play it
cool and swell
But I've been through
all hell
Plan to make a break
think then forget about it
Better if it blinks out
I'm not getting through
at all
I don't wanna pray
I just wanna get on...
Aah!
What the hell
are you doing?
Sending some e-mail photos
to Trish
in case she gets homesick.
She's been gone for weeks, pal.
Get over it.
Come on, you see
those waves out there?
They're gorgeous.
I've been surfing with a hard-on
all morning.
Come on. You want in?
Tyler, in all the years
you've known me,
have I ever gone surfing?
Oh, Nick, look at you.
You call this a life?
It's about
taking chances, man.
Kicking ass.
Look at Dime out there.
He's a total feeb,
and he risks dying
every time
he goes out there,
yet he keeps doing it.
Do you know why?
Uh, yeah, what is it?
Carpe Diem.
Seize the day?
Got it.
I don't think you do.
Excuse me?
Can you give me
a hand here?
I'm having trouble
with my straps.
Uh... yeah.
Sure.
Come on in.
You know, I'm not really good
with knots,
but I can tell...
you've got really great hands.
Thanks.
I bet you're really good
with them.
Yeah, I bet you are.
You know... I'm, uh...
I'm seeing someone,
so I'm a little
emotionally unavailable.
That's okay. We'll just leave
our emotions out of it.
Really, I'm flattered,
thank you, but...
Oh, come on.
I mean, they said you'd be tough,
but I am half-naked here.
They? Who's they?
Um...
- Hi, honey.
- Hey, bud.
We're just trying to,
you know, cheeryou up a little bit,
get your mind off Trish.
Oh, and she gave us
a terrific rate.
Yeah, well...
You guys got me a hooker?
Oh, no, no.
I'm a massage therapist.
But for an extra 50,
I can, you know...
No. I have a girlfriend!
And she's beautiful,
and smart,
and going somewhere.
And afterthese
Much Music Awards are over,
she's going to come back here...
- Whoa.
The Much Music Video Awards?
- Yeah.
Let me guess.
Internship
with Lenny Swackhammer?
You know him?
Oh, I know him all right.
All nine inches, in fact.
I had your girlfriend's job
last year. That Swackhammer,
he made those awards
one hell of a night.
Whoo!
Wait. Wait.
What are you talking about?
Well, I don't remember much,
but I do recall me and Swacky
in a Nickelback sandwich.
The Swackhammer intern deluxe.
Apparently, it's a tradition.
Want a demonstration?
No, actually,
I've got to go.
Can I keep this?
Oh, yeah.
Sure, babe, sure.
Oh, hey, you want
a free nipple ring?
Yeah!
[Horn honks]
Nick!
Free booze.
Get your ass out here!
Dude, a beertruck just
jackknifed on the highway.
A river of pale ale on the numberfour.
Let's go check it out.
Sorry, guys.
I got to sit this one out.
I've got some packing to do.
One-way ticket to Toronto.
Flight leaves in the morning.
You're flying out to see Trish?
Why?
The girl has a full-time job.
She doesn't have time...
I'm going to ask her
to marry me.
It looks real, doesn't it?
It cost me 10 bucks.
Hopefully it'll tide her over
till I can get her
something better, but...
What?
You guys think she's going
to know it's fake?
Have you lost yourfucking mind?
Dude, I'm just taking your advice.
You see something you want,
you go for it.
I meant get drunk, get laid,
go skydiving,
not throw your life away.
Fag.
[Revs engine]
Congratulations.
Hey, hey, hey.
Who wants brownies?
Not right now, thanks.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, and listen, son,
we're, uh...
Sorry about that whole
whore thing.
I thought she was
a massage therapist.
Honey...
We just want to make sure
you're doing this
because you love Trish,
not because
she finally popped your cherry.
Stop saying that.
Guys, I love her.
Okay? I really do.
Fine, fine, fine.
Have a brownie.
[Wind chimes clatter]
Uh, I'll get it.
Congrats on the wedding.
Let's drink.
I thought you didn't approve.
I don't.
But I can't send my dawg
off to the slaughter
without a properfarewell.
I appreciate it, guys,
but I got an early flight.
Muffin.
Okay, two beers, max.
Shit!
My plane. My plane.
Good morning, sunshine.
Dude, will you cut
that out, please?
What the hell's going on?
My flight.
Relax, Sparky.
We'll get you to Toronto.
Oh, thank god.
I thought I slept in.
Oh, you did.
What? How?
I had, like, two beers.
Mom.
Dude, your mom's
pot brownies are killer.
You're going to have to totally
hook me up with that recipe.
Please, would you
cut that out?
Just take me to the airport.
I'll fly standby.
Back off, man.
We'll get you to T-dot.
Dude, the airport's
that way.
Yeah, I know that.
We're taking the scenic route.
Road trip, baby.
- Tofino to Toronto.
- Whoo, surprise!
- No. Pull overthe van.
- No can do.
Schedule's pretty tight, Nick.
The awards are less than six days...
Pull overthe fucking van.
[Tires squealing]
Why didn't my parents
stop you?
Well, they were still passed out
when we left, man.
Nick, I don't know
what you're so upset about.
You owe us this.
- I owe you?
Call it what you will.
A rite of passage,
a final send-off...
Atravelling bachelor party.
- Good one.
- Thank you very much.
Okay, Nick, I've never been
to Banff before, okay,
and I hear Prairie girls
taste like corn.
What? You like corn.
As long as we get laid
and you're in Toronto by Sunday.
Come on, dude, say yes.
Say yes! Say yes!
Say yes, yes!
Say yes! Stop it!
Stop it! Fine, fine!
Just stop it!
Shit!
Yahoo!
Oh, oh!
Oh, oh, come on.
Look at all that room!
Why don't you try
showing some leg...
or something?
- Don't even.
I'm not the one
who got us into this mess.
Hey, you call it a mess.
I call it ourfirst legitimate gig.
Singing telegrams
is not a legitimate gig.
Yes, it is.
It's just...
What?
If I wanted a bullshit job,
I would've stayed on the rock.
Shut up.
Okay, we got to get
somebody here.
- I know.
- Come on.
Oh, Winnie!
Oh, god.
Show leg, leg, leg.
I'm showing.
Well, hello there.
[Sexy funk playing]
Oh, Johnny Leather,
we got lost
on our way to the beach.
Thank goodness
you picked us up.
How can we
ever repay you, huh?
How about you work my stick
while I drive?
Well, sure,
if you promise
to pop my clutch.
Oh, mine too.
Whoo!
Oh, ho, ho, ho.
Bowm bowm chicky-chicky
bowm bow bowm
- Yes!
- Go, go!
Okay. Um...
- No, no. We're not stopping.
- Why the hell not, dude?
This is a motor home, not a Pinto.
Share the wealth.
Dude, it's my car,
and I make the rules.
This is a road trip.
There are no rules.
Get off me!
The last thing we need
are a couple of hapless trannies
slowing us down.
Look, guys, come on.
They're girls.
They're needy.
We'll have to stop
every 10 miles,
so they can piddle
or change their pads.
Well, I for one could always find time
forthe sanctity of female hygiene.
I back that up, brother.
Hey, girls, need a lift?
Hi, my name's Dime.
Old Nick here's thinking
law school, U of T,
so he's taking the campus tour.
And me and Dime,
we're the entourage,
the "comic relief," if you will.
So what's the deal
with you two?
Spill it.
Oh, you know, just a, uh...
couple of hapless trannies
trying to find our way home.
I hearyou, sister.
Hey, hey, food stand,
two klicks.
Can we stop?
Well, yeah,
I can always use a piddle.
Fancy that.
I got to change my pad.
Ooh, what a gentleman.
[Laughs]
Hey, dude, what's up
with all this law bullshit?
It's your plan, isn't it?
U of T?
Yeah, eventually, but...
Besides, it's a whole lot better
than that stupid marriage idea.
And do us a favour.
Keep that to yourself.
You know, you wouldn't want
to scare off the talent.
Huh?
That one looks naughty.
She's buying a popsicle.
You know what that means.
We're both going to kill you,
if that's what you're wondering.
I was, as a matter of fact.
Look, I think we got off
on the wrong foot.
Um...
Sasha, Newfoundland,
struggling musician.
Excuse me?
That's my name,
where I'm from, what I do.
Thought I'd save you the time.
That's awfully kind of you.
You strike me as a guy who doesn't
have time for such trivialities.
Why'd you come over here
in the first place?
Look, ljust...
I don't mean to be rude,
but I have a girlfriend, so...
See, I knew it.
Look at that shit.
[Perry Como's
"Papa Loves Mambo" playing]
Ooh
Papa loves mambo
Mama loves mambo
Look at them sway
with getting so gay with it
Shouting "Ole" with it
wow
Ooh
Papa loves mambo
Mama loves mambo
Papa does great with it
swings like a gate with it
Evens his weight with it now
He goes to
She goes fro
He goes fast
She goes slow
He goes left
She goes right
Papa's looking for mama
But mama is
nowhere in sight
Ooh
Papa loves mambo
Mama loves mambo
Having a fling again
younger than spring again
Feeling that zing again
wow
Papa loves mambo
Psst.
Mama loves mambo
Don't play the rumba
and don't play the samba
Because papa loves mambo
tonight
Ooh
Can I offeryou
some carrot cake, Emile?
Sugar's forthe weak.
Right on.
So, um...
Jerry tells me you were
in the Special Forces.
Not since the court martial.
You were
court-martialled?
I was told
that you had retired.
Yeah, yeah,
but it was nothing, really.
I mean...
The general's poodle...
it bit me.
So I killed the bitch...
and ate it.
Oh, okay.
They wanted to lock me away,
but your husband,
he was my character witness.
He was very good to me.
Yeah, so that's why, you know,
now Emile wants
to repay the favour.
So we're going to be
his first clients
in his new P.I. Firm.
Right, okay.
This woman...
the one Nick wants to marry,
she's no good?
- I...
She's a conniving bitch.
Yeah.
And Nick doesn't see it.
He's confused, he's young,
and he's horny.
Which is why we think
it's better
if he not make it to Toronto.
So maybe he...
he loses his money,
or his RV breaks down.
Something like that.
We-we've tried everything
we can from here,
and now we're counting on you.
I'll find your boy.
I'll skin him and I'll stuff him -
forfree.
That was humour.
Yeah.
We're pitched
awfully close to their Winnie,
don't you think? I mean...
So let's talk
sleeping arrangements,
'cause I think gender separation's
a little old-fashioned.
Yeah, sounds outdated to me.
So are yourtactics.
Sorry, boys.
So how many beers we got?
Don't know. Why?
'Cause those girls
are gonna need a lot of booze.
I don't know about you guys,
but I'm pitching a tent
in my pants right now.
Shut up.
Dude, it's turning black.
Chicks like it black.
Haven't I taught you anything?
Dude, they're not
going to eat that.
Pull it out.
Hey, Tyler pulls out
when he is good and ready.
Chicks respect that, and they always
come back for seconds.
Dude, it's on fire.
Just take it out.
- Dude, let go.
Let go. Dude...
- Take it out.
Oh, that was smart.
That marshmallow was a fucking
masterpiece, you jackass.
Why don't you let
Dime cook this one?
Because the fire's too big,
too dangerous for Dime.
You guys just sit back,
relax, all right?
We'll be tapping that ass
in no time.
Oh, my god!
Guys, fire!
Shit!
Jill! My god. It's spreading!
Guys, it's spreading!
Stand back!
Stand back! Stand back!
It's empty.
Dude.
I cannot believe you guys.
Whisky?
I'm driving.
I'm rolling.
Ladies?
Jesus Christ.
I'm sorry. Okay?
How many times
do you want me to say it?
Here, I'll tell you what.
You can spank me.
Go on, I deserve it.
Spank me.
Fine.
Whatever.
I'm going to go outside
and get some fresh air.
[Jersey's "What a Wonderful
World" plays]
Whoo! Yeah!
That is what I'm talking about!
I see trees of green
Red roses too
You like this? Come up here.
Come on!
...From me to you
And think to myself
Yeah!
What a wonderful world
I see skies of blue
Golden!
And clouds of white
Bright blessed day
and the dark sacred night
And I think to myself
What a wonderful world
[laughs]
Thanks.
You're welcome.
[Sirens blaring]
Tyler!
What's up?
Cops! Fuck.
Whoa, uh...
Tyler!
What a wonderful world
World
Shit!
Relax. It's probably just a ticket.
We can't afford a ticket, Tyler.
We can barely afford gas to Ontario.
Uh, Sasha,
hide the weed
underneath there.
Cops'll look there.
Betterthan the dashboard!
No, wait!
Holy shit.
What the hell? Dime!
It's just a few
supplies, you know,
in case something happens.
Like what? A nuclear winter?
Oh, shit.
Good morning,
fun boys and girls.
I want you to step
out of the mobile home
and keep your hands
where I can see them, please.
Article C-17,
surfing on the roof
of a moving vehicle,
$200 fine.
Vandalism,
Article B-35, $300 fine.
But this is my van.
Resisting arrest,
$500 fine
and six months in jail.
Do you mind
if I search your vehicle?
You can say no, Nick,
'cause he needs a warrant.
Warrant.
Don't push it, Carbo.
I'll ask again.
May I search your vehicle?
Fine, just let go of his arm.
Jesus.
This sucks.
Open alcohol in a vehicle...
$350 fine.
Heh-heh.
If he finds my stash,
we're screwed.
Relax. He's not going to find it.
Oh!
- Shit.
- Oh, man.
That's a lot of weed.
So what's the fine forthat?
Two pounds
of illegal narcotics?
Yeah.
That's not a fine, hamster.
That's a bribe.
Okay, fine. How much?
How much you got?
You're robbing us?
It's called extortion,
sweet cheeks.
Now, you want to go to prison
or not?
Come on, guys, fork it up.
Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho.
- No, please!
- You want to go through that again?
It's your own damn fault.
You don't have to dump it all!
Just have a bit of compassion, Nick.
No. He's a bad man...
Shh. It'll all be over soon.
[Growling]
Guys?
Shit, dude!
How about a little privacy?
I'm sorry, uh, ljust...
I thought, um...
I thought
you were something else.
[Growling]
Oh, shit! Run!
Get out of my way!
Right, Furtado's in.
So is Avril.
I'm still waiting
to hearfrom Shania,
so keep a dressing room open.
Hopefully one...
close to my office.
Here's your double-shot latte,
extra foam.
Oh, thanks, sweets.
Sir, with all due respect,
I hardly think
that behaviour is appropriate.
Especially in a work environment.
You know,
you're absolutely right.
Trish, please accept
my humblest apologies.
It'll never happen again.
Judy, would you excuse us
for a moment?
Sure.
I thought
she would never leave.
She'll be cleaning out her desk
by the end of the day.
In the meantime,
how about a little...
ass with that coffee?
Mm.
You are so talented.
Oh yeah.
Nick...
Nick!
Hey, Nick.
Wake up, buddy.
Tyler's a hero.
He saved you from a bear.
Shut up, Dime. Here.
I got some painkillers.
Give me three.
Easy there, junkie.
And this is a guy
who calls caffeine a narcotic.
Are you sure you're okay?
I'll be fine.
Ljust need to walk it off.
Thanks, dude.
Whoa, hey, Tyler,
Where'd you get these?
Your bag.
In the small pouch
in my bag?
Yeah.
Dime, what did Nick
just take?
Three hits
of concentrated fungal toxin.
Mushrooms.
Sort of, but way stronger.
Like half a tab, normally,
and you are fucking zooming.
So what's going to happen
to him?
Well, he's not going
to have a headache.
[Music]
Whoo!
[Laughing]
How could you do this to him?
I didn't do anything.
This is Tyler's fault.
Okay, just relax. Okay?
We'll just get him into the van.
Oh...
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah...
[panting]
Oh, this is beautiful, man.
I'm going to build a home
right here.
That's great.
Let's get you back into the van...
Don't touch me!
No, I'm not leaving, man.
I told you, I'm building a house
right here.
Nick? Nick.
Trish...
Trish.
This is life.
Smell it. It smells like life.
Who's Trish?
Mushies talking. It's...
Oh, you hearthem too.
Oh, I love you, Tyler.
Oh, god.
Oh, my god.
The yellow cows are coming!
[Panting]
Yeah! Yeah!
I say we knock him out.
I say we call it a night
and camp out here.
Oh, my god.
Whoo!
He's alive!
Yay!
Oh, he's alive!
You made it.
So how is our little tugboat
this morning?
Tugboat?
What are you talking about?
Let's just say yourtypically...
private time with kleenex
and a little lube...
It kind of became
a public event.
Wankapalooza, you know?
We could've sold tickets.
- You're joking me.
- Dude, you were like a chimp.
Okay?
You were begging us to join you.
You know, some things
are just a little sacred.
Okay, everyone,
I'll be in the lake.
Yeah, so will I.
That is a good idea.
I'm going to grab my towel.
No, no, no, no, no.
You're not going anywhere.
Sasha, we're dipping in shifts.
Sorry, boys.
I'll keep an eye
on the pervs.
What a prude.
Bye, boys.
Come on, Dime. Let's go inside
and root through their panties.
Nick, you're, uh...
You're sweeping the forest.
You sure you're still not tripping out?
A little zoom-zoom?
You guys are messing
with me, right?
I got to tell you,
that little tribal thing
you were doing last night,
it was pretty impressive.
Help me with this?
Whoa. Tribal thing?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
What do you mean?
Oh, man, Nick's going to kill us.
Not when he sees these pictures.
We're going to hell.
Okay, let's face this, pal.
You're not going
to get in Jill's pants.
This is the next best thing.
All right? Look around.
Trees, lake, tits and ass.
This is a Kodak moment.
[Giggles]
What?
Nothing.
Uh, I'm going to go
check on the kids.
Guys?
Oh, god.
I hope Jill's
wearing her swimsuit.
What the hell?
Nick?
Hey, what the fuck
are you doing?
Sasha, it's that cop!
He's putting sugar
in our gas tank.
Okay, I can't see shit.
This angle sucks. Here.
Anything?
Lookee here.
Okay. Grab onto this branch
and reach out.
You grab onto the branch.
I eat, Dime. I exercise.
This branch is not going
to hold me, all right?
All you do is smoke weed
and masturbate.
Grab onto the branch.
"All you do is smoke weed
and masturbate, Dime.
I wear a cowboy hat.
I'm a big dick."
It's locked.
Get out of the way.
Jesus, Sasha, you can't do that.
Easy, law boy, I'm a musician.
I'll do what I want, okay?
I knew it. It's a fake.
Son of a bitch...
What's he want with us?
I don't know.
All right.
Okay, now reach out.
I'm just... hold it steady.
Reach out.
[Cell phone ringing]
Oh, shit.
What... what do I do?
Answer it.
Hello?
[Screams]
Oh, my god!
Dime! Dime!
Dime.
Dime, are you okay?
Oh...
Dime, talk to me. Dime...
Hey!
Was it worth it?
Definitely.
[Horn honking]
20 bucks?
Your mom will do it for 15, asshole.
[RV horn honks]
What's the matter, officer?
Better call for backup, asshole!
[Music]
[Tires squeal]
Well, well, well.
You came to play, boy.
[Music]
Well, we're looking
at $7.00 and change.
Yeah, and that's not going to
buy us very much.
Give me the cash.
Tyler's going to make it
all better.
Come on, folks!
It's for charity.
You know you want to.
I'm the Deputy Mayor of Moose Jaw,
for Christ's sakes.
Come on, pitch a ball.
Put me in.
Are you thinking
what I'm thinking?
Definitely.
What are you thinking?
You know, ljust... I love carnivals.
When... when I was a kid,
I'd beg my brothers
to take me.
See those balloons?
They would tie
as many as they could
to the back of my pants
to see if I'd have liftoff.
Did it work?
They eventually
found me in a tree.
At least you had carnivals.
In Tofino, a big crazy night
would be playing bingo
at the rec centre.
I like bingo.
Yeah, I know. So do I.
You know, being in a small town,
it's cool, but you...
You just eventually...
You want more.
Yeah.
Hey, buddy. How much
forthose balloons?
Nick, don't even think about it.
Fuck me!
I'm getting better.
Your mama didn't raise no quitter.
I respect that.
Save it, carny.
I'm out of cash.
Hey, dude, dude, dude.
If it's money
that troubles you,
I got a way you can
pocket some coin real quick.
I'm listening.
Come on... lover!
Is that the best you can do
with those balls, man?
I'm not even wet here.
Come on, anybody else here.
Psych!
Oh, come on.
You're running out of balls.
What's up?
I'm getting tired here.
I don't have all day.
Oh, wow.
Whoa.
That was good.
What does this pay again?
Two dollars...
a minute.
To act like a bunny.
You're shitting me.
What exactly do you need me to do?
- Uh, you'll figure it out.
And you might want
to put these on.
Okay...
Hop to it.
Looking good.
Hello?
What's up, doc?
[Ding ding]
Stop that!
Stop shooting me!
The pussy's down.
Go forthe face.
Forget the face.
Go forthe balls.
Honey, any time now.
Can somebody...
All right, gentlemen,
show's over.
Go home to your wives
orthe Internet,
or whereveryou get
your weird, sick,
perverted kicks from.
Oh, you were great.
- Thanks.
What are you guys doing?
At this rate,
about 75 bucks an hour.
[Screaming]
Excellent. All right.
Guys, where's, uh,
where's Tyler?
Where you going?
Get back here!
[Roaring]
How does this feel?
Now who's the little pussies?
Huh?
Yeah! Take that!
Look at you!
What?
[Laughing]
Shut up.
[Clattering]
What's that noise?
You guys hearthat?
Hey guys, what's this for?
It's a...
detour.
Buckle up, suckers.
Oh, yeah, this...
this way seems much better.
There's shit falling down
and stuff.
If the RV's a-rocking,
don't come a-knocking!
[Laughing]
This piece of shit's
falling apart.
You should've bought Japanese.
Shit.
We got to get off these
freaking tracks, okay?
[Train whistle blows]
- Oh, my god.
Nick, hurry up!
Hurry, hurry, hurry.
Nick, get...
Oh, my god...
- I'm trying!
Oh, shit.
Shit. We're stuck!
Get out of there!
Everybody, out! Get out!
For god's sake,
what are you doing? Get out!
My guitar!
Oh, no.
Oh.
My surfboard.
My Gibson.
My home.
Is everyone okay?
Maybe we should, uh...
go talk to somebody
or something?
We'll be stuck
filling out reports for a week.
Let's split.
Are we going to Toronto or not?
Yeah, let's...
let's get out of here, guys.
Come on.
Come on, Sash.
Coming.
Hurry up. Come on.
It's not bad.
It tastes like Prairie girls.
You don't know
what Prairie girls taste like.
It could use a little salt.
Butter.
I'm sure the farmer's got some.
Do you think he'd mind?
Thou shalt not steal.
Wait, wait.
Um, listen, we're sorry.
We're just a couple of kids
on our way to Toronto.
You with the Callahan boys?
Spreading gypsy moths...
killing my crops.
No, sir.
No gypsy moths here, sir.
No, listen,
we're just passing through.
Our Winnebago got hit
by a train.
We have no stuff...
That was you? Why...
caught wind of that
on the old transistor.
It's a miracle
you kids are alive.
Shucks, this here's a test.
The Lord brought you here,
and now...
I am your shepherd.
So how about
a home-cooked meal
and a warm place to sleep?
Sounds great.
You'll be bunkin' in
with the cows tonight.
I hope you're not
lactose intolerant.
All I ask
is that no one taint the purity
of my virgin daughter.
Oh, yeah. I get it.
It's like the old farmer's joke.
You know,
"You can sleep in my barn,
but don't you dare touch
my gorgeous,
cock-hungry teenage girl."
It's no joke, son.
In fact, in my house,
it's the 11th commandment.
Thou shalt not lie...
with thy farmer's offspring.
[Cocks gun]
Unless thou wish
the wrath
of thy farmer's boom-stick.
Got it?
Yes, sir.
Who's hungry?
Onward christian soldiers
Marching as to war
Oh, a train accident.
You poor souls.
Praise the Lord
you're all okay.
Everything looks
wonderful, Mrs...
My name's Libby,
and this is Joseph.
How do?
And Josephine
will be down in a moment.
Josephine!
Hey, dude.
How hot do you think this girl is?
- Dude, you're kidding me.
These people are hideous.
She probably has no teeth.
Ah, Josephine.
You finally decided to join us?
Hi.
God help us.
Oh, hi, sweetie.
You're just in time.
Oh, have you met
the boys?
Hi.
- Hi.
So, young man,
you mentioned you had a...
a joke back there
in the cornfield, huh?
Uh, yeah. It's a doozy.
[Clears throat]
Will you please excuse me?
I'm not feeling very well.
Oh, dear, she does this
every time we have guests.
Poor girl's just so darn shy.
So, you there.
Yeah, you.
Make us laugh.
Uh, yeah, the, uh...
farmer's-daughter gag.
Um, sure, what the hell?
Tyler, I don't think
it's a good idea.
So there's these three guys
that bagged
the farmer's daughter.
Oh.
Of course, uh,
the old man finds out,
and goes and grabs a shotgun
much like yours...
You know, Tyler,
maybe you shouldn't.
Uh, so he explains
their punishment to them,
that they have to go
to the orchard
and find theirfavourite fruit.
And anyhow, the guys
think they get off easy,
so they go
and get theirfruit of choice...
[unzipping]
Oh, oh, god.
You okay? Uh, yeah.
Do you hearthat, Joseph?
This darling young man
has volunteered to say grace.
Go ahead, son.
Uh... uh...
Uh, dear Lord...
thank you for giving us
such a...
succulent meal,
and bless us,
and please forgive us
for anything
that we've done
or are...
are doing right now.
And don't...
don't stop loving us.
Don't stop, baby.
Please, don't stop, oh...
And, uh...
And let us
just swallow our sins
and...
Oh...
Oh, Christ.
Oh, Christ...
[moans]
Praise Jesus.
Feels good, don't it?
When a good prayer
leaves you drained?
Okay, let's eat!
Pass the meat.
[Moans]
So then...
Whereabouts
did you kids grow up?
Oh, my god.
Jill...
Are you okay?
Hmm? Mm-hmm. Mm.
Oh. Oh... oh, god.
Joseph, something strange
is going on.
Oh!
Wait a second.
I know what's happening here.
Oh...
Oh, oh...
Fuck you!
Libby, call the exorcist.
These kids are possessed!
And get my gun!
No, no, no, sir,
I assure you...
Oh, shit!
Now, that's it. Everybody out!
Out, out!
And take Lucifer with you!
[Gunshot]
[Screams]
The power of Christ
compels you!
As you come down
I'm not ready to go
[sitar music plays]
[Cell phone ringing]
Oh, I'll get that, babe.
Thanks, honey.
Hello?
Jerry. Yeah, it's Emile.
Oh, hey, Emile.
It's Emile, babe.
Right on.
How are you doing, man?
So what's going on?
Is Nick going to
make it to Toronto?
No. No, he's not.
Oh, right on, buddy.
That is such great news.
Thank you, Emile. I knew
we could count on you, man.
Bye.
I'm not ready to go.
I'm not ready...
I told you
he was the best, babe.
So cool.
One drink each, guys.
We can't afford to booze it.
Nick, after all of this,
we can't afford not to booze it.
[Band plays
"I Feel Like a Woman"]
I'm going out tonight
I'm feeling all right
I'm gonna
let it all hang out
I want to make...
- You suck ass, buddy!
I really raise my voice
I'm gonna scream and shout
Rock and roll!
No inhibitions
Dude, I'm saving your life.
Beat it.
Get out of here.
Now, remember, folks,
the drunkeryou get,
the betterthey sound.
300 bucks
is still up for grabs,
so keep drinking
that liquid courage,
because we need
another sucker on stage.
[Playing "Where Have You
Been Lately"]
Ooh, I see a table.
Cougar alert. Avert your eyes.
And lose this opportunity?
Fuck that.
So what's the plan, ladies?
You going to sing a duet?
Mm-mm. No, no,
no, no, no, no.
Sasha's going up by herself.
Yeah, you have another,
you freaking lush.
Sasha, I want to sleep
in a bed tonight,
and I want a proper shower,
but you're the only one
with the talent.
Now, go up there and...
and make us some money.
Come on.
Yeah. Go for it.
Hey, I'll even buy you a shot.
A shot. Hmm.
Kung Fu. Really?
Black belt?
Naturally.
Impressive.
But the question is, Junior,
do you have your brown belt?
Ah.
The brown belt.
Ashamed as I am to admit it,
uh, I don't.
In fact,
my friend and I were hoping
to earn such a belt
here tonight.
Oh, well...
perhaps that can be arranged.
You just have to sit
really tight, gentlemen,
because we have to pee.
Tight.
Dude, what the hell
was that about?
What were you talking about?
What's with the whole
brown belt stuff?
Dime, let me
explain something to you.
The human female
has up to three openings
that can be used
for sexual pleasure.
To date,
we are familiar with two.
That's where
the cougars come in.
Oh, that... that's disgusting.
That's...
Well, I need a beer.
[Song ends]
All right, folks,
who's tanking next?
Right here, guys.
She wants to.
- Whoo!
- Give her some encouragement.
Come on. Make me proud.
Make me proud.
Whoo-hoo!
Yeah!
Show us yourtits!
You first, porky.
[Laughter]
Shut up!
Okay, this is...
uh, this is for all the assholes
out there.
Prisoner of your love
Entangled in your web
Hot whispers in the night
I'm captured by your spell
Oh yes I'm touched
by your show of emotion
Should I be fractured
by your lack of devotion
Should I
Whoo! Ha, ha.
You'd better be good to me
That's how it's got to be
'cause I don't have no use
For what you loosely call
the truth
And you'd better
be good to me
I think it's also right
That we don't need to fight
When we stand face to face
And you present your case
And I know you keep telling me
that you love me
Not bad for a Newfie, huh?
But did you think
I'd just accept you
in blind faith
Oh sure baby
anything to please you
And you'd better
be good to me
That's how it's got to be
'cause I don't have the time
for your overloaded lines
You'd better be good to me
Be good to me
Yeah
Yeah!
Yes! Whoo!
I don't know about you guys,
but I think we just found our winner!
Yeah!
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Not so fast, boys.
This one's foryou.
Whoo!
Oh, that's what I call talent!
Yeah! Whoo!
First prize.
Second prize.
Yay, Sash!
Yes!
Enough fortwo hotel rooms
and breakfast.
Not bad for second place.
Hey, you're...
you're supposed to be dead.
Stay away from us!
But how did you get out...
Sorry, pal.
This boy belongs to us.
You, let's go.
Come on, slick.
Let's get comfortable.
Okay, but I'm no cheap whore.
You're buying me breakfast.
[Laughs]
I don't think so.
Jill?
Jill, open up.
I guess it's me and you.
I have been dreaming
about this
my entire life.
Oh, I bet you have.
Ooh, ouch!
Ah.
Yeah, come on.
Get them off.
Hola!
Here we go.
What are those for?
Oh, you just wait and see,
little man. Hmm?
I really wanted to.
Yeah, well, so did I,
but we can wait
for anothertime.
You're so sweet.
Kiss me.
Are you sure, because it looked like
you're kind of about to release.
Just kiss me.
I can't.
[Vomiting]
Oh, God.
Shh. Okay, uh...
You were great tonight.
That girl on stage,
who is she?
Did you like her?
You take the bed.
I'm going to...
We paid good money
forthis bed,
and I demand
that we enjoy it.
Are you suggesting we share?
As long as you don't
get any ideas.
I don't get ideas.
Nice and tight,
around the horn...
Yee-haw!
So how does this work?
How am I supposed to earn
my brown belt this way?
Oh, you will, big boy.
Don't you worry.
Whateveryou're doing
back there,
just be careful,
because I bruise easy.
What do you think, Claire?
Should we use
the baby carrot
orthe Excalibur?
Baby carrot. Baby carrot.
Gosh, honey,
it looks like we left
the carrot at home.
Too bad.
So very, very sad.
Load me up.
Oh, dear Lord.
That was...
Yeah.
[Tyler screaming]
[Tyler moaning,
bed banging]
Sounds like we're not the only ones
having a good time.
Yeah.
This is great. Oh!
Cougars?
Hello?
Help?
Help.
Help!
Help! Help!
Somebody!
Help!
Tyler.
Oh, my god.
- Oh, dude.
Your place is way bigger
than ours.
Could somebody
just give me a hand, please?
Does your new friend
have a name?
You got hickeys.
No, it's just a rash.
Dude, you nailed Sasha.
You nailed my Sasha?
- I didn't nail anybody.
- Hey. Nick, come here.
What?
Nick, some details, buddy.
I knew you guys
were going to hook up.
Give us the juice, my friend.
Give us the juice.
Nick, come on,
come on, come on.
Guys? Okay, come and untie me.
Come and untie me, please.
Somebody!
Guys!
[Music]
Come on, come on, come on!
- Hurry!
- I'm coming!
Shut up! I'm a little sore!
Not a fucking word!
Yeah, Tyler, shake your ass!
Fuck you guys!
Hey.
You kids can't be in here.
Relax, old man,
we come bearing gifts.
You think you can shut me up
with a lousy mickey of booze?
You're kidding.
What? It's my personal stash.
Dude.
Make yourself at home.
Hey, this train goes
through Toronto, right?
Toronto, yes?
Of course it does.
Hey, uh,
mind if I have a little hit?
Beat it.
Hey.
So, did you want to...
I'll pass.
Oh, come on, Nick.
I know you're not
turning this down, right?
Sasha, I made a mistake.
You had sex with me
by mistake?
What, did you slip
and fall and accidentally...
We were drunk.
We had a one-night stand.
It was good, but that's it.
It wasn't that good,
so don't flatteryourself.
Look, I'm not going
to law school.
I... I have a girlfriend.
Trish. I know.
And I'm going to go to Toronto
and see her and...
and propose.
I'm, uh...
I'm going to ask her
to marry me.
It's fake.
I know. It's temporary.
Kind of like me.
Yeah.
Someday somehow
I'm going to make it all right
But not right now
I know you're wondering when
You're the only one
who knows that
Someday somehow
I'm going to make it all right
But not right now
I know
you're wondering when...
We're here.
Guys, wake up! We're here.
We made it.
I can't believe we made it.
We got here
with eight hours to spare.
- Nick...
- Guys, about five days ago,
Toronto was a faraway dream,
guys.
- Nick!
- What?
No... No!
No, you told me
we were stopping in Toronto.
You said "through Toronto."
You didn't say anything
about stopping.
I can't believe I gave him
the rest of my weed.
Montreal, huh?
Well, I guess we'd better make
the best of it.
["Super Freak" playing]
She's a very kinky girl
The kind you don't take home
to mother
She will never
let your spirits down
Once you get her
off the street
Ooh
Whoo!
Roast beef and a side of titties.
Are we in heaven or what?
She says that
I'm her all-time favourite
Relax, dude.
Propose tomorrow.
Propose in the fall.
All right? Who cares?
Especially now
that Sasha's in the picture.
Just drop it, Tyler.
That girl is really wild now
The girl's a super freak
The kind of girl you read about
In new-wave magazines
That girl is pretty kinky
The girl's a super freak
Did you get through?
Yeah.
And?
As soon as dad found out
I was in a strip club,
he offered me
a plane ticket home.
You're not going home,
are you, Sasha?
What about Toronto?
What about your music?
This is just not my scene, Jill.
I mean...
Please, Sasha, you can't,
you can't just leave me.
I need you.
Forget about Nick.
Just do it for me.
Stay. Don't leave.
Don't leave, don't leave.
Please.
Okay.
I'll stay.
She's a super freak
Super freak
She's a very special girl
Well, I'm still hungry.
Who wants thirds?
Oh, I'm in.
Hey, there.
Can I interest you boys
in a little... dance?
Nope.
Well, how about a massage, then?
We're fine.
Well, at least buy a drink.
Can't afford it.
This isn't a deli.
You can't just come here and eat.
Look, lady,
unless those are
breasts of chicken
that you're packing,
we're not buying.
Right.
R-row!
Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow.
Hey.
The sign says,
"All you can eat fortwo bucks."
We paid it, asshole.
Hey, she said I could touch her.
I had permission, dammit.
You know what?
Le Pamplemousse.
Hey, these guys
are Swollen Members.
No, they're not.
Swollen's in Toronto
performing at the awards.
Our set's not forthree hours.
We thought we'd get a lap dance
before we hit the road.
- Prev fucked it up, though.
- Wasn't my fault.
You guys are going to T.O.?
Yo, ourflight leaves
in, like, an hour.
Why, you guys need a lift?
Nick,
Swollen Members
have video games on the airplane.
Oh, Prevail.
You're such a riot.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the MMVAs.
Welcome to
the Much Music Video Awards,
Featuring, live,
Avril Lavigne...
Hey, these are live.
Aren't we missing them?
No, man, relax.
It's just a pre-game.
We'll be right on time.
...Fifi Dobson, Pilate
and Swollen Members.
It's kind of frustrating, isn't it?
What is?
We haven't been alone
since the Prairies.
Yeah, that sucks.
And here we are
on a private jet,
a few... miles high.
Yeah, it's awesome.
Miles high.
Oh. Oh... oh!
Shh.
As usual,
the party continues here
at the big pre-game show,
and look at this.
The best part
about this red carpet
is all the stars who show up,
and here's a famous one,
record producer
Mr. Lenny Swackhammer.
How are you, sir?
Oh, shit.
It's Swackhammer, man.
You know that guy?
Everybody knows the Swack.
You got three nominations
this year.
How do you think
you're gonna fare?
- It's Hammertime, baby.
- Who's yourfriend?
Trish?
Who's Trish?
- It's my girlfriend.
- Are you sure?
Okay. Shh, shh.
No, no.
Oh, god.
Please, I'm not even here.
Come on, shh. It's okay.
Hey, I love you guys.
Yeah, you guys too.
Swollen Members.
Yeah.
Uh...
It's, uh, sweat.
[Cheering]
Are you aware
of what you make me feel
Baby right now
I feel invisible to you
Like I'm not real
Didn't you feel me
lock my arms around you
Why did you turn away
Here's what I have to say
I was left to cry there
waiting outside there
Grinning with a lost stare
The action continues.
Swollen Members have arrived.
Mocha, Avril just got on.
You guys are next.
- Whatever, George.
- Whoo. I rock!
'Cause you weren't there
when I was scared
I was so alone
You...
You need to listen
I'm starting to trip
I'm losing my grip
And I'm in this thing alone
Yo.
Whoo-hoo!
Gob!
Gob is here,
and they're drinking free booze.
All right!
Who the fuck is this guy?
Uh, it's our little bitch.
He performs tricks
and simple errands.
You want to borrow him?
Sure.
Beat it.
Excuse me.
I'm looking for Trish Robinson.
She's an intern here.
She's got long blonde hair...
Oh, rocket of an ass, right?
Yeah, she's totally around.
Know what?
Try the other side.
- Thanks.
- Hey, can I buy you a free drink?
Uh, honey, don't you think
we have some unfinished business
to attend to?
- What? Here?
Mm-hmm.
Where?
[Giggling]
Trish!
Nick?
Hey!
Oh, my god.
What are you doing here?
I came to see you.
Oh, you're such a sweetheart.
We need to talk.
It's so good to see you.
Let's go somewhere
a little bit more private.
If you don't care
then I don't care
We're not going anywhere
Deep throat this, bitch.
[Groans]
You can do it.
Tom, the fruit tray.
That's good.
You guys rock!
Hey, guys.
What's going on?
That was awesome.
Good show. Good show.
Who's the cowboy?
He's no cowboy.
He's a banana-eating,
deep-throating bitch.
You want him?
No, I want a beer.
Give her a beer.
That's not beer.
That's water.
That sucks.
To the green room!
You guys are great.
That was funny.
Let's go!
Okay. Outside, I'll meet yas.
Excuse me.
Do you work for me?
No.
Well, you should.
'Cause you would make
an outstanding assistant.
What do you say
we go somewhere...
swing the Hammerfor a while?
- Um...
Hammer, you're on five.
Yeah, thanks.
Swing the Hammer later, yeah?
[Slaps her ass]
Sash, Avril Lavigne
just got me wet
in the pants.
That's great, Tyler.
Look, I'm leaving.
What?
Yeah. Look...
tell Jill I'm sorry.
I'm taking my plane ticket,
and just tell her...
ljust want to go home, okay?
All right.
I'm sorry about Nick.
I know guys can be jerks.
But Avril Lavigne's hot!
[Cheering]
Hey, what's going on?
Are you ready?
Well, give it up.
Swollen Members!
["Watch This" plays]
My motorcycle rings are flooded
I'm star studded
You motherfuckers
not going to be able to cut it
Listen bitch
I'm a tough act to follow
Suck my dick
And here's a nut sack to swallow
Want to get personal
close and intimate
Listen kid I'm a whole
different instrument
Mental I'm not sentimental
I'm intricate
It's impossible
not to get into it
My intent to vent
is not innocent...
Wow.
...Of being real filthy
with these menacing ways
It's time
to finish your phase
I'm proof that raw adrenaline
and energy pays
You're done your time is up
It's a brand-new beat
now turn it up
Swollen's been coming up
So watch these motherfuckers
burn it up
You're done your time is up
It's a brand-new beat
now turn it up
Swollen's been coming up
Now watch these
motherfuckers...
I can't.
I can't do this.
What is it?
I wasn't faithful.
You had a fling?
She wasn't a fling.
Well, who was she?
Do I know her?
No. No, I met her
on the way here.
She was...
She was hitchhiking.
You're dumping me
for a hitchhiker?
I'm sorry.
I'm a hurricane pop
with the speed of a cheetah
Believe in the new school
'cause it pees on the leaders
You're done your time is up
Never mess with a black belt,
asshole.
Swollen's been coming up
So watch these motherfuckers
burn it up
You're done your time is up
It's a brand-new beat
now turn it up
Swollen's been coming up
Now watch these motherfuckers
burn it up
Sasha!
Sasha!!
You marry Trish, you die.
What?
She's no good foryou.
No shit.
What do you mean?
We broke up, you psycho.
I want Sasha.
Oh.
Who the hell are you?
My name's Emile.
Your parents hired me.
My parents?
Yeah.
Kind of weird, huh?
[Applause]
All right.
In honour of Gob's
kick-ass new album,
famed record producer
Mr. Lenny Swackhammer
is here to present them
with an honorary MMVA.
Thank you, George.
You know, the truth is...
Okay, I'm coming. Oh, god.
...recording artist
while these kids
were still learning their g-o-bs.
[Laughs]
But I digress. I digress.
Yeah. Okay, come on.
Bring it home to mama.
Oh, baby, yes!
- Oh, my.
...to present to...
Oh, my god.
I love you guys!
[Smack]
Dude, are you okay?
[Gagging]
Oh!
So wrong, yet so funny.
Dime, are you all right?
Are you kidding?
You were amazing.
Guys, get in.
Where are we going?
- Does it matter?
- Not really.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Good luck.
[Darkness's "Growing On Me"
playing]
Sleeping in an empty bed
I can't get you off my head
And I won't have a life
until you're dead
Yeah you heard what I said
I want to shake you off
but you just won't go
And you're all over me
But I don't want anyone
to know
That you're attached to me
that's how you've grown...
Hey, wench.
Get me some tartar sauce.
Damn compact, fuel efficient...
Look, buddy,
if you call me a wench
one more time,
I swearto god, I'm...
Sasha, I need to speak with you
right now, please.
Excuse me.
Right now, please, Sasha.
Hey, there!
You fellers lost or what?
Whoa! They got surfing here?
Yeah. You guys ride, do you?
Are you kidding me?
We're from Tofino, man.
That means yes.
Hey, are you guys
Sasha's brothers?
Could be. Who's asking?
I'm Nick. I'm...
Oh, man.
I think this is the place.
Where's Sasha?
Over across the bay,
flogging fish and chips.
I've got to see her.
I'm afraid not, boy.
Ain't a chance in hell of seeing she.
Guys, we drove all the way here
just so I could apologize. Now...
If I have to take beats
to tell her I'm sorry,
you know what?
Just get it over with.
Go on, run for it, Nick!
All right.
Well, you guys got some ol' guts.
I'll give you that much.
Especially that one.
Oh, my god. It's... fucking cold!
He's not much of a paddler,
is he, boys?
Hey, easy on the boy.
It's his first time.
I hope he climbs
betterthan he swims.
Here's your bowl of jiz.
Oh, you're good.
Ow.
Aw, shit!
Nick?
Sasha.
What happened to you?
Oh, I, uh... I met your brothers.
Why are you here?
Trish turn you down?
No. No, I never proposed.
So you came here
to collect second prize.
Doesn't work that way, Nick.
Try not to fall on your way down.
Oh, come on, Sasha.
Ljust scaled a cliff.
Hey, wench! Think you can pull
yourself away from your man-whore
long enough to get me a beer?
Listen, you creepy little man!
Sasha!
What?
Take it outside now.
Come with me.
Oh, wow.
It's beautiful.
Yeah, you know, trees, rocks,
ocean, iceberg.
Look, Sasha,
I came here because l...
To sleep with me
by mistake again?
Oh, no, no, no.
For real this time.
I mean, I couldn't
turn you down in that get-up.
Am I still the biggest mistake
you ever made?
[Music]
[Cheering]
Oh, god. That's cold.
Oh, my god.
Yourfriends
are a bunch of idiots.
Yeah. Yeah.
[Sasha laughs]
It's a whale, dude.
Dude, my balls are curling
into my abdomen. I'm turning back.
- No, you can't. They're going
to think we're pussies.
We're from Tofino, man.
Tofino!
Tyler, that is an iceberg.
It's a fucking iceberg.
No shit, man. It's awesome.
Let's piss on it.
- Yeah!
What a wonderful world
Whoo! Whoo!
Yeah.
- Whoo!
Aah!
Aah, I'm going backwards.
Use your penis as a propeller.
I was producing
platinum-winning accord...
Whatever I'm saying,
I can't fucking
rememberthe words.
Relax. It's probably just a ticket.
We can't afford a ticket, Tyler.
Wanna kiss him?
Uh, Job says,
"Thou shalt not insert
anything into his rectum."
I want to.
"Under any circumstance."
[Telephone rings]
Jesus is calling.
[Retching]
[Dings tuning fork]
What's your name?
[Laughs wickedly]
Go on, kiss it.
Looks good on you!
Holy shit.
[Sum 41's "Open Your Eyes"
playing]
[Gob's "Break" playing]
Drop the corn.
Unless you know how to use it.