English Subtitles © 2012
International Historic Films, Inc.
All Rights Reserved
Starring
A film by
Music by
Cinematography by
Sound
Art Direction
Cast
Also Starring
Recorded using
Production Group
Directed by
For centuries, men have been
trying to produce gold artificially...
Because gold is the blessing
and the curse of this world...
For gold, there is war between
the clans, the tribes, the peoples...
For gold, people betray,
pursue and kill each other...
So, tonight at 7:00,
the crucial experiment
will be conducted.
Yes, sir.
- Who will be there?
- Professor Achenbach
and his assistant, Engineer Holk...
and me.
Becker.
You know exactly
what you've got to do.
Yes.
How long will you need?
About...
two minutes.
We'll make sure that,
shortly before 7:00,
you'll be alone in the laboratory
for two minutes.
Here.
There you go.
But be careful.
What's the matter?
But what if the professor
or Holk is--
Are you related
to those gentlemen?
- No, I'm not, but--
- Well, then.
Don't worry, Becker.
Nobody will be harmed.
The effect isn't that strong.
- It isn't?
- Sure.
All we're interested in
is that the experiment fails.
Becker!
Pull yourself together, all right?
Yes. I just meant to ask.
See.
Take care, boy.
It will work out fine.
RESEARCH LABORATORY
PROFESSOR ACHENBACH
HIGH VOLTAGE - CAUTION!
MORTAL DANGER
Becker?
- Good evening, Professor.
- So, how are you?
Everything all right?
Yes, sir.
- The pump installation?
- I checked it.
- The grounding switches?
- They're in place, Professor.
- What about the electricity?
- It's ordered for 7:00.
Very good.
You're surely glad, Becker,
that we're finally ready.
Yes, sure.
You've been working
hard enough recently.
Where's Holk?
- Mr. Holk?
- Yes?
Someone wants to
urgently speak with you.
- Yes?
- Brinkmann, from the press.
I have a few questions for you.
You come at the most inconvenient time,
I have no time right now.
- Maybe you'll come back tomorrow.
- I'm afraid it can't wait, sir.
I need some information about the
experiment and Professor Achenbach.
You know he never talks about his work.
It won't take you very long.
All right, five minutes. Go ahead,
what do you want to know?
Professor,
there's a phone call for you.
Who is it?
A certain Professor Lundborg.
Lundborg?
I don't know him.
From Stockholm.
- From Stockholm?
- Yes, Professor.
Yes? Achenbach here.
My apologies for disturbing you,
my dear colleague.
I happen to be in Berlin
and didn't want to miss--
Pardon?
From Stockholm?
No, no. I'm in Berlin.
It would be best
if you called me again tomorrow.
Hello? Hello, dear colleague,
just one important question.
Yes?
Yes, yes.
We can discuss this
face-to-face tomorrow.
I have to end this call.
Until tomorrow, then.
- Barely two minutes.
- Let's hope that was enough.
Here, let me repeat it.
Transformation of lead into gold
by atomic fragmentation.
Flame shots
of up to 50 million volts--
Five million volts, sir.
Don't throw the millions
around like that.
And please stress
that this is not some
kind of gold factory,
- but a purely scientific experiment.
- Of course.
- Good-bye.
- Thank you very much.
- Good luck.
- Yes, thanks.
HIGH VOLTAGE - CAUTION!
MORTAL DANGER
Excuse me, Professor. There was
a man from the press outside,
and I had to tell him a little bit.
- I see.
- Good evening, Professor.
Come on, let's start.
You already connected
the load switch, Professor.
Yes, I did.
- May I switch over?
- Yes.
For now, the gentlemen
are right to have their doubts.
Our experiments have
only been successful on paper thus far.
But Professor,
how can you say that?
So we must prove it.
Today!
It will work out.
I feel it.
Stop, one moment, please.
Let me out.
Good night.
Turn on the machines.
Yes, I'll turn them on.
All right.
What's wrong with Becker today?
Becker?
He's probably just a little excited.
I can understand him.
To be honest, Professor,
I've got some stage fright myself.
Attention, Holk. Now.
Becker?
Turn on the surge generators.
But in the right order!
Yes, Mr. Holk.
Ready.
Now.
Professor!
What's the matter, Becker?
What's the matter? Speak up!
Don't!
WERNER HOLK, ACCIDENT
Unfortunately,
he's lost a lot of blood.
Everything is prepared
for the blood transfusion, Doctor.
- Where's the blood donor?
- He'll be here soon.
It's high time
if the blood transfusion
is to be successful.
His pulse is weak,
irregular and accelerated.
Well, let's get everything ready.
Doctor?
The patient's fiancée is outside.
So? You can't let visitors in to
a seriously injured patient now!
Certainly not.
But she asks to be
taken as blood donor.
- Yes?
- Yes.
Did you examine her?
Blood type A?
Yes, sir. Blood type A
and in perfect health.
Makes an excellent impression.
I think we cannot deny this
to the young lady.
She pleaded for it.
Very well.
Bring her in.
But hurry!
Please come in.
The doctor has agreed.
- Are you scared?
- No.
That's good.
- Doctor, the lady is here.
- Fine.
Come in.
There's not a minute to lose.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Schäfermann.
Is Mr. Holk at home?
Werner.
Margit.
Good afternoon.
Your eyes are so clear
and shining today.
- You've been brooding again.
- Don't be so strict with me.
You've been reading those old
newspaper clippings once again.
Yes, I have.
What else can I do?
- I'll never get rid of that story.
- But, Werner--
I know what you're
about to say, Margit.
It's been a long time and people
don't think about it anymore.
Sadly enough.
Here, read this.
There it is in black and white.
"Irresponsible negligence.
Boundless dilettantism."
And I'm supposed to let
that hang on Achenbach?
No.
Not me.
He can't defend
himself anymore.
He's not here anymore.
But I'm still here.
It was no accident.
It was a malicious crime.
But I'll get those bastards.
I'll never forget the face
of that Becker.
He knew about the dirty trick.
He wanted to say something,
but then it was over.
Then came the unholy mess.
Margit?
- What time is it?
- Almost 5:00.
- I'm going back to the plant.
- But Werner, I just arrived.
I know you don't have it easy
with me at the moment, Margit.
You just need a little more patience, right?
- Then I'll go back home.
- No.
You should stay here and wait for me.
I'll be back soon.
Looks monstrous, doesn't it?
What are you looking for?
The gold?
None there.
They didn't succeed,
the two of them.
Maybe it's for the better.
The lead.
Compromised. That's how they did it.
You.
There was something in the lead.
Do you understand that, man?
Nope.
"Nope."
Well, there's no way you could.
Werner?
There are two gentlemen
waiting for you.
- Who?
- I don't know them.
They insisted on speaking to you.
Brann.
Vesitsch.
Holk.
Please take a seat.
Do you mind me smoking,
Mr. Holk?
No, no, I like a smoky atmosphere.
What can I do for you?
Have you ever heard
the name Wills, Mr. Holk?
Wills.
Yes, I know that name.
Wills owns steel
and lead mines, doesn't he?
- Yes, yes. That's him.
- Exactly.
And?
Perhaps you'll find it interesting
that for years Mr. Wills
has been doing
experiments similar to you
and the unfortunately deceased
Professor Achenbach.
That's very interesting.
Yes, yes. In the
practical basis, at any rate.
What does that mean,
practical foundation?
What do you mean?
Is he opening
a ducat factory, or what?
Maybe.
In any case--
and that's why we're here--
Mr. Wills wishes to meet you.
He wants you to work for him.
And what that means for you--
Well, you can guess.
It's a lucky chance for you.
Similar experiments...
- with atomic fragmentation?
- Yes.
If you want to see the plans
of the Wills plant...
- Let me see.
- There you are.
But that's Achenbach's apparatus.
With a few minor changes,
or, more precisely, some errors.
You know I owe it to a mere
coincidence that I'm still alive.
- Yes. We heard about the accident.
- We were sorry to hear about it.
But for you and Mr. Wills,
that accident was quite opportune.
How's that?
If Achenbach and I
had been successful,
we would have gotten there
ahead of you.
That's true.
- Aha.
- Pardon?
Well, I'm very interested
in meeting Mr. Wills.
I'm curious about
what he will suggest to me.
- When can you leave, Mr. Holk?
- Anytime.
Mr. Wills is currently on board
his yacht in the North Sea.
Your train leaves tonight at 9:00.
In Bremerhaven, a seaplane
will be waiting for you.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Well.
Tomorrow morning at 10:00,
you'll meet Mr. Wills.
Excellent.
- Have a good trip.
- Thank you.
The same from me.
Thank you. Well.
Margit?
Margit!
Now I've got them.
Do you know who these
two gentlemen were?
Two very dangerous fellows.
- Dangerous, that one.
- That's my impression, too.
- We need to send a telegraph.
- Nonsense.
Wills has handled
far more dangerous guys.
Nevertheless. Just in case.
But they're only minions, these two.
Common henchmen.
I'm not interested in them.
But in the man
who's behind them, John Wills.
Have you ever heard
of that noble gentleman?
John Wills.
I can't be mistaken,
I just have the feeling.
That's the bloke...
Who has the death of our professor
on his conscience.
I want to meet him.
Werner.
What's the matter?
Little Margit.
Are you scared?
Scared for me?
But I must go, child.
You'll understand that.
I know, Werner.
Otherwise, you won't be able
to find any peace of mind.
I'll be back soon.
You.
And I'm carrying you
with me always.
Here.
You're always with me.
Blood in my blood.
Gosh!
What a pretentious vessel!
I prefer this little boat here.
A pleasure cruise
on a yacht like this--
nothing to sneeze at.
Whether this is going to be
a pleasure...
remains to be seen.
- Good morning.
- Mr. Wills welcomes you, Mr. Holk.
May I show you to your cabin?
- I'd like to speak to Mr. Wills now.
- Very well.
Hello, Lüders.
Hello, Lüders. Willi!
Yes?
Man alive,
what are you doing here?
Excuse me,
but you must be mistaken.
But, Willi.
Old boy!
Don't you recognize me?
Holk. Werner Holk.
- As students. We were together--
- Excuse me, but you're mistaken.
My name is Jenkins.
Jenkins. Unbelievable.
Excuse me,
what's that gentleman's name?
Jenkins. Our first mate.
Is he?
And you know that for sure?
But of course.
That's the way?
One moment, please.
I'll tell Mr. Wills you're here.
Yes. Thank you.
...the consortium makes the
release of mining rights,
dependent on the decision
of the ministry--
- Excuse me, Mr. Wills.
- Yes?
- Mr. Holk.
- Show him in.
Mr. Wills asks you to come in.
May I take your coat?
...departure: immediately. Stop.
Surveillance of the gold mine
syndicate necessary. Stop.
- Good morning.
- One moment, please.
Stop.
Murphy seems incapable. Stop.
General power of attorney
on its way by air mail.
Signature Wills.
Next.
Cable to Gold Mine Syndicate,
Cape Town.
General Manager Murphy.
Radio report about monthly yield
not satisfying. Stop.
Please offer precise suggestions
for increase in production.
Send as flash transmission via radio.
Next.
Cable to International Lloyds, London.
Agree in principle with supplier
contract as a whole. Stop.
Following changes
are imperative. Stop.
To point sixteen.
- Establishment of regular London--
- Nah!
Call me when you're ready!
Mr. Holk?
Please.
My apologies. I didn't know
your time was so precious.
My time? No.
But I thought you were in a hurry.
Why else would you
fly me in by airplane?
Otherwise, I could have
leisurely paddled up here.
We'll continue later.
Please tell Jenkins
full speed ahead to Scotland.
No, no, stop, my dear man.
Hold your full speed back a while.
We haven't gotten
that far yet, Mr. Wills.
I see.
We're going.
Then I'll have to pull
the emergency brake.
I'm glad to find you
in such a cheerful mood.
- Do you smoke?
- No, thanks. Not right now.
My dear Mr. Holk,
I've got a proposition for you.
You will continue
your experiments in my plant,
we will quickly come to
an agreement
and for your collaboration,
I will offer you--
Your conditions are
so tempting, Mr. Wills,
that you'd have to be an idiot...
to say no.
- Right!
- One moment.
However...
perhaps I am just such an idiot.
What?
Yes, yes.
- Would you tell me, Mr. Wills...
- Go on.
How did Achenbach's procedure
actually come into your hands?
That's my business.
- Is it?
- Yes.
That means, you have--
- I don't want to be disturbed!
- But it's very important.
Then give it to me.
WILLS, YACHT SAVARONA.
HOLK SUSPECTS CONNECTION
WITH ACHENBACH. STOP.
CAUTION ADVISED. BRANN.
So, your decision, please.
What if I say no?
That would be very imprudent of you.
You can presume that
I will keep the only person
posing a real competition
to my work, at my side
under all circumstances.
So that's how it is.
Then let's call things as they are.
You're threatening me.
No. You'll just be,
for an indefinite period of time,
my guest, in my castle.
So, your decision, Mr. Holk?
I'll work.
That's very wise of you.
In which cabin is Mr. Holk?
- Cabin 18.
- So, Cabin 18.
- We'll meet at lunch.
- Yes.
Mr. Holk is to be kept
under constant surveillance.
But discreetly.
And you will arrange
for everything else.
Yes, Mr. Wills.
Ah, the double.
- Why are you snooping around here?
- Hush. Be quiet.
You're under surveillance.
Mr. Lüders?
Lüders!
So you are good old Willi!
Why did you act up like that,
earlier on?
Well, my dear man.
Mr. Lüders is--
- My name is Jenkins.
- Yes, you told me that.
For all I care, call yourself Lord Nelson.
But why the nonsense?
No nonsense. Here. Look.
Charlie Jenkins, citizen of Cuba.
- Is that a fake passport?
- A real passport.
You know what
happened to me in 1925.
No, I don't remember.
Oh, yes. Of course.
That stupid affair, with that ship.
Yes. The Cape Martino.
There was a woman on board.
I wasn't on the bridge when
it mattered.
With one fell swoop,
everything was gone.
My position, my career,
my good name.
Well, good heavens. Things happen.
- But now you're doing fine again.
- Fine?
So it seems.
Here, on the billionaire's ship.
With Mr. Wills?
Well, that's great.
You have no idea.
But, tell me...
what does he intend
to do with you?
Who?
He?
With me?
Don't make me laugh.
I! With him!
Yes.
Then be careful.
I know.
Holk!
Don't get involved with that man.
He is the dirtiest scoundrel I know.
He walks over corpses.
No one knows that
better than me, boy.
I almost experienced it firsthand.
- How?
- Lüders.
You have no idea
what that bastard did to me.
He blew up our plant.
And I lost my best friend with it.
A man, I tell you...
It may sound a little dramatic,
but I loved him like a father.
Well.
And the fact that you see me
walking around bright-eyed...
is only a coincidence as well.
Sheer coincidence.
And now I can tell you
why I'm going with you to Scotland.
Not to work...
but to get even.
I will pay him back for everything,
blow for blow.
And I swear to you, Lüders.
I won't spare him anything.
Please show Mr. Holk to his room.
And if it is all right with you,
we will meet in ten minutes.
- Thank you.
- This way, sir.
- Anything new?
- Nothing important.
- And my daughter? Is she here?
- Yes, the young lady has arrived.
Tomorrow she'll leave
on the Savarona for Nice.
- What?
- Yes, sir.
Didn't you remind her
that we have guests tomorrow?
Yes, I took the liberty
to point it out to her, but--
So?
I wish to speak
to my daughter at once.
What's wrong with you?
Why do you look so desperate?
Forgive me, sir,
but I can't find your tailcoat.
Impossible.
- You're joking?
- I'd never dare.
But it's not here.
Indeed.
My valet
must have forgotten to pack it.
Seems so.
- What will the gentleman do now?
- That's simple.
I will fire my valet at once.
- What else can I do?
- Yes, sir.
The young lady has a headache
and sends her apologies.
- A headache?
- Yes, sir.
Tell my daughter I want her
to postpone her trip to Nice.
And phone Engineer Harris.
Come on.
Step in.
- Will it go down the shaft?
- Yes.
You wanted to show me
your laboratory?
Just come on,
that's what I'm doing.
You've hidden
your laboratory very well.
Not me. Nature.
Lead.
Yes.
You've got lead,
and you want to make--
Exactly.
How practical.
Engineer Harris.
The man who didn't succeed.
Engineer Holk.
The man who will succeed.
Pleased to meet you, colleague.
Harris, you make sure that Holk
gets the whole thing running.
I think that's what he came here for.
Of course.
But he may have other plans.
Don't let him out of your sight.
Got me?
Harris, you're responsible
for the whole plant.
If the man turns out
to be a danger,
the plant is more
important to me than--
You know.
Harris.
Well, Mr. Holk?
Really impressive, Mr. Wills.
And the surge generators?
Where are they located?
Left in chambers outside the cave.
What's that up there?
The control station.
Hello.
At how many volts
have you run it so far?
- Five million.
- That's probably all you have.
Have?
We also have 10 or 14 million.
But I don't want to be there
when they're let loose.
We were well on the way
to solving the problem.
If we'd had a little more time--
Maybe well on the way,
but not the right one.
Really?
Well, I don't know
Achenbach's system--
What, you don't know the system,
dear colleague?
No.
But it's said to have
a certain resemblance to ours.
A certain resemblance?
An uncanny resemblance.
And what's the reason
it doesn't work?
I can tell you that.
The resemblance
is not close enough.
We-- Achenbach and I--
had gotten a little further.
But gold? You and your Professor
Achenbach couldn't produce it, Mr. Holk.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
That's right.
How far below ground are we?
We're not below ground.
- We're below the sea.
- Below the sea?
- You can't be serious.
- Yes.
The cave is 200 meters
from the coast.
Above us is the Atlantic Ocean.
- So, can you work here?
- Yes, you spared no expense.
Why laugh?
I just thought about how our
little laboratory in Berlin blew up.
What a big bang
that would have been...
if it had been a giant plant like this.
Mr. Holk.
I brought you here so that
you could do your experiment.
What neither you nor Professor
Achenbach have ever found,
I, John Wills, give to you:
Absolute confidence.
Whatever you command
will be carried out.
Whatever you need,
you will have.
No one has ever had
such possibilities.
And if you succeed in turning
the lead of Dunby into gold,
then you, Holk, will have performed
the most tremendous transformation.
Then this cave will be
the heart of the world.
And you, Holk, will decide
whether this heart beats...
or not.
And now, Holk,
it's up to you.
You're perfectly right of course.
It's up to me now.
- Did you find anything?
- No, nothing.
All this searching is pointless.
Holk won't be so stupid
as to leave something
lying around that no one is meant to see.
Tidy up here,
so he doesn't notice anything.
What are you doing here?
Who do these things belong to?
- Who is living here?
- Mr. Holk.
An acquaintance of my father's?
I can't say more. The gentleman
arrived just an hour ago.
And he knows you're rifling through
his bags in his absence?
Mr. Wills knows it.
I must tell Wills.
Is my father in his room?
Yes, Mr. Wills has just
returned from the plant.
Thank you.
Florence?
I want to talk to you.
Please leave us alone.
What's the matter?
Why so formal?
Who's that Mr. Holk
who arrived today?
A new engineer.
A very capable person.
He works for me,
down at the plant.
But he stays up here
and is your guest, isn't he?
Yes.
Then it's outrageous that
you have his suitcases searched.
I kindly ask you to show some restraint
in criticizing my measures.
And I kindly ask you show some restraint
in your measures against a guest.
Florence.
You don't know the situation.
I probably have my reasons.
The man could be dangerous to me.
I can't show consideration.
- Why then did you bring him here?
- Because I need him.
And now I want you
to end this interrogation.
I don't need to justify myself to you.
I don't meddle in your affairs either.
That Mr. Holk must be
an interesting person.
At least he's the first one
you seem to have respect for.
Very interesting.
By the way,
you've postponed your trip,
haven't you?
No, I leave tomorrow.
That's out of the question.
You will stay here.
I must go to Edinburgh today and
won't be back till tomorrow night.
You will have the goodness
to receive our guests.
The day after tomorrow,
you may go wherever you want.
That's very kind, but I've already
prepared for my departure tomorrow.
I'm afraid I can't change it anymore.
Florence!
Kelly!
Pitt!
Turn on number five!
Kelly!
Turn on transformer number five!
Nosy guy.
- Did you say something?
- No, no!
But if you keep standing
behind me like that,
I fear the electrical tension
might get too high.
I can easily get
a short circuit then.
Kelly!
Load surge generator five!
You and Pitt will stay here.
All the others, out!
Seven and a half million volts!
It's madness!
Who's experimenting here?
You or me?
- I'm responsible for the plant.
- Are you?
I forbid you to work at this voltage.
In one minute, you can forbid me
as much as you want.
And now you can follow me.
Now would be important.
Come with me, come!
Turn it off!
Mr. Holk, if you go on like this,
you'll destroy the apparatus.
Or I could succeed in making gold.
And that doesn't suit you, does it?
As long as I'm your chief engineer,
you won't mess around
with such high voltages!
I see.
You're the chief engineer.
- You're my superior.
- Yes.
- And I'm your inferior.
Then I'll tell you something,
Mr. Harris.
A long as there's
a chief engineer here,
I'm not interested
in all this crap.
For me, it's quitting time!
Blair, Pitt, your report!
Well, you better hurry,
or I'll do it first!
Yes. Holk?
- Mr. Holk? There's a car for you.
- Yes?
- What's the matter?
- The car's waiting above.
It's supposed to take you
to Dunby Castle.
To Mr. Wills?
Thank you, that suits me fine.
Hello?
I'm sorry, Mr. Harris,
you can't speak to Mr. Wills right now.
Maybe you can call again
tomorrow morning.
Ernst.
- Please tell him I'm here.
- You're already awaited.
Thanks.
- Mr. Holk?
- Yes.
Thank you for coming,
that's very kind. Please.
There must be
a misunderstanding.
I thought Mr. Wills
was waiting for me.
No, I asked you to come here.
Well, I'm Florence Wills.
But won't you come nearer?
- Cigarette?
- Thank you, I don't smoke.
May I ask to what I owe the honor
of being received by you?
You may light my cigarette,
Mr. Holk.
My apologies.
There you are.
- Some whiskey?
- Thank you, I don't drink.
You don't smoke,
you don't drink.
I hope you haven't made a vow
never to sit down?
No, I haven't.
Have you known my father
for a long time?
Personally, not until yesterday.
But I had heard of him.
Will you stay here for long?
Maybe.
Are you always so talkative?
Dear Miss.
You're asking me things Mr. Wills
has probably already told you, right?
You're wrong.
In the past three months, I've hardly
spoken to my father for five minutes.
By chance, today at noon.
That's when I heard of your
existence for the first time.
Do you want to know
in what context?
I can guess.
Mr. Wills must have asked you
to take care of me.
No. That is also wrong.
I wanted to meet you.
And I didn't think...
that it would be
so presumptuous of me
to ask you to keep me company.
On the contrary, miss,
its very flattering.
But after all,
I came to Dunby to work.
My head is filled with worries.
In such a state,
I'm certainly not much company.
So please don't take offense
if I say good-bye to you now.
One moment, Mr. Holk.
Yes?
You're only here to work, are you?
And not for some other reason?
I don't understand your question.
Are you sounding me out?
No.
I want to warn you.
They don't trust you here one bit.
I don't know why.
You don't need to explain.
I'm just telling you because
I want to prevent you
from getting yourself--
perhaps by some indiscretion--
into an unpleasant situation.
I won't keep you any longer.
Good-bye.
You're still here, Mr. Holk?
Yes, Miss Wills.
I think I owe you an apology.
I probably didn't behave correctly.
Never mind.
And I also want to--
You rang, miss?
You may serve lunch.
For two persons?
I'm being asked
if you'd like to join me.
So yes?
For two.
She says the Savarona will leave.
He says the Savarona won't leave.
Maybe you, Paddy,
can tell me what to do.
But, Mr. Jenkins, you didn't just
arrive here yesterday.
Of course what she wants
will happen.
Yes, but I must know
where I stand.
Please do me a favor
and tell her I'm here.
I'm afraid I can't.
The new engineer is with her
and I mustn't disturb them.
- Mr. Holk?
- Yes.
But it's really no use asking.
I'll give you a piece of advice.
Have the Savarona
ready for departure.
Excuse me, Mr. Jenkins.
Are you waiting for someone?
Yes. I'd like to speak to Mr. Holk.
Mr. Holk is still with Miss Wills.
But maybe you'd like
to wait for him in his room.
- May I show you upstairs?
- Yes, please.
Very well.
How is it you've hardly spoken
to your father in the last three months?
That's nothing out of the ordinary.
Sometimes, we don't see
each other for half a year.
My father doesn't care if I'm here
or traveling around the world.
He's only interested
in his business and...
I don't want to have
anything to do with that.
I see.
I'm only here for one day now too.
Tomorrow I will leave on the Savarona,
for the Mediterranean.
And who knows
when I'll be back.
Then the two of us
will never meet again.
You never know, Mr. Holk.
By the way, you don't seem
to be too keen on that.
Excuse me. I only wanted to ask
if you desire anything.
No, thank you.
May I bring you some newspapers?
Some cigars? Or some whiskey?
No, thanks. I hope it won't
take that long downstairs.
I can't say.
I'm afraid I lack experience here.
So far, Miss Wills has never invited
a guest to lunch alone on his first day.
Any other wishes, miss?
No, thank you.
Well.
It's gotten late.
You want to leave tomorrow
and have to rise early,
so I better take my leave now.
So, farewell, Mr. Holk.
It was an enchanting evening.
I must honestly say
that I never would have thought
I'd meet a person like you here,
Miss Florence.
I wish you a pleasant trip.
I thank you.
But if you really want me
to have a pleasant trip,
then please grant me one wish.
Of course.
Please don't take any steps
against my father here.
I say that not for his sake.
Good night.
- At last!
- Willi?
- I thought you'd never come.
- What are you doing here?
I've been waiting for three hours
to say good-bye to you.
- We leave tomorrow.
- Well, I couldn't come sooner.
You worked so long.
I had a lot of things
to do at the plant.
And how is it there?
Great, I tell you.
The machine this chap
has set up there is fantastic.
- One definitely could work there.
- Really?
But that's not what
you came here for.
You wanted to get even
with Mr. Wills, didn't you?
And I will, you can count on that.
That machine must go.
I already looked around
down at the plant.
Willi, if I turn on
all of those 15 million volts,
it would release energy stronger than
ten hundredweights of Ecrasite.
But it's not that easy.
And then something else
occurred to me
as I stood in front
of the machine today.
If I could show
even one ounce of gold
that I made with that apparatus,
then the name of Achenbach
would regain its reputation.
- Do you understand that?
- Yes, sure.
And that occurred to you
when you saw the machine?
And not during your
three-hour-long conversation
with Miss Wills?
Look, Werner.
You don't need to lie to me.
I've got nothing against you
working for Mr. Wills.
For all I care, you can flirt
with his daughter 10 hours a day.
But then don't tell me
anything about...
revenge or getting even
blow for blow.
Willi, you are an idiot.
Miss Wills just couldn't find
anybody else today.
Do you know how much
she cares about me?
- Not that much.
- Yes, yes, I know that.
I told you what happened to me.
You're lucky
she's leaving tomorrow.
See. Then you have
no reason to worry.
I'm tired.
Please allow me
to get some sleep.
Bye, Willi, I wish you
good luck and a nice--
Come in.
Excuse me.
- For you, Mr. Holk.
- For me?
Mr. Jenkins.
The Savarona won't leave tomorrow.
The young lady has decided to stay.
Good night.
Read this.
I kindly ask you to by my guest
at our soiree tomorrow.
Kind regards, Florence Wills.
You'll understand what that means.
Yes.
Then there's only one thing to do.
Tomorrow night,
the machine will be blown up.
Did you give Mr. Holk
my invitation?
Of course, miss.
My apologies for the delay.
It has just arrived.
I hope it fits.
- May I help you?
- No, no. I don't need you.
- Say, the guests are all here?
- Yes, Mr. Holk.
- Mr. Wills, too?
- No, Mr. Wills is expected in one hour.
I see. What about the engineers
and Mr. Harris?
Well, I can't say for sure,
but I've already seen
most of the gentlemen.
Permit me to remark that...
the young lady has already asked
for you several times, Mr. Holk.
I see.
Well.
Wonderful music.
And what a charming host.
Thank you very much.
I could get used to this.
Did you prepare everything?
Everything ready.
Start the generators in this order
and with voltages as written here.
One, three, four, two, five. Got it?
Golly! That's up to seven
and a half million volts!
So what?
These are the voltages
Mr. Holk gave me.
Spare me your remarks!
- Do as I've told you.
- Yes, Chief Engineer.
The gate is closing!
Mr. Holk?
What are you doing here?
What do you want here?
Why are you closing the gate?
Looks like I came just in time.
At night, behind my back,
the chief engineer
wants to run the show
and conduct the experiment!
And tomorrow,
in the eyes of the world,
he'll be the famous man,
the brilliant inventor.
And Achenbach
will forever remain the dilettante
who wasn't able
to tackle the problem!
Out of here, you thief!
Out! Get out!
What's the matter?
- Alarm!
- Put your clothes on.
Come on, we must get out!
Shut up!
Inform them up there!
Is that the siren from the plant?
Go, let's have a look.
What's that?
Something must have happened
at the mine, an accident.
- Is Mr. Holk still in his room?
- No. He left the castle half an hour ago.
Why didn't you tell me that?
I'll take my car.
But discreetly.
What kind of signal was that, miss?
The siren at the mine.
It's quitting time.
They just wanted to let us know.
I see.
The siren for quitting time.
Please play on.
- What's going on here?
- We don't know.
Take me down!
Come on, let's start.
For now, the gentlemen
are right to have their doubts.
Our experiments have
only been successful on paper thus far.
But Professor,
how can you say that?
So we must prove it.
Today!
Attention, Holk. Now.
Becker?
Turn on the surge generators.
But in the right order!
Pitt!
Turn on the surge generators!
But in the right order!
Five-one-two-four-three!
What's going on here?
Mr. Holk is in the plant.
He interrupted the gate
controls from inside.
Why didn't you take care?
Go on!
There.
Open your hand.
Just open your hand, man!
Gold!
Mr. Holk!
Mr. Harris!
What happened?
Holk succeeded.
I'm so glad that I can be
the first to congratulate you.
Come with me, Mr. Holk.
October 5th
The Dawning of a Golden Age!
Artificial Gold from Lead
by Atomic Fragmentation
Renowned Business Leader
Predicts General Prosperity!
October 6th
Mass Production of
Artificial Gold Planned
Boost to World Economy Expected
October 7th
Big Banks Warn of Gold Inflation!
Frantic Preparations
for Gold Production
Call for Legal Countermeasures
John Wills Objects to Any Intervention
October 8th
Stock Markets in Panic
Due to Gold Announcement!
Bank Presidents and Economic
Leaders Meet with John Wills
Riots among Unemployed Miners
in South African Gold Districts!
October 9th
Artificial Gold:
a World Catastrophe?
Dead and Wounded at Demonstrations
Against the "Wills Gold"
Dunby Plant Continues Preparations
for Gold Production
October 10th
"Golden Pest" Begins its Campaign
of Destruction Tomorrow
Wills Declares Ruthlessly:
"Every Invention Demands its Victims!"
Vast Amounts of Lead
Roll into Dunby Plant
Couldn't they find anything lighter
to make gold from than lead?
From Mr. Holk.
Very urgent.
What he demands by tomorrow--
Our people can't handle that.
They're completely exhausted.
Five days and nights at this tempo,
no one can take that.
Well, no one does.
- No, that's just too much.
- Yes.
Lunch break.
Is Mr. Holk out to lunch?
No, he fends off his appetite
by working.
Mr. Holk?
Yes?
- What's the matter?
- Miss Wills called.
She asks you to come up
to the castle tonight.
Yes.
Please tell her that I'll have
to work all night at the plant.
I'm sorry that again
I won't be able to come.
Enjoy your meal.
I tell you, it's going to be great.
Great!
Listen to the nonsense
Charlie is spouting again.
Why is it nonsense?
Once we've started gold production,
I know what I'll do.
I'll buy myself a nice big house
with a flower garden,
and a car
and a concertina.
And a telescope.
Why a telescope?
Why not?
What difference does it make?
Listening to you, you'd think
the machine will work for you alone.
You stupid goat!
All the money will go to Wills.
And to the banks.
- You won't get a damn thing.
- How's that?
The more gold, the more work.
The more work, the more money.
The more you talk, the more rubbish.
- Mr. Holk?
- What's the matter now?
Aren't you hungry?
Do you have to eat all the time?
I can stand it
for a few hours if I have to.
But you don't have to.
That's very kind of you, Pitt.
- Thank you.
- Here's your cutlery.
I'll tell you something.
If Wills is allowed
to construct his machine,
then I can set up a printing shop.
And print my own bank notes.
Is there any difference?
- It's exactly the same thing.
- Yes. You're right.
To me, the whole thing
seems a bit fishy, too.
Nonsense! If that's how it was,
Holk would never take part!
You have to admit,
the boy's all right.
He'd never do anything against us.
As long as he's there,
we don't need to worry.
May I ask you something,
Mr. Holk?
Of course you can, Pitt.
Even if it's something stupid?
Then more than ever.
Why do you want
to make gold here?
That's not a stupid
question at all, Pitt.
- Pour me another glass of beer.
- Yes, sir.
You know, at first I was just
as enthusiastic as the others.
But then I thought about it.
- And now I don't know.
- Thanks.
Is it right what you intend to do?
Well.
The newspapers write
such strange things.
If you read it,
you'd think that--
That we've caused
nothing but trouble so far.
Yes.
Yes, I know that, Pitt.
I read the newspapers, too.
But then I don't understand.
Then wouldn't it be better if--
If the machine just didn't
start working tomorrow.
That's what you want to say.
Don't you?
Speak up! Spit it out!
Engineer, you know better than I.
Yes.
Of course.
And what if I thought the same thing?
If I dropped everything
and went away?
- What then?
- Well, then--
It would be a mistake, my good fellow.
Tomorrow, others would be here.
And one of the gentlemen
would finally figure out...
how the thing works.
That's right.
Pitt.
There's only one solution.
Isn't there?
Lunch break is over.
We'll have a drink over this later.
Come to my cabin tonight.
Evening, Willi.
Thanks for coming.
I need to ask you a favor.
Can you post this letter for me
tomorrow at noon?
I might not be able
to do it anymore.
- What does that mean?
- Listen good.
You know the plant down there.
Listen.
The rock ceiling is very thin.
If I start the machine
with 15 million volts,
it will break and explode...
and the seawater will break through.
But the gate will withstand it.
Then everything depends
on whether I can get out...
before it has closed.
Do you understand?
It sounds damned serious this time.
It is, this time, Willi.
That's why I gave you the letter.
"Miss Margit Möller, Berlin,
Rankestraße 87."
And Florence Wills?
Because of her, I'd almost
forgotten the other one.
The other day, at the party,
I was well on my way
to falling head over heels
in love with her.
But then Mr. Wills came over
and gave me this piece of gold.
And he energetically explained to me
that he intended to tie me
to his family with it.
You can guess
what he meant by that.
I haven't seen Florence since.
And I won't see her again.
Well.
So...
Now I'll go down to the plant.
Bye, Willi.
- Can I do something for you?
- Thanks, my dear friend.
If all goes well, come down to the port.
Do you understand?
I'll prepare everything
to get us out of here.
Us?
I'll go with you.
Yes, "if."
If everything goes well.
Take me down.
Pitt?
Start the machine.
Turn on the transformers,
load the surge generators.
Mr. Holk?
Mr. Wills wants to speak
before we start working.
From up on the machine.
In a few minutes,
we will begin
to pump the stream of our gold
out of this machine
into the economic channels
of every country
thus spreading happiness,
wealth and blessings
over the entire world.
At this historical moment,
I must not fail to congratulate the man
who was first to succeed
in what previously
seemed impossible.
His ingenious creativity
gave this machine
purpose and life.
I thank you, Mr. Holk.
And now, to work!
Everyone to his place.
Gold production is about to begin!
One moment!
Mr. Wills!
For you and the others here,
I'd like to say a few words
that you, in your haste,
seem to have forgotten.
It wasn't my ingenious creativity
that brought the world
to this decisive moment.
We all owe it to the ingenuity
of somebody else.
Nonsense, please, my dear Mr. Holk--
Yes, yes, we do.
I must tell everything,
here and now, Mr. Wills.
I must say the name of that man.
And you know him very well, too.
Achenbach.
Professor Achenbach!
He was the one
who invented this machine!
My teacher was
a good, dear man
who wanted to serve
science alone--
Science alone!
And when he was mere seconds
away from his success,
then he was--
in the most ghastly way--
Sent to the hereafter.
I think that doesn't
belong here, Mr. Holk.
It does belong here, Mr. Wills!
You have Professor Achenbach
on your conscience.
You've stolen his invention!
- You built that machine with his plans--
- Have you gone crazy?
- I forbid you to go on.
- You can't forbid me anything.
- I'm talking now!
- No!
What does all this mean?
Let Mr. Holk speak!
Yes, we want to know
what's going on here!
- Let him finish!
Silence!
Be silent!
This is none of your business.
These are our private matters.
We'll settle them
between the two of us.
But what
does concern all of you,
what will really happen,
when this machine takes up
its work in a few minutes?
Not happiness,
wealth and blessings,
but poverty and misery
will be spread all over the world.
How much harm
have you already done
by simply announcing your gold?
Riots, bank crashes,
the suicide of poor wretches
who felt betrayed over
their last meager savings!
And what for?
You, Mr. John Wills!
What for?
Because you want to play at destiny,
because your thirst for power
is insatiable,
because you want to amass
ever newer riches,
because in your
delusions of grandeur,
you believe you can be
a leader of the world economy!
And now I'll tell you
what you really are.
A pathetic, lowly murderer!
- What do you say?
- A cowardly murderer!
So, boys, I had to tell you that,
because he'd forgotten it!
And now, everyone to work,
everyone to his place.
Gold production for John Wills begins!
- Gold production will not begin.
- Right.
What are you saying?
Hey! Who are you?
A worker, Mr. Wills.
Stop!
No one will leave this plant!
Didn't you hear me?
This is my last warning!
Get to work!
It is all lies! That he's told you!
And I tell you--
Everyone out!
You as well, Wills!
In four minutes, this machine
will be blown to bits!
In four minutes, fish
will be swimming around here!
Go on, boys,
everybody out of the plant now.
In one minute,
I'll close the gate.
Outside you'll be safe.
What are you doing there?
Turn off the machines.
- That's not possible anymore.
- Why not?
Why you...
I'm closing the gate.
Come with me!
Holk! Holk!
For God's sake!
Turn off the machine!
That's not possible anymore.
Come on, Pitt.
All right! Blow it all up now!
Now the whole mine
will be drowned!
The both of us will drown here!
The boys!
Pitt, a ladder! Come on!
Five hundred will die!
Get out!
The gate won't close anymore!
Quickly!
Get out!
Run!
Come on!
Pitt!
Get me a cable cutter!
Wills! Get out of there!
The fourth one is already whirling!
Mr. Holk!
Out of here!
Mr. Holk?
Come with me, Mr. Holk.
Yes.
Believe me, Holk,
I prefer this old tub
to the pretentious Savarona.
And I know why, Willi.
Because it's taking us home.
That's always the nicest cruise.
Werner!
Come!
And if someone
should ask you one day,
"Tell me, Mrs. Holk.
What's the story with the..."
Then you'll simply say,
"Werner Holk?
He never made any gold.
He can't make any.
And he will never try again.
Because no blessings come of it.
That's why you ought not make any."
English Subtitles © 2012
International Historic Films, Inc.
All Rights Reserved