Nuit d'Or?
Nuit d'Or!
It's no use hiding.
I know you're here.
It's me!
Michel Fournier.
Michel Fournier!
I'm all right.
I'm starting all over again!
And this time,
I will win.
So you can shuffle the cards!
Make the roulette wheels spin!
"Thank you...
"Thank you, Mr...
"Mr Private Secretary...
"for the kind words
you were good enough...
"to apply to me."
And...
"I'm not dead and you know it.
"You burnt me alive.
I'm rising from the ashes.
"Michel."
Hello?
Did I wake you?
You're a heavy sleeper.
- I've called you many times.
- Is this a joke?
I'm back.
Hello?
Are you still there?
I'm not dead.
You have burnt my body
but I'm not dead.
- Michel?
- Yes.
But what does this mean?
- Where are you?
- I'm here.
Nearby.
I see you.
Go to the window.
With the phone.
The wire is long enough.
MICHEL FOURNIER DEAD
Do you recognize him,
Superintendent?
It's your brother.
Please don't.
It's awful.
Hello, sir.
A man gave me this for you.
It's very urgent.
Good bye.
No crime remains unpunished.
You should know that, Henri,
my dear brother.
Henri?
It's Michel's voice.
Michel?
Mummy!
What's happening?
Nothing, sweetie.
Go back to sleep.
That's nothing.
Michel.
Mummy.
Mummy...
Mummy, wake up.
That's it.
Sleep.
Sleep...
One day, you won't wake up.
Hello?
Clinique des Amandiers?
Superintendent Pidoux speaking.
Ah, it's you. Hello.
How is my wife?
Did she eat?
I know you can't force her but...
And her sleep?
Nightmares.
She asked for Michel?
Yes, I'm still here.
Look...
I'm done with everything here in Paris.
I'll be able to go to Lausanne.
Yes, yes...
Yes, she'll be pleased.
Thanks for everything.
Goodbye, Miss Blanche.
She asked for Michel.
Hurry up!
Madam.
Your husband wants to see you.
Henri?
Henri, what's happening?
Oh, Michel...
I love you.
You're so beautiful.
I saw her.
She's grown, you know.
She looks like you.
I love you.
Stop it.
Your brother was dead for everyone.
And here I am again...
with my two sons.
I loved him a lot.
But...
I never knew how to talk to him.
We must forgive him.
You too, Henri.
There's a place for the two of you.
Don't play with that,
you may hurt yourself.
Michel is somewhere
here in the store.
How do you know?
I've found this in my office.
I won't let Michel...
destroy all I've got.
All I own.
Where's your father?
At the warehouses.
Tell me, Superintendent.
Michel and your wife, Marie,
were very close.
- They were very close!
- So what?
He made her crazy.
Your wife set fire to
the warehouses to avenge him.
Charles?
Ah, here you are.
Leave all that
and take this to the room.
I've been waiting for you.
I believed, like everybody else,
he was dead.
And all this time,
he was around us.
He was watching us.
Why playing...
this grim little game?
I loved him
despite the scandals
and the gambling debts.
And then...
there was the crime.
The dreadful crime
in the Rue Duquesnes.
No, no, no...
No! He must disappear.
For ever.
I'll give him what he wants.
His return will cause
too much harm.
Please, Fernand.
Find him.
I will, Charles.
As for the insurance,
it's sorting itself out.
They admitted the possibility
of an accidental fire.
A purely accidental fire.
Marie has nothing to do with it.
Officially.
I'll never forget
what you've done for my wife.
I'll find Michel.
Thank you.
We're not allowed
to forget men like you.
Men who, with a deep
sense of humanity, have
preserved the essential thing,
namely:
the honour of the police.
Thank you, Mr Private Secretary,
for the kind words
you were good enough
to apply to me.
Thank you too,
my dear colleagues.
This lamp you gave me
will always be on my desk
as a souvenir for the 30 years
I've been working here.
Let's hope he'll be brief.
I am expected at the Ministry.
You know the story of
The Phantom of the Opera
who come back to haunt
the place he liked so much.
Well...
If one day you met
the figure of an old man,
don't be scared by him.
Another present
has just been brought.
One more present?
I haven't seen it.
Let's open it together.
Sorry, I have to go.
- Take care.
- Thank you, sir.
What a strange idea,
giving a doll to a man of my age...
Have you seen this?
"My name is Marie,
"the arsonist, the lunatic.
"Meet me tonight at my mother's."
"Signed, Michel."
That's a strange doll.
Here he is.
Like every Monday.
Come on, Catherine.
I saw you in the park.
You shouldn't follow
the little girls.
I haven't asked you anything.
Of course you haven't.
I recognized you immediately.
You are Michel Fournier,
the golden chain killer.
- See you on Monday.
- Good bye.
Do you recognize me?
Superintendent Pidoux!
How glad I am to see you again!
Will you come and sit here?
Like old times.
No?
You always used to sit there.
At the table of the rich.
You were a sorry sight.
A poor man.
The poor are not
necessarily happy, are they?
Cheap ready-made suit.
Imitation silk tie.
Simulated leather wallet.
You had lost before
you started to gamble.
I know the face of luck.
I also know
the signs of misfortune.
Michel Fournier is dead.
If he wasn't,
he would be at this table.
And he would be losing
as he always did.
But he could afford it.
Blessed are the rich,
for theirs is the kingdom of debts.
Watch them.
Watch them closely.
They win.
They lose.
They always lose in the end.
They turn yellow, they turn pale...
They wither.
And they get old like their cards.
And then...
Look at this one.
Has been actor.
Old ham of second-rate play.
Always playing supporting roles.
In one word, shit.
All he earns as a TV whore,
he comes here to lose it.
He gives me all.
Old queen of the studios!
Nobody wants him anymore.
If I closed my business,
he'd kill himself.
Enough!
Where's Michel?
I don't like the smell of corpses,
especially this one.
You killed him!
They killed him.
Michel Fournier is alive.
Alive. Your hear me?
He's come back.
He shouldn't have.
They'll kill him.
Yes.
They'll kill him once again.
Who are "they"?
They hate us.
And you're the one
who'll kill him.
You're drunk.
Yes, yes...
I am drunk.
Why do you defend him so much?
Men like you don't
grow old gracefully.
Poor old fag!
Cop!
Hello, Mrs Jansen?
Did Catherine leave?
How long?
Half an hour?
No, thank you.
Hello, Henri?
Catherine hasn't come back home.
Come quick.
It's serious.
You'll never see her again.
Catherine is mine.
Like Véronique.
Your parents say hello.
Especially your mother.
I am Catherine.
If you call the police,
the chain will be pulled
and I will die
- You must call the police.
- I'm begging you...
He'll kill her.
He's going to kill her.
Like he killed the little girl
from the Rue Duquesne.
She was 11.
She was home alone.
She wore a short dress.
He came from behind.
A golden chain in his hand.
He squeezed very hard.
She didn't cry.
She didn't scream.
She had no time.
She fell down.
Her tongue was hanging out.
Her face was pale.
A childs neck...
is fragile.
It's flaky.
It cracks!
It's for me?
- Yes.
- Thanks.
And after that, I was...
in the Upper Volta.
I was a crocodile hunter.
I had an elephant called Jimboboy.
Jimboboy?
Is that his first or last name?
It is both.
But let me finish.
My guide and I,
we knew that,
at a specific time,
when the night is falling,
crocodiles come
to drink at the river...
as big as the Amazon River.
And then?
And then...
One hour passed.
Two hours passed.
Nothing.
Then all of a sudden...
Above me...
Crack!
What "crack! crack!"?
I hear a noise above my head.
Broken branches.
Jumping from tree to tree.
I grab my gun!
You had a gun?
No.
You're right. I had no gun.
What was this "crack! crack!"?
The guide says to me,
"shhh."
Like that.
Then we wait.
I hold my breath.
Then all of a sudden,
I see its outline!
You know what it was?
A panther!
A panther?!
Black!
The worst.
Hi, Pierre.
I didn't know
you'd been in Africa.
His name isn't Pierre,
it's Michel.
We have to go home now, don't we?
We have plenty of time.
Why did he call you "Pierre"?
Do you live here?
Yes. With them.
And my parents,
what will they say?
Nothing.
They know you're with me.
And for a long time.
Gabrielle.
Anne, Marie...
- Did they exist?
- Of course they did.
A long time ago.
And then they died?
They became dolls.
Did you change them into dolls?
He doesn't let anybody go.
You must put your hand in his.
Let me go, sir.
I want to go upstairs.
Once upon a time,
there was a man called
Michel.
He was alone. All by himself.
No one loved him.
His father, Charles,
was always finding what he did
was wrong.
His brother, Henri, was jealous
because Michel had met before him
a very beautiful queen.
Véronique.
Queen Véronique
loved Michel very much.
So...
Charles and Henri
wanted to make Michel disappear.
But Michel
was not dead.
He was in Africa.
There,
all alone,
he was thinking about
Queen Véronique
and the little princess Catherine.
You.
He loves them so much.
He says to the queen,
"Come."
He says to the princess,
All three go away.
And they are happy together.
Sleep, Catherine.
Sleep...
Is Catherine his daughter?
She's my daughter.
My daughter!
Michel?
Is that you?
Answer me, my darling.
I know that you will
come back to me.
You didn't leave me alone,
did you?
I have been sad.
Answer me!
You're scaring me.
They never come back to see me.
Never!
They never come to see me.
They're waiting...
for my death.
Dying...
It's very kind of you
to wait for me.
Tell them they'll never
see her again.
They'll give you
anything you want.
All the money you want.
Catherine is mine.
And if you try anything,
the police or you,
I'll kill her.
What for?
For me.
Don't try to understand.
You're too stupid.
Too thick.
What about the puppet?
Did you enjoy it?
It's a tribute to Marie,
the loony.
Institutionalized in Switzerland
by Daddy Fournier.
And Supt Pidoux says,
"Amen and thank you."
At his command.
Always at his command.
You're not a cop.
You're a puppet!
"The army of the exterminating angels
had two hundred million horsemen.
"They wore breastplates
the color of fire
"and of hyacinth and of brimstone.
"The heads of the horses
resembled the heads of lions.
"A third of mankind was killed
by these three plagues.
"From their mouths
the horses belched
"forth fire, and smoke,
and sulphur.
"I heard an eagle flying in midheaven,
saying with a loud voice,
"Woe, woe, woe to those
who dwell on the earth,
"because of the remaining blasts
of the trumpet of the three angels
who are about to sound!"
He is the way.
He is the strength.
I don't want to hide anymore.
He has taught you to say no
to this mediocre world,
without order,
without hierarchy.
He is the only true light.
You're betraying, Brother Antoine.
You mustn't go back to society.
I need your help.
He is our only family.
They killed me!
I have to tell,
Michel Fournier is alive.
What life are you talking about?
Tell me a story.
Come on.
I want to go back to my mother's.
Yes, but...
can't you tell me a story first?
Adam and Eve and Pinch Me
went down to the river to play.
Adam and Eve were drowned.
Who was saved?
Adam and Eve were drowned, so...
Pinch Me was saved.
Hello?
They hung up...
They hung up!
We're going to the country.
I don't want to.
I want to go home right now!
Today is my birthday.
- I don't want to be alone.
- I don't care.
I can't be alone.
I don't care. I hate you.
We are everywhere.
Europe.
Africa.
America.
We are very powerful.
God sent Him to drag the world
away from its mediocrity.
To uproot communism and atheism.
COME TO ME, I WILL
TAKE YOUR SUFFERING AWAY.
GIVE ME YOUR LOVE,
I WILL GIVE YOU PEACE
Do you like it?
Our army is big.
And it will get bigger.
In every country, in every family,
we're recruiting girls and boys
who'll form the Army of God.
Where are you going?
To have a wee. May I?
Go.
- Don't you like it here?
- I want to go home.
And his name isn't Antoine,
it's Michel.
- I know that.
- Where is he?
Don't ask questions.
We'll save you from your family.
From the world.
Do you understand?
Against your will.
- Supt Pidoux?
- Yes.
I'm downstairs. In the car park.
On behalf of Michel Fournier.
After the murder of the little girl,
Michel was hiding.
In fact, I knew Michel.
We had done stupid things together.
I was sent to kill him.
But I couldn't do it.
The body has been identified,
hasn't it?
- When did you see him last?
- Two days ago.
Where?
Answer me. Where?
No, no and no!
I want you to leave me alone.
- I am not a killer.
- Yeah, right.
Keep Henri Fournier under control.
But I have nothing to do with it.
Arsehole.
- Superintendent!
- Yes?
It's called...
The Temple of
the Son of the True Light.
- You'll find it?
- Yes, I know it.
I may be a loser but not a killer!
Say sorry to her.
It's a game.
She's going to say she's sorry.
Right?
Say you're sorry.
Do it.
Sorry.
And now,
we're playing another game.
Hide and seek.
Count!
One, two, three...
That's it. Hide!
It's a game!
Hide now, Catherine.
Wherever you want
but not in that room.
Come on.
I warned you.
You shouldn't have gone in.
Catherine...
I've been waiting for you.
I've always been waiting for you
for these past two years.
After school.
At your piano lesson.
I'm completely lost without you.
I could kill you.
Is anybody here?
I'm looking for Michel Fournier.
The man you call Michel Fournier
was known by us
as Brother Antoine.
He has betrayed us.
He has returned to your world.
The world of little people.
The world of mediocrity.
This world without faith,
without soul.
He has dragged
Sister Andrée down with him.
We'll guide you
so they'll be punished
and exterminated.
No one can escape
from the Master.
Brother Antoine?
No, I haven't seen him.
It's serious.
A child has been kidnapped.
I'm from the police.
I despise the order you represent.
There is nobody here.
You can do nothing against us.
Hello?
Michel...
What about Catherine?
Yes.
Yes, I'll be there.
Alone.
Give the girl back.
Michel?
Is that you?
Mummy! Mummy!
I beg you.
Don't drink.
Come on, darling...
Don't drink!
I need you.
Leave me alone.
I have the right to drink.
I have the right to die.
It's so good, you know,
sleeping, isn't it?
Sleeping for ever.
You're just like me.
You'll end up just like me.
Catherine!
He's going to kill me!
I love you, Véronique.
I love you.
We're leaving, the three of us.
Beat it!
Serves you right.
Come on.
Beat it!
I've been waiting for you.
I've been waiting for you
for a very long time.
Let's play.
You lost.
Nuit d'Or!
Give him his money back.
Go away, Michel.
I won't do anything against you.
And nobody will.
Poor Pidoux...
We are losers.
Both of us.
Marie doesnt love you.
She never loved you.
She became crazy
to never see you again.
And never recognize you.
How could anyone love you?
You're going to kill me.
This time, it will be for good.
The real Michel Fournier.
The show is over.
No more faux-macabre.
I am not a murderer.
I was wrongly accused.
You always knew it.
It wasn't loaded.
It has never been loaded.