Toei Company, LTD. Presents
TEHRAN
Whose agent are you?
Damn you!
Make him talk.
He's dead.
He bit off his own tongue.
Do you know this man?
Yes. I do.
Thanks.
Mr. Evans' suitcase.
Mr. Evans hasn't been back since July 5th.
He hasn't paid his hotel bill for a week.
BEIRUT
The manager of the hotel told me...
Evans has been missing since July 5th.
A maid said he was charmed by the moon.
And flew out of the window.
Where did he go?
To the moon?
Probably someplace a lot lower.
Maybe under the desert soil.
Damn luck!
Taylor, McGuire, Casey. Now Evans.
Four men! We lost four men already!
Evans was also wiped out?
The only way is for me to go to Tehran.
You don't have to go there.
You and your men are given leave.
Then our country...
We'll stop trying to catch Max Boa.
Meaning we must overlook Max Boa?
We've looked for him all over the world.
We know he's in Iran now.
This is our best chance to get him.
But we won't be able to get him in Iran.
It'd be infringement of sovereignty.
Iran has signed the extradition pact.
Arresting him is lawful.
Our nationality is different from his.
If we demand delivery, the police
from his country will cut in.
They'll just send him home.
He'll be released without a trial.
He has influence over his government.
You know that
Then why did you let four men die in vain?
Their deaths weren't in vain.
I'll avenge them.
How? We have no way to.
We'll kill Max Boa.
GOLGO 13
NAME: DUKE TOGO. NICKNAME: GOLGO 13
NATIONALITY: UNKNOWN
PLACE OF BIRTH: UNKNOWN
DATE OF BIRTH: UNKNOWN
HAIR: BLACK
EYES: BLACK
COLOR: YELLOW
HEIGHT: 180 CENTIMETERS
WEIGHT: 80 KILOGRAMS
FEATURE: MIXED BLOOD JAPANESE LOOK-LIKE
OCCUPATION: SNIPER
Five minutes to go. You sure he'll come?
He said he would. He'll be here any minute.
Golgo 13.
The name was given to him by fellow
inmates in a German prison.
It means the 13th man.
Judas - the one who betrayed Christ...
And helped crucify him on Golgotha Hill
Stop talking!
I've heard enough.
I'll have to be with him for a long time.
Excuse me.
You're wrong. We didn't order anything.
Someone is called for a pitcher
of water and glass.
This is Room 612.
We didn't îrder anything.
You might be wrong.
What's up?
The operator said she was asked to
call this room at 10 o'clock.
By whom?
That'll be enough.
Tell the operator to forget it.
Put it down there.
You called me, didn't you?
Duke Togo!
You let the waiter enter and sneaked
in while we were on the phone.
Don't you trust a client?
Stop talking!
Pleased to meet you. I'm Richard Flanagan.
Hey! You're rude!
Don't mind. He doesn't like his
right hand grabbed by anyone.
I want you to explain.
Catherine.
Now that I see you, I'm convinced
you'll succeed in this job.
This is a hard job. Your target is Max Boa.
He has secret hideouts all over the world.
We've been informed he's now in Iran.
There are many contacts in code
between his country and Iran.
So I'm sure Boa is now in Iran.
Nobody knows his real face.
Several men bear his name.
Maybe none of them are Max Boa.
They say he was born in either
Berlin, Canada or Spain.
I don't think 'Boa' is his real name.
It means snake.
He's a shipping agent registered in
a South American country.
But actually, he's smuggling drugs
and weapons using his ships.
He's the biggest of their gangs.
There have been recent changes
in their movements.
Wherever they operate
beautiful girls disappear.
200 Europeans. 300 South Americans
and Indians.
And 65 girls missing from my country.
My daughter's one of them.
Keep quiet while I read this.
I'm sorry. Take time to read it.
When you've examined it...
you'll know why we're leaving
Max Boa to you.
We can't reach him.
Only a hired assassin can.
Wait! Calm down, will you?
I'll explain. Hamil was careless.
He hates a man to stand behind him.
Amazing! He prepared water for this.
Will you accept our offer?
I want to know your identity.
Sorry, but I can't tell you that.
If the truth is exposed...
Wait a minute.
I was wrong.
If our plan to kill Max Boa is known...
international trouble will happen.
I'm sure you won't reveal us
Look at this.
Seems all right.
Then will you please...?
Deposit half a million dollars
to a Swiss bank.
Thank you for accepting.
Oh, I'm sorry. I forgot.
Use Miss Catherine Morton as your
assistant and contact.
Ask whatever you like.
Who is it?
Catherine.
I finished arrangements for going abroad.
Passports and plane tickets.
Why two tickets?
One for me.
I'll go with you. I'm your assistant.
I know Tehran. I went to Teheran University.
We're supposed to be a married couple.
It's Flanagans idea. So we
won't be discovered.
There's one more thing. I...
I was told to live the role of a wife.
You needn't do so.
Why not?
Embrace me.
If you don't love me, Golgo...
something may go wrong
TEHRAN
Original Story by.
SAITO Takao, MOTOMITSU Ê.
Cinematography: IIMURA Masahiko
Art Director: FUJITA Baku
Directed by: SATO Junya
I want to see Egbari. Contact him.
Tell him Duke Togo wants to see him.
Welcome. What can I do for you?
I'm Duke Togo. I have a reservation.
Yes, sir. We've kept a room
on the top floor.
You insisted it be near a fire exit.
Is there any reason?
It's an unusual order, sir.
There should be three boxes.
I see. I'll have them sent up at once.
Put them down there.
She's really beautiful.
She went to the police station.
Yes. Come in.
Am I bothering you?
You haven't been home for a week.
What's wrong?
I'm making a report about 20 missing women.
They disappeared in the past two weeks.
Their families didn't report it.
It's a mess.
Kidnapped for money?
Probably not.
I wish I knew.
I shouldn't have asked.
Don't mind. Come on, take a seat.
Let's eat out, Sheila.
You must be busy.
I'll forget you're my wife, if I stay
away from you for much longer.
I'll meet you at 8:00 PM.
I'll be at 'Paprika'.
Don't forget, darling.
Tell me the way to Hafiz Street.
Turn left at the second street.
At the second street?
Don't! Let go of me!
You!
Did you see who left this coat?
You didn't see the woman?
Found Max Boa's hideout?
Not a clue.
My assistant disappeared last night
and was found dead today.
He was in touch with a club manager.
What is his name, Egbari?
He's called 'Mr. Wine'
He's an underworld informer.
He's at the 'Club Scheherazade' every night.
I see.
Thank you. Take this.
Thank you.
I'll try to find his hideout some other way.
Be careful.
I'll see you in your room tonight.
Egbari?
MAX BOA IS FOND OF LITTLE BIRDS
Thank you. I understand.
That'll be enough.
Shut up!
Quiet!
Search the hotels for an Asian man.
Look for him and find him!
How do you like it?
Wonderful, Mr. Wine.
How did you know my name?
Who told you?
I'll pay one million.
Where's Max Boa?
Wait a minute.
I don't know where Boa is.
I'm not lying.
I'm telling you the truth.
His man has an office here.
His hideout is in the Old Town.
That's all I know.
Hello, this is Wine.
Thanks for remembering me.
I'm that Wine.
Business is so-so.
Listen, Mr. Walter.
I've got news concerning Mr. Boa's life.
Many men want to kill Mr. Boa.
Do you think you can get money for that?
The man in question isn't one
of these cheap guys.
Mr. Walter, I'm an expert in this business.
I know how much I can get for this info.
Okay, shoot!
Who's looking for Mr. Boa?
I want you to fix the sum first.
The man is a trained killer.
Not enough. I want more.
All right, I agree.
The man is Asian, with...
What happened?
Hello? Hello?
How did you find me?
We have ways.
And you registered your real
name, Duke Togo.
How about a drink?
No, thanks.
Take a shower?
Later.
Am I nothing but a nuisance to you?
Is a woman just oil for a killing
machine like you?
You're turning your back on me.
You trust me, don't you?
You like me...
as a woman.
I'll take a shower.
You couldn't find him? I see.
An Asian man's staying at the
Sheraton Hotel.
Why don't you change?
My agent was murdered.
You must be careful.
Who is it?
The police. Inspector Aman.
Wait! I'm changing!
Open up! Or I'll break it down!
I said, wait!
What is this?
Stop it!
Dress and come with me.
Why? What did I do?
You helped a murderer escape.
What happened?
Shut up, you two!
Mr. Boa, the Asian, killed
Wine with a single shot.
I think I can get some dope on him.
I asked our people all over the
world to check it out.
All over the world? Isn't that a bit much?
Julie, what's wrong?
You have no appetite these days.
He's only a gunman. Is he worth
all that trouble?
Yes, if he's the man I'm thinking of.
Julie, the man must be dreadful,
because Walter's so frightened.
If  you're so frightened  I'll call
Simon and Douglas from Paris.
Who are you?
Is Walter in?
Don't act big. Say, 'Mr. Walter'
Simon!
Is Mr Walter in?
A little search first.
Purely routine.
Net the lame big boy.
Calm down!
Mr. Walter's room is upstairs.
Come...
Wait! Don't you want to check
my artificial leg?
What can you hide in your leg? What a clown.
What happened?
One of your men made Simon angry
and was sent to the next world.
I didn't tell my men you two were coming.
Sorry. It's my fault.
Let bygones be bygones.
Did you learn the identity of the
man who opposes us?
I'll get the info we need tomorrow.
Then we'll decide what to do with him.
Do you think there are any killers
who want to fight three of us?
If he's the one I think he is...
He may try.
What's his name?
Can't say it now.
If I'm wrong you'll laugh.
I want you to wait till tomorrow.
I'll go to my place in the Old Town.
Make yourselves at home.
Open up!
Don't cry. Keep your chin up.
How many?
Sixteen girls.
What will you do with us?
Let me go home, please.
Shut up! Keep silent!
Let me go. I beg you.
How long do you intend to confine me?
I'm tired of hearing it.
Why did Duke Togo come here?
Tell me, then I'll free you.
We're on a honeymoon. Is that illegal?
Don't lie!
He has the key to solve this case.
We caught one of the kidnappers.
Is this the man?
We killed one in the shooting.
You'll have to talk.
Stop!
Why did you kill the man?
I'll tell you if you let me see Boa.
What?
You deliberately killed him knowing
he wasn't really Boa?
Who ordered you to kill Boa?
Who are you?
Do what you like. Make him talk!
Where are the girls?
My wife's among them
Search me.
Talk!
Inspector, take it easy.
Don't interfere!
It's my responsibility.
Let me handle this.
He's the toughest guys I've ever seen.
What's he made of?
He's only a man. If he's tortured
enough, he'll talk.
You have a call from Isfahan.
Hello! This is Walter speaking.
Walter's on the phone.
Don't smoke near Julie.
You know she hates smoke.
You're a nice girl. Be considerate.
All right. It's nothing.
You're frightened. Yvonne is a bad girl.
Hello, Walter.
You may know by now, but I've got a tip.
Two of your men were caught
by the Tehran police.
Is that true, Mr. Boa?
Are you surprised, Walter?
Then you must've become dull.
The man in charge of the case is
Inspector Aman. Take care.
I'm sorry, sir.
Transfer the girls you're keeping
to the place we talked about.
It's time for you to go to bed, Julie.
Sleep is most important for
your health. Come on.
What shall we do with him?
I'll kill him after he talks.
Damn it!
I'll go. You stay.
The dark is favorable to a
blind man like me.
What's your name?
Golgo 13.
Sure. Just as I thought.
Who's your boss?
Max Boa.
What?
Is he the boss? Where is he?
Isfahan.
What part of Isfahan?
Don't know. I've never seen him.
What's Duke Togo to you?
Mrs. Togo, you're released. You may go.
Your car is outside.
Is that all?
What about my husband?
He hasn't been reported dead.
When we find him, you'll
be the first to know.
Please go.
ISFAHAN, 472km
Why are you following me?
I want to see my husband caught.
You're under arrest for following me.
Suits me. Am I a hostage?
Get in.
There! After him!
Get him!
Don't shoot me! Golgo 13!
I'm the loser.
I surrender. Spare me.
I heard Golgo 13 wouldn't
shoot an unarmed man.
HOTEL SHAH ABBAS
Don't move!
Stand with your hands up!
You're under arrest!
Come with me.
Wait! He isn't one of Max Boa's men.
Shut up!
The police will decide that.
He'll be tried for murder.
Come on! Move!
Don't move!
Or I'll shoot you.
If you don't trust me, I'll shoot you.
Come on. Let's go.
Damn slut!
ISFAHAN
Where will you go?
The Hotel Shah Abbas.
You've found Max Boa at last, haven't you?
What's up?
Get out, will you?
Let me go with you.
No dice.
This is my job. I want you out.
You may think I'm sentimental.
I missed you the days you were gone.
You transferred the girls?
Be careful of the police.
What will you do with the girls?
Shut up! Don't meddle in my business.
Come in.
Julie, there's trouble.
Mr. Boa, Simon was killed by him.
Is his name Golgo 13?
He's a man to be feared.
She's right, Julie.
He's frightening. His name alone thrills me.
When will he come?
I don't think he's spotted this place.
You don't think?
Use your head, Douglas.
A man like Golgo should've found this place.
I'm scared.
Julie, let's have some tea on the terrace.
Golgo's trying to kill you.
The terrace is risky.
Don't tell me what to do.
You know I don't like changes in schedule.
Golgo's up there! The tower!
He's gone. After him!
Golgo, run!
Golgo, what are you doing?
Take the woman alive!
After her!
Hurry!
You did a fine job.
Take her away!
Drive slowly.
Golgo will shoot us.
These windows are bullet-proof.
I want him to follow us.
To a hill like Golgotha where he's to die.
Wait and see.
Only one dead?
Find the Oriental!
It's him!
Ñ squad.
Get Inspector Aman.
Aman here. You found the Oriental?
Heading for Persepolis?
Julie, you'll soon see a very
thrilling scene.
Golgo 13, I know where you are!
Come out, Golgo 13!
What are you doing?
Come out!
If you don't, we'll kill the
girls one by one.
Golgo, don't come out! Forget me!
What's up, Golgo? Are you scared?
Golgo 13, where's your pride as a killer?
Golgo 13, come out and fight with me.
You're Golgo, eh?
Listen! I'll give you one minute.
Golgo, don't come out!
Shut up, slut!
They're your target?
Golgo, I'll count to ten!
I won't wait any longer!
If you don't come out, I'll kill them!
Don't go!
Why stop me?
Don't die in vain.
This is Inspector Aman!
You're surrounded!
Throw down your weapons and surrender!
Give up!
If you kill the girls,
we'll kill all of you!
There's an added attraction.
Give up.
Darling!
Sheila!
We don't need the police.
Golgo, come out!
Aman!
Golgo, don't care about me!
Aman! Come and help! Hurry!
Golgo! Your woman is next!
Golgo! I'll shoot her at the
count of five this time!
Isn't this amusing, Yvonne?
This is the greatest show.
If you count, you'll get nothing.
Golgo will never come out. Go on! Kill me!
Hurry!
Golgo! I love you!
Beasts! I'll hang them all!
Come back, Douglas!
He won't fall into your trap.
He's looking for me.
That's enough. Come back!
Let's go back!
Take these girls with you! Hurry!
What do you want to say?
Ask Golgo...
to kill Max Boa... to kill Max Boa.
Douglas! Golgo is coming!
I'll get rid of him.
Please go back, Mr. Boa.
Mr. Boa, I killed Golgo 13.
The End