(waves crashing)
(gentle music)
- Hi, Paul, thank you
so much for doing this.
It's like last minute re-shoots,
so you are saving my butt again.
Okay, dog stuff, so
lockbox wag code is 201
but I think I wrote that down,
should be maybe on the fridge.
When they eat, T's really
particular about his food
and will just like stare at
it for a really long time.
That's his choice, sure.
But if you can just push all
the bowls quite close together,
I feel like it gives him some
incentive to hurry up an eat
which would be much easier and
more efficient for everyone.
If you can put just like
a little bit of water
with their food as well,
just so it's like cereal,
apparently it's good for
their digestion, maybe.
Actually, while I'm away,
put Ripley's bowl in
the spare room to eat,
she gets a bit territorial about her food
and then we'll try to
go after the other ones.
So, I mean, she's like
usually really good about it,
but maybe just while
I'm away, just in case.
Three walks a day.
So if you just look after
the first and the last,
like morning and night,
and then I'll have dog walker
come in while you're at work.
Barkley, he will bark at everything.
(dogs barking)
Emery arrives tomorrow,
I'm so jealous that
I'm not gonna be there.
She's really awesome and
I think you will love her.
And yeah, what a bummer,
I'm not gonna be there,
which is always the way I feel like.
Oh, and if you can walk,
oh, sorry, transpo van is coming.
Okay, water the plants, if you can.
You're the best.
I love you so much.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Okay, I'll speak to you soon.
(lips smacking)
Bye.
- Hey Maggie, looks like you're
having fun in the big city.
We are all good here.
The dogs are not in the
living room with me,
but they are here.
I'm working tomorrow,
but on Wednesday and Thursday
you don't need a dog walker
because I'm not working.
And I can not wait to meet Emery.
She seems awesome, so.
Wish you were here too
but you keep having fun
and doing your thing in New York.
Oh, and I got your plants
covered, no worries, all right.
I'll talk to you soon, bye.
(lips smacking)
(car horn honking)
- [Announcer] Loading dock
two, for intake four one five
- So Paul, what we're doing
is we're reconfiguring the warehouse,
we're checking inventory up in the racks.
It need you to go to location, E01H5.
- It's like, why do I
hire a property manager,
if you're gonna call me as
much as the tenants would?
If you need a plumber
Call a plumber don't call me.
Like I have a Rolodex of
plumbers and everything,
that's your job.
- That's why I don't do
apartment real estate.
I mean, why do you have an extra job
when you have this one, you know?
- Why is that hard for you?
- [Paul] I'm just
understanding why you work here
and also have real estate, that's all.
- So what, I should just have real estate
and sit at home all day?
- [Paul] A lot of people
just have real estate.
- That's what you would do?
You would just sit home
all day, if you were me,
and not work?
It's a family thing, you know
that, it's my responsibility.
How's the breakup going, enjoying that?
- Yeah, it's fun to be alone.
I didn't look at her
Instagram all weekend,
so I chalk that up as a win.
- No, good for you.
- Yeah.
- That's a real big win for you.
- [Paul] Thanks man.
- Don't you think maybe you
should get over it by now?
- I know that, thank you.
- You guys were together,
what, three and a half,
three years, four years?
- Three and a half.
- Yeah.
- So that should take you.
- As much time as I need.
- Three and a half months
and you should be over it.
- Again, like, that's your
way of getting over somebody.
For some people it takes
more time, that's it.
- You just like the simmer in it for years
and ruin any possible chance
for a real relationship.
- I have a different mindset
in the way in which I
fall in love with somebody
than you do.
- Yeah, it's like,
I don't do it right when I see them.
- Break.
- What's that?
- Break up with them.
- No, I don't fall in love
with every girl I look at.
- I don't do that.
- Just because we have sex,
doesn't mean I'm going
to fall in love with you
and then freak you out and
send you running like you do.
- Hey, hey, Paul, can you
give Noelle a tour please?
- Yeah, sure.
- Hi.
Hey, I'm Paul.
- Nice to meet you, Noelle.
- Nice to meet you, hey.
- Lewis, Lewis.
- Nice to meet you.
- Lewis, Lewis, you hear that?
- Lewis, Lewis, got it.
- [Lewis] Enjoy the tour.
Enjoy the tour, Paul.
- Yeah, fuck you.
So you're gonna need this first.
We have a pink one, but.
- This is good.
- Okay.
- Love it.
- You got it?
- Yeah.
- So I guess we'll start in
aisle N which is right here.
So aisle N has a lot of shirts.
- Cool.
- Actually all the aisles
have a lot of shirts.
So yeah, we basically,
if we need a certain shirt,
we'll send a picker to grab it
and then a sorter will then get the shirts
that we need to ship out.
- Cool.
- What exactly are you hired to do?
- I'm a checker.
- Oh, okay, yeah.
- Yeah.
- I kinda, I check too.
- Right.
And you're the store man
manager, store foreman.
- I'm the foreman, yeah.
- Cool.
How long have you worked here?
- I've worked here for three years.
- Cool.
- Yeah.
- Do you live nearby?
- Right now, I'm house
sitting for a couple of dogs
and they're a little bit
of a handful, but yeah.
- Have you ever tried
using a laser pointer,
pointing around?
- With the dogs?
- Yeah, my girlfriend
does that with her cat.
It exhausts the crap out of them.
- Wears 'em out hah?
- Yeah, yeah.
- You have a girlfriend.
- Yeah.
- Cool.
So this aisle right here is aisle...
- C.
- Exactly.
(Paul laughing)
Where is it, where is it?
Ripley, don't come after me.
What do you guys want to
play tonight, Pictionary?
- [Woman] Let's do variety.
- All right, yeah.
- Hey Paul, what's up?
I'm just calling to say hi,
I haven't heard from you in a little bit.
The kids were wanting to know
if you were coming to
the 4th of July cookout,
in our backyard,
which is a very big deal this year.
They're very excited.
They're in charge of the fireworks
and they said that they need your help.
So we'd love to have you.
Give me a call or text me and
let me know what your plan is.
And also just to say hi
'cause I haven't heard from you in a bit.
So anyway, I love you, okay.
Yeah, I'm coming.
Sorry.
- Hey Ally,
yeah. I don't know about 4th of July yet,
I don't know if I got it off yet.
So yeah, it seems you've
got a full house there,
so I won't keep you too long.
And I'll talk to you soon.
But yeah, I don't know yet, so.
All right, bye, love you.
(gentle upbeat music)
(virtual gun firing)
- [Lewis] We did eight
hundred lines before lunch.
- [Paul] I know.
- [Lewis] It's a lot.
- Busy day.
- For us.
- Yes, sir.
- We have a 40 truck
coming in after lunch,
so we need to get that out by five,
so we need you there too, you know.
- Okay, I can be here for that.
- Good.
- You just thinking about lunch right now?
- A little bit, 'cause the
taco trucks here today.
- Oh yeah.
- Yeah.
- We're doing tacos.
- Let's do some tacos, great.
Cool.
Also, having people over tomorrow night,
so I'd like for you to come too.
- [Paul] Okay, yeah, I
think I can swing by.
- Yeah, get out of the
apartment, you know, quit moping,
meet some people, you'll have fun.
- Yeah, I might swing by.
- No, you'll come, just come.
Everybody's gonna be there,
it's gonna be a good time.
- All right, maybe.
- Everybody is coming over.
Everyone is coming over.
- Yeah, I know.
- Hey Noelle you still coming
tomorrow night to the party?
- Yep.
Why are you shouting?
- Because you're far.
I'll see you at lunch.
- Hey, you found the smoking corner.
- Hey, yo.
- Hey.
- Mind if I take a seat with you.
- Heck yeah.
- Smoking on the second day, huh?
- Yeah, it keeps on, like going out.
- There you go.
- 'Cause it's so windy.
- That's good.
- You know what I'm saying.
- You liking it so far?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I like it.
- Good.
- It's fun.
- Yeah.
- How are you, how's, how's dog sitting?
- Dog sitting's great.
The laser pointer was a great idea.
- Really?
- Yeah.
They loved it.
- Knew it.
- They were literally running.
- They go nuts for that shit.
- It's insane.
They were running around and it was like,
it was hysterical.
- Sometimes I worry that it'll make,
it'll make like dogs or
cats kind of lose their mind
because it's this thing
that'll just appear out of nowhere,
so then they're constantly
gonna be looking for now.
- Yeah, I saw that in Barkley's eyes.
Like, he like was like.
- Who's Barkley, the dog?
- Oh yeah, sorry, yeah, he's the dog.
Barkley, Theo and Ripley.
- Cute.
- Yeah, they're all really cute.
But Barkley like would
just stand at attention,
kinda like this the whole time.
(Noelle laughing)
It's insane.
- You should see cats do
it, man, they're like nuts.
- They love it too.
- I'm gonna use your back
'cause the wind won't
let me keep my flame.
Hold on.
- Yeah, sure,
it's what it's there for.
- I'm gonna light you up.
Do you want some pizza?
- I'm okay, that's not.
- I found this on the fridge.
- That wasn't yours, but.
- Oh, you do know that.
- Yeah, no, that's Mario's.
(Noelle laughing)
- Yeah.
- Mark said that it was
in the fridge for a while.
So I was like this is mine.
- I think Mark said that
because Mario brings it in every day.
So he has like a slice of pizza every day.
(Noelle laughing)
- Oh my God.
- Yeah, so.
Mario's not gonna have lunch today,
but luckily the taco truck's here.
(Noelle laughing)
- It's fucking good.
- Yeah.
- Italian bread.
- He makes it.
- What?
- Yes.
- It's so good.
Oh my God.
- And Mark knows that too.
I think he was just like,
that's not good.
- Well it fed me, fed my soul.
- Yeah.
- I have to get back to work.
- Yeah, high as a kite, you're
ready to rock, go for it.
- All right, that's not gonna work.
- Yup.
- I was gonna do one of
those rolls, you know.
- Well, I didn't know
if you were trying to do
like a tuck and roll or just a.
- A what?
Yeah, tuck and roll.
(Noelle laughing)
- It's good hanging with you.
- I'll grab all these
matches, you're good,
you've got too much stuff.
Hey, what's going on Emery, how are ya?
Okay, great.
Five minutes, okay, let me,
I'll pull my car up a little bit
and you can just pull into
my spot behind me, okay.
I'm the Mazda.
So I'm the farthest one over to the left.
That's not gonna be your bed.
What's going on?
- How's it going?
- Good.
Sorry, I'm gonna roll up my window.
I think I just rolled that
tree up into my window.
- It's okay.
- What's up?
- It's not my tree.
- Hey.
- Hey, how are ya?
- I'm good, how are you?
- Nice to meet you.
Oh, can I help you with your bags?
- No, no, no, I'll just grab my backpack,
that's all I need right now.
- Okay, cool.
- Oh my God, oh.
- Drive was okay?
Oh my God, so long, but
I'm so happy to be here.
- Right.
- Yeah.
- You're finally in LA.
- Oh my God, look at the babies.
- Yeah, so that's Barkley
on the right there.
And then Ripley is a little white guy.
- [Emery] Yes.
- Living room.
- Cool.
- Okay.
Kitchen is in here.
- Nice.
- Alrighty.
And then the spare bedroom,
where you're staying, right here.
- Amazing.
- Alrighty.
- Thank you.
- You got it.
- This is so great.
- Yeah.
Have you had dinner yet?
- No, have you eaten yet?
- I have not.
- Wanna get some food?
- Yeah.
Let you set up here.
- Okay, cool.
- Cool.
So how long did it take
you to come on out?
- Like two and a half weeks.
- Okay.
- But I took time.
And it still didn't feel
like that much time,
but it was like, you know.
No, no you go.
- I was gonna say, did
you have a favorite stop?
- Oh my God, I love Montana,
I love New Mexico.
- I went through New
Mexico, that was good.
- Yeah.
- You took a road trip?
- I did, I stopped in Santa Fe,
I actually got a ticket there.
- For what?
- Well I was distracted,
which is not good driving,
but I was going 60 in a 35.
- Okay.
- And that was in Tulum,
not, it's like Tatum, Mexico,
which is really New Mexico.
- Right.
- Super small.
And then right after that
I hit a bird by accident.
Shouldn't have been going that fast.
- Poor bird.
- Yeah.
But it was a fun trip.
But New Mexico is beautiful.
Santa Fe with that sunset.
- I would live there so fast.
- Yeah.
- If there was like a legitimate way
for me to make money in New Mexico,
I would live there in a heartbeat.
- It was beautiful.
There's so many parts of,
you know, this country
that you just don't realize
how beautiful they are.
- What's this?
- This is a pawn shop.
- Oh my God.
- All right.
- I've only ever been to L.A.
like for three days, once.
- Really?
- When did you take your road trip?
- It was five years ago.
We got the crosswalk.
- Okay.
- Yeah, and that's
actually when I met Maggie.
Yeah, she was my first friend out here.
- That's amazing.
- She's cool.
- Holy shit.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, love that girl.
I'm so sad she's not here right now.
I'm glad you're here but like,
I'm sad she's not here.
- It would be cool
to have Maggie here too.
- Yeah.
- She really brings everybody together.
- So this place has a
really good sandwich.
- Nice.
- Best in L.A.
- Okay, I'll take your word for it.
But you know what I have heard?
I've heard that L.A. food is
way better than New York food.
- I mean, I should take
you to get like tacos
or poke's really good here.
- Poke?
Oh, poke.
- Poke, oh yeah sorry, poke.
Is it poke?
- Poke.
- Is it poke?
- I actually don't know,
I'm pulling that out of my ass.
(Emery laughing)
- But yeah, I, of course
went with the, you know, sandwiches.
- No sandwiches are
God's gift to the world.
I'm so happy.
- Here you go.
- Okay, okay, thanks.
Do you mind if I smoke a cigarette?
- No, go for it.
- Okay.
Sorry, it's only a summer habit.
- It's only a summer habit?
- Yeah.
- That's good.
- Okay.
Okay wait.
- I don't have a lighter on me.
- No, I got it.
Do you smoke?
- [Paul] No, I don't.
- Good for you.
- [Paul] I got plenty other vices.
- [Emery] Oh yeah, like what?
(Emery laughing)
- Fuck off.
- I swear too much.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- Drink too much.
All the above.
So what brings you out here?
- To L.A?
I don't know, like a lot of things.
Well,
my mom just died.
- I'm sorry about that.
- Thanks man, thanks.
Yeah, she was sick for a while.
But yeah, my mom just died
and then I got out of this
really bad relationship
with this married couple.
It kind of exploded and it was like weird.
So I needed to get away.
And I was like, there's just no way
that I can stay where I
am and go through another,
I don't know, like a year
there and I don't know.
Okay, that's a lot.
- I'm sorry to hear
about your mom.
- No, thanks man, thank you.
I mean, I'm sorry about your mom.
- Yeah, thanks.
- And I kinda heard a
little bit about the,
well I saw like on your Instagram
that you were in a
relationship with two other.
- Yeah, yeah.
Honestly, it's crazy
because when we first started dating,
I was like, fuck being in a couple,
like throuples are where it's at,
like three people is great.
Like the communication and
it's like, you have to,
you're like forced to be honest, you know.
And it was really good, until it wasn't,
then it was really, really bad.
But yeah, it just got shitty.
Mostly 'cause, you know,
I got into it for her.
'Cause I've been
historically gay, you know,
I've only dated women.
And then like I got into this thing
'cause she was like, "Hey, wanna date me?
"But also if you date me,
you have to date my husband."
Anyway so we all got together
and then it turned out that me and Kace
just got along way better,
which was such a surprise to everyone.
And it kinda, it was like
all downhill from there.
Yeah, that was a lot.
That was a lot of information.
- No, that's, I mean, I'm
happy you shared it with me.
- Yeah.
- It's cool.
- Okay, what about you?
- Well I guess we'll start,
my parents got divorced when I was eight,
so they're still both alive
with different people.
I didn't mean to say it
like both, alive, I mean.
- No, no, it's fine, please.
- But yeah, moved out here five years ago,
had a thing with a girl for
about three and a half years,
on and off.
It just didn't work out.
I never felt like I was
enough with her, you know.
But that's, I don't know,
it's a, yeah, that one
just kinda stuck, so.
But Maggie's been a great
friend through it all.
- Yeah, yeah, she's a good one.
- And you know, like,
the bus comes along
every 10 minutes, right.
- What?
What's the bus?
- I don't know, like
my mom always said that
when like you break up with somebody.
- There are a lot of fish in the sea.
- Yeah, but she just used bus analogies.
- Oh, so you're dating right now.
- Yeah, I mean, a little
bit like not a lot, but.
- Yeah.
- Trying, you know.
- Good, good for you.
That's great.
- I say trying
but more or less like barely.
(Emery laughing)
Barely doing anything with it.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- That's okay.
I mean, I have like a
dating site, but it's not.
- You own the dating site?
- I don't own an dating site,
that's not what I meant.
But I am on one dating site.
- Cool, which one?
- The worst one.
(Emery laughing)
- Okay, okay.
Okay, I'm gonna finish this
really quick and then we can go
'cause I'm really hungry.
- Yeah, sorry about the sandwiches,
but pasta will do, right?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, oh my God,
it's so fine, it's so fine.
I love pasta.
I love Italian.
I'm coming in baby girl.
(cellphone pings)
- [Kace] Hey, hey, hey.
I'm just checking in
to see if you made it to L.A. all right.
And yeah, I'm trying to
repaint the spare bedroom
that you originally used
to like white or eggshell
or flat white, Amber doesn't
remember, so I don't know,
she's not even talking to me right now.
I don't know, I think you
leaving, clarified a few things.
She thinks that like I pushed
you away, I don't know.
This is a lot, I'm sorry.
It's just, yeah, that West Coast gig,
I think it will pan out,
I just need to talk to
the producer about it.
Got a photo shoot tomorrow.
And yeah, I'll let you know,
I'll just, yeah.
Let me know about that white paint,
is it flat or eggshell?
Alright, love you, talk soon, bye.
- Okay.
- To be honest, I'm not
much of a game player.
- Okay, well that's good to know
because to be honest, I've
never made pasta before.
- You're first time making pasta?
How old are you?
- I never make it.
Doesn't matter.
I just never made it,
it was something I didn't enjoy as a kid.
(Emery laughing)
Just try it before you
judge it hard, okay.
- A, this is a lot of pasta
and B, pasta is not
supposed to look like this,
not supposed to do that.
- Okay. Well, when you do that,
like it doesn't look that appetizing.
But I'm just saying like
there's sauce in it.
- I mean, actually like
wait, do you have more sauce?
- This is all I have.
(Emery laughing)
- Okay.
Oh my God, it's so dry.
- You know what don't eat it.
I'm just kidding.
- No, no, no, I'm not
kidding, but like I'm kidding.
Okay.
- Alright.
- I have a word.
I think.
- Wait, did you just put one back?
- No.
- Yes you did.
- No, I only have six.
Look, I need seven.
C-A-R, care bitch.
- Care, okay.
Okay, so that's three, four, five, six.
I get six points.
- Is that what you do, you
stop at anything to win?
- The fuck are you talking about?
- [Paul] The fuck I'm talking
about, you just looked at it.
Yes you did.
- Okay, okay.
Would you rather be a winner or a cheater?
Wait, wait, wait.
- A winner, that's a very.
- No, no, no, would you rather be a loser
or a winner who cheats?
- Right now, you're both.
- I can't believe you
just called me a loser.
That's so mean.
- Well 'cause it's the first word
and you're already going for the thing.
I mean, that's really ballsy.
It's like, wow, "Okay, I'm down early,
"so I'm gonna go, I'm gonna double down."
- Okay, listen, honestly,
do you know how every single game ends,
every single board game has
ended in my entire life,
when I started losing, guess?
No, I'm just gonna tell you.
- [Paul] With the opponent
with the slit throat?
- No, no, I just fucking
flip the board and I scream.
I say like, I fucking
hate you and hate you.
It's really unlike me.
- [Paul] That's good.
- So I feel like I don't
play games with people
unless I've known them for
at least half of my lifetime.
- [Paul] Then why are we
playing on the first night?
'Cause I feel like we gonna
get off to a very rough start.
- I know it's really bad,
it's bad already, 'cause I'm losing.
You know what?
I'm going to fucking flip the board.
Let's just do.
Ready, one, two, three.
- Two, three.
Fuck this game.
- I think that's a dog.
- Is it?
That is one, which one is it?
You want to guess?
You already see Ripley's out here so.
- I bet it's Barkley.
Ding, ding, ding, ding.
- Hey buddy.
- He's fully ready
to go to sleep.
- He's ready to go to sleep.
- [Emery] Oh my God.
- I liked that she put up your pictures.
- Those are my pictures.
- They are.
- Yeah, wait how'd you know that?
- I recognized the car one earlier.
- By the map.
- Yeah.
No, no, no, the car one, that one.
- Oh yeah, yeah.
- I saw it on your Instagram.
- Yeah, you Instagram stalking me, Paul?
- No, I just want to make sure you know,
the person who's staying
with me isn't a murderer, so.
- Yet to be seen right?
- TBD, yeah.
- Yeah, TBD.
- Exactly.
- Okay, I'm tired.
- I'll get these guys out of here for you.
- Oh fuck, I gotta take out my contacts.
- Alright.
- Okay, yeah.
- Okay Rip.
Okay bud.
All right, I'm gonna take
you in my room, okay.
Come here buddy.
Okay, ready.
Alright, I'll come back for you, Barkley.
All right, come on, Rip.
(basin water running)
Goodnight.
- Night.
(crickets chirping)
- Come on.
Come on.
Hey Maggie, good morning.
Your guys are on our morning walk.
So it's a, and your ex is here,
to be continued.
Hey Nick.
- Hey buddy, how are you?
Long time no see.
- Good to see you.
- Yeah, hey.
Sorry for being creepy sitting over there,
I was watching you with the dogs.
I was over at Coffee Commissary.
- Okay.
- I was writing a script
and I thought, yeah, Doug, you know Doug,
you know Kimberly.
- Yeah, okay cool.
- But I just thought I'd
come over and say hi to ya.
- Okay, well, hey, what
are you writing about?
- I'm sorry, there's no script, I lied.
I saw that Maggie was in
New York from Instagram,
so I thought I'd just
come over and see if.
Listen, I got a self tape
that I need to shoot and.
- I've never done one, so I don't.
- Yeah, but I know she's
got like a setup up there
and I was wondering if
maybe we could just like,
help me knock one out.
It would take like five minutes.
- I mean, don't they have
the things that you can go to
and you can, I think Maggie,
before she had all that
stuff, she'd used that.
- Yes, they do, but they're like expensive
and I can't afford it right now.
- You can afford coffee,
but you can't get the.
- Well coffee's significantly cheaper.
I don't think you realize
how expensive those places are, yeah.
- Of course, yeah.
Well I would, but I'm supposed to be
over James's house later and
it's like my off day, so.
- Oh it's your day off?
- Yeah, that's why I was.
- It'll be super quick
and I'll owe you lunch.
- Okay.
- When I can get paid next.
- All right, yeah, okay,
let's go do it now then.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Come on let's go.
- Oh my God,
thank you so much, you're the best.
- Great.
- How's it going?
- I'm good, good, it's good to see ya.
- I like the shirt,
you're wearing colors now.
- Yeah, I'm trying to light up my life.
- Yeah, they look good on you.
- Go, go, go, go, go, go.
- Hey.
- Hey Emery.
- [Paul] This is Nick, Emery.
- Hey Nick.
- How's it going?
I actually know you from
your work on Instagram.
- Oh cool.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah,
you're such a brilliant photographer.
- Thanks man.
- Yeah.
I'd love to set up a
shoot one of the days.
- [Emery] Yeah, I'm here for the week so.
- [Nick] Cool.
If I can afford ya.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What are you guys doing?
- I'm forcing him to
shoot a self tape for me.
- Oh fun, actor, yeah.
(all laughing)
I'm just out here so you
guys can go and do that.
- [Paul] We should just be five minutes.
- Okay, cool.
- Cool, cool.
Let's go bud.
(cellphone ringing)
- Hey.
- I have this problem.
I, presets, I lost them.
I didn't back them up and then.
- Oh shit.
- Yeah.
- That's okay.
- And you had it,
you dealt with this before.
- [Emery] You're talking
about your Lightroom catalog.
- My Lightroom catalog.
- [Emery] Yeah, 'Cause that
happened to me like last year.
- I know, and I remember, I was just like,
don't know if I should call.
I don't know who to call, I mean.
- [Emery] Yeah, well did
you call tech support?
- Yeah, no.
- Okay, so call tech support.
'Cause they'll just walk you through it,
they like take over your
computer and then I don't know,
walk you through stuff,
but they'll probably find
it, I'm sure it's fine.
- Yeah, okay.
- [Emery] No, no, no, it's good, yeah.
It's totally gonna be fine.
It happened to me and I lost all my shit
'cause I don't back stuff up,
but you're really good
at backing stuff up, so.
- Yeah, it's just one of those things,
where you're just stupid.
- [Emery] It's totally good.
Okay, so call tech support,
let me know it happens,
but you should be fine.
- Alright cool.
Alright, I'll let you know how it goes.
- Okay.
- Alright bye.
- Bye.
- Am I supposed to read
both Griff and Michael?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Do you want different voices or?
- No, same voice.
Just roll with it, you know.
- Alrighty, let's do one.
Whoa, this place is.
- Oh shit, fuck, I forgot to the slate.
- What's a?
- Just keep rolling, I just
gotta like say my name and stuff
and then just keep rolling.
My name's Nicholas Rizzoli,
I live in Los Angeles.
Nicholas Rizzoli, Nicholas
Rizzoli, I live in Los Angeles.
Nicholas Rizzoli, Los Angeles.
I'm reading for the role of Johnny.
- Are we going?
- Yeah.
- Whoa, this place is crazy tonight.
Hey, check it out, that's the
guy I was telling you about.
Wow, look at his body,
I need a new trainer.
- Hey there buddy, didn't
think you'd actually come back.
- Johnny, this is Michael,
Michael, this is Johnny.
Don't spend it all in one place.
What do I get for a hundred?
- Depends.
- On?
- Where you put it.
All right scene, great.
That was great.
That's great, yeah.
- Wanna do anymore?
- No, it's just
for a guest spot, you can stop rolling.
I mean, unless you want to do another one,
but I think we nailed it.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, good job bud.
- Thanks bud.
- It's your phone.
- Let's see how this looks.
- Alrighty.
- That wasn't so painful.
- Not, it was not at all.
- I think it was kind
of fun, I don't know.
- And I don't need this either.
- What?
- I don't need this either.
- Oh.
You printed it.
- Bye Nick.
She's gonna want that back.
- Oh yeah, I'm going to go Joshua Tree,
I'm house sitting for a while,
but I'll bring it by in like a month, so.
- [Paul] Sure.
All right, bud, I'll see ya.
- Thanks for the help.
- You got it.
What's going on?
- Ooh, those look good.
- Yup.
- Can I have one,
do you mind, or two maybe.
- Of course, that's why I'm making 'em.
- Oh, nice, thank you.
- Oh yeah.
- What you got going on today?
- Today, I am going to hang
out with my buddy James,
a little later.
Tonight, a friend from
work is having people over.
- Oh cool.
- Yeah.
- [Emery] That's awesome.
- You're more than welcome
to come if you want.
- I can't come tonight, I'm so sorry,
I have a photo shoot
and then we're supposed
to hang out later, so.
- Okay yeah, that's cool
- Thank you,
that's so awesome.
- No, no.
- No, like I need friends here.
I don't have any, so.
- Can I tag along and see your photo shoot
and see how you do your thing?
- Sure.
Look at those claws.
- Look at him go.
- He loves you.
- He's got these,
like crystal blue eyes, Kev.
I'm just saying sometimes
when you're looking at him,
you kinda forget the words and he knows,
he's got it it like that.
- He knows.
- He's got it like that.
- Hey, what's going on?
I'm Paul.
- Paul, Brando.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too man.
- Okay, so Paul's gonna be my shadow today
during our shoot, is that okay with you?
- Rock and roll.
- Yeah.
- Cool.
- Okay, let's do it.
Yeah, it's good, it's good.
Wait, be more over the railing this way.
- Over the railing, like this?
- Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
No, no, no, actually down, down,
yeah, that feels good.
That's nice.
This is good.
- Yeah is it?
- Hey, Emery, I think I'm gonna, James is,
I'm suppose to meet him
in like a little bit.
- Oh yeah, yeah, yeah.
- So, it's cool if I go?
- [Emery] Yes, oh my
God, yeah, I know, sorry,
it's not like super exciting, but.
- No it was awesome, I
really liked, you know.
- [Brando] You're not
being paid for today,
just letting you know.
- Okay, yeah, no, I'm
not getting money for it.
You're great at this.
- Have so much fun with James.
- I will.
- And the party tonight.
I'm sorry, I can't make it.
- Yeah, let me know.
- I know, okay.
- If you can make it.
Nice meeting you.
- Bye.
- See ya.
- That was fun.
- He's great.
- Yeah, he's a good guy.
How do you know him?
- He's my roommate for like a week.
(upbeat music)
- Hey James.
- What's up?
- How are you?
- Good.
- Good to see ya.
So last time I talked to
you, was last Saturday.
- Yeah.
- Did the book deal go through?
- Yes.
- It did.
- There you go.
- I'm so happy.
- That's incredible.
- Thank God.
Now I just have to write the damn thing.
Easy part, right, we'll see.
Yeah, writing the whole thing is easy.
- Easy, when you're
not worried about rent.
I still feel, it's been five months
and I still feel like
I'm paying double rent
after Sam moved out.
- Well, yeah, when you
break up with somebody,
that you were living with,
you're gonna have double the rent,
you had.
- All of a sudden,
your like heartbroken and poor.
It's like great, love this.
I just can't get used to like just.
- Living on your own.
- Every freaking month.
But it's fine.
So you've been dog sitting.
- Yep.
- A girl moved in.
- She didn't move in,
she's just staying with us right now.
Maggie's in New York right
now, so that's why she's here.
- Oh, gotcha.
- Yeah.
- Is she cool or annoying?
- She's really cool.
She's a photographer.
- Artsy.
- Yeah, exactly.
And yeah, we had a fun night,
we were playing games and eating pasta
and we just kinda, we caught up,
we got to know each other
really well and it was cool.
- Cool.
- Yeah.
Like we talked about stuff that like,
like it was a lot of like,
really interesting conversation.
It was a deeper night than
I've ever kind of really.
- Deeper?
- We just had conversations
that I just didn't expect
to have with somebody that
I just met, but it was cool.
- [James] Is this like a thing?
- It's not a thing, it's not a thing.
- [James] It feels like a thing.
I thought you were gonna be like,
"Yeah, she leaves her dishes in the sink
"and she got in late last night."
And you're like describing
her personality.
- [Paul] No, we're becoming
friends, that's it.
- She's sleeping like
10 feet away from you.
- [Paul] She's sleeping in another room.
- 10 feet away from you.
(water splashing)
I'm excited to go to this party tonight.
- It's gonna be fun.
Lewis' place is always a good time.
- I'm like I'm like ready
to meet new people again, finally.
I feel like I've like reached that point
where after a breakup,
you like start to forget
how bad relationships are
and you con yourself into be
open to another one starting.
- Yeah, you're ready for
that next disaster to start.
- Right, I feel like I'm there.
(James laughing)
- Yeah, me too.
(cellphone pinging)
- Paul, I think I can
come to the party tonight,
so I'll see you later.
And also is it cool if Brando comes?
- Just say it really fast.
- San Luis Obispo.
- Yeah, I know where that is.
Up in the San Luis Obispo
area, we went to this winery.
(all laughing)
- San Luis Obispo.
- No, no, it's not the nice one.
It's St. Luis Obispo.
- St. Luis Obispo.
- St. Luis Obispo
Okay.
- Oh, it's a little tight.
- Little tight.
Sorry, it's how we like it.
- Yeah, it's great.
- You need to get your car washed.
- [Emery] Yeah, he's got it.
(upbeat music)
- Whoa.
- Thank you, heck yeah.
- Wait, wait, she's practicing,
she's allowed to practice?
- No.
- Okay, she's got it.
She's got it, we're so good.
- [Brando] All right, one, two, three.
- Go, go.
- Come one Brando,
come on Brando, you got it.
- Okay.
Do it, you got it.
(Noelle shouting)
- Go, go, go, go.
- Get it, get it.
- [Lewis] Come one.
(all laughing)
- It really is.
- It's just fun.
- No it really is,
'cause everyone gets mean
and then I feel like I
wasn't athletic enough
and then it's a whole freaking thing.
- Hey, hey, that was great.
- I need a second.
- My mom was always like stealing
stones from neighborhoods,
like my whole life, is
just, she's always like,
"Look at this rock I got."
- Oh no, my mom stole stones too.
But from like the Grand Canyon.
- Okay, that's better.
(Emery laughing)
- Hey, little tip, start
shaving the back of your neck,
girls don't like that shit.
- Okay.
- I know you're Greek and proud of it,
but you look fucking stupid.
- All right, thank you for.
- I do love you.
- We had donkeys and
goats and horses and fish
and we had a pet skunk.
- He's growing up with pet skunks.
- High school, yeah, okay.
- I feel like
when I was in high school,
when I first got boobs,
I felt like such shame, having boobs.
- Yes, shame.
Fuck man.
- But you shouldn't feel.
I don't know.
- No, I know, I know.
It's like, you look great
right now, it's totally good.
- You want to shave it right now?
- No.
- Let me shave your beard.
- No, no.
- I have a straight razor,
I've never used it.
- No.
- Let me shave your beard, dude.
- I'm gonna shave it when I go home.
- No, I'll shave it right now.
- No, I don't want you to shaving my face
when you've been drinking.
- It's not like driving.
- I know,
but it's just my face and I don't think.
(Paul burping)
Excuse me.
- So we go out there and I remember,
I'm in like cutoff shorts and my dad and I
are trying to round up
these little skunks,
we're picking them up by their tail.
And when a baby skunk is like fresh,
they just have no control
over their sprayer.
So we're getting sprayed in the face,
mist is happening, we drop them in a box
and then my sister comes
out, spoiled little brat.
Oh, got a little skunk hair on me, huh?
- Sorry, I'm with you.
- Okay.
- But okay, just to
like circle back though,
I'm right, the fire was
the first human invention.
- Okay, yeah.
- I'm just like, yeah.
- We should know that.
- There was definitely like a fucking,
like, everyone's always like,
yeah, "The man who made fire."
But it was definitely a
woman don't you think?
I think so too.
- Yeah, a woman discovered that shit.
- For sure.
- The guy was out being like.
- Yeah, fucking lazy or whatever.
- Kill something.
- Yeah, aggressive,
aggressive or lazy that feels correct.
- And she was like,
hold on a sec, hold on,
I'm gonna make fire.
- Yeah, yeah.
(Emery laughing)
- Should we get more liquor?
I feel like we're
running out of what beer,
fast.
- Yes, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, let's do it.
Let's just go to the bodega.
- Leave the fire, fuck it.
- Yeah, yeah, fuck it, it's fine.
It's totally good, everybody's here.
- What are you doing?
Why are you in the city?
Go away, you have a family now.
- They pay you rent.
- Yeah, so.
Get outta here, get outta here.
They call me, they always want stuff.
- That's, I mean.
- Like this one tenant keeps
complaining about his heater.
- It's cold.
- It's fucking Southern
California, it's not cold.
- I mean, just fix the
heat, it's your job.
- Go somewhere warm if you wanna be warm.
If you want to be cold,
go somewhere, go to Minnesota.
- They don't want to be cold.
- Why do they have to call me,
call your mom or something.
- They're calling you because you're.
- For warmth.
- Trying to spray him, you
know, give them a little scare.
It thought it was like running the house,
and then it would jump up on the couch
and it would lay on its back
and look into your eyes.
- And that's when you knew you were gay.
- When I knew I was what?
- Gay.
- Oh gay.
(James laughing)
(basin water running)
(music plays)
(Brando laughing)
(cellphone ringing)
- [Emery] Hi, you've reached.
(car engines revving)
(crickets chirping)
(car engine revving)
- [Commentator] 107 yards and a touchdown.
Once again from the gun, fake,
Mahomes at side on
delivered, as Sammy Watkins.
Ball pops free at the
end, Ravens came sliding.
- Hey.
- Hey, what's happening?
- Nothing, you?
- Nada.
- [Commentator] Back at the 49.
Wide receiver set
but they'll run Ingram on the outside.
Busting through, Ingram
stumbles across the 40.
[Commentator] Third and five,
Jackson, over the middle,
Jackson connects Mark Andrews.
Third and 10, Baltimore will go empty.
[Commentator] Jackson.
- What you watching?
- [Paul] Some sports highlights.
- [Commentator] Keeps the play alive.
[Commentator] Jackson
stumbles across the 10.
- Sure, thank you.
- Okay.
You good?
- I'm good.
- Are you mad at me?
- No, not mad at all,
I just, tried to call you.
- I know, my phone died.
- No, no, it's cool.
- I'm so sorry.
- I just didn't know where you went,
I was like, I'm gonna head out.
- No, Noelle and I went to go grab beer
and then we got sidetracked,
we just like walked our blocks and sorry.
- [Paul] No, no, hey, it doesn't matter.
- No, no, sorry.
- That's cool.
- No, it's nice that you're
like keeping tabs on me, dad.
- I'm not your dad, no.
- You're not my dad, that's true.
No, but seriously, I'm
sorry, that was rude of me,
I should've, sorry.
Wanna cheers it out.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Cheers.
So you wanna like, you wanna talk?
- Talk?
- I don't wanna
like interrupt your thing, I just like.
- No, no, we can.
- You're not mad right?
- No, I'm not mad at you.
- Okay, sorry.
- We already cheersed.
- I know, okay.
- All right.
Okay, I have questions
that I like to ask people.
- Okay.
- You ready?
- Sure.
- Okay, my favorite
question to ask people is,
what is your favorite, your
personal favorite compliment,
you've ever received to your face?
Okay, it's a two part question.
- Do I need to write it down?
- No, no, no, it's gonna be good.
Okay, what is your personal
favorite compliment
that you've ever received to your face
and also behind your back?
Meaning like you heard
it through the grape vine
that somebody said something
really nice about you.
- To my face, the nicest
thing someone said about me?
- Yeah.
No, not the nicest, like your
personal favorite compliment?
- The nicest thing someone said about me?
To my face, that I was thoughtful.
- Well, that's nice.
That's nice.
- Yeah.
- Behind my back.
That's a tough one.
- Okay, yeah.
I'll tell you mine so that
it'll like spark something, right.
- Yeah, that'll help.
- Okay, okay.
'Cause I don't know my
actual to my face compliment,
but my behind my back compliment is that,
two of my friends were talking
about me on the phone once,
I heard it, because one
of my friends told me,
and they were like,
"I wonder what Emery is doing right now."
And they both were like, this
is how they said it went,
they both got like
really quiet for a second
and then at the same time were like,
I bet she's doing whatever she wants.
And I was like, fuck, that's such a good,
that's my favorite thing that
anyone's ever said about me.
I am like, put that on
my tombstone, you know,
"Here lies Emery, died
doing whatever she wanted."
- No one has ever said
that cool thing about me.
That's for sure.
Never.
- That's okay.
- Like I was gonna say like
that I'm a good boyfriend.
That's pathetic.
That's puts it to shame compared to yours.
- [Emery] It's great
to be a good boyfriend.
- God, "Here lies Emery, just fucking
"enjoyed the shit out of her life.
"And then Paul, he was an okay guy."
- [Emery] I heard that you
were a great boyfriend.
- Yeah, "I heard you
were a great boyfriend,
"too bad you died from a
self-inflicted gunshot wound."
Just kidding, just kidding.
- Whoa.
- I know, God sorry.
- That got real dark, real fast.
- Sorry, are you hungry?
- Yes.
- Wait, do we have it?
- [Emery] I just assumed you
said, "No, we don't have it."
But I said son of a bitch
at the same time you said something.
- No, we don't have it.
- Son of a bitch.
Yeah, we didn't go grocery shopping.
- [Paul] Have you ever had cold pizza?
- You're just, fuck it like,
"Yeah, eat some cold pizza
"cause I don't wanna cook this shit up."
- Right, I don't.
- No, that's good, that's
good, it's fine, it's late.
Cold pizza is actually,
it's Chinese food and pizza,
the two things that are
just maybe better cold
than they are not cold.
Okay, you ask a question now.
- Okay, my question.
Are you a virgin?
- Am I a virgin?
If I said yes, would you believe me?
- I'd be worried, but I would believe you
because you're honest.
- I'm like clocking if
that was a compliment.
Wait, that took me a second.
- It's a compliment.
- It is?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Yes, no, no I'm not a virgin,
I'm 33, what the fuck?
- Good.
- Are you a virgin?
- No, but my virginity
story, like, I mean.
- Okay, well now you have to tell.
- Okay, I was working a summer job
at Eagle's Nest Country Club,
I was working the snack bar,
and there was a really
pretty girl, Jordy Bollinger.
- Wow, what a name.
- Right, she was a swim
instructor at the pool.
- Whoa, sexy.
- Yeah.
- Really hot.
- It was a 4th of July party
and we were having a lot of fun
and yeah, we, you know, had sex
for about like 10 minutes or so I think.
- What?
Oh my, okay, sorry, I'm
listening, I'm listening.
- It's okay.
Then I went home and I was
like smiling in my bed.
Like, you know, like, oh
it happened or whatever.
And then like the next day I went to work
and all my buddies from work
are laughing when I walk in
and I found out that she had sex
with a guy right after I left.
- What?
- Yeah.
- Oh man.
Wait so she had sex with you at a party
and then you left and she
had sex with another guy.
- Yeah, it's nice when you repeat it too,
it makes me feel really good about it.
- Sorry dude, oh my God.
- It's okay.
- I'm just making sure I
have the facts straight.
- No, it's good, I mean, like
it's probably where it
all started with like,
not like feeling like
I'm enough, you know.
- Oh shit, shit, yeah, sorry.
- [Paul] It's okay, these things happen.
- No, that's real.
- Yeah.
Did you lose your virginity
to a guy or a girl?
- Whoa, blunt.
I'm just kidding, I'm an open book.
- Sorry.
- It's fine.
I had sex with a guy first,
only one guy ever my entire
like twenties, early thirties,
and then I met Kace and
he was the only other guy.
Okay, so I had sex when I was in college.
- Okay.
- So not so young, yeah.
- [Paul] Probably a bit smarter to wait.
- Well, I had sex with this guy
and then after that I had
just had sex with women
for like the next decade.
- Wow.
- Yeah.
I told him that actually,
and he was like, "Fuck, was it me?"
- I would think that too.
- You would think.
You would think like,
"Shit, I really fucked it."
- I fucked it up.
- [Emery] God, that's so self absorbed.
- It's okay, I know, men.
- Selfish.
- I know.
- Yeah, how dare you take
away my queerness, you know.
You ever had sex with a guy?
- I have not, no.
- You ever make out with a guy?
- No, that's not been on my.
- Just a little butt stuff.
- No butt stuff, I mean.
I have to think, am I?
- No.
No butt stuff.
- No butt stuff.
Not yet, but.
- Oh, I like that you're
open to it though.
- Yeah, not really.
(both laughing)
- I get excited when
men are like, you know,
open to stuff.
- I'm in to butt stuff then,
yeah, for sure.
- Shut the fuck up.
- Yeah, I'm definitely into butt stuff.
- Yeah, let's let's do
butt stuff right now.
- Okay, don't make it weird.
- Sorry.
(both laughing)
(sizzling)
- Oh, okay yeah.
Cool.
- Morning.
Night shoots are killing me.
And there's this one sound guy,
he's like a little too handsy, you know.
It's like, read the year.
So, just an idea and no pressure,
but you should take Emery to the beach,
she loves the beach,
it'll be good for you.
The ocean's like really, you
know, cleansing and stuff.
Okay.
Love you, bye.
- She's doing good.
- Bye.
You think that security
camera outside actually works?
- No.
She put it up there as a fake.
- Oh my God.
I kinda wish it worked,
I was out there like picking my nose
and like look up, it's like
this red thing beeping at me.
- You wanna know like who's watching that?
- Is this for me?
- That's for you, yeah.
- Thank you.
Good, nice.
- Believe it or not,
no salt or pepper.
- Yeah, believe it.
It's good though.
Better than your pasta.
(Emery laughing)
No, no, it's good, it's good.
- Cool.
I was thinking, you wanna
go to the beach today?
- Yeah, yeah, I have some work to do,
but then I would love to.
- Okay.
- Is that what you're
gonna wear to the beach.
No, I'm not, I'm not like.
- I was thinking about it.
- I'm just thinking that
if we go to the beach,
I'll bring my camera,
and if I bring my camera
and you're the only person
I'm with at the beach,
you're probably gonna end up in photos.
- You're gonna take pictures of me today.
- [Emery] Yeah, yeah.
(music plays)
- Yeah, that's it.
- I think the last photo I took was with.
- Don't talk while I'm taking photos
your mouth is gonna be moving all over.
- I've never taken pictures.
- No, no, no, it's okay,
just try it one more time,
just no talking.
- Sorry, I'm trying to figure
out how to do like the whole.
- Oh my God, you're still
talking while I'm taking shots.
- I'm sorry.
- Just stop.
No, no, no, it's fine.
- Okay, all right, okay.
- It's fucking good.
- Am I knocking it out of the park?
- Yeah, yeah.
- Here we go.
- Okay, once more other hand.
- Okay, two hands?
- [Emery] Yeah, I fucking love surfing.
- Me too, I freaking.
- Yeah, you surf?
- Not at all.
- I don't surf either.
- [Paul] I want to,
but I've just never have
had the balls to do it.
- Dude, we should take a surfing lesson.
- You tell me the day and
I'm there in a heartbeat.
- Really?
- Yes, I want to do it.
I'm waiting for somebody to do it with me
so that I can actually
drive down the PCH to do it.
- I think surfing is one of those things
that I feel like I would be really good at
and then it'll be really
hard and I might suck.
- [Paul] I feel like I would be terrible.
- See that's good, you
set the bar really low.
I should have that perspective
where I'm like, I'm
going to go in sucking,
and then if I do anything other than suck,
I'll feel really great about myself.
- Yeah, I'm afraid I'm gonna fail,
so I never do it at all.
(Emery laughing)
- We both just said the same thing,
I just said suck and he said fail.
- Yeah, but.
- We both have the same fear.
- But you would actually do it.
Me, I'm like chicken shit,
I'm like, I'm not gonna do it.
- Yeah, well you're doing it with me,
'cause we're gonna take a lesson.
- All right, fine.
- Oh, pinky swearing.
- [Paul] Now, we're
gonna do this then we go.
- No.
Now you spit.
- Wacha!
- What?
- [Paul] What, do you spit?
- What do you, wacha?
Okay, no, do it again, pinky swear.
- Wacha!
- I'm not gonna say that.
- Okay, deal.
- Okay.
Wacha.
- Now you said it, there you go.
"I'm not gonna say it,
"there's no way I'm gonna say it."
And then you say it.
- What the fuck?
- What the fuck is that?
- [Emery] That is a family of Segways.
- Jesus Christ.
(Emery laughing)
When a family does that, that's like,
"Hey, we're a bunch of
nerds, we're the nerds."
You know what I mean?
- [Emery] Are they nerds
or are they the coolest.
- They might be the coolest in the world.
- Among us.
- You're right.
(Emery laughing)
- [Emery] I don't know, I mean, maybe.
- I mean, you're really cool.
- I am cool.
- You're the coolest.
- No, no, you're cool.
- No, you're cool.
- No, no.
Let's not do that.
- Okay.
But you know, you're cool, right?
- Yeah.
- You are the definition of cool.
You take pictures, you charge
people millions of dollars
and you live on a couch.
That's pretty cool.
What is that?
I'm gonna have glitter now.
You're gonna ruin the
shoot, are you kidding me?
(Emery laughing)
Everyone's gonna think
I'm a fairy godmother.
- [Emery] Well now you're cool too.
- Now I'm cool.
- [Emery] It's just the
glitter that makes me cool.
I take it off and I'm just a fucking nerd.
- No it's still on and you look,
even when it's off, I'm sure you're cool.
(cellphone ringing)
Is your phone ringing?
- Shit, hang on.
- What do you got?
- It's Noelle.
- [Paul] I don't even have her number yet.
- Noelle Party, is her and my phone.
- Noelle Coworker.
(Emery laughing)
- [Noelle] Hey.
- [Emery] What the fuck is she eating?
- [Noelle] Last night was so much fun.
I'm wondering if you guys wanna hang out.
- She wants to hang
out, you wanna hang out?
- [Paul] Yeah, let's hang out.
- Cool, do you know where she lives?
- I don't know where she
lives, I don't have her number,
I have no idea.
- Okay cool.
What's your address?
(birds chirping)
(gentle upbeat music)
- Hey, yo.
- Hey.
- [Paul] There she is.
- Hello friends.
- In overalls.
- I know, I'm like a little farmer girl.
- Yeah.
- Right, looking good.
- How's it going, guys?
- Hey.
- Okay, are you ready?
Let's hit the road.
- Okay.
You gotta watch out for that guy.
- Let's go.
- How was your day?
- Good.
- You didn't work today?
- I had work today.
- Oh you did?
- No, I did.
- Oh, okay.
- [Emery] Oh yeah, you guys work together.
- It's sad without Paul there.
- [Paul] I know.
- [Emery] Can't be that sad.
- Yeah, it really can not be that sad.
It's your third day, you kidding me?
You're freaking expert now.
- Are you?
- Yeah.
(Emery laughing)
- [Emery] Okay.
- [Paul] Did you pick today or did you?
- I did a little, I feel
like we were super slow.
So I did a lot of like Mark was,
I did more picking than
I thought I was going to.
- [Paul] Okay.
- What are you talking about?
- Okay, and we're in.
- Okay.
- It's your local liquor.
- Local liquor.
- Oh, I forgot my wallet.
- I got some cash.
- You do.
- We got ya.
- Okay amazing.
- My treat.
- [Paul] We work at the
warehouse, we're good.
- [Emery] Whatever, I can Venmo you guys.
- [Noel] We're gonna spoil you.
- Okay.
- Oh.
- Here we go.
- Hi.
- Hey guys.
- Cuties.
- Hello.
- Met these guys yet?
- Theo, Ripley and Barkley's coming up.
- Hi.
- Oh my God, I love them.
- They're big fans.
Before I put the food out,
I'll put them away.
- Okay.
- 'Cause I don't want
them eating anything.
Come here, come here.
- [Noelle] Are you guys
gonna jump on the table.
- [Emery] Yes.
- Oh my God.
- Hey guys.
No fighting, no fighting.
Come on, come on.
Treat, treat.
Come on, treat.
Treat, treat, treat, treat, treat.
- Barkley's like, I don't.
He doesn't trust it.
Here, I got him, I got him.
- He's like, "I wanna
stay with the women."
I love video games.
I feel like I'm not good at the ones
that go like this though.
Like the ones where you
have to like move your head.
There's like two controllers.
Here we go.
And here we go.
- There is.
- This is what I'm talking about.
My head has to move first,
my gun second.
Bam, gotcha.
(virtual gun firing)
Double bam.
Flaming trash cans.
- Oh my God.
You're good at this.
- Am I good?
Or is this the beginner round?
Some zombies are gonna
start shooting at me
while I have to get this.
But then at that point I
won't be able to manage
'cause my neck will have to move,
before I started running.
(all laughing)
I feel like no one knows
what I'm talking about.
- No, I can see the quick jolts
that you're talking about.
- Neck move, neck move.
(Emery laughing)
Do you have any games
that are just one button?
Are you gonna get that yellow thing?
No.
- No.
Out of the way.
- Just the pink things,
are you going for?
- Oh my God.
- Well, I think they're called moons.
- Definitely not a moon.
- Yes it is.
- No, those are asteroids.
- No, those are moons.
- Definitely asteroids.
Do you know what the
definition of a moon is?
- The thing that comes out at night.
What?
Isn't that what it is?
- Wait, give me your actual definition
of what you think a moon is.
(all laughing)
- [Paul] The thing that
comes out at night.
- [Noelle] The thing
that comes out at night.
- Yeah.
- No, it's always there.
- [Paul] Look in the
dictionary, that's what it says.
- It's always there, actually.
- I thought you're going to be more hippy
and be like the thing that like
makes women get their periods.
- The thing that everyone's
horoscope is all about, right?
- That's just like planets.
- Yeah.
- No, it's just.
- Each time he says
his own definition of a moon.
It's as far away as possible.
(Emery laughing)
- [Paul] Is it?
- Noelle and I are on the same page,
I don't know where you at?
- Okay, well you guys are on page 67
and I'm already going
towards the end of the book.
- Honestly, okay, we
gotta watch the movie,
I seriously can't play this game anymore.
- This is a game from the '80s.
- [Paul] Yeah.
- This is one of those things where,
I used to play this game on
my computer all the time.
That an Oregon Trail.
- I gotta check on the dogs,
think they need to pee.
Hey guys, how we doing?
You good?
Okay.
(sniffs) Oh.
All right guys.
- Oh my God, I'm so tired.
- Yeah.
- It's like that time of night
where you're like, oh no, I
have to like do the thing,
or I have to call an Uber and
like go outside in the cold
and wait to go home.
- [Emery] You can crash here.
Yeah, totally.
I have like the smallest bed in the world.
It's literally like a futon,
that's like this small,
like ideally I had Paul's
bed, he's got a king size,
but you're welcome to crash.
- I feel like that seems intense.
I'm like, hey, I met you yesterday.
- No, no, it's fine.
- Can I sleep in your
extremely small futon?
- It's fine.
How many piercings do you have?
- Just two, two in each ear.
- Two on either side?
- Yeah.
- That's it.
- It's not really impressive.
- No, no, it's great.
I got my nose and my ears.
I used to want to have my whole, like.
- Not interested.
You didn't want it in?
- No, I just like never
got around to doing it.
- You should get a second
one, it's really fun,
you can put like two
different earrings in it.
Where'd you get this glitter?
I've never seen glitter like this.
- Oh yeah.
- It's like chunky.
- I know.
- I love it.
- It's okay.
- I had a dream.
- Wow.
- I know.
- That's is so dope.
(Emery laughing)
- I always like feeling if
somebody's tats or like raised.
- I know.
- 'Cause I think sometimes they get.
- You think,
not really not after it heals.
You don't have any tattoos?
- No.
- Do you ever want tattoos?
(Emery laughing)
- I'm afraid that if I get something,
I'm not good with like styling tastes,
so I feel like I'll like put something on
and be like, that is dumb.
- Well, don't put it right here.
(Emery laughing)
- [Noelle] Like a Rose.
- I mean, okay, I think,
my theory on tattoos is that
they represent a time in your life
and it doesn't have to be a
thing that you love forever,
you just can look at
it and be like, "Yeah,
"that time in my life that I had a dream
"and then it just happened."
- Come on guys, let's go, let's go.
- Oh okay.
- I know.
- [Noelle] This is real cute.
I'm gonna roll off.
Oh my God.
You know what?
I'll sleep on this part.
- Come on.
Come on guys.
Come on, come on bud.
- [Man] The main key
of all there maneuvers
is to basically stay in the
power source of the wave,
which is in the pocket where
the white water is breaking.
(gentle upbeat music)
(birds chirping)
- [Announcer] Paging Paul,
dock three, dock three, Paul.
- Okay, so I'm trying to figure out why
the order on paper doesn't
match what physically came in.
- Well, Fox Print had a duplicate order.
There's supposed to be two of them.
- There's only one here, all right.
- I know I did two.
- Yeah.
- I was like what is this?
But this first one was all
the large, Xls and 2Xls
and then the other one was like kid sizes.
- Okay.
I think this may have been Martha's order,
before she went on maternity leave.
So let me just go up
front and check her desk
and make sure it's not
just sitting up there.
- Okay, thanks Mark,
appreciate it.
- Cool, thanks.
- Hey.
- That was so fun last night.
- Yeah, it was a blast.
- Yup.
Are you gonna be weird about it?
- Nope.
Just went in and checked on the dogs
and then you guys were in the bedroom
and I had the night with the dogs.
So yeah, it wasn't weird at all.
Just.
Yeah.
- Okay.
Don't make it weird.
(machine blowing)
- I'm not making it weird.
- Okay, fine.
- Okay.
(machine blowing)
- Okay, all right.
Okay, okay, okay, all right.
- [Noelle] I feel like the Terminator.
It's so early.
- It is early.
- Yeah, all right,
come here, I wanna show you something.
- What you got?
- Wait for it, wait for it.
Watch this.
Dance with me
(upbeat music)
- Okay.
Dance with me
(upbeat music)
- [Announcer] Paging Paul to
dock three, dock three, Paul.
- We gotta go back to work.
- [Lewis] So I fired my project manager.
- Yeah.
- He didn't even care.
Did not care, no emotion whatsoever.
(cellphone ringing)
(country music plays)
- So you got everything?
- I think I have everything.
Yeah.
Hey.
Kace, Paul, Paul, Kace.
- Hey, Kace,
nice to meet you man.
- Nice to meet you.
How are you?
- Good.
- I'm so sorry, I called you
just to tell you that
we're actually heading out.
Kace had a job here in L.A.
- Right now?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- It's fine.
- Okay.
- Yeah, I promise we're not leaving
'cause you like just
walked through the door,
but yeah, okay.
- [Emery] Yeah, we're not leaving because.
- [Kace] We're just glad we caught you.
- Yeah.
- I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
I love you, thank you for letting me stay,
you're so cool.
- Of course.
Thank you, I'll see you
next time your in L.A.
- Of course, I fucking love
this city, it was amazing.
- Hey Paul, thank you so
much, man, I'll see you, okay.
Sorry, short but sweet.
- Yeah, of course.
Have a safe trip guys.
- Bye.
- [Kace] Thanks man, take care.
- [Emery] Oh, I'm sad
I missed Maggie though.
- Did you tell her?
- Yeah, yeah,
she knows, she knows.
- She'll get it.
- I know, I just.
- Why don't you
just like FaceTime her from the road?
- [Emery] That's a great idea.
- On route.
I'm just waiting for my Uber
and I guess I'm going to
completely miss Emery,
I think she leaves today.
What a bummer.
So just leave the key
out and I'll be home,
yeah, pretty soon.
Paul, thank you so much.
You deserve many nice things
and I will provide some
of them, but not all,
get your mind out of the gutter.
See you soon bud.
(lips smacking)
Bye.
- There you go, Barkley.
(upbeat music)
Bye guys.
(waves crashing)
(upbeat music)