What's that you say?
Master's been killed?
Yes.
He was attacked by a stranger
in the night.
It was awful.
Let's go.
Hey...
Ugh!
Hiyah!
Ooh!
Hoo... huh!
Hoo-ahh!
You feel no repentance
in your challenging us.
All right.
You think my leg Kung Fu
is nothing.
You now destroy
my panther fist.
Huh.
Tell me what'll be next.
I know only
your panther fist
Can do evil killing
such as I have seen.
From now on,
I will be the most feared
of all warriors.
Hiyah!
Oh!
Ugh!
I have lost,
But you still
won't be the leader.
The Shaolin Temple
Has be destroyed
by you already.
Now who will support you?
The Shaolin Temple will...
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Hmm.
Hiyah!
Dragon?
Dragon Lin?
The Grand Abbot.
He's been found dead.
He's been murdered.
Found murdered?
Come on!
But wait!
The murderer fled
and left no trace behind.
We can't avenge him.
Hmm.
Master Ma,
You know I've done
nothing wrong.
You exploited
your reputation.
You've raped
another man's woman.
How can you say
that you're not guilty?
It's not true.
I obeyed your orders.
Now you accuse me of all these
ridiculous crimes!
Heck.
Just give half
of your wealth
To our master.
Then everything
will be all right.
It's no good to you, huh?
You know I'm right,
huh?
Huh?
Damn you!
What's that?
And the same goes
for all of you bastards!
You scum!
You can still decide
whether life or wealth
Is more important.
Now, woman,
Did that dog rape you?
Speak, I said!
Huh!
Speak!
Please.
Please tell him the truth.
Tell him it wasn't me.
You're guilty.
You can't deny it now.
You're guilty,
you flea ridden dog!
You're lying!
I'm no rapist!
She cries out of fear!
Fear of you!
You are the one
that keeps raping her!
Why not admit it?
I'll never admit it!
You're the rapist!
Stop it!
Huh?
What did you just say?
We're all powers
of the Buddha.
Why the whips?
Can you show no mercy
towards your prisoner?
You crazy monk.
I look for
our Abbots murderer.
Hmm.
Well, in that case then...
You should
mind your own business.
Huh.
Ugh!
Hi...
Yah!
Ugh!
Uh, what's the matter,
You don't think I clean
the teapot there or something?
Everything's unclean
in this world.
Leave it for one instant
and it all is soiled.
Everything.
What the heck are you
talking about there, huh?
There you are.
If I were to take your heart
and filter it through here
I'd find
there were dirt in it, too.
Why are you gonna
filter my heart through there?
You tell me that one.
I don't
understand this.
Think about it.
Hey, come back.
Huh?
Oh, come in, please.
Please you're welcome.
Please come right this way.
Right this way.
I'd like a room
for a few days.
Oh, yes,
certainly, yes.
One second and I'll go
find one for you right here.
Please register, huh?
Hmm.
Huh?
Uh, so it's you.
Great Master
of Shaolin Temple.
I'm so honored
by your presence.
Right this way.
I'd like to stay
for four or five days.
Since the robbers are gone
our town is so peaceful.
We're so happy now.
Ha, ha.
Were they really
as disruptive as that?
Oh, curse the memory.
We were defenseless against them
like little goats, uh...
Before a tiger.
What do you mean?
Go on.
They abuse the name
of fighters guild to prey upon
The village folk.
In three years,
they never paid a single bill.
Oh, I felt much stress.
I couldn't sleep,
you know.
My stomach went bad.
I even went bald, too.
Well, don't worry.
I'll keep 'em away.
I heard that you went forth
and took revenge for the Abbot
And now you work
for the common folk.
You know, you can really...
Hey, I'm sort of hungry.
You got anything to eat?
Oh, right away,
back in a flash.
Ha, ha, right back.
Put the heavenly spice
under the eaves.
Even from ten miles away
He'll be lured
by its fragrance.
Hey, you!
I haven't caused you
any trouble, have I?
What's inside your bag?
No!
You can't touch that.
Quick.
Get him!
I told you.
It's none of your business.
Now you've opened up my box
and let my pet out.
You stupid idiot,
lousy twit.
Get him!
Yes, boss.
Ugh!
Hmm.
Who are you anyway?
I'm a descendent
Of the great Dragon himself.
Ugh!
From here on after,
Don't give me anymore trouble.
I gave you a last chance
Whether you choose Shaolin
or play safe with us.
What is your decision?
I have only one word.
That word is "No."
I refuse to have
anything to do with you.
You should think
in terms of survival.
I'm not afraid of death.
You were the one
Who killed the Abbot.
Ugh!
Come on, try something new.
Cut off my head.
I need...
I need one of you guys
to try it.
Just one will get $10
if he can cut off my head.
It's very easy.
Come on,
you must be able to do it.
Come on, you guys.
You're all suckers
if you're not gonna come.
Come on,
just one!
Okay, I'll do it!
Hey,
That's not fair.
I'll show you how.
Now, listen carefully.
Listen, all of you.
I don't want anybody
breaking any rules.
This is my head
That's gonna go
through those holes there.
Now, when I poke it through,
You gotta try and cut it
with that sword, all right?
Hmm.
Ooh!
Ah, hard luck.
Come on,
the next one will be luckier.
$10 for anybody
who can do it.
$10.
What's $10 to you guys?
Come on,
don't just stand there.
Can I play your game?
Hey, a man can gamble,
can he?
That's right.
But with a trick so cunning,
I simply can't resist.
Now, can I play or not?
Here's my money.
But I'm warning you,
I'm pretty good.
All right.
But, hey, let's make
the stakes even higher.
I tell you what,
I'm gonna bet all my takings
from today on this.
You son of a gun.
That's exactly
how I'd want to play the game.
Hey.
I really appreciate
your zeal.
Right, just to get
things straight,
Let's do it.
Here, all my earnings
from today
Just in case
I'm gonna lose my head.
But I won't.
He-he-he.
Don't get nervous.
Hmm.
Cheating the people
out of their money
Is a great sin.
I'll punish you
for this crime of yours.
I promise you.
Nevermore.
You're forgiven.
But I'll take my earnings.
Any objections?
No objection.
Huh?
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Put it right here.
Here you go, miss.
All cut up for you.
Here.
Please take 'em.
They're yours.
Go on.
Oh, no thank you.
Oh, miss.
Oh-ho!
Oh, I am terribly sorry, sir.
That's all right.
May Buddha bless you.
Hey Gus, hurry!
It's coming.
Ooh, whoa!
Whoa-oh-ho!
You fool!
A thousand pardons.
Oh!
I'll teach you!
Did that hurt?
Oh, sorry.
Oh!
Oh-ho!
What's...?
What's your problem?
You're my problem.
Hey, you.
Uh-huh?
Hey, you can't
walk away like that.
First, you trip me up
and hurt me.
What's wrong with you?
Don't you think
you should quit
Before you really get hurt?
For all I know,
you've separated my vertebrae.
I will.
Huh?
Oh, I'm so terribly sorry.
Please forgive us...
No!
No, no, what're you...
No, no, no!
No.
Uh, no.
You lousy no good.
You have the nerve
to show up here right now?
Sorry, boss.
I... I'll work harder
and much faster.
Harder and faster?
You better give me
compensation right now
Or I'm throwing you
clear out of here.
You got that?
Now wait a minute.
I promise I'll work
much harder.
Get out of here right now
or else...
Or else I'm gonna kill you!
Oh, oh... okay!
Okay, okay!
Now you don't
have to harm anybody.
Be careful with that thing.
I'm homeless.
Just like an orphan.
Excuse me.
Huh?
Go away.
I've got no money
for beggars.
I've lost
all my business today.
Go on.
But, sir,
I'm not here for money.
Won't you please
listen to me?
Huh, you're here as a guest?
All right.
Right this way.
We got fried rice,
boiled shrimp, salt pork buns...
You name it,
we got it.
No, listen to me.
Huh?
What do you want then?
Tell me.
Please forgive me.
I'd like to ask you something.
Huh?
Wha... what does that mean?
I have a favor to ask
of you.
Huh?
Uh, all right,
but talk fast.
And what is this favor,
huh?
I heard that the Master
of Shaolin Temple
Is staying here.
You're looking for him?
Mm-hm.
Ah-ha-ha-ha.
Mm-hmm.
He's staying here all right,
but with you dressed like that
I don't know whether
he'd really want to see you.
It's something
of an emergency.
I really do
have to see him.
You can't see him
looking like that.
You go stand in the corner
and I'll call him down here.
Okay?
Oh, thank you, sir.
Some people say evil of you
in this town.
So I've come
to give you a blessing.
Buddha bless you.
They all lie.
The gang of Wu Dong
has done this.
They want us to join them.
They've destroyed property
and they blame it all on us.
The people misunderstand.
Before you blame others,
You should look at
your own self first.
Are you also here
for trouble then?
Is that is, huh?
How can you say that?
I am here
to look for the killer
Of the Shaolin Abbot.
That is my soul mission.
Mind your own business.
Please leave us alone.
And what if I don't go?
Then what'll you do?
I can do nothing
but fight you off.
That's my only defense.
Hiyah!
Ugh!
Have I really got
No place in this world
to go to?
Must I beg for food?
I've heard your Kung Fu's
pretty good.
Who me?
What're you talking about?
Come on, don't be
such a coward.
Now, you listen.
I don't fight with anyone.
But we do.
Ugh!
Ah, so, then our
master is back.
Anyone ask for me
while I was gone?
Uh, as a matter of fact, yes.
She's right this way.
Uh... What?
How can she disappear
like that?
Who was it?
Your caller,
A very pretty girl,
oh, yes.
Not so.
A girl?
Should have been a man.
Oh, yes.
She wanted to see you,
really.
I just can't figure out
where's she's gone now.
Ha, ha.
If anyone else comes for me,
send 'em up to my room.
Yes, yes,
of course.
Of course.
Where could she have gone?
Hmm.
What a coincidence.
I thought for sure
it was him.
Many fighters of Shaolin
have surrendered.
Why are you so stubborn?
Why do you resist like this?
Tell me, huh?
Why?
Because the spirit of Shaolin
Is totally different
to your Moja.
It's only one
of self interest, you dog.
Don't you know
that all has changed now?
The strong destroy the meek.
You had best
change your school
To the name
of Wu Dong or else
You will face disaster.
You understand me?
Is that clear now?
I would rather die
than bow to your kind.
Uh, are you...
Oh, oh, oh.
Ahem.
Wha... ha, ha, ha.
Why blush?
Your visitor is here, sir.
Hello, Master.
I knew you would come.
I had a dream
That I would meet
a pretty girl.
So how are you?
What's on your mind?
Have a seat there.
My name is Pinky Poon.
It wasn't my fault.
Please forgive me.
Hmm?
Oh.
The purse.
That's all right.
You know, money should be
kept moving
From the rich to the poor.
So don't you worry about it.
Please.
So, your name is Pinky Poon?
Yes.
Hmm.
That's fine.
You know, one of
my best friends little girl
Is named Pinky.
I'd like to invite you
to share a cup of wine with me.
I'd like to make up
for my very bad behavior.
You know, we Buddhists
don't take this wine
Quite so seriously.
We call it
"Rice Colonel Tea."
But, thank you all the same.
Ah...
Hmm.
Money for the poor.
Money for the blind.
What's going on out here?
Oh, you're a beggar
and blind, too, huh?
Here,
take this and go on.
Thank you.
Hey, beggar?
Huh?
Don't you pay
protection money?
So you're dumb
And blind, too?
Where do you come from?
I've never seen you.
I'll bet you talk.
What do you want?
Say it!
Oh, it's you again.
So you need another lesson,
do you?
Okay!
Don't you fight with me.
I'm pretty tough stuff.
You're just a cheap
little mongrel.
That's all.
Hiyah!
There!
Huh.
From now on,
I think you can take over
As a beggar.
Hah!
Ha, ha!
Now relax.
Do you like this?
What earthly heaven is this?
Hell's temptation
is so sweet.
But would you call this
a sin?
Don't you touch me
like this!
I only wanted
to please you.
That's all.
Buddha,
have mercy on me.
My flesh is so weak.
Massa!
May I come in?
You man enter.
Reporting for duty.
Do you know that you are
very indeed?
What is your reason?
I had to travel 30 miles
in just two days.
I'm sorry.
I sure doubt your dedication
To the cause.
Spare me.
Have mercy on me.
Spare me, please?
Have mercy on my soul.
I don't want you around.
If you won't have me,
I'll just lay down here
all the time and die.
Damn you,
get up!
I'll...
Hold it!
I'll fix you,
you little...
Shut up!
That poor boy
has no home.
Surely you can
employ him.
Yes, yes,
certainly I will.
Buddha be blessed.
I'll have him right back.
Hey, no more monkey business,
you've got that, okay?
But of course, boss.
Come on.
Okay.
I don't want you
bullying that boy.
I won't.
You understand?
Now go about your business.
Come on.
Mm.
Now I have
20 bags right here.
Now you're gonna move them
without wasting any time.
Have you got that?
No problem.
Ugh.
How was that, huh?
Okay?
Now, you're tops,
all right.
You bet.
That was very good.
That was wonderful.
Where did you
learn that from?
Huh?
If your job
depended on it,
You'd do amazing things
as well
To keep it.
Do you want to be
my student?
It's much better
than working around here.
How about it?
He's right, you know?
This great master
could tell you a lot more
Than you know about.
Huh?
You...
Got it!
You're the girl that was
begging around restaurant
The other day.
That's right.
And can you guess
who he is?
He's the Grand Master
of Shaolin Temple.
What?
Uh, you must forgive me.
I'm really sorry.
Forget it.
Will you follow me then?
Gosh, I didn't
know about that.
Will you teach me
the Shaolin Staff Kung Fu?
Hmm, Staff Kung Fu?
Yes.
I'm told that every member
of Shaolin learns this.
Uh, you ask too much.
Forget it!
You forget that this
is a great honor.
Don't rush me!
Please, I want you
to tell me some more.
Ha.
Greedy.
You just mind that you don't
ask too much of me.
Of course not.
I know how to strike
a good bargain.
Well, what's your offer then?
How about we have
a big contest then?
And if I lose,
then you make up the rules.
Okay then,
when do we start?
How do we start?
Now that's the kind of talk
I like to hear.
Now miss, you be witness
to this big contest.
All right.
Shall we go?
You bet.
You go first.
All right.
Then let's begin.
Hmm.
It's clear who lost.
So what do you
have to say?
I got nothing to say.
I'm only a student.
That's right.
I want to leave here now.
Well, certainly.
We'll go then.
Student.
All right.
Hey, Master.
I was thinking just now.
Did you and the Abbot
ever fight?
I mean,
really hate each other?
Yes, but Master
is a man of Buddha.
He has no time
for hate.
To be his student
is really a great honor.
Did you really
like each other?
They did.
Let's rest here.
I'm tired.
Thanks.
Master,
I'm really very hungry.
Please can I have some?
Hey, if you get so tired
after carrying so little,
How can you be
my student?
What is that?
Has the sun
gotten to you?
There's a lot
of dust in the water.
You must filter it out.
Otherwise, it could be
bad for you.
If I'm gonna be
your teacher,
You're gonna
have to smarten up.
Listen, Master,
it is all our fault.
Won't you please
lift us out of our ignorance
And show us Kung Fu?
We really want to learn it.
Won't you please show us?
Not right now.
Um,
I'll teach you when we get
to Chang's Village.
Ha.
That's such a long way.
It's over a hundred miles.
By the time we get there
I'll have lost interest
In learning your style
of Kung Fu.
Ah.
Take this.
It'll keep
your mouth shut.
Ha...
Hmm.
Where you going?
Hey, have you forgotten?
She's a woman.
She's got to do it
in the bushes.
That's right.
I'll be right back.
Go on.
Hmm.
How dare you
assault that woman.
Release her at once.
Who are you?
He's the Master
of Shaolin Temple.
Shaolin Temple?
That's right.
And if you had any sense,
You'd get out of here
right now.
My name is fighter Yang.
I have walked
three whole months
To challenge this very man
to a duel today.
And now I have my chance.
Hah.
Go on, Master.
You teach that guy
a good lesson.
Hmm.
Now's your chance
to show us.
I was losing just then.
Why didn't you
come and help me?
If you'd have taught me
your Shaolin Kung Fu...
Hey...
Listen to me.
If I beat him,
then I'm your teacher, okay?
What's that?
Otherwise, consider it lost.
All right.
It's a deal.
Go ahead.
Hmm.
We've made a deal.
You're my witness.
Who are you?
Master's student.
I'm Ko Dragon.
Now get going!
Yes, Mr...
Yes, Master.
Ha, ha.
That was great.
You really beat him.
Let me dust you off.
No thanks.
Student, come here.
Right now!
Wipe the dust off me.
Hmm?
I said, wipe it off!
You should call me
"Teacher."
Hmm?
Teacher.
Ah, ha, ha.
From now on,
I'm the leader.
Hmm.
Miss Poon.
I'd like to be
your student, also.
Hmm.
I'm not so sure.
How can a woman
be so reliable?
You're really so wise.
Keep wiping!
Hey.
Hey!
Hey, I'm really tired,
you know?
And, and these...
These,
these packages here.
You wanna take a rest?
How can a student of mine
be so weak, huh?
Hey, I'm really tired.
And these things
are so heavy.
Tell me,
How can we take revenge
for the Abbot?
You need to strengthen
your body, I think.
Let's get going.
Hey, I can't have a slouch
for a student.
You know, not far from here
is my hometown.
Please,
let's take a rest there?
I'll repay you for these.
Repay me?
But we can't stop.
Now let's get moving.
Come on.
Oh, please.
Enough!
There are so many beggars.
You've been impolite
to a monk.
You should be punished.
Hmm.
Ugh!
Hmm, although
you're in disguise,
I know you're a master
of the Shaolin Temple.
Hmm.
Take it easy, miss.
You know,
if you're nice to our chief,
He'll be nice to you.
Here's the chief.
Chief.
Are you the Master
of Shaolin Temple
Who wishes to take
blood revenge
For your dead Abbot?
I am.
Please excuse me
for treating an important guest
Like you.
Release him
right now.
Obey.
Yes.
I appreciate your reception.
Charming.
I know you're here
for a purpose.
You'd best forget it
While you live and breathe
this air.
It's still not too
To give up your ambitions.
Come back
to the ways of our Buddha.
You still have a chance
not to die.
Now get out of here.
If you force me
My only way
Is to steal your evil heart.
Bring him here.
Mmm.
Now I must destroy you,
You self-righteous dog you.
Don't think
you can stop me
By killing my mortal body.
What rubbish.
Come here and lick my feet,
Then I might consider
letting you go.
Get up.
Well, lick.
Quick.
Lick it.
Take him to the prison.
Yeah.
Get up.
Uh, chief,
I came here
to tell you.
Remember I mentioned to you
about that girl?
Hmm.
Take her inside.
Yeah.
This is your room.
You work for the chief.
And you better please him.
You understand?
For the dead Abbot.
You're his murderer.
You talk nonsense.
I've done nothing.
Ugh!
Ahh!
Shh!
I've come to help you.
Don't be afraid of me.
Hey, hey, you.
Give me some water.
I'm thirsty.
What is it, hmm?
I need some water.
Nah!
What's this?
The chief asked me to bring
this fruit for you two.
Oh, thank you.
You are all
completely useless.
Are you all clear now?
Uh, yes, very clear.
Yes.
Get up.
Come here, Chiang.
Oh, oh.
I give you exactly two days
to seize this fellow.
Yes.
Do you feel better now?
Thank you very much.
If not for you,
I would've died.
Don't talk like that.
Now you mustn't
say anything anymore.
You have to rest yourself.
And you must be quiet now.
The man who saved you
will bring you some medicine
Very soon.
No!... Ahh!
Master!
Huh?
Wake up.
Hah, what?
You were having
a nightmare.
Oh.
It's you.
I have decided
to follow the dragon
In spite of all the risks
that pose a threat to my life.
That day in the rice fields.
I decided to let you win.
To lure the dragon out.
Hey, come on.
Hiyah!
Where are they?
Stop.
Hmm.
Yes.
Watch this as well.
Sir.
Chief.
Dragon has escaped.
How can you be underchief
of the Wu Dong school,
The greatest school
in the entire world?
I have lost face.
But he is wounded
and could not have run
A great distance.
I will continue to search
with my men.
Attention you.
Search every tree.
We must have him back...
Or there will be
dire consequences.
Yeah.
Master Dragon,
please come now.
Your breakfast is ready.
It'll get cold.
Thank you, Miss Poon.
You're very kind.
Don't you worry.
When the time comes
I will take revenge
for the Abbot
And our loved ones
who have died at their hands.
I stand with you,
Because I know
you will take revenge
Against the Wu Dong school.
They're devils.
I would rather die
Than leave them to commit
more of their evil ways.
Okay, let's eat now.
Come.
We found nothing, sir.
Search over there.
Yes, sir.
Hey.
Come on.
Let me do the laundry,
all right?
Are you sure about that?
I don't mind.
Come on.
Huh?
Ugh!
Thank you, Master.
Thank you very much.
You've improved.
Hmm.
Good.
In a little while,
Dragon will come for you.
This time
you will die with him.
I wanted to die
A long time ago
with my father
Who also died
by your hand.
He was killed by you
About ten years ago.
Then you are...?
I'm the daughter
of Poon Yong Hoi.
You killed him
ten years ago.
Huh?
Poon Yong Hoi?
Ugh!
Hee-Yah!
Ahh!
Ugh.
Release the woman now.
Slowly.
And don't try anything.
You'll have to lick
my feet again first.
Or do you think I can't
Humiliate you
still more?
I have knelt before you
once before...
For that
I burn with vengeance.
I will never allow myself
to do it again.
You just want my throne.
That's all.
You're very jealous,
you filthy dog.
Ugh!
Huh?
So tell me,
where do we go from here?
There's a temple
on the hill.
Let's get married.