No!
- Death
Finish is our medley
for all you out there on the
graveyard shift.
This is your old buddy
the night owl
bringin' it to ya till 5:00am.
We'll be back with a mellow
medley of more music
right after this.
# Maybe had a hard day at work
# And no one talks to me
Day 457.
Another night, another nightmare.
At least I'm alive and
out of the life.
Lord knows I'd rather die before I
turn another trick.
Anything would be better,
even this.
Ow!
Blood.
Whoa.
Top of the morning to ya.
How'd you sleep?
Not so good.
The same nightmare again?
Yeah.
It never ends.
You take him.
I already got a couple live ones.
Can I get you somethin'?
- Give me a coffee, and a
waitress over easy.
- How about some hot coffee
all over your lap?
No offense, uh, Nora.
I gotta do somethin' to
fight off the boredom.
Now you may not believe it,
but I don't make many sales this
time of the evening.
Okay, I'll bite.
What do you sell?
The product line of the 80s,
condoms, prophylactics, rubbers.
Everyone needs 'em.
Can't live without 'em.
Age, you know, safe sex.
If you've got some time, I can
arrange a personal demo,
say your place or maybe the
backseat of my car.
- Gee thanks, but I've got a
splitting headache.
There you go.
Hello.
What can I get you tonight?
- Afriendly face, a little decent
companionship maybe.
That's not on the menu.
Ah.
I know what you mean.
My name's John Henry Cox.
It's easy to remember.
I know too many Johns already.
I'll call you Henry.
I'm Nora Edwards.
It's nice to meet you, Nora.
I know this is personal
and absolutely
none of my business, but are
you by any chance
married or involved with somebody?
No.
Then sometimes you must get
as sad and lonely as I am.
Do you ever think about
leaving this?
Never looking back?
All the time.
If the right man came along,
could you do it on impulse?
I don't know.
Maybe.
If I was the right man,
would you come away with me?
Henry, you don't even know me.
There are people out there
who spend their whole lives
together, Nora,
and they don't really
know each other.
What I'm offering us both,
is a chance.
Henry, it's beautiful.
It's a family heirloom.
You're bleeding.
It's nothing, really.
Will you marry me, Nora?
Yes, Henry.
I'll marry you.
Come away with me tonight, now.
- I can't leave in the
middle of my shift.
I have clothes and my stuff.
I'll send for them.
I'll buy you new clothes.
Where are you going, honey?
This is Henry.
We're gettin' married.
- I guess some girls
have all the luck.
Congratulations!
Do you have any idea what the hell
you're getting yourself into?
- No, but I've been
waiting an eternity
for an offer this good.
Didn't you see his limo?
- Oh, the best of luck to you,
both of you!
Send me a postcard from
your honeymoon.
Where are we going?
It's a little town
about 100 miles up the interstate,
a place called Newbury.
Your car is beautiful.
By the way, what
exactly do you do?
I own my own business.
Been in the family
three generations.
My friends, this is Nora Edwards,
the woman I'm going to marry.
This is Sheriff Potter.
- Glad to meet you, and
welcome to Newbury.
- Ms. Strickland, she
runs the library.
Call me Emmaline.
So glad to meet you, my dear.
He's quite a lady killer,
you know.
- And this is Bill
Billings, president of the bank.
Nice catch, John Henry.
Are there any more
like you at home?
I don't know.
I grew up in foster homes.
I've never had a family.
Well, you do now, my dear.
- Reverend Collins. - Welcome,
Nora.
Is everything ready?
Just like you asked for.
Come this way, my dear.
We have to get you dressed.
- Dressed? - For the wedding,
of course.
Fits you like it was made for you.
It's beautiful.
- Oh yes, it belonged
to Henry's wife.
His wife?
- Didn't he tell you that
he was a widower?
Is she ready yet?
It's time.
- Dear friends, we are
assembled here tonight
to join in marriage this
man and this woman,
to love and cherish in
sickness and in health
till death do you part.
Do you, John Henry,
take Nora to be
your lawful wedded wife?
I do.
Do you, Nora, take John Henry
to be your lawful wedded husband?
Z'!
Do.
- I now pronounce you
man and wife.
To Nora and John Henry.
- Heard you got
yourself a new bride.
We just stopped by to
wish you well.
- Thank you all for coming by,
but not tonight.
Ah, come on.
Let us have a look.
Bring her out.
What's the harm?
I said not tonight.
Who was that?
Just some friends of the family.
- There are a couple
of formalities.
Just to make it legal.
There's the blood test.
Well, since I gave the
bride away myself,
we can dispense with it.
What is your full name?
Nora Mae Edwards.
Date of birth? - March 15th,
She's just the right age.
For getting married and
settling down.
We best be on our way.
- Leave the newlyweds
to their night.
I love you, Nora Cox.
- And I'm going to learn to
love you too, Henry.
You know, I generally
don't do this
on the first date.
- I know you're not
that kind of girl.
Welcome to the bridal suite.
- Henry, the
bed is so cold.
I like it a little cold.
You know I want your body.
What would you like me to do?
Lie still, be still.
I said be still.
Good morning.
I see you found something to wear.
- There is a closet full of
clothes upstairs
and they're all my size.
Did you sleep all right?
- Actually, it feels
a little weird
being up during the day.
I'm used to working the graveyard.
I mean, nights.
What time is it, anyway?
We don't have clocks here
because time doesn't matter to
my clients anymore.
Would you like to see the
rest of your domain?
Yeah.
- Through this hall is the
dining room and kitchen.
And this gallery leads
to the mortuary.
Why didn't you tell me?
- My father brought me up
in this house,
taught me this business,
and left it to me
when he passed on.
Over the years, I've come to learn
that some people have an
unnatural revulsion
to my profession, to the thought
of coming into contact
with dead flesh.
I can live with it.
But why didn't you tell me you've
been married before?
Doesn't really matter, does it?
This is where we display the
deceased for the loved ones.
Those are the parlor rooms.
And this is the preparing room,
where we get the bodies ready.
You must promise me you will never
try to go in there.
But I-
- Some doors are best
left unopened.
Some things best left alone.
After breakfast, you might want
to explore Newbury.
Maybe I'll just watch some TV.
We don't have a TV.
I've got business at the
florist and cemetery.
I'll see you when I get back.
No clocks, no TV.
What do they do around here
for entertainment?
Morley!
Oh, you startled me.
I didn't hear you come in.
Nice day, huh?
Thought I'd tale a walk around,
you know.
I think I'll go now.
It was nice talking to you.
That Morley guy sure is
a strange one.
Hey boys and girls,
it's your old buddy the night owl
covering for JJ on the
nine to noon shift
right here where the hits
just keep on comin'.
# Die young
# Yeah, yeah # Die young
# Well Jimi Hendrix he
never got old
# Took some pills in his bathrobe,
woo
# Die young
# What you waitin' for
# I gotta know, I gotta know, yeah
# Die young
# I don't care what the
critics say, no way
It's the Matthews girl.
Somebody notify her brother,
and get Reverend Collins up here.
Poor kid, I hope it was painless.
- It doesn't look to me like
she was unconscious.
Probably writhed around in there
trapped underwater,
gasping and choking
for a good minute before
she ran outta air.
That must have been hideous.
No evidence of foul play.
You know how kids drive today.
What happened?
- Terrible introduction
to Newbury, Nora.
Poor little girl just
lost her life
out there in the pond.
Can I give you a lift?
No, thanks.
Sure is a shame.
Ain't enough live ones
to go around.
- Anybody ever tell ya you got a
morbid sense of humor?
# It ain't no fake, you
know I was real
# I could tell by the way
Yep, she sure is cute.
One of the cutest dead
girls I ever saw.
# Die young
# Oh, I gotta know, yeah
# 'Cause you got to go
# Die young
# I gotta know, I gotta know,
uh-huh
# Die young
# It ain't no fake, you
know I was real
# I can tell by the way
that those feel
# And in about 10,000 years
# They'll remember through
a million tears
# Die young
# What you cryin' for
# I gotta know, I gotta know, yeah
# Die young
# It's just begun, uh huh
Yeah, I love you too, baby.
# Die a young
# I gotta know, I gotta know,
uh-huh
- What are you doing,
man?
We're in no hurry.
She's got all day.
Can I help you?
- I'm Evan Matthews,
I'm her brother.
Ah, yes.
I'm sorry, I didn't recognize you.
Since my parents died,
she was the only one I had left.
And now she's gone.
Now it's just me.
- Evan, I know how you
must feel right now
but now is the time to be strong.
Come and sit down.
- I can't
believe she's dead.
Did she have any, feel any pain?
- I was told she didn't
feel a thing.
This is my bride, Nora.
Nora, sit with him a while,
if you would.
I have some
arrangements to attend to.
We'll talk about the economics
when you feel up to it.
Well, if you're so
concerned about it,
you better go check.
# I don't wanna let you go, lady
# You brought laughter to my soul
# And now you're in control
# I don't wanna let you go
# Come and dance a
little closer to me
Doesn't she look lovely?
# Oh, that's why our love was
never meant to be
# Come on and get close to me
- Yes, beautiful,
just beautiful.
- It won't be long now,
my friends.
Just a few more little odds and
ends to attend to.
# Come on and let me see you smile
# I don't wanna let you go, lady
And then...
# You brought laughter to my soul
# And now you're in control
# I don't wanna let you go
# I wanna hold you with
my arms tonight
# We will be all right
# Hold me tighter
# I wanna kiss you in the
clear moonlight
# It will be all right
# She was an
beauty queen
# Lovely as only in a dream
# She knew just how to turn me on
# She teased me all night
# With that good old
fashioned girly charm
# I thought we'd have
another round
All right, everyone.
Stand clear.
# I crossed my arms
around her hips
# I pulled her body close
# And gently kissed
her crimson lips
# But when I tried to make my move
# I don't sleep with strangers
# I'm not that kind of girl
# Strangers are for dancing
# Not chancing, romancing
# I don't sleep with strangers
# I'm careful from the start
# I won't let a stranger
endanger my heart
# I grew impatient with her game
# I had an image you maintained
# But as I turned to walk away
# And as she drew me close
# These were the words
I heard her say
# I don't sleep with strangers
- And best of all,
she's safe.
It's safe sex now because
we can't get AIDS
from dead people.
# I don't sleep with strangers
- I think maybe the
honeymoon is over.
- I didn't
mean to wake you.
You're dressed.
Where were you?
Downstairs.
There was some work to be done
on the Matthews girl.
I thought I heard something.
- Old houses make
sounds all their own.
Were you alone?
No, Morley was with me.
Nobody else.
Unless you count the body.
I know this all seems a
little strange,
but you'll get used to it.
- I guess I must have
been dreaming.
- And nothing real is ever
quite as frightening
as it is in our dreams.
Mr. Matthews.
Call me Evan, please.
Sure.
I'm sorry about your
tragic loss Mister,
Evan. - Thank you.
Have you seen Henry?
Henry?
Are you in here?
That's odd, the door's open.
Morley said he was in there.
Well, he didn't actually say it.
He just sort of gestured.
Nora, good morning to you.
Hey everybody, this is Nora Cox,
Henry's new wife.
What can I get you, honey?
- Just coffee, thank you. -
Coming right up.
She married the undertaker?
Yep, she married the undertaker.
- Well, how do you like our
little town, Nora?
Huh?
Oh, it seems very nice, thank you.
Oh!
Oh.
I'm sorry about the mess.
I never used to be this clumsy.
How much do I owe you?
- As long as its on the house,
it's on the house.
Well, I have to go now.
Thank you.
Welcome to Newbury, Nora.
- Why don't you look where
you're goin', young lady!
Oh, Nora, it's you.
Here it is.
We call it home.
Take a seat.
How about a nice cup of
hot chocolate?
- Oh thanks, no, the caffeine
keeps me up all night.
Could I trouble you for a
glass of water?
No trouble at all.
You do seem a little jittery.
I know it's none of my business,
but,
is anything wrong between
you and your new...
Everything's fine.
It's just that I don't
really know anyone.
Well, it takes a while for folks
to get used to the local customs,
but folks is folks once you
get to know 'em.
Where are you from, anyway?
Out of state.
I used to live in New York.
That was a long time ago.
Seems like another lifetime now.
- You know, Nora, when I
get to feelin' blue
I go out and get
myself a good book,
one of them murder mysteries
or somethin' by Stephen King.
Everybody needs a good scare
once in a while,
don't you think?
I guess so.
- Why don't you wander on
up to the library
and see Ms. Strickland?
I'm sure she'd be happy to
have the company.
- Dear Donna, people around
here sure are strange.
Death and dying may be
Henry's occupation
but in this town it seems to be
everyone's preoccupation.
Hello?
Oh, good morning, Nora.
Nice of you to drop by.
A fellow book lover is
always welcome,
especially in this town.
How is that new spouse of yours?
Fine, thank you.
- Are you going to the services
for the Matthews girl?
Oh, I don't know.
I don't think so.
- Everyone's going to be there,
you know.
But that's how it is in
a small town.
Everybody knows
everybody's business.
I, myself, have been a friend of
the Matthews family
for a long time.
Used to check out the
Nancy Drew mysteries
for that poor child myself.
And what can I get for you?
- I'd just like to browse around,
if that's okay.
You go right ahead, my dear.
- Sexuality, Abnormal
Sexual Practices.
Hm, maybe this is it.
The world is full of people
with peculiar tastes in
their sexual appetites
and behaviors.
Tell me about it.
Carnal, carnival, and yes,
even carnivorous
sexual practices have
been reported.
There are even people
whose bizarre tastes
run towards sexual acts including
intercourse with the dead.
- Oh, didn't figure you for
the science type.
Everything's okay between
you and Henry?
Oh, everything's fine.
- Well, I thought you might
like some of these,
a couple of romances, a mystery,
and a Stephen King to get
your blood going.
I've already checked
them out for you
and your library card is tucked
into the first good sex scene in
that romance novel.
Thank you.
See you at the funeral.
Death is always a tragedy.
And the death of a young person,
this young person, this
beautiful wisp of a child
is especially tragic
to those of us
who knew her well.
There's nothing we can do now,
nothing we can say to
call her back,
nothing we can do to
assuage the pain,
nothing we can do now,
nothing we can say to
bring her back
from the eternal slumber in
God's special place.
But know you this,
she is going to a sweeter rest
than we shall ever know,
a rest untainted by the
pain of mortal life,
a rest so pure and sweet-
This is taking an eternity.
Shh.
Wanted her at his side.
God bless her soul.
Amen.
_ No!
Please!
Let me see her once more before...
- Now, now- - Please,
you have to!
Son, it's too late for that.
What is, is.
Be a man.
You know your sister would
want it that way.
- His hand reached slowly
and deliberately
for the milky whiteness
of her throat.
She tried to push him back,
but his fingers...
Henry?
Is that you?
Hello?
Is anyone here?
Evan, have you
been following me?
No.
Yes.
Please don't be afraid of me,
but I had to talk to you alone.
I'm sorry about your sister,
but there's really
nothing more I can do.
- Please! - Let go,
you're hurting me.
You have to hear me out.
You're the only one I
can trust now,
and if I'm right, I may be the
only one you can trust.
What do you mean?
Do you wanna come up to the house?
No.
We can't be seen together.
They suspect me already.
Please, just come with
me for a moment.
We don't have much time.
What I have to tell you
involves practices so deviant,
so bizarre,
so against nature that
if I can't prove
that what I'm saying is true,
you'll think I'm insane for
even suggesting it
because it involves your husband.
Have you seen anything strange
around the mortuary?
- I don't have any idea what
you're talking about.
No, I can't tell you,
but if you'll meet me
tonight at midnight,
I'll show you.
Be ready when I come for you.
And whatever you do, don't let him
get you near the water.
Where have you been?
Just out walking.
I was thinking about poor
Evan Matthews.
Shame.
Some people have a harder
time letting go
than others.
Do you mind if I go into town?
I'd like to speak to
Reverend Collins.
Not at all.
Morley will give you a lift.
Reverend Collins?
Nora.
What's troubling you so soon
after your wedding?
I saw something, something awful
from a secret place at
the mortuary.
At least, I think I saw it.
What was it?
What did you see?
They were doing something
to that girl's body,
something perverse.
I couldn't keep from watching.
- But are you sure of
what you've seen?
Is it possible that that
young girl's death
touched you in some way beyond
your understanding?
Did perhaps maybe you only thought
you saw something that
really didn't happen?
- Yeah, Father, I think
maybe you're right.
I don't really know what I saw.
It may have just been the shock.
Maybe I was just a little confused
and this was just a
waste of your time.
Thank you. - Nora.
Nora, wait, please.
Hello, Reverend Collins.
She did?
She is?
It must be the strain of her
new surroundings.
Yes, I know.
Thank you, Reverend Collins,
goodbye.
Ah.
This has been a trying day
for you, hasn't it?
I know just the right
thing to relax you,
a nice hot bath.
I'm in here.
I know.
I came to wash your back.
- No, please, don't
trouble yourself.
It's no trouble.
No trouble at all.
Reverend Collins was right,
you are tense.
Yeah.
Relax.
What are you trying to do to me?
I'm sorry, my foot slipped.
I almost fell in.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Evan?
It's me, it's Evan, it's okay.
Please hurry, we don't
have much time.
My car's over here.
I must be out of my mind
to be here with you in the
middle of the night.
- I promise you won't think so
after you see this.
- Harriet Anna Cox, beloved
wife of John Henry,
born 1965, died 1985.
It's his first wife's tombstone.
I knew he was widower.
- Maxine Ina Cox, beloved
wife of John Henry Cox,
born 1964, died February 18th,
- But I didn't know he was
a widower twice.
Anyway, what does that prove?
What year were you born?
1964.
- That makes you the
same age as them.
- So, maybe he likes
younger women.
- Come on, we don't
have much time.
We've gotta find my
sister's casket.
Here it is.
- You're not actually gonna
break in there, are you?
- The only way you'll
begin to believe me
is when I show you what's inside
my sister's casket.
Nora, help me!
Oh, this is grotesque!
If I don't stop, you're
gonna be staring
at your sister's corpse in
about 30 seconds.
Don't you understand?
They're grave robbers!
Grave robbers?
Empty-
I knew it!
Those bastard grave robbers
have taken her body.
What for?
They do something to the body
during the embalming.
Please believe me now.
It's the only thing that
will save you.
What do you mean, me?
Nora, listen.
The bodies they steal
don't last forever.
They always need a fresh supply.
This can't be happening.
- Henry married you
because they mean
for you to be next.
And what they'll do to your body
after you're dead is the
ultimate nightmare.
You mean they...
Oh my God!
Yes.
And Henry's not in this alone.
There are others.
I'm not sure how many.
Maybe the whole town.
I'm not sure who we can trust
except each other.
Come on.
Promise me if anything
happens to me
you'll make sure they're exposed,
and finish this.
I promise.
I don't think we're alone.
Who's there?
What do you want from us?
Run, run!
Come on.
Oh my God, they're killing him!
- Promise me if
anything happens to me
you'll make sure they're exposed,
and finish this.
Promise me, promise me,
promise me.
I promise.
- God, where the hell
have you been?
Well, thank goodness
you're all right.
I woke up, I found you gone.
I thought you'd run away.
I thought something horrible
had happened to you.
- I just went for a drive,
that's all.
Nora, wait.
Tell me what's going on.
- I went to the
graveyard with Evan.
I saw their tombstones, Henry.
I saw mine.
We opened up her casket
and there was no body.
And then I think they killed Evan.
I know what I saw.
What do you do in that room,
Henry?
What do you do with the bodies?
I'll show you.
You can see for yourself.
I thought I would spare you
from the ugly side of my life,
but you want to see- - No,
let me go!
Please, I don't wanna see anymore.
See for yourself, go ahead.
_ No!
Go ahead and see for yourself.
Stop!
In the name of love, stop.
What is the matter with you,
woman?
Can't you see that I love you?
Evan is dead!
They killed him!
And what about Morley?
I saw Evan cut his head off.
You called, madame?
She's coming around now.
Listen, Nora, they're
playing our song.
No, please don't, no!
You don't want me.
I'm not dead yet.
I'm not dead yet!
Honey?
I heard you scream.
Are you all right?
Did you have another bad dream?
- If you love me, you'll take
me to the Sheriff.
Morning, Sheriff.
Nora and I need a
moment of your time.
Well hello, Evan Matthews.
Yes, Sheriff Potter. - Evan, Evan?
Could you come by the office
on your way to town today?
You see, dear, I told you
there was nothing to worry about.
Now I understand.
You wouldn't let me speak to him
because he wasn't there.
Everything Evan told me is true.
You, Henry, Morley, Ms.
Strickland,
you've got your own little club.
You're all in this together,
aren't you?
How sick!
How twisted and perverse!
How could you?
- Little lady, I think
you've been out
in the sun a little too long.
Accusing us of doing things
with dead bodies,
sounds like somethin' out of the
National Enquirer,
only nobody'd believe ya in
a million years.
And nobody'd take the word
of a common prostitute, a New
York City streetwalker
OVGI" OUTS.
- How could you
possibly know that?
I changed my name.
I started over.
It's all in the past.
I've got a clean slate now.
How did you find that out?
- Just ran a check of
your fingerprints.
Seems you've got a rap sheet
three pages long.
You're a convicted prostitute
and you did jail time too,
didn't ya?
No, that's all in the past!
I started over, I have a new life.
There, there, Nora, Nora.
Your past is forgiven.
Your place is with us now
forever and ever.
And no one will ever miss you.
- Reverend Collins,
they're after me.
You've gotta help me.
Who's after you?
Stay back, stay away.
Let me take care of her.
Nora, Nora, wait.
Nora, wait, you're safe here.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I tell you there's nothing
to be afraid of.
For God's sake, you've
got to believe me!
- You're in on it,
aren't you?
You're part of it.
- I don't know what
you're talking about.
Please, let me help you
before it's too late.
Nora, Nora please,
don't run from me.
Nora.
Stop it!
Talk to me.
Nora.
Stop, just stop for a minute.
Nora please, just talk to me.
Nora, Nora please!
ahuds)
Let me go!
You can't help, any of you.
Please, let me in!
Never open when you need one.
Hello Operator, I need to
make a collect call.
I haven't got much time.
I'm in a town called Newbury.
It's about 100 miles north
of the interstate.
Come as quick as you can, Donna.
They're trying to kill me!
- I'm on my way.
- I'll be in a place called
Cox's Funeral Home.
Just pull up and beep.
And whatever you do, don't
talk to anybody.
Don't tell them why you're here.
Honey, are you there?
Can you hear me?
Oh, honey!
God, they're after me.
Don't let them get me.
Duck in here, honey.
We'll save you.
She's in here, everybody.
Let's get her.
There she goes! - Come on!
Come back, my dear.
There is nothing to be afraid of.
Here's your goddamn ring back.
Something to add to the
family jewels.
Nora, please let me in.
Did you meet my first wife?
Oh, God!
My second wife.
I loved her so much.
I wanted to make you mine,
but all you wanted to be was
homecoming queen.
Dad, Stamps,
I'm trying to keep the
family business alive.
Would you like to meet the
rest of my family?
Get away from me!
Get off of me!
Morley!
Stop her, after her.
Don't let her get away.
- Nora Mae Edwards Cox, this
could be your lucky day
because one of these keys
starts the engine
of this beautiful 1982
Buick Electra hearse.
0K3)'-
Come on.
Esme, meeme.
Thank God, a domestic V8.
Nora.
Nora!
- Hey kids,
it's your old buddy
the night owl back with much
more of the music
you wanna hear.
This little valentine's
in dedication
to the woman I love.
It's from Henry and goes out
to a little lady named Nora.
Nora!
- Excuse me, sir, could
you please tell me
how I can get to the
Cox Funeral Home?
- Well, little lady, I'll
tell you what you do.
- No more one-night
stands in hell!
If I ever get outta this alive,
I'm never gonna let the
sight of blood
make me sick again.
Prepare to meet your maker,
you bald headed son of a bitch!
Oh, oh, oh, oh shit!
Nora, stop it, for God sakes.
It's me!
Evan!
They said you were alive.
I thought you were dead.
- I thought-
I didn't know what to believe.
- I thought I was going to die,
too.
I don't even know how I
got in the casket.
It doesn't matter now.
Come on, let's get outta
here together.
You better let me drive.
Oh my God!
What are you doing, Evan?
Evan, speed up, run the roadblock!
Why would I want to do that?
We're not going anywhere.
You bastard!
How could you?
It's simple, really.
I always loved my sister,
always wanted her in a way
that society would never
have accepted.
But after she died, Henry let me
do everything I always
wanted to do.
And soon, it'll be your turn.
Donna, Donna thank God it's you!
Same nightmare again, hon?
Stop!
- You know, Nora, you
should've listened
to Reverend Collins.
He wasn't one of us.
He was probably the only person
who could save you, and you
killed him.
Please, let me out!
No!
I figured you were tired.
We haven't been that busy.
I just let you sleep.
Here, drink up.
Nightmares are one thing,
but real life is something else.
- Nora
Mae Edwards Cox
got off on self defense.
She's writing her memoirs
and living in Woodstock, New York.
John Henry Cox survived the
diner shooting.
He's currently keeping the
family business alive
and has recently remarried.
Jack, the condom salesman,
was his company's top
grossing sales achiever.
He was awarded a big bonus
and lost it all in the
stock market.
Ma still runs the friendliest
little cafe in Newbury,
or anyplace else.
She's currently writing a book
of her favorite secret recipes
and has already sold the
screen rights.
Emmaline Strickland fell ill
after getting a bad shock
and is resting quietly
in seclusion.
Jimmy the dishwasher quit
his job at Ma's
to become a Neopop violence
performance artist.
He currently resides in a loft in
SoHo, New York City.
Evan Matthews works part time
for the Cox Funeral Home
and is in his second semester
of mortuary school.
Sheriff Porter Potter
continues to uphold
the traditional values of Newbury.
Cicely Matthews is still dead.
Reverend Collins took a leave of
absence from his church.
He is repeating a sky
diving course
that he recently flunked
at night school.
Larry and Ed are on call
24-hours a day
just in case you need them.
As for the young gossip,
she finally met the man
of her dreams
and the rest is history.
Yep, she married the undertaker.
- The
people of Newbury
want you to know you're
always welcome anytime.
Morley Leslie did not die in the
diner shooting either.
Through a miraculous operation,
Henry brought him back to life.
He walks among us still.
# I don't sleep with strangers
# I'm not that kind of girl
# Strangers are for dancing
# Not chancing, romancing
# I don't sleep with strangers
# I'm careful from the start
# I won't let a stranger
endanger my heart
# I grew impatient with her game
# I had an image she maintained
# But as I turned to walk away
# She took me by the hand
# And asked if maybe I could stay
# And as she drew me close
# These were the words
I heard her say
# I don't sleep with strangers
# I like to take my time
# Patience is a virtue
# won't hurt you
# I don't sleep with strangers
# I guess I'm just a square
# First you have to know me
# And show me you care
# I don't sleep with strangers
# Although I like your style
# If you treat me gently
# You just might be friendly
# I don't sleep with strangers
# Although I like your smile
# Maybe we could stay here
and talk for a while
# I don't sleep with strangers
# Although I must confess
# It can be so thrilling
# When two hearts are willing
# I don't sleep with strangers
# Although I Will admit
# That there must be a first time
# And this may be it
# You are cruel and unusual to me
- This is
your old buddy
the night owl signing off.
Goodnight, kids.
# Caution is a stranger to you
# Wishful never described you
# Bravery has left me too
# Loving you has made me blue
# Sometimes you might
feel so strange
# You seem to think you
need a change
# Losing you will set me free
# I gave into indignity
# You are cruel and unusual to me