I would score that ass!
Cheers, guys.
Sit down.
You took the wrong bullet, Lisa.
Here we use larger ones.
I have never encountered
With such large and heavy balls.
Stupid bitch!
Fuck you all! Damn fools!
If that shitty transvestite ever looks at me again....
He loves you, Joey.
It makes me sick to my stomach.
Ignore them!
Steve is furious that you didn't give him on the ball.
Yes, and that you did it with his best friend.
I never wanted to date Steve.
I used it to get closer to Jamie.
And I succeeded, didn't I?
Hey, Lisa, you have a great skirt.
We came just in time.
I would like to be able to walk without panties,
But I have to wait until after the surgery.
Isn't that unfair?
Asshole!
Let's put on the shoes.
Hey, John Bon, where are you going?
Shut up!
Screw it, Steve.
I should.
You could use some real bullets, Lisa,
and I have just such a pair here!
Shut up, A. J.
You don't have to show your balls here!
Idiot.
Lisa needs a real guy.
One with experience.
Why are you an expert, Steve?
Do you think you're a great pick-up artist?
At least I'm not a faggot,
shitty transvestite!
Unless I were to look at your pussy, huh?
Was that the experience you were asking about?
Guys, why don't you explain it to him?
With pleasure!
You're right, Steve.
Take her, or him
And let him try his luck.
Come on!
We will show him!
Back off!
Fuck off!
Leave me alone!
Just take a look!
Screw you!
Take a look at this cutie!
Leave it!
Leave the fag!
Are you okay?
Why are you doing this?
It's been a long time since anyone treated me like this.
This is between you and me Steve!
One on one!
Fuck you!
Come on Jamie!
Fuck him up!
Damn!
Shut up, you fucking bitch!
You think that when you fucked
The girl I took to the ball,
then you are better than me!
What were you thinking?
Was it worth it?
Keep your mouths shut!
You've slipped, huh!
Shut up!
Bitch!
You all better get out of here,
Before I call the cops.
I let you stay longer
and this is how you repay me now!
Are you all right?
Let's get the hell out of here.
Jamie, come on, baby.
What about the game?
We have a tournament to play.
Doesn't anyone care about bowling anymore?
Forget about bowling.
I bet 100 bucks that they will not win.
How are we supposed to win when
Steve is not able to play!
We can't play, don't you understand!
He can't play in such a state!
I said something!
Get out!
You can play tomorrow, provided,
That you will behave somehow....
You will regret it! You will see it yet!
My leg!
You're the one who started it, Steve!
We wanted to play, but you ruined it!
As usual!
We will meet tomorrow.
What do you think, Steve?
Driving. Patrick and Joey
will drive you to the hospital.
I have work tomorrow morning!
Are you still distributing newspapers, AJ?
Actually, yes.
My mother saw him,
as he peeped at her through the window.
Nonsense!
I would believe him.
If I saw him at my place,
he would get a good manto.
Okay, that's enough!
What's the matter, are you all queer?
Just talking about it...
When I was young,
we only talked about pussy....
You won't see any more pussy with your eyes, old man!
It's disgusting, I don't want to hear it!
Are we done?
Okay...
That's until tomorrow...
The bet still stands.
Double the bet or none at all.
Better take your wallet with you!
And you kids, better leave
your troubles at home tomorrow....
There will be no trouble, we promise.
It would be better if...
Let's go!
Better go home now!
It's quite a mess. You need to clean up here.
I will call your mother,
that will help me, smart.
Come on, ladies!
Damn, that was a good one, Lisa!
But also stupid...
She wanted to protect you...
I can take care of myself.
Steve's foot crunched like a grape.
Have you seen it?
And so he will play, he is the best of them.
This guy is a machine.
If he had to, he'd throw his own head around.
Can I go with you?
Thanks.
Call me later, Lisa.
All will be well.
Until tomorrow!
Did you see my purse?
You must have left it inside.
There is still someone inside.
I will go with you.
No, it is not necessary.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'll be fine.
Damn!
Come on!
Another damn chewing gum....
Damn shit...
How about at the vending machines?
This is what you are looking for!
I warned you, bitch!
You will pay me now!
Come on, Steve!
And now you will give me,
What I was entitled to, bitch!
Shut up!
Put it on this machine!
Don't tear up!
Shut the fuck up, bitch!
Not bad!
Download it!
Hey, I thought we wanted to
scare her just a little bit.
She's about to get scared, but with the size of my cock!
Do something to make it shut up!
You are spoiling the whole atmosphere!
Come on, Steve!
Pat, watch out for that old guy!
You are still here!
Get the hell out of here!
I think she likes it.
Oh yes!
Come on Steve, fuck her!
Fuck her!
You like that, huh?
I have a bigger one than Jamie, huh?
Steve, you don't have to be so brutal.
You need to be more gentle.
Dirty whore!
I wouldn't have guessed it was that good!
A.J. share it?
Do you know how cool it would be?
No way, man!
I don't want to see your mouth!
Suit yourself...
Fuck you, bitch!
You will not embarrass me....
What were you thinking!
You shitty bitch!
Fucking bitch!
I will come back here.
Get out of my way!
Fuck!
Beautiful ass you have!
We will close all the holes!
Joey, now it's your turn!
It was awesome!
Let's go now...
Shut up!
You will be next!
Don't shudder, you'll be next!
Fuck you!
Shut up Patrick!
You are such a wimp!
Where to, the lazy man?
My colleague Joey will take care of you.
We're having fun.
We will have a decent time.
Where are you going, dear reader?
Hurry up, man!
Yes, Joey, show her!
Hold it, Patrick!
You're useful for something!
What are you doing?
Bring it on!
Fuck!
What!
I can't finish!
Damn!
Hey, help me out a little!
Well, do something!
That's right!
Guess who's next?
No, I don't feel like it.
What?
Don't refuse! You'll be next!
But I don't want to!
What a wimp!
They'll be closing the door in a minute!
We have to go!
We're not done yet...
Unless I say so.
Steve, but Patrick is right.
Keep it up!
We're almost done, baby.
Everything has a beginning and an end!
Get ready, slut.
Come on, Steve!
Are you the boss, Pat?
Do you want to talk about what will happen?
Okay, so you do it!
What not!
Take it and fuck her with it.
I won't do it!
You do it, or I'll fuck you!
Take off his pants!
Give it a rest already Steve.
This is messed up.
I won't.
You know I'm going to do it, cocksucker!
Do it!
Damn it!
Come on, boy!
Sorry!
Not this tip.
What?
Use a bigger tip!
Steve, stop it already!
Come on!
It's too big!
Only deep!
Fucking bitch!
Good boy!
Now you know not to mess with me!
Bitch!
Let's get out of here!
Get the hell out of here!
Kurwa....
Open the door!
Get in the car!
Open the damn door!
What are you doing?
Quick!
What's up!
Open the damn door!
What are you waiting for?
Get in!
What's the matter with you?
My leg...
Do you think it will say anything?
He won't say.
Yes, who would believe a chicken?
Me.
What.
Me!
Would you believe it?
NEXT NIGHT
Hi.
Hi, girls.
Give it to me.
Where's Lisa?
Jamie called to her.
They will be here soon.
I hope today will not be a mess.
Of course not!
They are always looking for a hook.
But if we win, they will probably
they will make a brothel again.
What "if?"
Please, Sam...
You know we will destroy them.
We are the best.
I know.
Will they bring their hookers?
Do you think so?
And are they good?
Not like ours!
Super, Ben.
I would like to be someone's whore.
Sam, I was going to ask you...
Do you pee in women's or men's restrooms?
Very funny.
I'll pee on your mouth, because I know,
That you will like it.
You are disgusting.
Hey, ready to fail?
We will destroy you idiots!
You dreamed to me today, princess!
You have great feathers!
I'm already looking forward to it,
until you take off your shirt.
Did you know that you are a moron!
Want more?
Did you see their faces?
I hate those suckers!
Enjoy your evening!
Have you ever seen such a beautiful ass?
Where are you going?
Hey, stay with us today!
You can only dream about such an ass.
You are not funny at all, grandpa!
Why don't you answer one question for us?
Do you old people get screwed at all?
I bet you see your
little one only during peeing!
Be careful what you say, boy.
I am doing you a favor,
That you can play at such a time.
Do you understand?
You say it every time, Grandpa.
There go the faggots.
And it's a big bird!
Beautiful feathers!
Would you like one, eh?
You look like a hyena.
I know they like it.
Do you know that if you want to have fun
have fun, you have to pay for it?
We don't mind.
Are these shoes clean, Egerton?
I don't want to catch anything...
That's right, Edgerton!
Do you go to a private school?
Out!
I'm a size six.
And I'm a size eleven.
Twelve?
Then which one should I take?
Where is Jamie?
Take these, Einstein.
He should already be here.
And if Steve comes first?
That won't be a problem at all.
If anything... I have my secret weapon.
Where did you get this?
From Mexico.
I smuggled it in my luggage.
You better be careful with that, Sam,
or someone will stick it up your ass.
I don't even know how to use it.
Let's hope you never find out.
Fuck, my leg!
He brought his hookers.
Let me!
Let me go, bitches!
I can't walk!
I parked my car in a handicapped spot
Handicapped spot, they better not tow it away from me!
If you have the right credentials,
you don't risk anything.
But you are taking a risk. If something happens to him,
those bullets will be sticking out of your ass, old man!
Everything is supposed to be in order!
Do you understand?
Fuck...
You got your shoes!
And these are for... ladies.
Damn the leg!
And something for your cast.
I don't want any scratches on the dance floor!
Steve, put it on you?
It's just like a condom.
Of course, love.
And you bring me some beer!
Make yourself useful for something.
Calm. I can't be in two places at once.
Why not?
And do you know how far it is?
You won't know until you go.
Hurry up!
Steve!
Nice slice!
Damn cocksucker!
Son of a bitch!
She had the audacity to show up!
Who?
Lisa, the odd one out!
What a whore!
It's sexy!
Do you think she likes girls?
Now you probably do, stupid cow!
What do you have in mind?
I'm just teasing you!
The game is about to begin!
Come on, Sam!
Bravo, Sam!
Look who's coming!
Good to see you, Lisa.
Look at these savages!
A photo to remember!
It must be hard for you to see them again.
I have to go to the toilet.
We are about to start.
Lisa, I am so sorry!
I didn't want....
Don't blame me!
I tried to stop them.
I didn't want to come here at all today....
I just wanted to see if you would come....
and see...
Sorry. Forgive me.
Are you afraid, Patrick?
Am I afraid?
You came to see if I would notify the police!
It's not like that...
Are you afraid that you will be canned!
No, I swear...
You raped me!
Did you enjoy it?
Did it stand up for you?
Please Liso, don't do this....
What?
This?
Do you think an apology is enough?
Yesterday you guys had fun!
Today is my turn!
Are you ready to play the game, the burly people?
Suck it for me!
Screw you!
We are still waiting for Patrick!
Sorry, here we go.
We have two teams, to begin with
there will be three players in each.
Can it be?
Here we go!
Watch out for my leg!
Come on, AJ!
You are very sexy today, Sarah.
Scary!
Totally sucked!
It wasn't the worst.
Thanks!
BBK?
Who is the BBK?
Have you come to see my crutches?
No asshole, we said there are three people in the team!
There are three of us: me, him and him!
Can't you read?
then who is BBK, you idiot?
I don't know and I don't give a damn.
We're playing!
I'll tell the carpenter to delete it.
Shut up and play!
Next Sarah.
We'll show them!
Aren't we waiting for Lisa?
No, he is in the next team, with me and Cindy.
Come on!
Come on, gold, show that you are a champion!
I am not dreaming!
Come on, you bastards!
Excellent throw!
Will you help me get the fuck up!
You win, baby!
I have no desire to lose.
Show how you win!
Pepper leg!
You can win!
Get the fuck out!
Shut the fuck up!
Or I'll put this bullet in your cunt!
Just try it!
Fuck!
Damn the leg!
Shut your mouth, transvestite!
Or I'll cut off your dick!
You shut up too!
Heed my words!
I will kick your ass!
It's going to be a long night.
Yes.
What is it?
Hey, what is it?
I drank your beer.
What is it supposed to be?
Sorry.
Damn cunt!
Bring me the fucking beer!
Stupid bitch!
Sorry.
You'll give me a blow job as punishment!
Why don't you move your ass, old man?
You have to pay in cash.
I have no idea how I could collect the debt from you.
That probably wouldn't be so bad.
Your orders.
Hi.
Are you playing today?
Yes.
Are you on Steve's team?
I don't give a damn about Steve.
But maybe I will play.
I thought you were one of his girls.
I am definitely someone.
That's for sure!
Sweet you are.
Hey, go now!
Here's your beer.
I'll pay.
But it's not for me.
Never mind.
This is for Steve.
In that case... I'll pee on it.
Right.
Seriously?
And why not?
After all, he's an asshole.
I hang out with him because
he is with Hannah, my friend.
Sometimes I join them.
This Steve is an asshole,
But he's damn lucky.
Tell me that's not the case?
Not tonight, anyway.
In my opinion, his luck has already run out.
It's none of your business, shithead!
Fuck you!
Tell your mother that I will be late today.
It doesn't fly.
Don't look!
Or can I touch?
Guess what my favorite year is?
69?
Yes!
Steve!
Where is my beer?
It smells like roses!
You are so sweet.
Yes, right there!
You know how it's done!
I can feel your teeth!
You're biting me...
Fuck, you bit me!
Get off my back.
Come on, Sam!
Bravo, Sam!
Where is Lisa!
She went to the restroom.
She looked strange today.
She did not speak at all.
She looked like she was depressed.
He doesn't usually behave this way.
Maybe it's the influence of the moon.
And what do you know about it?
It's just an assumption.
You may be right.
I'm always in the mood.
Will you also get your period after surgery?
He's not menstruating, Jamie!
No....
My heart is bleeding!
Everyone judges me, but no one
really knows me!
Good...
We don't judge you at all,
We love you as you are, Sam.
Thanks.
I need to fix my makeup.
Cindy, why don't you replace me,
I'll go and refresh myself a bit.
Sure...
Thanks.
What's up?
Hey, take a look at this!
Fuck!
What is it?
I don't know.
I would also like such a skull.
Don't you think that's a little strange?
We don't know whose initials these are.
They are probably making fun of us.
Someone is sure to know something about it.
BBK, kiss my ass!
I don't understand the symbol.
That means death, right?
Whose is it?
Xcalibur, listening!
Hello!
Who is talking?
I told you not to call here.
If I get you, I'll strangle you with my own eggs.
Hello!
Strange...
No signal...
Deaf as a stump...
Motherfuckers....
I'm going, I'm going...
Fuck!
Have you seen it?
So what?
If it wasn't for this leg of mine, I would have shown you too.
Where did your spirit go
Of fighting yesterday, Steve?
Ask those shitty balls, Joey,
Or they'll end up in your ass!
You first...
If we're talking about fighting spirit,
then where has Patrick gone?
BBK wins!
Two strikes, eh?
Throw!
A one-man band?
What the fuck is this?
This is a computer!
This is not any BBK!
This we do not know....
Hello?
Lisa?
I could have taken the eye-liner.
This crayon sucks.
Don't you happen to have something in your purse?
Hello?
I'm starting to get scared.
Who is there?
Is there anyone here?
Jesus Christ...
Is this supposed to be some kind of joke?
Hello?
It's not funny.
You guys are starting to piss me off!
If I don't hear from you, I'll call the manager....
Did something happen to you?
Fuck!
I know someone is out there!
Who the heck is there!
Who are you?
Sons of bitches!
Are you ready?
Come on, brother!
Fuck Patrick!
We don't need that fag here!
Hey, bitches!
Where did Julia go?
She went, but did not return!
Go and get me a beer!
This time it's supposed to be full!
If you are polite.
Do you want something?
A big and wet pussy!
For me too, but not so wet.
Do you like the girls from the opposing team?
Yes, Joey likes the one with the dick.
Fuck you, AJ.
Is there a transvestite there?
Before or after the surgery?
I don't know! Ask him yourself.
You can find a blonde with a dick in the toilet.
Don't kill me!
Please...
I will do anything you want.
Really everything.
Hear...
I'll give you a blow job!
Anytime!
I'll do whatever you want!
I'm good at it!
Do you want to touch me?
If you want it, do it.
Please!
I'll do anything...
Damn it!
Our friend scored again.
What?
Never mind!
Stay focused.
Someone here is making a fool of us.
I bet it's Steve and his stooges.
I'll look around.
Julia can play.
We are still together.
We are one of a kind...
Hey, boss, how about....
All is well...
You have to be with the losers.
Don't you want to join
My winning team?
It is never too late to change colors.
You may not have seen the other pretty
girl from my team?
She was with you and the assholes.
I poured her a drink.
She went with one of your stupid friends.
My colleagues?
With Dave? Impossible!
Dave and pussy are like water and fire.
Are you sure?
Should I speak more clearly?
Of course I'm sure.
They left together.
Will you give this beer to Steve?
I need to find Julia.
Bright.
I'll set her off later.
What's your name? Matt?
Probably Doormat (doormat).
Dave is having his lucky day today.
I'll give him a beer already....
You can shove them up your ass, I don't care!
I have already sent two girls,
To bring me that beer!
What are they doing there!
I bet they are having fun with each other.
They're probably lollygagging somewhere.
I want to see it.
Give me the damn bullets!
First of all, these are my whores, do you understand?
Second, there were only three of us left....
And you play like patsies!
So you stay here!
And thirdly....
The only thing these whores will lick,
Is my balls, but that's after the game!
Fuck...
Speaking of crutches, I need to wax mine.
What are you? A faggot of some kind?
I'm talking about bowling balls.
How do you know that fags wax their balls?
Shut up!
Watch out
Then sit tight!
And while you're there, bring me some beer.
Right.
Screw you!
Keep.
I will have to impress your girls somehow.
Steve's girls.
What do you do?
Give it to me, whore.
What the hell was that supposed to be!
Christ!
After all, he duped yesterday.
What's his problem?
Waxomat....
"Please place the ball in the hole."
"I like your big ball"....
What a robot, great!
"Insert coin."
"Waxomat will now improve the speed and accuracy of the bullet.
"Shut up, you idiot."
"Do you think you're a police officer?"
"It's a joke."
Okay, what do we have here...
Super gloss?
"Supergloss.
Excellent.
Polishing.
Hot wax.
"Do not touch the burning wax."
Fuck!
"Debil."
Yes, honey, wax my ball.
"Your bullet will be ready soon."
Stop, stop!
"Waxomat.
Fuck!
Damn!
"More and more people are using
of waxing services."
He scratched my ball!
Please insert the coin.
Fuck you!
"Put the ball in the hole."
"Just don't go to sleep."
They fit right in, huh?
Yes.
But Jamie feels something for Lisa.
Really?
Yes.
Lisa is not bad,
But Sara is the real bomb!
What kind of bomb? Sometimes even shit can be good.
Sorry, but I don't do that.
Are you a natural blonde?
When was the last time you had a girlfriend?
A long time ago, if you want to know already.
I'm curious.
Right.
I know some who like secrets.
I sit at home with my guitar all the time.
This makes me a little shy.
Now I'm excited!
Really?
I didn't think I would have such an effect on you....
Don't you want to go somewhere off to the side?
When we are done playing.
Ben, standing up.
After all, it stands!
Hey, the dumbass!
Your fucking
Waxomat destroyed my ball.
It's your fault. I want a new ball.
First of all, dung....
There is a renovation there and it is not allowed to enter.
And secondly...
You are a fucking idiot.
This bullet broke down on its own.
And the machine just does the work for you.
I see no fault of my own here...
Open your eyes, moron!
There is a huge crack at the bottom.
This machine is broken.
I want a new bullet and that's it.
Take yourself the bullets that lie by the tracks.
The bullets there are one big crap.
I want a new one, fuck!
Take it easy!
Or I'll kick your balls.
Be good and get back on track,
and I might bring you something from the store.
If you are lucky.
Luck?
Are you talking about happiness?
The lucky thing is that your
Mother fucked you up like that.
You are lucky that I stayed
in Bison, otherwise I could have been your father.
Very funny...
Where are you going?
I hope to get a new ball!
I have to win!
Don't go anywhere!
Have your mom bring you one!
Hey, and did you get lost in that toilet?
No.
If anything, Sam got lost.
Where did the guy go?
Do you refer to him as "the guy"?
If he has balls, he's a guy.
At least for me.
Do you know that he doesn't like to be called that?
Do you see?
What?
You said "he."
You won!
You know what I meant.
Earth to Lisa.
Lisa, can you hear?
Hey, Lisa!
Are you all right?
Your turn...
Shall we take a walk?
You read my mind.
Just come back soon!
You are somehow strange today.
What's going on?
Everything is fine!
Well...
You are different today.
You are some kind of pissed off...
I said it's all right!
Give it a rest already.
She's probably on her period.
Hey, if a girl behaves like this,
it doesn't mean at all that she must be on her period!
Guys!
Do you like what you see?
You are sexy!
I know!
You have excellent boobs!
Let's do it here!
Damn!
What?
Fuck, I don't have an eraser!
And what will you do now?
Is a blowjob enough for you?
Do you want my moisture?
Toilet!
There is a vending machine with rubber bands!
I'll be right back!
What the fuck...
What else?
First my crutch, and now more track?
Your bullet?
That damn machine scratched my bullet.
Did you use it?
I wanted to, but now?
What a load of crap!
This is automatic.
You have to wait a while.
And what do you think I'm doing?
It only moves up and down all the time....
In my opinion, it welded together.
Did she mess up?
Calm down and I'll reset it!
Why don't you go and fix it then!
What if you go!
I don't want to argue with you!
I had to go to the carpenter to take care of it!
What's all the ranting about!
This moron is not back yet!
I was there on my own.
My whores have also disappeared somewhere.
Pat didn't even show up,
and these survivalists don't give a damn about anything.
Yes, it's that damn BBK!
They must be together!
I will walk over to the bastard.
I'm going to go fix this crap!
I'm going to finish this game.
Do you think a screwdriver is good for drinking?
In fact, Screwdriver is a drink, stupid.
Watch what you say, damn it!
The fact that someone didn't get their beer
does not mean that someone else will drink.
What do you mean?
Shit.
Fuck off!
Speaking of beer, where do you get yours?
You know what, A.J? Why don't you go and get them for me?
Make yourself useful for something at last.
And bring my whores if you meet them somewhere.
What the fuck are you looking at?
Shut up!
Just don't forget the fucking beer!
Fucking Steve!
Who does he think he is?
If he knew that Hannah gave me a blowjob yesterday....
And I didn't even take a shower yesterday.
French Desire.
I need something specific...
How about "Black Knight?" for the big one?
It's for big, black dicks.
Maybe not necessarily for me.
Strawberry!
A taste of the first time!
That's it!
Taste, after all, is not that important.
After all, there is no tongue in the pussy.
Damn!
That damn Steve treats me
Like some kind of lackey.
I would love to kick his ass.
Hey, faggot!
And what should it be?
Two hookers and a beer.
Beer I can still drink with you, boy.
Very funny, grandpa!
Who is this damned BBK?
What do you say? BB King?
No, BBK, you jerk!
The guy who wins!
Who the fuck is that?
Well...
These automats go crazy from time to time.
Names and results appear,
and then disappear...
The initials of previous players appear.
It's probably some kind of virus.
Probably in your ass!
Let me tell you something young man....
This is a crazy day...
Fuck...
What?
Yes, a crazy day....
In my time, we kept the list of results manually.
Everything had to be noted down.
It should be the same in bowling.
The person who took care of it
was specifically hired for this.
A man of flesh and blood.
No machine there.
Automation has displaced everything.
But people...
People are the same all the time.
Same crap as always.
Automated machines will never solve this problem.
So let's go back to my theory...
Which one says?
Which says...
That some things must
remain the responsibility of adults.
What the fuck are you talking about?
In any case, Joey went
to fix your machine.
You've got to be kidding, boy!
Only authorized persons can enter there.
This is dangerous!
You don't give a damn about all the consequences!
And you, old man, don't give a damn,
Whether your machines are running smoothly!
You don't even have to read.
You have it all in the picture.
DOES NOT WORK!
Take it!
What should I do about it?
Hang it on the track.
And on a waxing machine.
Your buddies must have messed something up.
I don't want any more
bullets get damaged.
And how much will you pay me for it?
What the fuck are you thinking?
I don't give a damn about you!
Damn the leg!
Damn!
What's up?
What a brothel this is!
Fuck!
The chains!
What kind of a brothel is this?
Why would anyone lock us in here?
What a load of crap!
What took you so long?
I like this mask.
I didn't know you had it.
Will you wear it while napping?
Do you have an eraser?
How do you want to do it?
Do you like it that way?
Because I do.
Put it in!
Insert very deep!
Fuck me!
I'll get there soon!
Come on, I can't wait!
Julia!
Julia...
Her shoe...
I see you left your shoes here....
Your dress...
Handbag...
And the other shoe.
Why do you have to cause
so much trouble, Julia?
I just wanted to help.
You scared the hell out of me.
"Waxomat.
That's what the old jerk was talking about.
"Polish your bullet."
Do not touch. Hot wax.
Hot wax, fuck.
People are morons after all!
Do not touch the machine with your hands or clothes.
Not surprisingly, it scratched the ball.
"Insert coin."
Fuck!
"Press the button."
"Hot wax."
Holy shit!
Do you think it's funny!
It is known that the ball will be scratched!
Act, act!
Act!
"Polishing.
"Glossing."
"A guy in a shirt like that must be a fag."
God.
Don't be afraid of him, have at him!
No, I would be surprised if
he was able to kick someone with that leg.
Kurwa....
Hey!
What the hell is going on here?
I think that's clear, no?
You're getting a pushback!
Take a look at the result, you shithead!
There's that BBK again!
The door is locked!
What is it supposed to be?
Really?
Probably the carpenter closed for a while, Steve.
Watch and admire, silly bitch!
My whores are gone!
Everyone else has also gone somewhere.
And I don't even have my beer!
And who the hell is that BBK!
Tell me!
Steve is right.
That what?
Ben, Sam and Dave have disappeared.
Lisa is constantly going somewhere.
And his buddies have also abandoned the sinking ship.
Maybe they are out there.
Tell the burly man to open the door.
People don't disappear like that,
after all, this is a bowling alley!
There is an explanation.
Grandpa definitely has the keys.
I'm going to go see!
Where are you going?
Joey can return at any time.
It is necessary to find carpenters.
I'm going back there and get it done like a man!
The debacles!
So it can be said,
That BBK won the game, eh?
Screw this game, screw the BBK
And the whole fucking bowling alley!
Damn!
Sucker!
We were the only ones left.
You and me?
And he.
As Steve said.
Screw B.B.K.
Let's play!
Fuck!
Joey!
Where are you?
Joey, what the hell are you doing!
What is going on here!
Joey, what the fuck are you doing, pervert!
Hide that dick!
Jesus Christ!
What is it supposed to be?
You are disgusting.
What's the matter with you?
Joey, fuck... What's in your head?
I knew something was wrong here!
Fuck!
Hey, jerk!
Did you fucking do that?
You tore my buddy's head off?
Sukinysnu!
Fuck!
Take off that mask, asshole!
I want to see the mouth, which in a moment
I will turn into a pulp!
Who the hell are you?
Did you do it?
I'll kill you, you bastard!
Kurwa....
Give back the damn bowling pin....
Is that all you can afford?
Fuck...
I'll kill you, motherfucker....
What do you do?
Fucked up faggot...
You're going to kill me.
I don't give a damn...
I don't give a fuck....
Kill me...
Next...
Did you see?
Good, huh?
Please, you were lucky.
I want to see it again.
This see.
Coming.
Where do you get the ball?
It's stuck there.
Do you have the little flashlight that
I gave you once that you don't use?
On a key ring?
I use it sometimes.
This guy must be in shape.
I can see something there.
What is it?
I don't know, but...
Looks like.
Like what?
Like an ass.
That wasn't funny!
Jamie, you have blood on your hand.
Jamie, you're bleeding.
It's Joey!
What is...
Jamie, we have to get out of here!
Look, they're all gone!
Or they are dead!
Let's go.
Come on Sarah, let's get out of here!
It's Patrick!
He looks like a damn Patrick!
Open that door!
I'm trying!
What the fuck is this?
Come on!
What?
It's plexiglass, it won't shatter.
Here is another option.
Come on, Sarah!
Hail!
That damn Steve was right!
Try to open.
I'm trying!
Harder!
Not a twitch!
Take it easy, Sarah.
We will find a way out.
Damn!
Here is another door.
Let's go!
Come on!
Whichever of them must be open!
Fuck!
We have to go back down.
Come on, Sarah.
After all, I'm going.
Damn!
Fuck!
Fuck, fuck!
It was Steve.
He deserved it!
Call the police from your cell phone.
It is discharged, otherwise
I would have done it a long time ago.
Typical!
Ben?
Dave?
What is it?
What's going on here!
They should not...
They shouldn't be dead!
I'm coming down, Sarah!
Cindy!
Cindy! Wake up!
Why are they all dead?
Sam?
Sam!
Sam, the guy with the vagina!
Oh no...
They screwed up his face!
We're not getting out of here, Jamie!
We must!
You won't get out of here!
Are you the one who killed all those people?
Jamie, what's going on?
Jamie, Jamie, Jamie.....
Be a good boy and go from there.
You know how it works...
She saw me.
This is plain murder!
I'm telling you to go!
Please!
Dad?
Dad!
Damn!
What have you done?
Lisa!
Lisa, what the fuck is going on here?
I got them, girl....
I got them all, baby!
But dad, they were my friends!
Friends?
And where were they last night, Lisa?
They weren't.
I'll tell you how it was.
They let those guys over there rape you! In groups!
Everyone is to blame!
We have already talked about this.
You pissed me off, man!
I...
I'm screwed, boy!
I've had enough of this!
Let the little bitch go from here!
Or you'll get a blowjob too!
Lisa, stop your father.
The plan was completely different.
The plan?
Jamie, what the fuck are you talking about?
I want to get out of here!
Lisa was assaulted.
They raped me!
I found out about it.
She told me everything!
So you knew all about it!
Now it's not important anymore!
Remember about Lisa's story,
That she never met her father?
He is: BBK.
BBK?
Bowling Bag Killer.
Bingo!
Why is Lisa in an evening gown?
When I found out what happened to Lisa,
I wanted to kill that son of a bitch Steve!
But...
I came up with an idea...
I wanted to take revenge in a different way,
with the help of a bowling pin.
And on those other miscreants!
What are you talking about?
What bowling pin?
We raped Steve with a bowling pin!
He mewled like a real pig!
We killed him.
Him and his buddies!
I needed a helper for that!
Did you think I would have figured it all out on my own?
Someone who would know what to do.
He was one of them.
Lisa, I tried to stop Steve, didn't I?
I tried, but he wouldn't listen to me!
They wouldn't listen to me!
Honey, it was Pat who called me yesterday.
He confessed everything to me.
He wanted to go to the police.
But I didn't let him!
Why?
I came up with another plan.
Lisa.
I swear I wanted to do something.
Lisa, I love you.
I have always loved...
I didn't want all this to happen.
I killed AJ and Joey to redeem myself.
The police would not be able to...
How could you let him live?
And include him in your plan?
He raped me with a bowling pin!
Hold.
Honey, I needed someone to help me.
For us.
I don't need it anymore.
We did quite well.
You have blood stains on your collar.
What and where.
On the shirt, scowling!
And just try to say you don't have one!
He got what he deserved!
This is not funny!
Do you think this is some kind of joke?
You are sick!
You're the funny one, my strawberry cake!
Did you really think I would let you go,
after what you did to my child?
I love you... Lisa...
Step back!
Or I'll shoot you too!
Why do you want to defend this cunt?
You're a bitch!
Let me go!
Let go!
I'll kill you for what you did to her at the ball!
You're the one they should rape, bitch!
Do you think I don't know that
have a taste for Jamie?
I'll kill you for that.
Damn pervert!
She wanted it!
Bitch!
Right in the face, grandpa!
Let me go, bitch!
Let go!
Dad?
Calm down!
He planned to kill me from the very beginning!
I had to do it, Lisa!
Wait for me!
Fuck!
Blood everywhere!
Did you see that?
How did I blow his head off?
Fucking carpenter...
Lisa's father.
I didn't know they were going to act in threes.
I thought he was going to kill them himself.
It was supposed to be Steve, Joey and AJ....
And he wanted to get me too!
You have to understand that, Sarah!
I didn't know that they would kill others.
I told you, Sarah.
Getting out is not a problem.
Incomplete...
You should listen to me.
That's because I'm always right!
Let it...
Put it down, Sara.
You are already safe.
Don't point that at me.
Aim for the ground, Sara.
What's up?
What do you want?
These types should die!
Put it down.
Like I said...
Screw you both!