HALFWAY
I think I'll get a divorce too.
What a house!
What's that?
Stef, what's that?
Unbelievable.
Put it around your head.
Come on, man.
-No, that's safer.
Lots of happiness in your new house.
Ellen from Immo Castelyns Real Estate.
Nice.
Man, this is huge.
You could organise some good
parties here.
Did you call us, Master?
Are there glasses?
The coolbox, in my car.
Your furniture has arrived.
Here?
-Yes.
I'm going to have a drink.
Come on, guys.
Stef...
Stef, where should the bed go?
Is this alright?
What will you do with all that
space?
Or do you want to play the macho for
Natalie?
My office is here too.
You won't continue to work for
her father?
No.
Will you leave some for the men
downstairs?
They're getting paid, we're not.
Yes, that's true.
-No, seriously.
What are you doing?
I didn't push it.
A target shot.
OK.
Thanks.
Here you go.
-This is for you.
There's no need.
For dealing with those two clowns.
That's not enough.
Join us for a drink?
No, I'll continue unpacking.
Will your Rebecca drop by?
-No.
She's not my Rebecca.
Fuck.
Boozers.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
I live here.
I think you're mistaken.
I just bought this house.
Do you have a woman?
I don't know you and I didn't invite you.
Get out of my house.
Children?
None of your business and I'm not
playing your games. Get lost...
or I'll call the police.
Can I make a call?
No, can you call for me?
I'll tell you what to say.
As you wish, pal.
I'm only asking you to help me.
-Yes.
Hello, Inspector.
Aelterman speaking.
I just bought the house at
14 Leeuweriklaan.
A bum broke into my house and he's
refusing to leave.
No, I don't know him.
Never saw him before.
Yes, thank you.
14 Leeuweriklaan.
They're coming.
Leave if you don't want any
problems.
Do you always react like this when
people ask you to help them?
Help?
You say help but you mean money.
Do you want money to leave?
Who mentioned money?
I only asked for one phone call.
-Are you threatening me now?
Are you threatening me?
-Damnit.
You're a hopeless case, you know?
The cops are here already.
You called us?
-Yes, he's in the room.
He took off, of course.
You don't know who it is?
No, he said he lives here.
A squatter maybe?
The house has been empty for
a long time.
Yes.
Do you want us to have a look
around?
To make sure he's gone.
Yes.
Can you describe him?
Maybe he's a regular of ours.
A man, around 40.
I think.
6 feet tall.
Only shorts and a towel.
As if he came out of the shower.
Reddish hair.
Did he threaten you in any way?
I'm just irritated.
Sorry about the mess.
I just moved.
And I'm divorcing.
As you said, he left when he
heard us.
We're checking the neighbourhood.
Maybe he's there somewhere.
Yes.
Hey, Rebecca.
Come see my new office.
I'll be there all day tomorrow.
I didn't touch anything.
-Bloody hell!
Aelterman speaking. Send someone again.
The bum's back.
He's standing in front of me.
Thank you.
Stop calling me a bum.
I don't call you a selfish asshole
either, do I?
Perfect.
One in the cosy corner maybe?
If it's not too much trouble.
Right.
A bit like the lord of the manor.
Which is what I am.
You'll be gone tomorrow.
I bet.
Another one. Thanks.
It's not hard to do someone
a favour.
Come in.
He's back.
Yes, that was to be expected.
Of course he took off.
I have pictures.
That's better than a description.
Sir...
What?
That's impossible.
The guy was here.
I saw him with my own eyes.
Wet, with a towel.
It's impossible. There must be
something wrong with that app.
There must be an explanation.
That's not mine.
I didn't have a drop of alcohol.
Can someone join you?
Friends or relatives?
So you're not alone when he
comes back.
Do you think I make it all up?
A divorce, moving house...
Those are stress factors.
Maybe also at work...
Am I going crazy?
No, that's not what we're saying,
but maybe...
Maybe the pressure's worse than
you think.
Sorry.
It's just that...
this guy makes me rather nervous.
We'll have another look upstairs.
Maybe we missed a spot.
Funny, guys.
Well...
Natalie.
-Have you got my car keys?
Why would I have them?
I don't know.
To annoy me?
I haven't seen them since you
came to get your boxes.
I don't think so. I'll have a look.
Quick, I have to go to court.
OK.
Damned assholes.
Karl and Lionel thought they
were funny.
Every shoe, sandal or sneaker...
You didn't wait long before someone
moved in.
I'm alone.
The TV turned itself on.
I was amazed. I was in Manhattan,
in the heart of New York.
And there were sales going on
everywhere.
Hey Rebecca, it's here.
Did you already lose your keys?
There's a bum going in and out as if
it's his house.
He must have the keys of the previous
owner.
And?
What do you think?
Our new office?
I'll call Max tomorrow.
I'll explain the situation.
Then he'll come to us with his
project.
And once we have him...
Stef.
-others will follow.
I'm doing Max' project.
Etienne gave it to me.
Not as an assistant, but with my
name on it.
Fuck, Rebecca.
-I know.
Are you serious?
Is that what happened?
Did Natalie hear from you that we...
Yes, I thought she had to know.
Jesus.
You weren't discrete either,
with Cappaert.
We can continue to see each other,
you know.
You'd better leave.
I'm sorry you're taking it
this way.
Alright.
Good luck with your new business.
Really beautiful.
We're done here.
Yes, beautiful.
Max...
Stef speaking.
I'm no longer working with
Etienne & Cappaert.
Yes.
What can I say?
Artistic differences.
No.
Too much production line work without
any personal vision.
Yes.
That's it.
And that's why I want to continue
working with you, Max.
You as master builder, me as
architect.
I'm certain that the two of us can
make the difference.
No, I understand.
Can't we discuss it once?
I'll send you a few new ideas and
then you decide.
What about the day after tomorrow?
Thanks, Max.
You won't regret it.
I swear. It'll be fantastic.
Bye.
Enjoy and cheers, bum!
Open that door.
Open up.
Open the door or I'll kill you.
Who's homeless now?
Get out of my house.
You're going to hurt yourself.
Where are you, asshole?
Show yourself.
There's no need for a court case.
-I knew that would get you over here.
I'm beginning to understand why
this was so cheap.
What didn't you tell me?
Nothing at all.
Why do you think that?
Because a man keeps coming in just
like that.
He has a bath or a shower and claims
that the house is his.
I've had all the locks replaced.
I'll send an invoice for that.
And yet this guy keeps coming in.
Did he do that?
It's his fault, yes.
And that window...
He also did that.
Is that the reason?
The reason why it was empty for
so long?
A fight with the previous owner?
There is no fight.
Besides, that would...
Yes?
That would be impossible.
The previous owner died.
Was he killed in his bed by a bum?
No.
It was...
Suicide.
Suicide?
Here?
The previous owner committed
suicide here?
So I heard. I wasn't working for
Immo Castelyns back then.
Some say it was an accident.
I'm beginning to understand your
discretion.
A dead person in the house doesn't
sell well.
You're the one who wanted to
sign fast.
I didn't want to ruin it for you.
-He's doing it for you.
Or is it a relative?
Who's against the sale?
I don't think so. The parents gave us
power of attorney.
If someone from that side's causing
problems, you should go to them.
We're not responsible.
The sale was completely by
the book.
VALCKE 14 LEEUWERIKLAAN SUICIDE
Sad to report the death of Theo
Valcke...
Julie Valcke, his daughter
Authorities investigate suspicious
death of 40 year old man
Theo?
Theo Valcke?
Anybody there?
Is your hand ok?
-Fine.
I'm on to you.
It took a little while.
The coin dropped.
I'm in some kind of stupid TV show.
Am I right?
My house is full of cameras.
Those assholes Karl and Lionel have
entered my name.
That Immo woman and those fake websites
are also part of it.
Where did you get that idea?
One.
I didn't chose to do this. Two.
I don't like this kind of nonsense.
I'll tell you what I plan to
do now.
I'm going to stab him...
with this knife.
Because if you're dead...
you won't feel anything anyway.
You can't die twice, can you?
No idea.
I only died once.
Ok, good joke.
I understand you have to continue
playing your role.
This is the moment to say 'stop' and
show me where the cameras are.
You really have too much...
imagination.
-Ah.
At three, I stab.
Ok?
Agreed?
One.
Two.
You can still stop me.
Three?
Fourteen over nine.
A bit too high.
It must have to do with
the divorce.
Other than that...
I don't see anything abnormal.
Pol, something absurd's
going on.
There's a guy walking around in
my house.
That asshole has already locked
me out.
Ok.
-I'm calling the police.
He disappears.
I take a picture.
Look.
The guy's not in it.
And I found this.
That's the previous owner.
And?
And it's my visitor.
You don't need to say it's impossible.
I know.
And yet I see him like I see you.
The police think I drink too much.
I'm starting to think so too.
Come with me.
Come. Look.
Did he do that?
-No, I did.
Ah.
I'm not even going to explain why.
Did anyone else see him?
I don't think so.
Pol...
am I going crazy?
I don't notice anything to worry
about yet.
But you can't deny that being fired,
divorcing, moving house...
can lead to stress.
-I already know that.
You can compare it to a process
of mourning.
Should I look at that too?
-No, it's alright.
Has it ever happened to you?
What?
-People who...
see dead people.
Yes?
A woman...
who saw her deceased husband.
What did you...
advise her?
Try to live with it.
Are you serious?
Are you serious, Pol?
-Stef...
I take all my patients seriously.
If someone sees a dead person...
I don't have medication for that.
Try to relax a bit.
Stop drinking for a while.
Maybe...
it will go away on its own.
And if not...
What's that?
-Someone who...
comes to heal your house.
Exorcize spirits.
The woman was quite content.
I'll forever deny...
giving you that number.
What if it was Natalie?
What if she did it to get back
at me?
I have to tell you... ghosts and
stuff...
I don't believe in it.
-Entities.
What?
We call them entities.
Entities? I don't believe in them.
Nobody believes in them, sir,
until you're facing them.
Put it here.
Is he or she...
a deceased family member?
No, he came with the house.
They want me to believe he's
the previous owner who...
committed suicide here...
in this house.
Smells?
Sounds?
Objects that suddenly disappear?
He has a thing with electricity.
Yes, typical.
Where do you see the entity
the most?
Here.
And in the dining room.
Ok, let's start there then.
Blow.
Sage.
Was already used by the old Indians.
You can open a window...
so the entities leave the house.
Please.
I'll measure it now.
You can see the result.
A remainder of an entity would
create a huge peak...
but here it stays green.
An old radio.
That's a magnetic field.
That's not abnormal.
Other devices will do the same.
This TV, for instance.
As I said, that's not abnormal.
Yes, our friend?
- The radio.
Did you create the device yourself?
-Yes, I did.
You could buy a detection kit,
if you wanted.
The professional kit...
that I use myself, of course.
You'd have to pay around 810 euros.
I wouldn't hesitate, Stef.
Such an opportunity...
Right next to you.
He's behind you.
No, I don't see anything here.
I don't see anything move.
No.
It's in the green.
Nothing.
I think we can call this a success.
Loser.
What do you want from me?
I want you to leave my house.
Why?
I was here first.
Then we have a problem, Theo.
I'm beginning to get
attached to...
this crazy house.
Natalie kicked me out of my home.
My father-in-law kicked me out of
my work.
Not again.
And certainly not by a guy...
who got out in a cowardly way
himself.
That was an accident.
How did you do it?
Pills and whisky?
No, you slit your wrists in
the bathtub.
That's more your style.
Can I see your wrists?
I could hurt you.
You don't know what you're getting into.
-Was it in the bathroom?
With a clothing line.
Don't you have to start searching?
-It's all under control.
There's been another accident.
Ok.
Is that it, Theo?
Is that all you can do?
Messing with the electricity a bit?
No flying cupboards or knives?
I think...
you're a second grade entity.
Not very impressive, Theo.
Not very impressive.
Let me tell you, Theo.
You don't need all that technology.
Back to basics.
Have a drink with me?
No?
Don't you miss that?
A red wine every now and then?
I can live without electricity.
But no red wine, that's hard.
Is that yours?
Did you stand here like this too?
Barbecuing for your wife?
I saw your obituary card.
Widower.
Did she go before you?
I'm wondering: why isn't she
standing next to you?
Drop it.
Or did she make a deal up there?
I finally got rid of him.
Please leave him downstairs.
That would explain why you're here,
annoying everyone.
Did she also kill herself?
To get rid of you?
I understand that.
You'd do it for less.
Come on, man.
Let's sort it out. Here and now.
Come on.
Come on then.
Come.
You can't go outside.
Are you locked up?
Locked up in the big house?
That's a pity.
Come, get me.
Come.
Yeah, walk away.
Make some more light bulbs explode.
Loser.
Little birdie is locked up!
You were hanging off a rope!
Max.
-Everything alright?
I've been ringing the doorbell
for a long time.
There's something wrong with
the electricity.
Come on.
Wow.
New?
Tell me, Stef, Rebecca gave her
presentation yesterday.
We were very impressed.
She's very driven.
Yes, very...
I won't beat around the bush.
I'm here because you asked me.
I'd say...
Come up with something brilliant.
Yes.
I need more time.
Don't you have anything?
No.
Not even the decency to call me?
There was no need for me to come.
Man, man.
Max.
Give me two days.
Jesus.
Max, two days.
Give me two days and I'll put something
brilliant on paper.
I know your private problems, Stef.
They're no excuse.
Rebecca, you used her, dumped her
and broke her heart.
But there she was yesterday.
Professional and with a good plan.
That bitch cheated on me.
Max.
Please, Max.
No!
Are you crazy?
Are you completely crazy?
That wasn't me.
You'll never get any work again.
Everybody will hear about this.
I swear, Max.
The dead guy inside did it.
Wait!
Max!
Max, wait!
Theo!
I needed that customer.
Asshole!
-What will you do?
Kill me?
Leaving is easier.
Never.
Do you hear me?
I'm dead, not deaf.
Mariano, I'm only asking for a chance
when you start a new project.
Hello?
To make a proposal too.
Yes.
I'll mail you my new data.
Alright. Thanks a lot, Mario,
Mariano.
Sandra?
Stef speaking.
Veronique, Stef speaking.
Aelterman. Yes, it's been
a long time.
Vero, did you know I'm a freelancer
again?
No, my window's open. Of my office.
Ah, at the camping?
No, no.
What did you say?
Colour advice?
Yes, I do that too.
Again.
Enjoy.
-Fuck.
Stef?
What are you...
What are you doing here?
Are you camping in front of your
own house?
Problems with electricity.
They'll pass.
That's what you think.
Why are you here?
I've come to warn you.
Etienne's furious.
He wants your hide.
He knows you tried to steal
Max from us.
He didn't get it from me, but from
Max himself.
What did you do to his car?
Long story.
I don't know if that was very
smart, sweetie.
No, that wasn't very smart,
sweetie.
Your contract has a competition
clause.
Etienne says you violated it.
He'll claim back everything he
paid you.
I think you need a good lawyer.
I'm divorcing the best lawyer.
I have a proposition.
I'm listening.
You help me with my drawings.
With my designs.
I admire your talent.
You know that.
It shouldn't get lost because you're
having a hard time.
So, you work for me.
Nobody at Cappaert needs to know.
Your name...
will be on my designs?
I'll pay you, of course.
I don't think you have a choice.
We can continue seeing each other.
I thought you didn't want that.
Do I have much choice?
Shall we go upstairs?
-With pleasure.
I feel like someone's watching us.
Come.
It will be a peepshow, Stef.
I'm very grateful.
Sex on this side is nothing.
No fun, useless.
Wait.
I'll be right back.
Stay.
Don't let us wait too long.
Are you crazy?
My car!
Asshole!
Stop it! Stop!
Stop!
There.
I changed the design of your car.
Put your name on it.
Madman.
Bitch.
Man.
When I scratch your car, you
get angry.
You could have had sex first and
then redecorate her car.
I understand.
You're a man of principle.
How do you do it?
How do you make enemies so fast?
It's a very special talent.
Did you study for it?
Well...
we'll wait for the bailiff.
Then the house will be mine again.
I'm not gone yet.
You're still a show-off.
Stefaan.
Yes?
I heard your father wants to
destroy me.
Do you remember New Year's Eve?
And that he said you were his son-in-law
and his best friend?
He'd been drinking, but he meant it.
You broke his heart as well.
And you didn't read your
contract well.
birdie, you've been caught...
they'll hang you by your balls...
Are you still there?
Everybody's entitled to defence.
You always say that.
Does it also apply to me?
Even to you.
I only know...
engineers...
carpenters and...
architects.
So, I'm coming to you for
a good lawyer.
To save my skin.
And your money.
I'll get your skin regardless.
But I'll see if someone can save
my money.
I'll let you know.
Thank you.
I can see your...
little entity, Stef.
Ouch! You're hurting me! Let me go!
What did you steal?
-Nothing.
Empty your bag.
I didn't steal anything.
-Empty it or I'll call the police.
Jesus.
What do you want here?
I saw you outside as well.
I used to li... work here.
For the previous owner.
Aren't you a bit young?
A holiday job.
Do you need someone?
Cooking, cleaning.
I can do everything.
First you steal from me and
then I have to give you a job?
I didn't steal from you.
What?
Who's camping there?
The new owner.
I don't need anybody.
Get lost.
Come.
Yes, I'm going.
-Wait.
You said you can do anything,
didn't you?
Could you look at the electricity?
You know where it is.
Ok.
Super.
Do you see anything wrong?
-No.
Me neither.
It all seems to work.
There's a problem, but the light...
works now.
That's strange.
I think you bring me luck.
Julie.
Julie, if you want, you've got
a job.
You can start right away, because
it's a mess.
Ok.
What?
Yes, I'm still here.
You don't have to come get me.
A guy alone. Why?
I don't know, Robin.
As long as I want.
What are you going to do?
Fuck man, stop that.
You know who that is.
I've only been making enemies.
Now I'm trying to help someone.
Sir?
Did you call me?
I missed a step.
Sorry.
Julie?
We haven't discussed your pay yet.
How much did the previous
owner pay?
Ten euros.
Is that too much?
-No.
Perfect. Oh, Julie, I'm Stef.
Not 'sir'.
Stef.
She's more than worth her money.
I've invited friends for a house warming
party tomorrow.
Do you want to help?
Tomorrow?
It would be great.
Ok.
Super.
Is eight o'clock alright?
-Yes.
You have a very nice daughter,
Theo.
Or should I say 'you had'?
I find that confusing.
Are you sure she's yours?
Or does she look like her mother?
-Don't toy with her.
I didn't invite her.
She came in on her own.
Just like you.
Maybe she's your daughter
after all.
Leave the child alone.
She's suffered enough.
-Can I make some coffee?
Child?
I see a pretty young woman.
I won't say no if she wants
my company.
You're scum.
-I want my house back.
Then I'll leave her alone.
Maybe.
There we go again.
Fuck.
Hello?
Mr. Aelterman...
we're getting lots of complaints
from the neighbours.
You won't believe me if I explain.
Let me guess.
Your wet bum's back.
Except he never left.
Tell him that the ban on noise after
10 pm also applies to him.
I'll tell him.
Weren't we clear?
-It's not me.
I'm not laughing, understood?
That was your last warning.
Honey, I'm home.
Had a good night?
Perfect, drunk on the left, drunk on
the right.
I felt completely at home.
Good that you're making friends
there.
Know where you'll spend your next night?
Especially after your housewarming.
It's going to be very noisy.
Hot water for the shower?
No, sorry.
-No hard feelings.
Stef, really.
I admire your stubbornness.
But it's like kamikaze.
You know what will happen at 10 pm.
Lots of noise, the neighbours will
call the police and you'll go to jail.
And so will all your friends, if
you're lucky.
Liar!
There won't be any friends.
You don't have any friends.
It's a tête-à-tête.
Who's the victim?
Wait, don't say anything.
Your almost ex.
You'll try to win her back.
You'll say something like
"Darling"...
"Sorry."
"Sweetie, Rebecca, it was a mistake.
I really fell into..."
"her cunt by accident."
"I'm sucking up to you because
I want to keep my money."
You look right through me.
Join the club.
Quite romantic, those candles.
Isn't it good that you don't have
electricity?
Shall I play some music?
Not too loud?
-Never before 10 pm.
Man, man.
Natalie will melt in your arms.
I'm telling you.
Unless I ruin it, of course.
I made a reservation here.
First row, expensive seats.
It's worth it.
Why are you wearing a dress?
Because I'll give them all
a blow job, Robin.
Everything ok with you?
Yes.
Is this alright?
It is for me.
For who...
Aren't your friends coming?
Happy birthday, Julie.
How do you know?
Your wallet.
Did you look in my purse?
Unforgiveable, isn't it?
Especially because you spoke the truth,
Julie Valcke.
Open it or not?
You don't have to stay.
Don't stay, Julie. Leave.
Ok.
But if you'll sing Happy Birthday,
I'll be gone.
A bit of improvisation.
I should really sue the previous
owners.
My grandparents sold the house,
not me.
They wanted to sell it quickly after...
-You didn't?
Yes.
Or not, I don't know.
It's strange.
We never used to have electricity
problems.
On the contrary. My father used to be
a maniac about electricity.
Your father, a maniac? Really?
Why are you living alone?
Because I'm divorced.
Why?
I had an affair with a colleague.
Didn't you love your wife anymore?
I did.
I don't know why.
Because I could.
Why? Because you could.
Good answer.
And now you're here.
In this big empty house.
Or in your little tent.
Was it worth it?
Do you always ask annoying
questions?
Only to pickpockets.
It wasn't worth it.
But you know what they say.
Repentance always comes too late.
It's my boyfriend.
Ex-boyfriend.
Suddenly, he can't be without me
anymore.
Come on.
Probably because I turned 18 today.
And I got the money from the house.
Really.
Where were we?
Why.
Why don't you say anything
about your father?
I'm not drunk enough yet.
Waiter.
She's had enough.
-You don't need to whisper.
She can't hear you anyway.
She's of age now.
You have no say over her anymore.
There's another reason why you have no
say anymore.
Yes.
You're dead.
What will you do?
I'll listen.
I'll be a shoulder to cry on.
The night's young, Theo.
We'll see what happens.
My dad couldn't live without
my mum.
She's...
A fog, a pile-up, a truck ran over
her car.
I miss her.
Every day. But I can live with
the pain. My dad...
couldn't get over it.
Alcohol, pills, he refused
all help.
Know what he said when I wanted him
to stop?
No.
That I didn't love mum enough.
I went to live with my
grandparents.
And then the cleaning lady found him
here, in the bathtub.
Electrocuted.
That's what did it.
Come.
Was it an accident or suicide?
Nobody was ever able to tell me.
When the house was empty, I asked
the walls. Guess.
I never got an answer, because
I already knew.
Dad didn't think I was worth
staying alive for.
That's not true.
Julie, that's not true.
I didn't love mum enough.
Him probably neither.
The asshole.
That's not true, Julie.
That's not true.
Enough sad stories.
It's my birthday.
Yes.
Shit.
I have another 'why'.
Why did you do this for me?
For your birthday.
And for you.
For me?
Am I the first person you receive here?
Here, now?
In your new house?
Yes.
The first.
What a responsibility.
We should make it memorable.
Because otherwise...
That's the curse.
Otherwise you'll never be happy here.
Never.
I want to stay here.
With you.
I want to feel good one more time in
our house.
Come.
Julie, don't do it.
He's using you. Against me.
Why? Because we could.
And we can now.
Ok, you've won.
Leave her alone.
You wanted a peepshow.
You're getting one.
Don't to it. She's my daughter.
I'll give you the house.
I'll bury myself.
You'll never see me again.
Don't do it.
Sorry, Theo. I think I'll choose
the sex this time.
Julie.
Leave her be.
Did you really think I was going
to do it?
How can you do it to...
such a beautiful woman, such
a great girl...
Your daughter.
Was it an accident?
I don't know anymore.
-Stop lying.
What do you want to hear?
Ok, no.
It wasn't an accident.
There.
I was fed up.
My body was full of pills and
still the pain didn't go away.
The solution was easy.
Pull the radio cable and that's it.
It was like the ring on
a merry-go-round.
It's yours.
You can go again.
Except my merry-go-round kept
on going round.
I can't get off.
I can't go forward or backward.
Not with Anna and not with Julie.
My own version of hell.
That she came here was my only
consolation.
And my torture.
Your daughter's entitled to
the truth.
You can tell her.
And tell her I'm in touch with
her father?
That I'm talking to you?
She'd go nuts.
Or she'd think that I...
We need something better.
Come, think of something.
Be creative.
You have enough inspiration to
annoy me.
A dream.
I appeared to you in a dream and
told you what to say.
Do you think that's a better idea?
Think of something yourself then.
Isn't deceiving people your
specialty?
Lying to Natalie was a piece
of cake.
I've got an idea.
You wrote a farewell letter.
I did not.
-Yes, you did.
You'll do it now.
You wrote a farewell letter...
but nobody's seen it until I moved
in here. I'll give it to her.
Aren't you forgetting something?
She knows my handwriting.
A printed letter.
A file on my PC.
-Not saved.
A printed letter.
And you happened to find it
tonight?
Very unlikely.
-Says someone who's dead.
But you're right.
It's better if she finds it
herself.
I might have an idea.
Don't go away.
Is that yours?
Anna used to collect that.
I hated it.
What will you do with it?
I can't go on.
Very good.
Julie.
I can't go on like this.
What should I say?
That she's right?
That I was a loser?
A deserter, a drunk jerk?
That will help her.
Don't write that down.
Is it a lie then?
It's useless.
I'd say the wrong things.
I'd continue to hurt her.
That she loved her mum less
than I did.
That's not true.
That was the booze talking.
What father would say something
like that?
Julie.
I thought she was strong enough.
Stronger than me.
I couldn't live without Anna.
And she...
She was better off without me.
I'm so sorry, Julie.
I'm so sorry.
There.
Was that so hard?
Julie, I can't go on like this.
You're right, I'm a loser... a jerk.
Useless... the wrong things...
That I didn't love your mother
isn't true, the booze...
strong enough, Julie, I'm sorry,
I'm so sorry.
Daddy.
Yes.
I can work with this.
Theo, a bit...
Dear Theo. Julie.
She's entitled to the truth.
I know.
But she'll hate me so.
And forever.
There were also good moments, Stef.
Really.
Happy moments.
Before.
Theo.
I'm going to wake her up.
Ok, Theo?
Inside, go inside!
Step back!
It's not the right moment.
-Hands up!
Other hand.
Come, tie up.
Come on!
Tight.
I want your car. Where are
your keys?
In my desk.
There?
-Yes.
Ok.
First, empty your pockets.
Push them over here.
Do something.
What? He'll leave.
-With my car.
Who are you talking to?
To myself.
You can buy a new car, but not
a new life.
I speak from experience.
-Thanks for caring.
You need to see a shrink, pal.
Alright, that Audi.
Does it have a tracking system?
No, I don't think so.
You had to ruin it all!
A fatso with a great house...
and an even greater car.
Did you sleep with her?
With who?
Don't bullshit, with Julie!
Why does he ask that?
-It's none of your business.
I have the gun.
It is my business.
I didn't sleep with her.
I don't believe you.
-Do you sleep with her?
She's got a birthmark here.
True or not?
He sleeps with her.
I don't know.
-Liar!
I'm not lying.
How can I make you believe me?
If she had one, I'd deny it.
Or the other way around.
Man! Wait!
Wait.
You're not helping.
Stop it!
What have you been taking
My daughter sleeps with a car jacker.
Stef?
What are you doing?
Robin?
I know it's you.
No no, not Robin.
Don't be a fool. I recognize your
gloves and your shoes.
Is that my sock?
Ouch, you're hurting me, Robin!
The guy from yesterday?
-I don't know.
Is that the guy from yesterday?
That's my boyfriend.
Was my boyfriend.
What do you want?
He wants his car.
He wants his car, my car.
Robin, what are you doing?
You could end up in jail.
I'm not Robin and I don't care.
My life's ruined!
It's his fault!
I waited all night for you.
I cooked for your birthday.
Another one.
Spaghetti and pancakes.
That's all you can cook, Robin.
Sometimes, you want to eat
something else.
You say 'eat' but you mean 'sex'.
Yes, yesterday was really three stars.
Stef's a great chef.
Julie!
Robin, nothing happened!
Nothing happened!
She was upstairs and I was
downstairs.
In the room.
She was upstairs in the room.
I was downstairs on the couch.
How did this get here?
I found it in the garden house.
Do you know it?
It belongs to my mum.
Do you believe me now?
-It doesn't prove anything.
Fuck.
Somebody else.
Why not? Come in.
We're having open house.
Inside!
Inside! Go up those stairs!
Robin, cut it out!
No, stay here.
No.
Tie her up.
Yes.
Ok, who are you?
My wife.
-Ex-wife.
Who is she?
My girlfriend.
-Ex-girlfriend.
Julie.
Hey.
Natalie, nice to meet you.
I'm Theo, pretend I'm not here.
Your husband's sleeping with my
girlfriend.
That doesn't surprise me.
No, no.
Julie's not here for you, but for
the house.
That fucking house!
That only makes you unhappy.
I was happy when it sold.
For yourself, for the money.
No, for you!
Yes, maybe to do something good
with the money.
A snack bar near the station.
I always dreamt of that!
Or a shop or a trip.
Or a boat, doesn't matter what.
But far away from here.
Not what I want, but what you want.
As long as we're together.
Together with you.
And you had to ruin it.
-Robin, stop it.
We did not sleep together.
I did not sleep with him.
Really.
Now untie us.
Only if you...
swear you'll forget about
the house and won't come back.
I can't.
That ruins you and it ruins me too!
I'll ruin everything!
If you do that, it'll be over!
I never want to see you again.
Trash it.
Then it's all useless.
Come, shoot.
Straight into my heart.
I'm already ruined anyway.
That's your daddy's alarm gun.
Fuck.
Pumpkin.
What am I going to do with you?
-Marry me.
I looked after you when your father died.
I want to continue to do that.
Julie...
there's nothing left for you.
Only sorrow.
He really cares about her.
Yes.
What?
Nothing.
No, sorry Julie.
It was really an accident.
I didn't mean to.
A note for Anna.
For Anna?
That's for your mother.
You.
My dearest Anna...
I miss you so terribly.
I so want to be with you.
You don't know how often I almost
did it.
But I can't.
I have to stay with Julie.
Can you forgive me?
I've neglected her so badly.
I've said things, ugly things.
Hurtful things that I didn't mean.
I'm going to make up for that.
First, I'll clean up the house.
And I could also use a bath.
Then I'll look after her.
So can you wait a bit longer for me,
Anna?
I promise you I won't get
too old, haha.
See you later, my wife and my love.
Your Theo.
Oh yes, sorry.
Do you think it will change
anything?
Stef.
Robin.
Nice to meet you.
I think so.
Here...
give that back to your dad.
Can I get my keys back?
-Yes, of course.
Here you are.
I'll get my Vespa.
He's very...
special.
Yes.
Full-time job.
Natalie.
I'm still here.
Strange friends.
You wrote that letter, didn't you?
I don't know what you mean.
Did the house do that to you?
Want to buy it?
I'll get it for free.
That's the lawyer I mentioned.
A very good one, but I'm better.
Did you come here just for that?
I came to say I'll make you suffer
the way you made me suffer.
When I've had you on your knees long
enough, I might call you one day.
To have a drink or something.
My own kind of purgatory.
What did you say?
Deal.
The being on my knees...
How long does that have to be?
Let's say two...
plus another seven months.
Natalie.
Fuck.
Theo.
Theo!
Did you hear that?
Are you messing with me?
Theo!
Or has he really...
Theo.
Theo!