If I pay close attention...
I can feel outer space
pulling at us.
One way to fight
the pull of the vacuum...
is to create your own.
The chaos deepens
in coastal areas worldwide.
Flooding along coastal Florida,
California, China, Taiwan,
Japan and Southeast Asia
has submerged entire cities.
Displaced refugees numbers
in the tens of thousands.
Activists crowded the streets
near UN headquarters today
as major industrialized nations
meet for the fourth time
to discuss
global warming initiatives.
Again, one of the few
countries not participating
is the United States,
consistent with the current
administration's refusal
to ratify the Kyoto protocol.
This is the
Diablo Valley Authority
with bulletins for your area.
We're issuing an air quality
alert for Thursday and Friday,
so remember to wear
protective masks
when exercising outside.
If you need a new one
go to your nearest gas station,
police station, or library.
Replacement masks
are six dollars.
The worst isn't over yet so
remember to keep conserving gas
and potable water to help out
our friends on the coast.
Conserve hard,
stay safe, neighbors,
and don't forget to watch
for the solar eclipse
today at 1:45...
Emergencies only.
Buy yourself
a pizza pocket, OK?
He will wipe away
every tear from their eyes.
And death will be no more,
nor will there be
sorrow or crying
or pain anymore,
for the former things
have passed away.
There are armed conflicts
in the Balkans, Iraq, Korea,
Russia, Mexico, Colombia,
Israel, and Peru.
Can anyone
tell me one thing
that happened
in the world today?
Jenny?
The mayor was
caught drunk driving.
I had a fight with my mom.
I tripped her.
All right, settle.
Sources from Chinese Central
Space say female astronaut,
Xian Wei Ming,
stationed on the
recently launched
Chinese space telescope,
has been reporting sights
of asymmetrical swelling
and solar flaring
from her sun observations.
Several hours after
Central Space authorities
refused to confirm
Xian's observations,
Xian reportedly changed
trajectory of her spacecraft
to a direct path
to meet with the sun
and expended all remaining
fuels to break earth's orbit.
Earlier today,
a 12 year-old Palestinian girl
was run down by an
Israeli tank at Hebron...
Yes.
There was an eclipse.
I know sweetie,
but it's not an emergency.
You didn't look at it, did you?
- No.
- 'Cuz you'll go blind.
Bye.
Your Mom lets you
walk home alone?
Hi, Wendell.
You want a ride back?
Off work already?
Yeah, they let me
go home early.
So, umm...
How are things
between you and Scott?
Dude, quiet down.
Oh, come on.
He's a good kid.
Aren't you, Tim?
Yup.
Hey!
You're home early.
Yeah.
I need a nap.
You're going out?
What do you
want to be one day?
I don't know...
Sorry you're just
dating a dumb jock
who only wants to go
whitewater rafting.
He's been practicing baptisms
with his dad all day.
Scott!
Pam's here.
Do you want some lunch?
What took you so long?
You need to quit smoking.
You need a
double-headed dragon dildo.
I did quit.
I can smell it
on your clothes.
I quit two hours ago.
Diablo Valley Animal Control
has issued a warning
for all residents
to keep their pets inside.
And in Fresno today,
Centron employee, Roderick Kent,
shot and dismembered
his wife and two children,
then severed his own
head with a chainsaw.
Kent had just been maimed...
Sorry - just been named
Centron Employee of the Month
for his efforts...
Folks are saying
these incidents are omens.
Any little thing and it's a sign
the world's gonna end.
Totally paranoid, huh?
We've been killing
each other off since day one.
We don't stop
because we don't want to.
Everyone keeps working,
going to the gym,
going to ball games.
How could the world end?
Some people think the sun
will swell up into a red giant
and burn up all the planets.
And some people expect
a sort of Antichrist,
who comes along
pretending to be all nice,
and making everyone
believe in him.
Then he tries to corrupt people
so they won't get into heaven.
But eventually he's overthrown
by God in a rain of comets
and good triumphs
over evil, et cetera, et cetera.
Silly.
Ow.
You just imagine it's not there,
as if it never happened.
Like turning back time.
Look at it...
and say hello.
Hello.
OK.
Now close your eyes,
concentrate...
and say goodbye.
Bye.
Own it.
Yeah, well.
Never worked for me either.
Drink your juice, OK?
Bye.
So what's new, college boy?
I had sex for the first time.
With that Jonah guy?
No...
Me and my goldfish.
Of course,
me and that Jonah guy.
That's really great.
That's really cool.
We had sex sex.
Mm hmm...
Anal sex.
- Yeah, I know.
- OK.
I figured.
I didn't know if you knew.
I don't know what else
you guys would be having.
So how was it?
Incredible.
I don't know.
I may really
be in love this time.
It didn't hurt?
No.
Well...
Yeah, it did initially,
but then that kind of fed
into the pleasure/pain thing.
You just have
to use a lot of lube.
Dinner time.
Let's not leave.
I have to.
Anyway, you really should
try it some time - anal sex.
Call me!
We are very,
very blessed, dear Lord,
to have this wonderful,
wonderful family.
So for that we thank you,
and for the food
you placed in front of us,
prepared by my lovely wife,
which we eat
in your name, O Lord.
- Amen.
I like to have sex with men.
Did you hear what I said?
Should anyone be blamed
for becoming bored?
Yeah.
He's black.
We really should make
more black friends.
And his name is Jonah.
Maybe another outreach meeting.
It is so hard to get blacks
to come into our church.
It isn't hard to find one
to come inside me.
Boredom leads to restlessness,
restlessness to recklessness.
And recklessness
puts all of us in harm's way.
I read in U.S. News
and World Report
that the anus is chockfull
with ecoli bacteria.
We used a condom.
Condoms provide excellent
protection against diseases.
We should put one
over our house.
Richard, didn't you
mention a Jonah
in your sermon last month?
He was swallowed
by a whale.
A very large fish.
You should
try it sometime - anal sex.
Heart.
My heart is broken.
Scissors.
Put down the scissors.
Genocide.
Avoid genocide.
Did you study for this?
No.
Why not?
I don't know.
I'm going to call your mom, OK?
She's not home
until 7 o'clock sometimes.
What about your dad?
He's not with us anymore.
When did he pass away?
He just said bye.
He's not really dead.
It's only three weeks
after I turn 18
that Timothy Wu files
his last official flight plan
and takes off west
into the sun.
For a year
we wondered where he went.
Now we don't care
what happens to him.
Last night a 67-year-old
fisherman dumped 40 tons
of toxic waste
into Catalina Bay.
Arresting officers mention
he was speaking incoherently
about killing off the jellyfish
that in recent years
have choked what was once
a vibrant fishing industry.
This one of a string
of desperate acts we've seen
in depressed fishing communities
which have dwindled
as the population
of jellyfish has exploded
as a result of rising
sea temperatures.
Exhale, inhale.
One more time for me.
Inhale, exhale.
Oh, shit!
Officer, haven't you
ever been distracted?
No, ma'am.
Bullshit!
I just think Timothy
needs a more stable
home environment to foster
his growth potential.
Why don't you just bring some
fucking dinner over then?
Well...
Kids need food
to grow too, Mr. Robertson.
I'm just trying...
I really need some alone time
or I will literally die.
Don't talk to your teachers
about our personal life, OK?
Take Timmy with you
to work tonight.
Take him to work?
It's just one night...
Please.
I can watch him.
I need you to watch me.
But who cares
about what I need.
Mom, it's not that
I don't care.
It's just that if
I take Tim to work
they're gonna be pissed
off if I show up with...
How long does it take
to mop a hangar?
It's not like you're
going to school
to do something
with your life...
Nobody wants what's good
for them at the right time.
You miss your moment,
and you find yourself...
stuck with...
Fine, I'll take him.
If we stress you out so bad
why'd you even have us?
Well, Pam...
Your father... -
Well, don't just stare at it!
Relax.
Mom!
Sorry...
Just clean it up.
That's really loud.
Please stop.
Why?
Because... It's loud.
Tim!
Don't make me
come up there.
What did you say?
Dad said it...
"Don't make me
come up there".
Do you miss him?
Should I tell you
it wasn't your fault?
'Cuz it wasn't.
I didn't know
you washed airplanes.
Well... they get dirty.
Whose fault is it?
Do you believe in heaven?
Yes.
Dad did too.
I don't know...
I guess he was
just ready for something new.
Do you like Wendell?
He's funny.
Funny like a clown?
Funny like the President.
I like that one.
Only for a second, OK?
Romeo Delta...
Timmy, Oakland center.
Go ahead.
Pammy, 628 Romeo Delta...
Experiencing heavy turbulence,
requesting niner point five.
Sorry...
Remain in current altitude
due to traffic.
Dammit!
Oh, no, a bird!
Aaaaaahhhhhh!
What I'm saying
is that while, yes,
you did draw very
nice cotton fields,
you also could diversify
your subject matter?
Like maybe draw a boat.
Or an Underground Railroad?
Or just a railroad.
That's pretty.
Good.
What's that supposed
to be anyway?
A waterfall.
Looks like a cool
alternate reality.
You know what I mean?
OK.
Sorry to mess things up
at home for you.
It's all good.
Do you want
to come over on Saturday?
We're having a barbecue.
Cool.
Are you sure your mom...
She said to invite two guests.
Oh, we gotta get this.
Yeah, we need salsa too.
Mild or hot?
Hot.
Speaking of hot,
you look good today.
What?
Come on.
Are you seriously one of
those people who can't accept
a compliment without accusing
someone of sexual harassment?
No.
I just don't like being
compared to a condiment.
Oh...
Well.
Where did you find that?
That's a project
your daddy and I started
when Pam was really young.
We were all addicted to sunsets.
We even took some
from your dad's plane.
I thought he took this with him.
Your mom really
cares about you, you know?
She never once
regretted having you
instead of finishing
med school.
You ever thought about
tracking down your dad?
You have us all figured out.
No, I don't.
But I do want to help.
It's blank.
Timothy and I were talking...
I got the impression
you needed flying lessons.
Flying's for
prick-waxing jerk-offs.
No need to be redundant.
Stop!
Shit...
Sorry.
No stars to guide us.
Another marine creature,
armed with a mass
of stinging cells,
can be found sailing the warm
oceans of the world...
Zay... jee.
Zayyyy... jee.
Zai-Jian.
Zai-Jian - Later, alligator...
Your dad could've
taught you more...
If he wasn't such a space case.
The bluebottle jelly,
or Portuguese Man O' War,
is actually a symbiotic colony
of four specialized animals.
One polyp fills up
with gas to become afloat,
enabling the bluebottles
to stay close
to the surface for feeding.
During the capture the chamber
will shift in buoyancy
to accommodate the weight
of large prey...
~#XX
I'm a whale!
My project explores
the relentless relationship
between the body and the self.
What do our bodies ask of us?
Who are we without our bodies?
Are these shells here
to keep us separate
from one another eternally?
So, yeah, my installments
explore these ideas
by consolidating flint,
barbed wire and live turkeys.
Oh, that's really
quite typical... topical.
Isn't it?
Totally.
That's amazing.
Off to the loo.
Down the hall.
So, Jonah, I had no idea
you were Timothy's
teacher and Scott's...
Small world, huh?
Can I get you anything?
Ro - Sham - Bo!
That's stupid.
Bombs are for psychos.
- Shut up!
- No!
Pacifier.
You mean pacifist.
Pacifist.
Why must people focus on
the darkness in the world...
when all most people
want to do is
achieve some kind of...
some kind of peace?
So...
Wendell is, um...
Thank you.
Yes, he's quite a catch!
He's a little...
Well, is he a student?
No.
He's an assistant manager
at Sports Lodge.
Great!
Isn't it amazing when people
see your inner beauty?
It floors me every time!
Swarms of Cessnas every day,
since they grounded
all the big planes.
So how long have you
and Saura been going at it?
Let me say that
a little differently...
About five weeks.
Hmm... not too long!
So, is Timothy doing OK?
He's sophisticated
for his age group.
He just doesn't seem
to study at home a lot.
Yeah, well...
Mom's real busy, you know.
Oh, I know.
Skippy put up
a good fight though,
more than most collies would.
In the end it's really just
your own self-interest
that's keeping them alive.
I'm just saying college
is actually a great way
to make new connections.
I truly think connectivity
is the only surefire way
to a decent career -
or lifestyle, for that matter.
I mean, a solid
network of connectivity...
Well, what's the point?
I mean everything
is hell anyway, right?
It's easy for you to say that.
I mean in your life,
you have so much freedom -
the way you live.
Millions of kids would die
for the opportunity
that you have.
I just think that you're
taking it for granted
because it is
within your grasp.
I mean just sitting
here talking to you,
you seem like
a pretty smart girl.
Well, millions of kids are dying
for our opportunities.
I just don't think
everything is hell.
Jell-o, anyone?
Do you want Jell-o?
I don't eat Jell-o.
You dropped your chair.
Pam is so pretty.
She's so wonderfully exotic.
She's so lucky.
I wonder if she realizes it.
We certainly don't want her
flying off any more roofs.
She's much better now.
You told me
about the 3.8 GPA.
That's great.
Pity college is so expensive.
Yeah, pity about
your dog dying too.
That must have
been really ruffff.
Do you know
where the tofu dogs are?
Try the freezer.
You seem agitated.
I'm wonderfully exotic.
Anything I can do?
It's OK.
It's all right.
I just wanna disappear.
You make me
want to disappear.
You're wasting our power.
For months
after Dad flew off
Mom had this
recurring nightmare...
Again and again
she'd wake us up
right before sunrise,
saying that the sun
had reached its half-life
and had turned into
a jellyfish that was
devouring the ocean.
Every creature in the sea
knew they were doomed
if they stayed in the water,
but outside of it
they'd suffocate.
Made so sick and sightless
by their own terror...
many destroyed
themselves in anguish.
But even in their most
futile of moments
they seemed to sense
something in us worth saving,
and they wouldn't
take us with them...
even when we asked them to.
Even when their stories
scared us half to death...
they were beautiful to me.
When she met Wendell...
her stories stopped.
She didn't have
to dream anymore.
400 thousand activists
and area residents
gathered in Slovenia today
to celebrate the demolition
of the last existing
nuclear power plant
on the European continent.
Demands for environmental action
from ordinary American citizens
continues to grow, however,
as politicians and celebrities
continue to sound the call...
Don't watch this.
Don't look.
Scott and Mr. Robertson
were holding hands.
Well, that's fine,
but they're gonna
go through some hard times.
How come?
Because...
they like hanging with boys
more than they like girls.
I like boys more than girls.
That's different, sweetness.
What do you think about
on your good days?
You know, your daydreams?
I just want peace, you know.
There are things
I haven't told you about...
that I'll tell you some time.
I really fucked up.
What?
I kissed him.
You serious?
Yup.
Why?
'Cuz I'm a fuck-up.
I guess I should go...
I'm fucking sad right now.
So?
I'm depressed.
You're the only clear...
exciting thing
in my life, basically.
I just feel like
everyone else is corrupt.
I hope it's not
anyone we know.
You can't fight me!
I'm Jesus!
Yeah, well, I'm God!
I'm your Dad!
You look depressed.
Did I do something wrong?
No.
Good.
What?
Does he make you
feel special?
He stands up for you
when I complain.
You complain about me too?
Mom!
I'm happy, OK?
OK...
Then I'm happy too.
Yeah?
Sorry all about the weird
stuff at the barbecue.
Sometimes adults
just do weird things...
Things that we don't mean.
We're very immature.
You're not an adult.
It's one month before he
realizes he's bored of us
when Dad insists
on reading me to bed...
which he hasn't done
since I was 6.
'We can start working with time
if you wish,' Chiang said,
'Till you can fly into
the past and the future.
And then you will be ready'.
The day that Chiang vanished
his feathers went
brighter and brighter
and at last turned so brilliant
that no gull
could look upon him.
As the days went past,
Jonathan found himself
thinking time and again
of the earth
from which he had come.
If he had known there -
just a tenth...
just a hundredth -
of what he knew here,
how much more
life would have meant.
It's nice.
When did you say that your
parents are coming home?
Monday.
They went on a retreat,
some church retreat.
Excuse me...
We're home.
- Oh, my gosh!
- Hi, Mom.
When you're done
I'd like a word.
Your parents called
the schoolboard, Scott.
There's been
a lot of complaints.
They're recommending
a transfer.
It's no one's fault, :
It's just the situation.
OK, everyone,
I'm Miss Gatzert.
Mr. Robertson came down with
the flu that's going around,
and he left
a spelling list for Friday.
I'd like you all to take out
your World History books.
Have we covered
The Crusades yet?
What are you looking at?
Are you a homo
like Mr. Robertson?
It's kind of hard
to put into words
what makes you
fall in love with someone.
It's indescribable.
Here you go, Scout.
There has to be an event.
It's an event that marks
a change in you...
Like a nova.
A nova is when
a star becomes unstable.
So it's like inside you've
become a hundred times bigger.
And no one can see it,
but everyone knows.
How's your sister?
Fine.
Have you seen
her and Scott kiss?
No?
Have you seen
her taking a bath?
I think she
must be beautiful.
Explode...
X~P~L~O~D~E.
Explode.
Silver...
S~L~I~V~E~R...
Silver.
Four Palestinians
and one Israeli soldier
were killed Thursday
in the West Bank in Gaza.
A 12-year old Palestinian girl
was crushed by
a tank at Hebron...
I feel sick.
Was it me?
No.
Did Wendell say something?
Not really.
Are you lying?
He was just talking weird.
Weird like how?
Like when you're eating
and you're crying,
and it doesn't taste good.
I know...
I hate that.
So, Jonah called.
It looks like the school board
sided with you guys.
I think it's time
that we reassess things.
Reassess what?
My rectum?
You know,
when I was very young
I thought I could find meaning
by using my time on this earth
to make up for having
more than others.
I failed at everything I tried.
We still rage, kill, starve.
There's only
so much you can do.
At a certain point,
the futility begins
to eat into you.
At a certain point
you have to abandon control.
You have to leave
the rest to God.
I think... you think...
the mere act of thinking...
is your God.
I do everything for you
out of love...
There is no God.
Don't you ever...
Don't you ever
speak to him again.
If you don't get the fuck
out of our house...
I'll fucking kill you!
Hey...
Stop, stop, stop.
You're sick!
You erase me
and you fill me up
at the same time.
I don't know
what to do about it.
I need your help
to figure it out, OK?
Shoot, dammit.
I'm almost home, Tim.
Hi. It's Saura.
I can't take
your call right now,
so leave a message.
I need you to help me, Pam.
I need you to...
be an adult with me.
Grow up and help me, Pam.
You know how to get everything
you want with your stupid smile.
So do you.
Get off!
Just let go.
You need to talk
to your daughter.
Mom, he's been asking Tim
sick questions about me.
I just can't handle it.
I can't!
Oh, my God.
He raped me.
Are you kidding me?
Tim was here the whole time.
He knows.
Oh, my God!
Did he?
Did he rape her?
No.
He doesn't even
understand what you're saying!
Where are we going?
Away from this stupid place.
Turn fuckin' green!
It's cold!
Go to the car
and turn the heater on.
Fuck.
You see anything?
Not yet.
I've been meaning
to give those to you
in support of your
cocksucking relationship.
You're special.
I'm not afraid of the world
ending when we hang out.
Do you think we'll be together,
hanging, when it all happens?
We'll probably be long dead
before it happens.
You never know...
We could go
at any second...
Now.
Or... now.
I think we'll be together.
If it wasn't Jonah...
it would be me, right?
I don't want to lie to you.
Lie to me.
No.
Yeah.
Just kidding.
You two lived
around here long?
Yes.
It's a very
safe place to live,
especially if you have kids.
Everybody is so good
to each other around here.
Looks like we're trapped.
Is this right?
I think so.
I think it would be wise...
to stop for the night.
I'll call a truck.
I have nothing witty to say.
Say something nice.
This is so stupid.
Are you all right, honey?
Yes, I'm all right.
Are you hurt?
Oh, I'm fine.
I think we should get home.
Help me, Pam.
Be an adult with me...
Grow up and help me, Pam.
It's not as bad
as I thought.
This whole experience has just
reminded me of something.
Did you remember to
send in our auto premium?
I can't keep my brother
out here like this.
I'm gonna stay
with my parents down south.
Maybe apply to grad school.
If you leave, they win.
What about me?
What about you?
Zai-Jian.
Love you.
I figured it out,
you know...
Why mom had Tim so late.
She was willing to do
anything to make him stay.
Didn't work.
I'm gonna not love you, OK?
I'm gonna not be
so stupid anymore.
Be an adult with me.
Grow up and help me, Pam.
When you jumped off the roof
you weren't
trying to die, right?
'Cuz Mom said
you were trying to die.
Well, I wasn't.
You were trying
to chase Daddy's plane.
Open.
So you're telling me that
she faked the whole thing?
Is that what
I'm supposed to think?
You know that's
not what I meant.
I'll go get my stuff.
Wait.
What?
Let's have a drink.
My Mom said to me,
"I think we should
reassess the situation. "
I said,
"Reassess what?
My rectum?"
This is good.
Now they can't just
sweep it under the rug.
It's like it was
meant to be or something.
I don't know.
I feel so close to you now.
Did you set this up?
What up?
Did you know
your parents would find us?
Yeah.
You know
we're through, right?
Scott?
Oh, my God!
He's all right!
Where were you?
Pam.
Weather experts say the showers
should be spectacular.
Sky watchers can expect to see
dozens of meteors per hour.
A meteor shower
can sometimes be
the brightest object
in the sky,
wandering through space,
rogue debris left behind
by a timeless comet.
The next heavenly display isn't
anticipated until next December.
So don't miss out
on this one, folks.
Tim!
- Eat.
- Hmm?
Eat.
Hey...
I'm sorry.
Aren't you gonna
drink your juice, buddy?
No.
Did your crazy sister
brainwash you?
Are you attracted
to stupid people?
Because I'm pretty stupid.
It's all right.
No!
Calm down. Please.
Get off of her!
Get off!
Mom!
What are you...
Help me!
I'm not going to hurt you.
I'm just gonna hold you here
so you can't hurt me.
OK?
Leave her alone!
Your daughter wants me dead.
You think it's dark in here,
but it's not.
The saddest thing
I've ever seen
is a nice woman
growing old alone.
Pam's not gonna be there.
I hate you.
Actually it's kind of pathetic.
Shoot, did I scare you?
Friends, right?
I could use more friends.
Couldn't you?
Mom!
Stop!
Say it, OK?
Friends?
Say it.
Zai-Jian.
Scientists had initially
discounted reports
of solar anomalies made by
Chinese astronaut Xian Wei Ming
one month ago, but astronomers
around the world
are now confirming
that solar flares
did indeed occur last week
beginning at 8 a. m. PST
on Tuesday.
A few hours later, a wave of
accelerated protons
hit the Chinese Space station,
with all likelihood destroying
the bulkhead and killing Xian.
Flaring continued with sporadic
but extreme solar winds
and geomagnetic storms
in earth's magnetosphere.
How's the peach?
Good.
Pam?
Hmm?
I think it's coming back.
That's never happened before.
Did you do that?