Sit down. Come here.
How much for this fighting cock?
One and a half million.
And for that one?
Two million tomans.
Two million.
Mr. Farshid's cock
is at one and a half million.
Kak Amin's fighter
is at 2 million tomans.
No one says 3 million?
No
No one bids higher?
No.
I quote the philosopher Kierkegaard:
"l am not afraid of death
because when I am here he is not...
"And when he is here I'm not.
"No gain or loss
is more important than death."
What did I say?
"No gain or loss
is more important than death."
Music's ready. 3... 2... 1.
Allo, allo.
Papa, Papa...
What is it?
It's for you.
Who is it?
Telephone!
Who? Who?
Mamo? Just a second.
It's Mamo.
Who?
Mamo.
Mamo! Quiet! Quiet!
Just a second.
Bring the phone.
Silence!
Hello, master. At your service.
Sorry?
At your service.
Yes.
Is it possible?
Really?
They gave you the authorisation?
Of course, tomorrow
I'll go pick up your sons
and then we'll join you.
Goodbye everybody.
My sons will stay to play some music.
Fayegh! Mamo has good news!
I'm not coming.
But you promised!
Give me the keys to the bus,
I only need it for a week.
You promised. Give me the keys.
I'll give you these cocks in exchange.
Two of them.
I love them as much
as I love my two children.
Make twice as much with them
as with your bus!
Here take them.
Rent another bus,
I'll pay you for it when I get back.
Your bus will be famous.
Why? There are a thousand buses!
A thousand. A thousand.
A thousand eyes will be on this bus!
See this camera?
My friend Nemat gave it to me,
no problem.
But you,
just to lend me this old wreck,
one day it's yes, one day it's no.
If you lend it, it's a good deed,
if not, say so straight away
and goodbye.
But I told you that I want it
on Friday for my niece's wedding
to decorate it.
I give, I don't, I give, I don't.
So don't. I don't care.
You're not human.
But you want my bus for two weeks.
You know how famous you'll be?
500,000 people are going to come
from different countries to see us.
You know what I'll say
when I'm up there
in front of 500,000 people?
That without you,
there wouldn't be a bus
and we wouldn't even be here today.
You'll be so famous: BBC, CNN...
In fact, you'll be known all over the
world. How famous you're going to be!
Is that true? Do you promise?
To God and His prophet.
I'll go crazy, I'll die from joy.
I agree, but promise me to go
only on asphalt roads
and you'll be careful about bumps.
Whatever you say.
And no dirt roads!
None. I'll take care of it
as if it were my own.
And you swear to change the oil often?
This bus feeds my ten children.
It's Afsaneh!
Get rid of her!
What should I say?
I don't know.
What?
Tell her...Tell her I'm in the toilet.
What? My bus is the toilet?
And you want me to lend you my bus?
Come on get rid of her.
Allo? Allo!
Hello.
It's Miss Afsaneh.
Hello, Miss Afsaneh. How are you?
My God, your wife!
Who was that?
Good day!
Shut up! I asked you who that was?
I don't know.
Tell her anything.
It was Kak Amin.
Kak Mohamad Amin, the singer?
It was a woman's voice. Don't kid me.
Who was it! Shame on you.
Let me ask him. Who was this woman?
But what woman? He's lying.
Kak Mohamad Amin had a throat operation
last year.
He sounds like a woman now.
How dare you even open your mouth?
You call yourself a man!
Shame on you.
Wife! Wife!
#l changed my name to Kako
out of love for Mamo.#
Hello.
I'm Kako, I'm at your service,
at the service of Mamo.
Please put your suitcases in the bus,
I'll help you.
Mamo said eight, but you're only seven!
One isn't coming.
Where is he now?
In his workshop.
Hello, Kak Shouan.
Hello.
Mamo ordered me to come and get you
and then to join him.
So what?
So come and join your brothers.
I told the others I couldn't come.
Even if it's Mamo's order,
I can't come.
What can I do?
I can't stop my work to come.
Kak Shouan, I don't want to insult you.
I have problems,
dear friend, big problems.
If I go, I won't be able to
sell all these instruments.
I can't just close my workshop,
I need to find customers, you know.
You see how cold it is in my workshop.
What's your problem?
I have more problems.
My wife is pregnant.
Science has made much progress.
So?
She's pregnant. So what?
There are doctors.
There are doctors and nurses
but I have a bigger problem.
What is it?
You wouldn't know. Come closer.
Really? I have the solution.
What do you mean?
Really?
No!
Come on, get up.
Come on, we'll see on the way.
I can't believe you.
How can I believe you?
Gentlemen, welcome to all of you!
Let me turn on the camera.
With your permission.
My dear Sons of Mamo,
we have a long way to lraqi Kurdistan.
For your safety and to save time,
we can't stop in restaurants
along the way.
I've got everything for making tea
in the back of the bus.
Serve yourselves.
I'm sorry, but as I'm driving,
I cannot serve it.
Kako, what's with the cockerel?
I lost his parents in a fight
and as he's an orphan...
I'm waiting for him to grow
to take revenge.
To be safe,
please put your things under the seats.
Hello, Kak Shirkooh. Sorry to be late.
It's OK. He's up there.
Kak Shirkooh...You have permission?
Yes.
Thanks to God.
My seven months of prayers
have been answered. We finally got it.
Kak Shirkooh, can I film you?
Go ahead.
I'm going to film Mamo too.
What a great man!
Hello, Mamo.
Hello, put this flag to one side.
Yes, sir.
Hello, Mamo!
Hello.
And your instruments? Where are they?
Kako told us to hide them
under the seats.
No! Take them out!
They'll let us into lraq.
I worked for seven months
to get the authorisation.
You can take them out
and stow them up top.
Let's go Kako.
Son, send an e-mail to my other sons
in Germany right away.
Doctor Majed and Mansoor.
Yes.
Ask them when they're leaving
and on which plane.
Where are we going now?
To Sortchoo.
Sortchoo?
Why?
Haven't you heard?
The water overflowed from the dam
and flooded a dozen villages.
Senoor transferred her school there.
Any human loss?
None, thanks to God.
Write!
From what e-mail address?
mamokurdistan
@yahoo.com?
Yes.
Teacher! The bus is here.
Over here!
Wait!
Don't go!
Hello, father.
Hello, daughter.
Shall we go?
Hello Mamo.
Could you come down for a moment?
I need to talk to you.
No, let's go. No need to go and talk.
What is it? Did you have a fight?
No. no fight, Mamo.
Please just don't take her.
Come this way please.
First come and see the state we're in.
Dear Mamo, your daughter is ill.
She can't make this trip.
Also, she has all these pupils.
She wouldn't come back
from this trip alive.
Bateen, what is it?
Go. Let us talk.
Why? What are you saying?
Father, I'm OK.
I've been practicing the music
non-stop for seven months.
You feel all right?
I'm all right. He's talking nonsense.
See if I have a fever. I'm fine.
Daughter, you have a fever.
Look! Stand up!
Sit down, sit down children.
They are...
School transfers.
Come on, let's get his autograph.
The floods in Beltchesoor
destroyed a dozen villages.
Their lands, houses, schools,
everything was submerged.
We set up a school here.
They have music lessons as well.
Without Senoor, we cannot do anything.
Enough Bateen. We talked last night.
About what?
We said that I would leave. Let me go.
And these kids?
Accept responsibility for a week.
No. I can't, I can't.
Children, sit down.
Please sit down.
What should I do now?
Whatever you say. It's either
your trip or these poor children.
I'll accept your decision.
Tell one of my sons to come up here.
How many are we with Senoor?
Mamo,
counting Kako and Senoor,
makes fourteen.
What?
Fourteen people.
Dear child,
I don't travel with 14 people.
You can't come.
Why?
14 brings bad luck. I won't go with 14.
Take care of the children.
Sorry Mamo, it's not my business,
But it's 13 that brings bad luck
not 14.
Go away.
It's people like you
that make 13 unlucky.
13 is innocent.
It doesn't bring bad luck.
You should stay
and take care of these children.
You too, take care of the children.
I'm leaving.
Whatever you say.
Goodbye.
Anyway, my dear Senoor...
Yes, dear father.
Don't cry, my dear.
Teach the children that neither 13
nor 14 bring bad luck.
Don't cry. Even dying isn't bad luck.
God bless.
Goodbye.
Care for these kids,
they're more important.
God bless you.
Mamo!
What?
Miss Senoor should come too.
Senoor! Why?
Well, one son just ran away.
Which one?
Shouan.
Shouan?
Yes, it was Shouan.
Where?
There.
Hey, Shouan.
Don't leave Shouan!
Stop!
Excuse me, if your voice
doesn't reach, use this.
What's this?
I brought it just in case.
"Just in case"?
It better be your last time.
Here, take this! Go now.
Hey, Shouan!
Stop! I'm talking to you. Stop!
Shouan...
Listen to me!
Sorry,
but I gave it to you to frighten him
not to kill him.
I told you to go away.
Stop! Three. Two.
One.
I told you to stop.
Shouan, let me see your ear.
Let me see if it suits you.
Mamo, look at
what you've done to my ear.
Look! I'm sorry,
I'll do whatever you say.
What else do you want?
Coward!
Do you think I came after you
because I'm in love with you?
It's a pity I spent 7 months
practicing with you.
If not, you'd be out.
Now you must come.
You know why?
You look like that foreign painter.
What's his name.
Do you know it, Shouan?
You mean Renoir?
No, no.
Picasso?
Rembrandt?
Another one.
Is it the Dutch one?
Yes. What is his name?
Van Gogh.
Yes. That's it.
You look like him.
Tell my father to come down.
Why are you standing there? Come on up!
I must talk to my father.
What is it?
Tell him it's important.
Shaho wants you.
What is it?
What is it, my son?
Hello.
We have to talk, but not here.
What?
Come with me.
Why don't you talk here?
You made me come all the way down here,
what do you want to tell me?
Would it be possible
to delay this trip?
What happened?
Last night, I saw the wise man.
What did he say?
He said to tell you
not to make this trip.
He told me
to tell you in secret
not to go on this trip.
Papa, don't go.
What else did he say?
He dreamt something bad will happen
on the 14th night of the lunar month.
The night of the fourteenth?
So what could happen?
I shouldn't do this trip?
Why not? I will make this trip.
Who wants to stop me?
For all these years,
they've stopped my singing.
This time I won't let them!
I have to go, even if it kills me.
Read me the speech text now.
All right.
"Excellencies, dear guests.
It is an honour for me, Mamo, to be
here among you for this splendid night.
As a composer and with my sons,
the first group to play the music
of freedom in free Kurdistan,
after the fall of Saddam.
Here among you, with joy I announce
that after all these years
of oppression of the music
of my country,
we find ourselves here
to listen and to witness
the rebirth of the roots of our music.
To utter a cry of freedom,
of beauty, of life
after the road we've come down.
Surely, a great part of our joy
comes from the overthrow of Saddam
and that after 37 years...
I can again see my occupied motherland
and come with my sons, to present
to you a music of love, friendship,
beauty and life.
A piece called..."
Here I have a problem, Mamo.
What's it called?
I'll say when we're there.
It's very good, but where you
put the name of Mamo and his sons,
add that a celestial voice
will also accompany us.
What do you mean, Mamo?
About a celestial voice
that will accompany us.
Who? Which celestial voice?
A voice that was lost all those years.
I hope not her.
A voice that was killed,
an extinct voice.
Not Hesho!
None of your business. Just write!
But she can't go with no permit.
At the fork, turn left.
Yes, sir.
Turn left.
Be careful.
I told you, turn left.
Mamo,
Mamo. Please don't go.
Leave me alone.
Without her, it can't be.
But so many checkpoints.
Be quiet.
Mamo, I'm begging you.
I'm begging you, please. I beg you.
Don't forget the old man's dream.
With her, they'll throw us all in jail.
It's dangerous for her and us.
I haven't forgotten the danger.
Don't orphan my child too!
Come on, move!
Be quiet.
She can't sing!
She can't sing?
She has a celestial voice
that I can still hear in my head.
Kako, Kako,
give me the gun.
You must show her respect.
For without her,
we are incomplete. Incomplete.
Stop, Mamo. Who are these people?
They're my sons.
Even if that's true,
this is a forbidden area.
They're not strangers. They're my sons.
What's wrong?
You are supposed to come on Mondays.
What's the difference?
Monday, Tuesday, any day...
You get your money, here!
Be careful, don't let it show.
Thank you. But don't forget
that this country has laws.
I know the laws.
Come on, open the gate.
Go ahead.
Goodbye.
You're welcome.
What is this place?
The place where 1334 woman
singers have been exiled.
Who is singing?
It's the voice of all 1334 women
singing. Listen!
It's like the voice of a single woman.
Hesho is here as well.
What are you doing here?
You told me to come with you.
When did I tell you that?
What do I do now?
Go back to your brothers in the bus.
#I'm waiting for the spring to come#
A bit louder.
#And colour all the meadows
and mountains.#
It was good. Sing it once more.
It's difficult, Mamo.
It's not difficult.
It's perfect. Sing again.
I can't, Mamo.
You can.
Wonderful, wonderful.
The smoke damages your voice.
Cigarettes have made you sick.
Give me the cigarette.
Let's start again.
You're ready? 3, 2, 1...
More effort.
All right, we've finished this piece.
And this other one as well.
Let's work on the Requiem.
God willing, we'll finish tonight.
Mamo, a checkpoint!
Hide Hesho! Quickly!
Get up, you!
Move fast!
Come on! Quickly!
Hello Captain.
Hello, hello.
Where are you going?
God willing to lraqi Kurdistan.
What?
To lraqi Kurdistan.
Iraqi Kurdistan! Your authorisation?
It's with my boss, over there.
Your boss?
You want it?
Great, so you are Mamo!
Yes.
Very well. You're very famous now.
On satellite, TV, radio,
they only talk about you these days.
Good. Who are these people?
They're my sons.
They're all your sons?
Yes.
Congratulations, you've a whole
regiment. What's all the mess?
It's their instruments.
Good. What will you do in lraq?
We're going for a concert.
A party, that's good.
What do you have? Opium?
Nothing.
Alcohol?
Nothing. We don't have anything.
What happened to your ear?
It got bitten.
By whom?
Family problem!
Mamo...
Hello, I'm Kurdish, from Kermanshah.
Hello.
With me here, don't worry.
At your service. OK.
My wife!
What? I'm at a police checkpoint!
Yes, a police checkpoint!
What woman's voice? It's my cockerel!
I swear it. The Captain is in here too.
Have a nice trip.
Captain! Excuse me.
It's my wife. She always thinks
I'm cheating on her.
She doesn't believe me.
Could you talk to her?
Put it away and get going.
Did you hear?
What's this dinosaur you have?
Captain this isn't a dinosaur,
it's a cockerel! It's all I have
in this world, it's my love.
Does it have the flu?
What?
Bird flu?
I could get the flu but him, never.
He's hygiene itself.
Well, clean under hygiene's feet!
Get going.
Mamo, we made it.
If you allow, I'll film a bit more.
Do we have another phone number?
Just this one.
Dear Mamo,
we're here at the border eight hours
and no one's come to greet us.
Maybe we're going against destiny.
We should turn around.
Allo!
Heiio?
Can you hear me?
Mamo, don't go too far.
It's lraqi territory there.
Come back to this side.
They shoot from the towers.
What are those gunshots?
There's been an ambush.
The road is closed?
Yes, it's closed.
The Americans are shooting
at anything that moves!
What are you carrying?
Corpses.
They are aiming at us.
I said they would shoot at us.
This time you were right.
My son, take your phone.
Don't go on lraqi soil.
Walk on the border.
Be careful.
Police! Mamo, police!
Hide Hesho! Hide her!
My God! Why all these police?
Come forward.
Everybody get out.
You lied to me!
What have we done?
So you don't have anything?
Line up over there.
But what have we done, Captain?
Quiet!
Don't just stand there, search!
Up, down, under, on top...
Your lD papers.
You, OK. ID!
Shut up!
Tell me what we've done!
Yes, why are you arresting us?
Shut up!
Here.
This picture is from childhood.
Your lD papers.
Captain, we searched everywhere
but we found nothing.
Start again. Every centimetre.
Use the dogs trained for women.
Come on, hurry up. Your papers!
Your military papers!
I only have lD.
I need your military papers.
You weren't even born
when I did my military service.
Why are you bothering us?
I'm exempt from the Shah's time.
My eyes.
And your papers?
They're at home.
I don't understand Kurdish!
Speak Farsi!
I've an exemption
from the time of the Shah.
Don't break them!
Why break our instruments?
I can't bear it! Stop!
Quiet. Stay where you are!
What do you do?
I study.
What subject?
Medicine.
Give me your student card.
I don't have it here.
A student is never without it!
I forgot it.
It's true.
It's not your business.
Give me your own lD.
He doesn't have one.
Come here. You two, come here too.
Stand over there.
They don't go through
till they bring their lD cards.
Captain, this one
has an eye exemption.
He did his military in the Shah's time.
We have authorisation. Why bother us?
I don't care. They're not allowed
to go through without their cards.
Mamo, don't get upset.
We're going to go home
and bring our cards.
How are you going to get them?
You'll never make it.
Captain! Please, don't let my sons go!
I have nothing. Please!
You have nothing in the bus?
Nothing. You can check.
That's what we're going to do.
I said quiet.
You're not going to come back!
Captain!
We found her.
Captain, please.
I can't have a concert without her.
She is guilty.
Guilty? What is her crime? Because
she sings? That's why she's guilty?
You talk too much. Be careful
or I'll arrest you all.
Captain, I beg you.
Mamo, stop. Don't do this.
What are you doing?
Come on. Get rid of these people.
Captain, he's Mamo.
All Kurdistan knows him.
They're waiting for him.
Listen, whatever happens, don't let
them cross from lran to lraq.
Get rid of them now.
Captain!
Why beg him? Who is he?
They took my singer.
Move. Step back.
Mamo, I told you I was Kurdish.
Don't worry. I'll fix everything.
I gave my number to your driver.
Come over here.
What do we do now, Mamo?
I'm going to continue on my way!
But the instruments! And Hesho!
You have no instrument, no singer.
Not even a road! Where can you go?
Wherever I go in Kurdistan,
I will find instruments and a singer.
He said he won't let us
cross the border.
How do you want to go?
That's my problem.
Those who want to, come with me.
I'm not feeling well.
I'm telling you,
don't look for excuses.
So if you're ready, get on the bus.
Rizgar!
Yes?
Bring your laptop.
OK.
See if you can find us a road.
I was searching for one
before you called me.
Both on the map and on internet...
We are...
Look.
There's no possibility
unless we go through
Western Azerbaijan.
It's far, but it's the only way.
From there we can go towards
the Turkish border.
Then there is a village called Soorab.
From Soorab to lraqi Kurdistan,
is half an hour.
Soorab?
Kak Khalil's village.
Kak Khalil?
Your friend the musician.
Kak Khalil, my friend.
That's good. Very good.
Why, Mamo?
If we go to his village,
he will find us instruments
and a singer with a beautiful voice
to accompany us.
Great. What are we waiting for?
Let's go.
No, don't hurry.
Why?
The sergeant said to stay.
He said stay in the area.
What for?
I don't know.
Kak Khalil, I'm bringing Mamo
and his sons!
Today! I promise you.
You don't believe me? Mamo is here
a few metres in front of me.
Hello?
Who are you talking to, Kako?
To Kak Khalil.
Who?
What?
He nearly died he was so happy.
You shouldn't have. Come on, let's go.
We have to fix these.
Impossible. I don't know what to do.
Do your best, we have no choice.
But how?
We just have to fix them.
#Now, all the world is
full of happiness,#
#Only my heart is suffering
from sorrow.#
I can't Mamo, I'm telling you, I can't.
We've been practicing together
for seven months.
I know you can. You're going to
have to work hard.
But you'll manage.
I don't want this money for myself.
It's for four poor soldiers.
40,000 for four soldiers!
So how much then?
4,000.
What do you mean 4,000 tomans?
Don't upset me, just give me 40,000.
What do you mean?
So, how much?
I gave you food. That's 10,000.
You slept in front of the fire
for two hours. That's 10,000.
You took a picture with Mamo
and he gave you an autograph.
Another 10,000.
I gave you something good to drink
as well. Another 10,000.
That makes 40,000.
You realise what I've done? Human
trafficking! And it's her, Hesho!
If they catch me, with this uniform,
you know what they'll do to me?
Execute me!
Mamo, can't you find someone
better than me?
My God. What are you saying?
Better than you?
Where? We've been working together
for seven months.
There's no more time.
Where could I find someone?
I'm scared, Mamo.
What's worrying you? Why scared?
That they'll arrest you because of me.
You understand?
You shouldn't be afraid.
We're incomplete without you.
I'm not going on stage without you.
Calm down, don't be afraid.
My sons and I aren't going anywhere
without you.
Do you have money?
Money? Yes.
Your bike?
No, it belongs to the police.
No need to count it. Give it to me.
Know why I want the money?
Why?
I'm going to buy petrol for my bus.
I don't have any more money.
Tomorrow, with petrol,
we'll get to Arbil in lraq.
500,000 people.
BBC, CNN...Everyone's waiting for me.
I'll tell them that, without the
sergeant-major, we could never make it.
Then you'll see, like a bomb,
your name will resonate.
You'll become a world famous
sergeant-major.
Really?
Sure! Here, let me kiss you.
Hurry. The road is dangerous.
Here take this, too.
Hurry up, go!
Mamo...
What is it?
Mamo, Hesho...!
What?
Hesho is gone!
When?
Half hour ago.
You only tell me now?
At night you fell asleep,
Hesho slept in the bus.
I just had a nap by the fire.
I was watching like a guard-dog.
I saw four people standing there
in the fog.
I heard them say: "Ho, hey, ho!"
Four people, four people.
I went forward, I wanted to shoot.
I said: "Who are you?"
They didn't answer.
I wanted to shoot,
but someone tapped my shoulder.
I turned, it was Hesho.
I got scared. Hesho said
to leave them alone.
They came for her
and I was not to follow.
What did you say?
She said they'd come to get her.
Hesho left with them.
I kept calling them. I yelled.
I ran after them, but they took her
and went till they were out of sight.
I lost them in the fog.
But Hesho gave me a piece of paper.
#Niwemang, Tangeh Beleh, Kak Khalil.#
Shirkooh, Shirkooh, my son.
Go with Shirkooh.
Get the bus ready, hurry.
What is it?
Hesho is gone.
Go with Kako and don't come back
until you find her. Go.
Go!
I'll wait at Kak Karim's restaurant.
Hello, Mamo.
Welcome, Mamo.
Mamo, how are you?
You are very welcome.
Thank you.
We haven't heard your voice
in a long time.
I was busy.
Sons of Mamo, you are all welcome.
Dear Mamo, what will you drink?
Tea would be fine.
Bring some tea.
And what do you want to eat?
What is there?
There's everything,
eggs, dizi, kebabs, ostrich...
What then?
Eggs and yogurt.
At your service.
Ibrahim, bring some tea!
And bring us eggs and yogurt.
Please everybody,
applause in honour of Mamo!
Put on one of the old tapes!
Mamo and Hesho's!
Mamo
Mamo...
Yes, Kako?
What? What's wrong with you?
I can't talk.
Speak up!
Kako?
Water, water.
Let me see? What's wrong with you?
When you sent me with Shirkooh
to look for Hesho,
we got to the mountain top.
The bus wouldn't go,
so we continued on foot.
We were holding hands
not to lose each other.
Then we saw them.
When we got a better look,
we saw there were five of them
with Hesho.
We were running after them.
But going too slow.
It was very strange.
We never managed to catch up with them.
Then Shirkooh let go of me.
He said he'd go another way.
I yelled: "Shirkooh!"
I couldn't find Shirkooh.
I heard wolves, wild animals.
It was terrifying.
Worse than any horror story!
The things I saw,
I've never seen before in my life.
What a calamity!
Then I came back to you.
Let's leave, Mamo.
Are you sure this is Soorab?
It looks different, strange.
You can be sure that it's here.
We also checked on the map.
There's nobody here?
Do you know what day it is?
Kak Diaco, this is the day
when two great Kurdish musicians,
Kak Khalil and Mamo are to meet.
Do you know what it means? All the
Kurdish channels will buy this film.
I'm not saying this
because of the money, all right?
I say it for Kurdish culture.
This is Soorab!
Why is it different?
There's nobody to greet us?
This camera is very advanced. I've been
filming with it for six or seven hours
and the tape never finishes.
It never finishes.
It's advanced? You've filmed
for so long? Let me see it.
Be careful!
Kako! There's no tape in it!
What?
What six or seven hours?
It'll only take 60 minute tapes.
There's no tape. Look.
It beeps when there's no tape.
It's not possible. What did you say?
Who gave it to you?
How could I be so stupid?
It's not important, stop!
Why was I so stupid?
It's alright!
You know how long I've been filming?
And there's nothing!
Oh my God.
Excuse me, old woman!
What is it?
Is this the village of Soorab?
No. It's #Tangeh Baleh.#
What?
#Tangeh Baleh.#
#Tangeh Baleh?#
It's not Kak Khalil's village?
Yes. It's Kak Khalil's village.
How could it be, if it's not Soorab?
It's been #Tangeh Baleh#
since the day I was born.
#Tangeh Baleh!#
So what about Kak Khalil? Where is he?
Kak Khalil's time has come. He died.
What?
When did he die?
Yesterday afternoon.
Where are the villagers?
They're at the cemetery.
What happened?
I don't know. Yesterday afternoon,
they called my father on the phone.
He spoke.
He was very happy, he was laughing.
But as soon as he hung up,
he said: "Allo, Allo" and then he fell.
We don't know what bastard called him.
He kept saying "Mamo".
He fell, and we shouted:
"Our dear father."
He entrusted his sons to Mamo.
He was so happy.
Give me the gun!
The "Just in case"?
Yes!
What for, Mamo?
Give me!
I don't have it here.
I don't have it, Mamo.
Give it to me!
You killed my friend.
Why did you call without my permission?
You?
It was him! He killed him.
I swear I didn't want to kill him.
I swear.
Who told you to call him?
Mamo, I didn't kill him.
Didn't I tell you not to call him?
Don't do it, Mamo.
He's a murderer.
We'll punish him some other way,
not like this.
Calm down.
Don't kill him on our account.
Mamo, please! Mamo, Mamo, please...
I'm going to die.
Help me.
Mamo...
Where are you going? Come back!
The dead has come to life!
Have that woman sing again,
to bring the dead back to life.
I can't hear anything.
He's passed away.
God bless the dead.
Doctor, I don't know
if he's dead or alive...
But the woman's voice made him move.
Believe me.
I've worked in this region
for 14 years.
They know that with cardiac arrests
they cannot bury without my permission.
Why don't you listen to me?
He's not dead. If that woman sings
he'll come back to life.
What you're saying isn't scientific.
I've already registered 213 deaths.
This makes 214.
Doctor,
science can't explain everything.
Some things come from the heart
and the supernatural.
Do you understand?
That woman's voice can make him
move again. Believe me.
I have work to do. As far as
I'm concerned, he's dead. Bury him.
Goodbye.
Sons of Kak Khalil!
Yes?
We came here so that your father
could find us instruments
and a singer with a beautiful voice.
Our father didn't say anything.
What should I do now?
We can find instruments,
if you spend the night.
But for a singer, we can do nothing.
Spend the night here. I'll tell
my brothers to find instruments.
I don't have time. I need a singer.
Sorry about the singer.
But that's just impossible.
My sons!
Throw dirt on me!
What? Come out of there.
Cover me. I can't take anymore.
Dear father, come out.
Tomorrow it will be OK.
Throw it, I have no more time.
Father, we still have a bit of honour.
Don't take it from us.
I'm talking to you!
Father, come out.
I said throw some earth.
I can't go any further.
Hurry and throw some dirt on me.
My time has come.
My God! My God.
Mamo, one of your sons is missing.
Where is Shahoo?
It's true, he's not here.
We forgot him.
There is a fork in the road!
To the right, it says lraq and Turkey
and to the left, it says lran.
What should I do?
Which way do I go?
To the left.
Why?
My God! What happened!
This is Mamo and his sons' bus,
isn't it?
Why, Miss?
Where is Mamo?
Where are you from?
I said where is Mamo?
He's in the back.
My God! Who is she?
Hello.
How are you, Mamo?
My child.
Hello.
Hello, everybody.
Dear Mamo, I was told to come
and help you get to Arbil in lraq.
You're not well.
Who sent you?
I will tell you later.
Why are you returning to lran?
Don't you have a concert tonight?
We don't have time.
We'll never make it.
Why?
We have no instruments, no woman singer
I have practiced with.
I will be your singer!
You sing? How's your voice?
You've heard it before.
Where?
In the cemetery!
It was you? My God!
Go the other way!
Everybody come down.
A bit faster please.
Quickly.
Welcome. This is the Turkish border.
Put your bags in the truck
and your instruments in the coffin.
They will go by the main road
by motorcycle.
We also have a death certificate
for the coffin. Come on.
Why? What will you do with us?
Who organised this?
Me.
Why trust you?
Trust me!
Listen to her, my sons.
Do what she says.
Please listen to her.
Mamo, let's go.
Why are you standing there?
Hurry up.
Hurry, don't waste any time.
Where are we going? Where?
I told you we're going together.
Where will we meet?
They all know where to go.
Don't part me from them.
Let me go.
No, Mamo.
Do whatever you must.
But just take us to our destination.
All right.
Turkish Border Guards!
Let's run!
What do I do, Mamo?
You go back.
You cannot come with the bus.
Go back.
But Mamo. I've come all this way.
How can I go back?
It's the Turkish border here.
It's dangerous.
For God's sake, Mamo. Don't leave me.
Don't leave me here.
#The earth's yellowness
is autumn's blunder#
#And the yellowness of my heart
is the burden of my beloved's absence.#
Where did you learn this?
I've practiced for seven months.
Did your parents sing?
They say my mother did.
What's her name?
I don't know.
Come on.
Let's go.
Mamo! Please get up, Mamo. Let's go.
You have to hold on, Mamo.
There isn't far to go.
It's late, Mamo. Let's go.
I can't. I can't do it anymore.
What? Get up!
Tell me who you are.
Where are you taking me? Leave me.
Don't say that. Get up.
Don't cry, and don't be afraid.
Don't let my sons go without me.
All right.
Please. Dead or alive,
take me on the stage.
All right.
Promise me.
I promise. Let's go.
What is your name?
Papoola (Butterfly).
What?
Papoola. They found me on the border.
I was little and called NlWEMANG.
What?
Niwemang (Half-moon).
It's late, Mamo. Let's go.
What did you say?
Niwemang!
What a mistake I made!
What are you doing here?
Why are you crying?
I couldn't resist.
Me, my cockerel and my camera,
we got inside that coffin.
The truck started moving.
Then I heard somebody speaking
in Turkish.
What do you want to do with me?
What do you want with me?
Nothing, my dear Mamo.
Whatever you do, don't let my sons
go without me.
I promise you.
And you promised to take me
onstage dead or alive.
Don't leave me. Don't leave me.
Don't leave me alone.
All right, Mamo, all right.
Suddenly the coffin opened
and I saw four Turkish police above me.
I don't know Turkish.
The only words I could remember,
were "Seni seviyorum" (l love you).
I forgot the meaning.
They nearly beat me to death.
And then?
They kicked me, hit me with chains!
Look what they did.
They took my coat. They took my camera.
They shaved my beautiful hair.
One of them chopped
my cockerel's head off.
He said it had bird flu.
He made kebabs with it
and ate it right in front of me.
Another one took
all of Mamo's instruments
and broke and burned them.
He broke them all.
What am I going to tell Mamo?
Where are the others?
When you sent us on bikes
to come to the lraqi border,
Turkish soldiers shot
and hit my brother.
Another brother took him back to lran.
I understand.
Go with them, quickly.
They'll let you cross into lraq here.
Where is Mamo?
You come with me.
We have to go by another road.
And our father?
He's waiting for me.
Meet us outside the concert hall
in Arbil.
What are you talking about?
Our laptop with all the notes
and information fell in a ravine.
Plus we have no instruments
and no singer.
How can we give a concert?
Musicians are waiting there,
everything is ready.
Let's go.
The concert is in four hours,
don't waste any time.
Come!
And me? What should I do?
You go with them too.
Go!