iDream
Greetings sir.
-You must save us.
- How did this happen?
What happened, Subbu?
The new ACP has baton charged.
Ravi is very serious.
This wouldn't have happened
if you were in town.
Who is that ACP?
ACP Ratnam.
He is police officerfor namesake.
But he is a rowdy.
He does everything illegal.
He is corrupt to the core.
He will do anything for money.
Very arrogant.
Awomaniserto boot.
He is little clever.
That's why he is still in office.
Since we don't have permission
for our caste meeting,
He ordered baton charge.
iDream
He should die.
Boys, kill him.
-Wait Suryam.
Why?
You are our caste leader.
4 lakh people are behind you.
Don't take any hasty decisions.
We must think & strike.
He is an ACP.
He must be handled legally.
First, speak to Home Minister.
Hello, what's happening?
You won because of our votes
and now ordered to hit us?
Who is that ACP?
Elections are not too far.
4 lakh votes.
Don't forget that.
Caste away all the evil
eyes fallen on him.
Our enemies are very angry.
Where is Madhu?
She has gone on a tour.
How many times l told you not to send
her out without my permission?
lt was organised suddenly in college.
l informed him to inform about this
when you went forthe meeting.
Didn't you tell him?
- Sorry, l forgot.
What will she do
becoming a doctor?
Why do you get angry?
Wait for a year and
she'll finish her studies.
Which place?
-Araku.
Give medicines to all patients.
How is your health?
How will he understand
if you speak in Hindi?
Now watch my Telugu language.
Spit it out.
We are leaving to Hyderabad
in another 2 hours.
Sir, are we eloping so soon?
Madhu, your upper cloth is flying away.
Where did Madhu go?
- Let's search overthere.
There she is.
What are you doing here?
lt's getting late. Let's go.
Look how beautiful this place is.
l wish l could stay here always.
That cuckoo is cooing in
a romantic mood.
lf we coo back and if it likes
our voice, it will answer us.
Really?
-Yes. Listen now.
Monkey is the right choice foryou.
Madhu, you do it.
- Do it.
Do you like my voice?
l don't love strangers.
lt was forthe cuckoo & not foryou.
Don't humans love you?
Who is he?
The cuckoo you mentioned just now.
Darling, will you divorce her & marry me?
Why are you teasing them?
lf not now, when will you enjoy.
-Yes.
Drag herto the party.
Come.
- Leave me. l won't come.
You must say ''l Love You''
to anyone you see now.
Me? Never. l won't.
Okay, forget it.
l thought you would become a great
doctor if you say ''l love you''.
Looks like it won't happen.
- Stop talking like that.
ls it wrong to think that you
would become a great doctor?
Whatever she says comes true.
- Common say it.
Shit! Don't you have any work other
than saying ''l Love You''?
What happened?
- lt's him again.
lt's all because of you.
- Look there girls.
You are beautiful, darling.
How could you go away just like that?
l too love you.
Just give me a kiss.
Just one kiss.
How could you hide yourself?
Look at me, my girl.
Show me yourface.
- Drive fast.
Driver, stop the bus.
What is it?
l will teach you a lesson. Come.
Don't you have any sense?
We were just joking.
Move. We both have to
open up our hearts.
What does he want to open?
-Just shut up.
Sorry grandfather.
l was just joking.
Even l thought the same way.
But some girls like variety.
Saying that some girls like old men,
he brought me here.
What?
Do you want to make trouble?
Who is making trouble?
You & me?
You say ''l love you'' to every
passerby on road.
Don't you have any shame?
What are you?
Girls or ghosts?
How dare you call me trouble maker!
Get up.
This is my seat.
Did you bring this from home?
- No. l paid Rs. 200 to T.T.
l've got a confirmed ticket.
Get up.
T.T. has cheated me.
Your name is Pentaiah.
-Yeah.
Are you 48?
-Any doubt?
Do l look like an idiot?
l would say my age is 80
if you were an idiot.
lt's true that my age is 48.
What is your age?
- 50.
Stop joking.
Why lie infront of girls?
You must be around 35.
Moreover girls are staring at you.
She might even say you
''l love you''
You are used to it, aren't you?
He is torturing me.
Why do you trouble her
for such silly things?
My seat.
- lt's behind you. Come.
He doesn't believe that
my name is Pentaiah.
Even l won't believe you.
-Why?
Pentaiah is my brother.
l told him to cancel the ticket.
But he sold it to you.
ldiot!
l pulled my own legs.
What happened?
Where are you going?
l missed the bag which contains
ourtickets & money.
Pentaiah might help us.
Shall we ask him for help?
You go & bring him.
Come.
-Very urgent?
Please show us something...
- She's punjabi, doesn't know telugu.
We lost ourtickets.
Save us from the T.T.
Okay. What is your name?
Why should l tell you?
Then why should l help you?
- Tell him.
Kanthamma.
-What?
lf you can be Pentaiah,
can't l be Kanthamma?
What is your name?
- Pichamma.
You said you're a Punjabi.
-Athamma singh.
All of you go to the bathroom.
-Why?
Do as l say. Go.
Why did squeeze all into
the bathroom?- Keep quiet.
Who is inside?
- Move.
ls it you Pentaiah?
-Yes sir.
Carry on.
Saw how l managed it.
What if the T.T. comes back
once we go out?
Show him the tickets.
How is it possible?
Tickets are in the missing bag.
ls this your missing bag?
Greetings sir.
ls he short-sighted?
iDream
Was he sleeping till now?
What is it?
My name is Bunny.
l am from Vizag.
Did you come from Vizag to say this?
Recommendation letter?
To Respected Appala Naidu...
Did you think l will say this.
l will slap you.
You're not so great.
You will come up only if you stop
sleeping with your eyes wide open.
A small obligation.
He is a very good boy.
My relative.
He is an orphan.
He got admission in MBA.
He wants to work & study.
So, give him a good job.
My recommendation is very high.
After reading the letter,
he will look at you.
Give him a smile.
Now he will ask you a question.
ls that idiot still alive?
My life got ruined because of him.
During my school days,
he squeezed me into pulp.
l've come to this level after
a lot of hard work.
l would've given you job if you
hadn't come with his letter.
Now, no job foryou. Get out.
l'm busy with my business.
What should l do now?
What is this nuisance?
- l don't know sir.
Sir, medical college gang is back.
When they were teasing girls,
l objected them and they hit me.
They have become a daily menace.
l will take care of them.
You refused to offer me a job
on seeing the letter.
Atleast look at my skills
and offer me a job.
What skills?
Why are you closing your ears?
l can't fight without music.
Fight & music?
- Keep watching.
Looks like you are teasing girls.
lnstead of exhibiting yourfighting skills,
you are getting beaten up.
Sorry sir. There are no batteries
in the walkman.
Play any music.
Music?
Play the music.
Didn't l tell you that l will beat them
to pulp if there is music?
Play some music.
Play some music, fast.
Someone please sing atleast.
Hit a six.
Play rough.
March ahead against all odds.
Victory is a must in a contest.
They must get admitted in hospital.
Beat them like a mega star.
Beat them to pulp.
Stop it.
He will die if you hit him more.
Superb!
Thanks brother.
You must do all kinds of work in the shop,
and should do door delivery.
Food, shelter & an egg everyday is free
Work in the morning.
Go to college in the evening.
lf you don't deliver in 30 minutes,
No pay.
iDream
Come let's go, friends.
l'm now a Hyderabadi.
lt has given me shelter.
Hyderabad is incomparable.
Everybody here is what they want to be.
We win heart with love.
lt's memorable always.
Get back & see.
Girls are so pretty.
Let's contest & fight.
This is Cyber city.
There is competition everywhere.
They love their duty & also party.
iDream
lf you think it is only a city of pearls
and bangles, you're mistaken.
lf you look at the fast growth rate,
you will be surprised.
The city is famous for Golconda,
Salarjung & Charminar.
But people are always seen
in Necklace road, lMAX theatre.
This is a city with lot of life.
This is our New home.
With life so busy all around,
iDream
Europe, America are eying us always.
The hardwork of the lT professionals,
will increase the economy
of Andhra Pradesh.
Youngsters come to Hyderabad
with lot of hopes & dreams.
lf you don't keep pace with the city,
you will be left behind.
Suryam, your daughter has
bagged a gold medal.
Her photo is published
in college magazine too.
Madhumathi!
What Madhumathi?
Where is the caste name & surname?
People will know you by
those two names.
Do not show me such silly photos again.
Did you hear what he said?
- He is a mad man.
Don't worry that he didn't appreciate you.
lf you complete your studies this year,
ourfamily will be proud to have a doctor.
Your mother would've been
very happy if she was alive.
iDream
l'm ACP Ratnam.
l've been suspended.
Everyone wants me to meet you.
You are suspended and are free now.
Any job vacancy here?
Ourtoilet cleaner quit sir.
Why are you laughing?
Not just toilet,
he will clean anything to get
back his job, won't you?
Don't worry.
l will get back your job.
Till then, he is free.
l will give him job.
He will do it.
Clean the toilet.
lf you don't deliver within 5 minutes.
l will crush yourface.
Director, once the fight starts,
our hero comes on a bike...
You?
Hey Kanthamma!
lt's interlocked.
l have to deliver pizza.
Try to understand me.
Just 2 minutes. Listen.
Order will get cancelled.
Just 2 minutes.
Try to understand.
Please sign it.
- ls she your girl friend?
She can never be one.
Can you?
She's beautiful.
Pizzas are much betterthan her.
Eat happily.
l've delivered the pizzas.
What is this?
lt's Kanthammas.
What will l do with this?
Others' belongings are like snakes.
Awoman's belonging is
like Anaconda. Keep it.
Are you buying this doll?
lt looks nice.
Buy it.
Rs. 4000...!
You cheat!
She broke it & went silently.
What are you doing there?
l didn't break it. She broke it.
l don't care about that.
Pay Rs. 4000.
l can get 4 such dolls for
Rs. 40 in Koti.
l can get you 6 such dolls
for Rs. 60 in Abids.
Better pay the money.
l can't pay you.
Will you pay or shall l call the police?
How will they pay so much money?
l don't have money.
l will pay his bill.
You saved me at the right time.
Who are you?
l'm GV, the fight master.
You drove the bike very well in traffic.
lnterested to work in films?
How can l work in films as
a hero all of a sudden...
Not as a hero but as a dupe.
Yes, there is a bike episode in ourfilm.
l will give you Rs. 1 lakh if you do it.
Rs. 1 lakh...!
-Yes, you're very talented. Use it.
Take my card.
Meet me at the shoot spot.
What did l tell you to do?
l told you to come straight. ldiot!
lt's very tough.
-You have grown very fat.
l've invited a skilled boy
to do that stunt.
He is the boy l mentioned about.
Bunny, show them what you know.
Superb Bunny.
Will you surely give me Rs.1 lakh?
l will give you once the shooting is over.
What should l do now?
Jump from that building and
land on this building.
l didn't get you.
lt is very simple.
Jump from the 10th floor & land here.
That's all.
Who will take that amount of Rs. 1 lakh?
l will give you once you come down.
How will l come down?
Only the bike will come down.
But l will reach heaven.
Don't ruin my life with your
stunts & jumps. Bye sir.
Could you give me your phone?
Sir, your daughter is on line.
Father, it's me.
-Yes.
My class hour is extended.
l would come home late.
l called up to inform you.
Why trouble yourself calling me
on phone? lt's alright.
Okay father.
Hey..
- Sir.
She said her class hour is extended.
Look in to it. - Okay sir.
He is not that good.
Finished talking so soon.
l thought you would call your boy friend.
l have no boy friends.
Why are you getting angry?
Boy friends are very common these days.
Boy friends for her!
She is a book worm.
Yes. My education is more important
than love & marriage.
ls that it?
- No. My father is a caste fanatic.
lf he comes to know that l'm in love,
He will stop my studies and marry me off.
Never again talk about
this topic, okay?
ln today program,
let's find out what the youth thinks.
What is the matter?
lf you answerto our questions,
yourfavourite song will be played.
ls it? Go ahead.
Your name?
- Bunny.
Tell me about yourfamily.
Mother, father, sisters, brothers.
l have none of them.
What?
- l have none.
So, you are an orphan.
How could you be so happy
while saying that?
Should l cry?
Only when there is no one for me
in this world, l should feel sad.
l don't have that problem.
Because people of this state
are my relatives.
Your opinion on love?
Your opinion on friendship
between boys & girls?
Their intentions would be different.
They shake hands to be friends
and do all sorts of nonsense.
Nevertrust such friendship.
Would you like to give any message
to any of yourfriends?
l will give a message to my enemy.
Hey Kanthamma...!
Where are you?
You made me lose Rs. 4000
and escaped.
l won't leave you this time.
Your studies will get stopped abruptly.
You will get married to
someone you hate.
Your husband will drink and
kick you every night.
Your mother-in-law will be a devil,
your children will be little brats
and you will face all kinds
of torture. This is my curse!
Kanthamma, why fight with him?
Return his money.
What should youngsters
do to be happy?
Words can't explain it.
- Then?
iDream
Happy! When you gaze at a girl.
Happy! When she falls foryou.
Happy! lf she kisses you.
Happy! When she own a Benz car.
Happy! When herfather is influential.
Happy! lf brother-in-law is old.
Happy! When a girl congratulates
you after dashing her,
Feel very happy! When a girl puts her
hand on you in a theatre,
Feel very happy! When your sweetheart
has no brothers,
Feel very happy! When beautiful
girls surprise you,
iDream
Happy! When a sweetie
smiles at you.
When herfather is a police,
your B.P. goes up.
Happy! When a beauty comes
to your party.
Unhappy! When she changes
her partner.
Happy! When your sister bring
herfriends home.
When herfriends are boys,
you are fooled.
iDream
Buddy, you wrote a love letterfor
my girl friend, didn't you?
Did you write such letter
for anyone else?
l gave the same love letterto
Vasu, Nandu, Swami's girl friends.
You ruined our lives!
All the girls are friends.
There is no relation between us.
Lakshmi, he is not to be blamed.
lt's all my fault.
Please try to understand.
- Don't try to convince me.
Let bygones are bygones.
Leave it.
- Shut up.
4 of like you guys can ruin lives of
all the girls in Andhra Pradesh.
ls he a womanisertoo?
Your logics about love is very good.
These apply to you only.
But for me...?
Happy! Until l don't have a sweetheart.
Happy! Until l don't fall in love.
Happy! Until l am free bird.
Happy! Until l am a bachelor.
Happy! lf l remain single all my life.
Happy! Until l am independent.
No need to punch holes
to my wallet,
No need to praise her.
No need to wait.
No need to be her servant.
No need to praise her beauty.
No stress.
No headaches. Only rest.
l couldn't attend dance classes
forthe past 3 days.
l feel very bad.
Sister, l am very hungry.
l didn't have food since morning.
Why don't work instead of begging?
l did.
But sent me out on child labour issue.
Take it.
How can l eat stomach full with this?
Now he's well trained beggar.
Trying to act smart.
Hunger sees no smartness.
Come, l will get you something to eat.
This is too much.
Sit.
You..!
l don't know whether he is sleeping
or awake. Let me check.
What?
Stop showing your monkey
face to the customer.
Sorry Sir.
- Go.
What do you want?
What do you want, madam?
Don't you have any common sense?
Get the menu card.
Very arrogant!
- lt's alright.
l will orderthe food.
iDream
Sir, coke at room temperature.
All this would cost you a hell lot.
Give the boy what he has ordered. Go.
Boy...?
Beggar.
l am hungry.
So l ordered a lot. ls it wrong?
lt is my fault.
You eat.
l will get money from my friends.
Which place are you from?
Every place is mine.
Where are you friends?
They are busy begging.
How could you eat when they
are working so hard?
Did you get my point?
Come here.
We don't have to beg for
the next 2 days.
Rs. 10000...how come?
Like this.
Don't you have any sense?
Will you supply anything he orders?
This order was given by your beggar boy.
Thank you sister.
l don't have so much money.
Pay the bill & leave the place.
Okay. l will get it from my friends.
What? You won't come.
Wait for me. l will come.
lt is my fault to have helped a beggar...
Why did you get on my bike?
Take your bike.
Planning to escape?
You cheated me for Rs. 4000.
How can l trust you for Rs. 10000?
Stop staring at me. Go.
lt's getting late.
Fast.
Stop it.
lt will take 4 days to get back
my money if you go so slow.
Get down.
Stop.
Our boss's daughter is going
on someone's bike.
See.
Wait in the parking lot.
l will get the money.
Will you come back?
lf l don't come, sell the bike.
- ls it not yours?
Excuse me.
lt's him who beat us at
the pizza corner.
You beat my juniors the
other day, didn't you?
Now beat them.
No, brother.
Please try to understand.
Stop.
lf 15 of you beat him at once,
the fun will be over in just a minute.
There will be no fun.
Each one of you play
with him for a minute.
15 minutes, full time pass.
No, brother. Please.
He is scared.
Please brother. l am on duty.
l don't have 15 minutes time.
Come in 3's.
l will finish you off in 5 minutes.
Are you all scared?
Beating 3 is very easy.
Come in 4's.
l can save time.
The other day you said you
can't fight without music.
Music is not necessary to fight.
A mood to fight is enough.
Just another minute is left.
Get 2 more guys.
l will beat you all.
Come.
Why are you crying?
A girl took away your bike.
l came to tell you but you hit me.
- She escaped again.
Sir, your daughter is coming.
Where are you coming from?
From college.
Go.
lnquire about the boy...
The girl who ran away
without giving money
has given money.
- Really?
There she is.
Good.
Bunny, a small help.
-What is it?
My sweetheart Shanthi stopped
talking to me for a week.
Please keep this letter in
her book. Just once.
How do l look like to you?
Please.
- Do l have to do this too?
Please...you will keep the
letter unnoticed.
Please buddy.
-Who?
The girl in blue churidhar.
Please.
- Oh! My customer.
Give it.
- Thanks.
Hi Kanthamma!
l have given the money.
So, don't come to me.
You talk well.
But your pizza is like shit.
Was it yesterday's or
day before yesterday's?
Everything in our shop is fresh...
just like you.
lsn't it?
Eat.
l will leave.
Father will scold me if l go late.
Buddy, you kept my love letter
in the wrong book
And she is going.
Hey Kanthamma...
My letter..?
lt is just a letter.
We can see to it tomorrow.
Your Sambar is the tastiest one.
Madhu, l want to talk to you.
Finish your dinner & come.
You eat.
Father...
His name is Arvind,
Deputy Commissioner of Police.
He is the richest man in our caste.
He agreed to marry you
on seeing your photo.
The marriage is on 10th
of next month. Go.
There are only 20 days
left forthe marriage.
We must send invitations
to our people in Delhi.
No one should be left out.
Make the arrangements.
Why all of a sudden?
What was my mistake?
Didn't you commit any mistake?
Where did you see herthe other day?
She was going with a boy on
a bike near Nagarjun Circle.
We have nothing between us.
The other day in Pizza hut...
How did this love letter
sneak into your book?
l swear l don't know.
Believe me. Please.
Stop beating a grown up girl.
Don't poke your nose in our matter.
lf people in our caste marries
someone else in other caste,
l will lose only one vote.
lf my daughter marries someone
else in other caste,
l will lose a lakh votes.
Listen to me...
- Shut up.
This marriage will happen.
No more studies.
ls all your hardwork a waste?
lf l get the one who kept
the letter in your book...
Have you organised a meeting?
Get up.
Move.
Yesterday, l kept a letter in
your book by mistake.
lt is not foryou. lt is for Shanthi.
Give it to her.
Vijay gave it foryou.
iDream
l don't understand what you are saying.
Anyone tell me.
What bloody should l tell you!
You have ruined my life.
lf this marriage happens,
l will die.
Then you will understand
how big your mistake is.
l never expected this to go so far.
Very sorry...
lf your studies are getting
ruined because of me,
lt is my responsibility
to stop this marriage.
Don't get tensed.
Conducting a marriage
is very tough.
But stopping is very easy.
Who is the groom?
Somebody Arvind,
Deputy Commissioner of Police.
DCP Arvind...?
No. He is an encounter specialist.
lt's not as easy as beating
few college students.
He uses gun like a pen.
l've a superb idea.
Shall we spread rumour
that DCP has AlDS?
Enough of your outdated ideas.
ls it DCP Arvind?
My name is Bunny.
l want to meet you personally.
What will you say after going inside?
l don't know.
But l must stop this marriage.
That's the only thing l know.
Buddy...
-Yes.
lf something goes wrong,
what remains is a dead body.
Don't worry. You will be fine.
l was talking about you, idiot.
lt's all because of you.
Wait for 5 minutes. He will come.
- Okay.
Give me a missed call
if something goes wrong.
Where is the old city gang?
Proud to be goons!
l will kill you if you repeat this.
And you...?
- l called you...
What for?
l said l wanted to talk to you.
What's the matter?
The one who is going to
marry Madhumathi...
lt's me, of course.
What's the matter?
Actually...
l've no time.
Cancel this marriage.
What did you say?
What did you say? Tell me.
Why should this marriage be stopped?
Are you trying to stop my marriage?
Why did you say that?
Why shouldn't l marry Madhumathi?
There must be a reason.
Tell me the reason.
Will you tell me or not?
l & Madhumathi are in love.
How dare you love the girl
l am going to marry?
Don't kill me. l beg you.
- How dare you love my fiance?
What do you do?
Pizza delivery...- Pizza delivery boy?
Do you know how rich she is?
l will make her my queen.
But you...shit!
l will marry her no matter
what so everyou may say.
Do anything you like.
Marry her.
You marry her.
But she will die the moment
you marry her.
l will also die with Madhumathi.
Then l will also die.
l can't live without her.
l'm late forthe next delivery.
iDream
Did the plan work out?
DCP was stunned by my performance.
You told him about your love. Fine.
Did you tell her about that?
-Why should l tell her?
What if the DCP inquires her?
Oh my God! DCP is here.
Will you call Madhumathi,
3rd year student to come here?
And you...?
Tell herthat herfiance has come.
A big clash broke out in Ameerpet.
Come immediately.
2 men are already dead.
lt's urgent sir.
Come fast.
l won't come to college
from tomorrow.
Can't you continue your
studies after marriage?
They didn't agree to it.
Someone is here foryou, Madhu.
-Who?
Yourfiance.
Him..?.
Did you say you're my fiance?
Why would l say that?
Then, what did you say?
l said we are just lovers.
-What?
Lovers?
Are you mad?
Don't shout.
DCP will kill us if he knows this.
Did you say this to that DCP too?
l told that DCP only.
DCP..?
You lunatic.
Why did you say that?
l didn't know how to stop your marriage.
So, l said that we are in love.
lf DCP asks you,
tell him that we are lovers.
Should l say that l love you?
Your marriage will be stopped
only if you say that.
lf you don't say that,
he will kill me.
l won't say that.
lf you don't say that...
Damn it! How dare they lie to me?
l will call you later.
Do you love him?
l am asking you.
Since when?
Since 5 years.
Then why don't you get married?
l want to marry after completing my studies.
You could have said this before.
l feel insulted.
l used to dream a lot.
l bought 100 silk sarees from Kanchi.
l will sell them foryou if you want.
Does yourfather know about this?
He can't understand.
l told you because you are a gentleman.
-Who said that l am a gentleman?
l'm not a gentleman.
Shall l tell yourfatherthat
the letter was for me?
lt's of no use.
l'm scared about what would
that DCP tell my father.
How dare they!
Everyone has insulted me.
l've lost my honour.
l will chop them into pieces.
l will kill them.
Be cool.
-What cool!
l am very angry forthe humiliation.
What happened?
Why are you shouting?
DCP is not interested
in this marriage.
Why?
Who knows?
He didn't tell me the reason no matter
how many times l asked him.
Father!
l'll say one thing if you
promise not to get angry.
Go ahead.
The letter wasn't for me.
Her boyfriend wrote the letterfor her.
With those books...
- Shut up!
Go away. l mustn't see you
again with my daughter.
Father...anyway the marriage
is cancelled.
You know it wasn't my mistake.
Can l go to college from tomorrow?
Please father.
- Go.
What is it Kanthamma?
You look very happy.
ls your marriage cancelled?
Can't you say thanks for it?
-Why should l?
You made the mistake
and rectified it.
This reaction for nothing!
He placed real gun on my forehead,
you know that?
How brilliantly l escaped!
Who?
Our DCP!
He's inviting us to have lunch
with him in Gandipet.
l'll not come.
- Good!
Policemen are generally suspicious,
if he comes to know the truth,
your marriage will be fixed,
l'll not come then.
l'll come.
- l'll not come.
l shouldn't have behaved
like that yesterday.
l meet only thieves, rogues, liars,
it has hardened me.
No problem sir,
you've understood our love.
That's enough.
Do you know Bunny very well?
Just 4 like you are enough to spoil
the lives of Andhra girls.
How did you both meet?
Nothing like that sir, l'll tell you.
lt was on a deepavali day,
l was sitting dull on the road after
a Pizza order got cancelled,
l heard a girl's laugh,
l was taken by her voice and wishing
to see her beautiful face l turned,
l saw a girl getting down from car
with few kids in the dark,
She lighted a flower pot,
in the flower pot's light...
the girl's legs...
...her waist...
...her neck...
...when l was about to see herface...
Madhumathi!
- lt's Keerthi reddy, you fool!
Police are very clever.
Just tell them the scene,
they'll understand everything.
He's narrating a scene from
the film 'Tholiprema',
and this man is enjoying
it as real.
Don't you watch films sir?
Films are full of lies!
ls it sir?
Then, temple scene,
a scene in smoke,
airport scene,
there are many scenes sir.
Just one scene!
iDream
Laser eyed man...
No man's land...
Don't jump O maiden...
My man is clever...
Come...come...come once...
l'll come...l'll come once...
Mischievous young man...
He intruded...
iDream
Why are you displaying your beauty?
lf a handsome is near me,
it's natural...
You can't escape from
coming out today...
Stop it man, my cheeks are
turning pink in shame...
Your sensuous sultry
beauty is inviting...
lt is in bliss falling
into your lap...
iDream
You're an elastic angel...
Tie it your heart...
Your beauty and youth
is devastating me...
Don't stare at me,
l'm getting intoxicated...
Whatever it is,
this night is festival of love...
l'm all yours and
let's have fun...
What are you thinking?
Are you not interested?
You think betterthan me
when you're cool.
Okay, l'll take leave now.
What is it father?
l was sad forthat DCP's rejection.
You too felt sad for me.
Did you feel sad or not?
-Yes.
You don't worry,
you'll get married on the
same day l had fixed.
Groom is my friend
Subba Rao's son Venu.
He's wealthierthan DCP.
Only thing is he's uneducated.
Father.
-What dear?
What have l done now?
Why are you arranging
my marriage again?
No dear, l told everyone about
your marriage on 10th.
if your marriage doesn't happen,
we'll lose ourface and honour
among our caste people.
Will you stop my marriage
for it, father?
Why are you again insisting on studies?
First understand yourfather.
Father, l'll not agree.
-Won't agree?
lf you don't l'll kill you.
This marriage will happen.
How dare you bite me!
Kill it boys!
Don't harm it.
l'll obey you.
Subba Rao doesn't like his
daughter-in-law to study.
l don't know why you
refused my daughter,
l'm getting her married on the
same day l had fixed foryou.
You're getting the first invitation.
lt has time and venue
of the marriage.
Stay away from the place on that day.
Come on boys!
iDream
Buddy, your boss is here.
Who is boss to me?
- Look there.
When did you come sir?
l would've come to you
for a missed call.
Look this.
Beautiful card!
You want me to supply pizza
to this marriage.
Look carefully.
- lt is good...
Marriage...my Madhu is...
getting married.
Don't you know it?
- l don't know sir.
What will you do now?
What can l do sir?
A pizza delivery boy!
You advice me sir.
- Okay come.
Bloody pain in the neck!
Buddy! Where?
- How do l know?
You may put me in fix,
bloody dirty face!
Look there, he's calling you sister.
Why is he here?
Sir...you here...?
l want to talk to you.
-What happened sir?
Come with me, l'll explain.
Hey you!
What happened?
- l don't know.
Tell him the truth.
Will you tell or not?
Sir...l want to tell you a thing.
- Go ahead.
l went to the place you told me sir,
he has cheated us,
he lied to us.
Lied to me?
Kill him in an encounter.
Kill him...kill him...he mustn't live.
Mood off...
lf anyone lies to me,
l feel like killing them.
Once l killed 5 people
in an encounter.
lt is common in my department.
You were saying something.
- Nothing sir.
Nothing sir.
Are the formalities over?
Why did you bring us to
the registrar's office?
You both are marrying now.
This is injustice sir.
-What?
This is injustice.
ls it a joke to marry
all of a sudden?
lf you don't marry Madhu now,
you'll lose herforever.
Just sign it, l'll take care
of otherthings.
l'll not agree.
Why?
Because we are not...
l'll talk to him,
you don't give him any tension.
Give us 5 minutes time.