So my first kiss was with a girl.
Her name was Yuri.
It sounds like a joke, but it's not.
Attending
Not
attending
Address
Name
She was on the softball team.
Popular with the older students.
She got lots of chocolates on Valentine's Day.
Attending
Not
attending
Address
Name
Congratulations on the wedding.
I'd be glad
to attend.
Suginami Ward,
Tokyo
Hoshino
Etsumi
And now she's getting married.
Coming.
Hoshino residence.
Ecchan?
So loud!
It's me, Takeda! Takeda Yuri!
Oh, hey.
Has the postcard arrived?
I already responded.
Huh?
So, are you coming, or...
I sure am.
Thank goodness.
I'm so glad!
Congratulations.
And then, on the day of the wedding...
Damn it. I can't believe I cried.
I wonder if she heard me.
She's following me!
Oh, th-thanks.
You're welcome.
How dramatic!
Oh, she's actually kinda pretty.
You're in love with Yuri, aren't you?
Huh?
I'm in the same boat.
Can you believe she asked me to make a speech?
Wanna grab some drinks?
S-Sure.
She definitely heard me.
Come over to my house.
Um...
I won't try anything weird.
My place is just around the corner.
Come on.
But...
I won't do anything!
Ahem
Liar.
This way!
Hell yeah!
Here we are. Apartment 502.
Oh crap.
It's a complete mess.
Sorry, but I'm starting to feel sick.
Like you're gonna puke?
I'm not sure.
But I want to lie down.
Are you okay?
Lying down really helped.
I touched your boobs.
See? You lied.
Off it goes!
S-Stop...
It's too late for that.
But...
What was Yuri like in high school?
She was really popular.
Was she in junior college too?
Nah, not really.
Everyone was boy crazy.
She talked about you a lot.
How you were her girlfriend in high school.
In high school...
Sorry. Don't cry.
I mean, I'm also her ex from college, so...
Honestly, she was infuriating.
You can say that again.
Though it'd be our mistake to ever think she was sensitive.
I know what you mean.
Two adult tickets.
Huh? It's fine. I can pay for myself.
Nah, it's on me.
I'm getting lunch, then.
Sure thing.
I-It's freezing!
Wanna go somewhere?
Wanna come over to my place?
Sure.
I guess we're not finished ranting about Yuri yet.
Right?
Hoshino
Thanks for having me.
It's not as spacious as your place.
It's really cute. I love it.
Do you have any yearbooks?
Wanna see Yuri, huh?
Takeda Yuri
Wow, her hair's so short!
Like a boy.
She started growing out her hair toward the end of high school.
She asked me out around the time that photo was taken.
Oh yeah?
She kissed me out of the blue.
And then just ran off.
She always was impulsive.
Where are you?
Never mind me.
Why not?
Hoshino
Etsumi
There you are.
So cute!
Jeez! Drink your tea already!
I see.
By this time, you two were already...
Must've been nice.
Ecchan...
Your boobs...
Oh, is my hair in the way?
Yeah, a little.
I like you better with your hair down.
You do?
I'll keep it down since you like it, then.
What was Yuri to us, anyway?
A mirage?
A total slut.
But she led me to you.
I'm blushing.
It's so anticlimactic.
Wednesday,\h\h
March 15th
Day duty:
\hMiyagi
I'll hand out your diplomas in alphabetical order,
so come up when I call your name.
First: Adachi Takahiro.
Yes, sir.
How lame.
Graduation should be held in a gym.
And be sentimental.
Second: Aramoto Masaki.
Yes, sir.
Also, with a female teacher...
See ya!
Bye!
Wanna go to Shimokita? Or Kichijouji?
Sounds good.
No emotion whatsoever.
A love letter would've been nice.
Though this is an all-boys school.
Mr. Sawa.
Yes?
He says he's from your class.
He was nervously waiting outside.
I'm not nervous, though.
You came all the way here to tell me that?
No.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Have any spare lead?
Nope, no girlfriend.
Is that what you came to ask?
No, not really. Well, actually, yeah.
Though I've been told I should "settle down already."
Oh, get married, you mean.
Marriage. Right.
Let's stop talking about my non-existent wife.
I mean, yeah, I guess.
You have a beautiful neck.
I'm in love with you.
What's up, Yagasaki?
Oh, I just forgot something.
But I found it.
If you'll excuse me.
Sure.
It's an exercise in futility.
My students just aren't motivated at all.
It's not a matter of seriousness.
More like they just don't care what happens in the world.
I totally get that.
Have a nice night!
Bye!
Shall we go?
Yeah, I've definitely had too much to drink.
The year just flew by.
Hey...
Yes?
Never mind.
Aw, what is it?
Now I'm curious!
Yagasaki Shinya
I'm in love with you.
Oh man.
I could die right now.
I'm like a blushing young schoolgirl dreaming of a rosy future.
A shiny, bright dream.
But that was a year ago.
Nothing ever came of it.
We will now commence our graduation ceremony.
All graduates should return to their classrooms.
At least, I think it was nothing.
Congratulations.
I'll be handing out your diplomas,
so please come up in alphabetical order.
Too obsessed with Yagasaki. Too much fantasizing.
A sweet, sweet fantasy.
Hey, that song's a classic.
I'm touched! Just kidding.
If he fell for another guy, so be it.
Acorn Bar
This is the place. It's on the fifth floor.
Welcome!
Table for two.
Certainly.
There's one over there.
Really? That's your sister?
Seriously?
Oh my.
Maybe I'll buy her a beer.
I was shocked to see you.
Me too.
Right?
Tanabe
Tanabe?
We're living together.
Or rather, he's letting me stay.
This used to be an old-timey love hotel.
Oh yeah?
I'm home!
Hey.
Five of us together at once!
Insane, right?
Wow!
Is my neck beautiful?
Huh?
Dunno.
Looks normal to me.
What's that about?
A non-flush toilet!
Sir, I just can't stop pissing.
How lame.
Hurry up in there!
Yoriko.
I love high school kids.
Huh?
But they toy with me, the punks.
Yeah, sure. Just go to sleep.
Spittin' image.
Huh?
Of who?
No idea.
How long has it been?
Three years?
Looks like he's been through a lot.
No kidding.
My sister's dancing 'round and 'round.
Even though she keeps saying to stop because it's embarrassing.
On second thought,
you look nothing like him.
At all.
Morning.
Morning. Breakfast is almost ready.
Well, I'll see you later.
Bye.
Um...
Please take care of my sister.
There was dancing yesterday.
Who was?
You and your boyfriend.
Oh, stop.
I want to be a part-timer too.
I thought you loved high school kids.
I want to be part of the circle.
Dancing 'round and 'round.
Another year flew by.
Our graduation is so lame.
At least it's simple.
Tuesday,
March 12th
Day duty:
\hSugita
Hey, how about we do a thank-you party for me?
Not ready to say goodbye?
I'd really appreciate it if you'd throw a party for me.
What the hell?
Fine.
This one's for you, Mr. Sawa.
You're paying for it, though.
The sky was so beautiful.
Maybe that's what made me say it.
Let's go to your place next, Mr. Sawa!
Yeah!
No way. It'd be too cramped.
It'll be fine!
We can all squeeze in together!
I guess that's okay.
More than okay...
There's a big, old house I know about.
We can go there.
Yeah!
When I told them it was an old love hotel,
they freaked out.
Which problem are you on?
Number three.
You working hard?
Why don't you take a break
and have some watermelon?
Thank you.
It's so cool in here.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah.
Call Sayo. Dinner will be ready soon.
Okay.
Get out here, Sayoko.
It's like a sauna in there!
Of course it is.
But you guys didn't do it!
Of course not!
It's dinnertime.
You're in sixth grade already.
Fifth.
Okay, sit down you two.
Why doesn't she go home?
Sayo was kicked out.
Serves her right.
Let me see the video later.
Sure.
Honey!
You should watch it too, Shin.
You're the devil.
Sleep over tonight.
I'll talk to your dad tomorrow.
You're the best.
Thank you for the food.
Let's eat.
Hey, studying hard?
I'm doing way better than when you tutored me.
I gave you a good foundation.
Don't smoke in here!
This is my room, you know!
Jeez! You'd better put that stuff back when you're done!
"Talk about your first period or ejaculation with your friends."
Hey, got any hair on your balls yet?
No!
Lemme see while it's still silky smooth!
Get off of me, you pervert!
Mom! She's sexually harassing me!
So smooth!
This is the video?
Yeah.
She graduated from college and then shot that.
What an idiot.
Did you watch it?
No way!
Let's watch it.
What?!
Stop it, Mika! We'll get in trouble!
I'll mute it, then.
That's not the point!
Mika, you should have some cold noodles too!
I told you we shouldn't.
There you are.
Did you get into a fight?
It's not funny!
Just do it with her already.
I can't do anything like that!
You say that, but I'm sure you're curious.
Crap! Titties!
What about 'em?
They're huge.
Lemme see your dick!
What's going on up there?
So? Did you see her dad?
I did, but...
"I didn't let her move out on her own to make some awful video."
He wouldn't say a word after that.
Can't say I blame him.
You'd better not have watched that video.
I haven't. I swear.
Mika, you idiot!
Am I in the closet again?
I'll sleep in the closet today.
You know, we can both sleep out here.
It's fine. Night.
It's hot...
You'll be steamed alive in there.
Night.
Hello.
Hi, Mika.
I brought cherries.
Oh, thanks.
Shin's washing his underwear right now.
You didn't have to tell her that!
Did you wet your bed?
No.
I didn't!
So don't go spreading rumors!
I won't.
How far did we get yesterday?
Um...
To here.
Are we going to get married?
What the heck?
Have some cherries.
I tried one. They're really sweet.
Good.
You too, Sayo.
It's so hot in there!
Hey, I'm the lady from the video.
Nice to meet you, Mika.
Sayo.
Coming.
She's my cousin.
Wow, it's really her!
Don't tell anyone in class!
You should come to my place tomorrow.
Okay.
She's got the hots for you.
No, she doesn't.
Jeez, who do you grade schoolers think you are?
That's enough! Put your clothes back on!
We're way too young for this!
Tateishi in the sixth grade already did it with an eighth grader.
Seriously?
Are you in love with Sayoko?
How did it come to this?
I'm home.
Welcome back.
You're still here?
I'm leaving tomorrow.
You are?
I know you'll miss me.
Did your dad forgive you?
No way.
Did you do it with Mika?
Nope.
Goodnight.
But it's still light out.
And you should change.
Yeah.
If you're lonely, you should just say so.
I got used to you being around, that's all.
Wanna suck on my titties?
You're the devil.
Sayoko went home?
Hey, Sasaki and the others are at the pool.
They'll probably tease us.
I'm home.
They're stubborn, but they wanted to thank us.
Shin.
Washing your underwear again?
Sasaki wrote me a love letter.
Told me to break up with you.
"Promise me you won't show this letter to Shinichi.
If you do, I'll have to challenge him to a duel."
A duel?!
No!
Shin! You start school today.
I don't wanna go!
I'll protect you if it comes down to it.
I haven't done anything wrong.
I will not have anyone fighting in my class!
I'm saved.
I'm home.
Hello.
Do you have more homework?
Yes.
Study hard.
We will.
I can tell you now that I was lonely.
What are you talking about?
When Sayoko was around
Shin made me promise not to say anything,
so I wasn't planning on telling anyone.
Hey.
Is it true your cousin did porn?
So what if she did?
So it's true? Wow!
It was a long time ago.
Have you seen it?
Let's go home.
I wish I could see it.
Did you know his cousin was in a porno?
Die.
Yikes.
Are they doing it?
That was ages ago.
Rumors never die.
I told Emi not to tell anyone.
And I told you not to tell anyone.
But...
Bye.
I'm home.
Hi.
Curry?
Your brother's coming home, so I made it kind of spicy.
I hope that's okay.
I'm kind of excited.
Shin's class is doing a haunted house.
Mika's going to sing a solo in her choir.
Really? That's awesome.
We're all going.
Can you make it too?
What time is it?
It starts at one o'clock.
37th Annual
North Junior High School Festival
It could use some more flowers.
Shall we add a few more?
Still have the video?
Nope.
Shin's watching!
I wanted to die.
You're still blushing.
My voice cracked.
I'm so embarrassed.
Bye.
Yeah.
I'm tired of watching this.
I still don't know how to make myself cum.
Pretend this is Shin's hand.
I really hate the rain.
I love the rain.
If it starts raining when I'm watching TV,
I mute it and listen to the rain.
It calms me.
Maybe you're just really tired.
Or you're oddly obsessed with imagining yourself listening to the rain.
How rude!
You've changed.
Huh?
I liked you better when you were a boy.
What's that supposed to mean?
But I still love you.
You and Yabe are pretty close.
Right?
I voted for you two for best couple.
Me too.
Look. They're taking down the sign.
There go the flowers.
Taking all the blackout curtains?
Just three of them.
I've seen people doing it here.
Emi and I watched in secret.
Lots of people do it here.
There can't be that many.
I'd do it with you.
No way!
Where are the blackout curtains?
Shinichi's getting them.
By himself?
Actually, he went with, uh... Tokunaga from Class 6.
The two of them...
In here!
Did you do it?
Do what?
I bet you they did it.
Right?
Blackout curtains
I always prefer the day before than the day of.
Huh?
The school festival.
Oh, yeah... Me too.
Don't watch when my class is singing.
You just squeezed them.
You never know about these things. Oh, they're back.
I'm home.
Sayo's getting married next year!
Isn't that great?
Yeah.
Where's the wedding?
Come in.
Are you still mad about before?
You said I could.
You said you loved Sayoko.
I never said that!
But I could tell.
It's annoying how you're popular and don't even realize it!
I feel better now.
I'm going to start a diary today.
My first entry will obviously be "That idiot Sayoko."
Choir recital for each class begins at one o'clock.
I guess we got nominated for best couple in eighth grade.
Yeah.
The prize was a condom. The note attached to it said, "Don't let the teachers find out."
We blew it up like a balloon.
Or maybe we didn't.
Happy-Go-Lucky Days
I cheekily sat some shampoo bubbles on top of your head
I playfully glanced your way and teased you saying you forgot to wash it out
After you washed it out., the shampoo ran down your body., but it still smelled the same
As fun as it was., it meant we found that our soap supply never lasted long
The roads we took were always one and the same
The sky we gazed at was always one and the same
Even the key chain we kept our keys on was the same
Each and every thing we did was exactly the same
The happiness we shared returning to the same home
The happiness we shared laughing at the same TV shows
This impression isn't even close
You made fun of me for how bad it was
It was nowhere close., but I wondered if maybe there was the smallest chance it could be
Even though you were crying., I was just laughing., blissfully unaware
It was nowhere close., and no matter how much you cry now., it's still an awful impression
It really wasn't even remotely close., and no matter how much you cry now., it's still an awful impression
The unhapiness we shared getting mad when our opinions differed
The happiness we shared accepting our feelings were different
You weren't even looking at me for who I was at all
You were being torn apart and things weren't all right
But if I pretended not to see., I wondered if maybe there was the smallest chance they could be
But you laughed., and so I just laughed., blissfully unaware
The fond memories of those days we spent
That happiness we found in every day
I have a feeling that somewhere it all exists even now., I'm sure of it
You've gotta find it
It was nowhere close., and no matter how much you cry now., it's still an awful impression
It really wasn't even remotely close., and no matter how much you cry now., it's still an awful impression