(MultiCom Jingle)
(dramatic music)
(gasping)
(gun banging)
(spurs clanking)
- Get up.
I said get up.
- What are you, a law man?
- Nope.
- He's mine, Kanning.
- I don't think so.
(rooster crowing)
- Maybe we can all share, huh?
- This has been a long
time coming, Kanning.
(upbeat western music)
(guns banging)
(spits)
- You're the one they call
The Holy Ghost, ain't ya?
(horse neighing)
(light music)
(thunder booming)
- Who's there?
(horse neighing)
Who's out there?
(dramatic music)
- Mr. Bartell was disappointed to hear
you turned down his offer.
- I ain't got no gun.
- I always like to make it a fair fight.
(thudding)
(guns banging)
(horse trotting)
- Kanning, back early.
$2,000, right?
Let's go.
(upbeat music)
(people talking over each other)
- You must be quite near a
rich man by now, Kanning.
- You'd think so, wouldn't ya?
If I didn't spend half of
everything I made in here.
- You lookin' for company?
- Donnie here?
- Well no, she's busy right
now, but here's Glory.
- I'll pass.
It's nothin' personal.
(moaning)
(knocking)
- [Man] Go away, this ain't your room.
- Donny, Kanning's back.
- Okay Cowboy, your time's up.
- [Man] Hey, I ain't finished yet.
- You are now.
- Dammit Donnie that ain't
fair, I was just about there.
- You were finished 10 minutes ago,
you were just pretending.
- Well hell for two bucks if
I wanna pretend I got a right.
- If you wanna pretend,
go home and pretend with your wife, okay?
- Jesus, Donnie, I'd have to
pretend I was in another state.
- Well maybe if you took
a bath once in a while
she wouldn't make you sleep in the barn.
- Hey, I pay good money to come up here.
I don't need the insults.
- That'll be two bucks,
the insults are free.
- I ain't gonna pay it.
There's no reason why I should.
- I can think of two real good reasons
why you should pay up and get out.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
(door slamming)
- You got no respect!
I paid good money.
I don't have to take that kind of crap.
You know one of these days one
of them whores is gonna go too far...
- Hi, Cowboy.
(groaning)
Are you ready?
(whip snapping)
(man screaming)
(knocking)
- Come in.
Hello, Martin.
- Hello, Donnie.
- You've been gone almost a month.
- Seems like two.
- Did you get what you were after?
- I guess you could say that.
Can't say that it was worth it, though.
Pull.
I think I'm gettin' to old for this.
- Maybe the bad guys are
just getting younger?
- Younger, faster, smarter, meaner.
- You just need some time off.
- I think I need to retire.
- Oh right, what are you gonna do,
raise chickens, farm pigs?
You couldn't say put for longer
than a week and you know it.
- I don't know, Donnie,
got a lot of parts on me ain't
working' like they used to.
- I don't know.
The only part I'm interested
in seems to be workin' just fine.
(horses trotting)
- Oh!
Just the way I like it Cowboy, oh yes!
Oh, more, that's it.
That's it, yes!
Yeah!
- You sure do look pretty Miss Jess.
- Why thank you, Willy.
Are you all set?
- Yeah.
- You think you can handle it?
That'll be $2.
- It's so damn hot I wish it would rain.
- They sure ain't wastin'
any time hangin' Mawbry.
- No sense is prolonging the agony.
What do you suppose it is makes people
wanna watch another man hang?
- Couldn't tell you.
- They seem really sure that the sucker
judge is gonna find him guilty.
- Well if he wasn't guilty,
I wouldn't of brought him in.
- Have you ever been wrong?
- Well if I was, I don't
wanna know about it.
- These came in last week.
Take your pick.
- What the hell this boy do
to get a $10,000 price tag on his head?
- Kidnapped and murdered
some ranchers daughter.
He put up the reward himself.
- They sure he did it?
- Couple of eye witnesses.
He was seen two days ago heading
this way out of Santa Cruz.
- I'll be back.
(horse neighing)
(horse trotting)
(light western music)
(door creaking)
- Well Mr. Bartell, except
for the men, everybody's gone.
The town's yours.
- And the Willow Mine?
- Your boy needed some persuading.
- Well, well, that is
real good work, Carver.
Here's what I want you to do,
you take the next train
to No Trees and I want you
to file this at the
land office there before
anybody gets a chance
to ask any questions.
- Well, aren't you forgettin' something?
- What's that?
- Persuading is extra.
- Well,
just so long as your negotiating tactics
don't land me at the
short end of a long rope.
Oh and Carver, one more little thing.
- What's that?
(sighs)
- Remember who pays your salary.
- Good day Mr. Bartell.
(spurs rattling)
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
I don't like to shoot
anybody I don't have to.
Especially so early in the morning.
You Bradly Hope?
- Are you a law man?
- Nope.
- I didn't kill anybody.
(dramatic music)
- Well, if I don't have to
shoot you before I get you back,
you can tell it to the judge.
(gun banging)
- No!
(light music)
- You got a family?
- No, sir.
Her Daddy didn't want us
to get married is all.
I didn't hurt her.
I swear.
(train roaring)
(squeaking)
(dramatic music)
- A little out of your
territory aren't you Mr. Carver?
- Well Sheriff, I'm in a new line of work.
Regulator for Bartell Mining.
- Oh, and what kind of business
would Bartell have in these parts?
- Big business.
The kind that makes a lot of money.
- Well this is a quiet town,
I'd like to keep it that way.
(laughing)
- I'm a respectable business man, Sheriff.
Don't worry, you won't have to sober up.
(upbeat music)
- Rachel, I know you took 'em.
I know you took my earrings,
now give them back to me.
- I didn't take nothing of yours.
You don't have nothing I want.
- Rachel you are the only
one who knew where they were.
- Maybe you misplaced them.
- I did not misplace them.
- What's going on here, girls?
- She stole my earrings.
- I did not.
- Is that true, Rachel.
- She's always in my belongings,
she always takes things
that don't belong to her.
- Maybe they just fallen behind something.
- See.
- Rachel, I'm sick of you!
- Ow!
- I want my earrings!
(yelling over each other)
- Now, now.
(bell ringing)
Hey, hey hey.
- Ow.
- Ow, get off me, cow!
- Now you got two seconds to
shut up and get back to work.
- Silly old blonde cow.
- I want my earrings back, Rachel.
- I swear with all the constant
bickering and complaining
it's a wonder a customer gets
serviced around here at all.
- You took those earrings
didn't you, Rachel?
Come one, give them to me.
I said give them to me.
Come on.
What's the matter with you, Rachel?
Why do you do things like this?
- I couldn't help it,
Donnie, they were pretty.
I wanted them.
- You can't keep taking things
that don't belong to you.
Do you understand?
Rachel.
(light music)
- [Rachel] Oh, Donnie.
It's beautiful.
- It was mothers.
Please don't lose this.
It's all we have to remember her by, okay?
- I won't.
I promise.
- Okay.
- She wouldn't have liked
it much here, would she?
- No.
- I miss her.
- I know you do.
You're so beautiful, you're just like her.
Come here.
(horse neighing)
- [Woman] Get out, whores!
(bottle shattering)
(fire crackling)
- Donnie, Donnie!
Donnie, somebody help me!
Donnie!
Someone help me!
Help me, someone!
- Oh, my God, get some water!
- Help!
Donnie, help!
- Jesus.
You don't drag 'em in, you know.
Let's go.
Don't worry it's just
somebody else's husband
had a better time here than
they have at home, okay?
- Honey it ain't about you.
- It coulda been my window
just as easy as yours.
Glory, I'm sorry about everything.
- What the hell is goin' on up here?
- Well as usual, you're
about five minutes too late.
- Just get it cleaned up, okay?
Don't make a meal out of it.
- Maybe we should just leave, Donnie.
Just move on to another town
or maybe even California.
They found nothing but gold and--
- Sweetheart, it's not just about
this town or that angry wife.
No matter where we go,
it's gonna be the same.
- So what are we gonna do?
- Remember when Rachel had the fever,
or Jess got that snake bite?
What did we do then?
We all pulled together.
That's what we're gonna have to do now.
We're gonna pull together
and hold our heads up high.
- Okay.
- We can save our money
and maybe buy some land.
- Yeah, somewhere where nobody knows us.
And we could be respectable ladies.
Maybe even get married.
- I've seen the way Harper looks at you.
I think he's sweet on you.
(gasps)
- Oh, get out, Donnie.
- Mr. and Mrs. T-bone Harper.
Has a nice ring to it, doesn't it?
Okay?
- Okay.
- Okay, you're okay now.
(horses trotting)
- I've never seen him come
back empty handed before.
(horse neighing)
(dramatic music)
(bottle shattering)
(screaming)
(gun banging)
Show's over.
- Let's go.
(people talking over each other)
(banging)
- Jesus, Martin, what are you doing?
- Get lost.
I said get lost.
- Martin.
Stop it.
Martin, stop it, you're hurting me.
What happened?
- I was wrong.
I was dead wrong.
(moaning)
- Your time's up, put
your money on the table.
- What are you talking about?
- You heard me.
If you're gonna treat me like a whore,
then you're gonna pay me like a whore.
- Look, Donnie.
- You're the reason I stayed
in this dust drenched town.
Rachel and I shoulda moved
back east a long time ago.
Do you have any idea what it's
like to walk down the street
and have the women talk behind your back?
And the men turn their heads?
Even the ones you were
with the night before.
- Donnie, I'm sorry.
- You're sorry?
That's a first.
- You remember you asked me one time,
how I live with myself?
Do you remember?
Live with what I do.
- Martin you just shutdown.
You shut everybody and
everything around you out.
- That's right.
Well I can't do that anymore.
(horses neighing)
(door slamming)
Come here.
- Right away.
May I help you, sir?
- I wanna cash these in.
- Ah, there's 22,000 of vouchers here.
- That's right.
Those are federal pay
vouchers, I wanna collect.
- They're perfectly legal.
The problem is we don't have that
kind of cash on hand right now.
I'll have to send to
the Federal Reserve Bank
in San Antonio for the funds.
- How long?
- Oh, two or three weeks, give or take.
- Two weeks, give or take.
- What have you got in the safe?
- $10,000 in cash, some security notes,
and the mortgage on the saloon, sir.
- That's it?
- I'm afraid so, sir.
I could let you hold the
mortgage as collateral.
- I got a better idea.
- What are you doing up so early?
Hm?
- I need to see Harper.
- You need to see Harper?
No, you need a bath and
some shaving rather.
He's not here yet, and the bar's not open.
- It is now.
I own the place.
- You own the place?
What does that mean?
- It means I'm in a new line of work.
- Oh yeah, what do you know
about running a business?
Huh?
- Nothing.
- Well I guess he'll make
up for it in personality.
(light music)
- That'll be two bits for the bath.
- Two bits?
- You may own the place, but the bath,
just like the rest of
the services aren't free.
- [Kanning] Put it on my bill.
- [Donnie] Oh, Martin.
(laughing)
So, Mr. Proprietor, are you
ready for Saturday night?
- What do you mean?
- Oh I can tell what kind of
saloon owner you're gonna be.
- What's the big deal?
Harper sells the whiskey and you ladies.
Well, you sell what you sell.
- And who do you think does
the ordering for this whole downstairs?
Or gets the clean sheets for the beds?
Or the hot water for the baths?
Who do you think does that?
- You do all that, don't you Donnie.
- No, Harper's been doing that.
He's been filling in.
Now it's your job.
- Well, I better get right to it.
- I almost forgot.
Some of the boys came down
from Lazy Eye earlier.
One of them pulled Jess in your room,
I hope you don't mind.
You know how spontaneous
those boys can get.
- You sure look pretty tonight Miss Jess.
- You know you're my favorite, Willy.
(light music)
- Damn, Jess.
I wish my wife could do that.
- That'll be $2.
(horses trotting)
- You gentlemen check out the bank.
I'll be in the saloon.
(spurs rattling)
(people talking over each other)
- Hi, you lookin' for some company?
- I'm lookin' for a card game right now,
but don't go nowhere darlin',
'cause I'll be lookin'
to spend my good fortune.
Deal me in.
(laughing)
- You're having an unbelievable
streak of luck, Cowboy.
- Must be my lucky night.
Get us a bottle, darlin'.
Least I can do is buy
these losers a drink.
- Glory.
Go on upstairs.
- What?
- I said, go on upstairs.
- What the hell is
wrong with you, Kanning?
I ain't had a decent customer all night.
Shit.
(chuckling)
- Full house.
- Last time I checked there were
only 52 cards in a deck, Cowboy.
- You just made a mistake, Mister.
Get up.
- I've got no gun.
- I don't care, I said get up.
- Keep your seat, Sam.
- This ain't none of your business.
- It's too late.
- Call it.
- Harper, the bell.
On three.
(bell ringing)
(gun banging)
- I always like to make it a fair fight.
(booming)
(muffled screaming)
(gun banging)
You should watch your back, Kanning.
- Never had any reason to, 'til now.
- What the hell happened?
- Well, I'm sure they're
wanted for somethin'.
- You know I think I
liked it better, Kanning,
when you went out lookin' for them.
All right, let's clean this up.
I need to have a word with
you in private, Mr. Carver.
- Whatever you say, Sheriff.
- This round's on the house.
- You wanted to see me Sheriff?
- Yeah.
You've had plenty of time to
finish up your business here,
it's time you were movin' on.
- Well I don't know, Sheriff,
maybe I got some new
business to attend to.
- And what would that be.
- I'm not rightly sure yet.
- This is a peaceful town.
Suddenly you show up and
I got dead men everywhere.
- I reckon you oughta
thank me for that, Sheriff.
Justice is served.
- Carver.
You ain't a law man anymore.
- I took care of things for ya.
So you can go on and crawl
back in the bottle of hooch.
I think I'm gonna stick around in case
there's anything else
I need to take care of.
You never were much of a law man.
(horses trotting)
- How much did I make?
- Not nearly as much as you could have
if you keep your mind on business.
- Where are you going?
- I gotta see the Sheriff.
- What's wrong?
Damn you, Kanning.
You're just like all
the rest, you know that?
(clicking)
- A little edgy, aren't ya?
You know Bartell Mining pays real good.
I could always use another gun hand.
- I think one lackey's enough, don't you?
- I guess those whores must keep you
pretty warm at night, huh Kanning?
- Thanks for coming.
What do you know about Randall Carver
and the Bartell Mining Corporation?
- I know Bartell's got a lot
of money, owns a lot of people.
Usually gets what he wants.
- And Carver?
- Stay away from him.
- I gotta uphold the law.
- Well that ain't gonna
matter much to Carver.
He sorta makes up his own law.
- I know he was a Texas
Ranger and your partner.
What I don't know is what happened after
the massacre at Nogales Mesa,
that changed all that.
- That was a long time ago, Sheriff.
Some things are better left in the past.
- Unless that past has
come back to haunt you.
He ain't done nothin' yet,
but it's like sitting on a
powder keg with a short fuse.
You got any idea what he's up to?
- Nope.
- [Sheriff] You gonna keep an eye on him?
- That ain't my job.
- Prove it.
- That's my weddin' gown and you know it.
Everyone knows it.
- This just looks like yours, Jess.
A riverboat gambler in Louisiana gave this
to me for being his good luck charm.
- That's just one of your
made up little stories,
you little liar.
- I am not.
- What the hells goin' on up here?
- Well, Rachel has a little problem
with things that don't belong to her.
- It's mine.
- Is not!
- It is.
- It is!
- Donnie, whose is it?
- It's Jess's.
- Well then give it back.
- I won't.
You can't make me.
Here's your wedding gown.
That ship sailed a long time ago anyway.
- You mind tellin' me what
the hell that was all about?
- She's still hoping that a man
is gonna take her away from all this.
- It's gonna be a long wait.
(upbeat music)
Little young to be
drinkin', ain't you son?
- I didn't come in here for a drink.
- What can I do for you?
- My Pa' gave me $2 for my birthday.
He told me I should spend it here.
- Take your pick.
- I like 'em both.
- That may be a little dangerous, son.
- [Benjamin] I think I like the brunette.
- Jess will take care of ya.
Go on, you scared?
- Kinda.
- They ain't gonna bite ya.
Gotta pay extra for that.
- Hello.
- What's your name, Cowboy?
- It's Benjamin, ma'am.
- Well, we're gonna have a
real good time, Benjamin.
- Oh yeah, this is your lucky night.
We see it's a birthday special.
Two for the price of one.
- That's right.
- Almost feel sorry for the boy.
- He's gonna get his $2
worth, and then some.
- He's gonna go down
those stairs an old man.
- Oh, buy me a drink.
- Hey, Cowboy.
You look kinda lonesome.
- Think so, huh?
(humming in agreement)
What's your name honey?
- My name's Rachel.
- Rachel, huh?
Well, Rachel, why don't you
go up and get us a bottle
and come back and keep me company.
- Whiskey?
- Who is that?
- He works for Bartell Mining.
Name's Carver.
- No one's mining this far north.
- I know.
- I've see that look before,
Martin, I don't like it.
It's that man Carver, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- What'd he do to you?
- It's not what he did to me.
Five years ago we were both Texas Rangers.
We were tracking these
killers down in Nogales,
we split up, he found 'em.
Pinned 'em down and tried to burn 'em out.
First people that came
through the smoke were women
and children, he didn't
care, he open fired.
- And?
- And nothin'.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- You are so welcome.
- Come on, have a seat.
- That's a boy.
- [Glory] Rules out, Benjamin.
- [Jess] Pretty little scarf.
- [Glory] Why don't you
just relax, Benjamin.
Jess will you give me a hand up here.
I think that's good
enough, don't you Jess?
- [Both] Are you ready, Benjamin?
- Yeah.
(giggling)
Whoa.
- This, is gonna cost you.
- It already has.
- Is that your gun?
- Yup.
- What a shame.
- You don't know how much
I'm lookin' forward to this.
- So am I, Cowboy.
- How long you work for Kanning?
- Oh, I'm self employed.
- You do it with him?
- Oh yeah, all the time.
In fact, I'm one of his favorites.
He might even marry me.
- Is that so?
(humming in agreement)
(chuckling)
Then I guess if something
were to happen to you,
he'd be real upset wouldn't he?
- Oh yeah, you'd be so sorry.
He'd just go crazy mad.
- Then I guess this'll
be a night to remember.
(gagging)
(crying)
- Donnie, Donnie!
(frantic knocking)
She's dead.
Rachel's dead.
Donnie!
- Rachel.
Oh Rachel.
Sweet Rachel.
Why would anyone do this to her?
- Jess, go get the Sheriff.
- Still such a child.
- I found the wallet.
She must've took it from him.
(sniffling)
- It was him, the guy
from the mining company.
He killed her.
(horses trotting)
What are you gonna do about it, Sheriff?
- Well it seems fittin' she
should get a proper burial.
- No I mean, what are
you gonna do about it?
- Well, I'll contact the federal marshal
in Abilene and we'll proceed from there.
- Proceed from where?
He'll be long gone by then.
Why aren't you going after him?
- Donnie, both you and I
know that Rachel was...
- Rachel was a whore.
Because she's a whore
you're not going after him?
(dramatic music)
If the guy had cheated at
cards or if he'd robbed a bank,
just because she's a whore.
- Donnie, I'm doing the best I can.
- No, you're not.
You're afraid of him!
You're a coward!
What about you Kanning?
You've tracked men for
weeks with nothing more
than a picture on a piece of paper.
I guess it's just a question
of money with you two.
What's the bounty for
killing a whore, Sheriff?
$2, $5?
Yeah, I guess it really wouldn't
be worth your while, would it?
- Ain't my job, Donnie.
- You're right about that, Mr.
Kanning, it ain't your job.
(door slamming)
(light music)
This is it.
This is her proper burial.
Rachel was a good girl.
There's not even a preacher here.
- You know everyone loved Rachel.
- I think every man that ever
afforded the price of your
company is gonna be standing
here weeping when you're gone?
- Donnie, don't.
- It's true.
No one's gonna stand up for us.
- What are we gonna do?
- We're gonna stand up for each other.
(upbeat music)
(whip cracking)
- What are you doing, Donnie?
- What does it look like I'm doing?
- You're gonna get yourself killed.
- [Donnie] Well at least
we know we tried something.
- You can't go tracking Carver.
- And why's that?
The job was up for grabs,
no one else wanted to do it.
- Listen to me.
Getting yourself killed is not
gonna bring back your sister.
- You just don't understand, do you?
- You can't do this.
- There's only two things I can't do;
one is make love to a woman,
the other one is piss up a wall,
and right now there's only one of those
I regret not being able to do.
(dramatic music)
(horses trotting)
(whip cracking)
- Ladies.
(chuckling)
And not a camp fire.
Ah, ah, ah, ah.
Now, is this anyway to
make four lonely guys
like us feel welcome?
Now then, we feel welcome.
Hello boys.
We're gonna have a little fun.
(gun banging)
- You ladies are gonna have
to do better than that.
- Sure is a good shot.
- Not bad.
(guns banging)
(bottles shattering)
- That's not bad.
You're not gonna have the gun
in your hand the whole time though.
Gotta be able to get
it outta your holster.
- I will.
- All right, good.
Do your thinkin' before you draw.
Jess, you're aiming too high.
Glory, well, you just stay low.
- Is he gonna keep sneakin'
up on us like that?
- Yeah, he gives me the willies.
- Okay, let's ride.
- Don't get too comfortable Carver.
Remember I pay you to take
care of things out there.
- My men will tell me if there's anything
I need to take care of personally.
- Well, you might just
wanna think about this then,
your men, the ones you sent
to propriate Cotton Ranch,
they ran into a little trouble.
- What kind of trouble?
- Well it seems their
bodies were left with
the Sheriff in White Rocks
yesterday, by three women.
Well I guess respect just don't go
as far as it used to, does it?
- Kanning.
- So is it personal
enough for you now, huh?
- Shooter.
Bounty hunter named Kanning, you know him?
- Heard of 'em.
- Well, he's headed here from
White Rocks with three women.
Take some men, see they never make it.
- Yes sir, Mr. Carver.
Pony up.
(horses trotting)
(gun banging)
- What the hell did he do that for?
- Come on, let's take it slow.
(light music)
- They'll be here soon.
I know it.
This is gonna be like
pickin' crows off a fence.
(clicking)
Wait 'til they're in range.
Put 'er down, boys!
(guns banging)
What the hell's goin' on here?
- Hey!
(guns banging)
I don't think so.
Drop the belt.
Get up.
I said get up.
You work for Carver?
- Yeah.
- You take him a message.
You tell him there's no amount of money
is gonna buy him peace of mind.
Do you understand?
Get outa here.
Martin, I know what you're trying to do,
but this is our fight.
- Just the same.
They know you're comin'.
You're gonna need help.
- Suit yourself.
But Carver's mine.
(upbeat music)
(gun banging)
- I figure everybody's
entitled to one mistake.
- You know your dirty business is startin'
to make me feel real uncomfortable.
You take care of this,
Carver, you hear me?
I'll be damned if I were to
have some gun totin' whores
turning my town into a free-for-all.
- Bigs?
- Hm?
- You just got promoted.
Now, put a couple men in
the north road into town.
Get somebody standin' on the hotel roof,
tell him to keep his eyes open.
If he sees anything move, kill it.
I don't want anybody getting
into town unannounced.
(wind whistling)
- [Man] Whoa, hey, hey,
what's goin' on here?
- [Man] Looks like
Curly and Jake's horses.
- [Man] Hey everybody,
come on, look at this.
- [Man] What's going on?
- [Man] It's Curly and Jake, they're dead.
- [Man] How'd it happen?
- [Man] I don't know.
- [Man] Oh, come one,
let's go tell the boss.
He's not gonna like this.
Last I saw they went out with Shooter.
- [Man] They ain't never came back.
- [Man] Mr. Carver, Mr. Carver!
The horses brought back Curly
and Jake and they're dead.
It musta been that bounty
hunter and those women.
- Well unless all of you
wanna end up like these two,
I suggest you find that son of a bitch
and those three whores he's
got with him, you got it?
Now spread out!
(door slamming)
(wind whistling)
(spurs rattling)
(dramatic music)
(gun banging)
(groaning)
(guns banging)
- Hey guys!
- We're closed.
- Sorry.
(gun banging)
- Damn you Carver.
I warned you.
You're supposed to be
looking out for my interest.
Where the hell are you goin'?
- I got a score to settle.
(door slamming)
(light dramatic music)
(gun banging)
(pounding)
- [Judge] Court will come to order.
Martin Kanning, you have been found guilty
of gross negligence and
dereliction of duty,
resulting in the death of innocent people.
This court therefore strips
you of your rank in the Rangers
and sentences you to two years
hard labor at Yuma Prison.
Sentence to be carried out immediately.
- Justice is served.
(fire crackling)
(light dramatic music)
(guns firing)
- Jess.
Jess.
It's okay, just stay still, Jess.
- I got 'em Glory.
(wind whistling)
(gun banging)
- Hell of a time to run out of bullets.
(dramatic music)
I always like to make it a fair fight.
(gun banging)
- Now, it's a fair fight.
Justice is served.
(gun banging)
(light music)
- It's a long ride back.
- I'm not going back.
I hear there some nice
farmland east of here.
- Jess, Glory, you okay?
- [Jess] Yeah, I'll be all right.
(upbeat music)
(thunder booming)
(MultiCom Jingle)