- Nick.
- What?
- Come on.
- Hold a sec.
Look at this.
Strange, isn't it?
- Strange, isn't it?
- Sorry, I did it accidentaly.
I'm so sorry.
This strange place is no longer inhabited.
Rumor said that this place was a murder scene.
Hey, how do you know?
The news is already widespread.
I don't know.
Shit.
Okay, okay, I relented.
This is for you.
What is it?
What do you want?
- Why did you do that?
- I didn't mean to.
Who did that?
- Not me.
- He said it was you.
Fuck.
Hey, don't be scared!
Hey, wait!
Don't run! Wait for me!
What will happen after that?
Just get there alone.
Sorry.
Hello? I don't have time.
It's like that, not like the others.
Okay, okay, I understand.
You better wait until I give the news.
- What does he want?
- How do I know?
- I know.
- Why didn't you say anything.
Come quick.
He always like that, always full of himself.
I can't stand him anymore.
If you can't stand anymore, forget it.
It's not that easy.
What you ladies know about it?
I just want to know the record goes.
But everything isn't according to plan.
You're not tired?
- Don't disturb me now.
- I disturb you?
- You don't like it?
- So what?
Listen, I'm so....
What would you say?
Don't, I want to go to the toilet.
Don't stay long.
What's wrong with you?
What?
What are you talking about?
Don't be like that.
- I don't trust you anymore.
- What else?
You said you'd keep your promise.
But you're not.
It's not like that.
Crazy!
What's that? What?
Hey, hey.
Hey, you're famous.
You are so famous.
- What happened?
- What did I say yesterday.
Hey, all thanks to my idea, isn't it?
Indeed, but not entirely your idea.
- Hey, Ghostland offers us someting.
- What?
- What offer?
- Check the offer first.
Indeed, it will definitely work
for us all.
What do you mean?
- About it.
- You listen to it.
Hello?
Alright.
Okay.
Yes! Yes!
- What is it?
- Maybe he has something.
Why do you look so happy?
Did you win a lottery?
- What If I really did?
- Don't need to be like that.
- There'll be a lot?
- Lots.
What can I do for you?
Sir, the issue is very important.
Well, if it's like that. I'll try.
Okay? Do your best.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- How?
- That's what I said, right?
- True.
Actually, not like this.
But it's very risky.
Sorry?
Actually, it is very appropriate concept.
Just not the same.
Honestly...
- Dangerous.
- What project do you mean?
A project.
Hajima project.
It happened in Nagasaki.
Does anyone know where Nagasaki is?
Don't explain it halfway.
Do you want to know?
It exists in Japan. Do you know?
I've never been to Japan.
So what?
- What does it mean?
- How did you get there?
You need to cost a lot. Lots.
- Seth.
- What?
You know, we need his approval.
- No problem, it's an easy matter.
- Really?
Don't you ask for the money later?
I won't, this time definitely so.
What about you?
Will you go there?
We'll talk more later.
This problem can be discussed later.
Please think about this again. Alright.
- What? Are you going?
- So what?
You don't have to worry like that.
The project is very dangerous.
But the project is far away to Japan.
But that's not the real problem.
- What is the real problem?
- What?
Don't you know?
You all know, money issues.
- Not a problem.
- Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Why?
- Tong?
- Okay, okay, okay.
- Yes.
- The others?
- Excellent.
- All right, we'll go.
- What are you doing?
- Why did you?
Actually it's not a big deal, isn't it? You can do it.
Actually it's not a big deal for him.
Hey, Ken, how about you?
He would agree anyway.
What will be approved?
You know why, you'll know.
- What are you thinking?
- What? Nothing.
Come on.
Actually... I...
- Shit, I could actually get it.
- It's all your fault.
Let's toast!
He want to say something to me
but he didn't dare.
- You don't need to be afraid.
- Hey, what are you talking about?
What is it?
It's okay, just a small problem.
Hey, you don't need to be such a smartass.
You'll see. I'll avenge.
We'll go to Japan.
That's right, in Japan,
There's a lot of fun there and Sato-san will pick you up.
Are you ready?
No, no, not like that.
Ah, this is fun.
- What's up?
- Good.
Hello, sir. we've arrived here safely.
You will be accompanied by Sato-san there.
Alright. Everyone follow me.
How are you all?
I'll be your guide here.
- Oh, you're not Japanese?
- Oh, you're not Japanese, aren't you?
Of course, none others.
Sato-san, how long we'll get to Hajima?
It's not far to Hajima.
only a few hours from here.
You should withstand this long trip
You shouldn't be separated from each other.
Sato. Sato-san, is it still far?
Yeah, how long will this last?
What's wrong with you?
Relax, chill out a bit.
It won't be much longer.
Understood, sir.
Listen, listen, she's like that (grumbler).
Alright.
Towards Nagasaki!
Excellent!
Sato.
- Where is the restroom?
- Oh. There, right there.
Wait a minute.
Don't piss carelessly.
I would ask people.
Yes, yes!
That's the goal. Winner.
- That was a good kick.
- Yeah, don't watch it.
I like a good team,
because they surely win.
- You'll see.
- Sure?
- Take it easy buddy, take it easy.
- Yeah.
Earthquake is definitely frequent here.
I think because it's close to the mountain.
Never mind.
- This is the hotel you are staying.
- Pretty good.
- Of course, a direct view to the mountain.
- Mountain?
What's that boat for?
- For the fishermen.
- Is there any nightclubs here?
No, there isn't. This is remote island.
This island also has many cemeteries.
Follow me.
Hey...
Why we're on vacation in a mountain full of graveyard?
It's not cool at all.
We'll find a pleasant place here.
- Then, see you later.
- Yes, see you later.
- Be careful.
- Yes, goodbye.
I go.
Come on.
- Excuse me.
- Welcome.
Come on.
- We are going to the toilet. You're coming with me.
- Yes, watch my stuff.
Yes.
Wait.
Me too.
- I'm going to the toilet.
- Hey, don't run away.
This is really troublesome.
Look, a beautiful woman,
She was beautiful.
She's beautiful but a bit strange.
What is it? She's amazing.
I know, she's beautiful.
It's heavy.
Hold a little while.
Like a bad omen.
You're scaring me!
Sorry.
What are you doing?
Can I see?
Where did you take pictures?
Oh, beautiful. Keep on, keep on.
I feel something bad here.
- I don't like this palce. What do you feel?
- What I feel?
Something..
I don't feel anything.
Come on.
Stay with me.
I want you here with me forever!
You must be with me forever!
I want you! I won't let you go.
Never!
Let you go!
How dare you disturb me!
Sorry to keep you waiting.
- All right, let's go.
- There's no time.
- Yeah, come on.
- Let's go.
- Well, well, well.
- Hey, hey, hey.
You see that photo there.
Looks like the women we saw yesterday.
You're dreaming a lot,
it could be her daughter.
You must be scared.
- You must be scared. Sato-san, here.
- Don't joking around. Never mind.
Please, please, please!
Ask him who's the person in the photo there.
Who is it, on that photograph there?
She was the wife of the owner of this building,
died during the earthquake.
Her name is Miko-san. She was the wife of the owner
of this building who died here.
It's weird.
Sato-san, it's weird, we saw
a woman just like her here.
Only few people stay on this place.
And there aren't many Japanese here.
Sato-san, I saw her.
I don't know.
- Miko buried here as well.
- Miko is a strong woman with a child Keiko.
I convince Miko to build this inn.
Miko was sick and couldn't get up from the bed.
So, she's always stay in her room.
- The sea is beautiful!
- The cruise is wonderful.
We never thought that there will be a happy beginning.
On our creepy trip.
It's for our memories.
Be careful.
Here, let me help.
Look.
Old buildings.
Come on.
Look at that.
Let's go, come here.
- Put all the stuff here.
- Ok.
- Hey, wait for me, I'm coming.
- Yes, I'm just around here.
You're here, coward.
This is really terrible.
It's a great place.
Hey guys, read it.
Read it... Sex place..
Wow this is a great place.
Hold a sec.
It was a settlement,
many people were falling from above,
When an earthquake occured, due to mass panic.
- They were encouraging each other to jump.
- Yeah, so a lot of people die here.
- Isn't it?
- No, no. Lower your voice.
- Sato, Sato, take it easy, we're just recording.
- I'm sorry.
Relax?
- Here we go again.
- Yeah, come on. 3, 2, 1.
Let him do the talking.
Yes, wait a minute.
- Don't go in there.
- It's okay. Wait for us here.
Okay, time for us to investigate.
Hey, you.
- Is this? Is this all?
- Yes, I've been walking here.
What?
What is it exactly?
Only this?
It's very fun.
There's something I need to tell you?
But I don't know what is it.
And that too?
All of it.
Is that it?
Give me like that, you already understand.
I'm very mad with you.
- Off?
- What?
What are you doing?
Nothing, I just want to write my name here.
Are we here for that?
Yeah, I know.
Damn it all.
What's this?
Ah.
- Are you done yet?
- Yes, but we still want to go again.
Why they're here?
Alright.
Aren't you scared? Let's stop all of this.
Goodbye to you all.
Only this?
This place hasn't been occupied for a long time.
Sato-san said that as long as we don't disturb them then it's okay.
Is that so?
We men go first, you follow us from behind.
Yes.
So what are we gonna do?
So, what are "they" look like?
So, are we together with "them" here?
So, what makes you like them?
What's wrong?
So we'll run again?
So what are you doing so far?
I already feel like it.
- What do you feel?
- Nothing at all.
yeah, I never feel.
- What are you doing?
- I'm spining it.
Thank you.
- Useless.
- All right.
What's wrong?
I'm here, what do you want?
So, what did they say to you?
I'm scared.
There is...
Look at this.
It's quiet here, nothing strange.
What is it?
What happened there?
I'm so scared, hey, what is it?
Let's get out of here.
Hey.
This is all.
We've been investigating this, so what
else do we need to know?
I already feel like they're here.
I understand what you mean,
So what you want to say?
So you already found.
All of "them"?
Sato-san, do you think we're here to have fun?
Maybe when we get there, we'll meet them.
Hey, stick around.
Maybe if you investigate it, you'll know,
and you'll like it.
Are they here?
- Yes
- Did you break it?
- Why are you here?
- Yes, I understand.
- Careful, we don't know what happened here?
- Yeah, I know already.
How many times I told you that they're here?
Like this?
Can you walk?
So, we have to approach them?
What if they're approaching you?
Have you ever heard their voices?
What for?
Are we done? let's go to other places?
Excuse me.
So they already know we're here.
I can't understand you anymore, I'm the worst.
Imagine if you're here, I can't imagine that.
Impossible.
I have no idea.
- Don't ever do...
- Yes, I understand.
Hurry, it's going to fall.
Come on, hurry!
Hey, do you want to save them?
Hey you guys...
- Hey...
- Why do you come here?
No!
Everyone, hurry!
I'll have the roasted crickets.
- Here. Thank you.
- Thank you.
Bye.
Let's try the roasted crickets.
- Disgusting.
- It's crispy.
- You'll be hooked.
- I don't want.
- You'll get stomachache if you eat it.
- Look how cute he is.
Enjoy your meal.
You're crazy.
- How does it taste?
- Like a chicken.
Hey May, what do you think?
Scary place for our next trip.
- Suitable for our project.
- After all, we've come to Japan.
We have to finish it.
- What about the equipment?
- I'll fix it tomorrow.
- I don't believe that ghosts exist.
- Don't be too sure.
It could appear anywhere.
- How are you all?
- Nick.
- Hey, good night.
- Good night.
- Nan, are you alright?
- I'm alright.
Be careful, you begin to sound like crickets.
What are you talking about?
We went to the island of Hashima.
Hashima Island?
The place was very creepy,
you've gone mad?
We must work on our college project.
What college project?
Why must go to Japan?
We want to prove that ghosts exist.
- Proving that ghosts exist?
- True.
If that so, why do you do a project like this?
Is there no other way?
- It's challenging.
- Challenging? It's useless if you die.
Do you know how many people died in Hashima?
- We know.
- Then why did you still want to go there?
You are young, now is the time to enjoy your life,
why don't you find yourself a girlfriend?
Especially you. I say to you,
change the project.
There were many people in Hashima at first, but
because of the war, many died and the rest left.
We don't plan on staying there.
I thought you guys think there is a hotel there.
Hey. I heard every night,
there's a woman crying there.
Anyway, let's toast.
Hey! Damn.
Why are you suddenly appeared,
I thought you were a ghost.
Bad luck.
Who are you?
I decide my own destiny.
Isn't that scary?
True.
Hey waiter. More drink.
- Where you going?
- The toilet.
I hate you!
Damn, I thought she was a ghost.
Damn.
- Ouch!
- I'm sorry.
- Is it safe?
- It's safe.
Don't go anywhere, I 'll be right back.
Off, open the door.
Are you there Off, open the door.
Help me.
Show me the video.
Halo.
- Nick. Everything is ready?
- Yes it is. I was going to go.
- I'll go there.
- I'll be waiting, this is creepy.
I told you, that ghost is following me.
- Maybe it's just your feeling.
- Many strange things have happened since we went there.
- I know what I saw.
- Off, We can't go before we finish the project.
Let's stop all this project.
Hey. I heard a problem,
what happened?
I want our project is stopped.
Why?
- That woman ghost is following me.
- Maybe we should postpone this?
You'd better stay alert, pesky star is
following you.
Well, this special event,
let's get started.
Let's get started.
What do I say, I've warned you
to ensure all the works.
This is an important event.
I leave!
This is just a small delay,
I'll clean it up.
I know it.
Yes.
We'll talk about it later.
What the hell.
Hey, power is lost.
Quick, turn it on!
Quick, turn it on now!
Well then.
Who's there?
You belong to me.
We will live together.
We will be together.
Stay with me.
Please don't.
Off, what happened?
Don't bother me.
I'm worried about you.
Don't interfere.
It's not your problem.
Why don't you tell me?
It's not your problem. You don't need to interfere.
Better mind your own problems.
This is not your problem.
What's wrong with you?
Who do you think I am?
- Why?
- What?
I'm worried about you.
I told you this doesn't concern you.
You ....
Off, You there?
Off.
Open the door.
Did you hear?
I want to visit.
Are you there?
Off,
Open the door.
Don't you hear?
Off,
I know you're hiding there, Off.
I'm not going to force you to come out.
It's up to you.
Alright.
I'll take anything.
You're his friend, right?
Hey, we've got guests.
We're going to do something.
What do you want?
We 'll have fun.
Relax.
I don't want to.
- Let go of me.
- Shut up.
Off, Off.
Shut up.
Hey, open the door. Fast!
Hey, quick, open the door.
I'm here.
Off, help me.
Hey, don't do it.
- Open the door.
- Please.
Off, help me.
I told you, Shut up!
Hey, open the door.
Don't do it.
Hey, don't.
Don't do it!
Open it! fast!
Hey! Open!
Hey! Open the door quickly!
Hey, open the door!
Off, do you hear it?
I raped her.
You should understand.
Off, your ring is nice as well.
I'll take it.
May, what happened?
What is it?
May
Who did this?
Tell me who did this?
Those who did this?
Are they that did this to you, May?
- I hate you.
- May!
Off.
What is it?
Why don't you say something?
Off, say something!
Huh?
What do you hide?
Are you a sissy?
You're a man right, Off?
Huh?
You're a man.
You should beat them, Off.
Huh?
Alright.
Don't say anything, Off.
Just shut up until you die.
Have you seen this ring?
Nope, not at all.
He sends a message.
What did he say?
It's nothing.
I'll call.
Not answered?
Not answered.
May
Where did she go?
We are looking for the owner of this room.
He screamed and ran upstairs.
To the top?
- May!
- May, stop!
- May, don't do it!
- May, don't do it.
- May, get back here!
- Come on.
- We'll help you.
- May
- Come back May.
- May, don't do it!
- May!
May
Arrive already.
Where have you been? Dagluk.
It's all because of you!
What's wrong with you?
Why are you angry? Dag?
Wait, Dag. Dagluk.
Dagluk...
Dag!
Dag, open the door.
- Leave me alone!
- Dag, open the door.
- Go!
- What's wrong with you?
Dag, let's talk.
Come on, open the door.
[ SOUND OF RADIO ]
Hey...
What the hell?
Hello?
Right, we'll send it.
Alright.
Dag! What's wrong with you?
Open the door!
Dag, open the door!
What happened in there?
Dag, talk to mom!
[ SCREAMING ]
Do you know what happened?
Aunty, what happened?
Dug is gone.
The ghost keeps coming.
Don't talk about it to anyone.
Don't let anyone know.
So what do we do?
- It's all because of you.
- How could I know?
What should we do?
Meng, Koh, and all our friends.
What happened to your hands?
You ask too many questions.
Bastard.
Good afternoon.
- This is it.
- Right.
Wait, let me check.
- Hey, come here!
- Gosh.
What happened to them?
Have you seen this before?
He didn't answer.
If you don't want to be friend
with me, go away then.
- I didn't mean that.
- I don't care Whatever you mean. I'm out.
She committed suicide, it wasn't my fault.
It was her own stupidity.
- She committed suicide after a quarrel with you.
- We don't quarrel.
It's because her own stupidity.
- Why are you angry?
- It's not your business.
So what? Don't be like a little kid!
You're a jerk!
Why is this happening?
What did I do wrong?
It's crazy.
It's not fair.
Why is this happening to me Dog?
Why is this happening to me Mai?
Listen, I want you to show up Mai!
Look at this ring, I love you Mai!
Get out!
Run!
- What is this writting?
- It is written in blood.
- What are you doing?
- Shut up.
Dog.
Off.
This is it.
We found the answer.
Run!
Hey, wait.
Come quickly!
Come on!
Friend, this is one big journey.
I'll challenge you later.
Hey, maybe he doesn't dare.
Whatever it is, I'll do it.
This is from the police, we find your two friend bodies.
Call me when you get this message.
I'm sorry.
Li!
Li, get out of there!
Li, hurry, open it!
Open, Li!
Where have you been this whole time?
I, I've been waiting for you.
I'm waiting for the promise that you gave me!
Come, come with me!
Li!
I promise I'll always be with you.
Eventhough it's in the next life.
- Really?
- Yes.
I promise you.
I promise I will always love you,
Even if it's in the afterlife.
Li!
This is a terrible ghost story.
Really?
That's where the ghost are.
Translated from bahasa Indonesia to English by rio_275
Please excuse the bad grammar.