Hello.
Good morning.
What brings you here?
I have an urgent letter for you.
Thanks.
Make yourself at home.
And stay as long as you like.
Are you going somewhere?
I have to leave immediately.
Fernando Carneiro
Alberto?
You look like an outlaw.
I'll pass by your house tonight.
I started working at Don Fernandes' place.
And now I live there, too.
It was dangerous living here alone
with he boy.
And how is my nephew?
He's at home.
I came as soon as I heard
you were back.
Why aren't you dressed in black?
The boss doesn't want
other people's sadness in his house.
I've come back to
take you away with me.
Your brother was killed
at the Hill Reed Bed.
But where exactly?
They say it happened
over near Pimenta's land.
I'll go and fetch the sheep.
Things are getting worse all the time.
Your brother was killed by bandits.
There are ambushes in the reed beds.
It seems like most of the sheep
have been stolen.
There won't be many left for us.
I'm here to avenge my brother's death.
I have to go to work.
They'll have noticed I'm missing by now
I'll pass by later to say goodbye.
You don't have to wear those rags any more.
Your brother's clothes are over there.
Take whatever you want.
He would've liked that.
I was sad to hear that
you'd left the mission over there.
Thanks for writing to let me know.
And I'm sorry.
You were the last person
I wanted to hurt.
But I wasn't born to follow rules.
I had to breathe in my own way.
And seeing other worlds
brought with it other needs.
I just hope you don't get lost, my son.
What do you plan to do now?
I came to sort out my family's affairs.
And to take what belongs to me.
So, are you planning on taking Noémia
and the child with you?
Yes.
They're my responsibility now.
Be careful, my son.
That might not be what she wants.
Is there something I should know, Father?
— What are you doing here?
— Fetch Fernandes for me.
Come round the back.
Go on.
Give your uncle a kiss.
Where are you going armed like that?
I'm going to find your sheep.
And the shepherd's murderer, too.
How much is the reward?
My workers are all scared.
After what happened to your brother...
I want to know where they are
and who's got them.
As soon as I heard you were back,
I knew there'd be trouble.
But I'd rather it was you
that fetched the sheep.
The only trouble I'm bringing is for you.
Just because your old man died
and now you're the Lord of the land,
it doesn't mean that
the people here are your slaves.
I see you don't plan to stick around
for too long.
When I leave I'm taking Noémia
and my nephew far away from here.
We'll see about that...
I need a horse.
A shepherd on horseback.
This I've got to see.
Rent it to me.
I'll pay you back with a week's work.
Just bear in mind that my horse
is worth much more than your twenty sheep.
Paulinho!
Prepare him a horse.
Stop!
What's going on here?
No one passes here.
Don't move a muscle.
What's your name, traveller?
Who wants to know?
António Bacelo.
Captain of the Royal Guard.
At your service.
Alberto Carneiro — mountain shepherd.
A shepherd?
Riding a horse?
I'm on my way
to retrieve some stolen sheep.
Then I have to tell you that
you must pay a toll.
But this route is free.
Listen...
your horse grazes, does it not?
And drinks water, too.
So you have to pay.
I don't owe anything to anybody.
Besides, I plan to return this way
with a flock of sheep.
And then I will pay what's due.
Then I must inform you that
you shall not pass...
without me defending myself
against such disrespect.
Listen, I don't want any trouble.
I just want to be on my way.
According to Article 10 of Chapter 9
of "The Duelling Code",
you have the right
to choose your weapon.
Or you may use your own,
if you so wish.
Choose your weapon!
If you leave me no choice,
mine is already loaded.
You have to the right to choose
the place of combat.
Right here will do.
No. It must be on flat land.
One, two, three...
four, five, six, seven, eight...
nine, ten.
According to The Duelling Code,
when one of the participants is not killed,
but merely wounded,
he has the right to revenge.
I'm sorry, but I don't intend to kill you.
So what can I get you?
A glass of wine.
What brings you to these parts?
I'm a shepherd.
So where are your sheep then?
I'm looking for them.
Some of them were stolen
when they killed my brother.
The others have been found
and retained by the King's officers.
Where are you from?
Covas da Serra.
So you're António Carneiro's son?
That's right.
I knew you when you were just a lad.
But there are so many bandits
around nowadays.
Weren't you a priest?
And I thought you went to America, too.
I was never ordained as a priest.
So now you've come back
to this damned place to get into trouble?
I had to come
and settle my brother's debt.
Apparently he was killed by a gang.
Watch what you say, son.
The walls have ears.
Unfortunately, things aren't
what they used to be.
You can't even trust the King's men now.
Yesterday I had the pleasure
of meeting Bacelo.
He wanted me to pay a toll to pass.
But he regretted it.
Careful!
Things are really different nowadays.
You'll still be crossing
Pimenta's land today.
Keep your money!
And this one's on me,
in memory of your brother.
Thanks very much.
Good morning.
My name is Alberto Carneiro.
I've come to fetch the flock.
We've been waiting for someone
for the past few weeks.
Are these the only ones left?
These and some others
scattered about here and there.
They didn't take them all
because they can't hide them.
And things left unhidden
may soon be found.
Careful! There are things
that one would rather not find out.
The agreement is four sheep per hundred
for you, right?
That's what was agreed.
So it's ten animals then.
Nine and a half is no good to anybody.
Right?
Thanks.
Take the ones you want.
What I'd like to do
is come back for them tomorrow.
I'm going to try and find the rest.
It's a deal.
I've waited for this long,
I might as well wait another day, eh?
Thanks very much.
Sit down.
Come and eat with us.
You look famished.
Thanks.
Don't be scared.
We don't hurt hungry people.
Our issues are with the authorities.
Discontent is everywhere.
Yet the king is proclaimed
as a great saviour wherever he goes.
Dog of Hell!
We should do the same to him
as we did to his brother and father.
What are you doing around these parts?
I've been abroad for a few years.
Things were very different when I left.
Now I'm back because bandits
killed my brother. He was a shepherd.
So I'm here to settle the score.
Do you know who did it?
He was passing by Pimenta's land.
I was hoping you might know who did it.
Put it down!
It wasn't us. Put it down!
The only argument we have is with
the King and his men.
I'm sorry for having taken you for bandits.
Apologies accepted.
And don't worry, Pimenta's men
won't come anywhere near here.
Some of the village's sheep
are grazing over near Marvao.
The only problem there is the King's men.
We're heading that way.
We can help you, if you want.
Sometimes a man on his own goes further
than a whole battalion.
And you've got your own fight.
I've got mine.
Thanks very much though.
— Good morning.
— Which way is town?
— That way.
What about the Hanged Man's Field?
Is it in the same direction?
Yes. It's that way, too.
Thank you very much.
Take it easy, my friend.
— What do you want?
— I'm not here to cause trouble.
— Who do these sheep belong to?
— They're mine.
And yet they have different brandings...
Let's sort out who these sheep
really belong to.
You're going to come with me
and clarify that.
Please sit down.
Thank you.
So what brings you here?
I've come to tell you
I've found a meadow with stolen sheep,
just a few kilometers from here.
Some of them are mine...
And you are?
Alberto Carneiro, mountain shepherd.
Aren't you the one who
wounded Captain Bacelo?
That was in self—defence. He tried
to rob me in the name of the State.
That's a matter for Justice to decide.
In the meantime, I've orders to arrest you.
— What about my sheep?
— How do you know those sheep are yours?
My brother was murdered
and most of our sheep were stolen
back in the Autumn.
You know that much, for sure.
And this gentleman's sheep had our brand.
We'll look into the sheep issue.
But you shall not leave here.
And don't worry too much —
I've heard that Don Fernandes
has already sent
two of his labourers to fetch them.
Give me your gun.
Good morning.
Américo.
Alberto Carneiro.
Alberto Carneiro?
I'm a shepherd.
Eh?
I'm translating a book into my language.
So it can be read and taught here.
I don't understand.
You've got half an hour outside.
Step to it!
Don't come any closer!
Stay calm!
I only want a light.
Now clear off!
Relax!
It doesn't look too difficult
to break out of here.
So stay cool.
Good evening, gentleman.
Evening.
Are you ready?
We're going to escape.
Would you like to come with us?
No.
I'm only here for the night.
Can we have one of your guitar strings?
Is one enough?
That'll be more than enough.
Thanks.
Let's do it.
Don't worry. We're safe here.
They'll only find out
we passed this way tomorrow.
Take a rest.
It's better than freezing to death.
How could anyone
escape from a prison like that?
I don't know what to say.
I've no idea how it happened.
And to cap it all, you tell me that
you don't have enough men to catch him?
I don't.
They have to send them from HQ.
We've only got a few men here. And to
be honest, it's not a serious offence.
Besides, they won't get far together.
Let me tell you then.
I will catch him myself.
Have you seen a shepherd with a moustache
and a black man?
Up here in the hills
no one has passed through.
— If you see them, turn them in.
— Why are you after them?
No questions!
Alberto! Alberto!
I have to head upstream, Américo.
I'll help you find your way soon.
But in the meantime, stick with me.
Come on!
Stop!
Put your hands up!
Put your damn hands up!
And to cap it all, they're armed.
Let's kill them. Let's kill them now.
Stay calm.
No one is killing anybody.
We'll take them to mother
and do whatever she tells us to.
To mother?
Mother doesn't need to know about this.
— Stay calm, friends.
— Stay calm?
We just want to go our way.
We didn't know this was anyone's land.
Shut your mouth!
Come on! Walk in front of us.
You hear me? Move it!
Walk ahead of me!
Damn it! Move!
Mummy...
We caught them.
Have them brought in.
Bring them in.
What are you doing here?
We're just passing through.
We mean no harm.
They came armed.
Show her his weapon.
Shut up!
Put those guns away.
Who are you running away from?
I was arrested for refusing
to be robbed by the State.
And you?
Don't you speak Portuguese?
No.
Bacelo is after you.
Everybody knows you're on the run.
And being together will
just make it easier to catch you.
He won't give up.
He's like a dog.
And there's only one way
to escape his sense of smell.
Arrange the transport.
But mummy...
Arrange their transport!
Our transport?
Your transport!
Yes, mummy.
I would advise you to head north.
Thank you very much.
You can go now.
Mummy...
We can't go much further.
We'll go on to our next stop together.
It's better for both of us.
Then you can go your own way.
It's me, Alberto!
Don't shoot.
Don't shoot! It's the shepherd.
Alberto...
So how's it going?
Who's this?
This is Américo.
He's a friend I made in prison.
I brought him along with me.
In prison?
It's a long story.
He wants to go with the flow.
But I've got to get out of here.
Where are you going?
He says he's going south.
But I'm heading up to the mountains.
Américo...
safe journey.
Have a good trip!
Alberto!
How did you get in?
That doesn't matter.
What about José Fernandes?
They're out looking for you.
Everyone is after you.
I came to fetch you.
Let's get out of here with the boy.
And go where?
Am I to wander the
mountains with a runaway?
Things will never improve here.
Let's go, Noémia.
I can't.
This is where I belong.
As little as I like it,
this is the place God chose for me.
You'd rather stay here?
Hello!
Is anybody there?
Have you seen the shepherd?
My dear fellow,
I hereby claim my right to another duel.
I'm sorry.
But I will not use this weapon again.
You shall not deny me my right!