The Wonderful March
Based on the book by John Raymond
Scenario
Direction
Music
Images / Assistant Cameraman
Production Manager
Production
That not-too-tall man with a round belly
is Napoleon Bonaparte,
the Emperor of the French.
He climbed up the hill to take a look
at his Grand Army.
With pride did he look at campsite bonfires
stretching as far as the horizon,
the long rows of tents and rifles
set like trestles,
the thousands of his soldiers,
horses and cannons,wagons and teams.
He could see his dignified marshals,
generals glistening with gold,
colonels and squadron leaders,
captains and lieutenants,
fifers with their long fifes
and drummers ready to play their marches.
The little Jean Francois was among them.
His uniform was faded, his boots cracked,
but Jean Francois didn't care,
as he had his admirable beautiful drum with him.
The Russian Tsar is too sure of himself.
What do you think?
Declare a war, Sire!
Silence! It's my task to give orders.
The war's been declared.
Forward, always forward!
After breakfast, of course.
Don't you know which way is the way forward?
This is the one.
Go marching right ahead of your shadow
in the morning
and right behind it in the afternoon,
and you'll reach the target soon.
Now, I won't get lost for sure.
Forward, always forward!
Viva the Emperor!
Forward!
Get formed!
To the right wing!
To the left wing!
March on!
I'll be marching right ahead of my shadow.
The battle isn't going too well, Ithink.
Everyone's marching in a different direction.
Where are you going?
Forward, always forward!
That's right.
I'lljoin them with my Grand Army soon.
Watch those cannonballs!
Halt!Who are you?
Ah,we've captured a Frenchman.
I'm going to be marching straight forward,
obeying the Emperor's order, if you don't mind...
To Moscow,you mean?
Nay... If only I could decide it...
Ah,yeah...
I can see you've captured an officer.
But do we still have to be marching
forward, always forward?
Yeah, in a couple of minutes.
I've run out of medals
but will decorate you with this.
Whew... Anyone having a footstool?
You could put your feet on my drum,
but please don't you scratch it with your spurs.
You're right, such a nice drum
can't be destroyed.
This is Moscow burning.
The town's dwellers set fire on it so it
couldn't give shelter to the French army.
Put out the fire!
Yes Sir!
What to put it up with? We've got no buckets.
Indeed.
We can use our drums instead...
Why didn't you say it straight away?
Don't stand like that! Put the fire out!
I'll relax for a little while.
Where's everybody gone?
Where is the Emperor,the Grand Army?
Are you the only one to have stayed in Moscow?
Okay, let's go,the three of us: me first,
then my shadow and then,you.
I am Jean Francois,the Grand Army's drummer.
And who's that one there? Napoleon?
It's my friend the Billy Goat.
A nice one, indeed.
Are you theTsar?
Ha-ha! I am General Morozov.
I've lost my army in this snowstorm.
Didn't you see them, by any chance?
No, I'm going forward, always forward.
As I'm ordered to.
What I'm doing is retreating, always retreating.
It's the tactics.
Let's go together then.
Perhaps we'll find our armies.
Let's first have a bit to eat,will we?
Excellent!We'll make a snow soup.
You take a portion offresh clean snow.
What else?
Nothing,you can't spoilthe taste.
Isn't it delicious?
It is...
Don't say anything else,
I feel awkward when flattered.
There's the ocean.
Are you willing to go any further?
I've got to march forward, always forward.
And I had to retreat, always retreat,
that's why we marched together.
But now, I'm changing my direction.
Changing your tactics?
Where's my army at last?
Goodbye, General! Bye, Billy Goat!
Goodbye!
Jean Francois sailed fast forward.
When hewas hungry, hewould take Emperor
Napoleon's hairpin away and fished.
When he got bored, he'd sing combat songs.
One day, a wave dropped him on a sandy coast.
By my scalp - may I preserve it for ever!
The Cockeyed Deer is chasing us!
I'm Jean Francois.
Lully Bull, at your service.
I've got to be marching ahead of my shadow,
couldn't you possibly turn in that direction?
No I couldn't, but, by my scalp - may I
preserve it for ever!
You'll make up for your lost time,
I promise you.
Lully Bull and Jean Francois arrived
in a small town
where Professor Jim Crackey lived -
thescholar, inventor, and great weirdo.
Jean Francois, Emperor Napoleon's drummer.
Whassat?
This is Jean Francois,
and my name is Lully Bull.
Bull?
Lully Bull!
Ah, bull-loon... Oh,there it is!
A balloon!You should've said it straight away:
you needed a balloon!
By my scalp - may I preserve it for ever!
I'd prefer meeting a Cockeyed Deer instead!
A real balloon!
Forward, always forward!
Fare you well!
A hell of a boy, by my scalp!
May you preserve it for ever, Lully Bull! Bye!
Jean Francois flied away with his balloon,
a favorablewind pushing him fast forward.
Waterloo has been the most horrible battle
I've ever fought.
Especially,from the moment I lost it.
The enemy's chasing us!The enemy!
Yeah... Now they'll put allthe guilt on me.
Aren't you going in the wrong direction?
Forward I go, always forward.
In the morning, I lead my shadow;
afternoon, I follow it.
You've marched round the globe,
without setting the direction
with a saber or cannon fire.
What a great march...
Aren't you going with me, Emperor?
What's an emperor without an army?
You march on by yourself, and take care
about your admirable drum.
Forward, always forward!