What color is good for the bedroom?
How about yellow?
Not so good
What about pink?
No!
Pasted Blue?
Oh! Always get stuck with colours
You're so picky, why don't you choose one?
OK. Green then?
Green bedroom? Are you crazy?
Sometimes I can't stand Alex
How can he stand out of the preparation?
I can't image
how he would be after setting married
So give him a good lesson
You shit!
You know his boss has just migrated to Canada
And Alex look over the business
It's understandable that
he's got so busy recently
Busy? So you do all the stuff
And getting so weary?
I've made up my mind from now on
I've to be the woman behind a successful man
I want to talk to Mr. Lui
He's not in, I'm his wife
See how eager you want to marry him!
There's still a week to go!
You haven't paid the
management fee for several months
Also, all these bills are past due
Really?
Didn't the ex-tenant settle them?
You rent this flat?
We bought it last year and pay
the installments from the rent received
Oh shit! We've just re-occupied it last month
So many bills to settle!
Rates, telephone, electricity
Home installments and the car!
I'm busy!
Madam the line has been disconnected
OK! Thanks!
Hurry up! This thing is heavy
It's here, not enough space
Going straight! Don't be too pushy
It's too heavy. Let's put it down first
It's new bed! Please take it with care!
Hey!
-Please sign here.
-Me?
OK. Alright
What? He's not answering your call
He's busy, OK, give me. I'll sign it
Thanks!
Hey! Aren't you guys
going to take it in for me?
Our truck is downstairs, you pay the ticket?
Even you're willing to pay
we've to go for another job
What?
Well, he's busy!
That's not what I mean
If you don't understand you can ask me
But you're busy!
Well, you could ask me when I'm not so busy
OK. I'll try once more
See how he speaks after becoming a boss!
We can't blame him it's my fault
Certainly it's not your fault. Oh, I get it!
The boss is getting married
and you're love-torn
So you're so absent-minded!
You go to hell!
Don't play around just because you're leaving
OK! Done?
We won't be here if it's done!
I'll be on the plane tomorrow
and I'm still trying hard for you
Do frugal? Smoking second-hand cigarette?
I've quit it!
Just for that woman?
Don't stick to the gamble table
It's so misty how can I bet?
Close the door please
OK. Let's go on!
Who's turn now?
Come on, hurry up!
Why are these houses so cheap?
A nice place to invest
In the Mainland's Wai Yang Town who'll buy?
Now the houses in USA, Canada, Thailand, Africa
Are sold in Hong Kong
So what?
Hello Sam? Where are you now?
We've got to go to the class!
There's a test today
The office was crowded with people
Just now I'm thirsty and taking the soft drink
They think that I'm one of the gang
So what's your number now?
I don't remember whether it's 128 or 138
Hang up the line and search for it
That's right
It's time for the class, let's go
Let me help you
No, thanks. Mind your business
Vivian, I've missed two lectures this morning
Did Dr Chow say anything?
I've told you to queue for a private business
I've been in the queue all night for all of you
How can you do this to me?
Don't you get a share if there's a profit?
Let's go!
Where is Alex?
Still working hard over there!
Make some modification here
Are you crazy? It's your wedding!
Don't you guys have to get pay
when I'm going to the church?
Don't you get some clues after these days?
Boss the church's decoration, the flowers
Regent's cocktail Macau's tickets
And Hyatts honeymoon suite
All are sponsored and free of charge
Such a good deal.
Have it twice if you have time
Can't you two shut your mouth?
If my bride hear this, I'll be in trouble
You suffer from wife fear so early?
Boss don't think that
fearing wife can led to great fortune
I've told you not call me boss, call me Alex
We're brothers right?
That's why we've never had any salary increase?
It's always hard to get start! Are we brothers?
What are you doing?
What are you working on?
Sorry!
I inform your mom!
Why are you so late?
Today is Saturday. The road is crowded!
Why don't we go to the church nearby?
Alex said that church offers him a discount
Why are you still following me? It's time to go
Go where?
The flats in Sha Tau Kok start selling today
Go and queue for one!
Today is your mom's wedding!
Why you're so care about my Mon's wedding!
Mom are you ready?
Are you ready? Your daughter is urging
I knows it's time,
but I've got to look perfect
Alex would acknowledge receipt
even if you don't look beautiful
I'm human, not a good for sale. Mind you words!
You look terrific even without make-up
Let me see what's going on?
Mom, hurry up!
Why are you so anxious?
It's my wedding!
You're also too anxious!
It will be erased in a moment
All right! I'm ready
I think my eye shadow
is little bit too dark isn't it?
The car has come!
Over there
Driver, we've ready to go!
It's so late!
Get on, get on!
See you later!
Come earlier!
Bye!
Care you pressing for life!
Vivian, why are you rushing me?
The car hasn't arrived!
Where is the car? It's just here!
Where is Sam?
I told him to go to Sha Tau Kok
What?
OK, I call him back now
Does the bride go to the wrong church?
She won't! The Father's got a light schedule
He's going to leave any minute
Can he do both jobs together?
But the next job is a mass for the dead!
It doesn't matter
What are you talking about?
Yeah right! Marriage is the grave of love
Call her up, see what's going on
Alex Lui, it's your marriage, what a surprise!
Shit head! Long time no see!
I'm Edmond Tang, call me ET
I'm in the bullion marked,
I'm Alex's former classmate
See if I can help you!
May 1?
Who is so powerful
to get our Valentino to marry her?
Just a mediocre
Go and call her up!
What kind of car is yours?
It's the kind that cannot be over-loaded
Oh! Shit!
I'm even worse
What are we going to do now?
It's hard to get a taxi here
I've an idea!
In HK you can have everything with money
Robber! Robber!
Hey, Goose (she) is coming!
Goose is coming. She is coming
What's happen? How come you
No more nonsense!
I've got enough from you and the geese
I'm going to be a goose too!
It's so late! The Father has gone!
So what shall we do?
Oh, it's fine,
it's a great relief. No more marriage!
Don't listen to them not a single truth
Who's he? Such a nasty mouth
Just a bastard! My former schoolmate
We're so glad to see the marriage
Between Mr. Lui and Miss Chu
OK! Cut!
Please take once more after a while
What's going on?
Shooting for the TV commercials!
Otherwise who will
sponsor your wedding expense?
So you're not getting married,
you're just shooting for the commercials?
Why didn't you discuss with me first?
Making commercial is one of our business
It's just an unimportant stuff,
I can make the decision
That's the usefulness of having brothers
It's brothers!
So... Are you two getting married?
The equipment is here
Please calm down
Do you two wish to get married?
Sure we do!
Is this Father an actor?
He's real
OK... Let's continue, don't obstruct others!
It seems that I've seen him in a movie
Me too
Begin
Unhappy things can happen
even when you're very happy
The World insurance can safe guard you!
You've gone too far!
If you buy from the World insurance
You can insure against anything!
Don't touch
I think you're taking
the wedding gown commercial
Insurance can also have ads
How come it be so?
Investing in the bullion market
is better than investing in property
-Pa pa
-Hi! Vivian!
Congratulation!
What's the matter?
Oh sorry, I've used to this
She likes it
But you've to hug the left-side
Who's he?
He's Vivian's father
So he's Alex is his runner-up'?
Haven't you told me to go honeymoon in Europe?
I think we go to Italy Spain
Macau is not much different from Portugal
There are also casinos there!
We've still speaking
in Chinese There's no difference
(Welcome!)
(Thank you)
Was! Speaking in Portuguese?
You are so crafty!
Hei! You've got much weight?
I don't care,
anyway I won't enter the room myself
Can you still remember the first time we touch?
Oh, it's fine we are alone now
No one will disturb us
Hello!
Is it Alex? I'm Dennis
Have you received my champagne and flowers?
Yes!
You're having a good time
while I'm suffering in Canada
Have you start
the Fight of the Century with her?
I have if not for your call
I hope this is not collet-call
Yes, it is! You pay the bill
Good-bye then
Who is it?
It's Dennis
Hello!
Oh shit, BCC bank has just announced bankruptcy
You've got to hurry back
I don't believe you
I'm coming... I'm coming
Operator? Yes
We are not to accept
anymore call today, thank you
Oh, fine we can have our own time now
Let's take a rest?
Rest?
Isn't today our honey-moon?
Yes, it is, but we've old couples
There's nothing so special how
What do you mean?
It's our first time to do it in a bold!
Are you prepared?
Oh yes
See, double pack!
A whole box?
Isn't that too many?
We've only here for two days
I think it is just enough!
What shall we do now?
SUKI?
Why don't you accept calls?
What's the matter?
BCC is going bankrupt!
You've to get your money back before live
Alex, are you ready, Hurry up
I'm taking a shit!
Come on, hurry up!
I've said! I can't go now
BCC is bankrupt! The bank is on run!
What?
What did you say?
Let's pack up and go. Hurry up!
We can get our money back
if we reach before five
Have we book the tickets?
Otherwise we have to go by helicopter
Are you joking?
I said before five o'clock yesterday
Don't worry! Our company is not in trouble
When will your boss come back?
Don't be so harsh, we've been long acquainted
The boss is back
Please settle these bills
Our money is in BCC bank
It's BCC bank goes bankrupt, not ours
We're brothers we've get the creditors away
But we haven't make a living!
So do our wives and kids!
So do our pas and moms!
I keep all the money in BCC bank
But you also have an account in Chartered Bank!
When I was going to the market,
I saw queues outside Chartered Bank
Will be also on run?
It's not a rum cur, the TV news also say so!
Thank you boss
My wife said that Chartered Bank is also on run
What?
Mom, what's wrong? Did you get rob?
Fortunately it's not me
But I'm not sure about those behind me
What do you mean?
I've taken all my deposit out from the bank
It's crowded with people
It's lucky that it remain opened at night
Can't that prove that it's not in trouble?
It's not worth to waste time in the queue!
The Government had said that BCC
wasn't in trouble before it went bankrupt
I could get back nothing
just because was late last time
This time I won't be so foolish
I took out all my money!
You've so much money
with you beware of the robbers!
I've only got eight thousand dollars,
no one will be interested
There've many others
who get millions with them!
What? Eight thousand dollars is all you have?
So how much do you think your mom has?
All the decoration,
furniture and miscellaneous items
In this house are paid by me
You know your dad has been working hard
on his new firm
He hasn't give me money for our living
I've paid for the food, the clothing etc
You could have asked him to pay
Come on, on family
He's been overloaded with work
I don't want to add to his burden
Remember don't say a word about this to him!
I don't want him think that I'm complaining
Oh! You've come back?
This bowl of noodle is mine!
I didn't expect you to come home for dinner
You know, sometimes
you're so busy with your work
I just come back from the Chartered Bank
I'm going to make
the dinner for you, it won't take long!
No, don't bother!
Oh! No! Instant noodle is no good for you
I couldn't help before we got married
Tell your mom
I deposit 20 Thousands
to her account every month
But the account is in BCC
I was in the queue all day,
I didn't have time to go in the market
Don't you mind a canned food meal?
Where's Alex?
Did talk too much!
Did he say anything about his company?
How is it now?
Is all the company's money in BCC bank?
Forget it it's no point worrying now
It's too good if this flat is mortgaged to BBC
Even if it closes down
we don't have to move for the time being
You're too idealistic!
The government has said that all BCC's debtors
should settle the money at once
Is it so unreasonable?
It demands others to settle
their debts while it doesn't settle its?
Well, by the way, we owe others much money
The home installment the car
How much is the company is debt?
There's only about eight thousand cash
Some gold accessories
and stocks of Hang Seng and Landmark
Where did I put them?
Oh, yes I've sold them
top pay the decoration fee
How is the company actually?
Can I help you?
Yes, just one thing
What is it?
Shut up!
Did your husband commit suicide?
What?
I just saw him jumping and
shouting outside the Government, Offices
He got very upset!
I've video-taped the scene
Who is my husband?
It's Alex
Everyone knows Alex is my husband
Which one is Alex?
Right here! Isn't he Alex?
He's a Indian
Don't you think
your husband's beard looks like an Indians
I sleep with him every night,
can I not recognize him?
I can't recognize my wife
Women get two distinct
looks for daytime and at night
I'd better go back to see him
Don't be silly! He's an adult
Can you watch over him 24 hours?
Yes, he is! He won't be
so stupid to do any harm to himself
He would not have
married you if he's not stupid
Shut your mouth! Check the stock in the store!
Otherwise I'll fire you
Didn't you say you want a job?
Well you may work for me!
You really mean to fire him?
No! was just scaring him
Are you going to keep the shop yourself?
How much can you gain with it?
What else can I do?
I can't even pass the Secondary School Exam
I deliver the money, you the effort
Doing what?
Prostitute
What?
Am I doing to pay to be a prostitute
I want you to pretend to be a prostitute!
Pretending? Acting in porno?
Scream like a fowl!
Oh! This must be a new technology
Human beings screams like a cock,
taped and broadcasted in the farm
To stimulate egg-laying!
So I just read it, why?
Do I sound like a cock?
Ih, Yo Ya, Yi
Do today's cocks scream this way?
You are really silly
Listen to me!
Oh Ah Yi
What are you doing?
Oh, I can't stand anymore...
I'm dying... It's too fantastic
Oh, it's wonderful
Please don't push me
Oh! Harder harder... Oh yes!
Damn you! I'm not doing it
This is adult's phone-call service
It pays good, six bucks per minutes
I've rented ten lines,
each can at least
make six to seven thousand per month
I won't do it
What if someone recognize my voice?
I just ask you to scream
Do you think you're so popular?
Whose voice would be
recognized once you scream?
My husband will recognize mine!
Your husband often turns to such service?
It's not for me!
Don't you do it to your husband?
That's different?
Forget it! Don't say I don't help you
It's you who wants to earn
some money for your family
OK. I'll try
Just imagine you've
with your little Beard, then you can do it
Right! Just keeping on!
Who's this man?
Little Beard
Duet is better than solo
Let's get to work, babe!
Wo Yi harder
Fuck you to die
Are we finished?
Man I have a contract with you
Yes but my boss only accepts cash
Can you do a favor?
Are you kidding?
I've said that I'll pay after I complete it
and deliver it to the client
Alex, you should know
I just do by order!
What should I do?
Teddy please help me
Teddy... Teddy
Let me do it
Tell them to go back to their post
Be in one's position!
We do it ourselves!
Can we?
Maybe lighting is not enough!
How is it now?
Yeah! Much better!
Sorry, Margaret, we can't pay you tonight!
Well, then you pay me double another night
Are you guys ready?
We've ready
How about you guys?
Ken, ask them in!
Cut
Move a little bit aside
Can you turn to your right side?
This lady wants to see Mr. Tang
If you want to know
how prosperous HK is now, just
Go to Cosmo,
Today's World Night Club then you'll get it
You bastard My uncle is very patriotic
He should prefer China City!
Of course! We've all Chinese
China City sounds more intimate!
Hello, Vivian! How nice to see you!
Uncle Tang be owing to the government's
and the bank's policies
Property market is
no longer a good place to get money
I want to learn bullion trading from you
What a smart girl!
College kids are much social conscious now
Contributing to HK's
economic prosperity while still studying
Uncle, let me to teach her!
Well but she's my niece
There'll be no problem, uncle!
Don't call me uncle, call me boss in the office
Yes boss!
Vivian, come with me now
Boss, we're leaving
OK
Little Tang she's so cute!
Keep out of her
How about just have a touch?
She is my niece
Little Tang,
can I just have a kiss to your niece
You Hong Kong people are so conservative
A little bit of it
Mom, this is for you
How come you have so much money?
Trading flats?
No, it's bullion! It's easier to make profit!
Bullion speculation? You're still a student
But many college students
also have part-time jobs!
You should be cautious!
It's a very risky undertaking
But risk is unavoidable
if you want to earn big money
Now I'm a part-time
investment executive in ET's company
You know, ET is
Alex's former classmate,
Edmond Tang
Edmond Tang?! Alex has said that
he uses fitter paper when going to the toilet
What does that mean?
No dregs remain!
He's a bad guy!
But it's a commonplace in the business world!
Alex loses just because he's not cunning enough
Anyway I'll be careful
Mom, didn't you say that you want to get a job?
How about working with me
I just know cookery
I know nothing about bullion!
It's easy I can show you the way
Frist of all, you must change your attitude
We're not speculating!
We just earn commission
by teaching others to invest
We can even earn profit
from the price difference
In a word, we do in and out
for the clients and earn money
How to do in and out for the clients?
Out is selling, in is buying
Going in and out means buying and selling
All in all it's easy, Just follow me
Really?
Good morning, Mr. Cock!
Good morning, Mrs. Mao
My new husband's last name is Lui
Oh sorry, I don't know you get married again
There's not much difference whether
You're Mrs. Mao of Mrs. Lui
I've got something nice for you today
Tsou-Cze hen, twenty-five bucks for one
Good for you, Mrs. Mao
Oh! What's his last name?
Lui!
Yeah! Good for your daughter too!
So terrific!
Mom, sales should be active
Shall we have one more?
Mom, we've here to sell gold, not to buy hens
Buying hen? I offer you a special price!
Mr. Cock, you often give me a discount
How about I give you one this time
I'm a sales rep in a bullion agency now
What rep?
That's speculating in bullion,
foreign currency etc
Mom, Not speculating its investment!
Isn't there any difference?
Of course there is
Speculation calls for luck, whereas investment
calls for strategy and tactics
She is professional,
I'm still learning from her
It's true! We have many
investment items for you to choose from
Such as gold, foreign currencies
I don't know what you're talking about
It's simply say for an example
Bullion trading if the price stays still,
it's called Cow market
If it is fluctuates greatly,
it's called Bear Market
If you want to make a fortune
You can buy and sell in the 'Bear Market'
I don't know anything
about 'Cow and Bear Market'.
In a word if you lose you'll
get a 'whole foot of cow shit'
It's not so easy to lose money?
We have many professionals
Computers, and graphs to help you
The prosperity of HK
depends on various speculation
Look
Mom, I've said it's not speculation
Right! You won't lose
if you're not speculating!
Look at these graphs!
There've many experts
PhDs working for our company
We're selling hen. We have no money to invest
You can invest with a small sum of money
As we were just engaging in margin'
We profit from the price difference
How much must I invest?
Ten thousand for 'ONE DAY'
Fifty thousand for "OVERNIGHT"
Overnight with you?
Or with this little girl?
Don't think astray
"ONE DAY" means settling daily
Whereas ' OVERNIGHT' means
setting once every 2 or 3 days
How much do you want
to invest? Come on, sign this
Vivian, explain it to him
This coequal is given to me by the clients
Please divide the amount among you guys
BCC's again?
Now, even the salary is deprived!
What do you mean?
Close the company!
What's the matter?
There're two ducks in the bath tub
Haven't you seen ducks before?
I've never seen people
doing business like you do
There should be a two way trading in business
Can these ducks can be eaten, and
Can also be reared to lay eggs
They can be kept if you eat them all at once
You ought to be more frugal like I am!
So if you meet a coffin trader,
you ask him to buy gold
And you get
Don't say such a thing! Open the door first!
Who are you looking for?
Is it Flat D, 4/F, Lui's home?
Hey police!
Parking is allowed here.
Why did you tow away my car?
We didn't!
So that's theft
Hey you!
Why do you stand here? My car is stolen,
don't you go and catch the thie!
What kind of cop you're?
Is this your car, Little Beard?
Mind you, there's jurisdiction in Hong Kong
Hong Kong Law is one should pay his creditors
You haven't paid five installments
so we towed away your car
Mr. Lui Mr. Lui
You've got to go back at once,
big heads from Tai Fung are in our office
They said if you don't settle the money today,
they'll call the police!
I'm cop! Who does you want to get?
You're home? Sit down for the dinner
Vivian dinner's ready
-My car has been towed away!
-Really?
It's fine less to feed!
Let me do it
It's ready, come on!
What is it? Are we celebrating?
Come on, this one's for you
Have another piece?
What's going on?
Last Supper!
Who are you two
Bailiff, come to seal the house
Don't worry about them
Come on, let's eat
Is there a mistake? What's wrong with you?
Talk to the court,
we're just doing our duty
But why are you taking pictures?
We have to take pictures
for whatever it is in this flat
Alex, take it easy! We've moving anyway
Why don't we enjoy and finish our meal?
Come on... Let's go in with our meal!
Hey!
Don't be so!
OK!
What's the matter?
Do we have to move out after this meal?
Right
Would you mind taking a picture
For us?
Sure!
Do you really mean to treat me this way?
It's so big here.
Can't I stay here for a night?
How can you prefer to be
with a dog than being with me?
This is a male dog!
That's even worse
Did you send this dog to deep track of me?
Do I need to do that?
You'll always come back here whenever you go
So you know where to find me
Oh, look! It's jealous!
Are you cold?
Hey! I'm jealous too
Didn't you say you'll sleep in a friend's home?
I miss you low so I called up aunt
And she said you've left
How do you know we're here?
You love to come here
Where else can you go?
You're so Clever!
I feel very cold!
I know!
Hi! Sir!
You're so bad!
Why do you look so beautiful today?
Your daughter is waiting for you in your room!
Thanks
Why do you read this stuff?
It's yours
Why do you come here?
Papa, I've got something to discuss with you
Be frankly, my daughter, how much do you want?
I'm not asking for money!
I just want to
live in your flat for a short time
Living in my flat?
It's because a quarrel with Mom?
Or because your
step-father did anything on you?
That Little Beard,
I've known he's guy at first sight!
Any eye-Witness?
If there's enough evidence, I'll get him
Beat him to death! OK!
BCC s liquidated. Alex's flat is taken away
We've homeless now
So fine?
My old Pa!
You and your mom can move in
But that Little Beard cannot! OK!
Why?
You're grown up now;
can't you just use your brain to think it out?
How a man can be so generous
as to give his daughter, his wife
-and his house to another man?
-Don't you care about me?
My daughter!
If I give you the flat, where shall I live?
Before you got the divorce,
you always said that you're busy busy
So you didn't come home for the night!
Only mom and I was in the flat
So you won't know
if there's another one in the flat!
So it's okay if
you can take it as the past, and
not to come back to sleep
No way! Go away, I've much work to do
No! Unless you promise me!
If you don't promise me,
I'll sit here and sleep here
Do you really mean to do this? As you like!
Hello!
Nancy!
Hi, it's been a long time to hear your voice!
Where do you usually have tea recently?
Don't be so naughty!
I'm talking in the phone!
Hei, is it Nancy?
Nothing it's just disconnected
Tell me, where you want to have tea
Hello
You're so bad now!
Does the Little Beard teach you so?
Don't you think I'll beat you?
OK! Come on, beat me dead!
Beat me dead so
I don't have to wander in the street
So I don't have to be
forced to go astray, to be a prostitute
Hello! Yes... yes
It doesn't matter
I'm exercise...
Don't come again
What are you two doing?
Hi! Sir!
Excuse me
My daughter!
She's your daughter of your girl?
He's really my old Pa
It's so nice that we meet again.
So we're a little bit too excited!
You Hen (whore)
killing superintendent is so smart!
Kill even you own daughter!
Mom, this way
I always tell you not to
engage in property speculation
And it is of use this time
This flat's owner has just gone for a trip
And won't be back for two to three months
I've kept it without letting it out
Let's live here for the time being
In Hong Kong,
there've flats without occupiers,
and people without flats to live in
Wo! I'm sure the owner is a playboy
He must be a bad guy!
This guy is abnormal!
How did you know him?
Don't let him get anything from you!
I have never!
But I think you have!
How is Alex?
Fine!
Why do I feel the things so familiar with here
It tastes like
VIVIAN!
You must tell me,
whose flat this is?
You've know the answer!
You're old Pa!
There'll be trouble if Alex knows it!
What's problem
for Dad to live in Old Pa's flat?
We can't afford to hotel room,
where else shall we live?
But it's not good to live under other roof
Mom, don't worry,
I'll put all Old Pa's things away
Why do this flat have
A taste that I hate!
Yes! I also smell it!
What are you doing?
Little Tang!
It's been a whole year!
And you haven't arranged the money for me
I tell you, I'll be
transferred back to Beijing soon
I know, Uncle
When USSR was broken up recently,
the gold price fluctuates greatly
We've made a good fortune,
we don't wanna close down
Close down!?
I tell you,
if you close this down you can open another
Damn you! I wouldn't have
invested in this company if I'd known this
Do you think I don't love money?
I have 3/10 share out of the ten millions?
Don't worry
I'll close it down once. I find a scapegoat
OK. Please do it as soon as possible!
What're you doing madam?
Keeping everything
And hold up all lines, how can we buy in?
It's all yours, we have nothing can do!
62, keep it 61 keep it,
60 also keep it?
59 also keep it?
Mom, the market is sliding
Why do you buy so much?
You can't say this way!
When I bought this wedding ring
The gold price is $3,800 a tael,
the current price is $3,259
It's cheap, I've got to buy some!
Madam, you know what it is?
It's very dangerous
to get so much!
Don't listen to him he's a bastard!
What shall we do now?
Sell it buy it again later if the price is good
Shit! The pork stall owner
has lost a great deal!
We've said, if he loses
He'll kill me!
But it's common to have price
fluctuations in the gold market
What's the matter?
Mr. Tang
Boss!
This Madam knows nothing
trade in a much manner
What shit are you saying? She's my friend
Mr. Tang
I find that I'm not
so suitable for this business
I'm afraid I've to resign
Don't you really need to do?
Let's have a chat, come on
Mr. tang, its URGENT
Ngao, give me a coffee
Uncle, what's the matter? Something missing?
OK! I'll ask Ming
to get you something better tonight
See you
Mr. Tang, it's coffee
What?
You asked me to give you a coffee!
Me?
You're called Ngao!
That maid is also called Ngao
Such a coincidence!
Can I call you
Call me Mrs. Lui or Miss Chu
Any English name?
Yes! Judy!
Judy! It sounds silly, it fits you!
Just a joke... Sit down first
Judy, even if you find
this job isn't suitable for you
You don't have to resign
You're honest and reliable
I just need such a person to help me
OK. I promote you to be Assistant to Director
Two pictures
300 bucks the you'll have the interview at once
30 bucks one week to want for the reply
Should I pay you?
It's up to you
Next one
Thank you
Come in
Hi! Alex, it's really you!
Let me introduced to you my partner, Frankie
Glad to meet you!
Alex, he's got a creative mind!
Don't be misted by his artless look
I was his subordinate
His brain can compensate
for the brains of thirty persons
We were no match to him! Sit ... Sit down
We're just discussing on the grape's ads
Give us a good idea
It needs a test anyway
Ten minutes! Ten minutes. OK?
We go out for a while! Remember ten minutes!
Don't eat all the grapes! They're just props
How is it? OK?
OK!
Let me look at it
Are you joking? This is an idea?
You've been so excellent
in the past, how come now?
Your performance is so bad,
How can't employ you?
Frankie, you see, it's okay. It's not bad
It's okay? Alright, you try it, come on, try it
How? There should be some dancers
Then our dance how can I
know the effect if you don't
I've drawn it out
Am I also to draw to show to my client?
You've got to show it in action
If the brain is grown in your asshole
Just don't use it
That note-book is mine!
Sorry, I've to go now
Hey... How about my 300 bucks?
300 bucks It's gone! Have a grape, come on
That guy is really great!
Of course!
I've said he's a genius!
Produce the ads on it!
I've good news! I've got a promotion
Assistant to Director
Don't you feel happy for me?
Take a grape!
So sour!
I mean the grape, not you
Alex doesn't know fruits. He must be cheated!
The fruit hawker nearby often cheats people!
The most honest is the shop No 9
near our previous apartment
Such a sour grape, how much for a pound?
Three hundred bucks!
What?
If you love grapes, I'll get you some everyday
Mom, I'm hungry,
Are we going out to dine?
I'm not cooking this evening
I'd like to have a celebration
So we are going out to have a pretty nice meal
I'm not going
You don't like it?
He's angry with me!
Oh yes! I forgot
to ask him how the interview is
It surely goes into failure!
Well, I just prepare
the dinner and wait for you back
It's ready; I don't want to waste it!
You two can go out
No! Sit down, let's have the dinner together
It's warmer to eat at home!
I didn't know that Alex knows how to cook!
Just like a house-husband!
OK
How is it? Still can't get a job
I won't depend on you
Come in
Please close the door for me
And also hang down the blinds
Please sit
What's the matter?
Nothing, how do you feel about me?
Quite food, willing to help others
You have to do something for yourself
How can you be so conservative?
I have my own principles to follow
I don't rely on any sideways
If you haven't got the capability,
you wouldn't have been in that position
However, you'll be
left behind if you're too conservative
Take off the clothes
Take off the clothes?
Take off the clothes so that
I can see it more clearly
ET you've mistaken! I'm not that type of woman
What?
How can you dress this way?
You don't look like a senior executive?
My opinion is that you should
buy some more beautiful clothes
Your opinion, buy some beautiful clothes?
Yes!
Please!
Sorry
Having an hour's freight,
it's time to change the clothes
Yes, the company is going to sponsor you
ten thousands as
clothing allowance, is it enough
Yes! It's enough!
Go the hair salon,
and buy some pretty clothes
Don't make me lose face!
Right
Is it beautiful?
Yes!
But you haven't look at me!
I've been looking at you all night
You stay a whole night with me,
But you've never look at me!
I've bought a dress
to show you it's very beautiful
Does it look good?
ET said that I'll have ten thousand
as clothing allowance every month
He also said
That pig head is a bad guy.
You're jealous
You've mad!
You don't want me t work?
No, certainly not
At least you have money
to buy the slippers for me!
I've been working
You don't know much,
but you get a promotion in such a short time
Be more cautious
I can learn to do it
Also ET said that I'm honest and reliable
I can help him to watch over the company
I've taken a course in Economics
Mr. Tang, you've come in?
Call me ET, we've known each other!
ET I'd like to ask
Why did you promote me to be Managing Director?
I often have business trips here and there
I need a trustworthy person
to manage the business
That's the only reason
But!
I know your pressure is getting greater
But I'm confident of myself never judge wrongly
Mr. Tang, excuse me, it's urgent
Just take it as if I'm not in the office
Sorry
Managing Director, excuse me
You put it down first
But it's urgent!
You should know that
everyone gets different styles
And I used to sign without reading anything
Miss Chu is different,
so if it's really urgent
Explain it clearly to her
Yes, I'm sorry Miss Chu, this letter is
OK, OK. I sign first!
Thank you
Signing is just a routine
All our staff are top guys
You don't have to be so anxious
I know what to do?
I go first!
Boss!
Managing Director,
let me explain this document to you
It's okay, OK
There's one more at the back, please
Here, please
-OK?
-OK! Thanks, sorry for troubling you!
Hello, you want to
speak to Ah Man? Just a moment
Ah Man your call
Thanks
Hello!
What? You damn drunkard
Going around in the bar at daytime?
I'm working as a collie in the bar I'm dying
You're lucky to have a brilliant wife!
If I don't work
My wife would have to be
a whore bring up the little spirits
Whore, drunkard and little spirits
Do you think it's the red light zone?
Hi Alex
Hi! Come in
What do you want?
Sit down
What's the matter?
I'd like to help me with an ads
OK
But you've to go to Macau for a few days
No problem!
What are you looking at?
Are my legs beautiful?
Can you
Take off your shows and let me polish them?
This one has to be steamed for a while!
Hello! Is it Ah Man? I'm Suki.
What's happened to Alex?
He's been so strange!
What? He only took off
your shoes but not your clothes?
That's really strange?
Maybe it's because
his wife is brighter than him
He's self-abused and he channels
his irritation through shoe polishing
What is he doing now?
He's steaming my shoe?
Don't irritate him anymore!
Otherwise you may be the next one to steam!
It's been steamed clean!
Judy! Judy
Mr. Tang
Why is the driver absent today?
Why don't you ride on your car?
I have classes tonight till nine
You don't have to ask him to wait for me!
Ah Shing is the company's driver
He can serve you anytime,
don't save money for the company
Oh, no, I just have an Economics lesson
The teacher said that
It's useless to take Economics and Management
If your teacher is really so great,
why isn't he a General Manager?
The most important thing
is to be loyal to the company!
I'm Vv E R Y lo Y a I
Are you free now?
Maybe you can go back to office
And watch over the night shift staff for me
But, I'm just learning more for the company
I just don't want you to learn too much
I mean I don't want you to waste too much time
Those commercial short courses are useless
You're the Managing Director
How can you give the time to study?
I've nothing to do in the office!
I'm not so clear about many things
That's why I take a course to lean more
Aren't you free now? Come on, get on the car
Come on please
Thank you Washroom
is the first one at left hand side
Who is coming?
-What is it?
-Mrs. Lui
You've come!
Alex, I feel envy of you!
You have such a capable wife
And I feel even more envy of you!
You've married a husband who is
even more hard-working than my Philippine maid
Polish my shoes if you have time
I won't shoe-shine for the one
who shoe shines for others!
Washroom is there
I'm going to change my clothes
You've to go out with ET, am I right?
Which shoes do you want to put on?
No, thanks, I can have this pair on
Oh no! This is too dirty, take it off
and I'll polish it up for you
Does Suki come to see you?
She has a job for me
Isn't it too good?
I've to go to Macau with her tomorrow
For how long?
Two to three days
Do I have to pack things for you?
Let me polish it!
Excuse me, are you Miss Suki Wong?
Yes, I'm
Your call, over there
Thanks
Hello!
What? How would it be that?
I'm sorry,
last night my client went to Zhu Hi
He called a whore?
Yes! The police have taken him away!
So he'll be back a few days later!
He's so unlucky
It's me
I'm sorry
for you've lost five hundred bucks
I feel bad, I'm so sorry,
I hope you won't be angry at me
OK, let's make it this way, bye!
Maybe next time
How dare you! You even change my lock
What've you doing?
Nothing, just playing around
Why do you come in such a heavy rain?
I'm coming to get my passport
Old Pa! Fortunately
Alex has gone to Macau last night
Next time call us
before you come back, can't you?
I just come back my home;
do I have to give a cal first?
Isn't it reasonable? This is my flat
Do I have to apply for the court's permit?
What's your last name daughter?
Are you on my side?
Where're you going Old Pa?
Where? I'm wet through,
I'm going to have a shower
Your passport has been kept up by mom
Don't touch the things
Alex hates people moving his things
Alex Its always Alex
If you say anything for the Little Beard again
I'll beat you!
Hello! OK. I'll be right there
Old Pa, don't use Alex's towel!
He doesn't like others using his things!
Mom, will be back soon,
tell her I've prepared the dinner
But I won't be back for it.
I'll be coming back late tonight
You're back?
It's raining heavily
Vivian has prepared the meal.
She was just mumbling
She must be annoyed by someone
There's a fish in the refrigerator.
Steam it for you, OK?
What are you looking at?
Never seen a man naked?
You're rude! You should knock the door first!
What are you doing here?
Why is he here?
Can't you hear I am asking him?
I thought you asked me why I am here!
The towel is mine!
So chicken-minded!
Haven't you seen that?!
Alex, I really don't know he has come
How do I know whether you know or not!
I only know that he has climbed up
Climbing what? What are you talking about?
We have done nothing!
Nothing!
You're only in
your night wear, and he seems so tired
He has just had a bath.
And you look so pleasant
I've seen you two
You're with a naked man
How do I know what you were doing with him!
You and he also look so pleasant!
You also said so
I've never let any man see my naked body
You are the first one!
Your boyfriend is so great!
He's not my boyfriend,
he's my husband!
Anyway,
He and I are cleaner
than the bleaching substance
To be frank,
I've had an affair with her!
But it's in the past!
Since you two had an affair,
it seems that our relation ship
Has really been beached!
You shut up!
I just explain it for you
Help what?
We actually haven't done anything!
You, get lost!
You're so good!
Hay Man. Don't you know that
you're living in my place?
You have an affair with my woman
I haven't angry with you yet
And you asked me to get out!
What is he talking about?
This place this place is his?
Why are you so angry?
Why didn't you tell me?
What do you want?
You never give me credit
for the tings I have done
You don't like me working
You get jealous when I got a promotion
and salary increase
You suspected I want you to depend on me
when I ask for your help
We have nothing left
I've got to figure it out!
There has to be a place to sleep in at night!
OK! You tell me!
What Should I do?
I'd rather sleep on the street!
Alex!
You're narrow mined, stubborn, and self-centred
But why did you marry him?
He's much better than you!
You just like to fool around with woman
He doesn't like to fool around,
and he doesn't have the bad habits that I have
So what's the result?
He's going at last!
I'm going to screw someone
Remember, all man is like that!
Can you give me the passport?
Passport!
Still want one more?
You've had 17 glasses, boss!
I've not been a boss for a long time
Don't excite him! He's already been so sad
Can he be worse than me?
I've to be a collie here!
It seems that we're in the same boat
How about a brothers' partnership?
Aren't we sisters?
Miss Chu, the gold price
has slided down beyond the bottom line,
shall we sell it
You ask me?
Mr. Tang has gone to Thailand
He said you'll be responsible for everything
Just a moment
Grace...wait
Grace. Who would know whether we shall sell it?
Mr. Tang
I don't know!
But Mr. Tang has gone to Thailand!
Miss Chu, Mr. Tang said
whenever he has business trips
I know, signing name! Come in
Anything else?
A regular meeting with
the brokers in the afternoon
and an appointment
with the IC of the Bank Bureau
You've to be present on behalf of Mr. Tang
Also, Mr. Tang has reminded you
to watch over the market
Miss Chu, shall we sell it?
Just a moment
Do you mean not selling?
No! Let me analyze the situation first
Now, the market is trying to
break through the psychological gate point
I'll make the decision in a short while
So when will you break through
you own psychological gate point?
Sit down and talk about it
Miss Chu, you've to sign this
financial report and the annual report at once
I know I know. You go out first
You also have to sign
the cheques from the Accounting Dept
You go out first, thank you
In fact, the problem between
you and Alex is just an psychological one
Are you so free?
Don't you have to go back to the office?
Don't you have to record all the calls?
Business can be done at any moment
But it's more important
to care about an old friend
You don't have to convince me
You see there's so much work to do
So you'd better go
But...
No one can alter what
've decided
Like a capable woman!
What's the matter?
The cheque is urgent, have you signed it?
You tell him to wait for a while. Thank you
Why don't you go?
I'm afraid no one can call the ambulance
if you suddenly has heart attack
I say it clearly once more
Just a moment
What are you doing?
I'm afraid
I can't hear clearly, so I take it down
I have no affair with Phillip
He is mistaking
Do you know why I'm working hard?
I don't!
Just for our family!
It doesn't matter even if I work like a dog
But even a dog needs master's care and love
But now he said
he's my fault. I've to comfort him
I won't downgrade myself
Where's your character gone?
You wanted to get married so crazily
Being a lady please
This is the first time you downgraded yourself
You word like a dog and no one praises you
This is the second time you downgraded yourself
I downgrade myself most to know you
How can you talk shit to me at this moment!
So it's the third time I downgrade myself
So, you may continue downgrading yourself
Go and comfort him
Impossible!
You should think it over seriously
Psychological hurdles to overcome,
No succeeding force...
No succeeding force? OK. Sell it!
Thanks
There must be understanding between couples
Like bullion speculation
You have to know
where is the psychological gate point
You haven't married you know nothing about it
Just knowing how to say it
without knowing how to do it
It's still better than your ignorance of both!
What do you think?
Vivian, you want to see Alex?
Uncle, didn't you migrate to Canada?
I get bored!
So I come back to visit the old friends
Is Dad's office upstairs?
I come for the first time
-No 99 I think it is
-5th Floor...
There are so many firms here is it here?
Boss, come in is it hard to find?
No! Just the staircase a bit awkward!
You have a very strange smell
That it can be easily followed
To be honest, though your mouth smells bad
I have been used to it
It's boring to be without it in Canada
You want to see Old Pa?
Daddy!
Her Old Pa and her dad is not the same! Shit!
Where's Alex?
He is meditating in the root garden
Though the space is small, we live happily
The meal is ready
I'm coming
It's so warm to eat at home
We have a Philippine maid
who does everything for us
You little Ben!
Don't call him Ben, his last name is Chow
Don't trick me!
We can't trick you only Alex can!
Damn you! Go to hell!
I don't go to hell! I go into your body
I am going to find Alex
Have the meal first
Thanks
"The heart is down and raining,"
"who can make love stay?"
Do I sing lovely?
Like an elephant which gets a cold
How can I sing if you don't teach me?
You are devoted to bullion speculation now
Do you still have time for singing?
You don't like me to be so money-minded?
Me too!
Whatever I think and do are for earning money
Don't disturb me, I want to complete this song
How is it?
Alex Lui's piece must be good work!
Shoe-shining! But I like it
Do you still remember how you teach me singing?
What? You want t go to the toilet?
It's what you taught me
Did 1?
You said one must sing from deep inside
And the mouth must be kept round
Mom used to think that
you tried to make a pass on me
Though Mom sometimes is too wordy,
she's quite good!
If she's not good I would not have married her
Furthermore, I quit smoking for her
So you feel great relief
as you can smoke now?
You don't care her anymore?
In fact it's not her fault
I borrow this flat from my Old Pa
It was raining
Anyway now I feel good when smoking
If Mom knows that
Suki is looking after you
She'll also be unhappy!
I don't have any affair with Suki!
Mom and Old Pa have also done nothing!
They quarrel whenever they see each other!
OK, I will quit smoking after I finish this one
Do you know that cigarette is very expensive!
You aren't angry with mom?
Will aren't angry at her having a job?
But she knows little about what she is doing
You can teach her
Just as you taught me singing is the past
I don't know bullion speculation
But ET, who had been
my schoolmate for such a long time
I have never seen him do a good thing
I also feel that he's little bit strange
Tomorrow I'm going to warm him
not to make use of my wife
He has gone to Thailand
Thanks
Mom
You ask him to come
Don't come if you're not willing to do so
I have been used to have a living
only with my daughter these years
But I'm not used to it
What
I'll get married sooner or later?
Then you'll be alone
It's even better! Feeling light happy!
Mom, we three can also
live happily together. You shouldn't
You sounds like
I've asked him to leave
He himself decided to leave!
Didn't he just come back?
Why didn't he come in if he had been back
This is Old Pa's flat
How can you expect him to come in
He feels jealous just because he loves you
Where is he now?
He is waiting for you at the old place
The old place?
So coincident
I come to see you
Really?
Just smoke if you want to do so I won't mind
We should be
adjusted for each other
Then I adjust for you
No! I can adjust for you! Smoke it
Well, but don't have to burn my beard
Where is Vivian?
Smoke it
Hasn't she told you?
Tell me what?
There's a serious problem in your company
Really?
Damn it! No one works at night-shift
Has it already been closed down?
Are you in the field?
Today is public holiday!
What are these keys for?
How do you get them?
These keys!
I'm the Managing Director, so I have the keys
Where are the switches?
Don't switch on the light!
I'm the Managing Director,
why can't I switch it on?
No need to hide!
But we are coming to break into ET's office
How can we be open and honest?
Oh damn it! ET is coming back
Don't worry, boss! I'll call you
If any changes take place here
The uncle's money
has not been deposited in our account
I know. After I get the money
I'll release information
so that our clients would force us
That woman is silly. She knows nothing!
ET's nephew!
So what shall we do now?
Let me take care of him!
How?
Comfort him!
Hi
Why do you come back so late at night?
I'm thinking of you!
Really?
Sure!
A bullion company suddenly closed down,
the clients and the staff are suffered
It's a trap
Alex,
this case is similar to our situation
But you're still signing names for your company
This company no longer belongs to ET
He transferred all the shares to you!
So what shall I do?
If the clients close their account,
you'll be put to jail
Ngao, they are here. Go out first
We want to see Miss Chan
What can I do for you?
We come to close our accounts
There's no problem
But our boss is having an appointment
Maybe you can wait for while here
Fine, the boss is coming
I really want to take over your company
I know you're soundly-based,
I don't want to be taken over now
I'm so sorry!
Miss Chu, this is cash
Why can't I open an account
We only trust cash in Taiwan
We don't trust cheques
Right We have pretty sum of cash in Middle East
Although some of the books cannot be publicized
I can give you any commission you want
Miss Chu,
you can't close my account without any reason
I've deposited millions in your company
and never asked for interests
It's useless to deposit money in our company
Even you don't ask for the interest
we'd responsible for you
You haven't had
any transactions for three months
I'm sorry, but we must close your account
Miss Chu, don't bother with her anymore
Open an account for me first
It's millions!
Please
What can I do for you two?
They want to close their accounts
No
We are confident of your company, aren't we?
We have been confident of your company
Thank you!
Hurry! These are props money
Be careful of being discovered
What's up?
I find a client very questionable
He's called KP Yuen
and his investments is 17 millions
But all are only figures on the book
Right... He's the one
who comes from the Mainland China
If he closes his account,
you'll be in big trouble
Maybe I can have a talk with him
If he is designated to trap you,
he won't listen to you
Go to arrest him!
Be careful
Don't worry!
Chairman Mao has said
overcome all the difficulties fearlessly
Mao vs. Mao, its sounds good
Don't let him gain anything from you
He likes to go to night club,
beware of his hands
Uncle... Oh Comrade Yuen
Who is your comrade?
We're partners to earn money
Aren't comrades?
It's better to call each other comrades
Chairman Mao has said...
It not convenient to talk here
Maybe we go inside, OK?
No!
OK
We'd better go to find comrade Cheung
Who is he?
We go inside first
I'm afraid someone would follow me
Come inside, hurry up!
-Thank you.
-Close the door
There are only you in the room?
Yes! What do you want to say?
Someone of China official
is investigating on you
Yesterday, a man called
Mr. Chueng come to our company to find you
Is he CS Cheung?
No! That one is called Cheung?
He gave me a name card
Forget his name first
You're suspected to steal a big money
from the Chinese Government
Any evidence?
Oh yes
You're crazy! You create it in the air!
What do you want?
Oh, he does not faint!
Has the electricity switched on?
You want to shock me?
I tell you, I've experienced
many adverse situations
I've knelled down on
pieces of glass and stabbed the lingers
You damn woman wants to trick me?
KP Yuen!
Mummy, smother him with Colophon
Mom!
Girl!
Are you okay?
For you
I lost my arm during the cultural revolution
Why can't I have something in return?
This is compensation trading
Mom, wake up!
Vivian
Vivian, how are you?
Are you alright?
Call the ambulance! Hurry up!
Yes
Open the door!
We heard the sound of fire What's happened?
Someone was shot. Take him to the hospital
Open the door now!
Sir, I've no relation with it. They intruded
Take her to the hospital
-it hurts!
-Don't be quick!
Please go with us
Sir, I'm not involved!
Someone fired in this room
and a girl may be killed
For such a serious case
All people must assist in the investigation
Let's go!
Get on!
Is it real?
Yes
Why do you lock me up
You like gold so much,
so I use a golden orange to block your mouth
Are you alright
It's merely honey its sweet!
My nose has just bled its real!
Give you some forged one!
"Prop Car"
Have a drink
Mr. Tang, how are you? Hong Kong's newspaper
-Thank you
Who do you want to see?
Is Mr. Yuen here?
I'm ET... No... I'm Tang
Let him in
Are you little Tang?
Damn it you're so stupid!
Who are you?
Call me' grandfather'
KP Yuen has been transferred back to Beijing
Damn it bastard
Wasting my time and effort
You...
Grandfather, also
comes from the Mainland China?
I can't do down now
You block my way
I'm sorry
Grandfather, how's comrade Yuen now?
He is being re-educated
He only lost ten millions during one year in HK
Don't you think he needs re-education?
And you
I promise
to lose 100 millions in a year!
A hundred millions!
Little Tang, you're so useless
I've never seen all who is as useless as you
Yes, I'm of no use!
But if I can be re-educated by you, Grandfather
I guarantee, I can lose
100 millions in six months
It's none of your business!
Your company is no longer yours
The owner is called something like Ngao
We can form another company!
It's not that easy
Your company has been registered
with the Chinese government
Otherwise I would not have invested in it and
Place ads for their
Oh I see... Yes 'Grandfather'
You give me three days time
Miss Chu? I'm talking about you
Yes, I remember
tomorrow 3pm I'll sign contract with you
Don't worry
Your commission I understand
I know all your deals with the 'Grandfather
I only want to have my company back
It's only necessary for you to sign here
then company would be mine again
Don't you think
you're too idealistic?
You're artists
You won't complete with me, will you?
I do some shits
so that you will look virtuous
And by the way you know
nothing about bullion and currencies
How about if I'm money-minded?
One million
Not really so money-minded!
Two millions
There've three people
in my family, so at least 3 millions!
3 millions
Yes, And it must be paid in cash cheque!
Grandfather would come
at 3 pm to sign the contract
OK. Sign it
No, I can't
I've to see whether it can be cashed
You still don't trust me!
We maybe in a mess if we trust you again
Don't worry if the cheque is cashed,
I will sign the contract
I'm not so cunning as you're
Have you seen my nephew?
He often goes around the girls.
He's seldom in the office
I... how do I know?
That bastard!
Sign it, it's nice to be able to stand out
Right! Being free from the trouble
is more important than 3 millions
Pig head!
Hay Man, I'm the boss of this company
So please don't call me pig head!
No more nonsense!
Alex said since you've his schoolmate
He told me to give you back the company
Oh really?
Give me the pen
Call you to tea if you've time
Don't call me I don't know you
Haven't you gone to Beijing?
Please save me
Call the police. They've swindles
We've also swindlers!
My 3 millions
Unfasten me first!
It's lucky this time!
Mom, the cheque has been banked in
It's my Phone-call
What?
What about now?
OK
Mom, it's too bad
The Bank said ET wants to cancel our cheque
Forget it. By the way, it's dirty money
But the bank manager said the money
has been transferred into our account
So it can't be canceled!