-Where are you?
-I'm here.
-Come on now children.
-Get up, and come to have breakfast.
Your mother is waiting.
-I'll catch her and...
-Yes, I know.
Come, have breakfast.
We have something to tell you.
-I really don't see why we have
to eat in the living-room
with this tablecloth and these
dishes for a simple breakfast.
-It's the last one we're having together.
It's as important as the first one.
-Dad, are we having chocolate?
-Excuse me children, this morning
didn't start too well.
-There you go...
-Your father and I don't
get along too well anymore.
Well, at least not like before.
So since we hurt each other a lot,
we decided to...
Well, we're leaving each other.
He's leaving this morning.
It's not because of you, that he's leaving,
it's because of me.
Alexis loves you a lot,
he will always love you.
He's a lovely father.
But we've got adult problems.
Love is fragile.
Very difficult.
You have to know that already.
And not too late, as I did.
-Mom, my chocolate!
-So we won't see you anymore?
-But of course, every day, like before.
I'm keeping my study in the house,
we will see each other every evening,
we'll talk, have fun...
For you, nothing will change.
I will continue to take care of everything.
I will give money to your mother.
-I don't want it, I already told you so!
-Don't be ridiculous.
-Since I can't offer you anything any more,
I don't see why you should be taking care of me.
-Think about the kids.
-I am, that's the point.
-You forgot the butter!
-I'll give private lessons.
-Really? What lessons?
-I have a history degree.
-Strange history... Thanks to you,
our children know better Khrushchev,
now there's only Napoleon left.
-If I was a man,
would you respect my ideas?
-Yes, but you are a woman, and a woman
should first of all make her husband happy.
-And didn't I make you happy?
-Yes..For a moment...For some hours...
-For a moment? For some hours?
Is that how you summarize twelve
years of living together?
-A life that we spent less and less together, no?
I can accept that you refuse going to Sunday mass,
while having an occult relationship with the abbot Bouteiller,
but your public, political opinions
are spectacular... You're a scandal!
Your fight against the war in Algeria,
against the law, what does it prove?
It shows that you're not happy with me.
It's well known...When a woman starts dealing
with politics it means that she's bored.
-You really talk like a lawyer.
-Fifty years ago this lawyer
would have made you obey.
But times have changed.
Now it's the lawyer who leaves.
-Then leave fast Alexis.
The children don't need any more explanations.
They understood everything.
-It has been a week now
that we said no,
to the 50 additional centimes,
that the company Roubier
wants to make us pay to go to the factories!
We refused the so-called winter charge,
because it is not the workers
who should pay this increase!
So, for a week now
we have been boycotting the company Roubier,
which means getting up every day,
at four o 'clock in the morning,
and joining the factory,
which means, going home
at ten o'clock in the evening,
which means walking at night
30 km's by foot on an icy road,
between -5 and -10 degrees,
which means being brutalised,
stopped by the police!
So this boycott might seem ridiculous
to those who don't know
what 50 centimes a day
represents for a worker!
So the Roubier company has to choose
between the two solutions that remain
either put back the old price
or face our anger!
So commies, are you scared?
-Pay for your whore of a mother...
Don't worry.
Give this prescribed painkiller to Jean-Paul,
and the aspirin for Laura.
And most of all very hot baths.
In a couple of days they will be fine.
-Thank you.
-Aren't you a little young to do politics?
Stay here, I'll find my way out.
Thank you.
For god's sake, what time is
your mother going to come home?
-She is surely with the strikers.
-With the strikers?
She should be making dinner.
-Usually she comes home earlier and
deals with everything.
-Why were you beaten?
-Because mom is brave enough to say the truth.
And there is no one to defend her.
-Jean-Paul!
-Jean-Paul! We have won!
Get out of here.
-I don't understand.
The day that your children are
massacred for your stupidity,
you will understand!
-That's enough.
-Look at the children, it is your
fault they have been beaten.
So no more politics, no more
publishing papers, no more unions!
I ask you to do this, at least for their sake.
-It's also for your sake, isn't it?
-Or for my sake.
You don't have any afffection for me do you?
But I still have rights over the children,
and I will insist on keeping them, to the end.
-Am I a monster?
-No.
You are not a monster.
You are too idealistic.
You don't know how to keep order,
you don't have allies.
-I don't have allies?
Half of the town was with us.
Even abbot Bouteiller!
-Oh poor thing. I can see him from here
singing the Internationale in his robe.
He will pay dearly.
Lives like others'. Like our children's.
What you would need is a man, a real one.
-And you dad?
-I don't believe so, I don't think
your mother needs me anymore.
-Why didn't you stop him mother?
-Because he loves another woman.
As time passed our parents
divorced amicably.
But there was in fact another
woman in my father's life.
???
My mother, Laura and myself
continued our life together.
Indians in a reserve, tenderly.
In the secrecy of happiness.
In ten years,
many things have changed.
Laura went to Paris to do
medical studies
while my mother sank into solitude.
Time passed.
I find myself married.
I work with my father, who
has kept his study in the house.
However during these ten years
something stronger than time
stronger than madness, didn't change.
My mother still loves Alexandre.
This morning, February 2nd,
Day of the candlemas,
Mamouchka while opening
the shutters declared spring.
-Would you be kind enough to take off the hat,
and take some coffee to Annie?
Like that you you could have coffee
together while waiting for spring.
-Well there you go,
you are also like me.
You're waiting for spring.
I'll bring the coffee.
Friday, 5th of February, auction room.
Barberousse city, Atoll.
-Very well. Thank you.
Do you know what time it is?
-Problems with mother.
-Again? What's going on
with your mother?
-It's the day of the candlemas.
And? I don't see the connection.
-Candlemas. 2nd of February.
-It has been exactly ten years that you left her.
-Yes, it is exactly the anniversary of the day
that we should rather be forgetting.
Don't you agree?
-For you maybe. But not for her.
Every year this date, it can't go on like this.
Two years ago she wanted to die.
And then the last year,
her first heart attack.
-Why didn't you tell me earlier?
-You have another wife,
another household.
-Everyone has their own responsabilites.
-What's going on?
You let her outside like this?
She declared this morning that it's spring.
Listen, something has to be done.
She can't go to town like this...
-Annie and I tried everything but...
-I'll speak to her...
-No!
-Marie-Louise!
-I would like to speak to you.
-It has been years that we haven't spoken.
-Exactly, years. We have many
things to say to each other.
-You should put on your overcoat,
you will catch a cold.
-You are right.
Let's go in my office.
-Well, we're in your stronghold.
Nothing has changed!
But yes, the wallpaper.
It's better.
-You haven't changed either.
-Do you still sit here?
So, Master Boursault.
What are those important
things you have to say to me?
-Nothing.
Well, actually...
Laura wrote to me.
She's coming home next week.
-You know, she wrote to me too.
-Her internship at Saint-Anne is over.
-Not all madmen are peaceful like I am.
I don't understand why people reproach me.
My husband has left me...
and I left politics.
The children are also leaving me little-by-little...
Laura in Paris, Jean-Paul married...
I have the impression
of being the last survivor.
A ship that repeatedly gets shipwrecked.
-Don't be that pessimistic.
I am here.
It's as good as if you
were a thousand miles away...
Nevertheless, it's unbelievable...
there are so many people
who can't bear each other
and still stay together,
because of conventions, children...
And us, who didn't get along that badly,
we left each other,
because of the same conventions.
-This cold that never finishes...
Tell me, don't you think
that this straw hat...
-You don't like it?
-But yes, a lot.
But you have a fur coat,
that fits you so much.
-Do you look at me sometimes?
-Of course I do.
You are charming with that fur coat.
Wear it, for my pleasure.
-Really, pleasure?
-Really.
-I thought this morning
that it was spring.
I wasn't entirely wrong.
-I took his head between my hands,
and then he put his hands on mine...
And we stayed like this for quite a while.
Ten minutes...
One hour...Ten years...
I don't know anymore.
When are you going to
take me dancing?
It has been a while since
we last enjoyed ourselves like crazy.
Being crazy without enjoying yourself...
It's not funny.
All this!
And this.
Thank you.
Keep the marriage bouquet,
and deliver me all the rest.
-She told you 6'o clock, are you sure?
-I'm certain.
-It's starting to snow.
I'll go find her, I'll take the car.
-Wait a little longer...
-You know precisely that
she has got no sense of time.
-Have you seen your father since?
-Has he spoken to you about...
about his meeting this morning?
-Yes.
He hasn't understood a thing.
Or at least he's pretending.
According to him, Marie-Louise is
fine, and she is absolutely sane.
It is us who exaggerate, distort...Well, you know.
-She must have forgotten her keys.
-What is this, who is this for?
-It's for Madame Boursault.
-From whom?
-Madame Boursault.
-It seems that we're just exaggerating,
and Marie-Louise is just fine.
-No, this one's Alexandre's, I recognize it.
-He's only had it for a week now.
It's open.
If it's something for us again...
Oh, you shouldn't have
waited for me with dinner...
Marc bought be some chestnuts.
-What is it Mamouchka?
-What is it?
-Alexandre is coming home,
we must prepare his return!
The house should be worthy of him.
I know Alexandre as the back of my palm.
Oh this is marvellous, it's spring, it's...
Your father hasn't spoken to me for
eight years now, eight years!
He still loves me,
he has never stopped loving me!
-Yes, he talked to you, that's true.
He lives with Clotilde. He surely loves her.
-Oh no, she's frigid.
As if someone who plays Mozart on the piano...
Are they going to have children?
-Mamouchka, you're raving...
-No, I'm seeing clearly!
He married a requiem.
Every time I see that woman on the street,
she's dressed in dark grey, like a grey mouse.
I always wonder who died.
No, Alexandre is like us.
He needs sleepless nights.
He is going to come back, I am sure of it.
-Jean-Paul...
How happy I am.
I have never been as happy as...
I have to write to Laura!
She has to know, she has to...
And all this because
of the red straw hat.
In Nordic countries they always
light candles at candlemas.
It's a day of hope.
The first for me since ten years ago.
My dear Laura,
Extraordinary things have
happened this morning.
Something that hasn't
happened for years now.
Ever since your father has decided to go through
with his ridiculous marriage with Clotilde.
We talked to each other. Him and I.
I took his face between my hands,
and he held my hands.
Have you noticed
how beautiful your father is?
I got to know him with dense, brown hair,
that you use to grab
when you where just a child.
You used to run your
fingers through his hair and asked,
"Wolf, where are you?"
"I am in the forest."
He replied: "What you touch
with your fingers is not the forest.
"It is the skin of my wolf head."
You pretended to be afraid,
and your father told you
"If you are afraid, then you don't love the wolf.
But if you love him,
you don't have to be afraid of him."
Laura, I am happy.
I would do anything so
that your father speaks to me again.
I would dress up in an even crazier way.
As a bohemian, as an odelisque,
as a prostitute, as a man,
as Clotilde...
-Jean-Paul...Jean-Paul!
-My word, we could put this in the basement.
-Come and help me, we'll
put this back where it belongs.
-Don't you think it would
be better to go to sleep?
-I want Alexandre to find the same room.
-I'm asking you to come back.
Talk softer.
As if we had anything to hide in front of others.
-Keep quiet!
-Are you afraid?
You even stopped wearing your engagement ring?
-I'm asking you, everyone is watching!
-Then watch closely!
-If he knew how much I've changed...
He would be very surprised.
All the same, I never stopped loving him.
Listen, we are all very tired.
What if we spoke about this tomorrow...
I don't want you to be miserable.
-Miserable?
I have reached bottom so often,
nothing worse can happen.
No, I am happy.
-It's 3 o'clock in the morning.
-Jean-Paul...You who knows him well...
He wouldn't have spoken to me,
just because of a hat?
It's not possible...
Jean-Paul?
You do know that it's 3 o'clock in the morning?
Don't you think that you're exaggerating?
I've almost finished.
This feverish activity that you have
been recently doing, hides something.
You take every chance to shun me.
Politics included.
-That's true.
Since you took over the office of your father,
you are suspicious.
You're too immersed in your work.
We pass ten days without
speaking to each other.
Evidently, I need to do something.
I don't want to feel useless.
I would like to exist.
But apart from that, nothing has changed.
I still love you Alexis.
Doctors,
social system,
even a certain church
are responsible for the death of Yvette Leblanc.
A woman is dead at 30,
for having refused to have a seventh child.
This death is a crime. -It is not a reason...
-A collective crime!
We don't have the right to stay silent.
-Bad news.
But a logical one.
I have been demoted.
-Bourgeoisie is stronger than us.
-That's not a hat, it's a ???
-And why, don't you like red?
-Marie-Louise!
-You're spending your life destroying mine!
I'm losing clients!
-Do you prefer losing me,
instead of losing your clients?
-You, always you!
Your office, your clients, your respectability!
This town is rotten to the bone,
and you say nothing, you approve!
-You're against everything,
against me, against my job!
I was suggested to leave this town.
Laura, don't ever subordinate
love to your ideas.
Don't ever be ashamed to feel
like a woman from head to toes...
-Be realistic, for god's sake,
you have to cope with other people!
-The others, always the others!
Exteriority, conventions!
Conventions.
Laura especially don't
commit the same errors I did.
Deep down neither your father,
nor I failed our duties
But we had our misunderstandings.
What an unfashionable confession.
-We have got to leave each other.
As fast as possible.
I will leave for a while now, I don't know,
I will stay in a hotel.
And in a couple of weeks,
we'll see what we should do.
I'll give you money.
-Money?
If you leave me,
we have to go all the way.
As soon as the children wake up,
we will explain to them.
-What is it Mamouchka?
-Nothing, go back to sleep.
Laura, this is what I decided.
I insist that you meet Marc.
My teacher friend.
My only friend.
He is handsome.
You will like him, I am sure of it.
I need your happiness so badly.
-Jean-Paul!
Tell me about mother
right away, how is she?
You read her letters, not better, nor worse.
-That is? -It's unbelievable,
but she is madly in love with Dad.
And not only is she in
love as one is at age 17,
but she is also sure that he will come back.
This is what they probably call madly in love.
Something has to be done, to cure her.
What right do we have?
Based on what?
We can all be cured from the
first love. But from the last one...
Reason that enters the world of passion.
You see Laura, before you pass a judgement,
you must have loved up to such an extent.
-I will end up thinking
you're all under her influence.
-That's easy to say from the outside.
I guess, that for you ???
Constant fight of the ill
between the maternal feeling and
the frustrated and passionate love, isn't it so?
-If you weren't my brother, I would hate you.
-And if you weren't my sister,
I couldn't bear you for a second.
-Charming.
No, I didn't come home to get to know this
Marc Chandois, or Champois as you call him.
-Champenois.
-Yes, Champenois.
-He's a good guy. He became a friend of Mamouchka,
you see Laura, her friend.
Her friend. A guy who has
her confidence, and who respects her.
A guy who reconciles her with other people.
-Whatever, I refuse to see him.
I feel ridiculous.
-I hope that feeling won't replace everything else.
No wait to see mother before judging her,
you will hardly recognize her.
-And Dad? How does he take all this?
-Very calmly. At least from the outside.
But he also has changed. He drives faster,
he leaves his office at 8...
I have the impression
that he is trying to avoid me.
You know, sometimes I ask myself, whether
mom has succeeded in seducing her ex-husband.
One has to admit that he's under siege;
she writes to him every day, crazy huh?
Every morning at 9, he gets his
letter, he opens it, reads it,
makes no comment, and
goes on to the daily routine.
-And Clotilde? Does she know about this?
-No, that's impossible.
-Mamouchka!
-How are you?
-Fine.
-Annie!
-Let me give you a kiss.
-And how about me?
-And me?
And my daughter of course.
-They had a daughter and
called her Emilie. What a strange idea...
-But no, Emilie is becoming a fashionable name.
-I have a friend, who just had a
daughter and called her Emilie.
-I also have a story to tell.
The Norois have left town, because
their son was involved in a drug affair.
-It's not for us to say.
-Do you know who I'm talking about?
-Here's my surprise.
-There's quite a few of us.
I came for the saturday card game, am I disturbing?
-No not at all, we're
celebrating the arrival of Laura.
-Good evening.
-Should I have canceled?
-No there is still some nice cake.
-Champenois.
-Good evening.
-Worth mentioning
but rather good, isn't it?
-What is worth mentioning?
-Nothing.
-What courage, to come here at such a time.
-I told you, why didn't you
tell him that we aren't available?
-Because we are.
-I genuinely support working women.
For their emancipation.
-You confuse work with freedom.
I think the more a woman works, the less she is free.
She becomes more of a slave.
-But how can one be free
without working? You also work, don't you?
-Very little. I have four months of payed leave a year.
It's a choice. I don't have ambitions.
I imagine that in Paris one needs ambitions.
No, you shouldn't confuse the relationship
work-freedom with work-salary.
I believe that women should be payed, even if they don't work, simply for the happiness they give us.
-That's priceless.
-You owe me a fortune.
-No, love is not the communion
of two exceptional beings.
There's a formidable error ???
-Love, always love, you
talk too much about it to be able feel it.
-Which means that you know it so well,
since you don't talk about it?
-Love at Saint-Anne, you know, in a sick person's bed,
between four white walls...
-I don't know why you react like this, I wrote you letters...
You did read my letters didn't you?
Yes mother, very attentively.
-I don't understand, I asked
Alexandre to come here during the dessert.
He didn't.
And I realize that he didn't.
-But mother...
-What?
-Obviously, no one believes me.
You refuse to accept the truth.
Alexandre still loves me.
He loves me Laura, do you understand?
-You're the only one who still believes this.
If I'm not wrong, it's been eight years
since dad last laid his feet in this room.
Excuse me, I don't know
what I'm saying anymore, I'm tired.
-I'm really sorry.
I never should have started this conversation.
It's not your fault. Laura and
her mother tend to exaggerate.
They resemble each other so much right now.
-Do you remember Laura?
-What a fuss.
-Good evening.
-Hi.
-Are you coming over?
-Yes.
-Be very nice with Marie-Louise.
-Especially tonight. We were all invited to Alexandre
and she hasn't got anything to do.
-Yes I know.
-Let's go, we're already very late.
-Do you want me to go with you?
-No, we're going by foot, we're almost there.
-Ok. Bye.
-Bye.
-Come with me.
-Your father has already taken Laura away?
-They must have so many
things to say to each other. Come inside.
-I suppose that Jean-Paul hasn't been hiding
things from you during this last week.
Your mother writes to me every day.
He shouldn't have told you.
Well, nevermind.
I wanted to speak to you about this anyway.
-Do you reply to these letters?
-What do you want me to reply?
I'm living with Clotilde now.
And she loves me.
-And you, do you love her?
-Oh, I see what you want me to say.
We only love once, isn't it?
That's true, it's nothing compared
to what I felt towards your mother.
-What are you planning to do?
-Nothing.
-Absolutely nothing.
-I'm counting on you. We cannot go backwards.
-But she believes so badly
that you will come back.
-Listen to me Laura, you are the
only one who can help her
I know, from the way she
speaks about you in her letters.
She wants your happiness.
-I can see that. Marc.
Always him.
Mom projects onto me a love that she owes him.
-He's the only nice guy who she has
ever met through abbot Bouteiller.
He feels affection towards her.
???
We must win some time.
Wait for the end of winter.
In Marie-Louise's drama
there is this cold, this iciness,
this snow...
Your mother is a woman of summer.
A woman of the sun.
A woman...
-How is your mother Jean-Paul?
-She's fine.
-I suppose she is glad to see her daughter.
-Yes, she is very happy.
-Excuse me, I have been kidnapped.
If the meal got burnt, at
least I have someone to blame.
-What do you think about Laura?
A little tired, isn't she?
Yes, she looks like it.
Surely because of Paris.
And she has lost weight.
-That's true, I need some rest.
-This is quite a good white wine.
-It's quite icy, isn't it?
-Yes, it is.
-By the way...
-Actually it's not related, but remind
me tomorrow to go to the upholsterer at 3.
-Mhm. What time?
-At three.
-Hurry up!
I have a meeting at 13.
-Would you pass me the
bread please Jean-Paul?
Would you please pass me the bread?
Thank you.
Do you still give piano lessons?
Yes, I do. I've got 5 students currently.
Amongst them there is the
son of Bertier, who is very talented.
-I even suspect that he is
in love with his teacher.
-Oh, Alexandre, listen to yourself.
-It's quite normal, even I took a
liking to piano, thanks to you.
-You know that Bertier's son is only 16.
Or 15 and a half, I'm not sure.
Love has got nothing to do with age,
it can happen at 15 just as well as 40.
-No thank you.
-Really?
-And you Laura?
-No, thank you.
It was delicious.
-Oh, you should eat more.
Look at Annie.
It's a real pleasure watching her eat.
Excuse me.
-It's OK.
-Does Dabores still work with you?
-The housekeeper? She left a month ago.
And you know why? Let me tell you.
She discovered one of my books, a book by Lenin.
She found it on my shelf,
she read it cover to cover,
I don't know whether she understood a great deal,
but after a week, she comes to me, and says
"Monsieur, I'm leaving, I will become a free woman."
So she perfectly understood.
I told her "You're leaving, that's fine,
but what will you do then?"
She says "Then I will be a free woman."
The last news I heard about her is that she's
cleaning the building of the communist party.
-Hurry!
Where is my raincoat?
-Your raincoat? It's in the corridor.
Tidiness is tidiness.
But it's not allowed in town you know.
Check the kitchen.
-It's unbelievable.
It's like looking for a needle in a haystack.
-Jean-Paul!
I think I'm pregnant.
-I found it!
It was in the cold-room.
-Jean-Paul!
-Excuse me, it's because of
that maid who read Lenin.
Damn it.
-What a surprise! Relax, I'm fine.
What a fiesta children!
Marc cooking, me playing the piano...
Ratatouille Nicoise with some Hallelujah.
Everything mixed.
Soup, religion, cheese, revolution.
And how about you, at Madame Boursault, the second?
Have you exchanged some gossips or lies?
Names, dates?
-No, no, nothing worth mentioning.
It was a very orderly party.
We only assassinated
Mozart a little... -I see.
She played ???
with elegant nuances... ???
I don't understand Alexandre's fascination
with these sweeties, who are boring of course.
Well then Laura. How is your father?
Does he have a good appetite?
And Clotilde? Always well? Always artistic?
Always as one should be?
-Please mother, please!
-What are you asking me to do? To shut up?
To finally learn how to stay silent?
To give you the proof,
that I will become sane again?
You expect me not to tell you
that I was heart-broken all night long?
It is just as well my fault as your father's
if you are unhappy!
Nevertheless, we still loved
each other a while ago...
We all loved each other.
What happened to us?
Laura, I'm asking you, how is your father?
-He's fine mother. He was
happy to see me, and look,
he gave me this beautiful bracelet.
-Fifteen years ago he gave me a bracelet
that looked exactly like this one.
Is it here to remind me, is it a sign, a call?
Laura, giving exactly the same
bracelet after fifteen years...
can not be an accident.
If I was sure he still loved me, I would...
I would accept everything,
I wouldn't be alone anymore.
Ask him, whether he still loves me.
I'm feeling better.
This bracelet makes me feel better.
I'm leaving.
-Already?
-Earlier, at Clotilde...
you surely haven't heard what I told you.
I'm pregnant.
I told you, I'm pregnant.
Without a doubt.
It's official since this afternoon.
-I'm expecting a child.
We're expecting a child.
I don't want to wait 9 months like this.
-What's going on?
-Nothing my love.
-Aren't you expecting a child?
*Singing*
-What's going on?
-Come on, Annie is expecting a child.
How happy I am, I am the
happiest father in the world!
-Shall we tell mother?
-Let's go! Mamouchka, Mamouchka!
You are going to be a grandmother.
-Grandmother?
Laura?
-No, Annie!
-Annie is pregnant?
???
-Let me kiss you.
Me too.
I knew alright that it is spring.
-Oh look!
You're so happy together,
I will take it as a miracle!
What are you going to call this boy?
-This boy?
-It will surely be a boy?
-We don't know yet.
-You will call him Alexandre.
After all, it might be a girl.
Then we won't name her anything else but Laura.
Everyone their heritage.
We'll give Laura's dresses to her children.
The Champenois children.
It's terrible that I can't say anything anymore.
Look at the face your making.
-I am not in love with anyone
and most definitely not with Champenois.
-Definitely not? -Look, what if we talked
about Laura's children another time?
-No, we must talk about it precisely now.
It's easy to say,
that I'm the one who isn't well.
That I'm the failure, the crazy one.
That I failed my life.
It is true, I failed, Laura.
And you are afraid of
not succeeding at your own.
You are so afraid of not
succeeding at your life as a woman.
And it is not easy, believe me.
You refuse Champenois. You turn your back to him
in advance. Well that's vanity.
Meanwhile you try to wear out his enthusiasm
with your lousy blouses and skirts?
-Stop it! Laura is very beautiful, leave her alone.
-I will be fine Jean-Paul. Go, see to Laura.
-We don't want Mamouchka
projecting her personal problems onto us.
-She's accusing us of her own weaknesses.
-We musn't leave her alone.
-She must feel very bad that she made me suffer.
Open up Mamouchka.
Mamouchka, I love you.
-How beautiful you are Laura.
I will stop saying my crazy ideas.
I only want your happiness.
-I will be happy, and so will you.
Tomorrow, we'll go to town,
and buy me clothes so that I look pretty.
So that Champenois will like me.
-It's 4 o'clock. I'm hungry.
-How about some pancakes?
-Good idea.
-It's good to realize now.
-Mamouchka, you're really unbearable.
-Every pregnant woman is.
It's a marvellous state.
You're being taken care of, pampered, cuddled...
The whole world is at your feet.
Like two apples.
Mom would like you to be the godfather.
Grandfather and godfather,
that might be a bit too much, no?
She insists.
Your mother is indulgent
towards Laura at the moment.
No.
No, I decidedly cannot be the
godfather of your child, I'm sorry.
Can you imagine me standing
next to the baptismal font?
Anyway, we're divorced.
I'll try to keep distance with your mother.
Champenois is going to fall head over heels
when he sees you. He won't know whom to chose.
It's Laura who is going to fall head over heels.
Wait until you see the dinner that is awaiting us.
-Nothing broken?
-No, no...
Give me a second, to
meditate over this fall.
Even if my backside is being kept cold.
You see, children,
this fall is the symbol of my whole life.
Marie-Louise Boursault, with her ass on the ground.
Thank god we didn't have to pass in front of Clotilde.
What would I look like,
Madame Boursault with her buttocks in the snow.
in front of the children from the first bed.
It's a funny expression, "first bed", isn't it?
-Look out.
-Look out, let's not fall over again.
-You see, I'm just joking. I'm much better.
It's great, being able to laugh,
when we fall to the ground.
At 5 degrees below 0.
That's optimistic, isn't it?
-To Annie's baby!
-It's rather strong your punch.
-You have to get drunk from time to time.
Especially in the winter.
-Where did you learn how to make couscous?
In jail, in Algeria.
The only book that wasn't
censured was a cooking book.
I traveled a lot.
The best way to learn about
a country is through its cuisine.
And its women. Here you go Jean-Paul,
Would you serve everyone?
This couscous is something I learned
in Djabel during the Algerian war.
When you are on a rock without trees or
grass, without any petrol beneath you,
you say to yourself it's pretty stupid to get shot
for a couple of pebbles under your feet.
You could just as well get
shot for some couscous, no?
-And you, what did you learn in the army?
-The genius of permissions.
Would you know something about that?
-It's good, having lived a lot of
things. You learn how to live better.
-By the time one learns
how to live, it is already too late.
-Oh, I'm sorry.
-Why did you take her off, she was very pretty.
-Personal memories.
-Come on, let's see all your conquests.
The whites, the blacks, the yellows...
You said earlier, that women
taught you more about the world,
than the world itself...
-Did I say that? -Yes.
-That's Monica.
-Monica, who is she?
-The love of his life.
-No, that was my black period.
I did inverse racism, I talked
about "Negritude" and black power.
The result: Monica took to my ideas so much,
she applied them word by word,
that one day, she couldn't
even bear the sight of a white man, me included.
She was maybe a victim of her liberalism.
-But there is no liberalism, ever.
Violence is everywhere, in every relationship.
Class conflict is very common.
One day, a director of a factory,
who thinks of himself as liberal,
organizes a competition for his workers.
The winner gets the rights to live like
the director of the factory, for a whole year.
So there is this worker, who during weeks,
months, travels in this Mercedes with a chauffeur,
goes for a weekend in Deauville, bets on horses,
passes his time in villas, in baths,
casinos, he goes hunting... Everything.
He goes to the theater, the opera,
meets all the famous people in the world
and when the one year is over,
he returns to the factory.
He finds himself working in the factory once again,
and that same evening, he goes into the office
of the director with a revolver, and kills him.
Monica hasn't killed Marc, but it's the same.
She couldn't thank you.
-I like you a lot Laura.
-Actually we are all victims of this free world.
-By now I have become tolerant.
I accept everything. All sorts of racism, liberation...
violence, sexuality, there are no more taboos,
everyone has to discover themselves.
Only in this town, everyone wears masks,
no one wants to be discovered.
If only we could get drunk.
-To Annie's baby.
-Everything is fine Jean-Paul, everything is fine.
You've already got a mad mother, a pregnant wife,
and now you have a sister in love.
-Oh, the amount we drank at Marc's place...
What time is it?
-Time to kiss me.
-Someone rang, no?
-Just in your head...
You drank too much at Marc's place.
What are you looking for?
-My glasses.
Someone rang the bell.
Are you expecting anyone?
Good morning children.
-Good morning Mamouchka.
-Did he sleep well?
-You aren't early birds, are you?
Well, I missed Laura, and since the weather
turned worse as I was walking, I came to see her.
I didn't think I would be waking
you at 3 in the afternoon.
Don't bother about me, I will
talk with Laura here, in this room.
-That's out of the question.
You're welcome amongst us Alexis.
I must be disturbing you
Marie-Louise, excuse me,
I'm here to see Laura.
-Since when does one have to excuse
themselves for loving their own children?
-Since when does love need an excuse?
-You see, nothing has changed, still a mess, still bohemia.
-Annie! Alexis came to visit us!
Let's go prepare breakfast.
Let's go to the dining room Alexandre.
Take a seat.
Do you recognize it? This was your armchair.
Jean-Paul is using it now.
-I am happy for the child.
-Eat some jam.
I started making orange jam
since a couple of years ago.
I'm not too hungry, I was silly
enough to have some lunch.
-Do you like it?
-In the old days, you limited
your cooking to plum jam..
-I am glad, very glad that you visited.
But I know that you didn't
come for my sake. I'll leave.
I will leave you alone with Laura.
-Where are you going mom, stay!
-Marie-Louise!
I came to see Laura, of course, but I am happy to see you...all.
I see Jean-Paul every day for work related
reasons, but it has been years since...
I haven't seen my children at home.
I must admit, today I couldn't resist.
It's not only you, who is afraid of winter...
-Yes?
-What was I saying.
Oh yes.
I also came to talk about the
child who is about to be born.
I would like him to help us bury the hatchet.
-You don't hate me anymore?
-I never hated you.
I would like this child to rebalance you. To calm you.
-I haven't been writing to you for the last three days.
I wanted to steal you from Clotilde. What madness.
What vanity.
What do you think of Champenois?
-Is there any point in talking about Marc?
-I think he must be a good guy, a free soul.
-They like each other.
-If you don't mind, I would
really like to talk about something else.
-Would like to see the house?
Quite a lot has changed.
-Happily.
-Why don't you come more often?
This is your house as well.
Crazy, isn't it?
One could spend a lifetime here.
Or even die here.
Come on. Follow your guide.
We'll visit the royal room.
This is the room of love.
Of hell.
???
-Psychopatology.
-Psychoanalysis.
-Perversion.
-Hysteria.
All this seems very serious to me. Too serious.
-You are looking in vain. Ther is no
man under that bed. At least for now.
-She is becoming more and more intolerable.
-Goodbye.
I have to get going,
Clotilde must be waiting for me.
-Alexis, I love you.
-Don't be sad.
It's so obvious that he came because of you.
-He didn't even ask to see my room.
-That's because of decency and
discretion, do you understand?
-It's him!
-What's going on?
-Nothing.
-Alexandre just left.
-Is it the end, or the beginning,
I don't know anymore.
And you Marc, do you love Laura?
Last night, I thought that you two...
-Well, I actually came to say that...
I'm in love with Laura.
-Oh Laura, how happy I am.
If only you could be as happy as I am.
We came to a full stop.
Ever since the visit of Alexandre,
my mother visits the countryside.
She goes cycling during the week ???
After an imaginary encounter with Alexandre,
Marie-Louise became once again happy.
She continued hoping for a second honeymoon.
-Everything has to shine for the big return of Alexandre.
Annie ceased to fight.
Her alibi: migraine, sleepiness.
Mother, you have to get better.
Without that, we will become like
a slowly sinking ship.
I know we can do it.
We are almost ready to throw the bottle in the sea.
I am unhappy, mother.
We are unhappy, Mamouchka.
-Concert in 8 minors, for Alexandre.
First part.
Return of Alexandre.
-Ten o'clock, and she still hasn't arrived.
You really cannot be trusted!
-But Jean-Paul, she is a grown-up!
-I have had enough of this, really!
If you two aren't able to take care of her,
I will get her locked up!
-Don't talk rubbish!
-It's not rubbish.
I'm saying what everyone is thinking.
I would like you to give birth in peace.
Without any scandals.
-You're talking about scandals,
and you don't even know where she is,
or what she's doing right now.
-Well, it's not my job to know what she's doing.
You were with her when she left,
she must have told you something!
-She told me that she was
going to post a letter, that's all!
-And right now she might just as well be
throwing cobblestones at Clotilde's window.
-Jean-Paul, you're exaggerating!
-No, but I'm not joking, if this goes on like this,
we should really start thinking about a psychiatric hospital.
-It's me.
-Here. What's with the face?
-Hello, Clotilde? It's Jean-Paul.
-Excuse me to disturb you at this hour,
but I would like to speak with my father.
He hasn't arrived yet.
Don't worry, maybe his car just broke down.
In any case, if he doesn't arrive shortly,
don't hesitate and call us.
No, nothing serious, just a
small problem in the Fournier case.
Good night.
Do you have your car?
-Yes. -Let's go find her.
-Four hours just to post a letter,
we thought of everything, an accident, a kidnapping!
-A kidnapping, at my age?
Well, you are not wrong.
I was kidnapped.
I didn't want to tell you, you would have been worried.
The night was so beautiful.
The sky full of stars...
with some waterfalls,
and in the end I met your father.
We walked together...
then we left town...
on the path next to the river with the small shed.
He wanted to take this walk as much as I did.
Your father is coming home.
Stop worrying. Winter continues.
But spring is inside me.
-Hello?
Jean-Paul? Your father has just arrived.
Were you worried for me?
That's kind. I went to see about this case...
Are you dining?
-No, not yet. Mom just arrived.
-Well then... Enjoy your meal.
-See you tomorrow.
-What is it?
Abbot Bouteiller wrote to me, he wants to
see me at 9, at the Hotel de France.
-What does he want?
-I think mother must have
sent him a letter, that got him worried.
-I would be grateful if you told me
what's going on when you arrive home.
-Why are you talking to me like that?
Do you think I'm enjoying this?
Mom must have written an exalted
letter regarding the engagement of Laura,
he wants to clear things up.
-You're right.
I haven't thought about that.
-To what do I owe the pleasure?
-I'm afraid this won't be so pleasurable,
but I received a letter from your mother.
And what she says in this letter, is beyond understanding.
-You know my mother.
-Yes, but... I don't know her anymore.
That's why I asked you to come.
Well...
Your mother has met her
ex-husband one evening, last week.
Alexandre took her back by car,
and she arrived home at 11 o'clock in the evening.
-I know about this.
-But do you also know that she is pregnant?
Well, at least she thinks so.
She is at a point where she imagines that meeting
with her ex-husband for two hours is enough to...
get her pregnant.
Your mother is completely losing her mind.
She tells herself stories, and
believes in them so strongly
that all this can become very serious.
For everyone.
For Alexandre's family, yours as well...
and also for Marie-Louise's well-being.
-She is mad.
And my father who gets involved
in this, taking her for a ride...
He probably just touched her hand at most.
I've had enough of this family.
-Don't get carried away.
You have to reason based on facts.
-What facts? Here are the facts: My father came to
our house one afternoon to speak to Laura,
then they met, they talked and nothing happened between them.
-And your father hasn't mentioned this encounter?
-Exactly.
-If I want to know the truth, I have to ask my father.
Supposing he didn't go mad too.
Dad, I have to speak to you.
-Hello Clotilde. Is my father here?
-No, isn't he in the study? Come in.
???
Sit down.
-My mother.
-I received a letter from her this morning.
-What did she write in it?
-Things Jean-Paul...Terrible things.
And strong things.
It's an ultimatum.
She is asking me to let your
father return to your house.
She says that he still loves her.
And that she is expecting a child.
A child, do you realize?
Only to hurt me.
Because I didn't have one with Alexandre.
-She's mad.
She writes to everyone.
There hasn't been anything going on between Alexandre
and her for ten years now.
She has to be cured.
-She has to be put in a house.
A clinic.
I know a very good one in Switzerland.
It's quite expensive, but it's almost like a holiday home.
In any case, Annie has to be spared.
-Alexandre always loved good food.
-Mom, I have to talk to you right away.
I know about all the letters, to the abbot,
to Clotilde, this child you're supposed to have...
-What's this Jean-Paul?
Why are you getting involved?
-Don't you think about Annie? She's the one pregnant,
do you want her to have a miscarriage?
-Shut up Jean-Paul, calm down!
-No.
Listen mother, there is no solution,
-Stop seeing dad or whoever,
or I'll have to get you cured
whether you want it or not!
-You still don't believe me,
that your father still loves me?
He's coming back Jean-Paul!
And sooner than you think!
-He won't come back! -He will!
This house is his, every furniture, everyone,
even Annie's child is his!
-I just spoke to my father.
He told me that all this isn't true,
the child, his return, nothing!
He doesn't understand why you made up all this.
-You spoke to him?
-Just an hour ago.
He even told me that
he was going to leave this town.
He's leaving with Clotilde.
I'm leaving Clotilde Jean-Paul, I'm coming back here.
I'm going to restart my life with
Marie-Louise, I cannot live without her.