HEAT WAVE
Aren't you napping?
I can't sleep.
Anyway, it's too hot.
If only you slept at night.
- I must run or I'll be late.
- Will you be home late?
I'm working 3 to 9 tonight.
Bye, Ma.
It's a new kind of pregnancy test.
Do you know how to use it?
Thanks.
How much is it?
9.90.
Thank you.
Bye.
Sorry I'm late.
No trouble.
I get so bored on my breaks,
I do nothing but eat!
Can I take 15 more minutes?
As long as you like.
I'll pay you back.
Miss!
Please!
Hello. So you work here?
Only for the summer.
Could you reach me
that bottle of milk?
Not that one! Glass is better.
This one?
Damn it! Can't you watch out?
Amelie, it's Ma here.
I know you're at work.
I've had to go to Aix.
My sister's taken ill.
Nothing serious,
but the kids need looking after.
Philippe's disappeared again.
Don't stay out too late, OK?
I've cooked you
some stew and macaroni,
and you can finish the tomato tart.
Don't warm it in the microwave,
it'll go soggy,
but you can microwave
the stew and pasta.
Invite Luigi if you like.
Take care, love.
I should be home tomorrow evening.
Could you hang out the washing
in the machine?
Lots of love.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Everything OK?
Amelie!
Aren't you at football?
No. We need to talk.
Not now, Luigi. I'm working.
I had to work late
so I missed your break.
It's important.
Can't somebody sub for you?
No.
Come round tonight if you want.
Please, just five minutes.
Luigi, go away or I'll get fired.
There you go.
I think you've given me too much.
Oh yes. Thanks.
Ten euros.
Thank you.
- Thanks.
- Have a nice day.
I've only got this.
Mind if I go first?
Will you listen to me now?
1.09, please.
What?
Coke is 1.09.
Moron!
I come to say I'm leaving
and you sell me a Coke.
Keep your job.
Luigi!
Follow us, please.
Meet me behind the store.
The loading bay.
11 euros 82.
I'm closed, madam.
What?
This till is closed.
I'm sorry.
You're joking.
I've been waiting ten minutes!
I'm not moving.
Call your manager.
I'm staying right here.
Switchboard.
Amelie, checkout 3.
Can you come? I feel sick.
I'll send someone.
- For God's...
- She's coming, OK?
Supervisor to checkout 3, please.
Hello.
- Something wrong?
- She won't take me.
I feel sick. Can I go home?
See to this lady.
Then you can close.
I said I feel sick.
I want to go home.
This is very unlike you.
Yes, well it happens.
Finish your work
and then we'll talk.
I'll check you out myself, madam.
This is ridiculous!
You can close, Amelie.
Till 3 is 250 euros short.
What?
It can't be.
I double checked.
It can't be!
Relax. Maybe it's a mistake.
I'll count again.
Sorry!
I forgot to count the float.
I'm sorry.
Hello,
you've reached Anne Gasquet.
I can't take your call now,
but please leave a message
after the tone.
Ma, it's Amelie.
Why don't you ever answer?
I'm coming home.
I feel sick and nauseous.
Call me when you get this.
I think I'm pregnant.
Good afternoon.
- Is Luigi here?
- He's out.
You can come in and wait.
No need. I'll come back.
Goodbye.
Hi.
Are you feeling OK?
I'm all right.
Want a lift?
Thank you.
Sorry about the milk.
Never mind.
Hassan, have you seen Luigi?
No.
Amelie?
It's me.
Open up.
Open up!
I know you're there.
I saw your car outside.
Please let me in.
Let me in!
Amelie! I know you're in there.
Don't.
It's gridlock.
I'll have to let you out.
Is it far?
Not if you take the back streets.
How much is that?
35 euros.
Thank you.
What's this?
Baklava. Made of almonds, honey,
orange blossom water, and sugar.
I'll take two.
Anything else?
Two krone el ghazal...
And one of those.
Will that be all?
That's 5.30, please.
Taxi!
Excuse me! I need to get off.
The door, please!
Careful, madam.
Sorry.
The door!
Dr. Altman will see you soon.
First we'll take a blood sample.
- Your stomach's empty, right?
- Yes.
Your room is here.
You're lucky to be first in line.
I'll be back
to take you to the doctor.
Thank you.
Slip this on.
I brought one with me.
This one is better for examinations.
And no earrings, please.
Thank you.
This is Amelie's voicemail.
You can leave a message.
Amelie, it's Ma.
I know you're at work.
I've had to go to Aix.
My sister's taken ill.
Nothing serious,
but the kids need looking after.
She's on her own.
Philippe's disappeared again.
Don't stay out too late, OK?
I've cooked you
some stew and macaroni,
and you can finish the tomato tart.
Don't warm it in the microwave,
it'll go soggy,
but you can microwave
the stew and pasta.
Invite Luigi if you like.
Take care, love.
I should be home tomorrow evening.
Could you hang out the washing
in the machine?
Thanks.
Lots of love.
Dad?
Where's Stephane?
Draining the 'dozer.
Make yourself useful.
Still at it?
I'm fuckin' sick of this.
No way to earn a living.
Smothered in grease...
Gimme a hand?
Luigi!
Come here.
After your shift, I need you and
your cousin to clear out the shed.
OK, Dad.
We'd finish sooner
if you did some work.
Fuck it.
Our first day
and you're moaning.
It's exploitation!
And we'll be late for football.
You playing tonight?
I'm seeing Amelie.
I'll meet you later.
She's all you think about!
I don't switch girls every day.
I do, 'cause I like virgins.
They turn me on.
Did you pop Amelie's cherry?
- I bet she never sucks you.
- Shut it!
She doesn't look the sort.
Fuck! Stephane!
Get a fire extinguisher!
Dad!
The shed's on fire!
Stephane!
- What happened?
- Nothing.
Speak up.
What happened?
Sorry.
What?
I said I'm sorry!
Jump on!
Leave me alone!
Don't be a dick.
You OK?
Fuckin' leave me alone!
My ankle!
Come on.
Get on.
OK?
You need a hospital?
Just leave me alone.
Mamma, it's me.
Not so good.
It's Dad.
I can't stay here.
I quit the job.
I've got to go.
I'll tell you later.
I'll explain everything.
Let me come home.
If I take the train tonight,
I'll arrive tomorrow morning.
I can't stay here.
Dad doesn't know.
Don't phone him.
I'll tell him myself.
I'll tell him
before I take the train tonight.
I promise.
Some.
Stephane will lend me the rest.
I'll call you when I arrive.
Kisses.
Mamma...
Nothing.
I love you.
Who was that?
My mother.
- Lend me some clothes?
- Sure.
This one?
Ready to go?
Wait for me here.
Amelie!
- Aren't you at football?
- We need to talk.
Not now. I'm working.
We had to work late
so I missed your break.
Can't somebody sub for you?
No.
Come round tonight.
Please, just five minutes.
Five minutes.
Go away or I'll get fired.
Go on.
Keep your job!
Luigi, wait!
Meet me behind the store.
The loading bay.
Where the fuck is she?
I need to see Amelie, the blonde
checkout clerk, you know?
There's no entry here.
Please let me in.
I hurt my ankle. I can't walk far.
You know Amelie.
The tall, blonde checkout clerk.
It's the rules.
You know her.
Can't you get her for me?
I can't.
I know you're doing your job
but it's not much to ask.
Back off, please.
Shut your faggot face.
Beat it!
Can't you give
that fuckin' ball a rest?
What's the matter?
Nothing!
Did she agree to go with you?
Let's go.
Casarsa? Where's that?
In Friuli, Italy.
Italy...
Can you spell it?
C-A-S-A-R-S-A.
- Can I come?
- No.
Leaving when, sir?
Now. This evening.
There's no direct train, sir.
You'll have to change at Venice.
The first train leaves tomorrow...
at 10:32.
I need to leave now.
There's no other train, I'm afraid.
You can stay at my place.
Would you like to book a seat?
Sir?
Are we going to play or not?
I can't. I hurt my ankle.
We've been waiting an hour.
Amelie.
It's me.
Open up.
Amelie!
I know you're there.
I saw your car outside.
Please let me in.
What happened to your cheek?
The stupid security guard.
He did my face in.
Why are you leaving?
I've got no choice.
My dad hit me.
I'm not running away.
I'm going back home.
Come with me.
Don't ask me to.
That tickles.
Meet me outside?
You can decide about Italy
in a few days.
Are you playing?
I can't. I hurt my leg.
Afraid to lose?
No, it's true. I swear.
Pick teams?
OK, you first.
I'll take Dorian.
I'll take Issam.
Romain.
Flo.
Can't I play?
- You're useless.
- You can be ref.
I've been waiting to play
for an hour.
We'll shoot penalties.
In the old man's gateway.
The spot's here.
OK.
Nice one!
Yay! It's in there.
Don't shoot so hard.
128 kilos.
I feel chilly.
May I get dressed?
Please do.
As I said before,
it's not really an operation.
The gastric balloon
is fitted without surgery.
- You've seen the anaesthetist?
- Last week.
I can't see any problem,
so here's what we'll do.
I perform an endoscopy
under general anaesthetic.
If I don't see anything wrong,
I insert the balloon in your stomach
and fill it with fluid.
It only takes about 20 minutes.
We monitor you for a few hours.
If all is well, you go home.
We do an X-ray follow- up
a few days later.
The balloon will make
your stomach feel full,
so you won't feel hungry.
After about six months,
I'll remove it.
How much weight will I lose?
A substantial amount
in the first six months.
After that, it will depend on you,
your future eating habits
and how much exercise you take.
You'll meet regularly with our staff
to help you control your weight
and stay fit.
They'll give you dietary advice
and psychological support.
That's all.
I'll see you later in the theatre.
One last thing, which I'm sure
you've already been told.
No food before the operation.
It could be dangerous.
Excuse me, Miss!
You work here?
Can you reach me
a bottle of milk?
Not that one!
Glass is better.
Damn it! Can't you watch out?
How much is that?
22.50, please.
Amelie!
We need to talk.
Your receipt and change.
Good afternoon, sir.
Store security.
May I see your receipt, please?
Thank you.
Stand back please, sir.
Do you mind if I take a look?
Just checking your purchases
against the receipt.
It shouldn't take long.
Wine...
Mineral water...
Go through the gate again, please.
This way, sir.
And now back again.
Please.
Thank you.
What's this about?
Just a routine check, sir.
Please come with us.
Bring your bag to the security room,
just for a minute.
Go ahead.
Thank you, sir.
Excuse us.
Wait, Luigi!
Come in.
Good afternoon, sir.
Please watch the screen.
Is that you?
I can't see without my glasses.
I don't need glasses
to see you stealing a CD.
Are you calling me a thief?
We've got the video
and you triggered the alarm.
I was a union shop steward.
You owe me respect, young man.
If I say I stole nothing,
it's true.
Not all shoplifters are trash,
you know.
We catch teachers,
ladies, cops' wives...
Let me go.
Why not shop stewards?
OK, strip. Gimme your coat.
Gimme your coat.
Arms wide.
Nothing there.
What's this, then?
Mozart's 23rd concerto
by Arthur Rubinstein. Heard of it?
Is that all you took?
Let's see. Shirt off.
Hurry up.
And your teeshirt.
Trousers.
What big balls you've got, Grandpa!
Out with it.
Pretending you've got a big one?
A leaky dick, more likely.
Now we know you're clean.
Turn around.
Nothing there either.
Get dressed.
Gramps!
The CD...
You buy it, you keep it.
Pick up your padding.
Till 3 is 250 euros short.
What?
It can't be.
Hi.
Are you feeling OK?
I'm all right.
Want a lift?
Yay! It's in there.
Dear Ma, I got your message.
By the time you get home,
I'll have gone to Italy with Luigi.
I'll phone you to explain.
Don't be sad. I have no choice.
Lots of love,
Amelie.
Good shot.
Nice try, Youssef!
Watch and dream.
Goalie saves.
Can't you even hit
a goal that big?
Show him where to fuckin' shoot!
Shoot straight.
Make my day.
Look at that!
Subtitles by Nigel Palmer
Subtitling by C.M.C. - Paris