- [Dispatcher On Radio]
I believe there were
shots fired there.
- [Officer On Radio]
10-4, we're on our way.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] Five-01?
- [Officer On Radio] Four.
- [Officer On Radio] It's Five-06
out of the office.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4. One-08.
- [Officer On Radio] 10-4.
- [Officer On Radio] 20, what's the 20?
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 13 and Washington.
- [Officer On Radio] We're en route.
- One-01.
- No response at 9 Hickman.
- [Officer On Radio] One-20 after Alpha.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
One-35.
- [Officer On Radio] 35.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
10-4, are you injured there?
- [Officer On Radio] Partner's been shot.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4, FD is 10-76,
500-Adam, copy?
- [Officer On Radio] No.
[Dispatcher On Radio]
Officer's been injured there.
(emergency vehicle siren approaching)
- [Cindy Voiceover] In the back
of every policeman's wife's mind,
lies that nagging thought
that, maybe, one night,
he just won't come home from work.
I guess I just never thought
it would ever happen to me.
(gun fires loudly)
(upbeat music)
♫ Some men live
♫ To forgive
♫ All men cry
♫ Some men die
♫ All men know
♫ Some must go
♫ Before their time
♫ Heaven's Heroes
♫ If you're living on the
brink of death every day
♫ You forget about the dangers
that are found in your way
♫ But you're doin' your job
(doorbell rings)
♫ Yes, you're doin' your job
♫ Heaven's
♫ Heroes
♫ You know
♫ Some must go
♫ Before their time
♫ Heaven's Heroes
- Cindy, there's been an accident.
Denny's been hurt.
- What happened?
I know you can't tell
me what happened, but...
Can you tell me how badly he's hurt?
- We don't know.
All we know is that he's in the hospital.
(police siren approaching)
- Denny?
- Hmm?
- I have been asking you for a month
to get me a date with
that guy in the first row.
Why won't you?
He's your best friend.
- Um, Cindy, see, I have a memory problem,
especially when I'm in school.
I can't remember his name.
- Oh.
Well, Mr. Hill, just how
long have you had this, uh,
problem with your memory.
- What problem.
(both laughing)
Um, Cindy, you
you could go out with me
until I remember his name.
(church bells ringing)
- Okay.
(birds chirping)
(light music)
(female vocalists singing
long, harmonious oohs)
- [Cindy Voiceover] As I
walked down the hallway,
I asked God to forgive
the man who shot Denny.
I did forgive him, and that surprised me,
that I could do it and mean it.
Is this a dream?
This isn't happening to me.
- [Man] I heard Hill got it in the face.
- [Cindy Voiceover] Oh, God
help me, I can't go in there.
Why doesn't the doctor come and tell me
when Denny will go to surgery?
Why do they make me wait?
It's not fair.
(sighs)
Jesus,
take my hand.
- Because you are Christians,
and because you have great
dreams in your hearts,
I hope you will pray together,
and practice those disciplines
that will undergird your
life forever and ev--
- Grandpa, can we watch cartoons on TV?
- Children, come on out of here.
Grandpa's havin' a wedding.
- Could you guys hurry?
We're missing our favorite cartoons.
- Hey.
We'll hurry.
- Mister, I hope you
live happily ever after.
(wedding music)
- How do you like being Mrs. Hill?
- I love it.
Say it again.
- Mrs. Hill.
(Cindy laughing)
- Say it again.
- (Doctor's voice) Mrs. Hill.
Mrs. Hill.
- Oh.
- I'm Dr. Kelsey.
Your husband has suffered a
very, very serious brain injury.
- Is there anything you can do?
- Well, the fragments could be removed,
but, uh, that would be
of doubtful benefit.
The brain tissue has been
severely torn by one pellet
that entered through his left eye,
and this damage is irreparable.
If it had hit 1/4 of an inch higher,
it would have hit the skull,
and that's something
we could've dealt with.
- May I see him.
- Of course.
Mrs. Hill,
your husband, uh, is not suffering.
Matter of fact, he hasn't been
suffering since the injury,
because he's been in such a deep coma.
Now, he's not responsive,
but I would encourage you
to go in and talk to 'im.
(dramatic orchestral music)
(heart monitor rhythmically beeping)
(respirator breathing regularly)
- Lord.
I need him.
Our children need him.
Please.
We love him so much.
I love you.
- You know,
people see a
a blue uniform
and they think we're different.
The whole thing is that
we are, uh, we're human.
This guy is a, uh, a little boy's daddy.
He's a guy who, uh... (crying)
- Wayne, you know, at this very moment,
Jesus knows exactly how we feel.
You wanna be alone with Denny?
I'll, um, go get you a cuppa coffee.
(monitor rhythmically beeping)
(respirator breathing regularly)
(helicopter engine running
and rotors turning)
(upbeat orchestral music)
- Freeze now!
Get your hands off of him!
(rifle being cocked)
- Hands on the car. You!
Move it!
Get your hands on the car.
Step back three steps.
Step back, stretch it out!
(police siren approaching)
You guys'll get pretty brave
when it's four against one.
Here, hold this, will ya?
I gotta go to the bathroom.
- So I said to the guy, look,
you were illegally parked,
you have to move it.
The guy said, it's in fronta my house,
and he wants to fight.
- Rick, some laws certain
people don't agree with,
so, when we try to enforce
them, we meet some resistance.
(makes a tongue click)
Comes with the job, pal.
- I musta met every creep in
town the first day on the job.
(both chuckling)
- Hey, Rick.
Cops don't get invited
to birthday parties.
Most of the time that's
all you'll see as a cop,
people at their worst.
(shotgun being cocked)
You'd do well to remember that.
- Boy, I sure wish they hadn't dropped
that helicopter program.
A guy's gotta work for
a living on the ground.
- How you getting along
with your new partner?
- He just got transferred.
- Oh?
You looking for a new partner?
- Yup.
I just came over to ask ya,
if you ever thought about a two man.
- Sure.
Thought about it a lot.
- You wanna team up again?
- Sure.
- Let's go see the watch commander.
- I already did.
- (laughs) What do you
mean you already did?
- How do you think your new
partner got transferred?
(monitor beeping rhythmically)
(respirator breathing regularly)
- Here's your coffee.
- Thanks.
- You know, you really
oughta get some rest.
It's almost daylight.
- Maybe I'd better.
(dramatic orchestral music)
(machine rhythmically clicking)
- Denny?
I think you'll feel better,
knowing God will help me to handle this.
He'll provide for me and the children.
You prepared me quite well
for this situation, you know.
I guess what I'm trying to say is,
don't worry about us, okay?
And, anyway,
You know what?
We'll be together again in the garden.
- I don't know what you're
saying to him, Mrs. Hill,
but his brainwaves are
just going wild out there.
Perhaps you could say something
a little more soothing.
- [Cindy Voiceover] I
had prayed all afternoon
for a miracle.
I told God we needed Denny.
We love and depend on him.
I felt the Lord say,
"Can't you love and depend on me?"
I said,
"Okay, Lord, if You want him he's Yours.
"But, please, take care of us."
All this Christianity
better not be a big put-on,
because, if it is,
I'll never make it.
- Mrs. Hill, you're, uh,
husband's blood pressure is almost zero.
And there are no brainwaves now.
Clinically he's--
- Is there a chance that
anything could change?
- No, I'm sorry, Mrs. Hill, none at all.
We can leave him on
the life-support system
for another 24 to 48 hours, if you wish.
- No.
- But it's really...
- Denny and I discussed this, and, um,
he said, if, if this ever happened,
he, uh,
wanted it turned off.
(monitor making a long unbroken beep)
- [Cindy Voiceover] Denny
knew that this could happen.
During our seven years of marriage,
he put me in charge of finances.
He always kept our
household matters in order,
and he kept me up-to-date
on insurance matters.
And he loved me.
(birds chirping and slow, dramatic music)
(Denny grunting)
- Giddy up!
- Oh.
(Denny laughing)
All right.
(Denny exhaling loudly)
(jack-in-the-box music)
(door of jack-in-the-box flying open)
(Denny laughing)
(Denny making a single tongue click)
- I love you, daddy.
(monitor making a long unbroken beep)
- [Cindy] And I love you, too, daddy.
(beep moving to a slightly lower pitch)
(female vocalists singing
long, harmonious oohs)
(Cindy crying)
- Denny may be gone now,
but you have 200 brothers.
(Cindy crying)
- It means a great deal to have
so many of you here today to honor Dennis,
especially those of you,
who were his fellow workers
on the police force.
I've thought a great about
policemen the last few days.
I'd often hear stories
on the news of policemen,
who had been injured or killed,
but it was always just a story.
But now I think I'm
beginning to understand
what it must be like for those of you,
who are here in uniform today.
The constant pressure, the tension,
not knowing what that day
or that particular assignment might hold.
And, if that's true for you,
how much more must it be
true for your families?
For your wives, and parents, children.
I've gained a real
appreciation for all of you,
and the high price you
pay to be a policeman,
or a policeman's wife.
And as I thought about Dennis,
and Cindy, and all of you,
I realized that your lifestyle
is not so far removed
from that of the Apostle Paul.
(dramatic orchestral music)
He also lived daily with
the possibility of death.
There were so many people who hated Paul,
because of what he stood for,
and he suffered a great deal
for the cause of Jesus Christ.
And, yet, in the midst of that life
of so much suffering and uncertainty,
Paul is able to say an amazing thing.
He says, "For me to live is Christ,
"for me to die is gain."
Incredible, isn't it?
That a man, who daily faced
the possibility of death,
could face death,
not just without fear,
but with hope.
How could that be?
What had Paul experienced in
his life that made him able
to face death with such
triumphant sureness?
He'd finally realized that Jesus Christ
was who he claimed to be,
the Son of God,
the Savior of the world,
and that his offer of
forgiveness and reconciliation
with God was available to anyone,
who would trust in Him as Lord and Savior.
Jesus Himself said,
"Whoever believes in me,
"though he were dead,
"yet shall he live."
So, we grieve.
I have wept this week.
I imagine most of us have.
But we do not grieve as
those who have no hope.
Our grief is for the many who love Dennis,
and who've lost an important
part of their lives.
(power saw whirring)
(hammer pounding)
- You know, Hill, I've been thinkin'.
How can a guy be a cop and a Christian?
- Hey, partner, police
officers are God's authority.
Says in Romans,
"Authorities that exist have
been established by God."
- The Bible says that?
- 10-4.
- Okay.
You know I believe in God, right?
- Right.
- Okay.
Now, on the other hand, when
it comes right down to it,
how can a guy put his trust
in something or someone
he can't really see, or
someone he can't touch?
- You can believe God is,
because of what you can see.
Creation.
- Suppose I was real atheist,
and said I needed more proof than that?
- Then I'd say, "Congratulations."
- (laughing) Congratulations?
- You've got a lot more faith than I do.
- What do you mean?
- Well, you have to accept by faith,
that everything came from nothing,
that highly intelligent,
complex forms of life
came from absolutely nothing.
(makes a tongue click)
That takes a lot more faith than I have.
- Wait a minute, Hill.
I don't quite follow you.
- Well, you like cars.
How do you like my Trans Am?
- I love it.
- Well, where did it come from?
I'll tell you where it came from,
it oozed up out of the pavement.
Couldn't happen, right?
Well, where'd it come from?
- All right, Detroit, they built it.
- A highly complex design demands what?
A designer.
So, it takes a lot more faith
to believe that God is not,
than to believe that God is.
- Geesh, Hill, you come
on like you nearly know
what you're talkin' about.
You know, you oughta put
in for police chaplain.
(both laughing)
- Uh-Uh.
- [Minister] Our grief is for a world
of hatred, and violence, and murder.
But it's not for Dennis.
Our grief is for the
countless men and women,
who must face the prospect
of death and the grave,
without hope, without Jesus.
But Dennis is with the Lord.
That message of hope and
life beyond the grave
comes echoing down to us today
through the Apostle Paul,
through all those who trust in Jesus,
through Dennis Hill,
that life, yes, even death
can be faced with hope and joy,
because of Jesus.
(light but somber music)
(motorcade driving slowly)
(birds chirping)
(female vocalists singing
long, harmonious oohs)
- [Man] Present arms!
(helicopters approaching)
(helicopters flying by)
- [Man On Television] The
agony of war in Vietnam
continues in the jungles, and
over the jungles of Chu Lai.
Here the giant Hueys from
the 1st Aviation Battalion,
1st Infantry Division, are flying
seek-and-destroy missions day and night.
Enemy ground fire is thick.
Casualties have been...
- [Man] Who distinguished himself,
while participating in aerial flight,
above and beyond the call of duty.
While serving as an aircraft commander,
a convoy was attacked near Lai Khe.
With complete disregard
for his own safety,
officer Hill flew dangerously low
to enable his crew gunners
to direct destructive fire on the enemy.
Officer Hill served as
a flying command post
for the direction of air and ground power.
Due to his heroic actions,
the main thrust of the attack was crushed.
Officer Hill, it is with great pride,
and by direction of the
President of the United States,
that I award you the
Distinguished Flying Cross
for bringing credit upon yourself,
- Firing squad.
- the 1st Infantry Division...
- [Man] Tench-hut!
Order, arms!
Half-right, face!
Ready.
Aim.
Fire.
(guns firing simultaneously)
Aim.
Fire.
(guns firing simultaneously)
Aim.
Fire.
(guns firing simultaneously)
(rifle being cocked)
- Gentlemen, you may
hear that sound at night
and it will scare you.
However, you may never hear this one.
(rifle firing once)
(rifle being cocked)
Gentlemen, one of the biggest enemies
of a police officer
today is police stress.
You must learn to deal
with these problems,
if you're going to succeed
as a police officer.
It can take your wife,
or it can take your life.
First, I'd like to talk about
the Sir Galahad syndrome,
or the Wyatt Earp syndrome, if you would.
Always looking for the bad
guy in everyone you meet.
Always wanting to put the gun on,
when you go to the grocery store.
Next, I'll talk about the
Niederhoffer syndrome,
which deals with police paranoia,
paranoia to the point
that everyone you look at,
you will think is looking at you,
because you are a police
officer, and they want a favor.
This is simply not true.
Next, we will talk about boredom,
boredom to the point that
you, as a police officer,
will become routine in everything you do.
Boredom to the point that 90%
of your time will be spent
in a police car, looking
at routine things.
You will build a false sense of security
that everything is routine.
Believe me, a routine
call can end in tragedy.
If it's an ambush,
they're going to get you.
There's nothing you can do to prevent it.
When they want you, they've got you.
- [Man] Present, arms!
(bugle playing "Taps")
(second bugle echoing "Taps")
- [Cindy Voiceover] Lord,
how do I tell a four-year-old
that his daddy's not coming home anymore?
- Honey.
Daddy got hurt.
Really badly.
And the doctors couldn't do anything.
So.
God
felt it would be better,
if daddy came to live with Him in heaven.
That means he won't be
living with us anymore.
(dramatic orchestral music with timpani)
- [Cindy Voiceover] Without Jesus Christ
I never could've made it.
There was always a police car
turning around in my driveway.
God was helping me
through his authorities.
Whenever I needed help, He was there
through my 200 brothers.
(cars driving by on street)
(dry grass crunching underfoot)
(birds chirping)
(cars driving on busy street)
(emergency vehicle siren approaching)
(dramatic orchestral music)
- Police! Freeze, mister!
(two gunshots firing)
- Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
(rifle hitting pavement)
- [Denny] Put your hands behind your head.
- [Wayne] Fingers interlocked.
- Look, the guy tried to shoot me.
Didja hear me?
He tried to shoot me,
and I took his gun away
from him, and shot him.
It was nothin' but self-defense.
(handcuffs clicking closed)
It's self-defense, that's all it was.
I got a right to protect myself.
(handcuff clicking closed)
- Let's go.
- I said it was, look, the guy,
he's comin' out with a shotgun,
and I took it away from him,
and shot him with it!
At least I got a right to
protect myself, don't I?
You can't arrest me for protecting myself.
It's just self-defense.
You guys are all the same.
I didn't do anything, it was his fault.
(car approaching and stopping)
- Is everything under control?
- Would you call Fire Rescue?
- Look, that guy shot at me
first, and I just shot back.
I got a right to protect myself.
- He's tellin' the truth, officer.
Some guy up there fired
three, four shots at this man.
- Who are you?
- Dale Lear, I'm assistant manager here.
- If you were shooting in self-defense,
then why'd you turn the gun on us?
- That guy said he was cops
and started shooting at me.
I got confused and excited.
- [Denny] How long since you've
been to the firing range?
- [Wayne] I was gonna ask
you the same question.
- [Denny] You know, they're
going to ask us why we missed.
- [Wayne] Yes.
Lucky for him we did.
- Hmmph.
- You think God had
something to do with that?
- I didn't say anything.
- Why do you think it was God,
and not just the fact
that we were lousy shots.
- Well, for one thing,
we're not lousy shots.
- It's kinda weird, isn't it?
I mean, if we'd have hit 'im,
we'd have hit the wrong guy.
- Question.
Suppose he had opened up on
us, and we'd bought the farm?
- Coulda happened.
- I know it coulda happened.
- What's the question?
- Do you know where you'd spend eternity?
And be honest now.
- Well, in heaven, I hope.
- But you're not sure.
- Are you?
- Absolutely.
- [Wayne] Well, I guess I
don't really know for sure.
- [Denny] Something to think about, huh?
- [Dispatcher On Radio] One-35.
- One-35.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
One-35, 1330 South Bettencourt,
1330 South Bettencourt, resusce and care,
child swallowed unknown substance.
Rescue's en route.
- 10-4.
- 10-4, 10-17, KV-Two-60 and out.
(engine starting)
(tires squealing)
- [Wayne] Emergency comin'
in, emergency goin' out.
(emergency vehicle siren wailing)
Oh, no, now we got trouble.
(dramatic orchestral music)
- [Denny] I'm gonna swing a right.
- [Wayne] We just lost 10 minutes.
If we can somehow get through to Hubbell,
we can get at least five minutes back.
(tires screeching to a halt)
- Listen, we gotta get to Hubbell.
A boy's life is at stake.
Can you get us through here?
- Yeah.
(starter cranking)
(diesel engine revving)
- One-35.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] One-35.
- We're on East 46th, East 46th,
cutting through field to Hubbell.
You might advise Rescue
that East 9th is blocked.
Come down East 46th.
The path bulldozed to Hubbell will cut ETA
to 1330 Bettencourt.
(dead branches being moved and crushed)
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
(heavy metal-on-metal thud)
(emergency vehicle siren wailing)
(birds chirping)
(dramatic orchestral music)
(light thumping)
- Ah, ah, ah.
Now lie still.
- [Wayne] Oh, ho, ho.
- Lie still.
(emergency vehicle siren approaching)
(car doors closing)
- How's he doin' now?
Feel better?
(conversation obscured
by diesel engine running)
- Thank God the button
had four holes in it.
Gave him just enough air to keep him alive
until we got here.
- [Cindy Voiceover] Denny
had been asking himself,
was being a cop really worth it?
He said God had given him his answer,
but, of course,
it wasn't long until Satan
tried to discourage him again.
- You filthy, dirty rotten pigs.
- Well, at least we know one little boy,
who's not gonna grow
up with that attitude.
(Denny sighing heavily)
(blow dryer running)
(blow dryer stops running)
- Dennis Hill, I don't
understand you at all.
- You know, there's a name for that.
- What is it?
- Dirty, rotten pig.
- Well.
You're spoiled rotten, that's for sure.
Denny, you're the most
organized guy in the world.
Your car will probably
never see a speck of dirt.
You hang up your clothes,
shine your shoes.
Your closet is ready for a
military inspection at all times.
But, why,
do you always throw your underwear
behind the bathroom door?
- Well, I can explain it.
If I did everything right,
then I'd be perfect.
Then all the women in the world,
who are looking for perfect husbands,
would be after me,
and that would make you most unhappy.
So, I, uh, throw my underwear
behind the bathroom door for two reasons.
One, so I won't be perfect.
And two, to make you happy.
- Smart cop.
- Mmm. You're a beautiful lady.
(power saw whining)
(saw turning off)
- Ah, thanks.
Phew.
You know, you asked me a coupla weeks ago
where I'd spend eternity, if I died.
- Oh, you've been thinking about it, huh?
- I can't stop thinking about it.
- Good.
- You know, the only thing is,
how come you think I'm such a sinner?
I'm good to my family.
I fought in Nam.
Man, I don't even drink.
- You cuss.
- Yeah, but only when I'm mad.
(both laughing)
- Well,
I'm a sinner, too, ya know.
- Shoot, I never even heard you cuss
or saw you take a drink.
- There's a lot more to
sin than those things.
It's pride.
It's all kinds of things.
But my sins are forgiven,
because Christ died on a cross.
What in your estimation
is the world's worst sin.
- Murder.
- Come on.
Let me show you something.
You know, doing good deeds,
and being a good guy,
won't get you into heaven.
Unless you receive Christ
as your personal Savior,
you will not spend eternity in heaven.
- You know, I think I've
come a long ways, Denny,
since you and I started talking about this
back in the flying days.
The only thing is, how come
I'm still not buying this?
- Because you're a typical, cynical cop.
You have a sick syndrome.
(both laughing)
Matthew, chapter 22,
37.
"Thou shall love the Lord,
thy God, with all thy heart,
"and with all thy soul,
and with all thy mind."
That's the first and greatest commandment.
So, what's the first and greatest sin?
Not to put God first in everything.
- You mean I should put
God ahead of my family?
- How important is your family to you?
- You know how important they are to me.
- So does God.
And He's even more concerned
about them than you are.
So, if you put God first,
He will help you take proper care of them,
to help you raise your kids,
make the right decisions.
Do you believe that Christ existed.
- Oh, sure, I believe that.
Well, he was a carpenter and a teacher.
That's, I've always wondered about that.
Why was he a carpenter
instead of, instead of a cop?
- Well, he is a cop.
He's a chief of police.
And, if you remember the scripture
we were talking about before from Romans,
we are His police force,
we are His authority,
and we should take our
instructions from Him.
You know, He still is a carpenter.
He helps to build lives into a purpose,
not just into an existence.
- How you doin'?
- The little, the little boy?
- The little boy is fine, thanks to you.
A lot of people wouldn't
have gotten involved.
- You helped save his life.
- I know.
But, you see, what I
didn't know, the other day,
when I helped you,
you see,
well, that was, that was my son.
(somber orchestral music)
Thank you.
(Denny tongue clicks)
- [Dispatcher On Radio] One-34.
- [Officer On Radio] 34.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
Need O-T for an M-T.
- [Officer On Radio] 10-4.
- "The heavens declare the glory of God,
"and the firmament"
show,
shew,
"sheweth his handiwork.
"Day unto day uttereth speech,
"and night unto night sheweth knowledge."
(light orchestral music)
(police radio chatter under music)
Psalm 19.
Whew.
This is worse than Shakespeare.
(Denny whistling a song)
(intense orchestral music)
Have you noticed that gas-station holdups
on our beat are at an all-time low?
- Really?
- Well, sure.
Every time a guy goes to rob
one, there's a cop in the can.
(both laughing)
Ah, listen, what do you
know about Psalm 19?
(intense orchestral music)
(tires squealing)
(tires screeching, pavement scraping)
That guy's crazy.
One-35.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] One-35.
- [Wayne] In pursuit of
vehicle, eastbound on Forest.
White in color, appears to be a 10-55.
(emergency vehicle siren wailing)
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
We just got a call from 107 Norwalk.
Car-pedestrian, PI,
involves a white vehicle.
(Dispatcher obscured by siren)
Send Rescue at this time.
Attention all units.
One-35 is in pursuit of a possible 10-55,
eastbound on Forest, eastbound on Forest.
No plate available.
This vehicle possibly involved
in a PI at 107 Norwalk.
- [Officer On Radio] 14-30.
- [Officer On Radio] One-02 en route.
- [Officer On Radio]
One-04. I'm in the area.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
Come one, One-02, One-04.
Any other units can assist.
(emergency vehicle siren wailing)
(tires screeching to a halt)
- Lunders, you and Hill
go to back to 107 Norwalk,
and see if you can do somethin'
'til Rescue gets there.
(emergency vehicle siren driving away)
(somber orchestral music)
(tires screeching to a halt)
(woman crying)
- If you guys would spend more
time enforcing speeding laws,
instead of writing parking tickets,
maybe our kids'd be safe on the streets.
- Did anyone see this happen?
- I did.
Eric lost his ball, and the
ball went out in the street,
and he went out to get it,
and this crazy, wild man
came down the street,
about 30, 40, 50 miles
an hour, and he hit 'im,
and he didn't even slow down.
- Can you tell me how many
occupants were in the vehicle?
- One. I th--
Yeah, I think one, just one.
- Mm-hmm.
Could you describe the driver?
- No, it happened so fast,
that I just, didn't even barely--
I didn't think anything like
this was ever gonna happen.
(vehicle starts and drives away)
(plastic tricycle bouncing around)
(vehicle door slams)
(vehicle starts and drives away)
(police radio chatter)
- Thanks.
- Coulda been one of our kids, Denny.
How could God allow that to happen.
- God didn't allow that
little guy to be killed.
Sin did.
A drunken driver,
whose mind was clouded
and controlled by Satan.
- I can't buy that.
What if that little boy had been hit by a,
by some little, old lady, who
goes to church every Sunday?
- Wayne, let me explain something.
In all our experiences of life,
there are times, when we cannot understand
why God would allow something to happen.
We can't understand it, because
we don't have all the facts.
God does.
But I can tell you this,
if you're in God's family,
nothing happens to you,
if not by design.
(police radio chatter)
- All right.
Okay, what if, um...
Okay, what if, let's say that--
- [Dispatcher On Radio] Building nine,
he has two subjects
barricaded 10-32, 10-33.
One-35?
- One-35, 4th and Carpenter, on the way.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
It's gonna be at Fort Des
Moines and Grundy Street,
building nine.
Officer needs help, subject's 10-32.
First unit 10-23 advise.
(suspenseful orchestral music)
(liquid dripping)
(officer cocking shotgun)
- [Man Elsewhere In Building] Jim?
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
Attention all units, 135 is
10-23 at northeast corner.
16-52.
(vehicles stopping quickly)
(guns cocking)
- Malwitz, what's your position?
- We're on the second floor,
and we got 'em in the northwest
corner, and they are armed.
- You and Steve take the northeast corner,
Wayne and I will go in through the door.
You ready?
Go.
Hey.
Two things.
- What's that?
- Before you try to be a
hero, remember eternity?
Try to remember you're a lousy shot.
Ready?
(Denny cocking shotgun)
(door crashes open)
(tense orchestral music)
(liquid dripping)
- Okay, in the corner,
we know you're in there.
Just give it up now.
The guy in the corner with the shotgun,
stick it out butt first and follow it out.
Now!
The other one, come on out.
Hold it right there.
- Man in the blue shirt,
take two steps forward.
(liquid dripping)
Take two steps forward.
- He's got a gun.
(gun hammer cocks)
- [Dark-Haired Officer]
Fall to your knees.
Fall straight forward with your arms out,
and your palms up.
(liquid dripping)
(handcuffs clicking)
- I'm gonna go get my shotgun, Ron.
(liquid dripping)
(shotgun fires)
Hill!
- Phew.
- You okay, buddy.
- I think I wet my pants.
So you have to shield yourself
from being hurt emotionally.
- Is that possible?
- Oh, sure.
Cops do it all the time.
It's called the callous-cop syndrome.
In other words, a cop deals with emotion,
day in and day out.
He has to build defense mechanisms,
or else he's gonna become
an emotional cripple.
Then the public sees
him acting unemotional,
and they wonder, what's
wrong with this guy?
Doesn't he care?
Doesn't he feel?
- Couldn't his being unemotional
have an adverse effect on his family?
- Oh, sure, and it does.
Praise God, our relationship,
faith in Christ,
has kept us in balance.
But it's not easy, you know.
A guy can become an unemotional
person and lose his family.
And, if he shows emotion on
the job, he can lose his life.
It's a thin line.
- That's frightening, Denny,
I mean, you lose either way.
- That's why a cop that
doesn't have Christ
is gonna have a pretty rough road.
That's why I want so much for
Wayne to be able to see that.
I really blew it today.
- What happened?
- I just couldn't handle
that little guy being killed.
Got to me.
Wayne, he was solid as a rock
on the outside,
but I know he hurt on the inside.
- You guys see a child beaten or killed,
and you're supposed to sit on all that?
It must be frustrating at times,
wanting to strike back
and not being able to.
- Well, it's natural to wanna strike back,
but you're right, we can't.
But it happens.
A guy can be a model cop
for an entire career,
and let go just once.
He'll answer for it.
- How does a cop get rid
of all that frustration?
How do you?
- I throw my underwear
behind the bathroom door.
- Oh, Denny, you know,
it would be really easy for
our relatioship to suffer,
if you shut me out, so, well, I
I appreciate you sharing with me.
(easy listening music)
(Denny sighs)
- Well, I better get ready and go to work.
- Mmm.
- Kids goin' to grandpa's tonight?
- Mm-hmm.
- Hmm.
I think you're looking at a cop,
who's about to have a close shave.
- Dad?
- Hmm?
- When can I get a blade on my razor?
- When you get a job,
and can afford to buy
them with your own money.
Hey.
Why don't I go to
grandma-and-grandpa's tonight,
and you go to work for me?
- You can't do that, dad.
- Why not?
- 'Cause your hat falls down over my eyes.
(Denny laughs)
(slow harp music)
- I surrender into the arms of the law.
- Cindy, could you pick
me up a new watch band?
- If anyone says you're a
spoiled, rotten cop tonight,
tell them your wife agrees.
- Cindy, you're...
I'll tell ya later.
- Tell me now.
You won't remember.
You never did remember
to tell me the name of
that guy in the front row.
- Jonathan Augustinsky.
- You're kidding!
I woulda been Cynthia Augustinsky?
- Mm-hmm.
- How gruesome.
(both laughing)
- Todd, after you watch the car go by,
help mom get your things together.
Have fun at grandpa's.
(smacking lips)
- Remember, I love you.
- I love you, too.
(car engine running)
- [Wayne] You know, you
never did explain to me
what that thing was I read in the Bible.
- [Denny] Psalm 19?
- [Wayne] Yeah. Well, it's
an interesting scripture,
because, um, I can't remember
it all without the Bible,
but it says that God placed
the stars in the heavens,
and put the earth in its orbit,
and that He created,
designed the universe.
- [Denny] Do you remember,
when we were talking about
faith and my car?
- [Wayne] Yeah.
- (chuckles) Well, Psalm 19 is telling us
that God created all the universe,
and that we can see his
handiwork in nature.
Now, in Romans,
it says that God has
given man the instincts,
to obey and follow God.
But Satan has filled men's
hearts with such pride,
that man ignores God.
You see, the thing is that,
since God has given us this knowledge,
the Bible warns us that
there is no excuse,
when man comes before the Judgment.
You know, Wayne,
you seem to want to receive Christ.
You ask so many questions.
Why don't you just do it?
- I don't know, Denny.
I want to.
And I can't quit thinking
about what you said about eternity.
But I, uh,
I don't know.
It's so hard.
I can't seem to feel about
it, the way that you do.
And, yet, I want to.
If I, um, if I did become a Christian,
how,
I mean, what do I do?
- Well, first you admit
that you're sinful,
and ask God to forgive you.
That's the tough part.
Then you must believe that
Jesus Christ is the Son of God,
that He died and shed
His blood for our sins,
arose three days later,
and still lives in the hearts of men.
Then ask Him to be the Lord of your life.
- That's all there is to it?
- That's all there is to it.
- (laughing) Man.
- You know, Wayne.
Once you've heard the plan of salvation,
you're responsible for it.
You must make a decision.
If you don't, God may do
something to get your attention.
Well, we better get to work.
(crickets chirping)
(Denny clearing his throat loudly)
I don't know if I wanna drive with you.
Besides, it's my turn.
- Go ahead.
Have at it.
(engine starts)
- Are you ready?
- I'm ready.
- You sure?
- I'm sure.
(yawning) Oh, man.
I'm beat.
I don't know if I can hack
this for another three hours.
This night shift is a bore.
- [Denny] Take it easy.
It'll be over soon.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] One-35.
- 16 Woodland.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
One-35, 13th and Jefferson,
13th and Jefferson,
possible shooting there.
- En route.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
It's unknown if anybody's injured or died.
Complaint is at 1632 13th.
(emergency vehicle siren wailing)
We have an NM dressed in white
going west on Washington.
10-32.
(dramatic orchestral music)
(gun fires loudly)
- [Wayne] Denny?
Oh, my...
One-35.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] Go ahead.
- [Wayne] We got an
officer hit real bad here.
[Officer On Radio] Get
the squad up here fast!
- [Officer On Radio] 10-4, officer. 10-76.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] All cars respond
to 13th and Washington,
13th and Washington.
They report an NM, dressed in white,
went westbound on Washington.
10-32.
(police sirens blaring)
- [Officer On Radio]
One-36, we're headed there.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] One-25.
- [Officer On Radio] One-26.
(police radio chatter covered by sirens)
- [Dispatcher On Radio] One-33?
- [Officer On Radio] Almost
back to the precinct.
- [Officer On Radio] 21 en route.
(dramatic orchestral music)
- Freeze.
(five gunshots firing)
(emergency vehicle siren winding down)
- [Officer] Freeze!
(two gunshots firing)
(dramatic, somber music)
- [Denny Voiceover] Suppose
he'd opened up on us,
and we'd bought the farm.
Do you know where you
would spend eternity?
Do you really know where
you would spend eternity?
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 500-Adam?
- [Officer On Radio] I couldn't read him.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
I believe there were
shots fired there.
- [Officer On Radio]
10-4, we're on our way.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] Five-01?
- [Officer On Radio] Four.
Five-06 out of the office.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
One-08?
- [Officer On Radio] 10-4.
- [Officer On Radio] 20? What's the 20?
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 13 and Washington.
- [Officer On Radio] 10-4, en route.
- One-01?
- No response at 9 Hickman.
- [Officer On Radio] One-20 after Alpha.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
One-35?
- [Officer On Radio] 35.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
10-4. Are you injured there?
- [Officer On Radio] Partner's been shot.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4. FD's 10-76.
500-Adam, copy?
- [Officer On Radio] No.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
Officer's been injured there.
Anyone 10-23 can advise on situation.
- [Officer On Radio] One-01,
we'll go up there now.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4.
- [Denny Voiceover] Do you know where you
would spend eternity?
Now, be honest now.
- [Wayne Voiceover]
Well, in heaven, I hope.
- [Denny Voiceover] But you're not sure.
- [Wayne Voiceover] Are you?
- [Denny Voiceover] Absolutely.
- [Officer On Radio]
500-Adam are you there?
- [Officer On Radio] This
is One-30, you're gonna want
all our cops to this area.
- [Dispatcher On Radio] 10-4. 24?
- [Officer On Radio] 24.
- [Dispatcher On Radio]
Start over to the area
of 13 and Washington.
- [Officer On Radio] One-26?
- [Officer On Radio] One-26.