Love is like a net,
capturing heroes' hearts
Like a sword, vengeance cutting through
love and hate
Even heroes have to succumb
...to love and hate
Not even the Heaven Sword and Dragon Sabre
can disentangle love and hate
Hatred in the sea of love
Regrets in this life
filled with resentment and love
Who can answer what is love and hate
Heaven Sword and Dragon Sabre
are legendary weapons in the
martial arts world
They were created by
Guo Jing and Wang Yung
The legend says that at the end of
the Sung dynasty
Guo Jing and Wang Yung guarded
the Xian Yang
which fell to the enemy's hands
Knowing there was
no further hope
before their anticipated deaths
They secretly sought a famous sword smith
using the hardest quartz available
on earth
to amalgamate with hero Guo's heavy sabre
to create the Heaven Sword
and Dragon Sabre
As a result, for hundreds of years
martial artists
wanted to find out the secret and
possess these weapons,
to be the best of all
The Heaven Sword had been hidden with the
Er Mei School by heroine Guo
while the Dragon Sabre drifted from
one place to other
Our story follows the route to
finding the Dragon Sabre
After a hundred years, the sabre
came into the hands of Ming Cult
Lion King Tse Shun
who because of having stirred up hatred
hid in the Ice Fire Island
There was only one person who knew
of his whereabouts
And that was Chang Wu Ji
son of Wu Dong's fifth master
Chang Tsui San &
Yan So So, Yan Tin Jing of
the Eagle Clan's daughter
After Chang Wu Ji grew up
he met a few ladies
The pitiful Siu Chiu
His cousin Yan Li
Yang Bu Heui, left guardian of
the Ming Cult's daughter
Heroine Chou Chi Yeuk of Er Mei
who was infatuated by him
By chance he
accomplished the Jiu Yang kung fu
Unintentionally he fought many at
Summit Guang Ming
and thereby saved the Ming Cult
By which he became their leader
After that he re-built the cult
and escorted a team of heroes
to welcome back his godfather,
the Lion King
However on the way
he met a mysterious lady Chiu Ming
who poisoned the Ming Cult's heroes
and went to Wu Dong disguised as
Ming Cult's leader
and injured Chang San Fang
To save Chang San Fang
Wu Ji sought Chiu Ming
to get the antidote
What antidote? What do you mean?
What's wrong with you,
we haven't finished our talk
why have you attacked already?
I really don't understand
why you have repeatedly challenged
Ming Cult
Who on earth are you?
I don't understand it either
Have you come for the antidote
or to find out about me?
To get the antidote, naturally
Then you don't have to care who I am
In any event you'll know one day
Alright, if you want the antidote
you have to accede to three requests
Three requests?
Hmm!
What are they?
I don't have anything concrete now
When I do, I'll tell you
Alright, I promise you...
as long as they are not immoral
Give me the antidote
I have sent it to Mt. Wu Dong
Has the antidote arrived?
Not yet
Your grace...
You're here, what should we do?
Chiu Ming said the antidote
has been delivered
Oh, Mister, when we were at the gate
Someone gave me a letter to pass on to you
This is not the antidote
The antidote is in the golden box
compartment
And the prescription within
the pearl flower's hollow
Mister
The antidote is really here
May I bother you to get...
the prescription ready for use to
the Grand Teacher
Yes
Right, have you found out
what I have asked you to investigate?
Yes
The 6 clans which came down from
Summit Guang Ming
have all fallen into the trap
of the Yuan generals
They are now locked in the Man Fat Temple
Man Fat Temple
That temple is the residence of
the western evil monk
and accommodates highly skilled
Yuan fighters
Let's take a look
Alright
Sir, please
What is it?
The prince is here & invites you all
to the main hall
Alright
Let's go
You wait for them at the tavern
I'll take charge here
Hero Ho, how come you're here?
We got ambushed
There are others up there
Seniors
Uncles
How come you are here too?
After leaving Summit Guang Ming
...we were poisoned at the tavern
We feel so very weak now
All of Er Mei's men are up there
Abbess Mie Jiue, how come you are here
as well?
Where's Chi Yeuk?
There's an intruder!
I'll get some men
Don't move
There are good fighters here,
come with me quickly
Thank you for saving me. What's your name?
You'll know in a while
Go to the Green Willow Mansion quickly
and free Chou Chi Yeuk
Miss Chou,
I hear you are the best pupil of Mie Jiue
So you must know about the secret
of Er Mei's Heaven Sword
I don't
How could the real sword be with her?
If you don't tell me honestly
about the secret of the Heaven Sword
I'll cut your face three times with
this sword
Are you going to tell me?
I don't know
Alright
Chang Wu Ji
Tell Chang to leave if you're smart
He can't take you with him now
Stop
Master Chang, I appreciate your
good intention
However I'd rather you went to
the Man Fat Temple
and save the six clans
Right, do you remember
you promised me right here
to do 3 things for me?
Now I have the Heaven Sword
The first thing I want you to do is
get the Dragon Sabre
Not now
Why?
That's because...
Because you've to go to
Man Fat Temple to save lives
Right?
That's none of your business
After 3 days
If Miss Chou is here
and safe, I promise you
I'll take you to the Dragon Sabre
Come, men
Yes
Take her back to Man Fat Temple
Frankly, I hope you'll die here
Chi Yeuk, come here
Teacher
What's your wish?
Being captured by the Yuan's monk
this time has
caused me my good reputation
I don't want to leave this tower
But Er Mei cannot be without a leader
I want to make you Er Mei's
fourth generation head
No, Teacher, I'm still young
Shut up
When have you become so indecisive?
I have my reasons for doing this
Chou Chi Yeuk, pay attention
Yes
Er Mei's third generation leader Mie Jiue
has passed on the leadership to
the fourth pupil Chou Chi Yeuk
Come forward and listen
You again
That's right
Who are you anyway?
The Monk Fu under Chiu Ming
He is Fan Yiu, the Right Guardian
of the Ming Cult
who has disappeared for 10 years
Then who is Miss Chiu?
She is the daughter of the Prince
of Yue Yang
What's she doing here?
The Prince decided to exterminate
various clans
and take control, so she sent
Chiu Ming down south
to grab the treasured weapons
Heaven Sword and Dragon Sabre
Then he sent his son Fufu Temuyi
to gather all the Yuan's monks
at Man Fat Temple
and poison the six clans on their way back
from fighting at Summit Guang Ming
and trapping them at Man Fat Temple
Then is there any way to save them?
First we need the antidote
Where is it?
It's always been with Yuan & Ming
You can steal it
No
But I did
Monk Fu, what's your business here
at this late hour?
Nothing
Pack up the body
Let's go up and save them
Okay
You help them, I'll go up
Alright
Bring some water, I have the antidote here
Antidote
How did you get it?
Don't ask, give it to them
After you've taken it
you need an hour to recover, quick
Abbess
The antidote is here
Chi Yeuk, help me
Sister, please bring a bowl of
antidote here
I have never taken a favour from
an evil cult
I won't drink
You're dying
and yet you're so stubborn
Can't you even rescind for the sake
of Er Mei?
I am not stopping them, but I won't drink
Intruder!
Damn, they need an hour
to recover their kung fu
The Yuan master fighters are here,
what's to be done?
Round them up
I don't think they could recover so soon
Archers ready, shoot on sight
Yes
Hey
The intruder in there,
come out and face your death
Chief, what should we do?
Let me stall them
In the meantime you try to open up
your meridian
Men from the Ming Cult are coming
Hey
Listen, if you still don't come out
I'll burn down the tower
Guardian Fan, please take control here
Okay
Who are you?
Chang Wu Ji, leader of the Ming Cult
Oh, you're the leader
That's why you are so powerful
Drink up
Miss Chou, please drink it
No
The Western Eighteen Dragon Formation
Your Highness
I just got news that
the people inside the tower
have got the antidote
and that Chang Wu Ji is the leader
of the Ming Cult
The Ming Cult will be here soon
I think it's best to get rid of them first
Right
Get ready to burn down the tower
Yes
Disaster...
They are getting ready to burn us down
They are pouring the oil inside
Wait, our powers have not yet returned
We'll die for sure if we jump down
the tower
Let's tear our clothes
and tie them together as a rope
to let us down
Good
Oh no...
The fire is eating its way up
Follow me
Quickly...
Look
Shoot
Uncle Yan
Bu Heui, what are you doing up here?
Bu Heui
Miss Yang
Bu Huei
How are you?
Miss Yang
At last she apologised to you on
her mother's behalf
Apologised? She hasn't done anything wrong
Bu Huei...
You're here
Who are they?
They are members of Ming Cult,
real good fighters
Your Highness, I think you'd better
leave first
What about the six clans?
We'll take care of them another time
The Ming Cult really lives up
to its reputation
The Yuan regime will not have peace
from now on, go
The Yuan's monks are all dead, come down
No, the ladder's on fire,
the ropes are burnt through
Make another rope
Quick...
There's not enough time
Then jump
Jump...
They haven't recovered their powers yet
They can'tjump
Chief, have eight of them jump each time
We'll catch them from below
Uncle Yan, jump eight by eight
We'll catch you
How can we jump?
They might not catch us
Hero Ho, one must have trust
There's only one option now
We must trust them
Master...
Are you alright?
Master
He is alright. Justjump
Jump
It's burning, jump
Jump quickly
Abbess, Miss Chou
the fire has made its way up
I have said good and evil don't mix
I'd never take a favour from an evil cult
Since we have not recovered our powers
we're as good as dead if we jump
Hero Yan, go quickly
There's no time, quick
Uncle Yan, Ching Shu, jump now
Ask Chi Yeuk to jump now
The fire will consume everything
Come down quickly
Jump quickly, hero Yan, jump
Quick
Miss Chou
If you don't move it you'll not make it
Go even if the Abbess doesn't
No... I won't go
If teacher is not going,
I'm not going even if I die
Abbess, are you going to let her die
with you?
No
You can't die
Er Mei's future is in your hands
Go
Jump
Teacher...
Why does she prefer death to my help?
Why does she hate us so much?
Teacher...
Miss Chou, you can't help her; she's dead!
You have to accept the situation
Chi Yeuk, get up
Don't cry any more
Listen... the six clans
have been fighting against the Ming Cult
Hero Chang has graciously
...saved our lives
While everyone is here I want to
recommend Chief Chang as leader
of all clans
to drive out the northern barbarians
What do you think?
Good...
I object
The Ming Cult is nevertheless an evil cult
How can they lead us?
Ching Shu, don't be reckless
with your words
Father, we should be
the leader of all clans
Why of all people choose a bastard son?
Nonsense
If you speak rubbish again I'll kill you
I don't believe it
I can't believe only Chang Wu Ji
can take the post
Sung Ching Shu...
Wu Ji, don't mind him
Listen to Monk Kung Man and
lead our fighters to drive out
the northern barbarians
I am too young for such an
important mission
Besides, I have to find someone
as I have promised to do something for her
Leader, didn't you say that you want
the Lion King back at the
Summit Guang Ming?
Yes, but now I've decided to go alone
You return to the Guang Ming Summit
& wait for my news
I have to go with leader since
when Miss was alive she instructed me
...to take care of you
Okay, await me at the east coast's
Golden Sand beach
Yes
Chief Chang, you're a man of your word
Since you're here, Miss Chou must be
all right
Miss Chiu, the princess of Yuan,
you're odd
On one hand you orchestrated
a comprehensive ambush
to exterminate the six clans
On the other, you're playing music
under the moon light
To destroy the six schools is
my dad's business
while playing the instrument is my concern
Then you know what happened at
Man Fat Temple?
Of course, you saved all the people
and killed many Yuan fighters
Then why don't you
avenge those men I have killed?
Since they are not your match
Why should I bother with them?
Right, now that you have released
all of them
You can take me to the Dragon Sword
Who could it be at this late hour?
There, that's the one
Leader Chou
It's you
Yes, It's me Sung Ching Shu
What do you want with me
at this late hour?
Something confidential which I want to
talk about
Leave us
Yes
How can you do this?
It's not a matter of whether we can
It's something we must do
for the sake of martial world
Are you willing to accept domination
by an evil cult?
Besides, as per my investigation,
Chang Wu Ji...
has agreed to lead Chiu Ming to
the Dragon Sword
It is obvious that the Ming Cult
is consorting with the Yuan Regime
How would you know?
Never mind
The two of them are
off to Ice Fire Island
Let's do it this way
If you need my assistance
Look for me at the Beggar Clan
Chang Wu Ji; Could he really...
Iove Chiu Ming & have conspired
with Yuan regime?
If you don't believe me
Take a look at Ice Fire Island
There is noise of fighting over there
The one coming for the Dragon Sabre
I've seen your kung fu style somewhere
Nonsense, we haven't met before
Hand over the Dragon Sabre
Wait
If I remember correctly
One of you here to grab the Dragon Sword
is the one of the four guardians
of Ming Cult
The Purple Gown Sea King Daisy
Daisy
How do you know?
You don't have to lie to me
To find out if you're from the
Ming Cult I deliberately
...showed a loophole to lure you
to kill me
But you couldn't bear to do it
It's because apart from those
from the Ming Cult
everyone in the martial arts world
wants to kill me
And in the Ming Cult
the only woman whose kung fu
is comparable to mine is you
I little realised that while I have fooled
so many others
I have failed to fool you
despite being blind
I really don't understand
why you want the Dragon Sabre?
For the same reason I came from
Persia to China
I have to urgently find the
Chian Kuen shifting Technique
of the former leader
I suspect he hid it in the Dragon Sabre
15 years ago at Summit Guang Ming
You have left the Cult
Now what do you want
with the leader's holy manual?
Tse, you don't know the story behind this
I was a holy maid of the Ming Cult
and was sent forth to the central region
to retrieve the manual for
guarding the cult
Who would have thought that
in saving Master Yang 20 years ago
a doomed affair started
I know about this
You left the Ming cult because
of your marriage with Mr. Ngan Yip
Because of this I broke the commandment
of the Persian cult
Because as a holy maid of the cult
I wasn't supposed to marry
For 15 years I drifted in
the central region
in search of the Chian Kuen
shifting Technique
to atone for my transgression
What? You've travelled across
central region
Haven't you heard of any
Chang Wu Ji's news?
Grand Teacher
Chang Wu Ji was Ah Niu
who bit my hand when I was mad
Oh, it's him
Hey, come out
What are you looking at?
Come out, all of you
Strange, why are there only
three sets of footsteps?
Where's the other one?
There're only three of us
No, I distinctly heard breathing
of four people
Right
There's me as well
Chi Yeuk
How did you come here?
I got news that
you brought Chiu Ming here
For the sake of the martial arts world
I have to come and see
No matter what happens
you two have re-united
Daisy, you needn't go
Your kung fu is excellent,
how should I address you?
I am messenger of Cloud of
the Persian Ming Cult
The other two are messengers of
Wind & Moon
We're here to bring back Daisy
because she's lost her virginity
and transgressed
Besides we want her to hand over
the manual
Wait
She doesn't have it
It's with Chang Wu Ji
Chian Kuen shifting Technique
From where did you acquire
our leader's kung fu?
I am Chang Wu Ji and I discovered
by accident
the manual written on sheep's skin
in the secret chamber of the Ming Cult
I am now temporarily taking over
as the leader of the Ming Cult
Siu Chiu, how are you related to her?
I am her daughter
I've been disguising as a maid
at the Summit Guang Ming
to find the sheep's skin to save my mother
When I found the manual
My cover was to serve you
in order that I could use you
to help me protect the manual
So this explains why in the secret chamber
you knew how to paint blood
on the sheep's skin
Mr. Chang, forgive me. In my place...
you would have done the same thing
That's good. Since you're the leader
of the Ming Cult
then please execute Daisy
in accordance to the rule of the Ming Cult
Stop
Cloud, you are so merciless!
I think you're here for two purposes
The sheep's skin manual which I can
hand over to you
But as for the holy maid
you'd better find someone else
to replace her
Chief Chang, there's something
you didn't know
Our holy maid pledged allegiance
with her blood
Unless Daisy spills all her blood
to another girl
We can never regard her as the holy maid
What if a girl has the same blood
...as Daisy?
Of course that will do
Siu Chiu
Holy maid, please go on board
Mother, I am going
Alright
Come back
if you feel Ionely and alone
Mother will always be at your side
Mother, I'll never come back
Go and say goodbye to her
Siu Chiu
Mr. Chang
The sun is going down, please go on board
Siu Chiu
I'll never forget you
No need, it's too far away
What are you talking about?
The Yuan princess wanted to borrow
my Dragon Sabre
Yes, I promised her
The purpose of my coming here
is to bring you
back to take over the leadership
of the Ming Cult
Secondly, I would like to borrow
your Dragon Sabre
so the princess could look at it
for an hour
Are you saying that the Heaven Sword
is now in the hands of Chiu?
Yes
If she finds out the embedded secret...
in the Heaven Sword
& the Dragon Sabre, then the...
Yuan regime will be able to
conquer the martial world
By that time, you will be blamed
by everyone
It's lucky that the Dragon Sabre
is still here
I'll think about it tonight
and let you know of my decision tomorrow
How come I awoke so late?
It's almost noon
Why am I so weak?
What's going on? Damn
Godfather, wake up
What happened to you?
I am weak. It looks like I've been drugged
Chi Yeuk
What happened to you?
Who beat you like this?
I don't know, when I woke up I saw blood
Two other persons are missing
Who?
Yesterday there were 5 of us here
Now I can only hear the breathing
of 3 people
Cousin...
What? Yan Li is dead
Where's Chiu?
Dragon Sabre
Dragon Sabre?
It's gone
Dragon Sabre is gone
Chiu Ming took it
What?
What a ruthless woman
When I first met her
she told me she liked to die in the sea
Wu Ji, you are too careless
Think about it, Chiu Ming
is the princess of Yuan
She used poison
in the Man Fat Temple before
But I still don't understand
why she did this?
Why?
She wants to have the Heaven Sword
& the Dragon Sabre
Then why didn't she kill us all?
Wu Ji, listen
I am your godfather, I want you to go back
and look for Chiu Ming
Yes, godfather
Why didn't you use the Jiu Yang kung fu
to help us counteract the poison?
Godfather, the poison
gathers in the diaphragm
To counteract the poison,
you've to start from there
Godfather, you're a man, of course
it won't bother you
But Sister Chi Yeuk is a lady
I can't ask her to take off the clothes
...in order that I can exercise my power
Wu Ji, Miss Chou has got to be saved
Hence let me make the decision
...that you two will get married
What do you say, Miss Chou?
I'm but a mere orphan
How can I decide for myself?
Good, if you can't decide
then I'll decide for you
This marriage is confirmed
Wu Ji, I'll go back with you immediately
to look for Chiu Ming
You are back
Where's Godfather?
He's in the room and hasn't come out yet
Godfather
Have you found the antidote yet?
There's no news about the Prince
of Yue Yang's men
but I've seen many men from
the Beggar Clan
I wonder what's up with the Beggar Clan?
Someone's outside
Who are you?
What? It's you
You should be ashamed of yourself
I don't blame you for stealing
Heaven Sword & Dragon Sabre,
neither for dumping us
at the Ice Fire Island
But Cousin Yan Li
doesn't deserve to be treated like this
Did Chou Chi Yeuk wrong you...
such that she deserved to be
killed by you?
Chang Wu Ji, I lured you here to...
let you know that I was not
responsible for
what happened over at the Ice Fire Island
There were only 5 people there
Apart from the one who died
& one who was injured
...there were just you, me and
my godfather
If it's not you, who else could it be?
I know that you won't believe what I say
Alright, you go back immediately
and find your godfather
Then you will know the whole truth
Alright, wait for me here
What? You again
Godfather
Chi Yeuk...
Beggar Clan
Drink it...
That way...
Deputy head of the Beggar Clan Si Foh Lung
toasts to Hero Sung
and the leader of Er Mei Heroine Chou
Please
Head of the Bowl
Head of the Stick
Yes
- Follow me
- Yes
Brothers, quiet please...
Please come forward...
The reason for having this meeting
of the Beggar Clan from the
9 provinces is that
the retired old leader
has got a sealed letter to
Hero Sung of Wu Dong
asking us to join force with Wu Dong
and Er Mei
And if necessary to acquire help
from the Yuan regime
in order to destroy the Ming Cult
Why didn't you bring along...
the Jade Dog Stick, the leader's token?
Yes...
Quiet, listen to me
The old leader was supposed to...
let me bring the Stick here
But the Stick
would never be given to outsiders
Secondly, it might get lost on the way
that's why it wasn't brought here
How come...
I am Chang Wu Ji from the Ming Cult
Has Tse Shun the Lion King and
Miss Chou of Er Mei been here?
Chang Wu Ji...
Chang Wu Ji,
you are looking for death
Set up the Dog Killing Formation
Attack
Wait
Chang Wu Ji, you'd better surrender
or Miss Chou will be killed
Grab him
What's happening...
Who are you?
The Stick?
It's the leader's Jade Dog Stick
True, it's like the imperial seal
of the Beggar Clan
Followers of the Beggar Clan
kneel to receive orders
The deputy head of the Beggar Clan
Si Foh Lung
conspired with Sung Ching Shu,
Yuan regime's spy
to forge a letter from the old leader
hoping that our
Clan will surrender to Yuan
& go against the Ming Cult
I have been sent to clarify the matter
and bring Si Foh Lung to justice
Si Foh Lung, whose idea is it...
to betray the Beggar Clan?
It's... it's Sung Ching Shu
He gave me a million taels of gold
to buy off the Beggar Clan
He's the mastermind
I have nothing to do with it
Where's Sung?
Brothers... Iook around
and bring Sung back
Go...
Luckily you've come in time
otherwise the Beggar Clan will bear
the shame forever
Who are you? We hope to repay you
some other time
No need, your welfare is my concern
You'll know who I am in time
Arrest the traitor first
Yes...
Take him away
Go...
Chief Chang, please forgive
our misbehaviour
You have saved my life
I should thank you for this
You are...
No need to ask
We may meet again if there's a chance
If not, why bother to remember
one more girl's name?
Could it be her?
But it can't be
Chief Chang, you'd better
release Miss Chou's vital points
What is it?
That's strange, there's a blast of
mysterious energy
coming from your body that resists
my Jiu Yang kung fu
You've have been hit by the freezing palm?
Me?
No
How come you and my godfather
landed into their hands?
I don't know
I only remember when I was sleeping
at the inn
...someone slipped in
and paralyzed me
When I woke up
I was at the Beggar Clan
Where's my godfather now?
You are always thinking about
your godfather
I don't mean that
But on the day when you disappeared
Chiu Ming came to me
and told me something strange
What did she say?
Said she didn't do what happened
at Ice Fire island
If not her, who else could it be?
Chi Yeuk, let me tell you
my godfather has a disorder
When he has an attack he can do anything
...without realising it himself
I am afraid that...
I understand. After listening to Chiu Ming
...you wanted to clear her name
Think about it
If your godfather was the murderer
who poisoned him?
That's true
Chi Yeuk, I feel that things
in the martial arts world
are getting more and more complicated
I hope that after I have saved
my godfather
You and I can retire to the mountain...
& not be bothered by matters
in the martial arts world
But, will you still...
Iove me then?
Why not?
Right, after coming back from
Man Fat Temple
I've promised followers of
the Ming Cult to return
immediately after I've gone
to the Ice Fire Island
When I return to the Summit Guang Ming
...we will get married immediately
Bow to the heaven
Wait
Chiu Ming
Ms Chiu, today is the big day
for our leader
and the head of Er Mei
Ms Chiu, have a seat please
I'll raise you a toast later
I need to have a few words
with Chief Chang
Speak your mind then leave
Ms Chiu, we can wait
until after the wedding
It'll be too late
Princess, there're ups and downs in life
You have to face the reality
Why do you think I am here?
Chang Wu Ji, do you mean what you said?
Of course
That day when I gave you the antidote
You promised to do 3 things for me
Firstly, I want to borrow the Dragon Sabre
I've brought you to the Ice Fire Island
Where's the Dragon Sabre?
You'll find out
Now I want you to do the second thing
for me
What is it?
You cannot marry Chi Yeuk today
What?
I can't
It was agreed that...
I won't do anything dishonourable
If you marry her, you'll be unfilial
and dishonourable
Miss Chiu, I respect you
as my guest today
I won't tolerate anymore
if you keep talking rubbish
Then you refuse...
to do the second thing for me
Sorry
Look what I've got on my hands
What?
If you want to get it
...follow me now
Please stay
Ms Chiu
Either you go with me
or you go get married
Alright, I'll go with you
Don't do that...
Chi Yeuk, you...
Don't do that
Stop fighting
Hey, how come your kung fu became
so good?
None of your business
Chang Wu Ji, don't come back to me...
if you leave today
Chi Yeuk, this has something to do
with my godfather
My godfather has done a great favor to me
Please forgive me
Go
Chang Wu Ji
Chang Wu Ji...
Everybody, you all witness
that he is ungrateful to me
From this day onwards, I will have...
nothing to do with him
Don't run
Tell me
Where did you get that thing?
You can tell...
this is the hair of your godfather
Lion King
Of course I can see that
In the martial arts world
he's the only one with...
blonde hair while practising
the Lion Roaring kung fu
Do you know where he is?
Of course I do
If not, how could I get his hair?
Where is he?
In Shaolin temple
We have nothing here
We can only offer you some plain rice
Thank you
The night is cold
You should cover yourself well
Thank you, we'll just stay here
for one night
We'll leave tomorrow
Don't take too much trouble
Oh, no trouble at all
Alright, get some rest
You look tired
Sleep early
Alright...
Goodbye
Alright... get some rest
Does it hurt?
Yes
Since it's not too far away from Shaolin
...you take some rest
Let me go there to investigate by myself
"Temple Grand Hall"
You are here
Follow me
Shing Kwun
Greetings to Grand teachers
You are back
Yes
Yuen Chun
You brought the Lion King Tse Shun
back to Shaolin
& invited all martial heroes for
the Tuen Ng Festival
to fight against the Dragon Sabre
and Tse Shun
We'd like to listen to your reasons
for doing this
Yes
Yuen Chun, the 3 of us have retired
for many years
and haven't been bothered by
secular matters
If Tse Shun deserves death...
why don't you just kill him?
Why bother to put him under
the rock of Amitabha
and let us guard him for you?
For the battle at the Man Fat Temple
Shaolin owes the Ming Cult leader a favour
What are we going to do
if the leader comes?
That's why all martial artists
are invited to this assembly, where...
Tse Shun's fate will judged by
central region's schools
Even if Chang Wu Ji comes for him
We are not responsible for it
At the Summit Guang Ming
Chang Wu Ji once said that
you have something to do with
Tse Shun becoming enemies
with the six clans
In fact,
we can ask Tse Shun about this
But he has refused to talk
since he arrived
Therefore only you can explain the case
He's been talking nonsense
Don't bother, Chang Wu Ji
will definitely be here
for the Assembly
We can talk this over then
It's late now
You should go back
- Yes, Uncle
- Grand Teachers
Who is it? Please show up
& have a seat here
I am Chang Wu Ji, the leader
of the Ming Cult
Greetings to you
Chief Chang, are you here
for the Lion King?
The Lion King is my godfather,
I am here for him
It has been said that the Ming Cult leader
is powerful in his kung fu,
now I know it's true
I was Dao Ngai the former Abbot of Shaolin
He is Dao Jit
He is Dao Nan
I apologize for having offended you
We three brothers
have sworn before the Buddha to guard
Tse Shun until the Assembly
This is for the honour of Shaolin
Please forgive us
Wu Ji
Wu Ji, come over
I need to talk to you
Please
Godfather...
I've been staying under the rock
in the past few months
listening to the prayers of these 3 monks
Looking back, I feel that
I have deeply sinned
and deserve all this!
There is one thing
which I still don't understand
Even if you are coming to save me today
I won't go with you
You'd better leave
Chief Chang, it seems you'll
have to wait till...
the Tuen Ng Festival if you want to
save the Lion King
Chiu Ming
Chiu Ming...
How come it's you?
Shhh!
How come you are there alone?
After you left, I saw
someone jump down
That's why I hid myself outside
and waited till you came back
Did you know that the 2 elderly couple
were already dead?
What?
Who are you?
We have been instructed to kill
Chang Wu Ji
Who instructed you? Speak
It's him
Are you alright?
That's strange, this person is good
in kung fu
and has practised the Jiu Yin kung fu
The power of my Jiu Yang kung fu
was absorbed to it
I've seen this person before
The day I found you at the inn
He struck me down the cliff
Luckily I fell on a tree
or else I would have died
Who was he?
He must be the murderer
at the Ice Fire Island
To silence me off he is after my back
That's right, what's the situation
at Shaolin?
My godfather is in Shaolin
That's strange,
how do you know he's there?
After leaving Man Fat Temple,
Ching Shu betrayed...
Wu Dong and swore allegiance
to the Yuan regime
Therefore I know what he's done
The day when you saved Miss Chou
from the Beggar Clan
...he took the Lion King away
from the back door
and gave him up to Shing Kwun
Shing Kwun brought your godfather back
...to Shaolin to claim credit
That was why I took you away from
your wedding
In order to save my godfather
I'll take you home to dress your wounds
and then rush back to the Assembly
"Lion Killing Assembly"
Everyone in Shaolin is honoured
to have you all present here
No need to stand on ceremony...
Tse Shun has done great harm
to the martial arts world
and is laden with sin
We've caught him but do not wish
to claim credit alone
That's why we have invited all heroes
to come
...to settle this
Er Mei school is here
Sung Ching Shu
I heard that since the
Summit Guang Ming incident...
she and Sung Ching Shu were engaged
Ching Shu...
Master Kung Man,
please excuse my being late
No problem at all, please sit
Please...
Alright
Apart from the Beggar Clan
which is now electing a leader
and is unable to come
All clans from the central region are here
To be fair, each clan will send
a representative to
fight in the competition
Whoever wins in the final round
will posses Tse Shun and his Dragon Sabre
He can then go to the 3 Pine Peak
to get Tse Shun,
whose life and death will be from
then onwards
of no concern to any other clans
First Combat, Ming Cult against Kung Tung
Ming Cult is the winner
Second Combat, Kwun Lun against Wu Dong
Wu Dong is the winner
Third Combat, Shaolin against Hai Sha
Shaolin is the winner
Fourth Combat, Er Mei against Hua Shan
Er Mei is the winner
The results of the first round are
Wu Dong, Ming Cult
Shaolin, Er Mei are the winners,
lots are drawn
First. Ming Cult against Shaolin
Yuan Ip
Teacher...
This concerns Shaolin's reputation;
I'll fight myself
Chief, let me...
No need
Master Kung Man is the Abbot of Shaolin
Out of courtesy I should fight
Master Kung Man, please
I should be the one to ask you...
to be merciful
Please
Chief Chang, I believe that
that is Shaolin's Dragon Fist
That's correct, my godfather taught me
If I win by chance, Shaolin Kung fu...
won't be said to have lost to other school
If I lose...
I can only blame myself for not
learning well
No matter what the outcome is
I must thank you for your favours
to Shaolin
Abbot, no need for formalities, please
Be careful of my attack
Chief Chang, what a young hero!
Please forgive me, I'm too eager to
save my godfather
Next is Er Mei against Wu Dong
Leader Chou, please
Ching Shu
Yes
Please
Ching Shu
You're Wu Dong's student,
why are you helping Er Mei?
Yan Lei Hang
You must be mistaken
I'm the future husband
of the head of Er Mei
I'm no longer the same old Sung Ching Shu
Huh...
No wonder your father fell sick
when he heard you are engaged
Ching Shu, although you are a new star...
you shouldn't be using the kung fu
of Wu Dong
to fight against Wu Dong
What's so special about the kung fu
of Wu Dong?
Everybody, listen
Today I won't be using the kung fu
of Wu Dong in the fight
Alright, let's see...
what kind of kung fu you are using?
Yan Lei Hang, Wu Dong kung fu is outdated
Don't boast!
Ching Shu, your kung fu may not be able
...to beat Wu Dong
Get up
Wait
The remaining parties
should be the Ming Cult and Er Mei
All other schools please step down
But this bastard
has wounded our Sixth Brother
from the back
Ah? No body said that...
there cannot be attack from the back
Did anyone say that?
Did anyone?
Well...
Chief Chang, it seems you put...
all your grudge to that attack
But don't forget that
you are the one who is ungrateful to me
Chi Yeuk, what happened at
Summit Guang Ming
was all my fault
I hope that you can give me a chance
to go and save my godfather
I have sworn in front of
all heroes at the Summit Guang Ming
that I no longer have anything
to do with you
Chi Yeuk, your kung fu is so powerful
where did you learn it from?
You absorb my Jiu Yang kung fu
None of your business
I now remember...
you were the one in black
in the wood house
Why did you want to kill me and Miss Chiu?
Are you responsible for
the Ice Fire Island incident?
Shut up
Speak, was it you?
No
If it wasn't you, who could it be?
Freeze
Chief Chang, don't let your mind
wander again
in any combat
Who is it?
Chang Wu Ji... here to visit
Er Mei Clan's head
Please wait
Chief Chang, please come in
Leader Chou
Chief Chang, what's the matter?
How is Hero Sung's injury?
It can't be minor,
considering he lost to you
I've brought the medicine
which can cure his injury
Really?
Maybe you will feel better
if you can cure him
and be a husband of Yuan princess
without any guilt
No, that's not it
In fact, I saved Hero Sung's life
in exchange for
my godfather's
And it's not easy...
to save godfather tomorrow
Over at 3 Pine Peak,
my godfather was guarded by
the 3 Shaolin monks of high renown
You and I mustjoin hands
to fight and beat them
Otherwise my godfather cannot be saved
Why do you have to save him?
Firstly, godfather has been good to me
Secondly, I want to find out
what really happened
at the Ice Fire Island
I've come here to plead with you
Wu Ji, the night of the wedding
at Guang Ming Summit
I spoke in front of all the people
that you and I have nothing to do
with each other
Therefore I don't understand
what you are saying now at all
Come, send him off
Chi Yeuk
Chief Chang, please
Wait
I've almost forgot to tell you
If you help me tomorrow...
you will regret for your life
At the last combat at 3 Pine Peak,
Er Mei has won
According to the rules
Leader Chou can have Tse Shun
However to maintain peace,
a special rule applies
As long as the challenger can
lure the monks
...out of the tree hole
and gets to sit inside;
He wins
In case he can't accomplish that
before sunset
...Tse Shun will still be Shaolin's
Leader Chou, please
Chi Yeuk, these monks are kung fu expert
You'd better be careful
None of your business
Sirs, excuse me
I am about to launch the attack
Although Leader Chou won all
other martial artists
three against one is disrespectful
to Shaolin
That's why I would like to join in
That seems to be fairer
What do you think?
Only winning counts,
not the number of people
Chang Wu Ji, I've told you
if you help me, you'll regret for
the rest of your life
Shaolin monk is really good
You again
Yes, it doesn't seem fair for
3 to fight against 2
3 against 3 seems fairer
And then each tree hole
has someone sitting in it
Dragon 18 Fist, the Beggar Clan's
ultimate kung fu
Amitabha...
How come you are here too?
I've brought the Heaven Sword
and the Dragon Sabre
The Heaven Sword and the Dragon Sabre
It's said that together
they are invincible
I must try
Sister Chou, don't be hasty
Let's talk about our matters later
Bravo...
Good...
They really are the most powerful
weapons in the world
I'm convinced
Who is it?
Amitabha
Godfather... I've finally saved you
I've saved you at last
The past months I've listened to
prayers under the rock
Thank you to the 3 monks
in showing me the right way
I feel that I have sinned greatly
I intend not to be involved in
secular matters again
However in order to clear all grudge
and put an end to
what a sinful affair started
I've decided to show up again
Masters, can I use this holy place
to settle some secular business?
Well, since it's that as you say
...why bother to ask us?
Thank you, Master
Monk Yuen Chun, you are my teacher
Shing Kwun
Please come out
What?
Shing Kwun, we are responsible for
all the grudges in the martial arts world
You raped and killed my wife to avenge...
for the Ming Cult leader who took
your loved one
You tried to urge all schools
in the central region
...to destroy the Ming Cult, am I right?
Yes
Last time you caught me
and put me in 3 Pine Peak
Now I understand
At the Summit Guang Ming
the 6 clans were unable to destroy
the Ming Cult
That was why you wanted to
make use of the 3 monks
...to kill Wu Ji first
By that time all men from
the Ming Cult will fight
and you can kill with other people's hands
Is that correct?
It seems that you've figured out
what I want to do
That's right
I've had only one wish my entire life
And that is to destroy the Ming Cult
Destroy the Ming Cult...
Good, now the grudge between the Ming cult
and other schools is resolved
and everyone is clear about this
What's left behind...
is the grudge between me and Shing Kwun
Uncle...
Shing Kwun, you killed my whole family
I should kill you
But by the mercy of Buddha
I'll just take out your eyes
and we have no more grudge against
each other
You can never see me
I won't see you either
Amitabha, take him down
Shing Kwun owes me but,
I owe hundreds & thousands
in the martial arts world
I'm willing to be maimed
and slaughtered in any way
by those whose families have been
killed by me
Godfather...
Wu Ji, if someone wants to kill me
don't stop them, I deserve it
I deserve death, go away
Good...
My father was killed by Tse Shun
I was supposed to kill him,
but I'm impressed by
his honour and gallantry
Besides, when Tse Shun
started killing, he was...
driven mad by Shing Kwun
who raped and killed his wife
Let's forgive him
Thank you, heroes
All is emptiness
why bother with tears?
I'm deeply in sin, please let me stay
...to become a monk
Amitabha, the doors of Buddha are
always open to you
Come in if you are called for, let's go
Godfather...
Sir, you've got the wrong person
Tse Shun is dead
I'm the monk who has just been converted
Amitabha
Old grudge has now been resolved
All is emptiness
Don't go, godfather
What are you doing?
I want to ask him about
the Ice Fire Island incident
Why do you have to ask him and not me?
You?
Who are you?
Cousin Yan Li
Chou Chi Yeuk, now it's the time
for you to talk
Let me relieve your pressure points
Don't
Chi Yeuk, why do you have to kill her?
Of course she wants to kill me because...
I know she stole the Heaven Sword
and the Dragon Sabre
Bullshit. These two weapons are...
brought here by Chiu Ming
Why are you accusing me of their theft?
That's right
I took the Heaven Sword
and the Dragon Sabre
but the hilts of the Heaven Sword
have been cut open
I think you must be curious as to where...
I got this Sword and the Sabre from!
Come
Sung Ching Shu...
Ching Shu, I'll kill you
I've got the Sword and the Sabre
...from your fiance
But you've already taken the manual
stored within them
Chi Yeuk
Don't fight
Chiu Ming, don't fight
Chiu Ming, what's going on?
Let's start from the night
at the Ice Fire Island
...when Siu Chiu went away
Chou Chi Yeuk put poison
in the water when we were all unaware
And we all passed out that night
Then she put me on the boat and
pushed it out to sea
After that she wounded herself
and killed Yan Li
Nonsense
No, she's right
That day you must be too nervous
You didn't kill me
And my cousin put me on the boat
...and that saved my life
On the island on the other side
of the sea,
I met the Beggar Clan's
recluse old leader. He not only
saved me but also taught me the
Dragon 18 fist kung fu
I am now the new leader of the Beggar Clan
Chi Yeuk, is she telling the truth?
Yes
I don't want to lie to you anymore
I can't fool you anymore
That day at Man Fat Temple
Teacher told me that
the secret of the Heaven Sword
and the Dragon Sabre
is the Jiu Yin and the
Dragon 18 fist kung fu
which are both hidden in their
respective hilts
You can easily get the...
Dragon Sabre from Wu Ji
That's why I made you my successor
But you have to promise me that...
you have to make Er Mei
conquer the whole central region
by whatever means
I have to follow the instructions
of my late teacher
Hence, come what may I have to...
get hold of the Heaven Sword
and the Dragon Sabre
In the hilts of Heaven Sword
& Dragon Sabre
is really hidden half book
of Jiu Yin kung fu
and Dragon 18 fist kung fu
Is it why your kung fu
has progressed so fast lately?
Did you betray Tse Shun?
Yes, I was afraid Tse Shun
would let out the secret
Therefore I went to Sung Ching Shu...
and made use of Yuan to kidnap Tse Shun
I was hoping to use Shing Kwun
to kill Tse Shun
Unexpectedly, Shing Kwun intended...
to use Tse Shun to destroy the Ming Cult
and I had been victimized until this day
Don't move
Chou Chi Yeuk, what do you want?
I want Chang Wu Ji to do one thing for me
What is it?
I repent for all my wrongdoings
I want to shave my head and be a nun
But I hope that you will be the one
...to shave my head
Glory to Amitabha
Because ofjealousy towards Chiu Ming...
Chou Chi Yeuk had made a grave mistake
Since then, the leader of a clan
becomes a Buddhist nun
...for the rest of her life
The story of the Heaven Sword
and the Dragon Sabre
...is now coming to an end
What now remains is...
a short episode of Chiu Ming
and Chang Wu Ji
Wu Ji has promised
Chiu Ming to do 3 things for her
And the last thing Chiu Ming requested
...was to have Wu Ji go with her
What is this place?
It's a place for bidding farewell
What?
The Willow's Shore isn't necessarily
a place for adieu
...neither is it the Pavilion;
It's the time where bidding farewell
is most proper
Didn't you say that your third request
...is for me to go with you?
That's correct
This is IT then
The ultimate aim of you people
from the Central Region
...is to fight against us,
the Yuan regime
And I am the princess of Yuan;
How long can we stay together?
Everyone's destiny
has been arranged at birth
And this is called fate
We are on 2 separate roads
Fortunately, I've never said I love you
...neither have you
Love is like a net,
capturing heroes' hearts
Like a sword, vengeance cutting
through love and hate
Even heroes have to succumb
...to love and hate
Not even the Heaven Sword
and Dragon Sabre
can disentangle love and hate
Hatred in the sea of love
Regrets in this life
filled with resentment and love
Who can answer what is love and hate!