Greece is all ruins.
It's just for tourists.
I'm glad we came here.
If we combine our savings,
we could buy an apartment next year.
I might even be working out here
for about a year.
Here?
Don't you like Australia?
It's the biggest branch outside Japan.
With the experience that I'd get,
I should be up for promotion.
They like people with
international experience.
- Your salad, sir.
- Thank you.
I wonder if he's a real Greek?
Are you all right?
I'm just a little tired.
You don't want to go back
to Japan tomorrow, do you?
Hello.
You're still here?
Yes. It's our last night.
Have a farewell drink with us.
Back in Tokyo,
they would never forgive me...
if I didn't entertain you on your last night.
I'll only keep him for one drink, Mrs. Takada.
I won't be long.
This is one of our employees,
Yukio Takada.
How do you do?
Please excuse him, he's on his honeymoon.
Thank you for everything.
Enjoy yourselves tonight, won't you?
Midori-chan?
Midori!
- You saw her leaving the lift?
- Yes, sir.
- And she was heading towards her room?
I got off on this floor to deliver a file, sir.
And that was the last time you saw her?
- We've cameras there and at the staff door.
- So that's the out?
Between when he left to have a drink
and when he arrived in his bedroom.
Kinda cute, isn't she?
Well, maybe she just pissed off,
couldn't stand him or something.
It was their honeymoon.
Got something. Staff entrance.
The hotel manager's just had a call.
It was her.
All she said was that she'd been kidnapped.
- That's all?
- Yes.
- And then she put the phone down.
- How much English does he understand?
A little.
Tell him that his wife has run and
all she said was that she was kidnapped.
Your wife rang the hotel manager
and said she'd been kidnapped.
That was all she said.
Does he have any idea
why she'd be kidnapped?
Do you have any idea
why she was kidnapped?
No!
Now, an update on the kidnapping
of the Japanese honeymooner.
...she was gone.
It was the last night of our honeymoon.
I don't know why she's been kidnapped.
If the kidnappers are watching this,
please give me back my wife.
I beg you!
Please, give her back to me!
Shit!
Like this.
So, she paid you to take her out this way?
I felt sorry for her.
Said she hated her husband,
she wanted to leave him.
We know where she is. Paradiso Motel.
The manager just called.
Come on, let's go!
Use the key this time!
Break it down.
You two, check the bathroom. Done.
An international code.
Yeah, Japan.
Same number over and over again.
Could have gone anywhere, Bish.
Hey, who's gonna pay the bill?
His wife rang one number in Tokyo
over and over again.
It was the manager of a software firm
she worked for.
A man by the name of Sadao Kinugasa.
Your wife rang one number in Tokyo
over and over.
It was the manager of
the company she worked for.
His name is Sadao Kinugasa.
The Japanese police spoke to him.
It appears his wife and Sadao
had a relationship.
The Japanese police spoke to him.
It appears your wife
and he had a relationship.
And she planned to leave him in Australia.
The manager was gonna fly out
and they'd live together.
But at the last moment he got cold feet.
She planned to leave you here in Australia.
The manager was going to fly out here
and they would live together.
But, at the last moment, he got cold feet.
Thank you, Mr. Bishop.
- He took that well.
- You think?
I mean, he'll be the most publicized
cuckold in Japan.
I can have you back on a plane to Tokyo
in a few hours.
She destroyed me.
Go back to Japan.
I can't!
I'm a laughingstock.
Why don't you come and stay with me
until things settle down?
You can't stay here.
Hello?
"Dear Yukio,
How can I apologize to you
for what I've done?
I don't think you'll forgive me,
no matter what I say.
I have no idea what I am going to do
in the future.
What I've done is unforgivable.
I hope you never meet
another woman like me.
I am really, really sorry."
Dad.
This is the fella I was telling you about.
- You drive a car good?
- He's brilliant.
This is Gill Boden, my brother,
and Tony, good friend of the family.
Butchers don't do it right.
Has he done this sort of thing before?
No, but he's the best driver I've ever seen.
- What's your name?
- Colin.
Are you gonna help us?
- Well, are you?
- Yeah, all right.
Why are you doing this?
I need the money.
He had a crash repair business.
It went broke.
He owes money.
Now I'm gonna trust you.
If you let me and my sons down...
then I'm gonna kill you.
What if they let me down,
you gonna kill them?
I hope...
you drive fancy as you talk.
I do.
Here.
I don't need a gun, man.
- Take the gun.
- Hey, I'm just the chauffeur.
You do what we agreed. We share the risk.
Hey, I'm doing you a favor. You carry a gun.
Next.
- Teller five.
- Thank you.
- Can I have change?
- I have to see your passport.
Here.
Down! Get on the floor, all of you!
Get on the floor!
Everybody down!
Everybody, on the floor! On the floor!
- Get down!
- Move it!
Want some tellers here.
We want to know where...
Fill that up.
Shit!
Put the fucking screen down!
- Let's get on it! Let's go!
- Fucking put it down!
- We're out of here! Come on!
- What about him?
- Come on! Let's go!
- We can't leave him there!
- It's too late, mate. Too late!
Come on, let's go!
Come on!
Everybody stay down, stay down!
Told you. Christ!
Let's go!
We've got a girl!
I swear, we'll shoot her!
Get in the car. Get in the fucking car!
Move it!
Shit!
Where'd the bloody coppers come from?
The stupid bastards!
- What happened to Tony?
- The fucking idiot's dead!
You're supposed to watch
the fucking teller...
- you stupid bastard!
- Shut up!
What are you doing? She's seen you!
- So fucking what?
- You fucking take care of it now.
Fuck!
Shut the fuck up!
Or I'll fucking kill you, all right?
- Come here!
- No!
- What are you doing?
- She saw us.
You can't just kill her.
She didn't do anything.
You stay in the car, Colin.
You stay in the fucking car!
Get down! Down!
Stay down!
Brother!
Oh, Jesus.
Go back to the car.
- She didn't do anything, man.
- She! Who the fuck is she?
You killed my brother!
You stay there.
Stay there!
You fucking traitor.
I'm gonna come and get you!
You'll never get away with this!
- I'll find you!
- Get in the car!
You're a fucking dead man!
You're a dead man, you hear me?
You're gonna fucking die, man!
It's her, and she left these behind.
She dropped it during the robbery.
I had it translated. It's an apology to him.
He said, "Why is she doing this to me?"
You're on your own.
It's safer if you stay here.
He took her hostage! If he had listened
to me, he wouldn't be shot!
You bastard.
You give him the gun.
And he killed your brother.
- Hello?
- I wanna speak to Mahood.
It's Colin.
Colin.
You know it was an accident
with your brother, mate.
You said to me no one would get hurt.
I'm not gonna pretend I'm not angry, Colin.
Things just got a little out of hand.
You know?
What about you?
You okay? You need some money?
No, I'll manage, mate.
Look, things got a bit messy,
didn't they, you know?
Just thought I'd try
and do you a bit of a favor.
Where are you, mate?
I'm in the middle of nowhere.
I'll call you when I get to a town.
We get gasoline for the car?
Can you get me a hamburger?
Hamburger?
Yeah, hamburger. Just right over there.
- Hamburger.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
- Hungry?
Christ, I've never seen one
without a camera before.
Excuse me.
- Can I have a hamburger?
- Sure. What would you like on it?
A hamburger.
Do you want the lot?
- A lot?
- The lot.
Bacon, lettuce, cheese, tomato, sauce.
The lot?
What the hell are you doing with my truck?
Don't you realize that stealing is a crime?
You're so lucky I'm not
on Benzedrine today.
Otherwise, I'd be doing
a lot more than hurting you.
I think I'll ask what his hamburger wants.
Thank you.
No! Don't do that!
Piss off!
Naughty boy!
You let our standards slip...
by interbreeding with inferior races...
and before you know it...
we'll be breeding halfwits and mongrels!
You okay?
Why didn't you just tell him?
I was coward.
He was so desperate to marry me.
And my parents says it's a good choice.
I thought I could do it. But I was wrong.
Why don't you just give yourself up?
Tell them I kidnapped you
and forced you to help me.
No.
Don't you wanna get back to Japan?
I don't want to go back.
I have no future there.
Many people in Japan...
they have no true life.
Everybody has dream,
but they scared to make dream come true...
because they raised in a certain way.
That's why...
I like Sadao.
He was my lover.
He said...
we would live here...
you know?
We would have a future.
But he was too scared to leave.
I was stupid.
But I dreamt that I could have a new life.
It was all my fault.
I think I should have told Yukio
the truth from the beginning.
What is that?
It's a kookaburra.
Kookaburra?
It's a bird.
The bird?
The bird laughs?
This is strange country.
I can breathe here.
What do we do now?
- Keep on going?
- Not without money.
I know how to get money.
From a bank.
I've had enough of banks.
We can do better than your friend.
When we do it...
we can go backward.
- I hate people staring at me when I eat.
- Sorry, Bish.
Yeah, so what?
This morning at a country bank.
This morning.
Looks like they're a team.
The police think they're a team.
I'll kill her.
What'd he say?
He said she's a strange woman.
One in a million, all right.
Were you in on the robbery
with your brother?
- No.
- So he did it without your knowledge.
I was not my brother's keeper, all right?
You seemed to me
to be a pretty close-knit family.
He was a bad boy.
So it would seem.
Do you know who those people are?
No.
My bet is...
that the bloke in the balaclava
shot your son.
Keep an eye on them.
Christ, fancy living here
with that yodeling five times a day.
We might as well be in fucking Arabia.
- Can you hack into systems?
- What sort?
You know, American Express,
or something like that.
Sure, given time.
What about hotel or motel chains?
Check it out.
Well, he's always been wearing a balaclava.
So nobody knows who he is.
He's traveling across country.
He'll check into a motel.
And use his real name.
We'll check every day.
I will be vengeance.
No AIC?
No. Fair enough.
I'll give you $250 off.
- Indicators don't work?
- It's only a fuse.
Hand brake's fucked.
Don't park on any hills.
All right, $300 off. That's it.
- Done.
- Good.
We'll leave that for 30 minutes.
Nice hands.
- What?
- Nice lines.
Except for that one.
What does it mean?
You or somebody important to you
dies suddenly.
When?
I don't know.
Palms don't have dates.
See?
Follow along yours.
The rest of your palm's great.
- You got any welding gear?
- Yep.
- Can I use it?
- Be my guest.
It's $25 an hour.
Two hours minimum.
What a spunk.
Spunk?
It's when you give a blowjob
on the first date.
Blowjob?
It's something to do with whales.
I can breathe!
They robbed the bank in this town.
I'm going to find her.
But you don't know where she is.
I can find out.
There are not many Japanese
in the countryside.
I've read this. I'll track her down.
Leave it to the police.
But they don't want to kill her like I do.
Yukio, stop this! Go back to Japan!
Only after I've killed her.
I want you to get me a gun.
I can't do that!
Get me a motorbike and get me a gun,
and you'll never see me again.
I hope you don't find her.
All I want is to ask her
why she embarrassed me
in front of millions of people.
I went to some effort to get this,
and it can't be traced.
Is there a safety catch on this?
How would I know?
It looks like a toy...
I think that's enough practice for today.
What are you doing?
Changing our fate.
Are you okay?
Jeez, Japs taking over heaven, too?
You're lucky we didn't kill you.
Call that luck?
Unless you got a bottle of Scotch.
Where yous two heading?
My dad's got a farm outside Rally Town.
Rally Town.
I used to shear sheep down there.
What's his name?
- O'Brien.
- I know him. Did a season for him.
He's okay. Top man in his field.
Why are you out here?
Couple of smart bastards kidnapped me
in a pub last night.
Pissed as they were,
they dropped me out here.
- Why?
- They're fucking wankers, that's why.
They know nothing about classical music.
And nothing about accordions.
Maybe your mates know something
about noise pollution.
What the fuck you mean by that?
Don't you know any other tune?
This isn't a tune, mate.
This is a masterpiece.
Hey, why don't you play something
we all know?
What would you fucking know, pal?
Why don't you just stop
fucking playing, huh?
Fucking make me.
I think I fucking will.
All right. A bit of radio.
If you hang on to this,
it would be a major favor.
Yeah, just give it here, you fuck.
- Look out for yourself. Smile.
- Yeah, thanks for the lift.
Which way's that motel?
About an hour down the road,
you can't miss it. Straight ahead.
- Bye, Jonah.
- See you later.
Bye.
Cretins.
A beer!
- Please.
- Give us a break, Gloria.
Could I have a beer, please?
You couldn't fucking get rid of me,
could you, you pack of scumbags?
Jonah, stop it.
Get out of here. Go on, get out.
Now throw me out!
You stop that bloody racket.
It's not racket, it's music!
Hey...
- How long do you wanna stay?
- Just a day.
- Maybe two.
- Room 19.
Thanks.
Thank you very much. Okay. Bye.
Are you sure that's him?
The woman at the motel said
he's with a Japanese or Chinese girl.
- That's him all right.
- How long will it take us to get there?
We hire a light plane, three, four hours.
We are not hiring a plane.
We can be traced then.
It's 14 or 15 by car.
We are going to do it in my way.
Come.
I'm your bloke.
Look out.
Now let me get this right.
You're Laurel and I'm Hardy.
You can take the double.
I like this one.
- Goodnight.
I really like this.
- I feel like I'm alive.
- Good.
I like you very much.
- Do you like me?
- Yes, I do.
I made a mistake with my husband.
I didn't love him.
And my other mistake was my boss.
I thought I loved him.
That's okay.
People make mistakes.
Two bad, bad mistakes.
But you're not a mistake.
Thanks.
I really feel...
deep thing in my heart for you.
There's nothing wrong with that.
I don't want to hurt you.
I'm bad luck.
Bad luck for any man.
I have dreamt of this,
even when I was awake.
She's not here.
Where's the Jap?
She left me.
Where is she?
You are not going to tell us.
Very well.
We'd sooner talk to you.
Didn't mean to kill your son.
There is a hurt, here...
where my son should be.
Now I have to fix this hurt.
What is the saying?
An eye for an eye, a hand for a hand.
Well, I want a heart for a heart.
- Good morning.
Are you looking for something in particular?
Can I have a makeup?
We don't have makeup. Just what you see.
Come here.
You have a beautiful face.
Thank you.
He was gonna kill an innocent woman.
I think that before you talk...
you best listen to me.
See these eyes?
They have seen a lot.
I have seen men naked on stone floors...
shitting themselves in fear.
I have seen men with broken backs
and torn out eyes begging to be killed.
I have seen men, strong man...
weeping tears of blood
when I touch electrodes to their pricks.
I have seen what men
are capable of doing to other men.
And what men go to is without boundaries.
In Afghanistan, where I come from...
I was an interrogator for the Russians
after they had invaded us.
People ask me,
why did I interrogate my own people.
The answer was simple.
I was good at it.
The important thing is to see...
what is happening to you.
Which is why mirrors are a great help.
- Can I buy these things?
- What things?
Clothes on these dolls.
- Oh, the store dummies.
- Yes...
Sure.
But you'll have to undress them yourself.
Yeah.
The other one.
I said the other one!
A hand for a hand, plus interest.
This is only the beginning.
You see my son die.
You will see yourself die.
But only with one eye.
This eye, or this eye?
Mahood, pluck out his eye.
Let's see if you have the guts to do it.
You come from a weak generation.
I will show you how to do it.
I've blinded many men.
But I will take only one eye from you...
so you can see what else happened to you.
Once you're dead,
I pluck out your other eye...
so you will be eyeless in Heaven.
- Hi.
- Put your hands up! Shut the door!
Shut the fucking door!
Kill her.
Now what was his name?
The name of the bloke
that booked the room?
Colin O'Brien.
- Hey, Dad.
- Long time no see.
This is Midori.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
Hi. What happened?
Bit of an accident.
Some accident.
Come on, let's get inside.
Fix him up properly.
You in trouble?
Nothing I can't handle.
'Cause if you are...
maybe I can help.
Just being here is help enough, mate.
You took all them?
I take them to prove I exist.
You see, sometimes I don't know.
Rembrandt did it. Painted himself a lot.
How is he?
He having rest.
They're beautiful.
Not really. They've eaten all the grass...
and they've taken the last water
from the dam.
- Why are they doing that?
- The drought.
I just sit here every day...
watch all my land blow away.
So, what are you and Colin doing out here?
Traveling, you know...
just traveling.
You didn't see Colin for a long time?
Years.
Not a very close family.
- That's not very good.
- I don't know.
Don't get in each other's pockets that way.
What about you?
Know him long?
No.
Not so long.
I ran away from my husband a few days ago.
What are you laughing at?
I forgot people did things like that.
You don't like me much, do you?
You think that's beautiful?
Well, I don't.
It's in the eyes of the beholder.
Some of the most beautiful birdcalls
are their cries...
of distress and terror.
No, I don't have the energy to hate anyone.
I wish I did.
- I thought you were asleep.
- I was just dozing.
Can't get my boots off.
- I'll help.
- No, that's all right.
Yeah, I'll help.
- Did you live here?
- When I was young.
There was grass everywhere then.
Every year, it got drier.
Mom was lonely.
She likes people. Dad, doesn't need them.
Lots of arguments.
One day, Mom just ran off with this guy
who was passing through.
Took me and my sister to the city.
Sydney first...
eventually, all the way up to Kent.
I've only seen Dad a couple times
since then.
Where is she now?
Mom? Up in Queensland.
With some new guy.
My sister's in the Philippines, though.
You think?
We're not a close family.
When you take this off...
you will have new lines and new fate.
Our fate brought us together.
Why would you want to change that?
I'll tell you what.
Let's go down south, to the coast.
We'll take Dad. There's a beach there.
It's wonderful.
I'd like that.
- The moon is calling.
- Waning.
The moon is waning.
Now I know what love is.
Real love is...
what I feel for you.
It's real love what I feel for you.
Good day.
Hi. Juice, no ice.
You should dye your hair blonde.
- Excuse me?
- Your people look good blonde.
Well, that was fucking embarrassing.
Have you seen her?
It was her.
A bit hard to see with chicken soup
in my eyes, but maybe.
Which way they went?
Jesus, that was some good stuff.
- Which way?
- Don't yell at me.
- Which way!
- Fuck you.
Stupid whore.
- Good evening.
Beer.
- Beer?
- Yes. Beer, please.
Long way from home.
Japan.
Go on past me, you got plenty of room!
Well, get fucked!
All right, smile.
- Sure you won't come?
- No. You always liked the sea.
I wasn't as keen on it as your mother.
- Have a good trip.
- Thank you, Cam.
- Bye.
- Should be back in about a week.
- Son, I can wait for years.
- Thanks, mate.
- Take care.
Bye.
Thank you, Cam.
Thank you.
Hello?
"Beach."
I want information.
Where's beach?
Who are you?
Where is beach?
I said, who are you?
- My wife.
- I don't know where she is.
Where the sea? Where's the beach?
I said I don't know where she is.
You do!
You tell me!
I'll tell you.
I'll tell you something.
But I don't know if you'll understand me.
- What's your name?
- Yukio.
Well, there's a word. It's called karma.
Sort of means you can do bad
or evil for a long time.
But eventually,
eventually it'll catch up with you.
And you'll be destroyed.
When I was young...
I was a bit of a lad.
I did some bad things.
Ended up in jail
for almost killing my best friend.
He took my girlfriend from me.
I served my time.
It was bad karma, what I did.
He was my best friend.
Now, it's caught up with me.
Bad karma's this land.
There's been a drought here for 10 years.
And it'll continue until I die.
But you, Yukio...
Japan started the war against China...
then the world.
You lose the war. What happens?
You become a world economic power.
Unfair.
But your karma will change. Soon, Yukio...
your tiny country,
with its millions of tiny people...
will get the karma it deserves.
Earthquakes, tidal waves...
storms will destroy Japan.
It will sink below the waves and drown.
As if it never existed.
And you will die, Yukio.
You will get the karma you deserve,
you understand?
I understand.
This is your karma!
I understand!
You want a lift, man?
- That's cool.
- There's plenty of room.
Thank you.
Where you headed, friend?
Going this way, pal?
The beach.
- What'd he say?
- I don't know.
Think he's been out in the sun
too long, mate.
A bit down, eh?
I want to go to beach.
- The beach? You would like to see?
- Yes.
- Okay, cool.
Well, we'll drop you off in Porter.
That's on the way.
What do you want to go
to the beach for, anyway?
To talk to my wife.
Ain't been married long, eh?
- What's "B and S Ball"?
- It's a dance for bachelors and spinsters.
Is it a dance place
where you can wear good clothes?
Yeah. Sunday best for the B and S.
Hi. It's $25 each, thanks.
Won't be a bachelor for long.
- Last of our money.
- This is worth it.
Before some spinster
won't let you ask me.
Bachelor and spinster.
Two beers. Thanks, mate.
- May I have this dance?
- Yes.
I'm a spinster tonight.
Porter.
No man. We're not going there.
Porter!
We haven't danced yet.
You'd kill me?
I love you.
You don't know what love is.
Wait... wait...
I have no time.
Colin!
Why here?
It's the coldest place in town.
- All the witnesses saw her do it?
- Yeah. Then she and the guy headed south.
- And what's south?
- The ocean.
You'll be okay, darling.
- Tell me.
- Tell you?
Tell me about the beach.
About the beach.
This is the first beach I ever went to...
with my mom and dad and my sister.
I didn't know it was gonna be so big.
Just went on and on.
The horizon made me happy.
Happy?
It meant there are other places to go.
Places I didn't know anything about.
Beach makes things better.
Fixes things. You wait.
Concentrate.
Left.
I feel very cold.