"Hebbuli!" (Ferocious Tiger)
"Hebbuli!"
[English rap song]
Sir, we're ready for
the surgical strike.
And our target is Hafiz.
Sir, Hafiz is the
Muslim commander.
And he has killed 65 of our
soldiers since the last four years.
Hafiz is in Kotli, PoK.
He has kidnapped 4 doctors
of our relief camp.
According to the sources, he was
injured by last night's cross-firing.
Four commandos from Team A under Captain
Ram, are on this mission currently.
These are one of the best, Sir.
Captain Ram one of the bravest
commandos of our country.
Keep going.
- Thank you, Sir. Jai Hind!
- Jai Hind.
Mission Blackboard is on.
Mission: freedom.
The objective of this mission
is to save the civilians of..
..our country from
the terrorists.
Team of highly trained Para
commandos led by Captain Ram.
This is the real battleground..
where there's only one thing
that determines life or death..
one bullet.
Our commandos have to infiltrate
the enemy's area stealthily..
and shoot them at point blank.
There is threat to life.
Soldiers, we have to advance towards
the enemy camp cautiously..
and save our people.
- Okay, Sir.
- Be alert.
There!
Sir, we have shot two
terrorists down.
And, Sir..
News is that we have
completely secured the area.
We have found a huge amount of
bombs, grenades and weapons.
Over and out, Sir.
Soldiers, I've found the entry.
- I'm going in.
- Sir, may I come too?
You stay there,
I'll go and check.
Be alert. Wait for my signal.
Indian army!
Don't worry, it'll
be alright, okay?
Okay, quiet.
Where?
I'll be back.
For the first time, to kill
the Indian commandos..
They have come so close to us.
Such a big risk for
such a small income?
You all will die! All of you!
This is our land!
And we are even ready
to die for it.
Even if I die, there are thousands
like me who will fight..
..for the freedom of this land!
You will die first.
I'll send others after you.
Wait.
Jai Hind, Sir.
Jai Hind.
You could've brought that
terrorist here, alive.
Why did you kill him?
I want an explanation.
We could've got so much
information from him!
Sir, we collected
the entire data.
And he didn't have any
more information.
Who are you to decide that?
Sir, this was our only option..
through which we
sent the message.
What message?
Sir, if they can invade
our land and attack us..
even we're not any lesser.
We're calm, that doesn't
mean we're weak.
We can invade and
destroy them as well.
What do you mean? Won't they attack
again for doing what you did?
They will if they are
not scared, Sir.
This is the message I sent.
They will think a hundred
times before attacking us.
This is not the answer
to my question.
And remember, this will
not stop your enquiry.
And if that happens,
you will regret it.
I'm a soldier born in India, grew
up drinking River Ganga's water.
I will not hesitate to give
up my life for my country.
As far as enquiry is concerned, no
enquiry is bigger than my courage.
What?
I'm ready for the enquiry, Sir.
His looks, his daring..
I fell for him at first sight!
His height, his personality..
He was just handsome soldier!
Wait a minute, you're talking
about a soldier, right?
Yes.
Captain Ram.
- What are you saying?
- I think she likes you.
Who?
Who else? The doctor.
Shut up.
She might have seen guns
and bazooka only in films.
She saw everything.
Really?
What can I say? I'm
crazy about him!
I fell madly in love with him!
- You hide so many things!
- Hey!
Stop it already.
- He got a wicket in his first ball.
- Leave it!
I love him.
But I have no idea
what to do ahead.
Go talk to her.
It's not that easy. I'll have to
find out what's in his heart.
- But when did I say that I love her?
- What's the need to tell?
Okay. I'll propose him
tomorrow in the morning.
Dr. Nandini, you look pinker
than this rose today.
I wanted to tell you
something since many days.
I love you.
Excellent! Your pair looks
like rose and it's thorns!
Dr. Harish, Nandini
is calling you.
- I'm coming!
- All the best!
Thank you! Nandini!
Doctor Harish, he
has high fever..
- ..but I gave him back pain's medicine.
- Don't worry.
I've got the syringe.
He'll be normal in
just two hours.
Harish!
You're a genius.
Thank you so much, Nandini! I
will inject such syringe always!
Are you crazy?
Am I sick that you're
giving me injection?
I've cured Nandini's
patient with an injection.
Have you seen your face? You
two have no connection.
Oh, shut up. We are
meant to be couples.
Nandini is a doctor.
So, am I a plumber? I can even
treat sick cats and dogs.
First do your own treatment!
- "Gave my heart, gave pain.."
- Hello!
- She speaks English fluently.
- I can speak Kannada fluently!
Listen up.
What?
I will propose her like this..
"Listen to my heartbeat, I
chose you, you choose me too."
And she will choose me!
- Hi.
I can see a black pigeon
dancing on that mountain peak.
- Look there, Boss!
- You wanted to tell me something?
- Yeah, actually..
- Jai Hind, Sir.
Jai Hind.
- Actually..
- Jai Hind!
Jai Hind.
- Actually..
- Sir.
Okay, one second.
Sorry.
Actually, can I take
a selfie with you?
Why so?
You saved my life.
So I will tell people
that you saved my life.
Instead of my name, if you say Indian
Army helped you, then I'll help you.
I will be happy
I think he is now
your competition.
Are you on his side?
How can you say this?
- Boss, look at his height.
- He's big.
- But my heart is bigger.
- Boss, he's a hero.
If he's a hero, I'm
hero's father.
Look at his strong body, Boss.
- He's strong..
- So?
I have a long black tar road.
I'm proud of our
country just like you.
I'm a proud of my country.
By the way, do you
know our national song?
Vande Mataram.
Can you sing?
Yes.
Sing.
Actually, I used to sing it
on stage in school every day.
- Okay. Sing.
- Now?
Yes, why not? Begin.
"Vande Mataram!"
(Mother, I praise thee!)
It's okay. Give me your phone.
Come.
Nationalism and selfie,
are two different things.
Nothing, sir.
Excuse me.
- Hi.
- Hi!
Can you please stand up?
Okay.
What is it?
Harish!
Nandini makes an entry, my
heart jumps with excitement.
Ding-dong-ding! Hold
this, I'll be back.
I'm coming!
What is it, dear?
Can you get that stone here?
Please?
Nandini. Oh, yes..
There's no need to say thanks.
It is to be said to strangers.
But I'm yours.
Wish me luck, okay!
Yes?
"Vande Mataram!"
"Rich with thy hurrying streams,
bright with orchard gleams,"
"Cool with thy
winds of delight,"
"Dark fields waving
Mother of might,"
"Vande Mataram!"
Nandini doesn't even move a
stone without my permission.
I'm a nationalist too.
Do you believe now?
Your voice is sweet.
Actually, singing was my
hobby since school days!
I couldn't sing that day because
you asked me out of the blue.
Infact I've got many
awards too for singing.
One selfie..
- We did take one yesterday,right?
- No!
I posted that one
yesterday in Facebook.
We look so good!
Look at the likes!
Our pair looks
amazing, doesn't it?
Who wrote this comment?
I think it was about me..
- Harish!
- Yes, Nandini?
- Was it about me?
- I'll see you soon!
Yeah, I'm coming!
- Jai Hind, Sir.
- Congratulations!
Congratulations on your wedding!
- Marriage?
- Yes.
- Whose?
- Your.
With Dr. Nandani.
Right. My marriage
is in Bangalore.
I'm going to book ITC
Garden or Hotel Taj.
Wow!
- I've invited friends.
- Okay.
There will be food, vegetarian and
non-vegetarian, and cocktail party.
And of course, North Indian
style Punjabi food for you too!
- Wow! That's brilliant.
- Amazing!
When did you do all this arrangement?
Tell us.
You will do the
arrangement, why would I?
You're so funny!
- Is the wedding confirmed?
- Captain..
- ..there's a letter for you.
- Yes.
It's here! The love-letter from
the neighbour tent is here!
Now both of them will
play Doctor-doctor!
- Thank you.
- Jai Hind, Sir.
What's written?
Read loudly, Sir!
Let us know what's in it!
What happened?
- He's so quiet!
- I can't wait to know what's in it!
I think it's really romantic.
- Tell us!
- Read it!
I'm reading it, have patience!
Read it already!
Your brother is no more!
Start Immediately
Uncle!
My father!
What happened?
It's clear.
He committed suicide.
My brother was a rival to none.
And he wasn't a coward
that he commit suicide.
What happened?
Ram, I know you two
were very close.
I understand.
He was my sister's husband.
I was present during
the investigation.
Let's be practical, Ram.
It's useless to
complicate things..
Being his younger brother, I have a
right to know what happened to him.
If I be practical..
I'm not requesting
you, I'm asking you.
What happened?
Sir, we have court's orders. We
have to demolish this building.
The officer that messes with
me, is never seen again.
If any of you have even
a tiny bit of courage..
then demolish it.
We won't do it, Sir. But our new
Commissioner won't spare you.
Who's that joker?
You must have seen stars
only on police's uniform..
but stars favour his luck.
Injustice shivers at his name.
He's the icon of justice.
Who're you?
There no need to give
you my introduction.
You have no capability
to know who I am.
But you don't know who I am.
You're that goon who snatches lands
and makes buildings on the same.
I'll transfer you to such a place where
you won't even get water to drink.
Step forward, if you dare.
Run!
Hey? Hey! Are you mad?
What are you doing?
Hey! You want to kill me?
Hey, if you can have so much pride
by being in power for five years..
then imagine how much pride I would have,
being in the powerful post for 58 years.
- Come, Inspector.
- Sir.
Obstructing Government
officers' duties..
and for the crime of
threatening them, arrest him.
Are you mad? Reconsider.
One reconsiders when
he does a wrong thing.
It takes no reconsideration
to do the right.
- I won't spare you!
- Hey!
I'm an Administrative officer,
not some sage.
I'll kill you if
you mess with me.
- Officers.
- Sir.
- Demolish the building.
- Okay, Sir.
After some days, that
corporator got out of jail.
And created a ruckus
outside your house.
Get out! Aren't you a man?
Mom!
Let me go!
Hey! You'll regret it.
I will destroy you
and your family!
Your brother was
very hot-tempered.
So he went to the corporator's
house for revenge.
He was really angry.
He shot him with the
corporator's own gun.
He was arrested
because of murder.
I bailed him out,
and got him home.
And the very next day..
He committed suicide.
Look it's a clear case of suicide.
Police investigation has ended.
Post-mortem report tells us the same.
What do you think?
This is a murder, not a suicide.
Stop being unrealistic.
You're being over-emotional.
The entire room was
full of evidences.
- What do you mean?
- Evidence number 1...
In my brother's personal room..
..I could still smell weed from
the curtain beside the table.
That means whoever came into the room,
his height might be 6'2" or 6'3".
Evidence number 2, the
bean bag in his room.
It looked as if a heavy or
a tall person sat on it.
That means the killer's
weight must be around 100kg.
Brother didn't like dust and that's
why he always kept his window open.
Even if he had sat..
..it's impossible for the bean bag
to have such a big impression.
Evidence number 3...
..tell me did you find any
fingerprints on my brother's computer?
According to reports, none.
- Why?
- Impossible.
I couldn't find brother's
fingerprints as well.
That means killer used
gloves to use the computer..
and wiped away all
the fingerprints.
Last evidence is the rope
around my brother's neck.
Did you notice the knot?
Whoever tied it,
was left-handed.
Whereas, my brother
was right-handed.
How could I commit
such a big mistake?
I think they missed all
of this on purpose.
I'm not blaming your department.
But it's very difficult to conceal an IAS
officer's murder without police's aid.
Ram.
I'll investigate this
case personally.
Inform the forensic department
as soon as possible..
I'm reinvestigating
the Satyamurthy case.
I need the names of all the
criminals with height 6'2"-6'3".
- Excuse me.
- Yes, Sir?
Where can I find Dr. Ravindra?
There's his office.
- There?
- Yes.
Tell me.
Ram has come to meet Dr.
Ravindra.
- I want to meet Dr. Ravindra.
- Actually Ravindra Sir is..
He is on leave for many days.
Oh my God!
He's here!
- You guys go!
- Okay.
Hi!
- Hey.
- How come you're here?
I was here to meet Dr. Ravindra.
Oh. So did you meet him?
No, he's on leave.
What? Dr. Ravindra is on leave?
Someone lied to you.
- Oh.
- I know where he is, come.
I'll take you there.
I told you so. You'll
find him here.
Hi, Doctor.
He's the younger brother of
IAS Officer Satyamurthy.
He wants to meet you.
I want to speak to him privately.
Can I?
- Of course.
- Thank you.
Yeah.
May I sit?
Thank you.
I read the post-mortem
report of my brother..
..IAS Officer Satyamurthy,
which you made.
What about it?
Nothing.
If someone hangs himself
to commit suicide..
..there's always a 'V'
mark on his neck.
If someone else does that
forcibly, there's an 'O' mark.
There's an 'O' mark
on my brother's neck.
The report's true, isn't it?
What do you mean?
Anyone would tell me anything
and I'll change the report?
When did I say that? You
said that yourself.
Listen, use your brain on the
border for you're an army officer.
There's no need to lecture
me about anything.
This report has been made
after the post-mortem.
If you think there's any problem,
go and report the police.
I have no time for
your nonsense.
You may leave.
You said a lot without
saying anything.
I'll return soon.
"Hebbuli!" (Ferocious Tiger)
"Hebbuli!"
- The pigeon flew away!
- Shut up.
Where are you flying to?
- Did you talk to him?
- Yes.
- I think something's wrong, Boss.
- Hey!
Stop saying 1947 dialogues.
I thought this friendship would have
got martyred on the border itself.
But look at his daring, Boss.
He even came to the hospital.
You think so negatively.
This is a hospital. He must have
come to cure his stomach ache.
I think Fortune is
not on your side.
He looks like Superman.
And you say that he's a patient?
Can I have your number?
Boss, she's taking his number!
I don't use a phone. Sorry.
Your home address, residence
number, anything?
I'm going to shift
to another place.
You're so innocent!
It starts with chatting, moves
on to meeting and then wedding.
Then he'll pick her up, and drop
her from and to home respectively.
And then after marriage..
Don't forget to give me your
address after you shift.
- Yeah. Sure.
- Thanks.
My heart's desires
flowed away in tears?
- Bye!
- Bye.
Don't forget.
I spared him for he's a
young Indian soldier..
..otherwise I would have
destroyed his youth.
Mom!
Why are you crying?
What happened, dear?
Was Dad a bad man?
Who told you?
My friends are saying so.
Ritu, come here.
Come. Sit.
- Who knows your Dad the most?
- Me.
Right? Who else?
- I don't know.
- Don't know?
Me.
You must not know him
that well like I do.
Oh, I don't.
Okay, so you know him, right?
Was he a bad person?
No, right? Then don't worry.
Okay, don't worry.
He always used to
fight for justice.
He used to punch his
enemies and put them down.
Your Dad was a great man.
Like Superman?
Superhuman!
Never think wrong about him.
Sister-in-law, I can understand
what you're going through.
Please, Sister-in-law.
Was brother ever worried
about anything?
Think and tell me.
Was he under anyone's pressure,
or was he tensed about anything?
I just know about the
driver's daughter.
- Hello, Madam.
- Hello.
I'm sorry, I am late because I
took my daughter to the hospital.
You're right on time, Shankar.
Right?
He could've come even later.
You both talk, I'll get coffee.
Come, dear! Come to me.
Go, dear.
I heard you went
to the hospital?
I am unwell since
last night, uncle.
She has fever but
she's fine now.
Why are you looking around?
Why is our house so small,
and yours so big, uncle?
Shut up! Sir is an officer that's why.
Understood?
Why are you scolding her?
You want a bigger house? Why?
Our house is enough only for
my father, mother and me.
Whenever my friends come over for my
birthday, there's no space for them.
If you study hard and
become an officer like me..
..you'll have a bigger
house than mine.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Tell me, do you want to study?
- Yes!
Great!
Dad, did you hear
what uncle said?
If you study hard and become
an officer like him..
..we'll have a bigger
house than his.
Then we will celebrate your birthday,
Mom's birthday and my birthday..
at our home only, right, Dad?
Yes, dear!
Then, one day, we got news that Shankar
committed suicide along with his family.
- His daughter had cancer!
- Cancer?
She was in the final stage.
He couldn't repay the loan
he took for her treatment.
And he committed suicide for
he couldn't save his daughter.
He was very upset about
Shankar and his family.
He thought that Shankar
took this step since..
..he had no money
for her treatment.
He loved Shankar's daughter as his own.
And he constantly thought about her.
Dad, I've heard that poor people
can't survive if they get cancer..
Who told you this?
I heard Aunt Kamla saying this.
It's not like that, and I found out that
her treatment was not done properly.
- But why?
- Her poverty was the cause of her death.
That means Aunt Kamla was right.
If poor people get cancer,
they can't survive.
Stop listening to such
things and go to play.
Okay.
I don't know what happened
to him after that.
He used to stay in his room for
hours, working on the computer.
One day, when he wasn't home..
The corporator entered our
house and threatened us.
When I told him this,
he got very angry.
And he went to his
house in wrath.
The next day, police
arrested him as they..
..found him guilty of
killing the corporator.
He was fired from the job.
My brother bailed him
and got him home.
He looked quite
upset after that.
Have food.
You won't ask me anything?
I can read your mind even
if you don't say anything.
I didn't kill him.
You're the icon of justice.
I know you did nothing.
But whose life is
free from troubles?
It will be alright
someday, let's go.
I want to tell you something.
Have food first, talk later.
He sat there till
we were not asleep.
After that he went
to his study room.
The next morning when I entered
in his room with coffee..
He wanted to tell me something..
but I didn't listen to him.
- Isn't it cute?
- Sister-in-law..
Hi!
Surprise!
You? Here?
You both talk, I'll get coffee.
Okay, Sister-in-law.
Sister-in-law, did
you see my phone?
Is this your phone?
- No. Why?
- Then this?
How did you get my phone?
Why did you lie to
me about your phone?
Okay, I forgive you.
Your phone is outdated, that's
why I got a new one for you.
It's the latest model!
With unlimited talk time.
Thank you, but I'm
happy with my old one.
It's rude to refuse
things given out of love.
I said I don't want it.
Poor girl! She bought it for
you out of so much love!
- She'll feel bad if you don't take it.
- No, I..
Sister-in-law said so.
You'll have to keep it.
I've saved your new number.
- But, I need my old phone..
- Have coffee.
Thank you!
Sit!
Coffee was amazing!
You must be late?
Thanks for coming.
I'll come again!
- Bye!
- Bye.
See you soon.
Thank you.
I have downloaded Facebook
and Whatsapp on your phone.
I have uploaded our
photo to Facebook also.
I have stored my number too.
- Do call me.
- Yeah.
- Bye.
"Hebbuli!"
We are investigating all left-handed
criminals of height 6'2"-6'3".
Sir, all these people have no
connection with the murder.
We have evidence. They were not present
there when the murder happened.
And every person from Shivaji Nagar
except Faiyaz Ali are present here, Sir.
If everyone are here, why isn't he?
Get him right away!
We are trying our best.
I don't want such excuses,
just get him here.
- Get him here already!
- Okay, Sir.
'Faiyaz has been killed',
someone put up such a poster!
Hey, who's that?
Matching...
Left hander.
Hesitation...
Perfect match!
- May I talk to him for a minute?
- Hey!
How dare you talk like that?
Hey, who're you?
What's your blood group?
O+ve.
Who all have O+ve
blood group here?
You two, come this side,
he'll need blood.
May I talk to you now?
Hey, how dare you
threaten us in our area?
Who're you, Mr. Over-smart?
- What did you say?
- How dare you..
I'm standing in your area unarmed and
alone and you're talking about daring?
Rats change their area
after the tiger's entry.
"Hebbuli!"
Hey, handle him!
Hey! Take care of him!
Why don't you all help me?
This handsome, strong, young man is Kabir.
Business, trade..
He handles the all the
illegal businesses.
He is peaceful to those
who agree to him.
The one who rebels, is
sent to hell by him.
I hate two kinds of people.
Those who don't listen to me,
and those who betray me.
Do or die?
I'll go underground
for a year, Boss.
I told you never to show
me your dirty face again!
Someone killed Faiyaz Ali from
Shivaji Nagar before the enquiry.
- Hello, Sir?
- Yes, I got it.
I'm coming.
I think somewhere he's connected
to your brother's case.
By the way, CBI will
handle his case now.
I thought you should know.
Did you ever see this logo?
I searched all over Google,
internet, couldn't find it.
Do you have any idea?
I think I have seen it.
- Yeah?
- Yes.
Did you ever see him?
Anywhere?
No.
But I have the logo somewhere.
Photo?
Newspaper?
Television ads? Memes?
No, no. Wait.
I think..
You think?
I guess..
I have seen it on the
road I come from.
Let's go.
Now?
Why, are you busy?
Sorry, I didn't ask you.
No.. Hey!
Here.
Hello?
Hi, I'm out right now.
I'll call you back, okay?
- I wanted to become a doctor for Nandini.
- Oh!
Just see how I surprise Nandini
on her birthday today!
Great, Boss.
It's over, Boss.
Hey, is it necessary that a boy and a
girl are lovers if they're on a bike?
Can't they be siblings?
Nowadays siblings can't roam freely
just because people like you!
Look! It's that logo.It's
the logo of a gym.
They have two branches, one in
Malleshwaram and other in Jayanagar.
If the logo's here, there's definitely
some connection with the gym.
Hey, Sweety. Thank you for calling
but I'll call you back, alright?
Thanks, bye.
Are you free tomorrow morning?
Why?
You can keep an eye on this branch and
I will do the same on the other one.
I meant you can keep a watch on one
branch and I can on the other.
No problem, you may pick it up.
It's fine.
In fact, I brought you here
without your consent..
Sorry, you can continue.
No, it's my birthday.
Thanks.
I want to tell you something.
If you don't mind.
Are you going to propose me?
Sorry.
What do you think? I won't understand
that you love me even if you don't tell?
I'm not that dumb or insensitive.
I know.
But you should know one thing, I have
other important things in my life too.
My aim doesn't let me think
about such things in my life.
I don't know when
all this will end.
And on top of it, I don't want
to put your life in danger.
I want you to look for your
life's happiness elsewhere.
Now may I say something?
Sure.
I can understand the relation
between you and your brother..
those emotions and
your aim very well.
In fact, I did not share
my feelings with you.
Probably, if I were in your place,
I would have said the same.
You told me to look for
my happiness elsewhere.
Of course, this is my happiness.
With you.
Just like I am respecting
your feelings..
you should do the same
for mine as well.
By the way..
You said so many
things till now..
but you didn't say even once..
that you don't love me.
- Let me tell you a great joke.
- Go ahead, Boss.
I'm busy right now,
I'll tell it later.
Right here.
- Because that gym's branch is here also.
- Okay.
- Take care.
Nandini! Give me your phone.
I'm tracking your GPS.
Keep this in your pocket.
Did you see, Boss?
Why are you putting
oil to the fire?
- Bye.
- Take care.
Don't you understand what I say?
Think positive.
Every friend is necessary.
Pay the bill or you'll
have to do the dishes.
Hi, Workout's over?
Yeah.
- Sir, tea.
- Thank you.
- Yes, tell me.
- Hi.
I wanted to ask about
the membership.
Advance is Rs. 5000..
- You have to pay Rs. 3000 every
consecutive month. - Okay.
Right now, we are
offering a discount.
Thank you.
The man we're looking for, who has a
tattoo on his hands, is in this gym.
- I'm coming.
- Okay, come fast.
Excuse me, please.
- Madam, what did you do?
- Sorry.
Keep it back.
Hello? There's a girl
who's following me.
Get some men and come
into the factory.
Great, brother. A girl is
giving you attention..
..and you called us here
to play the gooseberry?
- Excuse me?
- Brother!
Brother, doll starts talking.
for you.
I need to make a call.
Is it to your boyfriend?
Do you think your boyfriend would come
and bash us the moment you call him?
And save you too?
Is your boyfriend some hero?
Just one call, please.
Okay, just one.
But on one condition.
We will just wait 2 minutes
for your hero's entry.
If he doesn't come, you'll
have to do as I say.
Yes.
What? Isn't he picking up?
I think he's busy.
I don't care about all that.
The time limit I
gave you is over.
- Ten.
- Nine.
- Eight.
- Seven.
- Six.
- Five.
- Four.
- Three.
"Hebbuli!"
Who are you?
He's my hero.
May I talk to you for a minute?
When a jackal wants to die,
he comes to the tiger.
Shut the shutter.
Let's finish him.
Don't do this, or
you'll regret it.
Why? You'll beat us?
Normally, I don't beat anyone, but
when I do, he becomes abnormal.
"Hebbuli!"
Now may I talk for a minute?
You don't know them!
They're very dangerous.
Listen to me, go away!
Who?
If they find out, they'll kill
me as well as you! Just go away!
Who?
- Why doesn't he understand me?
- Who?
They'll kill my family,
don't you understand?
Who?
Hey, why can't you understand?
They'll destroy my family.
They are not humans!
They are beasts!
Hey!
- Ranveer?
- Yes, Captain Ram?
Note a number.
Tell me, Sir.
I need the call
details right now.
Yes, Sir. On it.
Mail me about it as
soon as possible.
Okay, Sir.
Yes, Captain Ram?
- Ranveer?
- Sir.
I need the exact location
of these numbers.
Call on it with your
private number.
Record the call and make a voice match.
Try to find out who he is.
Okay, Sir.
Yes, Ranveer.
I have found his location, Sir.
It's latitude 13.0441 degree north.
Okay.
And voice match?
The voice match is
also found, Sir.
Who is it?
Yes, okay.
Will it be done?
Yes, don't worry
it will be done.
Did I tell you to sit?
Sorry, Sir.
Then why are you standing?
Have a seat.
Saturn's anger, since 9 years.
My clothes are black but
heart is pure as white.
Hail the lord!
Tell him.
Sir, the thing is..
His father has many
colleges and hospitals.
After his death,he's
here to settle the
property dispute between
him and his brother.
He has no share in it!
What about my share?
What?
Are you deaf? What
about my share?
Rs.500 million from my side.
I'll give you 100 million more.
But the dispute will be cleared, right?
Thank you, Sir.
I'm happy to meet you. I can
never forget your favour.
What's my brother doing here?
You were planning to
kill me, weren't you?
Why are you here?
What's happening here?
Tell me why did you come?
- This is my father's property!
- I made the business grow!
50% of the property is mine!
- No, 25% is enough.
- Calm down, you two.
I'll kick you out!
Hey!
Why you are all shouting?
Come and have a sit, please.
Would you like to have coffee?
Hey, get it.
Get some coffee.
What? You transferred
900 millions of my
1000 millions property
to your daughter!
You should have thought
a thousand times
before coming to the
cunning Anjanappa.
If Saturn's anger increases,
everything destroys!
Everything's over.
Don't do such injustice
with us, Sir.
Listen to me, Sir.
This is our hard-earned money.
Please, Sir!
Don't do this to us, or
we'll be in trouble.
This is wrong, Sir.
Look, Sir. I had come to
you with a lot of hope.
We'll be destroyed if you do this!
Please, Sir.
If you sign it, then only
you'll go home. Else..
Hail the Lord!
Don't even think
that you are safe.
I could have killed you
right now if I wanted.
Who're you?
IAS Satyamurthy's brother.
You killed my brother. And I
will surely avenge his death.
You can't do anything
without evidence.
What evidence do you have?
After my brother's death..
..I received a call from the
same number he had received.
I have recordings of
everyone who call me.
I didn't call you to
give you any proof.
But to tell you that I have
made an entry in your life.
Your days are numbered!
Who are you?
Pick up the phone!
Do you know what happened here?
What happened?
He started firing at my house
and is threatening me!
Who is he?
IAS Satyamurthy's brother,
Para Commando Ram!
Owner of the Shah Industries
and Shah empire, Amruth Shah.
He made a big mistake
coming there.
From today, forget one step, he
won't even be able to move an inch.
Let's put an end.
Do anything you want, but fast!
Britishers, get out
of my country!
India is great! Jai Hind!
I found his vehicle, I think he's
inside the school auditorium.
Find him quickly, and
shoot him at sight!
Hello. My name is Ritu. I'm Satyamurthy
and Anuradha Satyamurthy's daughter.
All parents teach good
manner to their children.
I will always remember
one thing my Dad said..
One reconsiders when
he does a wrong thing.
But it takes no reconsideration
to do the right.
Alas! My Dad is not
with me anymore.
I miss him very much.
I will study hard and become
a collector when I grow up.
And I will help
people free of cost.
Dad will always be
with me if I do this.
Dad, your princess will always go on the
right path and become an honest officer.
I love you, Dad.
Is she your daughter?
No, she's his
brother's daughter.
Is he your husband?
How many kids do you have?
Not one yet. It's too early.
Really? In your age I
had four healthy kids!
You should start. Motherhood
is a pride for every woman.
I was lying. I'm unmarried yet.
So what? Get married quickly
and do some family planning.
To be honest, your children
would look very beautiful!
Bye, uncle!
A Para commando can never miss his shot.
He could have killed you.
But he didn't do that.
He was right. He shot the cup on purpose.
What's his aim?
What does he want from us?
Why is he doing this?
Is anyone else supporting him?
Or is he trying for
some evidence?
probably..
he wants to reach to me.
Call Kabir.
Any news?
He's drinking tea at
a roadside-stall.
Drinking tea?
Is he drinking tea?
He's setting a trap..
He's setting a trap.
He's setting a trap!
Call Kabir again! Tell him
to run away from there!
What happened?
- He's not picking up!
- Try again!
Try again!
Hello? Here.
Kabir, get out of
there right now!
I said get out right now,
I'll explain later! Move!
He is messing with us!
He's playing with our minds.
I won't spare him.
Boss, you are looking
like a hero in this suit!
I'll say 'I love you' to her today.
She'll become flat at hearing it!
All the best.
Come.
Nandini..
She's coming. You sit.
Boss! Wait.
What happened, Boss?
The soldier won the
battle of love too.
She loves that army man!
Love is not for a loser like me! I'm
going to station to board a train.
- Ouch!
- Oh God!
- Sorry.
- Wait, I'll pick it up.
She's Nandini as well?
Your name is Nandini?
Yes. And your name?
Preetham!
She turned! Yes!
Here. Go to advocate and change
my name to Preetham from Harish.
Boss, you'll change your
name again for this girl?
If I can become Harish
from Timmegowda for her..
Can't I become Preetham
from Harish for her?
My heart is playing guitar
the second I saw her.
What about her?
She's the past.
And her?
She's the future!
I'm coming, my dear!
Now who will explain that he
looks Preetham(idiot) by face?
- That way.
- Okay.
What do you want, Sir?
Ha! Kabir!
Hello!
May I know who's on
the line,Please?
May I know who you are.
Are you scared to
tell who you are.
Captain Ram
Good to know my name.
Your partner has entered
your name as "Boss"
That does't mean,I can't extract
the real facts from your partner.
All the best.
In my life, I've faced
many people like you.
You've seen many people like
me but you've not seen me.
I'll meet you as
early as possible.
You're making a big mistake!
Who're are you?
You know who I am.
And you know what I want.
Are you threatening me?
What can you even do?
Your brother, being a
officer, could do nothing.
If you think I'll get scared..
then this is your
biggest mistake.
When you have decided
to stay shut..
there's no point in
keeping you alive.
Hey!
Hey, are you crazy?
You're commiting a big mistake!
You're not aware of this.
Leave me!
Oh God!
Wait, don't kill me!
Wait! Don't kill me!
I said wait!
This all began with..
Generic medicine.
Driver's daughter got cheap treatment and
his entire family committed suicide.
Your brother was gravely
affected by this.
Being a doctor, he tried
to solve this problem.
And he did a lot of research.
He caught up with his old batch
mates and created a report.
Sir, Government data tells us..
..that millions of people die
because of expensive treatment.
There's only one way to lower
this number, generic medicine.
Generic means general.
General means for everyone.
Whenever there's a new disease, the
doctors try to discover the cure.
Big companies lead in this race.
And they patent that
cure on their name.
But such brands' medicines
are very expensive.
The common man can't
even think to afford it.
Generic medicine has the same quality,
it has the same effect on the patient.
When the patent is removed, any company
can make that medicine with the formula.
That means the cost
can be lowered.
If cancer treatment costs
Rs.0.2 million a month..
then generic medicine would
cost only Rs.10,000 per month.
Think, a poor man would
benefit so much from this.
If the medicine's cost
would become so low..
then what about the
quality & the company?
Our country is called as 'the
pharmaceutical hub of the world'.
India supplies 50% to 60%
of generic medicine.
If the quality were poor, then America,
Japan, and other countries of the world..
would not purchase
medicines from India.
You say that India supplies generic
medicines to many countries..
and the quality is good too, then why
isn't it in use in our country yet?
Sir, in the year 2008,
Indian Government initiated the
'Jan-Aushadhi Campaign' (Medicine for all)
If this scheme were just a plan in
the paper, and were not executed..
medicines for small illnesses like
cold and fever would have been costly.
Big pharmaceutical firms
have used such strategy..
that the medicines
have become costly.
I say, generic medicine should be
available for both urban and rural poor.
If health care is Government's aim, it
should also aim to provide it cheap.
And there's only one solution. Cheap
medicines, that is generic medicine.
You prepare this proposal right away.
I'll get its approval.
Minister Anjanappa took that report and
made a business deal with my boss.
Thank you!
He gave Minister Rs.1 billion..
Big Brother Kuldev! How are you?
AMRUTH SHAH, President of
Pharmaceutical Association of India.
Why did you call me here?
I want you to forget the
generic medicine project.
Listen to me, company
is giving me shares..
If you want, I can
make you rich too!
Hey! You're second grade fail
then also people voted for you..
..and gave you the post..
And you don't even care a
bit about those people?
Sir, you're getting me wrong.
I'm not doing this Generic
medicine project for money.
I'm doing it for
welfare of people.
There's nothing in this world
which can't be bought.
Everything has a price.
What's your price?
It would be better to reduce the
cost of medicines than bribing me.
People would bless you.
Most of the Indians
believe in family values.
Now a days, it's
slowly decreasing.
When parents get old,
children leave them.
Brothers have disputes.
They get separated.
There was no love in life, if love is
there, there is no money for treatment.
Today's condition is so bad that people
want to die quickly than slowly.
They think it's better to save the
money spent on their treatment.
Great observation. People will surely
get a benefit. But what will you get?
I'll get the satisfaction
of doing a good deed.
Honest people like you are
begging on the streets today.
Reconsider.
One reconsiders when
he does a wrong thing.
It takes no reconsideration
to do the right.
I've studied on the street and become a
doctor and an Administrative officer.
I won't back away without protests
on the same street again.
I will make you accept the
generic medicine project.
You will regret putting
this deal down!
Whatever be the consequences,
I'm ready to face it.
Okay. Good enough.
Bye.
Sir, there's a bad news.
Someone along with IAS Satyamurthy
is conspiring against us.
We have to do something, Sir.
When your brother tried
to destroy our empire..
we bailed the
corporator to kill him!
And then everything
happened as per our plan.
Wait!
Sir? Sir!
Hey, wait!
After your brother
was sent to jail..
we thought he would
forget this out of shame.
But it didn't happen that way. So at the
night of the day he was bailed out..
How are you, collector? Oh!
You're not a collector anymore!
Satyamurthy, have you called
to get your job back?
You can only snatch my job with your
wit and power, but not my degree.
This is the power of education.
Don't think that it's all over.
The project will be executed!
Calm down! There's no
need to get so excited!
We placed false case against you to
stop you from completing the project.
I made you get arrested, fired you
from your job and embarrassed you.
Now stop being so
stubborn, Satyamurthy!
Listen, this is our area. Our
power is exercised here.
Area might be yours
but the law isn't.
Who are you to embarrass me?
Just wait and watch. I'll pull you
in court and strip you naked.
Satyamurthy, court wants evidence!
Not your stupid lecture!
That's why I called you.
What do you mean?
Do you think I called you for weather news?
Everything is being recorded.
There's no point in being
silent now, Minister.
- Shut up!
- The call has already been recorded.
Get lost!
I have got so many
evidences for the court.
You go inside!
Your speech is recorded.Let
us meet in the court.
Then it was decided
to end your brother.
Who said that you have become old?
Just have a look at this first.
If you give me your project's documents
and hard disk data, I'll leave.
If you delay even a minute, your
wife and daughter are finished.
You have just given me
one terabyte data..
But what about the 100
terabyte data in your mind?
I'll have to crash
it too, right?
The generic medicine project
ends with your death.
The man might die,
but the truth won't.
It's just the beginning.
Beginning of your end.My son
"Ram" will come to you!
Sister-in-law?
People work hard to
improve their life..
..but your brother gave
up his life for them!
He never harmed anyone in his life.
And they..
They killed him!
Ram!
What did you do? Are you crazy?
Just a minute..
It's bleeding.
I'll get the bandage.
Ram?
I can understand what
you are going through..
..but by punishing those
people and taking revenge..
..your brother won't
come back, will he?
Sister-in-law, two days are
very important in life..
One when we are born, and the other
when we find out our life's aim.
Today, I promise you..
I won't let my brother's
work go waste.
You are right. He won't come back
even if I take revenge on them.
But I'm not such a good human
that I'll forgive them.
Firstly, I'm here to see
the fear in your eyes.
Secondly, to show you
the trailer of death.
You made two big mistakes.
Firstly, betraying your country..
And secondly, murdering my brother.
You'll get punished for both!
You might have killed my brother, but
his dream. And I will finish it.
What will you do?
You should have figured what I can
do when your brother went missing.
You have messed with a soldier who
fights on the border for his country!
No matter how good
the enemy is..
..he doesn't hesitate for
a moment to shoot him.
Nor he pities anyone.
You are the traitors of our land!
You have betrayed it!
You had enough fun, but your
death will be a horrible one.
So horrible that your
soul will shiver!
Your soul will shiver with fear!
Yes, Ram.
Sir, I found out who
killed my brother and why.
See, I can understand
your feelings.
And I know what
you're capable of.
Just don't take a wrong
step in a hurry.We're with you.
Take care of yourself.
Okay.
Happy birthday RAAM.
Surprise!
Happy birthday, Ram!
Thanks.
Happy birthday, brother.
Oh, is it his birthday too?
I don't know when he was born.
He always celebrated my
birthday along with me.
Oh..
I don't want to come.
Why? Stop being so stubborn.
- Just come and cut the cake!
- Let's go.
If not for you, just cut the cake
for those who have come today.
Look, I don't know
when I was born.
I always celebrate my
birthday with my brother.
He's absent, that's why
I won't celebrate.
What happened?
Hello, Sister-in-law!
- Looking nice!
- Hi, uncle!
Hey! How are you?
I'm fine!
Ram, you said you won't come.
How all of a sudden?
- Why? Can't I come?
- It's good that you came.
- He said he won't celebrate without you.
- Who?
Your brother, who else.
He's being stubborn.
I'm here, so he
will come as well.
No chance. Just look
around for a second.
Ram!
I told you!
- Happy birthday to you!
- Happy birthday, dear brother!
Stay blessed.
Happy birthday to you!
Tasty! Enough. I'm full.
Aren't you full yet?
Oh, I forgot! I'm full too.
Are you two up to something?
- Yes. - What?
- No.
Shut up. I'll handle it.
Don't worry.
I'm full too.
Your sister made you
food with utter love.
Have as much as you
want and go to sleep.
You are over-acting from the
time your brother came.
No, nothing like that.
I'll be back.
- Hey!
My brother came back after so long!
I have so much to tell him.
- Why did you trap me and left me alone?
- You sit.
- I don't eat so much sweet.
- Eat it.
They left me here! I
won't spare them!
Brother always considered
me a part of him.
He was always with me
- Yes?
- What happened?
Sister-in-law!
- Ram!
- What happened?
Those people..
- They..
- Sister-in-law, tell me what happened!
- Ritu!
- Ritu?
Did you get it?
Sorry.
We don't want to
kill your daughter.
We like kids too.
But we love our life
more than that.
She's a fatherless girl,
please leave her alone.
She should also understand
why her father died.
It will be better if
you do what we say.
Else your daughter
will be killed.
Tell me, what do I have to do?
Good. You're smart.
But your husband was foolish.
Our car will come to
your house in an hour.
Tell Ram to sit in the car
with all the evidences.
Your husband committed suicide, and your
brother-in-law should have an accident.
The one who was to die a
martyr for his country..
will be killed on the road!
We made arrangements
to catch the tiger.
The moment he is caught..
your daughter will be sent home.
Ritu will come back.
Ram! If you go..
there will be..
no hope of you returning.
Sister-in-law, when one goes
to work he might return.
But when a soldier goes to work,
there's no hope of him returning.
Anything can happen
to him any time.
There's no idea when he dies.
When a person becomes a soldier, he's
ready to give his life for the nation.
If we can give up our life
for our nation's security..
can't I give up my life
for my family's security?
Every soldier, faces his enemy on
the battleground with courage.
The one stands by his family,
is a courageous soldier.
We're soldiers. Wherever we
are, in whatever condition..
we always wish for
our family's safety.
Ritu will certainly come back.
When she comes back,
give her this.
No matter how strong the enemy is,
our nation will overpower it.
I have full faith.
When Ritu grows up, she
will make our nation proud!
Greetings, Captain Ram.
Won't you talk about patriotism
or nationalism today?
Why are you quiet? Patriotism fell
short against family, didn't it?
I thought you would
come like a tiger..
..but you are standing in
front of me like a jackal.
Do you know what I
feel like saying?
Salute to your master!
Calls himself a patriot!
You're a politician, and you don't
know anything more about a soldier.
It's not your mistake. But
of those who elected you.
Stop your nonsense. People gave
me votes, and I won as well.
Listen to me carefully.
You will sit in that car,
have an accident and..
With that, you, your evidence and your
brother's project will go up in flames!
Hail the Lord!
- Mr. Ram.
- Yeah?
We have an arrest warrant against you.
Please cooperate.
We don't want to use any kind of force.
Please come with us.
We have got orders to arrest you and
take you to them. Come with us.
I need to talk for a minute.
Okay.
Thank you.
Don't even touch Ritu.
Why did he say so?
What happened? Has
the plan changed?
No. Did you reach
there to get him?
That's why I'm here!
But police came and took him away
saying he has court martial..
..they are handing him over to the army!
What's all this?
I don't know.
One thing's for sure.
Till we have the girl..
..he'll have to come.
- Sir..
- If there's any emergency..
..it's our duty to save her.
Your niece is the
citizen of our country.
It's our duty to save her.
Thank you, Sir.
- Jai Hind.
Sir, people from your
regiment will take over.
Thank you.
He called the minister
after your arrest.
- Location?
- I think it was here.
This tower is near
the Avenue Road.
He'll call again. Be alert.
Sir, he's calling him again.
Location?
I think near Avenue Road.
We are tracking
his GPS location.
Start tracking the number.
Pass this information
to the Home Minister.
Yes, Sir.
Hello?
Don't call now,
someone might notice.
Get a towel for the girl too.
Are you blind?
Here.
Everything fell!
"Hebbuli!"
Where's Ritu? Tell me!
Hello, do you think you're the
only intelligent in this world?
I drink the juice of intelligence
every morning, get it?
I trapped you in your own
plan, did you get it?
This is called
politics, my patriot.
You know what you've to do next.
Come.
Don't hit me!
Come!
Brother!
You also proved today that there's
no one more faithful than dogs.
My secret has been opened..
so you'll have to be closed.
Sorry.
I always told him to obey
the elders, but see..
Hail the Lord!
I got all the documents with
me, just like you said.
Now according to your
promise, let Ritu go.
I can understand the pain of
losing someone from the family.
Kill me, but let her go.
I won't kill you so easily!
You dared to interfere
in my business, right?
How dare you!
My future plans have already
spoiled because of you..
and you're looming
here as Death!
You troubled so much. Now you'll
understand who you messed with!
Here!
Your brother was an Administrative officer
and you're an Army Officer, right?
You could've lived your life
like a normal person, but no..
Both of the brothers were so
interested to become patriots!
You can show your strength
only on the border, not here.
If the poor die due to
diseases, let them die!
What will you do if
they remain alive?
Hey! People protest when
grocery's prices rise..
and they protest when
diesel's prices rise!
But do they protest when medicines
prices rise? No, right?
Because they're afraid of death!
The fear which is their weakness,
we exploit that in our business.
Generic medicine!
This was your brother's dream, right?
Now it has shattered.
Now it is impossible to fulfil.
Because this is my strategy
and no one can outsmart it!
Hey, tiger, you've turned
into a helpless cat!
Not angry yet? Want
me to feed you some?
We planned your
brother's murder!
We are the ones who killed
him as if it were a suicide!
Aren't you angry? Why
don't you get angry?
You can kill me if you want..
but let the the girl Ritu go.
I thought you were a tiger.
But you turned out to be a rat. Listen,
let him go! He's already dead.
What are you looking at?
End him!
Exhaust all the
ammunition on him!
He's no ordinary
man, but a tiger!
Ferocious tiger!
Oh no! I was right!
If a tiger is silent, it
doesn't mean he is tired.
That means he is
planning his attack.
I wanted your attention for
fifteen minutes. You know why?
I wanted to reveal your truth,
which the entire world just saw.
I was just faking it.
I want you to listen to something.
Listen carefully.
We soldiers give up our lives on the
border for your family's safety.
Whoever dares to
trouble our family..
You told that my niece was in your
possession. Just check it once.
No one's picking up, right?
No one will.
When a country's
soldier gets angry..
..he beats the country's
traitors into pieces!
You got help only to
carry out the project..
not to trouble people!
There's only one answer for you!
People try to save
each other's lives!
And you have established this as
an illegal medicine business!
Now the entire would will
know out your truth.
They made a big mistake
by making you win.
You'll give them medicine
only when they protest?
People like you are bashed on the road!
My brother's dream will come true.
I won't let any traitor
live peacefully!
My brother served people with
honesty and died for them!
This one's from my brother!
Hello, Commissioner. There's
just been a gang war.
All of them need to be
taken to the hospital.
We'll need ambulances! Send some to
the dock as quickly as you can! Fast!
See to it no one leaves from here.
Do it fast. The ambulances..
Mr. Anjanappa has been exposed!
He was doing an illegal
medicine business.
Mr. Anjanappa has been proven
guilty of IAS Satyamurthy's murder.
People have come on to
the roads for protest!
Ritu, have milk.
Mom, where's uncle?
When will he come?
You want to know where he is? He's
there where he should be. See.
"Hebbuli!"
This film is dedicated to
thousands of peaople who
can't afford medicines
and are dying everyday.