Do you want to hear my prognoses
for the next century?
Clocks will disappear
little by little,
as no one will be interested
in punctuality any more.
In architecture right angles
will be abolished,
because we will learn to let
buildings grow like plants.
Men will become women.
And women will be men.
Simply humans.
And enjoy the freedom of choice and
learn to do everything at the same time.
And Aids will be curable.
Will you marry Delveau?
As the woman at his side
I could accomplish anything.
No money troubles.
Lukas would go to the
best French schools.
That gave me the most to think about.
And Delveau had something which I liked.
I don't find him unsexy,
but I threw all that away.
I am totally crazy, huh?
Every time I thought of saying
'yes', it saddened me.
You don't love him, that's all.
I begin the new millenium without
work, without plans,
without money, without security.
They say that one day your
gaze turns backwards.
Your youth ends on this day.
But what was that, youth?
Was it the present or the future?
Only the future?
And the joyful present.
Had they instilled our youth into us
like a language or good manners?
'You who are young, to you belongs the world.'
But then, who do they belong to? Us?
The world? Us?
Before everything else, I
belonged to it, to the young.
To the helpless children of the '68
generation, to whom everything was permitted.
we, who from our fathers had the
choice to change anything,
but nothing to grab hold of.
It's a miracle.
And then this view of myself,
as I return from my friends
As I hug my child and before the window
at once the future ceases.
Behind me
the gifted child.
And in front of me, outside, in the light,
the new day, the new century
that is just beginning before my eyes,
the past.
The present looms like the top of an iceberg
on the sea of the past.
I have yesterday' eyes,
yesterday's hands.
My foolish sorrow is from yesterday.
Perhaps I am not yet born?
Logical, as before I was born,
everything was past.
Perhaps then the present...
perhaps then the present
once again arrives.
Where there is a place to build,
there begins life.
My architecture professor always said,
You need your tools,
your discipline,
a good plan,
Happiness follows behind.
The houses that we build,
will outlive us.
They are there so that one day
we will be carried out.
Feet first, as they say in Hunsrück.
But our shadows remain.
All those who live in a house
stay as shadows in the walls.
The shadows of the dead
are not in the graveyard.
Only we are there.
Sad,
that the gap gets ever wider.
Klara.
You can touch me anywhere,
but not on the forehead.
That makes me cry.
I don't know why that is.
But it is so.
Then I am scared that
she looks at me.
I find it exactly so.
In the school the teacher
is suddenly far away.
He opens and closes his mouth,
but no sound comes out.
So it was for me today in maths.
The soul doesn't recognise time.
It is our bodies which become older.
Time plays itself out in our bones.
In our faces. In our breathing.
From this we know what time is.
And that it washes us away, every day.
Paul, there you are!
We have been so worried.
How do you look?
We heard from the police
that you died at Boppard.
Child, you have a fever.
His head is very warm.
I knew it,
I knew it.
You didn't sleep at all last night.
Your face was white.
And you came out with such
impossible things.
Like Eduard would have come out with.
The featherbrain.
- Good Afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
- I want to see how Paul is.
- He's over there.
Good evening, Paul.
In a couple of days,
everything is back to normal.
Then will you come by
and build that radio?
Not only the old lie in the ground,
who have throw away their lives,
as a tree throws away its autumn leaves.
No,
age itself also lies there.
The skin.
How often has my form died back to renew itself.
Hans.
Not on the rubble,
that would break it.
Let him fly like in the spring instead.
- Yes mother, So when are we going?
- Now.
If the weight of the cells I
have shed from my skin
weighs three or
four times my weight,
How much would my lost thoughts weigh?
Then I came past and the road was ready.
In a year cars with hundreds
of things were driving past.
How much does the first glance
from the eye of a girl
who will one day become a woman?
How often must one molt
before one can fly?
How much time is passed?
Little brother, little sister.
Martha, are you crying?
No.
Yes you are.
No, Hermann, I'm not crying.
You're mistaken.
Of course you're crying.
Why this time?
Oh, Hermann.
I've been waiting so terribly long for you.
And waiting.
Do you know what that is, Herman?
To wait?
Yes.
In heaven, they speak the
Hunsrück dialect.
How could it be otherwise when
there are so many Simons up there.
Aunt Lucie, here. Come!
But, Lucie!
What are you up to then?
It's good that you came, Maria.
It was time that we talked.
But not here.
- Lucie.
- Why not?
I want to talk about death.
One can do that in any place.
In the fullness from the void.
In the essence from the appearance.
From the falshood to the truth.
from the darkness to the light.
from death into light.
From the the world into heeaven.
Amen.
Each of us is manifold.
In so far as each of us has lost many dreams.
With every dream we lose a body.
Hello Ernst.
- Hello.
- Good day.
- Ernst, wonderful that you have come already.
- Hello mother.
Come on, up now.
Don't trouble yourself with it.
The brute would have only brought you work,
and would have brought nothing in.
I wouldn't have brought anything more in either.
I asked myself often how memory worked.
Remembrance keeps only fragments and leftovers
which don't want to make a whole.
To remember, that means
to dig for fossils.
The true histories lie
deep under the earth.
Yeas, it's good.
Martha, I thought
mother was dead straight away.
Yes.
So, I think,
we have to call the police.
The dog had found a scent.
When the dog smells something,
it is no longer led astray.
The dog behaves strangely,
there must be somthing there.
Do you mean, the woman could lie there?
Look at what I've found.
That looks like a prehistoric snail.
It is at least 100,000 years old.
Neither of us was here,
but this snail was here already.
That isn't a snail.
It looks more like a May beetle.
When I look all around here,
this was all sea.
'Greetings from Migenne.
I wanted to visit my old friend Apollonia,
but she is not longer alive,
only little Gretel, her daughter.
I am well accommodated, and am coming back
to Schabbach on 07.10.1975.
Come and pick me up from the tour
bus in Kirchberg at 1.15 PM, mother.
I am bringing Gretel with me.''
Anton.
We're here.
I was worried that Gretel wouldn't
enjoy staying with us.
But she is enchanted with Hunsrück.
This is my Anton.
- Bonjour Monsieur.
- This is Martha. - Bonjour Madame.
You must know at last
where you come from.
Stop, Martha.
I can do what I want.
I am finally an adult.
You are my dainty Visavis.
That's what Otto always says to me.
Piece by piece
I must carefully excavate the rubble.
by remembering.
From the disordered fragments,
I put something together anew.
Remembering is a labour.
We build ourselves a landscape in our minds.
A second house in the clouds.
And hope that it is more durable than the first,
which turns to dust
on the ground below.
Look at the sky,
do you see it?
That would be great.
For me, it's not going well.
It's going badly now.
You could hear the fair until now.
- You've got a beautiful belly button.
- You've got a beautiful belly button too.
That is the gateway of life.
- Back then everything chopped and changed.
- Back then?
Before. At that time.
For once there are no more time-tables.
Time and logic
have ceased to rule us.
That makes me happy.
Myself again.
Goodbye, Hermann.
Hermann, what makes you run so?
- Good day, Aunt Lucie.
- He neither sees nor hears.
- Good day, Uncle Eduard.
- Help us with the cases.
- Edu, go on, but be careful.
- Okay.
Go on! We're going to the
holy rock. At Trier.
- Do we need to stay over, Lucie?
- Well, if we need to.
It should work miracles,
it's like Lourdes.
Not by the window, Eduard,
there's a draught.
Hermann.
- Have you come from school?
- Yes.
- How was it?
- Same as always.
You're in the sixth form now.
The techer has to say 'Sie' now.
Hermann, if only my
little Horst were still alive.
He got an 'A' in maths
just before he died.
- Yes, it's all haywire.
- Hermann, come.
I have to go. Goodbye.
- Do you know how Horst died?
- Yes, Aunt Lucie.
- I have to go.
- Hermann.
He was your age.
How he found the land mine
in the woods.
Oh well, my child, it's okay.
- My greetings to your mother.
- Okay.
Much simply stays as it is.
Always the same.
Only spiders settle down.
When I hit the anvil,
it breaks the stiffness.
Don't worry, it's only
briefly disturbed here.
Everything stays dead.
Nothing will be alive again.
only briefly a little noise.
When I strike the anvil,
I summon ghosts.
The ghosts of all those who have known
the sound of the anvil since childhood.
From the distance.
From the confusion of wars.
The armourers.
May I take the coat with me?
That my mother, when she
was my age, was older.
And that my grand mother,
when she was the same age
was even older ...
and when my great grandmother died,
she heard the same noise of the
anvil that my grandmother heard.
and they collected all of them around
them and had nothing more to say.
Men and animals appear to
live on different planets,
and yet, when they are
afraid, seem the same.
Ernst!
Ernst, where is it safer,
in the North or the South?
In the North, Hermann.
Definitely in the North.
Christine, do you know these things here?
These are 'Arschkratzele'.
'Arschkratzele'?
That my father changed his face,
when he could change it.
That he wa somethines older,
sometimes younger in his life,
when he was in love,
or changed his location.
Or, when he remembered,
or turned around.
One gets one's name from the house,
not the father, in Hunsrück.
Whoever came from the Simon-house, was a Simon,
regardless of who the father was.
and when the men went forth,
drawn into the war, or were unfaithful,
the house remained.
The house of many mothers.
Hermann, look here.
I have to show you something.
Look here.
This is the Simon-Journal.
We are more than 1,500 families.
- 1,500.
- All called Simon.
Do you not want to go in?
The soup is very good.
Glasisch ... look around now.
So many people.
They all came to honour Maria.
How was I to know that?
Glasisch, see those behind?
The foreigners.
Those are the relatives from Brazil.
They have come from America
and Paderborn.
- From Hamburg.
- Those are Martha's relatives.
- Where do your children study?
- ln Berlin, in Paris and in Mainz.
And they all came because of Maria.
- As if she was our mother.
- But she was as well!
Paul!
Glasisch.
- Now I want to know at last.
- What do you want to know?
What was it with that dead, naked
woman in the woods, in 1927?
Time doesn't heal every wound.
when all those who have done monstrous
things to one another are dead,
when they are all under the ground,
Then the mark of
the monstrous remains.
like the water mark,
which always returns.
A broken waterpipe is unlikely.
There are no water pipes in Schabbach.
Yes.
It must come from underground.
Tastes like spring water.
Is that really Schabbach water?
Herr Simon,
Thank God that you're here.
We were waiting for you.
A miracle has happened.
- What do you mean?
- A miracle.
Whoever has stayed their whole
life in Schabbach,
doesn't believe in miracles and ghosts.
That is because one knows and recognises
everything which one has faith in.
and what he doesn't.
Causes and effects are always
clear in the heimat.
Only the one who leaves,
who rips out his roots
the seeker, brooder und stormer of heavens,
the fearless enlightener
of all secrets,
they must beware of ghosts.
We won't let our Schabbach
become a circus!
'Our Schabbach',
I don't think I heard right.
We won't let ourselves be concreted over!
That would be the absolute end.
What time is it?
It's half one, Rudi.
Go back to sleep.
I'll say to the doorman,
Now I'm through.
- What are they doing at this time in the office?
- I don't know.
- Udo Trötsch?
- This is for you.
- Abolish the national anthem of the DDR?
- No.
You didn't come any more in the week,
so we won't count on you any more.
- Frau Wurz.
- You must know that.
That is our final word,
Herr Trötsch.
The business must finally continue.
- Notice of offences from the party training course.
- Take it away.
Honour, pride, heroism,
all ideals and utopias,
in which they believed in for 100 years,
went awry.
Everything, in which men believed,
changed into tobacco smoke
and the smell of bars.
Each has become his own memorial.
stands lost in the landscape, and asks
himself how the world would look without him.
When belief goes away,
there is nothing more to save.
NVA electrical equipment for various
purposes, power, and aircraft equipment.
munitions cases.
transportation cases for aricraft parts.
Around 450 engines for the T-55 tank.
Tyres for armoured
personnel carriers.
Gearboxes from T-55s.
Robur-LKWs
with various beam constructions
and water treatment plants.
Tank tracks for the T-54.
Little Zweibel jumped through the fields
and said: 'The world is round.'
Grandmother had always said
that when I wanted to run on.
From the heimat,
behind the red flashes of lightning.
There come clouds,
But father and mother
are long dead,
No one knows me there any more.
How soon, how soon,
will the quiet time come.
When I too shall rest.
There near me rustles the beautiful
Forest's loneliness.
The beautiful forest's loneliness.
And no one here shall know me anymore.
Wasn't that Peter?
A classmate.
We played music together.
Nothing is alien here.
I am alien.
Once I almost drowned in an inn
near here. There below.
I was seven.
But the green water
spat me out again.
My mother warmed me
endlessly in her arms.
Endlessly in her arms.
I never come back any
more to Wasserburg.
I have never understood
why we reproduce.
It would have never come into question
had I never had a child.
Now the story goes on,
without me having anything
to offer Lukas.
But how was it with the others?
with Ernst, who hoarded his
underground treasure for those to come,
who never were.
They all believed that the
future was something manageable.
Even the childless.
- Good evening.
- Christian Ballsegel, Maitre de Cuisine.
- Henri Delveau, Maitre d'Architecture.
I have a surprise for you.
- A recommendation?
- No.
I thought you lived in Wiesbaden?
My beauty studio is still there.
Only now I'm back in Hunsrück.
I always find my happiness here.
It must be in my stars.
We have a full house again,
but I hope it suits your French guest.
Good evening.
Lulu,
I'm the happiest woman in the world.
You could guess, and you're
the first I've told.
We're getting married in October.
Yes.
And then ...
Wait, I'll show you the pictures.
Here.
The pictures of Saint Petersburg.
We're opening a restaurant there.
Christian has a good enough
reputation to always stay employed.
A restaurant of the highest class,
that one respects,
every cook dreams of that.
Naturally I do too.
Is it near to the opera?
You know that? Do you know that
I grew up in Saint Petersburg?
Here, do you see?
Gold leaf on the roof.
In Brezhnev's time,
When the tourists came
for the olympic games.
I heard that Russia was hard up
because of corruption and the mafia.
You know, when we have a place
like that in that situation,
then we'll manage everything else.
You're only young once.
Especially as a woman.
True, Lulu?
Often I wake up and have the feeling
that everything has already happened.
The houses are all built,
The business all taken care of.
The couples have all coupled, and
the trees and the grass grew
and the children are grown up.
Only I lie heavy in my unfulfilled
hopes and am no longer needed.
Shit.
I thought it would outlive me.
But that it reckoned on
leave its ghost here.
Cable fire.
You can forget it.
Such a fuck up!
So, brother heart.
Now I am curious when
you last drunk.
Still a little cold.
But we have time.
That is something fine.
A '61 Château Lafite Rothschild.
I have 10 bottles of
that in the cellar.
''Una bottiglia del destino''
What?
l have to think about 1961.
'61.
They built the Berlin wall then.
I was in Munich,
second semester.
My God,
I had no idea then.
As the young genius that I was.
It doesn't matter, gone is gone,
the past is the past.
We were totally convinced
that it depended on us.
For all eternity.
The fathers, disempowered, brought
the whole mess down on us.
Never military again.
An end to Americanism, capitalism.
The fantasy of power.
Freedom for love.
Life for music.
- I never feel at home.
- But you have your family.
- You call that heap of garbage family.
- A daughter, a grandchild ...
Wife ...
Honoured in all concert halls.
Your work.
What does all that add up to?
Listen to me,
We have known death since
we came into the world.
But the slow traceless vanishing,
after years, no longer
seeming successful, that is new.
That is the new horror of the '90s.
One lives second hand.
This is my vault.
Everything is hermetically sealed.
The first part of my life ended
on this underground walk.
When the ancient water course
was one day breached,
and here under everything the treasures,
which Ernst brought together
through his whole life, drowned.
I saw myself at this time as
guardian of the family treasures.
Finally no longer disconnected.
No more running away from connections.
No longer needing to
clarify who I was.
A whole for ever.
Then the water came.
I saved my child,
my reputation, my building site.
I struggled with and lost the future.
The old future of childhood.
Where is the Frauenkirche,
Herr Ludwig? Wasn't that it, just now?
- That was the German museum.
- You're winding me up.
Because I'm new to Munich.
You've just started too.
If I could find out from
where I originated,
then I would perhaps have an answer.
I perhaps knew where this journey led.
But obviously, it was just chance
that Hermann was my father,
That my mother, from Hunruck,
ran into him in Munich.
Up to that point, she had simply
nothing to do with his life.
Normally, we get out in front of the
Opera house, but obviously not today.
Because of the opening this evening.
You see it?
Everything locked up.
Have you ever been in, Herr Ludwig?
What does an opera ticket cost?
They cost at least 100 Marks
for a standing ticket.
Why should I want to go in there.
I thought I could enjoy it.
to be beautifully dressed,
chic little bag
and a little perfume from Dior.
and naturally opera glasses,
With that I could look the
singer right in the throat!
Nauturally, I would have to
be in charming company.
A gentleman, who would translate the text for me.
They always sing in
Italian or old German.
So I would like to understand it as well.
Above all the plot.
Shall I tell you what the
opera has to do with me?
Nothing, Absolutely nothing.
Or almost nothing.
I once played the tombola to
raise money for the reconstruction,
I won a bicycle for the fortune of 50 pfennigs.
Now the opera house is ready.
One can hardly believe it.
For once, the times have interchanged.
I am once again a '68 child,
who must play with the adults.
To enjoy all freedoms, to fight
until one can fight no more.
To run around nacked, to shit on the
floor, to run away when it gets boring.
The friends of my parents
will be my family.
Where is Munich,
I asked my mother.
lI was perhaps four years old.
'Here, you are in Munich.'
She's quite savvy after all
her years as a tour guide.
But my child's view
couldn't see Munich.
I couldn't see the borders. Munich
was all around. It was the world.
Would you like a coffee?
Hello.
Two coffees.
- It's over!
- What is over?
You'll never see me again.
I'm leaving you all.
I'm leaving Munich.
And where to you want to go to?
To Africa.
City of my childhood.
When I consider things properly,
I wasn't really there.
I wasn't there, in my childhood.
I was only a part of the scenery.
I had breathed the air, and felt
the shadows of my agitated parents
as they scampered by.
Always looking for something which
they themselves didn't even know.
Is he a nigger?
I mean, is he black?
He is a doctor.
And he has seen more of the world
than all of us put together.
And what are your plans with him?
To marry him.
Marry?
Helga, you're crazy.
What does marriage have
to do with love or Africa?
For me, a lot.
I don't want any discussion about concepts.
I want to take
leave of your life.
What do that mean for my life?
You were never in it.
We are friends. We have written
poetry together, songs.
- We've kissed.
- and embraced.
And that's normal, or not?
Helga ...
you are smitten, or, in love.
I pity this doctor of
yours already.
Is that him in the photo?
He could be your father.
He wants to have a child with me.
Helga, I thought you
wanted to be a lyricist.
Or to write novels.
You wanted to live your own life.
You want to throw all that
away for a little love?
Helga, I'll tell you what.
Love ... is only in art.
It is only an idea.
And something more.
When you exchange life and art for each
other, that is the most brutal kitsch.
- I'm sorry, we're finished now.
- I only want some information.
- Goodbye, have a nice weekend.
- I have a short question.
That you could perhaps answer as you leave.
Come again on Monday morning.
No, that's much too late. I want
to know how fast one can marry.
Is there some sort of lightning wedding?
When it's a matter of life and
death, we have some special rules.
We can apply them if the bridegroom is
close to death. Is he close to death?
- No.
- And can he walk?
Yes, he can walk.
- Have you ordered a summons?
- No, do I need to?
As a rule, and when he can walk, yes.
We want to emigrate to South-West Africa.
- When?
- By plane on the 1st December.
1st December?
Let me look...
December, December ...
- Do you not want to marry in South Africa?
- ln South Cameroon?
- For example.
- No.
- You want to get married in church?
- Yes.
That makes it hard.
What are they down there?
Muslims?
Hamites, Bantus.
Sudanese with priest-kings.
Is that admissible in Germany?
I can only give you advice
from the EGBGB Article 11 paragraph one.
When this, shall we say, priest-king
is authorised by local tribal law ...
this tribal law will be recognised
by the appropriate government entities,
when the priest during the marriage
ceremony issues
a certificate, or certificate equivalent....
But that would be very tough in the bush.
When they come with fetishes around their
necks or rings through their noses ...
So, in principle, fine, but never
before tried in practice.
By airline pilot it's even
more problematic, I believe.
Something else. The German consulate.
What's the capital down there?
- l think it's Douala.
- I don't know it.
Is it big?
It rains a lot down there.
Over 10,000 Millimeters a year.
- Twenty times as much as in Munich.
- And you want to go there?
I've never been to the
music conservatory.
My mother must have prevented it.
There were even places,
from which nothing good came.
A thousand assumptions, unseen precipices.
Mothers can plant their bitterness
in the souls of their daughters.
The music and the other women.
Both had the same smell for my mother.
And my mother had instilled that
sense of smell in me, and that disgust.
The bad smell of the Munich years
flowed out of the musical instruments.
Volker.
Can you clarify this for me?
what is this note?
Hello, Clarissa,
I've been looking for you all day.
You can't publish that
I'm doing a concert with you!
- Let's talk it over, Clarissa.
- We've already done that.
- You never said, no.
- I never said, yes, either.
Volker, I'm a cellist.
I'm not going to
play the fool for you.
Take care, I'll explain it for you.
Behind you, two drums,
Piano, flute, double-bass.
And then you with your cello
in the middle of the stage.
- Floodlit by spotlights.
- And I don't play a note.
Volker, for that reason,
you could get anyone.
For that I don't need
11 years training.
Clarissa, I'm not asking anything indecent.
I don't want you to undress,
or make obscene gestures.
I just want this theatrical moment.
And what do you say to that?
- I don't know.
- Will you do it?
I've not been here that long.
Volker, I'm going now.
I will come to your concert,
but I'll sit below, in the stalls.
and I won't be your little
mascott, on the stage.
Goodbye.
Hello, Lukas! It's your mother.
I'm in a house of 1,000 smells.
Do you want to hear?
I thought that as you are a little
musician, you could smell with your ears.
- That is Clarissa.
- Lichtblau.
- What blue?
- Lichtblau (light blue).
Lichtblau.
A very poetic name.
In Spanish: 'Celeste'
In Italian, 'Azzurro Chiaro'
In English, 'Lightblue'
- Okay.
- Greek: 'Phosphompleanos.'
- Chinese: 'Tanla-ü'
- 'Tanla-ü'
In Dutch: ''Lichtblau''
I see.
I admire him very much.
A polyglot.
He can speak 11 languages
with recorder.
May I try to?
'The art of speech.'
What do you need that for?
- I would like to ...
- He attends an acting school.
- He wants to lose his accent.
- Exactly.
- Accant?
- I would like to study that too.
A shame.
I find your accent so pleasant.
- May I?
- Yes.
Aha, look, your famous ''ch''.
- l didn't understand anything.
- Me neither.
How come?
Don't disturb yourself, I'll come to you.
- Good day.
- Herr Simon.
- Ah.
- He's doing the entrance examination. Composition.
- Is that by you?
- Yes.
I see that's a wonderful instrumentation.
What is it for?
It is for orchestra,
piano accompaniment und choir.
- Where do you come from, Herr Simon?
- I come from Hunsrück, Rheinland.
- Where is that?
- In the Northwest.
- Is it a beautiful landscape?
- I find it so, yes.
- Mountains and beautiful valleys?
- Yes.
I am a great nature lover.
But unfortunately, my life is a martyrdom.
I am in New York today, Tokyo tomorrow.
The day after tomorrow Donaueschingen
today Munich, you see.
Pardon me, Herr Simon.
Could you play these two measures for me?
- Maybe three, but sing as well.
- yes.
Do it as you would play it.
tighten, young ones, master,
and build high the middle ship.
Wonderful. Beautiful. Beautiful, Herr Simon.
Congratualtions, Herr Simon.
Truly a very beautiful piece.
Goodbye then. Many thanks.
Goodbye.
Adieu.
One of our vice-presidents.
Life or art.
An eternal tale of woe.
I must have felt that as a child.
I refused to learn an instrument.
Before everything for women,
art stands in the way of life.
I'm used to going mad,
It guides every path to their ends.
Our joys, our sorrows,
All a play of lights!
Have you spoken with Evelyn already?
About what?
Do you want to talk to me about Clarissa?
You are her best friend.
I was with her in Coburg, in Nürnberg,
in Augsburg, in Regensburg,
in Memmingen, ... in Neu-Ulm.
The whole odyssey.
ln the mountain stream's dry channel
I quietly wound my way down,
Every stream wants to reach the sea,
Every suffering also its grave.
What should I do with it?
Nothing.
Simply look.
The madness is loosed
on this world.
I always saw a godsend in him.
Not for all, but for us,
the young generation.
Who knows what happens now.
For the time being, everything is quiet.
Deathly still.
Greetings.
come on Evelyne, are we going up.
Herr Distle, I'll be right back.
Evelyne, now you can eat until you're full.
There's roast pork.
Evelyne, are you coming?
So Evelyne,
I've always known,
that you would come home one day.
- What are you doing, Evelyne?
- l'm going back.
- What have we done to you?
- You've done nothing to me.
I wanted to see you once more.
Evelyne ...
Stay a little longer.
At least for a few days.
You don't know what you want.
You're at the end of your nerves.
- Jürgen, can you lend me a little money?
- We don't have any money.
- How much do you need?
- 500.
I know, it's a lot.
But I need it.
Mum, I'm going down with Evelyn
to take the money from the till.
I've done it already.
Sometime I'll tell you everything.
Evelyne.
I belong to a generation
of happy childhoods.
They wanted to keep
all hardships, all injustice
all existenial struggles away from me.
My clever, enlightened unfaithful parents.
But life ...
I'll write down the address.
It is Rue André del Sarte.
Near Montmartre.
When you get in, it is to the
left of the gas tap.
Please don't use the chimney,
as it's walled up.
- I won't.
- And there's fresh milk in the fridge.
- Can you speak French?
- Yes, from school.
Good, then you'll get
to know people quickly.
This is Boni.
- Bonjour.
- Bonjour, ça va?
Oui.
- We have to go now.
- Okay, have fun in England.
See you again in Munich.
- See you.
- Okay.
Don't ask if you may do what you like,
but if you can.
A stupid expression of my father
that shows to the child that it doesn't belong.
Therefore I was happy
when he left me and my mother.
He should tramp around
with his musician friends instead.
I told myself that
I wasn't descended from him.
What did all this Schwabing
chaos have to do with me?
I tried again to
construct images.
Tomorrow's Süddeutsche.
I give more regard to
natural necessity.
Now I have a ravenous hunger, for instance.
After, the sense stands higher than you.
Here we could eat Linsen soup.
Then we fart in a Nitroglycerine
cellar, which makes a good combination.
Hey.
Hey, such a crazy woman.
Do you know her?
Yes, she is a stage... stage...
stage school student. shit!
Introduce me to her.
The night is yet young.
Good evening. l ... l ...
- I'd rather you said nothing.
- May proletarians sit here?
- Are you an actress?
- Has he said something?
- Have I said something?
- Have I smelled something.
I see in you already
dishonesty in those eyes.
So she is a natural actress.
You are a gruesome pest.
- And who are you?
- Shall I put you on the silver screen?
My best friends are in short films.
Short film?
Surely you mean Tesafilm (sellotape).
Hermann, would you confirm what
I have said to the young lady.
You old cynic, sit down.
You definitely come from such a farmer's village.
Just learnt German.
Have you heard how
well she pronounces Tesafilm?
And you?
Where was your nursery?
I've cut myself free.
My father was an old Nazi from Rosenheim,
his hands covered with Jewish blood.
My mother was his slave, day and night.
They both gross me out.
Above all when I imagine
how they conceived me.
Can you imagine your
mother fucking?
- There are still also beautiful things in the world.
- Today art is just destruction.
Everything must be shattered,
everything atomised.
I heard a concert the other day.
Ice cold.
I believe in progress.
Since the moon landing
millions people have seen the earth from
the perspective of the universe.
The thought makes me crazy.
The beautiful and the reasonable
are one and the same.
Like goulash soup.
nice and reasonable.
- You disgust me.
- l imagine so, you are still a young woman.
- See you tomorrow.
- The day after tomorrow.
I wish I had a beautiful, practical,
nordic housewife.
- What singular experience.
- I should have paid more attention.
- Want to bet that you dream of me?
- Hopefully not a nightmare.
She shook hands with you and not me,
because you were blase with her.
I'm not interested any more
in the lives of women.
She saw that.
Because of that, you looked
better than me.
But something about you is a
puzzle to her.
Me too ...
To me, I mean.
Do you want to live forever?
Not you?
I'm sorry.
I love you.
Your music is truly wonderful.
- Thankyou. - But why
this rhapsodic element?
What do you mean by that?
Because I write melodies?
- Someone once said:
- Excuse me.
'Whoever writes melodies
betrays the working classes'
What do you think of that?
'What man sees in the stars,
woman knows how to
use in the saucepan'
- What do you mean by that?
- Hebbel.
That pleases me too.
Hermann.
Thank you.
This evening is a
wonderful thing, no?
The cello.
You!
That moved me a great deal.
I was totally mystified.
Ach, Juan.
- Are you coming to mine?
- Are you still coming to mine?
- Good evening, Renate.
- Hello, Hermann.
That was a successful evening.
I've never cried so much at a concert.
- Good.
- We're going for something
to eat. See you later.
- See you.
- 'til then.
I've seen through you, Hermann.
Your piece'Sine nobilitate'
is about a sex change.
That's new to me.
Four men and one absent woman,
so it seemed.
But I kown better. It was four
women and one absent man.
The piece betrays you, Hermann.
Did you enjoy it or not?
Elisabeth.
I'm staying with Hermann.
It's getting late, perhaps very late.
Then you'll meet him
some other time.
I have to cry.
It's so beautiful.
And we're going to the cinema later.
No, Hermann ...
That a single day
can be so beautiful...
Fathers remain our secret heroes.
From my mother,
I got a sense for the real.
From my father,
a sense for the possible.
I can go into my mirror image.
I can pull the spade ...
... from the water still dry.
I can hear the voices of
happy guests beneath each step,
who have danced here many times.
In the sun-drenched, daylight
garden of my father, everything is possible.
Time can develop fissures.
Past and present collapse into one another.
And under the gravel,
the buried treasures become visible.
I am the archeologist of the future.
And dig up the present.
Ah.
It's going well.
I could never forget you,
Waltraud.
I should have been a musician.
Did you say something?
I should have studied music.
- Instead of philosophy?
- Fräulein Cerphal, that's right.
I've somehow lost 20 years, father.
Sadly the house shall become
a living pyramid.
Fräulein Cerphal,
those are historic places,
which cannot be touched in any circumstances.
Historic places ...
I had this hope once.
And I did much in return.
But in between I had great doubts.
Do you believe that something
happened here of historic importance?
I was conceived here too.
They have both told me that.
The realist and the dreamer.
But like all historical events,
this one too is shrouded in mist.
- Are you happy?
- About your child?
In my mind I can't understand that
I had something to do with it.
But you did.
- A miracle.
- Yes, Hermann. A miracle.
Smile please. Good.
Look out, friends!
- come on, get off.
- A small packet ...
- An outing?
- Au!
- I'm innocent.
- You have the burden of proof.
- l'll prove it to you.
- Ach.
- Hello.
- Objection!
- Now I'll give it some gas!
- Great, granny, give it some gas!
l'm going as fast as I can,
Jacqueline.
Pauline, do you think we'll
find the right street?
- Munich Schwabing, is that right?
- Yes, granny, we have to get off there.
That's a heavy case.
That's not just silk blouses.
And watch out.
No scratches, please.
1943.
When the councillor was 60,
I was also 13.
One wouldn't believe it.
That time exists no longer.
Look here.
Wilhelm Cerphal.
That's what he was called, the councillor.
And from that we still have all 32 pieces.
Don't drop any,
the strawberries must arrive whole.
Please,
leave your things in the library.
How nice and ceremonial!
Look, Jacquelinsche,
so many books.
A very elegant house, Frau Ries.
Please but your things by the table.
Good ...
Under the picture ...
Is that really Meissner?
Yes.
We only have Nymphenburger at home.
I have a Meissner bowl as well.
- How beautiful.
- But this leaves me speechless.
That must be my envy.
We could never afford that.
I can hardle wait to meet,
Frau Cellophan.
- Cerphal.
- That's right.
Are you not scared the young
people might break something?
I'm having so much fun cooking
something nice again.
- You cook as well?
- Yes.
Could I give you a hand with that?
I feel better when
I've got something to do.
Pauline, you can understand that?
Most of all I would like to
look at the whole house.
Houses have a childhood,
an adolescence and the
golden years of maturity.
Then later, the smell of old age
comes up from the foundations.
New paint on the walls no longer helps.
The house will no longer
display its elegance.
- Hello, Schirmer.
- Please.
That is Jacquelinsche.
Good day, I'm Kröber.
I've never seen such a beautiful house.
And so nicely decorated today.
Pauline!
- Have you brought in the silk blouses?
- Yes, they're in the library.
Where?
Oh, yes.
Our students should
have it good for once too.
And see how we used to live.
I'm cooking you a great,
13 course menu.
What, 13 courses?
Such a thing doesn't exist.
- What are you cooking there?
- This is my kingdom.
I want to go home.
Jacquelinsche, but you've enjoyed the big city.
Ach, child. I understand.
It's the same with me.
I want to go home too.
Genuine pure silk.
And the accordian's playing
a farewell dance for us.
Come and dance our
Tango d'amor with me.
I am in love like never before.
Every hour with you was wonderful.
What they had found here,
and made me,
was Hunsrück.
Once again Hunsrück.
I'm made up of two ends,
cut from the same material.
One end swings like the
indian rope trick, above,
and wants to conquer the air, the other
writhes on the ground, seeking a firm footing.
Half past seven.
Yes. Yes.
I won't get the bread in this weather.
The butter's rock hard.
But your wife has wrapped
it up so warm, Herr Ludwig.
There's a time for sewing
and a time for reaping.
That is an old proverb
of my mother's.
No one else is coming today
because of the bad weather.
Shall we go to Hertie in the
canteen to drink some Glühwein?
But Herr Ludwig,
no alcohol when you're driving.
We can have soup.
Glühwein soup?
For some reason my wife doesn't
like it when I eat here.
I don't understand that.
We met each other here.
She worked next door in Hertie shipping,
And I called myself a 'colleague'.
- Hello.
- Yes?
One moment, stay there.
- Fräulein,
- Yes?
one moment, do you belong to the house?
Wel yes, you know ... l ...
It's okay, apologies.
She's from the perfume department.
- So you're from the house?
- Naturally. That settles it. Thanks.
- Perfume department, I, Yes, Perfume department.
- Then that's fine.
- Thank you.
- Come with us.
- Herr Ludwig. My friend Olga.
- Müller.
Herr Ludwig.
Hello, and thank you.
Thank God it went well again.
- Take off that jacket, it's so flashy.
- Sure.
Come on ... You get the meal vouchers
in front of the entrance.
How did I do that,
Herr Ludwig?
- You don't eat anything.
- A picture of a girl's room.
- It's a fact!
- She is an actress.
Oh.
That's why I thought we knew each other.
I haven't had a hot meal in 2 days.
Do I know you from a film,
or pictures?
You look insanely familiar.
Let me think about it ...
- From television.
- I'd rather you didn't remember me from that.
No! It was last week.
But help me.
It was an Edgar Wallace crime story.
- I hope you didn't watch that.
- I swear it, I saw you.
- Are you on television?
- It's embarrassing.
Why embarrassing? Tell me.
What should one do,
when your friend's don't see you.
I'm surrounded by young film makers,
but none of them offer me a role.
Have you been on television?
The woman with the ovarian cyst.
What?
Ovarian cyst?
Right, it's come back to me now.
on that recent health program.
How you played the fear
before the operation!
Magnificent!
I said to my wife:
'Do they use real sick people?'
It was so real.
Do we have to keep on talking about it?
- Was it so badly recounted?
- How you played fear!
During the diagnosis, did you
really believe it would be cancer?
- I'm glad that you liked it.
- Really good, I must say.
No difference from real life.
And then the tears.
How do you do that with the crying?
You cried so bitterly when
your friend visited you.
Were the tears real?
- There are certain means.
- So there are means.
Do you use onions?
I cry when something is sour.
Do you know, at the
chief's birthday party,
the wine,
it was pure sorrel.
But Fräulein Olga,
you're a genuine actress.
You know, Fräulein Olga,
I'm mighty proud that I could
ask you all these questions.
I think we should leave
Fräulein Müller to eat in peace now.
So ... arrived.
You don't see anything.
Lulu, what then?
In the stony ears of bears,
one can tell one's most secret wishes.
They are not guaranteed to be fulfilled.
But they remain secrets,
that's how it goes.
You must finally understand
that we cut what you've shot.
That is what the public will
see and feel.
And what do we see?
Below the greenery and above
a grey sky, nothing else.
A really banal picture, by the way.
It tells me little.
Your Don Gusto and the
tropical nights were of little use.
That's clear in your head,
but not in the film.
well, was that arranged differently?
But Reinhard,
I captured the clocks wonderfully.
That was a fantastic approach.
Yes, fine, but it wasn't mine ...
Go ...
and stop.
Okay ... now piano.
piano now ...
and stop.
- Okay, work that out, please.
- Hm.
Rob, Reinhard.
I've been thinking that we
should cut this scene in two.
A closeup of a closeup.
Look sharp!
- Ulla, have you worked it out?
- We'll save 70 to 80 seconds that way.
We were all agreed that the
scene wasn't realistic.
Those are dream images,
and there are no cuts in dreams.
What do you mean, no cuts?
I always dream with cuts.
I can't verify that.
My opinion is that that's false.
Think about it,
try to remember.
I think Reinhard is right.
I often dream, but there are no cuts.
Also, no closeups,
when I'm honest. Sorry, Stefan.
Also, I have no sound in my dreams.
Normal music won't work, we need
sharp violins or the music of the spheres.
Cries for help.
Or something like cries for help.
- A plant, which cries for help.
- Perhaps.
What did Reinhard say?
He left it up to me, or you.
Can I see the scene again?
I've got the feeling that he hates this film.
He hates it, and doesn't want to edit it.
What are you looking for here?
What?
The end of a story.
That's simpler.
Cerphal.
Collapse! (Zerfall)
- Do you understand?
- I had imagined it differently.
That is evening light.
That is a broken up piece.
picturesque ruin.
Downfall in pink.
Beautiful death.
But in reality it doesn't die beautifully.
- Glass eye.
- It looks so benign.
I hate cameras.
One should always seek out the hideous.
Horribly difficult.
Simple impressions.
without hate, without disgust. Ice cold.
That'll often bring them to tears.
Then the work is done for the day.
Is there hideousness (haesslich)
without hate (hass)?
Does the word come from hate?
- I've never thought about it.
- Typically German, that word.
- beauty lies.
- Brutto, laid, ugly ...
Language falsifies everything.
- Is that why you take photographs?
- I've never thought about it.
Yes, you're right.
That would make an exhibition.
If that's true, I'd want to.
- Thank you. 'Olga Müller'.
- Mullère. - Mullère.
She is the heroine, so to speak: Esther?
A beautiful name.
- Is it based on real life?
- It's more beautiful than real life.
Yes, certainly.
Must be, Cinema should be more
beautiful than life, I always say.
I can hardly wait to read it.
The remaining copies will be
picked up tomorrow and sent to Bonn.
They must be at the
Home Office by Friday.
So. Take a look here.
Come here. Take a look.
In the corner ...
All screenplays.
I have to get them read for
the screenplay awards.
Yes ...
They're all hoping for the grand prize.
Just like you.
What are we going to do, Reinhard,
if you don't get the prize?
No ...
We won't think about it now.
Those are Chinese nightingales.
From where does one
understand one's own life?
Memory is only a part.
What hasn't it told us?
The plans which have been forged. Everything!
Parents, their friends, playmates,
my own friends.
I am surrounded by dreams,
by projects, which will never be fulfilled.
From their beginnings great stories,
which trickle away into the quicksand of time.
Life is not a broad stream.
It is made up of thousands of beginnings.
Never tired, always discontent.
Would you like to
come with me to the cinema?
My mother doesn't like me,
And no sweetheart do I have,
Oh why don't I die?
Why don't I die,
What am I doing here?
Yesterday there was a church fair,
But of course no one saw me,
For I am so unhappy
that I do not dance at all.
Let them be, those three roses
that bloom near the little cross:
Were you acquainted with the little maiden
who lies under it?
Thank you.
- Marianne.
- At the very front.
- The front gives you neck ache.
- Ach, rubbish.
I thought we'd be too late,
and now we're too early.
Helga, I've been thinking a lot about
your reproach from yesterday afternoon.
It wasn't a reproach, Marianne.
I don't know either why I'm often
so dissatisfied with my life.
But Westphal is the
perfect picture of a man.
And a doctor,
that all Munich raves about.
Helga writes poetry.
You have to see how the
patients make eyes at him.
and send presents.
My living room is often a flower shop.
What am I complaining about?
We're building a little house
soon in Meerfelder Bruch.
When I hear that,
I get so homesick for Vienna.
Helga-Putzi.
Come.
And when I sit in the cinema ...
Sadly I can't show you
'Die Pariserinnen'.
because the projectionist has vanished,
Although there's no football on TV.
- It's a crying shame.
He's taken the key to the main
switch with him, unfortunately,
otherwise I could run the projector.
- So what now?
- Let's go.
Something has already occurred to us.
I don't feel like it any more.
But come. Come.
Dreams in the cinema.
I don't dream of the film,
the film dreams of me.
Where is myself?
Where am I ... Then?
- Dorli? - Yes?
- Entrust yourself quietly to me.
München is almost my Heimat,
I know everything here.
- I live above the square, up there.
- Ach, how cool.
Helga, I want to go out.
Shall we?
- In spite of the long journey?
- That doesn't matter.
02Have you got a suggestion?
- We should discuss it.
Another problem -
have you got any money?
- A little still.
- l'm flat broke.
- Fed up?
- Thoroughly!
I'll introduce you to my landlady,
then we'll have no hassle.
- Frau Heimhauser?
- Helga?
- How is your room?
- nice and clean.
Frau Heimhauser.
Seems to be no one there.
- Helga?
- Hm?
Does the policeman sleep behind this door?
Sure.
That's the bedroom of both of them.
You can look through here.
- Hopefully, he doesn't take his
pistol to be with him. - Rubbish.
You, Helga?
I'm imagining how we both
sleep in this narrow bed.
The policeman is just a few
centimeters away, behind this door.
Dorli ...
Wild horse.
Helga?
- Have you never had company?
- What do you mean?
Wild horses or what?
- Men, naturally.
- Oh, men.
- Yes, once.
- And?
Was nothing,
I sent him away again.
So, not because of the police?
No, not because of the police.
So, wait.
- Look, there's some space here.
- Is that another room?
- Yes, my walk-in wardrobe.
- Cool!
Something smells funny here.
Like a big city.
Helga, I'm so agitated.
Shall we put some cool clothes on?
Make ourselves beautiful?
My friend, don't worry about clothes.
I don't believe that.
Helga, do you always go around
in thrown together clothes?
Ach, Dorli.
Come, there's cake.
Shall I show you the present I got?
Boah!
Walter from Düsseldorf
got me them.
Sexy, yeah?
He said, a woman must always
have a secret under her clothes.
Get a hold of that.
That's pure silk.
Helga, you must have something too.
You always have something like that on you?
You're nuder than nude.
- Dorli?
- Yes?
I think I'm in love.
Really?
I want to see him.
I'm curious. Is he coming too?
I don't know. l hope so.
What sort of person is he?
Hm.
- He's a musician.
- Aha.
And?
He set some of my poems to music.
They sounded good.
- Does he know that you love him?
- Ach, Dorli!
You must always think
so horribly practically.
I always think, fantasy ...
is much greater than reality.
It's said,
the fathers are always in doubt.
It's different for me.
I am the woman with many mothers.
They have 100 Names and are
always on the trail of happiness.
I always read them in secret as a child.
beautiful, no?
So, sleep well now, Hermann.
Early tomorrow I'll wake you
with a little buttered bread.
You suit me, Dorli.
Good night.
I recently saw a black singer in Dortmund.
I have perhaps dreamt of him.
Of his rangy, sweat soaked body.
It was no longer a body, it was a landscape.
He had looked at me with red, evasive eyes.
Like an animal.
I sat in the front row.
Those are little girls dreams, Dorli.
I say to you,
if happiness encounters you, then,
you cannot count on it.
In a dull job.
In an office, a hospital, a school.
Perhaps a playground.
This just occurred to me.
Often, when I go to play with the twins,
I see the young mothers,
who sit their with their gazes,
which go straight through their offspring,
into the distance.
The women sit there and smoke one cigarette after another.
You must check it ouut sometime,
they lie there at the edge of the sandpit.
Hey, look here.
Do you know, Dorli,
we are like powderkegs.
You simply need to strike a match.
When someone goes by ...
Naturally invisible for the city.
The squaw brings the big chief ...
... his breakfast.
And I try to remember,
what I dreamt.
Has my soul finally arrived?
Now I know it again.
Staves, which turn themelves
into spaghetti when they're played. Idiotic.
Ah!
Do you want milk in your coffee?
No.
- Milk?
- Yes!
Sugar?
- No, none.
- None?
This evening, Helga's parents
are holding a birthday party.
But don't worry,
there's definitely no spaghetti.
- How is your back?
- Take a look.
Marianne's oinment is wonderful,
it's already much better.
Hermann ...
Hermann, leave that now.
Only only comes in dreams.
Awake, all men are the same.
The weather's nice again today.
Are you in love with Hermann?
Hermann is the same as me.
He is always looking for something,
Like the mad wanderers
of the old stories.
Perhaps it's overstated, butr ...
when one is like that,
one must remain alone.
And how does he relate to you?
Do you know what he thinks of you?
Do you know what I think?
Hermann cannot love,
because he's incomprehensible.
Every time you think you've caught him,
he's already far away.
What I seek in particular
is a story with an exit.
But the exit doesn't lead out.
It leads into the interior of the machine.
My life is a train which
crashes through time.
Around 24 pictures a second.
So ... arrived.
You don't see anything, Lulu.
Lulu, what then?
Calm, sounds ...
noises, electronic sounds ...
Texts, poems ...
all interwoven.
And when I entered this jungle of sounds,
something else stepped into the foreground,
a string quartett.
- the sound of the spheres.
- Please, a moment.
I conduct the investigation.
Don't come to me with your ideas.
But we should talk about ...
- We project the images into each other.
- Yes.
- Interweave them like tones.
- Aha.
We let the loudspeaker
rotate above our heads.
- On 100 screens, the sun goes down.
- Beautiful.
Or it snows.
It snows over everything which you see.
In the music too?
- Herr Stürmer?
- Have you got a moment, please.
Herr Stürmer,
That's top notch
how you instruct people
to set up the camera.
That is your talent,
you do it with the wrist.
It's like that for me,
when I'm with the bank people.
I know which buttons to press,
to get them to finance us.
That's my talent.
We complement each other,
together we're a whole.
Watch out! That's
where the camera stands!
Here it stands: 'Magimobile',
'Transoptal Vision',
'Kairo Kinetische Vision',
'Ars Nova Vision',
''Musi Vision'', ''Multi Vision'',
''Varia Vision''.
'Mediascope' und 'Megascope'.
I would like to see our letters there.
lnternational ...
Reportage Association.
- Reportage sounds so journalistic.
- It's also so long.
Perhaps something else ...
- The world is round.
- Rotation ....
- Realisation ...
- Journey ...
Journey, yes, journey.
- ... Route.
- No, I'm for Varia Vision.
It's open, we don't need to fix it,
we can change it later.
- Hm.
He looks at me.
In this moment he
has recognised me.
He thinks of me.
He anticipates that I'll come.
Champagne,
the people's drink of the future.
Give Erika some more.
So, here, Herr Zielke.
Come my love.
It's lovely.
The American administration
made me mayor after the war.
- And I can tell you ...
- Herr Fingerlein.
I will never forget you
for what you have done for me.
It was simply wonderful.
I was totally penniless ...
We were all penniless then.
The only thing we had was hope.
Hope was our capital.
We had nothing and started from scratch!
We built our business and were like a family.
Where is Erika?
- I can't tolerate all this film chatter.
- It all hides something.
Shall we have another
glass of wine somewhere?
At mine?
I need to concentrate now.
I'll disturb him.
- Is it near?
- Hermann.
- You'll see.
- Can you hear me?
But don't be shocked,
my flat is tiny.
Hermann, do you hear me?
I'll show you something.
Katrin.
I'll close this case carefully,
they haven't noticed.
And the genie is trapped
for the next 1000 years
- Where is your child?
- With my parents.
ln Dülmen.
I still often think of Dülmen.
An end to cinema.
How do I get away from here?
I don't belong to you.
I want to become invisible.
That means, that one day
one's gaze turns back.
On this day, youth ends.
In the first moment of terror,
it appears to be a loss.
What made one so happy until then?
But then you can wake up.
You have finally arrived.
I open my eyes ...
I breathe ...
I can for once exactly determine
what is here and now,
And I am both inside and outside.
In me the bright 'I'
and outside, the world.
I can go in both directions.
Into time and out onto it.
I am free, I live.