♪ My girl moved away, huh ♪
♪ Can't help but think
It's something that I say that ♪
♪ Makes her flee
My loving arms and smiling face ♪
♪ And moves to a place where
Nobody even lovingly says her name ♪
- Yo.
- Hi.
You took long enough.
How long were you waiting
alone in the street?
- I wasn't gonna go in without you.
- It's weird, Clare.
I don't know anyone in there.
♪ She makes my Ruby Tuesdays
Taste like Benihanas... ♪
I'm normal. I'm fun.
Clare, we're in high school, okay?
- I know.
- We're supposed to be doing this.
- Having these... these wild adventures.
- Ooh, yeah.
The suburban house party. Yeah?
Embrace it.
- See where I'm going here?
- I see. I... Yeah.
We're having fun.
- No, I'm not.
- We are.
- We're gonna do karaoke.
- No, we're not.
♪ Yes, we are ♪
You're signing us up.
Okay, but I'm gonna pick
a terrible, sappy song.
- They won't make good duet songs.
- They'll make great...
- It's gonna be a disastrous... Sorry.
- Oh, you're good.
I can help you pick.
What?
- Your song.
- Oh.
I typically save my suggestions
for people in costume, but...
Oh, well, then you're confused.
I am in costume.
Oh. Like, if I like squint my eyes
and tilt my head?
- Hold on. Give me a second.
- I'm with you.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
Party animal.
- What?
- Let's... Okay.
- It's good, right?
- Yeah.
- It... it's on the weaker side of costumes.
- The weaker side?
Well, I was dragged here against my will.
And I'm sorry,
but you're not really one to talk,
Mr. White T-shirt Ferris Bueller.
You didn't really have to go all out
for that one, did you?
This is iconic. This is movie magic.
Okay? And frankly,
I think your anti-party ass
could use a little Ferris.
Are you always this confident,
or is this the Ferris Bueller act?
He's always this confident.
- I can answer that. Buddy?
- Good to know.
- Let's go.
- What... what's going on?
Just, um... just wait.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
♪ Well, shake it up, baby, now ♪
♪ Twist and shout... ♪
Hey.
Who is that?
Aidan.
Aidan who?
Aha.
- Okay. Uh...
- I mean, we just... I just met him.
He moved to town right after you left.
I just met him. I was wondering...
We didn't introduce ourselves.
- Well, that is Aidan.
- Good to know.
♪ Work it out now, honey ♪
♪ You know you look so good ♪
♪ You know you feel me goin' now ♪
♪ Just like I knew you would... ♪
It's looking good.
See, this is fun.
This is a lot.
♪ Ah! ♪
Thanks for walking me.
You didn't have to.
It's not really Halloween
without candy.
- Right? Like we kinda have... Yeah, come on.
- Wait.
Isn't it cheating
if we, like, buy it though?
More than stuffing on a party hat
and calling it a Halloween costume?
I didn't realize I was talking
to the mayor of Halloween right now.
See, you are though. There was a vote.
- Must've been before I moved back.
- Moved back? You used to live here?
Yeah, that's how I know Stella.
I moved away in the first grade.
Since then,
it's been six schools in three states.
Yeah.
It's why I don't spend
too much time being social.
I'd rather focus
on getting into a good school.
Oh! So that's why we never met.
You're a nerd.
Yeah.
Oh, miss.
So I'm in a band.
Oh my God, of course you're in a band.
It all makes sense.
Okay, you said it like it was a bad word.
No, but I bet it's actually good.
Which is the annoying part,
'cause it should be bad.
But I'm sure it's great.
Why is it annoying?
'Cause I bet you're one of those people
that's, like, good at everything.
The rest of us are out here overthinking,
and you're the king of karaoke.
I bet you're gonna go off
and become, like, a famous musician.
Actually, it's gonna be med school for me.
Hmm.
Yeah, both my parents are doctors,
so they kind of expect me
to follow in their footsteps.
But you don't want that?
I mean, my dream, honestly,
would be to apply to Berklee.
It's my favorite music school,
but my parents don't think it's practical.
Well, then you should change their minds.
Come on.
There.
I mean, you get into the perfect school.
And then what? What's next?
And then I become a lawyer.
I'm gonna fight for people
that need protecting.
Something my mom and I talked about.
Like the next RBG.
Sounds like you got
your whole future mapped out.
Yeah, I don't know.
You move around as much as I do,
and you crave a little stability.
My parents were
actually high school sweethearts
that didn't pan out.
And since the divorce,
my mom's kind of taken us all over,
and usually, each stop means
falling in love with a new guy.
And right now, that guy is Steve.
- We don't like Steve.
- He's fine.
But no, I'm just...
I give her credit for never giving up.
I mean, she just...
I don't know, she sounds
like a hopeless romantic.
Maybe.
I just don't wanna...
...make the same mistakes she did.
Yeah.
One...
two...
Three!
Sorry.
- I think it's gonna rain.
- Yeah. Mm-hmm.
And we're still, like,
six blocks from my house.
- Yeah.
All right.
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
This is me.
I'm glad to have witnessed
you live up to your party-animal name.
Mmm.
I'm not looking for a boyfriend.
- Oh, yeah...
- I'm sorry.
You didn't even ask and...
I'm just afraid. We've had this night.
If we kiss, we'll wanna kiss again.
Or at least I will,
and I don't wanna do this whole thing
if we'll break each other's hearts
in ten months when we graduate.
I'm sorry.
What? Why do we have
to break each other's hearts?
This whole thing,
high school, this is the prologue.
It sets the stage
for the rest of our lives,
and no offense, but I'm not
gonna be taking my prologue with me.
Okay, you think I'm insane. Look.
We... we... Okay.
We... we... we can kiss. That's fine.
But I just...
I needed you to know all the facts,
'cause, like, I...
- So... okay, that...
- Okay. Okay. Okay.
- I think you need a new plan.
- My plan's pretty set.
It doesn't include me, so I'd like
to make an amendment if I may.
I'll allow it.
Okay, how about... we kiss again?
Mmm.
If that kiss leads to something else,
then we make it
the best year ever, you know?
And then we'll just end it. It's done.
- Like a breakup pact?
- I'm proposing a breakup pact.
So what's gonna happen
in ten months when this is over?
I'll take you on
some kind of epic date, you know?
And then... and then...
and then we just go our separate ways
to close out the...
- Prologue. Yeah.
- Prologue. That's the one.
Do we have a deal?
Deal.
- Hi.
Um...
Yeah, I'll just go for it.
I'd like to take you on a proper date
to see a band I'm pretty confident
will be your new favorite.
Are you now?
Whoo!
- Saw you dancing.
- I heard music.
I might have moved a little.
If anything, I just did like this.
- If that's the base, it started there.
- That's a light swaying.
- It was also like this right here.
- My arms were not up.
♪ I just wanna get groceries ♪
♪ I'll pray you wanna get close to me ♪
♪ I'll give it some
Give it some, give it some time ♪
♪ But I think we're supposed to be ♪
♪ I wish that I could let it pass ♪
♪ I don't mind that you put it last ♪
♪ I made it worse, I put you first... ♪
Whoa!
Yes!
The senior swim to Rusty starts... now!
♪ This sucks, I'm lovesick ♪
♪ Too important to rush this ♪
♪ I'd miss our kiss ♪
♪ If it ever left ♪
- ♪ My lips... ♪
- Whoo!
Yeah!
♪ This sucks, I'm lovesick ♪
♪ Too important to rush this ♪
♪ I'd miss our kiss ♪
♪ If it ever left my lips ♪
♪ No one I know ♪
♪ Is sticky on my mind when I go ♪
♪ Heart broke, but I spend it ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm Miss Independent ♪
♪ I just wanna get groceries ♪
♪ I'll pray you wanna get close to me ♪
♪ I'll give it some
Give it some, give it some time ♪
♪ But I think we're supposed to be ♪
♪ And if you wanna get groceries ♪
♪ And if you wanna get close to me ♪
♪ Just gimme some
Gimme some, gimme some sign ♪
♪ I think that we're supposed to be ♪
What if he takes you
hot-air ballooning tonight?
He's not taking me hot-air ballooning.
For your last date?
Clare, he could get a bunch of doves,
fricking release them,
and they assemble the words
"Clare, we can make it" in the sky.
Come on.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
If a girl sent me doves, I'd be done for.
That would require you
to actually talk to a girl.
"Require you
to actually talk to a girl."
For your information, I'm working
a very diligent long game with Tess, okay?
- Long game, now?
- Yes, it's very long.
Well, the long game's
gonna have to speed it up
because time is running out.
Time's kind of running out
for you too, dude.
It's for the best.
I'm not gonna be like my parents, Stel.
I'm not doing that.
Okay.
Casually pivoting,
uh, I think a few people are
maybe going to South Point Beach later...
- Tess is going to South Point Beach later.
- Don't make me sound like a stalker, dude.
- I'm not.
- We did Spring Awakening together.
We're bonded.
That's one
of Broadway's horniest musicals.
It was hot and heavy.
Mrs. G didn't even make us
do the junior version.
- We straight up got to do regular.
- I think you should message her.
I think you should slide into her DMs,
but that's just me.
Clare?
Oh f...
No.
What?
I just sent a crying reaction.
- To... to Tess?
- To Tess.
Okay, fine, you DMed her.
That's good. This is a good thing.
Just say it was an accident
at the bonfire tonight.
Are you gonna be next to me
while I have to suffer and do this?
I'm at the mercy of Aidan tonight,
but, um, we'll see. I'll try.
Speaking of, he should be here,
like, any minute now.
- Okay.
- You need help.
- It's okay to ask.
- I don't need help.
- You do need help.
- Look, it's going.
Look at that.
Something ugly's in here that's asking
to not be brought to college.
- That's what's happening.
- Probably the whole bag.
But don't worry about it.
All right, well, um,
call me if you need backup.
You, uh... sure you're ready for this?
Yeah. Yeah, no, for sure.
It's obviously not gonna be
the easiest night in the world,
but it's a good goodbye.
- Lilies.
- Hi.
- Good choice.
- It's the flower of funerals.
I like it.
- You ready?
- Final date.
- Whoa.
- Ah, damn it.
Oh, Mom.
- Hey.
- Hey there.
My folks are right behind me.
Good to see you. Let me help.
I mean, we were all ready,
minus the chaos.
Let's get this up.
We're gonna be lost without you.
You kids break up yet?
- Hi.
- How are you?
- You know everyone thinks you're idiots?
- Of course.
- Hi.
- My favorite sister.
- Oh, my only brother.
Okay, here we go.
While no parent loves their teen dating,
Clare did manage to find
the one thoughtful high-school boy.
I did.
And even though
she's letting him get away,
Aidan, I loved
having you in our family this year.
And, Clare Bear,
God knows things
have not always been easy for us,
but somehow, you have managed
to grow into this brilliant,
caring, and determined young woman.
I'll kill you if you're late
for our 7:00 a.m. departure, so...
Okay, we know it'll be me
dragging you out of bed in the morning.
Ooh!
- Okay. Yeah, maybe.
- It's true.
Okay. To Clare.
- Yes.
- To Clare.
Clare.
Steve.
I... I wanna thank you
for letting me into your life.
I mean, who would've thought
that a year after getting kicked off
the city council, I'd be living in a house
with a beautiful,
intelligent, capable woman
and sending a pseudo stepdaughter
off to college.
Not me.
Clare, most importantly,
do not get mono in college.
Steve! He's not wrong.
- It spreads like wildfire, guys.
- He knows what I'm talking about.
Cheers.
This is why
we didn't need to do the toast.
- To Clare and Aidan.
- Okay.
- So, Clare.
- Yes.
- Poli-sci at Dartmouth.
- Mm-hmm.
- That's amazing. So cool.
- I'm excited.
And Aidan is pre-med.
- I thought you'd do something with music.
- Oh...
No, Mr. Perfect over here
is gonna follow in their footsteps.
Yep. Cardiologist, like his old man.
Excuse me.
He's gonna be a radiologist,
just like his mama.
Well...
- I think we have places to be.
- Yeah.
We should, uh... we should get going.
It's a lot on the itinerary.
Itinerary?
- Bungee jumping?
- Yes.
We're going to buy a dog?
I've been really patient.
You need to tell me what's going on.
You texted me 13 times
asking me what we were doing.
It was me holding back.
It is my epic date. It's my rules. Period.
Technically, the whole "go to college
single" thing was my idea, so...
Clare, do you trust me?
Yes, I trust you.
- Even though everyone thinks we're crazy.
- Oh, please.
They wish that they could end
a relationship this well.
We're like the anti-broken hearts club.
- Poster children of modern relationships.
- The king and queen of ending things.
I'm breaking up with you
because I love you.
Easy breezy.
♪ Oh, here we go ♪
♪ Yeah, here we go ♪
♪ There's an ocean in our mind
Where the world just floats... ♪
Thank you.
I thought you said this was sold out.
Summersets is like a big deal.
How did you manage to pull this off?
- I, uh... have my ways.
- Okay.
This takes me back to our first date.
One, two. One.
Check. Check.
- One.
- Aidan.
Colette, thank you so much
for hooking us up.
I can't believe you hooked him up
after he bailed on your band.
- How dare he bail on us?
- Whoa.
I'm still mad at him
for not applying to Berklee.
I am too.  I told him.
But he just had to go pre-med.
- The golden boy has lives to save.
- Okay, I'm standing here.
- Yeah, we know.
- Yeah, we see you.
Have a good breakup or whatever this is.
Thank you.
Hey, we're Milk & Bone.
It's a first for us
to do a breakup shout-out,
but Clare and Aidan, here's to your song.
♪ I've been lost for a while
In this conversation ♪
♪ Mmm, it wakes me up
In the middle of the night ♪
♪ I can't say what it's all about ♪
♪ All I know is that I want out ♪
♪ The words ever-spinning
In my head for days ♪
♪ Can't seem to breathe
Running into space ♪
♪ Nevermore ♪
♪ Where did I go wrong? ♪
♪ I wanna know the score ♪
♪ I won't wait for long ♪
♪ Nevermore... ♪
Whoo!
You didn't lie.
This has been
a pretty incredible first date.
♪ What if you stayed tonight, tonight? ♪
♪ 'Cause, boy, you're my daydream ♪
♪ Boy, you're my daydream
You're my daydream, boy ♪
♪ 'Cause, boy, you're my daydream
You're my daydream, you're my daydream ♪
♪ You're my daydream, boy ♪
Stella, hey.
So... you were right.
This is, like,
a lot harder than I thought.
Wait, take a breath.
What's going on?
Just... what if I'm throwing away, like,
the best thing that ever happened to me?
But maybe I'm... I'm also just clinging
to that, 'cause Aidan's safe and easy.
But also it, like, wouldn't be easy at all
if we were long-distance.
Also, we're supposed to go off
and be our own people
and have our own experiences and...
That was the point of this whole pact
in the first place. Yep.
Know what? I'm being
really stupid right now. I'm sorry.
- How we doing?
- Great. Clare'll be out any second.
I wanted to make sure we're still good.
Yeah, we're all set, man.
This can't be the end.
We're making the right call.
Aidan knows it. I know it.
We're gonna have our last date,
and it's gonna be incredible,
and then that's it.
I feel like we can make it, and hopefully,
by the end of the night, she'll...
she'll feel that too.
Thank you...
for everything.
You don't want to be
the douchey guitar guy in your dorm.
Bring, like, a keyboard or something.
You think my dad is gonna let me haul
a whole-ass keyboard to school?
I mean, he's not the grandma from Coco.
I don't know. Music's allowed at college.
I don't know, you say that,
but he's downloaded
an eight-part cardiology lecture
for the trip.
- Rough.
- I'm dead serious.
Well, at least your parents can road trip
without killing each other.
Once, mine fought so bad
that, I kid you not,
my mom made us stop
on the Golden Gate Bridge
so she could get out and walk.
No. No, no, no.
Hockey?
What gave it away?
- I've no idea.
- Like the hockey rink?
Wait, okay, what are we doing?
What're we doing?
Tell me what we're doing.
- You got an hour.
- Thanks, Rhoda.
Thanks, Rhoda.
Who's Rhoda?
Oh m...
- The whole place?
- Oh, all of it.
- You're impressed, right?
- I... I... I'm speechless.
Just take it all in.
No, just take it all in.
Everything that the light touches
is all ours for the next hour.
Whoo!
Okay.
Tonight, we are reliving our firsts.
All right?
We've already gone on our first date,
and now we return
to our first hockey game.
Okay, but that hockey game
was our first fight.
I don't know why we need to memorialize
our first fight on our last date.
A first fight is momentous.
It's a moment of growth.
That is such bull.
I don't know why
you just can't admit you farted.
I don't know why you're bringing this up.
Aidan and Clare?
- Yeah.
This way.
The race's about to start in one minute.
You guys look good. Ba-boom!
Aidan, you can't say that you farted.
I announce it. Like, "Yo, I let one rip."
It's funnier if you do it like that.
You don't have to be perfect all the time.
Not with me.
Please turn your attention to center ice
for the intermission race around the rink.
We've got the hot dog and the popcorn.
We've got the mustard and the ketchup.
"Sorry, I let one rip. My fault."
It's not a big deal. Admit the truth.
I didn't fart. I don't know
what else you want me to say.
I was in the car with you.
Okay, so is it disgusting if I fart?
You can fart if you wanna fart.
Everybody farts.
I'll hold it in.
Whenever I'm around you, I'll never fart.
You have my word. Oops, I just farted.
- Let me just move.
- Three!
- But that's what you're acting like.
- Two!
- One!
- Team Hot Dog, baby! Team Hot Dog!
Go!
- You can't admit it.
- Can we just focus on the race?
You were so excited two minutes ago.
- I'm over it.
- It's for Ellie's Deli.
I'm over it. I gotta go.
Are you actually leaving
'cause you think I let one rip?
I'm leaving because
you don't trust me enough to admit it.
I do think we owe it to ourselves
to finally win not only one
but two pastries...
Oh my God.
...from Ellie's Deli. What're you... No, no.
Are you... Excuse me?
Oh, no, no. You gotta win these bad boys.
We gotta right this wrong.
What are...
What are you doing?
Okay.
It's on.
Booyah!
- No, no, no, no, no.
- One, two, three.
Ready? We'll play nice and fair.
- You won't play fair.
- I'm a fair... I'm a fair player.
You ready? Three, two, one, go.
♪ This time next year ♪
♪ Won't pretend that I know ♪
♪ Where I'm gonna be ♪
♪ Big boy cruising on my Radio Flyer ♪
♪ That's where I wanna be ♪
♪ Look, look, no hands, I'm unstoppable ♪
♪ Don't know the plan, so I'm dreaming ♪
♪ I'm gonna leave it ♪
♪ All up to you ♪
♪ You seem to know more about it than me ♪
♪ I'd love to be in on the plan ♪
♪ So tell me when you can ♪
♪ I'd appreciate it ♪
♪ This time next year ♪
♪ Won't pretend that I know ♪
- ♪ Where I'm gonna be... ♪
- I have to tell you something.
I farted on the way to the game.
That might be the most romantic thing
you've ever said to me.
Hour's up, lovebirds.
Let's go!
- I wanna watch Shark Tank.
- Thanks, Rhoda.
Thank you.
This has all been so perfect.
Whoo!
First time you kept
outdoing yourself on a date?
Oh, first time we went waterskiing?
No, think, um... think more sentimental.
More meaningful to us as a couple.
If I can find it.
Here it is.
Maybe this'll jog your memory.
The first time you ever
proposed to me on a boat.
- Oh, you wish.
- Aw.
No, open that.
Thank you.
It's a rocket.
Flip it over.
Easy breezy.
Hey! Slow down, Scotty!
No, I wanna get off! No, no, no!
Yes!
It's good. I got you.
- Easy breezy.
- Easy breezy?
Easy breezy.
Easy bre... easy breezy.
Here we go!
Yeah!
Let's go! In three...
Scotty!
...two...
Here we go!
Scotty!
Clare! Scotty, pull around.
Where the hell did she go?
Clare!
- Clare!
- I'm over here.
Clare, Clare, you're good.
That's what I like to see.
Okay, okay, I got you.
Aidan.
I got you.
I got you. I got you.
Come here.
Yes!
Yes! Yes!
Hey.
Oh my God
I love you.
That was not easy.
What did you say?
I love you.
Easy breezy.
Okay.
You got rocketed!
You got rocketed, Clare!
- Let's go.
- Whoo!
The first "I love you."
This was definitely worth the trip.
Clare, um...
I know we made a deal.
We don't...
I wanted to know what it was like
to be launched into the air.
- I mean, you were flying.
- Stop. Enough.
- It was crazy though, right?
- I mean, it was crazy.
I made that work.
- You hungry?
- Yeah.
- Pizza? All right, let's go.
- Mm-hmm.
♪ In the end, it ain't the end ♪
♪ It just goes on and on again ♪
♪ And all the people that you meet ♪
♪ Are just the same as you and me ♪
Wow.
First Valentine's Day.
Okay, just, um...
just chill here. Wait for me.
Will do.
You need to be
shutting this down, immediately.
You can put me facedown all you want,
but you can't avoid this.
- Okay, well, I just texted Stella...
- Uh-uh.
- This is about you and Aidan.
- He's still my boyfriend.
Yeah, he's still her boyfriend.
Her Valentine.
No, no, no, no, no. One is enough.
- Hi.
He'll hold you back from becoming
the woman you were meant to be.
Or... or he'll be
your biggest supporter along the way.
- Doubtful.
- Guys, I have a plan.
And I'm gonna...
I'm gonna stick to that plan.
You can't fault someone for loving
big, romantic gestures. It's kinda cute.
You can't fault someone
for wanting to do their own thing.
You wanna move forward
from your true love?
- We are too young to know.
- Okay.
Thank you, but this is more than enough.
I'm getting a little anxious right now,
so let's stop.
- Don't wanna mess this up.
- No, look at me.
You give an inch,
and you can lose your whole future.
- You wanna move away...
- We need to stay strong.
I'm trying to. Wow.
It's okay. I'm here.
Okay, and so is James Bond.
You called Stella?
You're wearing a tux?
We never got a prom.
It's our next stop.
Stella. What's up?
- It's a... it's a big energy shift.
- Yeah.
- I told you guys it was good.
- I like it.
Come on.
That's adorable.
- This is a production.
- Planning the night for a while.
- You stud.
- I'm gonna miss this.
- Miss what?
- Us just, I don't know, all hanging out.
I mean...
- Not to be sappy or anything, but...
- Uh-huh.
Okay, stop. I never thought
I'd have a group of friends like this.
'Cause you did
nothing but school.
Ow-wah!
No. Well, like, a little bit.
But because I, like...
I moved around so much.
And, I don't know, it's our last night
before we all go off to our new lives.
Aidan and I are celebrating our firsts,
but how often do you know that
this is, like, the last time of something?
Damn.
For real. I got suspended
before I even got to tag the senior wall.
Never got to leave my mark.
I'm pretty sure you did that
when you streaked at the soccer game.
Well... well, yeah. I mean,
you know I like to show my school spirit.
Everybody saw your ding-dong, my guy.
- Aight, uh, this has been a blast.
- But I'm saying...
- Okay.
- This has been a blast.
You guys are awesome. I love you both.
- But Clare and I...
- We should go tag it.
What?
I think you should tag the wall.
We have time, right, Aid?
Yeah, I mean,
it's kind of a full night planned.
I know, I know, but it's our last night
as a group together too.
And Scotty, Scotty needs to make his mark.
Absolutely.
We can't leave him hanging like that.
We can't let him be forgotten.
No, we don't want him to be forgotten.
- Don't you have to work tonight?
- Dude, I got off like an hour ago.
Aidan, it's just one stop,
and we get back to our night.
For Scotty.
Break into the school?
And also there's...
My...
- Your character shoes.
- Character shoes.
- Your what?
- In your locker.
- In my locker.
Let's go. Let's go tag the wall.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Let's go tag that wall
and save Stella's character.
- Yes.
- Close enough.
This is gonna be really fun.
Am I crazy?
- Aidan? Dude?
- Come on.
Let's go.
Aidan.
- It's gonna be fun.
- Come on.
- Please?
Come on.
- I mean, I guess it is our only...
- Come on! Wow!
- Let's go.
- Yeah.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- To the school.
- Party bus!
- Oh yes!
♪ This is me all day, all week
No, they can't say what I can't be ♪
'Cause they ain't got nothin' on me ♪
Quite a vibe, huh?
If I spent a lot of money
to rent a party bus,
this is how I'd be behaving.
♪ This is me all day, all week
No, they can't say what I can't be ♪
'Cause they ain't got nothin' on me ♪
♪ I could stay in, or I can go out ♪
♪ But whatever I do
I'mma do without a doubt... ♪
Aidan, what about you?
♪ This is me all day, all week
No, they can't say what I can't be ♪
'Cause they ain't got nothin' on me ♪
♪ We the ones who turnin' the heads
Yeah, we the ones you hearin' about ♪
♪ We the ones who set all the trends
Yeah, we the ones you can't live without ♪
♪ This is me all day, all week
No, they can't say what I can't be ♪
No, they can't say what I can't be... ♪
Yo!
So there's no plan at all?
Here we go.
That's all I got.
Okay, follow me. Follow me.
I know what to do.
- Let's go. Let's go.
- Be quiet, man.
- Trying to get us in trouble.
- I know people who've done this before.
- You're breaking and entering.
- I'm not breaking and entering.
So technically, this is the only door
in the school that doesn't fully lock.
I know 'cause of fire safety checks.
Whatever. Watch this. You go like...
What the... Okay, Clare,
you legit just made me a feminist.
- Well-done.
- A lot better than my attempt.
- Let's go.
- Thank you.
- Student Council paid off. Maybe not.
- Football. Aidan, go long.
- Nope, took too long.
- I don't like this.
- Scotty, why? Why would you do that?
- Okay.
Okay, you and me,
we're gonna go to the art room
and get our paint for the hands.
You guys, character shoes?
- Meet back here?
- Yeah.
- Let's go. Ready?
- Wait, what?
- Oh. Okay.
- Scotty, we're out, okay?
- Pick up your feet, guys. Let's go.
- All right. All right. Okay.
Okay.
Nothing like the theater, I tell ya.
Well, okay,
time to find my character shoes.
- Which are in my locker.
- Stella, you can drop the act.
Yeah, we cleared these out in May,
and honestly, I've never owned
a pair of character shoes.
I mostly work on set stuff,
but you knew that.
You know, we should be recreating
our prom night right now.
You know,
when Clare got sick before the prom,
she was actually relieved
she didn't have to go.
Stella, you know good and well
that she would've had a great time
if we would've gone.
I actually don't think I know that.
You can't control
everything, Aidan.
You can't...
"Aidan" your way out of situations.
Aidan my way out of situ...
- What in the world... Please tell me what...
- You know what...
I think you know what I mean.
I have no clue. You used my name
as a verb. What does it mean?
Positively, when one,
an Aidan for example,
behaves in a sort of manner
where, you know, you sort of...
You know?
And then things kind of go your way.
I'm just saying,
you both set the rules at the start.
You can't be upset
if she doesn't wanna break them.
There's no way we could've known
it would've turned out
to be as good as it is though.
It's good.
Yes, you guys are my favorite couple.
I'm obsessed with you.
So you think I should keep trying?
You just need to be honest with her.
Just... be real with each other.
And then when you're done with that...
hope for the best, my light-skinned king.
Thank you. Yeah.
Okay.
I feel like mixing black...
- Wow, that's a lot.
- Just gotta get the right color.
You did just mix black paint...
Now, can you check
that there's blue, please?
Or purple, for that matter?
Thank you.
You need to hurry up
because they're waiting.
What's the rush? I thought you'd be happy
about avoiding your relationship
a little longer.
- No, I... wasn't.
- I'm messing.
Sort of. Kind of.
Not really.
This isn't working.
I know.
I just wish Aidan would see that too.
I was talking about the paints.
Right, the paints.
Do you wanna just go
with a... a solid color?
Not whatever that is.
Let's... let's go with red.
Dude, tonight just wasn't the clean break
I was hoping it would be.
Please, Clare,
it was always gonna be messy.
And you know it.
I don't know, maybe if Aidan were
more excited about school,
or if he ended up
deciding to, you know, like...
Go to Berklee?
Yeah.
I've heard that.
You know, he's just so talented,
and I know his parents think
it's a huge risk or whatever
to pursue that, but I don't know.
I don't know if it would end up actually
being that much of a risk with him.
Well,
I don't think Aidan thinks
it'd be much of a risk with you.
Oh, there she is.
In the flesh.
My Everest.
What color you going with?
Red. The color of war.
Disturbing.
- Scotty! Scotty!
- Oh, yeah.
Ready for the Senior Week suspension.
Scotty! Scotty!
Scotty!
Ooh!
- Scotty!
- Yo!
Okay, a bold choice.
- But we'll take it though.
- There's so much paint and no towel.
- Okay, well...
- Well, thank you.
What you gonna do?
Wipe it on my jacket? Who raised you?
- Go to the bathroom.
- Okay.
- Why would I voluntarily...
- I don't know.
- That is barely a handprint.
- Yeah.
How many couple prints
you think actually last?
I don't know.
Jade and Marcus already broke up.
Stella said she hooked up with some guy
at MSU before school even started.
Wow.
Didn't even last a month.
Is that what you're afraid of?
I don't know, Aidan. I just...
I wanna give ourselves
the chance to be our own people.
Don't you just wanna be able
to jump into any situation
and not have to give it
a second thought, you know?
I want that, and I want that for you too.
It's one of those things
I've always had in the back of my mind.
And I'm sorry if that sounds selfish,
but that's always been my plan...
For two seconds, forget...
forget about your plan.
Okay? What... what do you want?
Aidan...
I may have triggered the alarm.
He definitely did.
It's the one that's ringing right now.
It really doesn't matter.
Just run.
♪ I feel, feel like a cokehead ♪
- ♪ I feel, feel like I can't get drunk... ♪
- Go, go, go, go, go.
♪ Looking for some matches
Just to cook up a score ♪
♪ I feel, feel like shooting up... ♪
Come on.
- Where's the bus?
- Go, go, go, go!
Come on, come on!
Think someone's
actually chasing us?
To safety.
Here. I got you.
- Come on.
- Dude, hurry.
Come on!
- Oh shit.
- Oh my God, are...
Oh my God. Are you okay?
- I'm good. Yeah.
- You're okay? Okay.
Oh God.
Oh no.
No.
Stella, no, no, no.
- Stella, no.
- Should I call the driver?
Hold up, hold up.
- You feel okay? Okay.
- I'm good.
Just one more stitch here.
How's our patient doing?
I'm all right, Mom.
I already told you, I'm good.
Well, you're lucky it's me on call
and not your dad.
You know, Dr. Olsen,
my son is gonna be pre-med this fall.
- Is he now?
- Mm-hmm.
He'll be just a short drive from Clare.
She's off to Dartmouth in the morning.
Bright and early.
Oh.
- That was good.
- Yeah.
Ooh!
- Come on. Yeah.
- I mean, you know?
What's your plan? Like, after school...
- I got a houseboat.
- You got a houseboat?
Yeah, well, I'm gonna have a houseboat.
That's my plan.
- Okay.
- What about you?
- You're going to college, right?
- Yeah.
Is that...
- Meeting new people.
- That is what it is.
That stuff takes time, you know?
It takes people actually, like, being, uh,
interested in you, maybe?
I was interested in you.
- Sorry.
- I had a really big crush on you.
- Yeah, in seventh grade.
- Huh.
On the bus back from Lansing.
I brought mints on it,
'cause I was gonna make out with you.
The mints are a nice touch.
If there's one thing I know,
you gotta be bold.
Be bold.
Tell me more about what women want.
I'm telling you,
it's gonna get you places.
Like a houseboat?
So, your last stop is a bonfire?
Sort of.
It... The beach was supposed to be
just the two of us,
but the night's taken a few turns.
Ah. Well, if I were a better parent,
I'd make you both go home right now.
Oh, thank God you're so terrible then.
Ah.
We'll be okay.
- Mmm.
- He's alive.
Ooh, let's see those stitches. Mmm.
This is gonna be the last time I see you.
- Clare, you're gonna do great things.
- Thank you.
And if you ever change your mind,
he won't be too far away.
When he didn't get into Berklee,
he was at least excited about that.
Oh, sorry, I... I thought
that, um, he wasn't allowed
to apply to music school.
Oh, honey, no. Uh...
He didn't get in.
Aidan didn't tell you.
Um...
No, he didn't.
But it was good to see you.
You too.
♪ When we sail into the sun ♪
♪ Into the sun ♪
♪ Sail into the sun ♪
♪ Won't touch the ground ♪
♪ I'll stay up here, just you and me ♪
♪ And I, I'll pull you closer ♪
♪ When you're floating far away... ♪
Oh, yay.
- So you were in the hospital?
- Relax.
I'm good. I promise.
Uh, we're gonna meet you guys over here.
We patched him up really good, though.
Really good.
Dude, I'm sorry
I dragged you into all this.
It's a lot.
Yeah,
sort of like my whole night.
But I am willing to excuse it
on the grounds of you being
in the midst of the most
complicated breakup of maybe all time.
You didn't lie.
But thank you.
Like, for real.
You know, this is, like,
our last night together too.
I know.
Mmm.
Aidan is not the only one
who can do a big gesture, okay?
Okay.
- I... I've been planning for months, and I...
- Don't joke about that.
I present you this pine cone...
Oh.
...which represents...
Mmm.
...how I felt when... when you moved.
All sappy inside.
Sappy.
I give you this.
- Cheers, bitch.
- Cheers.
And may this pine cone
burn like our friendship.
- I don't know, I can be sentimental.
- Is that sentimental?
- Yeah.
- You put a hex on me.
- That's not a hex.
- That's a bad omen.
I'm saying, like,
our friendship is like heat. It's like...
Okay, for sure.
No, I got there. I got there.
No, but you know what's heat though?
This seaweed.
- Oh no, it's a sock.
- That's nasty.
Oh!
It's a sock.
Did you just throw a sock at me?
Mmm.
Tess. Uh, that was... that was an accident.
We were, like, doing, like, a bit thing.
Uh, 'cause here I thought
the sock and the crying emoji
were you acting out
'cause summer's ending.
Uh, yeah, no, for sure. Yeah.
Some people have love languages.
I have a grief language,
where I throw debris
and send random emojis.
Yeah, a few of us are heading up the beach
to Ladarian's house, if you wanna come?
- We kind of like...
- That would be so cool.
- We'd love to come.
- Cool.
- Uh, yes, that is cool with me.
- I'll meet you guys in a sec.
- Hey. Do you...
- Yeah, let's...
Yeah.
For the record, um, the beach was all part
of the date night anyway.
We're just hitting it kinda late.
Uh, yes. I assumed you wanted us
to relive the senior swim out to Rusty.
Yeah, had to happen at some point.
I mean, you kind of bailed
on the whole graduation race thing.
Yeah, well, the water was freezing and...
I... I just don't understand the tradition
of swimming out to a buoy.
I know, it's stupid.
No, it's...
But Rusty is still bobbing out there,
and it's waiting for us.
Aidan, your mom told me about Berklee.
- Whoa. What?
- Why would you have kept that from me?
Clare, I'm... It's not...
There was nothing to talk about.
- Not a big deal.
- All I've ever been is honest with you.
Clare, it... it... it...
I don't... I don't know
what you want me to say.
I just thought tonight
was about saying goodbye.
Or is that just another lie too?
It's dare.
Truth bomb.
- What do you wanna know?
- Dare, baby.
First song you knew as a child,
like an opera.
♪ Itsy bitsy spider ♪
All right. Dare.
Go smooch that orange, Stella.
You are making out with an orange.
Gotta make it steamy.
- Ooh.
- Make it good.
Mon chérie...
Ooh, yes!
- Look at that.
- Very good.
Thank you. Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
Ooh, ooh, okay, I got one. Uh...
Tell us a secret
that nobody knows about you.
Secret. Hmm.
Well, I don't know if it's a secret,
but the truth is that...
I wish you would've dared her to kiss me.
- Ooh!
- No, I heard it.
You heard it.
- Okay.
- Now that's a dare. Now that's a dare.
- Now that's a... Yup.
- Oh!
Yup.
- Oh. Oh my...
- Sprinkles.
♪ Tell me what to do ♪
♪ I'll say that I'm great ♪
♪ The people that surround me ♪
♪ Half of them are fake ♪
- ♪ But half of us was real... ♪
- Hell yeah. Sorry about that.
Everybody wants to know
where the dorms are...
You were my friend Allie's
prospective student. What're you studying?
Uh, poli-sci.
Okay. Whatever you do, avoid
Professor Holmes for political theory.
You going?
Where?
- To Dartmouth?
- Oh. Yes. Yes.
Yeah, I'm, like,
actually leaving tomorrow.
What's up?
Oh, it's so good.
Hey, what up, my man?
Uh, sorry, have you... have you seen Clare?
No, I... I haven't.
Are you good?
Cool, no, yeah.
You don't have to answer. It's all good.
I'm good. I'm fine.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
You seem fine.
- I'm good. Yes. No, we're good.
- You sure?
We're gonna be good.
You don't seem good.
♪ Tryna figure out
Who dat chick, who dat chick, who dat ♪
♪ Who dat chick, who dat chick, who dat
♪ Who dat chick, who dat chick ♪
Absolutely.
Yo! Yo, yo, can we, um...
can we cut the music real quick?
What's up, guys? How we doing?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
It's been a cool night, right?
- Oh, he's standing on a table.
- Yeah.
It's uh... it's been a year, man.
And it's just weird,
thinking about, like, moving on
and growing and... and all that stuff.
And, you know, you... you meet people,
and you hope that you have them
for a long time. It's crazy.
Some of us might see each other
in college, and some of us might not.
And the good parts,
I don't really want to end.
And I'm sure we all feel the same way.
Either way, it's the end of the year,
and it's the end of summer,
and... and what's... what's the end
without bringing it back
to the beginning, right? So that said, um,
I would love to invite Clare to come over.
- Yeah.
- Whoo!
Uh, it... it all started with a song,
if you guys remember, back at Halloween.
What's up, everybody?
Aidan. Aid...
♪ Gimme da loot, gimme da loot
Hands up, and I might not shoot ♪
♪ Swerving, blowing out of the coupe
White gold, champagne, campaign... ♪
Occupied.
Dude.
Oh.
It's not what it looks like.
It looks like
you're kissing my sister right now.
Well, yeah, you got me there.
- Aidan...
- We kissed. It's not a big deal.
You guys kissed?
I don't... I don't know what to say
about any of this.
About any of this, actually.
Wow.
We're gonna leave.
Yeah, um...
I don't know what the hell
that was back there.
Oh, it's just... it's me
trying to do some... anything to save us.
I'm sorry that you put
an impossible expectation on the night.
- That's not my fault.
- Impossible expectation?
Clare, we... we made a ridiculous joke pact,
and you somehow
turned it into a binding agreement.
It wasn't a joke. I know you think it was,
but I was very serious
when I said I wasn't going
to college in a relationship.
That was before we fell for each other.
That's... Sometimes things change.
Eventually, the prologue
turns into the book, Clare.
Right, because we're the ones who make it.
We're gonna feel the same way
for the rest of our lives.
We're not gonna hurt each other.
It's already starting.
We can't do this the rest of our lives.
Oh my God,
you should be studied for your ability
to see the worst possible outcome.
Aidan, but that's... Aidan!
That's not the worst possible outcome.
That's the most realistic one.
I'm sorry you can't be real,
but I kept it real with you,
and you couldn't even tell me
about Berklee.
What do you want me
to say about Berklee?
My parents finally let me apply,
I went to the audition and bombed it?
It was the most humiliating thing
I've ever experienced?
- There. There you go. There's Berklee.
- Oh my God.
Oh my God, Aidan, it's... it's the fart.
- It's always the fart.
- What are you talking about?
You have this impossible expectation
to be perfect all the time.
It's bleeding into everything.
- I'm not trying to be perfect.
- Yes, you are.
Berklee's not the only program.
There's hundreds of other programs.
You know what? Maybe if you told me
and let me in, I could've helped.
- But it's too late.
- No, no, you're right.
You're right. Is there a world
where I wish I could say screw it
and go to LA or New York
and try to make it work
and most likely fail doing so? Yeah, 100%.
And you say I'm unrealistic
when I'm going to school close to you
so we could try to make this work.
Don't use that as an excuse.
It's not why you're going to that school.
It's not an excuse when you believe in us.
It's not an excuse when I love you.
And maybe you would feel the same way
if... if... if you could actually say it.
- What are you talking about?
- Easy breezy. "I love you." "Easy breezy."
Do you have any idea how much it sucks
to tell someone you love them,
and their response is "easy breezy."
What does it even mean?
- You know exactly what it means.
- Just say it.
Just say it.
Yeah.
So we're... we're done.
Okay.
Come on.
Honey.
I feel like I can't breathe or something.
My heart's like beating out of my chest.
Okay, okay.
I know that you wanted it
to be painless between you and Aidan,
but that's... that's not how it works.
Not when it's real.
I just thought I was so careful.
You and Dad...
you know, you committed so young and...
and fought until you broke.
I just... I didn't wanna do that.
You were so unhappy, Mom.
Well, I'm no expert at love,
no need to tell you that,
but there is one thing that I do know.
And that's
a relationship doesn't have a shot in hell
if you start planning its end
before it even starts.
I just don't wanna lose myself.
If he's the right guy, he won't let you.
♪ Need some space ♪
♪ Just a little bit
Get my head together ♪
♪ Take my time ♪
♪ All of these questions
Fuel the pressure ♪
♪ Don't always know why ♪
♪ 'Cause I've been missing one to ones ♪
♪ Is my thinking overdone? ♪
♪ We don't see eye to eye ♪
♪ And I know it's not the same ♪
♪ 'Cause you messaged me again ♪
♪ Can I see you in person? ♪
♪ I really don't mind where ♪
♪ 'Cause what's the point in friends if ♪
♪ You're not even there ♪
♪ I'm finding it so hard ♪
♪ You know I'm bored of staying up ♪
♪ To watch the stars ♪
♪ You're still my friend ♪
♪ But all my days start just ♪
♪ As lonely as they end ♪
♪ I'm finding it so hard ♪
♪ You know I'm bored of staying up ♪
♪ To watch the stars ♪
♪ You're still my friend ♪
♪ But all my days start just ♪
♪ As lonely as they end ♪
I was afraid.
I was afraid of falling for you
because I was worried that if I did,
I wouldn't be able to be on my own again.
I don't know.
I've moved around my whole life,
and I've always been
just so focused on the future
and picturing what that was like.
I never put much energy into the now.
Then I met you...
...and I... I had the best time of my life.
But I was terrified. I...
You messed with my plan.
So here I am in the middle of the night
on a beach giving you this speech,
because I'm not afraid of that anymore.
And I wanna swim out to that buoy,
and I wanna finish this night,
and I wanna have our last first,
because I love you so much.
I love you.
Easy breezy.
♪ If this is love ♪
♪ I want my money back ♪
♪ My world's become a mess ♪
♪ I'm second-guessing all the things ♪
♪ I used to wanna be ♪
♪ So if you think it's love, it is ♪
Come on.
♪ And if you think it's trust, it is ♪
♪ So if you think it's love... ♪
It's so cold.
Maybe this was stupid.
♪ And if you think it's trust, it is ♪
Sorry. Come on.
So close.
♪ And if you think it's trust, it is ♪
This doesn't have to be the prologue.
Except it is.
You're right.
You're always right. It's really annoying.
♪ And if you think it's love, it is ♪
♪ And if you think it's trust, it is ♪
- So are you really gonna defer?
- Yeah.
Just going to LA.
Do you know where you're gonna live
and where you're gonna work and stuff?
Thank you
for the push that I needed.
You always make it work.
All right.
- What'd you pack in here? A body?
- Yeah.
I'm gonna miss you, dude.
Love you, bud.
Miss Nancy, you look good.
Done some exercise?
So...
- This is it.
- This... Yeah.
Yeah.
This doesn't have to be
the whole "goodbye" goodbye thing.
No.
No, no.
Could be like a "see you later."
See you later.
I like that plan.
Me too.
I'll see you later, then.
Lift.
♪ I'm not sure what you see in me ♪
♪ But I miss the nights we stay up late ♪
♪ With no care for what's tomorrow ♪
♪ I wish I had it in me ♪
♪ Three words that I just want to say ♪
♪ 'Cause your heart I want to follow ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm better with you ♪
♪ You're the reason ♪
♪ I don't want to feel it
The other way, another way ♪
♪ I'm elevated, come alive again ♪
♪ You show me a meaning, so hear me out ♪
♪ I don't want to get too deep ♪
♪ Oh man, that's too deep ♪
♪ But you're kind of
Everything I ever wanted ♪
♪ Everything I ever wanted ♪
♪ If I sound too cheap ♪
♪ It's 'cause I can't fight this feeling ♪
♪ You give me everything I ever wanted ♪
♪ Everything I ever wanted ♪
♪ Everything I ever wanted
Everything I ever wanted ♪
Heard the new song.
So good.
♪ Everything I ever wanted... ♪
Hey, stranger.
Thinking about you.
So I'm gonna be home
for the summer.
Too soon for a first hello?
♪ Would you come back home ♪
♪ If I told you the truth? ♪
♪ 'Cause I just can't let go ♪
♪ To the thought of who ♪
♪ I can be with you ♪
Hello.
♪ Everything I ever wanted ♪
♪ I know I can't ♪
♪ I can't be everything ♪
♪ All in one ♪
♪ Just the one for you ♪
♪ We make up ♪
- ♪ Up some pieces ♪
- ♪ Pieces ♪
♪ Puzzle pieces ♪
♪ We'll fit, all adding up ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going nowhere, yeah ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going nowhere, yeah ♪
♪ A balance act ♪
♪ I fill up everything ♪
♪ Down to one ♪
♪ Just the one, it's you ♪
♪ You make up ♪
- ♪ Up a pieces ♪
- ♪ Pieces ♪
♪ My favorite piece and ♪
♪ You fit, all adding up ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going nowhere, yeah ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going nowhere, yeah ♪
♪ A balance act ♪
♪ I fill up everything ♪
♪ Down to one ♪
♪ Just the one, it's you ♪
♪ You make up ♪
- ♪ Up a pieces ♪
- ♪ Pieces ♪
♪ Favorite piece and ♪
♪ You fit, all adding up ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going nowhere, yeah ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going nowhere, yeah ♪
♪ A balance act ♪
♪ I fill up everything ♪
♪ Down to one ♪
♪ Just the one, it's you ♪
♪ You make up ♪
- ♪ Up a pieces ♪
- ♪ Pieces ♪
♪ Favorite piece and ♪
♪ You fit, all adding up ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going nowhere, yeah ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going nowhere, yeah ♪
♪ I'm coming up with all the things ♪
♪ So won't
So won't you come and join me? ♪
♪ Life, life can deal some crazy things ♪
♪ But don't worry
Don't you worry, we'll find it ♪
♪ If you want a second to breathe ♪
♪ I'll give you all of my love
I'll give you all that you need, yeah ♪
♪ Don't worry, I'm not in a hurry ♪
♪ Not going nowhere ♪
♪ I'm not going... ♪