GRUPO GALlNDO
presents
in
HELL'S TRAP
with
Director of Photography
Original Music
- Story
- Screenplay
- Editor
- Assistant
Sound Editor
Executive Producers
A production of
Too bad, Mauricio.
Again you had to lose, brother.
- Right?
- Yes.
- Stop, Nacho.
- Let go!
- Calm down!
Now!
This one is a poor loser.
You're right.
This guy is a loser!
You know what?
Hand over the dough. Move it!
Give it to him!
Nice toy you have.
Look, Charly.
He pays for our beer again.
- How nice of you, man!
- Let's go to the bar.
Cheers.
Give up, Mauricio.
You are a loser--a poor loser.
Shut up, you idiot!
You know damn well
l can't stand that bastard.
As a matter of fact,
l just thought of something.
We're going to look for them
at the bar.
So pick everything up.
lsn't it true, my Charly?
Alejandra doesn't
want to believe me.
Well, there was a moment
when l was behind some pipes
and Mauricio walked by real, real close.
l don't know how he didn't see me.
- Oh, yeah, sure!
- l'm serious.
Please tell her, Charly.
She doesn't believe me, brother.
lt's true, it's true Alejandra.
Mauricio never saw him.
And l don't know how,
but in the end, Nacho shot him twice.
No, no, wait a minute!
They weren't two shots.
They were two ink pills.
And by the way, those toys
are kind of fun. Right, Charly?
Okay, okay, l do believe you.
And l love the fact
that you beat Mauricio.
But what l don't like is that
you are always fighting with him.
Oh, Alejandra, are you going
to start with that again?
Don't make such an issue, will you?
All right, but keep in mind
that you don't make me happy.
Hey, you know that Mauricio is a clown.
Watch it, watch it.
Look who's coming in.
Oh, dear God,
why do you do this to me?
Show up with this asshole.
Oh, no, Nacho!
Are you all going to start again?
l want them to come to my table,
so go and tell them exactly what l told you.
What you did today
was real good, Nacho.
There's no question about it.
You were better than Mauricio.
And he already accepted it.
Except that this time
we have something new to offer you.
Stop the nonsense!
What's behind this?
Let Mauricio tell you.
Except this time, it's not a game.
Nacho!
Don't you want to see this?
Oh, Mauricio! Mauricio!
What are you planning now?
Since you like to compete so much,
l thought of something more interesting.
Something that
you might be interested in.
''Massacre.
''Three hunters dead
and two missing at Filo de Caballo.
They're sure it was a bear.''
So what's with this?
Oh, Mauricio, that's enough!
Stop wasting your time.
These guys will never accept your bet.
What's it about?
Look, Alejandra,
this is what it's about.
Whoever kills the bear
will be the winner.
Don't fall for his game, Nacho.
All of this is stupid.
Hey, hey, hey!
Since when
do you decide for him, Alejandra?
What? Doesn't he wear the pants?
What's your plan?
What's the bet?
This time there will be no bet.
lt's about showing the town
who's best!
Besides, you owe me a rematch.
Do it, Nacho!
You know they will not beat us.
Listen carefully to what
l am going to say, Mauricio.
l will give you the rematch,
but this will be the last time
l make a bet with you.
Did you understand me?
The newspaper says that the bear
is around Filo de Caballo,
and that place is about
five hours away from here.
So Charly and l recommend
that you all go to bed early.
Look, you don't need to worry about us.
lt's not the first time
that we've gone hunting.
Keep this. lt's yours to read.
Don't worry.
We'll make them look ridiculous.
You'll see.
Look, l'm sorry, Alejandra.
l couldn't get out of this one.
Please understand me, will you?
Yes. l know, Nacho.
l just hope that this is really
the last time you wager with him.
l promise!
No, no, no, no!
Don't think this is going to be free.
There's just one condition.
Whatever you want!
Which one?
That this time...
l am going with you.
Hey, but...
l'm going to the car for some things.
- Listen, how...
- l'm going to the office for some things.
And now
what is Mauricio doing here?
Well, who knows?
But it smells like food.
Quesadillas, beans with epazote...
Good nose!
You can't think of anything else.
That is why you have such a big belly!
Big belly!
You wish!
Contrary to the dog feast
with your sack of bones!
Just wait and see.
Oh! You're the one who has to watch out
if you keep messing with me.
What a strange place. l can't understand
what Mauricio is doing here.
lt looks as if something
was for sale, right?
Quesadillas.
Well, l am only interested in 30-06.
But you want to take advantage
of me, Mr. Jeremias.
All right.
Thirty thousand for all of them.
Javier, pay him.
Oh, Mr. Jeremias,
l want you to meet my best friend,
Nacho Castillo.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- How are you, young man?
What place are you going hunting?
Well, we are going to Filo de Caballo.
Do you know how far we are from there?
Did you say Filo de Caballo?
The problem is not the distance,
young lady,
but how to get out of there.
You're about ten...or...
fifteen minutes away.
l have something for you
that could be useful.
One million pesos.
And l guarantee that it's a gift...
considering what you plan to do.
Well...l don't know...
We don't understand
what you're talking about.
We're just going hunting.
Listen to me, you kids!
You are not going
on a normal hunting trip.
For an additional
ten thousand pesos...
l can tell you
the story of that place.
Well, Mr. Jeremias,
thank you for everything.
Follow me.
l need to tell you something.
Kids. Don't go, man.
Look, you guys, l'll give it to you
for half a million pesos!
You'll need it!
Hey, Mr. Jeremias,
Mr. Jeremias, listen.
How much do you want
for this helmet?
Go to the pickup.
Can't you see where this old man lives?
He's crazy!
What's that he said
that we need to get ready for war?
l don't understand.
Those are just stupid ramblings.
Don't pay attention to him.
Anyway, if you want to hang around
and talk, that's your business.
lt's getting late.
l am going ahead.
What a weird guy, huh?
l don't know, Nacho, but there is
something he said that l don't like.
Yeah. You're right.
Well, don't worry about it.
l'll make sure Mauricio
tells us what it is about.
Let's go.
Hey, and Charly?
We'll see you, Jeremias.
l'll come by another day!
Thank you.
How did you get that? How much
did he charge you for the helmet?
l didn't pay for it.
l just paid the tax.
This is the closest place to the lake.
We are about 1 ,000 feet from there,
so you have to unload everything.
Sorry about that, Alejandra.
We have to carry it.
But let's get his help, right?
Go on, wake him up.
Pull!
That's as far as it will go.
Well, then, it's done.
- lt's done?
- lt's done.
Make sure it is well tied down,
otherwise the wind will blow it away!
lt's done. The knot is real good!
Perfect.
Then it's ready. lt is perfect!
We do fit, right?
With Charly?
No. We won't fit.
Let's go to the boat
for the rest of the stuff.
Careful.
Javier! Look for
the other rag, please.
Sure.
Darn it! lt is getting late.
Are you guys not going
to get your swimsuits on?
The day is great to sunbathe.
No, l don't have time for that.
We have little light left,
and l want to go after that damned bear.
Javier, are you not
going to stay with us?
l know what l'll miss,
but you heard Mauricio.
Remember we're dealing with a bet.
Yes. Let's go.
We'll see you, baby!
Let's go. Mauricio is leaving.
Gimme.
ls that it?
No. l don't think so.
Finding a bear is not that easy.
That must have been Mauricio.
He must have confused it with a rabbit.
Hey! What's wrong with you?
What did you shoot at?
A rabbit.
A rabbit?
We came here for a bear!
By shooting you only scare it away!
Don't do it again!
Now it's your turn.
You go for it.
Carlota!
Diana!
Hey, Nacho.
Do you really think
we're going to find something?
l think the bear story is not true.
Oh, please, Alejandra!
What happened to that optimism?
We just got here,
and already you're exasperated?
Give it your best!
Charly, are we going
to search or not?
All right.
l'll search over there.
Charly!
l found human remains.
Let's go! Let's go!
Don't worry. lt wasn't anything.
You'll be fine tomorrow.
Thank you, Nacho.
l owe you one.
Hey, Javier.
Lucky these guys came, right?
At least they were good for something.
l'm going over to Mauricio's.
He has something to tell me.
Do you want some advice?
Why don't you go and ask Charly
how l get when l'm upset.
That could help you a lot!
Listen.
l think it was a mistake
to bring the women.
Why don't they just leave?
They're just a burden,
don't you agree?
Are you going to get started?
Very funny. l don't think l have
anything to do here.
Well, anyway.
l came to do my thing,
and you can do what you want.
Look, l can't decide for your friends,
but l think the best thing to do
is to spend the night here.
l already told you what l saw,
Mauricio.
And you better tell me
what you know about this place.
lt's nonsense, the old man's stories!
Well, stories or not, there's a boy
in the forest that's completely mutilated!
And what about the trap
that Javier fell in?
There's someone else here
besides us. Who is it?
lt could be the one they call Jesse.
According to Jeremias,
Jesse was an American soldier
who came here after the war
to live with some friends.
As a matter of fact,
Jeremias' truck was theirs.
Supposedly
this Jesse guy went mad.
He thinks he's still at war.
Furthermore, he thinks
everyone is his enemy.
No! Are you crazy or what?
Why did you keep all this to yourself?
Why didn't you tell us before?
Because l don't believe in those things.
Did you hear that?
A while ago l heard it,
but on the other side.
lt must be a rabbit,
or something else.
Turn the lamps off!
Don't fire, Mauricio!
lt's impossible for us to see him!
So, just stories.
lt's Viviana.
Did someone see where she went?
l just saw her go over there.
l told you! Women are a problem!
Wait for me here.
l'll go get her.
Be very careful, Nacho.
l am in the river.
No!
Viviana is dead.
What?
What are you saying?
l'm sorry. lt's the truth.
We can't waste any more time.
We've got to get
out of this place somehow!
Let's go.
Mauricio, Viviana is dead.
Didn't you hear it?
That's not my problem.
Before leaving l told both of them
what we were going to do here.
So let's go.
No, no, wait a minute!
You're not giving orders here.
Besides, to leave right now
would be stupid.
That guy knows this place
better than us.
Charly, Alejandra, and l are staying.
Javier and Carlota
can decide for themselves.
Do you agree?
Nacho is right. We're staying.
All right, but then someone
has to stand guard here.
l think that's a good idea.
What do you say we start with you?
We have to gather the ammunition
in one or two bags.
We better spend the night in this tent.
Okay, guys.
l think this is it.
Are you ready?
How ridiculous you are! You want us
to stay two more days here or what?
Okay. Javier and Charly, go ahead.
Get the women in the middle.
Mauricio and l will cover you.
Be careful.
Hey, Nacho! Mauricio!
Hurry up. The pickups
are over here. Let's go!
Grab here!
Come on, climb!
Hey, Nacho.
l think something happened to my hand.
Can you cure me?
On the hand?
lt's dirt. lt's nothing. Let's go!
Hey, baby.
Hey, Alejandra!
What's the matter with you?
You can't be fooled
if you have been warned.
Alejandra! Again?
Hey! He's over there.
That crazy guy.
He went into the woods.
Let's get out of here.
We have to hurry.
No, Nacho, wait!
This guy has traps all over the place.
lf we don't catch him now,
we will never be able to get out of here.
He's right.
Javier, drive the pickup.
You all go ahead with him.
We'll ride in the back.
Hurry up!
This is it.
lf we follow him,
we can hunt him down.
Let's go!
We can't let him go alone.
He can't be far.
Let's go after him.
Please!
Carlota! No!
- Wait.
- Let go of me.
- Calm down.
- Calm down, Javier.
- No!
How are we going to get out of here?
Wait for me here.
l'm going to check around.
We shouldn't have ever
chased the madman.
l don't know how we listened to you!
Hey, Charly,
l don't see Nacho.
Alejandra, come.
Don't worry.
Soon we will get out of here.
That guy can't be smarter than us.
You're an idiot!
Viviana and Carlota are dead
because of you, or haven't you noticed?
l going to check to see
how Javier is doing.
Do you feel better?
What happened was terrible.
l understand.
But that's life!
We all run the same risk.
You have to accept it.
What do you mean, Mauricio?
Look, let's not fool ourselves, Javier.
Carlota and Viviana
were just a temporary fling for us.
Furthermore they're the ones
who wanted to come.
lt's not your fault.
You're crazy, Mauricio.
- lt's Javier and Mauricio.
- Let's go.
Nacho!
Mauricio!
You go that way.
Nacho!
Alejandra! Are you all right?
l'm fine. l hurt my ankle,
but it's nothing.
Drop to the ground!
Alejandra, don't move.
Charly should be close by.
Nacho!
Alejandra!
Charly! We're down here!
Remove the branches.
How did you get in there?
What a dummy.
Remove the branches
so we can get out. Move it!
Nacho and Alejandra are down there.
Help them get out.
There it goes. Grab it.
You got here just in time, Charly!
And not just that,
l blew the madman's hand off!
- What?
- Yes!
- How did you blow one of his hands off?
- With a shot! Pow!
l blew his hand off.
Look at the puddle of blood.
That's my Charly!
Good old Charly!
That should stop him chasing us.
- Yeah.
- Although...
We'd better try to get out of here.
l think that if we follow the river,
it will take us directly to the road.
Could be.
Let's go, let's go. Hurry up.
Well, this time you were wrong.
Because here...
there's no sign of a road!
l know.
But as long we don't have to see
that maniac again,
l don't mind walking all day.
Let's go.
Guys! l found the road.
That's my Charly!
We made it, guys!
Hey! Look over there.
lt's Jeremias' truck.
Home sweet home.
We made it!
l never thought l'd be so happy
to see Jeremias.
Well, knock.
Don't waste your time knocking.
The damned man must be sleeping.
Besides, he's half deaf.
Well, then, go right in.
Jeremias!
You see? What did l tell you?
The old man must be real drunk.
His bed is behind that curtain.
Let's wake him up.
Hurry, hurry.
What happened?
lt's impossible!
That was Jesse.
l don't know how.
l don't know how,
but he got ahead of us!
Let's go, please.
We have to go, please!
Calm down, Mauricio!
We can't go out now.
He must be waiting for us outside.
Pay attention!
The worst thing we could do
is leave this place!
No! l'm leaving.
l am leaving.
You want to kill me.
You all want to kill me!
l'll take care of him.
Mauricio!
Charly.
- Charly, are you okay?
- l can't see!
Alejandra!
Wake up!
Alejandra is gone.
Come on.
What are you doing?
Can't you see?
We need weapons and bullets.
Calm down.
Listen to me!
Calm down, Nacho!
What's the matter?
That guy took Alejandra.
That guy wants to play with us.
And l don't think that this
is the way to play his game!
Okay, what do you suggest?
Let's go to town for help.
Don't speak nonsense!
You are making me waste time.
Look.
This guy is not going to hurt Alejandra.
What he wants is for you to go after him.
lf that wasn't the case, he would have
already killed us when he was here.
All right, Charly, all right.
And how do you plan to get to town?
There's a vehicle outside.
l don't know what it is doing there,
but let's go in it.
That's it, my Charly.
What you're saying isn't that bad.
But you know what?
lt's best if you go by yourself.
- But how am l going to go by myself?
- Yes, Charly, pay attention.
That way l can get ahead.
lf l find the guy, l will light a fire.
That will make it easier
for you to find the place!
Do you understand?
Sure.
Sure, you're right!
Let's get going, my Charly.
We're running out of time.
Be careful.
You too.
No!
Charly!
Damn you.
Son of a bitch!
You are going to die.
Nacho!
Alejandra!
- Are you all right?
- Fine.
And Charly?
Charly is dead.
Take cover!
Nacho...
he brought me through that tunnel.
On the other side
we'll be close to the road.
Let's go!
Let's go.
l'm sure that Jeremias' truck
is close by.
Let's go.
Hurry up! Come on!