Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
That,
that is what I like to see.
Passion!
You guys,
you guys fought for every
square inch of the ice tonight.
You let them know they
were in our house!
How about Justin here
taking the lead as always.
And Matty, Matty absolutely
bleeding for it in the corners.
And how about these two
young guns over here,
Tyson and Schultzy banking
in those hard minutes
at the end of the second.
Let's give it over.
I think we all know who this
hardware goes to tonight.
Let's give it over.
Way to go.
King for our knights!
That's how the
fucking warriors do it!
Yeah!
Harper, you know what Yeezy
says, watch the throne baby.
I'm coming for that crown bud.
You get hit in the head too
many times tonight Schultzy?
Or are you still spinning
from when that guy
turned you inside out out there.
You don't know
what you're talking about bro.
That there is
an education bud.
Playing with the big boys now.
Yeah big boys,
that's for sure eh?
Your fucking fat ass can
hardly get up and down the ice.
You little bitch.
Easy boys, give it a
rest, Dylan have a seat.
Alright as you all know
I take a lot of pride
in wearing the C.
It means a lot more to me than
just a letter on my jersey,
just like coach always
says, everyone has a role,
and every role has
it's responsibility.
So I want you rookies to
get up there for a minute.
Look we've all been
rookies before,
we all know what it's like.
New town, new teammates,
we've all been there.
You boys have shown
us a lot so far.
We're proud of you, and so
as is tradition
a proper Warriors welcome
means we gotta scalp em!
Come on!
Mother fucker!
Ahh!
Won't stop now boy!
Oh crying for your mother huh?
Hey Wendy.
Looks like
this little devil
has been keeping you occupied.
He's good, tons of fun huh?
Thank you for
keeping an eye on him.
Let me give you
a hand with that.
Thank you, that's
very sweet of you.
- Is Cody home?
- Huh?
Is Cody here?
Uh no, I think he went over
to Tracy's after practice.
Left you all alone huh?
I guess.
Hey Bill.
Hey, hey.
Can I give you
a hand with that?
Sure, thank you.
Just get it down to
the crawl space there.
Hey.
Hold on, hold on, okay.
The theme of the
game this week is focus.
If I'm gonna play on the
fourth line I need to be
so concentrated, so in
tune with what's going on.
Party.
Is your head still tingling
from that fucking yeti hit?
No man, I'm fine.
You know that ringing sound
when everything
is totally quiet?
What do you mean?
When like if you're
all alone somewhere,
and everything's completely
silent, like nothing.
Not like this cause
the heater's going
but if it's actually
quiet like nothing.
Yeah no I think I know
what you mean it's just that,
it's like your ears
or something right?
Yeah.
Like that type of ringing
is just you hear nothing,
or something like that.
Pretty much.
I used to hate that
when I was a kid though.
Oh yeah?
Yeah I just, I don't know
it just really bothered me.
- Huh.
- Still makes me feel weird.
Oh yeah?
Yeah.
I get really sick to
my stomach and sweaty.
It would feel like,
I don't know like what a
black hole would feel like,
or something, can't
really explain it.
Huh.
I get all freaked
out and scared,
so my parents would have
to put on this music
so I would like relax and
eventually fall asleep.
Oh yeah, what type of music
would they play for you?
Didn't matter.
Anything, just like
any sound, any noise
just to drown out that ringing.
Yeah I
don't know I never,
never really had any problems
sleeping when I was a kid,
I was always super afraid
of heights actually.
But yeah, never scared of the
dark or anything like that.
I didn't say I was
cared of the dark.
I don't
know, I don't know.
Its just that sound of like,
the way I feel when I hear
that sound, like nothing.
I'm not trying to freak
you out right now man.
- You're good.
- Alrighty.
Night buddy.
That a boy that a boy.
30 more!
Oh man, you killed that
man, nice work man.
Thank you.
What's up baby boy?
Woo!
Where's the knock back?
Hey nobody can left
your ugly ass bro.
Hey you know what
kid you talk too much,
fucking blah blah blah.
Such a
fucking charity case huh?
What you say?
Hey you
little whipping boy.
Don't take it out on me.
You shut your mouth or I'm
gonna sick the boy on you.
Listen just cause we
got you from make a wish
doesn't mean I'm gonna
be all nice to you
you fat fuck.
At least I'm not from
fucking Maple Ridge
you little honky tonk bitch.
You gotta fucking problem,
where you going hey!
Look at you fucking hiding.
Which way you going?
Why don't you take out
what's in front of you?
That's right.
Oh hey watch it.
Fuck yeah!
Busted eh boys?
You boys are lucky this
guy's a lawyer and not a cop.
Relax boys I'm on your side.
These are
the young princes.
Oh, they make a lot
bigger now a days don't they?
No kidding.
Wendy said she wanted to get
a Rottweiler for the house
or something, I said
why don't you just get
a couple of hockey players.
They already come house trained.
More or less eh boys.
Don't worry I won't tell nobody.
K, goodnight fellas.
- Night Bill.
- Night night.
Bricks and mortar.
These things.
They're important right?
They are important because we
are building something here.
We're building
something that is great.
Because at the end of the day,
these things need to be built.
They don't just appear,
there's no magic potion,
there's no shortcuts, but
they have to be built.
Because you're only going
to get out what you put in.
I mean this is why
we work hard right?
This is why we burn and bleed.
To achieve greatness, it's
like we have to take this
rough hewn piece of steel
and we gotta pound it,
until we get Excalibur.
You know that story right?
The story of King
Arthur and the sword.
Well, here's a little
history lesson for you.
Because history my
friends is so important.
Because when you look at the
history books from school
or google or wherever the hell
you get your history
from nowadays,
what's the thing that you
see and remember the most?
Heroes.
Hm?
Because last time I checked,
there isn't any room
in the history books
for losers now is there?
No sir.
No.
Championships, banners,
trophies, all of that,
that was determined by
people who were writing
their own history.
This is the place
where it happens.
Not amongst the glamor
or the spotlights
or how many likes
on your phones,
no, no, no none of that.
Because it's here in this place
where we build our own legacy.
This is where it all comes from.
That's it move him move him.
That's the way, work
for it work for it!
Who wants it more,
that's it good.
Move him out there.
Easy easy, that's it,
it's okay it's okay.
Good amount of aggression there,
that's exactly what we need
when we're in the corners.
Not get in a fight, whoever
wants it most gets it.
Beautiful, go.
That's what I want
to see from you man,
show me that, show
me lots of that.
Next two.
The nose?
No let me see it.
Very cute.
Fucking right I'm cute boys.
Man you're such a dumbass.
Dude I look like I could
beat the shit out of everyone.
Oh yeah?
That's coming from the big
boy that believes in ghosts.
Oh yeah, ghost
whisperer over here.
Alright fuck you guys
cause that shit's real.
So laugh all you want.
What are you talking about?
The hotel in Cranbrook,
he thought he saw.
Alright, fuck you guys.
Next time I'm going
to befriend the ghost
and I'm gonna have him
haunt every last one of you.
Then we'll see who's laughing.
- I got like candles out,
- Yep me and my ghost friend.
Grams and Gramps,
back from the dead.
They got walkers
and dentures and shit.
Howling after us
biting us or something.
Just use your movie method,
you know when you close
your eyes, plug your ears,
and just know that
everything's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be alright.
I thought that was your
method with the ladies.
It's true, it's true.
Yo Cody buddy, hey Cody.
Yeah, what's up?
Do you know how to do this?
Uh maybe let's see.
It's damn near impossible.
Fuck man I don't know.
See.
How do you do yours?
Oh I just I got one
of those clip on ones.
This is ridiculous.
Struggling?
Hey.
Do you want it any longer?
I think that works.
Good.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
You guys will have
to shine your own shoes though.
Come on!
Guys you're going on the open
ice, that's not how you do it!
Come on Kellan!
Same.
Brutal.
Unbelievable.
Come on!
Let's go, bring it up the
boards, up the boards,
I'm not gonna say it again!
Screaming my god
damn head off here.
That's it, let's go,
let's go, let's go!
Is everyone on fucking vacation!
What the fuck is wrong
with you guys huh!
Can somebody please tell me
what the fuck is going
on out there, huh?
One of you guys come on.
Cause I have no fucking
idea what's going on!
Can one of you
enlighten me please?
You are fucking embarrassing
yourselves tonight.
You're embarrassing me,
and you're embarrassing
every single fucking fan
that's out there, watching you.
For some fucking reason
you guys have decided
to stay out of the corner
and off the fucking boards.
And on top of that
they're taking liberties
with our top guys and what
the fuck you guys doing?
Nothing!
They are in our
house for fucks sake.
Our fucking house
for fucks sake!
Protect the fucking house!
Will somebody wake the fuck up?
Let's go warriors!
Let's go warriors.
Break it up,
break it up boys!
Let go.
We're done.
You're done.
How am I done?
You're done,
hitting from behind.
They're jumping on me.
Let's go, you're done,
you want another game?
To the dressing room let's go.
Wait what about this guy?
To the dressing room.
Hey!
Dressing room or
you get another game, go.
What the fuck was that about?
Don't worry about it.
These guys are
fucking all over me,
I didn't know what the
fuck was happening.
I didn't know what was going on.
- I know, it's okay.
- I'm going back.
- Calm down.
- Move Coach get off me!
Calm down, take
it easy, stop it!
You're not going back out there
it's a bit of a cirus right now.
What the fuck man, these
guys are jumping all over me!
Take a breath, calm down.
- What happened?
- Shh.
What happened out
there to this kid?
I'm looking around he's
not getting up off the ice,
- what happened?
- They're loading him up.
Is he okay?
We don't know yet, he's
going to the hospital.
They'll check him out.
Just take it easy.
Let's go get changed.
Let's get you
changed up, come on.
Oh shit.
Get you a lift home.
Hey Coach, it's Tyson calling.
I just wanted to get you
on the phone and check in,
see what's going on.
I guess I'm gonna see you
guys this afternoon anyways,
but I never got a chance to
talk to anyone since last night.
Yeah, so I just
wanted to check in.
Just give me a shout back when
you can, please thank you.
Hey Tyson, come in here man.
I was just wandering
around downstairs there.
Didn't see anybody, but
I was trying to figure
out what's going on.
Haven't really had a chance
here to talk to anybody
since last night.
I know, we know, well things
have been pretty chaotic
around here as you can imagine.
Everybody's got
their mind on you.
It's been wacky the last
16 hours, let me tell you.
But, we have a number of
issues we have to weed through,
with the league,
and the media right.
Yeah I know for sure.
I'm just wondering what I
can do, what I should do.
Honestly probably the
best thing you could do
is just take it easy.
Go lay low, alright.
You don't need to be talking
to anybody about this.
Don't need to concern
yourself with any of this.
We got people to take
care of that, right?
Yep.
How is he?
He's in the hospital.
That's all we know.
Hey listen man, around here
we're worried about you alright.
Worried about making
sure you're good to go.
So just try to take it easy.
You alright?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Yeah it's just a
little overwhelming.
Well uh, things are
getting pretty chaotic.
Gotta get back to business here.
Back to work, but uh.
Thanks for seeing me,
and taking the time.
I appreciate it.
Oh yeah, like I said man,
just take it easy, alright?
And you'll be alright.
The game
came to a disturbing end
after a violent hit by
Prince's defenseman Tyson Burr
left Cheif's player Kyle
Ridlowe critically injured.
I don't
know exactly what
his condition is right now,
we have not heard specifically.
All I can say right now is that
all of our hearts and
prayers are with Kyle.
This
morning doctors said
that Ridlowe was
in stable condition
but the extent of his
injuries are severe.
The hit left him with
a broken vertebrae
as well as hemorrhaging
in his brain.
In a moment the young
man's life changed forever.
It's
disgusting, disgusting.
How is that a hockey play?
They're down in the
third, down by five.
Five nothing.
Nobody can tell me that
that's a hockey play.
You scared me.
Sorry about that.
I don't know what to do.
I feel like,
I don't know.
Just feel like I'm messed
up or something you know?
Like sick.
Well there's Tylenol and
all that in the kitchen.
Do you need something,
you can help yourself.
Have any need to
be inconvenienced at all.
Appreciate that.
Hey Tyson.
Hey coach.
Well it's
good to see you.
Yeah
likewise, I gotta run
but I'm sure we'll talk soon.
Hey Bill take care.
See you soon.
Tyson, why don't
you come have a seat.
How you doing Tyson?
Good, thanks.
Tyson, this is Elliot
Carr, he's an attorney.
He does some specific
work for the organization
from time to time.
Pleased to meet you Tyson.
Nice to meet you.
Elliot's just here to
go over a few things.
Some technical detail stuff.
So the league is reviewing
this whole incident.
And we've been speaking
back and forth with them,
and well we've been
waiting to hear back
about any disciplinary action.
We've been looking
into our options
and we've decided to make
some organizational decisions
based on the current situation.
At this point, we're
suspending you indefinitely.
I know that's not what
you wanted to hear,
but you need to see this
as an act of good faith.
This is a chance for the
team to show the league
that we're willing to
take responsibility
for what happened here.
- Okay.
- Okay good.
Now this is all just
part of the process.
We just have to make
sure that everybody
comes out alright here okay?
Now to make this easier,
Elliot has drafted up
a statement for you
for the team to
release on your behalf.
Um, I can read it for
you now, if you like Tyson.
Please, yeah please.
We just want to
get it out there.
Be able to put it
out there right away.
Of course.
First and foremost, I
wish to extend my heartfelt
thoughts and sympathies
to Kyle Ridlowe
and his family, his
friends, and his teammates.
My prayers are with each
and every one of them
in this difficult time.
I'm profoundly sorry
for both the physical
and emotional hurt I have caused
and I cannot forgive myself
for inflicting these wounds,
but I can try my very best
to take full responsibility
for my actions.
I also wish to issue an
apology to my teammates,
my team, our fans and the
entire city of Prince George.
What happened on Friday night
was not at all reflective
of the values or culture of
the Prince George Warriors.
And I am very sorry that
my individual actions
have cast such a dark
shadow over the organization
and this city.
I'm prepared to be fully
accountable for what I have done
and hope that
through this process
am able to repair some of
the damage I have cost.
Now this
is a chance for you
to get out in front
of this thing okay?
We can put this
out there for you,
and all you need to
do is step back okay?
You don't need to
talk to anyone,
or do anything alright?
Alright.
I didn't mean for
that to happen.
Hey, we're
not here to judge
the way you play the game, okay?
We're just here to help.
I know.
Thank you guys.
Guess I just feel bad you know?
I know you do.
And this, this
says you do, okay?
Yeah.
How long is indefinite?
We'll have
to wait and see.
Okay.
Nice talking with
you Tyson, take care.
Thank you.
We'll
see you again soon.
You bet Coach.
Hey Bill.
Hey.
Listen,
I've spoken with Wendy over
the last couple of days here,
after discussing things
we feel at this point
it would be appropriate for you
to find another place to stay.
I don't really
have anywhere to go.
Look, we're not trying to
complicate things here but,
this is our home.
I got priorities to our son.
And with that in mind,
I don't feel comfortable
having you around here.
Yeah, I understand that.
I uh,
I'll figure something
out, I will.
I'm not telling
you to pack your bags
right this minute and get out
on the street tonight but,
by tomorrow you need to
have your situation sorted.
That's fair.
Like I say, my
responsibility is to my family.
I don't want people coming
around knocking on my door
and I don't want to explain
what the commotion is
to my son, you know?
He's just a kid, he's
young, he's impressionable.
Yeah I know.
He needs positive role
models around here and not,
this other stuff you know.
Yep.
So I'm a fair
person you know but,
my family always
comes first, always.
Always you know.
Yeah, I know.
I respect that.
Hey brother.
Alright, so that's you.
Perfect man, thank again.
That's alright.
So you just gonna
chill for a bit, or what
cause we gotta head to the
rink pretty quick here.
Yeah I'll probably
step out or something.
Well if you want to shower
you know where it is right?
Yeah I know, just back there.
- Cool.
- Cool man.
Yeah I'm gonna get
going, talk to you later.
- See you later buddy.
- Yeah see you.
Take it easy okay?
Yeah man, have a good one.
Dude for real, she's the best.
Tron fucking broke.
Oh my god, Tronda's
fucking broke.
Danger cat.
Is a danger cat.
Get any
refills for you guys?
Good thanks.
And the second one
when they go to the screamer.
Yeah that's the one!
As a kid I was up
there, I remember,
fucking knees shaking,
scared out of my mind.
After my grandma when,
it went straight all
the way up the sign.
Granny.
It was so bad that I
puked, shit and puked.
I know man I'm such a pussy.
There's your change.
Thank you sweetie, oh
it's right this time.
I'd wash your hands first.
What's that buddy?
I wasn't talking to you
disgraceful piece of shit.
Hey fuck you!
Whoa, whoa!
Fuck you!
Hey hey hey!
Get off my property!
Fuck you sack of shit.
Fuck you!
Burr, woo!
You know next time I'll let
you knock him out alright.
That's right baby, damn
that was a good one.
Fuck yeah!
Hey man.
What's up man?
Not much.
Where's Derek?
He's already gone.
Is that right.
Yeah,
coach wants to see us
both earlier today so.
You gotta bounce.
Yeah man.
See you later.
Yeah.
- Hey.
So what's your plan?
He's gonna work.
Yeah, I'm gonna go
see Hank tomorrow,
see if he's got
any shifts for me
over at the slaughter house.
Good.
I'll also get you working
on the old property.
Haven't any time to get to that.
Gotta rip down that fence.
Get all the wrecks
off the acreage
and finally tackle
that house, finally.
Yeah for sure.
I'll stay busy.
It's probably just going to
be for a little while anyway.
Well it's
nice you're home.
Hey Coach it's Tyson calling,
I was just hoping to
have a chat with you
when you get a moment.
I've been taking some time
to straighten myself out here
and yeah I'm really looking
forward to getting back
and contributing and just
being a part of the team,
helping you guys out.
Yeah, just looking forward
to getting back out there.
So if you could give me a shout
back when you get a chance
that would be really
great, alright thank you.
Gotta clear
everything out of here.
May as well start
in the living room.
Look at this, garbage.
And the bathroom
I guess, stinks.
It's crap.
Keep anything of
value, metal, copper,
toss it in the truck.
Whatever.
Whatever you can salvage.
Thought of tackling this eyesore
just gives me a headache.
Anyway I'll talk to the
guy and see what day
the can actually take her down.
Alright.
Just, do the best you can.
Yep.
Alright.
At one point she had two kids
and I guess she was
jealous of me sleeping.
I didn't get much sleep,
I had to work the next day
for Popolson, and I was driving
from Prince George to
Smithers on a coastal run.
Popolson's
a good company.
I got a buddy work for them.
It's not too bad.
I'd say good good.
Yeah?
I told Jack, he
decided to retire.
Oh okay.
Harold was in order
but Jack took off.
Right?
So anyway I was driving
form Houston to Smithers
thinking I wasn't that tired,
ended up doing a little
bit of the blinks,
going down the road.
Whoa whoa, you gotta come out
and play hockey tonight man.
Don't forget they
guys gotta see you.
I know, Phil was saying
something about it.
Yeah, I might do that.
Yeah, new age hockey.
Skates with a walker.
I'll have my head up.
You'll like it, they're
a good bunch of guys man,
you'll like it.
No I mean I went to
one game, it was a gift.
I don't know, I'd
rather watch it on TV.
I went to a Buffalo
Sabers game growing up,
versus Toronto and then
I like being at home.
Hey, somebody come here!
I want to talk to somebody!
Hey!
I'm waiting here, come here!
Somebody hey!
I know you can hear me!
Come here and talk to me!
This is my house.
This is our home.
We built this place,
and you need to show
some god damn respect for that.
You just don't seem
to get it do you?
You have all these
people out there
bending over backwards
trying to help you.
And you just keep shoveling
shit back in their faces.
Do you have any idea what we've
been though because of you?
Any idea at all?
The embarrassment, the
fucking humiliation!
Do you?
That's a question!
You need to learn
to take some responsibility
for you actions.
You're not a god damn child.
Get your shit together.
Please dial 374.
You've
reached Coach Weller,
please leave a
message, thank you.
Is the window for style
points here or what?
No it was just an accident.
I say you just chop
the roof altogether man
and rock a little
convertible action you know?
Oh I'm on a budget.
Tyson.
Tyson, Eric.
Nice to meet you.
What happened to
your hand there bud?
It's like um.
You know man don't
even worry about it.
Shit happens you know.
Yeah shit happens.
So you
from around here?
Yep, I was away for awhile
but now I'm back
for a little bit.
Well you picked the proper
spot for a vacation huh?
Yeah.
See you back in there.
Alright.
Ah, fuck!
Ah!
Oh fuck.
What's up man?
Hey.
So you get that window fixed?
Not yet, nope.
Gonna take her in sometime soon.
Yeah I could have a
look at it if you like?
Do you do that kind of stuff?
I dabble, a little bit of
this, a little bit of that.
Yeah.
How'd you end up here?
I was working a rig about
150 clicks north of here,
I was just sick and
tired of the rat race.
Had big plans you know.
Shacked up with the old lady,
I wanted to take that extra
step and get a house going
and maybe get a couple little
young ones running around.
Nine months in she
went and started
a whole new life without me so.
Shit man.
Kind of shook up.
Sucks.
What are you gonna do?
At least I got out of there,
it was such a dark place,
you need to stay focused,
stay positive you know?
Take the good with
the bad you know?
Yep.
Should probably get
back to work huh?
Yeah you should
get back in there.
Hey!
Yeah it totally
seems doable man.
I mean I've never done
anything like this before,
but doesn't seem impossible.
That'd be wicked man.
How much would you
charge for that?
I don't know like a
hundred bones maybe,
you wouldn't have to cover
much after parts and stuff so.
Definitely.
I could place an
order on Monday.
Yeah.
I would probably
take a couple of weeks.
Rolling with the Saran
wrap until then so.
Cool man, well you
wanna come in for a beer?
Yeah, I could have one.
So you found the bathroom
alright in my mansion?
You should see the fucking
place I'm working on.
What you got a little
rental job on the go?
Yeah, it's basically
like this scrap job
on one of our properties.
Just trying to pull whatever
we can out of there you know.
Collect from the floors, walls.
Most of it's rusted to shit.
Woods all finished but
there's a few things.
And after that we're just gonna
knock it down for pasture.
Total salvage mission eh?
Mm hmm.
Nice, has it been in
your family for years?
Yeah, it's my Godparents.
But no one's lived there
after my Grandpa died.
It's been empty for ages.
You grew up there as a tyke?
I spend a lot of time
there when I was younger.
But it's like early
memories you know?
Never really met my Grandma.
My Grandpa died when
I was really young.
And him and my Dad had
this weird kind of thing.
It was kind of old school
military guy right.
So they had their
problems I guess.
So after he died we didn't
really hang out there too much.
It's like a place that's
always been left alone.
Out of sight our of
mind kind of thing.
Mm hmm.
So how'd you grandpa pass?
Throat cancer.
Throat cancer eh?
Yep, rough shit.
Yeah.
I can totally relate.
I was in the hospital and I
had this young guy beside me
that had a trach, and his
breathing would be fine
and then about a half an
hour into it you could hear a
you know it was the flem
buildup so they would come in
with a tube and
stick it in his trach
suck out all this flem.
Yeah.
And meanwhile I'm just
like, shut the fuck up!
I'm trying to sleep, go die
somewhere else you know.
Just being totally
delirious of the fact.
And two days in, the next
night, following night,
wake up in the morning
and I'm usually woken up
by this suction of
this tube and whatever
and I look over and
the bed was gone.
I ask the nurse
and I yell nurse,
what happened to the
little kipper her.
And the nurse it like
yeah, didn't make it,
you know and whatever,
throat cancer got him.
And I was just like, what?
I'm being me being six years
old, I'm like holy fuck man,
that's heavy.
Dying, he just died
right there man
What you end up in there for?
I actually like, I was
in a coma for two months.
No way.
Yeah dude, I
survived the coma,
and yeah it was pretty heavy.
My mom organized this
parade in Fort Mac
when I was living up
there and the theme was
cowboys versus indians.
Well of course me being
an indian I came prepared
with my bustles you
know, my pow wow regalia,
my gear you know,
totally jiving.
And then all of a
sudden, it stops.
And we're like
what's the hold up
and we look over there.
Here like someone was,
there was some holdup.
So I just kick back,
waving at the same people
doing whatever, and
then it violently shook
and I went flying eight
feet off this platform.
Right onto my head, like
smacked my dome and everything.
The driver behind us in the,
passed like the following,
18 wheeler didn't even see me
and it straight just
ran my leg over,
crushed it in seven place.
Oh fuck.
I was unconscious you know.
God damn.
Gretzky came and saw
me in the hospital,
you know, Gretzky
straight up showed up.
The great one.
I'm all tubed up like totally,
like sheets across they way,
full of tubes and everything.
There's Gretzky puts
down a home jersey
and an away jersey and
that's the photo I have.
Smiling for the camera while
he's autographing these jerseys
and I'm fucking, I got
a little teddy bear
stuffed under my arm, I'm
fucking out of it you know?
I'm gonna go grab
another beer alright.
I'm fucked up man.
I'm just fucked up man.
You alright there buddy?
Yeah, I just fucked up.
You'll be alright man.
Just fucked up you know.
I was just drinking too
much, fucked up you know.
You'll be fine bro.
Yep.
No worries.
Everything's gonna be fine man.
Yep.
Do you need
a ride on Thursday?
No that's alright I can drive.
Do you want a ride?
No thank you.
Okay.
How's everything
looking up at the house?
I didn't have a chance
to get up there today
but the house is looking good.
Things be, they'll take
it down on Wednesday.
K.
That sounds good.
Thank you for that, work.
Appreciate it.
Yep, no problem.
If you need something
else just let me know.
There's always something.
Yep.
Yeah we're
all set back here.
Come in.
There she is.
Lovely to see you.
Are you here to collect Alex?
If I can pry him away.
Good how are you.
Let me take this little guy.
Let me get your
jacket for you.
How you doing?
Pretty good.
Where you putting these?
Oh, I'll grab that.
Here can you take him for a sec.
Sure.
Well come on in,
have something to eat.
Lots to drink in there
too, help yourself.
Careful man.
Now I understand
there has already been
a private settlement
reached between the parties
representing Mr.
and Ms. Ridlowe,
and the Prince George Warriors?
Yes,
that is correct sir.
Alright, so that
leaves us with the matter
of Mr. Burr, and the
liability of his part
regarding his actions with
relation to the adverse impact
that those have had on
the respective parties
represented here today.
I would like to
remind all parties
that this is simply a
preliminary hearing,
however you are welcome
to submit statements
at this time should
you choose to.
Mr. Howard, I understand
that you would like to do so.
Yes, your Honor.
We feel that it is
imperative in this situation
to recognize the responsibility
of the individual.
And that the
individual's actions,
taken on their own, were done
so without the direction,
endorsement, or support of
the Prince George Warriors.
We feel that this is
specifically vital in context
of the character
of the individual.
In this case we have
a young man who,
since the incident on
which we are focused,
has been held in police custody.
What this would seem to indicate
is a pattern of violence.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org