I had said to catch him first!
He must be killed by his own men
We've lost our clues
I had asked
to keep him under surveillance
What do your people do?
How can you blame me?
You know
Or Wing Fu keeps many Vietnameses
They had been through the war!
If you are that good
grab a killer and show us!
Do you think you are Stallon!
Don't argue here!
I've kept an eye on Or Wing Fu this long
I have to put him in jail this time
It doesn't matter this man dies
I have one more witness to accuse him
You two be careful, no more mistakes
Skinny accuses Or Wing Fu in court!
Yeah, he betrayed Or Wing Fu!
I heard that he had been his follower
Who would be loyal these days!
You two go over there! Yes!
Don't stand here!
Did you hear me? Go away!
Give way!
Don't get too close Watch out
What's the matter, this early?
I've done everything you said
Well, people say 'time will tell'!
They deserved it!
I'm afraid the police won't stop!
I had told them to hide for a while!
Stop the business in Thailand
I had told them to stop
we can start again later!
We smuggled fire-arms in the Korean War
We dealt with drugs in riots
We helped people sneak-in in Vietnam
We've got enough money
Boss, you mean...
That's not much left in HK
I wanna emigrate
and you should retire too
Yuen Lick is with you?
I'll give you some names tonight
Ask Yuen Lick to do it, no trace
Master, breakfast is ready
And Master, your daughter had rung
She'll have OT tonight
not having dinner
Not coming back again!
You ring her up for me!
Hello
Please wait!
Pui Lam, your call!
Thanks!
Daddy!
Dinner?
No, I'm busy!
Aren't you going to Thailand?
When?
OK, bye!
We should go to the press conference!
What do the police have to say
on the killing?
We are investigating it!
We have set up a task-force
We believe that
we can have a report soon
According to our investigation
the suspect got gunned down yesterday
is a migrant from Vietnam!
We have so many killings lately!
What is the tactic of the police?
Well, we have a bit more killings lately
around 80%
but not that many deaths
We had 21 traffic deaths last month
excluding the one
who jumped off the train
Relatively, not that many killings!
Does it link with the special case?
We have given information
to the task force!
Because of the killing
of the two witnesses
will the police stand stronger
against the triads?
Of course, no doubt
I can tell you now!
The information on triads
is in the hand of the police
I believe when the time comes later
we will have a lot of operations
When do the police think
the time is right?
When is the right time?
Hard to say!
The criminals are smart!
We want to avoid alerting them
So I can't answer this!
We have to stop right here!
Thanks for coming!
This press conference
is time wasting!
Thanks everyone of you!
Any more questions?
Here is your pay!
Man killed Skinny outside the court!
And you killed Opium Hung
I think that the police must be angry
But Man was killed, too!
He had a grand-mum
did you give her money?
I talk it over with boss!
He is narrow-minded, I think he won't
That's too bad!
Man and I had been in Hong Kong
these years!
We had been working for him
You Vietnameses, what else can you do?
What can you do in Hong Kong?
Risk for rich, no one forces you!
You have to be careful!
Don't copy what Man had done!
He deserved death!
He didn't want to kill
I'm like him, was a soldier in Vietnam
I had killed!
Killed many people
I killed in Vietnam
I kill here in Hong Kong too
Boss asks you to finish the rest tonight
Tonight?
I'm afraid it's not the right time
People had been alerted!
If they are afraid
and co-operate with the police
that's the end to us!
But
Either he dies or I die
How many did you kill in Vietnam?
Here is Hong Kong
The same, it is a cruel
and realistic world
You have to be the first one to win!
And leaving no trace!
I could get you out from Vietnam!
I can get your family out, too
Money is the most important
Man!
Man, how are you?
Who is that?
It's Licky!
Hi, come in! Thanks!
Tea!
Thanks!
That's alright!
Ah, how is my grand-son Man?
Why didn't he come with you?
He is busy!
He went to Thailand to do business!
He asked me to give you the money!
And some roast pork bun!
Thanks!
Did Man write to you?
Yes!
What did he say?
I read it to you!
Dear Licky, how are you?
I am fine in Thailand
Go to see my Grand-mum if you can
Bring her some roast pork bun
I'll be back soon!
Tell my Grand-mum
I don't gamble anymore
Licky, I had been saving up in Vietnam
I wanna send you aboard to study
Didn't expect I use the money
to let you refuge to Hong Kong
You keep it!
Brother!
Licky, take care!
Get on board, quick!
Brother...
I'll get you to Hong Kong too!
Licky, this is Fenny!
I've finished shooting
Let's go to disco
I have no time!
Ask Kenny!
Why?
Don't ask, decided!
Boss asks you to finish
the rest tonight
Leave no trace!
Fan Man Pui!
What's happening to Licky lately?
He's always like this!
I know, the report is here
OK, I bring it over later
OK, no problem. See you
What then, finished?
It's a busy day, two scenes
What cases?
Two killings!
Horrible!
Police, this is Fuji Hotel
Main switch!
This is main switch
I'm Or Pui Lam
I'm now on location, over!
How is it? You need help?
Why don't you talk, over!
Don't ask, Miss Or is upset
She's gone, over!
What upset her?
You looked down on her
she needed no help!
OK, you two go up there OK
I stay here
No, you can't enter
No!
Let us go up, we are reporters!
Please be quiet!
Is it a male or female?
We just arrived, we know nothing
Is it suicide? Let's go up!
We don't really know, ask the police!
Be quiet. Captain Ng is coming!
Please be quiet!
Is it the revenge of triads?
Right, tell us Captain Ng!
At 5:00 a.m., this morning, a waiter
found a dead male body in a room
he called the police
How did he die?
We have to wait for the coroner!
Does it link with the other killings?
It's under investigation!
Please give way!
Watch out It's coming down
Excuse us. We're taking this out
At 5:00 a.m., on 2/F, Fuji Hotel
A man was found dead in his room!
When he was found...
Pang, come here!
Inspector Lau
the task force is two months now
and the case is still these
and someone got killed
What do you have to say?
What, you can't face it?
He's unlucky coming across you!
Let's go!
Nothing else
Brother, we have got your parcel!
Mum was happy, we all miss you!
The government
is having an economic reform
The Chinese shops are closed
They say dad messes up the finance
officers come to get information
all the time
You are late?
Well, I hurried!
Dad is getting worse, mum worries!
We all want to unite with you
in Hong Kong
But we have to
give 30 Oz of gold each to get out
We are not sure if we can see you again!
It's news time!
A man was found dead
in the Fuji Hotel at 5:00 a.m.
He was of the 30's
A waiter found him dead in his room
and called the police
According to the coroner
he was beaten to death
It's the 5th killing this week
The police had set up a task force
to investigate the case
International news
Inspector Lau, can I sit down?
Why eat alone?
Why I meet you here?
It's a high-class restaurant
no business talks!
Take it easy, it's my job...
wouldn't it be good to have a lady?
It doesn't matter
you can't finish the case
And you won't be fired because of this
Hey, miss, shut up!
What would you like?
Fried squid with rice
Fried squid with rice, quick
OK!
What do you want?
Nothing, just wanna make fun with you!
I'm sorry about yesterday!
Don't say it again!
I won't tell you anything
about yesterday!
Inspector Lau!
Stop talking, and stop seducing me!
I know nothing about yesterday's case!
Well, you know nothing
about yesterday's case
What about in the lift
and outside the court?
You've been investigating
can't say I don't know
We have clues on these two
I know the dead was a man
the killer was a man too
No more jokes!
I have finished!
Miss, I can't tell you anymore!
I need to have my meal, please!
I'll go
if you will give me some information!
Are you going to sit here for life?
Well, I'm here with you today!
Why me? So many officers in the station!
News, news, go home rest!
Be cool
I've never met such a bitch like you!
Be careful, no one wants you!
Taste good!
He is Kam Ta Fu
an ex-soldier from Vietnam
He became a killer in Thailand
very dangerous
Any news about him?
I heard that he had come to Hong Kong!
Our informer said he had met Or Wing Fu
It's better to catch him!
How can we?
We have no proof, it will alert them!
You
I think he's right!
He is a trouble maker
Send someone to keep an eye on Kam Ta Fu
Stop, police!
No, don't shoot!
Fire!
Don't shoot!
Shoot, it's an order!
Don't shoot! Don't!
Watch the time!
I give you one minute!
Yuen Licky, what are you doing?
Don't move. I ask you
do you know Kam Ta Fu came to kill me?
You tell me the truth!
Man is dead, you are the only one left
Why should I kill you?
Then who wants me dead?
Yuen Lick, I don't know!
But I can find out!
You have 30 seconds
I will kill you myself if I want
because you won't be alert!
Think, do I have a reason to kill you?
Leave it all up to me!
I know who dares
I am going to Thailand
When are you coming back?
I don't know yet
Do you know Kam Ta Fu?
I don't!
You really don't?
I haven't even heard about the name!
Really, that's strange!
What do you mean?
Don't have to go around circles
Boss, I hire Yuen Lick to be a killer
Only you and I know about it
He nearly got killed two days ago
That killer was Kam Ta Fu!
He met you after arriving at Hong Kong
So you two know each other
Why do you want to kill Yuen Lick?
Because he knows too much!
You mean...
To kill them all!
I don't wanna leave any trace this time
I wanna kill those who know about me!
What about me?
You think it over!
First done, first win!
It's me, where does dad stay
in Thailand?
I wanna stay with him
in Thailand next week!
He didn't say!
Well, then, bye!
You told me dad had gone to Thailand
He didn't ring after this long!
You two are good friends
I thought dad would contact you!
Right, I remember!
After the rushes that day
he went to the airport
He said he would go to Korea
after Thailand!
What to do in Korea?
My dear, would you stop asking?
Well, I say for Jin-seng in Korea
It's up to you to believe!
Come with me!
Where to?
To the studio!
I have to keep an eye on the shooting!
Let's go!
Tighter!
Be careful, be good if only one time!
Don't worry, no problem!
Ready, camera!
The water stings!
Get up and come out
All right
Let me introduce!
She's my friend's daughter Or Pui Lam!
You should know!
He's our effect specialist, Yuen Lick!
He's brilliant
Hi Hi
Seems that we have met?
Well, I see you on TV
Pui Lam, let me show you over there!
Good!
Let's go
We built an old street set over there!
I show you over there!
How does that gas smell?
Hard to describe
I have never smelt that!
What's the feeling after smelling?
Feel fainted and wanna throw up!
And what else?
Feel painful on the chest!
Can you tell me how it happened?
We smelt it in class!
Do you know where the gas came from?
I don't!
How many pupils are in hospital?
All P.5 pupils!
Some strange gas affected Luther School
Pupils felt sick
in the middle of their lesson
The pupils are in hospital
for treatment!
It's the 3rd time
pupils struck by strange gas...
authority has no clue
of where the gas comes from
Or Pui Lam, ATV news!
The wind direction
was southern yesterday
Thanks!
As shown on the map...
the gas could come from
the south side of the school
Let's try to find out!
Still smoking, you may get lung cancer
So smoky!
Yeah, it comes from above!
Go in and have a look! OK
Quick!
Let's go over there!
My lady, let's stop
it has been more than ten!
You think I am a dog?
Smell the toxic gas!
It's been a hard day
I buy you some lunch?
Thanks!
No thanks, we have to go on after lunch!
Well, you go by yourself!
I have to attend
my father's celebration!
I had talked to you clearly on the phone
About the lab report on toxic gas
it's official report, I can't tell you!
Uncle Ng, let me see it
for the sake of public!
I am a civil servant
I have to obey the law
I have to be loyal!
You want me to be sent to jail!
Uncle Ng, do me a favour?
No!
Civil servants
can't reveal any confidential
Keep an eye on the document
I'll be back!
I'll be back soon!
Don't mess up the document
I know!
I'll be back soon!
Thanks!
How dare you?
Taking pictures of official document!
You know it's a crime!
You fool! We're all responsible!
Why don't you keep an eye on her?
You supervise her
when she does her assignments
You can leave!
Let's knock off?
Bye!
What's the matter, can't you drive?
It's hard to get a taxi!
I give you a ride!
What's up? Don't you know me?
Oh, it's you!
Hop in!
Thanks, but no!
I'm not passing by
I come to pick you up!
The reason is simple
I want to make friend with you!
It's embarrassing!
I'll give you time to think
Hop in!
Do you like Vietnamese food?
Yes!
Do you know which one is the best?
I don't know!
I show you!
OK
Take a seat!
Well, here is the one you've mentioned
Where's the menu?
I'm not sure if the food is good here
I don't like the way they serve!
Really, I like woman like you
who can talk!
I show you here
because you're my good friend!
But I don't think you're my good friend!
You'll change in the future!
What have you got to make me change?
I'm alone in Hong Kong, living dull!
I see you on TV every night
I treat you like a relative!
So, I want to make friend with you!
Have some more!
Not bad!
Very nice!
Can you tell me what you did in Vietnam?
Relax, I wasn't a pimp!
What else do you wanna know?
I want to know nothing!
Why are you so narrow-minded?
So?
Then you must be bad-tempered!
Well, thanks for the meal!
How can you be a reporter
you're so hot-tempered?
Everybody has secrets
It's better not telling than lying!
Disgusting!
I go to see a friend
in the refugee camp tomorrow
I think you are interested
Smell good
They seem to be happy!
But they have their tragedy
Some have lost their parents
some their kids
Everyone leaves home
they can never return
Just like me!
My parents had divorced for years
I went to the USA with mum
when I was young
I came back
after finishing TV news course
I have never lived with my dad!
When I was in College
I saw the anti-Vietnamese War
student movement
Did you think about Vietnam?
Yes, it's like a nightmare in Vietnam!
I feel that the war isn't over
I don't feel the killing, the death!
My only hope is
to get my family out!
Let me up...
Don't run!
I won't kill surrenders!
Yuen Lick, let me up! Don't run
Come up, we will treat you right!
Who is it?
What? Scared?
Of course, you shit stirrer, come in!
You're insane!
You're good, don't have to work
I'm very tired in the studio
For you!
The director must be a maniac!
That Fenny yells in front of me!
She said you hide from her
I don't have time to be with her!
That silly girl, I don't know what to do
The captain Kam Ta Fu in Vietnam
has come to Hong Kong lately
I heard that
he is a professional killer!
Right, you had confronted him?
Be careful!
Help!
Be quick!
Why so careless!
Licky, are you alright?
Get up first!
Are you OK?
I'm fine!
Hey, take it over there!
Come and give me a hand
Licky, have some water!
Give me
How do you feel?
Take a rest, are you alright?
I had told you not to do the stunts!
It doesn't make a lot more money
Shut up, will you?
What's the matter with you?
What do you mean?
You've changed lately!
You wouldn't treat me like this before
Stop!
I know, you must have a new girl friend
Leave me alone!
Who do you think I am? Make it clear!
Fenny! Leave him alone first
None of your business
if you don't clear it
We split up, say it!
They really split up!
Ride me home
What are you doing?
No!
What is it?
Licky, listen!
My man had killed your girl!
Come see me at Mt. Devil
if you wanna revenge
Are you a beast?
Fenny was good to you
why did you do it?
I had no choice!
Call the police!
I can't!
Why can't, tell me!
Don't ask me if you are my pal!
Why?
Listen!
I have to execute Fenny's killer!
That Yuen Lick may not dare to come!
Wait, wait!
Shoot!
What do you want?
Is my dad really in Korea?
I haven't heard from him since he's gone
Right, has he contacted you?
We planned to meet in Korea!
But I was busy, so I stayed
I guess he must be happy there!
Relax, take a seat!
OK!
You stupid fool, I'll kill you!
Can you hear me?
Miss Or?
Yes, I am!
I am Kenny, Yuen Lick's friend!
Well, I don't know where to start
Yuen Lick got the news from Vietnam
saying his family
got blown up
when sneaking out of Vietnam!
His heart was broken after hearing it
He doesn't eat nor sleep
better go to see him!
OK, let's go!
Licky!
Good son
Brother I'll get you to Hong Kong!
I came to Hong Kong alone!
I risked my life to make money
only want to get my family out
I did what I didn't like for them!
But, so what!
It's all been wasted!
Do you know it?
Licky!
Pretty little girl, get up early
take a basket to the market
Why didn't you knock first?
Boss, it's bad!
What's the matter?
Old Or's body was found in Lung Har Bay
No, you can't go back to Vietnam!
Why not?
Think about it
your family is no longer there
What do you do going back?
You have no reason going back!
You don't understand
I feel real bad lately!
I know you feel sad!
You won't feel good even if you return!
You don't have to say anymore!
I won't let you go
no matter what you say
My dad, how could it be?
Where?
What happened...?
My dad is dead
He was found in Lung Har Bay!
What's your dad's name?
Or Wing Fu!
Well, what a coincidence!
You date with Old Or's daughter
Why do you want me here?
Or Pui Lam is smart, she'll suspect me!
You know what to do?
You don't have to say, I won't do it
It's my order, no negotiation!
She's a famous reporter
it's worse killing her
I tried so hard to escape from Vietnam
I'm in Hong Kong at last, but a killer
I don't wanna kill anymore
I'm tired, too tired!
Don't pretend in front of me
She'll know you killed her father
You can't be emotional
We can't let go of her!
I beg you, let her go!
Remember, once a killer
always a killer!
You think it over!
Ready?
Not yet! Longer
OK
Listen! Two cameras, ready!
Bring it over there! Get ready!
Go away, a real take!
Ready, real take!
Camera!
Cut!
What's the matter, come out so soon!
You can't concentrate
drive faster later!
You come out slowly, understand?
Understand!
Again!
Are you ready? Quick
Are you ready? Yes!
Real take!
Ready, camera!
How is Yuen Lick?
How did he get hurt, tell me!
I, I don't know!
Doctor!
Doc, how is Yuen Lick?
Don't worry, he only got burnt slightly!
We have to observe him for a period
According to my experience
he'll soon recover
That's good!
Why were you so careless?
Someone wanted to trap me!
I must find him out!
How do you feel?
What did the doctor say?
You'll soon recover!
I don't wanna disturb
I go first!
Help him, go first!
Run! Come!
Run quickly!
Be careful
Some more?
No, enough!
Why did he want to kill you?
Maybe I have killed too much!
You were in the war, it's different now
The war will never end
You're useless! Licky is recovering!
You ask for money
leaving no marks on him
Mr. Tang, you can't blame me
The powder in the studio is old!
And he reacts promptly, he alerts!
I have an idea
he and Kam Ta Fu are enemies
We can use Kam Ta Fu's hand to kill him!
Make them kill one another
What do you think of my idea?
Is it good?
Good!
Let's do it!
Licky!
What are you doing, come, have a tea!
Good!
After your recovery
I apply for a holiday leave
We go for a trip!
We go to the USA
to see my mum on the way!
She wrote that she wanted to meet you
Pui Lam!
I have to go out!
Where are you going?
Just for a walk, be back soon!
Haven't seen you for long!
Where had you been?
For recovery!
Recovered?
Well, what's the matter?
About Or Pui Lam, let her go!
You're protecting her
do you wanna go against me?
Yes!
Why don't you wanna kill her?
Killing is an easy job for you, why?
It's different if killing my love one
It's right time for you to be here!
What you wanna do, Tang Kin?
You'd better leave!
I can kill you even if you fire first!
Try it if you suspect
Yuen Lick
you can't hide what you've done
It's no use!
She'd know you killed her father!
Is he telling the truth?
Tell me...!
Yes, but I didn't know he was your dad!
I don't believe it!
Pui Lam!
You are bad luck, you just walked in!
Now I send you to your father
No!
Pui Lam, don't come out!
Licky!
You know too much!
No!
Licky!
Why you won't let me go?
Don't cry, deliver it for me!
I don't have to kill anymore!
Bye!
Come in!
Grand-mum!
Your grandson asked Licky
to give you the money!
Thank you!
Where is Man, when is he coming back?
I don't know!
What about Licky? When is he coming?
He will never come!