Once upon a time, two years ago...
five lives were suddenly
transformed.
One got a second chance.
One got old.
One became young again.
One got a raw deal.
And one hit the jackpot.
Five bodies, five souls,
one story that changed my life.
Stef!
Wake up!
This is the day we've been waiting for.
Good morning!
Good morning, Mom.
This is the big day, my princess.
Did you sleep well?
- Yes Mom, 8 hours more or less.
- That's just enough.
More than that
and your skin gets puffy.
What's the weather forecast?
ls it going to rain,
or is it clear skies all day?
Of course!
We picked the best date.
There's a solar eclipse today
and it will be clear.
ln some cultures,
solar eclipses are considered lucky.
- Really?
- Yes. Come on.
- Mom, l'm nervous.
- Don't be such a baby.
lt's the nicest day
for a beach wedding.
Come, hug Mama.
My princess.
When you do the groceries
don't forget the dog food.
Check.
- And the dog shampoo.
- Check.
And don't forget to call Jim-Jim the
dog shooter, Mrs. Covarrubias' son.
His Shih Tzu is in heat...
you have to schedule a breeding session
for Bogart so he'll stop sulking.
Oh, Bogart! My baby's a big boy,
he's ready to mate!
Lucky Bogart, he has a love life.
- What did you say?
- Nothing, Ma'am.
l said l'd call Jim-Jim
the son of Mrs. Covarrubias.
l heard you. lf we were in court
you'd be cited for contempt.
Where is Mr. Pedring the driver?
l don't want to be stuck
on EDSA at rush hour.
He sent a text message
that he can't drive you today.
He has lactose intolerance.
Mr. Pedring has lactose intolerance?
ls that correct, yes or no?
Yes.
How swanky of him,
a rich people's ailment.
Get my driving shoes from
the closet.
So many churches in Manila...
and they choose to get married
on the beach.
Oh it's a wedding you're attending.
l thought you were going
to a baptism.
So you're a godmother
at weddings now.
Yes. Accept the truth
that l have long accepted.
l am of age to stand as godmother
at weddings, is that correct?
Yes, Ma'am.
Godmother at weddings...
do you want me to underline
and highlight that for you?
l'll even spell it. W-E-D-D-l-N-G-S.
l am the godmother to the daughter
of my best friend from high school!
You got that?
lf you're through annoying me,
get my loafers before you get hurt!
Yes, Ma'am. Enjoy your breakfast. Alone!
Bogart! Bogart!
Nanny, make sure lñaki
does number two.
lt's hard to find a bathroom
on the way there.
Yes, Ma'am.
lt's too early for poo-poo.
Can l bring my toys?
Okay, but not all of them.
Nanny, his toys.
What's taking you so long?
We're going to get stuck in traffic,
get moving.
Yes, Sir, good morning.
Have you seen my diver's watch?
l don't know, ask the maid.
Sir, l checked the air in the tires.
What about the gas?
Enough to get us there,
we can fill up on the way back.
lñaki, finish your food.
Don't get up until you've finished.
Where's my diver's watch?
Daddy says eat.
Good morning. See you later.
Nanny is flirting with the driver!
l'll tell Mommy.
Be quiet. Eat your bacon and eggs
so you'll grow big and strong.
l don't want to be big and strong,
l want to be rich and powerful.
Come on, eat your eggs.
Eating eggs everyday
will turn me into a girl.
Alright, just the bacon.
That's high in cholesterol.
Do you want me to die early?
Please eat.
After this l have to give
you a bath and get you dressed...
then we're going on a long drive
and we can't be late...
because you're the ring-bearer
at the wedding.
They can't start without me.
You horrid brat.
You little demon.
The minute l pay off my
parent's debts, l'm leaving you.
Pest. Demon. Troll!
Nanny, you're speaking Bisaya again.
You must be saying bad words.
l'm telling Mommy!
Whatever!
- lt's not Bisaya, it's llonggo.
- Whatever, Nanny.
Eat... Eat...
(Coughing)
Are we bringing that oxygen tank?
That's what the doctor
and your son said.
They should've had
the wedding in the lCU.
Sir, we have to be prepared.
Prepared for what?
You're all paranoid.
Where are you putting that?
Didn't l tell you l'm not riding
that wheelchair?
Sir, your son said to bring it.
Who is paying for this wedding,
him or me?
Does he give orders now?
Take that down! Right this second!
Sir, l'll get reprimanded.
Goddamnit, take down
that wheelchair instantly!
Sir, if you don't want to ride it,
then don't.
But your son specifically
told me to bring it.
Then he should ride that wheelchair.
Why don't we get in the car.
l left my checkbook
in the clutch bag, get it.
Sir, here it is.
The late Toffee Carbonell.
- l'll miss you, baby.
- Have to go.
- Bye, love you.
- No kiss?
Here's your coffee.
- 1 1 seconds.
- What?
l timed your embrace. 1 1 seconds.
How long will you be parted?
l thought this was a day trip.
What was your breakfast,
hot sour soup?
lt's too early for sourness.
Not even a thank you for the coffee?
lgnore her, Sister,
she's been like that since yesterday.
- Shit.
- Huh?
l'd understand if you and your ex
had split up a week ago.
Even a month ago.
But it's been 3 months...
and you were only together
for one month.
Your recovery is longer
than the actual relationship.
Sister, aren't you tired?
We're so tired for you.
Butt out!
You never learn.
How self-righteous you are.
Just because you have lovers.
Sister, it's your fault because you
always fall for boys who like girls.
Correct.
Why don't you open your heart
to boys who like boys?
Yucch! Like you?
With boyfriends as gay as yourselves?
Over my dead, sexy body.
Then suffer.
Your gayness is so Seventies.
- lt's a new millennium!
- Exactly.
You're such
a stereotypical gay beautician.
Excuse me, l am not a beautician.
l am an image stylist.
Let's go!
Before you make me vomit.
- And the road trip is on!
- How long is the drive?
According to the map, 3 to 4 hours.
That's so far!
lmage stylist?
l wonder what that is?
- lt's not far, go to sleep.
- The sourness!
The bitterness!
Your Auntie Carla called last night.
She wishes you the best.
She insists that you stay with her
when you visit L.A.
Your cousins are excited
to meet Harold.
l'll tell Harold.
lf it's alright with him, why not.
l'm sure it is.
Speaking of...
- Hi, Babe.
- Babe, are you on the road?
- Yes, we're on our way.
- Good.
l told you, the house
is only 30 minutes away.
l can't wait to see you.
- Excited!
- More excited for the honeymoon.
Stop that, l'm with my mother.
lt's so embarrassing.
- So?
- Stop that.
Babe, could you check the wedding
souvenirs with the suppliers?
- l hope there's no problem.
- l've seen them.
Are they tasteful?
- Very appropriate.
- Good.
- Are you near?
- Yes, we're near.
Stop that.
l don't have time for this!
l don't care if you camp out outside
City Hall the whole weekend...
just get me a copy
of that land title!
And tell Attorney Montinola...
the deposition from his witness
is useless!
We need to win this
land dispute case at all cost.
What? l didn't get an email.
Wi-fi? l'm driving, you nitwit.
l don't want that!
How many times do l have to tell you?
Mommy, we have to go back
to the house!
lñaki, l told you to stop that.
Turn up the airconditioning.
We can't go back,
we're too far from the house.
Nanny, how could you forget his PSP?
lt must've been
in the other bag, Ma'am.
Nanny, my PSP!
How could you leave it!
Father is in the hospital.
Mother is also ill.
Your brother was stabbed.
Your youngest sister is pregnant.
Your dog is missing.
Send money.
And cellphone credits. Thanks.
l want my PSP!
Nanny, make him stop,
he's giving me a headache.
Yes, Sir.
Let's just read a book.
You'll like this. Moby Dick.
Moby Dick? That's cruelty to animals!
What do you want?
l want my PSP!
Here it is, citizens.
ln a few moments we will witness
an amazing event.
- lt's time for your meds.
- A solar eclipse!
Give them to me.
Get your video cameras
and cellphones ready!
The next partial solar eclipse
is two years away!
Take care when looking at the eclipse,
you don't want to damage your eyes.
- Give me my sunglasses.
- Why?
Didn't you hear the radio?
lt's two years
until the next solar eclipse.
l'll probably be ashes by then.
- Driver, slow down.
- Sir?
Slow down, you devil.
Marvelous!
Sisters, what about
the division of labor later?
l'll do the bride.
JR will do the makeup
of the maid of honor, bridesmaids...
and the mother of the bride.
You'll do the godmothers
and grandmothers.
Are you punishing me?
How many godmothers?
- 12, l think.
- 12?
ls this a wedding or a fund-raising?
That's why l charged them extra.
Anyway the bride is nice...
she comes to our salon regularly
for her manicure and pedicure.
Beautiful girl, pretty face.
Very kind. Sweet.
Kind of dowdy, though.
Have you sighted the groom?
ls he hot? A cutie?
Harry my love?
Yumminess itself!
There's an over-the-top reaction.
- For real?
- For true!
Listen, gays of the year, we're close
to the electromagnetic field area.
- Really? ls it nearby?
- Yes.
You can turn off the engine
or put it in neutral...
and the car will still drive up.
- Let's try it!
- Okay, let's try!
Mom, are you crying?
Didn't you say, no tears?
Our makeup will be ruined.
Those beauticians charge so much.
Princess, they're not beauticians.
They're image stylists.
l just wish your dad were here.
l wish he could walk you
down the aisle.
Mom, whatever his address
in heaven is...
l know he's happy.
Besides, he's with us in spirit.
And we'll walk down
the aisle together.
l know, Stef.
- So stop crying.
- Okay.
l'll stop if you stop
biting your nails.
Eww, look at that, they're cracked.
What does that word mean?
Even if you email me that 18-page
affidavit l can't decide on it.
l'm at the beach until late tonight.
A beach wedding.
Yes, l am a godmother at a wedding.
Did you think it was a baptism?
Are you laughing?
Are you laughing at me?
Chubby? Who's Chubby? Hello?
My battery's low, wait.
Where is my charger?
Let's try this.
Hansel and Gretel.
- Once upon a time...
- l don't like that!
- lt's disturbing!
- Disturbing...
Here, Little Red Riding Hood.
- Once upon a time...
- l don't like that!
lt's too violent!
Now this was my favorite
when l was a child.
- The Legend of the Lanzones.
- l don't eat lanzones!
l want my PSP!
Sir, you might get sideswiped.
Stop that. Here it comes.
- Sir...
- Wait a second.
- You might get caught on something.
- Here comes the total eclipse!
lt's beautiful!
- How does this go?
- Turn off the engine.
- Put it in neutral.
- lt's in neutral.
- This is great!
- Such fun!
lt's because we have
electromagnetic personalities...
unlike certain people in this car.
Correct!
Big freaking deal.
ls this your first time
to experience a magnet?
Don't you have refrigerators at home?
- ls that it?
- Kind of.
So, what? That's that?
Aaaah!
- You're so cheap.
- Killjoy!
All of a sudden,
in a blink of an eye...
in the middle
of the national highway...
at the center of the magnetic field
and temporary darkness...
the five of us-
Ninang Precy,
yours truly, the beautician...
l mean the image stylist Toffee,
Grandfather Bien...
and the Nanny temporarily
lost consciousness.
- Nanny!
- Medelyn...
Nanny!
Dad, go get water for Nanny.
- lñaki, get water for Nanny.
- Why me?
Medelyn, are you okay?
Where am l? Who are you?
State your full names for the record.
Dad, maybe we should call a doctor.
She's probably just nuts from hunger.
Medelyn, have you eaten?
Am l dead? What happened?
There was an accident.
A minor one.
Maybe it's whiplash.
Oh my gosh.
- Dad, get water!
- lñaki, get water!
Nanny, you're so weird.
Why don't you call a doctor
just to be sure?
Dad's doctor is in France
attending a conference.
- Weren't you listening?
- Then call any doctor?
Any doctor?
Dad has a complicated
medical history.
Not that you would know,
you don't care about him.
Don't you start with me.
His blood pressure is normal.
Then why isn't he speaking?
He might've had a stroke.
Why don't we try asking him?
Mister Bien, are you alright?
Would you like to return to Manila?
Are you in pain?
We could take you to a hospital.
lt's okay, Sir. l feel fine.
You don't have to take me
to the hospital.
When did Dad learn to speak Bisaya?
- Not Bisaya, llonggo.
- Whatever.
Ha!
The other one's awake.
Maybe someone can do my makeup now?
Sorry, Ma'am, l'll call him.
Patience.
Hey, are you okay?
Can you start working?
Could you do the makeup
of the other godmothers?
That's your assignment, remember?
Miss Catatonia, did you hear me?
You fag.
Who are you calling fag?
Straighten up.
You shake your hips like a woman.
Shameless hussy!
Wow, a Best Actress performance!
Hey! You look like a tomboy!
Get out here
or l'll never give you a job again.
Since when do you speak Spanish?
- Where is that fag going?
- Where else?
Our work is here,
and he's wandering off.
Best friend?
- Mom?
Are you okay, Best friend?
Doctor, what drugs did you give her?
Nothing hardcore.
My dear, are you hallucinating?
Shall l have the driver
bring you to Manila?
St. Luke's Hospital
or Makati Medical?
- Mom...
- Dear...
- Why do you call me Mom?
- Because you are my mom.
Precy, you're freaking me out.
Mom, l'm the one who's like
totally freaked out here.
- l'm your daughter.
- Excuse me?
l'm too young to be your mother.
But l'm Stephanie.
Your daughter.
- What's the matter with you?
- The matter with me?
What is the matter with you?
Best friend, have a little dignity.
l don't know if you're on drugs
or playing a trick on me...
but you are definitely
not yourself today.
Wait, where are you going?
Mom, l have a wedding to catch!
My own wedding, duh.
You're not leaving this room.
You're not going to ruin
my daughter's most important day.
But l am your daughter.
Precy, you are having
a nervous breakdown.
lf you're depressed or destructive...
because you have a concussion
from the accident...
please stay away from my daughter.
- But l am your daughter.
- Lunatic!
Doctor, nurses, no matter what happens
she must not leave this room.
Let me go! Mom, they're hurting me.
Precy, stay here.
Don't make me call the police.
But it's my wedding day!
You're pathetic.
Doctor, medicate her.
l don't care if she's out for a week.
Mom, don't leave me,
it's my wedding day!
Thank you so much for this face,
this body, this flower.
l am a woman now!
l don't know why l've been blessed,
but l know this beauty has a purpose.
And if l'm dreaming, please God,
don't wake me up.
That's all. Thank you!
This beauty is insane!
Gorgeousness from every angle!
Eyes, nose, lips, cleavage, armpits.
The butt's a little small,
but l'll manage.
l'm so sexy! Can l handle it?
Yes. Yes! l deserve this.
l so deserve this!
ls everything ready?
Yes, Ma'am, everything
will be ready by sunset.
The wedding cake?
That's the only thing
we're waiting for.
Don't worry, l've talked
to the supplier.
How is godmother Precy?
ls she okay?
No, she's far from okay.
Really? Will we need a proxy?
Wait. Can you alert
all the security guards...
not to let her in here
under any circumstances?
- What?
- Can you just do what l say?
Noted, Ma'am. By the way,
the videographers are here.
They'd like to take a video
of you and Stephanie.
- Okay. There?
- Yes, Ma'am.
- Are the tables ready?
Princess, you want it more tame?
No, Mother, here it is!
How are you,
is your neck still painful?
lt's all in the past, Mother,
l'm ready for my close-up.
Your godmother Precy
won't be coming to the wedding.
What? My entourage
won't be complete. Why?
She can't come to
the wedding in her condition.
She's not herself, it's almost creepy.
lt's like she's possessed.
l didn't want to tell you,
you might worry.
Forget that. Spill it, Mother.
One more shot. Smile.
Spill?
Yes, make like a talk show.
Okay. Precy claims that she's you.
Really?
Yes, she says she's the bride
and it's her wedding day.
And she says it with conviction.
She insists on coming here to be
married, can you believe that?
That's crazy!
She might ruin my wedding.
Don't worry,
she can't leave the hospital.
But Princess, l feel bad for my friend.
l knew that deep down
she's really depressed.
You know,
being all alone in the world.
After the wedding
l'm taking her to Manila...
to have her checked by a specialist.
- ls that alright?
- Whatever.
Okay.
Don't worry.
One more shot.
Nanny, what else
have you forgotten today?
You're such an incompetent fool.
- Useless!
- Silence in the court!
You shut up when l tell you to shut up!
l don't know how
your parents raised you...
but l will not stand
for this abusive behavior.
From now on you will only speak
when spoken to.
You will respect all adults
and stop acting like one.
You will say ''please'', ''sir'',
''ma'am''. Understand?
Understand!
Yes, Ma'am.
Good.
l'm telling Mom what you said, Ma'am!
Then tell her! l'll see you in court.
Well? Have you decided?
What are you talking about?
Our plan, remember.
l hope you've decided.
Tonight, when they're asleep.
Don't leave me hanging.
Where are the bridesmaids
so we can photograph them?
l'll take you to their room.
Princess, l'll guide the videographers,
then l'll check on the cake.
Put some ice on your neck, okay?
Mom, stop treating me
like a helpless chick, go! Fly!
Okay. You need to get your makeup
done, l'll send the stylist.
Get ready for me,
world, here l come.
You're about
to experience total hotness.
Sir, stay here and take some air.
- l'll prepare your outfit.
- Alright.
Excuse me, old man. Are you okay?
Nanny! Nanny!
What is wrong with you?
You made the boy cry again.
You're always screwing up.
You forgot the PSP, the inflatable raft,
the steam iron last week.
Just pay up your cash advances...
pack your things and
go back where you came from!
Madame, can you briefly describe
my job description here?
Let me rephrase the question.
What is my job exactly?
Can you state for the record that l am
a nanny and not a child psychiatrist?
Let me call your attention
to provisions in the Labor Code...
concerning all persons rendering service
in the household for compensation.
Article 1 45: assignment
to non-household work.
No house helper shall be
assigned to any work...
commercial, industrial, or agricultural.
Furthermore, no household help
shall be assigned to discipline...
and teach your child good manners
and right conduct.
lt is the parents' obligation
to instill values in their children.
As to your accusation that l am an unfit
nanny for your badly-behaving child...
let me state for the record that you
are unfit, unreliable and irresponsible.
lsn't that correct, Missus?
Yes or no?
- Yes or no?
- Yes!
l rest my case. Excuse me.
l'm so smart!
There! This is it.
Miss Stephanie, it's Alfie, are you ready
to have your makeup done?
Appear, appear, appear!
No need for makeup here!
Just a spritz here and there,
throw your eyebrows in the air!
Why are you dressed like that?
Why? Are you mesmerized
by my gorgeousness?
You're envious aren't you?
l have achieved perfection.
Here, help me with this.
Careful with the hair.
The hair is top priority.
Where are you going?
To the beach, where the boys are.
But we're running late...
Never mind that.
What about your makeup?
Go! There!
Stephanie?
Stephanie, child.
This is insane. A blast from the past.
Stephanie, is that you?
Uh... yeah.
This is your Grandpa Bien.
Harold's grandfather.
Oh?
l know this is hard to believe,
but you must listen to me.
l don't know how l ended up
in this body. l'm confused.
Okay.
Can you help me?
Of course. We'll discuss it. Here.
- Where?
- We'll talk. Here.
Here. Yes.
There.
Blasted pest!
lnterfering with my plans.
Where have you been?
We have so many clients to do.
Were you picking up boys on the beach?
You have a job to do.
- Toffee, do me first.
- Excuse me, l got here first.
Excuse me,
l'm the maid of honor and l go first.
Where are you going?
Do the bridesmaids.
- What's up, boys? Got a drink for me?
- Come on, guys, a drink for Stef.
Quick!
Why don't we dance? Let's party.
Party!
That's what l like!
We're on the beach, we're so happy.
So. Are you my first victim?
Yes. And hopefully your last.
Those are fighting words.
l may bite you.
Just say ''Yes, l do''
and l'm yours forever.
Oh my god. Forever is a dangerous word.
Won't you get tired of me?
Me get tired of you? lmpossible.
So where to? Your place or mine?
Are you serious? Now?
Yes. Life is short. And you are so hot.
Then again, that's where
we're headed. Why wait.
Let's go!
We can have seconds and thirds.
Hi.
Hello, child.
l'd like a fresh look.
Fresh?
The no makeup look. You know.
Alright, let's try that.
But highlights on the cheekbones
and nose, and a bit of blusher. Thanks.
Here.
- Look at that. What a hunk.
- What are you doing, Stef?
- You're making me crazy.
- Stef, what are you doing?
Delicious.
Babe, Stef, are you sure
you want to do this?
Yes! Absolutely!
- ls that your final answer?
- Yes, is that your final question?
Stef.
- Come on, let's go.
- Stef, this isn't right.
What do you mean it's not right?
Don't be so fussy.
- Stef.
- l need to make my quota, hurry.
But didn't you say you wanted
our first time to be special?
What! l said no such thing! Come on!
Stef, we held back for 4 years.
4 years? l refrained for 4 years?
Let's not break our oath now.
What oath?
l have not signed any contract.
We made a pact, Stef.
We would do this the right way.
We would wait until we were married.
Married? Us?
Yes, us.
You, me, here, later.
Later? Here? You, me? Us?
My wife is so cute.
You never fail to surprise me.
l promise to take care of you,
to cherish you forever...
to make you happy
every single moment of your life.
l love you.
Such things exist?
Besides, it's just a few hours.
When the sun sets, we're legal.
See you later, Babe.
l'll be getting ready. You too, okay?
Catch you later, wifey.
l'm so fabulous! My God!
There.
What have you done? You jerk!
My apologies!
l didn't know what l was doing.
lsn't that the fashion today?
You look like a mascot.
This is a wedding,
not a children's party.
You didn't become beautiful,
you just got colorful.
You look like a fool.
You nitwit! What have you done!
Sit down!
Wait for me, lady.
Stop! Come back here!
Miss, where are you going?
You can't leave.
Nurse, l have a wedding to catch.
My very own. Can't you understand?
Man, she's really stoned.
l heard she's super-smart...
that's how she lost her mind.
Poor thing.
Why am l in a straitjacket?
lsn't this for crazy people?
Do l look like a crazy person?
Tell me.
The doctor says
you're a threat to human life.
To yourself and others.
Believe me, l'm not crazy.
You can't lock me up,
l'm getting married!
Dad, here's the check for the resort
and for the wedding package.
1 .5 million pesos?
This is the price of a condo!
l am not talking to you.
Dad, this includes all expenses,
including guest lodgings. Sign it, Dad.
lt's the wedding of Harold,
your first grandchild.
Dad, don't tell me you're signing that.