LOLA: Ok, Howard - meow...
Meow...come on - meow...
Meow...meow...
Come on, Howard.
Come on - me-ow...
GLEN: We'll dub it in later.
Keep going.
JAMIE: Ta here.
GLEN: Bigger.
JAMIE: Ta here!
GLEN: Bigger!
JAMIE: Ta here!!
GLEN: Alright, cut!
♪
SANDY: Welcome
back, everybody.
I'm Sandy, and
I'm an ex-lesbian.
ALEX: I'm Alex and
TEAGAN: I'm Teagan
and I'm an ex-lesbian.
AMBER: I'm Amber,
FELICIA: I'm Felicia,
and I'm an ex-lesbian.
RUBY: I'm Ruby and
I'm an ex-lesbian.
JAMIE: My name's Jamie
and uh - you're a lesbian.
You're a lesbian.
Jill, you're a lesbian.
You are a lesbian.
Jill you are such a lesbian.
You're a lesbian.
Come on - you're a lesbian.
You're a lesbian,
you're a lesbian...
JILL: I'm an ex-lesbian!
JAMIE: AAAAAAAAHHH!
DAVID: Well, you
can shut the door!
DAVID: Well that was a
good way to start the day.
JAMIE: Yeah, too soon David.
You know I just saw your um...
We need to wait two days.
DAVID: Two days?
How about I come
back in an hour?
JAMIE: What?
No no no - you
gotta hear me out.
We got to wait two days
because I've never seen
a...you know, and
it needs some time.
Too soon.
DAVID: I'm coming back later.
JAMIE: It's too soon.
Hi.
GLEN: Alright Jamester,
we're going to go again.
Now remember what I said about
enthusiasm and commitment.
This is going to be the best
mockumentary about cat actors
that the world has ever seen.
JAMIE: You got it, Glen.
LOLA: Smile, Howard.
Oops - I goofed up.
JAMIE: What's up, Lola?
Lo-lee Lola?
I'm all moved in.
You should come by
and see it some time.
LOLA: I'd rather not.
JAMIE: See I don't know what
it is that you bisexuals do,
but lesbians are usually
friends with each other after
they break up.
So maybe we
could be friends...
...Or not.
Ok, well I'll be over there.
JOSÉ: Places, everybody.
Quiet on set.
LOLA: Ok, we're going to do
this one more time Howard.
You are doing so great.
Keep it up.
JOSÉ: Roll camera.
DAVID: Take 2.
GLEN: And...action!
LOLA: Meow.
JAMIE: Ta here!
LOLA: Meow!
Get...
LOLA: Meow.
JAMIE: Ta here!
Get me - ow - ta here!
Me-owtta here - you owtta
here - we are out of here!!
GLEN: Cut!
Bravo!!
Bra-vo!!
SANDY: Jill, how long has
it been since you and your
boyfriend Jamie broke up?
JILL: It'll be
four years next week.
SANDY: And you haven't
dated anybody since.
JILL: ...No.
SANDY: Any thoughts of women?
Relapses?
JILL: ...Sometimes.
GINGER: You know what I
did to convince myself that
I wasn't a lesbian anymore?
I made a date with
my ex-girlfriend.
Just to close that
chapter before moving on.
And you know what?
It actually worked.
One last fling with her
and I never looked back.
SANDY: I find that
unscrupulous at best
and dangerous at worst.
Ladies, attraction is
a beast that needs to
be tamed, not taunted.
Jill, I think going out and
finding another man to date is
the best course
of action for you.
It's important that you
keep your willingness.
That you don't close
that door on possibility.
We are all rooting for
you to be heterosexual, Jill!
Yeah?
GROUP: Jill!
Jill!
Jill likes the dick!
Liking the dick!
Jill!
Heterosexual!
JAZZ SONG: ♪ Heterosexual
Jill (Jill!) Heterosexual Jill ♪
♪ (Jill!) What a thrill
it's not to be her... ♪
♪ Heterosexual me (Me!)
Heterosexual you (You!) ♪
♪ That's how we'll
all get through... ♪
♪ Jill had a boyfriend
His name was Jamie ♪
♪ She didn't know
he was a girl... ♪
♪ How can you blame me?!
♪ But Jill, don't you see
♪ There's unfinished business
between you and Jamie. ♪
♪ How can you move
forward, how can you let go ♪
♪ When there is
so much to know? ♪
♪ Heterosexual, heterosexual,
heterosexual Jill!!! ♪
♪ Jill...
JILL: Ugh - no!
Yuck.
Gross.
Hi!
It's good to see you too!
I think I left my
jacket in here.
JAMIE: You've never been here.
JILL: I know.
Can I come in?
JAMIE: Jill, how
did you find me?
JILL: I'm stalking you.
I'm kidding!
I'm just kidding.
I'm kid...
Yeah, I was just in
the neighborhood,
and I - you know.
Can I come in?
I'm harmless.
Really.
Go ahead, search me.
Pat me down.
Feel me up.
JAMIE: Do you want
something to drink?
JILL: Yeah...do
you have water?
JAMIE: Yeah.
JILL: I'll have some of that.
Thanks.
So you moved, huh?
JAMIE: Uh huh.
JILL: How's what's her name?
Psycho roommate girl?
JAMIE: Lola.
JILL: Right, Lola.
JAMIE: She's fine.
JILL: Does she live here?
JAMIE: No.
JILL: Thank you.
Mmm.
Oh that's good.
What kind is it?
JAMIE: Tap.
JILL: Mmm.
Jamie, I have
something I need to ask you.
Why don't you come sit.
Ok, I know you had your
reasons for deceiving me.
JAMIE: Jill, I
wasn't deceiving you.
I got cast as a man in a film.
They had me sign a
confidentiality agreement,
they told me that
if I told anybody -
JILL: Listen, it doesn't matter
why you were deceiving me.
The fact is that you were.
JILL: What is that?
Did you just have
surgery or something?
JAMIE: Yeah.
JILL: Maybe I should have
been able to read the signs.
But when you
tried to seduce me -
JAMIE: Ok, wait -
no, you seduced me.
JILL: I don't think so.
JAMIE: No, I'm
pretty clear on this.
You seduced me.
JILL: Do you think I
have that kind of power?
JAMIE: I wouldn't...I
wouldn't say "power"...
I mean, you know.
JILL: Jamie, if I were a
lesbian I would be totally in
love with myself too.
So it's OK - I get it.
Stop trying to seduce me!
JAMIE: It was an accident.
JILL: You say
accident, I say Freudian slip.
JAMIE: You can go at
anytime, you know.
JILL: I have a
favor to ask you.
I came up with a
plan that's going to
solve all of my problems.
JAMIE: Uh huh.
JILL: I think we should date.
I think we should date so that
I know I was only attracted to
you as a man and
not as a woman.
So what do you think?
JAMIE: ...No.
JILL: You don't have to
make a decision right now.
You know what?
Sleep on it.
JAMIE: No.
JILL: Ok, I should get going.
JAMIE: Jill -
JILL: Thank you so
much for the water.
It was really good!
Thank you.
Bye!
Call me!
JAMIE: She's the
craziest person I've ever met.
I mean, come on.
David - who does that?
Who wants to date a lesbian
to turn themselves straight?
DAVID: I thought you were
in love with her anyway.
JAMIE: She's crazy.
DAVID: Well the crazy ones
are always the best in bed.
JOSÉ: One minute to places!
DAVID: How about one
minute at your place.
JAMIE: This film is
such a friggin' joke.
DAVID: What is
that bitch doing.
He's gay, you know!
And he's mine.
JAMIE: Do you think
I owe this to her?
DAVID: Who?
JAMIE: Forget it.
DAVID: Jill?
JAMIE: I kinda
feel like I messed up
her brain or something.
DAVID: Because you lied
about not having a pussy?
JAMIE: Yeah, you're a pussy.
JILL: Jamie used to lie a lot,
and that was really painful.
I even thought I
was in love with him.
So I needed to see
him to sort things out.
Wipe the slate clean so
that I could really move
forward with other men.
So I went to his apartment
last Saturday, and I -
SANDY: Hi there.
Are you here for
better day tomorrow?
JAMIE: Ex-lesbians?
SANDY: Yes, welcome.
Have a seat.
JAMIE: Thank you.
SANDY: Sure.
We started a little while ago,
but if you'd like to introduce
yourself before we continue.
JAMIE: Sure.
My name's Stephanie.
LeBlanc.
You can call me Ms. LeBlanc.
Or Stephanie's probably fine.
Anyway I'm not an ex-lesbian,
just a real lesbian.
SANDY: So are you
a pre-ex-lesbian?
JAMIE: No, just a
pre...futuristic lesbian.
Or a post....modern lesbian.
But I have a friend
who's an ex-lesbian and
I'm convinced it's a phase.
SANDY: Is that right.
Well let's just see if
we can broaden your
viewpoints a little bit.
Welcome, Stephanie.
GROUP: Welcome, Stephanie.
JAMIE: Thank you.
SANDY: Now Jill
here was just telling us
about her ex-boyfriend Jamie.
JAMIE: Oh - well I'm
sorry to have interrupted.
SANDY: Not a problem.
She was just telling us how
she showed up at his apartment
after having not
seen him in four years.
JAMIE: Oh...four
years is a long time, Jill.
To still be
thinking about him.
SANDY: It is never too
late to rekindle an old flame
with an eligible bachelor.
Isn't that right, ladies!
GROUP: That's right!!
JAMIE: He must be
quite a catch, Jill.
SANDY: Any man we can
catch is worth catching.
Isn't that right, ladies!
GROUP: That's right!!
SANDY: So you went
to his apartment...
JILL: Yep, and that's it.
That's the end of the story.
SANDY: Well was he there?
What did he say,
what did you say?
JILL: No, he wasn't there.
SANDY: Ok then...good for you,
for taking that first step
toward getting back on track
with your heterosexual life.
Alright, we have a few
minutes before break.
If you'd all just
sit back please.
Close your eyes, relax.
We'll start with a
few deep breaths.
Inhale...
and exhale...
I like the dick,
pussy be gone.
GROUP: I like the
dick, pussy be gone.
I like the dick,
pussy be gone!
SANDY: Balls.
GROUP MEMBERS: Cunt.
Penis.
Lactose intolerant.
Erect penises in my mouth.
Jello!
Tahini.
Penis.
Hummus.
Melty cheese!
Coal miners.
Wet pussy!
Yes!
Rectum.
JILL: What are
you doing here?!
JAMIE: I wanted
to check it out.
JILL: This isn't
a joke, Jamie.
JAMIE: I'm not laughing, Jill.
JILL: I would like it very
much if you would leave.
JAMIE: I'm going to
stay until I get my turn.
JILL: What are
you going to say?
JAMIE: You'll see.
JILL: Don't embarrass me.
JAMIE: You'll see!
SANDY: So Stephanie,
would you like to tell us a
little more about your friend?
Stephanie?
Stephanie!
Would you like to tell
us about your friend?
JAMIE: Uh - yeah.
Yeah, sure.
So my friend...ish, came
to me the other day wanting
me to help her
with her ex-lesbianism.
Call me
old-fashioned, but I really
don't believe in this stuff.
I believe that God
created lesbians.
God created man,
and He created woman,
but He also created two
women, hence lesbians.
MEMBER Yeah, but he made it
so their parts don't match.
JAMIE: What do you mean?
They match perfectly.
They're like a pair
of furry slippers.
MEMBER: God did not
create two women.
He created Adam and
Eve, and they had kids.
JAMIE: Yeah, but Adam
and Eve had two boys.
Where did their
wives come from?
MEMBER: Their wives
weren't lesbians.
JAMIE: John 18:12,
and on the seventh day,
God created lesbians.
MEMBER: You're an idiot.
SANDY: Stephanie,
this is a secular group.
We try to help
women become heterosexual
outside of conventional
religious teachings.
JAMIE: How come?
SANDY: Well ex-lesbians
come from all different faiths.
And some from no faith at all.
JAMIE: Oh.
I guess that's kinda cool.
SANDY: So how did you
leave things with your friend?
JAMIE: Well I told Jill....O.
Jill-O.
That I don't know
if I could help her do
something that's so unnatural.
JILL: What's so unnatural
about wanting to be happy?
JAMIE: But what
does being straight
have to do with being happy?
JILL: Maybe being
accepted, maybe fitting in.
Maybe not having
to be ashamed,
maybe not having to hide.
Maybe not having your
friends and family desert you
for being some kind of freak.
Not everyone's
life was like yours.
Some of us didn't
have it so easy.
You can't compare your life to
mine, or anyone else here.
You can't even begin to
compare those things.
DAVID: You are so whipped.
JAMIE: I just think that
maybe I can help her, you know?
I mean maybe she'll end up a
lesbian or maybe she won't,
but I feel like
either way she just needs my
help to get out of this limbo.
DAVID: You just want
to get into her pants.
JAMIE: Yeah right
David, I wouldn't
touch her with a 10 foot pole.
DAVID: But you would
if it was 9 inches!
Eh?
Get it?
See what I did?
JAMIE: Yeah, hmm.
More like 4.
DAVID: OK mine is
at least 5 or 6!
JAMIE: I don't want
to know about it.
DAVID: You brought it up!
(Lola and José talk in Spanish)
DAVID: She's such a hussy.
JAMIE: Don't I know it.
DAVID: Tell her to keep
her hands off my man!
(talking in Spanish).
JOSÉ: Hi.
JAMIE: Hey.
LOLA: Hey.
(talking in Spanish).
JAMIE: Oh don't
let me interrupt.
I'm just walking by.
So Spanish.
Flavor of the month, is it?
LOLA: Excuse me?
JAMIE: Well, it's obvious
what kind of tactics you have.
First German, now Spanish.
I'd say it was clever but
I don't think that it is.
LOLA: I like languages.
JAMIE: José's gay anyway.
LOLA: No he's not.
JAMIE: Don't start.
LOLA: Don't start what?
He's not gay.
He winked at me.
JAMIE: Oh he winked at you.
You know I do expect
more from you than that.
LOLA: Not all
effeminate men are gay.
JAMIE: Ok, here we go...
LOLA: Well it's true.
JAMIE: Ok I'll
give you that, Lola.
Not all
effeminate men are gay.
The rest are from Europe.
But since José is from
Mexico, he's actually
exempt under that clause.
You think that's funny?
LOLA: It's kinda funny.
You're still an
asshole though.
JAMIE: What did I do?
I never did anything.
LOLA: That's right.
You never did anything.
JAMIE: That's the end
of this conversation.
LOLA: Have you
found anyone desperate
enough to date you yet?
JAMIE: Yes, I did.
JILL: Hi.
What's that?
JAMIE: It's a rose.
JILL: What are
you doing with it?
JAMIE: I thought you wanted
this to be like a real date?
JILL: Yeah, a
real lesbian date.
Try again.
Jamie, when was the last
time you gave a girl flowers?
JAMIE: I gave my mom
flowers for Mother's Day.
JILL: Exactly.
So plant that in the
ground and try again.
JAMIE: You can't plant - ugh.
I've given
girlfriends flowers before, OK?
And my friend gives her
girlfriend flowers every week,
so you just can't -
JILL: And take off
that ridiculous tie!
Who is it?
JAMIE: It's your lesbian date.
I'm wearing a backpack
and carrying a BPA-free
refillable water bottle.
JILL: Jamie, we are
not going on a hike.
And a real lesbian
would never knock.
A real lesbian would use
the keys that I gave her.
JAMIE: Jill -
JILL: Let's do that.
It's the big silver one.
The big silver one!
JAMIE: They're
all big and silver!
JILL: It's this one.
JAMIE: Jill, I'm a
lesbian - a real one.
I don't know what
you've been doing,
but I'm a real lesbian and
we don't do any of this,
so get your
purse - we're going!
JILL: A real lesbian
woman who takes charge.
I like it!
Alright!
JAMIE: Let's go.
JILL: Ok!
What, nothing?
JAMIE: What do lesbians say
when they go out on a date?
You tell me Jill.
JILL: I don't know -
you're the lesbian.
JILL: Rule #1 - I
call all the shots.
Rule #2 - First base only.
Rule #3 - No means no.
Do you know what that means?
It means that if you make a
move and I think it's too
much, and I say no, that
means you have to back off, OK?
JAMIE: Yeah, I got it.
JILL: Rule #4 - have fun being
my last lesbian girlfriend!
Because we're
going to get married!
LOL - we're so not
getting married.
We're breaking up
as soon as I'm ripe
for the heterosexual picking.
JILL: Women are pigs.
BARTENDER: You
should try dating men.
JILL: I've tried.
Tried with no success.
BARTENDER: Well you know
what they say - If at first you
don't succeed -
try, try, try again.
Then quit.
'Cuz there's no point in being
- you know, dumb about it.
JAMIE: Ooh - look at that.
The bartender's
flirting with you.
JILL: Who, Yentl?
She's not my type.
JAMIE: You sound disappointed.
JILL: Ok, here's to...us.
May our relationship be
short and to the point.
May it end
effortlessly and painlessly,
and - oh shit!
JAMIE: What?
JILL: Shit, shit, shit...
JAMIE: Uh, hello?
JILL: Shhh.
Don't talk to me!
I'm not here!
I'm sorry - I'm so sorry.
I think I dropped my quarter.
JAMIE: It's OK...honey.
Come back up - I
have more quarters.
JILL: Is she still there?
JAMIE: Who?
JILL: The girl with the red tank
top and the huge big boobs.
JAMIE: Ohhh....
JILL: She's in my
ex-lesbian group.
JAMIE: Ohhhhh....
JILL: What is she doing doing?
JAMIE: Probably the
same thing you are.
JILL: Here.
Go try to buy her a drink.
Flirt with her or something.
JAMIE: Why?
JILL: Because I want to
know what she's doing here.
JAMIE: What if she
recognizes me from the meeting?
JILL: Jamie,
don't flatter yourself.
All you dykes look the same.
JAMIE: That wasn't nice!
JILL: Just go!
JAMIE: Not until you tell
me that I'm a unique and
original-looking lesbian, Jill.
JILL: Jamie...
JAMIE: Fine.
JAMIE: Hey.
RUBY: Hi.
JAMIE: How's it goin'.
RUBY: It's going....
JAMIE: Yeah?
RUBY: What's your name?
JAMIE: Jamie.
RUBY: Ruby.
JAMIE: Oh, Ruby -
that's very nice.
RUBY: It rhymes with booby...
JAMIE: Huh?
RUBY: Did you come here alone?
JAMIE: No, I came
with my friend.
She's straight.
Are you straight?
RUBY: What do you think?
JAMIE: I think
you're...very pretty.
RUBY: Jill??
JILL: Let's go.
JAMIE: I'll call you.
JAMIE: Woah, wait - stop.
Stop.
JILL: Why?
JAMIE: Because you're drunk and
you're going to regret this.
JILL: I'm not drunk.
JAMIE: Then I'm
going to regret it.
JILL: You don't
think I'm sexy?
JAMIE: You're very sexy, Jill.
But you're also a little nuts.
You're a little crazy.
And this is counter-productive
to whatever you want to do.
JILL: Just fuck me.
JAMIE: No!
JILL: Please?
JAMIE: Jill...no...
JILL: Pretty please
with a cherry on top?
JAMIE: No means no.
Remember?
Your rules?
JILL: You're no fun.
Male Jamie was
so much more fun.
He was up for anything!
JAMIE: Yeah well, he didn't
have sex with you either.
JILL: Well he had a
heart problem and that
was a whole other issue.
Do you have a heart problem?
JAMIE: I don't, no.
JILL: No?
What was his problem then?
JAMIE: His problem
was he had boobs.
JILL: Oh...man boobs.
Those aren't sexy.
JAMIE: No, they're not sexy.
JILL: But lady boobies are!
JAMIE: Ok.
Right.
Yeah.
You know what?
God gave you some
lady boobies so you could
enjoy them all by yourself.
So you don't need me there!
JILL: Oh yeah?
JAMIE: Yeah, just...no no no.
JILL: OH YEAH!!!
JAMIE: Ok, why
don't you lay down?
JILL: Oh yeah?
With you on top of me?
JAMIE: With a blanket on top.
JILL: What's the
blanket going to do?
JAMIE: It's going
to keep you warm.
JILL: Like hot?
JAMIE: Sure.
JILL: Very hot?
JAMIE: Yeah.
JILL: Yeah!
JILL: Why is my shirt off?
JAMIE: You took it off.
JILL: Did you touch
my boobs last night?
JAMIE: No!
JILL: Oh.
Did you want to?
JAMIE: Your shirt's on
the living room chair.
JILL: Thanks, I saw it.
Did you want to touch
my boobs last night?
JAMIE: You can go put it on.
JILL: Jamie, just because
you're a lesbian doesn't mean
everything has to be sexual.
A bra's basically
like a bikini top.
JAMIE: Yeah, and a
pussy's a patch of hair.
JILL: Not mine; I shave.
JAMIE: Ok...do you
want some coffee, Jill?
JILL: Yes please.
JAMIE: Hand me the mug by you.
I'll pour some in there.
JILL: So this guy, a couple
of days ago, he came up and
he was like - "Does the
carpet match the drapes?"
And I was like -
"Hard wood floors, baby!"
I don't wear underwear either.
JAMIE: Don't your
pants get gross?
JILL: Why would
they get gross?
JAMIE: Cream?
I meant in your coffee.
Do you want cream
in your coffee.
JILL: Jamie, you
need to lighten up.
God you're a prude.
JAMIE: Cream, sugar?
JILL: Yes please.
Both.
JAMIE: I'm surprised
you're not hungover.
JILL: Did we kiss last night?
JAMIE: Yes.
JILL: Did I like it?
JAMIE: Well, since you are
a sex-starved lesbian...
JILL: I am not sex-starved.
I've gone five
years without sex.
Big deal.
I've gone longer
without carbs.
Let's kiss.
Let's kiss!
Get on my lap.
JAMIE: I'm not
sitting on your lap!
JILL: Get on my lap.
I want to know what it's like.
JAMIE: You haven't
even brushed your teeth.
JAMIE: How did I let
you talk me into this.
JILL: You don't even know
what we're going to do.
JAMIE: It doesn't matter.
JILL: Ok.
This is good.
Promise me that you'll
kiss me whenever I say go.
JAMIE: No.
JILL: Jamie,
this is part of it.
You've kissed me
before so it shouldn't be
a problem doing it again.
JAMIE: Yeah, like the
time you spit afterward?
JILL: I was trying something.
JAMIE: Are you going
to spit afterward?
Because if you're
going to spit afterward,
I don't want to do it.
That's just insulting.
JILL: I'm not going
to spit afterward.
JAMIE: So you're
going to swallow?
JILL: Don't be gross.
JAMIE: Do you think you'll
ever give a guy a blow job?
JILL: Don't be gross!
JAMIE: I won't.
Thank God.
Oh, God.
That shit stinks.
JILL: Yeah, it does.
Ok - go!
JAMIE: What are you doing?
JILL: Aversion therapy.
JAMIE: Oh my God.
JILL: What, you
have a better idea?
JAMIE: I do.
Yeah, come here.
JILL: Ok.
OW!
JAMIE: Oh, I
think it's working.
JILL: That wasn't nice.
JAMIE: Come here,
let's try it again.
I think this is
really going to help.
JILL: Ok, yeah.
JAMIE: Ow!
JILL: Yeah.
JAMIE: Yeah!
JILL: OW!!
JAMIE: Come on, straight girl.
Aversion therapy.
This is very
effective I think.
JILL: Take that!
What is that?
JAMIE: I'm doing my defense.
JILL: You're doing
your chicken dance.
You're not even fighting.
JAMIE: It's my defense.
JILL: It's my defense!
JAMIE: You got to admit,
last night was way more fun.
If that dumpster and
Girl Club had a fight,
that dumpster would
so kick Girl Club's ass!
No, no, no - Girl Club would
so kick the dumpster's ass!
JILL: Jamie, I've
been thinking -
JAMIE: Hey, would do you
get when you offer a blonde
a penny for her thoughts?
JILL: I know that we're
not in a real relationship -
JAMIE: Change!
JILL: But I think
the both of us should
start taking it more seriously.
JAMIE: I'm
taking it seriously.
JILL: Good.
Then you'll have no
problem being exclusive.
No Ruby, no hot girls.
JAMIE: Why can't I
have any hot girls?
JILL: Because that
makes me feel jealous,
and that makes me
feel like a lesbian.
So no hot girls.
And no un-hot girls either.
And no boys.
JAMIE: Gross.
JILL: And no Lola.
JAMIE: Lola's not even human.
JILL: Well I thought
maybe you guys had a thing.
JAMIE: Yeah we used to.
But it's over.
JILL: Do you still talk?
JAMIE: Yeah but
even when we do talk,
I just try to insult her
and make her feel bad.
JILL: What happened?
JAMIE: Nothing really.
It just didn't end well.
She doesn't think I'm
good enough for her.
She doesn't think
I'm smart enough.
JILL: She said that?
JAMIE: Yeah, kind of.
She used to talk during sex.
JILL: Like dirty talk?
JAMIE: No, talk like
quote facts and stuff.
JILL: So that's why
you guys broke up.
The sex was bad.
JAMIE: It wasn't bad.
I mean, how bad could it be.
JILL: I've had
some really bad sex.
JAMIE: Yeah?
With men?
JILL: No.
Not yet.
JAMIE: Yeah me neither.
Not yet, not ever,
never, for as long as I live,
so God help me!
JILL: That's
pretty closed minded.
JAMIE: Closed minded?
Don't fucking get me
started on closed minded.
JILL: If you're
referring to me,
I am not closed minded.
I am just strong willed.
JAMIE: Strong
willed in a lesbian way.
JILL: No, strong willed in
a...Hillary Clinton way.
JAMIE: You do
realize that you just said
the exact same thing I did.
Ok, good.
As long as you realize.
It's the same as yours.
JILL: I know.
DAVID: Ooh - quinoa's on sale.
JOSÉ: I like your shirt.
DAVID: Thank you.
JOSÉ: It fits you well.
DAVID: Thank you!
JAMIE: Thank you!
DAVID: Shut up.
What am I supposed to say?
JAMIE: I don't
know - want to fuck?
DAVID: You're such a dude.
JAMIE: You're such a girl.
DAVID: Is that pot?
JAMIE: No, dumb ass.
It's catnip.
Oh.
LOLA: Hello David.
Hello Jamie.
I did some research.
Yesterday at 8:24am, José
made himself a cup of coffee.
Black.
Only straight men
drink black coffee.
JAMIE: Oh come on.
LOLA: 9:30 am - José makes
himself a regular bagel,
not the low carb kind.
And he uses regular
cream cheese, not light.
JAMIE: So?
LOLA: 10:15 am -
José says to Time,
and I quote "I could jump
start your car blindfolded
with my hands tied
behind my back."
11:30 am -
JAMIE: Wait a minute, Lola.
Since when do you
believe in stereotypes?
LOLA: Jamie, I think if you're
honest with yourself about
this, you'll see that
you're just jealous that I've
moved on and you haven't.
JAMIE: Oh really?
OK.
Well then why don't
you tell that to Jill?
Because she spent
the night on Saturday.
LOLA: No she didn't.
JAMIE: Yes she did!
And she's good in bed, too -
just like you
always were afraid of!
LOLA: I wasn't afraid!
Why would she say that?
I mean, how immature
does one need to be.
Really.
DAVID: José likes my
body in this shirt.
LOLA: Did Jamie ever tell
you if I was good in bed?
DAVID: No.
I mean...yes?
LOLA: She's just jealous.
I mean, José gay?
Come on.
If that man's gay, then I'm...
I don't know -
what would I be?
DAVID: A hussy?
LOLA: Ok, sure.
If he's gay,
then I'm...a hussy.
You don't think
he's gay, do you?
DAVID: I think
he's in love with me.
LOLA: Yeah.
Sure.
JAMIE: How much
time do we have left?
JILL: Well, you
just ruined it.
JAMIE: Good job, Jill.
We did good.
We didn't kiss - you're on
your way to being straight!
JILL: I know.
JAMIE: I think you
can win at this.
JILL: Well I am
straight - not on my way.
JAMIE: Right, of course.
What are you
doing in bed with me?
JILL: It's like a sleepover.
JAMIE: We should like braid
each other's hair and stuff.
JILL: Well I have a
feeling you don't know how.
JAMIE: I can braid hair.
JILL: Really?
JAMIE: Yeah.
JILL: Ok, well we'll do that -
JAMIE: I don't
think I want too, though.
I'd rather go to
the strip club.
Wouldn't you want to?
Wouldn't you rather do that?
We'll have fun.
We'll get you drunk
and get you a lap dance.
JAMIE: Yeah
show us your vagina!
DAVID: Yesterday, 10:51am -
José smiles at me and not
Sarah, who was closer
to him in proximity.
LOLA: That's just
because Sarah's a bitch.
DAVID: 11:28am - José sits
down and crosses his legs,
but keeps them together.
LOLA: That's just a
cultural difference.
DAVID: Ok, 12:45pm José
makes himself a salad.
He uses light salad dressing.
A diet salad?
Really?
LOLA: That's because
he gained so much
weight from all the bagels.
JAMIE: Why don't
one of you wimps just
ask that guy out on a date?
LOLA: This is more fun.
Besides - I'm winning.
DAVID: That's because you
totally discounted everything
that happened yesterday.
LOLA: Yesterday
was an anomaly.
José is getting a cold.
DAVID: So?
He still bought that
scarf at some point,
and has it in his wardrobe.
LOLA: Well today
he's wearing socks
that don't match his outfit.
DAVID: They're black.
LOLA: Exactly.
And his pants are off-black.
JAMIE: You guys are dumb.
LOLA: Not as dumb as
you in that outfit.
Sparkle buns.
Hello, 1984 called and
they want their outfit back...
JAMIE: Well you seem to
know from experience.
JILL: I'm not bisexual.
JAMIE: Why not?
JILL: Because I'm
not attracted to men.
Except - I was
attracted to male Jamie.
JAMIE: Yeah, I know.
Male Jamie was
the love of your life
and I'm a huge disappointment.
JILL: Don't say that.
JAMIE: Can we go to sleep now?
JILL: Jamie, don't say that.
You're not a disappointment.
JAMIE: Can we just
go to sleep now?
JILL: What's wrong?
JAMIE: Nothing.
I'm just tired.
JILL: You look sad.
JAMIE: I'm just tired.
JILL: Look at me.
JAMIE: I don't think
that we should do this.
JILL: You don't want to?
JAMIE: I don't want to
if you don't want to.
JILL: I want to.
JAMIE: Hey.
JILL: Hi!
Want some eggs?
JAMIE: Yeah, that sounds good.
Um...what are you doing today?
JILL: Just running
errands, looking for work.
JAMIE: Cool.
Sounds fun.
Pretty good day lined up.
JILL: I'd kiss you, but I
haven't brushed my teeth yet!
JAMIE: Yeah, it's not a
problem...I mean uh...
you know uh...me too!
Me too...
JILL: Why are you being weird?
JAMIE: I just um...I
just...want to make sure
you're OK with everything.
JILL: Yeah.
I'm OK.
JAMIE: Good.
Because it doesn't
need to mean anything.
I'm not saying that it
doesn't mean anything to me.
I'm just saying that
it doesn't need to.
It could.
But it could not, too.
I mean, it is what it is.
Or it's not...that.
JILL: You're pretty
cute when you stammer.
Pretty cute!
JAMIE AND DAVID:
AAAAAAAAHHH!!!!!!
DAVID: Why are
you still here?!
JAMIE: Who does that?!
DAVID: We need five days!
Five days before we
can see each other!
JAMIE: Who masturbates
in an unlocked bathroom?!
DAVID: No one ever
uses that bathroom!
JAMIE: I use that bathroom!
You know that I
use that bathroom!
DAVID: The lock's broken.
JAMIE: I know it's broken,
that's why I like using it!
It keeps everyone else
away from using it, David!
You picked an unlocked
bathroom to masturbate in.
Who the fuck does that?
You couldn't wait
until you got home?
DAVID: José's
wearing a tank top today.
JAMIE: Ew!
DAVID: You asked!
JAMIE: It was a
rhetorical question!
DAVID: Fine.
Let's just forget it.
Let's just stop
talking about it.
JAMIE: Fine.
DAVID: Agreed.
DAVID: Hey Guys.
What's up?
JOSÉ: Hey.
Lola was just practicing
her Spanish with me.
LOLA: Hablas Español?
DAVID: So I was taking this
new Spanish cooking class.
You should come over
sometime and uh - sample.
JOSÉ: That sounds
delicious, thank you.
Maybe Lola can come
and add some flavor.
(talking in Spanish)
LOLA: That sounds like
fun - thanks for the invite!
DAVID: You know
Jamie's going to be there,
so you probably don't
want to deal with that.
LOLA: I think I
can handle her.
Thanks though.
DAVID: Mother fucker.
JAMIE: Is everything OK?
JILL: Yeah, I'm fine.
JAMIE: Is it OK
we're going to David's?
JILL: Of course.
(José and Lola
talk in Spanish).
DAVID: So here's an
idea - why don't we speak in
English so we can all join in?
Or I could talk in Chinese.
(David talks in Chinese).
DAVID: Lola, can I see
you in the other room?
LOLA: Why?
LOLA: What is going on?
DAVID: I'd like to
ask you the same thing.
LOLA: Ok...
DAVID: You're
purposely talking to him in
Spanish to leave me out!
LOLA: David, you're
being hypersensitive.
DAVID: Jamie, can you
come here for a second?
DAVID: Please tell Lola
that talking to José in
Spanish in front of us is rude.
LOLA: David,
this is very mature.
Bringing Jamie in
here to gang up on me.
JAMIE: You guys, this
is stupid and I'm bored.
Can I go?
DAVID: No.
JOSÉ: Jill.
Just the woman I
was hoping to see.
Smoke?
JILL: No thanks.
I quit.
JOSÉ: That's good.
Quitting is sometimes
the best thing to do.
JILL: Yeah...
JOSÉ: So tell me
something about yourself, Jill.
What makes you tick?
JILL: Oh, I don't know.
Not much, really.
JOSÉ: Oh come on.
You're holding out on me.
JILL: No, I'm
probably just really boring.
JOSÉ: Boring!
I don't believe
that for a second.
You know, you have
really pretty eyes.
JILL: Woah!
JOSÉ: Oh I'm sorry.
I have mints here.
It'll clear that right up.
I'm sorry.
JAMIE: Well I really don't
think that José's attracted
to either one of you guys.
LOLA: Do you
think he's asexual?
JAMIE: No.
He just thinks
you're repulsive.
LOLA: Jamie!
JAMIE: So can I go now?
I think this is settled.
DAVID: No.
It's not settled.
We're not leaving
until you're friends again.
JILL: I thought you were gay.
JOSÉ: Excuse me?
Oh, that's funny.
Me gay?
Oh that's funny.
JILL: Yeah...
JOSÉ: Oh, you're funny.
You're really funny Jill.
You want a mint?
JILL: No thank you.
JOSÉ: Well why don't
you get closer so you
can smell my fresh breath.
JILL: That sounds
like a trick question.
JOSÉ: Maybe the trick is
that it's not a question.
JILL: Then what if I say "no"?
It must be a
question if I can say "no."
JOSÉ: What are
you so afraid of?
JILL: I'm not afraid.
Maybe I just don't
want to kiss you.
JOSÉ: Maybe doesn't
sound like a "no" to me.
DAVID: Because you
used to be in love,
and now all you do is fight.
JAMIE: That's how life works.
LOLA: It doesn't need to.
JAMIE: Yeah, and that's what I
told you - that lesbians stay
friends after they break up.
But you didn't want
to go along with it!
LOLA: Maybe because
you inherently excluded me
when you said "lesbians."
JAMIE: Oh, that's right.
We have to give
Lola special treatment
because she's "bisexual."
LOLA: You don't have to
put it in air quotes.
JAMIE: We have to have a whole
special language for her,
make special considerations.
You're just like those
people on the airplane who
get their own special meal!
LOLA: You can order
a special meal too.
JAMIE: ...I don't want to.
LOLA: Then who cares?
JAMIE: Yeah!
Right, exactly!
Who cares?
We don't care.
So you and all your special
meal people can go form a
colony on some island
together, for all we care!
LOLA: Do you see what
I have to put up with?
JAMIE: Now if
you'll excuse me,
I'm going to go
home and have sex
with my hot blonde girlfriend.
LOLA: And I am going to go
have sex with my non-asexual,
hot Latin lover!
DAVID: Yeah me too.
JOSÉ: Jill!
JILL: It didn't mean anything.
JAMIE: It doesn't matter.
We were never
really a couple, so
you can't really cheat on me.
JILL: Why can't I
just go to your place?
JAMIE: Don't ask
stupid questions.
JILL: So you're just
breaking up with me?
JAMIE: We never had a
real relationship Jill,
so we don't need to break-up.
JILL: Can you
stop saying that?
Stop saying we didn't
have a real relationship.
JAMIE: Well did we?
JILL: Look, that
was in the beginning.
Things are different now.
JAMIE: It's different now why?
Because you have sex with
me, and now you're such a huge
dyke that you can't even
keep your hands off other men.
JILL: Look, I freaked
out about last night.
And I was talking to José
and he smelled really nice.
I think he wears your cologne.
JAMIE: Oh right.
Yeah, and the cologne
confused you - of course,
I understand Jill.
JILL: Look, I made a mistake.
JAMIE: Right, because
you're obviously blind and deaf
and you need to rely on
your keen sense of smell
to lead you to your mate.
I mean, it could've
happened to anybody, really.
JILL: What do you
want me to say?
I'm confused.
I'm fucked up.
I made a mistake!
JAMIE: Yeah well, now you can
make all the mistakes you want.
But you're not
going to do it with me.
JILL: Fine.
JAMIE: José's gay anyway.
JILL: Good.
Then I guess we
belong together!!!
DAVID: José's
wearing a tank top today.
JAMIE: Ew!
DAVID: Jamie, I'm
getting so desperate,
you're starting to
look good to me.
JAMIE: AAAAAAAAHHH!!!
JAMIE: Ha ha Howard.
This is so hilarious.
You're so funny, Howard.
You gotta - stop
making me laugh, ha ha.
GLEN: Cut!
James, come with me.
GLEN: James, what
is going on today?
JAMIE: I just have
some girl trouble.
GLEN: PMS?
JAMIE: No Glen.
Trouble with girls.
I slept with this girl.
She's an ex-lesbian.
And -
GLEN: And Howard
reminds you of her.
JAMIE: No.
GLEN: I'm sorry about
what you're going through.
But this isn't about you.
This is about Howard.
Our whole day
revolves around Howard.
This whole movie
revolves around, who?
JAMIE: Howard.
GLEN: Howard.
And you know what the greatest
thing about Howard is, Jame-O?
JAMIE: What.
GLEN: It's the
purity in his heart.
When you look at his face,
doesn't it just melt your soul?
JAMIE: I'm coming in.
I'm coming in!!
AAAAAAAAHHH!!
LOLA: Jesus Jamie, calm down.
JAMIE: Why do you
even use this bathroom?
The lock doesn't work.
LOLA: I like it
because no one else uses it.
JAMIE: Listen Lola.
I got to talk to
you about something.
LOLA: Can I go to
the bathroom first?
JAMIE: No, because -
no, no, you can't!
We don't have enough time
before we start shooting.
LOLA: Then we'll talk after.
JAMIE: No, I have to
talk to you about it now!
LOLA: Can't it wait?
JAMIE: It can not wait!!
LOLA: Fine.
We'll talk while I go.
JAMIE: So I need to ask you
about something but you got to
promise not to make fun of me.
LOLA: Huh?
JAMIE: You got to
promise not to make fun of me!
LOLA: Why would I
make fun of you?
JAMIE: Just open the door!
LOLA: Fine.
JAMIE: So I recently saw
David's...male anatomy.
LOLA: Uh huh.
JAMIE: Twice.
And it was my first
time seeing a real one.
And it's not like seeing one
in a movie or looking at the
statue of David - no
pun intended with that.
LOLA: Uh huh.
JAMIE: But I have this vision
of it that won't go away.
And it haunts me in
my dreams at night.
And there's activity.
LOLA: Activity?
JAMIE: You know,
um...not paranormal activity.
But um...sexual activity.
LOLA: So what
you're saying is,
is that you dream about
having sex with David.
JAMIE: No, not with David!
Just men in general.
LOLA: Men in general?
JAMIE: No, not men in general!
Just individual, specific
- can you not look at me?!
So...are you done?
LOLA: Yes.
Let's switch.
JAMIE: So this is
obviously bothering me.
And I want to ask you
what you think it means,
but I know what
you're going to say.
LOLA: What.
JAMIE: I don't want to say it.
LOLA: So you
want me to say it.
JAMIE: No!
I don't want you to say it.
I just want to tell
you that you're wrong.
That what you're going
to say is just not true.
LOLA: You don't even
know what I'm going to say!
JAMIE: Yes I do!
LOLA: Jamie, you just
broke up with Jill.
JAMIE: Can you not look at me?
Please!
LOLA: You hate
doing this movie.
You fight with me
every chance you get.
JAMIE: You fight with me!
LOLA: Would you
just listen to me!
JAMIE: No, because I know
what you're going to say!
LOLA: What am I going to say?!
JAMIE: I don't want to say it!
LOLA: What I am saying is,
is that I think you're
just under a lot of stress.
JAMIE: Oh.
So...what you're saying
is...that it doesn't actually
mean that I want to
have sex with men.
LOLA: No.
Unless you think
there's something more to it?
JAMIE: No.
LOLA: Ok.
Because if there's more to it,
then there's
probably more to it.
JAMIE: No.
There's not more to it, Lola.
LOLA: Ok.
JAMIE: So does this mean
that we're friends now?
I know I've been kind
of an asshole lately.
LOLA: I know, I've
been a bitch too.
JAMIE: So does that
mean we're both sorry and
we both forgive each other?
LOLA: Come here.
DAVID: Sorry, I thought there
would be more women here.
JAMIE: I should go.
DAVID: Stay for
awhile, please?
I don't know anyone.
JAMIE: Then why
don't you come with me?
DAVID: Because I was
hoping I'd meet someone.
Sorry.
About Jill.
JAMIE: Now she's
gallivanting with José,
so there you go.
Who knew we'd both get
screwed by the same bitch.
DAVID: You in love with her?
Well, let's dance.
You know, just have some
fun and not think about it.
JAMIE: I don't want to
dance with a bunch of men.
DAVID: OK it's just
dancing; it's not sex.
You don't even
have to touch anyone.
JAMIE: Why would
I touch anyone?
DAVID: Jamie, it's a joke.
JAMIE: If you ever
catch me with a man, David,
you got to really do something.
DAVID: Ok...
JAMIE: No, I'm serious.
I'm not joking on
this one, David.
You got to really intervene.
I'm talking about
major intervention.
Do you promise me?
DAVID: Promise what?
JAMIE: That you will intervene
if I get too drunk and I
start mackin' on some guy?
DAVID: Jamie, stop
being so ridiculous.
JAMIE: Do you promise me?
DAVID: OK, I promise!
JOSÉ: I hope I didn't
interfere with things
between you and Jamie.
JILL: No, not at all.
Jamie and I were
just good friends who
went down the wrong path.
But let's talk about you.
Tell me about Mexico.
JOSÉ: Oh I'm from Brazil.
JILL: Ok, tell
me about Brazil.
JOSÉ: Brazil is home
to the Brazilian wax.
Have you had one?
JILL: No.
JOSÉ: Oh, there're the best.
JILL: Well, I
shave down there.
JOSÉ: No, this is way
better than shaving.
Plus it reaches places
a razor could never go.
JILL: Maybe I'll
have to try it.
JOSÉ: I have a home wax kit...
JILL: AAAHHH!
Fuck!
Mmmm...
JOSÉ: You like that?
JILL: Mmhmm.
Fuck!
FUCK!!
GAY DUDE: How's it goin'?
RUBY: Hi.
JILL: Aaaaaah!
Aaaaaaah!
AAAAAAAAHHH!
Yeah...
JOSÉ: You make me so
horny when you scream.
JILL: I should go.
JOSÉ: I thought you liked it.
JILL: No, I do.
I just need to go.
JOSÉ: I promise to make it
feel better when it's over.
JILL: I think we
should take things slower.
JOSÉ: It's just a wax job.
I mean, you'd pay
some lady 50 bucks
to do what I did, plus tip.
JILL: No, I loved it.
It's just late and I'm tired.
So let's take a rain check.
RUBY: I knew you'd be back.
JAMIE: Oh yeah?
RUBY: I did.
JAMIE: Um, let me
buy you a drink.
RUBY: You can buy me
anything you want,
as long as you don't buy
your time getting into my bra.
JAMIE: Huh?
RUBY: Sure, whatever you want.
JAMIE: Hey, we'll
have a couple of drinks.
Whatever you recommend.
BARTENDER: How about a
couple of lemon drops?
JAMIE: Yeah.
You want one of those?
RUBY: I want
you...inside of me.
SANDY: So we've
missed you, Jill.
Anything new?
JILL: I started dating a man.
SANDY: Congratulations!
GROUP: Congratulations, Jill!
SANDY Tell us about him.
JILL: He's from Brazil,
and he has an accent,
and he wears cologne.
SANDY: He sounds
perfect for you.
Have you guys been
to third base yet?
JILL: Sort of.
SANDY: And you liked it.
JILL: Yes.
Until I was reminded
that it was him that
I was with instead of my ex.
Girlfriend.
Jamie.
Jamie is my ex-girlfriend,
not my ex-boyfriend.
SANDY: I see...
Transformation
takes time, Jill.
It takes time.
JILL: That's it?
That's all you
have to say to me?
I had sexual and emotional
relations with another woman,
and all you have to say is that
"Transformation takes time?"
SANDY: I don't know what
you want me to say, Jill.
JILL: Why am I still here?
SANDY: To
become an ex-lesbian.
JILL: No.
Why am I still here?
I've been coming to these
longer than most of the other
women, and everyone's moved on
with their heterosexual lives!
Why am I still here?
SANDY: I'm not
going to lie to you.
Most of the
women who have left,
we've lost to the gay agenda.
But you.
You have commitment,
passion, perseverance.
If anybody can do
this Jill, it's you.
GROUP: Jill!
Jill!
Jilly likes the dick!
CASSANDRA: Welcome everyone,
to Reclaiming Your Lesbianism.
As most of you know,
my name is Cassandra,
and I've been living
the lesbian lifestyle
for the last 30 years.
Looks like we have a
bunch of brand new faces,
so why don't we
start to my right.
MARY: Hi, thanks.
My name's Mary.
CASSANDRA: Hi Mary.
MARY: And I went to a series
of ex-lesbian meetings where
they showed gay
male pornography.
They said it would
be twice as effective.
You know, men times two.
And it was hot.
Those gay men fucking
each other was really hot.
I had never really
seen a penis before,
and now - I just can't
get it out of my head.
It's all I think
about, is just penis.
You know, it's everywhere -
just penis, penis, penis!
JAMIE: Can we not
talk about penis?
CASSANDRA: Just one moment.
You'll have your
chance to speak.
JAMIE: Sorry.
CASSANDRA: That's OK.
I know penis is a sensitive
topic to a lot of lesbians.
JAMIE: That's right.
I'm sensitive.
CASSANDRA: Mmhm.
Continue Mary.
MARY: Anyway, I think
about penis so much,
I'm afraid that I
may be bisexual.
I wanted to be straight
because being gay isn't
accepted into society.
But if I'm
bisexual, and I love penis,
then everybody hates me.
So really I just want
to be a lesbian again.
CASSANDRA: Well you see, we
try to focus here on accepting
yourself into the
lesbian lifestyle.
We don't actually
change people's sexuality.
MARY: But if the porn
changed my sexuality,
then why can't I just find
a way to change it back?
CASSANDRA: I don't think
porn changed your sexuality.
I think it just
helped you discover
a hidden part of yourself.
And perhaps we can help
you with accepting that.
RUBY: So I see you've
been hanging out with
that dykey friend of yours.
JILL: Well I saw
you rubbing your
big huge boobs in her face.
RUBY: Well I saw you
pull her away aggressively
and make out with her.
Then I suppose you went back
to her place for some sex,
but you must not
have been very good,
because she came
looking for me last weekend.
JILL: No she didn't.
What did you guys
do with each other?
RUBY: What does
it matter to you?
JILL: It doesn't.
RUBY: When I didn't
see you come back here,
I thought you must have
switched to that lesbo group.
JILL: What's that?
RUBY: Just some group in
Hollywood that Mary joined.
JILL: Does she like it?
RUBY: I don't know.
I don't talk to her know that
she decided to go gay again.
JILL: But you go to lesbian
clubs and pick up on girls.
RUBY: Jill, I'm a lesbo-holic.
If an alcoholic goes to a
bar and has some drinks,
doesn't it makes sense
that he would stay in AA,
and not go to some wine tasting
festival down the street?
JILL: So does that mean you
didn't have sex with Jamie?
RUBY: You know, if you look
sex up in the dictionary,
it doesn't describe
anything that lesbians do.
JAMIE: She has
these huge tits.
Like huge beacons of
light to a lost sailor at sea.
And they talked to me, too.
Kinda like -
"wah wah wah wah."
But in actual words, you know.
Then she took my hand and she
tried to - not really insert
it inside of her, but you know -
kind of put it in the region.
Then I looked down at my
hand and I saw this big,
bulging package!
Like a - like a - like a penis!
MEMBER: She was a
pre-op transsexual?
JAMIE: No, she
wasn't a transsexual!
I was having visions.
CASSANDRA: Ok, Jamie.
It sounds to me that you have
a problem objectifying women
and dealing with a
phobia of male sexuality.
Does that sound
accurate to you?
JAMIE: I don't see
why that's a problem.
CASSANDRA: Well the first
step to solving a problem is
admitting that you have one.
JAMIE: Well I don't.
CASSANDRA: Then I'm
afraid I can't help you.
JAMIE: Yeah but I
mean - you don't think
I'm attracted to men, do you?
CASSANDRA: I'm afraid
I can't answer that.
JAMIE: Yeah but come on,
I mean have you ever met a
butch lesbian who
was attracted to a man?
I mean guys -
look at me, right?
Come on!
I mean come on, that would
have to go in the Guinness
Book of World
Records or something.
That'd be kind of cool.
I could maybe do
that...no, I couldn't do that.
Anyway, so as I said, I'm
basically here to meet chicks.
JAMIE: Oh, I had to go.
Had a booty call to tend to.
Got me some pussy.
DAVID: Cool.
JAMIE: Yeah, you know.
Just another day in the
life of a lesbian, that's all.
DAVID: That's good.
I got myself some
penis action as well.
JAMIE: You know David, what
you do in the bedroom is your
business, but - I don't
need to know about it.
DAVID: You can
tell me about pussy,
but I can't tell
you about penis?
JAMIE: David, please stop.
DAVID: What about cock?
JAMIE: You know, I asked you to
stop and now you're continuing.
So it's called
sexual harassment.
DAVID: Oh yeah?
What about dick?
JAMIE: Lesbians
don't like dick!
DAVID: Dick?
You like dick?
How about dick?
JOSÉ: Is your
hair stubbly yet?
JILL: No.
JOSÉ: Can I see?
Or not see.
I could touch without seeing?
JILL: Maybe we
should start with a kiss?
JOSÉ: Of course.
Where are my manners.
Feel this?
Smooth as silk.
You could eat dinner
off of these babies.
JILL: I should go.
JOSÉ: What's wrong?
JILL: This isn't working.
JOSÉ: It'll grow back.
JILL: I'm gay.
JOSÉ: You think I'm gay?
JILL: No.
I'm gay.
JOSÉ: But you're so pretty.
JILL: So...
JOSÉ: Did I do
something wrong?
JILL: No.
JOSÉ: Is it because
you think I'm gay?
JILL: No.
Are you?
JOSÉ: Jill, how
can you ask me that?
Aren't I a good kisser?
JILL: I don't see
what that has to do with -
JOSÉ: Don't I
treat you like a lady?
JILL: Well...
JOSÉ: Didn't I
seduce you like a man?
JILL: Maybe you're
overcompensating.
JOSÉ: Maybe we
should have sex.
Just to make sure.
JILL: I need to go.
CASSANDRA: I want to guide
each one of you toward a
fearless approach of
understanding and accepting
yourselves, all
parts of yourselves,
no matter how much it might
scare you or repulse you.
Close your eyes.
You're inside the
belly of a whale.
Now imagine what would
happen if - someone left
your class without asking...
JAMIE: Wait - Jill!
What are you doing here?
JILL: No, you do not get
the pleasure of knowing
what I'm doing here
until you tell me what the
hell you're doing here?
JAMIE: I'm...here
to meet chicks.
JILL: Don't lie to me.
JAMIE: Why are you so mad?
JILL: Why am I mad?
The fact that you came to
a support group for people
who are trying to be
comfortable with the
fact that they're lesbians?
The fact that you're such a
cocky bastard who thinks she's
got her shit together,
and dumps me for an honest
mistake, when she
doesn't even know who or
what the hell she even wants!
JAMIE: I want chicks.
JILL: Why are you here?
JAMIE: I'm here
to meet chicks.
Chicks like you.
I'm here to meet you
and...and here we are.
JILL: You're here because
you're a hypocrite who can't
even be honest with
herself right now.
DAVID: So did you
hear that Jill and José
broke up because he's gay?
LOLA: That's because
he's straight and Jill's gay.
DAVID: That's because
Jill and José are gay.
JOSÉ: You think I'm gay?
DAVID: Oh, José.
I didn't know you were...
JOSÉ: Why does
everybody think I'm gay?
DAVID: ...there.
JOSÉ: Ladies and Gentlemen, I
have an announcement to make.
I am not gay!
I am a heterosexual man.
I love women.
I love women
underneath me, on top of me,
naked, in the shower.
I love them all the
time, in all the seasons,
in every way!
LOLA: A straight man
would never do that.
DAVID: A gay man
JOSÉ: I'm starting a blog
site at José not gay dot com.
18 and over only please.
Thank you.
DAVID: How unfortunate.
LOLA: I can see you now!
CASSANDRA: So what made
you decide to leave the
ex-lesbian group and join us?
JILL: It was time.
I dated a man for
awhile and then I
just couldn't do it anymore.
A real man.
Not to be confused with the
man that I dated who turned
out to be a woman, who
turned out to be an unforgiving
hypocrite, who started
showing up at Reclaiming Your
Lesbianism when
Lord knows why,
because she's supposedly
she's such a die hard dyke,
and she claims that
she's here to meet chicks!
Meanwhile, it's obvious to
everyone but herself that
she's too insecure to be
honest about her own issues.
JAMIE: Yeah well,
it sounds like you're
the one with the problems!
CASSANDRA: Ladies, the number
one rule here is respect.
And rule number two
is we all have problems
or else we wouldn't be here.
MEMBER: Yeah, and any idiot
knows the best place to meet
chicks it at a
political rally.
JAMIE: Oh.
Really?
MEMBER: No, they
don't put out.
You got to go to a bar.
JAMIE: Well, not if you're
looking for an emotionally
committed LTR,
long-term relationship.
JILL: The only way that you
would be emotionally committed
is if you were
committed to a mental hospital!
JAMIE: Yeah well, the only way
you could be in an LTR is if
it stood for
"Lesbian Traitor Retard"!
CASSANDRA: Ladies!
Woah, please!
Ok.
I think what needs to happen
between the two of you is a
good
old-fashioned heart to heart.
Right?
Honesty, respect,
clarity, acceptance.
Do you think you
ladies can manage that before
the next session tomorrow?
JAMIE: Yeah, whatever.
JILL: Yeah, ok...
CASSANDRA: Thank you!
Alright, who wants to sing?
Here we go.
Pass that over that way.
Happy place, everyone.
Happy place!
Pass them out.
Everyone have one?
Good.
Let's start from the top, OK?
OK.
5, 6, 7, 8 - ♪ Lesbians will
heal the world some day, ♪
♪ lesbians will show
everyone the way ♪
♪ Oh lesbians, we are lesbians,
and we will heal the world. ♪
♪ And if there's ever
a cure for cancer, ♪
♪ you can bet it'll be a
lesbian who found the answer ♪
♪ Oh lesbians, we are lesbians,
and we will heal the world. ♪
Slow it down.
♪ And if we ever
repair the ozone, ♪
♪ you can bet it was a
lesbian or a lesbian clone. ♪
♪ Oh lesbians, we are lesbians,
and we will heal the world. ♪