During the winter time of 8th grade
I suddenly fell ill after receiving high school
Had to be in bed for more than a week due to high fever,
And when I realized ...
... I can no longer hear the sound of a clock or a vehicle.
The morning was so quiet.
I still remember that feeling of loneliness.
Until I heard the warm and soft sounds of the sunlit place.
Hidamari ga Kikoeru (Silhouette of Your Voice)  Based on Yuki Fumino's manga
Eh?
Cost per hour is ¥ 1500!
It was not bad
Well, if for tutors, the price is too normal
Actually, this is pretty low compared to his job
And also, Taiichi
People like you want to be a tutor?
If this does not go well ... I'll be in trouble.
From today, I will not even be able to buy food
What's wrong with your workplace?
I think you've got to eat in the restaurant.
I have my own problem that I can not say!
Your voice is noisy!
Do not say like that.
That's why I say reduce your voice.
In that case, would you treat me to a meal?
We're scissors, rocks, paper .... Yeah !!
Series?
It's the first time I've heard anyone get fired because of the noise.
Emangnya your voice that hard huh? : v
Did not you say I was noisy?
It turned out to be hard ...
Sorry Sorry...
I do not matter because I'm a regular ..
The manager initially praised for my excited voice, but eventually told me to leave.
You're that ...
Are you not being polite to customers?
Yes ... So ...
You should just leave it alone.
It's because of your useless sense of justice.
Not like that.
A ... I'm hungry ...
I also.
I'm going to the cafeteria.
Do you want to go there by yourself and leave me starving?
Then why do not you come too?
I told you I do not have any money.
Oh so .. Bye.
Lu base does not have feelings !!
Sorry..
Money this time can eat what try?
A .. Hungry ...
I plan to work after high school
But the teacher advised me to enroll in the university,
and here I am.
I'm starving ...
Can not hold ...
Lapaaarrr .....
Sick..
Oh, sorry it shocked you.
What are you doing sitting there?
Oh !! It looks good!
What? May I eat?
Serious? You're really good .. ^^ o ^^
The person who wants to offer the food is a great individual.
Enjoy your meal.
Enaakk!
Wait .. This ...
What is wrong with her?
That .. Sugihara, right?
Sugihara?
Sugihara Kouhei. He is also still the first year.
How do you know?
He's pretty famous.
You're busy working part-time so you do not know, but,
He is quite striking and popular among women.
Ah, and also,
This,
Wanted Note Taker?
It is for students who have problems understanding the lessons because of hearing loss,
So other students can make notes about lessons for them.
Can not he hear anything?
I'm not sure.
Oh, look.
Uwah, they seem to use sign language.
Yes it seems right.
He may indeed have a hearing problem?
By the way, why are you looking for Sugihara?
I want to return something.
Restore?
I go first.
Tu - Wait for Taiichi.
What?
Do not deal with it.
Ha?
I told you. He is not close to other people.
I've never heard anything good about her.
He does not even look like a senpai.
You do not want to be bothered right?
Wait.
Uh, well, come on.
Ouch!
Hello.
I think I can see you here,
You're right here.
Oh yes.
Here.
I want to return this.
I've cleaned it up.
Bentonya is very good.
At that time I almost died of hunger,
but luckily you saved me.
Oh yeah, I heard you have a bad reputation,
but such a person will not offer me food, right?
So to return the favor,
It .. Let me do it.
Instead, make me a bento.
Why can I hear you clearly?
Oh yes I forgot. I will write.
If you talk slowly, I can still understand.
What? You can talk anyway.
I thought you could not make a sound.
Thank God..
I got confused how to communicate with you.
You can hear my voice, right?
Ano ..
First do you want to tell your name?
Sagawa Taiichi.
Taiichi, tumben you go to class,
Still not working yet?
I'm working again now.
Work? What?
Note taker.
Do not you, Sugihara?
Yes.
Is not this a volunteer job?
Actually, I just want to do it temporarily,
But he wants me to do it for a long time.
And the rewards ...
One bento box for one note.
Where else can I get a dream job like this?
Luck was finally on my side.
Are you okay?
Just writing notes, right? No problem!
... the first visionary concept was coined by a British sociologist named John Erly.
... a visionary consumption that leads to a change of lifestyle .. People are starting to miss the rural nature ...
Uenakk!
Sagawa-kun ..
Hmm?
Something you forgot to write here.
Oh, that..
Sorry I overslept.
I will not sleep again next time.
Sorry, I promise.
It's hard to write everything the professor says in class.
It usually takes two trained people to do it in turn.
But since I can only hear half of it,
your job just write down the important parts only.
Uh, what's up?
Are they your acquaintances?
They are from the sign language club.
They invited me to join him many times.
Ah .. So that's why they use sign language.
I've never seen anyone who used sign language before ...
I also...
Even with the difficulty of hearing, the level of each person is different.
Many people out there who do not understand sign language.
Always think if people with hearing impairment can sign language it is quite annoying.
I do not need that.
Let's eat.
This is not bad ... Quite useful too.
After all, it's easier for me to read my lips.
Is not it even more difficult?
Not really..
Everyone can do it through practice.
Yes, even if you do not need it.
Why?
Does not anyone ever say that you're talking too loud?
Ah .. There are some ...
... that complains if my voice is too noisy.
That's a bash thing.
That means you can communicate effectively.
That's why I can easily talk with you.
I do not have to ask you to repeat your words.
Can you stop calling me Sagawa-kun?
Eh?
Note: Sagawa Xpress  Because that sounds like a shipping company.
Anyway, how ya ...
What?
Anyway, just call it by my first name.
I will do the same.
OK.
Taiichi-san ...
What happened to you later?
You become diligent in class, and always pay attention to the lesson.
Yes, it's because I found a perfect part-time job.
What's with Sugihara?
Yes.
Bentonya really good.
Now my goal is to get lunch.
What is that?
The Sugihara is not bothered?
Ha? Not at all!
Precisely people make it a problem that is actually problematic.
Why are you so serious?
Sorry Sorry. Come on.
Why do you look disappointed?
His voice is loud yes.
Hey, Taiichi!
Your netnet is everywhere.
You know! The class?
Already ..
Drop ..
Sorry!
This time...
... I overslept again.
Sorry.
Bentonya is left behind at home.
Eh .. You did not bring bento?
What...
.. no problem really.
Then, going to the cafeteria together?
Eh?
Yes, you know, there's cheaper than outside.
Occasionally eat at different places.
Eh, do not want to?
No, not that.
- Then come on. - I'm not used to going there.
Tun--
What money do you bring?
Why should I tell you?
Never mind .. How much?
Uwaa .. Keliatannya delicious.
Which is it delicious? Everything looks good.
Is it true?
Obviously it's hard to decide.
= Eh there is Sugihara. - Sugihara-kun!
It's rare to see you here.
Do you want to have lunch?
Let's eat together.
Sugihara-kun is alone, right?
We have reserved a table there.
-Ayo..ayo ... - I ...
Oh yeah, the club will have a meeting today, you want to come?
Right ... You'll be happy to join us.
Come yeah ... you wanna come right?
Everyone will be happy if Sugihara want to join.
Want to come?
You want to come? You come later, right?
Hey, hey, how about we join too?
People like you do not fit into our club.
What? Sugihara-kun is also not a member of the club.
Sugihara is different from you guys ..
Would not it be fun if we all left? Sugihara is different from you guys ..
Would not it be fun if we all left?
Correct.
Sugihara-kun ..
We are ignored.
Kouhei!
Who does she think she is?
Do not be like that. He just can not hear us.
Right .. He's sorry he can not hear.
What? What? It's not even our fault. Right .. He's sorry he can not hear.
What? What? It's not even our fault.
- That's right ... That's true. - You're just a bunch of fools who are crazy about him.
No, we're not like that.
Are you stupid? (Kouhei)
Just because these people,
You are alone in a place like that. (Under the tree)
Avoid interacting with others.
You do not have to come.
So what if he can not hear?
He's a bitch for being cool.
Stop ...
- What are you talking about? - It's stopped.
It's their fault,
already interrupt my lunch.
Taiichi.
Finally you say my name.
Eh? That ... You have not mentioned my name yet.
Had it earlier.
When you left I called you Kouhei.
Are you laughing?
No ... no ... I'm not laughing.
You laugh right?
If you laugh enough, then.
I often hear your laughter.
Is that so often?
Hmm .. Yeah.
Though I think I'm always in a depressed fashion.
Those people were,
Why are you doing that?
Ha?
They have nothing to do with you, you should just ignore them.
Moreover,
I can not hear them.
What do you mean?
Just because you can not hear, does not mean they can speak badly behind you.
Are you always like that?
If you can not hear, say it aloud!
Ask for as much as anything.
Why do you always dodge?
Inability to hear ...
... it's not even your fault, is it?
Kouhei,
Why are you crying?
A sudden hearing ability echoed, yes.
Although not necessarily because of high fever,
but it's been a while since symptoms have arisen,
It is almost impossible to improve the ability to hear it again.
It might be a good idea to use a hearing aid,
How?
That might help his hearing.
Want to apply for a disabled certificate?
Everyone, welcome.
I am your homeroom guard, Kitano Seiichi.
Please cooperate.
So, what if we start with self-introduction?
But before that,
there is something that I want to convey to all of you.
Your friend, Sugihara, has a hearing loss,
I hope you guys help as much as possible.
Already .. Please calm down.
Poor yes.
I never feel sorry for myself.
But I do not understand why I have to experience this kind of thing.
Why should I think like this? I do not understand.
Poor, yes.
Wuah .. Seriusan?
Sick .. sick ..
Wow cool.
Do not take it carelessly.
It's really cool.
What are you talking about?
Her sister is a model.
She is very beautiful.
Is there something wrong with your eyes?
She's skinny, but still ugly.
Your eyes are troubled.
How could it be?
Sorry, what are you talking about?
Ah, he has a hearing problem.
It sucks.
Not important ... We are not talking about anything important.
Go.
Sugihara-kun! Here I help!
Ah, sorry what did you say?
Here I help.
I can do it myself.
It is okay. It's hard for you because you can not hear, right?
What's the connection trying?
I do not know what to do with people who speak fast like this.
I hope he speaks more slowly ..
Uh, are you cold?
Hm?
I'm wondering are you cold?
What?
I say, cold.
Because your voice is a bit naughty.
Eh? Why?
Why are you so quiet today?
We have not seen each other, talk more.
Hey, what are you wearing in your ear?
Earphone?
Kouhei.
Are you bored?
Then see you next month.
You've worked hard.
I also want to go down, want to go together?
Good.
The way you communicate more smoothly, yes.
... so here's how to pronounce soda in sign language.
Sign language.
Can not they all hear?
Hmm?
No.
They are here to get a sign language certificate.
Usually, deaf people have studied in extraordinary schools.
So they will not come here.
Am I also like that person?
You're not going down?
No, I'm coming.
Sorry.
That's why I feel uncomfortable.
Because behind this curtain,
no place for me.
I can not blame senpai if they have a bad view about me.
Why?
Before you,
oran who became note taker for me is his girlfriend senpai.
He took me to the hotel but I refused.
Then there are rumors everywhere.
Did not you already reject it?
Maybe somebody saw us in front of the hotel.
So the rumors began to spread.
But,
I do not really care how people judge me.
Because of these things,
will continue to happen.
Why did you decide to be alone?
Because people do treat me so long.
But I do not!
Not that out there is someone like me?
Taiichi ... you are that,
suddenly appeared out of nowhere.
Two more times.
So what?
- Back then, I was thinking, is this guy stupid? - Ha ?!
Because you say the person who offers you food is a good person.
This time you really laugh, right?
Hmm.
Wooah, this is the first time I've ever seen you laugh.
Tuh right,
You look better when smiling.
By the way, what is Taiichi's favorite food?
Well, you rarely go to the kitchen,
are you hungry?
Bento create tomorrow what?
Eh?
What?
This is the first time you ask that.
Ah, that's ... the guy who wrote me a note,
Loved my bent.
Oh, I see.
So, what if spend a little longer to prepare tomorrow?
Oh, I see...
Taiichi will be happy tomorrow, right?
So beitu.
Today Taiichi does not need to write notes.
Though the weather is good.
Taiichi.
Taiichi ...
That is true.
There's a part in Taiichi life where I'm not there.
And, he also has his own friends.
Hey, Kouhei!
Again I wish.
Taiichi is with me for my reward .
Besides, she has no reason to be with me.
Nevertheless,
It's not your fault you can not hear.
I'm glad.
Kouhei.
Just now why?
You see me but ignore me ... It's sick to know!
Eh?
Why?
What do you mean?
I'm not asking you to write a note today.
So without a note we can not chat?
Do-do,
because you want to eat my bait?
Nothing to do with bento.
[Pavlov Dog: A passionate dog to be fed] Stop treating me like a Pavlov dog.
See. Because of this,
I remember that I'm hungry.
Then ... Let's eat together.
Yes, but I do not have the money.
I brought bento.
You are a God!
You're too much.
No ... you're too good.
The best?
I do not know who it is.
Hey ... you know dong.
I want to see the bentonya.
I am very hungry.
Wahh .. Is not this Steak Hamburger?
You do not like it?
How could I not like it?
I really like it till I want to marry her.
Thank God.
I always thought,
are you the one who made this bento?
Yours is very tasty yes.
Not possible lah. My mother made it.
He teaches cooking classes.
I can not remember the taste of my mother's cooking.
Is it true?
My parents divorced when I was in junior high.
When they were married again, I lived with my grandfather.
Sorry.
Ti-no nothing, I have not thought about it.
But I think, hamburger steak is very tasty, yes.
Finally met, Taiichi!
Yoko.
Hello.
I forgot to tell you,
Do you know my cousin, Miho?
He's also studying here.
This is the first time I know you have a cousin.
Miho suddenly asks for your contact number.
Why?
He said he saw you in the cafeteria.
Stop it.
He said he wants to chat with you.
Are you feeling excited?
Stop it.
Not to be taken seriously, what are you looking like?
You...
That is all. Please take care of the rest. Bye bye.
Hey, Yoko!
What is wrong with her?
Why?
Hm? Oh no. There is no.
It's really nice, yes.
Sagawa-kun?
Are you her cousin Yoko?
Nice to meet you, I'm Yokohama Miho.
Nice to meet you.
Sorry, suddenly asked you to get out.
Oh, it is okay.
By the way, lots of books here.
Oh, here is actually a bookstore.
Good marketing, right?
Please.
Oh, the hourly rate is high.
I want iced tea.
Iced tea? OK.
So, here it is,
Yes.
The thing I want to talk about is ... about Sugihara-kun.
Hah?! Kouhei?
At that time I saw him in the cafeteria, he was very handsome.
The two of you seem close enough.
Ah .. So that's it?
Ah, sorry.
I asked my cousin because I thought you were very close.
Am I bothering you?
Not. No problem.
So he, what does he usually do?
Something he likes or his hobbies?
I do not understand about those things.
Are you two in the same department?
Not.
We're different.
Then in the same club?
We both did not join the club.
Then how can you know each other?
We both do not know each other intentionally,
I wonder how?
In essence, I'm now helping him as a note taker.
Note taker?
Yes, he has a little hearing problem,
he could not hear the lecture material clearly.
Or things that matter.
So I wrote it down and gave it to him.
Sugihara-kun can not hear?
No, instead of not being able to hear,
he is not completely deaf.
Only trouble hearing.
Oh, I see,
Like the main character in the novel.
What?
The main character of women accidentally met with the main male character who lost his hearing,
And the seeds of love began to grow between them but,
I really like this novel.
The main character of women always helps the main male character, it is very touching.
I always hoped to be able to use sign language,
but there was no such person who appeared near me.
For some reason, now I feel like I'm the main character in the novel.
Mother,
Can you make a bento for tomorrow?
Yes yes.
Two, right?
Anu ...
What?
I have a request.
What? Why are you so serious?
Why?
He can communicate fluently even without sign language.
And also, he's not really deaf.
He can do anything himself.
Do not equate him with the characters in the novel.
Sorry.
Maybe for you this is just a novel,
but for him, this is the reality.
Sorry.
I am home.
Grandfather?
Not at home yes.
[On holiday to hot springs]
Must say something before leaving.
What the fuck is this day?
Why did I say that?
Indeed i am her?
I just want to see her laugh more.
Here,
note for today.
Why?
Not.
It's rare to see you're not excited.
No, I'm just hungry.
What is bento today?
Steak hamburger!
Because you said you wanted to marry her.
I like! I like it very much.
But I'm not sure what it feels like.
What do you mean?
Of course this is good.
Your mother's bento is always delicious.
Enaak ..
Very delicious...
Thank God..
I want to check the note today first,
Hmm.
What I said then,
though I said I did not care about what happened to my parents,
I've actually felt depressed.
Because without parents, people began to look down on me.
And also, the fact that I'm poor makes the situation worse.
That's why I often get into a fight.
There were also times when I ran away from home.
But,
on my birthday,
Grandpa made me a burnt hamburger steak.
Since then,
I am grateful to be living with my grandfather.
The hamburger steak was as good as it was.
Thanks.
Are you saying something?
Not important anyway.
Eh?
Not important.
Sorry, I did not hear.
I myself am ashamed to say so.
Is it true?
Buzzed again.
What is wrong?
Kouhei!
Kouhei.
I can not...
... heard Taiichi's voice.
Your hearing ability deteriorates.
Perhaps because it is deteriorating slowly,
you do not realize it.
The buzz can be caused by this,
but can also be caused by other complications.
So it needs further inspection.
Can you come again next week?
Ano ...
My listening ability will worsen slowly?
Does that mean one day ...
... will I be totally deaf?
I still can not decide.
But do not give up.
Too much pressure is not good for your health.
It's hard for you to resist life ...
... environment with people who have normal hearing.
My listings got worse.
Also,
I probably will not be able to hear the things I've been hearing forever.
This .
I can do it, right?
Call me by my first name .. I will do the same.
Sagawa Taiichi.
Kouhei !
You look better with a smile.
Steak hamburger ..
Like .
I love it so much.
Delicious .. Very tasty.
You ignore me even though you see me,
That's painful!
If you do not hear it, just say it aloud!
You can request any number of times.
Kouhei .... Kouhei..Kouhei ..
All things I can hear up to now,
Loh? Sugihara?
Ah, it's true.
Have you heard what happened from Taiichi?
What?
About Miho.
Sorry, I can not hear you clearly.
Ah .. It's okay, it's nothing.
Sorry Sorry.
He said you're okay.
That's all Miho's fault.
Miho?
It turns out Taiichi did not tell you anything?
What happened between them?
Yes .. Not so also,
In fact,
I do not know if you're aware,
but it looks like Miho is not interested in Taiichi, but with you.
Taiichi would not be happy to have been lied to.
And he also seems disappointed.
She looked depressed.
What happened to you?
Sugihara?
Why does not Taiichi tell me about the girl?
I will wait for you at the temple of Hachiman
Kouhei? I will wait for you at the temple of Hachiman
Kouhei!
Sorry I'm late.
Taiichi.
Why do you bring an umbrella if you do not use it?
Do you want to wear my towel?
Hold on for a moment.
It is okay.
No ... You're gonna get the flu.
Suddenly I realized,
What?
I realize how much I want to meet you.
What? You really like me huh?
Yes.
I like you..
Taiichi.
Seeing you who so enjoy your food,
I feel so comfortable.
What?
Every time you say good,
I feel so happy.
I'm afraid I can not hear your voice anymore.
What is wrong? Did something happen?
Kouhei?
Hey! You are okay?
Kouhei.
Taiichi,
how do you feel about Miho?
You met, right?
Yes.
Why are you angry with him?
What do you mean?
Anyway how do you know?
Why are you asking this?
Why do you ask?
Because this is important to me.
What did the girl say to Taiichi?
How do you see it from your perspective?
Not.
Taiichi.
Sorry, but I will not let you know.
And I will not tell you.
Taiichi .
sorry if suddenly.
You've helped me a lot.
Therefore,
I do not want to trouble you anymore.
I will ask others to become my Note Taker.
Where are you, Kouhei.
[Sorry for bothering you for this long, Goodbye.]
Sorry to bother you.  [Sorry for bothering you for this long, Goodbye.]
Goodbye.
I do not understand.
She is not coming today?
What? Sugihara lai?
She has not been in for more than a week.
He may try to avoid you.
Have you hurt her yet?
No!
I do not know.
Is it hard to get in touch with that person?
Eh but I got to meet and talk to him, and it's not as hard as my shadow.
When did you talk to him?
I told him about what Miho asked you.
You tell him about Miho?
Sick..sakit..sakit .. what's wrong? Ill woy!
What did you tell him?
I told you that Miho actually likes Sugihara not you.
You!
Besides, if you're so eager to see him, why do not you just go to his house?
I do not know where his house is.
Sick..she ... pain ...
Does not the family have a cooking course?
You can look it up on the internet.
- That is true. - Pain oy!
Woaahh .. The house is very big.
[Cooking Suihara Course]
I get nervous.
Iyaa ~~
Eh? Who?
I'm his friend Kouhei.
Is Kouhei at home?
Forgive me.
Her friend Kouhei has never been here before.
So I thought you were here for the course.
Ah, sit down first.
The boy never told me.
Sorry there's only cookies.
Please eat, yes.
Oh no.
It's my fault that suddenly came here.
Please do not hesitate .. Eat yes.
Then eat good.
Uwenaakk!
Ah, .. So all this time she gave her bentonya for you, huh.
Yes.
Kouhei often talks about you.
He said there are children who really like to eat.
So where is Kouhei?
That boy?
He is now at the hospital..so not at home.
Hospital?
Yes. It seems his hearing is slowly deteriorating.
This week she did a physical check and got an IV.
It would be great if he was hospitalized.
But he does not want to.
So so yes.
I want to go home first,
Sorry to have made you wait for this long,
he may soon arrive.
Thank you kuenya.
Wait.
Yes?
Are you willing to stay beside Kouhei?
Eh?
The child is introverted, lacks socializing and always keeps distance ... He is very difficult to approach.
But he seems pretty close to you.
When he finds out if you really like a hamburger steak,
he asked me to make it.
Even asked me to make it even better.
So I asked him to make it himself.
Very strange..
She had never cooked before.
But he really meant it.
Why? Am I wrong?
No, you did well.
He really wants to hear you say good.
I am home.
Ah, welcome.
You're late.
And if you go home early you can meet him.
Eh?
The bento.
He's been here waiting for you.
Why did he never say anything to me?
Why does he always decide everything himself?
Shit.
Is not she avoiding you?
Maybe you hurt him already.
I do not.
Taiichi ... What do you think about Miho?
Why are you angry with him?
Kouhei ...
Perhaps...
Taiichi!
Why did not you pick up your phone?
Sorry. my phone is missing.
What happened?
By the way, have you met Sugihara?
Not yet.
But this seems to be my salary.
What does it mean?
He probably likes Miho.
It's not possible. You think about it too much.
Yes but if he misunderstands and thinks I like Miho ...
... maybe that's why he's avoiding me.
He let me have Miho.
He was afraid that would interfere so he dodged.
He's that kind of person.
I do not understand ...
After all, why are you so attentive to Sugihara?
He is very smart,
good cook,
also popular among girls.
I just thought he was great.
He is too perfect.
But he is very lacking in self-confidence.
Do not want to hang out with people around him,
Always try to do everything yourself.
Just because he has a hearing problem ... Things do not go the way he wants.
I do not know what it is that makes her not confident.
I feel guilty for her.
What's wrong with not hearing?
That...
Kouhei is a good person.
Though he's a quiet person and closed.
But he's really good.
You alone do not know.
How he has tried hard ....
... with that quiet expression of his face.
Actually no one is trying to understand it,
and excommunicate it,
with a bad opinion about it.
What you say is true, but ...
Bottom line, I can not leave it alone!
Can not!
Taiichi ... That's enough.
So what?
He's at the door.
Stupid! you should have said that!
That's because you keep talking.
This...
You left him at my house.
- Te-thank you, - See you later.
Kouhei!
Taiichi?
Wait!
Did you hear what I was talking about?
I'm wondering do you hear it?
Hey!
Kouhei!
So what if I hear it?
You already know, right?
If my listening worsened from before.
Even if you say something,
I will not be able to hear it.
Oh, I see?
Sorry...
... I'm lying.
Even if I can hear other people's voices,
I do not know why ...
... just your voice that sounds clear.
Why do you have to say that?
Do not you just say that?
Not that you are alone?
Trying to break off a relationship with me with a message like that,
your own fault for not expressing your true feelings.
Because,
- even if I say it you will not understand! - What do you mean?
Even though I do not understand everything,
I will try to understand it little by little.
After seeing you cry that time,
How can I understand if you keep silent?
You should say everything you want to say!
About Miho,
It is my fault.
He said if you're useless,
IAM very angry.
If I knew this would make a misunderstanding between us,
it should be from the beginning I tell you the truth.
Therefore,
stop trying to bear it on your own.
Just tell me what you want to say.
Do not give up on yourself.
Why?
Why Taiichi cry?
Where I know.
You did not understand me.
[Meaning about Kouhei feeling like Taiichi (Taiichi is not sensitive: v)] You're too slow.
But...
.. that's what I like about you.
In fact,
Rather than lose my hearing, I'm more afraid that you hate me.
Forgive me.
But,
I'm glad I told you this.
Thank you...
... for your time all this time.
Uh, Sugihara-kun?
You cut your hair?
Yes.
- Cute .. Fit with you .. - You look cool ...
This is for you.
[Sign Language Club]
Ano ...
Are you still accepting new members?
Of course. You can join ..
But why all of a sudden?
I was thinking that I should not have stopped before trying.
So you want to join?
Yes.
Hurray ..
You will come right?
OK.
Serious?
Yes.
We'll be waiting for you. thanks.
See you again..
Kouhei.
Am I imagining?
Kouhei!
Why?
Is it weird if I come through here?
Taiichi ..
Oh yes..
This is it...
Wait a minute ,,,
You do not mind that time?
You really do not want to see me, do you?
That time...
... I was just surprised and did not know what to do.
I keep thinking about it until I forget to eat.
But,
no matter how hard I think about it, I have no reason to hate you.
Therefore,
[Wanted Note Taker]  This ..
[Wanted Note Taker]
Am I still allowed to apply?  [Wanted Note Taker]
Am I still allowed to apply?
Kouhei ...
can you hear me?
Hmm.
Very clear.
Since winter when I was 8th grade,
My days are like frosty winters.
Memories filled with solitude,
Until I heard a warm, sun-like sound.
I do not know why,
only your voice I can hear.
Indo Sub By: Nee ~ Chan