♪ SITTING IN THE MORNING SUN ♪
♪ I'LL BE SITTING WHEN
THE EVENING COMES ♪
♪ WATCHING THE SHIPS ROLL IN ♪
♪ THEN I'LL WATCH THEM
ROLL AWAY AGAIN ♪
♪ YEAH, I'M SITTING ON
THE DOCK OF THE BAY ♪
♪ WATCHING THE TIDE ROLL AWAY ♪
♪ OOH, JUST SITTING ON
THE DOCK OF THE BAY ♪
♪ WASTING TIME, TIME ♪
♪ I LEFT MY HOME IN GEORGIA ♪
♪ HEADED FOR THE FRISCO BAY ♪
♪ 'CAUSE I'VE HAD
NOTHING TO LIVE FOR ♪
♪ LOOKS LIKE NOTHING'S
GONNA COME MY WAY... ♪
FIRST THING WE WANT TO DO IS
GIVE YOU THE DAILY BULLETIN.
YOU'D BE SURPRISED... A
LITTLE NOTICE SOMEWHERE
THAT YOU MIGHT THINK
DOESN'T CONCERN YOU
MIGHT CHANGE YOUR WHOLE LIFE,
MIGHT DECIDE ON WHAT
COLLEGE YOU'LL GO TO,
OR MIGHT DECIDE
ON WHAT ACTIVITY.
AND THEN JOYCE HAS A
FEW THINGS TO SAY.
RIGHT, JOYCE?
ALL RIGHT, THE THOUGHT
FOR THE DAY...
LIFE IS CAUSE AND EFFECT.
ONE CREATES HIS TOMORROW
AT EVERY MOMENT
BY HIS MOTIVES, THOUGHTS,
AND DEEDS OF TODAY.
AND THIS QUESTION OF CAUSE
AND EFFECT, YOU KNOW,
AS I SAY, I MIGHT READ SOMETHING
THAT MIGHT CHANGE YOUR LIFE.
Anoche concocimos a un
filósofo existencialista.
Girl: Anoche conocimos a...
A un...
A un filósofo...
Existencialista.
¿Quién puede pronunciar
esta palabra?
Existencialista?
Carla? ¿El nombre del hombre?
¿Frances?
¿No?
Sí.
Boy: Sartre.
Sí, Sartre.
Y el nombre es su apellido
¿pero el nombre?
Jean Paul.
Muy bien.
Excellente, Roger.
¿Y ahora, hmm?
Jean Paul Sartre.
Existencialista.
Students: Existencialista.
Este lado.
Existencialista.
A un filósofo.
A un filósofo existencialista.
[ TYMPANI ]
Students: 1, 2, 3, 4.
1, 2, 3, 4.
2, 3...
1, 2, 3...
WHAT DO YOU MEAN YOU
CAN'T TAKE GYM?
YOU GET DRESSED IN THE MORNING?
Boy: YEAH.
DO YOU GET UNDRESSED? YEAH.
WELL, YOU CAN GET
INTO A GYM OUTFIT.
I CAN'T TAKE... YEAH, I KNOW.
ALL RIGHT, WELL, YOU
GET INTO A GYM OUTFIT.
I CAN'T TAKE GYM, THOUGH.
WE'LL DECIDE THAT.
I HAVE A DOCTOR'S THING.
I AM SICK AND TIRED OF
YOU TALKING, YOU JUST...
MY MOTHER WAS IN, THOUGH.
I SPOKE TO YOUR MOTHER.
NOW, LOOK...
I'M GOING TO THE DOCTOR TODAY.
YOU'D BETTER BE IN A GYM OUTFIT.
WE'LL DETERMINE WHETHER
YOU TAKE EXERCISE OR NOT.
WE'LL DETERMINE THAT.
I CAN'T TAKE GYM.
I CAN HARDLY... I'M
NOT EVER ALLOWED...
WHY DON'T YOU JUST...
I'M NOT EVEN SUPPOSED
TO COME TO SCHOOL.
HEY, LOOK.
I'M GOING TO TELL YOU SOMETHING.
DON'T YOU TALK, AND
YOU JUST LISTEN.
YOU COME PREPARED IN A GYM
OUTFIT WHEN YOU GO TO GYM.
IS THAT CLEAR?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
NOW, DON'T TELL ME YOU
WON'T DO ANYTHING.
NOBODY'S GOING TO PUT YOU INTO
AN UNCOMPROMISING POSITION.
BUT YOU'LL COME DRESSED
IN A GYM OUTFIT.
I SAID I WOULD.
YOU ARE SUSPENDED.
GO ON, WAIT OUTSIDE.
BUT I SAID I WOULD.
GO OUTSIDE.
OH, MAN, I SAID I WOULD.
Man: YOU GOT A BOOK OUT
ON THE FIFTH OF JANUARY.
Teacher: Oui, mais
avant de manger,
il est nécessaire de...
Girl: Préparer le dîner.
Préparer le dîner. Ou
préparer le déjeuner.
Ou préparer le petit...
Girl: Déjeuner.
Oui... mais en France,
c'est différent.
En Amérique, on mange
généralement dans la cuisine.
Mais en France, ou est-ce-qu'on
mange le petit déjeuner?
Le déjeuner? Le dîner? Ou?
Généralement, naturellement
il y a des exceptions...
Mais en France, ou
est-ce qu'on mange?
Girl: Dans la salle à manger.
Exactement, dans
la salle à manger.
Chez nous, en Amérique,
c'est différent.
On mange plutôt
dans la cuisine...
Oui, il y a des exceptions,
naturellement.
Girl: Naturellement.
Mais généralement, dans
la cuisine... oui?
En France, non.
On prépare dans la cuisine,
on mange dans la salle à manger.
NO, NO, NO, NO... A
FLUNKING STUDENT...
NO, NO, A FLUNKING STUDENT
SHOULDN'T RECEIVE SUCH
ACCOLADES AS "FABULOUS."
FABULOUS... NOW,
THAT'S ALL I'M SAYING.
SURE, THEY'RE FLUNKING.
I COULD SEE MAYBE A "C" STUDENT
HAVE A "FABULOUS" HERE.
BUT A FLUNKING
STUDENT, "FABULOUS."
Man: WHY DON'T YOU
PUT IT IN REVERSE?
WHY DON'T YOU SAY, WHY
DON'T YOU SAY THAT
A STUDENT WHO CAN WRITE FABULOUS
PAPERS SHOULDN'T FLUNK,
SHOULDN'T DO THINGS WHICH
WOULD CAUSE HER TO FLUNK?
YOU SEE...
NO... IT DEPENDS
ON THE LANGUAGE.
YOU KNOW IT'S STRANGE...
I'VE ALWAYS FOUND THAT A MAN
WHO USES THE WORD "SYMPATHY"
IS NEVER SYMPATHETIC.
HAVE YOU EVER FOUND THAT, DR.
BOODISH?
TELL THE TRUTH.
[ WOMAN GIGGLING ]
AND I HAVE NO REDRESS,
ALL RIGHT, NOTHING.
NO REDRESS?
NO REDRESS, NONE.
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
NO, ALL I WANT YOU TO SAY,
THAT AT LEAST I'M RIGHT
ABOUT THESE FEW
PAPERS, THAT'S ALL.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO TELL YOU,
THAT YOU ARE RIGHT
ABOUT THESE PAPERS?
I WANT YOU TO SAY THAT A
GIRL WHO RECEIVES "FABULOUS"
AND ALL THESE MARKS
SHOULDN'T FLUNK.
I CAN ONLY SAY THIS...
THAT THE TEACHER, IN
READING THESE PAPERS,
THOUGHT THEY WERE FABULOUS,
BUT THE TOTAL MARK INVOLVES
MORE THAN JUST THOSE PAPERS.
THAT'S ALL I CAN TELL YOU.
BUT I THINK THIS IS A
RATHER UNIQUE SITUATION,
WOULDN'T YOU SAY SO?
RATHER UNIQUE?
WELL, WOULD YOU BE HAPPY
IF I SAY IT'S UNIQUE?
I'D BE HAPPY.
ALL RIGHT, I WOULD SAY
IT'S SOMEWHAT UNIQUE.
IS IT COMPASSIONATE FOR A
TEACHER TO WRITE "FABULOUS"?
LET ME GET BACK TO THIS AGAIN.
AND THE GIRL FIGURES
SHE IS DOING WELL.
"VERY GOOD, RHONA."
AND ESPECIALLY THIS "FABULOUS."
AND THEN, FINALLY, SHE
GETS HER REPORT CARD.
AND THE GIRL IS STUNNED
IT'S ANOTHER "E."
IS IT ALSO FAIR FOR A GIRL,
AND I THINK MR.
SCHUSTER WILL CONCUR,
DOES THIS GIRL CAUSE ANY
TROUBLE, HER DEPORTMENT?
IS SHE WILD? TALK A LOT?
WELL, SHE DID GET A SATISFACTORY
MARK IN COOPERATION.
WHY DID SHE GET AN
"E" THE FIRST TIME?
IT'S COMPLETELY AGAINST
HER CHARACTER.
IN BEHAVIOR.
WHY DID SHE GET AN
"E" THE FIRST TIME?
COMPLETELY AGAINST
HER CHARACTER.
AN "E?"
YES, IN BEHAVIOR? IN BEHAVIOR.
WHAT DID SHE GET IN THERE?
AN "E."
"E" IS A GRADE, IT'S
NOT A BEHAVIOR MARK.
DID SHE TELL, WHAT DID SHE SAY?
UH, 4, 3, THE LOWEST YOU
CAN GET, I IMAGINE.
WE CANNOT JUDGE RHONA'S MARK
BASED PURELY ON THIS TEACHER'S
REMARKS OF THESE PAPERS.
THIS IS ALL I'M SAYING.
RHONA, LIMITED IN MANY WAYS,
KNEW WORLD EVENTS AND
THE WORLD AROUND HER.
SHE KNEW THE DIFFERENT
FORMS OF GOVERNMENT,
THE DIFFERENT STRUCTURES
OF TYPES OF GOVERNMENT.
HERE RHONA FAILED.
BECAUSE SHE FAILED
IN ALL THESE TESTS.
WE CAN ONLY JUDGE ON THE
BASIS OF PERFORMANCE.
YOU MAY HAVE HIDDEN
TALENT IN YOU, SIR,
BUT IF YOU DON'T PERFORM
IT, WE DON'T KNOW.
THAT'S TRUE, TRUE.
AND THE WORLD WILL RECOGNIZE
YOU ONLY BY YOUR PERFORMANCE.
THAT'S TRUE, THAT'S TRUE.
BUT IF YOU WANT YOUR DAUGHTER
TO BE BASICALLY A
WELL-ADJUSTED...
ULTIMATELY, I'LL USE
THE WORD "HAPPINESS"
IN A VERY BROAD SENSE, AND
I KNOW THAT HAPPINESS
IS NOT THE ULTIMATE THING IN
LIFE, BUT IT'S IMPORTANT...
YOU CANNOT IMPOSE
PRECONCEIVED VALUES AND DREAMS
ON AN INDIVIDUAL,
INCLUDING A CHILD.
YOU CANNOT DO THAT.
BUT AGAIN, I WANT
YOU TO UNDERSTAND
THAT PART OF YOUR JOB
IS TO DEAL WITH RHONA
AS A SYMPATHETIC AND
UNDERSTANDING FATHER,
BUT RECOGNIZING HER LIMITATIONS
AND THE FACT THAT SHE IS A
PERSON IN HER OWN RIGHT,
AND THAT IF YOU IMPOSE TOO
MUCH YOUR DESIRES ON HER,
EVEN WITHOUT PUSHING
THEM OR FORCING HER,
SHE MAY REACT IN A WAY WHICH
MAY BE DAMAGING TO HER, TOO.
MICHAEL, THIS HAS TO
DO WITH YOUR CUTTING,
WHAT IS IT, PHYSICAL SCIENCE?
NO, SIR, I NEVER CUT IT.
MRS. GANIN WAS YELLING
AT ME AFTER CLASS
AND SHE STARTS GOING OFF.
AND, YOU SEE, SOMEHOW I WAS
MAKING NOISE IN THE LUNCH LINE,
AND THE TRUTH IS, MR. ALLEN,
I WAS BEHAVING IN THE
BACK OF THE ROOM.
I DIDN'T OPEN MY MOUTH BECAUSE,
SEE, THE OTHER KIDS WERE,
AND I DIDN'T FEEL
LIKE GOOFING OFF,
AND SHE THOUGHT IT WAS ME.
AND SHE CALLS ME UP AND
SHE STARTS YELLING AT ME,
AND I SAY, "IT WASN'T ME."
AND SHE STARTS YELLING, YELLING.
SO I FIGURE, MR. ALLEN...
COULD YOU STAND THERE AND
LISTEN TO A LADY YELL?
SO I FIGURE I'D GO OUT
AND TALK TO HER LATER
WHEN SHE IS CALMED DOWN.
AND SHE WAS PRETTY WORKED UP.
AND I WENT TO WALK OUT AND
SHE GOES, "YOU DON'T LEAVE."
AND I GO, "I'LL SPEAK TO YOU
LATER AT A BETTER TIME."
AND I WALKED OUT BECAUSE...
FIRST OF ALL, MICHAEL, YOU
SHOWED POOR JUDGMENT.
WHEN YOU ARE BEING ADDRESSED
BY SOMEONE OLDER THAN YOU
OR IN A SEAT OF AUTHORITY,
IT'S YOUR JOB TO
RESPECT AND LISTEN.
SHE DIDN'T ASK YOU
TO JUMP FROM THE EMPIRE
STATE BUILDING...
SHE'S NOT ASKING YOU
FOR YOUR BLOOD.
SHE'S ASKING FOR A
LITTLE BIT OF TIME,
TO HELP YOU OUT.
NOW, HERE'S THE THING...
WHAT YOU SHOULD HAVE DONE
IS SHOWED SOME
CHARACTER BY SAYING,
"OKAY, I WILL GO
TO YOUR DETENTION,
"BUT MAY I SPEAK WITH YOU
AND GET THIS MATTER CORRECTED?"
SHE DIDN'T ASSIGN ME DETENTION.
WELL, ACCORDING TO THIS...
"GIVEN THE CHOICE OF A
DETENTION AT 7:30 OR AT 1:45,"
AND YOU REFUSED TO TAKE EITHER.
NOW, WHAT IS THAT?
THEY SENT ME DOWN TO MR. WALSH,
AND I TRIED TO EXPLAIN IT TO HIM
AND HE STARTED
YELLING AT ME, TOO.
WELL, NO ONE IS GOING
TO YELL AT YOU, AND...
WELL, I DON'T FEEL
I HAVE TO TAKE
ANYBODY SCREAMING
AT ME FOR NOTHING.
NO, NO, THERE'S A POINT TO THAT,
BUT IN THE MEANTIME,
IT'S TIME YOU SHOWED A LITTLE
CHARACTER ON YOUR OWN, RIGHT?
YES, SIR.
I WOULD TAKE THE DETENTION
AND THEN YOU CAN
COME BACK AND SAY,
"NOW, I TOOK THE DETENTION,
MAY I SPEAK WITH YOU?"
I CAN'T SPEAK TO THAT MAN...
WELL, YOU CAN TRY.
DO YOU KNOW...
ANOTHER TIME IN THAT CLASS,
THIS IS ANOTHER REASON WHY...
SIT DOWN.
THIS IS ANOTHER REASON
WHY I WON'T TAKE IT.
WHY?
I WAS GIVEN A... THESE
KIDS TOOK A BOOK
AND THEY WERE GOING TO
THROW IT AT ME, RIGHT?
AND THE TEACHER CAUGHT HIM
WITH THE BOOK IN HIS HAND,
AND HE TOOK IT OFF THE
OTHER KID'S BOOK.
AND THE OTHER KID
STOOD UP AND SAID,
"GIVE ME MY DAMN BOOK BACK."
SO MRS. GANIN SAYS,
"YOU TWO GET OUT.
"YOU KNOW I DON'T WANT
LANGUAGE AROUND HERE,
AND NO USE TO GET UP FOR IT."
DO YOU KNOW THEY BROUGHT ME
INTO THE DETENTION ROOM?
THEY BROUGHT ME INTO MR.
WALSH'S ROOM,
AND THEY GOT ME DRAGGED
IN FOR NOTHING.
AND I TRIED TO EXPLAIN
IT TO HIM, AND HE SAID,
"WILL YOU TAKE THE DETENTION?"
WHICH WAS UTTERLY RIDICULOUS.
SEE, WE'RE OUT TO ESTABLISH
SOMETHING, AREN'T WE?
YES.
WE'RE OUT TO ESTABLISH
THAT YOU CAN BE A MAN
AND YOU CAN TAKE ORDERS.
WE WANT TO PROVE TO THEM THAT
YOU CAN TAKE THE ORDERS.
BUT, MR. ALLEN, SEE, IT'S
ALL AGAINST MY PRINCIPLES.
YOU HAVE TO STAND FOR SOMETHING.
YES, BUT I THINK YOUR PRINCIPLES
AREN'T INVOLVED HERE.
I THINK IT'S A QUESTION NOW
OF PROVING YOURSELF TO BE A MAN.
IT'S A QUESTION HERE OF HOW,
HOW DO WE FOLLOW RULES
AND REGULATIONS?
IF THERE'S A MISTAKE MADE,
THERE'S AN APPROACH TO IT.
I THINK YOU DON'T
FIGHT WITH A TEACHER.
I THINK YOU ASK
PERMISSION TO TALK.
AND ASK THEM TO LISTEN TO YOU.
NOW, THIS ISN'T
WHAT YOU DIDN'T DO.
NOW, IF YOU HAD TAKEN
YOUR DETENTION...
AND, AFTER ALL, THEY DIDN'T
REQUIRE MUCH FROM YOU.
THE TEACHER FELT YOU
WERE OUT OF ORDER,
AND IN HER JUDGMENT, YOU
DESERVED A DETENTION.
I DON'T SEE ANYTHING WRONG
WITH ASSIGNING YOU A DETENTION.
AND I THINK YOU SHOULD
PROVE YOURSELF.
YOU SHOULD SHOW
THAT YOU CAN TAKE
THE DETENTION WHEN GIVEN IT.
I SHOULD PROVE THAT I AM A MAN
AND THAT'S WHAT I INTEND TO
DO BY DOING WHAT I FEEL,
IN MY OPINION, IS WHAT I,
IS DOING WHAT IS RIGHT.
ARE YOU GOING TO TAKE YOUR
DETENTION OR AREN'T YOU?
I FEEL THAT YOU SHOULD.
I'LL TAKE IT, BUT UNDER PROTEST.
ALL RIGHT, THEN, YOU
TAKE IT UNDER PROTEST.
THAT'S GOOD.
YES, I'D LIKE YOU
TO TAKE IT TODAY.
WILL TODAY AFTER SCHOOL BE OKAY?
ALL RIGHT, WHAT ROOM, ROOM 120?
118.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
GOING TO THE LUNCHROOM.
WELL, GO TO THE LUNCHROOM.
GOODBYE.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING?
YOU GOT A PASS?
YEAH.
YOU GOT A PASS? DO
YOU HAVE A PASS?
HOW ABOUT YOU?
HANG UP.
LET'S GO.
IT'S FOR EMERGENCIES,
LET'S GET ON THE BALL.
I TOLD YOU TO GET OFF OF THERE.
LET'S GO!
EXCUSE ME, MR. MURRAY,
YOU SEE, I'M AT SCHOOL AND
A MAN'S YELLING AT ME.
YOU GET A PASS.
ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT. BYE.
I HAD TO CALL MY
INSURANCE COMPANY.
WELL, YOU GET A PASS.
BUT I HAVE LUNCH
NOW, I HAVE LUNCH.
I WAS COMING FROM MY LUNCH.
LUNCH MEANS LUNCH.
IT DOESN'T MEAN
MAKE PHONE CALLS.
ALL RIGHT.
YOU GOT A PASS?
OKAY.
♪ AND IT'S SO MUCH FUN ♪
♪ AND IT'S NOT SO
VERY HARD TO DO ♪
♪ THE NAME OF THE GAME
IS SIMPLE SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ AND I WOULD LIKE FOR
YOU TO PLAY IT, TOO ♪
♪ PUT YOUR HANDS IN THE AIR ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ SHAKE THEM ALL ABOUT ♪
♪ DO IT WHEN SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ AND YOU WILL NEVER BE OUT ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS PUT
YOUR HANDS ON YOUR HIPS ♪
♪ AND YOUR BACKBONE
SLIPS, SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS PUT
YOUR HANDS ON YOUR HIPS ♪
♪ AND YOUR BACKBONE
SLIPS, SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ PUT YOUR HANDS ON YOUR HEAD ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ BRING THEM DOWN BY YOUR SIDE ♪
♪ SHAKE THEM TO YOUR LEFT ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ NOW SHAKE THEM TO YOUR RIGHT ♪
♪ PUT YOUR HANDS ON YOUR HEAD ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ SWING THEM DOWN BY YOUR SIDE ♪
♪ SHAKE THEM TO YOUR LEFT ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ NOW SHAKE THEM TO YOUR RIGHT ♪
♪ NOW THAT YOU HAVE LEARNED
TO PLAY THIS GAME WITH ME ♪
♪ SEE IT'S NOT SO HARD TO DO ♪
♪ BAH BAH BAH BAH ♪
♪ LET'S TRY IT ONCE AGAIN,
THIS TIME MORE CAREFULLY ♪
♪ AND I HOPE THE
WINNER WILL BE YOU ♪
♪ CLAP YOUR HANDS IN THE AIR ♪
♪ SIMPLE SIMON SAYS ♪
♪ DO IT DOUBLE TIME ♪
AND WHEN THE DUST HAD LIFTED,
THE MEN SAW WHAT HAD OCCURRED,
THERE WAS JIMMY SAFE AT SECOND
AND FLYNN A-HUGGING THIRD.
AND FROM 5,000 THROATS AND MORE
THERE ROSE THERE A LUSTY YELL,
IT RUMBLED THROUGH THE VALLEY,
IT RATTLED IN THE DELL.
IT POUNDED ON THE MOUNTAIN
AND RECOILED UPON THE FLAT,
FOR CASEY, MIGHTY CASEY,
WAS ADVANCING TO THE BAT.
THERE WAS EASE IN CASEY'S MANNER
AS HE STEPPED INTO HIS PLACE.
THERE WAS PRIDE
IN CASEY'S BEARING AND A
SMILE ON CASEY'S FACE.
AND WHEN, RESPONDING
TO THE CHEERS,
HE LIGHTLY DOFFED HIS HAT,
NO STRANGER IN THE
CROWD COULD DOUBT
'TWAS CASEY AT THE BAT.
10,000 EYES WERE ON HIM
AS HE RUBBED HIS
HANDS WITH DIRT.
5,000 TONGUES APPLAUDED
WHEN HE WIPED THEM ON HIS SHIRT.
THEN WHILE THE WRITHING PITCHER
GROUND THE BALL INTO HIS HIP,
DEFIANCE FLASHED IN CASEY'S EYE,
A SNEER CURLED CASEY'S LIP.
AND NOW THE
LEATHER-COVERED SPHERE
CAME HURTLING THROUGH THE AIR,
AND CASEY STOOD A-WATCHING IT
IN HAUGHTY GRANDEUR THERE.
CLOSE BY THE STURDY BATSMAN
THE BALL UNHEEDED SPED...
"THAT AIN'T MY
STYLE," SAID CASEY.
"STRIKE ONE," THE UMPIRE SAID.
FROM THE BENCHES
BLACK WITH PEOPLE,
THERE WENT UP A MUFFLED ROAR,
LIKE THE BEATING
OF THE STORM WAVES
ON A STERN AND DISTANT SHORE.
"KILL HIM! KILL THE UMPIRE!"
SHOUTED SOMEONE ON THE STAND.
AND IT'S LIKELY THEY'D
HAVE KILLED HIM
HAD NOT CASEY RAISED HIS HAND.
WITH A SMILE OF
CHRISTIAN CHARITY,
GREAT CASEY'S VISAGE SHONE,
HE STILLED THE RISING TUMULT,
HE BADE THE GAME GO ON.
HE SIGNALED TO THE
PITCHER, AND ONCE MORE
THE DUN SPHERE FLEW, BUT
CASEY STILL IGNORED IT,
AND THE UMPIRE SAID,
"STRIKE TWO."
"FRAUD!" CRIED THE
MADDENED THOUSANDS,
AN ECHO ANSWERED, "FRAUD."
BUT ONE SCORNFUL LOOK FROM CASEY
AND THE AUDIENCE WAS AWED.
THEY SAW HIS FACE
GROW STERN AND COLD,
THEY SAW HIS MUSCLES STRAIN,
AND THEY KNEW THAT CASEY
WOULDN'T LET THAT
BALL GO BY AGAIN.
THE SNEER HAS FLED
FROM CASEY'S LIP,
HIS TEETH ARE CLENCHED IN HATE,
HE POUNDS WITH CRUEL VIOLENCE
HIS BAT UPON THE PLATE.
AND NOW THE PITCHER
HOLDS THE BALL,
AND NOW HE LET'S IT GO,
AND NOW THE AIR IS SHATTERED
BY THE FORCE OF CASEY'S BLOW.
OH, SOMEWHERE IN
THIS LAND OF OURS
THE SUN IS SHINING BRIGHT,
THE BAND IS PLAYING SOMEWHERE,
AND SOMEWHERE HEARTS ARE LIGHT,
AND SOMEWHERE MEN ARE LAUGHING,
AND LITTLE CHILDREN SHOUT,
BUT THERE IS NO JOY
IN MUDVILLE...
GREAT CASEY HAS STRUCK OUT.
Teacher: WHAT'S THE PROBLEM
WITH THE BAKING SODA?
DID YOU USE TOO MUCH?
YOU'VE GOT TO TASTE
THE SODA, RIGHT?
AN EVEN MORE EFFICIENT WAY
TO USE THAT KNIFE IS THIS.
SEE HERE?
IF YOU PIVOT IT FROM HERE,
YOU MAY CUT YOURSELF.
ONE PART GRANULATED SUGAR
AND ONE PART BROWN SUGAR.
RIGHT?
NOW YOU NEED ANOTHER
MEASURING CUP.
YOU'LL FIND ONE IN THE
CLOSET, RIGHT HERE.
Boy: YES, MA'AM.
RIGHT.
AND, GARY, WHAT ABOUT
THIS BROWN SUGAR?
HOW IS HE GOING TO MEASURE IT?
Boy: PACKED.
PACKED. ABSOLUTELY RIGHT, OKAY.
WHAT'S YOUR NUMBER, DOLL?
Girl: 11. 11?
[ APPLAUSE ] GREAT! SHE SURE
IS, AND ISN'T SHE A BEAUTY?
JUST LOOK AT THAT, SHE
IS A VISION FOR SURE.
LET'S HAVE NUMBER 14.
UM, YOU MAY DISAPPEAR.
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE, GIRLS.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I THINK THIS IS A
GOOD TIME... HOLD IT.
IT'S A GOOD TIME TO
TALK ABOUT CLOTHES.
A GIRL CAME INTO MY CLASS
TODAY IN A CULOTTE COSTUME.
AND IT LOOKED JUST
ABOUT, YOU KNOW, AH,
IT LOOKS AS SPORTY AS THIS.
IF IT WERE ON SOMEONE
WITH SLIMMER LEGS,
I THINK IT MIGHT LOOK GOOD.
COULD YOU FIND SOMEONE
TO MODEL IT FRIDAY
WITH REAL THIN LEGS, HONEY?
AND, GIRLS, DON'T WEAR
CULOTTES TO SCHOOL
BECAUSE YOU'LL LOOK
JUST LIKE THAT.
YOUR LEGS ARE ALL TOO
HEAVY FOR THE STUFF.
DON'T WEAR IT TOO SHORT
THEY LOOK MISERABLE.
I LOVE YOU. GOODBYE.
OKAY, NEXT... LET'S SEE.
NOW, I THINK IF THIS YOUNG LADY,
SHE'S GOT A LEG PROBLEM, TOO.
IF SHE DID SOMETHING
ABOUT THOSE STOCKINGS,
SHE MIGHT WELL LOOK BETTER.
COULD YOU GET A MATCHING PINK
OR FLESH-COLORED
STOCKING FOR FRIDAY?
YEAH, SOMETHING THAT FITS IN.
SALMON-COLORED, PINK, OR WHITE.
OR WHITE, ALL RIGHT?
WOULD LIKE TO SEE YOU
AGAIN ON FRIDAY.
WHAT'S YOUR NUMBER, HONEY?
NUMBER 14 AND YOU WILL
TAKE CARE OF THAT.
WE AREN'T EVEN ASKING YOU
ABOUT IT, BECAUSE I THINK
SHE'S GOT A PRETTY NICE
COLOR HERE, LOOKS GOOD.
AND IT'S THE LEG THING
THAT MAKES IT DIFFICULT.
ALL RIGHT, AND LET'S
SEE OUR LAST ONE,
AND I THINK THAT THIS YOUNG
LADY HAS DONE A LOVELY JOB
OF REALLY PUTTING SOME STYLE
INTO THIS PARTICULAR GARMENT.
LET'S SEE HOW SHE LOOKS.
SHE'S DONE A NICE JOB.
AND THIS IS A SAMPLE,
GIRLS, OF WHAT YOU CAN DO.
THIS GAL, SHE'S GOT
A WEIGHT PROBLEM...
SHE KNOWS IT...
SHE'S DONE EVERYTHING
SHE CAN TO CUT IT DOWN.
I MEAN, SHE DESIGNED THIS
GARMENT HERSELF WITH THE IDEA
OF MAKING IT GRACIOUS
AND GRACEFUL,
AND SHE HANDLES IT WELL.
SHE HANDLES HERSELF
BEAUTIFULLY, YOU SEE THIS?
OKAY, AND THAT'S WHAT YOU CAN
DO WITH FASHION AND DESIGN.
BUT THESE ARE THE
IMPORTANT THINGS, GIRLS.
TO WALK WITH YOUR
SHOULDERS HIGH AND PROUD.
AND THIS IS ALL THE TIME.
AROUND NORTHEAST HIGH SCHOOL,
THIS IS THE FAVORITE WALK.
AND YOU'VE JUST GOT TO DO
SOMETHING TO CONQUER IT,
YOU REALLY MUST,
HANDLE YOURSELF BEAUTIFULLY.
WHEN YOU STOP FOR APPLAUSE,
AS HERE FOR A TURN,
PUT YOUR FOOT BACK AND
PULL YOUR SHOULDERS BACK.
IN OTHER WORDS, "I'M
NOT IN A HURRY.
"I'M NOT TRYING TO
HIDE IN A CORNER.
I'M BEAUTIFUL... I HAVE
EVERYTHING IN CONTROL."
ALL RIGHT?
Girl: MRS. C., ARE YOU GOING
TO HAVE MUSIC PLAYING?
YES, THERE WILL BE MUSIC FRIDAY.
IT'S A VERY SHORT
TIME ON FRIDAY.
AND WHEN YOU TURN,
THIS IS THE FAVORITE,
THIS IS THE FAVORITE TURN,
KIDS, NOW, WATCH IT.
WATCH IT. THIS IS THE
WAY THEY GO HERE.
YOU COME ALONG, SEE.
NOW YOU'RE NOT HERE TO
SHOW YOUR DERRIERE.
THEREFORE, IF YOU ARE
SHOWING YOUR BACKSIDE
ON THE STAGE AT ALL,
IT'S MERELY A QUICK TURN
IN THIS FASHION, AND MISS FISHER
DID IT, A KIND OF SWING TURN.
ALL RIGHT? AND WATCH THESE FEET.
DON'T EVER END UP WITH
YOUR FEET LIKE THIS.
IF YOU WANT TO TEST THIS, GIRLS,
IF YOU WANT TO TEST THIS,
LOOK DOWN A LONG CORRIDOR.
RIGHT ACROSS HERE SOMETIMES,
FROM ONE END TO ANOTHER,
AND WATCH THE KIDS
COME UP THE HALL.
AND THIS IS THE WAY THEY
COME, ALL YOU GIRLS.
YOU SEE.
WHEREAS IF YOU GET YOUR
FEET, YOU GET YOUR WEIGHT
RIGHT STRAIGHT OVER
YOUR FEET AND WALK,
ONE ALMOST IN FRONT
OF THE OTHER,
YOU'RE DOING SOMETHING
FOR YOURSELF, OKAY?
COURSE, I STILL LOOK
LIKE A FAT LADY,
BUT THE POINT IS THAT YOU
LOOK MUCH MORE GRACEFUL,
MUCH MORE BEAUTIFUL
IF YOU DON'T DO THIS.
ARE THERE ANY QUESTIONS?
ANY QUESTIONS?
EVERYONE READY?
ANYONE NOT READY?
BEGIN.
[ STUDENTS TYPING ]
STOP TYPING, PLEASE.
ALL RIGHT, AS I READ THE
PARAGRAPH FROM THE BOOK,
LET'S FOLLOW ON
WHAT WE'VE TYPED.
"THE TWO MEN WENT DOWN WITH ME
DOWN THE LONG ROAD,"
COMMA, SPACE,
"AND IN NO TIME AT ALL,
WE HAD REACHED THE LAKE
AND FOUND THAT PATH
UP TO THE SPRING,"
PERIOD, DOUBLE SPACE.
CAPITAL W... "WE
HAD MADE THE HIKE
IN LESS THAN TWO HOURS"
SEMICOLON, SPACE.
THE DAY WAS FINE FOR
IT," COMMA, SPACE,
"MILD AND COOL," COMMA, SPACE,
"AND THE THREE OF US FELT FINE,"
PERIOD, NEW PARAGRAPH,
INDENT FIVE.
CAPITAL W.
"WE HAD A SNACK AT THE SPRING
AND THEN PICKED UP OUR GUNS
AND WENT ON DOWN THE PATH."
PERIOD, DOUBLE SPACE, CAPITAL W.
"WE LOOKED HIGH AND LOW
FOR SIGNS OF GAME,"
COMMA, SPACE,
"BUT THE BIRDS HAD SEEN
US AND SCREAMED AT US
ALL THE WHILE," COMMA, SPACE...
"SO THAT WHAT GAME THERE MIGHT
HAVE BEEN NEAR THE LAKE
HID FROM US OR TOOK
TO ITS HEELS,"
PERIOD, DOUBLE SPACE.
"WE CALLED IT A DAY AND
TURNED BACK HOME."
PERIOD, DOUBLE SPACE, CAPITAL W.
"WE HAD NOT FIRED ONE SHOT."
NOW, THERE ARE VARIOUS
TYPES OF FAMILIES.
WE HAVE THE FAMILY,
FOR INSTANCE,
IN WHICH THE DOMINANT
INDIVIDUAL IS THE MOTHER.
NOW, THIS IS A NATURAL
SORT OF THING.
YOU CAN SEE IN MANY
OF THE NATURAL, UH,
HABITS OF, LET'S SAY,
THE LOWER ANIMALS...
THE MOTHER IS DESIGNED,
WITH AN EYE, FIRST OF ALL, OF
TAKING CARE OF THE YOUNGSTER
BEFORE IT'S ABLE TO
FUNCTION ON THE OUTSIDE.
AND AFTER THE CHILD OR
THE OFFSPRING IS BORN,
SHE TAKES CARE OF IT.
NOW, IN SOME CASES, BIRDS,
SOME OF THE ANIMALS
MATE FOR LIFE.
BUT FREQUENTLY IT'S A
SORT OF SEASONAL THING...
THE FATHER IS FINISHED
HIS OBLIGATIONS
MAYBE AFTER HE
PROTECTS THE FEMALE,
AND THEY MAY NEVER
SEE EACH OTHER.
THEY DON'T TALK MUCH ABOUT
WOMEN IN THE BIBLE,
IN THE OLD TESTAMENT.
MOSES WAS THE BIG SHOT,
AND THE VARIOUS OTHER PEOPLE
THAT I'M NOT TOO WELL
ACQUAINTED WITH.
ONCE IN A WHILE A WOMAN
GETS IN JUST BY ACCIDENT.
NOW, THAT'S NOT TRUE IN
THE MODERN JEWISH FAMILY.
YOU KNOW WHO RUNS YOUR
HOUSEHOLD PRETTY WELL.
YOUR MOTHER COLLECTS THE MONEY,
SHE TAKES CARE OF THE BILLS,
PAYS THEM, SHE
DOES THE SHOPPING,
SHE HANDLES ALL THE SORT OF
ECONOMICAL SORT OF THINGS.
ONCE IN A WHILE, SHE'S
NICE AND ASKS YOUR FATHER
IF HE WOULD LIKE TO LOOK AT A
NEW CAR THEY'RE GOING TO BUY.
OR IF SHE'S IN
DIFFICULTY WITH YOU,
SHE'LL HAVE YOUR
FATHER SPEAK TO YOU.
BUT ORDINARILY, IT
TENDS TO BE THAT WAY
IN A GREAT MANY OF OUR FAMILIES.
SO THAT WE GO BACK TO
THAT MATRIARCHAL SYSTEM.
SHE SAYS, "WHY, IF A MAN
AND A WOMAN LIVE TOGETHER,
DOES SOCIETY THEN SAY
YOU'RE MARRIED?"
I THINK THAT'S GREAT, BECAUSE
SOCIETY DOES HAVE A WAY
TO TAKE CARE OF REGULAR,
RESPONSIBLE, STABLE UNIONS.
I THINK PROMISCUITY
IS WHAT ANY SOCIETY
CANNOT TOLERATE.
THAT'S A GOOD POINT.
WHY DO YOU HAVE YOUR
MENSTRUATION PERIOD?
YOU KNOW, THERE'S NOT AN
AWFULLY GOOD REASON FOR IT.
ONE OF THE INVENTORS OF
THE BIRTH CONTROL PILL
UP IN BOSTON, A VERY
EMINENT GYNECOLOGIST,
HAS SAID THAT HE DOESN'T...
HE CAN'T THINK OF ANY
GOOD REASON WHY WOMEN
HAVE TO CONTINUE TO MENSTRUATE
IF THEY DON'T WANT TO.
THAT WITH THE USE OF THE PILL,
WHICH REALLY REGULATES
YOUR CYCLE...
THIS IS WHAT THE PILL DOES...
YOU TAKE IT FOR, SAY, 20 DAYS,
AND THEN YOU DON'T TAKE
IT FOR A FEW DAYS.
YOU TAKE IT, YOU SEE,
ACCORDING TO DOCTOR'S ORDERS.
YOU DON'T JUST POP THESE
THINGS IN YOUR MOUTH
AN HOUR BEFORE A DATE.
IT'S A MEDICINE.
[ LAUGHTER ]
IT'S A MEDICINE THAT YOU TAKE
ACCORDING TO A PRESCRIPTION YOU
MUST OBTAIN FROM A DOCTOR,
AND YOU TAKE THEM JUST AS
YOU DO ANY OTHER MEDICINE,
REGULARLY AND CONTINUOUSLY.
YOU HAVE HAD PRACTICE
IN CONTROLLING YOUR
FEELINGS AND IMPULSES
EVER SINCE YOU'VE BEEN A BABY.
BY THE TIME YOU GET TO
BE A HIGH-SCHOOL SENIOR,
YOU DON'T EAT ALL THE
CHOCOLATE CAKE YOU WANT TO
BECAUSE YOU DON'T
WANT TO GET FAT.
YOU DO YOUR HOMEWORK WHETHER
YOU WANT TO OR NOT.
YOU TAKE YOUR COLLEGE BOARDS
EVEN IF YOU DON'T FEEL
LIKE IT THAT DAY.
YOU DON'T WALK INTO STRAWBRIDGES
AND STEAL DRESSES OFF THE RACK.
[ LAUGHTER ]
THERE IS NO BETTER ANSWER...
YOU HAVE LEARNED BY NOW,
AS PART OF BEING HUMAN,
THAT YOU CAN'T HAVE WHAT
YOU WANT WHEN YOU WANT IT.
THE GIRLS WHO HAVEN'T LEARNED
THAT... AND THE BOYS...
ARE IMPULSIVE AND
THEY NEVER CONNECT
WHAT THEY ARE DOING TODAY
WITH WHAT HAPPENS TOMORROW.
NOW, IF THIS BECOMES STYLE
FIVE YEARS FROM NOW,
THAT'S SOMETHING ELSE.
BUT RIGHT NOW, FOR FORMAL
WEAR, IT IS NOT STYLE.
IT'S STYLE FOR A VERY SMALL
PERCENTAGE OF PEOPLE.
AND WE'RE GOING TO DO IN THIS
SCHOOL WHAT THE MAJORITY WANTS.
UNTIL THIS KIND OF RULE CHANGES,
THIS IS WHAT WE'RE GOING TO DO.
THE MAJORITY WANTS
A FORMAL AFFAIR,
WHICH MEANS A LONG GOWN OR
A COCKTAIL-LENGTH GOWN.
Boy: THE MAJORITY OF STUDENTS?
THAT'S RIGHT.
Girl: EXCUSE ME, WHAT'S
THE COCKTAIL LENGTH?
Counselor: KNEE LENGTH.
Girl: HERE?
Woman: THE KNEE IS
NOT ABOVE THE KNEE.
Girl: THIS IS MY KNEE.
Woman: NO, IT ISN'T.
IF YOU FELL ON THAT
PART OF YOUR ANATOMY,
YOU WOULD NOT INJURE
YOUR UPPER THIGH.
Counselor: WOULDN'T
TEAR THE DRESS, ANYWAY.
[ WOMAN LAUGHS ]
Counselor: NO, I THINK THAT IT'S
NICE TO BE INDIVIDUALISTIC,
BUT THERE ARE CERTAIN PLACES
TO BE INDIVIDUALISTIC.
Girl: I DIDN'T MEAN TO
BE INDIVIDUALISTIC.
Counselor: NO, I'M
NOT CRITICIZING,
I SAY IT'S NICE TO BE THAT WAY,
BUT THERE ARE CERTAIN
TIMES TO BE THAT WAY.
UH, I THINK YOU CAN BE
INDIVIDUALISTIC IN YOUR DRESS,
BUT IT DOESN'T HAVE TO BE...
Girl: I HAPPEN TO
ENJOY A SHORT GOWN.
I DIDN'T KNOW IT WOULDN'T
BE ACCEPTED TO THE PROM.
I DIDN'T DO IT PURPOSELY
THIS IS WHAT I ENJOY.
Counselor: WHAT
DOES FORMAL MEAN?
Girl: WELL, FORMAL MEANS DRESSY.
I DIDN'T THINK OF IT AS A GOWN.
Counselor: OH.
Woman: FORMAL MEANS
MORE THAN DRESSY.
Counselor: WHEN YOU
GET AN INVITATION
TO A FORMAL AFFAIR,
IT SAYS "WHITE TIE
OR BLACK TIE."
IT DOESN'T SAY THAT THE
GIRLS OR WOMEN WEAR
ANY LENGTH THEY WANT.
IT MEANS A FLOOR-LENGTH GOWN.
YOU GET AN INVITATION
TO A COCKTAIL PARTY,
IT DOESN'T MEAN A
FLOOR-LENGTH GOWN,
IT MEANS A KNEE-LENGTH
GOWN OR A FLOOR-LENGTH.
BUT "FORMAL" MEANS A LONG
GOWN FOR A YOUNG LADY,
A MIDDLE-AGED LADY,
ELDERLY LADY.
SEE WHAT I MEAN, AND FOR
A MAN IT MEANS A TUX,
AND IT'S DETERMINED
BY THE TIME OF DAY
WHETHER IT'S WHITE
TIE OR BLACK TIE.
THERE ARE NO QUESTIONS.
I DIDN'T KNOW ANY OTHER,
REALLY, WHOLE STORY.
I DIDN'T KNOW THAT THEY
WEREN'T PERMITTED.
THIS IS WHAT I
FELT LIKE WEARING.
Counselor: IT DOESN'T MATTER
IF IT'S NOT PERMITTED,
IT'S A MATTER
OF WHAT YOU'RE GOING TO DO
IN A SITUATION LIKE THIS.
THIS IS OFFENSIVE
TO THE WHOLE CLASS.
Girl: I DIDN'T REALLY
MEAN IT TO BE.
Counselor: I KNOW YOU PROBABLY
DIDN'T MEAN IT TO BE THIS,
BUT THIS IS WHAT IT IS.
Woman: WE BOUGHT AN ATMOSPHERE
BY RENTING THE SHERATON
BALLROOM, WHICH IS VERY FORMAL.
Counselor: WE COULD HAVE
HAD THE DANCE IN THE GYM.
Woman: WE COULD HAVE
HAD THAT IN THE GYM
AND THEN IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
A LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
Counselor: MAYBE A COUPLE OF
GO-GO GIRLS UP ON THE STAGE
WITH A $50 ORCHESTRA,
AND WE WOULD HAVE
HAD A NICE DANCE,
BUT THIS IS NOT JUST A DANCE.
THIS IS THE SENIOR PROM.
THIS IS FORMAL.
IT'S THE ONE TIME IN YOUR LIFE
THAT YOUR CLASS
LOOKS SO DIFFERENT
YOU DON'T RECOGNIZE ANYBODY.
IT'S THE FIRST CHANCE YOU HAVE
TO BE YOUNG LADIES
AND YOUNG GENTLEMEN.
Woman: I HAD A BOY ASK, AND I
HAD A GIRL COME UP AND SAY,
"CAN MY BOYFRIEND WEAR
A DARK SUIT BECAUSE
HE CANNOT AFFORD THE MONEY
FOR THE RENTAL OF A TUX?"
I SAID, "NO, HE CAN'T."
BECAUSE THEN MY HUSBAND
HAS A RIGHT TO WEAR
THE BEAUTIFUL SUIT
HE JUST BOUGHT...
BUT WE HAVE TO PAY, WHAT IS
IT, $10 OR $15 TO RENT A TUX.
NOW, MY HUSBAND HAS NOTHING
TO DO WITH THE SCHOOL,
BUT HE'S HONORING THE YOUNGSTERS
BY COMING DRESSED PROPERLY.
Counselor: AND I WOULDN'T THINK
OF COMING WITHOUT WEARING A TUX.
I RENT ONE EVERY YEAR.
Woman: I HAVE TO WEAR A
LONG GOWN, I'D LOVE TO...
AND I CAN'T WALK IN IT.
I CAN'T GET INTO THE
CAR COMFORTABLY.
Woman: 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
OH, BOY, WE'RE FEMININE.
LET'S GO.
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
TARZAN.
1, 2...
3, 4, 5...
6, 7, 8, 9, SUPER TARZAN.
1, 2, 3, 4...
5, 6, 7, 8...
THE DARK FELLOW
HERE IS PAUL SIMON,
AND THE BLOND IS ART GARFUNKEL.
THE POET IS SIMON.
AND IF YOU DOUBT THAT
HE'S A POET NOW,
WAIT UNTIL YOU HEAR
SOME OF HIS POETRY.
AND YOU'LL NOTICE ON THE
BOARD I HAVE SOME THINGS
THAT YOU'RE FAMILIAR
WITH... IMAGES, SETTING,
FIGURATIVE LANGUAGE,
THEMATIC WORDS.
AND WE'LL BE FINDING HOW
HE SAYS WHAT HE DOES SAY.
WHAT DO THEY WANT TO SAY
ABOUT OUR LIVES AND HOW?
AND I THINK THE BEST WAY
TO START IS BY LOOKING
AT ONE OF THE BEST OF THE POEMS,
"THE DANGLING CONVERSATION."
THAT'S THE FIRST
ONE ON YOUR SHEET.
THE PROCESS WE'LL USE...
FIRST, WE'LL READ THE POEM,
THEN LISTEN TO IT, THEN
WE'LL TALK ABOUT IT
AND SEE HOW ALL THE
VARIOUS POETIC DEVICES
REINFORCE THE THEME, AND SEE
WHAT YOU THINK ABOUT IT,
AND THEN WE'LL LISTEN
TO IT ONCE AGAIN,
AND I'LL BET IT MEANS SOMETHING
A LITTLE BIT MORE TO YOU.
"IT'S A STILL-LIFE WATERCOLOR
OF THE NOW-LATE AFTERNOON,
"AS THE SUN SHINES
THROUGH THE CURTAIN LACE
"AND SHADOWS WASH THE ROOM.
"AND WE SIT AND
DRINK OUR COFFEE,
"COUCHED IN OUR INDIFFERENCE,
"LIKE SHELLS UPON THE SHORE,
"YOU CAN HEAR THE OCEAN ROAR,
"IN THE DANGLING CONVERSATION
AND THE SUPERFICIAL SIGHS,
"THE BORDERS OF OUR LIVES.
"AND YOU READ YOUR
EMILY DICKINSON
"AND I MY ROBERT FROST,
"AND WE NOTE OUR PLACE
WITH BOOKMARKERS
"AND MEASURE WHAT WE LOST,
"LIKE A POEM POORLY WRITTEN,
WE ARE VERSES OUT OF RHYTHM,
"COUPLETS OUT OF RHYME,
IN SYNCOPATED TIME.
"AND THE DANGLING CONVERSATION
AND THE SUPERFICIAL SIGHS
"ARE THE BORDERS OF OUR LIVES.
"YES, WE SPEAK THE
THINGS THAT MATTER
"WITH WORDS THAT MUST BE SAID...
"CAN ANALYSIS BE WORTHWHILE?
"IS THE THEATER REALLY DEAD?
"AND HOW THE ROOM
IS SOFTLY FADED,
"AS I ONLY KISS YOUR SHADOW,
"I CANNOT FEEL YOUR HAND,
"YOU'RE A STRANGER
NOW UNTO ME, LOST,
"IN THE DANGLING CONVERSATION
AND THE SUPERFICIAL SIGHS,
THE BORDERS OF OUR LIVES."
LET'S LISTEN TO IT.
AND NOTICE HOW NOT
ONLY THE DEVICES
REINFORCE THE THEME
BUT ALSO THE VERY
RHYTHMS, THE MELODIES,
AND HOW THEY USED THEIR TIMING.
NOW, WHEN I TAPED THESE,
THEY WERE FROM A MONAURAL
AND STEREO RECORDS.
THE TAPE IS A LITTLE FAST...
IT'S THE DRAMA CLUB
TAPE RECORDER,
SO YOU'LL HAVE TO BE A LITTLE
PATIENT AT THE VERY BEGINNING.
[ SONG BEGINS ]
♪ IT'S A STILL-LIFE WATERCOLOR ♪
♪ OF A NOW-LATE AFTERNOON ♪
♪ AS THE SUN SHINES THROUGH
THE CURTAIN LACE ♪
♪ AND SHADOWS WASH THE ROOM ♪
♪ AND WE SIT AND
DRINK OUR COFFEE ♪
♪ COUCHED IN OUR INDIFFERENCE,
LIKE SHELLS UPON THE SHORE ♪
♪ YOU CAN HEAR THE OCEAN ROAR ♪
♪ IN THE DANGLING CONVERSATION ♪
♪ AND THE SUPERFICIAL SIGHS ♪
♪ THE BORDERS OF OUR LIVES ♪
♪ AND YOU READ YOUR
EMILY DICKINSON ♪
♪ AND I MY ROBERT FROST ♪
♪ AND WE NOTE OUR PLACE
WITH BOOKMARKERS ♪
♪ THAT MEASURE WHAT WE'VE LOST ♪
♪ LIKE A POEM POORLY WRITTEN ♪
♪ WE ARE VERSES OUT OF RHYTHM ♪
♪ COUPLETS OUT OF RHYME ♪
♪ IN SYNCOPATED TIME ♪
♪ AND THE DANGLING
CONVERSATION ♪
♪ AND THE SUPERFICIAL SIGHS ♪
♪ ARE THE BORDERS OF OUR LIVES ♪
♪ YES, WE SPEAK OF
THINGS THAT MATTER ♪
♪ WITH WORDS THAT MUST BE SAID ♪
♪ CAN ANALYSIS BE WORTHWHILE? ♪
♪ IS THE THEATER REALLY DEAD? ♪
♪ AND HOW THE ROOM IS
SOFTLY FADED... ♪♪
HEY, YOU! TURN AROUND, PAL.
SIR.
DON'T "SIR" ME.
DON'T FEED ME THAT
"SIR" BUSINESS.
YOU PUNCHED THIS
GUY IN THE MOUTH.
ON WHAT BASIS?
SIR, SIR, HE STARTED MOUTHING
OFF, STARTED LAUGHING, SO...
Dean: YEAH, THAT DOESN'T
GIVE YOU A RIGHT TO HIT HIM.
IF IT WAS A 6' 2",
215-POUND FULLBACK,
YOU WOULDN'T BE SO QUICK
TO PUNCH HIM IN THE MOUTH.
P-E-R-G.
Boy: O-L-I-N-O.
WHERE DO YOU COME
IN TO HIT THIS GUY?
HE HAS A RIGHT TO
ERASE THE BOARD.
Boy: THAT'S NOT
WHAT IT WAS OVER.
Dean: JUST AS MUCH AS YOU
HAVE A RIGHT TO WRITE ON IT.
YOU DIDN'T ASK PERMISSION
TO WRITE THOSE NAMES
ON THE BOARD, DID YOU?
PARDON ME, SIR, BUT THAT
WASN'T WHAT IT WAS OVER.
WHAT WAS IT OVER?
SIR, JUST BEFORE CLASS STARTED,
WE HAD AN ARGUMENT, AND
I DIDN'T DO NOTHING.
WELL, YOU'RE NOT
SUPPOSEDTO DO ANYTHING.
YOU DON'T STRIKE OR HIT ANYBODY.
LEVINE WEARS GLASSES
ON TOP OF IT,
YET YOU STILL HIT HIM.
SIR, I WEAR GLASSES, TOO.
Dean: THAT'S WHY YOU ARE
GOING TO BE SUSPENDED,
FOR THROWING THE FIRST
PUNCH... YES, SIR.
DON'T GIVE ME THAT
"YES, SIR" BUSINESS.
I DON'T LIKE THE "SIR" BUSINESS.
YOU KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE THERE'S NO
SINCERENESS BEHIND IT.
Female dean: AND HOW ABOUT
THE POOR, POOR TEACHER,
WHOEVER IT WAS?
I DON'T KNOW.
Girl: I DON'T EVEN KNOW WHAT
SHE SAID THAT WE DID, BUT...
Dean: IT'S A MATTER OF
BEING INHUMAN TO
ANOTHER HUMAN BEING.
THAT'S WHAT IT AMOUNTS TO.
Girl: BUT ALL I KNOW
IS THAT SHE GOT SUE
IN A LOT OF TROUBLE AND...
Dean: SUE WHO?
Girl: THE OTHER GIRL.
AND SUE DIDN'T... I DON'T
THINK SUE HAD ANY...
SHE TOLD... SHE SAID THAT WE
LOCKED HER IN THE CLOSET.
Dean: YOU MEAN SUE AND YOU?
Girl: I MEAN THE CLASS.
NOBODY LOCKED HER IN THE
CLOSET AS FAR AS I KNOW.
LOOK, IF SHE WOULD'VE BEEN
LOCKED IN THE CLOSET,
I SURE WOULD HAVE HEARD THAT
AND TURNED AROUND AND LOOKED.
Dean: SHE MAY HAVE HAD A
LITTLE MORE CONTROL THAN THAT.
THAT MUCH NOISE, IT'S A
LITTLE EMBARRASSING TO HER.
SHE WASN'T GOING TO CALL
EVERYBODY'S ATTENTION TO IT.
Girl: IT WASN'T FAIR.
SUE WAS JUST MESSING AROUND,
JUST AS MUCH AS US.
THE REST OF THE CLASS...
AND NOW SUE'S IN
SO MUCH TROUBLE,
JUST BECAUSE OF
THAT ONE TEACHER.
AND BECAUSE SUE GOT IN TROUBLE,
I BLAME IT A LOT ON THE TEACHER
'CAUSE...
Dean: WELL, LET'S KEEP LOOKING
AT THAT BECAUSE, AGAIN,
THIS IS MY CONCERN, EILEEN.
SUE GOT IN TROUBLE
BECAUSE OF THE TEACHER.
SUE DID NOTHING TO HELP?
WHOEVER SUE IS, I DON'T KNOW.
I'M GLAD YOU DIDN'T ANSWER
WHEN I ASKED YOU HER NAME
BECAUSE IT'S EASIER TO TALK.
Eileen: SHE JUST MESSED
AROUND LIKE EVERYBODY ELSE.
Woman: LOOK, CAN YOU TELL ME
WHAT "MESSING AROUND" MEANS?
THIS IS WHAT I'VE BEEN TRYING
TO FIND OUT FOR MONTHS.
EVERY TIME YOU WOULD
SAY "MESSING AROUND."
WHAT DOES IT
ACTUALLY CONSIST OF?
Eileen: I DON'T KNOW, WE
WERE TALKING, LAUGHING...
WELL, JUST PLAIN TALKING AND
LAUGHING ISN'T OFFENSIVE.
Eileen: WELL, WE WERE
CATCHING A BOOK OR SOMETHING.
OH, YOU THREW A BOOK AROUND?
Eileen: NOT JUST ME!
BUT WHOEVER WAS INVOLVED.
Eileen: I KNOW I DID A LOT.
LIKE, I DID A LOT. I
TALKED BACK A LOT.
DID YOU TALK BACK
TO THE TEACHER?
Eileen: YEAH.
AND THIS IS WHAT YOU
CALL "MESSING AROUND"?
Eileen: NO, WELL...
ISN'T THAT MORE DISRESPECT?
Eileen: WHAT I DID WAS
DISRESPECT, BUT WHAT THE REST...
WHAT EVERYBODY ELSE DID
WAS MESSING AROUND.
I DON'T... I DON'T KNOW.
Dean: YOU SEE, WHAT
MOTHER IS SAYING...
AT LEAST WHAT I'M SAYING, I
THINK WHAT MOTHER IS SAYING...
IS THAT WE HOPE, EILEEN,
THAT YOU DON'T SET
YOUR STANDARDS BY
THE SO-CALLED "EVERYBODY ELSE,"
THAT YOU SET YOUR STANDARDS
ON WHAT YOU KNOW IS
THE THING TO DO.
I REPEAT, THERE'S NO DOUBT
THE TEACHER WAS NOT
HOLDING THE CLASS,
WAS NOT DOING THE JOB YOU
THINK SHE SHOULD HAVE DONE,
FROM WHAT YOU SAY,
I'LL ACCEPT THAT.
BUT WHO BREAKS THE CIRCLE
WHEN THINGS GO AROUND
AND AROUND AND AROUND?
SOMEONE HAS TO BE MATURE ENOUGH
TO MOVE OUT OF THE CIRCLE AND
INTO THE STRAIGHT, RIGHT?
SOMEBODY HAS GOT TO
BREAK AWAY FROM IT.
YOU'RE INTELLIGENT,
YOU'RE MATURE,
YOU HAVE THE BACKGROUND.
YOU CAN BE THE ONE
THAT CAN DO IT.
WHY DON'T YOU OFFER THE POSITIVE
KIND OF LEADERSHIP THAT YOU CAN,
THAT YOU KNOW YOU HAVE AND
THAT I KNOW YOU HAVE,
THAT MOTHER KNOWS YOU HAVE?
YOU CAN BE A REAL FORCE
IN ANY GROUP, EILEEN.
CAN'T YOU?
THE KIDS RALLY AROUND YOU A BIT.
Eileen: WELL, NOT REALLY.
I'VE SEEN YOU IN THE LUNCHROOM.
WE'VE GOT US A POTENTIAL LEADER.
Mother: EILEEN CAN.
Dean: IT SHOWS WHEREVER SHE IS.
I'VE SEEN HER ONCE IN
A WHILE IN A GROUP.
YOU CAN SEE WHO THE LEADER IS
IN A GROUP, AND SHE HAS IT.
EILEEN HAS A VERY SET MIND,
AND IF SHE DECIDES THAT
SOMETHING SHOULD BE DONE,
THIS IS WHAT SHE PURSUES,
THIS I KNOW ABOUT HER.
Dean: I THINK THAT'S GOOD.
I THINK IT'S EXCELLENT
IN MANY WAYS,
BUT I'VE OFTEN SAID TO HER,
"EILEEN, USE YOUR
DETERMINATION FOR RIGHT.
AND AS LONG AS YOU DO,
YOU'LL BE ALL RIGHT."
AND ONE THING, THIS IS THE ONE
THING THAT BOTHERS ME SO MUCH...
THE MAIN THING IN OUR
HOME HAS ALWAYS BEEN
RESPECT FOR AN ADULT.
I WAS BROUGHT UP THAT
WAY... MY HUSBAND WAS.
AND WE HAVE BEEN TRYING TO TEACH
OUR CHILDREN THE SAME THING.
TO ME, I THINK, ONE
OF THE WORST OFFENSES
IS BEING DISRESPECTFUL
TO AN OLDER PERSON.
IRREGARDLESS OF WHAT
THE CONDITION MAY BE.
YOU CAN SAY THE SAME THING
IN A PLEASANT MANNER
THAT YOU CAN IN
AN OFFENSIVE WAY.
AND THIS IS ONE THING
THAT'S DISTURBED ME
RECENTLY ABOUT EILEEN.
THAT EVEN AT HOME, NOW SHE...
I DON'T SAY THE LANGUAGE
THAT SHE USES IS WRONG,
BUT IT'S THE MANNER
THAT THE SAME...
THAT A SENTENCE
IS BROUGHT FORTH.
AND I TOLD HER,
"EVENTUALLY, EILEEN,
THIS IS GOING TO
HURT YOU OUTSIDE."
AND FINALLY IT HAS.
AND I THINK YOU WOULD KIND
OF HAVE TO DECIDE, ARLEEN,
HOW DO YOU FEEL ABOUT WHERE YOU
STOOD IN YOUR COLLEGE CLASS,
WHETHER YOU WOULD RATHER
BE IN AN EASIER SCHOOL,
AND TOWARD THE TOP OF THE CLASS,
OR IN A HARDER SCHOOL
AND TOWARD THE
BOTTOM OF THE CLASS.
I THINK I WOULD GAIN
MORE BY BEING, LIKE,
IN THE MIDDLE OR THE TOP THAN
BEING AT THE VERY BOTTOM,
NOT BEING ABLE TO KEEP
UP WITH EVERYBODY ELSE.
Counselor: DO YOU WANT A
COLLEGE COURSE, THEN, DEAR,
WHERE, AT THE END OF FOUR
YEARS, YOU WOULD BE FINISHED
WITH YOUR EDUCATION AND ABLE
TO GO OUT AND MAKE A LIVING,
OR DO YOU WANT THE KIND OF
COURSE WHERE, AT THE END
OF FOUR YEARS, IT IS
LIKELY THAT YOU WOULD BE
GOING ON WITH YOUR EDUCATION?
Arleen: I'M NOT SURE RIGHT NOW.
I THINK I WANT TO GO TO
FOUR YEARS OF COLLEGE
AND, MAYBE, IF I
BECOME A TEACHER,
STOP, AND THEN I CAN
ALWAYS TAKE COURSES AGAIN,
GO HIGHER, GET A HIGHER DEGREE.
OR, I THINK, UH, A SOCIAL WORKER
OR PSYCHOLOGIST HAS
TO GO FIVE YEARS.
Counselor: OR SIX
YEARS OR SEVEN YEARS.
IT WOULD DEPEND ON WHAT
YOU CHOSE AFTER THAT.
I DON'T THINK I WANT
TO GO MORE THAN
MAYBE FIVE OR SIX YEARS,
OR MORE THAN FIVE.
WELL, I THINK YOU'VE GIVEN ME
A PRETTY COMPREHENSIVE IDEA
OF WHAT YOU ARE LOOKING FOR.
AND THEN I WOULD HAVE
TO ASK YOU, SIR,
THE HARD, HARD
QUESTION OF HOW MUCH
COULD YOU CONTRIBUTE TO
YOUR DAUGHTER'S EDUCATION?
Father: WELL, UH,
THAT'S A HARD QUESTION
TO SAY BECAUSE, UH, IF SHE
LIVES AWAY FROM HOME,
THEN IT'S A DIFFERENT
STORY ALTOGETHER.
AND IF SHE IS AT HOME,
IT'S ANOTHER STORY.
BUT THE WAY SHE'S TALKING, SHE
DOESN'T WANT TO STAY HOME.
SO I WOULD SAY ABOUT $1,000,
$1,500 IS ABOUT THE BEST
I COULD GIVE HER A YEAR
TO GO AWAY TO COLLEGE.
MM-HMM.
THEN IT WOULD SEEM
TO ME THAT, ARLEEN,
THAT THE MOST REALISTIC
WAY TO PLAN IT WOULD BE
TO THINK ABOUT
WHERE YOU COULD GO
IF YOUR FATHER COULD GIVE
YOU $1,000 TO $1,500,
AND THEN TO TRY FOR SCHOLARSHIP
IN SOME OTHER PLACES
THAT MIGHT BE SOMEWHAT
MORE EXPENSIVE.
BUT, I THINK YOU
KIND OF HAVE TO PLAN
FOR WHERE YOU WOULD GO
IF YOU DIDN'T GET ANY
FINANCIAL AID FROM SOMEONE.
I MEAN, YOU ALWAYS HAVE TO...
YOU LOOK AT THE BRIGHTER SIDE
ABOUT WHERE YOU
WOULD LIKE TO GO,
YOU CAN HAVE ALL
YOUR DREAM SCHOOLS,
BUT AT THE BOTTOM,
YOU OUGHT TO HAVE SOME
COLLEGE OF LAST RESORT
WHERE YOU COULD BE SURE
THAT YOU WOULD GO,
IF NONE OF YOUR
DREAMS CAME TRUE.
RHONA IS THE RECIPIENT OF A
$10,000 HERO SCHOLARSHIP
TO ANY COLLEGE ANYWHERE IN
THE COUNTRY SHE WANTS TO GO.
Father: I'M NOT SAYING
SHE IS COLLEGE MATERIAL,
BUT AT LEAST SHE CAN HAVE SOME
TYPE OF EDUCATION, FOLLOWING...
SHE CAN GO TO ANY COLLEGE
AND DO WHATEVER SHE WANTED.
TELL ME AGAIN,
DO YOU THINK YOU WANT
TO GO TO COLLEGE?
YES.
Father: PLEASE, NOW,
YOU'RE LYING TO THE MAN...
YOU DON'T WANT TO GO TO COLLEGE.
WELL, I DO, BUT NOT
THE KIND OF COLLEGE
THAT YOU WANT ME TO.
WHAT KIND OF COLLEGE
DO YOU WANT TO GO TO?
I WANT TO BE A COSMETICIAN.
COSMETICIAN? BUT THAT'S
NOT A COLLEGE, IS IT?
WELL, IT'S A BEAUTY
CULTURE SCHOOL.
IT'S A BEAUTY CULTURE
SCHOOL, IT'S NOT A COLLEGE.
THE REQUIREMENTS FOR THAT ARE
DIFFERENT THAN FOR COLLEGE.
YES.
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY
FOREIGN LANGUAGE. NO.
YOU DON'T HAVE ANY ALGEBRA,
YOU DON'T HAVE GEOMETRY.
SO THAT ACTUALLY, AS FAR
AS GOING TO COLLEGE,
YOU'RE NOT EVEN
PREPARED FOR A COLLEGE.
DO YOU FEEL THAT YOU ARE
DISAPPOINTING YOUR PARENTS
BY NOT GOING TO COLLEGE?
NOW, TELL ME THE TRUTH.
YES.
YOU FEEL YOUR PARENTS
ARE DISAPPOINTED?
MY FATHER.
YOUR FATHER IS?
TELL ME, WOULD YOU FEEL BETTER
IF YOU KNEW YOUR FATHER
REALLY ACCEPTED THE FACT THAT
YOU DIDN'T GO TO COLLEGE?
YOU FEEL A BIT GUILTY FOR
NOT GOING TO COLLEGE?
YES, WHAT DO YOU SAY?
WELL...
THAT YOU ARE DISAPPOINTING
YOUR PARENTS?
I'M DISAPPOINTING MY FATHER,
BUT I DON'T THINK I'D FEEL
GUILTY ABOUT NOT GOING.
YOU DON'T FEEL GUILTY AT ALL?
NOT GUILTY... IT'S MY LIFE.
IT'S YOUR LIFE.
I FEEL THAT WHAT I WANT TO BE
IS MORE IMPORTANT THAN
WHAT HE DESIRES ME TO BE.
I SEE...
BUT YOU KNOW YOUR PARENTS
ARE DISAPPOINTED,
YOUR FATHER IN PARTICULAR? YES.
YOU CAN'T UNDO THE PAST.
EVEN IF SOMEBODY
HAS MADE A MISTAKE
AND BEEN WRONG AND UNFAIR,
YOU CAN'T UNDO THE PAST.
THE ONLY THING YOU CAN
DO IS TRY TO DO BETTER
IN THE PRESENT SO THAT THE
FUTURE WILL BE BETTER.
SO WHAT I'M SUGGESTING TO
YOU, WORK AS HARD AS YOU CAN,
DO THE BEST YOU CAN,
AND CONFER WITH MR.
SCHUSTER ABOUT, ABOUT THIS,
AND LET'S SEE WHAT HAPPENS AT
THE END OF THE SEMESTER, OKAY?
YOU GO BACK TO CLASS
NOW, OR ARE YOU THROUGH?
NO, I'M THROUGH.
Father: THANKS AGAIN, DR.
BOODISH.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
YOU'RE WELCOME. GOODBYE.
OH, INCIDENTALLY, HOW ABOUT GYM?
THIS IS THE STRONGEST
CHILD IN THE SCHOOL.
Boodish: WHAT ARE YOU
GOING TO DO TO PASS GYM?
WELL, I HAVE TO DO MY MAKE-UPS.
Boodish: THAT'S NECESSARY
FOR GRADUATION, YOU KNOW.
IT IS?
IT IS... SHE HAS TO PASS.
I WISH, DR. BOODISH,
SHE WAS AS SMART
AS SHE IS STRONG.
THANK YOU, DOCTOR.
VERY STRONG GIRL.
Boodish: I'M GOING TO ASK
YOUR DAUGHTER A QUESTION.
HOW DID YOU FEEL
ABOUT THAT REMARK
THAT YOUR FATHER JUST MADE?
I LIKED IT.
YOU LIKED IT? GOOD, OKAY.
Man on Intercom: THERE IS A CAR
IN THE STUDENTS' DRIVEWAY
BLOCKING THE EXIT
OF TWO OTHER CARS.
BUT I DON'T BELIEVE IN GIVING...
GIVE THEM JOBS.
BUT I DON'T BELIEVE IN GIVING,
LET THEM EARN IT.
THERE'S TOO MUCH RELIEF
GOING ON, THAT'S ALL.
WE ARE TOO MUCH TO A POINT
WHERE THEY ARE
GIVING ALL THE TIME.
YOU'RE ALL HUNG UP ON
THE PROTESTANT ETHIC.
THERE ARE SO MANY
FACETS TO THIS.
I DON'T BELIEVE IN
WHAT BILL SAYS.
I DON'T BELIEVE 100%
IN WHAT BILL SAYS ABOUT
GIVING THINGS AWAY.
I NEVER THINK THAT ANYBODY
APPRECIATES ANYTHING.
LOOK AT YOUR OWN CHILDREN...
WHEN YOU GIVE THEM, DO
THEY REALLY APPRECIATE IT?
SOMETIMES IF THEY WORK FOR
IT A LITTLE BIT, BILL,
THEY APPRECIATE
THESE THINGS MORE.
Man: LOOK AT THIS MONEY
WE ARE GIVING AWAY TO
THE WORLD, FOREIGN AID.
THEY'RE LAUGHING AT US.
THEY'RE CRAMMING IT
RIGHT DOWN YOUR THROAT.
ACTUALLY, THIS FOREIGN
AID BUSINESS...
WE'RE REALLY GIVING
MONEY TO THE GUYS
WHO ARE BUYING FROM
THE RICH PEOPLE
AND FROM THE
MANUFACTURERS OVER HERE.
THAT'S WHERE THE MONEY'S GOING.
IT'S NOT JUST BEING
GIVEN TO THEM.
BUT THE THING IS, THERE IS
SO MUCH MONEY BEING WASTED.
Girl: W.H. SILVERS.
Teacher: YES, W.H. SILVERS.
NOW, WHAT WAS HE TRYING TO
DO, WHAT WAS HIS PURPOSE?
YES, AIDELE?
Aidele: HE WAS
TRYING TO ESTABLISH
AN EIGHT-HOUR WORKING
DAY FOR LABORERS...
Teacher: YEAH, WELL, HE
WANTED HIGHER WAGES...
HE WANTED AN EIGHT-HOUR WORKDAY.
BUT HE TRIED TO UNITE...
THIS IS THE IMPORTANT
THING ABOUT THIS...
HE TRIED TO UNITE ALL LABOR
UNIONS OF THE COUNTRY
INTO A FEDERATION MEMBERSHIP.
WHAT ON THE HORIZON,
OR WHAT EXISTED
THAT FORCED LABOR TO TURN
TO COLLECTIVE BARGAINING?
WHAT WAS THERE A LACK OF?
Girl: COMMUNICATIONS.
Teacher: YES, COMMUNICATIONS,
LACK OF SECURITY,
CONCERN FOR THE JOB.
THE IMPORTANT THING IS THIS...
LET'S GET TO THE BEGINNINGS.
FIRST OF ALL, THERE WAS
THE LACK OF SECURITY.
SECOND OF ALL, THERE WAS A
LACK OF COMMUNICATION...
THE ATTITUDE OF THE EMPLOYEES,
OR OF THE EMPLOYERS
TOWARDS THE EMPLOYEES,
WITH REGARD TO
WORKING CONDITIONS,
LIVING CONDITIONS,
WITH REGARD TO WAGES...
VERY LITTLE COMMUNICATION.
Teacher: ALL RIGHT,
WE HAVE EVIDENTLY
A GREAT IMBALANCE IN
AMERICAN SOCIETY.
WE HAVE, ON THE ONE HAND, WE
HAVE AN AFFLUENT SOCIETY...
AND THAT'S ONE AMERICA...
AND ON THE OTHER HAND,
WE HAVE ANOTHER AMERICA
AND, BY THE WAY,
THAT'S THE NAME OF A GOOD
BOOK BY MICHAEL HARRINGTON
CALLED "THE OTHER AMERICA."
AND WHAT IS THIS OTHER AMERICA?
ANOTHER AMERICA THAT IS NOT...
AMERICA OF POVERTY, AMERICA
THAT IS NOT SHARING
IN THE AFFLUENCE OF
AMERICAN SOCIETY.
AND KING WAS THERE TO TRY TO
UPLIFT THIS OTHER AMERICA.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT THE
DEPARTMENT OF LABOR
SAYS SHOULD BE THE COMFORT
LEVEL OF A FAMILY OF FOUR...
A MAN, A WIFE, AND TWO CHILDREN?
WHAT THEY SHOULD EARN
TO BE COMFORTABLE.
NOT... MODERATELY
COMFORTABLE, NOT AFFLUENT,
BUT JUST MODERATELY
COMFORTABLE IN OUR SOCIETY.
KNOW WHAT THE FIGURE IS, ANY
IDEA WHAT THE FIGURE IS?
CHRISTINE? HOW MUCH?
Christine: $9,000.
YES, A LITTLE OVER $9,000.
SO YOU CAN IMAGINE...
DO YOU KNOW WHAT PERCENT
OF THE AMERICAN POPULATION
EARNS OVER $9,000?
IT'S NOT THE MAJORITY.
LET'S DETERMINE SOME OF THE
ATTITUDES IN THIS CLASS
AND SEE HOW WE COME OUT.
ALL RIGHT, HOW MANY OF YOU
WOULD BE A MEMBER OF A CLUB
WHERE MINORITY MEMBERS
OF THE CLUB WERE NEGRO?
HOW MANY WOULD ACCEPT
THAT SITUATION?
YOU WOULD BE A
MEMBER OF THE CLUB
IF A MINORITY OF THE
MEMBERS WERE NEGRO?
ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, FINE, PUT YOUR HANDS DOWN.
HOW MANY WOULD NOT BE
A MEMBER OF THE CLUB?
ALL RIGHT, HOW MANY WOULD
BE A MEMBER OF A CLUB
WHERE HALF THE MEMBERS
WERE NEGRO MEMBERS AND THE
OTHER HALF WERE WHITE?
ALL RIGHT... PUT
YOUR HANDS DOWN.
HOW MANY WOULD NOT BE A
MEMBER OF THAT CLUB?
ALL RIGHT.
REMEMBER, THERE'S NO
RIGHT OR WRONG ANSWER...
IT'S JUST, I'M JUST TRYING TO
DETERMINE WHAT ATTITUDES ARE.
♪ DO ♪
♪ MI ♪
♪ SOL ♪
♪ FA ♪
♪ MI... ♪
♪ SOL ♪
Teacher: YOU FORGOT SO SOON?
THREE, GO!
♪ DO ♪
♪ MI ♪
♪ SOL ♪
♪ LA ♪
♪ MI ♪
♪ DO ♪
♪ SOL ♪
♪ MI ♪
♪ DO ♪
♪ SOL ♪
♪ MI ♪
♪ DO, SOL, MI ♪
♪ SOL ♪
♪ DO ♪
Boy: BECAUSE NORTHEAST
IS SUCH A CLOISTERED,
SECLUDED PLACE.
IT IS.
THE POLICY OF NORTHEAST
IS TO AVOID CONTROVERSY
COMPLETELY.
Woman: MISERABLE ATTITUDE.
THERE ARE GOOD POINTS, MARK.
CAN'T YOU FIND ANYTHING
GOOD ABOUT THIS SCHOOL?
[ STUDENTS ALL TALKING AT ONCE ]
IT'S GOT LOTS OF ROOM,
EXCEPT NOT FOR AS MANY
KIDS AS ARE IN IT.
IT'S VERY NICE, WELL-VENTILATED.
[ STUDENTS LAUGHING ]
I CAN'T SAY ANYTHING
ABOUT THE PEOPLE
WHO GO TO IT, THOUGH, REALLY.
WITH VERY FEW EXCEPTIONS.
AND MOST OF THE PEOPLE I COULD
MAKE THOSE EXCEPTIONS ABOUT
ARE RIGHT IN THIS ROOM,
WITH MAYBE FIVE OR
SIX EXCEPTIONS.
AND THE REST OF THE SCHOOL
STINKS, IN MY ESTIMATION.
YOU KNOW, I'M NOT QUALIFIED
TO MAKE, YOU KNOW,
GIGANTIC JUDGMENTS
ABOUT THE SCHOOL,
BUT I THINK IN ITS
ATTITUDE TOWARDS EDUCATION
AND ITS RELATIONS
WITH THE WORLD TODAY,
THIS SCHOOL IS MISERABLE.
IT'S CLOISTERED, IT'S SECLUDED,
IT'S COMPLETELY SHELTERED
FROM EVERYTHING THAT'S
GOING ON IN THE WORLD.
AND I THINK IT'S WRONG,
IT HAS TO BE CHANGED,
AND I THINK THAT'S
OUR PURPOSE HERE.
AND NOT TO TALK ABOUT FILMS.
Woman: A LOT OF YOU
ARE SO NEGATIVE
THAT I CAN SEE SOMEDAY SOMEBODY
COMING OUT AND SAYING,
"YOU KNOW, YOU KIDS
JUST DON'T BELONG.
"YOU SPOIL NORTHEAST,
NORTHEAST HIGH WOULD
BE A NICE..."
Mark: THAT'S JUST WHAT HAPPENED.
MR. SIMON PULLED ME TO
HIS OFFICE AND SAID,
"YOU DON'T LOOK LIKE
A NORTHEASTER, SON.
YOU DON'T LOOK LIKE
A NORTHEASTER."
Man: I THINK ONE THING THAT
HAS TO BE CHANGED AROUND
IS THE FACT THAT YOU HAVE THESE,
SEE, LIKE, YOU HAVE THESE
VARIABLES EXISTING
WITHIN THE SCHOOL
SYSTEM IN NORTHEAST.
AND THE THING ABOUT IT
THAT MAKES IT SO ALIEN,
OR, FEEL TOWARDS US,
IS THE FACT THAT, UM,
YOU HAVE TO LIKE,
CONFORM TO THESE IDEAS
WHICH PEOPLE LIKE MR.
SIMON, DR. ALLEN...
Woman: WHY DO YOU PICK ON HIM...
ALL RIGHT, HE'S GOT PROBLEMS.
BUT I WOULD ALSO LIKE TO
SAY THAT THE SCHOOL...
I LIKE TO THINK THAT
HE IS IN A POSITION
WHERE MAYBE YOU'LL FIND SOME
OTHERS OF THE SAME OPINION.
THE ONLY DIFFERENCE IS, HE
HAS A JOB AS VICE PRINCIPAL
THAT IS IN CONTACT
WITH THE STUDENTS.
HE HANDLES THE
STUDENT ACTIVITIES.
NOW, I'M NOT SAYING THAT MR.
SIMON IS THE ONLY ONE
THAT SAYS THESE THINGS.
THE RULE IS FAIRLY, I
THINK YOU'LL AGREE,
CONSISTENT AMONG MANY
MEMBERS OF THE FACULTY.
AND DON'T JUST PINPOINT POOR MR.
SIMON.
HE MAY BE RIGHT,
HE MAY BE WRONG,
BUT HE'S THE ONE VOICING
IT ALL THE TIME,
BUT HE'S VOICING IT AS A
QUITE COMMON FEELING.
WELL, I'LL SAY SOMETHING
GOOD ABOUT THE SCHOOL.
I'LL SAY THAT SCIENTIFICALLY
AND TECHNOLOGICALLY,
NORTHEAST IS AN ADVANCED SCHOOL,
APART FROM OTHER HIGH
SCHOOLS IN THE COUNTRY.
A COMPLIMENT, I'M
GOING TO FAINT.
APART FROM OTHER HIGH
SCHOOLS IN THE COUNTRY,
POSSIBLY IN THE WORLD ALSO.
THIS SCHOOL, IN THAT
PARTICULAR FIELD,
IS THE LEADER.
AS MARK HAS SAID...
MORALLY, SOCIALLY,
THIS SCHOOL IS A GARBAGE
CAN, LET'S FACE THE FACTS.
Woman: MORALLY? COMPLETELY?
YES.
WELL, I VENTURE TO SAY
THAT THE MORAL PROBLEMS
YOU HAVE HERE, IN GENERAL,
ARE IN EXISTENCE
IN MOST SCHOOLS.
I DON'T THINK IT'S THAT BAD.
NOW, BOYS AND GIRLS, UH,
WE HAVE A VERY NEW PLAQUE
OUT IN THE HALL,
IF YOU'VE NOTICED,
OUTSIDE THE MAIN OFFICE,
FRAMED, WHICH HAS A SPECIAL
THOUGHT FOR THE DAY,
WRITTEN TO ATTRACT
YOUR ATTENTION,
AND I THINK IT'S VERY FINE.
BUT, AS ALWAYS, WE
HAVE ON OUR BULLETIN
ANOTHER THOUGHT FOR THE DAY,
AND THIS ONE, ESPECIALLY IN
MY FIELD, IS VERY IMPORTANT,
BUT IN ANY KIND OF RESEARCH,
TO HAVE THE RIGHT WORD
FOR WHAT YOU HAVE TO SAY
IN THESE DAYS TO EXPRESS THINGS
SO THAT PEOPLE DO NOT
MISUNDERSTAND YOU.
"THE DICTIONARY
IS THE ONLY PLACE
WHERE SUCCESS COMES
BEFORE WORK."
FOR THE TENTH- AND
ELEVENTH-GRADE BOYS
WHO SIGNED UP FOR FOODS
EXPERIENCES FOR BOYS,
YOU MUST GO TO
ROOM 130 THIS WEEK
TO VERIFY YOUR REGISTRATION.
THE SPECTATOR CLUB WILL DISCUSS
MARTIN LUTHER KING'S
ASSASSINATION
TODAY AT 3:15 IN ROOM 228.
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ]
[ BAND PLAYS ]
[ MUSIC STOPS ]
♪ NORTHEAST MAMBO ♪
♪ OLE, OLE ♪
♪ OLE, OLE ♪♪
AND IN GENERAL,
THE MORE A FELLOW GETS INTO BED
WITH MORE DIFFERENT GIRLS,
THE MORE INSECURE HE IS.
AND THIS SHOWS UP,
ACTUALLY, LATER,
IN ALL THE DIVORCE STATISTICS
AND IN THE MARITAL STATISTICS.
THE MORE INTERCOURSE
EITHER A BOY OR A GIRL
HAS HAD PRIOR TO MARRIAGE,
THE LESS LIKELY THEY ARE TO MAKE
SUCCESSFUL MARRIAGE PARTNERS,
HUSBANDS, WIVES,
AND THE GREATER...
IN OTHER WORDS, YOU CAN
GRAPH IT RIGHT ON A GRAPH.
THE MORE GIRLS A FELLOW
HAS GOTTEN INTO BED WITH,
OR VICE VERSA, THE
HIGHER THE DIVORCE RATE,
THE GREATER THE
SEXUAL INADEQUACY
AND THE FAILURE
OF COMPATIBILITY.
AS WITH ANYTHING ELSE, THE
REAL PROS IN THE FIELD
KEEP IT TO THEMSELVES
AND AREN'T PROFLIGATE.
"IS IT POSSIBLE TO
IMPREGNATE THE GIRL
BY RUBBING THE SURFACE
OF THE VAGINA?"
WITH WHAT, YOUR NOSE?
[ LAUGHTER ]
I MIGHT ADD...
THIS BRINGS UP ONE
OTHER GOOD POINT NOW.
THIS BRINGS UP ANOTHER
DARN GOOD POINT.
VIRGINITY IS A STATE OF MIND.
BY THAT, I HAVE
SEEN SEVERAL GIRLS
WHO HAVE BEEN PHYSIOLOGICALLY
OR BY PHYSICAL
EXAMINATION, VIRGINS.
THE HYMEN, THE MUCOUS
MEMBRANE COVERING,
THE SO-CALLED CHERRY...
IT'S CALLED THE CHERRY
BECAUSE IT PRODUCES RED
FLUID WHEN IT'S BUSTED...
[ LAUGHTER ]
IS INTACT.
I HAVE SEEN GIRLS WHOSE
HYMENS WERE SO SMALL
THAT I COULDN'T PASS A
FINGER THROUGH THEM.
IN FACT, I ONCE SAW A GIRL...
I HAPPEN TO BE A GYNECOLOGIST
AND GET PAID TO DO IT.
[ LAUGHTER ]
[ WHISTLING ]
I ONCE SAW A GIRL
WHO HAD RICKETS WHEN
SHE WAS A BABY,
WHOSE BONY STRUCTURE
WAS SO DEFORMED
THAT I COULD GET MY
FINGER IN THIS WAY,
BUT NOT BROAD-WAYS,
WHO HAS SUCCEEDED IN
BECOMING PREGNANT.
SPERM HAPPEN TO BE
VERY ACTIVELY MOTILE.
THEY HAVE A GOOD ABILITY
TO MOVE ON THEIR OWN.
AND MANY A GIRL HAS BECOME
PREGNANT THROUGH SPRAY.
IF YOU ARE NOT PREPARED
TO HANDLE THE RESPONSIBILITY
OF THAT GIRL'S BECOMING PREGNANT
AND HAVING A BABY,
YOU'VE GOT TWO CHOICES...
ONE, MAKE SURE THAT THERE'S
ADEQUATE PROTECTION
TO PREVENT HAVING A BABY.
TWO, IF THERE ISN'T, DON'T.
BECAUSE YOU ARE JUST
AS MUCH RESPONSIBLE,
IF NOT A LITTLE BIT
MORE, THAN THE GIRL
IF A PREGNANCY ENSUES.
NATURE SETS US UP
THAT THE MALE IS THE AGGRESSOR
AND THE FEMALE IS THE PASSIVE
IN THIS SET OF CIRCUMSTANCES.
IT TAKES A GIRL LONGER
TO GET SEXUALLY AROUSED
THAN IT DOES A BOY.
THIS IS THE NATURE OF THE BEAST.
Narrator: WE CAN GET A BETTER
IDEA OF THE RELATIONSHIP
OF THE FALLOPIAN
TUBES AND OVARIES
IF WE VIEW THEM FROM THE FRONT.
UNDER NORMAL CONDITIONS,
AN OVUM MATURES
IN THE OVARY,
THEN PASSES DOWN
THE FALLOPIAN TUBE
ON ITS WAY TO THE UTERUS.
WHEN GONORRHEA SPREADS UPWARD,
THE INFECTION CAN CAUSE DAMAGE
WHICH BLOCKS THE
FALLOPIAN TUBES,
SOMETIMES CAUSING
SEVERE COMPLICATIONS.
AS IN A BOY,
UNTREATED GONORRHEA CAN
MAKE A GIRL STERILE,
UNABLE TO BECOME A MOTHER.
HOWEVER, A GIRL WITH GONORRHEA
CAN BECOME A MOTHER,
BUT THIS CREATES
ANOTHER PROBLEM.
WHEN THE BABY IS
READY TO BE BORN,
THERE IS DANGER
THAT SHE MAY TRANSMIT THE
DISEASE TO THE CHILD
WHEN IT PASSES OUT OF HER BODY.
YOU DIDN'T GET HIT, HUH?
GOOD, GLAD TO SEE YOU.
YOU HAVE TO GO BACK?
WHEN DO YOU GET OUT?
I GET OUT SEPTEMBER '69.
THAT'S TERRIFIC. SEPTEMBER?
SEPTEMBER '60...
'69, I GET OUT WITH HALSIE.
IS HALSIE BACK?
YEAH, HE CAME BACK,
HE WAS WOUNDED.
I HEARD THAT. I DIDN'T SEE HIM.
I HEARD DAVE WAS WOUNDED ALSO.
SO ARE A LOT OF GUYS.
PEPPY GOT HURT.
PEPPY WAS SHOT UP PRETTY BAD.
PEPPY WAS ABOUT,
I GUESS ABOUT 5 YARDS
FROM ONE OF THEM MINES
IN ONE OF THOSE LITTLE
HOLES THEY DIG,
AND THEY POPPED UP WITH
AN AUTOMATIC RIFLE
ON HIM, OPENED UP,
REALLY GOT HIM IN THE FOOT
PRETTY BAD.
AND HE TURNED AROUND
AND HE KILLED THE GUY.
BUT HE'S DONE FOR SOCCER
OR ANYTHING LIKE THAT FOREVER.
HE CAN NEVER PLAY THAT AGAIN.
YEAH, HE WAS A GOOD
SOCCER PLAYER.
HE'S THROUGH WITH THAT.
AND FIRST, THEY THOUGHT
THEY MIGHT HAVE TO AMPUTATE.
BUT HE WAS DOWN AT
THE NAVAL HOSPITAL
FOR QUITE A LONG TIME,
AND THEN HE CAME UP WEARING,
WITH A CAST AND CRUTCHES,
AND THEN HE CAME UP WITH A CANE
THE NEXT TIME I SAW HIM.
THIS LAST TIME I SAW HIM,
HE WAS WALKING PRETTY WELL,
BUT HE'LL NEVER BE ABLE
TO HIT WITH THAT
FOOT OR ANYTHING
BECAUSE THEY ARE REBUILDING IT.
YEAH.
HE WAS PRETTY... THE
FIRST DAY BACK,
HE WAS PRETTY MELANCHOLY-LIKE,
AND NATURALLY SO,
BUT I THINK HE'S GOT
HIMSELF ADJUSTED NOW.
HE SEEMS TO BE ALL RIGHT,
I'M GLAD TO SAY.
I'M GLAD YOU DIDN'T GET HIT.
[ WHISTLE BLOWS ]
I GOT IT!
WHERE?
YOU'RE ALMOST THERE, JAN,
YOU HAVE 19 SECONDS, JAN.
18, 17, 16, 15,
14, 13, 12, 11,
10, 9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4, 3,
2, 1.
THAT'S IT.
YAY!
Man: JERRY, DISCONNECT AUDIO.
IS THE HATCH CLEAR?
THE HATCH IS CLEAR, YEAH.
ALL RIGHT, PULL.
HOW YOU DOING THERE?
YAY!
[ APPLAUSE ]
HEY, I RECOGNIZE YOU.
I GOT SOMETHING FOR YOU, MAN.
OH, THANKS.
GOOD GOING, MAN.
IT'S GOOD TO BE OUT HERE AGAIN.
HOW DO YOU FEEL?
GREAT.
YOU MADE IT.
WE ARE SO PROUD OF YOU.
GOT THE STRENGTH OF A BULL.
MR. GORDON, GOOD SEEING
YOU AGAIN, BOSS.
JAN, OH, YOU LOOK REALLY GOOD.
REAL GRIZZLY, JAN, REAL GRIZZLY.
AND MR. MONTGOMERY, HUG
ALL THREE OF THEM NOW.
I'M GOING TO HELP,
I'M GOING TO JUST
START GETTING THIS
THING OFF HIM, OKAY?
HEY, KID, I WANT TO
SEE THAT BEARD, MAN.
THE BEARD.
READY?
WAIT A MINUTE.
HERE COMES HIS HEAD.
HEY, THE BEARD.
YEAH, BUT I'LL
TALK TO YOU LATER.
GOOD JOB, JAN, REAL GOOD.
THANKS A LOT.
JAN.
HOLD ON, HOLD ON.
SCOTT, GOOD JOB.
THANK YOU.
DICK CASEY'S HERE.
HEY, SCOTT, MAN.
SCOTT, HOW YOU DOING?
SCOTT.
WE RECEIVED A TELEGRAM
THIS MORNING.
I WANT TO READ IT AT THIS TIME.
"STUDENTS AND FACULTY OF
NORTHEAST HIGH SCHOOL,
"ATTENTION: ROBERT MONTGOMERY.
"I SHOULD LIKE TO TAKE
THIS OPPORTUNITY TO EXTEND
"MY BEST WISHES TO EACH OF YOU
"FOR YOUR CONTINUED SUCCESS
WITH PROJECT SPARC.
"SPECIFICALLY MY HEARTIEST
CONGRATULATIONS
"TO ASTRONAUTS JAN GABIN,
HARVEY RUBIN, AND SCOTT CHERRY,
UPON COMPLETION OF 193 HOURS
OF SIMULATED FLIGHT."
THE TELEGRAM COMES FROM L.
GORDON COOPER,
NASA ASTRONAUT.
[ APPLAUSE ]
I'M GOING TO CRY.
I'M ALL MISTY, MAN.
GETTING ALL MISTY.
THIS IS MAN NUMBER ONE,
NUMBER TWO, NUMBER THREE, OKAY?
GET A LITTLE CLOSER.
Woman: HEY, HOW ARE YOU?
Man: GOOD MORNING, HOW ARE YOU?
Boy: RUBIN, HEY.
SCOTT.
DRUMS.
ROLL.
[ DRUMS BEAT ]
[ PLAYING "HEY, LOOK ME OVER" ]
NOW, LET ME READ YOU THIS ONE...
IF I'M ABLE TO GET THROUGH IT.
THIS IS WRITTEN FROM...
AND I MIGHT SAY THAT
THE LETTER I'M ABOUT TO
READ IS FROM BOB WALTERS.
BOB WALTERS, AS FRAN
COULD TELL YOU...
SHE COULD WRITE HIS BIOGRAPHY...
WAS A BOY WITHOUT PARENTS WHO
MIGHT HAVE BEEN A NOBODY.
HE CERTAINLY WAS NOT A
HIGH ACADEMIC STUDENT.
HE WAS MOST AVERAGE OR
SUB-AVERAGE IN MANY WAYS.
BUT A FEW TEACHERS WHO CARED...
MADE A GREAT DIFFERENCE
IN THIS BOY'S LIFE.
HIS LETTER COMES ON STATIONERY
MARKED "USSOKINAWA."
I HOPE I CAN GET THROUGH IT.
IF I DON'T, HY,
YOU'LL HAVE TO GO ON.
DEAR DR. HALLER,
I HAVE ONLY A FEW
HOURS BEFORE I GO.
TODAY I WILL TAKE A PLANE
TRIP FROM THIS SHIP.
I PRAY THAT I'LL MAKE IT BACK,
BUT IT IS ALL IN
GOD'S HANDS NOW.
YOU SEE, I AM GOING
WITH THREE OTHER MEN.
WE ARE GOING TO BE DROPPED
BEHIND THE DMZ... THE
DEMILITARIZED ZONE.
THE REASON FOR
TELLING YOU THIS IS
THAT ALL MY INSURANCE MONEY
WILL BE GIVEN FOR
THAT SCHOLARSHIP
I ONCE STARTED BUT
NEVER FINISHED
IF I DON'T MAKE IT BACK.
I AM ONLY INSURED FOR $10,000.
MAYBE IT COULD HELP SOMEONE.
I HAVE BEEN TRYING TO BECOME
A BIG BROTHER IN VIETNAM,
BUT IT IS VERY HARD TO DO.
I HAVE TO WRITE BACK AND FORTH
TO SAN DIEGO, CALIFORNIA,
AND THAT TAKES TIME.
I ONLY HOPE THAT I AM GOOD
ENOUGH TO BECOME ONE.
GOD ONLY KNOWS.
I REALLY PRAY THAT THE YOUNG
MEN IN YOUR COOKING CLASSES
WILL USE THIS CHANGE
OF LEARNING VERY WELL.
THANK YOU, DR. HALLER,
FOR HELPING THESE MEN BECOME
GOOD, VERY FINE COOKS.
HE SHOULD HAVE SAID,
"THANK YOU, MRS. C."
MY PERSONAL FAMILY USUALLY
DOESN'T UNDERSTAND ME.
THEY DON'T UNDERSTAND WHY I
HAVE TO DO WHAT I DO DO.
THEY SAY THAT I'M A REAL
NUT TO DO SUCH WORK,
BUT...
THUS THEY SAY,
"DON'T YOU VALUE LIFE?
ARE YOU CRAZY?"
MY ANSWER IS... "YES.
"BUT I VALUE ALL THE
LIVES OF SOUTH VIETNAM
"AND THE FREE WORLD
SO THAT THEY AND ALL OF
US CAN LIVE IN PEACE."
AM I WRONG, DR. HALLER?
IF I DO MY BEST ALL THE TIME
AND BELIEVE IN WHAT I DO,
BELIEVE THAT WHAT I DO IS RIGHT,
THAT IS ALL I CAN DO.
DR. HALLER, IF ANYTHING
HAPPENS TO ME,
JAMES C. HECKWICKER...
I THINK IT IS...
WILL SEND YOU A TELEGRAM,
AND IN TIME, HE WILL
SEND YOU THE MONEY.
PLEASE DON'T SAY ANYTHING TO MRS.
C....
BUT I DID.
SHE WOULD ONLY WORRY OVER ME.
I AM NOT WORTH IT.
I AM ONLY A BODY DOING A JOB.
IN CLOSING, I THANK EVERYONE
FOR WHAT THEY ALL
HAVE DONE FOR ME.
YOURS TRULY, BOB WALTERS.
THANK YOU ALL AGAIN VERY MUCH.
PLEASE FORGIVE MY HANDWRITING.
I AM A LITTLE JUMPY.
PLEASE UNDERSTAND.
NOW, WHEN YOU GET A
LETTER LIKE THIS,
TO ME, IT MEANS
THAT WE ARE VERY SUCCESSFUL
AT NORTHEAST HIGH SCHOOL.
I THINK YOU WILL AGREE WITH ME.