HIGH AND LOW
What brings you here?
National Shoes is in business
to make money.
Take a look at this shoe.
Will it increase our sales?
Wait.
We're not losing money.
It's a good shoe, but it
costs too much.
Old-fashioned too.
And another thing.
It's too durable. Shoes
must wear out.
Shoes are accessories, like
hats and handbags.
Women want new styles at
moderate prices.
Right.
Our shoes are practical...
but hats don't wear long.
Shoes shouldn't either.
I don't agree with you.
Hats are decoration.
Shoes carry all your
body weight.
You win.
You may be satisfied with
this kind of shoe...
but sales have been flat
for a whole year.
That's why we're here.
What do you want me to do?
Let me be Frank.
We are the directors
of our firm.
I'm in charge of sales, you,
the factory...
Ishimaru, design, Kamiya,
publicity.
Kawanishi's your top aide...
and a future executive.
We're all agreed on what
our problem is.
What is it?
Our president.
The Old Man's backward. Army
boots are more his style.
But he owns enough stock to tell
all of us what to do.
By the way...
Take a look at this design.
It's a sure winner.
Good work.
And it can be made at
half the cost.
Well?
What would the Old Man say?
Who cares?
He owns a lot of stock, but
we can join together.
He has 25%.
You have only 21%.
You can't vote him out.
Gondo, you own stock too, and
we're counting on you.
How about joining us?
With your 13%, we'd have 34%.
We could out-vote
the old mule.
And who'd be the new
president?
Well, you'd be in the running.
But as the new policy is
Baba's idea...
he'll be the next president.
You, executive director.
Fair enough?
The Old Man may be
old-fashioned...
but he makes real shoes.
Yours are trash.
Listen.
I came to work at National Shoes
when I was 16.
I've been in that factory
for 30 years.
I know every sound and
smell there.
I remember every shoe
ever made...
all good, durable shoes.
I can't put our name on junk.
This wouldn't last a month.
There's no shank in it.
A cardboard base.
No sewing.
It's just glued together.
You want money for this?
The costs!
The profits!
- Business is business!
- I know.
But this business is my
life and love.
I can't do this.
So you'll make the Old Ma's
army boots?
No. The Old Man is wrong.
He's wrong. We're wrong.
Who's right?
I'll make my ideal shoes
durable, yet stylish.
Expensive to make, maybe...
but profitable in the long run.
How romantic. Only we
won't let you.
If we vote with the boss, we
can force you out.
Go ahead. The shareholder's
meeting is next month.
The gentlemen are leaving.
See them out.
You're leaving already?
Mrs. Gondo.
Isn't my husband seeing
you out?
What happened between
you and them?
Nothing.
Didn't look that way.
Don't worry. You wouldn't
understand.
It's business.
Business. That's what you
always say.
What's his game?
You're his right-hand man.
You must know.
He's confident enough to
throw us out.
What is he up to?
Why didn't you ask him?
Don't be sarcastic.
If you help us stop him...
We'll make you a director.
Don't tempt me.
You want to be his flunky forever?
Think it over.
Stop it, Jun!
They're furious.
Are we safe?
Wait and see.
Trouble again?
Looks like it.
They want to kick me out,
but I've taken steps.
- They'll have to be big steps.
- How?
Wait till it's all set.
Then I'll kick them out.
He takes after you.
He likes violent games.
Jun!
Oh, it's you, Shinichi.
I'm the sheriff now.
Jun, is it your turn to be
the outlaw?
Then don't run. Hide and
ambush the sheriff.
A man's got to attack or be
attacked.
Go on, and win.
It's getting worse.
Your attitude.
Success isn't worth losing
your humanity.
What do you know about it?
I just want to make good shoes.
Yes, it is.
Osaka Hotel?
You called Osaka?
One moment.
Room 310, please.
Gondo calling.
Hello, it's me. How did it go?
All settled?
How much? Within my limit?
Good work!
Yes, settle it.
Right away.
Say I'll send the deposit
tonight.
Call me back.
I'm counting you.
I want you to go to Osaka.
Book a fligth.
Use the other phone. I'm
waiting for a call.
Is everything all right?
I'm frightened.
Hello. It's me.
So it's all set?
Just a moment.
10:00 p.m. Plane.
Kawanishi's off at 10:00 with a
check for 50 million.
Now a toast!
I kept it a secret, but now
I can tell you.
My share isn't 13%.
I've bought 15% more over
the last three years...
and I just arranged
for 19% more.
Even with the Old Man, they're
46% to my 46%.
It's a gamble, but National
shoes is mine.
How did you raise the money?
I borrowed on everything,
even this house.
Raising 50 million was rough.
One yen less... and Osaka
would have refused.
I've bet my whole fortune
on this.
Wait. This is just the deposit,
isn't it?
It's only a third. What about
the other 100 million?
If I have control of the firm,
I'll get the rest.
Too big a surprise?
Have a drink.
Excuse me.
Is my boy, Shinichi, here?
He's outside with Jun. Why?
I brought him this.
I'll call Jun.
Aoki, drive Kawanishi
to the airport.
10:00 flight.
Yes, this is Gondo.
What? You... You have kidnapped
my son?
Stop joking!
I'm not joking.
Listen. I have your son.
Do as I say, and he'll be safe.
Get 30 million yen.
What?
No consecutive numbers.
Wait.
One thousand...
10,000-yen notes...
three thousand 5,000-yen
notes...
and five thousand 1,000-yen
notes.
Total: 30 million yen.
Have it ready by tomorrow.
Then we'll talk again.
If you love your son, don't
call the police.
No, of course not.
Good-bye, Mr. Gondo.
30 million yen? Please get
Jun back. Hurry!
Keep calm.
I'll get him back, no matter
what it costs.
I'll raise more money later.
I'll call the police.
No! You want Jun to be killed?
Don't worry. It'll be all right.
Did you call me, Mom?
What's the matter?
What is this? A practical joke?
Jun, where's Shinichi?
I hid like you said, but he never
came. Some sheriff!
Shinichi was wearing
Jun's outfit.
Even I got them mixed up.
Shinichi!
Call the police.
No! The kidnapper might
hurt him.
A chauffeur can't pay ransom.
He'll let him go.
But I won't let him get away
with this.
The police?
No, a department store
delivery.
Odd at this hour.
What's keeping the police?
Don't worry. Your son's safe.
He has to be.
It's the police.
Would you please close
all the drapes?
I'm Chief Inspector Tokura.
From down there, if he's got
a telescope...
the kidnapper can see this
entire room.
- Any more phones?
- One upstairs.
- Listed?
- Just this one.
Here's the phone.
We'll get ready to
tap his calls.
Only he may not
call again.
Not if he finds out.
He may still think he
has your son.
Broadcast the mistake on
radio and TV.
Then he'll know you've
notified us.
So?
He warned you he'd
kill the boy.
He thought the had
my son.
He has to return him.
You think so, but the kidnapper
may not.
Kidnapping cases are hard.
His protection is the hostage.
On our way here the
Chief told us...
"Save the child first, then
catch the kidnapper."
And this time we must be
especially careful.
They usually ask 200,000.
The highest was two million.
30 million is an incredible
ransom.
The kidnapper's extreme, maybe
mentally disturbed.
You're the boy's father?
A widower. It's his only
child too.
You'll find him.
We'll do our best.
What will you do?
Wait for his next move.
It's all we can do.
It's an ordeal for you...
but safest for the boy.
All ready.
Have the telephone company
trace all calls here.
Where's your son, Mrs. Gondo?
Inside.
Ask him what happened before
and after the kidnapping.
Wait. Nakao, you go.
Taguchi might frighten
the boy.
You talk to the father.
Do you have a recent photo?
Yes. I'll get it.
It's time to drive Mr. Kawanishi
to the airport.
You're in no shape to go.
Take a cab.
Wait. It may be the
kidnapper.
Upstairs phone.
Keep him talking. Maybe we
can trace him.
Hello. Gondo speaking.
I got the wrong boy.
Don't celebrate yet. Listen.
I don't care whose boy it is.
You're paying.
Why me?
Don't ask.
Just pay up, or he dies.
Understand?
Absurd.
Exactly. It's absurd.
The wrong boy's a lucky
break for me.
Extortion can only be threats...
against a person or his kin.
So I can't be charged
with extortion.
But you have to pay anyway.
You're a fool to pay,
but you must.
Who says I'll pay?
I absolutely will not.
You will.
You won't kill him. You don't
have the guts, Mr Gondo.
A fiend.
Smartest crook I ever saw.
He could kidnap any child...
and ask ransom for anyone.
And it's not extortion.
Not kidnapping for gain
Simple kidnapping. He'd get only
five years at most.
This is no joke.
It's absurd. He can't get
away with it.
It's not just moneyche wants
from me.
He wants me to be humiliated,
to suffer.
Forcing me to throw away my
hard earned money.
He wants to laugh at me.
I won't let him.
I won't pay him.
I'll tell him so next time.
No ransom. Never!
Ow! That hurts.
Put him to bed.
I'm not sleepy. I'll wait
for Shinichi.
He understands what's happened.
He feels responsible for it.
I feel the same way.
No one's responsible.
The man is a maniac.
But Shinichi was kidnapped
in place of your son.
Then you think the ransom
should be paid?
You know the position
Mr. Gondo is in.
But he was willing to pay
for his own son.
Said he could raise more
money later.
How? From where?
He's mortgaged everything.
He can't raise more money
to save his own life.
Giving 30 million to a madman.
Stop it!
Let's go to bed.
But I...
Come on.
Time for bed.
Inspector.
Can you promise the boy's safety
if Mr. Gondo pays?
The boy may be dead
by now.
Or he may be killed
afterwards.
What's the sense
in paying?
But if he is still alive,
we can still hope.
What will the kidnapper do
if he isn't paid?
Would he kill the boy?
From the way he talks, he
seems intelligent.
I don't think he'd risk capital
punishment.
He may be intelligent, but he's
not a rational person.
His plan is so cruel, he
must be sick.
We must believe he'll
carry it through.
If he's paid, he'll return the
boy as he said.
If not, he said he'd kill
him, didn't he?
It's a vicious case.
I'll ask the Chief for a special
investigation.
See what you can find
out here.
Mr. Gondo, call us before you
answer the phone.
What about me? Am I going
to Osaka or not?
If I am, I'd better hurry.
Why are you hesitating?
It's very clear.
Pay ransom and we're ruined.
That's all there is to it.
Go.
I'm going, no matter who's
calling.
All right, go.
No Kawanishi, wait!
Inspector!
Keep him talking. We need
more than last time.
Upstairs phone okay?
Hello. This is Gondo.
The boy's fine. I'll let him
talk to you.
Daddy? Are you there?
Shinichi!
Whether he lives or dies...
depends on you.
Good night, Mr. Gondo.
He got away again.
Please save my son!
I couldn't ask you before to
pay all that money.
But now I've heard his voice...
and I must.
Please save him!
Once he's safe, the police will
get your money back.
Please lend it to me!
I'll do everything you want
till the day I die.
I'll make my son work too.
Stop it. Stand up. Damn it,
stand up.
Please save him!
Stand up, I said!
I want to pay, but I can't.
You don't understand.
I'm going.
Wait.
Get up. Please get up.
He won't let your son die.
I'll reason with him too.
It'll be all right.
Isn't Shinichi back yet?
Go to Osaka tomorrow.
Postpone it!
Then I'll return this.
Excuse me. I'm tired.
Please close the curtains.
Sorry.
You slept here?
No, the Bos'n and I...
Bos'n?
The Bos'n is head of
our squad.
A lot of our work is connected
with the harbor.
"Bos'n" fits him.
A real slave driver.
Dragging me out all night.
You dragged me out.
Scaling walls...
and hiding in shadows
like thieves.
The Chief has set up a
special section.
We can use the whole
police force.
The kidnapper says he isn't
extorting money...
but he's driven you into a corner
and demands ransom.
The department says that's
"kidnapping for gain."
It's a maximum 15 years
imprisonment.
That doesn't help me.
His deadline is today.
I thought it over all night.
This is my decision.
The boy's father wants me to
lend him the money.
He says once his boy's safe...
you'll get my money back.
But even if you guarantee it...
I won't pay any ransom.
I'd get it back too late.
Without that money now,
I'll lose everything.
Please understand me.
My work is part of me. Without it,
I'd be dead.
You may say I'm callous, but
won't pay the ransom.
It's not true.
I know he'll pay it.
I won't.
I can't.
I told you why last night.
You know what'll happen
if I pay?
I'll be bankrupt.
They'll force me out on
the street.
You'll be all right.
You can start over.
What do you know
about poverty?
A big house, fancy clothes
and fine food.
That's been your life.
I could start over, but
you can't.
Yes, I can. I don't want luxury.
It's all you've ever known.
That's why you can say,
"Pay the 30 million".
It doesn't mean anything to you.
You're spoiled.
It's not that.
Can't you see how the boy's
father feels?
Yes! I can't stand his
groveling.
Look, I'd pay if I could.
But I can't just think
about him!
There's you and Jun and my
own survival.
It's ridiculous!
Plenty of men richer than me.
And at a time like this.
It would be suicide for me to pay.
Why should I?
I know.
But it can't be helped.
Aoki has no choice but
to ask you.
I'm asking too.
So is Jun.
Enough! I'm not paying, no
matter who asks me.
I'm not paying any ransom.
Just in time. Take this check
and get to Osaka.
I've been thinking it over.
What?
About that check.
Whether I should take it or not.
You told me not to hesitate.
Well, I was wrong.
If I went to Osaka and
closed this deal...
you'd control the firm.
But you'd be hated for
sacrificing a child.
You'd be ruined. No one would
buy your shoes.
You're not paid to think!
Take this and go.
No. Think about it.
Think of Mrs. Gondo.
You got started on her dowry.
She has a say in this, and
she wants to pay.
And ruin myself?
I know how much this money
means to you...
but a life means more.
A helpless child!
A helpless child, eh?
Sounds odd coming from you.
What happened to the cold-blooded
businessman?
When were you reborn?
What happened after you
left last night?
Nothing. I just...
If I succeed, you'll be
an executive.
You know that, so you were
ready to go last night...
arguing with anyone who
stood in your way.
But not today.
Is it sabotage?
No. I just...
If I pay the ransom, there's
no deal.
You want that?
What are you up to?
Shall I tell you?
If the deal fails, I fail, and
three men celebrate.
You sold me to those three,
didn't you?
Yes.
- The Osaka deal?
- Everything.
Scum!
All right, but let me
have my say.
You weakened last night...
enough to pay the ransom.
What would happen to me then?
You'd be selling me.
I had to protect myself.
- Get out!
- I'll go.
But you'll go next.
Baba and the Old Man are
talking right now.
But I still have the money.
I'll throw all out.
I wonder.
Maybe the kidnapper's right.
You don't have the guts.
Get out!
Mr. Gondo...
I know it's late to be
saying this...
but you have the right to
protect your own life.
It's our duty to help you.
We want to save the child...
but not by sacrificing you.
But we hope you'll do this:
When the kidnapper calls,
say you'll pay.
That's all.
Ask him when and where.
We'll take it from there.
I'm sorry. I didn't know what
I was asking.
Please don't worry about
my son.
The kidnapper was just
bluffing, that's all.
No human being could kill
an innocent child.
Anyway, Shinichi is a
smart boy.
He'll watch for his chance
to escape.
Where's Gondo?
Mr. Gondo!
Phone! Hurry!
Hello. This is Gondo.
You're not up to any tricks,
are you?
What do you mean?
Drapes closed in broad daylight.
First time.
- You can see us?
- Very well.
You're on a hilltop.
It's hot as hell down here.
An inferno. 105 degrees.
But you're air-conditioned,
aren't you?
I understand the closed windows,
but why the drapes?
What are you up to?
Nothing.
Nothing?
People who are up to
something say that.
I'll open the drapes then.
Good. I can see you now.
Your wife, the chauffeur...
Only three, including you?
Yes.
Let's talk, then.
Have you decided to pay,
Mr. Gondo?
I have no choice.
And is the money ready?
By evening, but only if the
boy's all right.
- You heard him.
- I want to see him.
- Lf I refuse?
- I won't pay.
It sounds fishy.
I'll think it over, Mr. Gondo.
Stay there!
The kidnapper's watching.
Damn. A little longer, and I
could've traced the call.
Thank you, Mr. Gondo.
By talking like that, you bought
us more time.
Your demand was very helpful.
We can start moving.
Bank of Tokyo?
It's Gondo. The branch
manager, please.
Gondo speaking.
Send over 30 million
yen in cash.
No new bills and no consecutive
numbers.
One thousand 10,000 notes...
Three thousand 5,000 notes...
and five thousand 1,000 notes.
Yes, right away.
Stop it.
I don't know what to say.
Then don't say it.
Leave me alone.
- What is it?
- Mom's crying.
Hello. This is Gondo.
You're not up to any tricks,
are you?
I hear a coin dropping.
Check all the pay phones
in this area.
The kidnapper's right. One case
holds 15 million yen.
What a sight, eh?
Hello. This is Gondo.
Got the money?
Yes, but...
All right. You'll see
the boy first.
- When?
- Tomorrow.
We'll swap the boy
and the money.
Where?
Calm down and
listen carefully.
Get two briefcases under 7 cm,
thick for the money.
Close them tight, but don't
lock them.
Take them on tomorrow's
second bullet train.
- Understood? That's all.
- But where to?
Get on and you'll see,
Mr. Gondo.
He's much too smart to plan
to trade on the train.
At a station?
That's risky too.
I wouldn't do it.
Two cases under 7 cm.
Thick.
I wonder why.
"Get on and you'll see".
Say, Bos'n, where can we hide
these inside the cases?
Can't take chances. I'll call
a professional.
What do we need?
We want to find him through
these brief cases.
We purposely chose
unusual ones.
They're so conspicuous, he'll
have to get rid of them.
He'll bury, sink, or burn them.
If it gets wet...
this powder gives off a
nasty smell.
If this burns, it emits a
pink smoke.
Not much hope...
but it just might give
us a lead.
Reiko!
My old tool bag. Would you
find it for me?
If we record only the 1,000s,
will we make it?
We can do ten a minute, 5,000
in 500 minutes.
That's eight hours, 20 minutes.
Tem hours with coffee breaks.
A waste of time. I never
notice numbers.
We can't neglect any
possibility.
When the boy's back, I'll flush
that rat out.
I'd burn him alive.
Fifteen years isn't enough.
The capsule should go here...
and the powder there.
In the old days, shoemakers
made cases too.
My apprentice days come
in handy again.
Starting all over already.
That Gondo is all right.
Usually, I waste no love
on the rich.
I didn't like him at first.
Excuse me.
"The boy's not on the train."
This isn't a pleasure trip.
Railway telephone service...
paging Mr. Kingo Gondo
of national shoes.
Please take your call in the...
buffet car phone booth.
- That's him.
- What do we do?
The next stop is Atami.
Go have coffee.
Coffee.
We just passed Kozu.
Perfect.
You're about to cross the
Sakawa River.
He'll be at the foot
of the bridge.
Coffee.
The boy's at the bridge.
I'm supposed to toss
the money.
These windows don't open.
He said the washroom window
opens seven cms.
Damn it. Of course.
There's no stop before Atami.
He'll get away clean.
Damned clever. The wretch!
Na emergency stop would
endanger the boy.
He's got us on every angle.
But he can't do this alone.
He's got help.
We'll be able to see them.
Where's the boy?
- Left side.
- Toss the cases here?
Yes, washroom window.
We'll look for the boy
from here.
Split up for pictures.
Still shots on the left and 8mm
front and rear.
The bridge is coming up. Take a
good look at the boy.
It could be a switch.
I don't know him.
I'm trading my life.
I won't make a mistake.
Shinichi!
You're sure?
Now go get him.
For Mr. Gondo's sake, be
bloodhounds.
Can you see the living room?
This is the best view so far.
The criminal knows this
area well.
But would he use a phone
this close?
Try the next one.
The kidnapper's right.
That house gets to you.
As if it's looking down at us.
"Kidnapper Uses Bullet Train
To Get Ransom"
"Company Executive Throws
Fortune Out Train Window"
"Police Force Mobilized In Bizarre
Kidnapping Case"
The police say money is not the
kidnapper's only motive.
There's a taunting attitude
in his phone calls...
as if he has an extreme
hatred for Mr. Gondo.
Apparently, the kidnapper
seeks...
to torment Mr. Gondo.
The public is aware of Mr.
Gondo's sacrifice...
and sympathy has grown...
to national acclaim for him.
As for the kidnapper...
if he is listening, I'd like
to say this:
You've made a hero of
Mr. Gondo.
We learned from Shinichi...
that a woman held him.
Hats hid the faces...
of the man and woman...
but you may recognize
their movements.
Watch carefully.
Any idea as to who they may be?
Don't hesitate to tell us.
Grocer's boy, milkman...
junk man, salesman.
Recall everyone who comes here.
It may suddenly strike you.
Take your time.
They're good films...
but not much help yet.
The figure is blurred in the
pictures, but it's helpful.
Look at this.
It's the accomplice.
See this? It's a farmer
with a cow.
This gives us information.
A man with two bags ran
into the shadow...
then a car left.
We checked and found
car tracks.
He bumped into a wall.
We found bits of paint.
We had them checked with
the following results:
The car's a gray Toyopet Crown,
59 model.
This is the car you rode in,
isn't it?
Yes.
- Can I go?
- Yes.
Shinichi, try to remember.
You saw Mt. Fuji and the sea?
What road did the car
take to the river?
- I don't remember.
- Don't say that!
What did you see from
the car window?
Lots of things.
That won't do!
You must remember.
What did you see?
Stop.
When you remember, tell us.
We know how you feel.
We feel the same way.
We're desperate to get
Mr. Gondo's money back.
We can't let him lose it.
Guests, sir.
Go easier on the boy,
Mr. Aoki.
Excuse me.
He's remembered some
important things.
They covered his nose with
gauze soaked in ether.
He saw Mt. Fuji and the sea.
That's all today.
Oh, yes. We've received a
mountain of mail.
Mr. Gondo is hard pressed...
but everyone admires him.
Makes us feel better about
this case.
You're a hero. The public is
very sympathetic.
But what about national shoes?
The struggle for power
isn't pretty.
We hear your position is shaky.
Is it true?
Frankly, we're worried.
Sympathy costs nothing...
but we've invested money.
We're your biggest creditors...
so we got together.
We're returning the interest
you sent...
to postpone paying us
the principal.
Pay us when it falls due...
or we'll attach your property.
You can't pay a kidnapper...
and not pay us.
The house can be seen...
from Nishi-ku and Naka-ku...
but in some places...
trees or buildings block
the view.
These places are filled in
with hatch lines.
From inside this circle...
the living room can be seen...
with an ordinary telescope.
It can also be seen...
from seven booths here.
Each mark indicates a
phone booth.
The best view...
is from these three booths.
We think the suspect used
one of these phones.
He also said it was hot
where he was.
He called a little before
9:00 a.m.
Which booths does the sun
shine on at that hour?
Of the three...
this one is shaded.
So we can assume...
He used one of the other two.
It seems...
he always watched them
with a telescope.
So we can narrow down
where he lives...
to this vicinity.
Judging from his voice, he
seems young.
But with the boy...
he wore a mask and dark
glasses.
Next, a report on the phone
call to the train.
You can only call the train...
from Tokyo, Osaka, or Nagoya.
It's relayed by microwave...
but with a long delay.
So we found where he was:
Yuraku-cho, Tokyo.
Near the railroad station.
But the shop woman had bad
eyes and worse hearing...
so we gave up.
We asked at the shops
around there.
But no one remembered a man...
phoning there at that hour.
Next.
The boy mentioned Mt Fuji
and the sea.
Any leads?
He drew a picture.
The call was only local
long distance.
A nearby spot...
Where you can see Mt. Fuji
and the sea...
has to be around Kamakura.
A setting sun, maybe.
It looks that way all
along the coast.
Next, the ether.
It's hard to trace.
Druggists don't carry it.
Hospitals and doctors get
it wholesale.
But ether is used in
industry too.
So we can't be sure...
the suspect is in medicine.
In industry...
it's used by shipbuilders and
auto manufacturers...
and by small iron works...
and repair shops too.
Next, the car.
The farmer said it was
a gray car.
It was probably stolen.
I asked Vehicle Theft to check.
This month, 18 Toyopets
were stolen.
But before this case came up,
12 were found.
That leaves six still around, and
only one is gray.
And it was stolen the day before
this case broke.
The license number...
is Kanagawa 3059.
But the plates may have
been changed.
Vehicle Theft is making a
through search.
All right. Next, the 1,000-yen
notes.
We made copies of the
numerical lists...
for tobacco shops, cafes, and
movie theaters.
They're helping out of sympathy
for Mr. Gondo...
but none of the notes has
turned up yet.
Next, reports from the public.
We've received 1,305 reports
of sightings.
Almost all from genuinely
concerned citizens
All reported seeing men with
boys Shinichi's age.
But half the sightings were before
he was kidnapped...
or after he was found.
And he was seen simultaneously...
in many different places.
Still, we're checking.
Today we heard...
from a turnpike toll collector
About 7:00p. M,
a man with dark glasses
drove up.
A boy was sleeping under
a blanket...
on the back seat.
The car was dark. He couldn't
see his face...
but he did see a toy rifle and
a cowboy hat.
He took the seaside turnoff.
This could be our man.
We're rechecking all reports
from that area.
Next, the bullet train.
It isn't that different from other
express trains.
He knows every detail of it...
but that may not mean...
he's a railroad man.
But we checked...
the bullet train personnel...
who were absent that day...
or who had quit recently.
There were very few.
I'll have all the data soon.
Next, grudges or other motives.
I saw the executives at
National Shoes.
What a gruesome lot.
A grudge?
Do you think...
we were behind the kidnapping?
Absurd.
We went to join forces with him.
What a narrow escape.
Until Kawanishi told us,
we had no idea.
Served him right.
He tried to buy up enough stock
to gain control...
and then this happened.
Poetic justice, huh?
It's not that I doubt you...
but you've known Mr. Gondo
a long time.
I just wondered...
if anyone held a grudge
against him.
Anyone?
You couldn't count them all.
One more question.
The kidnapping occurred just
after you left his home.
Did you notice anything
near the gate?
A car, for instance...
or a suspicious-Iooking man?
We'd just been thrown out.
We weren't admiring the view.
They were no help.
But at the factory...
Mr. Gondo has a temper that
sure can rip into you.
But he keeps na eye on the
work, all right.
A fine boss to good workers.
No one here...
holds a grudge against him...
except maybe the front office.
I don't think anyone holds a
grudge against Mr. Gondo.
Except the big shots.
They'd decorate the kidnapper.
Your blood pressure, Taguchi.
Now for the results of
our meeting.
Inspector Tokura.
So far, this case sounds almost
impossible to break.
But we've got to find that
"almost".
Follow every lead through to
the bitterest end.
And when you're worn out
and discouraged...
think of Mr. Gondo's pain.
Take the boy...
and drive to the shore
tomorrow.
Find this "Fuji and the sea"
scene.
If you can jog his memory, you
may find the hideout.
Division three.
Hello. Tokura speaking.
We'll be there right away.
Don't touch anything.
They found the car.
Abandoned on a highway.
Get the lab.
Have more men sleep
over here...
the rest on call.
Mud-spattered, but there's
been no rain lately.
It's dust that settled on
drops of water.
What's this?
- What's wrong?
- Listen to this!
Hello. This is Gondo.
The boy's fine. I'll let him
talk to you.
Daddy? Are you there?
Hear that? A trolley.
So?
A trolley runs near the
hideout.
Three different trolley lines...
run through Kamakura.
Maybe a specialist can tell
which streetcar it is.
I'm on my way.
An Enoshima trolley?
Absolutely. I live near there.
I've heard that sound...
a million times.
It's an old single-wire trolley.
Only the Enoshima line uses
those old lines.
There are lots of curves...
and the rails are narrow.
The wheel base is short, so it
makes that noise.
Thanks.
Is Mr. Aoki in?
I'm sorry. He's out.
At your husband's office?
No.
Where?
He took Shinichi in the car.
He wants to make him remember.
He's a nuisance.
He just felt he had to do
something.
You were let out here?
We came that way.
Good. You look out the back.
Tell me if you remember
anything.
Now what?
We can't move without the boy.
Aoki will go to the
Sakawa River.
Let's follow him.
Daddy!
What? Remember something?
I peed there.
We'll find Aoki's car and
get the boy.
Wait, bos'n.
The lab says...
there's fish oil and blood...
bonito and mackerel scales
on the stolen car.
It must have gone through a
puddle of refuse...
from a fish market.
The Koshigoe market is the only
one near that trolley.
Got it.
We get bonito and mackerel
around here
And other types of fish...
come by truck from Tokyo.
Thanks. Where does the
trolley run?
Under the cliff.
Does it look like this from
up there?
Let's see.
You should see Enoshima
Island from there...
a little more to the right,
near the station.
With that cape in front, it must
look like this.
You saw Enoshima Island?
You must have.
We didn't come this way.
Bos'n, I feel we're getting
closer.
Up there. Try no to look
like a cop.
Okay, but you'll need plastic
surgery not to.
Daddy! I saw this tunnel!
You passed here?
Which way?
From there.
Here, Shinichi?
Look.
Enoshima doesn't look
like an Island.
Let's go back to Koshigoe.
They'll have Aoki by now.
The boy will show us that
hideout.
We'll raid tonight.
Got your pistol?
I'm not going after a madman
with my bare hands.
Let's look around on foot.
That car!
It's Gondo's.
Don't be stupid. Stop playing
detective.
When I got the car out this
morning, he said...
"Aoki, we aren't going to the
factory anymore".
He was smiling...
but I know how he felt inside.
Those executives are cruel...
but it's really my fault.
But you can't walk around
here with the boy.
What if the kidnapper saw him?
Bos'n! He's gone!
Daddy!
Here it is!
They're asleep.
Take the boy away.
They're dead.
The inspector will explain.
Yes, but we're asking you
not to print it.
The accomplices...
a man and a woman, were
found dead.
Heroin overdose.
Suicide?
I'll explain.
Their arms were covered with
needle marks.
Both were advanced cases
of drug addiction.
It's unlikely they'd make
a mistake...
in the dosage.
And dealers don't sell heroin
that pure anyway.
They died in bed.
Near their pillows...
were two empty packets
and syringes...
and a cup for dissolving
the heroin.
There were two more used
packets nearby.
So they had four...
and had taken the first two.
It doesn't suggest suicide.
Then why did they die?
The heroin was unusually pure.
What they took was over
90% pure.
When it's smuggled in...
it's 70% to 95% pure.
The dealers cut it...
with glucose and hydrochloric
procaine...
till it's only 30% pure.
A one-gram package...
contains only 0.3 grams
of pure heroin.
What happens to na addict...
Who takes heroin that pure?
A very clever murder.
Here's important evidence.
It was found in their room.
The imprint...
of what they'd scribbled on
the page above.
It's been restored and
enlarged.
It shows the agony...
of an addiction withdrawal.
"Bring us the stuff. Fast.
"If you don't, we'll spend
the money.
"We won't do what you say
anymore."
Obviously, they tried to
blackmail him.
We can't be sure...
but it looks like he
killed them.
And the money?
We found 2,500 of Mr. Gondo's
1,000-yen notes.
The kidnapper figured that
out too.
He gave them a share...
but made them wait to used it.
Who were they?
Caretakers of a villa.
We found that out from the
villa owner.
So you're close?
No, now we have to start
all over again.
Of course, narcotics is
doing its best.
We'll get valuable data
from them...
but the accomplices' death...
is a great setback for us.
The line leading straight to the
kidnapper has been cut.
So I'm asking you:
Don't print a word of all this.
Why not?
The kidnapper doesn't know
they're dead yet.
If he did...
he wouldn't have left all that
money there.
What'll he do...
if we convince him they're
still alive?
He'll probably try to kill
them again.
So you don't report anything.
He'll go back to check.
And you'll arrest him there?
Right.
Even if we keep quiet...
the neighbors will talk.
It's a new development.
There aren't many houses.
And it's off-season. Hardly
anyone's there now.
Drug addicts are cautious.
They had no visitors.
Our keeping quiet will
convince him?
No, I want to ask you
another favor.
Print that one of the 1,000-yen
notes was spent.
Say it's our announcement.
I'm asking your cooperation for
Mr. Gondo's sake too.
Did you know he lost his post
at National Shoes?
That's bad. Don't they care
about public opinion?
They'll vote him completely out
of the firm soon.
I think we ought to give National
Shoes a whack.
Let's do it.
"Gondo shut out public
opinion ignored"
"Women start boycott of
National Shoes"
"Second tragedy Gondo
voted out"
"Marked 1,000-yen note found"
"30 million Ransom in this
Briefcase"
We've recovered 2.5 million.
Will you come for it?
Sorry it's so late.
No, it's a great help now.
We want it all back.
The kidnapper hasn't spent any.
But he'll be hard to catch
unless he does. Ironic.
Mr. Kawanishi is here.
Kawanishi? What for?
A request.
Send him in.
Nice to see you.
I must thank you.
You've made Mr. Gondo a hero.
Now what?
Don't be so cold.
We've been so close all
these years.
I objected to your being fired.
I risked my own position...
to keep you as an executive.
The Old Man's stubborn...
and the executive are schemers.
I had a hard time.
Fortunately, public opinion
is for you.
So I succeeded.
Get out! Tell your new
master for me:
You can't use me to save
your hides.
I won't be an executive with
no power.
I'm no puppet.
Can you afford to say that?
You went too far.
If you quit now, you'll have
only debts.
Back on the payroll, your
credit stands.
Get out!
I'm my own man now.
You're nothing not
even a man.
Excuse me.
I'd like you to see something.
It's not much, but the last one
seemed to be of use.
Shinichi drew it
the kidnapper.
Dark glasses and a mask.
Not much to identify.
What's this?
A handkerchief. He always
wore it.
Mom! Look at the pretty
pink smoke!
Burn anything here about
9:00 a. M?
Yes, yesterday's trash.
What do you burn?
Junk that can't be disinfected.
They even bring stuff that
won't burn.
Who does?
The janitors.
Anyone else?
The hospital nurses and
attendants, sometimes.
Anyone like that today?
Come to think of it...
a man brought a cardboard box.
How big?
Know him?
No. An intern maybe.
A young man?
Yes. Too young to be a
regular doctor.
"Burn this, pop," he said.
Doctors don't talk like that.
Now look at that, will you?
You can't burn tin.
You know what section he's in?
No, but he headed toward
Internal medicine.
Bos'n's report says his name
is Ginjiro Takeuchi.
He took three days off during
the kidnapping.
He lives in a studio apartment
in Nishi-ku.
His room faces north and looks
up at Gondo's house.
One of the phones we marked...
is near his apartment.
The accomplices had been
examined...
at his hospital.
They were lung patients and
drug addicts...
suffering from edema of
the lungs...
and heroin withdrawal.
Pure heroin would cause death
from shock.
Takeuchi's name was on their
medical reports.
We can conclude that he
is the kidnapper.
But we can't arrest him.
If we arrest him now...
he'll only get 15 years.
But he gave Mr. Gondo, who
paid the ransom...
a life sentence.
We can't allow that.
The kidnapper deserves capital
punishment.
It's clear he killed his
accomplices...
but if we arrest him now...
we can't prove it.
There's only one way to bring
him to justice.
Let him reconstruct his crime.
How?
With this.
Lower the blinds.
"Give us more stuff. We'll
talk if you don't".
Not a bad imitation, huh?
Mr. Takeuchi?
He'll start moving today.
First, he'll have to buy
heroin.
When he gets it, he'll try to
kill them again.
But what he does till then...
and how he gets the drugs...
we can only find out by
watching him.
Don't get too close...
but don't take your eyes
off him.
Bos'n, Nakao, Ari and I...
Will head for the hideout when
he goes after the drugs.
I'll give orders from the car.
He's waiting for a dealer?
Just killing time, I'd say.
Walking up and down for
two hours already.
He may recognize us if we
stick together.
Inspector!
Yes. Tokura here.
He's in a florist's.
What? Flowers? Have someone
buy some flowers.
There's no face here fit to
buy flowers.
He bought one carnation?
Yes. One red one.
A girlfriend?
Now the suspect is at a
pay phone.
It must be his connection...
and the flower must be a sign.
Watch who approaches the
red carnation.
Watch how the money and
dope change hands.
Inspector Tokura!
Tokura speaking.
He changed his course.
He got out at Dope Alley.
Didn't he buy any?
We thought he did.
We're turning back. Watch him.
What are you looking at?
Get out!
What are you doing here?
A lot of strangers around
tonight. Be careful.
What are you, a cop?
We don't know you.
Get out. Get out, I said!
Bos'n, I don't understand
what he's up to.
He should be taking the dope
to the hideout.
And if he hasn't got it yet,
why go to the junkies?
They don't have any pure
heroin.
- Inspector!
- This is Tokura.
He picked up a girl.
"HOTEL"
Oh, no! He'll use her as a
guinea pig!
He wants to test the drug
he's got.
He came out.
- And the girl?
- One moment.
Two men went to check.
On to the hideout?
Wait. The girl's a clue as to
what he'll do.
He's going to Isezaki-cho.
This is Isezaki-cho.
Which side?
Left side.
- Stop!
- No standing, sir.
The girl's dead. Overdose.
He's coming.
We found him. I'm cutting
off the radio.
A real prize.
To the hideout.
No standing.
I brought the stuff.
Takeuchi, you're a dead man.
We recovered 27,480,000 yen.
He had spent only 20,000 yen
on the heroin.
It's a great help.
- Too late?
- It's all right.
Have a seat.
You can use them till
the auction.
"Attached Article"
"Kidnapper Gets Death
Sentence"
Thank you for coming.
He refuses to see a priest.
But he insisted on seeing you.
Well, Mr. Gondo. Thanks
for coming.
You seem well.
What are you doing now?
Making shoes again...
for a small company, but I'm
in charge.
I'm trying to make it as good
as National Shoes.
Why do you look at me
like that?
I'm going to die, but I'm
not afraid.
So you needn't feel
sorry for me.
That's why I refused a priest.
I should repent, pray for mercy,
ask forgiveness.
But why?
I have no time for lies.
I want the truth.
Are you glad because I'm
going to die?
No?
Why should you and I hate
each other?
I don't know.
I'm not interested in
self-analysis.
I do know my room was so
cold in winter...
and so hot in summer
I couldn't sleep.
Your house looked like heaven,
high up there.
That's how I began
to hate you.
That gave me a purpose
in life.
It's interesting to make fortunate
men unfortunate.
Were you so unfortunate then?
You want my life story?
I'm not looking for your pity.
That's not why I sent for you,
Mr. Gondo.
Why did you then?
I didn't want you to think.
I died crying and afraid.
My hands don't tremble
because I'm nervous.
It's from being in solitary
so long.
Just being outside that cell
makes them tremble.
I'm not afraid of death
or hell.
My life has been like hell
since I was born.
But if I had to go to heaven,
I'd really tremble.
THE END