Original Indo subs by: GAIJIN
English subs by Stheno_221 on subscene. Please do not claim as yours.
Please support the movie by buying the original DVD/Bluray.
Please bear in mind that translation is not 100% accurate.
-The SWORD region is divided into 5 major groups-
-A casino is planned to be built in the area-
-Nameless Street-
Let me go!
Let go! let go!
It's alright now.
Hey, hurry up! go!
- Watch out!
- Its the Rude Boys
How are the children?
They're fine
Who are those guys?
I don't know
Everything's a success
Yes, but...
given the Casino development plan...
We still don't know what will happen in the future.
Oya High School
Every single day...
Why do we always fight?
The gang from outside keeps attacking us,
so we don't have a choice other than fighting them.
Let's try to stop it.
- Let's go!
- Alright!
everyone let's go
Lately a lot of strange people come.
Let's party
What's this place? its always empty
It became quiet, because of the casino development plan.
Bad things always happen in remote places.
Come on' attack!
Hope you bastards don't regret this.
In this region...
There are five major groups.
Do you want to die?
For what reason are we using our fists?
We can not lose.
-HOODLUM SQUAD: Sannoh Rengokai-
We give confidence to women...
and guide them in their lives.
We...
must protect women.
Heidi, Marco, Lassie, Cosette.
Actually, those names...
shut up!
I think they are all just high school students.
-White Rascals-
Let's go bastards!
The most beautiful scenery ...
could only be seen with your friends.
-Oya High-
We are a family
In order to survive
we fly higher than the rest
Jump!
-Rude Boys-
How can the SWORD have fun without Daruma?
Are you the gatekeeper?
Let's go, baby
-Daruma Ikka-
Taking the first letter from each group
The area is named "SWORD".
Please destroy the SWORD.
Destroy them
Are you ready everybody?
Chanson and Lee from the foreign mafia
Tried to take over SWORD.
In order to drive everyone away.
These areas previously controlled by ...
the Mugen in which their leader...
Kohaku was a part of.
Music and fashion saved us.
We're gonna create our own place to change our lives.
right?
-Mighty Warriors-
A scout group that will do anything for money.
-Doubt-
Those two groups teamed up
and had a fierce battle in the coastal region.
However, with the five SWORD groups united.
And their concern for their friend, Kohaku's condition.
The plan to take over SWORD failed.
Kohaku finally went back to his old self
Who killed my brother?
The one who killed Kohaku's friend, Tatsuya
and tries to take over SWORD region ...
is the Kuryu Group.
On the other hand, Mugen's rival, the Amamiya Brothers.
While looking for their brother Takeru
who was in Little Asia.
Takeru discovered that their parents' deaths were caused by Kuryu.
Thus, he sneaked into the group.
If the contents of the USB is leaked to the public, everything will end.
He decided to steal the USB that contains files about the casino development plan.
And expose it to the public.
However, Takeru was killed by Kuryu.
The Amamiya Brothers tried to fight.
Upon the death of their brother, they decided to give the USB to...
For the sake of his beloved friends,
For the sake of a loved one,
and to protect their hometown ...
In the SWORD region...
a fight to obtain the USB.
Started immediately.
Where is Smoky?
We are here for him.
Is that poor guy dead?
Stop it.
What do you want to talk about, Cobra-chan?
After the fight at the coastal area,
I realized that our enemy are Kuryu and Chanson.
Do you want to fight the Kuryu?
No
Kuryu will soon be destroyed.
I gathered all of you here.
To discuss what will happen in the future.
If Kuryu disappears.
The Chanson and other mafias will target the city.
For that, I have an idea.
I want to make an agreement within SWORD.
Agreement within SWORD?
Wait a minute!
What do you mean by, Kuryu will be destroyed?
Do you know what happened with the Amamiya brothers in Little Asia?
Yes
Are you serious?
Yes, we have to work together from now on.
are you kidding
This is not the time for the SWORD to fight.
Do you want a fight?
Hah? By the way, who are you?
We fought together...
ah never mind
Nobody recognized you after you had a haircut.
I know, but women don't like men with dreadlocks.
There's not a trace of your old self now.
Obviously, as explained by the Sannoh Rengokai.
Have you lost some members?
You're right, the four shadow members of their group are not here.
Rocky have kicked them.
They wanted to form a band.
Although they can't play musical instruments.
You shouldn't just kick them out because they formed a band?
In your area,
how is the struggle for land?
Kuryu has taken over several shops in our neighborhood.
Tetsu's bathhouse has also moved to the Rasen area, right?
Ah, yes... yes
I understand.
But that has nothing to do with us.
We only need to protect women.
I don't need any help from you...
..at all
I think this idea is good.
You want to have an agreement...
let us see the USB, then we can trust you
We wouldn't believe everything just by hearing about it.
We need to discuss it with Smoky in order to decide
Compared to the agreement,
we still have a lot more important things to do.
Let's go.
Okay
Our union before isn't a start of friendship.
Cobra-chan
Like Hyuga-chan,
We can't start an agreement easily.
But...
I will give you a chance.
This is over.
Rocky, why did you reject it?
-Prison Gang-
-DOUBT Founder: Ranmaru Hayashi-
Why is the atmosphere like this?
Shut up! ugly!
You cut your hair?
it's none of your business
Why did Rocky reject it?
He hates being grouped together.
He even kicked out his friends.
I don't know what he's thinking.
Although, we don't know his personal affairs.
I can't believe he kicked his friends out.
I don't think it's easy.
Looks like Hyuga also doesn't believe what we said about the USB.
We can't do anything for now.
But if the contents of the USB is exposed to the public ...
This is the Casino project is being carried out by Kuryu.
On the list of people involved, there are names of politicians and police officers.
In fact, there are also lists of illegal donations and account books.
If this is leaked to the public.
This country ...
Will be in chaos.
Kuryu will be destroyed
and the casino development plan will be stopped.
Then, Hyuga will understand it.
We only need to wait for Kohaku-san to expose it.
No matter what happens. We can't change anything.
These things are needed to be done in order to protect this city.
Where are you going?
I'm going to see Rocky.
If Kohaku-san leaks the contents of the USB ...
then that means we defeat the Kuryu, right?
Of course.
Then, what will happen to the casino development plan?
Perhaps the casino will be built somewhere else.
As expected, the bath house will be demolished?
If we can defeat Kuryu, our bath house will be better.
I don't know if there is anything I can do.
Tetsu
To be honest,
I thought with the redevelopment of the area.
Bath houses can continue to operate.
So dad was delighted.
It was difficult.
I know we have to defeat Kuryu I also understand what you say.
There is no point worrying about them.
Let's talk with Cobra.
No, but ...
That is what friends are for!
Yes
The casino will generate more than ¥2 Trillion.
Other candidates are upset.
Have the candidate site been decided?
No, Kurosaki,
Our plan to redevelop SWORD remains unchanged.
I heard there was a conflict before,
that there was a riot in the coastal area
There's nothing to worry about.
I tried hard to restore security.
If that's the case,
We can work with the police,
that is the duty of the police.
what do you mean?
He works independently.
Maybe I should introduce you.
My name is Saigo. I'm looking forward to working with you.
We also have subordinates who are just starting.
Genji.
-Kurosaki's subordinate: Genji Kuki-
Honestly, when will they be satisfied?
I'm so sick of hearing about that USB.
He said that it was related to Kuryu.
Well, what do we do next?
Where do you want to go the most?
What do you want?
My brother...
my brother is dead.
From now on,
we will end everything with the Kamizono Group.
This is a memento from my brother.
Use it to destroy Kuryu.
Why me?
We've known each other ever since you're in Mugen.
If you don't hear from me.
You can expose it.
What would you do with it?
Will you fight Kuryu again?
If you want something to change,
you have to do it yourself.
Lately I remember ...
what Tatsuya said about me.
That I'm afraid to change.
I don't want to make that mistake again.
Where is everyone?
At least he should have left a contact info,
You did enough.
Saigo.
Little Asia has always been under Kuryu's surveillance.
It's not under anyone's authority.
Even if you commit a crime, it will not be recorded,
because of having extraterritorial rights.
We will help you.
Who are you?
You have the USB right?
I don't know what you're talking about.
It's a USB that is owned by your brother right?
brother!
The USB was stolen and your brother died in vain, right?
Hiroto!
Let's go!
Don't talk to Kuryu's dog.
Hey,
Kikuchi-kun
If you need something, contact me.
We don't need your help.
I understand.
We're meeting the Amamiya brothers.
Kohaku.
It's Kuryu.
Tsukomo!
Let's go
Hey, hey! What happened?
Are you ok? Can you stand up?
Okay, 1, 2 ..
You're fine, right?
You guys fought hard
Are you okay? Can you stand up?
I understand, I get it ...
If you sleep here you'll get sick.
You're fine
it's ok, it's ok
Where does it hurt?
Which one is injured?
It's okay tell me, are you alright?
What are you an amateur!?
Stop playing games!
You're all going to die!
He doesn't intend to meet you.
Leave!
Thanks for everything.
Thanks
No matter how many times you come, it's useless.
Ranmaru is free.
Ranmaru.
That's our problem.
We don't want to receive help from others through this agreement.
Do you understand?
What kind of person is Ranmaru?
When we emerged as the White Rascals,
there was a conflict with Doubt.
Ranmaru does unacceptable things.
Not only his friends, even civilians are sacrificed.
Many women are trapped in the dark.
He easily crossed the line that everyone was afraid to pass.
He obliterates everything in the street just for fun.
That's who Ranmaru is
Ranmaru.
Because of his cruelty,
even the police could not control him.
Because of that incident, the station was closed.
Since then, the boundaries must be strictly obeyed.
If he returns, the same thing will happen again.
To protect women,
we can't let it happen again.
Hey,
Can't we resign from the USB thing?
what?
Are you saying that let's just forget about it?
No, that's not what I mean.
It's not such a bad thing if the Casino is built.
I meant to Tetsu and even the Big Chicken restaurant.
In addition, many people can benefit from the redevelopment.
But knowing that Kuryu is there, it couldn't be better.
This is a good thing if they can make the city survive.
Tetsu.
Although it's currently difficult,
We must look forward to the future.
The USB is a golden opportunity to destroy Kuryu.
If we miss it, there might be no other chance.
Even without the redevelopment ...
We will not have a future.
You saw the contents of the USB?
That is not something we can keep up with.
I also can't forgive Kuryu.
But I don't want to see my allies sacrificing their lives.
Cobra, you feel the same way right?
We are trying to protect this city.
But now we have to fight Kuryu.
Not only the Iemura Group.
It's Kuryu!
This time,
they're not opponents that we can defeat.
Tatsumi Iemura
- Kuryu Group -
Tatsuhito Ryu
Tatsuo Fujimori
- Kuryu Group -
Ryuhei Ueno
Yoshitatsu Zenshin
- Kuryu Group -
Ryukai Minamoto
Kimitatsu Kurosaki
- Kuryu Group -
Ryuichiro Katsunari
Ryushin Kuze
- Kuryu Group -
let's start
I don't know...
Why they didn't expose us.
We need to find the USB quickly.
That is important.
We have been looking for it.
The boy named Kohaku from Mugen had it.
Is that true, Kurosaki?
You already know where it is.
Why don't you take it back?
what? are you getting old?
In this case, should we start moving?
Good heavens
Do you badly want to be replaced?
You did well.
I want to play with you again.
There he is.
We finally found you.
So you were here
I'm so hungry ... let's go home.
Indeed there's a nice view here.
When I come here, I could see the future of this place ...
I thought I could see more of it.
I understand what Dan and Tetsu said.
It's difficult.
But,
if Kuryu gets involved in this city.
There will be no future.
Although I can't boast about the way I live,
but this city is already like a way of life.
If it's stolen from our hearts,
I don't see the reason in living.
In the end, we can only..
protect our friends.
Yes
Let's not commit a mistake.
-Sun Kings Prison-
Oy, Jesse! someone is looking for you!
I don't want to go out just like that.
Hey, did you hear me?
Okay, let's do it.
Smokey
Are you alright?
I'm fine.
I'm giving you this.
Is that ok?
It's important for you, right?
That's why I'm giving it to him.
I'm fine.
This is something you have to take care of.
Eri?
Give me a break!
Hey, what are you doing in front of all these guests?
Who gave you permission to open a gambling place here?
Do you have a problem with that?
Hey!
Wait a sec!
I don't need anything from a small fish like you.
Where is Hyuga?
Hey!
Hey wait.
Seeing you makes me nostalgic.
Prison, huh?
You were finally released from Rasen.
Hyuga.
Aren't you going to fight Kuryu after you got released?
My father who lost to Mugen, was cut off from Kuryu.
To defeat Kuryu, we must take over SWORD.
You're weak.
Are you really Hyuga?
I'm not saying I won't fight.
Come with me.
what?
You can start from the bottom and work your way.
But first, you need entertainment.
White Rascals?
Excuse me.
Someone from Doubt...
Jesse, you're back!
Little Asia
Don't call the others, this is an odd job.
You're finally here.
You trash.
Let's run, Kuma!
Stop!
Kaito-san
Indefinitely...
Hey
Who are you?
Are you Rocky?
So what if I am?
Hey
Attention! Attention!
This is a memento.
What? Who are you?
Pho
Long time no see
Sorry for the trouble.
Ranmaru, do you know him?
He's a comrade from Rasen.
There are two prisons in the SWORD.
Even if you are behind the fence, you're still in SWORD.
There is an organization called Prison Gang.
Inside, the strongest group...
consists of these people.
Hurry up and give us a job.
Children are waiting.
Hey, Ranmaru.
Can we trust these people?
I don't know.
They look like the Mighty Warriors.
Do you want to play a little?
Listen
First, everyone takes one coin and goes down.
That is interesting.
Yo! let's party
What should we do?
Get the money.
Have fun.
You too.
It doesn't matter how you do it.
After collecting five coins, go up here.
That's easy, right?
Game start
Money and power are everything.
As expected.
Now that was fun!
move
We don't need weak people in Doubt.
Looking forward to working with you.
These people will do anything for money.
Really a great part time job.
Are you released from Sun Kings?
I got some details from Pho
You're the one who attacked Rocky, right?
So that was Rocky.
No wonder
There are rumors that some of the SWORD has been destroyed.
They can't be destroyed easily.
So that's why you called us.
Right?
Give us an explanation.
There are too many new faces.
Our boss
I'm Jesse.
Nice to meet you.
This person is crazy.
He even moved from Rasen to Sun Kings.
I didn't expect you to join.
Let's thank God.
Ranmaru brings all these crazy people.
Rocky was beaten to a pulp.
I want to know who did it.
I want to know if he's okay
Hah?
Are you serious?
Are you worried about Rocky?
No, idiot!
I'm talking about Tetsu.
Oh, I see.
If Tatsuya is here, I wonder what he'll say.
He might talk about destroying Kuryu or saving your friends.
As a matter of fact,
I can't forgive Kuryu.
Also
I don't want to leave this restaurant that my brother has protected.
We have a lot of memories with Tatsuya here.
There is no place like Itokan.
I wanted to create a place where you can always come back.
A place where we can always come back ....
But I understand Tetsu's feelings.
He wants to do everything he can to help.
I don't know what else to do.
That guy...
I can't believe he just went abroad like that.
You trusted that kind of person.
Don't say that.
Hey, when will he arrive?
Is he really the most trusted person you know?
Trust your brother!
Look, he's here.
why are you not exposing the contents of the USB to the public?
What did you do abroad?
Everything is ready.
All right.
Let us expose it.
I'm not the one who will do this.
You both have to end it.
This was protected by your brother.
We'll wait until the end.
Catch this!
Hurry up!
Don't touch me!
Damn!
Oh my God, my God!
Take this!
Shit!
Amamiya! Hurry up!
Hurry, Amamiya!
Be strong
Strong!
Be strong in order to live!
Faster!
Hey
Is it done?
Yes
Kohaku, I really can't drive a car.
Yay!
So? Where is the car?
We will compensate you.
This afternoon, it was revealed that the casino project
promoted by the government has been abolished.
It's clear this time that the group named Kuryu and ...
some people from the National Police, too
Pulled strings in order for the project to advance.
Everything is now under investigation
Because it's still under investigation,
I will refrain from commenting.
I'm running out of time.
Just do it as soon as possible.
With this, the police also can't remain silent.
Looks like Kohaku did it for us.
It finally ended.
But...
I know.
Dan and the others, from now on ...
Stop!
Stop it!
I don't know what happened, but if you don't stop they'll die.
Yamato!
Hey, baby face.
You're part of Sannoh Rengokai?
I've never seen you before.
SWORD is interesting.
I'll remember your face.
What's wrong with these people?
We are the Mighty Warriors.
You know what it is
You know
welcome back bro
Jesse is back, everybody!
Yo Bernie, spin that shit
Let's go
welcome back, Jesse!
welcome back, brother!
Jesse!
When were you released?
You haven't changed
Hey, Diddy!
You have returned.
And? Who is she?
Dixie.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
Jesse.
Who is that?
He is a friend from prison.
If you ask what he loves, he will answer "children"
Why?
We came from the same place.
He protects the children in Little Asia.
Hey everyone, Pho is back.
I bought a lot of food.
what?
Hey!
We both grew up in Little Asia.
After you enter Rasen, there are rules.
To protect yourself, you must choose a team.
Then he picked me up.
We came from the same hometown.
I have no reason to refuse.
I see
So? Why did you bring him here?
I want him to join the Mighty Warriors.
Okay
All right, starting today he is our friend too.
By the way, what happened to Ryu?
He's part of Kuryu now.
Kuryu?
If he wants to come back
we'll always welcome him.
Funk Jungle, huh?
Is this your ideal?
Are you interested in working with Doubt for money?
No
We're focusing on promoting this.
I see
Well, this is an easy task so I'll finish it myself.
Pho.
Doubt
They're gonna give you that much money for the job?
It's not just because of Doubt
I'm interested in this fight so I want to find the best support.
Rocky.
Rocky, are you alright?
Yes, I'm fine, don't worry
Kizzy, take them home.
Everyone, let's go.
Lassie and Cosette...
Let's go
Thank you
Rocky, Cobra is here again.
Will you close the club?
Yes
Until the trouble with Doubt is done.
It's dangerous for women.
Who did it?
Ranmaru
Can you reconsider the agreement?
If you do, we can help you face Doubt.
I can not...
depend on other people
To be independent, you must stand on your own feet.
I understand.
I won't interfere in your problems.
I'm sorry.
Just remember
You can contact me anytime, when you can't stand up.
Even if I continue to persist, it won't change anything.
I have to take care of it at once.
If we do not proceed in our own way
then it doesn't mean anything.
Love and pride.
Listen
Our goal is not to steal.
We try to protect.
Don't forget that.
First, we will take over the Rascals,
then the next is SWORD
What happened to the bath house?
I'm not sure yet.
But maybe...
Not just Tetsu's place.
Many other places will be desroyed.
We need to protect this city.
however...
what is Sannoh Rengokai fighting for?
Ask Noboru.
Noboru?
Sannoh Rengokai is where Noboru can return to, right?
It has nothing to do with us, so I'm not sure.
Will Daruma fall?
What nonsense is that!
They aren't just Doubt right?
Only the White Rascals.
It's over
I thought their SWORD friends would come.
They say they are good friends, but eventually they only think of themselves.
Hey, it already started!
You're not going?
Shut up
It seems that its not just Doubt.
Shiba, Nonoriki, give us info about Doubt.
Shiba is now in the area
This is Nonoriki. We will report now.
Those guys at that time ...
It seems that Doubt hired them.
Thank you for checking on it.
I thought it was only Doubt against the White Rascals.
Cobra.
I won't fight in this battle.
what?
What are you saying?
You want me to leave Tetsu ...
and go help someone who refuses to have an agreement?
Rocky refused the agreement ...
because he doesn't want SWORD to be involved in this battle.
Tetsu.
Do you think its enough just to protect the city?
Have you done everything you can?
Trust me.
I'm serious...
I will not go with you.
Dan!
Me too
Kabuto
I'm sorry
What the hell?
Cobra
Your friend is not just the people beside you.
Hyuga-chan
If I win,
Can you reconsider the agreement?
What if you lose?
Well,
I'll think about it when that happens.
Aren't you a scout group?
What?
At this level, women will not approach you.
Aren't you a scout group too?
You don't protect women...
They're just a tool to make money.
You...
do not understand women
As expected, I really hate this man.
Let's hurry up and attack as hard as we can.
But, the difference in the number of people
worries me a bit.
I'll deal with you later.
Party time
What should we do now?
Well, this is our job.
make money
Watch your step.
Kizzy, step aside!
Everyone spread out!
Let's go!
Seems like it started.
That's too easy
This will end soon.
stop!
get up!
go!
Attack them!
They are there too!
Teach them!
Hang on.
Stop!
Your enemy is me.
You had enough.
Shut up idiot
I'm sorry, Cobra.
Perfect
We will finish you together.
I'll face Ranmaru.
Hey!
Let's finish this.
Ready?
Let's go!
I just started fighting again.
What is this?
reinforcements?
Don't avoid me.
Make this fun for me.
Are you weak without cats? Boku
shit!
let's go bastards!
beat them up everyone!
Teach them!
Let's go
Teach them, beat them!
Is this a battle cavalry?
That's the best!
Oya High's extracurricular activities begin!
Kizzy-chan,
goodbye
You have good friends.
What?
They came to Nameless Street in full costumes.
Please help them.
Please
They also helped us, so now it's our turn.
Ah those people...
You poor guys
Are you resting?
I'm not on duty today.
You really have no mercy.
Hyuga.
You're finally here.
Here to block your path.
You can't trust a man who kicked you out.
Don't call yourself a SWORD leader if you want to be involved with these people.
We're responsible for the festivals in SWORD.
We do it whatever way we want.
If you fight with White Rascals
You fight with the SWORD
In other words!
This is!
the SWORD Agreement!
Go!
Oh, does that hurt?
Stand up straight!
Sit!
Let's go
Oh, I'm stuck.
'sup bro?
You guys have nothing to do?
This is what we have to do now.
Ice!
Ice, you bastard!
Don't turn your back on me.
what are you jealous?
Change or die, baby!
Ranmaru's work is finished.
Rocky won't lose.
You have a strong friendship.
That's beautiful.
It's not just that.
He prepared for the worst from the start.
Our groups fighting as one ...
are you really ready?
Ah, I'm tired.
I have finished everything for Tatsuya.
We plan to visit Tatsuya in the morning.
What about your people?
They went to battle.
They're fighting again?
Even though nothing will change even if they fight.
That's true.
The fact that they are fighting
is surely wrong...
but
Their desire to fight
isn't wrong.
Hey!
Are you alright?
That's Japanese
Okay
I understand.
Thanks, Ryu.
Yo! Jesse!
wait...
we are (leaving)
Ok, let's go
all right,
see you again
Where are you going?
These children...
We've been through this before.
Is that guy the boss?
It's Kuryu
Did you start this fight?
You have a pretty face.
Look,
Don't make things complicated.
Don't you know?
your quarrel won't solve anything
Stop!
Why are you angry?
When anger is beyond control,
You have to deal with it with compassion.
People who are below average ...
think they are above the average
when they hang out with their friends.
You're a stupid kid.
Don't you understand that everyone in the SWORD must die?
In the past, the leader of Mugen ...
we got full of them and used his death as a warning.
And now, you, he's just like you, very earnest.
Oh, he died in vain, right?
No matter how many of your members die,
it doesn't change anything.
You bastard.
Why?
Do you still want to fight us?
We fight at different levels.
I will show you.
We can cover everything.
No matter how many of you die,
We can make it look like nothing happened.
The whole Kuryu will attack and destroy you all!
You will either run away or crawl on us,
It's up to you!
This is my answer.
Casino project promoter, Minister Shinohara
have allegedly given and received counterfeit money.
President of Kuryu Group, Kuze Ryushin
is released today
Seriously
It's a waste of time.
For
a dream ...
Why is he released?
All the evidence is exposed?
What's wrong?
Nothing
Did you see the news?
What's happening in this world?
This is the end for the SWORD
Do it
Finish as soon as we find the leader of Rude Boys.
Do it right
Go!
watch till after credits!