Hilde Warren and Death
Joy May's German pastor reluctantly
approved the script
Hilde Warren, famous actress,
is happy with life ...
and especially with Hans von Wengraf,
a theatrical director and ardent admirer
Roger Hector, a young aristocrat, is
worthless, fatuous, and associated with the underworld.
A friend of Hector's, a bank employee
Hans Hilde, making a trip to the bank
Hilde onstage, before her first encounter with Death.
Hilde meets Death, who
invites her on a desert trip.
Hilde, very attached to life,
rejects his ominous invitation.
Hans finally decides
to declare his love for Hilde
Trying not to hurt his feelings,
Hilde rejects him
A chance encounter between Hilde and Hector.
Hector and his friend plan to rob the bank.
Hector declares his love for Hilde.
Hector and his friend rob the bank.
Hector takes Hilde to be married.
At the bank, Hector's accomplice raises
suspicions about his role in the bank robbery.
Hector's accomplice is arrested.
Hans returns to ask Hilde to marry him.
She rejects his proposal again.
Hilde discovers that she is pregnant with
Hector's child.
Death appears to Hilde,
renewing his invitation.
Hilde rejects it again,
deciding to give birth to the child.
Hilde moves to the countryside
to raise her son.
Hans meets Hilde's son, Egon, by chance.
Egon shows his aggressive tendencies.
Hans suggests that Hilde be very strict
with her son.
Hans asks for Hilde's hand
in marriage again.  She accepts this time.
Hans asks Hilde to give up her child.
Hilde refuses Hans's request ...
and asks God to make her a good mother.
Hans does not return.
Hilde reads in the paper that
Hans has committed suicide.
Hilde believes she is the cause of
Egon's aggressive tendencies.
Hilde again rejects Death's lures.
Egon, like his father, needs
lots of money for his pleasures.
Hilde is informed of the poor state
of her bank account.
Hilde tells Egon not to
pay so much for his whims.
Egon, like his father, is
prey to bad company.
The criminal proposes a shady deal to Egon.
Egon asks his mother for help
while running from the police.
Hilde refuses to help him, then
shoots and kills him.
Hilde goes to jail.
In the prison, Death again offers
Hilde consolation and comfort.
This time, Hilde accepts his offer.