Home Port
Hello, Tali.
- Hello.
I thought we agreed that you
would keep the unions in check,
and allow me to promote the move
with Giladi for the good of port.
I thought you were a man of your word.
- The good of the port.
That's a hell of a phrase
for privatization.
Ben Ami, I have made a deal with you
and I will make any deal your want,
so long as you don't touch
my employees.
Let him in.
- Okay
Aaron?
What are you doing here, son?
It's my first day.
What's going on here?
What do you mean? This is our new
head of the Marine Department.
Really?
That's nice.
Don't you forget,
I hold the on/off switch.
Good luck, son.
- Thank you.
Ben Bassat. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you. -Avitan.
We all know there isn't
another seaman such as yourself,
and that the department
is in good hands.
Just one thing,
it's about people, too.
Not just sea and machinery, right?
So try to be a little gentle.
Good luck to you.
Good luck, Avitan.
Cheers. -Cheers, guys.
Cheers, cheers.
Help yourselves, guys.
Help yourselves.
You still haven't
handed me those forms.
I haven't forgotten.
- It's not him, it's me.
You had it mixed up.
- So why isn't it here yet?
You promised you'd bring it.
No, I can't wait another week.
What do you mean?
Those are my stuff, I need them.
Yelena, darling? It's Azulay.
This is our new head of the
Marine Department,
you can't keep him hanging.
Alright. Alright.
See her first thing in the morning,
you'll get the VIP treatment.
Azulay, is everything alright?
I find out about
you working here from Ben Ami?
I've known you since the day you were
born, we're family, have you no shame?
Azualy, this is...
- This is what?
One thing led to another,
and I didn't know I'd be coming back
until the last minute.
Forget it, it's bullshit.
You're right, I...
I apologize. I'm sorry.
After 30 years at sea,
I've decided
that I would like to try
and earn my family back.
My daughter, Tali.
Did you know I have
a new granddaughter?
I heard. Congratulations.
Look.
- That's nice.
Look, if anyone gives you any trouble,
come straight to me,
I'm warning you.
Have to keep an eye on things,
we are all walking
a fine line around here.
What about what we talked about,
about the tugboat crews?
They're good kids,
they can barely make ends meet.
So what? They have a new manager now,
it's not your concern.
First of all,
every employee is my concern.
Secondly, why should they suffer
until their new boss settles in
and figure out what's what?
- What is that supposed to mean?
We both know they take their time
with the unloading,
for the 150 percent premiums
I pay them for overtime.
What do a couple of logistic workers
taking a short break have to do
with the Marine Department
tugboat crew's salaries?
It has everything to do with that.
You will be the end of them
with your conduct.
Giladi and I are waiting
for an answer.
You give it to me, and then maybe
I'll find the time to talk about
the tugboat crew's salaries.
- You just keep waiting.
Why didn't you tell me you were
the new head of the Marine Department?
I never got around to it.
The deed fell of that one.
Is it yours?
Let's see.
Hold on...
Yes, it's mine.
What is it?
The first color mini-TV, 1985.
Cheburashka.
- Right.
I know who that is.
I'm here to make sure
all is well.
Is it taken care of?
Big time. Thanks, Azulay.
- Good.
Go on, anchors up.
Life is short.
Alright, we're done here.
I'll leave it open for you.
Pick up your stuff
and I'll close up later, okay?
No problem.
I know about every little thing
that goes on here,
so there's nothing for you
to worry about.
Son of a bitch. Azulay!
Azulay!
Azulay! Take your piece of shit
of a car and get out of here!
What's the matter with you?
Are you crazy?
What a piece of shit!
Stay out of it.
I told that guy a thousand times
to stay away from the department,
so this is where he decides
to clean his car?
If you don't apologize
and make it up to Azulay right now,
I will call the police.
Did you hear me?
This is the last time you use violence
in my department.
Is that clear?
- Alright, alright. You're right.
I don't know what came over me.
- What a jerk...
Azul ay! I'm sorry.
It was an accident, it slipped out
of your hand. I saw it, it's alright.
Get back to work.
Shabbat Shalom, Mom.
Shabbat Shalom.
- Shabbat Shalom.
Here. -Shabbat Shalom.
- Here...
Are you Ronen?
- Hello, Aaron.
I understand you work at the port
as well. -In the tugboat crew.
Where were you before you joined us?
- Ronen, where is her bib?
In the kitchen.
- Can you get it for me?
Sure.
Would you like some more?
She's so cute.
Hello, Sivan. Is this your ball?
Is this your ball, or mine?
Have a seat and eat something,
so it doesn't get cold.
Is it yours? -Sit over there.
I'll prepare a plate for you.
Here's the bib.
What? What?
What do you want?
Do you want a carrot?
Thank you.
Here, have another carrot.
Tali, sweetheart,
I completely forgot.
Brurya needs me for an emergency
this Monday,
to help with preparations
for her daughter's wedding.
I won't be able to babysit for you,
I'm sorry.
Grandma, what's the matter with you?
You know that's the day
I have night school.
I can help you out, I'm free.
No.
I wouldn't want you to miss
your classes. -No, no.
It's alright,
just change my shift.
Okay.
Lift up your glass.
To the port!
- To the port.
Go on.
Nice. Another one.
Cheers. -Cheers.
Do you know who I miss sometimes?
Your father, God rest his soul.
Morris was a hell of a man.
One hell of a man!
How could he have just died on us
like that at 40 years old?
Look, Azulay.
About what happened with Kravitz...
I really am sorry.
- No, it's alright.
Forget it, it's nothing.
- No, it isn't.
It's nothing, I'm telling you.
Forget it.
He was out of line,
but just between you and me,
you waltz in with your Buick...
- My Buick? Is that the problem?
Everytime I give an Ashdod local
a job, they yell "corruption".
As if those guys up there,
sitting in their comfy offices,
aren't stuffing their pockets
every other day,
with social benefits.
- You have turned this port into a joke.
I've only been here a week,
and there hasn't been one day without
an unloading problem of some sort.
I don't want to talk about that.
- Just between us. -Here, let's drink.
Cheers.
No, no, it's on me.
- Forget it.
Aaron, listen to me,
you are one of us.
- Good night, Azulay.
You are a local, don't forget that.
Good night. Take care.
What was your name again?
Aaron Avitan?
I don't see you on the list.
Are you a freelance worker?
Are you for real? This is the new head
of the Marine Department,
the new head of Logistics.
Talk to Rina in Personnel.
Rina? I have an Aaron Avitan
at the gate. He's not on the list.
It's okay, let him in.
- Okay.
Thanks a lot. Do you need a lift?
I can take you to Customs.
Sure.
Well, good luck in your new job.
- Thank you very much.
Oh, I have that Cheburashka
that you liked.
Here, I want you to have it.
Thank you.
Do you have another container
full of funny stuff?
I actually do, my yacht
is full of stuff I'm getting rid of.
Do you need a coffee table
by any chance?
No. -Why?
It's nice, it's wood.
It's as good as new,
it would be a waste to throw it away.
Come and take a look, if you like it,
I'll bring it to your place. -Okay.
Thank you.
- My pleasure.
Goodbye.
- Have a nice day.
Didn't you hear me?
Start up the engine, let's set sail.
Didn't you hear me? No.
Wasn't it enough?
Didn't you get the message?
You guys didn't
get the message.
No more slacking around.
And you will pay for that, too.
- Kravitz, what's going on?
Why aren't you on your way
to pull the shipin?-! tried.
Those assholes don't want to set sail
because of the waves.
Elfasi, can you please come here?
Look, Elfasi,
the Marine Department
isn't just any department.
It's the best department.
It's a privilege to be working here.
It's good you're here, Azulay.
Have a word with that tight-ass.
He wants us to set sail
in 6 feet high waves.
The new manager has balls
and you guys are complaining?
What's the matter with you?
Are you scared of a couple of waves?
Come on, everyone set sail! Now!
Take your friend, for example.
Do you know where he was two years ago?
I dragged him out of the sewer.
I did everything I could
to get him back to the port.
He graduated from the Naval Academy
with honors. -Right.
What's become of him
is a real tragedy.
What's on your mind, son?
Talk to me.
Honestly, I don't like it.
I have to be able to get my crew
to set sail without you intervening.
You're absolutely right.
You saw how I got them on their feet.
- Avitan, everything's ready.
I'll be right there, Gabriel.
Meet me at the tugboat.
Come on, get off.
Have you forgotten the shit
I've dragged you out of?
Is that all you've got on you?
Go on, give it here.
I'm sorry, Azulay.
It won't happen again.
What do you think?
It's nice, isn't it?
It's handmade.
It﻿'s very nice.
Is it steady?
- Come on, come aboard.
I bet I'm the first woman here.
You'll be surprised, but you're not.
But she had enough. Yeah.
Of Ashdod, of the sea, and of me.
But our daughter is here.
She's grown up.
How about you?
I'll tell you all about it
if you ask me out properly. -Okay.
Alright, my husband is long gone.
I'm sorry to hearthat.
- I'm not.
Let's get off this thing
before we drown.
There's nothing to worry about,
believe me.
So what is this piece of junk?
I bought it for pennies years ago.
I promised Nicole at the time...
- Nicole?
Your former wife?
That's not an Israeli name.
- It's Dutch.
Anyway, the plan was...
you know,
to fix the yacht up and to set sail,
as a family.
It never happened.
I came back for my daughter.
To be with her.
I left a nautical career.
30 years, it's a big deal.
What?
Don't you have a test today?
Grandma, where are you?
What is he doing here?
Are you kidding me?
What difference does it make?
I'm here to help you.
Aaron, I really appreciate
you coming here, but it won't do.
Why are you so angry with me?
It's been so many years.
Okay.
Look, she's asleep
and she shouldn't wake up, okay?
If she does,
if she even makes a peep,
call Grandma right away
and tell her to come over,
or give me a call, I'm not very far
from here, okay? It's just a test.
I won't be gone for long, alright?
But if she wakes up,
call me right away. -No problem.
Aaron?
I know it's none of my business,
but this is completely unsafe.
You've got three burnt fuses here.
Look at this.
It's all charred.
You've got a baby at home.
You have to tell Ronen to check the
power circuits every now and then.
Haven't we discussed this already?
You can only wear work boots
on the tugboat,
not sneakers,
are you insane?
It's just shoes, Aaron.
Don't be such a tight ass.
I may be new here at the port,
but I've spent 30 years at sea.
You'd lose your job indefinitely
over this at the ships.
Is that how it is?
- Listen to me, smart ass,
take your guys,
and you've got five minutes
to get back here
with work boots on.
Aaron, am I okay?
- Yes, great.
Thanks, Elfasi.
Azulay
-Berko.
You remember him, his mother is the
Romanian who owns the shoe store.
You were in the Naval Academy
together, remember?
I know him.
- That's good.
He was also assistant marina manager
in Ashkelon.
He was fired, you know how crappy
things are these days.
Give him a job
on the tugboat crew.
What does he know about tugboats?
- He's a seaman.
He's also from Ashdod.
Give him a chance. -Seaman?
30 years ago, in the Kishon Delta,
he puked his guts out on a pedal boat.
What will I do with him?
- Two courses and he's great.
Besides, his brother has
a lot of power in the union,
and we may need him in the future.
- So what, Azulay?
It's the most professional
department we've got.
Alright, give me a break, Aaron, give
him a job as a department attendant
and call it a day.
- Kravitz is my department attendant.
I don't have another
department attendant post.
Alright, so? If someone needs help,
we help them out.
If there isn't a post,
we'll create one.
You remember Aaron.
How are you?
- Great, and you?
Fine. -He really is
a great seaman. Excellent.
Besides, a logistics man will help us
keep this port in order.
Sure thing. -Go wait for me
in the car. -Alright.
See you.
- Goodbye.
Give him a chance.
My son and his wife
packed the little ones up,
and went on a coast to coast trip.
They left the eldest with me.
He's a wild one, I'm telling you.
So the teacher
gives me a call and says:
"Mr. Azulay, your grandson
is disturbing the class".
So I said: "Mali, that kid has been
disturbing me all summer,
"have I ever given you a call?"
Alright...
Now that I've gotten you this great
department attendant,
let's give a nice farewell
to Mr. Kravitz.
He's my best worker.
- But he's management.
He's getting in my way
of helping the employees.
And I should get rid of an employee
for that reason?
I don't work that way.
Who will take care of us
if we don't look after ourselves?
Those guys sitting in their
comfy offices in suits and ties?
We are at war here.
I need him, I need his brother.
I'll be wanting to pull the plug
on this place in a day or two.
Azulay, it's the end of the day,
we are both tired,
believe me, you won't remember a word
of what you said tomorrow morning.
I'm sorry, Avitan. This isn't
your decision, this is an order.
An order? Are you nuts?
He's my best worker.
Maybe, but the man is violent.
We were lucky the windshield
was the only thing he smashed.
We will not tolerate any kind
of violence at the port.
Azulay is talking about
filing a police complaint,
he'll get a record and then he
wouldn't be able to work here at all.
Would you like that better?
- Do you think I'm an idiot?
Don't you see what's going on here?
Azulay is playing games with you,
and you take him seriously?
Who will replace Kravitz?
Have you thought about that?
Do you know why I called you here?
Let's just say
this isn't easy for me.
Constructive criticism is always
a good thing. Shoot, Boss.
You will be transferred
out of the department.
Ben Bassat will give you
a new assignment.
I've been working in this department
for 25 years.
You also deprived me of the ability
to fight for you.
Azulay is threatening to press charges.
- What for? What, over the pipe?
Are you insane?
Are we in Switzerland here?
People get violent
every day around here.
Aaron, you told me off,
I heard it, and that's it.
I still haven't given up.
Give me a couple of days
and I'll do everything I can
to get you your job back.
For now, I'm sorry, but that's
the decision. -The decision?
Don't you see what's going on here?
How you let them have their way
on my expense?
Aaron, we both know
that if I leave this place,
there will be 40 ships lined up
at the port entrance tomorrow,
with now one to tug them in.
I would like to remind you that
you are still a port employee.
A port employee? I've figured
you out, you're his bitch, too,
because of what he did
for your family.
see you as a professional.
But if you talk to me that way
one more time,
I will fire you from the port completely
without a second thought.
Get out of my office.
I was wrong.
I looked up to you.
Even those who were here before you
stood up to him harder.
You loser.
I'll have the dumpling soup
and some bread, please.
And for you?
I'll have the Kiev patty, please.
That comes with
a side of potatoes.
That's fine. I like potatoes.
- Thank you.
What was that all about?
I spent a few years on a ship
with a Russian crew.
So how many languages do you speak?
Russian, Polish,
Greek, Spanish,
a little Italian,
and French and Moroccan from home.
How many are those?
Seven languages.
And Hebrew.
- And Hebrew.
Say something nice in Russian.
"I drink for the home
that was destroyed,
"to my cruel life..."
"To being lonely together..."
"And I drink to you".
- "And I drink to you".
Good.
- Thanks, Azulay.
Put the money away,
put it away.
We had a nice harvest
this month, huh?
Alright, get back to work.
Don't forget, take your time.
Work slowly. Don't rush it.
You're thirsty, you want some water.
Fine, have a drink of water.
If you start working fast,
they'll get used to it.
Who will take care of us if we
don't look after ourselves, right?
It's like you forget everything
we talk about at the meetings.
Nice and slow, nice and slow.
Good morning, Shlomi.
I need a word with you.
Good morning.
When was the last time you took
a tugboat refreshment course?
In January, I think.
Have you got your papers?
- No.
I'll tell you why I'm asking,
because my records show it was on
January, only four years ago.
Possibly.
Well, there's a problem. You can go
aboard the tugboat like that.
Go to the offices and sign up
for a refreshment course today.
Get off it, Avitan. You know
they don't keep track of that.
Lots of people didn't take
a refreshment course.
A problem indeed. It's a good thing
you told me, I'll check on everyone.
Are you joking here?
Is this some sort of seaman joke?
I'm sorry. Normally,
you'd be going home over this.
I don't understand, Aaron, why do you
want to send me home? -Shiomi!
It's all good.
We work by the book from now on.
Sign up for the course,
do it properly.
Go on.
Why didn't you tell me?
I tried, I really did.
See for yourself.
I've been calling you all day.
Sigal. Is your husband there?
Hi, Shiomi, honey,
why didn't you tell me about this?
Okay, forget it. Forget it!
I don't care, go back to work tomorrow,
as if nothing's happened.
Did you hear me?
Go back to work tomorrow!
And Shlomi did all of this
since yesterday?
The last time I checked,
this is a week long course.
Alright, Avitan,
what do you want from me?
The coordinators asked me
to give this to you, and I have.
This is unacceptable.
Shiomi, get off the tugboat.
Aaron, I'm not getting off.
Is there a problem
with the papers, Avitan?
I will not eat your crap
for no reason.
If I see you on a tugboat
one more time, I'll call the police.
Let's go.
I want you to let Shiomi
back on the tugboat.
You want me to take Shiomi back,
after you got rid of my best worker?
- He was getting in the way.
You know,
when your father dropped dead
right next to me, on the dock,
without a penny in pension
to give you guys,
I swore on his grave that no one would
be taken advantage of here again.
That's fine, Azulay,
but keep your hands
off of my department.
You know what? Done deal,
but let Shiomi back on the tugboat.
You don't get it.
This is my decision, not yours.
You're a little confused, Aaron,
but that's okay.
Azulay, I think you are the one
who got confused.
Take it off. -Harder.
- Harder, let it have it.
What's going on here?
What are you doing?
What's the matter with you?
- Did you put that up here?
You're out of your minds, the order
came straight from management.
Oh, management, is it?
- Yes, management.
Take the clock off.
- Don't you dare touch that clock.
Who are you to tell him
what to do?
You can tell your wife's father,
that if he's here to be a mole
for the management, we won't let him.
This isn't right, guys.
Come on, get out of here, please.
Who are you to tell me
to get out of here?
So I'm calling security, right now.
How are you?
- I'm fine.
I want to understand
what exactly happened.
I saw those idiots trying
to take the clock down.
Who? -Haven't you done
enough damage? Huh?
And my husband was stupid
enough to fight his people for you.
Get out of this house.
- Tali, please calm down.
I will not calm down,
get out of this house.
Tali, please calm down.
- Get out of here, now!
I'm here to see Ronen!
- Don't you yell at me! Get out!
And don't come back, you hear?
I want to know who did this,
so I can kick them out of the port.
What don't you understand?
- Avitan, stop.
Don't jump to conclusions.
- Conclusions?
You forced a loser on me,
who hasn't been at sea for 30 years,
made me get rid
of an excellent worker,
and now you're turning
a blind eye on violence.
They've gotten to my family,
Ben Bassat.
We have already investigated,
no one touched him. Drop it.
The kid slipped, it happens.
Barak, what's up
with the cleaning crew?
What are they using
to wash the docks?
Workers can't be slipping
like ballerinas all over the place.
Alright, I have to run.
Avitan, keep up the good work.
I've figured you out, Ben Bassat.
Are you the security officer
of the port?
It's nice to meet you.
Are you part of the scheme, too?
Look, I've been working here
for 15 years.
My father punched his card
for 45 years, so you listen to me,
Azulay is the port.
There isn't a single employee
who wouldn't die for him.
You are threatening me.
- God forbid.
You can go after him,
but remember,
when you pull the tree's roots,
the whole trunk might
fall down on your head.
I need to talk to you about
Aaron's son in law. Get in the car.
Shut the door.
Get out of the car.
Internal Affairs officer
Hello.
- Hello, Ronen.
Look at the state of him.
How are you feeling?
- Alright. Better.
Look, Avitan,
you know I love you and all,
but you're wasting your breath.
Get off Azulay's back.
Listen to me, leave him alone.
You know, this isn't like the sea.
At sea,
if you get caught up in a storm if you
get caught up in a storm by yourself,
you turn the wheel
and you're over it.
Here, you have to work with people,
you can't manage on your own
around here, do you get me?
Good. There were a lot of people
like you around here before.
They all came and went.
Azulay always stayed.
- Right.
Look, I have to go,
my daughter is waiting for me.
Come on, let me
throw you in your boat.
Didn't you say
she wasn't talking to you?
What can I do?
She's angry with me.
She's angry with you?
Let me have a word with her.
Are you guys talking?
- Of course.
2, 3...
- Pull!
Haven't I told you
not to come around here anymore?
Grandma is really late.
- What do you mean?
We spoke this morning,
she said she talked to you.
Are you out of your minds?
Tali, give me a chance,
why are you fighting me?
Okay, you can go, alright?
Goodbye.
Tali, come on.
I've known you since we were babies,
from the neighborhood.
Are you starting with me, too?
This is your father. My friend.
Can't you give him a chance?
Have you no heart?
What will you do?
Who will look after the baby?
I won't go to school today.
- Right.
The baby's grandfather is here,
but you'll be missing school?
Who helped you out when you gut drunk
when you were 14?
18.
Alright, fine. Come in.
Hurry up, before I change my mind.
Wash your hands.
Look, Sivan, look.
Look how pretty.
Bro, I think...
- She's loaded.
Do it.
- What?
Change her.
- I don't know how.
Who taught you to change a diaper?
No one. How complicated can it be?
Here...
Easy. Easy.
Stay out of it.
Good job.
Threatening people,
kicking them off the tugboats,
threatening to go to the police,
jail time.
You're a real inspector.
Don't you think
you've crossed the line?
You came into my home, Azul ay.
That was my son in law
you kicked the shit out of.
I raised you.
You grew up on my lap,
you piece of shit.
Don't you see we're family?
My son in law is my family!
That didn't stop your thugs
from kicking the shit out of him.
You squeal over a few punches?
You should be ashamed of yourself.
I told you more than once, Azulay,
I told you calmly and politely,
get your dirty hands
off of my department.
Your department?
Nothing is yours around here!
We built this port, while you were
sailing around the world
with your ships! No one tells me
what to do in this port,
and you sure as hell won't!
There was an unwritten rule
up until now,
that management can't be touched,
but you broke the rules,
and that rule will change,
as of now.
I've lost control over my people.
None, you messed them up!
Now sign on Shlomi's
return to the tugboats.
I see you, Azulay.
I see everything.
And as for Shlomi,
he will not return to the tugboats.
I will kick you out of this port,
you will not get
another job in Ashdod.
And be careful when you
cross the street, too. Now, sign.
Get out of here with your thugs,
you are keeping me from my coffee.
Whose bed is this?
My daughter's.
She's not here,
she's in the Ukraine.
You have a daughter?
Why haven't you told me about her?
Because it's not something
I am very proud of.
I had a really rough time
for a couple of years,
until I got the job at the port.
I had to send her away, to my mother's.
Until things work out.
Only by the time things worked out,
it's already been ten years.
Marina.
She's little in this picture.
She will be 14 this spring.
She comes here on vacation
every summer.
What's with you, bro?
You tossed all our balls
into the water.
I don't drink that shit anymore,
only milk and water.
Really?
- Yeah, really.
Maybe you can start eating again,
change your clothes once a month,
maybe girls will start
noticing you again.
Bro, you take too much to heart.
Forget the port. It's only a job.
You left the sea for Tali, right?
Don't waste your time fighting with him.
Do you think I'm stupid?
I know exactly what's going on here.
But this type of corruption,
that's so deep and organized,
it's just unbelievable.
- Why are you saying that, bro?
He's protecting us, I swear to you.
- Protecting us? -Yeah.
He got rid of my best manager.
Got rid of him, as if he were garbage.
What did I do about it?
Nothing.
Just forget about it.
Kravitz, hold on.
I want to talk to you.
What about?
I﻿'m on my way to see Ben Ami,
either you get your job back,
or I'll leave my keys in his office.
Why?
My department isn't functioning.
I've got four ships stuck at sea,
a dock full of cargo,
I've been trying
to reach Berko on the phone,
and he's been screening my calls
for two days now.
Really? I knew you'd come here.
We've got nothing to talk about,
Avitan. You and I are through.
Give me five minutes, please.
I was wrong.
I want to help you.
Avitan, you took sides.
I'm taking sides right now.
You will get your old job back
tomorrow morning.
Kravitz?
It's a painful subject.
He is a senior, devoted worker.
I still don't understand why you
did that. -Why we did it? Okay.
Anyway, Ben Ami,
I need a signed paper from you,
today, reinstating Kravitz
in my department.
No less, huh?
Anything else, Avitan?
- As assistant manager,
with Personnel privileges.
I can have your ass out of here
over this, you know that?
Save your breath.
If Kravitz isn't back on my crew
today, I'm going home.
Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
You all know me already.
I will not tolerate disobedience.
Pinto. Come here, please.
You sabotaged the punch clock
a while ago,
and now, a security camera caught you
punching time cards for people
who are currently at home.
Well... -You are suspended from work
until further notice. -What?
You know I think
very highly of you.
You are the most
senior worker I've got,
but you are setting
a criminal example.
You are suspended,
and that is my final decision.
Everyone back to work, please.
Aaron, he's about to go on retirement.
- I was clear, get back to work!
What am I doing here
in the middle of the night, Kravitz?
Every Monday, a ship from Liverpool
pulls in the port.
Around sunrise, I realized
that the cargo was being loaded
from the ship straight
to Shlomi's tugboat.
Shlomi parked the tugboat,
a forklift came along, took the cargo,
and put it here, with the containers
that were already inspected. Cool, huh?
Totally. But my question is...
It seems that with a little help
from the guys over at Customs,
and since the security guard
slacks off at night
while inspecting the garbage trucks
that leave the port,
that cargo leaves the port
in less than two minutes.
15 minutes later, it's already being
unloaded at the importer's warehouse,
and who do you think
is waiting for it there? Elfasi.
And all of Ashdod is drinking
prime whiskey for half the price.
Like the whiskey you were drinking
with your friend at the pub, in Lido.
The question is
how to tie him to it.
So what do you propose I do?
That's your problem.
I'm sorry, I hadn't had
I'm sorry, I didn't eat anything today.
So, Avitan, what can we do
with this interesting information?
Look, Ben Ami, I have no interest
in stirring things up here for nothing,
but... -Excuse me.
Yardena, I need napkins.
I'm listening.
- This terrorism his funding
with the whiskey bottles
must be stopped, immediately.
I want Mishali from the Customs
Investigation Unit here tomorrow.
Avitan, you know as well as I do
that we've got nothing on them,
no evidence. If you want Azulay
you'll have to bring in some facts.
This isn't a vice squad.
- Isn't it?
So I will personally make sure
that everyone will know
what kind of port
you are running here.
I'm done playing the role of the
stupid puppet from the sea, okay?
Enjoy your meal.
Yardena? -Yes? -Get me
Nachum Mishali from Customs. -Okay.
A customs investigation was initiated.
You know what brought this on.
So in light of the information
that I was presented with,
I am forced to suspend you.
But don't worry, Azulay,
I'm sure this has nothing to do with
you and that it'll go away quickly,
and you'll be back with us and...
You know very well
that we are all behind you.
I understand you were cornered into this,
got you cornered,
and that you have no choice
and so I'm not angry.
I just want to make one thing clear.
Jacques Pinto will
return to work immediately.
It's not that simple, Azulay.
The order came
from a department head.
I don't care if the Prime Minister
gave the order.
If he's not back,
your port will burn.
What is Shlomi doing here?
This is his place of work,
this is how he makes a living.
Elfasi.
You have one minute
to get out of my way to the tugboat.
No one goes on the tugboats today,
and they are not going anywhere.
One minute, or you'll be
in deep trouble with me.
What will you do?
Will you get rid of me?
Get rid of everyone,
work by yourself.
No boat will set sail.
- Keep your hands off. Calm down.
Elfasi. Let me go on the tugboat
or you will all be in trouble.
We agreed to keep it peaceful,
why are you making this harder?
Why are you making this harder?
Keep your hands off!
- Come here!
Keep your hands off! -You will not
get rid of me, or my friend.
Pinto, don't hit him!
Pinto! Pinto!
- Enough! Let go of him!
Don't hit him, Pinto!
I'll fuck you up!
I'll pass the information
to the police.
You just file a complaint
and we'll take care of everything
from then on. -No.
He's only the symptom,
he's not the problem.
And he's about to retire in a month.
You order his early retirement and...
We put this thing behind us.
Have you lost your mind?
You still have bruises
from his beating.
This man is a criminal.
- No.
He's a good man.
That made a mistake.
Thank you.
Get well soon.
What a wuss.
This cowardly clerk fled away
as soon as you gave him a chance.
Does it hurt?
- So bad.
What's up, guys?
Romano.
Can you tell me why people
aren't loading sacks to the ship?
The Union shut the docks down
until Azulay gets back.
I tried working earlier,
but you know how it is,
the Union guys are patrolling
the place and threaten anyone
who even tries to lift a box.
I need one more person,
we're setting sail.
No one goes aboard.
I want to make myself clear,
the Marine Department workers are not
allowed to participate in the strike.
You can't do that, Avitan.
It's our right
to strike for a friend,
even if he's from another department.
Let's set sail, Kravitz.
God damn them all to hell!
Fuck you all.
Let's go, I'm with you.
Throw one in his face.
Here, you asshole.
So you're taking part in the strike
as well, huh?
That man helped me.
He's always been there for me.
You know what he's been doing
in the port, don't you?
Can't you see no one
really cares about that?
It's a game of Musical Chairs.
Even Ben Ami. Today he's at the port,
but tomorrow he might become
the CEO of a gas company.
Azulay is the only one who truly cares.
- Who put this nonsense in your heads?
Listen to me.
You must put an end to it
before more people get hurt.
Before it really is too late.
Come on, let's huddle up.
These trucks will not go inside,
not a single one!
Go over there!
Come on! Azulay!
This is for you!
"You can sit in your offices,
the port belongs to the workers!"
Come on!
"You can sit in your offices,
the port belongs to the workers!
"You can sit in your offices..."
- "We will not leave the port,
"don't waste your time!
We will not leave the port,
"don't waste your time!"
What do we do with that mess
you've made here?
We all know exactly
what has to be done.
The strike has been going on
for a week now, Avitan.
A ship is turned away
every day a ship is turned away
and every one of those is a lawsuit.
The European Union has declared us
as an At Risk Port,
and the movers want my head.
What do we all know so well?
The price. If you give in,
he'll crush you.
I've seen it happen more than once
to those who were here before you.
You have a lot of good people here,
who I learned to appreciate.
Fight this strike, for their sake.
You will have a brand new port
in a month's time.
No terrorism and no schemes.
The kind of port
we all would have liked to have.
We want Azulay!
Corrupted pigs! Corrupted pigs!
They got freelancers
to replace us!
You can't work here!
Sons of bitches!
- Come on, guys! -Motherfucker!
Motherfucker! You can't work here!
I'll kick your asses if you get off!
Go home! Go home! Go home!
We won't let anyone
take away our livelihood!
We won't!
Go home! Go home! Go home!
Bread! Work! Bread! Work!
I suggest to anyone who wants
to end this embarrassing strike,
to cross the fence
and get back to work. I repeat,
I suggest to anyone who wants
to end this embarrassing strike,
to cross the fence
and get back to work.
This is our port, not yours!
No one goes in the port.
This strike is illegal
and I'll do everything in my power
to put a stop to it.
We will not leave the port!
The biggest port in the country
will not be held hostage
by unlawful workers,
as senior and entitled
as they may be.
We will not leave the port!
Keep you hands off!
- Sons of bitches!
Why are you hitting us?
No, no!
Stop! Don't!
You son of a bitch!
Let go of him, let go of him,
you're killing him!
Let go of him!
- Let me take care of him!
Where are you taking him?
Listen to me, listen to me.
You go to Azulay right now
and tell him to call this off,
people are getting hurt. Go!
Go, Shlomi!
Azulay!
They fucked us.
They burned us to the ground.
They called the police-
to the port, Azulay.
They broke everyone.
Hey.
I'm so glad you came.
This is amazing.
What you've done here is amazing.
Excuse me.
Yes, Kravitz.
Take your things and go home,
you no longer work at the port.
I﻿'m sorry.
I'm sorry I had to call you, Avitan.
What's up?
Can't you handle things on your own?
I don't have the manpower.
I've got two tankers on the water,
with no one to show them in.
- Isn't the strike over?
They're at the Bris.
- What Bris?
Azulay's grandson.
Did you really think
the mess was all over?
As if that's the first time
he's ever done this.
Get some people together.
see what I can do.
I would like to thank you all
for dropping everything
to celebrate our
fifth grandson's Bris with us.
You are all part of my family,
and I love you guys.
Mazal Tov!
I am very pleased to see
my good friend, Aryeh Rosenberg,
from internal affairs. To you.
My good friend, Ben Bassat.
When this baby grows up, what will
he know about what used to be here?
Will he ever believe us if we
told him that was nothing here?
Nothing but sand?
Will he believe us if we told him,
that back in 1957, not even a dog
would pass by my parents' trailer?
Or that
of Jacques and Liz Pinto's,
or Shlomi Chohen's parents'.
Shiomi, here's to you.
We love you. -Or my good,
dear friends, rest his soul,
Morris Avitan,
and his wife Madeline,
may she live a long life.
Ben Guryion said: "There will be
a port here". So he said.
But it was your parents,
and you and I,
that turned his words
and this sand into...
Shabbat Shalom.
- Shabbat Shalom.
Enjoy.
You're not planning on opening
that bottle, are you, Mom?
I would like for you
to remove it from the table.
Excuse me?
You heard me.
Don't step out of line.
This is my house.
I am asking you to remove it from
the table. This is stolen property.
Remove it from the table.
This is a gift from a friend.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Grandma, I'm the first to admit that
Azulay has many rights around here,
but this isn't right.
Do you even know
what he's doing at the port?
I know what he did
when your grandfather passed,
and left me all alone
with two small children.
Fine, but that doesn't make it
any less stolen.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
Azulay has poisoned your soul.
Read her a bedtime story.
- What story?
This is what we're reading now,
"Good Night, Porcupine".
Alright? What else?
Isn't that the teddy bear I
gave you for your fifth birthday?
And change her before
she goes to sleep, alright?
I put the nappies
in the bottom dresser drawer.
I wasn't there
on that birthday, was I?
No. You weren't.
Well, I really am in a hurry.
Is everything clear?
Huh?
- Yes.
If there's a serious problem,
just put her in front of the TV
or something, okay?
Honey. Sweetheart.
I'm going now, okay?
You stay with Grandpa.
What? Are you okay?
What's with you?
I came back here for you, you know?
Why have you waited for so long?
I'm here now.
Just this once,
and with CEO's permission,
Don't worry, Avitan,
I brought this whiskey from home.
To the port.
- Cheers. -Cheers.
I spoke with Mishali,
he has agreed to close the case
with Elfasi, who ran the smuggling,
getting fired, and he said
he'll get rid of the Customs guy.
It's for the best, Avitan.
The most important thing
is that we get back to our routine.
You sent him a message.
Azulay knows
we're on his ass now.
I want him here,
I want him at the port,
he is good for the port
and he's good for the people.
Besides, he's a dead horse.
You took away all of his power,
he can't touch you now.
Don't you care at all
that we both put our necks on the line?
Ben Ami, are you trying to tell me
that you can really sleep at night
with that decision?
You can't be a vegetarian
when running a port, Avitan.
And thank you for your interest,
but I sleep just fine.
I hope you won't regret this
when you wake up.
Are you threatening me?
Take it as you wish.
I'm just telling you,
if you're planning on
getting Azulay back here,
you'd better find yourself
a good lawyer right now.
Come, have a seat.
What's the matter with you?
Why are you fighting me?
I've accepted the situation,
Ben Ami wants me back,
so why are you objecting?
This port is a place of business.
People come here
to work and make a living,
and you have corrupted it.
You turned it into your own backyard.
You and your thugs
have risked these people's
livelihood and their future.
You will not return to the port.
It's a real shame, Aaron,
because I really do like you.
No one can take away
how you helped my family out,
but that's it.
Your story is over.
That Customs guy that was suspended
was no more than a pawn.
You know the one who really
took care of things for me.
Nice long legs, blonde hair.
Sounds familiar?
Here's the deal.
If I go back to the port,
her secret goes with me to the grave.
But if I don't, kid,
her pretty face will be
all over tomorrow's papers.
She wouldn't be able to get a job
working for a dog.
I know I'll take the fall with her,
but I don't care.
Where have you been?
Where did you disappear to?
Azulay told me everything.
I was only trying
to make ends meet.
That's life.
There is no other way
to make do around here.
You can't refuse, don't you see?
What am I supposed to do now?
Do whatever you like.
Goodbye.
Here's the guy
I was telling you about.
Hello. -Aaron Avitan.
- Hello, hello.
This is the man who helped us
clean up the port.
That's no easy task.
Good on you, Aaron.
Thank you, Ben Ami.
What can I do for you?
Aaron.
Your fight has allowed me
to finally begin the transition
to the port's activities
as a privatized port.
The proper way, the way ports
are run all over the world,
no Unions, no thugs and goons,
a financial enterprise,
that operates on profits.
These are the representatives
of the business company
which will purchase the bulk
of the port's shares.
This is Ram Giladi, the CEO...
- Ben Ami, what's going on here?
Azulay.
The board has approved
the move yesterday.
We won. Ben Bassat, please.
Excuse me, Ben Bassat.
Ben Ami, what's going on here?
- Avitan, listen to me.
Thanks to the filth
you've helped me clean up,
the government and the Union
gave me the go ahead.
I've been waiting for this
for years now, and so have you.
I did not clean up the port
just so you could take it
and sell it to a bunch of people who,
with all due respect,
only care about making money.
- You're not listening.
I am offering you and Azulay the
opportunity to head a historic move.
I need you both,
there's a ton of work to be done.
You've seen the world,
you've seen your share of ports.
You know how a real port
needs to operate.
I know you would have wanted
things around here to be the same.
That is your dream, I know that.
- That's right.
But for the employees,
fortheir parents,
who built this port,
not for some Giladi Group,
that will fill the tugboats
with freelance workers by tomorrow,
who will work for pennies.
Work for pennies?
What are you talking about?
Zoom out,
don't think small, think big.
Think about the future. Do you know
how people talk about our port?
Do you know what the entire country
thinks about us?
Think about the benefit this move
will bring to the economy.
Avitan. Privatization,
isn't all about you, the good guys,
against the bad guys out there.
It's a lot more
complicated than that.
Here, ask Azulay
what he thinks about the move.
If it's good for the port,
I'm on board.
See? There you go.
Even Azulay thinks
this is a good move.
I don't.
I did what I did for the people.
Not for these people.
I am not your man, Ben Ami.
That's a shame.
Right.
Azulay. Avitan.
If you don't mind,
we will now move on
to the financial part of this meeting.
Stages of transition to a privately
owned and run operation.
The ideological part needs some more
work, that goes without saying.
I was wrong, Azulay.
But you will have to answer
to your people,
after you fire them all tomorrow.
Shlomi! Azulay! Azulay!
Azulay!
- Guys! Azulay is back!
Azulay is back at the port!
You don't have to stay on my account.
But I'm warning you,
Sivan's birthday is on April,
and I'll have your head
if you're not here.