(calming music)
- The thing is, I've
loved you from the moment
I set eyes on you.
Sorry, no, no, that was cheesy.
What I wanna say, what I've
wanted to say for months is,
I think I've fallen in love with you.
Well, what do you think,
was it really that bad,
if you were Aiden, would
you run for the hills?
If you could run, obviously.
You like playing hard to get don't you?
Yeah yeah you can grin.
Bet you've had millions of
people tell you they love you.
Whereas I've had...
(cheerful music)
♫ Well you fill your
days with a long schedule
♫ Come time to breathe,
you don't even know how
♫ Kids in white T-shirts giving free hugs
♫ In the name of Jesus,
the gypsy boy shrugs
♫ Sometimes I feel so lonely
♫ With all this love all around me
♫ Singing is human but the birds do it too
♫ And there's nothing better than waking
♫ To the red robin's tune
♫ Well the wind blows softly
but the waves crash so strong
♫ And it rattles your wind pipes
♫ And your voice sings its song
♫ Sometime I feel so lonely
♫ With all this love all around me
- So I need to tell you about Aiden,
he's scarily posh, but also charming,
grown-up, well-traveled
and impossibly intelligent.
Over the last month, the
urge to tell him how I feel
has become unbearable.
I can't put it off any
longer, I just need to find
the right way to say it.
I love you.
I love you!
I love you, I love you?
I love you, I love you!
I love you...
I love you.
- Thanks.
You're not so bad yourself.
- [Woman] Crap.
My first thought was to slide
behind the counter and hide.
My second thought was why
the hell did you do that.
- Hello, you okay?
You okay down there?
- Uhm, yeah, yeah I'm fine, I just...
Dropped my paperclip.
- Paperclip, okay.
Vital bits of office
equipment, paperclips, yeah.
Wouldn't wanna lose one.
- Uhm, how can I help?
- Is Mrs. Blackstock in?
- Edna, you wanna speak to her?
- Matt Jones.
- Beth, are you after a job?
- Kind of. Is she in?
- I'm afraid not, but I
might be able to help you.
Have you worked in a cinema before.
- Yes I have, a few actually.
- [Beth] Oh, any I might have heard of?
- CineFlex.
- Oh, which one?
- Oh a couple, do you want
me to list them for you?
- Oh yeah if you like.
- I'm sorry, I'm not being fair.
I'm the Southeaster Manager for CineFlex,
and we're expanding our
business to Brighton.
- Oh.
- I guess Mrs. Blackstock
hasn't come around
to talking to you yet?
- No.
- Ah, sorry.
Well anyway uhm, I should go.
It's nice to meet you, Beth.
By the way, I preferred
your final I love you,
it sounded the most sincere.
(groaning)
(upbeat rock music)
I swear mate, she
followed me to the cinema
I was visiting today.
I mean all I did was break up with her.
I didn't cheat on her, didn't
float with any of her mates,
didn't treat her badly, even
broke up with her face to face!
I split up with her three
weeks ago and since then,
she has turned up at my flat,
or my office every single day.
She posts notes through the
letter box, she's ringing
me all the bloody time.
She even e-mailed me some photos of her
to show me what I was missing.
- Naked photos?
- It's not funny.
- Call the police then.
- I can't, it's not like she's
threatening me or anything.
And anyway, what am I gonna say?
I'd like to make a complaint
because a beautiful blond
has threatened to shag me stupid.
- Yeah good point.
- So what am I gonna do?
- Well here's what I'd do.
Take her up on the sexual
favours and then dump her again.
- I don't know why I
thought it was a good idea
asking for your advice.
(upbeat pop music)
- [Beth] I still remember
the first time I met Aiden.
- Evening pimp.
You're looking a bit
rosy tonight, what's up?
Acne medication stopped working?
- Yeah I could say the
same about your shampoo.
- Not bad Beth.
Certainly better than
your normal insane drivel.
(phone ringing)
- Good evening Beth
speaking how can I help you.
- [Woman] Beth, oh God!
- Sorry hold on I didn't get
that can you say that again.
- Beth it's Lizzie, oh
God I need your help.
- Liz, I told you, you
can't call me at work.
- Ah I'm stuck, I'm stuck in a window.
- What, how did that even happen?
- I'm trying to escape.
He just a fabulous turn
into a Mr. Flatulence.
And he won't shut up, I
swear, he only pauses to fart.
I made an escape to the
loo, I can't breathe.
And well I had a
fantastical idea, and, well,
not so fantastic as it turns out,
now I'm stuck in a bloody toilet.
- Okay okay hang on, hang on.
(throat scraping)
Just don't go anywhere.
- Very funny.
- I'm sorry.
- What?
- Can I just?
(groaning)
- What?
- Bloody teenagers also,
they're taking pictures of me
on their mobile phone,
and I refuse to be on
You-bloodin'-Tube with my arse hanging out
the pub (mumbling), come
and rescue me or I swear
our friendship is over.
- Okay sorry, my friend is
stuck in the toilet, no,
no she's not stuck in the
toilet, she's stuck in
the window of the toilet,
she was on a date.
- Classy date.
- No, no, the date wasn't in
the toilet, it was in the pub
but she went to the
toilet to try and escape,
and now she wants me to go and rescue her,
but obviously I can't,
because I'm stuck at work,
and if do go, my boss is
probably gonna fire me,
but if I don't go, then
Liz is definitely gonna
chuck me out.
- Wow, it's okay.
Go and rescue your friend,
I'll take over the booth,
just run through what I have
to do and I'll pick it up.
How hard can it be?
- Really?
It was ridiculous really, there
I was sitting in the cinema
where I'd spent six years
of my life waiting for
Hugh Grant to walk through the door,
and here he was, almost
exactly 10 months later,
and I was gonna tell him
just how much he meant to me.
What could possibly go wrong?
It's fine, he probably
thought I said 10 o'clock,
I mean eight o'clock and 10
o'clock do sound a lot similar
when you mumble, which I
do, according to Aiden.
(phone ringing)
Aiden, oh, hi Mum.
- Delighted to talk to you to too.
- Sorry I'm expecting
Aiden, anyway how are you?
- I'm marvellous, thank you.
Look I just called to tell
you I've booked a ticket
to Australia for you.
- What?
- Australia, the flight's
on the 24th of December,
just think how exciting it'll be darling,
winging our way to a
new life over Christmas.
- Mom I've told you before,
I don't want to move
to Australia, I love Britain,
I've got loads of great
friends here, and not to
mention Aiden and a good job.
- A good job?
- Yeah.
- Printing tickets and
putting money in a till--
(door knocking)
- Mom I've gotta go, I think Aiden's here.
- About the ticket, shall I
send it to you or hang onto it?
- Mom I'm not going,
hopefully it's not too late
for you to get your money back okay?
- What?
- I've gotta go.
I'll speak to you tomorrow, okay bye.
- Beth!
- Bye.
Coming.
Oh, Aiden.
- Beth.
- You made it.
- You are dressed as a pumpkin, right?
- [Beth] Yeah.
- So there's something I've
been meaning to tell you.
- Oh well that's great, because
actually I've really wanted
to talk to you about something too.
- Beth, we need to talk.
I need some space.
- Sorry, sorry, say that again.
- [Aiden] I need some space Beth.
- Uh, space, right, great okay.
There you go, you got
like a whole extra metre.
- It's not working Beth.
- What's not working,
it's my outfit isn't it?
I knew that you would expect
me to be in something sexy
and not, you know a pumpkin,
so, don't worry, don't worry
I can just go and put on
my little black dress--
- Beth it's not about what you're wearing.
- Have I done something wrong,
is it something I've said?
- It's not you, it's got
nothing to do with you, it's--
- No don't say it, please.
- It's me.
- It's, it's fine, you've
obviously had a couple of drinks
and it's Halloween and
it's probably a full moon,
and you know what everyone's a bit crazy
when it's a full moon,
especially werewolves,
because you know they
just sit in the middle of
the field and howl, not
God, not that I'm saying
you're anything like a werewolf, because,
I mean I don't care what
Lizzie says, I like the bushy
eyebrows and they don't even--
- Please don't make this more
difficult than it already is.
- No no no, it doesn't
have to be difficult,
I mean you're obviously
just having a shit day,
and I love space, I mean, I, I
love space, I need space too.
- Beth I'm sorry, look, I
just, I needed to escape
you know, you're a
lovely girl, you deserve
a much better than me--
- But I don't want
anyone else, I want you.
- I'm sorry, really I am.
Perhaps it's best if I just go.
(sad music)
- Turn back, if I ever
meant anything to you
turn back and look at me.
Tell me you just made a huge mistake.
Aiden!
Aiden?
Aiden, I love you!
(alarm ringing)
(calming music)
- [Mrs. Blackstock] Hello Beth.
- Oh, Mrs. Blackstock.
Are you here for the takings,
because I can just go
and get them--
- No no uhm, stay where
you are, there's something
I want to discuss with you.
- Discuss, oh God is it to do with the guy
that came last week, Matt
somebody, because I swear
that he was a student after a job.
If I had known that
he'd had anything to do
with CineFlex, I would've
definitely gotten him a coffee.
- No Beth it's not that.
Beth, our cinema has not
been performing as well as
expected over the last year.
- No no I know that,
but we can get it back,
I know we can, and I've actually
had some really good ideas
which I've made a note of in
my book, and I can show you
that now, if you would like.
- No thank you.
- Okay so what about, a loyalty scheme.
You know watch five
films and get one free.
- Model our cinema on the
supermarket, no dear no,
that, that wouldn't do it at all.
- Well it works for them, and
I know it could work for us
if we just tried it.
No okay, no fine, not loyalty schemes.
Theme night, theme night.
We could show Eurovision,
people love that kind of thing
especially in Brighton,
and people could come to
the cinema all dressed up
with their friends and fans,
I know it would generate
loads of interest.
- No Beth these ideas are much
too modern for this cinema.
- No, no it's not, they'd fit right in.
- I'm sorry Beth, I'm selling the cinema.
- No, no you can't sell it to CineFlex.
- It'll be fine Beth,
Matt Jones has promised me
that they'll respect this place's history,
and they'll invest money in
trying to make it better.
- And you believe that.
- I'm sorry Beth, I've got no choice.
- Oh but...
What could I say, in just 24
hours I'd lost my boyfriend
and I was now about to
lose my job, what next?
So that's, that's it?
You're just gonna sell the
cinema and we're gonna just
lose our jobs?
- There is some hope,
there's a management position
available for someone
who has been working here
for more than two years.
- I'll take it, I've
worked here for six years,
so you just tell him that
I will have that job.
- All right Beth, I'll tell
Matt Jones to let you know
when the interviews are going to be.
Thank you Beth.
For all you've done.
- Balls.
(weeping)
(upbeat music)
(muttering)
- Of course...
Beth, oh...
Look, here, some more drinks.
- I just, I just miss
him so much, you know me,
and I, (mumbling), but I just
so want him back so much!
- Really?
- Yeah!
- Why don't you just watch
some of these bloody romcoms
you like, that'll put
a smile on your face.
Something where Gosling
takes his shirt off.
What about that, that stupid crazy--
- Crazy, Stupid, Love.
- Exactly, that one!
We can (mumbling) over those abs.
- Do you know, I'm just, I'm
just not in the mood for Ryan.
- Hey, hey now!
Let's not say anything
we're gonna regret now okay.
- Yeah I know, I mean,
you know what I mean.
- Yeah.
- But you know what?
He doesn't love me, so what am I gonna do?
- Honestly, honestly?
Forget about him.
- Yeah but I don't wanna forget
about him, I want him back!
- I thought you'd say that.
- What is wrong with me, you know?
- Nothing, nothing.
Just like Bridget
(mumbling), you're perfect
just the way you are.
- Well Aiden obviously
didn't think that, did he?
- That's because he's a raving dickhead.
- Is he?
- What, he is!
Look you deserve way better than him.
- Well you know what he said that too.
- Beth, you're well rid of him.
- Well that's the point
though, I don't wanna be rid
of him, I want him back.
Please Lizzie help me.
- How?
- Well tell me how I can be hotter.
- What?
- Well you know you can be
like one of those people
on a TV show where your
entire job is to make me look
like a total babe.
- Huh?
- You know think, think She's All That.
- What the hell is She's All That?
- Really, Rachael Leigh
Cook, Freddie Prinze Jr.
- Has anyone told you that
you watch too many movies.
- Oh please Lizzie.
- Fine, fine, fine.
Well, I mean, you are a little pale.
- Okay a bit of take tan then.
- Yeah, yeah.
And your hair.
I mean it's just...
It's kinda...
And you really, really
should learn how to use
a hairdryer Beth.
- Lizzie!
- Too far?
- Well no, no carry on.
- Look Beth you don't
need to do this you know,
it's not right you
changing the way you look
for bloody Aiden.
- No I'm not, I'm not.
- Really?
- Yes!
- Hmm...
- No.
- Uh-huh.
And well don't you think it's a bit soon,
I mean it's only been a day.
- Please Lizzie you gotta help me.
- Fine, fine, fine.
But first you must abide
by the two-week rule.
- I abide, I abide, what
is the two-week rule?
- I will tell you.
But you're not going to like it.
- [Matt] Hello, Granddad?
- What?
- Open the door!
(muttering)
- Matt!
- Hiya Granddad.
- Matt, if it isn't my
least-loved grandson.
Hey listen, I thought you'd
forgotten all about me.
- Fat chance.
- Well look are you gonna come in?
Or are you gonna stand out
there like some bloody prat eh?
- Charming.
- All right, yeah.
- Men, respond to distance, not words.
If you've got any hope of getting
him back, you need to give
him time to realise that
he has made a mistake.
Sending him a bunch of texts
telling him how much you miss
him is only gonna scare him off, you need,
to maintain an air of mystery.
So what we need to do is
implement the two-week rule.
Where you do absolutely nothing.
- Nothing.
- Hmm-mm, nothing.
Two weeks, you are forbidden
to contact him Beth.
- Forbidden, that's a
little bit strong isn't it?
- It felt like a forbidden moment.
- Okay.
- Do you think the reason
I'm 30 and still single
is because I keep running
away from commitment.
(coughing)
You all right?
- I'll be, oh, stop slapping
me on the bloody back.
- Sorry, you okay?
- Oh God yes.
I was just taken a bit back
from your question you know.
In my day, we left all
that mushy stuff to women.
- Sorry, yeah, forgot I said anything.
- All right, tell me.
How's business.
- Same as usual, working hard as always,
CineFlex are taking over a
new theatre on London Road.
- Oh the one on London Road,
oh God I do love that cinema.
Oh and that lovely girl who's there, Beth,
that's her name, Beth Beth.
She always, you know sorts me
out with a nice cup of tea,
you know, yes.
Eh, she's very pretty isn't she.
- I don't really know
her, seems nice though.
- And you know, Blondie?
- We split up.
- You sp...
Oh, right.
Another one?
- Another one.
- Yeah?
- No.
- Yes.
Well you know, okay, listen.
You're not getting much younger you know,
and I'd like to see you
settled in with a nice girl,
before I sort of you know toddle off.
- I'm very happy as I am, thank you.
- Oh yeah you'd be a
bloody sight happier mate
if you had the love of a good woman.
- Yeah and a bullet in the brain.
- Oh come on don't give me all that crap,
of all your friends
and all the rest of it.
Come on listen I know
you, right I know you.
You need the love of a good woman.
Listen in my day you got
married, that was it.
Better or for worse, none
of this running away.
No, Blondie, what's her name?
- Alice.
- Alice, right, Alice.
Now I'm right, right?
She was very fond of you wasn't she?
- Yeah.
- Now listen.
I don't know why you broke
up, listen I don't care
why you broke up but I
wanna tell you one thing.
Very difficult to find
a woman who loves you
in this world, they're
not 10 a penny you know,
and I should bloody well
know that I tell ya.
Look all right, you know my
eyesight, it's not very good.
But listen I can tell you're
not happy, no you're not.
Look tell me something, why
don't you give Alice a call,
yes, no, listen, right,
ask her out to dinner.
See if you can sort something
out over a nice, you know,
glass of wine.
- No I don't know.
- Oh come on, give the girl a chance.
Now listen if you don't wanna
do it for you, do it for me.
You've seen the signs on
the road, Help The Aged,
well that's me, I'm the aged.
You help me all right mate, come on.
(upbeat music)
- Read the affirmation
every night and then again
every morning when you get up.
I'd also like you to do it
aloud in front of the mirror--
- (throat scraping) Beth.
I need you in the bathroom,
time to pluck those brows.
- We're busy Elizabeth.
- I'm sorry.
- Apology accepted.
- Actually no, I'm not sorry.
See, I came to speak to Beth, not you.
- Beth is busy.
- Really?
Because she looks pretty bored to me.
- There is no need to be rude.
- You can talk.
- [Mother] What's that supposed to mean?
- You are always rude to Beth.
- You abandoned her to go gallivanting off
with any Tom, Dick or Harry
and then just expect her
to rescue you and you get stuck
in a bloody toilet window.
- You told your mom about that?
- Yeah but only because she asked me how
me and Aiden met and it kind of--
- Fine, I got stuck in the toilet.
But at least I'm not a bully.
- A bully, how dare you call me that!
- Yeah come on Lizzie
you can't, you can't call
my mom a bully.
- Well she is a bully!
You're bullying Beth to
go to Australia with you,
she doesn't want to go.
- Oh I see.
I get what this is all about.
You're afraid of losing
the person who picks up
all the pieces when you mess up.
- Mom come on you can't,
you can't talk to her
like that, she has been a really
good friend to me as well.
- I have, and that is why I'm
giving her this make-over,
because we're great friends,
and I want her to be happy.
- Why do you think I'm helping
her with this business plan.
I've agreed that she doesn't have to come
to Australia with me if she gets this job.
Whether you believe it or not,
the only thing I want from my
daughter, is her happiness.
- Fine.
At least we agree on one thing.
- Fine!
- Uhm sorry guys, I know
this is probably a bad time
but I've got a question.
- [Both] What?
- When was I supposed to wash the tan off?
- Shit.
(upbeat rock music)
- Are you okay?
- Do you know what I've been better.
- Is it your liver or something?
- Liver?
- I mean is that why you're that colour?
- Oh my God is it really that bad?
I knew Lizzie was lying,
I'm orange aren't I?
- So you're not ill?
- No!
- Oh, that's a good thing right?
- Yeah it's a good thing
that I look ill and I'm not.
- Uh yeah, I'm just here
to measure things up.
- [Beth] Measure up what exactly?
- Oh you know just
dimensions, ceiling heights,
that kind of thing, just to
get a rough idea of costings
you know, doesn't have to be exact,
the contractors can do that.
- You okay?
- Yep, just got away from
me for a second there.
- What would you wanna change anyway,
this cinema is perfect.
- Oh there's no such thing as perfect.
- There is, it's between these four walls.
Did you know this is the
oldest working cinema
in the whole of the UK, it's
not just a pile of bricks
and cement, it's a
living, breathing theatre.
Do you have any idea the number of people
that get lost in here,
it's not just a place
where you can come and watch a film,
it's a place where for two
hours you can completely
become someone else, and just forget about
all the crap in your life and just smile.
This cinema is priceless.
I'm gonna go and do a stock take.
Be careful with that tape measure.
(upbeat rock music)
- Jesus fucking Christ,
what happened to your face?
- Oh don't say a word.
- I only need one word, I'm just not sure
which one best describes how you look.
- What are you doing here
Carl you're not even working.
- I know, I just popped
in to see if you're going
on Saturday night?
- What is Saturday night?
- Proud.
- Why would I be going to Proud?
- For Aiden's engagement party of course.
- What?
- Oh...
Did you not know about it?
Well, she's a lovely girl, Fi's her name.
Bumped into her and Aiden the other night.
Blond, pretty, massive tits too.
Yeah, God, everyone who's anyone is going.
Oh, well you're not obviously,
anyone that is (mumbling).
You're out Beth, you
look a little bit peaky?
Is there such a thing
as a peaky (mumbling)?
Well, I'd better shut off.
I still need to get them
an engagement present.
Laters.
- [Alice] Hi Matt.
- Alice you're here.
- Uhuh, yeah!
- [Matt] Hi.
- Good to see you.
- And you, glad you could come.
Your hair's brown.
- Oh yeah I changed it, it's kinda sexier.
A bit more darker, it's matches yours.
His and hers hair?
- Yeah...
Do you wanna sit down?
- I'll just pull out my own chair.
- Yeah.
- I'm kidding.
- Sorry, I should've, yeah.
- I was just playing with you.
- I've already ordered
a nice bottle of red.
- Good, great, thank you.
- Yeah, okay.
So what would you like to eat?
- Pork belly for main and
oysters to start, to share.
- Do you know what, I'm
okay, I'm not the biggest fan
of seafood.
- Oh Matt come on, it would be romantic.
- I can't really I...
- Go on!
- Oh, here's the wine.
- Well I need to try it first.
It's okay.
Yeah it's cool.
Thanks, she's gorgeous isn't she?
- Oh I didn't notice.
- She had massive tits.
Why are you acting so weird?
- I'm not.
- Is there someone else you wanna be with
or somewhere else you wanna be?
Do you wanna be with the
waitress, just kidding.
- I was just thinking, do
you know what, forget it.
So, what are you having?
- I already said I'm having the pork belly
and we are having the oysters.
- Okay...
- Are you sure about this?
- Yep!
- How do you even know
you're gonna get in?
- Well I don't really.
- Okay, so let's just say
you've charmed your way in,
what then?
- I'm not exactly sure.
- Right, so lemme get this straight,
you are going to gatecrash Aiden's party,
his engagement party, and you have no idea
how you're gonna get in,
or what you're gonna do
when you get there.
- Pretty much yeah.
- Do you want me to stir, are you nervous?
- No.
- That's so cute.
I'll start.
- After you.
- Well, you can just watch me and learn.
Swallowed.
Go on your turn.
- So I?
- Yeah just, knock it back.
Oh for God's sake, just swallow it.
Fuck's sake.
Oh my God...
Are you gonna give me
something to wipe it off of me?
- Sorry.
- Oh my God.
- I am really, really sorry.
- Everyone is looking at me.
- It, it's fine.
I think it might've been an
allergic reaction in here.
- I cannot believe I've
sat here and really thought
that you were serious about
us getting back together.
I cannot believe I've fallen for it.
- Alice you didn't fall for anything.
But please sit down.
- What causing a scene
am I, well fuck you Matt,
I'm not standing around here
to be humiliated by you!
Oh, had all that lovely
wine and I didn't give you
anything for it, how's that, dick.
Dick!
- [Beth] I'm not gonna lie,
the two bottles of wine
had given me a newfound confidence,
and I only meant to have
a couple of glasses,
God, how did I get my life so wrong?
(soft rock music)
- Oh, Beth!
What are you gonna do now.
- Oh don't worry about me, I
know exactly what I'm doing.
- Of course, you'll do great.
(soft rock music)
- Oh sorry.
- Everyone, ladies and gentlemen,
a little hush if you please.
Ladies and gentlemen I
am absolutely delighted
you could all be here tonight, on this,
the happiest of occasions.
As many of you know.
- Twat.
- This night has been a long time coming,
and shrouded in secrecy
for obvious reasons.
But before we go to the main announcement,
there's someone I'd like you all to meet.
Mommy, Daddy, Granny, Gramps.
I take great pleasure
introducing you to someone
you thought you'd never get to see.
Everyone, this is Fi.
(applauding)
Beth.
- Surprise.
- What are you doing?
- Let me take that.
I'd like to say a few
words if that's okay.
So today is a really happy
day, a very, very happy day.
But the truth is, the truth is that,
it's actually a really sad day.
A very very sad day
indeed because, because,
well you've all been lied to.
Yeah and I, Beth Prince, I'm
here to tell you all the truth.
- Beth?
- Look stop it, stop it.
Stop pretending to everyone
that you're a nice guy.
- Beth I can explain!
- No shush, shush.
You!
This man, this man is a liar, and a cheat.
And, and he's been making love,
shagging the hell outta me.
And all the time he's been
pretending to be in love
with that woman.
(gasping)
Exactly, I probably
should chop his head off,
and I probably should off her head too.
But you know what, I'm not gonna.
Because I may be a lot of things,
but a murderer just is not one.
And so now, that man,
is going to marry that woman,
and I just feel like, it's, it's my duty,
to, to, to expose him
for the cheat and the
liar that he really is.
So there you go ladies and gentlemen,
Aiden Dowles is a
complete and utter, what!
- No one's getting married here.
It'd be quite wrong if Aiden
and Fi we're getting hitched.
- Exactly.
- They're cousins.
- Cousins?
- And Fi here has flown in
specially for my 50th birthday.
- Your birthday.
- Yeah.
- Carl!
Happy birthday Dad.
(upbeat music)
- Wow, happy birthday!
(sad music)
- Beth?
Beth?
Beth is that you?
What are you doing out
here, you must be freezing.
Here, take this.
Are you okay?
- You should go Matt.
- Why?
- Because I'm a loser.
- No you're not.
- I am.
- Why?
- Because I gatecrashed a
50-year-old's birthday party
and then made a complete
tit out of myself.
- I bet you didn't.
- Oh I did.
- Well then I'm sure that it
wasn't as bad as you think.
- It was.
- Oh yeah, well I bet
you didn't accidentally
spit an oyster in someone's face.
- You're just saying that
to make me feel better.
- No, right in the face.
(laughing)
- That's funny.
- She didn't think so.
- Do you ever wish that you
could rewind your life Matt?
- All the time.
- Life is messy, love is messier.
- Who said that?
- Jennifer Garner, Catch and Release.
- I don't think I saw that one.
- I think I might've
been the only that did.
So go on then,
tell me what happened tonight.
Why did you spit an
oyster in a girl's face.
- Long story short, I went out for dinner
with an ex to see if we
should give things another go,
and things didn't quite
go according to plan.
In fact things went so far off plan,
that they made a plan of their
own and then by the time I...
Beth?
(calming music)
- [Lizzie] Coffee!
(groaning)
Oh you look bloody gorgeous.
- Oh my God.
Please tell me that I did
not try and snog my potential
boss last night.
- You were in no state
to kiss your own hand,
let alone him.
I've never seen you so drunk.
Or (mumbling) for that matter.
- Yeah but I hit it,
tell me I hit it right?
- Yeah, eventually.
After you puked in the
bath, and the kitchen sink,
ah huh, you might wanna take (mumbling)--
(growling)
(coughing)
- Oh my God I am never
ever drinking again.
- Patties for breakfast.
(growling)
(coughing)
Sorry.
(calming music)
- [Beth] It had taken us
five hours on a minibus
to get to Swansea, and the
only thing I knew about Wales,
was that it was bloody freezing.
- Hi everbody, firstly, I'd like to say
thank you all for coming,
especially those of you
who aren't fans of leadership weekends.
Hopefully it won't be as bad as you think.
Now I know that there's
only one management position
available, but I still hope
that everyone takes something
out of the weekend anyway.
And as you know, it's gonna
be a mixture of group classes
and some one-on-one interviews.
So if everyone would like
to grab a bit of lunch,
change into your track suits,
and I'll see you shortly.
- Track suit, I don't even
own a bloody track suit.
Have you got an alpha I can borrow?
(rock music)
- Okay so we're gonna
do some warmup exercises
to get us all ready for
the rest of the day,
and I'm gonna hand it over to Bob.
He's gonna lead the exercises.
- Okay everbody!
Repeat after me!
Bananas, attention!
I said, repeat after me.
- [Group] Bananas, attention!
- Better, better.
Now go bananas!
(cloth tearing)
(laughing)
- [Carl] Banana split!
Banana split.
- Shut up Carl.
Here, take that.
Are you okay?
- I'm just gonna go back to the hotel.
- Okay uhm, just carry on Bob, it's good.
- Bananas, attention!
(electronic pop music)
(phone ringing)
- [Man] You have two new messages.
- [Mom] Hello darling,
how did the interview go,
I'd love you to get it, but
you know how I keen I am
for you to join me in
Australia, let me know.
- [Man] Message deleted, next new message.
- [Aiden] Hey Beth, it's Aiden.
Look I wanted to talk to
you about what happened
the other night, I dropped by your flat
but Lizzie said you'd gone away?
Where are you?
Please, call me back.
- [Man] Message deleted.
- Matt?
Matt it's Beth are you okay?
- Beth.
- Hi.
- Come in.
Would you like a drink?
- Sure.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- You can sit down if you like.
- We missed you at dinner,
is everything okay?
- My granddad had a heart attack.
- [Beth] Oh God, is he all right?
- He's still alive, which
is a good thing, right?
Apparently he's heavily sedated.
It just sucks that I'm stuck
here while he's all alone
in the hospital.
- The doctors will look after him.
- Yeah, okay.
Thanks Beth.
For checking I was okay.
- No problem.
I was just, I mean, we
were just a bit worried.
- Yeah, I imagine the boys
are (mumbling) to the booze
just fine without me.
- You could say that.
- It's nice to talk to someone.
- Is it?
- Yeah, it's not until something happens
to the one person in the
world that you really love,
that you realise how alone you are.
- You're not alone.
- Aren't I?
- No.
I mean I don't know who you've got,
but you must have so many
people that care about you.
- Do you know what?
My granddad says you were
kind, and he was right.
You're a very special Beth,
none of the others would've
thought to check up on me.
- How did he know I was kind?
Had he been to the cinema or something?
- Yeah, it seems you made
quite an impression on him.
He said you were pretty too.
- Oh.
- What's the matter?
Beth, hey look at me.
You are pretty.
Don't you believe that?
(phone ringing)
- [Beth] Shit, sorry, sorry!
- Oh that's you.
- Uhm, just a...
- Who is it?
- Uhm, no one, no one,
it's just complicated.
I think I need to go.
- No, you don't have to go.
- Sorry I need to leave.
Thank you, thank you, sorry.
- Beth!
Beth, Beth!
Granddad?
- Yes it's Granddad.
Oh well if it isn't my
least-loved grandson.
I thought you had forgotten all about me.
- Oh so you're the grandson,
I've heard a lot about you.
- He's been telling you
all my secrets has he?
- Now I wouldn't say that, but
I have heard a few stories.
I'll be back to check up on
you in half an hour okay?
- Not if I can't get you first, love.
- Promises, promises.
- All right then, come on, get in.
Oh dear, dear, dear.
- So how are you feeling?
- How am I feeling, I feel,
like I've punched in the heart.
- I'm really sorry that I wasn't there.
If I hadn't been in
Wales, if I'd been here--
- No, there's nothing you could've done.
I mean come on stop
talking like a bloody prat.
- Well I've been thinking.
Maybe I should move in.
- What move in with me?
- And I'll look after you.
- Are you joking, I would rather
have another heart attack.
- So what did the doctors say?
- What did the doctor say?
He said, I've gotta
stop me nightly tipple,
my sex life has gotta come to an end,
I've told all the women
you know, God did they cry.
And, ah yes, yeah, I
gotta start taking drugs.
- Drugs?
- Yeah, LSD last night, XTC tonight.
- Yeah very funny.
- Hey I'm rather looking
forward to it actually.
Hey listen no look, you got
a little glow about you.
Oh, yeah got a bit of totty
did you in Wales did you?
- Totty?
- Well come on talk to me,
it's not exactly buzzing
with bloody conversation
here is it, is it?
Who then, I know, oh come
on, it was Blondie wasn't it?
- No, not Alice.
- No, who then?
Oh come on, don't tell me you
don't know her bloody name.
- It was Beth.
- Beth, Beth, you mean cinema Beth?
Cinema, oh good on you,
she is a keeper son!
- Yeah anyway, would
you like a (mumbling)?
- Oh God yes I would,
listen, if you're gonna go
downstairs, would you go
and get me one of those
fruit bars and a sandwich
because, the food here is shit.
(laughing)
- Bacon and egg?
- Oh, I would kill for bacon and egg.
- Coming up.
- Okay lad.
- [Beth] Matt?
- Beth?
What are you doing here?
- I don't actually know really.
But I brought a card.
- I can see that.
- It's for your granddad.
- Right oh, uhm, he'll
love that, thank you.
He'll really appreciate it.
- Right I need to talk
to you about last night.
- Okay.
- The phone call that I
got, it wasn't anything--
- It's fine.
- No, no it's not, and I'm sorry,
I shouldn't have run off.
- Really I'm sure we'll
laugh about it one day.
And on the plus side I'm
pretty sure none of my ribs
are actually cracked.
- Oh my God I forgot about that.
- It's all right, sex-related injuries
happen to the best of us.
Come on, let's go and see the old man.
He's just in here.
- Oh hello!
Hey look, it's that lovely
girl from the cinema, Beth eh?
- I got you a card.
- You got me a card, oh isn't that nice?
You really shouldn't have done!
- Oh it's nothing.
- Really.
Let me have a look at it, oh that,
lots of love, Beth, I mean she loves me.
I've never had a get well soon--
- I'll put it over here.
- Thank you very much, oh, thank you,
I'll eat this after what they call dinner.
- [Matt] All right.
- Thank you very much.
So then Beth Beth Beth Beth, I uh,
I hear you had a bit of fun
with my grandson last night.
- Granddad!
- Well what's the matter,
what's the matter,
we're all adults here aren't we?
- Yeah, definitely.
- So you know Beth, let me
tell you something about life.
(calming music)
- [Beth] Matt's Granddad
was a real sweetie.
He told me all about his late
wife and how much he loved her
he didn't give a shit
about reality TV, fashion,
or Botox and he happily told me why.
He would raise his eyebrow
at the end of every sentence
which made me giggle.
He laughed easily and unselfconsciously
just like his grandson.
I could see why Matt adored him so much.
- Yes.
- I'm off.
- Oh, are you off my boy.
- Yeah.
- Oh!
- But I'll come back tomorrow.
- Yeah, oh yeah, yeah son.
Come here.
Be healthy eh, healthy.
- [Matt] Good night.
- [Woman] The vain thing
isn't really real you know.
And don't forget...
- [Both] I'm also just a girl.
Standing in front of a boy.
Asking him to love her.
(phone ringing)
- [Man] You have one new message.
- [Mom] Hi honey, it's your mom here.
So I haven't heard from you,
so I guess things didn't
go so well and you didn't get the job.
I'm sorry honey, but I think it's probably
for the best, so the
flight's on Christmas Eve,
just over two weeks away, write it down,
it's time you forgot about
that stupid film obsession
of yours and start a-fresh,
I'll see you soon darling,
and only bring one suitcase,
maximum weight 20 kilos.
Love you!
(door knocking)
- Coming.
Matt.
- Hey.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah uhm, sorry, I
shouldn't have come here.
- Did you wanna come in,
you must be freezing.
- Maybe just for a bit, if that's okay.
- Yeah of course it is, ah
but one condition though.
(calming music)
Um, how did you know where I live?
- I gave you a lift back in a taxi,
the night we met on the seafront remember?
- Right, yeah.
- Well this is a long shot,
but are you a fan of romcoms
by any chance?
- Well yeah, yeah you could say that.
- And let me guess, Hugh
Grant is your ideal man?
- Well obviously I love
him, but I wouldn't say
that he's my ideal man, I mean,
I'd probably take his
personality in Notting Hill
but then I'd Ryan Gosling's body
and young Richard Gere's face.
- That'd be a weird-looking guy.
- Okay what about you, what
about your perfect woman?
- I'd probably go with Angie's legs,
Scarlett's boobs, and bum,
and Monroe's face.
- And what about personality?
- Natalie Portman, yeah,
but she'd have to have
a dirty side to her too.
- Oh...
- Can I use the bathroom.
- Sure yeah, yeah it's just down the hall.
- Okay.
- Oh my God.
(calming pop music)
Oh yeah, smells good.
Come on!
- What are you doing?
- Too desperate?
- Why are you talking to
yourself in the mirror,
you never normally do this do you?
Oh she might think I'm having a shit.
Candles.
- Uhm yeah it's just makes it smell nice.
- Oh I wasn't--
- No no no, no it wasn't for that,
it was just, God I am nervous.
- Good, because I'm shitting myself.
- Why?
- Because I kind of like you.
- Kind of?
- Yeah.
- Are you drunk?
- No, you?
- I'm a little bit pissed.
- How many have you had?
- One or two glasses, maybe three by now.
Maybe I should?
- No, wow that was a desperate no.
- Well you did light a candle, so.
- There's so much stuff
that's messed up in my life
at the moment and there's
one thing that I know
I'm 100% certain of.
And that's that I don't want you to leave.
- [Matt] Why not?
- I just...
I just...
- [Matt] Just what?
(romantic music)
- Matt?
- Go back to sleep.
(sad music)
- Matt?
(phone ringing)
Matt?
- [Sheila] Oh hi Beth, this is
Sheila, I'm Matt's colleague.
- Oh, hi.
- [Sheila] I'm sorry to
the bearer of bad news,
but I'm afraid to say you
didn't get the manager's job,
I'm really sorry.
- Oh okay, is Matt there?
- Uh yeah just a second.
She wants to speak to
you, what shall I say?
- That I never wanna see here again.
- [Sheila] Sorry Beth, I'm
afraid Matt's in a meeting.
He did say to tell you that
you'll work your notice
until the end of December,
and you'll be paid
your finally salary on
your last working day.
Oh and uhm, if you need a reference,
I shall speak to Mrs. Blackstock.
- Okay.
Thanks.
(sad, calming music)
Ahem.
- Sorry can I get two tickets
for It's a Wonderful Life
please.
- Oh what's so wonderful about it?
- Sorry?
- Nothing.
Enjoy the film.
(phone ringing)
- Hi Beth, I understand
why you're ignoring me
but we really need to talk,
please call me as soon as
you get this.
Do you know what, you
look beautiful tonight.
Actually radiant, and
you're not orange which
is a good thing.
That said, I'd probably still love you
if you were (mumbling) coloured.
- Okay...
Okay no no no stop stop
wait, Aiden, Aiden.
- Sorry, I shouldn't
have gone for the boobs,
it's just I love them so much--
- [Beth] No Aiden, stop
look at me, look at me.
- You're just so sexy, and--
- Look at me!
You just said, you'd
probably still love me
even if I were (mumbling) coloured.
- Well yeah I would.
- I don't want probably.
- It was just a joke.
- No no I don't jokes either.
You said the word love.
- Well yeah.
I love you Beth.
Is everything okay.
- I don't think we
should get back together.
- Oh.
- Uhm, I mean I think it was unfair of me
to say that I'd give
it another go with us.
I was really confused and I am sorry.
But I think you were
right to break up with me
when you did, because
I was just pretending
to be someone I'm not.
I'm going to Australia.
I'm sorry, I'm leaving.
I'm moving to Australia with my mom.
- Oh, uhm...
Well I guess this is good night.
- I think this is a bit
more than good night.
(sad romantic music)
- You're going, aren't you?
- Yeah.
(phone ringing)
- Hello.
Speaking.
Are you all right?
I'm on my way.
(sad pop music)
What the fuck are you doing?
Mrs. Blackstock is Beth working today?
- Beth?
- Yeah Beth!
Is she working today?
- I'm afraid not.
- Fuck!
- Matthew Jones!
- I'm sorry, I just really
needed to speak to her.
- [Mrs. Blackstock] Is everything okay?
- I'm afraid not, no.
I've been a bit of an idiot.
- Oh I'm sure it's nothing
that a good old fashioned
apology can't put right.
- I wouldn't be so sure.
- Do you love her?
- What?
- [Mrs. Blackstock] Do you love her?
- Uh, I don't know, I
mean I think she's great.
But, love, well, that's a big word.
- I beg to differ it's quite a small word,
just four small letters, taken apart,
they don't mean anything
but put them together
and it's the most magical
feeling in all the world.
I knew as soon as I met my husband
that I loved him with all my heart.
How do you feel when you look at her?
There's your answer.
- I should've made Beth
manager of this place.
She had some great ideas,
she could've turned this
around in six months.
- I'm sure she could but she's quit.
- [Matt] Quit?
- [Mrs. Blackstock] Oh
she left a while ago.
- Where'd she go?
- [Mrs. Blackstock] Off
Down Under apparently.
She had her suitcase with her.
- So, so she's gone?
- [Mrs. Blackstock] I
think she's gone for good.
- I can't believe I messed this up.
- Do you believe in faith Matt?
- I used to.
- So what's changed?
- I met Beth.
- And that made you stop believing?
Oh, ah, there we go.
- No, it made me happy.
And a happy man doesn't need faith,
because he's already got what he wants.
- I think I know how to cheer you up.
How about a free ticket for the movies.
- What's playing?
- It's a Wonderful Life, what else.
- Of course it is.
Why not, you can drink
in the cinema right?
- Have as many sherry's as you
like my dear, on the house.
Don't give up on her Matt.
It is Christmas after all.
(upbeat romantic music)
- [Man] That's a Christmas present for
a very dear friend of mine.
- [Child] Look Daddy,
teacher says every time
a bell rings, an angel gets his wings.
- [Man] That's right, that's right.
- What, really?
- Hi.
(sad music)
- Have you been crying?
- No of course not.
- Can I see your ticket?
- [Matt] I don't have one.
- Did you sneak in?
- No, Mrs. Blackstock let me in for free.
- She did?
Why?
- Because I was sad.
- Is that why you were crying?
- I wasn't crying.
I thought you'd gone?
- I did.
But I came back.
- Why?
- Cameron Diaz, Julia Roberts.
Kate Hudson, they all come back.
- So who am I?
- You're the idiot that
has to try and convince me
that I made the right decision.
- I am an idiot.
Fuck no I'm worse than that, I'm a twat.
- Yeah, you are.
- I am.
I really am.
You didn't deserve the way I treated you.
You really didn't deserve that.
- So then why did you?
Why did you sleep with
me and then disappear
and refused to talk to me?
- Because of the sign.
- What sign?
- On your bedroom wall.
- [Beth] What about it?
- I saw it the morning after
we'd spent the night together.
- I didn't write that sign, my mom did.
- Your mom?
- Yeah.
- I didn't see that coming,
I thought that you'd had
written it and then the only
reason you'd slept with me
was to get the manager's position.
- Did you really think
that I would do that?
- I suppose deep down I didn't.
I panicked.
And I could blame my ex for
making me mistrust women
but the truth is,
that's no excuse.
I became the man that
I swore I'd never be.
I was Bridget Jones' Hugh Grant.
Not Four Weddings.
- Did you just make a
romcom reference for me.
- Yes, yes I did.
You know the job's yours if you want it.
- What?
- The manager's position
is yours if you want it.
- Are you joking?
- No.
You breathe life into this cinema, Beth.
It needs you.
I need you.
I don't have anyone else.
- Matt what's wrong?
What happened?
- He,
he passed away.
- Oh my God.
Matt I'm so sorry.
- You, you...
- Sorry, what was that?
- You...
Granddad knew you were the one.
He saw how nice you are, how special.
How beautiful.
He told me not let you go and then,
I let pride get in the
way and I fucked it up.
And I hurt you.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for everything Beth.
Let's just leave.
- What's this, well that's just it?
You're just gonna leave?
- What do you mean?
- This isn't how a romcom ends.
The guy and the girl don't
just go their separate ways.
- They don't?
- No.
What kind of an ending is that.
- A shitty one.
- Yeah.
A really shitty one.
- So how do you think it should end?
- Well, there's pressure now isn't there?
I mean we've just had
the whole over-dramatic,
I'm so sorry I shouldn't
have hurt you I should leave
speech, and you've got me up on stage.
And I don't even know if
a kiss would be enough,
it would have to be one hell of a kiss.
(muttering)
(cheerful romantic music)
- I love you.
Sorry, that might've be a bit soon huh?
I got caught up in the moment, and,
with being on stage and everything and?
- Has anyone ever told
you, you talk to much?
(cheerful romantic music)
(warm, cheerful, happy music)
♫ I wanted to say
♫ All the right things before I said
♫ All the wrongs instead
♫ Much to your surprise, well I
♫ I wasn't surprised at all
♫ Oh, oh, well it's such a beautiful day
♫ On the other side of the world
♫ Oh, oh I feel so young
♫ But my soul is so old
♫ So won't you cut a slice of
your life and hand it to me
♫ Well I don't like phone
sex but if we're on Skype
♫ I don't mind, seeing a nipple or two
♫ They say the heart
grows fonder with distance
♫ But that wasn't the case with you
♫ Oh, oh it's such a beautiful
day on this side of the world
♫ Oh, oh well I am so young
♫ But my soul is so old
(vocalising)