- Today's story ends.
It was all over the news,
It says Frankie Moore was troubled.
All that most people saw
was a homeless kid wandering
the streets.
A Killer on the run.
The truth as always is
far more complicated.
Frankie was just one of
the many dispossessed,
ignored, hated
but I knew him.
I was there at the beginning.
And I was there at the end.
- No batteries?
- It's not battery powered.
- How does it work then?
- Why do you want to know?
- I'm curious.
- Are you?
- Okay, bored.
- I built something
called a Stirling engine-
- Mm-hmm.
You're a clever one.
- I don't know
about that.
- Do you want to work for
my dad when you're older?
- An inventor.
Nowadays he says he's a philanthropist.
- What's that?
- If people build things
for him, he makes them rich,
that's what he says.
- Where is he now?
- In a meeting.
- He tells you you know?
- What's he going to do?
Run me over?
Come on,
Show me the rest of your town big guy.
- My name's Frankie.
- I'm Nicole not Nikki, or Nick or Nicola.
Don't you dare call me Nicola.
- You're funny.
Do you think fish have dreams?
- No fish are just fish.
- You don't reckon they
at the surface.
Everything looks so
different for them though.
- You know, I thought i met some
seaweed boys in my time but you.
Hey, daddy.
This is a pity you left.
But
fine.
I'm coming.
He's mad at me.
- Where's he now?
You know it?
- Just remember that my offer
does have an expiry date.
Mr. Langford.
- Frankie?
- Hi Mr. Langford.
- He is a nice chap Frankie.
- So why did you fry your start?
- Mr. Langford this is
my daughter, Nicole.
She's very much like me.
Once an idea occurs she
pursues it regardless of cost
It's our calling, helping
people build their ideas into
reality,
- As I said, I will
certainly consider your offer
Mr.
- We must be getting back to the city.
It's soon night after all.
- See you fish boy.
- My name is Frankie.
- So, how is your dad doing?
- He's fine Mr. Langford.
We're fine.
- Hi,
- I was playing with a
girl from out of town.
- Oh yeah.
- Why isn't anything like
that mum
- Franklin, we've talked
about that before.
Dad and I don't want you
hanging around there anymore.
- So, what's cooking?
- You're cooking mate.
- I thought was cooking.
Fish and peas
and of course I love fish and peas.
- Hey,
- Lot's of ketchup.
- It's great food love.
- Thanks.
It makes a nice difference
to fish fingers and peas
in front of the TV right?
- I love fish fingers.
- You can have them tomorrow.
brain food fishes.
- You looking forward to
going back to school Frankie?
- I guess.
- Remember what Miss Simon said?
You're right boy.
Don't you let your mind wander out.
- I reckon these teachers
are just jealous.
Probably wish that they had
as big an imagination as you.
- Just try to teach the
boy to be pragmatic Abbie.
- I'm sorry.
How'd it go at the
- How many times have I got
to tell you the day out there
is bloody slow?
- Yeah, well, Sunday for a
little while isn't it you know
what once we've got some more
money you can get a computer
or something and then or what
then then you can spend all
day looking for work.
- Don't you think that's
what I'm doing now?
- I didn't mean it like that.
- Maybe I don't have a
vivid enough imagination.
Sit down Franklin.
- Please may I go upstairs?
- What?
You don't want any dessert?
I will get you all some strawberries.
- Sure, okay.
- Why don't I do the washing
up and you get going on
to
- I love what you're thinking Mrs. Moore.
- Do you mind folding up the chairs?
- Eat nicely Frankie, no one wants a pig.
- Now leave him alone, he's a growing boy.
- He's growing into a pig.
- I
They are looking for engineers.
- I'm not an engineer.
I was never was an engineer.
- Yeah, I know but Langford-
- Langford was a shipbuilder.
Me I took the
Kansas and boathouse.
I wasn't a fucking engineer.
- I'm sorry I didn't think.
- No you didn't think.
And I don't want about work
no more again tonight, right?
- Now follow me.
- Aye, aye captain.
- Let me try to help.
- You can't help him.
And if you start talking about work,
think before open your mouth.
Allright?
I'm trying to think
practically about things
and all you're doing is fill
Frankie's head with nonsense.
You can go and rant it
jerky place.
You mollycoddled him all his life
and now he knows more
about things
than he does normal life.
- Are yoU ashamed of our son?
- Don't go putting words in my mouth.
Stop giving me shit.
I'm thinking practically
about these things.
You pat him on the head for
being a dreamer that is on you.
- Frankie,
why don't you go up to bed?
Hey, I will tuck you in
at night
- That is pathetic.
You are going to go up
upstairs and tuck him in like
he's a toddler.
- I hope you are happy with yourself.
- Do you?
- Our son has gifts.
And you are letting him down.
- I'm letting him down.
I'm fucking letting him down.
Allright, is that what you said?
This is your fault.
This is what you made me do.
- Not nice.
It's not right.
- Sometimes grownups fight Frankie.
Just like children.
- That wasn't a fight.
- One day I'll take you way far away.
When my boat full sized.
- That's nice.
This is the real life Frankie.
And he needs me,
The world is a cruel place Frankie,
I'm sorry for teaching you different.
And a cruel world it
can get in people's head
and make more wrong.
- Doesn't matter who he is.
I think a lot is what he does.
- I know that's quite clever.
But have I ever told you
how smart you are?
- All the time.
- Yeah just like granddad Charlie.
He was a one and
a dreamer and just like you.
I have to tell you, he gave me this.
- Yeah
- Yeah, he gave me this.
When you were born,
- Can you tell me please?
- Come here,
why don't you hold on to that?
Till the world becomes a better place.
Oh Frankie.
- Do you know where
your son is Mrs. Moore?
Mrs. Moore do you know where your son is?
- Right, just grab it and run
fast enough that I don't catch
up, slow enough that
the dog will snort you.
I will just need to
get distracted a while.
I need time to get in there.
- Just be quick about it okay?
- That's it boy, there you go.
- Hey, you plan on paying paying for that?
- I'm sorry I-
- Stealing off me?
- Please, you don't have any
problems of a little grill?
Sometimes it won't turn on.
- And your point is?
- You need to replace switch.
I can fix it.
- But in exchange for that
I'm going to give you popcorn.
Well come on then.
- You should have run faster.
That girl in the wheelchair, get her bag.
- Why?
Sick people have pills,
painkillers, stuff to sell.
Go.
- Frankie, stop.
It's you, isn't it?
- Yeah.
So, it's good to see you, Nicole.
- Frankie, is it true?
Frankie?
- He was hurting my mum.
- Meet me at front
entrance, tomorrow, okay.
Have you been sleeping on the streets?
- Yes.
- You are just a kid.
- Yeah and I'm like two
years younger than you.
- Exactly, I sleep in a penthouse.
- That's hard to believe.
- Frankie, you can't stay out here.
- I can't go home.
- So if you're in hiding,
why would you come on a busy playground?
- Where's the bag,
- Thief.
- Leave him alone.
- Either you swipe to or you didn't.
If you want to stay at
our place, come to me.
- I will call the police.
- Hey my little princess.
None of your business.
- Police
- Shit.
- Get yourself some
better friends fish boy.
- I better go.
I'm sorry
- Stay safe, okay?
I haven't seen you around
for a couple of weeks.
- Yeah,
They kicked us out of the old church.
- What?
- I barely had even the
time to gather my tools.
- You are still
parlor of yours
- Yeah, to the
riverside apparently there's
some safe place to stay.
- Or you could be sensible
and go to the hospital.
- Hungry?
- Look, this is why it's
going to work, right?
- I'm going to pretend there's
a problem with the grill.
You're going to fix it and then
I'm going to give you a hot
dog, we just skipped the ritual this time.
Boom
- Thanks man.
- Don't worry about it.
Just remember it's my birthday
next month.
- Get you a card?
- Never mind the card.
You just sort that hair out.
It's ridiculous.
- Piss off.
- Stay away from me.
All right.
I mean it.
I'm warning you.
- I'm just like you
I'm just like you.
Are you like me?
You know nothing about me.
Okay, I need this.
I need it.
- Go on look in the case.
- These are just tools.
What do you want me to do with them?
I need money.
Seriously, I need money.
- It's all I have.
- It's a doggy dog world mate.
Being nice will get you killed.
- I know you.
You used to run with Viv.
- Just calm down, man.
Calm down.
- Hey, babe
- Hey Nicole.
- Are you at yours?
- Yes, come over.
- Can I yeah, I'm not
feeling all that right now.
- Yeah, I just need
something to help me relax.
- Sorry, I didn't mean to scare you.
- I was just practicing.
- I wish I could dance like that.
- I'm I doing this?
Hey, let me show you some moves.
- Really?
Not ready to trust for that.
- It's all right.
What's your name?
Frankie Moore.
- All right.
I'm Jess.
Allright so have you ever danced before?
No.
Okay, so put your feet
together just like that.
And let's make the round
arms, round with further down.
- That really lifted my low.
I was just being chased before this.
Thank you Jess.
- Who are you running from?
- Those are different people.
Doesn't matter.
Happens all the time.
- That's not really an answer.
- It was better dancing than running.
- You must be hungry from all the running.
- No, no, no, no, it's okay.
- Come on it's just
and carrots.
- I'd love some carrots.
- Yes.
- Okay.
It's beautiful.
- Yeah, it's my favorite spot.
- Do you want one?
- Yeah.
- Nicole it's me.
- Frankie Moore,
and now I'm going to
leave you with nothing.
I want to hurt you
Take all of his clothes off.
all of them.
Take them off now, take them off.
- Off you bitch.
- Take them off.
- You need help my friend.
Come on.
You want to be more careful yeah.
- Hey
Frankie
get a burger and a hot dog or
whatever processed sludge meat
your friend gave you.
I'm just kidding you.
Your friend he's a nice man.
His food isn't worth a shit.
He's a nice fella
Nice tires over here out of
the way I might burn one later.
I used that that foil
wrapper and battery trick you
taught me.
A clever one I'll give you that.
Me I'm the handsome one
Shit Frankie, what the hell happened?
What happened?
No no no no no.
Talk to me.
- It's just Viv.
- Viv?
Did she violate you?
- No, it's okay.
- But we've got to do something.
In fact we need to call the cops on her.
- No
- we have got to do something I mean what-
- No, nothing.
- What else is it Frankie?
No, there's something else happening.
- Just saw
- Who?
Well, if you want to talk
I've got no place to go.
Put too much wood in there.
There's a tire in the bottom.
It might burn all night.
- Sounds allright.
- Sure is.
- Come on, come on friends.
One man's trash is another man's
treasure as they say, right buddy.
Point is ladies and gentlemen,
what you've been looking
for is right at your bedside.
And my good associate here
Frankie has repurposed
reconditioned and recycled
everything that you in fact need.
We have it right here.
Take a look take a gander
find what you're looking for.
Now everything looks like
a normal everyday item
But in fact, they've all
been reconditioned to fit in
your household very uniquely.
Something you won't find it
your department stores, no.
Something of very modern fashion.
It looks like an ordinary
camera at some point it made
memories but in fact,
it's been repurposed to a-
- Radio.
- What?
- It has been repurposed
to also be a radio.
So that while you're making
memories, you can play your
favorite melody.
Why in my day, we call
this in fact a slingshot.
It was quite used to take
down the occasional squirrel
for dinner.
Mark Twain, I think that'll
serve you quite well.
That's just one pound now.
Oh, thank you.
Bless you, ma'am.
Bless you.
- Thank you.
- All right.
Well, just remember one
man's trash is another man's
treasure.
Pretty good day.
- I enjoyed it thank you.
Sounds
- I suppose I do.
I always liked when I was a
little kid going to the circus
and seeing that guy down
the middle of the ring.
I guess I'm just a showman at heart.
- You are good at it.
- The main thing is we got
enough to replenish our supplies.
Get some real food.
I'm going to go have a look.
- Right back up.
- Strawberries.
- Chico, is that
I haven't seen him since last winter.
Chico
- I will be damned.
Prince.
You old rascal.
I haven't seen you in years.
Man play that song.
Oh, yeah.
What's wrong with these people?
Frankie, come on?
Come say hi to Prince.
Bless you
Thank you.
We will appreciate you ma'am.
Allright, thank you.
Hey not bad.
- Oh my God-
- Not bad at all.
- Oh my God, is this money?
- It's all yours.
- 30 years I have been doing this shit.
I couldn't make a coffee sometime.
And you come along, dance like an idiot.
And making me some money
- I aim to please.
Good to see you brother.
- Good to see you bro.
Frankie is still hanging
around with this old brat?
- Yeah, well, you know Chico,
it's always entertaining
friends.
- Who are two friends here?
- Man.
Let me introduce you.
Eva.
- Hi.
- She came to this country
looking for a better life.
And a friend Al.
He just left the army.
- Good to meet you.
- We been sleeping in
some abandoned buildings.
Not too far from here.
- Yeah?
- At the edge of the Industrial Estate.
- Frankie and I were
thinking about heading
to the waterfront.
They got some places down there we hear.
- My brother from
another mother
- Brother from another
mother man.
- If I don't see you
tomorrow, hello today.
- You got it going on dude,
you got the dancing going on
man.
You need some lessons, dude.
Frankie, pleasure man.
- This feels weird.
I don't exactly have my sea legs
- I always pictured myself
sailing away on one of these
things, you know leaving it all behind it.
- Really?
Is it possible to be seasick
if you're technically
still on land?
- Jeez, Frankie.
I mean, I know your fascination
with machines, but I've
never known you had interest
in boats.
- Yeah.
I made a promise.
- Promise is a promise.
- You allright?
- Yeah.
- Nice digs.
- You should go home mate.
- It's nothing.
It's just a tickle.
- Just a tickle?
I want to talk to you about something.
I don't know.
Advice, I suppose.
- So you are going to ask
a bloke who sells hot dogs
for a living for advice?
I'm not the brightest
bulb on the bubble mate.
- Yeah, but you've lived
much longer than me mate.
- Well, thank you very much for that.
So what is it young man?
What is it that's bothering
you apart from the whole
destitute thing?
Just got me thinking.
- I'm sensing a question.
- Just how long is too long?
I know you think if I could I just
go home.
- Why are you asking me this?
Why don't you ask your pal.
- Chico is
he's involved and y'all know Gavin.
- Oh, so the only person you
could think to talk to is me.
- Well, I think your
answers right then mate.
When the only company you
can keep us in an old fool,
then perhaps a journey home
is exactly what you should be
doing.
You're lucky enough to
have a home to go home to.
- Nicole.
It's me, fish boy.
Frankie
- Frankie.
- I won't bite.
Do you mind to go to a walk with me?
Look I'm about to meet a friend.
You will like him, he's nice.
Would you like to come?
Let's see where I live.
it's not nothing special but
It's a home.
- Yeah, sure.
- Cool.
- Where is it?
Here?
- They are good people.
Very good people.
- So yeah, I felt it was
pretty much the last place
we saw each other.
So I guess that means,
you've known Frankie longest.
- Yeah.
- Tell me something.
Was he always this fucking boring.
I mean boy is boring, right?
- I haven't seen fish boy for so long.
- Fish boy so you notice the smell too?
- What?
I don't smell.
- Are you kidding me?
Seagulls fly around thinking
you're a big sardine
waiting to pick your eyes out.
- Sorry listen, I suppose
that is your friend.
- I'm not the one being called fish boy.
Right?
I mean, it smells like a fish.
I think it will be a
little hard on Frankie.
Old lads been picked on enough.
Prince,
Play that song.
- Do you mean the one you like?
- You know, yeah, the one I like,
play that one.
- No problem dude.
No problem.
- Check it out man.
- I like him.
- Chico.
- Yeah.
- Yeah he's great.
- When you live like I do.
It's good to have someone
like that to have your back.
- That's what I want to ask you actually.
Have you been out on the
streets all these winters?
- Yeah.
- State has some shelters.
roofs as big as this one.
Keeping a low profile when you're homeless
pretty much invisible to most people.
- So what you energy goes
just traveling around now?
Wait, you said you can
remember you me as a kid.
When did you meet them?
- Three years ago.
Left his job just walked
away from his old life.
- Wait, he just willingly became homeless?
That's insane.
- I just wanted to be
where people were Nicole.
Where tools were, build my things.
Besides me and Chico
make money for supplies.
- So what, you two just
been piling around together
ever since?
- Yeah.
- As I'm a psychic.
- You were always a serious young boy.
- Those were serious times Nicole.
- Do you ever think about your dad?
- Obvious.
- Your mom
- Had a boyfriend, had a girlfriend.
Had a better boyfriend.
I lost the
for about six weeks.
- it's pretty funny full
book about investment.
- My dad will love him.
No matter how hard he makes it.
- Things okay with you guys?
- No.
Kind of
I love these things.
- Do you want to buy one?
Allright, maybe a bit later.
- Does your dad hurt you?
- What?
No, nothing like that.
Frankie he is not an evil man,
I just wish he cared less
about profit margins.
That's all.
- I wish you could do
something about all of this.
You know you me.
- Not everything can be repaired.
- I know.
- I've got to go.
- Nicole, What have you been taking?
- Dad-
- What have you been taking?
What have you taken?
I have called the ambulance.
- Give me my phone.
- I just called the ambulance for you.
You need to get some help Nicole.
I'm just looking out for you.
- I'm going to go.
Check on the ambulance.
- I've been there.
I've been there Nicole.
Don't kill yourself.
Let me help you.
Okay.
I have been there.
Okay, listen I have to go.
- No, don't go.
- The next
few weeks were tough.
I wasn't going to rehab.
Not this time.
was a gesture nothing more.
I needed places to get more.
Sometimes I did get more.
Data for counselors and
doctors Frankie gave me
the helping hand and
the shoulders to cry on.
To my father, my addictions
were an embarrassment.
To Frankie they were
a problem to be fixed.
Neither of them totally understood.
At least
- The script that got me fixed.
Tried maybe one of our cronies.
Serious Nicole.
That's what you got right.
Snuck a voice that just
comes in your head.
- Well, I've been getting help for that
from my online group.
their advice
is not anything I have known
before.
- It doesn't mean it's
not going to work Nicole.
. No, I have no easy answers for you.
Look at me, all I could
do is just be your friend.
- What did you do when the lights came on
- Build things.
- Sometimes weeks had passed
where I wouldn't go to him
at all.
We didn't always talk.
He helped me by just being.
Just to me
- Yeah it is fine.
They are my friends.
Right,
- Hey
- Listen I'm sorry about before.
I wasn't really thinking straight.
The way I see it if we start
stealing from each other
we're screwed right?
The world has taken
enough from us as it is.
That's no excuse.
You gave my toss back.
we are good.
- Allright.
I'm PJ.
- Frankie.
- They already see us as thieves.
So different tools.
Other than a few missed bills
away from being right here.
- PJ you haven't been
homeless long have you?
- If you told me two years
ago that I was going to end up
living like this I would
have laughed in your face.
I had my own bar, believe it or not,
fiance, a plan.
But I was too quiet for too long.
Bills kept coming in.
Wedding was delayed
I was bankrupt.
I was alone.
Don't take much for everything to unravel.
- Just takes one thing, right.
- So what happened to you?
Just one thing?
- No.
Hey another word.
- Chico's over there.
Hey.
- All right.
- Hello.
- Hey, Miss Nicole.
- How are you feeling?
- Feeling okay.
- How are you doing?
- Good.
- Chico can I ask you something?
What if
you walked away from your life.
- I don't like to talk about that.
- Okay, I'm sorry.
- Don't ask me.
Heavy burdens Miss Nicole.
Heavier than the weight
of the world on your back.
around your neck.
I wasn't always on the streets.
I had a life,
a family.
- The green ones are my favorite.
- Allright, they are
your dad's favorite too.
- Ho ho ho, merry Christmas.
- Daddy.
- Hi, pumpkin.
Hello.
Are you all right.
- Yeah, I'm good.
How are you?
How is it out there?
- Terrible.
It's madness.
I'm not even kidding.
I mean
literally people are mad.
Traffic, that's awful.
But this tree is fantastic.
- Thank you.
- We did a good job, didn't we?
- I think so?
- Mm- hmm-
- I think you couldn't
have done it by yourself.
I'd say that we've got a
pretty good helper there.
And it was cold outside.
You know what's worse?
Crowds.
- Yeah.
- Mayhem
- Daddy would forget his
head if it wasn't attached
to his body.
I've already been out
the shops quite a bit,
getting things we don't
need like wrapping paper...
Who wraps gifts?
- Santa and his howls.
- Santa!
- Yeah, me too.
- Bye daddy.
Get some sleep.
- Sweet dreams.
- Don't get too long.
- I won't.
I love you.
- I love you.
- Merry Christmas
- Merry Christmas.
- We are finished.
Yes, good girl.
Dad
- Yeah,
fire brigade.
There's a house it's
completely up in smoke.
Three people I think.
- Stop.
- Beautiful wife.
An angel for a daughter.
I don't have them anymore.
They're gone.
So after that, I didn't want
to live this life anymore.
I wanted to take myself
out of the equation.
Just didn't make sense to be here.
I don't know.
I might have been looking
for some reason to stay.
One day I found it.
Several years ago.
I was squatting at this
place where I would
do some bad things.
Are you doing all right?
- Oh shit, Chico.
Bloody mate.
- What?
- You are shitting me, right?
You live in here?
- No.
- You did a good job.
- Come on Chico, I
Come on, I want some things.
- There was a little boy there.
- Frankie?
Did I hear you say Frankie?
- No.
I didn't save him Miss Nicole.
I had some training.
I actually did what I could, I tried out.
I didn't know what I was doing.
I was scared.
Frankie saved himself
- No, Chico you saved him.
- No.
- Yes.
His strength to survive
is what saved Frankie.
He is such a bright light.
- Yeah, he is.
- Well after.
We got together, we bonded.
We were in the streets together.
He makes these contraptions
he invents these crazy things
that people love off the streets.
I mean they're fantastic.
Really and I sell them
I got the gift of gab,
And that's how we
make our money and get by.
It isn't a bad life.
- Frankie.
He had nothing
Nothing.
He was on the streets and on the run.
Me I started using because I was rich.
And spoilt.
And I hate my dad.
Coming
here was a big mistake.
- No Miss Nicole, don't do that.
- You've been through so much Chico.
You can't keep running from yourself.
Funny thing that you're
always with yourself.
- Chico, some people live in such shit.
And some people live without a care.
This all just feels so damn wrong.
I'm exploiting you.
You shouldn't be helping me.
- Nicole?
- Yeah.
- Where are you going?
- I just need to be alone
for a while Frankie.
- Let me help you.
- I just need to help myself.
Wait, I got you
something
Early birthday present.
I'm getting good, huh?
Meet me at the bridge in an hour.
- Okay.
Hey
- Hi mate.
- Yeah.
- what can I get you?
- Can you get me Gavin?
Give this to him
- He passed away a few days ago mate.
I'm sorry.
- Of what?
- Pneumonia.
He always liked cards.
- Frankie.
It's your mum's new address.
Frankie, I haven't seen her for 10 years.
- Thank you.
Hey bro.
- You just fuck off allright?
Just get on, just fuck off.
- I'm just a friend.
Same situation as you,
you can't stay here.
- I don't give a shit.
You just leave me alone yeah.
- Do you want to go to a
safe place man, come on
You can trust me man.
- Why the fuck should I trust you, huh?
Just leave me alone, just fuck off.
Help me, wait come
here, this is my friend.
- Is she all right?
- Viv, what happened?
- I thought you guys were friends.
- Friends?
Friends is what you have or not me.
- Where's Ryan, Viv?
Where's he?
- Frankie,
on time but I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
It's okay.
Please, come, on.
- What the fuck.
Get the fuck off me.
- Grab him.
- Just fuck you.
- Fuck you, I'm going to fucking kill you.
- I got it.
- Get off me.
- What are you doing?
- You deserve worse than this fucker.
- Fuck, I will fucking kill you.
Go, Frankie go, go.
- You fucking pig.
- Thanks, allright?
- Is that all you have for your hat?
- That's okay, you can give me
more when you make a fortune
some day.
- Deal.
- I want a big house a hot tub
and my own recording studio.
- Recording studio?
- Yeah.
It's not what goes to them, isn't it?
Beg, sing, sell magazines
and they just walk straight
past us.
- Don't forget about the ones
that speed up when they notice
you.
They look at absolutely anything
in the street as long as
they don't have to look your way.
- I think it's easy for them.
To pretend to themselves
that they just don't see us.
- When they look at us they feel guilt.
Nobody likes to feel guilt
- I suppose.
I felt like they need to help
us and everyone has their own
problems I guess.
So it's easy to blank us and just move on.
- Sometimes part of me wants to hate them.
Walk right up to them and
yell until they can ignore me
anymore.
It's the kind of thoughts
that make you sick.
So instead of yelling I sing.
I sing and every once in a
while someone tosses me a coin.
- I did something bad.
A long time ago.
Every time people ignore
us it feels like judgment.
- I could just trade one
prison for another, right?
The attitude to you doesn't define you.
You do and then the only
person you can answer to is
yourself, allright.
If you've done right by
the people you care about,
you will know it.
If you haven't you'll know that too.
So if you feel like you're being judged
it is is because you're judging yourself.
It's your life.
maybe it's time you face
what you've been hiding from.
- What are you fucking looking at?
I said what do you fucking looking at?
- Nothing I'm sorry.
- So what do you want then?
A punch?
Money?
Because I haven't got no money.
- I'm sorry.
- Where's my manners?
- Come on have a drink.
- I'm good.
Thanks.
- Do you think you're better than me?
You are going to fucking drink it.
- Why don't you just go.
- I swear, on your life, if
you don't fucking drink it.
I want to fucking
- Why don't you just leave me alone?
- Yeah.
- Drink the fucking drink.
- You bastard,
You fucking bastard, I'm a veteran.
And I fought for this country.
- Yeah.
- So what's your point?
Soldier.
- That I deserve-
- What, deserve what?
Look at you.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
You dirty, filthy
So come on then soldier.
Come on then.
You fucking, dirty, filthy
- Wait, what are you doing?
Leave him alone man.
- Now what are you, I'm
going to have to punch you.
What are you going to do?
- I hate you.
You're a mess.
- Look at you, you are a
waste, you are a drunk.
You know what, I wonder whether
one day, you don't end up
like one of us.
- The boy has become a man.
And the man has become a
- Allright.
You haven't told me about this.
- No
- Good.
I've got some good news on-
- I found my mom's new address.
- What's the bad news?
- Chico, I found my mom.
Nicole, she's found my mom's new address.
I think it's time for me to go home.
I wanted to ask you, would
you like to come with me?
- Well, from we hit the
open road, my advice
to you is pack right.
Sleep fast.
Goodnight Frankie.
- Allright.
Probably don't understand
a word what I'm saying.
- My English is pretty great.
Thank you.
- Sorry.
- I've watched you these past days.
A lot is on your mind.
- Yeah.
I stopped a bad man
from hurting my friend.
And I'm going home.
- Where is home for you?
- I don't know.
It's a house that I've never seen before.
- You're weird.
- You're not the first to tell me that.
What about you?
- I was from
Romania.
- Come here.
- What are you all about?
It's my turn.
- Yes.
Very wrong.
Now you tell me a bad English word.
- Arse hole.
- Like arse hole.
You, arse hole.
- Yeah.
- I want to know every English insult.
- Idiot.
- Like idiot.
- Dickhead.
- You are a dickhead.
- It's my turn.
- What are you on the about?
It's my turn.
- I'm not playing.
- James stop playing, you
are always cheating man.
- We didn't even have
enough money for food.
He wanted me to do things for money.
- Sorry.
I don't want to say.
- Well, I knew what to say to him.
Go to your home Frankie.
Then go to see your friend, the lady.
- Enough about helping her.
Just be there.
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
- Rise and shine.
Let's go Lover boy
burning daylight.
Road trip.
- What's wrong?
- This is silly this.
Sadly I haven't seen my
mom in a long time Chico.
- Well, it's a little late
now Frankie and me were pretty
long ways up the road.
- Look, Frankie.
If I would give anything.
For the chance to go home.
Still, I can see why
you're a little hesitant
about leaving after last night.
She's pretty cute.
- We are just friends nothing happened.
- Friend?
Mate, that's what you said about Nicole.
We passed the threshold.
- You think so-
- Frankie Moore.
You sold me out man.
It's on you.
- Promise me.
Honestly, I just wanted to
leave this message just to let
you don't need to worry.
We've been planning this
party for the last two months.
Honestly, everybody's
put so much effort in.
Everyone's going to be there.
It's not going to be a big deal.
It's just...
It will be all right.
Okay just...
Shit.
- You promised me you is
going to come see my mom?
- I know I did, Frankie.
I'm sorry,
Sometimes life flips the script on you.
I wanted to introduce
And I knew that's my mom.
- I know Frank.
I wanted that too.
We had our ride and listen,
we couldn't have done
it with anyone better.
You are such a bright
light Franklin just keep
shining on this won't we?
You go and see your mom.
- Hello.
- Mom it's me.
Frankie.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Yes mom.
- Need some toast?
- Yeah, sure.
- 11 years, Frankie
11 years.
- Mom,
I always said I was going to come.
After what happened for you to hate me.
- Hate you?
I could never hate you.
I called the police that night
because I want you to found.
I wanted you safe.
Come sit down.
Do you know what I think every day?
is he alive today?
Will it be alive tomorrow?
I kept on thinking you're going
to walk through that door.
I even stayed in that opera
house because I thought you'd
come home.
Your dad's death did not have
to be the end of your life
Frankie.
Okay.
So the way to see
Just wanted to know if you were okay.
Oh, God, Frankie, what
else have you been through?
- It doesn't matter.
Mom, this is really hot.
- Okay, I'm sorry.
- You got water?
- Yeah.
Here you go.
- I love you mum.
I love you so much.
- I love you too Frankie.
God I love you.
- Have you got any mayonnaise?
- Yeah.
Some things never change hey.
- As far as the world's knew
Frankie Moore was a young boy
who brutally killed his father
and fled to the streets.
That was the only story
most people ever heard.
But for those of us who knew
him, it was a different story.
We knew a guy who'd always
tried to make things better.
Today, his story ends
- Are you sure you are ready, mum?
This is what he'd have wanted.
- Mm-hmm.
- Welcome home, fish boy.
Welcome home.
No, I don't want to leave you
I don't want to say goodbye
You don't want me to feel the pain
And I don't want to see you cry
So let me be there for you
I will be right by your side
All through until the sun goes down
I will house you until you are around
Until you are around
So just be positive
I know you can do this
All we have to do is just be you
You will make good friends in time
And you will start to find
All you have to do is just
Be you
Just be you
You don't have to feel low
I don't have to feel this way
So for me I will my darkest hour
Just know with me you will be okay
Let me be there for you
Know, Cause everything
I know this place don't feel so lonely
I'm on your side
there's no thing to fear
So just be positive
And know you can do this
All you have to do is just be you
You will make some friends in time
And you just have to find
All that you have to do is just be you
Just be you
In lightning like this
Not without a fight
I will never let you go
In lightning like this
Not without a fault
Never let you go
So just be positive
And know you can do this
All you have to do is just be you
You will make good friends in time
And you will start to find
And all you have to do is just be you
So just be positive
And know you can do this
All you have to do
Is just be you
You will make good friends in time
And you will start to find
All that you have to do
Is just be you.
Never looking back
I will soar again
No hill so high
No mountain too high
Above the clouds
Well the mountains and rivers
Not bowed every time
And the youthful hills
And the rivers show
The thing I will
Don't you run away
Don't you run away right now
I gave you pieces of my heart
The world taught
Like don't run away
I see your smile and your face
In my mind all the time
But not until a while
To pay the token for you right now
So don't you run away
Don't run away
Don't you run away
Right now.
So don't you run away
Don't run away
Right now
Come back to me
I will change you today
Don't you run away
Run away
One today
I found these
No mountains too high
No hills to high
Well the mountains and the rivers
Are there all the time
So come back into my life now
Don't run away
Don't you run away
Right now
So don't you run away come back
Don't run away right now
Come back to me
No mountain too high