How lovely!
Sir?
Sir!
Where is painter Heo Sek's house?
I heard it's around here.
There's a house
up the hill that way.
Thank you, sir.
Excuse me.
Oh my.
Are you Heo Sek, sir?
Isn't it pretty?
How did you arrive here faster than me?
I took the shortcut.
Why not walk with
me in the first place?
I got lost.
Then I'd want to hold hands.
Silly old man...
Is he senile?
He really is a painter.
What a peculiar drawing.
What's so peculiar about it?
Why is a little boy
surrounded by gisaengs?
Men are jealous of that boy.
Men and gisaengs...
Oh my.
I don't know who the boy is,
but I can guess how he turned out.
That little boy is me.
What? It's you, sir?
Why were you with gisaengs?
Curious?
I'm not that curious.
Very well, then.
I'm curious.
I was born in a gibang.
A gibang?
The gisaengs were my family,
and the flowers were my friends.
I was born the son of a gisaeng
and was a gibang boy
who grew up in a gibang.
What happened? Why?
What did you do there?
How long?
Why are you here now?
Why are you so curious?
Well, it's to pass time
as you draw me, sir.
Now, shall I begin?
What?
Do I look weird?
My eyes...
You're dazzling.
Goodness.
You're being silly.
No. This is wrong.
What are you doing?
Take off your slip.
What? Even this?
Wearing this won't hide it.
Hide what?
Your beauty.
- Goodness!
- Oh, no!
Your beauty is slipping through!
Here. And here.
- Stop!
- And here.
Aunt! Wait!
Listen to me!
Carry on!
Hello!
I can explain!
Follow me!
You slimy fool!
What do you mean?
You loaf around and do nothing!
You womanizer!
You flirt with family now?
You filthy bastard!
I wasn't flirting!
I was just asked to draw her portrait.
A portrait.
A portrait? Don't fool me!
Though you can't work for the state,
try to be successful!
Why aren't you studying?
What success for a
humble son of a gisaeng?
Why would I study
if I can't take the state exam?
You can take the translator exam!
It was your mother's wish.
What?
They're words from Thailand,
a country far south of China.
Aunt.
It means, "I just want
to live an idle life."
Come in, Gap-deok!
- Throw him out of my house!
- Aunt.
But...
I've been patient with
you as your mom's friend,
but no more!
Throw him out at once!
Think of your friendship
with my mother!
Aunt! Please! Stop!
Aunt!
Don't call me Aunt!
Madam...
Saw that?
Then I'll go hang out.
Sek?
Sook-jung.
Are you all right?
Don't worry.
She won't be angry
if I return a few days later.
Sweetheart, listen well to the others.
And eat well.
Come back soon.
- See the flower in his hair?
- He's beautiful!
Kim Nam-hoon's wife, Park.
Ko Tae-young's wife, Kim.
Kang Hun-woo's wife, Lee.
Choi Mun-chang's wife, Shim.
Lee Chan-nam's wife, Park.
Shim Yeon's wife, Lee.
Virtuous Women Hall
Virtuous Women Hall?
Preposterous!
- Pain...
- Pain is borne by women,
but others receive the credit.
It is bestowed on them in praise
of being chaste and devoted...
Wait, my lady!
My lady? Who is she?
I should've asked for her name.
What?
Why are you here like that?
Ever heard of the Way?
No.
I'm an ascetic who lived in the
hills and sought enlightenment.
Just before I reached perfection,
I met some bandits.
Oh, you're not a bandit? I see.
Still,
why walk around like that?
Come empty, return empty.
You're born naked and die naked.
What good are clothes?
No! Stay back!
No!
- What's wrong?
- Stay back!
Are you ill?
No, I'm okay.
At least put this on.
I have no need for clothes!
Stop moving! It's dangling!
- It's just natural.
- Stop! No!
Mother!
That was good!
That hit the spot.
You know, this is a tavern,
not a restaurant.
That means we have to order drinks.
Ascetics drink alcohol?
Just as Master Wonhyo
drank water from a skull,
if you think it's booze, it's booze.
But if you think it's honey
water, it'll become honey water.
An ascetic, my foot.
Drink! I love drinking!
Open the gates!
Isn't this a gibang?
When cast out of your
home, bring a friend.
That's the way of life.
What?
You fool! Why are you back?
My mom's waiting...
What mom?
Buddy! You owe me for the food!
That wasn't even much!
What the...
You little brat!
You dare treat a guest like that?
A guest?
Yes!
I came here as a guest.
Two guests coming through!
What?
Dang!
This is pure honey!
Pour me another.
You're a grown man, now.
Should I get married to you?
We're family. That's wrong.
A dog would laugh to hear that.
If it smiled at me,
it must be a female.
With such hospitality,
I should rightfully repay you.
I can tell people's fortunes
by reading their faces.
Reading faces?
Very well.
You look like a gisaeng's brother.
- What?
- Nothing.
How dare you say that!
But you are our brother.
Right.
A gisaeng's brother?
You're a gifted face reader!
How did you know?
That's nothing.
What else?
Let's see.
Your raccoon-like nose is
full of mischief and bluff.
Your goose-like eyes
contain signs of tears.
What a daring face!
There are signs of
love all over your face.
Usually, a reading
like this is for women.
He must resemble his mom.
Mom?
Hey!
What?
What's the rush?
Here.
I might not look it,
but I'm half an aristocrat.
However,
I don't know who my father is.
Must be one of the aristocrats
who fooled around with my mom.
We haven't exchanged names yet.
I'm Heo Sek. And you?
Do you know the ten heavenly stems
and twelve earthly
branches of yin and yang?
Heavenly stems and earthly branches?
Wood, fire, earth, metal, water...
Ten heavenly stems!
Rat, ox, tiger, rabbit,
dragon, snake, horse, goat,
monkey, rooster, dog, and
pig! Twelve earthly branches!
I read people's nature
and their fortunes.
I also studied the cultural sphere
called the sexagenary cycle!
I mastered the sexagenary cycle!
I'm the master of the masters!
I'm Uke-gap!
Uke-gap.
That was dang long.
That was dang hard.
So Uke-gap.
As Yubi and his friends pledged
an oath at the Peach Garden,
let us pledge to be brothers
with this glass of liquor.
Sure!
Since we're at a gibang,
let's call it the Oath of the Gibang!
Oath of the Gibang?
- Wait!
- Let go!
You can't leave like this!
Then pay me what you owe!
What about the girls?
Please.
I'm begging you.
It hurts!
If you don't pay me by
the end of the month,
you'll lose this place for good!
No! Wait...
Ma'am!
Uke-gap? What are you drawing?
Laver.
What?
Laver!
Laver? Then it should
be coated with perilla oil.
Hey, Choon-boon!
Choon...
Oh, ma'am!
Yes! You're my type!
Come here!
Lock them up
and hand them over to
the authorities at dawn!
Aunt! Please stop.
It's killing...
Harder!
Why you!
Welcome!
It's nothing. Please come inside.
Wait! Help me!
Don't mind them, sir.
Why won't he shut up?
- Yes! You're my type.
- Let go!
Come here.
Sek?
Sook-jung!
Why are you out here?
What if Aunt catches you?
Hungry?
Eat this.
And water.
- I must go.
- Sook-jung! Wait!
Girls?
Come here.
Come close!
What's wrong?
Was someone mean to you?
That guest.
I've never seen a
guest so rude like that!
He complained about
the food from the start.
Then he said the girls' makeup is
too dark or flashy
and refused all of them.
He came to vent his anger,
not to be entertained.
- I know!
- Right!
Girls.
Go tell Aunt I have something to say.
What? Why would you go in there?
Trust me. I'll take care of it.
You have no other choice.
How will you make money?
Fine.
But if you make this worse,
I'll turn you into eunuchs.
I have no use for it anyway.
First,
I need to change.
How many bottles?
4 of our most expensive liquor!
We're racking up sales!
- Escort him out.
- Yes, ma'am.
This way, please.
Take care, sir.
What did you do?
You've lost your touch.
Can't you tell?
What?
That guest is...
a woman!
What? Why would a
woman come to a gibang?
She is a chaste widow.
The nights are long and lonely.
But as a virtuous woman,
she has nowhere to drink
and no friends to drink with.
She dressed as a man in hopes
of finding someone to drink with
because gibangs are private places.
I see.
How did you know she was a woman?
I knew right away
when our eyes met in the yard.
Her eyes...
No man can look at me like that.
Aunt! We had a deal!
Just go!
What deal?
Move!
Aunt! Wait!
Although Seong Chun-hyang was
of humble birth,
you must all follow her
example of chastity and fidelity.
Understood?
Yes, ma'am.
Madam Nam? Step forward.
It's a silver knife
to honor your patience and chastity.
Remain faithful as a
widow for a few more years,
and you'll be named a virtuous woman.
Continue remaining strong
for a few more years.
Yes, ma'am.
"It's a silver knife"
"to honor your patience and chastity."
What honor?
What good is this?
It's to stab your thigh and be patient.
Be glad it's not a kitchen knife.
At least Chun-hyang
had a husband to wait for.
How long must I wait
for my dead husband?
- You'll meet him after death.
- Goodness!
Madam Yoon.
May I see your silver knife?
Ah... I don't have one.
What? Why not?
I lost it.
How can you lose
the symbol of chastity?
I can't believe you!
Something smells fishy.
What do you mean?
Wait! She's wearing makeup!
Oh, dear!
Are you...
- I have to report you.
- Wait!
Please!
Then spill it.
Is he a pimp?
No. He's a gibang bachelor.
A different woman from
last night has come?
Yes. She asked for Heo Sek.
What?
Where did they go?
They couldn't have escaped
from here without breaking the door.
- But...
- Did they use magic?
Catch the sacs!
Come out of the sac!
My apologies.
I should've become one with the sac.
How frustrating!
How could my tactics fail?
I won't fail a second time.
Why do women keep coming to the gibang?
So?
Will you go in again?
Not for free.
Fine. I'll let you out.
How could I trust you?
Promise me you'll let me out
as well as stop meddling with my life.
In writing, of course.
- Then I'll go in.
- Why you!
Well, well! It's not
so bad living here!
Just give me a potty!
Fine.
If you're so desperate,
I'll go instead...
How much do you have to pay back?
Should the girls and I sell our jewels?
If we lose the gibang,
we'll be sold off as street girls.
Madam Aunt!
I'm coming in!
Why are we here?
It's hard to be the breadwinner.
Have a seat.
I came to discuss something.
I suddenly had this great idea!
- Go away!
- Aunt.
Why don't we make
a business out of this?
Business? What business?
Women...
Let's take them as guests
and make some money!
What?
I'm saying, I'll be a gisaeng.
A man with balls can't be a gisaeng!
What's so special about balls?
He's right.
Not only I can play instruments,
but I'm also gifted in
poetry, writing, and drawing.
I know all the gibang rules,
so I'm fit to be a gisaeng.
Most of all, my way with women...
I don't have to give details.
Did you memorize that?
No. How could a man...
I saw a loan shark come by here.
I'll just take 20% of my sales.
No way.
- 10%.
- 15%.
Deal!
What am I doing?
Then let's start marketing.
Marketing?
The key to business is good marketing.
We must let the women know.
How about using him as a tout?
He looks like a beggar.
No one will suspect him.
What? A beggar?
Right! He looks like a beggar!
Good idea!
What? Are you two serious?
No, it's not a good idea!
Though I may live humbly
because I was born in Joseon,
I have the blood of
Goryeo's royal family
flowing in me!
How dare you!
That's preposterous!
I won't force you to anything.
Gap-deok?
You'll regret it.
You lowly fools.
Hand him over to the authorities
- for dining and dashing!
- Yes, ma'am.
Fool!
How dare you touch a royal...
Get lost, beggars!
He's a beggar!
Beggar!
The beggar king!
No! I'm a king's descendant!
Dismiss!
Beautiful flowers bloom.
Know the way of pioneers?
Find the secret,
and you'll be rewarded.
It is not nonsense.
Explore at will.
You'll be enlightened.
Read it right to left.
Beautiful bachelor available
My name is Heo Sek.
What is it?
May I offer you a drink?
Allow me.
Please don't keep
my pretty hand waiting.
If we can meet outside,
we can eat more delicious dishes.
To me, what I eat and
where I eat don't matter.
Whom I eat with is what matters.
Mr. Heo...
It is done.
It's pretty!
But is it really me?
A portrait must be embellished.
Mr. Heo!
I want to see you even in my dreams.
Please stop.
You won't meet me there.
Why?
Then because of me,
you won't sleep a wink.
Oh, dear!
Lowly fools!
Why am I helping that fool?
Your Majesty!
Oh, a beggar!
Beggar! The beggar king!
Stop calling me that!
The beggar king!
You got the wrong man.
I don't think I've done much
as an older brother to you girls.
Sek!
Take whatever you want!
You're spending money like crazy.
Aunt and those girls are
the only family I have.
I didn't know they'd be so happy.
I should've done this for them sooner.
Family is nice.
Sek. Can I have this?
Why would a little girl
need a wedding hairpin?
I'll use it when I get married.
You're too young for that.
I was going to get married to you.
But you're family, right?
I'll marry someone
more handsome than you.
- Not again.
- Oh, please. Let's go.
Get that one?
That one! A bit higher!
Be patient.
- Mother, please!
- Wait.
Not again.
It's not that.
A little to the right!
Please give me that.
My lady, allow me to get it for you.
No thank you, sir.
I'll get them. Allow me.
I said it's okay...
Very well.
Come, Deok-se!
Deok-se!
Come here at once.
Yes, you! Deok-se.
My servant will get it for you.
Damn brat! Why did I
agree to be brothers?
What in the world...
...can I do for you, sir?
Pick the persimmons.
Persimmons, sir?
Go on. Pick them.
Yes, sir.
Please, just once.
He stinks.
Go on.
Hurry up and pick them.
Yes, sir!
- Right.
- I'll pick them, sir.
- I'm picking them!
- Good job.
I'll pick them all!
We've met before.
My name is Heo Sek. And you, my lady?
Ar-soon, let's go.
If you won't take this...
At least tell me your name?
I got this for you.
She's Lady Hae-won.
Lady Hae-won.
Deok-se?
I'm sorry, but you fit the role.
What role?
Just think of it as
helping your little brother.
You made me be a beggar,
and now I'm your servant?
How can you use me?
- What?
What?
Come here, or we're through!
Deok-se! Hurry, lad!
Oh, right.
The guest in the Orchid
Room has been waiting long.
Oh my!
What?
Foolish lad.
What? Those are my clothes!
You put makeup on, too?
You disrespect me so much.
So I dressed up
to prove I'm of royal descent.
What damn royal descent?
You punk!
What?
What's your secret?
Tell me your secret!
What secret?
The secret to cajoling women.
It's not cajoling. It's communicating.
Get that through your head!
Of course!
So what's your secret to
communicating with women?
By chance, is yours...
big?
Men are so foolish.
You're a man, too!
Then what is it?
- Nothing!
- Damn!
Fine! Keep your secret and
have all the girls to yourself!
Greedy pig!
No secret, huh?
Communicating? Like hell!
You must've had a secret!
Maybe you slept with them?
No.
They didn't seek me out of lust
or for my sweet talk.
I want to leave here.
I want to see the world
and meet many people.
But I'll just grow old here
like a withering tree.
But you're so beautiful...
No need to say such sweet things.
Will you just listen?
Just listen to me.
I always listened.
All I did was look into their eyes
and listen to them every night.
Did you love them?
I've never been in love.
That's my fate.
I'm not worthy to love anyone.
Not even one woman?
What a great son!
She must be happy to
see her son as a gisaeng!
How can you say that?
- You know I'm right.
- What?
You won't even tell me your secret.
What?
Persimmons?
Lady Hae-won.
Brother! Change into Deok-se.
Jeez! Not again!
I can't tell you apart
from the flowers.
Do you remember me?
I'm Heo Sek.
Hello, sir.
A flower talks?
Oh, please...
Chance meeting twice is a coincidence.
Three times, it's fate.
How about a friendly chat
over an aromatic cup of tea?
Hae-won!
Sir.
- Who's this?
He did me a favor once before.
What favor?
Why didn't you ask me?
I'm Yu-sang, the second
son of the Minister of Justice,
Lee Si-young.
Who are you?
I'm Sek, the only son of
the respectable Heo family over there!
As you don't mention
your father's name,
your family must not
be very respectable.
It is!
I've asked the chief monk
to take special care of you.
You should be comfortable here.
Thank you, sir.
Are you all right?
I can send you more maids.
- No. I'm fine.
- You sure?
I'd better go.
You're still here?
He even walks frivolously.
Chirp! Chirp! Chirp!
What's that noise?
You got the bird from him! I
never knew I'd live to see this.
What?
I did not get the bird!
I wonder what kind of bird it was.
A dog got the bird while
chasing after a chicken...
So you're a dog bird!
- A dog bird!
- What?
Move!
Ouch!
He looks so classy and rich.
You are a classy guy too,
but you stand no chance against him.
You're a gibang bachelor.
Chirp! Chirp! Chirp!
Stop it!
Chirp!
Thought you were a bag of
wind, but you're pretty strong.
A flower talks?
Look, Nan-seol.
How about a friendly chat
over an aromatic glass of rice wine?
Cut the crap!
If you've got too much
energy, go scoop the dung!
Dung?
I'm not your slave!
What?
How can you throw dung
on a man's words like that?
And show some respect!
You're younger than me, woman!
You crazy fool!
You should be thankful
that I'm not kicking you out!
Younger?
What makes you think
I'm younger than you?
Because you look young!
You look very young!
I look young?
What good is being pretty
with all that makeup?
A kind heart is what counts!
My kindhearted brother!
Follow me!
What is it this time?
Where are you going?
Lady! Look.
Another coincidence?
Cool horse!
Isn't it?
A man should ride a horse.
I see fools riding palanquins
like elderly men.
What a laugh!
What brings you here today, sir?
What?
Oh, why did I come?
What else? You came
to see the lady, sir.
With me, your servant.
I did not.
What?
Just act like how you usually act.
Sir.
What? Please ignore him.
What is its name?
Its name is Maniac.
Heo Sek's Maniac.
Why you!
Sek's Maniac!
Mister, can I ride it?
No. For what?
Let's go!
Ar-soon!
Sorry.
Say, ah.
What are you doing?
Oh my! It's just a habit.
A habit?
No way!
The tea might be bitter.
So I brought some cake...
Foolish hand!
What are you doing?
My hand...
Why are you staying here at a temple?
I'm praying for my older brother
to pass the state examination.
I see.
By the way,
that bastard I saw before...
Who might he be?
Oh, are you talking about Mr. Yu-sang?
Are you betrothed to him?
No.
He's just my brother's best friend.
Of course!
I knew it.
Still, be mindful of him.
The way he looks at you is treacherous.
It can't be...
He treated me like a
sister since I was young.
He's classy and gentle.
And he's a great scholar.
Why is your mouth...
What about me?
Sir?
What kind of man do I look like?
For instance...
Judging from my classy and
elegant appearance, I must be...
- A fraud, right?
- A fraud.
What? No way!
I'm not a fraud.
It's time to pray, my lady.
I must go.
Wait! Please...
- Doesn't he look like a fraud?
- Must you pray today?
Please stay a little longer...
You don't look like a fraud.
However...
However?
Lady Hae-won!
However, what?
It'll drive you crazy!
Throwing bait at you like that.
However... Wow!
Mr. Dong-ju! It's me, Ar-soon.
There is heaven above and earth below.
Earth below...
Mankind and all things are
between heaven and earth.
The sun, moon, and
stars are in the sky.
Rivers, seas, mountains
are supported by the land!
Ar-soon? How did you know?
Even a slave girl like me
learned it from listening to you!
Why can't you memorize
that for more than 10 years?
You're better than me.
If I had been as clever as you,
I would've passed the examination.
Let's see. I'll memorize the
"Thousand-Character Classic."
Sky "Chun." Land "Ji"...
Poor Lady Hae-won.
All that work for a hopeless brother!
Black "Hyun"...
Yellow "Hwang"!
Right! Yellow "Hwang"!
- Sky "Chun"...
- Dong-ju! Are you inside?
Why aren't you eating? Have some.
Can you study in a place like this?
A lighter does not blame the brush.
I'm fine.
It's not lighter, but writer.
Ah, writer.
How long will you
leave Hae-won like that?
She's late in getting married
because she's been supporting you.
I feel ashamed.
Give your sister to me.
I must marry her as soon as I can.
She likes me.
She likes me not.
Not working out for you?
The one who falls in love first
has the lower hand in a relationship.
You're teaching me about love?
Brother, have you ever dated?
Over a thousand times.
A thousand?
Through books and imagination.
Being a virgin at my age,
I'm an expert in love's theory.
You could say I've
achieved enlightenment.
But are you serious?
About what?
Your feelings for Lady
Hae-won. Are you serious?
If you are, then give her your heart.
Not your mouth.
I'll be Deok-se all you want.
I can't believe I'm Deok-se!
You look as if you live here.
What? No...
Look.
I'm warning you.
Stop roaming around Hae-won.
I've never done such a thing.
She keeps showing up in front of me.
It must be destiny.
You met Hae-won again?
Yes, I met her recently. Alone.
I'll be watching you.
Rotten bastard.
Sek! You're wanted in Room 1.
I'll be back soon.
But you just got here.
How many guests do you have?
Others are waiting.
I'll return soon.
Already?
So many guests came at once.
I'll have them together.
Together?
I'm very sorry to keep you waiting.
Thank you so much
for your understanding.
This way, please.
Mom!
- She's her daughter?
- Oh my!
You brat...
- Madam!
- If I catch you, you're dead!
One of us will die tonight!
Ma'am! Stop!
Family feuds are fun to watch.
That family is a mess...
Your father has 3 concubines.
He left with the youngest
one over two months ago
and lives with her.
How do you think I feel?
So I came here this once
for a breath of fresh air.
It's my first time here.
But we met in the bathroom...
Shut up!
What about you?
A virtuous woman must...
How could you come
to a place like this?
What is wrong with coming here?
Men drink and enjoy the arts
in places like this night and day.
You ladies are just here
to drown your troubles.
How is that reproachable?
He's right!
Now.
I, the gisaeng, shall entertain you.
Welcome.
Welcome back.
Wait.
One new guest!
Is it your first time here?
Dad isn't back yet?
I just hope he croaks.
No blessing of a husband,
but you have a good son.
It's a daughter.
Daughter?
I see your daughter
must get married soon!
Marry her off next year.
She's not even a year old.
Right! That's way too early!
This was made in South Manchuria.
See how the pearls twinkle?
Good to see you!
Who's here before breakfast?
What? Repeat what you said.
We know everything.
We heard men can be gisaengs here.
Who are those fools?
- They're trainees.
- What?
They're the new trainees.
Your juniors.
Aunt is crazy over money!
Little brother,
what are you drawing?
It's not Ae-OK.
It's not Choon-boon.
It's not me, either.
I didn't ask you.
It's Lady Hae-won.
I'm gifted in drawing portraits.
But why can't I draw her?
Wait!
Does it mean that her beauty is
too great to be captured
on a mere piece of paper?
Yes! That must be it!
Don't try so hard, fool!
Sek!
Sook-jung! Why bathe so frequently?
You'll lose all your skin.
So pretty.
Sek.
I'll become a woman tonight.
What?
How much did you get?
I'll pay you! Leave Sook-jung be!
She played a big part.
Sook-jung saved our gibang.
Aunt! She's just seventeen!
I was fifteen.
It's just her turn.
How can she be sold off to a man
she doesn't even know?
Sook-jung made the choice.
Rather than serve many guests,
she wanted to serve one man.
She asked me.
I hope her husband will
love her dearly.
Sir? May she come in?
Love is so crude.
Why can't Mr. Heo come here?
He's not feeling well.
Shut up!
I didn't ask you!
Bring him here at once!
Forgive me.
May I show you our new gisaengs?
What?
New gisaengs?
Go on.
I'm Joong-dae.
I'm Joong-so.
Lady.
Lady Hae-won?
Who's there?
It's me.
Heo Sek.
I'll scream.
Scream if you must.
I came with my life on the line.
Wait!
If I get hit, I could die.
You said you're ready to die.
Were you just bluffing?
Lady Hae-won.
Let's go outside.
How could I...
Let's go see the moon.
It's too pretty to watch alone.
He won't give up.
I almost peed in bed.
I'm infatuated.
Are you serious?
Yes.
With persimmons.
Right. Persimmons.
I loved persimmons as a child.
My brother climbed
trees to get them for me
every autumn.
The persimmons he picked for me were
so delicious.
Without thinking,
I nagged him to pick more for me.
I nagged a lot, too.
If only I didn't pester him...
One day, he fell from a persimmon tree
and was injured badly.
Oh...
Luckily, he survived,
but he lost his intelligence.
So many books for someone so dumb!
Even now, the sight of
persimmons scares him.
Look! See this?
Since then, I've been
devoted to my brother.
It's all my fault.
No, it's not your fault.
Is sacrificing your life
really for your brother's best?
Please live for yourself.
I know now.
The reason why you seemed
different from other men.
My looks?
Not my type.
But you don't seem like a fraud.
However...
What?
The night is too hot!
That fool!
Let's get up.
The night is too hot and long!
Lady Hae-won, look over there.
My body feels so hot!
It's hot! I'm too hot!
What is he doing?
Let's go.
I'll make sure he keeps his mouth shut.
It's hot! So hot!
What are you doing here?
What brings you here?
Well...
I came to see the moon.
By chance,
are you hot?
I don't know what you mean.
Wait.
What are you doing?
Help me!
How old are you?
I'm twenty-five.
Call me Sister.
However...
You seemed like a little boy
grumbling out of loneliness.
Nagging me to stay with you.
For some reason,
I didn't mind that.
Pom rak khun.
Pardon?
It means "beautiful."
A word from a foreign
country in the far south.
Pom rak khun.
I wrote a poem about
how I felt that night.
Would you like to hear it?
A poem?
Tell me.
I didn't know you liked me, too.
What should I do? I'm so happy.
Thinking it's a dream,
I keep pinching myself.
I'm so happy.
I fretted so long,
thinking you may not like me.
But you like me, too.
Oh my!
Tell me one more time.
Tell me. Tell me. Tell me.
Say you love me and waited for me.
Say you need me again.
You must return before
the monks wake up.
Then, I'll go first.
You loved her, right?
Why do you keep asking?
For some reason,
I wish that you loved her.
Brother! I've returned.
Me, too!
This is it?
Hae-won! You're back!
I've never seen an
aristocrat so poor...
Welcome home.
Did you study hard?
Of course I did!
You really studied hard?
Of course he did.
It's cold! Let's go inside.
Brother.
Hmm?
Why don't you quit
studying for the state exam?
What do you mean?
It won't be so bad for the 3 of us
to farm and live like this.
Hae-won.
I promise I'll pass this time.
I want to try one more time.
What's with him?
He must've come to his senses.
What a relief.
What about the guests
who come for him?
Don't worry.
We have other male
gisaengs to replace him.
A body of iron!
Rock, at your service.
I'm Scholar Kim. I
recently quit college.
If you'd like to have an
intelligent conversation...
I'm Bicheollang.
I'll be your bodyguard forever!
Come and sit down.
Stupid fools.
They'll drink to death.
Aunt!
Do you want me to study or not?
How do you expect me to
study in such conditions?
- Let's talk tomorrow.
- No! Let's talk now.
I'm coming in!
Why are you coming out of there?
Why?
Strangers aren't allowed here.
I'm no stranger.
Why are you still awake?
I can't fall asleep.
It's nice and quiet here.
Want me to read you a
book till you fall asleep?
Are you crazy?
What if someone sees you?
Such a virtuous woman!
At this rate,
you'll make it to the
Virtuous Women Hall.
Really? If I become a virtuous woman,
can't I be a part of
my husband's family?
Snap out of it, girl.
A gisaeng can't be a virtuous woman.
Don't joke with me.
Why are you here like this?
Your husband won't care even
if you stay here all night long.
You should go. I'm fine.
My husband said he'll come for me.
Not now, but later.
Is it interesting?
It's terrible.
Why are you buying so many?
I read all my books
until they were worn out.
Thailand?
What is this book?
Ever heard of a
country called Thailand?
It's far south of China.
The weather there is
warm all year round.
It is filled with mystical fruits,
so people don't ever starve.
It's a paradise on earth.
Is there really a country like that?
Of course.
There are even elephants!
- Ele... what?
- It's amazing.
The people there raise
animals called elephants
just like how we raise oxen.
It's as big as a house.
Its ears are as big as a sail,
and its nose is so long!
I heard it's longer than
a 100-year-old snake.
No way.
But it's true!
When I pass the translator exam,
I'll take you to Thailand
and let you ride on the elephant!
Why would a nobleman like you
not take the state exam
but prepare for a
low-ranked translator exam?
You're kidding, right?
I trust you will pass the state exam
and become a great
minister in the court.
Don't worry, sir.
Oh...
Why?
Are you done?
Let's go.
Sir?
It hit me.
Because she was kind to
everyone regardless of their class,
I had forgotten about my lowly status
and the fact that I had
been deceiving her.
Sir! Wait!
Open it.
Will you marry me?
Sir?
Why are you surprised?
We promised to get married
since we were young.
But we were playing house...
I was serious.
My feelings for you
haven't changed once.
Please take it back.
What?
Until my brother becomes successful,
I can't get married.
Don't worry.
I'll take care of Dong-ju, too.
Please have dinner before you go.
Is it because of him?
Find out about Heo Sek.
Sook-jung?
Sook...
Ma'am!
Ma'am...
Such a virtuous woman!
At this rate,
you'll make it to the
Virtuous Women Hall.
Really? If I become a virtuous woman,
can't I be a part of
my husband's family?
Snap out of it, girl.
A gisaeng can't be a virtuous woman.
I hope her husband will
love her dearly.
A gisaeng?
Did you just say "gisaeng"?
Yes, sir.
He's a male gisaeng who serves women.
Where are we going?
Just follow me!
Virtuous Women Hall
Find him!
What's happening?
He's not here, sir.
- Look!
- Isn't that Virtuous Women Hall?
You fool!
You son of a bitch!
How can this happen?
Who dared to burn this place?
Why did you bother to come here?
It's no big deal.
Since you're here, let's
all watch the fire together!
You fool!
Do you know what that is?
What are you doing?
Put the fire out now!
Of course I know what it is!
It forces patience on women
under the guise of fidelity!
It's a prison that makes women wither
with the shackles of chastity!
Men who keep concubines
because they're not
satisfied with their wives say,
"Serve one husband!"
"Be submissive to husbands!"
Haughty men who say wives
must obey their husbands!
Now!
To hell with you!
Damn fool! You'll be punished!
To my mother and Sook-jung...
And to you all, I apologize.
I didn't see the depth of your pains.
I was wrong to just
pity and neglect you.
The most vulgar man
in all of Joseon!
I...
Gisaeng Heo Sek will
take heaven's bitter wrath!
Step aside!
Sir! No!
Watch carefully, Hae-won!
He is...
a lowly gibang bachelor!
He's a male gisaeng who serves women!
That brute
has been mocking you!
Sir! No! Stop!
Please stop.
Please spare his life! Please!
Hae-won...
How could you?
Don't mind me!
I wasn't insulted in any way!
I beg you!
Please spare him his life, sir!
Please.
Take him to prison.
If he is a mere offender,
we wouldn't be here like this.
Right, Minister?
Why are you asking me?
I heard your daughter-in-law
had a lot of fun with him.
What?
But your daughter
planned to flee by night with him!
You old miser!
- Let me go!
- Enough!
Where is your dignity?
Don't act high and mighty!
I heard
your wife and daughter
visited him together!
You son of a bitch!
You bastard!
Get your hands off me!
I'll beat you up!
Stop!
That's enough!
Such a shameful behavior!
It's not a matter of mere humiliation.
If His Majesty hears of
this, what about my family?
It's not just your family.
It will affect everyone here.
I understand what you mean.
Let's just bury this quietly.
As promised, I'll take
care of Dong-ju, too.
I've always waited for you.
If you tell me to wait longer,
I will.
So much silk and jewels!
Lady Hae-won struck it rich!
Hae-won.
Your older brother
is a good-for-nothing.
I have nothing to give my only sister
as she's getting married.
I'm so sorry and sad.
Why did you do this? Why?
They're damaged from the winter wind,
but I picked the best ones.
Please take them
and share them with your husband.
I'm so sorry...
It's okay, dear sister. Don't cry.
I'm the one who's sorry.
- Not on a day like this...
- I'm sorry!
Don't cry!
Can't sleep?
I heard you can't sleep
before the wedding.
I wish I could get married soon.
How can you eat that?
Just one. Want some?
Pom rak khun.
Pom rak khun?
It's pretty.
The persimmon is so pretty.
You must be happy to
marry into a good family.
What if
you had fallen for that playboy?
Who cares if his feelings were real?
Whatever!
What do you mean?
Ar-soon.
Deok-se came a few
days ago and said that,
so I chased him out.
It's bad luck before the wedding.
Hurry!
Why would you come here?
I must hear it from you.
Hear what?
Why did you hide everything from me?
I didn't hide it from you.
You were foolish not to see.
Why should I point it out to
you when you didn't even ask?
It didn't matter!
I didn't care what you do
or what class you belong to.
Those things didn't matter to me.
But why...
Why weren't you honest with me?
That's who I am.
I say sweet lies to entice women.
I almost won you over, too.
Too bad you found out.
I'll ask one last thing before I go.
Even for one second...
did you not love me?
I...
I, Heo Sek...
I never profess my love to anyone.
- Aunt!
- Sek!
Keep your promise!
Or we'll have to flee by night! Hurry!
Hurry!
Thank you.
Hurry! Let's go!
Hurry!
- Hurry! Get on!
- Hurry!
Go ahead.
Sek! What do you mean?
If you're with me,
you'll all be in danger.
I'll hide on my own,
so please go.
Sek!
But...
When we meet again,
please be wearing clothes.
Damn fool...
Aunt.
Please...
I wish you good health.
Well...
Men leave from
gisaengs' arms all the time.
It's how we live.
No need to be sad.
Let's go.
She's so beautiful!
Be careful.
- Heads?
- You sure?
Stop playing games!
One last chance.
Madam is resting!
Use your head.
- Heads?
- Oh...
If you're so anxious, why
didn't you go yourself?
Why you...
Why would I be anxious?
I just want to know if he's well
as I'm passing through.
It's a long way to come
just to pass through!
We went 40km off course!
You couldn't sleep at night
after learning he lives here.
Am I right?
I guess.
Now that I'm close to dying,
I must miss old memories.
Why miss the past...
Aunt Ar-soon!
There she comes!
I've returned, Madam.
Good. How is he?
He's strong as a horse
and sly as a fox, ma'am.
He hasn't changed.
I'm glad he is well.
Well done.
Let's go home.
Yes, ma'am.
What's that?
It's my portrait. He drew it for me.
It doesn't resemble you at all...
What?
Madam. Look.
It's ruined.
It's okay.
Please draw it for me next time.
I'll draw your portrait again.
I promise.
Pom rak khun.
Pardon?
It means "beautiful."
The portrait is so beautiful.
No, ma'am.
He taught me
a few words from Thailand.
It means "I love you."
One sentence...
Why was it so hard to say?
Sir. Why didn't you share
a keepsake with her?
Like simple rings?
The scent of flowers that day...
A sip of tea that day...
The sound of water flowing...
The touch of our lips that night...
My five senses remember
our every moment together.
What good is a keepsake?
When I pass the translator exam,
I'll take you to Thailand
and let you ride on the elephant.
So?
Will you go with me?
HOMME FATALE
LEE JUN-HO, JUNG SO-MIN
CHOI GUY-HWA, YEH JI-WON
GONG MYOUNG
JEON NO-MIN, LEE IL-HWA
Written & Directed by NAM DAE-JOONG
Thank you for coming.