NETFLIX PRESENTS
Good morning.
You'd better lower the heat.
Thanks.
That smells good.
Are you celebrating something?
You idiot. We're having a wake.
-Huh?
-A wake.
We hadn't seen Ken around for a while,
so I went to check his tent,
but he was already cold.
An-chan, he taught you lots of things
when you first got here too, right?
Yeah.
So where's Ken now?
They removed him already.
You should have said,
"They took him away."
He's not an object, you know.
Here. You can have this.
-Sake for mourning!
-See ya.
An-chan, how about a drink?
Hey! Don't waste your time.
His friend just died,
but he doesn't feel anything?
He's been living over there
for a long time.
It seems he can't remember anything.
Is it amnesia?
Who knows?
He seems to be doing fine,
but there's something fishy.
Can you smell that?
Thank you.
Could you please sign here?
SUSUMU NAKOSHI
Please open the door.
I'm not a weirdo or anything.
Who are you?
It's cold out here. Could you let me in?
I don't give rides to strangers.
You're homeless, aren't you?
You don't have a home or a job.
Sorry. If I've insulted you, I apologize.
To get down straight to business,
I have a certain job
that I'd like you to take.
How does 700,000 yen sound?
Sorry, but I've already got money.
Hey.
Hey. What are you doing?
It's a simple human research experiment.
It's called "trepanation."
Right here,
I'll drill a tiny hole in your skull.
Leave.
No, I know the thought of
boring a hole in your skull is scary,
but it's really no big deal at all.
-Just leave.
-Frankly,
it's just like teeth.
It's just a little hole.
Your brain won't be harmed.
That's all.
You've heard it before, right?
Humans only use 10% of their brains.
If we could leverage the other 90%,
what would happen?
An intuition sharper than anyone else's
could be unleashed,
or a sixth sense could awaken,
or memories could return.
Then put a hole in your own skull.
You can just try it on yourself.
I mean, it's just a tiny hole here, right?
No way.
It sounds scary!
Get lost. Find someone else.
Plenty of other people need money.
It has to be you!
This park is where homeless people gather,
and that luxury hotel
is where ordinary people go.
I want you, the one who's smack-dab
in the middle of both!
Listen, I'm just taking time off work
to see what it's like to be homeless.
Well, you could say…
I'm trying to "find myself."
Get someone else.
Whenever you lie,
the left side of your mouth goes up.
You can't cry, can you?
You can't even feel sad.
You're desperately
trying to feel something.
Right?
I'm right, aren't I?
You must be bored.
No, that's not it.
Most people would get angry
if someone said that to them.
Nakoshi.
Do you ever feel alive?
You…
How did you know my name?
You don't remember… do you?
I'll be back.
Hey! This is bad!
Hey!
An-chan with the car!
-An-chan!
-What happened?
Your car!
Quickly!
DAY ONE
They got you, huh?
SHINJUKU TOWING
They just had to go
and take your car, didn't they?
You had your clothes and your stuff
in your car, right?
The tow truck
is going to cost a lot of money.
But An-chan,
you've got lots of money, right?
Hey. You've got money, right?
Hey. Are you okay?
I've never seen him look like that before.
The only place
you could return to is gone.
Are you going to stay here forever?
So it was you…
What are you living for?
How should I know?
You finally look annoyed.
Seven days.
I'll give you a reason to live.
What a creepy room.
Trepanation is a surgical procedure that
has been done since the Neolithic Period.
Nowadays, a group called ITAG
in the Netherlands works to promote it.
There are even people
who put a hole in their own head.
What a sicko.
So, who are you?
I'm Manabu Ito. I'm a medical intern.
My father runs this hospital.
That makes me the boss's kid.
The boss's kid?
What if your parents found out about this?
I just want to learn about humans.
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah.
How much do you remember about yourself?
Who knows?
You're not interested in yourself?
It doesn't matter anymore.
I'm right in the middle of Shinjuku,
but no one's looking for me.
What worth is the life of a man like that?
"A man like that."
That's exactly why I'm interested in you.
When humans are born,
they have a gap in their skull,
meaning there is a hollow space.
But after a year and a half,
that hole closes up,
and the skull
starts pushing on the brain.
Therefore, if we open a hole in the skull
and improve the blood circulation,
it would activate the brain again,
just like how it was at birth.
It would draw out abilities
that hadn't been used before.
That's the simple principle
behind trepanation.
Don't worry.
Honestly, I'm better
than most doctors around here.
Oh, please make sure you don't move
while I'm drilling the hole.
It'd be bad if your meninges tear.
If that happens, then whatever.
Even if I become a vegetable,
it wouldn't be any different
from how things are now.
Is the anesthetic working?
Yeah.
Ouch…
LET'S HAVE DINNER TOGETHER
ITO
DAY TWO
The experiment will last for seven days.
I'll pay you 300,000 yen in advance.
You'll get the rest once it's over.
I told you I've got money already.
So? What are you trying to do?
Shouldn't you have asked that
before I made the hole?
Here.
ESP experiment,
sixth sense check,
psychokinesis experiment…
What is all this?
I thought this was a medical experiment.
I'll be honest.
I don't believe in spirits
and supernatural powers and the occult.
Everything can be explained by the brain.
That's why I want to use this experiment
to clear all the remaining doubts I have
and proudly deny that it exists.
Deny what?
This world right in front of me.
Excuse me. Here's the chili shrimp.
-Thanks for the meal.
-Thank you.
Then let's get started with a simple game.
What?
I've got these cards
with these five symbols.
Guess which card has the star symbol.
All right.
Nakoshi.
Huh?
Use your left side.
-That's not what I mean.
-What?
I want you to try feeling it
with your whole left side.
Your senses of sight,
hearing, smell, and touch.
Use all of that from only the left side
of your body to envision the card.
All right.
Don't get too full of yourself.
Today was just practice.
We'll get to the real stuff tomorrow.
So what? Four cards is better than usual?
Oh, this is so you can contact me.
It has my number in it.
Okay.
And…
Hey.
It looks good on you.
I'll see you tomorrow.
This is an announcement
for all Kabukicho visitors.
Recently, there have been incidents
of fraudulent soliciting in Kabukicho…
Ouch!
What was that?
Hello? Today?
Now?
Well, I'm in Kabukicho right now.
Where are you?
Oh, okay. Then…
What's wrong with him?
There's a weird guy here…
I understand you better than anyone.
Really?
Then let me hear it…
What's going on?
Sorry!
-Hey!
-What's wrong with you?
-Sorry…
-You stink.
Hey.
Boss…
What are you winking at? You bastard!
No, I didn't mean to…
You...
No…
Boss, he's a civilian.
What if he goes to the police?
It doesn't matter.
Don't move.
How about if I cut off your pinkie…
No…
How many am I at?
He's the 77th.
Wait.
You can't.
What are you doing?
That's your own finger!
Don't do it!
Wait! Put down
that sickle-like thing. Okay?
Sickle?
Yeah.
Hey, what did you do?
No, just stop. Calm down.
Don't hurt yourself.
-Okay?
-You bastard!
What did you say?
Boss!
What's going on?
Stay back!
-What's wrong?
-Boss…
What's the matter?
I said stay back!
Hey!
-Boss!
-What did you do?
Hurry up! Let's go! Come on!
Do you believe me?
Let's assume I do believe you.
Don't give me that crap.
Wow, this is amazing!
I didn't tell you,
but studies abroad say 36%
who did trepanation felt a sixth sense.
It's more common
for people to feel nothing!
-What else didn't you tell me?
-Hey, Nakoshi…
What about me?
How do I look to you?
What?
I don't see anything.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
You said you believe me, didn't you?
What's wrong?
DAY THREE
When I saw this, it all made sense.
What's that?
It's a homunculus.
Homunculus?
Yes.
Basically, it is a man-made
human being created using alchemy.
However, a neurosurgeon named Penfield
used the word "homunculus" to refer
to a miniature human inside the brain.
Its hands and lips are huge.
Since we were born,
we've used our hands and mouths
in order to feel something.
Sex is a good example of that.
But it looks
nothing like the monsters I saw.
For example, we use the expression
"He's lacking substance," right?
That describes this man perfectly.
No. He was kind of fat…
What's key is that this is
a person's source of mental stress.
That's the issue.
Well, they might lack substance,
but aren't you jumping to conclusions?
It's one interpretation.
I think they're the self-images that
each individual has of themselves.
After all, the homunculi you saw
were not all the same simple shape, right?
In other words, since we activated
your brain through the surgery,
you've gained the ability to visualize
people's deep sources of stress.
In other words, trauma?
Yes, that's it! That's right!
Trauma is created
from past emotions and memories.
That's what you're able to see.
Then why can some people see homunculi,
but others can't?
That's what we're going to find out.
We're going to create hypotheses
and verify them. Experimentation.
Is this really going to be over
in a week?
I don't want to spend my whole life
seeing monsters.
You're no fun…
You're experiencing
something amazing right now!
You can see inside people's hearts.
I'm so jealous.
That's it.
Let's go out now
and test out your new ability.
-Go ahead.
-Okay.
Are there any here?
I'm leaving.
Rumors say this place
has real high school students.
It's like a modern freakshow.
You like monsters like her?
Huh?
Found one.
She's a sand monster.
Sand?
You mean that girl?
I'm going to make direct contact with her.
Did you think of something?
If she's made up of dry sand,
I'll just have to make her wet.
You just want to fuck
a high school student.
No.
I want to fuck a homunculus.
You're disgusting.
Hello.
Are you alone?
Are you studying?
You're shaking.
Are you perhaps…
Hey, are you okay?
Too bad. She ran away.
No, that's not what I mean.
Your face.
-My face?
-Yeah.
I swiped this.
You stole it?
Hold onto it.
If anything happens, report it to me.
Thanks.
You're shaking.
Hey…
What are you so scared about?
Are you perhaps…
a virgin?
MOM: Where are you?
Call me if you're running late.
MOM: Why aren't you picking up?
MOM: Don't you have to study?
MOM: You're not smart like Kaede.
MOM: Where are you?
MOM: Call me!
1775.YUKARI
FILL ME UP…
I'M SO DIRTY…
NOTICE ME, FIND ME…
JUST THE WAY I AM…
DIRTY FEELINGS…
HELP ME.
NEED ME.
WANT ME.
TOUCH ME.
Geez…
"When I become one with you,
-everything becomes real."
-…everything becomes real.
When I become one with you,
I become one.
Soon, I want to become one.
That's so creepy.
Hey.
We've been looking for you.
-No, wait…
-Come on! Hey!
-Wait!
-You bastard!
Yesterday…
what did you do to me?
Well…
I saw something.
You saw something?
What did you see?
A robot.
A robot?
Does that mean anything to you?
Something about a pinkie and a sickle…
I have no idea whatsoever.
Oh.
Sorry.
Hey. What are you doing?
A child…
Sorry…
Don't move!
Stay back!
I'll cut off your pinkie!
There he is!
What are you talking about?
What a wound…
Ouch!
Sorry!
That must have hurt, huh?
Yeah…
You bastard! Hey!
This will cost you
more than just a finger.
What is this?
What's this feeling?
What the hell are you doing?
When you were a kid,
what did you do to your pinkie
with the sickle?
Oh, wow! It's a sickle!
Whoa! Hey! Let me see!
No! I'll trade you for that.
Huh? No way.
Stop it!
You bastard!
I see…
Guilt.
You're not the one
who got hurt with the sickle.
You hurt someone else.
No!
-What's the big deal?
-No!
-Let me see it!
-No way!
-No!
-Come on!
-No! I don't want to!
-Hey!
-Stop!
-Give it to me!
No!
Kazuo…
Kazuo!
No!
You were scared
and couldn't apologize.
Right?
-I…
-did that to Kazuo's pinkie…
-Kazuo,
-I'm sorry!
I'm sorry…
I'm sorry!
The only thing you could do
was cover up your regret and your sin.
You deliberately hurt people…
and accepted your loneliness…
Your guilt…
turned you into a yakuza.
As of today, I'm quitting the yakuza.
Allow me to compensate for what I've done.
We hadn't seen Ken around for a while,
so I went to check his tent,
but he was already cold.
An-chan, he taught you lots of things
when you first got here too, right?
What is this?
Hey, An-chan.
Hey.
I heard you got your car back.
Yeah.
Let's have a drink.
Yeah?
Okay.
I see.
An insurance company?
Yes.
I calculated probabilities whenever
someone wanted to buy life insurance.
For example,
that guy in the suit
eating a piece of bread.
60 million yen max.
That family over there,
no more than 80 million for the father,
and for the mother, 38 million.
And 48 million just for the kid.
That's more than 100 million.
Well, it's just a rough estimate,
but every life
has a monetary value assigned to it.
What a bunch of rubbish!
Who decides stuff like that?
Ryo.
How old are you?
I'm 41.
Forty-one.
How often do you drink?
Wh-What you see here.
Every day.
Do you smoke?
No, I don't.
Have you ever had any major diseases?
No,
but I had appendicitis once.
Do your parents, siblings, or any of your
relatives have any hereditary disorders?
Well… um…
Oh, and what's your income every year?
-What? Even if you ask me…
-Well,
an approximation is fine.
That comes out to…
Ryo, your value is--
You idiot!
Don't decide how much someone's worth!
Don't put a price on someone's life!
Calm down!
Hey, take it easy!
The moon is the moon…
Ouch…
Hello?
You want me to give you
your phone back, right?
Just tell me where to bring it.
Okay.
I'll be going now. Thanks for the food.
Hey, you have my phone, right?
Yeah.
Hey! Don't just get in without asking!
MOM: Where are you?
Looking out for your mother?
You checked my phone, didn't you?
Give it back to me.
Gross.
You work with that pimply guy, don't you?
So what if I do?
Is this where you live?
Do you work?
You don't?
What a half-assed loser.
"When I become one with you,
everything becomes real."
You did check my phone.
"When I become one with you,
I'm freed from this world.
When I become one with you,
I become one.
Soon…"
Stop!
"I want to become one!"
This… isn't sand…
They're symbols?
Pervy old man…
PERVY OLD MAN
Wh-What's all this?
Let go of me!
Ouch…
What are you trying to do?
Hey!
Hey, what are you thinking?
What are you trying to do?
Being a virgin is embarrassing.
Are you crazy?
You want to fuck me, right?
You…
That's so gross…
What a half-assed loser…
You're the one who's a loser!
Do you understand what you're doing?
If I become one with you,
everything becomes real…
Sex is your only way
of rebelling against your parents.
You're holding onto a shitty fantasy.
Please.
Be gentle with me.
Stop!
Seriously, what are you doing?
I am you.
I AM YOU
I'm not like you!
Wait a minute--
What's that?
Hey! Stop!
Don't look!
Stop!
You're finally showing your true colors…
No!
Spit it out!
Give it back! It's mine!
It hurts!
It hurts! It's hot!
You became human.
It hurts!
What are you doing? It hurts!
MOM
What in the world are you thinking
going out so late?
I know.
You have a boyfriend, don't you?
I told you to talk to me about it.
To go that far--
That's…
What are you going to do?
How can they do that here?
They didn't get a proper education.
Don't mess up my car.
What are you talking about?
It's so pretty.
DAY FOUR
Not again…
Hey…
Hey!
Bring me Ito!
I said get the medical intern Ito
out here right now!
Excuse me. Can I have your name?
I'm his patient.
Please wait over there.
Empty.
What?
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Sorry.
Nakoshi.
Don't come without contacting first.
-Tell me what's going on!
-Calm down.
Something happened, huh?
I thought you didn't
give strangers rides.
You're not a stranger anymore.
Homunculi are warped elements
locked up in the back of the subconscious.
That's why they look so weird.
I see.
Your brain regained
the sensitivity of a child's mind
while retaining the knowledge
and experience of an adult.
Your rare sixth sense
has saved two people!
This is a fantastic achievement
that'll revolutionize psychotherapy!
Well, if they disappeared,
then why are they part of my body?
About that, please have a look at this.
Could that woman see homunculi, too?
Who knows?
This picture is a self-portrait she drew.
The homunculi transferred…
This is the first thing I thought of
when I heard your story.
I told you that some people
can see homunculi and others can't, right?
Yeah.
For example, people with similar interests
are drawn to each other.
If minds have similar problems,
their homunculi are drawn to each other.
In other words,
the yakuza and high school girl
may seem different from you,
but maybe your mind has similarities.
You must be joking.
I'm not a monster like them.
But their stress disappeared, right?
And it's been transferred to you.
Feeling guilty, living according to
someone else's rules…
Does it sound familiar?
Your own problems
have begun to surface.
My problems?
That woman in red with the flat face.
You felt something
different about her, right?
You're looking at the homunculi,
but the homunculi are looking at you too.
You know what that means, right?
It means that you, yourself,
are a homunculus.
So? What's this woman doing now?
She committed suicide.
Did you already know that?
Yes.
She drew this picture before she died.
Close it.
Huh? But it's only been four days.
Stop joking.
Just hurry up and close it now!
Y-You've turned into
a completely different person.
Nakoshi, have you noticed it?
You weren't this emotional four days ago.
You said you didn't care
if you turned into a vegetable.
That's why I told you…
I'd give you a reason to live
in seven days…
I will not die with those monsters!
Okay, I understand!
In exchange, I have one condition.
Before I close the hole,
please look at my homunculus.
I told you.
I didn't see anything.
-Nakoshi.
-What?
I know when you're lying.
Do you see yourself…
inside me too?
Nakoshi.
Don't be stupid.
Your own problems
have begun to surface.
That woman in red with the flat face.
You felt something
different about her, right?
SUSUMU NAKOSHI, ENGAGEMENT MANAGER
CONSULTING DEPARTMENT
NANAKO
Nanako…
Do you have a business card?
Wow…
-Mao, want mine?
-Handsome with a Porsche.
-I don't want it.
-What a catch.
-Seriously!
-Yeah.
Aren't you being too forward?
Any girl would want him.
There's more to a man than just money.
He should be accepting, too.
Yeah.
Can you live off of being accepting?
-You can.
-Yeah.
But Nakoshi has everything.
Yeah, you're right.
Even if the guy's accepting,
if he's ugly and doesn't have
a stable job, what's the point?
Nice to meet you. I'm Nakoshi.
What's your name?
NANAKO
Empty.
Nakoshi! Let's go drink some more!
Nakoshi!
Nakoshi?
-Hey! Nakoshi!
-Nakoshi!
Nanako.
DAY FIVE
Nanako!
Huh?
You're Nanako, right?
What's wrong?
I'm not sure.
Huh?
I've lost my memory.
Do you… know me?
I want you to come with me.
ITO
You don't have to answer that?
Yeah. It's fine.
Did I live here?
"Empty."
Huh?
When we first met…
that's what you told me.
With that one word,
I was saved.
I, too…
had forgotten who I was.
But…
when I found you…
I remembered.
Here.
Is this…
mine?
You… used to like it.
Did we…
live together?
Yeah.
We were happy
living together,
Nanako.
Nanako?
Nanako, what's wrong?
Are you okay?
Nanako.
-Nanako.
-No.
I don't remember anything.
Nanako, calm down.
Nanako.
Take it slow.
Am I…
Nanako?
Yes.
You…
are Nanako.
DAY SIX
I can't see it.
I can't see it…
No way…
Hey!
It's me!
Hey…
Hello?
It's been a while.
Where are you?
That's what I want to ask you.
You ignored my calls.
Oh, and don't mess up my room.
Are you the one
who did trepanation on Nanako?
I wasn't expecting this.
What a surprise.
I never imagined that you'd run into her.
Why didn't you tell me?
Well, that's a good question.
But the answer
is none of your business.
Of course it's my business!
Nakoshi, please calm down.
It would be boring
if I explained everything to you.
Today's the sixth day.
The experiment you promised to do
isn't over yet.
I got myself back.
And the other homunculus parts
have disappeared.
Too bad.
I can't see homunculi anymore.
Your experiment is over.
Oh, really?
That's good.
Thanks to you,
I've just about proved my hypothesis.
You've proved it?
Of course, it's all reality to you.
I'm not denying that.
You saved your dear girlfriend
and got together again.
And you can't see
homunculi anymore, right?
What are you trying to say?
Nakoshi,
maybe this world is nothing more
than an illusion created by the brain.
I mean, I said that you yourself
might be a homunculus, right?
The homunculi show you
what you want to see.
Everything is just your own imagination.
No, that can't be true.
I'm sure I saw it.
No.
It means that this world is a convenient
illusion created by the brain.
You see?
Well, I don't mean to destroy
your happy ending…
but the real her
is going to remember everything soon.
She's going to remember the real world.
Remember?
What's this "real world" bullshit?
What are you thinking?
You might find out that some memories
shouldn't be remembered.
What exactly are you trying to say?
Nakoshi, don't you have any idea
what I'm talking about?
You saw her homunculus too, right?
Yeah.
I saw it.
She was in red…
But that was only in your world.
Unlike you, nothing happened to her
after she underwent trepanation.
So my experiment went no further.
But she brought about
an unexpected turn of events.
Because she met you.
But you can't see homunculi anymore.
And you can't protect her.
Unfortunately, the thing that was wrong
was your brain itself.
H-Hey…
Nanako…
Ito?
I knew it was you…
Right, Chihiro?
Chihiro?
Nanako.
But the real her
is going to remember everything soon.
She's going to remember the real world.
Nanako…
Hey…
Who are you?
Who… are you?
No!
No…
-Nanako…
-Let go of me!
No…
I want to see the real you.
I have to see it!
Okay?
It'd be better
if you didn't know the real me!
I want to know the real you anyway!
Okay?
Nanako!
I killed her…
The one who killed Nanako…
was me.
I've told you over and over again!
You did tell me!
But I didn't think
my mom would be that mad.
You should have known!
She's always like that,
like at the funeral the other day.
That was different.
Different?
-How is it different?
-Shut up!
You're such a pain.
I've had enough.
What are you doing, Chihiro?
Stop! What are you doing?
Nanako!
Nanako…
I didn't want to remember…
No…
You're…
empty.
Hey, over here! The annular solar eclipse!
Look!
Oh, it was today.
Yeah!
Oh…
They're overlapping.
It's coming.
Look.
I'm not…
Nanako.
Nanako…
-What happened?
-Don't touch me!
Please, Nanako, calm down.
Were you paying any attention to me?
You never change.
I bet you wouldn't cry even if I died!
You are empty.
PRECAUTIONS FOR DAILY LIFE
AFTER MISCARRIAGE
Nanako!
Nanako, wait!
Stop!
Nanako, let's talk!
Let me go!
Nanako!
Nanako…
I've wanted to apologize…
I've wanted to say…
I'm sorry.
What is…
your name?
Chihiro.
Chihiro…
Wow, Nakoshi. That was amazing.
You even saved
the woman who did this to you.
I wasn't expecting that.
Can you say "I love you"
to the woman before you now?
The feelings inside of you
are for Nanako, right?
My experiment got derailed.
It's just an illusion
created by a misunderstanding!
And yet,
you're comforting each other.
You're projecting yourself onto others
and getting high off the feeling.
Are you okay with that?
I thought you didn't want
to die with a monster.
Hey.
Why are you getting so worked up?
What is it about me…
that you want to deny so badly?
The connection between myself and others…
It's the homunculi, right?
No. When are you going to wake up?
Water.
Huh?
You're…
made of water.
Well, at first glance, you're invisible.
But when you get nervous,
there are bubbles.
Yeah. Here they come now.
Over there, too.
There, too.
No! I told you!
It's nothing more than an illusion--
I can finally see you.
No…
What do you mean?
This is…
Oh…
It's your father.
So it was hiding there?
The goldfish.
He kept it as a pet when I was a kid.
It was his only hobby--
Did you… like that goldfish?
Why are you asking me that?
Where's this goldfish now?
Your father…
Between you and the goldfish,
who did your father cherish more?
Oh…
It's coming out.
It has no eyes.
It can't see.
He won't look at you.
"Look at me."
You want him to look at you…
but he won't.
Nakoshi…
Look at me closer!
Please.
The homunculus is gone.
You're lying!
Help me…
You're the only one…
who can see me.
I've finally found you…
It has to be…
It has to be you…
The homunculi aren't the problem.
We both…
only wanted to be seen.
We didn't try to see the other person.
When you look at the other person…
you can create the world.
DAY SEVEN
Thanks for waiting.
Let's go.
Subtitle translation by Astrid Oliver