Dream of the Red Chamber
Based on the novel by Cao Xueqin
Directed by Bu Wancang
Master Jia, rest easy.
What? Why can't we enter through the
front.
Mistress Lin has arrived.
Grandmother.
It was so unexpected.
Your mother passed away in front of me.
Please don't cry.
Don't cry. I am more dismayed.
Mother, you shouldn't feel sad.
Though Grandmother weeps, it is the
hand of fate.
She has a good granddaughter.
You can take comfort in knowing that.
Daiyu, this is your aunt and uncle.
Aunt. Uncle.
Make yourself at home.
Child, your body feels a little weak.
Are you ill?
Since childhood,
I've been taking medicine nearly every
day.
We have sent for many doctors
but to no avail.
The young madam has traveled far.
No need for her to be tutored.
Yes.
Ah I seem to have arrived late.
I've neglected our guest.
Grandmother.
Don't you recognize her?
She's a spiteful woman, as we all know
around here.
This is my niece and elder brother's Lian's
wife.
Her name is Wang Xifeng.
Second Sister-in-law.
The world is truly blessed by her beauty.
I cannot blame Grandmother for missing
you so.
Old Madam, Master Bao has arrived.
Very well.
Grandmother.
Mother.
Second Sister-in-law.
Do you know who she is?
It seems that I've met this younger sister
before.
Of course not, you've only just met and
now you call her sister?
Are you sure you're not mistaken?
Yes, I'm sure I've seen her before,
but I've forgotten where.
Don't be ridiculous. Where could you have
seen her?
She is your cousin, Lin Daiyu.
Of course.
It's not wrong to call her "little sister".
Little Sister Lin, where did you study?
I believe you certainly can read.
Miss Lin, do you have one of these?
No.
Silly child. That jade stone was made for
your
when you were one month old.
How could just anyone have one?
A gift or not,
both younger and elder sisters do not
have one.
What use do I have of it?
Hey! Hey! What's the matter with you!
Come on, put your arms up!
I don't want it! I don't want it!
Take it. I don't want this old thing.
All right. Give it to me.
Silly child. You make too much trouble.
Your cousin Lin had one once,
but your aunt had died. She couldn't give it
up.
So it had been buried with her.
Your cousin does not wish to discuss it.
So please don't mention it.
Why are you being silly?
Dear child, put it on.
Quickly.
Dear child, your sister Lin has arrived.
Let her wash up. Come,
let's go to the courtyard.
I'm not going.
I want to follow Sister Lin.
Miss Lin, let me taste the rouge from your
lips.
Eh, you are a devil child.
She has only met you today, and you are
being unruly.
What to do with you!
Very well. Let's go.
Feng Lazi.
Call the servants to prepare two rooms for
Madam Lin.
Make her feel at home.
Yes, madam.
Is this the serving wench you've brought?
What is her name?
Her name is Xueyuan.
I believe see she's too small for the task.
But I have many servant girls.
Yuanyang, call Zijuan here
Yes, madam.
You're so thin.
Have you been taking your tonic?
Yes, I often take renshen yangrong herbal
pills.
I have some here.
Let me have some prepared for you.
This is Miss Lin.
There are too many people here.
From now on, you will serve Miss Lin.
Miss Lin.
Madam, it's cold out here.
What's on your mind?
I see that you shouldn't worry so.
Is your grandmother's home similar to
yours?
I'm not homesick.
I just think my fate is a bitter one.
You think I've only just arrived here.
Let cousin start the rumor.
And cast away the jade as he tried to.
As he should have.
Such is my fate.
He's a fool.
Since your cousin has lived here so long,
he's familiar with everyone.
He has a bit of a temper.
It's cold out here. Come inside.
What are you doing?
Doing? Just preparing to have your child
someday.
Xiren, we have a relative over, did you
know?
I knew. It's Mistress Lin.
Did you see Miss Lin?
She is truly beautiful.
Qingwen, I think Miss Lin looks a bit like
you.
What rubbish. If I could be like her,
I'd be ecstatic.
Either way, 'tis better to be a woman than
a man.
Why's that?
You don't know.
Woman is made of water and man is
made of mire.
When I see a woman, I can feel how clean
she is.
A man simply feels dirty.
Stuff and nonsense again.
Master Bao.
Second Grandmother.
What's he up to?
Today, we have a double surprise.
Guess who's here?
Who?
Your Aunt Xue has brought your cousin
Xue Baochai along.
She has come to live here.
Are you fooling me?
Is there lack of housing in Nanjing?
Why should they come here?
Certainly with Xue's abundance of
farmland,
she'd still visit her relatives.
They've just arrived in Beijing today.
The main reason for this trip is because
your cousin Xue Pan killed a foreigner.
So in order to avoid trouble,
they're traveling here.
By the way, they also wish to visit your
mother.
That sounds good. Where are they?
Take me to them.
Come on, help me get dressed in the...
Look at you.
So impatient, you can't even finish your
sentence.
It's certainly busy idleness.
I want to see if this elder sister is as
beautiful as Cousin Lin.
So I especially invited her here for you.
Good woman, you cherish me.
Here, put this on.
In one year, this child Baoyu has grown so
high.
I heard that when Baoyu was born,
he had a jade stone in his mouth.
Is this true?
Look, isn't that it hanging on his chest?
His mother often speaks to me of this.
Baoyu, may I look at it?
All right.
"Lose me not, forget me not,
Eternal life shall be your lot"
Well...
those two sentences do sound familiar
when the two slices of jade are put
together.
Sister, can you show me your jade piece?
I don't have one, or don't you believe
sister Feng?
No, I want to see.
Don't be like that. I'll show it to you.
Very fragrant.
"Let not this token wander from your side,
And youth perennial shall with you abide".
"Lose me not, forget me not,
Eternal life shall be your lot".
This really is a pair.
All right, then don't ever lose that jade
piece.
Look at Baochai's gold locket.
Doesn't this mean that you are destined
for each other?
Sister Bao,
was this gold piece found in your mouth
when you were born?
No.
This is Miss Lin.
Miss Lin, please sit down.
I didn't mean to interrupt your
conversation.
How do I put it...?
Had I known you were here,
I wouldn't have disturbed you.
Everyone here is a good sister.
No one will be left out.
Miss Lin, I finally recognize you.
Really? - No fooling.
I think tomorrow, you should carve out a
slice of gold.
What? A slice of gold?
Sister Bao has a gold locket.
The inscription goes along with my own
jade.
Ah, what a coincidence.
Could you announce to everyone
that we shall now have some wine?
Baoyu, you can't drink wine.
Good mother, I'm only having one cup.
No, if you get drunk, Grandmother will
blame it on me.
I won't get drunk. Don't worry.
I see that Baoyu still listens to Aunty.
If you cannot enjoy wine,
you cannot enjoy anything.
True, if you cannot enjoy,
you should not drink.
Yes, Brother Baoyu is willing to be a little
naughty.
Please have some.
That little strumpet.
A wench worth two pieces of silver!
How dare she assume such arrogance
in front of me!
Oh! This harlot.
She'll take Baoyu as her own,
and forget that I was the woman who
nursed him.
I'll soon tell old madam not to find you a
man.
Will you still be up to your tricks?
Qingwen.
Why are you crying?
I don't want to stay in this house any
longer.
You ran me out to be with another.
What rubbish is this?
Why are you so upset?
After you left,
everyone went out.
I was taking a nap when
your wet nurse Lee came.
I didn't know.
She said I didn't greet her.
She called me a strumpet.
She said she'll make sure I won't have any
man.
That old hag.
Why do you listen to her?
I'll leave anyway.
It's useless. She'll run me out.
The first two days, my elder brother came.
Prepared to give you silver
to buy me back.
Is this true?
Good sister, would you leave?
So strange.
I'm not the mistress of this house. How
can I stay?
According to your words, you assured me.
Certainly.
I knew early on
you'll all want to go.
Leaving me all alone.
You really don't want me to go?
Why do you need to be so sullen?
If you want me to stay,
promise me three things.
If you say three pieces, I'll promise you
three hundred pieces.
Tell me.
First, I forbid you to taste another woman's
lips again.
Second, I forbid you talk about staying
lonely.
Third,
Where did you come from?
From Miss Lin's.
What did she say?
She wonders why you didn't come up to
see her.
Yes, I should go see her.
Did Miss Lin really say that?
No, I lied. She's in her busy idleness.
Let her attend to her own affairs.
Spring is here again.
Where is she?
Miss Lin, Miss Lin.
What's the matter? Don't touch me.
I see you've overslept.
Get up! Let's chat.
My entire body aches. Too tired to get up.
So, let me lie down too.
There's no other pillow.
We'll have to share one.
Oh, for heaven's sake.
You really are the evil star in my cluster.
Whose nails have pared your face?
It's just a piece of rouge.
You really should be more discreet.
Otherwise, we'll both be blamed for it.
This is a good fragrance. Show me what it
is.
It's nothing.
Dear miss, may I take another sniff?
What for?
I have no gold locket
that could compare to your beloved
Baoyu.
'Tis no use to sample my fragrance.
If you say that to me again,
I will give you some of this.
Elder brother,
I won't say it again.
How lively it is in here.
Wherever this devil child goes, he makes
a lot of noise.
That's true.
Did you come to interrupt us?
No, I came out to join in the fun.
You wench, you whore.
You shameless thing.
You dare to leave.
I tried to reason with you.
Even if she's in the wrong, she's still your
wet nurse.
Do you want to have her beaten?
You have to be careful around Baoyu.
What? You still need him to tend to these
affairs.
Well, this is really none of my business,
But he doesn't want other people to do it.
There's no reasoning with him.
You are too busy.
May I be of some help?
Miss Baochai, you're too kind.
I really want to thank you.
You should feel at home.
From now on, if you need something, don't
hesitate to ask.
And if you need anything, just tell me.
Please tear it.
It makes a lovely sound.
Won't you regret it?
They say, "A thousand pieces of gold can't
buy a smile".
How much is this fan worth?
I'd say I got a bargain.
Master Bao, you're smiling.
Just now a servant in Madam's room has
told me
that Jincha has fallen into the well and
died.
She has died over you.
It's all my fault.
I got angry and beat her once.
Then I let her outside.
I only meant to send her away for a few
days,
then ask her to come back.
How would I know she'd jump into the
well?
I fear Aunty may be mistaken.
Perhaps she lost her footing
while playing alongside the well.
That may be so,
but I'm worried.
Then it's of no consequence.
If you feel bad, simply put two pieces of
silver
into her coffin with some fresh new clothes
for her memorial.
I think I should.
I've already given her 52 pieces of silver,
but there's no time to make a new dress.
That's easy.
I have two new outfits that I haven't
altered.
We can pack them into her memorial hall.
You are truly good and wise.
Stop.
Father.
What did you do?
Nothing.
Uncle.
What's the matter, that you should cry?
Master, my sister Jincha jumped into the
well and drowned.
Why did she jump in the well?
What is it?
I don't know.
Dammit. How can this happen in my
family?
Young master raped his serving wench,
and she jumped in the well.
And we have to bury the body.
Damn, the shame of it all.
Go to the den with me.
Go.
Mr. Jiao, what were you talking about?
Mind your own business.
My sister died by herself - by her own
hand.
You're drunk. Your mouth is not clean.
Clean?
In this house, I see two lions guarding the
doorway.
Those are the only clean items in this
household.
You have to tell me. How did Jincha die?
I don't know.
Beast. Didn't you hear me?
How many young masters live in this
house besides you?
Bar the doors.
Father.
You unfilial beast.
You've trampled on everything I've taught
you.
Now you've committed a serious crime.
Father. Father!
My child.
What are you doing?
The master should teach the child.
I've waited fifty years to bear a son.
Master, can't you see in his face that he is
yours?
Well, if you kill him,
you'll have to kill me too.
What right does Old Madam have to tell
me this?
Why are you barging here?
I have no son. Not one who treats me like
this.
I am speechless.
Mother.
I'm simply teaching him a lesson. It will be
good for him.
If you speak this way,
how can I bear it?
I say that you cannot bear the
responsibility.
You beat him with no evidence?
Can you bear this burden?
Mother, don't be upset.
I won't beat him.
You don't need to follow your anger.
You've shown me how you feel about
mother and son.
Come.
Prepare a sedan chair for me.
I shall return to Nanjing with Madam and
Baoyu.
Don't cry.
Baoyu is still young. You have hurt him.
When he grows up, he will remember you.
Mother please.
Your son has no ground to stand upon.
That much is clear. You've brought that
upon yourself.
Call them to prepare the sedan chair for
me.
Look how you've beaten him.
Old Madam, you take a rest.
Quickly, get a bench here to lift Baoyu
aloft.
Xueyan,
what are you two talking about.
Elder sister says
that Master Bao's father beat him for no
reason.
That he was beaten badly.
Melt this pill in his wine
and take it to him.
This should cause his blood to clot.
Okay.
Miss Lin, why do you cry?
You must correct your own mistakes from
now on.
You needn't worry.
I'm only faking to teach them a lesson.
In fact, I feel no pain.
Second Daughter-in-law is here.
Don't go.
If one were to look me in the eyes,
I would feel humiliated.
Do you feel a little better now?
He was in pain, and now he's fast asleep.
Maybe a little better.
When he wakes, he'll be hungry.
Call someone to bring him something from
my room.
Qingwen.
Why did you pretend to sleep?
Do me a favor. Take these handkerchiefs
to Miss Lin.
Master Bao wants to give you this.
Even in such dire peril,
he still thinks of me.
"Vain are all these idle tears,
tears shed secretly - for whom?
Your kind gift of a foot of gauze,
only deepens my gloom".
Good morning, Aunty.
Come sit with me.
I feel a bit stuffy.
You worry me.
I can certainly ease your sorrow.
After Baoyu's father flogged him,
I haven't slept well.
Baoyu has grown older, but more
mischievous.
I think we should have a wedding
breakfast for him.
You're not mistaken.
But Baoyu's affairs have already been
taken care of.
Taken care of? Are you referring to Lin
Daiyu?
No. - No?
Of course not. I'm talking about Miss
Baochai.
When you compare Miss Lin with Miss
Baochai,
only Miss Baochai has many blessings.
She is also a good relative of the Wangs,
if Aunty can turn them in our favor?
Sister's niece is the perfect match for my
son.
It'll be for the best.
Miss Baochai is not as unique as Miss Lin.
But I've always liked her.
However, Old Madam knows Baoyu is
very fond of Lin Daiyu.
If Old Madam won't promise Baochai his
hand in marriage...
Then we should tell Old Madam
that one is gold and one is jade.
Gold and jade together will make a good
match.
Wouldn't Old Madam agree to that?
You are so clever.
I also heard that Brother Fan
plans to move Aunty and Miss Baochai
away.
This will be much better.
In case Baochai's not able to come back
for a while.
Second Daughter-in-law.
Sister Baochai.
When you move, we'll truly be saddened.
We've bothered you enough.
Nonsense.
I think you should come visit my home
some time.
It's autumn already.
The garden appears more desolate.
For sure. Miss Lin has taken ill.
And Xue Baochai has moved away.
How desolate indeed.
Baochai was happy here. Why did she
move?
She has her own house.
Why must she live here?
I'm going to see Miss Lin.
Don't disturb her.
These past two days, she has felt rather
sad.
Why?
A few days ago, a letter arrived from
Yangzhou.
Her father, a scholar-official, has just
passed away.
Why am I not told of these things?
Because you were ill.
Madam ordered us not to discuss outside
affairs.
"Upon one's self are mainly brought
regrets in spring and autumn gloom;
A face, flowerlike may be and moonlike
too;
but beauty all for whom?"
"Cool autumn is here once more.
Alone I dwell, my heart is sore.
Day lilies in the northern halls
cannot make me forget my cares.
"I pace the court. Where can I go?
Lost, my past happiness.
Remembered joys.
But fill me with distress".
"The Milky Way is twinkling,
there is no sleep for aching hearts.
The atmosphere strikes chill.
My grief I must impart".
Miss Zijuan.
Can't you hear? She is depressed.
Don't you make her angry again.
I heard that Uncle has passed away.
She is ill all the time.
She might grow thinner.
Remember, these past two days, she
wasn't that ill.
Amitabha.
This is news. You practically shouted it.
If I'm being disorderly, send for a doctor.
Are you feeling cold? Your dress is rather
thin.
Don't get fresh.
What will other people think?
Zijuan.
What did the doctor say about Miss Lin?
Don't shout and make a scene.
We'll discuss this over there.
The doctor prescribed some bird's nest
soup.
Easy enough. Tomorrow I'll tell Old
Madam
to order one or two liang of soup.
That should be good for a few years.
You say it so eloquently.
What will you do when she goes home?
Who's going home?
Miss Lin.
You're lying. Her parents are dead.
Where can she go?
Young Master, you should know.
Your family, the Jia clan is very big and
powerful.
Sure her parents are gone.
But I'm sure she has many uncles.
She is of the Lin family.
Why would she live with the Jia's?
We're related. Why can't she live here?
The Lins come from a long line of scholars.
They won't neglect their progeny.
So early this year, or late next year,
someone in her family will pick her up
and marry her off.
I believe Miss Lin will loathe
to leave here.
Not exactly.
Night before last, Miss Lin told me that
she wants to tell you
that she intends to go home.
Master Bao, Old Madam is calling for you.
What's the matter?
Miss.
Please take your medicine.
Did someone just come by?
Only Young Master Bao.
Why didn't you tell me?
You looked so sad.
I didn't want him to disturb you.
It's no use!
Oh, Baoyu. How truly horrid!
Zijuan. Zijuan.
What did you tell that simpleton just now?
His eyes were glazed over.
Hands and feet are cold.
He couldn't say a word.
It's as though he were dead.
You... You... You...
Stop doing that.
Have the courage to
strangle me to death.
I spoke in jest.
I told him you wished to return to Suzhou.
And he took it seriously.
In any case,
come with me.
Old Madam and Aunty are with him.
You'll have to take the responsibility.
Go. Go.
Perhaps he'll wake up when he sees you.
What is it now?
He's near death.
Baoyu, what is wrong with you?
Baoyu.
How did this happen?
You useless wench.
What did you say to make him like this.
I was only having fun with him.
I told him Miss Lin wants to go home to
Suzhou.
I didn't say anything else.
Come see what you've done.
Little witch.
Master Bao.
If you have to go, take me with you.
I was only having a little fun.
We won't leave.
Isn't that the ship that will pick up Miss
Lin?
Quickly, bring it here.
Now it can't leave.
Baoyu, stop worrying.
Miss Lin will not be leaving.
What?
His jade is missing.
He just came back with Qingwen.
I was frightened and didn't notice.
That jade is Baoyu's life-giver.
Perhaps it's the lack of the jade
that made him careless.
What can we do?
Old Madam, don't you worry.
Xiren, when Master Bao went out, did you
hold his jade?
When I put it on him, he still had it.
He had it on when he talked to me.
Then it's lost in his home.
All right then.
Old Madam and Aunty, go have a rest.
We'll call the doctor to attend to Baoyu.
As for the jade,
hand it to me when you find it.
Did he feel better?
He has no disease.
It's because he lost his jade stone.
He believes it connects him to the spiritual
world.
If Baoyu has lost it, how...?
You know him.
I wish to see him.
Miss, I notice you're still immobile.
Without that jade stone...
Second Sister-in-Law is looking for it
in the garden right now.
She'll find it.
I found it.
Where?
Here!
(Reciting Twelve Earthly Rows)
To the west!
Look here.
Madam, I've seen that Qingwen
has been behaving in a frivolous manner.
Though I don't believe she stole the jade,
it wouldn't be wise to keep her around
Baoyu.
You're right.
With her snake-light waist, and her thick
shoulders,
she's a bit like Lin Daiyu.
Madam, Second Sister-in-law.
I've checked Qingwen's wardrobe.
The jade isn't there.
What did she say when you checked her
wardrobe?
She was getting annoyed.
She hasn't eaten since yesterday.
That little witch.
It isn't good for her to be here.
We should send her away.
Master Bao!
Master Bao! Master Bao.
I don't understand.
How can the jade completely disappear?
I see this is one of those disasters.
Yesterday, I asked a fortune teller.
She said, only someone born of gold can
help him.
Only she can bring him happiness.
Otherwise you will never recover the jade.
The stars are in place for him to be
married.
Let the stars solve this problem for him.
Old Madam speaks wisely.
I watched Brother Baoyu grow up.
Should have married him off earlier.
So we would have no worries.
Yes, I certainly think so.
Hey, am I not the mistress of the house?
Why would I not be allowed in?
Old Madam is talking. Wait a while.
I see that Baoyu is completely taken with
Lin Daiyu.
If we want him to recover,
we must allow her to stay with him.
Surely under normal circumstances,
Daiyu is fine for him.
But I think the child's physical endowment
is weak.
And don't forget.
She is not the one born of gold.
Right. This is Baoyu's future we are talking
about.
Old Madam should plan ahead for him.
I understand completely.
For the sake of our dignity,
it's Xue Baochai who is destined to be with
him.
Old Madam has good taste.
And both sides are all related.
It isn't for me to say.
It's only for Baoyu's future that I care.
A younger sister of the Xue family
and Baoyu will make a good pair.
Old Madam, do you believe
a slice of gold and a slice of jade
are destined for a good marriage.
Regrettably, the jade is lost.
Never mind that.
We have the gold.
Perhaps after they wed, we'll find the jade.
I expect to.
So is your younger sister willing to make
this vow.
Certainly.
She has said that the gold locket comes
from a monk
who told her to find the special one who
has the jade.
Old Madam, don't you see this is a good
opportunity.
Yes, don't you see?
I concur,
but Baoyu is still in love with Daiyu.
We should settle this matter in secret.
I think it's a good idea.
What's so funny?
Master Baoyu marrying Baochai?
Why is that funny?
Miss Baochai is Baoyu's first cousin on his
mother's side.
What would we call her?
Silly wench.
They were having a private conversation.
Don't make a scene.
Yuchuan.
Yes.
Why were you shouting?
This silly wench tried to come in. I stopped
her.
If you heard our conversation,
I forbid you to repeat it. Understand?
Yes.
I haven't seen him for days.
I don't know what to expect.
I forgot to take my medicine.
I'll go get it.
Why are you crying?
Sister Yuchuan beat me.
Why did she beat you?
For something I said about Master Baoyu
marrying Baochai.
If Master Baoyu marries Baochai,
why would she beat you?
Old Madam and Aunty were talking about
having
Master Baoyu marry Baochai.
And I asked what are we supposed to call
her.
Baochai is his first cousin.
So she slapped my mouth.
Mistress, how did you end up over there?
I want to speak to Baoyu.
Is Master Baoyu home?
Baoyu.
Why are you sick?
I am sick over Miss Lin.
This is not normal.
Zijuan, take her to get some rest.
Mistress, please take a rest.
Mistress, let's go back.
All right.
Time for us to leave.
Meet me in my room.
Yes, madam.
The situation with Baoyu is very serious.
Yesterday, I called in a seer.
She said only a person who is born of gold
can help.
Only then can he recover.
I heard it said that Xue Baochai was born
with
a piece of gold in her mouth.
She has made a gold locket from it.
This gold and jade would make for a good
marriage.
What are your thoughts?
Since Old Madam loves him so,
and cares enough to arrange a marriage,
How can I refuse?
But if Baochai's Aunt gives her blessing
and Baoyu remains ill,
then this marriage will be for naught.
I've already consulted your daughter-in-
law.
Her aunt's given her blessing, concerned
for Baoyu's health.
She'll follow the matrimonial rites
according to southern law.
Send for a sedan chair with eight men to
bear them.
They'll take their vows in the hall,
then entreat to the nuptial chamber.
And what about friends and relatives?
We don't need to bother.
When Baoyu recovers,
we'll let them know and then invite them.
All right.
We did our part.
Now you do yours.
Yes.
This affair has me worried a bit.
Worried a bit, indeed.
I know what you mean, Old Madam.
You're afraid that Baoyu still loves Miss
Lin.
He will take no pleasure in marrying
Baochai, yes?
Yes, it's a difficult matter.
Old Madam, you need not worry.
Let me talk to Baoyu.
I have a plan.
Okay, do it.
Brother Baoyu, congratulations.
Old Master has already chosen a day for
your wedding.
It's Miss Lin you wish to marry, isn't it?
Old Master says,
while you are ill, you can marry Miss Lin.
But if you stay silly, she won't marry you.
I'm not silly. You're silly.
I go to see Miss Lin.
Miss Lin is the bride now.
She is bashful and unwilling to see you.
Fortunately, my heart
belongs to Miss Lin.
She will bring it to me when we are
married
or put it in my belly.
How did it go?
I see we'll need to make a switch.
What sort of switch?
We tell Master Baoyu that Miss Lin
is to be wed to him.
While we disguise Miss Baochai to
secretly take her vows.
Good plan.
Though Miss Baochai may frown upon it.
Miss.
I know you've no reason to listen to me.
But with Baoyu's illness so severe,
how can they hold a wedding for him?
Give me some light.
I'm about to throw up
and I want to see if anything's wrong.
Blood.
Don't be afraid.
Mistress, Mistress.
Mistress.
The betrothed will enter through this door
with Aunt Xue.
Do not let our guests from Xiaoxiang
Garden know.
Yes, madam.
What is your wish, madam?
Tell Baoyu that today is a joyous day.
He will be married to Miss Lin.
He must not act silly from here on.
After he'd heard he will wed Miss Lin,
His head seems a little more clear.
Handkerchief.
Handkerchief... in the chest.
No... not this one.
The one with the embroidery.
Mistress, what's the matter?
Heat... heat.
The brazier.
Mistress, what are you doing?
Mistress... Mistress... Mistress!
What's wrong with Mistress Lin?
Zijuan, come with me.
I see Mistress Lin doesn't look well.
But it's of no consequence.
This isn't Old Madam's affair
and she needs you now.
Let me take you to her.
I cannot.
Look at her. I can't leave her side.
Tell her this.
If Mistress Lin stops breathing,
I will leave.
But why give me orders at this time?
If you can't go, then call Xueyan.
Tell her yourself.
Zijuan, I'm going.
Since you are marrying Miss Lin,
your head must remain clear.
If you act silly, she will be very angry.
I know. I know.
Miss Lin is coming from the garden.
Is there a problem? Why isn't she here
yet?
When the time is right, she'll be here.
Xueyan, I'm weak.
Xueyan.
She went to Old Madam.
I'm Zijuan.
Zijuan,
I have nothing here.
Listen.
My body is clean.
Call them.
Send... me...
Send... me... back.
Yes, mistress.
Baoyu.
Hello.
Miss Lin.
Miss Lin, I haven't seen you for days.
Ironically, you are now beneath the
wedding veil.
Why do you need to cover your face?
I want to...
Would she be angry?
She will not.
Where am I?
Am I in a dream?
Today is your special day.
What dream do you mean?
Who is she?
She is your fiance, Xue Baochai.
No... no...
I am to marry Miss Lin. Where is she?
Don't shout. Old Madam and Aunty are
here.
I have to find Miss Lin.
You'll do no such thing.
Miss Lin is very ill.
When she recovers, she will see you.
Of course. She's ill.
I've also become ill.
We will both die.
Old Madam, I beg you.
Beg you to give us an empty house.
Let me die with Lin Daiyu
together.
Old Madam, I beg you.
Have some porridge.
Master has promised me the hand of Miss
Lin.
Why did Baochai take her place?
I was to be married to you.
Your father and Old Madam has agreed.
It was not my idea.
Even now,
you still pine for Miss Lin.
It will make Old Madam feel sad.
Don't talk to me.
Who do you tell these lies to?
Honestly, I tell you.
Your sweetheart Lin Daiyu
has just died.
She's dead?
When?
On the day of our wedding.
Baoyu, please don't be uncivil.
I'll do as I please.
Lin Daiyu has died. I've never been more
serious.
Baoyu. Baoyu.
Miss Lin.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
Whose nails have pared your face?
It's just a piece of rouge.
You really should be more discreet.
Otherwise, we'll both be blamed for it.
My body feels weak.
Touched by such exquisite beauty.
What are you saying?
I'll tell Uncle and Aunt.
You show me such licentious songs
and impudent verse,
only to humiliate me.
Dear miss,
if I had the heart to humiliate you,
then tomorrow, let me be a tortoise and
drop into the river.
The world is no banquet.
Tomorrow I shall return home.
What about you?
I'll follow you.
If I should die?
If you should die, I shall become a monk.
Baoyu.
Zijuan, come help.
I'll call Old Madam and Aunty.
You just missed her.
It's too late.
I know.
I don't even know her last words.
She said she has no close relatives here.
She wished to be buried in the south.
She... what else did she say?
When she spoke her last breath,
she called out your name.
Miss Lin.
I will never forget your love for me.
Baoyu.
He just left.
Xiren, he's probably returned to his room.
Go find him.
He never runs outside aimlessly.
Why did he just leave?
Don't worry. I'm sure he...
Sir.
It's Mister Jiao.
What is it?
Master,
I've been all over Beijing.
Inside and outside, I've asked around.
No news.
Just one man who told me,
he'd met a man under Wutai Mountain
who very much resembled our Master
Baoyu.
But he can't swear it's him.
I should have seen this coming.
The End
Subtitles by T. L. Young