Here she comes,
the woman that makes
you ask are those lash
marks or stretch marks?
Are those remnants of lustful
pains or varicose veins?
It's Sister Sadie Safeword!
Seriously?
That is my intro?
What?
I, uh, said your name right,
didn't I?
I will have you know I am
100% Grade A fresh as a daisy.
Stretch marks?
I don't see any!
I don't see any on these pumpkins.
Anyway, enough of that, Cretin,
how are my movie loving maggots?
Are you ready for another
painful picture
to pound your putrid
peepers into submission?
Good to hear, my wormy weirdos.
You have pleased your mistress.
But do not think that
I will go easy on you.
I'm in a very torturous mood.
Slave, bring me the sack
of cinematic Sadism!
Thank you, Slave.
You will be thrashed soundly
for your loyal service.
Let's see what we have today.
What in the Holy Hell?
Horndog's Beach Party.
What, what is this?
Is this like a porno or something?
Is this even a real movie?
It's on tape, isn't it?
Of course it's on tape.
But look at it, look at the label.
It looks like child wrote this.
A movie is a movie is a movie, right?
I mean, do you think our
audience tunes in for high art?
I would hope that they
tune in for these babies.
The movies are just,
how you say, gravy.
Whatever helps you sleep at
night, Sister.
Don't make me come over there!
Anyway, let's get to the
movie or whatever this is.
I don't know,
your guess is as good as mine.
If is beach party,
perhaps there will be girls
in bikinis.
Or maybe there will be sand
where it doesn't belong.
Now that is true torture!
I will be back to check on
the progress of your torture soon.
You know, I went to beach once.
There was beautiful sun,
happy people,
children laughing, I hated it!
Come on down to
the 10th Annual Horndog's
Beach Party.
Located on beautiful
Venice Beach, California.
And oh boy,
do we have all sorts of fun
in store for your whole family.
Plus, our famous Wet T-Shirt
Competition for adults only.
This Sunday, don't miss it.
Sponsored by the Riverside
County Jaycees.
Hey Man.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm out here by the
paddle boats.
Alright.
Yeah, I'll see you in a little bit.
This is so awesome that your aunt
let us have the condo for the weekend!
Well, at least part of it.
You know, Auntie Brinke never
lets a buck go to waste.
Hmm, I really hope the
two girls are actually cool.
I'm sure they'll be good.
It's just I hope they
don't party too hard.
When did you become such a buzzkill?
Didn't you use to rule
the beach party scene?
That was like 30 years ago!
Thanks Man, get ya on the app.
Dude, this is gonna be so sick.
Look at this.
Hey Fellas.
Huh, uh, I guess nobody's
here to meet us yet.
Let me see.
It says if this guy named
Dusty isn't here
just get the key from under
the doormat.
Oh.
Here it is.
Got it!
Not bad!
Not bad at all.
This will do.
Two bad it's only two bedrooms.
Yeah.
We'll just have to take turns
when we got the chicks in there.
Oh, yeah!
Hey, nice day, Ladies!
Hi!
So you think we can do it?
What?
Come on, Man!
The best beach party ever!
Hope so.
I guess we'll have to see what
our weekend roommates think.
Yeah.
Hey, you okay?
Yeah, just don't like travel.
That's true.
Those 4 a.m. flights suck.
Hey, do you need the bathroom?
I'm gonna take a shower.
Ah, no, I'm cool.
Cool.
Sweet.
Check under the doormat for
the key.
Okay.
They must already have it.
Hmm, maybe they're
already down at the beach?
Hey, this place is pretty sweet!
I've been here a few
times back in high school.
Always had fun.
Killer view!
I can't wait to get down there.
I think I hear the shower.
I'm gonna go pee and change.
Shouldn't you wait until
she's done?
It'll be fine.
It's a great way to meet new people.
Hello!
I hope you don't mind.
We just got in and I need to
go change.
Is that okay?
Uh, sure.
Thanks.
It sure is a nice place here.
Mhmm.
I'm gonna go change real quick
and go down to the beach.
You should join us.
Sounds like fun!
Whoops, sorry!
What was that?
Whoa!
Okay, what's the deal?
They're guys!
What?
Who are you?
Why are you here?
We're obviously here
because of your double D.
You son of a bitch.
Cory, call the police.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
We're here because of the
Desired Destination Rental.
Hold up.
Here's our receipt for the
Desired Destination Rental.
It says Stacy and Loren.
Yeah, I'm Stacy.
And I'm Loren.
So, who are you two?
I'm Dusty.
And I'm Cory.
What the hell are we
gonna do about this?
Do about what?
We already paid Brinke or
whoever, here's our receipt.
There's no hotel rooms within
20 miles,
we just have to make it work.
I'm gonna call Auntie Brinke
about this.
Excuse me, is it okay
if I go back and change.
Uh, I'm gonna go get
something on too, okay?
So...
I'll come change too.
Hello?
Hi, Auntie Brinke.
Oh, hi Dusty.
Did you and Cory make it okay?
Yes we did, thank you.
Is everything alright?
Well, there's a slight issue.
Oh no, what's that?
We are having to share it
with a couple
of guys who rented through
Desired Destination.
What?
I thought I turned those two down.
Well, they're here.
That doesn't make any sense.
I specifically turned down
Brad and Tad
and accepted Loren and Stacy
so there
wouldn't be any boy trouble.
Loren and Stacy are here.
Did they bring Brad and Tad
with them?
If so, I'm really gonna be pissed.
I told them no more than
two for their group.
No, there is no Brad and Tad here.
Well that's good.
What two boys did Loren
and Stacy bring with them?
Just themselves.
Well then I don't see the issue.
Hopefully they're a couple of
nice girls.
No, Loren and Stacy are the boys.
Really?
Did Brad and Tad change their
names just to get the place?
No, Brad and Tad are nowhere here!
Loren are Stacy are two
totally different guys.
So instead of Brad and Tad,
I accepted
two other boys that I thought
were girls?
Yes!
Huh, I wonder why their
parents named them like that?
Oh well.
So is there anything we can..
Oh, I'm so sorry, I gotta get going.
I'm sure you'll all work it out.
Oh, and don't get too crazy there,
Brigitte still likes to freak
out and call
the neighborhood association
at the first sign of fun.
But..
You know, she had the
nerve to call them a few
weeks ago when I had
the music up too loud.
It's a good thing she didn't know
why I really had it up so loud.
I bet her gardener is still smiling...
Anyway, y'all have a great time.
Love you.
I'm in insanity land.
Yes?
Hi, I'm Brad, and this is Tad.
'Sup.
Of course you are.
You know it, Dude.
Are you Loren or Stacy?
I'm Dusty.
Ooh, dirty name.
Cool, Brah.
Anyway, is Loren or Stacy here?
Just wanted to tell 'em no
hard feelings
on losing the place to them.
We got a room just down the street
and was wondering if
those two chicks wanted
to join us in that Horndog
Beach Party competition?
They are dudes and not your type.
Bro, that sucks.
Dude, I know.
What's up, Bro?
She was so uncool, Bro.
Dude, that chick definitely
had some
kind of massive stick up her ass.
Totally Bro.
I mean, what are we gonna do?
Those two chicks have the
best spot
on the beach and we can't
even use it.
I don't know, Dude.
And what about those
two chicks being dudes?
I mean, what's up with that?
Dude, I think we may have to do
something about these two dudes.
Like what, Bro?
Dude, the way I look at it,
if we can't have the
best spot on the beach
for a party, we're gonna
make sure these two dudes
and Miss Stick up her ass
don't win the best beach party.
I knew it!
They're planning a party.
Totally, Bro.
Totally, Dude.
However, they do look very nice.
No, I mustn't give in to temptation!
I've gotta let the
neighborhood association know.
Right.
They won't take my calls
anymore without proof.
Well, if it's proof they
want, it's proof they'll get!
Dude, what are we gonna do
about this?
I don't know.
Um, it's really awkward.
Uh, we could make sure,
we could go talk to them,
or try to figure out how
to make it less awkward.
I mean,
I guess we could talk to them,
but I thought we were just
gonna have
like a dude's party weekend.
This was gonna be sick.
Now we got two chicks here?
But I mean, they're not
half bad looking, you know.
Right, they ain't ugly.
No.
Well, we gotta do something.
They saw me in my underwear,
so it's already kinda awkward.
I do think that I am going to
go talk
to Cory though and try to
make amends.
That would be a good idea.
So it's less awkward all weekend.
I don't know, Man.
Look, Dude, just go talk to her.
Uh, yeah.
You don't have to apologize
or anything, just talk to her.
Yeah.
I mean,
she's really cute and I think
it would make things
better for the weekend.
This is gonna be good for you.
Yeah, yeah.
Alright.
Hi.
Okay.
Hey.
Yeah, um,
she's being a little more
stubborn than I thought she
would be.
She's kinda stressed out.
It turns out the two
we're sharing the condo
with are actually a couple of guys.
Mhmm.
Yeah, they're kinda cute.
Hmm, I dunno,
we'll just see how it goes.
Okay, tell ya what.
You guys come around three,
by that time
it'll be super late and Dusty just
totally has to go along with
the party.
Oh, shoot.
One of the straps of my top ripped.
I have to get a new one
before the party starts.
Well yes, but I'm trying to
start with the top on first.
Okay, see you guys around three.
Okay, bye.
Come in!
Oh, I'm sorry.
I can come back if you like.
No, it's okay.
I just wanted to
apologize for what happened
in the bathroom earlier today.
That's so sweet of you.
I just don't want you thinking
I'm some sort of creep or anything.
Let's just say there were
a few misunderstandings.
Yeah, I'll say.
So, what makes you boys
come out here to Cali?
Stacy always wanted to come
to this beach party weekend,
so I...
Oh, you mean the Horndog
Beach Party?
Uh, yeah, uh.
Oh yeah.
Yeah, Sex Panther.
I'm sorry, I gotta go.
He's going to be fun.
How about the, uh,
whatever the hell that was?
Painful enough for you,
my masochistic minions?
I don't know about you,
but I think this one
has left me speechless.
No, you know what?
Just for that outburst,
I think I am going to
talk about this movie.
First off,
something I'm sure none of you
would have any experience with,
but this movie
has more padding than a bra
on prom night.
Not too mention the gardener,
who is apparently in
totally different time zone
from everyone else around
him that he's talking to.
Then we have the male and the
female lead,
and they have approximately
a 20 foot height difference.
Step stool, buy one!
Then there is this lady who's trying
to stop all these frisky frolics,
but she's the kind of woman
who would
never turn down a good time,
trust me.
It takes one to know one.
And, and..
Playing Devil's Advocate here,
I should mention that Uncle Rob,
I mean,
our producer, of this program,
in conjunction
with the award losing
Hollywood Studios
that provide our top shelf
filmed entertainment,
require you contractually to say
at least one positive thing.
Brinke Stevens.
We are in the presence of
true scream queen royalty.
I bow to her in all of
her beauty and glory.
See, I knew you had it in ya!
That check better clear.
Anything else you wanna say?
Anything else I have to say.
Have you even been watching
the movie?
In so many ways.
In so many ways?
What does this even mean,
in so many ways?
I mean I was thinking about
the film.
You went around the corner
for another
one of those special
massages again, didn't you?
Yes, the $20 bill
was just burning a hole in my pocket.
So you leave me alone
to suffer with this movie?
Well, not totally alone.
I think it is time to turn
the screws
ever tighter on you,
my filthy maggots.
Roll the rest of the movie!
Announcer, you may want to consider
Purelling yourself, thoroughly.
Hey Dude, you all right?
Yep!
Oh, come on!
Look, I know things got
mixed up with the reservation
or whatever,
but that's not our fault.
I know.
What?
Didn't catch that.
I know.
I'm sorry about that as well.
It's cool.
It's just this weekend
is not turning out
the way I thought it would at all.
So, what did you have in mind.
I hoped it could be an all nice
and relaxing weekend on the beach.
Relax, are you serious?
This is like one of the
biggest college
party weekends ever for this area.
Why would you pick this weekend?
I don't know.
Hmm, alright.
Interesting.
What?
I think you just wanted to come
down here and party all weekend.
No, I just..
Look, did you know it was gonna
be like this this weekend?
Yes, but that doesn't mean anything.
But you did know, and you still
chose these dates for your weekend.
What are you, a psychology major?
Uh, actually yeah, yeah.
I just finished my first
year in grad school.
Perfect.
Hey Dusty!
Yes?
Can you take me swimsuit shopping?
Mine just broke.
Sure, I'm gonna get a coffee
as well.
Great.
It wouldn't work out here.
This part of the beach is shared
with the crazy neighborhood
lady next door,
she will call the association
about everything that happens here.
Oh really?
So why doesn't she just move,
why does she stay here?
Because she loves this beach.
This is where she used
to spring break herself.
Cory, you ready?
Yep, I'm ready.
Sorry about the attitude earlier.
Oh, it's cool, me too.
See ya.
Bye.
They left, you can come out!
So what happened?
Uh, I don't know.
I was talking to Cory and
she came on to me, and..
Dude, alright!
And then I freaked out
and rushed to the bathroom.
What?
Really?
I rinsed the shower out
pretty good.
Oh, gross.
It was wild.
It took everything I had just
to knock
on her door and I hadn't been in
a situation like that since Jennifer.
Baby steps, Man.
Baby steps.
So, what are the odds
of hosting a party here?
It might actually be
a little bit difficult.
Apparently their neighbor
is a pain in the ass.
Why don't we just find
somewhere else down the beach?
No, no, no, no, no, no.
We said we're gonna throw
the best beach party ever,
and we're gonna do it.
What about Dusty?
She seems to hold the key as to
whether or not we can have
the party here.
Don't worry about her.
I think I can get her on board.
I do know that Cory's all on board.
That's good.
We just gotta figure out what we're
gonna do about this Brigitte chick.
What if we just go talk to her?
Smart.
Then we'll know who we're
dealing with.
Alright.
I didn't realize it would
be that hard of a decision.
It is a very important decision.
Nah, the first one never
quite works out.
That's why so many.
You should really try some on.
I don't know,
I'm just not in the mood.
Why, what's the matter?
Well, this whole weekend is not
working out the way I thought
it would.
It really was kind
of a stressful morning.
Between Loren and Stacy,
Auntie Brinke isn't much help,
and then this Brad and Tad
guys come by.
Really, who are they?
Just a couple
of frat jocks that were
in the running for the condo
as well.
Nah, maybe my
freshman or sophomore year.
They seemed like
a couple of real idiots.
You know what?
I really think you should try
this on.
Trust me, it'll make you feel better.
Whatever.
I think the last semester of college
really got the good of you.
I mean, all these clinical classes
and the extra classes kicked
your ass.
Well, I'm just glad
it's over and what I want
is just a quiet nice weekend
away from everything.
Well, it is definitely
But I don't think it should
be quiet.
And I don't think you
feel it should be either.
I don't know.
Well, it's a start.
But again, never the first one.
Here, try this.
There we go, the first
cracks are starting to show.
So what do you think
about Loren and Stacy?
Well I guess they're good guys.
I talked to Stacy this morning.
Really, what did he
say about this morning?
Well we had mutual apologies
and understandings.
How 'bout you?
Loren came in to apologize.
He's such a cutie.
Ooh, I know what that means.
Hmm, this one
goes to the maybe pile.
Getting closer.
Mhmm, so are we going to participate
on the beach parties tonight?
Look, it's not going to be
able to work.
We can't risk getting into trouble
by the bitchy Brigitte
and the association.
So what you are saying is that
we need to get rid of her.
In a sense, yes.
At least, we have to get her
to go along with us having a party.
Hmm.
At least we have plenty of
other parties
to go even if we can't host one.
Well, I'm not really giving
up hope
because I kinda invited some
people over.
What?
Um, I may have mentioned to Steph
and Becky that we're hosting
a party.
You did?
Yeah.
They are going to invite everybody!
Probably.
Oh my gosh, oh my gosh, oh my gosh.
What are we gonna do?
What am I gonna do?
We're going to get into so
much trouble.
Auntie Brinke's not going
to have her condo intact.
It's going to be ruined by us.
Okay, okay, okay.
Calm down.
It'll be okay.
How can you say that?
Because anybody who can rock this
swimsuit like you do can do anything.
Mhmm.
Um, looks perfect.
You know what?
We're going to host the best
Horndog Beach Party tonight.
Yes!
Oh my God, I'm so happy.
We have a lot to do.
Yeah.
Did you pick your suit yet?
Um, mhmm, yep.
Isn't that the first on?
Yeah, so?
Let's go,
we have a lot of work to do.
Okay, so let me get this straight.
You want to invite a few
friends over
and have a party on my beach.
On the beach that we share.
You want to have a giant sin party
with drinking and drugs and fornications..
I wouldn't that far.
And get your fornication
juices all over my beach?
I think not!
And I am warning you, I will
be watching and taking notes.
So you go back to your
weekend condo
and get some sun, maybe
splash in the water a little,
but you will not be having
a party on my beach!
Do you understand?
Uh.
Good day.
Any ideas?
I'm sure we'll figure
something out.
What the hell?
Bro, you got him so good!
Good throw yourself, Dude.
Seriously, what the hell is
that about?
That's for taking our
room for the weekend.
Yeah, you totally snaked our room
pretending to be girls!
We didn't pretend anything!
Whoa, you just stop right there.
Hey, we applied just like
everyone else.
It's not our fault they
mixed up the names.
Yeah?
Well because of you,
we don't have the
best spot on the beach to
host a party.
Yeah, you tell 'em, Bro.
We're not going to be
able to have a party either.
Yeah, because we're
gonna make sure you don't.
Whatever, screw you guys.
Let's go.
Yeah, you go on and hide!
Yeah, you tell 'em, Bro!
You okay Dude?
Uh, yeah Bro.
I just think I saw something
awesome over there.
Hey.
Hey, what's the matter with
you guys?
I'm starting to think having
a party
isn't really in the cards anymore.
What makes you say that?
We tried to talk to Brigitte
next door.
Ooh, it didn't go well, did it?
And a couple of jerks
started throwing water balloons
at us and said it was
for taking their room.
And we're not going
to have a party anymore.
What?
Were they a couple frat
looking boys
that kept saying brah and bro
a lot?
Yeah.
Hmm, sounds like Brad and Tad.
Those guys are a couple
of real douches, by the way.
Well, it's time to
start thinking positive.
Oh really?
Yes, because we are going
to have us a beach party here!
Are you serious?
Yes.
So what brought this about?
Well, maybe you were a bit
right earlier
that you guys came here for a party
and it took me a while to
realize that I did too.
Mhmm, alright.
That's awesome!
So what do we have to do to
get ready?
Oh, and what are we gonna
do about your neighbor?
I'm not sure about her yet,
but I know the first thing we
need to do
is to find everything we need
to decorate.
Yes, because we need balloons, booze,
tiki torches, booze, hats, booze.
Oh wait, I forgot something.
Did I mention booze?
Uh, I suppose I better go get
my wallet.
Um, is he alright?
Yeah, uh.
He actually just got out of a
really serious relationship.
Three years.
They were engaged.
Turns out at the end of our
fall semester,
he found out that she was cheating
on him for the last year.
Oh wow, that is so sad
she would do that to him.
Yeah, he took it really hard.
Almost dropped out of school.
That poor guy.
Yeah.
It's actually pretty amazing he's
even on this trip in the
first place.
He might kinda put up a
little bit of a front,
so if it seems like he's acting
a little bit off, that's why.
He's such a sweetie, though.
Yeah.
Hey, if you can, try to take
it easy on him a little bit.
Don't rush him into anything.
Okay.
Okay, ready to go.
Alright, nice.
Yeah, we can just..
Hey, wait, Loren.
You're going with me to the
party store.
Oh, uh sure.
Can I have your keys?
Awesome.
Don't worry, she will
take great care of him.
Look at them.
They're not even trying to
hide it.
Oh my, ooh!
Oh my God!
Oh!
Are you okay?
Nerds!
What is this?
Seriously?
Chocolate milk?
You goobers!
Oh, don't worry,
it does the body good.
Right, Dude?
Oh, yeah, Brah!
Oh yes, this is good stuff.
This is not funny.
No, it's not!
I think it's kinda funny.
What about you, Brah?
Oh, let me look.
I think it's even funnier!
Let's go.
Yeah.
Seriously?
This never gets old.
Yeah, Bro.
Ooh, whoa, what happened?
Brad and Tad.
That's what happened.
What is it with those guys?
I don't know, but I know
what we need to finish it.
What?
Cory.
Yes?
What time are Steph
and Becky coming over?
I told them around three.
Give them a call and
tell them the party's on
and we need their help for a special
situation as soon as possible.
Alright, I'm going to
give them a call right now.
Hey Cory?
Yes?
You can shower first if you'd like.
Thank you.
Please do.
So what are we gonna do?
You know we have to get some supplies.
Right, but what about Brad
and Tad?
Hmm.
We're going to have to
get some distractions.
What?
Sorry man, you're going to
have to take one for the team.
You just want me to go out
there unarmed
and just run around taking it?
Pretty much, but not unarmed.
How'd it go, Bro?
It looks awesome, Dude.
Oh, nice!
What the hell is that joker doing?
Hey Guys.
What the?
Oh, Dude, gross.
It smells like,
it smells like pickle juice.
Oh.
Screw you guys.
Oh!
Oh, Jesus!
Oh, poor boys.
Oh, look at him go.
Will he be alright?
Oh, yeah, he'll be fine.
He was all-college track and field.
He ran the 1600.
Nice.
Looks like the coast is clear.
Oh, that is so wrong.
Maybe a car wash first?
Guys, I got a hold of Becky
and Steph
and they'll be here in like...
Hello?
Where did they all go?
Oh, I'm so sorry.
Uh, it's okay.
The other two went to go get supplies.
I tried knocking to let
you know what was going on.
Thanks for letting me know.
Okay then.
Um, I'll just have to take
a shower when you're done.
Okay.
Loren?
Yeah?
Can you please hand me
the shampoo bottle on the counter?
Uh, sure.
Just hand it through the curtain.
Oh!
Well, now it's time to
get you all cleaned up.
Uh, I, uh, I haven't been..
There, how was that?
That was really good.
Gettin' a bit of a late start,
ain't ya?
Oh, you know, it's a bit
of a last minute addition.
But how is the weekend
a last minute decision.
Well, I don't know.
It just turned out that way.
But better late than never, right?
Heh, party on, Man.
So where ya hosting at?
My Aunt Brinke's condo.
Oh, the one with the little
beach point.
Yeah, that's it.
You been there?
Oh yeah, Brinke and I go way back.
Oh, very cool.
So it's a nice area?
Oh, it's the best.
Sweet.
She still got that crazy ass neighbor?
Yes, unfortunately.
Ah, it's too bad.
She's a real ball buster.
Wonder what her problem is?
Oh, like 15 years ago she was datin'
this college frat boy type.
He left.
She ain't never been the same since.
Yeah, she was a real cougar.
I even tried to get with her,
but I guess I'm not her type.
Whatever.
She couldn't land anybody
after that.
Not that year, not the year after.
Then she got this whole moral
authority bug up her ass,
and well, never been the same since.
Wait a second.
You're tellin' me if we
can just get her laid
by some college frat jock?
Bow chica bow bow!
Right on, Dude.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Oh, I think so.
Alright, that is 11.95.
There, keep it.
Whoa, seriously?
Yeah.
You told us exactly
what we needed to hear.
Awesome.
Thanks.
Hey, come on out tonight.
Alright, Man.
Boom, I'll be there.
See you tonight.
Alright.
Yeah, party down.
You know what?
I think I was too hard on
this film.
I think it has transcended
being a mere motion picture
and has emerged from it's
celluloid cocoon
as a full on sadomasochistic
social experiment.
What are you on about?
No, hear me out.
I'm not even doing a bit.
What kind of sex comedy would
provide so precious little sex?
There is more shopping than anything,
and more talking than
My Dinner With Andre,
and to finish it off,
a fully clothed shower scene.
And as for sex, not a single thrust.
Well played, Horndog's, well played.
You have tortured my subjects
to levels
of submission that I could
only imagine.
I have to admit, you aren't wrong.
Am I ever?
Remember when you
opened that strip club for cats?
Cat Nips?
That was genius idea.
Cat sexuality is untapped goldmine.
It devolved into a hissing,
spraying hell within seconds.
So it had a few kinks.
And who amongst us here doesn't?
Anyway, this movie has subjected
one and all to unholy levels
of torture.
I believe we are done here.
You are aware the film isn't
over, right?
Really?
No, we haven't even seen that
party that they've
talked about incessantly.
I just assumed this was plot hole.
Plot hole?
It's the entire point of the story.
Have you seen the rest of the movie?
I would not be surprised
if the film makers
just forgot to finish it.
Another good point.
You know, you're on fire today.
Oh, speaking of fire.
I have been advised that the following
reel of tonight's film may
cause burning sensation
in the eyes and loss of
sensation in the genitalia.
These symptoms should persist
for only two to four days,
but if they continue
then you should contact
your primary care physician
or call 1-800-CROTCH-ROT.
Anyway, enough of that.
Here goes nothing.
Roll 'em, Boys!
You know, I think this
movie is the worst thing
that has ever happened to me,
and I grew up in Chernobyl.
Oh yeah.
That was amazing.
You were awesome.
I've been needing that so bad.
You're such a sweet guy.
When are your friends gonna
be here?
Um, in a little bit.
Maybe you should get dressed?
No, there's no rush.
Hey, you girls need some waterin'?
Hey!
This is gonna be the best one
yet, Dude.
Oh yeah, Bro.
They are totally gonna have
to leave after this one.
Totally, Dude.
Jesus.
Dude, what are they doing to you?
Oh my God, make it stop,
make it stop!
We've been told that you two
have been causing problems.
We're sorry, we're so sorry, Bro.
Dude, really?
Now, are you two gonna
apologize to the others?
Yes, yes, I promise I will.
Ew!
What, what is it?
Do you smell pickles?
Yeah.
Oh now, what do we have here?
A few more whores.
Alright you two, front door, now!
But...
Now!
Yes, Ma'am.
Get in!
Steph, hey!
Hey!
Hi!
Brah, I'm sorry, Brah.
I'm sorry, I'm really sorry.
Well.
Where's your bathroom, Bro?
Please, Brah?
Uh, right over there.
Thanks, Brah.
Oh God.
Dude, that's just nasty.
Sorry, Dude.
Loren, come here.
So, Loren, this is Steph and Becky.
Hi.
Cute.
Yeah.
He is a cutie.
Yeah, he really is,
and he's such a sweetie,
and I mean he really is a sweetie.
Hey Girl!
Nice to see you two!
Hey!
You guys need some help?
Yeah, absolutely.
Here, grab some
Did you guys get booze?
Duh!
Alright, that's what I'm
talkin' about!
It's in the back.
Hey, can I help?
It's cool.
Uh, well alrighty then!
Alright.
Let's go.
Did you wash your car window off?
There.
I think we have everything we need.
Everything except your
neighbor's permission.
That'll never happen.
Uh, not necessarily.
What do you mean?
Hmm, I think she has a
weakness for the young guys.
Well, she didn't seem to like
us at all.
Apparently we're not her type.
Well what is her type, Dude?
You guys, Dude.
I think the other one.
Bro, I'm really sorry about earlier.
Oh man.
We were acting like assholes.
It's cool, Man.
We're cool.
You okay, Dude?
Oh yeah, Brah.
Actually, I feel pretty refreshed.
Hey, any of you two guys
into cougars by chance?
Not me, Dude.
I'm into 19 to 25 only.
Well, I know I am!
I'm totally into cougars, Man.
That's totally my bag, Man.
Why, you got something in mind?
Bitchy Brigitte next door.
Yes.
Oh, see, I told you.
I knew something awesome
was happening next door!
Hot cougar on the prowl, Brah!
To each his own.
Well, it's been a while
for this one, I think,
and this cougar is hungry.
Oh no, even better, Brah.
Well, if you really wanna
party tonight,
you better get over there.
Oh wow, this is good stuff.
Oh my, well hello.
Hello yourself.
Would you like to come in for
some tea?
Yes, I would.
Do you smell pickles?
Um, I love pickle, don't you?
Yes, so do I.
He's in!
Okay, we've got a lot to do.
Let's get ready for the party.
Show me what you got
Rock your body
Come out and play
The beat's here to stay
Dance the night away
Into the next day
Come out and play
The beats here to stay
Dance the night away
Into the next day
Get on your feet
Rock to the beat
Do the dirty deed
Call me when you're green
Fellas in the club
Ladies in the club
Show me what you got
I'll tell ya if it's hot
We came from far away
To scan this rave
These beats fill our tank
Partying is our thing
We came from far away
To scan this rave
These beats fill our tank
Partying is our thing
Show me what you got
Move your body
Groove your body
Show me what you got
Rock your body
Now all we have to do is
wait for her permission.
It's already 5:15.
The Horndog Beach Party starts
in less than two hours!
Don't worry, it will work.
In the meantime, would you
like to see my swimsuit?
Heck yeah.
Let's go.
I got a new one, too.
I can't wait to see it.
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
Yes, here's my swimsuit.
Oh, that?
I thought you were gonna
put it on or something?
Well, don't you think it
looks great as it is right now.
I mean, it's cute,
but I wanna see it on you!
Of course.
Oh my gosh, what a tease.
Hey, I need to change.
Get out.
Really?
Yeah.
Already?
Get out.
Really?
Yeah, get out.
Dude, what?
Well?
Don't you need to?
No.
You can see it later, come on.
You know, you're not
such a bad guy after all.
Sometimes things just
get the better of me.
Get the better of us all.
Ooh, but good things
come to those who repent.
Oh yeah?
And you repent very well.
Dude, I don't know how
Tad's gonna pull that off.
Brigitte really is a bitch, Dude.
Bitchy Brigitte, I have no idea.
I hope he does.
We really need to have this party.
What do you think, uh,
what do you
think's gonna happen if he doesn't?
Can we still have the party?
If he doesn't?
We have to have this party.
He has got to bang that out, now.
Or I don't know what else
we're gonna do.
You think she'd call the cops
on us?
She has in the past.
Yeah.
I'm hoping he does.
I mean, this party,
we've been planning
on coming here for a long time.
The girls are down.
What do you think's gonna happen?
We can't not have this party,
so hopefully he just bangs
her out,
comes back over here,
and we're set.
I don't know what we're gonna do
if we can't get her on board.
You actually think he's
gonna be able to do it.
I hope so.
I mean, I don't know.
Cougars are crazy, Dude.
I don't know.
If it doesn't work out,
I'm still gonna have a party.
I don't know what everyone
else is gonna be doing.
Yeah, Man.
Want something to drink.
Yeah, I need a drink.
Oh, wow, what a fantastic swimsuit!
I just wanted to apologize for
the way I've been acting lately.
It hasn't been very lady like.
It's okay.
Well, the reason why I'm here is
I heard that there's a beach
festival going on tonight
and my new beau and I wanted
to see
if you wanted to host a beach party?
Really?
Mhmm.
Don't we?
Well, we've gotta go out and
find new swimsuits ourselves.
Gotta keep my new cub looking fantastic.
Thank you.
We'll see you tonight!
Well?
She wants us to host a party!
Oh my God.
Oh, hey, hey, Everybody.
Guys, Guys, Guys, I need you.
We only got like 20 minutes
to start setting up.
So just grab whatever you can
and let's go out on the beach.
Alright, let's do it!
Woohoo!
Yes, we did it!
Hey!
I'd love to thank you for all
of you.
At the beginning, I thought all
I wanted is quiet in nice place,
but I realized what I really need
is you and a real good time!
So toast to all of you!
My old friends and new friends!
I love you all!
Hello!
Hello Everybody, how's it going?
Hey!
Say, who's in charge here?
Hi, my name is Dusty,
what's your name?
Why, I'm the legendary Horndog!
Hey, thank you, thank you.
Ladies and Gentleman,
after 15 long years,
both sides of the beach have
been reunited
by the lovely Horndog Queen, Dusty!
Thank you, My Queen, thank you.
And I hope to see you all
again next year!
Let's party, Everyone!
Oh, looking good, Brigitte.
Oh, thank you.
Wow, what a great party!
Thank you.
Looking good, Dude!
Oh, thanks, Bro.
What was that?
Oh, um, I'm sorry.
Thank you, Brad.
There, that's better.
You gotta teach these cubs early
or they'll run right over you.
So, what happens after this weekend?
I don't know, and I honestly
don't wanna think about it.
I'm just enjoying this
perfect weekend.
So did you really mean that?
What?
About coming back here next year?
Hmm, it depends.
Are you coming with me?
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
Woo!
You know what?
I thought this movie
had reached it's height
with the fully clothed shower scene,
but the sex scene with the door?
The whole goddamn screen was
just a door!
Not too mention the reuse
of that hilarious gag
from the gross out diarrhea scene.
You idiots must have indigo
orbs the size of Venus by now!
At least we got our party!
Proving yet again that
you have no social life.
You call that a party?
There were people gathered and..
And there was nothing!
There was some babes and some boobs,
and I mean idiots,
I don't mean tits.
And they were sitting
at a table and nothing.
Well, there was..
There was people at a table,
stock footage not withstanding.
That's not a party.
That was a casual get
together at best.
But, it was implied
that there were alcoholic
beverages and snacks.
The whole damn party was implied.
But Horndog said Dusty
saved the day by reunited
the two sides of the beach.
That's a real crowd pleaser, right?
Dusty did not do jack shit!
That dude bro wanged the coug
and that's
the whole reason the party
took place!
Oh, my faithful lap dogs are
still here.
What do you want?
Haven't you had enough
torture for one week?
Maybe you should throw them a bone.
You know, under normal circumstances
I would tell you to shut
your stupid cake hole,
but I think considering
these circumstances,
I would have to agree.
Here, take these.
There, satisfied now?
Well, too tough.
You will take it and you will
like it.
That's it for us this week.
You know, normally for
that little outburst
I would promise that next week
I make you suffer even more,
but I don't think after a
movie like that
I can make good on the promise.
So I will paraphrase my G
randpa de Sade
and say,
it is by way of cinematic pain
that we arrive at pleasure.
Or was it,
rock out with your cock out?
Either way,
whatever works best for you.
Roll credits.
I'm out this bitch!
Ain't nobody here!
Well, did we?
Oh man, we missed the party.
I told you we should
have taken a ride share.
Oh man.
What are we gonna do now?
Well, we could have a little
beach party
of our own, little horndog.
Ooh, bow chica bow bow.
What did that even
have to do with anything?
Give me that back!