This is the city's heat wave warning.
Global warming has reached crisis point,
temperatures are at a record high.
This is the Shenzhen weather forecast.
Today's temperature is the highest ever.
Demand for electricity is never ending.
Please reduce your energy consumption.
Several governments have announced
ways for the public to keep cool.
Ahhh, it's so hot!
You're useless!
The AC just broke down again!
Hey, Wai, did you hear me?
Don't blame me.
You should replace it.
At least it lasted through the night.
You promised it would work!
I'm going home to eat.
What're you doing, man?
Don't ever touch my radio!
Sorry... Sorry!
I'll fire you!
Hurry up,
everything in the fridge is melting.
Okay, I'm working on it!
My money... My money!
Stop pestering me!
Have you noticed recently that
people get angry all the time?
More... More.
One more... Here.
How does the weather affect emotions?
Did your dad die or something?
In such hot weather,
how can we remain calm?
Hey, babe, fancy hearing a joke?
What animal has two legs and
wakes you up when the sun rises?
That's easy... A rooster!
- No, your mom!
- My mom...
Rent an umbrella?
It's frozen!
Pretty girl, want a popsicle?
This is the hottest year ever in HK.
Feel so bad!
But what can we do?
Move to the North Pole!
So cool there.
Hong Kong is really hot!
Please go there, thank you!
Going for sushi as soon as you land?
Is it really that good?
It's too hot.
The fish won't be fresh.
Master Chef, the fish has arrived.
Let's get started!
How long will you stay in Hong Kong?
I'm not just visiting.
I won't be leaving this time.
What's up with you?
No, your dad's dead!
- Nothing! You are nothing!
- I've never seen a photographer like you.
Thank you!
You're nuts, stop there!
Wrap!
Honey,
I feel so blessed today.
I wish it were hot all year round,
then I'd be really rich!
Cheers!
Do you want to know how hot 42 °C is?
Look at this!
The egg is cooked!
Come here.
You're the best pianist.
Thank you.
But I won't hire you.
Why? I really need this job.
I don't even have money to eat.
You're Li Yan, right? Unfortunately,
you're just not hot enough.
I'm hiring her instead, understand?
However...
If you can dress sexier,
I'll reconsider.
In your dreams!
Foot masseurs wanted
Do you have any experience?
I've had extensive training.
I have strong
and flexible fingers,
skillful, rhythmical.
No. 98, you can start tomorrow.
Thank you!
Both of my marriages were failures!
What happened?
My first wife ran away.
What about the second one?
She won't leave me!
Freedom is precious.
Why tie yourself down?
Do you mean her?
You can't keep
your eyes off her.
She's not easy to catch.
What if I can? What would you bet?
Well, what do you want?
Your watch.
No way! It's from my days in the army.
So, you wanna bet or not?
And what if you fail?
I'll work for free the whole summer!
Deal!
Hey, pretty girl, fancy a popsicle?
No.
But it's free today!
But I have one question for you first.
What is it?
Will you be my girlfriend?
Keep your popsicle!
My wages will be docked if I'm late.
Then, say "yes".
You...
All right.
Prove your sincerity,
stand over there every day at noon
for 100 days!
Are you joking? It's so hot!
- Okay, never mind.
- No... Deal...
Okay, one hundred days... Deal!
You'll be my girl in 100 days!
Lunchtime!
A scorching day...
Isn't he hot?
What is it?
There's a fool standing over in the sun!
No kidding!
Do you know him?
No way! He's crazy!
Let's go!
Go ahead, I'll be there in a moment.
Come quickly.
Got many towels to dry?
You'll get used to the swollen fingers.
98, there's a customer!
Boss.
Boss!
What?
The car...
It's overheating!
Go take a look!
Just heatstroke. No big deal. It's okay.
Your number's changed again.
How'd you know I'm sick?
What number?
I didn't change my number.
Conductor, you're my only friend in HK.
Are you making fun of me?
Conductor? Who's that?
Who is this?
This... Hey, who are you?
You sent me the message! Who are you?
Who am I?
I've a friend in Shenzhen. Wrong number.
Wrong this, wrong that, what a fool!
Overseas SMS is very expensive, idiot!
Sorry.
Sorry...
I need someone to talk to right now.
Isn't it very expensive?
Do you have a dream?
Of course!
What do you do? Why are you sick?
I'm a pianist.
I was performing outdoors today.
The sun was too hot,
and I passed out.
How about you?
Pianist?
I'm
a driver.
I'm a Ferrari racer.
Ferrari!
Really?
You know what?
Experts say that when you're in love,
words spoken in the right ear
are sweeter.
But you're on my left now.
Am I on your left? Will you marry me?
Why do I have to marry you?
We're the only ones of our species here.
Hold on! I wanna see what they're doing!
Who?
Something's going on between them.
It's not my concern. I care only for you.
Spawning season is coming!
Please marry me?
You?
I'll only marry you
if they kiss each other.
What? That mass murderer?
No soy sauce necessary!
Poisonous?
Taste the seaweed beneath the fish.
But I love
soy sauce.
Your face is as dark as soy sauce...
Still so uptight.
Master Soy Sauce.
This nickname is so perfect for you.
Your nickname is no better.
Did people laugh at you overseas?
Not at all, Wasabi
sounds cute and is easy to remember!
Is it too spicy? Too much wasabi?
I just haven't tasted this for so long.
Hey...
How's your book?
You finished writing The Perfect Meal?
Now that you're your own boss,
can't we be together?
You said you'd finish the book first.
Only because you needed more time.
In a year,
I traveled all over the world,
but I couldn't find the perfect meal.
I returned when this restaurant opened
because I believe
I can find the most perfect meal here.
You have a restaurant now, you're not
some bloke hanging out in the kitchen.
I barely finished elementary school.
Give me more time.
Even if I waited another 100 years,
you'd still be just an elementary grad.
Fine...
Give me back the postcards
and recipes that I sent.
All of them!
I trashed them.
Kiss her! Kiss her! Kiss her!
Not again!
I've failed.
Show me, show me!
No...
Sexy!
More... Come on.
Show me!
Don't you know sexy? But you're a woman.
Da Fu!
I'm a man. Man! Man!
I don't want this,
not like this!
Look at my eyes!
No good! Try again...
Come on...
No... Not sexy enough.
Sexy!
The last 3 hours are wasted.
Why? But she's been great!
What do you know?
Leslie, calm down.
Yuan Yuan has potential.
We believe within a year or two...
She belongs in a wax museum.
I can't photograph her. Find someone!
What's wrong with me?
You're just awful.
What are you talking about?
I've told you.
Your eyes are completely empty!
You are empty, can't you see?
Empty? You're going blind! Blind!
- Let's go.
- Let me go! He's blind!
Did she just curse me?
Tell all advertising agencies
she's not fit to be a model.
What's wrong with my eyes?
What's wrong?
I can't see, what's wrong with me?
What happened to my eyes?
Are you the
very famous photographer, Leslie Guan?
That's not me!
What's wrong, Doc?
It must be you!
It says you can make 1,000 bucks
with each click...
Tell me what happened to my sight!
It's not clear.
We have to run a series of tests.
Maybe just an infection...
- It's too early to say.
- Doc.
It's the end if he can't see.
Please help us!
Airport, please.
Oh! It's you again, madam.
You said you weren't leaving again.
This time, I won't ever come back!
Just give him a call.
Otherwise, you'll regret it.
Don't worry, I won't listen in, okay?
You promised to deliver the AC today.
Out of stock?
Hey,
I'm dying of the heat!
Hang up on me?
Ferrari racer
What are you doing?
Test drive. Race tomorrow.
Delicious! One more, please.
Yes.
I'm not available. Leave a message.
Master Soy Sauce,
I've seen your new restaurant.
I'm happy for you. Congratulations!
I saw your online rating. Taste, full score.
Hygiene, decoration, 100% Service...
Only 1 point.
You know why?
Because customers say that
the chef never smiles.
I had always thought
that, if I tried harder,
I'd pry open the door that you kept shut.
But...
Now, I understand
only you could
open that door to me.
I'm leaving.
Wai, please take it.
It's pink. Hard to sell.
Don't you accept anything secondhand?
Discriminating against pink?
No, it's just rare.
$400!
More, Wai, please!
No one will buy a pink AC for $400.
Just take it.
All right.
Hey, you...
Hey...
Hey, do you even know how to ride?
I'm talking to you!
Has the heat wave made you crazy?
Hold this for me.
I'm taking off. Here's your key.
298...
Pardon?
Swimming to the raft
takes 298 strokes.
Nuts!
You...
Waisun AC.
You've got the wrong tires.
Wanna race?
You think you can beat me?
What if I win?
Then you can ask for anything.
296, 297,
298...
Ding Dong, how many?
It takes 298 strokes to reach the raft.
I'm a good swimmer.
298 strokes, I can do it.
My mom always worries about sunburn,
so I've never been to any beach.
Will you take me when I'm better?
Sure, I'll buy you ice cream too, okay?
Fang, at least $10.
No more bargaining.
Just $2, take it or leave it.
Give me the money.
Go... Go!
25, 26, 27...
28!
Why are we here?
Remember, she cursed you,
and then you went blind.
Maybe...
Watch out.
Who are you looking for?
We're looking for Zhou Yuan Yuan.
Yuan Yuan? You are?
We're her relatives, very close ones.
Come in then.
She left in a hurry
without paying her rent.
Why don't you pay it for her? $500.
Give her $500.
Do you know where she went?
Heard she went to Shenzhen.
Can we check her room?
Sure, over there.
Now we helped her, maybe your eyes...
- Look.
- What?
Your magazine cover.
I've seen it. What is it?
- Feel it.
- Why?
- Get it?
- Get what?
- Holes!
What are the holes about?
Those were your eyes!
Can we swim to Shaolin Temple
from here?
Get off!
I'm considering becoming a monkfish.
She hasn't shown up since,
I'm afraid...
What's the most perfect meal you had?
Ying's beef fried rice. So perfect!
Hmm. What about you?
Double cheeseburger.
My mom would only buy me one
if I got straight As.
No wonder you're just my apprentice!
Master Chef,
still dreaming up your perfect meal?
She hasn't answered her phone since.
I think she's avoiding you.
In 2 weeks,
I'll prepare the perfect meal here.
Post invitations all over the internet!
She'll see it!
What if she doesn't?
Then we would have wasted our time!
Leave now if you don't want to help.
All right, I quit then.
Wait.
When she came to you, you ignored her.
You deserve it.
Seems the restaurant is not busy today,
so many calls.
Three calls already!
Now you start to care about me.
I have a poetry recital this afternoon,
will you come?
I'm going out to look for a job.
Again?
Storyberry, daddy needs to make money.
For the 100th time, it's Strawberry!
There's soy milk and rice in the fridge.
Microwave for 30 seconds only,
or it will dry up again.
I know.
Daddy, I've told you 100 times,
I won't play again.
What're you doing?
Are you playing the piano or massaging?
I'm really sorry.
Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
- Your face is burning red!
I'm okay.
Sure?
Good...
Just a second.
I've got to go.
Just a minute, one moment...
Are you sure you're all right?
Stop standing there if it's too hot!
No!
I won't give up. There are...
53 more days.
You counted?
Yes.
What're you doing tonight?
Wanna go for a drink?
Speak Cantonese. I can understand.
Your Cantonese has improved.
Let's go! So...
Are you hitting on me?
I like tattoos. You like to be tattooed.
We're made for each other.
Bull!
How come you're so rude?
It's the 8th year.
You've been coming here for 8 years.
Why get a tattoo of a ring every year?
I'll tell you when I see you next year.
You said the same thing last year.
So are we still going out?
Thank you! Bye!
Hey!
Super cold drinks and germ-proof straws.
Free drinks for all...
Free drinks! Welcome!
Welcome. Come.
My friends, cold drinks.
Welcome. Try...
Fang, I'll stand in for just $1 today.
No thanks.
Well, how about 50 cents then?
Today's temperature hits a new record.
The outdoor temperature is 48 °C now.
Ice cream is now a prized commodity.
You can't buy it even if you're rich!
$70, anyone?
- $75.
- $80!
- $85.
- $100.
$200.
$200, once.
$200, twice.
Deal!
We're used to standing in line for food.
Now we need to queue up
to get space on the beach.
Plot 795 for 3 people, going once...
3 people, twice...
Here!
Getting bigger!
- I'm training every day!
- So firm!
Sweetheart,
I'll tell you a joke.
Another old joke, old man?
What's the difference between
jumping from the 2nd floor
and the 20th floor?
- I don't know...
- No, I don't know.
When a man falls from the 2nd floor...
Bang... Aiya!
When a man falls from the 20th floor...
Ai... Ya... Bang!
Gas tank, horsepower, shock absorbers.
Everything must be the best.
Why don't you just get a new bike?
No way!
I want to be the fastest in Hong Kong.
It'll cost you five figures!
That expensive?
You repair ACs, right?
The weather's so hot. Advertise online.
It's easy to raise enough money!
Latest bid: $1,000, $1,100...
Hi, Mr. Chan. Waisun AC.
Right.
$1,600? My fee is now...
$1,700.
Confirmed. I'll be right there.
Thank you.
Crisis creates opportunity.
The hot weather
has made some people rich.
Next to me is Wai, who fixes ACs.
He's one of the lucky ones.
What gave you the idea
to auction your services online?
I needed to raise some money,
so if you need to fix your AC,
you can come to Waisun.
You really understand marketing.
Where did you learn your trade?
I studied in jail.
You were in jail?
Why? Do you mind telling us?
My dad ratted me out.
Brat!
Your mother is spinning in her urn!
If I win, I can ask for anything?
We'll see!
Let's race then!
Sure.
It's so fast! It's really fast!
I had no idea it was so fast!
You've won. So what do you want?
Maybe the bike has the answer.
Let me know soon! There's a deadline.
"There's a deadline!"
Let's look for Yuan Yuan in Shenzhen.
I don't want to be blind for life.
Must find a cure by any means necessary.
Go get me a drink.
Okay.
What's that smell? Da Fu...
Fire! Fire! Run!
What's wrong?
Photo, my photo...
Which one? There are too many!
Just one, the one and only one.
Where is it? I will get it for you.
Wallet... In my wallet.
Free drinks for all!
Strawberry, that ice cube is cute!
Let's take a picture.
I want a snapshot.
- No, don't...
- Just one picture...
Strawberry!
Hey!
Why did you flee when you saw me today?
You were a walking ice cube!
Did I embarrass you?
How much money
do you make in one hour?
Why do you ask?
Tell me.
Do you look down on me?
No.
$50, okay?
Then can I borrow thirty bucks?
I thought you understood my situation,
but you only want money!
No.
I don't have it!
- Daddy.
- No!
Daddy!
Storyberry!
Daddy, here's $50.
Can I buy one hour of your time?
Come to my poetry recital this afternoon.
Hey.
Can you do me a favor?
My service is $1,700 an hour now.
Do you take credit card?
Cash only.
Please...
It's not a business if I only do favors.
Come on.
Go!
Go... Right now!
What do you want me for?
The old lady inside has a brain tumor.
She's dying.
She wants to see her son.
Pretend to be him.
- I...
- She can't see. It'll be fine.
Remember, your name is Ah Keung.
You just came back from the States.
- But I'm not her son.
- Just hold her...
Give her some final comfort, okay?
Will it work?
Keung, you can do it. Go...
Should I say something?
Auntie,
Keung is here.
Keung...
Tortoises!
What are their names?
Hey, why did you kiss me?
Because you are so nice.
I just want to help people.
Why? It has nothing to do with you.
I help them fulfill their final wishes.
The girl had never swam to a raft.
She wanted to know
how many strokes it needs to get there.
That's why you deserve a kiss.
Hello.
We're calling from Shenzhen Orchestra.
We received your resume earlier.
You can come for an audition tomorrow.
I'll definitely be there. Thank you!
Finally!
I'm so dead...
Sorry...
Sorry.
Take it slow.
Welcome.
How was your performance?
It was awful.
Don't push...
You told me that Mozart was an optimist
even though he had a harsh life.
Just a small setback,
you'll overcome it. Break a leg!
If it's sushi, it'll go with soy sauce.
Half past three!
Hurry up... Just one more!
I've been there, now it's your turn.
Is Wasabi there?
You are the Hong Kong man!
What kind of drug
did you put in my daughter's sushi?
Uncle...
Is she in Taiwan?
Idiot. She's still in Hong Kong.
You suddenly care about her?
Learn to love or be a loser forever.
Leave her alone.
Sorry. I can't do that.
Look at you. So uptight.
Is Leslie Guan in Shenzhen?
This model is very ordinary,
she's even less than ordinary.
I have much better ones!
Ordinary?
Yes.
Take another look.
Is this ordinary?
Very ordinary!
You know nothing.
This is the first photo I ever took.
Your girlfriend?
She's the one who hurt me the most.
Do you know where she is now?
She lives in Suzhou.
Divorced.
Wait a sec...
I remember she came looking for you.
You told me to lie, say you were out.
She left me.
I don't want to see her again.
When she left, she was in tears.
Why didn't you give her a chance?
It's expensive. Never mind, let's go.
Wait. You're standing all the time.
It's totally worth it.
Two people, please.
Really?
Trust me.
You SMS her all this time.
We're in Shenzhen. Why not ask her out?
See if she's pretty.
Crazy.
Look at me. I'm a nobody.
I can't meet her...
Welcome!
She looks good. Let's swap.
Hey, miss.
He likes you. Why not serve him instead?
Yes.
Your legs are really stiff and swollen.
I was a driver,
then worked in construction,
and now...
I need to stand all day long!
Just like a coolie.
Odd jobs.
It will be okay, I'll press harder.
Your technique is unique. What is it?
Self-taught.
Piles.
Not piles. It's self-taught.
It feels good...
So good.
Sir, how do I address you?
Just call me Coolie.
Mr. Coolie.
What about you?
I'm No. 98.
Ask for me next time you come.
Definitely 88.
No, it's 98.
Nine...
Your cell phone, it's beeping.
I can't use my phone during work hours.
Go see the boss after work.
Come in.
Sit down, please.
Boss, you wanted to see me?
Mom, don't worry,
I'll send you some money tomorrow.
Why do you ask about my boss?
Yes, he's interested in me. But...
I understand.
I'll give you a better life.
Do you know the story behind
Mozart's No. 545?
You have a real interest in him.
That's because of my daughter.
Married? What do you think I am?
A mistress?
How's married life? Happy?
She ran away with someone last year.
Fantastic!
I'm so sorry.
My daughter used to love playing piano.
She's got real talent.
But since her mom left,
she stopped playing.
This light bulb is discontinued.
I have to get one
before my wife's death anniversary.
Please help.
Try another kind.
Impossible,
once she got used to something.
She hated changes.
This light bulb
has been with her for over ten years.
Try your luck across the harbor.
Boss, one more set please.
Wai, you've become a celebrity.
Give me a discount then.
Let me see if we have it in stock.
I don't have it.
Sold out!
Thanks.
You're lucky. It's the very last one.
Thank you.
Ungrateful brat,
you don't even greet your own father?
Father?
My father ratted me out to the cops!
If not for me, you'd be dead already!
Selling fake goods,
loan sharking, getting into fights!
You'll get yourself killed!
Then just consider me dead!
You brat!
This is from the boss.
It's your birthday. He'll buy you dinner.
Give it back to him.
Take it.
That boy is only fooling with you.
Don't be so serious.
Enjoy your meal.
Happy birthday.
Let's go.
Xiao Qi?
Go to hell!
It looks almost real...
But...
But what?
It's still just a bike.
What's wrong with a bike?
Happy birthday to you...
Happy birthday to Daddy.
Happy birthday to me!
Do you want to know my wish?
It won't come true if you tell me.
I wish to hear you play piano again.
I've told you that I won't play again.
Why? You are really good at it.
I don't want to play.
Come on, listen to daddy just once.
You enjoyed it so much.
I don't like it.
Why did you give up?
I just don't want to play.
Your mom's gone.
I don't want to listen!
She won't come back again.
- And then?
- Nothing, that's it.
Uncle Fai, any jokes today?
Today's jokes are not funny.
Can I have two of these? Thanks!
No more.
An old man bought the last one.
He said he must get the light bulb
before his wife's death anniversary.
Please.
Call me if you find one.
This is my number.
Let's celebrate.
Celebrate what?
I learned to face reality today.
Didn't we need to find her first?
Two weeks ago,
the doctor told me
there's a tumor near my optic nerve.
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
We needn't stay here for her.
I wanted to make it up to her.
We've tried our best.
Let's head back to Beijing tomorrow.
Pianist?
Is your daughter playing again?
Don't let her give up.
You once asked why I liked playing piano.
Let me tell you.
Mozart and I share the same birthday.
I haven't heard from you, are you okay?
Don't blame yourself.
You didn't fail your daughter.
Sorry, daddy. Did I wake you up?
No.
I don't mind a piano wake-up call.
I'm a fish, I'm not afraid of the heat.
What do you want the most right now?
An AC.
I'll get you one.
Why?
My daughter's playing piano again!
His daughter is playing again!
My daughter wants to see you perform.
Can we come and visit?
Excuse me. I want to buy a hose.
A hose.
$5.
You have anything longer?
Longer?
$10.
$10? Too expensive.
How much is this AC?
It's a classic...
Pink, very rare, $450.
$450! Cheaper?
Any discount?
But it's pink.
Good stuff, durable. Are you
discriminating against pink?
- I'm in a hurry.
- Just a moment.
Look, here's all I have.
Let me keep $20.
It's a deal!
Will it work on the mainland?
I thought they still used fans.
How long have you been away?
It's all ACs now!
It's none of your business!
Take a plug, free of charge.
- Thank you.
- No, I don't want it.
Fussing over a few bucks, big shot?
Sorry about that, boss.
- Be careful, it's rare.
- Thank you.
I'll sell more pink stuff from now on.
Stop!
Sorry!
Wai.
Your pants are torn. Any plan tonight?
I come here just to thank.
No more pretending to be someone else.
Get going.
Are you okay?
It's here.
You're sick. Why didn't you tell me?
How much time
does the doctor say I have?
I've been sick for 8 years.
I'm well prepared.
I'm not.
Don't worry.
What do you want me to say?
I don't care about anything.
I only care about loving you.
All I want is that
you will always be there to hug me.
You'll eat breakfast with me.
Walk on the beach with me.
Just that simple. Can you do that?
You only care about yourself.
Have you ever thought about me?
I don't know what you want.
I've said enough already.
Call me when you figure it out.
Some hot tea.
Thank you.
Can I smoke?
Sorry, you can't smoke here.
There's no one here.
Let me smoke.
It's a matter of principle.
Principle? But you're closed already.
I should get going then. Sorry.
No hurry. Take your time.
I'll be all right in a moment.
Actually, the food is very good here.
Where did you study?
Tokyo. Ginza.
My master was Mr. Maeda.
I've trained under him for 8 years.
Suddenly, one day,
he cooked me a bowl of hot noodles.
After I finished, he asked me to go home
to promote his way of cooking.
A bowl of hot noodles again...
When I was in Tokyo,
I ate at a stall in the red light area.
I met a couple.
They were very sweet.
They looked just ordinary.
But I noticed that under the table,
they held hands, never letting go.
They looked at each other so fondly.
When the chef set the noodles down,
the boy prepared
a pair of chopsticks for the girl.
He even fed her.
I was really touched
because I felt that,
even though they shared a single bowl,
they were really happy.
That is love. Very simple.
Yes, it should be simple.
The Perfect Meal
Xiao Li.
Please tell the boss
that I cannot accept his gift.
You should meet her if you miss her!
Mind your own business, kiddo.
Where's the pianist?
Hello.
This is Strawberry.
My dad bought a really beautiful AC.
He really wants to give it to you.
Can you please see him? Just once.
Storyberry!
Daddy, tomorrow at 3 o'clock.
I've arranged a date for you.
Really?
Tomorrow? Oh, no!
Is this the truffle you're looking for?
Right, thank you.
Wasabi? We have fresh wasabi.
That's not what I want.
How come he hasn't called?
Hello, Anxin Bank.
Would you'd like a loan?
A loan? Idiot!
Your call cannot be connected...
Do I look good?
Daddy, you're really
handsome!
Go. Women don't like men to be late!
Really?
I am here, where are you?
Wah.
- Coolie?
- No. 98?
You...
Pianist.
Ferrari...
Liar!
You too!
Hong Kong people are very romantic.
This restaurant makes the perfect meal
for a special guest.
It's an inspiring idea.
Da Fu, you go back to Beijing.
I'll go to Suzhou.
To Suzhou, to look for her?
I want to see her before my operation.
I'll go with you.
No, I need to be alone.
Okay, I will wait in Shenzhen for you.
You always want to be
a great photographer.
I want to tell you something.
Lighting, make-up, costumes
are not that important.
Through their eyes,
you must capture their joy, excitement,
their loneliness, their sorrow,
their very soul!
Hey.
You found Zhou Yuan Yuan?
What's up?
I am sorry, Dad.
Wai.
Brat.
Do you remember that I still owe you?
You won the race last time.
I promised you could ask for anything.
I'll tell you when you get better.
No!
I want to know now.
You've been helping others,
so my wish is to help you.
Take down the sign. She won't come.
Let's clean up and go home.
We're not open tonight.
Just one, may I?
Wasabi? Master, Wasabi!
You know where the wasabi is. You get it.
It's your Wasabi, Master Chef.
I'm a bit hungry.
Are you still open?
These aren't your usual ingredients.
Eat from left to right, please.
Hope she likes it.
Oh! No! She spat it out.
Well, it is not that bad,
but this is not your style.
To be original is always best.
Why all this fusion food?
The recipes you sent me,
I read all of them.
Didn't you say you had thrown them out?
I just didn't want to return them.
You know what?
This is the worst meal you've made.
It's also the most touching meal ever.
Good job in your disguise.
Especially that Ferrari cap.
The cap is real!
I didn't lie to you.
I'm really a driver.
It's just that I don't drive a Ferrari.
I'm in fact a pianist too.
It's just... I've never been to Vienna.
Then why don't you play again?
With these?
If it's really her, we'll look backstage.
Okay.
Tickets, gentlemen.
Yes, sure.
Master, over there!
Zhou Yuan Yuan!
Is she the star?
No photo.
Is she the lead?
Da Fu.
Is she?
I can't even tell if she's an extra!
Teacher, hailstorm!
Hailstorm... Hailstorm!
Are you all right?
- I'm okay.
- Come this way.
Zhou Yuan Yuan!
We've been trying so hard to find you.
Sorry.
This is not the perfect meal.
But I am moved...
That means it's perfect!
You...
Can you stay?
Looking for me?
Wanna see how pitiful I am?
Sorry. Because of what I said.
I ruined your career.
I'm terribly sorry.
Can I invite you
to be my student's model?
Let him take some photos of you?
- Teacher.
- You can do it!
It's just like you said about my eyes.
I'm almost blind. I can't take photos.
My teacher is telling the truth!
We wouldn't come all the way
from Beijing to lie to you.
Sorry.
You can trust him.
He will capture
the beauty inside of you,
that one important moment.
Please?
You're bleeding.
It's ready.
You want to turn it on?
- Me?
- Yes, do the honor.
At last, I have my own AC!
It really works!
And it's pink too!
It stopped.
So cool...
I didn't see the ad.
Then why did you come?
Because Wasabi and Soy Sauce
are meant to be together.
Today is the 100th day, go take a look!
What's wrong?
He didn't come.
Where is Xiao Fang? Where is he?
He said he wanted to see the big world.
He's gone?
He just left for the train station.
Why don't you continue?
Who am I? You think that I deserve her?
I'll go out into the world
and make some good money.
She'll be married by then.
Then I'll win her back.
Silly boy!
Take it.
I lost.
Not yet!
Shanghai, economy class.
Xiao Fang!
The train is leaving soon.
Please board the train...
Xiao Fang! Where are you?
Do you love me?
Can you tell me
why on the 100th day did you give up?
Tell me.
Why did you quit on the last day?
Where are you?
Xiao Fang!
Come...
Where to?
Let's go.
You've been helping others.
It's my turn to help you.
I always want to ride my bike forever
without stopping for anything
until the end of the world.
It's cool.
They're really going to kiss!
Honey, our son is not that bad after all.
What's happening?
What's wrong?
I think I've used the wrong plug.
How come it's so dark?
No way! Lost my chance again?
Remember
you asked me once if I have any dreams?
My dream is to drive a Ferrari,
listening to Mozart with you next to me.
Now...
My dream can come true.
Just a moment.
I need to fasten my seatbelt.
But, there's no Mozart.
There is.
I can hear the music you play,
it's Mozart.
Honey, I've made up with our son.
Wai, when I hold you,
I can feel your heart.
Thank you.
I was so lucky to have met you.
If you remember me, remember me now.
Look over here... Very good...
It's perfect...
Perfect.
Sorry, I took up so much of your time.
It's okay.
Shall we go for breakfast?
Sure!
It's 6 in the morning already.
Your watch is really cool.
My dad gave it to me.
20 years ago, my dad bet with his boss.
He had to stand under the blazing sun
for 100 days!
My dad told me
100 days represent persistence and hope.
Xiao Fang, you came back to me!