ripped by qwerzz
Among the first Emperors of each dynasty
Emperor Zhao Kuang Yin
was the most magnanimous
On his mother's bid,
he gave his throne to his Brother
Zhao Guang Yi and then to
Guang Yi's son, De wang
Kuang Yin passed his throne
to his brother Guang Yi
It had been rumoured that he was
killed by his brother in the palace
This had remained a mystery ever since
But when Guang Yi became Emperor
he forced Kuang Yin's son, De Zhao
to kill himself
De Zhao's son Zhao Jue
was crowned Prince of Xiang Yang
He was eager for revenge
and planned for a revolt
In his own residence he built...
the House of Traps
"Fu An Inn"
Brother... are you alright?
Brother, never mind me, chase him
Too late
"Federation of the Righteous"
who is it?
A robber
Just by the flying dart
and the light technique
one can tell that
the well-renowned Brother Hua is here
Brother Deng
This is Hua Chong, the Butterfly
Everyone must have heard about him
Master Hua...
Brother Hua, since you know I'm here
why did you still shoot the flying dart?
Aren't you concerned about
hurting your friend?
Precisely because I know you are here
these four darts wouldn't hit people
You think I'd miss?
Alright, let's sit down and talk
Brother Hua, this packet is...
It's a gift to you
I already know what it is
The Jade Horse lost in the palace
There's a warrant from Kaifeng county
for the robber's arrest
It was just ajoke that day at the banquet
not knowing that
you'd take it so seriously
This is nothing
I just don't understand why
you are here instead of the Deng Residence
This Horse has stirred a sensation
all over the country
You sure have the guts to steal it
but I don't have the guts
to keep it in Deng Residence
Do you see what this place is?
Federation of the Righteous
This belongs to the Prince of Xiang Yang
He's the brother of the Emperor
If the Jade Horse is hid at
the prince's residence
even Bao Zheng wouldn't dare to come
and search the place
Since the birthday of His Majesty
is drawing near
I'll decide for you
and send this to the Prince
as a birthday gift
Brother, that's very considerate of you!
His Majesty arrives
Your Majesty
No need to stand on ceremony
I suppose this is the renowned Butterfly
Yes, he is my sworn brother Hua Chong
Greetings to Your Majesty
Fine...
This is not the prince's residence
You are my VIPs
Please have a seat and chat
Thank you, Your Majesty
Brother, this is Shen Zhong Yuan
A great kung fu hero and
also His Majesty's think-tank
Nice to meet you
I've heard a lot about you
My sincere respects
You're too kind
Please
Please have a seat
Deng Che, chief of the Deng Fortress
to preside over
the Federation of the Righteous
I've heard from Hero Deng
that he's a sworn brother of Hero Hua
Yes, Brother Deng's business is mine too
I'll do whatever it takes
Good
I'm willing to work for Your Majesty;
even risk my life
It'd be best if Hero Hua could join us
There're heroes all over
who have pledged loyalty to me
Once the food and weapons are ready
we can start the revolt
The pledge of our allies would be
in the House of Traps
Hero Shen will bring
Hero Hua to sign the pledge later
Yes
Your Majesty,
the Jade Horse Brother Hua stole
is an Imperial treasure
It may be a good sign
that Your Majesty will be crowned
For security, may we lock it up
in the House of Traps &
bring it out for viewing
on Your Majesty's birthday?
Alright
"House of Traps"
Master Shen
This is Hua Chong, the Butterfly
Your fame precedes you
I am Lan Xiao
Also recommended by Master Deng
to work for the Prince
It's the Iron Man brother Lan
By the order of His Majesty,
I am here to collect
the Jade Horse to be stored
at the House of Traps
Master Hua is now the VIP
of the Prince's Residence
He can come and go at any time
you needn't worry, Brother Lan
Yes, Master Shen
Please
Brother Hua,
please place the Jade Horse in it
There's also a copy of the pledge
please sign it
"Fu An Inn"
Brother, don't bother me
Do whatever you have to do
Then wait for me at the inn
I hear Hua Chong has joined
the Prince of Xiang Yang
I'll go to the Prince's Residence tonight
and investigate
Regardless of my investigation
I'll bring you back to Kaifeng
early tomorrow morning
Someone went in,
hurry and trigger the traps
who are you?
So it's Lord Bao's secret emissary
Brother wang, your brother died
at the House of Traps
The Jade Horse
which the Butterfly has stolen
is stored at the House
There's something more important
The list of all those
participating in the revolt
is also stored in the House
I know you are wounded badly
But no matter what,
you have to go back to Kaifeng
and tell Lord Bao about the news
Yes
I've been fatally struck
by the Butterfly's dart
and have come here to report the news
before I die
I'll serve you again in my next life
These two brothers
are men of great loyalty
But there's one thing
which I don't understand
Prince of Xiang Yang's rebellious acts
are obvious
Your Honour's great name is well-known
among Kaifeng
You'd rather handle this case yourself
instead of
delegating it to
an inexperienced person like me
It's precisely because everyone knows me
If I go to Xiang Yang,
the Prince will take special precautions
But for a person like you
smart and capable, but of low profile
the Prince will be lax in guarding against
It'd be much easier to find out
his rebellious acts
That's why I've recommended you
to the Emperor to be
the Inspector-General of the
9 provinces of Jing Shiang
I'll send over someone
to help you discreetly all along
when you see this plaque,
you'll know that
he's the secret emissary sent by me
"Prince Xiang Yang's residence"
News from the capital
Lord Bao recommended
Inspector Yan to come here
He has come for me
Bao Zheng doesn't dare to come
but has asked a book-worm
to spearhead the attack
Once he arrives at Xiang Yang
I'll kill him;
Let's see who dares to come again
Of course it's very easy for you
to kill Yan Chun Min
But Kaifeng has lost wang Dong
and wang Liang here
and it's all because of the Jade Horse
I'm afraid it's not easy now
to cover up your stay here
If anything goes wrong
it may get His Majesty into trouble
Your concern is indeed warranted
Nonetheless your idea of giving a warning
isn't a bad idea
It'd keep people from
coming to Xiang Yang to inspect
But it's not appropriate for you to do it
Besides,
it would be an overkill to involve you
Alright, let's do it this way
The three-hand general Cao De Yu,
Fang Diao
will launch the first wave
Yes
Miao Tien Luk and Chai wan
shall launch the second wave
and kill him on the way
Yes
"Yun Lai Inn"
Please...
Sir, please
Sir, what do you think?
Wait, what's the charge per night?
A tael and a half,
you can't come by a better deal
Little housekeeper, what do you say?
One tael
Alright, one tael
You must be hungry
we have everything
I'll pick some fresh food for you
So that you could charge us
in whatever way you want?
Anyway, forget about the fresh food
Just get a pot of rice and two dishes
Alright
You dare to bully people
what are you doing?
It's not right to bully
Sir, please adjudicate
I came here for food and accommodation
He said the inn is full;
well, that's alright
But he was abusive and even pushed me
how could something like this be condoned?
Sir, if you don't mind
come and stay with me in my room
You are quite a gentleman
Please
It's Brother Bai, have you eaten?
Good question; I'm hungry indeed
waiter
Coming
Anything to eat?
Just add a bit more
for the pot of rice just ordered
Order what you'd like to eat
Anything good?
The best rice is 8 taels,
medium grade is...
No one wants anything mediocre,
just get the best
what's the choice of wine?
A great choice, but no single-order sale
Bring the whole pot then
Okay
Oh, fish and chicken
Some more, oh my god
what do you think?
How much would it all cost?
Such a big pot of wine,
how are we going to finish it?
What a nuisance
Brother Yan,
I'm not used to sleeping with others
Sorry that you need to
make a compromise tonight
who knows if it's just a dream,
only I can make sense
Sleeping in peace here,
my great ability awaits assent
It's already dawn
Sir, you are early
Give me the bill, I have to set off
Alright
Sir, it comes to a total of
thirteen taels forty-eight
Not much; I'll give
an additional three taels as tips
Thank you...
Brother Yan, I'd rather not have
any formality among us
If we are destined to meet,
we'll meet again
Oh God, someone's killed
Over there
"Bandit Cao De Yu"
"Bandit Fang Diao"
If I encounter this Bai chap again,
I won't be too kind
You don't understand
what Master Bai did seems unreasonable
That's why it can't be overlooked
Two robbers were killed last night
at the inn
but no one knew about it,
that's very unusual;
Guess it must have
something to do with Master Bai
I long to get acquainted with
such extraordinary people
Extraordinary?
His skills lie in cheating for
food and lodging
Brother Yan,
what a coincidence we meet again
If we are destined to meet,
we'll meet again
The little housekeeper is right
Your master and I are destined to meet
Master Bai,
are you supposed to go that way?
Please...
Sir, have a seat inside
I don't want to go that way now
Since we've met
and there's a restaurant here
why don't we go in for a drink?
Great... please
Brother Yan, please
welcome Sir...
Upstairs please
Be careful
waiter, what's the best food?
Wait, who wants average food
Bring me the best
Alright
who wants single-order wine?
Bring the whole pot
So long as the wine is good,
you'll have your tips
Thank you
So far so good
Brother Yan,
where will you be staying tonight?
I haven't decided yet
There's an inn ahead, it's quite good
why don't you go with me there?
As you wish
"Fu An Inn"
Sir, how come you're back again?
I like your look
Sir, you are making fun of me
You know, it's because
I like your look more and more
that's why I'm unwilling to leave
But I don't have the money to pay;
So I went out in the street
and found this Master Yan
Come...
This Master Yan has a lot of money
That's why I came back
Sir, you're making jokes
No, I'm not. The one who'll pay is here
I can now eat and live for free
Boss, please offer us your best room
Alright... Please
Please
Sir, is this room okay?
So far so good
Bring the best food and whole pot of wine
So long as it's good,
you'll have your tips
Yes...
This little housekeeper
understands me much better
I'm not used to sleeping with other people
Sorry to make you suffer
Yu Mo, get up, don't be rude
Brother Yan, this bed
we should let
the little housekeeper to sleep
Brother Bai, is he the shopkeeper here?
That's correct
This is Prince of Xiang Yang's
secret place
The shopkeeper here
is supposed to be his guard
He is called Zheng wa
Your identity has already been exposed
That's why the Prince has sent someone
to kill you
Those two at the inn last time
were also guards at the Prince's residence
Thank you for helping me twice,
I appreciate that
They are all notorious bandits
who worked as guards
at the Prince's residence
I'm just not too happy with it
Bao Zheng is well aware
of the Prince's great power
There're so many people at Kaifeng
why did he have to
put such an important mission on
a scholar like you?
I felt it's unfair and
so I stuck my neck out
Bai Yu Tang,
you've blamed Lord Bao wrongly
I've been protecting you secretly
all the way
Lord Yan, guess you'd recognize this
So you are the secret emissary of Lord Bao
You must be Zhan Zhao?
I can't tell you my real name
at the moment
But I'm not Zhan Zhao
Bai Yu Tang,
you too have despised all the heroes
Alright, let's have a match
Stop fooling around,
we've more important things to do
wait until
the Prince of Xiang Yang's revolt subsides
You'll know who I am
If you're still interested then
I'll be pleased to have a match with you
So you're Bai Yu Tang
who caused trouble in the capital
because you sought to spar with Zhan Zhao
Your fame precedes you
Lord Bao has been trying to recruit you
but you keep refusing
I wonder why you would help me!
I must fight against all this injustice
and so I repeatedly played tricks on you
But if you are a sycophant
I wouldn't care less
Lord Bao has his own difficulties
we'll talk about this later
we seem to get on well
what do you say we became blood brothers?
You're a high rank official
and me just an ordinary chap
I fear it'd be way out of my league
You're a great hero of the time,
how can you say this?
Um, I look older than you
so maybe I'll be the big brother
If so, please
accept my greetings
Brother
"Inspector's residence"
Order in the court
"Prince Xiang Yang's residence"
Your Majesty,
Yan Chun Min has arrived at the office
I didn't expect he got
the assistance of Bai Yu Tang, the Rat
The two teams we've sent
together with Zhang wa
have failed the mission
If I were to go,
it wouldn't have come to this
Brother Hua, no need to be angry
who would have thought that Bai Yu Tang
would change sides and help Bao Zheng
That's right, maybe we ought to
get rid of Bai Yu Tang
Yan Chun Min is just a scholar
and we needn't fear him then
Bao Zheng should be in deep trouble
It's heard that
the palace has lost the pearl crown
This incident will be
the responsibility of the Kaifeng
No one knows who did that
Let's just sit back and watch
"wanted:
The thief who stole the pearl crown"
Your kung fu is marvelous
How about working for
the Federation of the Righteous
what?
I'm afraid I've gone to the wrong place
I thought this place traded in booty
Friend, what do you mean?
What do I mean?
I heard that this place bought booty
I've just stolen something
so I want to bring it in
and get a good price for it
This is the Federation of the Righteous
so I must be in the wrong place
Friend, this belongs to
the Prince of Xiang Yang
It's not the place for you
to create trouble
what? I've heard that a couple of days ago
the Butterfly has stolen
ajade horse from the capital
He becomes a VIP once he came here
I thought this is the place
which traded in booty
So I've also stolen something
hoping to get some profit here
not knowing that you...
I am Hua, we haven't met before
You keep saying we are thieves
so you are teasing me, right?
Well said
I am proud we have such a friend with us
to glorify us thieves
You steal treasures from the palace
and became VIP
once at the Prince's residence
It's such a glorious thing
to be a thief like this
You keep talking about thievery
what do you want?
Not much
I'm a thief too
and just seek to share some glory
I've also stolen something
I wonder if you'll take this
Stealing is stealing,
and robbing is robbing
It depends on what you've stolen
I'm afraid the stuff you've stolen
is no match for my jade horse
Maybe not;, do you recall
any big case recently
that is comparable
to the stolen Jade Horse?
Could you be the one
who has stolen the pearl crown
at the imperial palace?
Precisely
Let's see if this is genuine or fake
Here it is
A treasure of the court could hardly be
replicated by ordinary folks
So you come here today
just because you want a contest with me
I wouldn't dare; your chained flying dart
is well-known in the martial arts world
How would I have the guts
to challenge you!
Once you fling your darts
I'll be dead
It's good that you understand
I'm sorry Master Hua,
your darts are all here
This is simply petty burglary,
no skill at all
what's your real skill?
Master Hua, I'm here today
It'll be too disappointing
if we don't have a match
Stop, we are all friends
Brother Hua, please forgive him
this brother of mine loves tojoke
Master Shen's brother is...
The renowned Black Fox, Zhi Hua
That's right
Brother Hua, don't be suspicious
Master Zhi is well known long before
for being humorous; he's a good friend
Master Zhi, your fame precedes you
I won't mind
even if you have made fun of me
But His Majesty's business
is no small matter
Alright...
Brother Hua has stolen the Jade Horse
Brother Zhi has stolen the pearl crown
They are all imperial treasures
There're warrants for their arrest
and there's no turning back for them
So they only have to be loyal
to His Majesty
Zhong Yuan, you know me
I'm weird at times
Sometimes I don't mind
being taken advantage of
If I knew what we stole
went to this same place
You tell him that
we are doing things in
different ways
I don't mind to let him have an upper hand
and say what should I steal
before I could prove my loyalty
to His Majesty
Let him name something
and I'll steal it back
Brother
There's no need, we all are good friends
It ain't so
You know my character
I am tough like a rock
You must think of something
Brother, maybe...
If you don't want to
I'll think of something myself
How about the seal of the special envoy
Do you think this would be adequate?
Good, I am holding a feast
to celebrate your success
Hero Zhi's kung fu is very good
and resourceful;
I think he wouldn't be in any danger
However, we could have the feast first
while we await his return
what are you doing?
The seal
Sire, congratulations
Brother Zhi has stolen the seal
Brother Hua, sorry
Hope I didn't dirty your clothes
Clear the table quickly
Congratulations on your success
Please come to the feast
You work very stealthily
I am anxious to know how you did it
I followed brother Hua's way
I pretended to be caught
Mr Hua, I'm teasing you, it's true
when I left
I was thinking
I had to steal Yan Chun Min's seal
How could I do it?
Stealing the seal shouldn't be difficult
the challenge is knowing where it was
Then I thought I might as well
go to his place and assassinate him
His officials naturally
were not my match
So I pretended
to be captured by them
Yan Chun Min asked me...
'what are you doing here? '
I replied...
'I came to kill you'
So I confessed, right?
Then he asked me...
'who asked you to do it? '
I said... no rush... someone did direct me
and he is a man of position
But if I didn't tell you
you would question me for sure
and might use torture on me
I am not afraid of death, but of torture
As soon as you write a note
that says to execute me by beheading
and put your seal on it
Then I will confess
Great plan
He fell for it
no sooner was the note written
and chopped by the seal
I moved swiftly
I broke the ropes
and pushed down the officials;
I leapt on the table
and snatched the note and the seal
Then I jumped over the wall and ran
At that time Yan Chun Min
was trembling under his desk
Great
This is the note
The great robber Zhi Hua
who set out to assassinate me
will be beheaded on sight- Yan Chun Min
Mr Zhi, you are a true hero
That's wonderful
I propose a toast to you... Here, come on
Hero Shen, after the feast
please take hero Zhi
to the House of Traps
and put the seal,
together with the pearl crown
and the jade horse in it
And you also sign your name tojoin us
Thank you
You're welcome.
I only hope to unite all heroes
and win back my kingdom
His Majesty has put
all these important items
in the House of Traps
If they're stolen,
wouldn't that be a waste of efforts?
Don't worry, the house has many traps;
it is fool-proof
Mr Lan, could you demonstrate to us
how these traps work?
He'll be less worried that way
Alright
Behind this trap door are guards
If the intruder has great kung fu
and they fail to withstand his attack
They'll fall back
The gate will fall
But the intruders will only be trapped,
not injured
Master Zhi, please go up the stairs
Please
Not bad, but the intruder
might leap right on top of the stairs
Please go up to the next floor
Not bad
But if the intruder has
great jumping technique
he could get to the second floor easily
The 2nd floor
has the deadly copper net trap
Brother, I heard today in the court room
Zhi Hua pretended to be caught
and robbed the seal; was that really so?
Yes, indeed
Zhi Hua has great skills and quite a hero
why do you say this?
This Zhi Hua
is notorious for his treachery
He is known as the Black Fox
If I were here
you wouldn't have fallen for his tricks
You went out just because of the duty
After a day's investigation
I confirmed that
the Prince formed the Federation of
the Uprighteous to unite the mercenaries
and built the House of Traps
with traps guarding
stolen treasures from the court
It is obvious Zhi Hua
has joined him and stolen your seal
to claim his credit
I am afraid so
You can't lose your seal
I plan to go
to the prince's residence tonight
and see how good
are that Zhi Hua and Hua Chong
And how deadly are the traps
in the House of Traps
No doubt the seal has been lost
with Lord Bao's support however,
it would be alright
You shouldn't underestimate dangers
Right, but having the seal stolen
is a grave matter
Besides,
I want to have a go at that Zhi Hua
The House of Traps is very dangerous
wang Tung of Kaifeng also died there
we must have a meticulous plan
Don't be rash
Brother, where are you going?
Since you wouldn't let me go,
I'm off to sleep
That's the right thing to do
The traps here are really deadly;
especially the copper net trap
But if you are not here to launch it
it'd be useless
You needn't worry
Since Brother Lan turned off
the main switch outside,
he'd need to launch the traps one by one
If the main switch was turned on,
the traps will
go into action automatically
I see
You understand now?
Brother Lan
The pearl crown could be placed inside
and please sign tojoin in too
Sure
Master Deng guessed right
why let him in on purpose?
Master Deng told me privately
that he will offer me a great credit
He said Yan Chun Min lost his seal
So Bai Yu Tang must come tonight
If we could get rid of him
Yan Chun Min wouldn't do any harm
we'll have done a great deed
for his majesty
Then set the traps in motion
Right, once inside the House of Traps
Bai Yu Tang is dead
Black Fox Zhi Hua?
Though my nickname is not good
I was sent by Lord Bao
Lord Yan, you must know this
So you are his secret emissary, please
I have come to return Lord Yan's seal
Then why did you
rob it during the day?
Lord Bao asked me to
sneak into the Prince's Residence
Though I stole the pearl crown
Prince of Xiang Yang
might not be fully convinced
The incident of the seal
should shock the whole city
and Prince of Xiang Yang
would have no more suspicion
and I could accomplish my task easily
So the seal...
Before I came here
I made a fake seal
for the Prince of Xiang Yang
The fake seal is in the House of Traps
I have the real one
I also asked Lord Bao to
notify the court secretly
that the seal had not been lost
All that occurred in the court room
was merely a show
You have thought of everything
Brother Bai was worried about
the loss of my seal
and insisted on going to retrieve it
I stopped him
I'll send someone to get him
to meet you now
Good
Brother Bai has great skills
and is upright
but he is a bit rash
He saw me robbing the seal
and must have felt bad
Please explain on my behalf
when he is here
Naturally
Master, Lord Bai is not in his room
Oh dear, he must have gone
to the House of Traps
I'll go back at once
Brother Lan, he must be dead
put him down
Bai Yu Tang is dead
He's dead
I was thinking
Descendants of late Emperors
are vying for the throne
Heroes are being involved
and many want fame
Unlike us
who enjoy a care-free life on this island
You are right, big brother
but fifth brother might think differently
I know him well
He is young, rash and impetuous
but he is not after fame or riches
He might not agree to work for Lord Bao
That's the point,
fifth brother is ambitious
and would easily
blend into this environment
Once in, it's not easy to get out
Masters
Report to fourth master
Master Bai and Inspector Yan Chun Min
became blood brothers
He went to the Prince's residence
to get back his seal
and died in the House of Traps
what's to be done?
I declined lord Bao
despite his many invitations
but I must avenge fifth brother
You're right
Coming...
we'll do according to your instructions
Master Zhi
Mr Xu, what do these men do?
Your Majesty birthday's is near,
these are tile makers
here to mend the roof;
sorry for disturbing you
It's alright
Check the roofs of
every part of the residence
and replace the damaged tiles
with new ones
Yes...
There are many affairs
I have to manage these days
I fear I might not serve you well
Ai Fu, come here
He has worked here since he was a kid
If you need anything just ask him
Serve Master Zhi well
and don't sneak away to
practise your kung fu
You practise kung fu too?
It's quite a funny story
Masters like Master Zhi, Master Shen
Master Deng and Master Hua
are all top martial artists
Even this kid practices kung fu;
what ajoke!
Not really
The best kung fu is accomplished by
steady practice
No one is born a martial artist
when I have time I'll show you a few moves
Thank you, Mr Zhi
Mr Zhi, Mr Shen
You look quite busy
The residence must look new
for his highness' birthday
Go about your work, never mind us
Yes
Look at that fellow digging
doesn't he look familiar?
Who could a workman resemble?
Your kung fu is not bad
I am a tile maker
I am used to climbing, no kung fu at all
Climbing is also a kind of kung fu
There is a Sky Rat
who is known for scaling heights
I wouldn't know about him
Are you suspicious that those two
might be the Sky Rat, Lu Fang
and Han Zhang, the Ground Rat?
Just a little doubt
Bai Yu Tang is dead, they should be here
Please have some tea
Come in... careful
Carry it into the living room
Here
what's the matter?
What are you doing here?
This is the prince's residence,
don't run around
That's great
That's where we want to go
Let's go
No entry
Let us in
Stop that noise...
what are you doing here?
A palace should have a king, right?
Naturally
I hear he is going to
celebrate his birthday, isn't it?
Yes
we are acrobats
and could entertain His Highness
Right
what has celebrating birthday
to do with acrobats?
Celebrating birthday should be joyous
and should not show a crying face
what are you doing? Get lost
You drive us away, we'll cry
Let us stay, we'll laugh
Get lost
You made Mr Xu neither cry nor laugh
Master Zhi, Master Shen
These two are agile
Looks like they know some kung fu
Zhong Yuan, what's with you?
Last couple of days
you think everyone knows kung-fu
they are just street performers
They only know magic
That's right, we only know magic
we could shift and
delude perceptions in many ways
It's getting unacceptable, drive them out
Get out...
Turtle is an auspicious sign
for His Majesty's birthday
why drive it out?
That's right,
it's a good symbol for His Majesty
Mr Xu, you should let them stay
Yes
Ai Fu, come with me
Ai Fu, did you see that?
Yes
These two are Lu Fang and Han Zhang
of the Five Rats
Ai Fu, what do you intend to do?
Whatever Master Zhi says
well said
You seldom talk
Maybe you'd like to tell me
what's on your mind
I think Master Zhi knows that very well
Being a nobody in the Prince's residence
I don't know
when I'll have a successful career
what would you consider as successful?
Make a name for yourself
in the martial arts world?
That's exactly right
The martial arts world is full of dangers
I've heard that
your parents were security escorts
and were killed, leaving you as an orphan
My parents were attacked
by a powerful gang and were badly wounded
But they killed over ten of them
before they died
Everyone in the martial world
regards them as heroes
I'd rather die a glorious death
than be a slave for the rest of my life
Good
what if I took you as my student?
Teacher, please accept my greetings
Now you have the opportunity
to do a great deed
It'd all depend on your own courage
I'll go through hell
to accomplish teacher's teaching
Report the Prince's rebellion case
to Inspector-General
Go at once
Brother, you are wrong
You saw that Lu Fang
and Han Zhang have bad intention
You didn't stop them
but took Ai Fu as your student
and ask him to sue the Prince,
what is your intention?
Yes, I don't trust him
so I wanted to test him, then you arrived
Ai Fu, you have planned to rebel
against his highness
follow me to accept your punishment
Right, Zhong Yuan
It's about time for the truth
aren't you Lord Bao's secret emissary?
I couldn't hide it from you after all
You may not wish to test Ai Fu, but I do
I want to test how brave he is
He went to the Inspector-General
to expose the crime
Lord Yan has yet to win
the confidence of the people
He has no choice but to go by the book
He would inevitably suffer torture
and if he breaks down
he'll mess up the whole thing
I believe he has the guts to do it
How did you guess
I am Lord Bao's secret emissary?
Merely a guess
I heard you didn't show Hua Chong
the traps
when you brought him along
to the House of Traps
when you brought me there
you asked Lan Xiao to show me
how each trap worked
It was obvious you wanted to show me
how they worked
That gave me the lead
Lord Yan
Hero Zhi
Yu Mo, wait at the door
no one comes in here without permission
Yes
You must have something in mind
so as to come here
You must know
Bai Yu Tang has 4 blood brothers
Lu Fang, the Sky Rat and
Han Zhang, the Ground Rat
Xu Qing, the Mountain Rat,
Jiang Ping, the River Rat
The five of them live on Xian Kong island
calling themselves
the Five Rats of Xian Kong
People call them the Righteous Five
I heard brother Bai mention this
Lord Bao had long wanted to recruit them
but they kept declining
Now because of Bai Yu Tang's death
they have accepted
the invitation from Lord Bao
to avenge Bai Yu Tang
I suspected that now they have
sneaked into residence of the Prince
Now in the residence of the Prince
There're 6 secret emissaries of
Lord Bao staying there
Besides me and the Four Rats
there is also Shen Zhong Yuan
They all have the plaque of Kaifeng
I know
The men inside the Prince's residence
would be adequate to do the job
If you wish to capture the Prince,
you could do it now
In any case
he is the grandson of the late emperor
He enjoys a respected position
If we don't have a legitimate reason
how could we search his place
and the House of Traps
and retrieve the stolen treasures
and the list of the rebels
to prove his treason
I have made some preparations
There's a servant named Ai Fu
at the Prince's residence
This kid is sharp and courageous
He's good in kung fu and
awaits a good chance
I've already taken him as my student
Day after tomorrow
is the birthday of the Prince
It'll be a busy day at the Residence
I've asked him to appear in court
to sue the Prince
would this be an excuse then?
Yes, indeed
By the law of Song,
if a slave wants to sue the master
he'd have to suffer flogging
I fear he can't endure torture
and change his confession
that'll cause more troubles
Don't worry
This kid will be able to tolerate
You then bring Ai Fu to cross-examine
with the Prince
while I'll bring my men
to the House of Traps
to catch them unprepared
This way they can't deal with
two things at one time
Order in the court
Bring the complainant
Yes
Kneel
what's your name?
Ai Fu,
I am a servant of the Prince's residence
what is your complaint?
I want to report a revolt case
Someone at the Prince's residence
wants to revolt?
It is the Prince of Xiang Yang himself
How dare you, you are only a young servant
Do you realise
that this is a serious accusation?
Prince holds great respect,
if you accuse him wrongly
you'd suffer the consequences
I am young but not ignorant
and I won't dare talk foolishly
Prince has really recruited rebels
preparing for revolt
I love my country
and that's why I risk my life
to report the case
Is that really so, what proof do you have?
The Jade Horse and the pearl crown
which the court lost
are hidden in the House of Traps
The ones who stole them,
Hua Chong, Zhi Hua
are hiding at the Prince's Residence too
If Your Lordship would
send men to search there
you'll catch them red-handed
Do you know
that a servant suing his master
will have to suffer flogging?
I am here to risk life for my country
My own life is of no importance to me
Alright,
prepare for the instruments of torture
Yes
Ai Fu, do you want to
change your confession?
It's true that
the Prince is planning a revolt
I won't change it
Good, a great hero
Let him down
Let's move to the residence
of the Prince of Xiang Yang
Yes
"Prince's Residence"
Come
Lord Yan arrives
Lord Yan, you're here to celebrate
Prince's birthday
why bother to bring
so many guards with you?
Yes
You're here for the
Prince's birthday celebration
You bring guards and
dare not kneel to the Prince
where are your manners?
I apologize for not realising that
But I'm not here for this purpose
You're rude
Your Majesty, excuse me for being rude
I am here today because
someone is suing Your Majesty
for sheltering rebels, hiding stolen goods
How dare you!
Although I'm low in rank,
I've the order of the Emperor
Although Your Majesty is
highly respectable
treason cannot be taken lightly
You said you have the order of the Emperor
but I don't know who you are
How can you prove yourself?
I have the seal
where's the seal?
Your Majesty seems to know
that I've lost my seal
Unfortunately, the one stolen
was a fake one
Yu Mo
Yes
It seems Yan is going to
arrest His Majesty, hurry...
Master Lan, by the order of Master Shen
Yan Chun Min is taking his men
to arrest His Majesty
There are people fighting in the hall
Master Shen told me to ask you
to take some men to help
Yes
Master Lan, what are we going to do?
Let's turn on the traps first
How cunning of Lan Xiao!
I suppose he'd be sent away
by Shen Zhong Yuan
not realising that he'd turn on
the traps before going
Don't blame me if you're dead
The trap is activated
Finally there's no need
to be left dangling anymore
Brother Han
You must be Brother Zhi, the Black Fox
Alright... Yan Chun Min
You said someone is suing me for treason
who's the plaintiff?
Of course there's someone
Bring Ai Fu
Yes
So it's this Ai Fu
who's he?
He's a servant at our residence
Servant suing the master
Yan Chun Min,
do you know the laws of our regime?
Of course I do
Your Majesty,
please have a look at Ai Fu's wounds
I have already flogged
and cross-examined him
Take this traitor away
Yes
Your Majesty wants to silent him?
Capture Yan Chun Min too
Yes
Hurry
There's a Copper Net upstairs,
it's terrible
It was said that brother Bai died there
That's correct
But just standing here won't help either
At least we have to try
That's correct
Then I have to hang in the air again
we may not be able to go upstairs
but do as I say and try
Alright
Come on
They are Master Xu, the Mountain Rat
and Master Jiang, the River Rat
That's us
It's Master Zhi
You're too kind, I am Zhi Hua
Hey, I'm still hanging in the air
Brother, don't worry, I'm coming
Go...
we're going too
Shen Zhong Yuan, you are from the Kaifeng
Are you alright?
I'm fine
Be careful, there's...
- Brother Xu
- 3rd brother
3rd brother
Brother
It's my fault
I think brother Bai
would feel Ionely over there
I could keep him company
Brother Xu
- 3rd brother
- Brother Xu
3rd brother
If only Big Brother could be here earlier
This is Zhi Hua, our Big Brother
Brother Lu, we've met before
Brother Zhi
The Prince of Xiang Yang
has hidden all the treasures in here
the Jade Horse,
Pearl Crown are all in there
How are we going to take them out?
They are controlled by traps
Although Lan Xiao was sent away
by Shen Zhong Yuan
he turned on the traps before he left
The switches don't work here
The key is with Lan Xiao
Then we can't take it
I've made some preparations
This seal is a fake one, it's useless
This is the Dragon Pearl Crown
This is the Jade Horse
what's in this box?
This...
It used to contain the list of the names
but now it has disappeared
The list is
the most important thing of all
Brother Zhi, where else could it be?
You'd have to ask the Prince,
I really don't know
Prince of Xiang Yang is in the hall
Although Lord Yan has brought a lot of men
Not to mention Hua Chong, Deng Che
Even with those guards,
they can't resist them
Let's get back quick
2nd brother, protect His Lordship
The list is not at the House of Traps
Your Majesty,
the list is not in the House of Traps
So what?
You should realise
that you have lost your power
Hand over the list
His Majesty might spare your life
Everyone outside is
fighting for their master
I can't blame them, but you,
who I have treated so well
turned into a traitor
and is now putting pressure on me
Your Majesty, did you hear that?
Hua Chong and Deng Che are dead
You'd better hand over the list
Alright, I'll help you fulfil
your career aspirations
Take it
Father, please forgive my incompetence
I can only follow your footsteps to death
Prince of Xiang Yang
committed suicide, here's the list
The list is in my stomach
Cut me up and take it
Then I'll cut you up
You can get the list
but why did you let Hua Chong grab it?
Once Prince of Xiang Yang is dead,
his power is gone
This list will cause the death of many
what do you want it for?
Fame and riches bring disasters to many
These people used to live comfortably
in the Island
now they end up like this
I'm afraid the list can never be found