1962 Arts Festival   Minister of Culture Award
Winner
1962 Arts Festival   Official Participant
HUMAN
Based on Nogami Ayeko's  "The Neptune"
Screenplay by Shindou Kaneto
Cast
Otowa Nobuko
Tonoyama Taiji
Satou Kei
Yamamoto Kei
Kaji Kentarou
Watanabe Misako
Directed by Shindou Kaneto
Hi!
Hello!
I don't really wanna go if we won't
be back in time for the Obon Festival...
Even if we take it real easy, it won't
take more than a couple of days.
We'll be back tomorrow night.
And we'll have money
to enjoy the festivities!
Captain Kamegorou,
can you give me a ride?
What are you gonna
do on the island?
I've picked some abalone
and want to sell them there.
Gorosuke, trying to make
some money for the Obon, hey?
There's too little to make a real profit...
But you ladies just dive and bring
money up from the bottom of the ocean!
You complain too much.
Sankichi's  coming, too?
Didn't have much choice...
He pulled me into this.
What are you carrying?
We'll pick up some stones.
You're not taking anything
on your way there?
A shame! We'll only
be paid for the trip back!
Hey, Hachi! We're leaving!
Get the anchor!
Gorosuke!
Comin'!
Sea God
Sankichi, I'll do the cooking.
You just watch.
Good thing for me you're on board!
Hey, Sea God!
Where are you heading?
Going to pick up some stones!
Working during Obon?
Gotta make some money
to spend in the Festival!
Hey!
Is the food ready yet?
You sound like you're
starving, you crybaby!
Sankichi, bring out
the miso soup!
Got it!
Love the way food tastes
when cooked this way!
Captain Kamegorou! Food's ready!
You go ahead.
The captain's always the captain!
You eat first.
I'll steer for ya'.
Hey! Sea God!
How was the fishing today?
Very good indeed!
Think we could have one?
Sure!
Thanks a bunch!
That's a beautiful skipjack!
Sankichi, you should slice
some sashimi from it for lunch!
The rest we should cook
with some ginger. It's delicious!
Hachi, you're turn here!
Or are you gonna eat
all 5 kilos of rice?
Gorosuke, I'm afraid
there's nothing left.
No way!
You bottomless pig!
Gorosuke, never mind him. Not
even Hachi could eat that much.
He doesn't stop eating!
Now I feel like a human being!
Don't throw up!
That'd be a waste!
There's a storm coming!
The western wind is blowing too strong.
Our "guest" should pay us a visit soon.
What a day for us to meet on!
By now we should be on the island,
and I should be embracing my girl.
We're drifting towards east.
What will we do?
There's nothing we can do.
Not in a situation like this.
So we won't be back home tomorrow?
Damn ship I got myself in!
Blow as much as you want!
-Sankichi! You should eat something!
-Do you think we'll be ok?
Don't worry. It will be over by morning.
Sankichi! Eat something!
Hold on tight!
Don't you go dying
before marrying some girl!
I have the sea in front of me
The mountains behind me
Omatsubara...!
Gorosuke! The barrel!
Hachi! Get over here!
There's something wrong with
the rudder! Hachi, take a look at it!
Gorosuke! Hachi!
We've lost the rudder!
Captain! Uncle!
The engine stopped!
What are all of you doing?
You don't want to live?
Don't wanna be saved?
And you call yourselves 'seamen'?
We have no rudder…
No fuel…
There's nothing we can do…
Fool! You think this is
enough to bring me down?
Let's get the water out!
I'm not gonna die!
Gorosuke! Sankichi!
Come with me!
Come!
Captain Kamegorou,
how far have we drifted?
Well...we've been drifting
eastward for 5 days now...
That's quite a stretch...
There goes the Obon Festival...
That will do. Let's work
on the rudder, now. Come up!
-So?
-It's fixed!
What's the use?
There's no fuel!
Stupid! Without a rudder,
the ship could be overturned!
Uncle?
How far do you
think we'll drift?
Will we survive?
Fool!
Have no fear!
Sankichi, how much
rice have we got left?
About 15 kilos, I'd say.
Then we're gonna have
porridge, starting tomorrow.
And how are we
gonna live on that?
What did you say?
Will the porridge make the
rice last that much longer?
If we're going to starve, I
don't want to do it eating porridge.
Gorosuke, ain't I right?
Don't you agree?
I don't want no porridge!
Me neither!
I won't eat porridge!
Why cook the rice into a porridge?
We're not gonna make it, either way!
Since we're going to die, let us at
least eat all we can before we do!
Fools! How can you say
such desperate words?
No matter what,
I don't want porridge!
You're gonna give up that easily? How
could you pass yourselves for seamen?
What good would come from persevering?
How can we survive without fuel?
Rotten luck!
I feel it in my guts!
How stupid can you get?
I'm not gonna die!
The God Konpira is
watching over me!
Even if the ship is destroyed
and a plank of wood is all that's left...
Whatever happens, I'm not gonna die!
The Sea God Konpira is watching over me!
Sankichi, never mind if Hachi
and Gorosuke don't want to eat it.
We're having rice porridge
strating tomorrow at breakfast.
Understood?
Bastard!
I should not have let him
convince me to come...
I wanted to quit this job, but he said we
could make some quick money before the festival.
Bastard!
He fooled me!
Mother Gorosuke?
My father drowned in the Genkai Sea...
when a coal ship sank.
But what an
unlucky bastard you are!
My father is
waiting at the bottom.
Hachizou, you're
gonna die, too!
You'll be food
for fish, too!
I won't die! I have
a son waiting for me!
I won't die before
seeing Gorou married!
Sankichi!
You're Kamegorou's nephew, aren't you? You're
in cohorts so the two of you survive, aren't you?
I won't have that! We'll all die together!
I won't be the only one to die!
Hachi! What's
the meaning of this?
Didn't you hear
your captain's orders?
I don't wanna die eating porridge!
I'll have me some proper rice!
Sankichi! Where have you been?
This bird-brain has cooked rice!
Bird-brain or not, I want rice!
I'll have some, too!
Well, if you'll behave like
that, I know just what to do.
From now on, I'll guard
the provisions myself.
Sankichi, take all the
rice and miso to my room.
Gorosuke's abalone, too!
Now... we have a little
over 6 kilos of rice.
The miso is half full...
One takuan roll...
Two white radishes
with some leaves...
56 eddoes...
23 abalone shells...
3 bottles of water
with 2 litres each...
Now take a good look.
This is what we'll have to live on.
This is the key to our survival.
Look at this.
Not a grain of rice left...
We ate all of it in 8 days.
And there's less than
a litre of water left.
6 abalone shells...
We'll have to make do with
that and the eddoes and radishes...
Now you know
where we stand.
Shouldn't you peel them?
Stupid! We'll
eat all of it!
Lord Konpira!
Won't you please
make it rain?
Please help us!
Send some rain!
Oh, Mighty Lord Konpira
That's all the water we have...
There's some left!
Yes, there is!
As you can see, just a sip.
We'll use this and some
sea water to make miso soup.
It doesn't taste good if
made with sea water alone.
It's too salty to eat!
We'll only get thirsty!
Sip it slowly.
Don't taste it,
swallow it straight away.
Gorosuke, be strong!
Believe it!
We must believe we'll make it!
If we lose our
faith, we'll die...
Uncle...
You really think we can make it?
Of course!
As long as we believe it!
Souvenir from the
Temple of Lord Konpira
Kamegorou!
I bring you water!
Don't worry!
I'll send as much as you can drink!
You'll see!
Kamegorou, it's water!
Have some!
Hey! Wake up!
Water! Water!
Wake up! Wake up!
Lord Konpira sent me a sign!
He said "Don't worry,
I'll send water!"
And it started to
flow from his fountain!
It's gonna rain!
Follow me! It'll rain!
How could it rain on
such a sunny day?
There are no clouds!
Not a drop will fall...
No! It will rain!
I got the sign!
It was just a dream.
You can't count
on Lord Konpira.
Sankichi, don't blaspheme!
He's the protector of seamen!
The Lord of the ocean!
You're speaking nonsense!
"Lord Konpira" my ass!
You're going crazy!
Look!
I can see it!
It's a cloud! Sankichi,
bring the binoculars!
Look! I can see it!
I see it, too!
Is it an island?
I can see it!
Is it a ship?
Those are clouds!
Rain clouds!
It's gonna rain!
It's coming this way!
Rain clouds!
Hachi! Gorosuke! Sankichi!
Those are rain clouds!
Like in Konpira's sign!
Bring the empty barrels!
The bottles!
Hachi! Gorosuke! Sankichi!
You understand it now?
Seeing this marvel!
We mustn't lose heart!
It's proof Lord Konpira
has not turned his back on us!
Let's take this to the bow,
where the wind blows.
That will keep it from rotting.
Since you've drank all you could,
you seem to have livened up!
Hachi...
Today makes it 24 days.
You should stop. It's like
counting down to your death.
I can't stand
drinking more water.
I'd like to see
dogs, cats...
Horses, cattle,
mountains, rivers...
It feels like it's
been a thousand years...
Gorosuke...
every single day...
all we've been eating is miso soup that tastes
like water that's been used to wash a wall...
But I believe
Kamegorou and Sankichi...
have been secretly eating
from the eddoes and radishes.
Not Kamegorou...
He wouldn't do such a thing.
Think about it.
If not...
How could Kamegorou
remain so confident!
He keeps the miso and the
eddoes. What could we do?
You're such a fool!
You'll just accept
things as they are?
Gorosuke...
We should keep our share.
So? What ya' say?
Divide the provisions...
Yes.
We should do that.
Hachi, let's do it.
Captain Kamegorou?
What? What do
the two of you want?
We...
came to ask
you to split the food.
And why would
you wanna do that?
Never mind the reason!
We just want it!
Gorosuke! You too?
Gorosuke! Don't you?
I want it!
Give us our share!
The miso? The eddoes, too?
Yes. Our share in everything.
If I give you your share, you'll eat
all of it at once; It won't last 3 days...
It's better than being robbed!
What? Robbed?
Yes! We won't be robbed anymore!
You think I'd rob
even a single eddoe?
How should we know?
You keep all of it here!
You've dragged us
into the open sea...
and you keep the best
for yourself and Sankichi?
Not even in death we'd have peace!
We've all grown up
on the same beach...
How can you say
such harsh words?
Gorosuke! Hachi!
Do you think I'm a man
who'd do such a thing?
We're going to die!
Let us do as we please!
No one has saved us so far!
We see no tuna ships,
no airplanes...
We've drifted too far away...
Death has got us on her hand!
I want to eat something!
Just give us our share!
Well...
If that's how you feel...
Sankichi, the draining basket!
We've eaten all the abalone.
All we've got are
eddoes and miso.
That's 15 each.
So...
No complaints so far?
Now, the miso.
Half a radish.
That's all of it.
You can search the
room, if you'd like.
We still have lots of water.
It's on the bow,
drink as much as you like.
If you want to live, use the
water to make a thin miso soup.
Wait!
There's that other thing...
These are pickled plum seeds.
I thought they
might come in handy.
There's some taste left in them...
One could add water and make tea.
You can have
half of these, too.
That's 5 for you.
The two of us will sleep in that
compartment over there from now on.
Why?
You're trying to avoid me?
Never mind...
Do as you like.
Just a moment!
I know I'm repeating myself...
But that's all the food we've got!
When that's over, all we'll
have to chew on are the ropes.
Keep that in mind.
Don't forget that!
Bastards!
How can they
say those things!
Let's put our food back.
From now on you'd
better sleep here, too.
We all worked
together during the storm,
But look what happens
when we run out of food!
Sankichi! Shut up!
Not ready yet?
The eddoes are not cooked yet.
Don't lick it like that!
I have to check for salt!
There's no need!
Then you lick it, too!
Should I use more miso?
It's fine!
Quit doing that!
Delicious!
We'll finally have some
soup that tastes like soup!
I don't want to wait for the
eddoes! Let me have some!
We settled on five each, right?
You saw it with your
own eyes, didn't you?
How about you?
Watcha' waiting for?
I'll wait
for the eddoes.
Uncle, let's eat!
That was great!
I can feel it in my stomach!
It'd been a while since I'd
had food you can actually chew.
You should eat, too!
Not just yet. I'll wait
till it's well cooked...
And creamy...
Uncle?
Will we survive?
Sure we will. Lord Konpira
is watching over us.
Won't they eat all their food
and come asking for ours?
Don't worry.
I'd never let that happen.
Well cooked?
Yes! And creamy...
Let me have one!
No way! You've
eaten your share!
I'll pay you back!
It's just a loan!
Nonsense! What would
you pay me with?
Whatever food is left,
belongs to both of us.
I have money!
I'll pay you!
Money is
no good out here.
Then finish quickly!
You shouldn't eat so slowly
on purpose, like that.
Wether I'm slow or fast,
that's my own business.
The slower I eat,
the more it will last.
Hachi!
What are you doing over there?
I'm not doing anything!
You've licked some miso!
No, I haven't!
I just looked at it.
I can look, can't I?
Don't touch the food!
It's mine, too!
Gorosuke...
Let's eat 5 more...
Eating so little
makes me hungrier!
Stupid! If we eat like
that, it won't last two days!
We won't make it... There aren't
even tuna ships around...
We've come to a cursed place!
Since we're doomed anyway,
why not eat properly?
C'mon, Gorosuke...
Let's eat!
If you won't eat, I'll just
have the whole thing myself!
Uncle?
Wanna change?
It's been 28 days.
That much? 28?
It's impressive humans can
survive that long on so little...
Uncle?
We can't go
on like this...
We'll die...
Sankichi!
You're a man!
Don't despair!
I'm scared! I'm scared!
Focus on surviving!
Fight death!
I'm scared!
Think of the things to come!
About getting married!
How can a man die without
having slept with a woman?
I'm scared!
Jerk!
Why not?
We'll die anyway...
Not with you...
Sankichi!
What?
In your compartment, there's
still lots of food, isn't there?
How's that?
Don't lie! When the division was made,
the two of you hid it somewhere.
Impossible! The captain
would never do that!
Liar!
You're still having soup!
What soup?
All we've had since yesterday
morning is plum seed water...
What are you chewing?
Gorosuke!
I see...
Pickled plum seed...
I've had it for so long,
I can't taste anything anymore.
Why do you keep it in your mouth?
It helps time pass...
I'm so hungry!
I want to eat!
Some sukiyaki...
rice cakes...
Anything...
I want to eat!
I WANT TO EAT!
That skewered chicken tasted so nice...
I could eat... a whole shank...
All by myself...
I think...
I might lose my mind.
Oh, Mighty Lord Konpira
Oh, Mighty Lord Konpira...
Gorosuke?
Don't say anything.
It makes me hungry...
Let's talk...
Silence is scary...
Didn't you say...
You've tried monkey meat?
A long time ago...
During the typhus epidemic...
A relative who's already died
brought it home and gave us some.
He said it was a spell to
protect us from the fever.
How did it taste?
How it tasted?
All four-legged animals taste alike...
You say badger meat stinks?
But raccoon dogs taste nice.
I heard snakes are good, too.
So they say...
The lumberjacks in
the forests of Hyuga...
dip them in sweet soy
sauce and broil them.
They say it's
much better than eel.
If prepared right...
you could eat just any creature...
No doubt about it...
During the war...
people ate worms,
lizzards and insects...
Don't come near me.
You stink!
I wonder...
What a person would taste like...
They say it's like pomegranates...
It's probably better than that...
You think so?
That it tastes good?
I'm sure of it.
Fish and cattle taste good.
Why would humans be an exception?
That makes sense...
Of course it does...
Let's stop!
This food talk is making me hungrier!
Gorosuke...
It isn't just "talk"...
If we set our minds to it...
We can have lots of good food to eat...
Sankichi.
What about him?
Even now... I don't
think I could do it...
Easily said, you hypocrite!
The truth is you want it!
Hachi...
That's too much.
Fool!
If we don't do it to them,
they will do it to us.
Those two have already robbed us
of so much miso and eddoes...
That alone would justify it.
Gorosuke...
If we were to starve to death...
They'd eat the two of us.
Sankichi!
What?
I've been keeping
an eddoe for you...
Come get it!
Who'd have an eddoe by now?
Don't tease me!
Silly! What would
I gain from lying to you?
I found them yesterday, in a
straw bag in the middle of the junk pile.
There were three of them,
so I've kept one for you...
You should thank me!
Ain't that right, Gorosuke?
Sankichi...
It's true!
See...
Come down here!
Sankichi!
What are you waiting for?
Come down here...
It's true?
Of course...
It' already cooked!
Let me have it!
Give it to me!
It's in the pan.
Sankichi?
Sankichi!
Quick!
We have to hide the body!
Sankichi?
Sankichi!
Hachi!
Gorosuke!
Where's Sankichi?
Give him back!
Hachi! Gorosuke!
What have you done with Sankichi?
Why won't you answer me?
Have you done
something you can't tell me about?
Shut up!
How the hell should
we know where Sankichi is!
I know it!
You've... killed him, haven't you?
Haven't you?
Hachi!
Hachi! Gorosuke!
You've... killed Sankichi, haven't you?
Come up here.
Out here on the deck.
I'll deal with you!
I'll avenge Sankichi!
What's the matter?
Why won't you answer?
Bastards! Cowards!
Animals! Pieces of shit!
Hachi, don't!
-Don't do it!
-Let me go!
He'll kill us if
I don't get him first!
Hachi! Don't!
Hachi! Gorosuke!
Come up! Come up!
Let go! Let go!
Kamegorou! I will not deny it!
We've killed Sankichi!
We've killed him to eat him!
And so what?
You barbarians! Monsters!
And who's
to blame for that?
If you're so hungry for meat...
Eat your own!
Hachi! Stop!
Put the cleaver down!
We brought this on!
Killing Sankichi was wrong,
no matter the circumstances!
We should starve
before we eat human flesh!
Sankichi, forgive us!
Captain Kamegorou!
Have mercy! Mercy!
I beg forgiveness!
On my knees, I beg!
I'm so scared of Sankichi's spirit!
Sankichi...
Won't you please forgive
Hachizou and Gorosuke?
And forgive me, too?
We'd all turned into monsters...
We were no longer human...
The sun seems like
it just won't set today...
Gorosuke!
Sankichi...
Please forgive us!
Don't cry, Gorosuke!
Hachi!
It's Sankichi!
We're being punished!
Oh, Mighty Lord Konpira
Oh, Mighty Lord Konpira...
Captain!
Hachi?
Please open!
Captain Kamegorou, please open!
What do you want?
Please open!
The waves are
breaking on the deck!
Please let us in!
I'll allow you two to stay in here,
but you must take all your clothes off.
I have no knives on me...
Hachi, how about you?
Hachi!
What's this? What's this?
Hachi! Why did you
have a cleaver on you?
I didn't intend to use it...
I was afraid you'd try to
avenge Sankichi and attack me...
Is that the truth?
Hachi!
Why didn't you give it
to the captain right away?
Kamegorou...
We'd better throw these
out to the sea!
You two should use that
rope to tie yourselves...
We're so weak that
being thrown about could kill us!
Tightly, now.
The knot!
I'm evoking Lord Konpira,
so that we'll be saved.
How do you do that?
You don't have to
say it out loud...
Just concentrate on it.
After the horrible
thing we've done to Sankichi...
There's no way Lord Konpira
will listen to our pleas...
Why didn't I stop Hachi?
We were like beasts...
Sankichi...
Please forgive us...
It was all my fault, Sankichi...
Sankichi! Sankichi!
Forgive us, Sankichi...
Sankichi...
I'm to blame...
I'm sorry, Sankichi...
Sankichi!
Hachi!
The storm has passed.
Hachi, hang on!
Gorosuke!
The storm is over.
Gorosuke! It's water!
Don't give up!
Hachi! Hachi!
Have some water.
Here!
Hachi and Gorosuke,
you mustn't quit.
I think we might be saved.
Lord Konpira appeared
in my dreams last night.
Like that other time...
He was standing by my side.
A ship, on its way back
from San Francisco...
has changed its course
due to a typhoon...
and should be somewhere
in this area today...
You're lying to
try to give us strenght.
It's not a lie.
That's what he said.
If you doubt it, we'll be punished
and good fortune will slip away.
Did you really see him?
Would I lie to you?
Now, we must be strong.
Let's climb to the deck.
If we stay down here like this, we'll die.
Stand up!
Fool!
Get up!
We've survived for
too long to die like this.
Up! Up!
Let's climb out.
Outside!
Can you see anything?
There's nothing to see!
If Lord Konpira was
any help at all, we'd already...
A ship! A ship!
I can see it!
Hachi! Gorosuke!
It's coming!
It's coming our way!
A ship!
Oh, Mighty Lord Konpira
Oh, Mighty Lord Konpira...
Hachi! Gorosuke!
This is Lord Konpira's doing!
Thank him! Thank him!
And wave your hands! Wave them!
Were you adrift?
Are you Japanese?
Get aboard!
H-Helps us...
Scum! Stand up!
Or else I'll leave you here!
Wait!
Quick! Lazy people will
be thrown overboard!
I yelled at you to keep you
from letting go and dying.
Please don't take it to heart.
Don't worry about a thing.
We'll arrive in Yokohama
in two weeks time.
You mustn't talk for now.
You should rest.
So... do you feel better?
You should take that beard
back home with you as a souvenir!
59 days...
It's amazing you've survived...
I'm impressed
you haven't gone mad.
Where is this
ship coming from?
We're on our way back
from San Francisco...
There was a typhoon,
so we had to wait around.
But I guess our bad luck was
your lucky break, huh?
Captain Kamegorou...
What is it?
I'm sorry I doubted
Lord Konpira's message.
I am scared.
I just said those things
to keep you two from quitting...
Don't worry...
Is that true, Captain Kamegorou?
I believe in Lord Konpira,
so I dreamed with him a lot.
But I never dreamed
about a ship from San Francisco.
On the other hand,
things went exactly as I said...
So he must have inspired me.
Lord Konpira will
probably punish us!
You're right. We will pay!
Lord Konpira is not
such a vengeful god.
He's saved all of us, hasn't he?
You're being silly...
You two should just
forget all that's happened.
Don't think about it...
Hachi! Gorosuke!
You should see this!
I can see Ohshima!
We're back!
Look! It's Ohshima!
And Mount Mihara!
We've made it back alive!
I knew we would make it!
We're back! We're back!
We're finally back!
Sankichi! We're back!
Sankichi!
We're back!
Aren't you glad, Sankichi?
Let's dance! Let's dance!
Sankichi! We're back!
Gorosuke! What's the matter?
Don't lose control!
Let's dance, Sankichi!
Dance! Dance!
Gorosuke!
The woman, Gorosuke.
She went mad?
Correct.
She went mad,
and then fell off?
Correct.
Why did she go mad?
I don't know...
The boy, Sankichi, he got
sick and died while you were lost?
Exactly.
What were the symptoms?
After we ran out of food...
He developed a fever...
You're telling the truth?
Yes. That's exactly what happened.
-And you threw his body overboard?
-Yes. That's what we did.
We wrapped him in a raincoat,
and committed him to the sea...
That's the whole truth.
Hachi!
Sankichi!
The End
Subtitles by Mazaliche