MAGYARS
"If we don't count stupidity,
our past, our lives and our stomach,
Oh, then we're very pure indeed.
Let hope open up it's gates before us!"
- Attila Jozsef: MAGYARS
WINTER
Dear father!
- They're waiting for you in the pub!
- Nobody's waiting for me there!
But of course they are! Uncle Daniel just
knocked on the door a moment ago. There
were others's with him!
Have gave it a thought?
The child is too small still. There's
nobody to look after him.
Your brother said he would... He did.
You never had such an opportunity before,
Andras! Come with us!
Or you wish to live in a rented house
all your life?
You're the youngest and the strongest
among us!
We'd feel much safer with you!
- I'd want to take the woman as well,
if I'd decide to go! - You can!
Dani Kiss brings his one too, just like
Janos Szabo and Elek Viktor!
Well, let's talk about it then!
Go! Tell your mother to come here!
Hear me out, Daniel!
My son would like to go with you too!
The air too damp there, Karoly,
and your son is...
He's recovered already. His
lungs are fine.
Well, if that's how it is, all right then.
Whoever wishes to come,
may come.
But we can't take everybody with us either!
There is a war going on.
The village cannot be left
without menfolks.
- There are lots of work here as well.
- I got that.
But I can spare my son.
Are you certain that he's recovered?
Why would I lie to you?
I talked to the notary. He wants
the list by tomorrow morning.
I write down everybody who applies.
They are making a contract
with everybody.
How much is the payment?
If they'll only pay half of what
they promise,
we'll still be all right.
We're going to be paid after performance.
Whoever works more, will get more.
That's how it is.
- I went to the notary.
- I'm not going anywhere!
Goddamnit! I'm not going!
I'd rather just die here! But I'm not going!
You're just like your father! He lived his
entire life here, and he never even
left the village!
What are you talking about my father?
My father went as far at the land
of the Italians!
Stop yelling! You wake up the child!
If I said I won't go,
that means, I won't go! Goddamn it!
My father had stabbed an Italian
at Isonzo!
He had to! He was taken!
But following his own heart he
never went not even as far as Debrecen!
And they can also take you to the war
again, too!
Which is a another good reason for us to go!
But no... I'm not going!
Well, look! The Bandi Bacsko, the fool!
What does he want? He's looking at you,
Andras! Do you hear me?
Why is he looking? It seems he wants to
tell you something, but I wonder what?
Do you hear me? Don't go! Don't go away!
Don't go, Andras! You mustn't!
Where are you running, you? Are you
trying to race with the train?
You hapless! He fell!
- I wonder what he wanted...
- I don't know.
I think I saw him crying. And fools
cannot cry at all, you know.
- How come?
- They just can't.
In Kallo, in the loony bin, I never
saw not even one to cry.
Not once. 'Cos they don't
have the brains for it!
Ah, Dani! Dani! By God, I can't
deal with it. Help me, Abris!
Abris! Hold the legs! Come on, now!
Why are you pushing me?
Stop that, Irma!
You be blessed by the Good All-mighty!
How many times I have to ask you
to stop crying?
Let's say one Our Father!
We're not heading to the fair, Rozi!
Why are you sounding the bells?
If only we'd go to Pocs, at least!
I just want to pray to
meet my mother alive still,
when we return!
This is not a funteral! We're not
going to die there!
Say your prayers silently! This is
nobody else's business!
German [too quiet]
- Do we have everything?
- Yes.
We can go.
Good day, folks! This gentleman
here, beside me is the Master!
You'll be working on his farm!
(in German) Hello! How do you do?
(in German) Welcome! Welcome! Welcome!
The Master kindly welcomes you.
Other Hungarians have worked here before
as well, but they returned home right
before Christmas.
Only I stayed behind.
I'm called Brayner. Brayner.
Well, let's go then.
You can always come to me with
whatever problems you've got.
Anton! Hey!
Well, please! You'll be living at this
wing of the castle, upstairs.
Couples will be given their own rooms.
You can find the kitchen downstairs.
Everybody is allowed to cook for themselves
there. And if you look where I'm pointing now,
there are some barracks beyond the trees.
It's got fences all over. Don't go there
if possible!
By the way, you'll be given an card, and you're
free to go wherever you want with that.
You're not restricted in your movements.
The only thing the Master asks you is
not to inquire about the barrack-camp!
Nice and warm room!
What are you looking for?
- I want to talk to the Master!
- What do you want from him?
- I must talk to him!
- Come!
(in German) Come in!
(in German) This Hungarian lady wants
to talk to you.
(in German) Please.
So, say it! What do
you want from the Master?
Ask him, where is the church
here?
(in German) She asks, where the next church is.
(in German) The church...
There is no church here.
This is a farm.
It was a pity to turn to the Master
with this. The church is in the town!
We'll go there sooner or later!
There was no need to disturb the
Master over this!
Abris! I brought you some tea!
Don't tell this to the Master!
I'll be all right by tomorrow!
I just got weak. Otherwise
I'm fine!
- Do you know how to deal with horses?
- There is no need to know much about that!
But these are different horses
than the ones back home!
Horses are horses wherever
they are!
I cleaned horses before,
although not too often,
but I want to do it, like...
And this? You're full of hay, you!
(In German) Nah! What do you want from me?
Why are you so jumpy? Why are you
so jumpy? You fool!
- You must be Anton, right? You're Anton!
- (in German) [unintelligible/drunk]
(in German) [unintelligible/drunk]
(in German) Just wait. Come, come.
in German [unintelligible/drunk]
I don't know what's this, but it seems
like palinka. Even though it's not.
It's sweet. It's better than nothing!
(in German) Come, come.
- (in German) [unintelligible/drunk]
- Dear God, Anton!
Your mouth must be rotting away,
'cos your breath really stinks!
(in German) Come, come.
(in German) Look here! Come on...
(in German) Come...
Where are you hurrying, Fabian?
You're faster on foot than
others on horseback!
One must hurry if he really wants
to get there!
That's the spirit!
But there is no need to do
everything in one day, Fabian!
That long one, the Szabo!
He carries up two bags of potatoes
from the cellar, and then complains
that his back hurts!
There is no need to exert yourselves yet!
The time has not come for that yet!
Only when the summer comes!
The fall! That's when! Then you'll
have a lot to do!
That's when most of the work is!
That's right!
The Master will be glad!
I'd love to smoke some Hungarian
tobacco, Fabian!
If only you'd accept mine
in exchange!
Careful with your tobacco, Fabian!
Not always can we get that!
- No?
- Well, there is war going on, if you wouldn't know!
Mr. Brayner!
There are only flatlands in this
area?
Not a single living soul comes
all day long!
Tell me, Fabian! Do you know who
are fighting these days?
- I know. - Well, who?
- The folks.
Folks? What folks?
Have you heard about
the name of Hitler yet?
Hitler. Hitler Adolf.
I think I might have hear it
before.
And you, Fabian, what have
you heard about him?
With all due respect, but I don't
read no newspapers.
Hitler is a military man!
That right! A military man!
A Chief-commander!
What's wrong with this one?
Mr. Brayner! Can I ask you something?
Go ahead.
Who are there in the neighbourhood?
There, in the barracks,
which is surrounded.
French POWs.
- I'd like to have a look at them, if I may.
- Why would you want to do that?
What's wrong with them?
You see, Fabian! Your wife understands
reason much better than you do!
What's to point looking at them?
POWs? POWs. I don't look at things
I have absolutely no business with!
Such people are capable of everything!
Why did you came up with those
prisoners?
How could you ask anything at all
from such a man?
He is a Hungarian. He speaks
Hungarian.
He worked here last year, and
then he stayed around.
He is a Hungarian.
Can you hear this, Ilonka? Airplanes!
SPRING
But who're playing on the fiddles
and trumpets?
And how do they know what
to play?
They must be playing from paper,
that's for sure!
That must be very hard!
But almost like a miracle!
Almost like... like a miracle!
A letter came from back home again!
The money arrived to the post
for second time as well.
But my brother says only I can
collect it!
- Once I return home.
- They wrote the same to us, too!
Our fortunes are growing! That's
what my aunt wrote to us!
By the time Christmas arrives again,
you'll have so much money you won't
even know what to do with it!
Ahaha! That's our smallest problem!
Money is very easy to spend!
That's right! Very easy!
Especially is somebody likes
to go the pub!
(in German) Bloody idiot. I told you a thousand times...
(in German) What are you doing down there with the critters.
(in German) I'll whack you good you fool.
Back home, in my childhood,
I used to go to school barefoot
as early as March!
But here, the ground is still cold
and wet!
And there are no birds either!
They should have at least skylarks!
Back home, in the old days, one could
always find skylarks at least, if nothing else!
Skylarks? Skylarks!
Skylarks!
(in German) ...on.
(in German) Don't linger! Go on.
(in German) The other side, forward march!
(in German) Sergeant, come over here.
(in German) Now come with me.
(in German) Come on now.
(in German) Halt!
Polish
- (in German) You are welcome...
- Back off.
(in German) 16 women into the last room.
Polish
(in German) 24 into this one.
(in German) and the rest into the one back there.
Polish.
- (in German) Now go on!
Polish
For the children! Kind!
Bring this one back!
Bring it back! This one!
Polish
(in German) Here in this room. Into there.
Andras!
Polack cigarettes!
Filled with tasty tobacco for gentlemen!
I'm coming soon!
They shot somebody! It must have been
a Frenchman!
Or a Polack! He probably tried to escape.
Open the window, Andras! Maybe we
can see something!
There is no need for you in here today!
This is what Brayner told me. Word-by-word!
But why? And he also sent the woman
to work on the beet-field!
- Why do you think he did that?
- How would I know?
You hear me, Dani? Have you
seen the carter this morning?
- No.
- That's just it. 'cos me neither!
Something is not OK here!
Come on, Lisie! Let's keep on!
Nobody seen him!
Who the heck understands this?
God only knows where he might be!
Last evening, when they were shooting!
I wonder if it was...
We can't know that for sure!
And stop talking now!
Stop talking about that now!
Keep quiet!
God bless, folks!
You're going well! If goes on like this,
the harvest will be much better
than last year.
And everything goes well, the women
will finish working on the root-field, too!
The Master noticed that you are
interested in music, Abris!
And said you can go in to his room
if you want to listen to some music.
- You just have to tell me before that!
- Thank you very much.
We haven't seen the carter today, Mr. Brayner!
And he is usually here by now.
- Bringing us some water...
- There is no need to continue, Fabian!
I wouldn't ask such questions if I were you!
Not from me, nor anybody else! I wouldn't
even mention the carter's name actually!
I suppose you didn't come here
only to be sent home!
Listen to me, Brayner! How dare you?
If I would grab you...
- No! No!
- Andras!
- Why do you care so much about the carter?
- Sit down!
Care or not care!
It's not about that! But he should
talk to us with respect!
Mr. Brayner!
We're among each other.
And you just started to threaten.
We asked you about the carter
respectfully.
And you can only threaten as an answer?
I'm sorry. It wasn't my intention.
But you came here to work.
Not for sightseeing!
You're paid good money for
your work!
So, concentrate on that, and on nothing else!
And for your own sake, it's better if you
just close your eyes even now!
Good Lord!
(in German) Deal with the 2 back there.
SUMMER
Ilonka! Ilonka! German
(in German) Come! Quick! Come quick! Quick....
(in German) [unintelligible]
German
Polish
Dear God! He won't live to
see the morning!
I'll be back soon!
Ilona! Ilona!
Polish
Come, quickly!
(in German) Come!
(in German) ...quick! Quick!
You must! You must!
German
Polish
He's dying! Dying!
German
Polish
That's it! This will bring
down the fever!
It will help, you'll see!
I've a son like you, too!
I've two...
- Two? - I've!
- German
Polish
How could you come up with that?
- No!
- Polish
- You want to give that to me?
- You need it much better!
- Polish
- I've one upstairs!
- You need it, too!
Polish
- Polish
- Well, thank you. Thank you.
- Folks! Here is the...
- Polish
- That's enough!
- Enough while we're here!
- Polish
They made the Polack women
pack their things!
They are taking them away!
It's Brayner and two
military trucks!
The soil too wet.
There'll be no hoeing here,
not even in the afternoon!
There is water between the lines still!
Well, then there's no point waiting here,
let's go back to the Farm!
- What's with the boy?
- It seems like he's covering up.
He said he can come with tomorrow.
They tired. They were all up last night
during that war in the sky!
Would you believe that? Water!
A bit of Palinka would turn into
blood in me now!
Not even I would spit it out this time!
Palinka is a medicine!
It was the carter who gave us Palinka
the last time, on the very first day!
- Do you remember, Dani?
- Uhum! Very much!
I very much remember it, because
that was the last time as well!
I wonder where the carter is now?
That poor fool smells very bad
by now!
- What kinda bird is this?
- Some kinda crow.
First time I see a bird ever since
I got here.
There are not even skylarks here.
So! Let's some some gentlemen's
cigarettes!
What kind of cigarettes? Oooh! There's
no point wasting it on us!
This really is gentlemen's cigarettes!
This cigarette refreshes me!
Me too. I feel like something
is stirring in me!
I feel like I could do
a thing-or-two!
- Like what?
- Well, for example, if...
no better things show up, I'd wrestle with you,
and push you to the ground!
- You really feel like you would?
- Right!
Then you just wait until I'll feel like it too!
You!
'this good! Like a horn!
Or like an elder-whistle!
- You, Elek!
- What?
- Can you blow that in tune with me?
- How on Earth could I not?
Well, then play with me that...
This roundshaped sky when it goes dark,
it lights up!
A little bench in front of our house,
don't sit on it!
Or if you sit on it, be careful
not to fall!
You used to be my lover, but
I don't need you anymore!
Dani has a good voice still!
That's true. That he has!
- So far it was good... This day, I mean.
- Good-good. That's right.
So far it was the best among them all!
The Master and Brayner are not at home.
It seems like they'll only be back in the evening.
Abris had a bad dream!
Tell us about it, it will relieve you!
I dreamt about colours. Many colours!
Red, blue... and pure white as snow.
What was white?
Only the ending was white! At the end...
We're listening to you from
the beginning till the end.
It started with me getting lost,
at first we were all inside,
but then all of a sudden, I was
left alone in a big forest.
And this forest seemed to have
neither a beginning nor an end.
I was just wandering around in it.
I was wandering in it for days,
and the interesting part was that
I never seemed to get tired.
My legs were light.
When I looked up on the sky, the
Sun was always right above my head.
And because of that everything
seemed much whiter.
And then there was that great
silence!
Whenever I yelled, my voice reverberated
from the distance!
Magyars! Magyars!
Where are you?
I'm looking for the Magyars!
Magyars! Answer me!
Magyars! Why don't you answer me?
Hallo!
Magyars!
I'm looking for the Magyars, uncle!
You're at the right place then, son.
'Cos I'm the very last one of them.
The last Magyar.
Look at me carefully! You won't find
another Magyar in the world anymore, but me.
There are endless waters beyond the forest.
You won't find any Magyars there either!
You're lying! This is not true! After all
I'm a Magyar, too!
There's got to be more Magyars still!
Of course there are!
Like, Kisdebi, and Andras Fabian!
And Daniel Gaspar!
Magyars! Where are you, Magyars?
Magyars! Where are you?
Magyars!
The Master's son might return home
on a leave from the army.
This is his room. It's been closed
for years.
So, this what you are supposed to
clean up.
The Master would like to offer
you some beer.
Come! We can drink some good beer now!
That doesn't sound bad!
- The Master says, 'to your health!'
- To all of us!
To our health!
German
The Master says, in his son's name as well.
You did a very nice, very good work
today, folks.
Tell it to the women as well.
Except that all this work was
in vain already.
Because the Master's son got lost.
I was already told about it
in town.
- But he can still return.
- Look, Mr. Fabian!
Whenever somebody gets lost in war,
he never returns home.
And the Master's son got lost in Russia.
I'll count in your day as usual.
You did a good job.
I'll count it as if you were
hoeing.
- Thank you, Mr. Brayner!
- Thank you very much.
- Have a good rest!
- Good night!
Could you help me, Mr. Brayner?
- In what?
- I'd like to buy a bicycle.
For my brother. We left the kid
with him. He looks after him.
I'd like to send him a steel-framed
bicycle.
We're going to town with the Master
next week. Whoever feels like may
come with us.
You can buy it then!
But why haven't you got married?
- 'Cos I didn't feel like...
- Why?
Poor folks should never get
married!
Because when poverty grabs its own hand,
it gives way to a much greater poverty!
But then are we just supposed to kick
the bucket, only because we're poor?
I thought about this myself, too.
And if I wouldn't be such a curious man by
nature, surely I'd be smelling the flowers
from down below by now!
What are you curious about?
Myself. And the world around me.
I always wonder about that even though
the days seem to be the same,
people's lives are different every day.
What's the reason behind that?
What kind of machinery is hidden in humans?
When two people start talking
to each other,
they can tell everything about themselves,
but still!
None of them will actually find out
what's the other's biggest problem!
There is a chasm so great between
people
like the distance between
heaven and earth.
Have you heard that we're
going to Paris next week?
To Paris? To the sea, perhaps?
There as well! Brayner told me
last time he came in here!
Just before they took away
the Polack women.
And he said that whoever wants
might come with us!
- Well, I wouldn't mind to go!
- Me neither! If only I'd get better by then!
Brayner said we could even
go to a church there!
I'd even do my confessions
if that's possible!
Of course, you want to do your confessions.
After all the priests speak Hungarian
around here!
You too smart, Aunt Zsofi!
But if you'd really be that smart, you
should know that one cannot live without God!
That's for sure!
But if you wish to do your confessions,
you must talk to Brayner as well, no doubt!
And make sure you thoroughly discuss your sins
with him!
Otherwise the priest might misunderstand!
Careful, Aunt Zsofi! One is not
supposed to make jokes about God!
Stop! Stop, will you!
- Mr. Brayner! It's Sunday,
Goddamn you! - Let him!
So what? If it's Sunday, it's Sunday!
Is that why you had to stop the truck?
Because I can't buy anything today!
All the shops are closed!
I told you! I want a bicycle!
They're expecting it back home!
I want that bicycle!
You be careful, because if there will be none,
God have mercy on you! You hear me?
What do you want, man? We'll still be
in town tomorrow morning!
Then you can buy as many bicycles as you wish!
Whoever doesn't want to come, tell me now!
I can still take'em back!
Look, Uncle Daniel!
This castle has so many towers,
that I haven't seen this many, not even
on churches!
- This must be a rich country!
- Right! A rich one!
It seems like one!
German
- German
- Stand up!
German
Holy Virgin Mary!
Holy Mother of our Lord, Jesus.
Guardian Angel of the Hungarians!
We pray to you, help us!
Help us to get back home safely from here!
Help me to be able to meet my mother still
when I arrive back home! Help me!
Grant me strength to be able to work
and to put an end to our poverty!
Help us, Virgin Mary!
My spine shivers! Strength deserts my arms.
But give me endurance to be able
to raise up my little children.
Help us, Virgin Mary!
I'll express my gratitude to the Maria
in Pocs when I return home!
Help me until then, Virgin Mary!
Guardian Angel of the Hungarians!
Help us, my Lord!
Great God!
Help me to be able to thank
the graceful support of the Holy Virgin!
And your mercy, for keeping
us in good health!
And for preserving our strength!
And helping us raise our children!
To your Glory! May it be so, My lord!
The river! There's the river!
- Aha!
- Good Lord! My wife!
Rozika! Rozika!
Dani! To the tree!
Her heart! Her heart must be
massaged!
Such a heat came over me.
But I already feel much better.
- Where is the Master, Mr. Brayner?
- He left. He's got some business elsewhere.
We'll only meet up with him in the morning.
I need to leave now as well.
I got to take care of something.
Get back on the car!
I wouldn't mind if you'd hurry
up a bit!
I'll take you to the river.
You can wait for me there.
But don't wander off from there,
because then we won't be able
to find each other!
Mr. Brayner! Where are we
going to sleep?
On the truck! There is
enough space!
That much is true. There is
enough space for us there.
Just like the river Tisza!
What river is this, I wonder?
- It's called Seine.
- How do you know that?
From school. We learned about this.
Main in Frankfurt, Rhine in Strassbourg,
and Seine in Paris.
It's hard to forget that!
Such valiant soldiers!
They are marching as if some
machinery is moving their legs!
You just don't envy them so much!
You can still be a soldier again!
The Master is a good man, after all!
He took us to Paris, to the
Church of Our Lady!
And now, to the beach! Nobody else
would have done that!
Your face is on fire, boy!
- You've got the fever!
- Nothing's wrong with me! I feel just fine!
It was a pity to come here! It will soon
be raining!
Let's not despair now,
that we're here!
Let's rejoice that we're here!
Ilonka! Zsofi! Rozi! Irma! Come!
You won't see something like this
ever again!
Water without end! You've never
seen such a thing before! Come!
If the weather would be better,
we could even have a swim!
Well, that's just the kind of thing
we're missing...
What are you doing, Abri?
Stop there, will you!
- You're not my father to give orders to me!
- You're sick, you unfortunate!
I am not an unfortunate!
Just because I'm younger than you,
I'm not an unfortunate at all!
Daniel!
Here, put it on! This water
would make you sick!
Daniel is right! You mustn't
go into the water in this cold!
Well, it's raining already!
There is some kind of house there!
Shouldn't we go there?
Of course, we should! Everybody
go up there!
I'll bring up the truck!
Come!
Nobody must go in!
- What? Is there something wrong?
- Nothing wrong, but there is no need
to go in!
Why can't we go in there?
Hell knows!
What is it? Is the door closed?
- Why don't you enter, Daniel?
- With all you respect, there is somebody in there.
German
Who is that who stops us from
getting in?
It seems like he won't be able
to harm us anymore!
Don't kid with me, please! If you're
seeing a dead man, just say it!
- Anything can happen in war!
- Well, this one is certainly dead.
He is just sitting by the window. One
would think he's just asleep.
But no. This one is not asleep.
This one is dead for sure!
God Allmighty!
What are we waiting for?
Let's go in, until it stops!
Don't! You, godless! Next to
a dead man?
- Ah! Ah! Ah!
- Dear God! The bicycle!
Let's go back to the truck!
Brings some branches! And a tilt!
Hide underneath!
Give me the end of the tilt, Andras!
Hide underneath, quickly!
German
What does it mean, I wonder?
Surely some kind of prayer.
The wrapping on it is
soaking wet.
Which sea was that?
I've been thinking about that too.
It must have been the icy Northern Sea!
- It could only be that!
- What? There was no ice there at all!
So what? A sea is a sea!
Let's sleep!
A steel-framed bicycle! By God,
I haven't even heard of such a thing!
Where did you get the idea from?
We're under a curse! The entire village!
Because it was built over a graveyard!
Do you hear the bells?
Magyars rest here all around!
And His Lordship, the Baron expects you
to drive fast and don't just stand there!
Do you hear me? Balint Fabian!
- Do you understand, or not?
- Yes, Sir, I do understand!
Let's move it, then! These
are all Lenin-boys here!
Drive so fast that'd spit out
their own guts!
Go!
I knew them since their childhood.
If this is what they deserve
then what do I deserve, I wonder?
I had to kill people during the war,
people I didn't even know.
Who never hurt neither me,
nor my family.
When the sergeant gave
this to me, he said,
Nothing can stop this.
It pierces through even the bones.
That's what he said.
That Italian comes to my mind
quite often these days.
I can still feel the warmth of his blood
between my fingers.
It was my face he carried with him
into death.
My face was the last one
he could ever see in life.
It wasn't his children's or his wife's.
But mine.
- What's your father, Fabian?
- With all due respect, a farmer.
But he wasn't always that.
He used to be the Parade carter
of his Lordship, Baron Ugry
- back in '19.
- There is a big problem, Fabian!
Your father died, my son!
He hanged himself on the
bellrope.
You've got a five-days leave.
Five days from now
you report back to us saying
that you respectfully buried your father!
- Is that understood?
- Yes Sir! Understood! With all due respect!
Here rests Balint Fabian,
Aged 43 years.
He lived in happy marriage with Anna
Szabo for 27 years. He died in 1922.
Rest in Peace.
AUTUMN
Move aside! I'll pick your line too!
French
I said, move aside! Leave these two
lines for me!
French
Look at that frenchman! He must
be some gentleman of sort.
He's got long, slender fingers.
Save your strength, Ilonka!
- A long day is ahead of us!
- That's just right! But if he hurry up today,
we can make as much money in one day,
than at other times in a week!
Brayner said he'll calculate according to the
number of the bins! He did say that!
They're not given any food!
Well, not much. They say
that at the next farm the Russians are
only given food once every day.
Raw potatoes.
- Only once? - Only once. Brayner
told me.
God curse them al!
Grab the bacon, Ilonka!
Bacon and potatoes.
I brought them for you.
- Eat it
- Mercy.
French
How are they supposed to work like that?
Hungry?
They are given food in the morning
and in the evening.
Nowhere else in this country are
prisoners kept so well as here.
And all that because of the Master.
You can believe me.
By the way, that thin-faced frenchman
told me
that he has never seen a women work
as hard as you do, Mrs. Fabian!
Why is a cross hanging in his neck?
Is he that religious perhaps?
Quite some. That frenchman is a priest.
??? Jean-Pierre Derion ???
- That's his name.
- A priest?
- How could they do this to a priest?
- Dear God! Even a priest?
Gaspar! The Master is looking for
Abris Kontor!
It was me, who told him to stay at home.
He hardly slept anything last night. He
had a fever. And a bad cough.
German
The kid very much looks like
the Master's son.
He had a similar child-face. Nobody
wanted to believe that he's a doctor.
By now even the Master knows
that he disappeared.
He was notified.
Duck! Into the ditch!
German
- What is he saying?
- Well, that it's over.
- What is?
- Everything.
The war, he himself, the Germans.
So, it's all over.
Well, yes. If they wouldn't have
teamed up with the Hungarians,
they wouldn't get defeated now.
- How come?
- Because the nations just don't seem
to learn it for once and for all
that it doesn't worth to befriend
the Hungarians.
After all, when did the Hungarians
ever win? In which battle? Where?
The Hungarians never won anywhere.
Unless,
back in the days of our forefather, Chief Arpad.
What? If the Germans lose the war,
- it will be because of the Hungarians?
- I didn't say that.
I only said that whoever befriended
the Hungarians in the past,
was always squashed.
I mean, always. Just remember back.
Always! Alongside the Hungarians.
German
30, 35, 40, 45,
50, 55, 59.
Today's results are as follows:
The Kiss - 54,
the Fabians - 70, the Tars - 47,
the Szabos - 59 bins.
How did you say, Mr. Brayner,
how many bins for me and my husband?
70.
Well, I beg your pardon! Are you sure
you counted them right?
How dare you accuse me of
such thing?
Who are you? You cannot even count till two
and you dare to question me?
I'm the farm manager, if you forgot
about that!
The fucking whore of a mother of yours,
you, farm manager!
How dare you talk to me like this here?
If I tell about this to the Master he'll
kick you out of this place in not time!
I'll dug out our eyes!
- You dirty scum!
- No!
- What are you doing?
- Diry scum!
You mustn't do this! You hear me? Come here!
Your... your mistake, Mr. Brayner is
that you didn't count these!
Because those were picked by
the French!
Who picked those?
You turd! You dirty turd!
- Ilonka! This isn't nice!
- Bastard!
Bastard!
Mr. Brayner! I saw it, and I can
testify
that these bins were brought here
by Andras Fabian!
The two of you might be having an
agreement! I don't have to believe you!
German
But I put a sign on all my bins!
There is a potato stem on the
top of all my bins!
Here! Here is the potato stem!
It's mine! Here! Here! Here,
it's mine! You can see!
I'm not lying! Nobody among us
would lie to you
because of a wretched bin!
German
Don't cry, Ilonka!
Calm down!
You were smart to put
a sign on the bins!
You're a smart woman!
German
Anything happened, Mr. Brayner?
Forgive me. I was wrong.
I'll fix the numbers accordingly,
Mrs. Fabian. I'm sorry.
But this kid brought some very bad news.
I don't even know how to put it.
The Master sent word that Abris Kontor
just died.
It must be burned.
He must be buried as soon as possible,
to avoid an epidemic.
What's wrong with you, Brayner? He just
died an hour ago, and you're already
hurrying us?
Go out, everybody! I'll wash the dead.
Alone.
I do it alone back home as well.
And then he'll need a coffin.
German
Mr. Brayner! He'll need a coffin.
I heard. I just have no idea
where to get one.
A coffin, nowadays? Wouldn't
a bin be good instead?
A bin? Fuck your mother, you lousy
bastard! A bin?
No coffin! No bells! No priest!
'cos everything's good for a Magyar?
Everything's good for a poor man?
Sound the bells, by the love of God,
I'm telling you!
Is it the Magyars everybody wants
to play tricks with?
Is it the Magyars everbody are after?
Do you really think... that even bin is
good enough for us?
You're right. Everybody are after us.
I wonder why do they like
us so much?
All-in-all, he need a decent
burial.
The Master.
His wife lays there.
She died last year.
I'll go there and clean it a little.
Don't you have a family, Mr. Brayner?
I do. In America. They went there
2 years ago.
I've already been working here back then.
It was very hard for them to achieve that.
- Why don't you go after them?
- From here? Now?
Germany is at war with America.
With them as well? The French here
next to us,
beyond Hungary the Russians, and
America as well?
It's a lot even just to enumerate them! Not
to mention fighting them all!
Thank you.
I'd like to ask something from you, Mr. Brayner.
- What?
- There is a picture in my room.
A picture of a saint. I'd like to take it with
me if I may.
- Why do you need that?
- I'd like to take it home, if I may.
All right, Mrs. Fabian. We'll have a
look at that picture.
The Master should be told about
the burial.
Why?
Because we've already decided
about it.
That frenchmen will be the priest. That Lyon.
... or whatever he's called.
Latin
Lord, thou hast been
our dwelling place,
In all
generations.
Before
the mountains were
brought forth.
Or ever thou hadst formed
the earth and the world,
Even from everlasting
to everlasting,
thou art God.
And will be that
at all times.
It's still some time until
we finish the harvest.
How much longer? Like a month?
One and a half at most. What's that?
Nothing.
Now I'm certain that I'm pregnant.
That's why I fainted at the chuch.
There, in that big city.
Be happy for that! You go home now,
and raise them all.
At least you've got some money now.
My brother-in-law wrote again.
He got the steel-framed bicycle.
He even settled the advance payment
for the house!
We'll have some animals too.
Hopefully we'll live much easier from now on.
And perhaps we might even go to the carnival
once with Andras. I mean, if there will be any.
Never in my whole life have I ever danced.
Except on my wedding.
Only once? You see, I haven't danced not
even once!
And as it is, I probably never will!
The Master wanted to talk to you
about this long ago.
It's about that he suggests you
to stay here.
Whoever wants. You'll be given some land,
and a house.
And everybody can be his own Master.
German
You'll feel welcomed here. He says.
- They're waiting for us back home?
- Who's waiting for you?
They are... Relatives, friends.
Anyway, I lived my whole life there.
That's where I'm at home.
So, I, for my part, don't
want to stay here.
Don't annoy that dog all the time,
Bandi!
Don't you hear that?
This is the 424, Bandi! Hear that?
Why are you telling me this is
the 424?
Andras! Andras!
Aunt Zsofi! Uncle Daniel!
You're here at last! Welcome back!
You're here at last!
Let me help! Let me carry something as well!
You're here! Andras! Andras! Andras!
Ah, you're back! You're here at last!
You're back!
The 'Americanas' are coming!
There!
The 'Americanas' are here!
The 'Americanas' have returned!
Aunt Zsuzska! They're here!
You hear me?
How can you have such
long steps, Andras?
Folks are amazed how long
you can step!
- It's almost like a miracle!
- Man must go fast! He must!
- Was he a German soldier?
- Yes.
A child-soldier.
And... and how old was that
German soldier?
Well, about 17 or
even younger. They are all just children,
just as poor Abris was. God rest him.
Cheers!
They're conscripting everybody here as well.
Even the young ones.
The village is empty. Only women, children
and old ones. Nobody else is left.
God grant you a good evening!
So, here you are!
Well, you're back then!
- As you can see.
- I see.
Well, lads. You must sign these.
- We must?
- Andras Fabian, Dani Kiss,
and Elek Tar. An immediate draft.
You must go immediately. But...
you can stay here for the night at least.
Somebody take the child to
his mother.
There is no need for me to go home
for such a short time.
All right, all right! Enough of this!
Don't cry, Rozika! This will soon
be over. It's already over, anyway!
You'll see, one or two months only, and
Dani will be back home!
They can't bring them out!
The train is here soon!
They're coming!
Well, This roundshaped sky when
it goes dark, it lights up!
This is not the one to sing now, Dani!
This is what my father sang
in '14, in the first war...
Oh, Magyar, keep immovably
your native country's trust,
for it has borne you, and at death
will consecrate your dust!
No other spot in all the world
can touch your heart as home
let fortune bless or fortune curse,
from hence you shall not roam!
After all we're Hungarian soldiers already,
I was told!
That's right! Hungarian soldiers!
Rozika!
- Don't be afraid, the war will be over soon!
- God bless you!
Stop crying!
You've always been a good wife, Irma!
Come, will you! Come up!
God be with you, Rozika!
Take care of yourself!
- Where is my big coat?
- Up in the wagon! - Move!
Here it is, indeed!
Dani! Dani! Where are you?
Take care of yourself! Andras!
- Irma! - Here they are!
- Rozika! God be with you!
Based on a novel by