Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Civilization wouldn't
end with nuclear fire.
It'd be tattered and torn
by the likes of disease.
One that could mutate rapidly.
The greatest minds in the
world couldn't understand it.
And therefore, it took over.
Chaos followed.
But the disease
just didn't stop at death, no.
Those who survived it became
something entirely different.
Aggressive,
almost indestructible.
Cannibalistic. Mutants.
We began to call them hunters.
Every once in a while,
I find something out in the wild.
Something unexpected, useful.
Sometimes I even find things
that remind me of a time
that was a hell of a lot
better than right now.
Sometimes I wonder,
you know, bringing something
back to the camp
is better than nothing, right?
It's definitely better than
not returning at all.
Days are long
and the terrain is tough,
but it keeps the monsters
at bay for now.
This is John Wrecker,
Trace Operative, Station 222.
The world we knew is gone.
Pacifica has become a land
of death and despair.
Every day, we fight to
survive this new nightmare,
to survive each other.
Dangerous creatures
now roam the island,
born out of the apocalypse.
They hunt us
from station to station.
And I do the same to them.
They're evolving,
becoming more dangerous.
And therefore, so must I.
When I'm out here by myself,
I start understanding
these creatures more and more.
I start noticing patterns.
I start realizing
their tendencies.
They're starting to become
more predictable.
My biggest fear, though,
is that I am too.
Sleep is a luxury.
But I know
I'm gonna grind it out.
I think of my father
and my father always wanted me
in those corners,
grinding it out.
I'm just praying to
whatever gods are up there
that maybe let the hope
shine in a bit first.
Hey, John.
Didn't see you come in.
No, I don't suppose
you did there, Lewis, did ya?
You get one?
Yes, sir.
I found
their little feeding area,
just outside of
that point right there.
What'd it take
to bring her down?
A little too much C-4.
Anything left of 'em?
Got the usual bits and pieces.
Copy that.
Did you hear any chatter
on the wire lately?
Yeah, 221.
They had a couple of refugees
come down with a fever.
A lot of them didn't make it.
Shame.
John, that looks pretty rough.
Go get changed. Go see Grace.
She'll bandage you up.
Yeah.
Going out again soon?
Yeah, in the morning.
Anything I can get for you?
Besides a bit of shuteye?
I need more grenades.
Copy that.
We're running pretty low.
Well then I guess I'll have to
use them sparingly.
And some more C-4, please.
Oh, John, John, hang on.
I almost forgot.
Got you all fixed up.
Replaced the Lithium reactor,
managed to weld some of
the plates back together,
and we fixed the comm unit.
Should be pretty good to go now.
No worries.
Should give you
a tactical advantage.
Let's hope so.
All these people, my people.
I walk by,
they're huddled in the camp.
They're looking for warmth.
They're looking for food.
They're looking for supplies.
Anything that can help them
get by each day,
each hour, each minute.
John.
Sergeant Wrecker.
Ah, the war,
it's been over for years.
I'm pretty sure
we could lose the formalities.
If you say so.
What can I do for you?
Lewis thought that I might need
a bit of a seeing to on...
Take a seat in my chair.
Thank you.
Not too deep.
Let me grab some gauze.
Was it a scab?
No.
Was it close?
Close enough.
You know, John,
their cells aren't like ours.
What?
The scabs, their cells,
after the infection takes over,
it mutates the cells.
You're telling me these
creatures don't feel any pain?
That's correct.
It starts on the frontal lobe
of the brain.
- What do you mean?
- The brain starts
to disintegrate.
I've done a lot of research,
uh, motor skills,
judgment, social skills,
they're all shot.
Yeah, but these things they...
they communicate
with each other.
Yes, they do.
- And?
- The cells mutate.
Bone density, it grows slightly.
Then the heart,
it goes to a crawl.
After several days
of rapid mutation,
that's when the lights go on.
Rapid movement agitates them.
Motor function
now increases dramatically.
As does hunger.
Yeah. Um...
What am I telling you
all this for?
You already know it already.
I guess it's just a lot...
it's a lot better hearing it
from somebody like you.
I do imagine a lot, by the way.
What do you imagine?
Oh.
Uh, I... I know you're going
back out on patrol again soon.
So get some rest.
Get some food in ya.
And be safe.
I just found this incredible,
uh, reading material
when I was...
and, uh... it's new words. Uh...
It is a base... it's baseball.
- Baseball?
- Mm-hmm.
I love baseball.
I remember baseball.
I'm gonna, ah...
Oh, I...
Okay.
I got some tests to do.
Right. I'll...
Okay.
I'm not looking
to mess up anybody's day.
All right?
Hey, guys.
I'm not looking for any trouble.
Put the guns down.
Bastard!
Don't waste the ammo.
John? John?
John? John? John? John?
Wake up. Wake up, John.
- What's going on?
- We need you.
Yeah.
Okay.
Hey guys.
Go ahead, Lewis.
Tell him what you heard.
Scanning through the channels
like I always do.
And I came across
this communication.
Could barely make it out,
and I...
You know, it's just
better if I play it for you.
I repeat, we're under attack!
Something, scabs,
they're here!
They must have followed a
scouting party back to our camp.
If there are any trace operatives
in the immediate vicinity,
we need help!
Did you try
getting back to these guys?
John, I've tried every channel.
Every open line
of communication.
I've just got static.
Breakwater Creek.
Breakwater Creek. Why do
I know Breakwater Creek?
Isn't that... isn't that
the old fifth well station?
We used to trade plants
and spring water
with them a while back.
Okay.
John.
What, you don't want
me going out now?
I just don't understand
why another operative can't go.
'Cause I'm pretty sure
we don't have any around.
John to Lewis.
Lewis? John, do you read me?
Lock the bunker down.
No one leaves.
I'm on my way back.
Lewis, do you read?
Lewis, I'm staring at
a trace map right now.
And if these things didn't know
where we lived before,
they sure as hell do right now.
I'm on my way back. Over.
What's this?
Hi, John.
It looks like a bladed weapon
of some sort.
A bladed weapon of some sort?
Are you kidding me?
I've never seen anything
handcrafted like that before
in all my tracing days.
Where'd you...
where'd you find it?
Are you kidding me?
Ye... yeah, where'd you find it?
Where did I find...? I found that
at a marauder camp.
These scabs are
making their own weapons.
They're crafting
their own fucking weapons.
I haven't heard any chatter
on the radio about this.
I haven't heard anything
from any other camps.
That's your job.
That's exactly what you should be doing.
You should be on the radio.
You should know these things.
I'm going out there.
I'm naked. I have no idea.
And yet these scabs
are out there now creating,
crafting their own weaponry.
You're supposed to be
on top of this!
I'm going out there.
I'm risking my life.
I'm risking the lives of
everybody here in this bunker.
And that's what I gotta
go out and find?
What are you worried about
bladed weapons for?
You got guns and explosives
and all sorts of technology.
They're making it on their own!
I mean, how do you know it was
the scabs and not the marauders?
You said it yourself,
you found it in a marauder camp.
I don't know.
I'm going out there.
This is your job.
You need to be on that thing.
That is what you do.
I mean, there has been
some chatter on the radio
of some refugees gone missing
past couple of weeks.
I mean, that...
that does seem to connect,
to make a little bit of sense.
Lewis, goddammit,
they're handcrafting weaponry!
They're evolving!
Can you imagine if they get their hands
on guns and explosives?
- Jesus.
- No.
No.
This, you, me,
everything we're doing,
the whole bunker,
done and dusted.
I... this bunker is done!
These lives that
we're trying to protect
are for naught!
John, how long
have you been out there?
Three days!
John, you look like shit.
You need some rest.
You're no good to us dead.
You do your job, John.
Protect us.
You wear the colors.
You wear the armor.
You must know the words.
Convince me you're not a thief
who just stole
some soldier's uniform.
I'm John T Wrecker.
Identification number 00324.
This is my quadrant.
This is my sector.
I trained
in the Anchorage facility.
John T Wrecker. 00324.
This is my quadrant.
This is my sector.
And how long
you been hunting for?
I don't know.
None of us do.
You don't wanna go in there.
Well there's problems
to the north,
as I'm sure you've heard.
Thanks.
Yeah, I've heard.
A lot of missing people.
Is that what brings you
around this way?
Yeah, for the most part.
Plus there's been shortages
of ammunition
for quite some time.
Pretty sure that's been
a problem for us,
for everyone, everywhere,
for quite some time.
So what's your situation
down in this sector?
I'm starting to notice
the scabs are fewer
and farther between.
Well, that's different
from my experiences.
- Pardon?
- Scabs, I've...
I've seen them migrate
a little bit more.
Migrate?
- Like a herd?
- Something like that.
That makes sense.
Go on.
There's something new out there,
from what I gather.
Yeah, there's been
a few instances
where I've run into
some survivors who...
who've been to camps
with missing people
and in the way those camps
have been...
attacked is...
It's different.
Yeah. I'm starting
to notice that too.
How do you mean?
I'm checking out these camps
and there are no bodies
to be found.
There's no way that one of
these creatures, these monsters,
whatever you wanna call it,
these scabs,
there's no way that
they can do that by themselves.
These things
are next to invincible.
You can barely kill 'em.
And now I'm starting
to think they're not
working alone anymore.
And I'm thinking if we can get
a group of people together,
prepare them properly,
that we can all work together
and we can take them out.
- No.
- Yes.
We need your help.
I need your help.
No.
- Yes.
- No.
Why not? We need help.
We need to work together.
We have to bring everybody,
side-by-side
and start picking them off
like they're picking us off.
- It could work. Yes.
- No.
- Why not?
- Because.
- Because what?
- Because you know.
You know we're depleted,
you know we have no ammunitions.
Why do you think
I'm walking around here?
I lost my entire camp.
And you think that
you can just kill all these?
With what? What do you have?
Three clips?
How many clips do you have?
- How many clips?
- Three.
- You have three clips?
- I have three clips.
You have three clips.
They've told you.
We've ran out of soldiers.
We have no supplies.
We have no ammunitions.
What do you expect?
I'm expecting to do something.
It's not gonna wor...
I'm not gonna sit around here
and just die.
Well, it's not gonna work. Okay?
So do me a favor,
pack your shit,
and when I come back, be gone.
Understand?
Yeah, I understand.
John.
I was just about to call you.
I'm just happy
to be counted, sir.
It's easy to think
you've been forgotten
when you're left out here in
this pretty piece of the world.
Oh, no. Quite the contrary.
There's a lot of activity
going on
in your neck of the woods.
I just received
a video transmission
that was sent over six days ago.
Yes. 227.
And what's the status
on that, General?
Yeah, they've been dark
for over 24 hours.
They've been dark?
We can assume
they've been overrun.
Give me a sit rep, John.
What's the climate like
over in your quadrant?
Pretty typical
until a few days ago.
Some scavenging scabs,
poaching refugees, marauders.
I tracked them.
I took care of it.
And then you know what happened?
And then you saw
this new breed, huh?
Yeah, I did.
Scabs have always been tough.
Their biological makeup
stresses their cells
and nerve endings,
but we've always known
and dealt with the fact
that they're hard to kill,
but this new breed
is much more... trying.
How many trace operatives
have we lost recently, sir?
Look, John,
you know as well as I do
that our numbers
are dwindling.
Especially since the Red Road
rose up back east
and started their own
personal war over territory.
They've actually conquered
quite a bit
but we can't fight two wars
at once.
Sir, how many?
I've got 16 operatives left
on the entire
western seaboard.
These new scabs,
they've been watching us,
waiting, it would appear.
Still primitive
in their fashion
of using bladed weaponry,
but they're communicating,
coordinating attacks.
They've killed over 50
operatives in the last 10 days.
Who knows how many refugees?
Hundreds,
maybe even a thousand.
Well, I have reason to believe we
have two of those scabs out here,
and I'm fairly certain
that they know
where our bunker is located.
Then they'll come
for you, John.
What's your inventory like?
Low. Yeah.
Always low.
Although I'm sure
I could fashion together
whatever we needed.
Do a quick MacGyver
if necessary.
Everything else
is peachy though.
We've been working on
something in the lab.
Desperate times call for
desperate measures, right?
I may have something
that could work.
Can you get to an airdrop
if I can manage
to get something to you
within a few miles?
I think anything would help
at this point, sir.
Okay.
I've got one available helo
with enough extra fuel
for a slight detour.
I'll send you the coordinates
through the telecom.
Hell, I'll even throw in
something from the old war
that might help.
I appreciate it.
You'll know
what to do with it.
But John, only take a dose
if you know
you're in for a battle.
You understand
what I'm saying?
Yes, sir.
Look, I can't make
any promises about this stuff,
but it works, then luck's
gonna be on our side.
Good luck, soldier.
After receiving the care
package from General Taylor,
I headed back to camp.
It was refreshing fighting
something more human than not,
but nothing about it felt...
human.
Killing to be able to kill.
I know Grace or... or Lewis would
have something to say about it,
but if they asked me
right now what I thought,
I'd tell 'em
straight to their faces
that I'm glad
it's in our hands now.
Wrecker,
can you hear me? Come in.
Listen, I don't know
if you can talk
but you got to
understand something.
Grace went out
looking for you.
She hasn't come back.
I think she's gone missing.
Hello, John.
I was just given some
information about your post.
Lewis, he's a good soldier.
Anyway, he's a good asset.
Did you get the package?
Everyone is a soldier
at this point.
We're fighting
a losing battle.
And I need to know
if what I gave you works.
Do you understand me?
You've always been one of the
best soldiers in my arsenal.
Humanity needs every man
and woman we can muster.
You understand me?
I see you had no problem
finding me again.
What is it? What's wrong?
I lost something today.
Well, I guess that's something
you're just going
to have to get used to.
Shit.
It was August, or I...
think it was,
I have no fucking clue.
There were two men
in my quadrant.
We lost Miller a few months ago.
Son of a bitch didn't even die
by one of those scumbags,
he had pneumonia,
if you can believe that shit.
Anyway, I was outpost
for a couple of days
and when I got back...
camp was destroyed.
No bodies, no bones.
Just the smell of death
and evidence of slaughter.
Did you go out
and look for anyone?
What difference would that make?
I know they were dead.
Being eaten
off somewhere in the dark.
I failed my mission.
This is
a different type of Hunter.
All right?
They're still animalistic but...
they're starting to remember
that they're human.
They're starting to remember
the English language.
And I'm not talking about
grunts or scribbles.
I'm talking about they're
starting to learn how to write.
Yeah. And I've seen that too.
More than one
is just impossible.
It's impossible.
That's why I have one of these.
'Cause you need
one hell of a punch.
The doctors
wanted a sample of them.
They just don't have
the resources anymore.
So now it's just every man,
woman, and child
fending for themselves.
Some reason I think God
just fucking hates us.
Well, I need your help.
No one else has the training.
No one else knows
how to use the firepower.
Plus maybe...
you and your death wish
wouldn't hurt us.
Now is a chance for you
to redeem yourself.
Whether you want to or not,
you have an obligation
to the oath,
to the people
that you swore to protect,
to get big where others hide
and they get small.
You wear those colors
because you honor those
who came before you.
Honor them by fighting
in their memory,
fighting for the ones
that you swore to protect.
I'm going back to my post.
And if you feel like
completing your mission,
you know where to find me.
You still recording?
Commander is gonna wanna see
these things in CQC.
Keep it rolling, Wrecker.
A limb for a limb.
This is John Wrecker,
Trace Operative, Station 222.
We have disbanded
and I've sent what little survivors
we had left to another outpost.
One where hopefully
they can find safety.
On the orders
of General Taylor,
I was given a serum
and I wanna confirm
that it worked.
No pain and a surge of
adrenaline overtakes the body.
It is my hope and
my belief that this serum
will put us on a level playing
field with those scabs.
I've killed two of 'em,
this new breed,
but I am certain that
there are more out there.
I no longer consider
this outpost my home.
And I believe that
I've found a new purpose,
a new mission,
not to protect just one place
in particular,
but to roam Pacifica
and wage new war
on this new breed of hunter.
This is John T Wrecker
signing off.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull