Husband And Wife
Production: Sanezumi Fujimoto
Script: Toshiro Ide, Yoko Mizuki
Cinematography: Asakazu Nakai
Art direction: So Matsuyama
Cast:
Ken Uehara, Yoko Sugi,
Rentaro Mikuni
Keiju Kobayashi, Mariko Okada
Kamatari Fujiwara, Hisako Takihana, Chieko Nakakita
Direction: Mikio Naruse
Why doesn't she change
her hairstyle?
You should tell her.
She looks so provincial now.
Moreover, as she has no kid
she has time for herself
and she doesn't live
with her in-laws like me.
Life is easy with her.
I wawed like a child.
I have to leave now, my husband
should be home early today
Me too, I have to go.
Well, hurry up.
You're the only who can
come back home late.
Next time, we should meet
at my place!
With pleasure. It was so nice
to see you again.
It had been 5 years
since we met.
You could also rent an apartment.
Whatever, as long as there is no
deposit and the fee is reasonable!
Good evening.
Mr. and Mrs. Hayakawa, I'll pass on
the message right away
Thank you very much for your
consideration.
- Thank you very much.
- Not at all.
Here is his sister Kikuko.
We'll see you at the
engagement party. Goodbye.
Well? You feel relieved,
don't you?
What?
Mr. Hayashi wants some grilled eel.
Be careful. Don't mistake the head
for your thumb when you chop it off!
Have you already decided the
date of the engagement?
The next month.
We haven't heard of Isaku.
Is that normal?
Why don't you contact him?
He should be here soon.
But it's already been
two weeks!
He is probably must have things
to finish up.
At his office?
Yes.
Kikuko, you don't eat?
No, I'm not hungry.
You should go to the public bath
then.
It's not very busy at this hour.
Who'll take care of the shop?
- It's OK.
- He can see through the wall.
Stop it with the chopsticks.
- You will never find a husband.
- I will never marry.
Next time, it's your turn.
We should start looking
for someone.
You should better hurry.
You want to get rid of me.
What kind of man should we look for?
Better a shop owner than an employee.
- Like me!
- No way!
- What's wrong with that?
- I don't want him to spend all day here.
Graduating from the university
is useless.
- Tired of looking for a house?
- No.
She went to see her
school friends, today.
I'm going. See you later.
Thanks for the meal.
What is Isaku doing? He leaves her
looking for the house alone,
and then he comes here once
everything is ready?
One can't trust him.
It's worrying.
Is that not Isaku?
That's him. Go and fetch him.
Isaku has arrived.
- It's been a long time.
- Come in.
You must be tired after that
long trip in train.
Sorry for arriving so late.
Come in!
This neighbourhood has changed a lot,
I didn't recognise the house.
Thank for your consideration.
Welcome.
We are glad that you've been
transferred here.
Thank you. Sorry for causing
so much trouble.
Your family is fine?
Yes, thank you.
My parents are fine.
Really? Your sister-in-law is
settling down on the 1st floor?
That's why we need to find
something before she moves in.
It's difficult.
Mummy, I want an orange.
I want an apple.
- I want a persimmon.
- I want persimmon too.
Keep quiet!
I'm going!
Thank you very much.
Here I am.
- Isaku has arrived.
- Really? What's going on?
What do you mean "what's
going on"?
He came without notice.
He went past the house
without recognising it.
Why didn't you send a wire
to tell me you were coming?
I want some cigarettes and paper.
- Has your company done something?
- About what?
The house. What are you going to do?
Can't you ask them to do something?
My position is not so high.
But we must find something before
my sister-in-law moves in.
It should be all right.
"Kasai Electronics - Tokyo Office"
House mortgage: the sooner you start,
the sooner you own.
You know, after his wife died,
he was so depressed...
I heard it was a love match.
How sweet. You could give
him some relief, couldn't you?
Who are you talking about?
Please, apologize for my absence.
It was the funeral for my wife.
Cheer up. Work should help
changing your mind.
If you want to go in the province,
that will hit your carrier.
I understand.
Please, accept my condolences.
Thank you.
I have been transferred here.
We will work together then.
At the head office...
Mr. Takemura!
Excuse me.
Anyway, it's harder to find a house
than a second wife.
No, not at all.
On the contrary!
I will never find someone
better than my wife.
It's impossible to find a house.
It's not easy.
Life is difficult.
Why don't you rent it to me?
- What?
- Your house?
What? My house?
But I'm living there!
You are by yourself. You could take
a small apartment.
It's not possible!
Or at least, you can rent me
a room.
This house is full of memories
I want to keep it as it is
and spend my days there in silence.
Some more sake, please.
Listen, I'll tell you how
I met her.
You already told me earlier.
She was a good housekeeper.
She came from a small place.
She was in such a good shape.
When she sat down, she could
raise a leg that high...
But, how could I find?
A house...
I'll have a look for you.
Thank you.
It's not much,
but please feel comfortable.
Help yourself.
Mokichi, give some sake.
Our house is not big.
Ours neither. Don't worry.
Congratulations!
The engagement party went fine.
We feel relieved.
Thank you very much.
Mokichi, give them some sake.
Hello. I have some boxes to deliver
for Mr. Nakahara. Is it here?
Already?
What are we going to do?
- How many of them?
- A lot.
It's not all of them, is it?
No. Most of it goes
somewhere else.
What can we do...
OK! Mokichi, clear those place.
You, put the stuff here.
- We'll move them over there.
- Thank you.
Excuse me, where can I
find a toy store?
What is it?
What are you looking for?
A toy store.
- Games!
- Yes.
Games... it's over there.
"Room to let"
We already had three visitors today.
I am not sure if it's still available.
Can you go to granddad and check if
he already has a tenant?
- Please wait here.
- Thank you very much.
- Relax, and take your time.
- Thank you.
- Excuse us for the hustle. Please.
- It's good. Mokichi is engaged.
- Yes, thanks to you.
Kikuko, give another glass
to your uncle.
- Good evening.
- Your stuff has been delivered today.
Good evening.
- This is our family from Fukagawa.
- Good evening. It's been a long time!
I remember your wedding
as if it was yesterday.
Time flies... It's been 4 years,
right?
- It's been 5 years.
- No, 6 years.
You're right.
Such a long time...
Mokichi, congratulations!
- Moving all the stuff, it was hard.
- Really?
- Really hard.
- Thank you so much for your help.
Takemura?
You come to see him?
Is he in?
Mr. Takemura?
- Be careful not to break the door.
- What is it happening to him?
Mr. Takemura?
Are you still sleeping?
Are you already here?
Takemura, come down
and open the door. Hurry!
I'm coming down.
Here they come.
I caught a cold.
Really? Here is my wife.
Thank you very much
for your help.
It's ok.
Come on, get in.
I have to clean the place.
Where should I put this?
Where could you...
Takemura-kun.
Can I put this one upstairs?
Yes, upstairs is fine.
- Let me do it.
- I'll put it in the closet.
- Don't worry.
- Really?
Is that your wife?
Can you help me?
Yes.
What's the matter?
Come on, help yourself.
Really? You don't want
anymore?
No really not, please?
While the odon are warm.
It taste better in good company.
We should thank you for helping us.
Without your help, we don't know
what we would have done.
It's hot.
Mr. Nakahara, don't you feel hot?
No.
It's me then...
Do you have some fever?
You should check.
I am sorry... with fever...
It's OK. A good sleep,
and it will be over!
You shouldn't take cold.
Mr. Takemura is 38ยก2. We are causing
so much trouble. It's worrying me.
We should better call a doctor.
A doctor?
What if he catches pneumonia?
It would be our fault.
I'm going to buy some fresh vegetables.
Mr. Takemura would like some oranges.
Hello.
- Takemura is not coming today?
- No.
- Is he sick?
- No, not really.
You see? I told you.
No, it's me who said that.
Don't argue.
Thank you for waiting.
You shouldn't have bought flowers
for Takemura
What should I do then?
You should buy apples.
We can share them.
Takemura has a lot of success
with women.
Not with me.
Come on in.
Anybody here?
Your wife is not here?
Good evening.
Do we have guests?
Some colleagues: Ms. Fujita and Noda.
They come to see Takemura.
How do you do?
I shaved off his barb. Please,
he's upstairs.
Takemura. Miss Fujita and
Noda came to see you.
Takemura is all dressed up,
it's the right time.
It's difficult to shave the sideburns.
It's always too short on the left
or on the right.
Come on.
His wife is beautiful.
If I give them biscuits,
Takemura will feel ashamed.
Hey?
I thought you were sick,
but you look very well.
Today, I feel much better.
You don't have a picture
of your wife?
Do you have a vase?
I don't have a vase.
You can take a bucket.
No, it's impossible!
Wouldn't you have a vase
by any chance?
- I'll bring one right away.
- Thank you very much.
Takemura, one can think that
you are the tenant.
- Where did I put it?
- What?
The vase.
Good evening.
I brought some firewood.
Just put it there. I'm coming.
Did you find the vase?
I'll fill it with water.
It's a wedding gift.
Here you are.
Nakahara, come with us upstairs.
I should stay downstairs. My wife
has to go out shopping.
It's hard for your wife. So many things
to do upstairs, downstairs.
We have to ask them to stay for
dinner, don't we?
Yes.
I'm going to buy some things
to cook.
This weekend could you
chop wood?
He brought only big log.
That's all he had.
Here you are.
Thank you.
Just one bottle.
I feel today. Your cooking
is very tasty, isn't it?
Yes, you are right,
That's the first time
someone told me.
You're not eating with us?
No.
Come on, eat something.
Life of a married woman
is difficult.
Not at all. The husband has
to work hard all day.
But the wife only
takes care of the house.
When I was working, I liked it.
You were working before?
Yes, at a watch shop in Ginza.
Is it where you met
Mr. Nakahara?
He brought his watch supposedly
to have it repaired.
Many times.
That's not true.
Yes, it's true.
Enough speaking about me.
You should take care of yourself
and find someone.
I would like to fall in love
with someone.
Men are lucky, they can fall in love
several times in their lives.
It's better to look at the
bright side of things
than to stay in remembrance
of his wife.
I think that you've already
found someone.
Here you are. Let's eat!
Mr. Takemura is off sick again.
He had too much fun
yesterday evening
because of this two women
who visited him.
Really. He had a relapse
because of us?
I think he's spoiled and he's taking
advantage of a good-hearted person.
- Who is that?
- Your wife, of course.
I always have my bra on,
even at home.
After two kids, my breast is deformed.
Can you see?
Really?
You are so carefree.
You had children early.
Yes, but my husband think that
I'm not making enough effort.
What? That's funny.
It's not funny. You don't know it yet.
As years goes by, the husband grows
weary with his wife in bed.
What do you mean?
He's weary of making love
to his wife.
Is that what your husband
is thinking?
Generally speaking, all men
are like that.
They don't show it.
The woman doesn't know,
but they want to find
another woman.
It's sad.
But, I can understand.
Well, you don't deny it. It
must ring a bell to you.
It could happen to you, too.
What does a man do
when he goes out?
Only one man in a thousand never
cheat on his wife.
If he has a lot of money like yours,
maybe, but...
No. My husband doesn't
only go with geisha,
but with a girl at his office, too.
They call her his concubine.
- This is strictly between us.
- Of course.
I didn't know he had a mistress.
It's hard.
You're the only one I told about it.
- Don't ever mention it to Ms. Koike.
- Of course.
I can hear noises.
Is this a burglar?
Not at all.
I am sorry, but next time
I'll go with you.
I understand. Sometimes, one is
tired of going out with clients.
Thank you for going with him.
Take us to Yanagibashi.
Tofu.
Takemura!
I'm going.
Wait!
What?
I'm not talking to you.
My belt!
You scared me.
Where's my belt?
You can't find it?
What's the matter?
Where's Takemura?
He is not in?
Mrs. Akamatsu came today. When
I went to take her back to the station,
I asked him to stay at the house.
Are you back?
That's my belt!
Yes, I couldn't find mine, so
I took yours.
He was complaining, looking
everywhere for it.
Really? I'm sorry.
The neighbour came to ask me
to play chess with him.
It's cold.
Because of this visit, I haven't
cooked any thing yet. I'm sorry.
What is this?
Some meat.
But we already have some sushi.
What a pity...
There's some for you.
Do you want to eat now?
Yes.
It's almost 100 "Mei".
It's too much money, if we buy meat
today and tomorrow.
Sorry. It's a special offer.
That's why I bought it.
- I'm going to the neighbour.
- OK.
Excuse me.
Your move... it bothers me.
If it bothers you,
I take it out.
You are back?
We stayed at the exit of the theatre,
but there was few people.
Too bad!
Excuse us. We are still playing.
Give me some tea.
This is for the school fees.
How many times
do you have to pay?
Before, it was for last month.
Don't waste it.
How could you say it's a waste?
Tea!
One moment!
I'm back.
Mr. Takemura, bath is ready.
It smells good.
I'm starving.
Would you like to have dinner?
I'll cook something while you
are taking a bath.
Really?
Well, I've never seen
underwear like that.
Like what?
At the time of rationing,
my wife made it by herself.
Really?
Does it look strange?
What's this?
Underwear made out of a kimono.
It looks ridiculous.
Ridiculous?
I'll take that.
Look darling, this is nice.
Take it. I buy it for you.
- No, that's too expensive.
- You don't have to do it.
I just want to thank you.
You don't have to.
Let's go.
Let's go dancing.
But I'm not dressed properly.
It's all right.
Darling, can I go?
Nakahara, come!
Where is Nakahara?
What is he doing?
Here you are, Mr. Nakahara!
I was over there with my colleague.
It's for me. Just to thank you
for everything you've done...
You don't have to.
Do you want a drink?
No, thanks.
It'll warm you up.
If we were coming back home,
would you take care of the
fireplace and cook for me?
It's not my plan.
At last, a quiet place.
It tastes very good.
Really?
You almost never go out.
We should go and have dinner
somewhere every Sunday.
If we do that, we'll be bankrupted.
No, it could be something small
like a curry, or breaded pork.
Thank you very much.
I'm serious.
I don't know how to thank you.
You are exaggerating.
My wife was so different,
may she rest in peace...
Now, I can see woman differently.
Thanks to you and to what I felt
the first time I saw you.
Well, you are
a bit strange, tonight.
I'm serious.
With you, I have discovered
another type of woman.
It's too much.
Come on, one more glass.
My wife was in very good shape.
That's all she had.
She was not beautiful. She couldn't
keep the kitchen tidy.
I thought that was normal.
And finally, she died, despite
her good health.
She had nothing special.
I draw the wrong number.
I envy your couple.
Mr. Takemura, life goes on.
You still can have hope.
You speak like an old lady.
It's because it's not that ideal.
If my husband were like you,
more joyful...
Like me?
When I married him,
he was not like that.
Now, he has no interest in anything.
Only baseball makes him thrilled.
I feel alone.
You and I are the same,
we feel lonely.
We should help each other.
All right.
Let's have a drink!
Cheers!
He is not home yet.
Wait here.
- Be careful.
- I'm fine.
Let me make your bed.
I can do it.
It's ok.
I take care of it.
Kikuko.
Where were you?
We looked for you everywhere.
Are you drunk? Mr. Takemura had
too many drinks, too.
- Had you a drink?
- Yes.
We were looking for you.
I was cold.
Where have you been?
I had a drink with Mieko Fujino.
Is she the shortest one of the two?
Did you see her?
What's this?
A shawl.
Mr. Takemura bought it for me.
You went back to that shop?
I didn't want to, but...
Give it him back!
Why does he offer you a gift?
For thanking me to help him.
And you find it natural
to accept a gift?
That's petty-minded.
All right, I'll give it back to him.
Let's dance, Kikuko.
Let's go dancing!
Nakahara, when did you come back?
Where were you?
We looked everywhere for you,
didn't we, Kikuko?
He had a drink with miss Fujino.
Really?
She took the opportunity
to get a free drink.
No, she's a nice girl.
Youth is so nice. She's fresh.
We too, we had fun.
Hadn't we Kikuko?
What a noise!
Don't play the music this late!
Are you going back home?
You don't look fine.
Is there anything interesting
to watch?
A movie?
Yes, whatever it is.
They have a special show of nice
movies for 30 yens.
Hello.
Takemura.
Are you going back home?
- Let's go together.
- All right.
Do you have any? I need some
for my wife.
I'm going.
Goodbye.
He is not home yet?
No.
Can I help you?
No, thanks. I'll be fine.
It's still early. I have plenty
of time.
Nakahara, what is he doing?
Yesterday, he was with Miss Fujino
and today they left office together.
I'll have a small conversation with him.
Yes.
OK then, I'm going
to the neighbour.
At this time?
Good evening.
You want to talk to me?
Nakahara, I think there is
a misunderstanding between us.
A misunderstanding?
Yes. I don't think you realise
what you are doing.
You can go out with Miss Fujino
if you want to,
but you should think about
your poor wife.
My poor wife?
It's indeed a misunderstanding.
Liar! You love my wife.
Yes, I love her.
But I'm not losing head.
My love for her...
...is like the love of children
for a beautiful rose.
I'm simply innocent.
But talking about me is
not what matters...
If you can not trust her,
it's terrible.
Our couple doesn't need
your advice.
I don't care what you have to say.
Mr. Nakahara, the boss
is waiting for you.
Nakahara, I would like
you to go to Sendai.
All right.
But can you leave
tomorrow Sunday?
Yes, no problem.
Right now, material is expensive.
When spring comes, we can get a deal.
Then we can find something nice.
Are you going somewhere?
- I count on you.
- OK.
- OK. Have a nice trip.
Today it's Sunday,
I should fix season's decoration.
Let me help you.
Yes, please. Do you how
to drive in a nail?
Here you are.
- Like this? Is it OK?
- Yes.
Hello.
Everybody has left already.
- The boss too?
- Yes.
The boss wants that you bring
your report at Yoshikitae restaurant.
Now?
Here I am.
Here's the report.
It's my third year-end party.
Can you bring it to the chairman?
It's the last day before the holidays.
We'll speak about it next year,
but it's better if he reads it now.
Should I bring it to his place?
He told me he'll leave for
Atami, tonight.
But now, he must be at the
restaurant "Hanamura".
I must be going now.
We'll talk about it later.
I rely on you.
Are you going already?
- No.
- Goodbye.
You have something behind.
You have something hanging
behind.
It's the lining, stupid.
I'm so sorry...
What's the matter?
Good evening. Thank you for waiting.
- Is this for us?
- Yes, your wife ordered them.
- Here are the noodles.
- Already?
Good evening.
The noodles have arrived?
You're back?
What are you doing upstairs?
- Be careful not to spill it.
- It's all right.
Are you bringing them up?
My brother in law is back.
Really? There is one missing.
You're right.
I start just tasting.
Wait, this is with vegetables. You
asked for meat!
What are you doing!
Why is it ripped like this.
The linen was hanging out.
And you ripped it off?
It is not funny.
But before, it was not
so much damaged.
You ripped all this off.
That was too strong.
Do you want to take
a bath now?
- Is it ready yet?
- It won't be long.
- Kikuko?
- What?
If you are not coming now,
there won't be anymore left.
No... That is not allowed.
The fire put out
Really?
I've just started it.
Sorry.
How was the trip?
I'd love to go spend
a few days somewhere.
Since the school trip,
I didn't go anywhere.
Kikuko? Kikuko?
You are hungry, aren't you?
Where are you going?
To the public bath.
- But it's almost ready here.
- Too late.
- You want some? It's a bit cold.
- No.
What happened?
I dropped it. Bring me
the floor cloth.
It's not my fault, if
I invited my sister.
I thought that, while you
were not here,
it's better if she stays here.
I'm very busy for year-end...
I had no intention
to have fun with her.
But once I've asked her to come
I had to take care of her.
That's why I bought some noodles.
Takemura let me do this.
Even though this bothers him.
But you can't understand this.
I want you to understand that.
I must be careful.
You just leave for the public bath,
I make dinner and waited for you.
And you come back after midnight!
Think about me.
I had to warm you dinner
several times.
You're so rude!
You told me that you'll buy
an overcoat, this year.
I never thought you would
wear that old coat again.
We've spent a lot on the wedding
of my brother and on moving houses.
I knew that I had to darn
the linen of your coat,
but you know this takes time.
Anyway, when you left,
it was not hanging out.
As you don't have anything else,
you had to be more careful.
OK, that's enough.
Because of this, you made a fool
of yourself in front of geisha.
Is it so embarrassing that geishas
see you like this?
Me too, my friends are making
fun of me.
Because I'm like a country girl, now.
To save money, I'm not going
to hairdresser.
Even my kimonos are old-fashioned.
I should have turned them into futons.
You are exaggerating.
I'm making many efforts,
but you don't seems to realise it.
You don't understand how
careful I must be...
while you are not here.
Since we came here,
I have to take care of everything
and you've changed and became
aggressive.
I can't stand it anymore.
You're not the same anymore.
When Takemura wakes up,
there is miso in the kitchen.
You could warm it up for him.
When the rice pudding comes, could
you store it next to the others.
There's clean cloth for that
in the cupboard.
I have to go and think over it
by my side.
One well-cooked eel with sauce.
Thank you very much.
I envy you, having time to argue
with your husband on
New Year's Eve.
I'm really exhausted.
Do you have herring's egg?
Hello. Does it look ugly?
No, it fits you well.
I went to the hairdresser
at 6 o'clock in the morning.
Are you hungry?
Yes.
Thank you.
You are not going back?
No.
Why not?
You have to go home.
We decided to think over it
by our side.
As long as I don't want to,
I won't see him.
Today is New Year's Eve.
It's my problem.
But, Isaku never shows his mind.
It's difficult to know
what is on his mind.
Isn't it?
That is what everybody thinks.
I feel like fighting windmills.
I have enough.
Mokichi. Once you get married,
be careful
or your wife well go back to her
parents complaining.
Don't worry.
Namiko is not like this.
One time: 10 yens.
It's true, today you didn't
pronounce her name yet.
If Namiko were here...
One more time: 20 yens
Mokichi, you know women...
They show their true nature
5 or 6 years after the wedding.
- All of them?
- Yes.
When it will hit you,
it will be terrible.
Yes, probably.
It's cooked.
Your wife is late.
Tonight, the train is working all night.
But, don't you feel worry
about her?
It's almost midnight.
And you? You stay here
for new year's holidays?
Yes, I'm not interested in family.
You're not visiting
your wife's grave?
I just went there,
but it was for the funeral.
Doesn't matter.
Your wife is really late.
She left since this morning.
It doesn't bother you?
What?
That your wife is not here?
Good evening.
You grilled the rice cake?
We were hungry.
You shouldn't cook
fresh rice cakes.
Really?
There was many customers
by my parents.
They are very busy today.
My mother gave me that.
It's very good.
Here you are. Try it.
It is midnight
Everything is ready for
the new year.
A new year.
I am going to sleep. Good night.
- Do you want some tea?
- No, thanks.
Is it cold outside?
Warm yourself up.
I was late.
What's the matter?
"To signal the new year,
you are listening to the bell
of the Ishakuji temple,
in the Yamagata prefecture"
You just got married, so I
don't want to scare you,
but you must be careful
during the early days.
Don't be too nice nor too obedient,
or she might become pretentious.
Men, Namiko, are happy if you
flatter them.
If you look at them as big children,
you'll be fine.
You shouldn't forget that.
Everything is fine, if you
know how to cradle them like babies.
It's difficult.
Yes, a couple are like scissors.
Who said that? Koda Rohan?
Yes, that must be.
Or maybe Ogai Mori.
Whoever. He said that.
In a couple, nobody can
cut the sheet alone.
It's like scissors, two knives
cutting together.
Is it true?
It's true.
Well said.
What's not normal is when the
husband is working hard,
and the woman let him wear
old worn coat.
Or when the husband comes
home late and tired,
and his wife hasn't
made the bath ready.
Moreover, even if the fire
has put out,
but she foolishly claims
the bath should be ready soon.
Of course.
Men think that they alone
can be tired at night, which is wrong.
For me, that shouldn't be
an issue, as I'm working at home.
Moreover, if I'm going out
I'll take you with me.
Don't worry then.
- We should go now.
- Already?
Are you still looking for a house?
Namiko... A relative of my wife...
does she have something to rent?
Yes, under the condition there
is no children.
Where is it located? We are interested.
It's very quiet.
- Here it is.
- Really?
Good day.
I'm a relative of Mr. Mishima
who rented a room in this house.
You are a relative of
Mr. Mishima?
How do you do?
Do you still have a room to let?
Upstairs? Yes.
Let me introduce you
my sister-in-law.
How do you do?
The room upstairs is very quiet.
We had many applicant,
but it can't be rented
to anybody.
Good day.
Downstair, we have two students.
And this lady rents one
of the room upstairs.
She teaches tea ceremony
and ikebana.
We don't accept couples...
with children, it's too noisy.
It's perfect for you.
What about the deposit?
There is no deposit.
But when someone
brings a gift as a token
of good understanding,
then I accept it.
Is it for you and
your husband?
Just the two of us.
- Are you going out?
- Yes.
- Do you wish to see the room?
- Yes, please.
Good day.
Mr. and Mrs. Nakahara
already moved out?
Yes, earlier today.
What do you want?
Yesterday, the boss left
a message for you,
but you didn't come back.
Then I...
As today is Sunday,
I took the opportunity
to pass it to you.
What is it?
The managing director will visit
the office tomorrow at 9:00.
The boss wants you to come
early that day.
Really? 9:00?
Do you want to come in?
- It doesn't bother you?
- No.
Excuse me.
Could you move that cupboard
over there?
Again?
Why are out of breath?
Since the morning we went
up and down the stairs so many times.
Is she the Ikebana teacher?
She could hear you.
It's quiet.
But, here, it's only short time.
Why?
If we have children...
Don't worry.
Maybe, there is something.
If it's right, it's nice.
I confirm!
Why didn't you tell
if you knew it?
Because...
What could we do?
We had to move out.
We still have another 6 months.
It will be alright, we'll look
for some other place.
But I don't have any
money left for that.
I'll ask my father.
No way.
We can't give him back.
I don't want to.
You should stop always counting
on your parents.
You know that your family
is not that rich.
I'll look for a job at home.
In that case, we should get rid
of the baby.
It's not the right time.
No.
- But..
- No.
Come on, let's go.
You shouldn't feel guilty.
It won't last long.
"Obstetrician"
It should be all right.
Let's go.
Let's go back.
Let's go back!
- We should have something to eat.
- Yes...
We'll keep it, even if it's difficult.
The End
Translation: unknown
Adjustments: Dan