Stop right there.
Get on the floor now.
Ladies.
I wouldn't do that.
Who the fuck are you?
What do you want?
Lucy Swanson.
Lucy was here a week ago
on a night out with her friends.
Thing is, this is the
last place she was seen.
Do you know how many bored
little rich girls run away from home?
Happens every
day in the big city.
Unfortunately,
your boys did a terrible job
of disposing of the evidence.
The police found
her body last night.
Lucy's parents
are friends of mine,
- so here I am.
- So here you are.
So what now, then?
Now, turn yourselves
in and confess.
And what happens
if we say fuck you?
- That.
- Kill this fucking prick.
Haven't lost your touch, I see.
Frost. What are you doing here?
Got something to tell you.
Nope.
Don't you want to
know how I found you?
Satellites, cameras, et cetera?
John, look, I needed to
speak to you face to face.
About a job.
How many times?
Not. Interested.
You will be this time.
It's Teague.
Sean Teague is dead.
This was taken yesterday.
The operative who sent it was deep
undercover for the past two years.
He was about to
take his targets down
when he was introduced to an arms
dealer that turned out to be Teague.
I'm putting a team together to catch
Teague, and I want you to lead it.
You want me to bring
Teague in... alive?
I know what he did to you and your
team, but we need Teague breathing.
His intel and contacts alone are enough
to bring down the baddest of the bad.
Come on, do it for your country.
Oh, that's rich coming from you.
Okay, do it for yourself, then.
- Meaning?
- Meaning you bring Teague in,
in one piece, the department
wipes your slate clean.
All is forgiven.
No more running.
Think about it, John.
Bring Teague in alive, and
you get your life back again.
Gentlemen. Ladies.
You all know Commander Grayson.
- Morning, everyone.
- Morning.
Our target: Sean Teague.
As you all know, Teague
was an elite operative,
one of our best, until
he turned on his team
during their final mission in
Eastern Europe several years ago.
Many of them met
with rather grisly ends.
Quite.
After going rogue, Teague was responsible
for the deaths of dozens of personnel,
as well as countless civilians in
mercenary operations across the globe.
Arms deals, smuggling
state secrets, assassinations.
You name it, Teague
profited from it.
Well, yeah, he did.
Until he was reported killed
two years ago in the ♪.R.C.
Yes, well, we've
all heard that story.
Authorities on the ground confirmed
that Teague had been killed,
but he's here now, and
we're going to bring him in.
Who's the tree trunk?
You're kidding. It's
only John fucking Gold.
- Get away.
- Uh-huh.
Wonder how many
people he's killed this week.
Five.
So far.
Nice to meet you.
Likewise.
Lynch and Shapiro, you've
somewhat preempted me.
Everybody, meet John Gold.
Nobody knows Teague better
than Gold, especially in the field.
And nobody has a more
compelling reason to bring him in.
From what I've heard, you'll more
likely put a bullet behind Teague's ear
than put him behind bars.
People do like
to talk, don't they?
Your mission is breach
Teague's location,
transport him to an
off-the-books airbase,
then fly him to an ever-so-hush-hush
black site secure facility,
where he'll live out
his days in a steel box.
So what's the play, boss?
Gold here will lead,
with you two reprobates providing
ground support and flying/driving services.
- Shit work. Standard.
- That's what we get paid for.
What? They pay you for this?
That's enough, you two.
Kelso, Plachecki and Stiles, you'll
serve and support the operation from here.
Any questions?
'Course not. I'll
see you at the R.V.
I'm sorry we can't give you the
support you need for this one, John.
You know I can't be seen
to authorize a full team.
If news about Teague
being alive got out,
top brass will have
a major flap-on.
But Lynch and Shapiro
are two of the best.
Believe it or not.
A team can be a liability.
Teague taught me that.
Morning, lads.
- Boss.
Nice morning for it.
- Heard from Pearl yet?
- Not yet.
We agreed on radio
silence until she arrives.
Yeah, yeah, just in case.
Pretty smart... coming from you.
Okay, lads, we're here for the
duration until we hear from Pearl.
Smoke 'em if you've got 'em.
Come on.
What's all this?
What? Oh, uh, nothing.
What is all this?
[, uh...
I-1 really need a piss.
So go take a piss.
What am I, your mother?
Better than sex!
Then you're doing it wrong.
Fuck!
Steady!
As I live and
breathe. John Gold.
Teague. You're coming with me.
Yeah, of course I am.
Lads!
Bennett, move!
Go.
Go, go, go.
Teague!
Teague! Hands in the air!
Don't stop us now. We're
just starting to have some fun.
Assume the position.
Or what?
To be continued.
Are you sure you're
going to make our window?
We've got a tight timeframe
to get that plane in the air.
Yeah, we'll make it.
Our E.T.A's about 60 minutes.
Okay, great. Just get
Teague to that airbase,
- and we can all breathe out.
- Yep, copy that.
Lynch and Shapiro are securing
Teague, and we'll be on our way in a few.
Just make sure that
plane is good to go.
Twat's ready for transport.
Hey, you're going nowhere, mate.
Here's Prince Charming now.
I'll keep you
updated. Stay frosty.
Yeah, funny, I've
never heard that before.
This is excellent, by the way.
I know.
Good to go.
Believe it or not, Teague,
this is all for your own good.
You're being flown to a
remote, black site prison
"cause there's too many people out
here that want your head on a pike."
People like you?
You're a traitor, you're a murderer,
and you sacrificed our own team.
Now, you either pay
for those crimes this way,
or someone's going to
tear you limb from limb.
Alleged crimes.
And I'm supposed to
believe all this from a man
who wants to see me
dead more than most?
For my own good,
eh? That's bullshit.
Let's go.
Get in! Get in!
I knew it... you're
trying to kill me!
Don't be ridiculous,
we'd just let him do it.
Anyone got eyes on the shooter?
Right, we need a
volunteer to draw their fire.
Fuck off.
- Fucking...!
- Where are they?
Three o'clock, tower.
Probably one of Teague's...
- No, Teague's the target.
- Bollocks.
Whoa...
- Maybe.
- Let's go.
On it.
- Mine.
- Really?
Lynch! Step on it.
Hold onto your balls back there.
Talk to me.
We had an unexpected
guest, but we're on our way.
Any idea who it was?
Not a clue, but they
wanted Teague's head.
And nearly got it.
I'll keep you posted.
We're on our way, people.
Take it steady.
Hey, hope you've got some nice, hot
stewardesses on this flight for me, John.
I wouldn't get your hopes up, Teague.
You're going to prison, not Ibiza.
And they're called
cabin crew these days.
Touch a nerve there, did 1?
Oh, for... We've got incoming.
Shit!
Lynch, floor it!
Come on, then.
Shit.
Dead end!
Brace! Brace!
Move! Now!
- Everyone all right?
- Fuck off.
Lynch, you okay?
Yeah, just great.
Look, I don't give a shit
about whoever's out there.
But you either give me a gun or
you get me the fuck out of here.
Someone's finally got to the big,
bad, tough-as-fuck Sean Teague.
I'll shake them by the hand.
Gold.
Check this out.
You think we can make
it over to that factory?
Yeah, that'll do for now.
Okay, I'll draw his fire,
you two follow Lynch.
I'll catch up to you once
I've dealt with our new friend.
Or we could just hand
Teague over to whoever that is.
You're supposed to protect me.
Tell me again what my job is?
Shapiro.
You see, John?
That's what it comes down to.
Me, and a quarter-ounce of lead.
Don't tempt me.
Guys, if we're going,
we should go now.
Right, then.
Move!
Who the fuck are you?
Greetings.
Now this... This
is gonna be fun.
- How are we doing?
- We got held up again.
Our new friend took out our van.
There's something else.
We were attacked
by another team.
As in a different team
that attacked both of you?
That is what the sentence
that I just said would mean, yes.
Any idea who they were?
I didn't hang around to find out.
I'm regrouping with the others now.
Okay.
We're not authorized, but fuck
this sitting on our thumbs shit.
I'm going in there to
help our guys. Fancy it?
Just say the word.
That's what I like to hear.
Let's get going, people.
- How long should we give it?
- Ten minutes?
I mean, we can't
wait much longer.
Who was that back there?
Didn't get a name.
They're still out there.
Some others too.
Others like who?
No idea. You?
How the fuck do I know?
So it could be anyone, then.
Right, we need to
get to that airbase.
Take a look around, see if
we can find some wheels.
You lot don't know what
you've got yourselves into.
Quiet!
Move!
Gold.
Gold!
That's it. Get up.
Say hello to my boys,
and my beautiful fiancée.
We're going to use
this to keep track of you.
How long does it take to work?
Should already
be up and running.
We're good.
Just don't lose that phone.
I told you there'd be no
plane for me, didn't 1?
You just wouldn't listen.
You're going nowhere, Teague.
It's Mr. Teague to you.
Cut these, Gunnar.
Keep them here.
Any trouble, you
kill the chick first.
Fuck you!
You got it, boss.
When you're all done
with the womanfolk...
why don't you just come show
us how tough you really are?
I'm gonna need this.
Moan feebly if that's okay.
Good. Right.
I'm gonna go kill those guys,
while you go after Teague.
Right...
But don't engage him.
Just let me know where you are.
Yeah, but hold on. I...
Hey, Gold!
I always heard you were some
kind of one-man killing machine.
So, what're you waiting for?
Hang on, I'll be through in a
second to kick your teeth in.
Go find Teague, and let
me know where you are.
We'll get him together.
Okay. Don't get
killed and stuff.
You too.
Right, then.
You all right, mate?
Finally.
Pleasure to meet you, Mr. Gold.
Likewise.
So...
you're John Gold.
The John Gold?
Yep.
You know, Teague told us all these
stories about how bloodthirsty you are.
Yet here we all
are with... these.
And there you are with...
With that.
I mean, what're you
even going to do with...
- Kendrick, get the car.
- Okay.
- Be out of here in five.
- Knew you'd come through, babe.
Teague!
Stay where you are.
Look, we've got somewhere to
go. Why don't you just back off?
What? This shouldn't take long.
Yeah, you're right, it'll
take me about 30 seconds.
Maybe we should offer her a job.
Fuck...
Shoot him!
Say goodbye, prick-hole.
Shit!
Stoppage.
Okay, okay.
Let's get bloody.
- Get behind me.
- Do something, then.
Just stay back.
Step aside. This
isn't your fight.
Who are you? Who is she?
Long story, but
she should be dead.
Oh, your men tried all right.
You're trying to save
the life of a murderer,
which makes you naive at
best, but you're not my problem.
Just get out of my way,
I don't want to hurt you.
Then don't. But I'm not moving.
We're taking Teague
to prison, to face justice.
This is justice!
Well, come on, do it!
Don't rush me!
I'm killing a hero here.
It's a big moment for me.
Any last words?
Prepare to be
deeply embarrassed.
He's a live one, all right!
But not for long.
Here it comes.
Well, stop dicking
around and kill him!
I'm trying...
Last chance. Walk away.
Okay.
I tried.
All right.
Getting paid
overtime for this, right?
Well, thanks for all your help.
You okay?
Where's Lynch?
Right, I'll deal with that,
you go cover the entrance.
We don't need any
more unexpected guests.
Roger that.
Use this.
Stand back, babe.
Come on, babe! Let's go.
If you...
Teague!
You want to have
a go hand-to-hand?
Yeah, I fancy my chances.
Hey. Whoever you are.
I can see you've
got your reasons,
but let us bring
Teague in the right way.
You don't understand, he...
Dumb fucking luck!
You're amazing, but give it up.
Get real!
Gold!
Lynch! Hold on!
You okay?
We had a disagreement.
That's her specialty.
Long time, no see, Jen.
You know her?
Jen Quaid. I served
with her father.
Until Teague ended all that.
Let me go, Gold. I've
got no problem with you.
Not this time. We're
taking Teague to prison.
Three square meals a day
and a roof over his head?
After everything he's done?
That's not nearly
enough, and you know it.
I'm amazed you haven't
killed him yourself.
He's come close.
This is bigger than what
Teague's done to either of us.
You've got clean
hands, is that it?
My dad told me
about every mission.
All the horrible, fucked-up
shit you guys did together.
And that's my point.
Do you want to end up like us?
We both know that's not the
path your dad wanted for you.
So don't make this
harder than it has to be.
He's off again.
What do you want me to do?
Call Frost. Check on Shapiro.
Then catch up with me.
I'll catch you later.
Boss.
- Lynch?
- Yeah, it's me.
- Go ahead.
- We caught up with the sniper.
Name's Jen Quaid.
Christ, really?
Gold and I worked
with her old man.
Yeah, that's right.
She's tied up on the upper
level of our current location,
- if you want to pick her up.
- Copy that.
I've got Gold after me, and
I've got Jen Quaid after me,
so come and pick me up now.
We've got your position.
Just keep moving,
and we'll come to you.
Gunnar, Price. Let's get movin'.
It's okay, chum. It's okay.
Even if you get Teague
to that prison cell,
how long do you
think he'll last?
That's not my problem.
My mission ends
once he's in that cell.
All the shit Teague
has on the government.
All those black bag, disavowable
jobs he did with my dad and Gold?
They just want him in there so that
they can make sure he dies on their terms.
Well, seeing as you want
Teague dead so badly,
why don't you
let us bring him in,
and he'll get what
you think he deserves.
No!
I have to kill him myself.
Jen.
Do you really think your dad
would want you to go through
all this emotional agony and
violence, just to murder this one man?
Yes.
Okay, that's not
crazy or anything.
See you around.
Preferably not.
You're coming with me.
I'm going nowhere with you.
We don't have time for this.
You're not listening to me.
Or do you want me
to beat it into you?
I said we don't
have time for this.
How many of your mates
did I have killed again?
They were good men.
And you sold them
out for cold, hard cash.
I didn't do it for the
money, and you know that!
Teague! Just listen...
Just like old times.
Always did like giving the
orders, didn't you, John?
This is your last warning.
If it wasn't for me, Jen Quaid
would have killed you by now.
If it weren't for you slowing
me down, I'd have killed her!
I put everything on
the line for this country,
and I get made the scapegoat
for mistakes made over my head.
Shit rolls downhill.
You know that.
Years of loyal service, and I
get thrown on the scrapheap.
Well, that's no excuse for
betraying your own team.
You wouldn't understand
until it happened to you.
Why don't you
just admit it, John?
You're enjoying this.
That's it. That's the
Gold I remember.
Come on!
Lynch advised that
Qaid is on the upper level.
Be ready to move in.
Is this what you want?
Is this what you fucking want?
Enough...
Are you fucking
happy now, Teague?
Gold!
Hey, John.
You're killing him.
I'll call the team
to pick us up.
No. Let's just get to
the airbase ourselves.
The three of us will be
harder for Jen to track.
You really think Jen's
still gonna be a problem?
There's one thing you need
to know about Jen Quaid.
She's always going
to be a problem.
Hello, boys.
Frost.
You know the routine, Jen.
Down on the ground.
Hands behind your head.
All right?
I want a chat about hazard
pay, but apart from that...
I'm a-okay.
Jen, I had a lot of
respect for your old man.
But we have to treat
you as an active threat,
so just behave and
let us bring you in.
What're we doing?
She's just some chick.
She's not even strapped.
That "chick" nearly
killed us all. Twice.
She's amazing.
Kelso. Cuff her.
Take cover!
Let's find some wheels.
This is a wild goose chase.
I'm done, I ain't
going any further.
Fine.
You stay here, then,
wait for Jen to catch up
and shoot you in the head.
You fucking arsehole.
Hold fire! Hold fire!
Jen!
This is your last chance!
Surrender!
Right now!
Check it out.
Be careful. She's much more
dangerous than she looks.
Okay, on me.
Foyer clear.
You two, clear the upper
floor. We'll check this level.
- RV. back here.
- Roger that. Let's go.
Keep comms open.
- You heard the boss. Don't get brave.
- Understood.
Just some chick?
I didn't mean...
Someone talk to me.
What's going on?
You okay?
Kelso?
Stiles?
What about this one?
Yeah. I can work with this.
You think you
can get it running?
Please.
Gold?
Cheers.
Right, straight to the airbase.
- Roger that.
- You hear that, Teague?
Very soon we'll be
flying the friendly skies.
We'll see about that.
How's that, Gunnar babe?
You look quite lovely, miss.
Not far now. Take the next left.
You got it.
Okay.
Okay. So she got one over on me.
Can one of you at least
give me something to wear?
Sure. Here.
Quaid deactivated the
vehicle tracking system.
- She could be anywhere.
- Smart move.
Come on, you lot.
Let's get moving.
We're making good
time. Not far now.
Yeah, as long as this rust
bucket makes it that far.
Jesus...!
Come on, we've got to move.
This way, Mr. Teague.
That's fucked, innit?
Teague!
Let's go.
Sean! Come on, let's go.
You okay?
I'm seeing three of you.
Other than that, I'm good.
Right, I'm going
to go after them.
You R.V. with Frost, and
I'll see you at the airbase.
On it.
Fucker don't know when to quit.
I've got this.
Guard her with your life.
- What's he doing?
- He needs to see this through, miss.
This fucking guy.
Go and finish him.
Sean!
Not her again.
Shit.
Who is that?
That's the daughter of a
man I killed a long time ago.
Gold.
Jen, listen...
I understand why you
want to kill Teague.
And trust me, I want
to put a bullet in him too.
But it's not gonna
bring back my men.
And it's not gonna
bring back your dad.
So, please, help me
to do this the right way.
Here.
- Kill them both.
- You got it.
You get Teague,
I'll get the other guy.
Not bad.
We've got to make that plane.
Why the fuck would I
go anywhere with you?
Well, in case you've
forgotten, that's Jen Quaid.
You know he's killed
his own men, right?
- Really going to take his money?
- I'm a mercenary.
The clue is in the
job description.
A highly trained killing machine
who's been following you all day,
and so far everything you've
tried to do to stop her has failed.
Now, are you sure your guy's
got what it takes to bring her down?
"Cause I've got to
be honest with you..."
My money's on her.
Now, move it!
You know what?
I might just stick around
and see how this pans out.
You know...
I'm really starting
to enjoy this job.
Damn it, Jen.
I've got to say, fighting you
has been a bit of a thrill for me.
Best part is, you're next.
You did good, by the way.
You've got some moves.
And you've got fighting spirit.
But now it's time to say...
Come on, let's go.
Fucking prick.
Ah, fuck.
Sean! Go!
Price, Gunnar. Shoot them!
Go after Teague, I'll cover you.
You really want to take
on this lot by yourself?
You would.
Go now, before we lose him!
Take cover!
Gunnar, Price, move in.
Close in, we'll surround her.
Right, then.
Fuck me. You're like
herpes... I can't get rid of you.
On. Now.
Move in.
Shit.
She's a tricky one all right.
Room for one more?
That your summer
look or something?
Don't want to talk about it.
But where are your
trousers, though?
What's the latest?
Teague's men grabbed
him, and Gold was...
Speak of the devil,
and he shall appear.
Gold, you're on speaker and
I'm with the gang, so no sexy talk.
Gold! Let me off
this fucking thing!
- So you got him again, then.
- Yup.
- I got some wheels too.
- Cool.
We'll be at the airbase
in about ten minutes.
Roger that. I'll see you soon.
You heard the man, let's go.
Fucking dead man,
Gold, do you hear me?
Fucking dead man.
You might want to hold on tight.
It's gonna be a bumpy ride.
Well? Did you get her?
- Enjoy the ride?
- You're a prick.
Any more trouble out of you, and
I'll be carrying you onto that plane.
And how much trouble
do you think I can get in?
Just move.
Your gun, please.
That's what I'm talking about.
Now the keys, please.
You know, you might be the most
polite mercenary I've ever encountered.
That's very kind of you to say.
And we're taking the plane.
We're flying out of here.
No, you're getting on that
plane, and you're going to prison.
I've had enough of this
you-and-me bollocks.
Get on your knees.
Do as you're told.
You might want to
stand back, darling.
This is over.
Now.
Hey, Teague.
That was quite the entrance.
Dad always said I was dramatic.
Shit. Teague's guys
are already here.
Stiles. Take point.
Let's go get these bastards.
Okay, stay here, you'll be safe.
Do what you've got to do.
Move in.
I'm nearly out.
You?
Don't ask.
Go!
Fuck.
Believe it or not, this is
how I killed your old man!
Let's just go!
No, I can't, I've got to stay.
- No.
- I've got to finish this.
John!
You're really starting to
fucking irritate me now.
In my office.
Just... Kill him... already!
Ladies.
Do you really think
you can take me?
Fuck...
It's your choice.
Jen...
I've been there.
What're we going
to do with him now?
This ain't over, John.
Believe me, this ain't over.
I'm coming for
your friends, John!
I'm coming for your kids, John!
I'm coming for your dog!
Well, it may not be a
plane, but he's on his way.
Well done.
We'll debrief tomorrow at 0900.
Did we win this one, then?
Beers are on me, so I guess.
Victory. Yay.
I'll see you in the pub.
You know, Teague's probably
gonna die in that prison.
Maybe.
But I can live with
him being behind bars.
Think I can too.
Or I could just break in and
kill him if I change my mind.
So.
So?
How's it feel to be
a free man again?
It's all right.
Come on, let's get plastered.