(moody blues music)
Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
- "Listen, if you shoot
him, put two in his face.
"This gun is long but
it's not that powerful,
"so if you shoot him one time,
it's not gonna kill him."
He said that to me like
it was good advice,
and gave me a little pat on the shoulder,
like he just taught his son
how to ask a girl to prom.
I think I was 15 when I
bought that gun, 15 or 16.
Newhallville is changing all the time,
and the more it changes,
the more it stays the same.
(moody blues music)
There are specific sections that are owned
by certain groups of young men
and it's crazy that one
small street, like a block,
something that could be
maybe 100 yards in length,
can be owned so tightly
that you could be afraid
to into go to that corner store
if you're from another section
and this is all just a couple blocks.
You can drive through the Ville probably
within four to five minutes
and each section is so heavily
guarded, almost.
Strange.
It's like guerrilla warfare,
it's like civil war,
all within a tiny area.
And sometimes these small
sections or factions are allies.
Sometimes they get along.
And then other times,
they're beefing so hard with one another
that if you go to a specific corner store
that is in another person's
area, there's a great chance
that you'll be shot at or
killed or stabbed or robbed.
Where you get off at the
bus stop is very important.
You gotta know what streets
or what area you can walk to.
If you're from a specific area,
you may have to take the longest way home
just to walk all the way
around to avoid another spot
that you're not allowed to go into,
(acoustic blues music)
where it's dangerous for you to go into.
And then if you go further
down street up Dixwell,
there's Yale University.
Where everyone has a Starbucks
cup and a peacoat on.
But inside the Ville,
it's a different world.
And I remember the terror on
my mom's face all the time
and I remember the terror
on my brother's face
and they would always say,
I used to hear this all the time,
all different points of the day,
"Henry, come inside right now,
"Henry, come inside right now."
At different points in
the day and I never knew
how much danger I was escaping.
I never knew people were being killed.
I never knew people were
being molested, like friends,
family, people close to
me, houses next door,
I never knew that and to a
certain degree, my childhood was,
it was like a sanctuary
in the middle of hell.
Then at some point in time,
your innocent world just crashes.
It crashes around you.
My teacher had proposed that
my mother bring us some cups
and some juice, some cupcakes
and some juice and some
chips, some snacks or whatever
for this birthday party
that she wanted my mom
to throw for me.
All the kids, whenever
they had a birthday,
their parents would come
in and they would bring in
some candy or something for the kids
and it was kind of the norm.
And she said, "Henry, go
tell your mom to bring us
"some cupcakes and
everything for the next day."
I go home, I ask my
mom, of course she says,
the same sentence, "Honey,
we can't afford it,"
so I go into class the next day,
when my teacher calls
me up in front of her
and the whole class is staring.
It's dead quiet in the classroom
and I walk up with my head down
'cause I'm already embarrassed
and the teacher says, "What's wrong?
"Why didn't you bring the cupcakes?
"Why didn't you bring the juice?"
And I say, "My mom said
we couldn't afford it."
And I'll never forget
what this teacher said.
This teacher looked at me and said,
"It's only cupcakes and
juice, you can't afford that?"
In short, I was poor. (laughs)
And you never know you're poor
until you're compared to
somebody else, like food stamps,
I don't care what nobody
say about food stamps, yo.
It's the most embarrassing
thing to walk into a line
and swipe that card, I feel like,
and this may just me being paranoid,
but I feel like the cashier
kind of gives you a side eye,
like this nigga's on food
stamps, you know what I'm saying?
Okay, you didn't earn this,
you know what I'm saying,
you didn't earn this, and
all that made me angry.
It made me angry to the point
where I did not want to use
food stamps, I didn't
want to use my mom's card
to go and buy nothing,
you know what I'm saying.
I hated going to the
grocery store with her.
If she was gonna use her food stamps card.
I never said that to her
but it was embarrassing.
And after a certain point,
you start to lose it.
It be enough is enough.
You reach a certain limit.
You're wearing the same
hand me downs every day
up through eighth grade.
If your brother's friends
go to the same school as you
and he wears a shirt one day
and then the next day
you're wearing a shirt
he was wearing the day before,
it becomes kind of hard to hide,
and it becomes kind of
hard for kids to miss.
And you know what's crazy is that
everyone else can live in
the same projects with you.
They could live in the
same neighborhood with you,
but for some reason every time
they walk to the bus stop,
they look fresh.
They still have a brand new jacket,
they still have good shoes,
they're dressed well and you're not.
And then you start to question,
what am I doing differently?
What am I missing, what am
I lacking that they have?
(moody blues music)
I always felt like other people loved me
more than I loved myself.
(moody music)
Every time someone would talk about me,
I would be confused,
people would say things
and it's like, who are they talking about?
Then every now and then, like
a teacher would pull me aside
and say something to me at
the time which was cryptic,
they say, "You know,
Henry, you're very talented
"and we don't want you
to throw that away."
and my response would be
like, "Cool, me neither.
"So, see you later."(laughs)
I didn't know what they were poking at.
Some people wanted me to go into acting,
people wanted me to, I had
a teacher at Juilliard,
who was pushing me to
audition at Juilliard,
because of a summer theater program I did,
and I had so many people saying
"You should do this, you should do this."
My response was, "I might."
I just for some reason,
I just didn't care.
There were other things that
were on my mind stronger.
There was so much more danger.
There was the danger that
I never knew was around
started coming for me.
My little brother texts me and says,
"Yo, I just got robbed on our porch."
I get up out of class, I rush down there,
I go, I get a gun from my boy.
And I run down, we go around
looking for this person,
because now he knows where I live.
He's gonna come back, so
then I call other people
we go start looking for him.
And I go back to class the
next day and the teachers like,
"Oh, well you shouldn't just get up
"and come out of class like
that in the middle class."
And I'm like, "Somebody
pulled a gun on my brother.
"I don't really care about
my English paper right now."
I felt like everyone I knew
was in danger all the time.
If I left my post who was
gonna to protect them?
I don't know, it's
easier to leave your post
when you feel like everything's okay.
If you feel like you leave your post
and someone's gonna die.
It's a scarier thought
like how many people
will go to college if they thought
that their sister or brother will get shot
with them not being their?
College wasn't as important.
I didn't know what theater was
for me at the time actually.
I don't think I knew it was important.
I didn't know what was important to me.
At that point in time, it was my fix
and what other people saw as my talent
and as a bargaining card for success,
I just saw as my fix.
Everyone was going to college,
everyone was applying for
colleges and discussing,
"Oh, I'm going to Temple
University, I'm going to NYU
"Henry, where are you going?"
But when people were asked
me where I was going,
I had no idea.
And that's because I had
no idea who I wanted to be.
I had two personalities that
were supposed to be joined into one
But my, I was split.
I didn't know how I wanted to be.
I didn't know who I was supposed to be.
I never did it because I thought I'd be
a professional at it one day.
I did it for myself.
And then when everyone went to college,
I had no direction.
I didn't feel worthy.
I didn't feel like I deserved it.
I felt like I deserved a new Haven.
My favorite book when I
was in elementary school,
I read this book called "Nightjohn"
about this this slave who
you know what I'm saying
in his circumstances,
would rebel against
against everyone around him
'cause he would teach
the slaves how to read
and he will run and help him escape.
And I wanted to be
Nightjohn so bad, you know,
I wanted to be able to just rebel
against everything that I should be,
Nightjohn should be a slave,
he shouldn't be able to read.
He should listen to his masters
and I just wanted to rebel against that.
I wanted to be the best,
the best person at where I was
and lead them into the next phase.
I wanted to be that so bad.
I thought that was coolest thing ever.
Renegade, that name was
a originally given to me,
by my brother, my little brother, Solomon.
The name means to defect or to betray,
to leave one group and become a soloist,
so to leave one group and to join another.
He originally gave me that name because
I never wanted to be
exactly like everyone.
So then my little brother said to me,
"So you kind of like a renegade?"
And I was like, "Yeah, that's right."
I had to find some type of way
to name what I was doing positively.
Sooner or later, though, that name
began to mean something very different.
I had this dream of this
guy, this powerful guy,
with no face,
chained in this room,
locked up with a chain and a skeleton key
hanging around his neck.
And this was the key to let himself free
but he sat inside this room
and just cried and cried and cried.
He had a key to himself
free, but he didn't.
He was afraid to.
Somehow I began to associate
that person with Renegade.
Kind of like my Jekyll and Hyde.
It wasn't what I wanted it to be.
Renegade was supposed to be the thing
that wasn't afraid of the streets.
He was supposed to be the thing
that wasn't afraid of
people doing him harm.
The person that wasn't afraid to succeed.
But instead, Renegade became
a name for violence.
He became a symbol for apathy,
apathy for life.
And the more I said the name
the less I wanted to be Henry.
The double life thing probably started,
once I became afraid of where I lived.
If the thing that rules
your neighborhood is fear,
then you do well there
and you either do well at being afraid,
or you do well at making
other people afraid of you
so that you have less people to fear.
And at first, I did very
well at being afraid.
I did really well at being afraid.
I remember being at the bus stop one time
and I was in like fifth grade.
And I remember some kid saying,
"Oh, I'm gonna fight you,
I'm gonna fight you."
And I did not wanna fight.
I didn't know how fight.
In fifth grade, I was
real skinny, awkward,
my ears was huge.
They're probably still
a little big right now.
But you know, I didn't know how to fight.
So I remember trying to
worm my way out of this
and asking everybody,
you know what I'm saying,
"What do I do?
"I don't wanna fight him,
I don't wanna fight him."
And I remember somebody standing
me up straight and saying,
"Listen, you don't want niggas
to think you're a pussy.
"If you don't want them to think that
"then you have to fight him."
Ronda won.
And I remember coming
to this realization like
that there is no escape.
There's no escape from it.
If you want to escape, you have
to make them afraid of you.
I became slightly addicted
to taking things from other people.
Even if it was I'm just
taking their dignity
and a horribly violent way.
When it came to me targeting people.
I think, to me, my main enemy first
was people who I thought were
gonna put me in harm's way.
Any person who that was was a target.
But mainly it was black people.
I mean, to be honest, I mean,
a few Puerto Rican people
like it's New Haven.
So the colors that separated
people were mainly gang colors.
That defined you almost
as much as race did.
We divided ourselves in
our own little subculture.
And that is how I was able
to divide people in my mind.
So I had enemies based upon their faction,
and most times they were
black and Puerto Rican.
The second enemy for me personally,
I think this was a personal thing for me
and a couple of people who I knew
were people who are of
a higher class than us.
The thing about New Haven is
New Haven can be broke on
one side of the street,
one side of the street, houses boarded up,
naked babies running around,
crack noodles everywhere.
Liquor store and corner store
and a church for some reason
on every corner, right?
You go 10 minutes up the street, mansions.
Why are there mansions,
if I live in a project
down the street from you?
And you think you can walk?
You think you can walk
through these projects,
and you gonna be street
when you got a mansion?
Okay, that's what made
you my enemy right there
is you're gonna live life to the fullest
right next to me when I'm
in a projects, really?
That's what you're going to do?
So for me that made them a target.
And I didn't care what race you were.
I didn't care, that's not
what made life unfair.
The thing that made life
unfair was who had the power.
And either you have power through a gun
or you have power through cash.
And if you had power through cash,
I was a little more angry at you.
So if I could use that same
fear that was used on me on you,
then that's your fault.
That's really what I thought.
And if I saw weakness in other people
that I once had to myself,
it made me hate them.
It made me hate them because
I was weak at some point
and I felt like it was
my fault for being weak.
So I don't know.
Don't be weak.
It's your fault for being weak.
(upbeat music)
You know, I remember being
downtown a lot in high school
and watching Yale students
ride by on their bikes,
and they'd be going from class to class
from restaurant to restaurant,
enjoying life laughing,
smiling all the time,
walking in front of traffic.
And no matter where we
were, for some reason
us as kids, it'll be a group my friends
we'd be like 10 of us.
We were a problem.
The police would come over
and they won't want us in a group.
You gotta move here.
You have to do this.
This is school property.
But Yale's never had a problem.
They were going to a great
school, they had great clothes.
They just were happy all the time.
And I felt like it was something,
I remember feeling like
this is something that
they didn't deserve,
you didn't earn this.
I remember feeling that and
I remember feeling angry.
And then I started to catch a pattern.
Whenever I would walk
with my friends downtown,
it'd be a group of five, 10 of us,
you know, wearing all black hoodies.
And if they saw us coming,
they would cross the street.
And at first, I didn't
really take notice to it.
But after a while, I started to recognize
this look in their eyes.
It was this look of fear.
It was this expression of fear.
And for some reason,
my power was greater than
theirs at that moment.
And these are the same people
that are going to one
of the top universities.
And I'm more powerful than you right now
because you're afraid of me.
I was able to take their pride.
One, just because of how I looked.
If I could take your pride
you know, what else can I take?
Not only can I take your pride
but I can take your bike.
If I can take your bike,
I can take your phone.
If I can take your phone,
I can take your cash.
And if I can do that,
then I'm more powerful than you.
I have control now.
And it's an addictive feeling.
You don't have control over
anything else in your life
but you have control over this person.
What's funny is, it's never
actually about the money
'cause you can't take enough from someone
to the point we'd be
able to live off of it.
It's never about the money,
it's about the control.
You have to somehow make it so that
you feel sane where you are,
so that you feel like I'm in
the best situation possible.
I did that in school
by getting good grades.
I did that in the streets
by inflicting fear when I
needed to where I needed to
and materialistically I did
it from taking from people.
It made me feel like I had
control over my own situation.
I remember another time
when there was a kid downtown
who had said something
to one of my friends
and someone comes from behind him.
One of my friends comes from behind,
and I don't even know if
this kid said something
along the lines of
"Watch where you're going."
And that was enough,
that was enough challenge.
One of my friends come
behind and smacks this kid.
You know like, right hook to
the right side of his face
from behind.
And the rest of us come in and
just start unloading punches
and kicks on this guy.
And we feel powerful
because we're able to
make one person cower.
And this was actually a
kid that was pretty big,
he wasn't a small kid.
And he's on the ground and we kick him
and we punch him and in these moments,
everything's happening so fast
that you don't wanna miss your chance
to be a part of the event.
You don't want to miss your
chance to prove to other people
that when something happens,
when something goes down,
you'll play your part.
And inflicting pain on a stranger is
it can be thrilling
and it can be exciting.
Everyone around you is watching.
You hear the crowd reacting and it's like
you almost feel like a
gladiator in a coliseum.
(acoustic blues music)
You know relating to Tybalt was probably
one of the easiest
characters I've ever played.
I felt like he was me.
He said some of the things I would say
except in Shakespearean dialect of course.
He was me, Tybalt was angry and aggressive
but only out of pride,
only out of this desire to
have what you don't have,
and to go and get that at any cost.
And I immediately saw the resemblance,
I saw the similarities
between myself and Tybalt.
That we'd be willing to hurt other people
and hurt ourselves
to hold on to a piece of dignity
or a piece of pride or reputation.
Something that I think
Shakespeare stories,
something that they do
is he talks about pain,
I feel like in such a way
that I was able to relate to.
He didn't sugarcoat anything.
When I was able to
transfer like translate it
and understand the language,
suddenly this dude was
reading out my diaries,
it sounded like, you know,
and he was speaking about things
that everyone is going
through and no one listens to.
Then it stops being a play.
He stops being a character.
He starts being a reflection of your life.
You focus on on walking in their shoes
and breathing in their
shoes and feeling emotion
from their perspective.
If there's no other way to forget
what you're going through
that's the way right there.
Acting in front of
hundreds, maybe thousands.
Such a powerful classical
piece with people
who are considered the cream of the crop
in the acting world,
and me coming from Co-op High School,
you know what I'm saying,
coming from New Oroville.
It was real man.
I felt easily like the most
important person on the planet.
After Romeo and Juliet was over,
I had so much idle time
and I lost contact with Henry.
I just had way too much
time to be Renegade.
I felt like I didn't fully belong
in a world where people
thought I was a great actor,
I was a great student,
'cause I didn't believe that about myself.
I didn't wanna go back to a world of fear,
paranoia and violence.
And I had no one to tell about it.
I was always looking to
reach out to anybody.
I just had to wait for the right person,
and it had to be someone
who wasn't proud of me on either side.
It couldn't be someone who
was proud of me in the streets
and it couldn't be someone
who was proud of me
in the world of theater or
school or anything like that.
I remember I met this girl
'cause it was always a
girl who liked me whatever.
And I remember calling her
and her thought was, "Oh, I like Renegade,
Oh, he's gonna call me blah, blah, blah."
So she's all happy and everything.
And I remember calling her
and talking to her for a few minutes.
And I remember trying to vent to her
to tell her my situation.
I remember trying to tell her,
"Sometimes I don't wanna live anymore.
"Sometimes I wish that all
I can do is be on the stage.
"I'm afraid that people
are trying to kill me.
"And I need help."
And I never said that sentence before.
I never said that to anybody.
And this was a nobody
girl, this was a nobody.
But I had to reach out to someone.
I said, "And I need help."
And I remember her reaction being,
"Oh okay, I gotta go, this is weird.
"You should call the police.
"I don't know, but I'll text you."
And when a girl says that,
you already know what that means.
She's not gonna text you.
She's not gonna call you.
That means, leave me alone,
don't call me no more.
You did something to weird me out.
And I remember hanging up the phone
and feeling so alone
and feeling like I didn't
belong in either world.
And I remember going upstairs
into my room and I had kept
a gun inside of a book bag
that was inside of another bag
that was inside of this box.
And I remember going
upstairs and taking a gun
and staring at the barrel for a long time.
And the way a gun trigger works
is you pull it a little bit
and all this power and
fury unleashes all at once.
And I remember debating,
could this end anything?
Could this help me
belong in a better place?
'Cause I didn't feel
like I belonged anywhere
and I did not like my life to the point
where I wanted it to end.
And I pushed the thought
away and I put the gun back.
And I didn't talk to anyone about that.
But then I remember leaving
and hoping that someone would
kill me for some reason.
And whenever there was a time
where I thought somebody
was gonna be doing
something stupid I went.
(upbeat music)
Actually in the wintertime,
there's a term that
everybody in New Haven anyway
that on behalf of wintertime
they call it grimy season.
They call it grimy season
because during those months
when it starts to get cold
and it starts to get dark early,
everyone becomes a little bit more bitter,
everyone becomes a little more violent.
The chance of you getting
robbed increases dramatically,
the chance of someone doing
a home invasion in your house
increases dramatically.
It's dark earlier, it's easier
for people to do crimes.
And you can feel the
transition into grimy season.
There was such an influx,
like an increase in
violence in New Oroville.
I remember this one time
we were walking up shouting
and we ran into this old guy who we knew
who used to be really well known.
He's just this old man.
He had a funny voice, really raspy voice
and he had a cane all the time.
And we ask him, "Yo what's
going on, like what happened?"
And he says, "Yo, these
three kids, they came up
"and I'm a old man and they they rob me
"and after I gave them everything I had,
"they still started beating me,
"they still started beating on me."
And me and my friends we're
surprised like, "What?"
'Cause this is someone who
no one really messes with
you know, he's an old guy,
everyone knows him around the neighborhood
and like who would do that?
And he was kind of telling us he's like,
"Yo, listen, y'all need to watch out,
"y'all need to be careful out here."
And he kept warning us about that.
As the violence increased in the Ville,
I expected it for there always to be
someone ready to attack me,
someone ready to hurt me.
And it's like every couple
weeks or every few days
you hear story about someone
who you knew that got shot,
you hear someone that you
knew that got cornered
and jumped and beat
down by multiple people.
You hear stories about and
these are innocent people,
some of them are bangers,
some of them were criminals.
But it seems like everyone
was a target at this point in time.
It felt like a quiet night initially.
It was cold, dry.
Like a typical winter night,
real starry, I remember that.
Bus ride wasn't but four
minutes from downtown
to get to my bus stop
which was on Munson Street
and Dixwell Ave.
I usually get off right there.
I hopped off and my boy
D-Eazy was waiting for me,
one of my little brother's friends.
Nice kid, wasn't involved
in anything crazy,
not involved in any criminal activity.
He was just a nice kid
that I liked to chill with.
I hopped off the bus and
D-Eazy is all happy to see me.
He's dancing at the bus
stop,(laughs) looking crazy.
This was one of those 'cause
no matter where he was at,
he was always getting liked all the time.
I meet up with D-Eazy and
he starts telling me about
this day that he had.
He starts telling me about
this girl that broke his heart.
That's usually what we talked about,
you know, girls that broke his heart.
And during the first
few steps down a block,
it just felt like a normal night,
we felt good, we felt safe.
And then we spotted these four boys
and there's a certain
dress that people have
when you know that they're out robbing.
It's like standard, it's a black hoodie.
All black hoodie, hood up,
a black ski mask, dark pants
and sometimes they have some gloves on.
And when I see people wearing this outfit,
I know that they're robbing.
They are dressed in a certain way
where no matter how you describe them,
the police won't be able
to narrow them down.
I see these four people,
they're probably maybe like
20, 30 feet in front of me
and I'm walking from Munson up
to Division by Moe's Market.
And I see them and they're walking slow.
I tap my boy D-Eazy and I say,
"Yo, look, they robbing people,
"you know what I'm
saying, they're juxing."
So I say, "Yo, listen,
"let's just take this right over here."
I think it was Gibbs Street.
So we take that right and we
start cutting down that block
in my hopes to avoid them.
I see these boys, they turn
around, they look back,
they see that we turned down Gibbs Street
and now we're not behind them
and they make an about-face,
they make a straight U-Turn
and come back and start speed walking,
they start increasing their speed.
So I know now they're targeting us.
And at this point in time,
you know that there's gonna
be one of two inevitables.
You have to run away or
you have to face them
and either deal with whatever harm
they're going to put towards
you or fight them off.
So I know that there's no way out of this.
I start walking a little bit faster
and what's crazy is my house is not even
a five second, 10 second walk.
I didn't stop at my house.
I knew if I would have went to my house,
while these guys are behind me,
they would have known where I live.
They would have known
where my family lived
and I didn't wanna bring that danger
to my family, to my house.
So I keep walking down Shelton Avenue
and they start speed walking faster.
At this point, D-Eazy is
getting extremely nervous
and he starts tapping me saying,
"Yo listen, they following
us, they following us man,
"we gotta run, we gotta run."
And in my mind, I'm
contemplating what to do.
Because for me running
means I've been defeated,
running means that they've
been able to instill fear in me
and they were able to take my pride.
I know it sounds dumb and
it doesn't sound like much
but that was the main thing.
That was the most important thing to me.
Most important thing to me
was my dignity, was my pride,
was my control over myself.
Because I know D-Eazy
isn't someone who wanted
to live a life of crime.
I know he was someone
that didn't want to be
involved in violence.
I thought it would be
unfair for me to turn around
and face them and involve him in that.
I wanted to face that harm alone,
I wanted to face that danger alone.
He didn't need that pride,
he didn't need that.
So I tell him, "Listen, run."
I told him, "Run."
D-Eazy starts booking
it fast down the street.
I turn around and I
start walking up towards
these four kids that are all blacked out.
The first thing I say, I open my arms
and I say, "Yo what's good?"
When you say, "Yo what's good?"
that's the same thing as saying,
"Whatever you are ready
to do, let's get it done.
"If you're gonna try to stab me,
"if you're gonna try to fight me,
"if you're gonna walk past me,
"let me know your intentions
right now because I'm willing
"to handle whatever you
gonna throw out at me."
So they walk up to me
and the youngest one of the
group is short, light skinned.
It looks like he got he got
braids underneath his ski mask.
He pulls out this shiny nine millimeter
and puts it right on my
stomach, point blank.
And he says to me, "Yo,
give me everything you got."
At this point in time I have
another two choices to make.
I can decide to let go of
everything that I have,
to release whatever bullcrap cash I have
which is probably a few
dollars, maybe my phone
and then with it, my pride.
And I don't want to give up my pride.
And considering what's been happening
in the past few weeks,
everyone who's gotten robbed
has gotten beaten or shot anyway.
Why would I give up my cash
and my pride and then
still take a beating.
I know the possibility of me
getting shot is a little high
but I test those limits,
I push those limits.
See the thing about the
kid who was holding the gun
is his hand was noticeably shaking.
When you hold a gun to somebody,
when you hold any weapon to somebody,
when you're standing there
and it's your strength
against their strength
and you're trying to rob them,
it's a scary moment.
Everything is on the line.
Your pride is on the line,
your self esteem is on the line really.
You're trying to conquer another person
mentally and emotionally.
You're trying to overcome
them through intimidation.
And since I've done that
to other people before,
I didn't want someone to
be able to do that to me.
So my response to this kid is,
"I'm not giving you nothing,
I don't got nothing for you."
Now me saying that, now
I'm challenging him.
He tried to overcome me
and I'm pushing back.
When you do this, the levels,
the risk continues to rise.
He rises up here, he gave
me you know what I'm saying
he put the gun on my stomach,
gave me an ultimatum,
"Give everything you got
or I'm gonna shoot you."
And I raise it here, "I'm
not giving you everything,
"I'm not giving you anything."
So if you do want it,
you'll have to kill me,
you'll have to shoot me.
The only way that that
ends is one of us win.
(slow acoustic music)
And he has these three kids
behind him that are all
egging him on "Yo shoot him,
"yo shoot that nigga
yo, shoot that nigga."
And you can see in this kid's head,
he's having a battle inside his mind.
You know there's people behind him
that are watching him,
that are analyzing and
critiquing his power,
that are critiquing the
control that he has over me.
That are egging him on
that are pushing him on.
And in his own mind,
he is probably debating
'cause I'd be debating the same thing.
You know, what's worth it?
If I shoot this guy, I will
get dignity, I will get pride,
I'll get the sense of control.
But the risk,
one, you're taking somebody's life,
two, jail time possibly.
And it shows how important pride is,
it shows how important control is.
If the benefit of getting pride
is just as high as the risk
or as higher than a risk of jail time
and of taking somebody's
life, it's worth that.
In that world, it's worth that.
This verbal battle last
maybe five seconds,
but if Feels like an eternity
because it's two lives clashing,
two lives with the same struggle.
And in the heat of this battle
and in the heat of this conflict,
I'm able for a split second,
I don't know if this was
God giving me a moment
or clearing my mind so
that I can see this,
so I can see beyond my primal instinct,
my Renegade mindset.
But I was able to clearly see
beyond this little world for a second.
For a second I was able to
see beyond me versus him
and I was able to see beyond New Oroville,
I was able to see me on
New Haven, Connecticut,
and this is only for a few seconds,
but I saw a lost child in this kid's eyes.
I saw a human being that
was lacking something.
A human being that was
lacking understanding.
I saw a human being that was
confused and hurt and angry.
And I guess in that sense I saw a mirror.
I saw a mirror in his eyes.
And it's at that point that I see
the similarity between
me and this young man.
I see how we're both broken.
We're both fighting for control
that we are lacking in our lives.
I see how we're both the same
in that brief second
and then the gun went off.
A lot of people asked me
if I saw a white light
and the response that I give to people is,
at that point in my life,
there's no way I would have been seeing
a white light at all and
that's just being honest.
There would have been no
white light coming for me.
(slow blues music)
During the coma, I think
the thing I remember most
was my dad coming to visit me.
See, like, I've never seen
my dad cry before this,
and in a coma, everyone thought
that I couldn't hear them
but I heard everything to the point
where I came back to
people after I woke up
and I told them what they said.
My dad came in, teary eye and he said,
"How you doing H?
"You're gonna get out of here soon,
"everything's gonna be fine."
And then I remember him sniffling
and sang, "I love you so much son."
I never felt closer to my dad
than at that point in time.
I couldn't hug him, I couldn't touch him,
I couldn't tell him I heard him
but I never felt closer to my dad.
And what's weird is the thing
that allowed that to happen was a bullet.
They changed my name from Henry
Green to Stanley Galbraith
because the kid who shot me
was running around still,
they thought that he might
come into the hospital
to finish me off.
So they literally said
we're gonna choose a name
that sounds really white,
so that no one thinks
it'll be you in the charts.
During that entire time, the
doctors were really just trying
to figure out a way for me to stay alive.
My femoral artery had
been singed by the bullet,
the night of and when they
were doing surgery on me,
it actually popped, it popped open.
And a femoral artery is one of
the much larger arteries in your body
so I lost so much blood.
Actually that night or
those first three days
when they're trying to save my life,
I had actually flatlined three times.
So three times total my heart stopped.
They told me that they gave me a total of
I think 42 units of blood.
So a unit of blood is like
the little IV bags of blood
so 42 units is enough to fill
the body a couple of times.
That's how much blood I lost.
All the blood loss took
a toll on my intestines
because the blood from my
femoral artery was coming up
to make sure my intestines
were getting oxygen
and getting life and when the
doctors I had opened me up,
they told me later that they
smell something rotting.
It smelled like garbage and
the thing that was rotting
was actually my intestines.
They were rotting inside my body.
I heard one doctor say, they
actually walked up to my mom
and they said, "I'm so
sorry for your loss."
Of course, I'm still alive
but they thought that I was gonna be gone.
They started coming in and telling her,
"Listen, you have to let go of your son."
There was this one doctor
who kept telling her
that "You have to let go,
"you can't keep holding
on to him like this."
And the sad thing is about to be over
after I began learning who I was,
but I wasn't gonna give up there.
I remember the week when I had to learn
how to sit up by myself.
I felt like an infant.
I didn't have the abdominal
strength to be able to sit up
'cause I've been laying down for months.
Imagine when you first wake up
from just sleeping overnight
when you first sit up
you're a little bit dizzy.
Imagine laying down and sleeping
for two to three months.
The dizziness is unreal.
I had a practice first
sitting up a little bit.
A little bit for each day.
I would sit up for maybe
5, 10 minutes a day
just to get the strength to sit up.
And they had to stand
me up after a few weeks
and I took my first couple of steps,
steps that they didn't think
I was gonna be able to take.
Sooner or later,
I was able to get myself
around in a wheelchair.
And at that point in time,
they had moved me over to Gaylord Hospital
and here, I really
started my rehabilitation.
I had to learn how to get
around the house again,
I had to learn how to walk.
I had to learn how to get out
of my bed and into a walker.
So I came from being this
powerful, strong feared Renegade
to walking around with a walker
with a colostomy bag.
Really sharp contrast,
really humbling.
(guitar music)
I spent a couple months
at Gaylord Hospital
and then I was finally taken home.
Still with no intestines,
some intestines enough to have a colostomy
but not enough to eat.
So I was I was attached to
this bag which is called TPN.
Total parental nutrition I
think is what TPN stands for
and this is bag of white
fluid that they hooked up.
I had wires connected all over me,
I had a tube for my own colostomy bag,
I had another tube that basically fed me.
It was this huge white IV bag
that gave me all the nutrition I needed.
I had a tube for all my IV fluids
because nothing I drank, stayed down.
Anything I drink came in and
came out the colostomy bag.
As a matter of fact,
I would test this by drinking Kool-Aid.
So I would take a red cup of Kool Aid,
even though red isn't a flavor.
It was red Kool-Aid, I would
drink it and in 30 seconds,
you'd see red start coming
out of my colostomy bag.
Anything I ate I couldn't
hide from anybody.
I went to go visit the doctor
to ask them how I was doing.
How I was gonna get out of the situation
'cause at this point in time it was,
this is how my life was
going to be forever.
Just medicine and IV bags
and walking around the house in a walker.
That was gonna be the reality of my life.
And I remember being
referred to this hospital,
Georgetown University
Hospital in Washington DC.
So we took the train down there,
and the doctor gave me a projection
of how long I was gonna live
after taking a series of tests.
They said, "You probably
have about five good years."
They told me that there was a chance
for me to get a transplant
an intestinal transplant
which is incredibly rare.
You know you hear about heart transplants,
liver transplants and kidney transplants.
Intestinal is weird,
that's a strange and unique transplant.
So they put me on a list
and the only thing I could do is wait.
I waited and I got stronger and stronger
and healthier and healthier
despite what doctors thought might happen.
Of course I was still dying slowly
but my physical strength was coming back.
And I had one false alarm actually.
One day they had called me and they said,
"Hey, we have a transplant for you."
So they put me in his
private plane, we flew over,
I got to the hospital, I got to my gown.
They took all these tests and
then they walk into the room
and told me, "I'm sorry,
"but this transplant doesn't match you."
Man I flew back to New Haven heartbroken.
And this next time
that I went to the hospital
for unrelated reasons.
I actually went because
I had pancreatitis.
I had an emergency in my
stomach, that's what it was.
I had pancreatitis and
I was flown down to DC
actually it was an ambulance
drive the second time,
which is a six hour drive by the way
in an ambulance very, very uncomfortable.
Six hour drive and I'm in DC,
I'm talking to Daviya,
trying to get her to fall
in love with me.(laughs)
And then comes this doctor who says,
"Listen, we have a transplant for you
"and this one is a match."
It was my chance to get my life back.
Everything that the doctors told me
were unlikely to happen was happening.
My doctor told me that I had
a one out of a 100% chance
of surviving the gunshot wound
and all the rest of the infections
and everything that'd
survived from the wound.
They said less than 1%
would have been able to survive that.
That's a miracle number.
I woke up from that transplant,
weak but with new hope.
I got that transplant
August Friday the 13th.
It was from a young boy who was 13
from Colorado named Jack.
He was killed in an automobile accident.
And I think I've always felt
kind of guilty for that.
Not for his death but
for the fact that an
innocent person's death
gave me second chance at life.
And I certainly wasn't innocent.
And this family wrote me afterwards,
they didn't know my name.
The hospital doesn't give out the name,
but they wrote me and
they told me how Jack was,
they told me that he
was a football player.
He had a great personality,
he was popular with everyone.
He was actually a flirt, his mother said,
irresistible to ladies and
he had so much life in him.
And she said, now she feels so
blessed that his death means
that someone else can continue to live.
And I keep that letter
because for most of my life,
a big chunk of it at least I
felt like I deserved to die.
But I can't die now.
I can't give up because I'm
continuing this kid's life,
I'm continuing Jack's life.
And even though I don't think it's fair
that somebody like me is still living
and someone like Jack is dead.
I'm gonna use the blessing
that he's given me
to carry on as much as possible,
to make as big of a
difference as I possibly can.
But I always feel a slight guilt
and not only just for Jack but for...
I see a Facebook post, I see pins,
I see tweets and news articles
about someone else getting killed,
shot almost every week.
And I wonder why these
kids die and I didn't.
I'm alive because Jack,
an innocent young kid died
and I dealt with,
I guess this is called a survivor's guilt.
But there's so many people
who die in the same situation
you are and don't get me
wrong, I'm not a soldier,
but when soldiers are on the battlefield
and they're fighting towards something
and they're all on the
same level of suffering,
the same risks.
And for some reason, they come back
and so many other people die.
You question whether or not
you were the right choice.
Was I the right choice to be alive?
I think even now I'm trying
to earn my life still.
Deserve?
Deserve is a loaded word.
I think I'm earning my life now.
I don't think I deserve it, deserve it no.
But I think it can be used
and I think that's how I can earn it.
I think that's how I can honor Jack
because now I can honestly say
that I am starting to love myself finally.
And it's not because
anyone else is proud of me.
It's not because anyone
else is applauding me.
I heard someone say this to me before.
They said, "I think that
the bullet saved your life."
And when said that it made a lot of sense.
Maybe it took this,
maybe this was necessary,
maybe this was needed for
me to reach this point
for me to be able to
effectively impact people.
It pushes me to keep bettering myself,
it pushes me to make my
story transparent and open.
'Cause this isn't something
that's easy to talk about.
I'm making it my mission to talk about.
I mean, here people ask me to
lay out my biggest failures,
my biggest moments of shame and guilt,
my darkest secrets and sins.
But if I know it's gonna help people,
if I know it's worth something
then I'm willing to take that shame
and I'm willing to take
that embarrassment.
I'm willing to take that
uncomfortable spotlight
and I decided, if I'm gonna
change my life mentally,
if I'm gonna change my life spiritually,
then I'm definitely gonna
change my life physically.
One of the things they said is,
"He's always gonna be
addicted to pain medicine.
"You're always gonna have
neuropathy in your right foot.
"It's never gonna go away."
They said that, "All the pain
medicine that we give you,
"they might give him brain damage.
"He might have brain damage,
he might not return mentally."
All those things were wrong.
I was taking approximately 60 pills a day.
I was taking pain medicines,
I took methadone, Dilaudid.
There's another pain
medicine, fentanyl patches.
I had to take tacrolimus
or what's known as Prograf,
CellCept, prednisone,
pantoprazole, calcitriol.
Some medicine I can't pronounce,
some other medicine it starts
with M but it's literally.
I don't know if the doctor
gave me this to prank me,
but it's the worst tasting
medicine I've ever had.
It looks like yellow paint
and I had to swallow it two times a day.
And it is as bad as
swallowing yellow paint.
I used it to paint my
name onto a piece of paper
and it said...
See, I have a nine millimeter
bullet lodged in my sacrum,
which is pretty much like
my spine near my pelvis.
And it's not going anywhere,
it's lodged in that spot.
They told me if they remove
it, I'm probably gonna die.
So they said, "Let's leave
the bullet right there."
Actually, I named the
bullet, I forgot about this.
I named the bullet Byron,
because I realized it gonna
be there for a long time.
So I named it, fun fact
my bullet's name is Byron.
I had rehabilitation nurses
come in and tell me,
"Oh I'm sorry, you're
not gonna run anymore,
"you're not gonna build muscle anymore."
I had showed a picture of it to the doctor
of how I used to look.
And I had this great picture,
I had a six pack and everything.
And he said, "Oh, wow, you look great,
"but those days are over."
I remember him saying that,
"Those days are over, give it up."
I went home and I started
doing squats on the bed.
Of course, I could only do about five.
No weight, could only do about five.
And I was determined to get back
to where I was supposed
to be, to exceed that.
I was determined I was
gonna get my life back
in every aspect.
And I had no control over some things,
I couldn't control whose intestines I got
or how well they were
going to react to me.
And one of the few things
I was able to control was my body.
I was able to control my muscles,
I was able to exercise as
much as my body would allow.
I think the body is the greatest
manifestation of progress.
You can take someone who has
no muscle tone, no growth, no potential.
And the same way where you
can take someone's life
that has no potential, no talent.
And if everyday you push to
get to where you wanna be,
you can get there.
And every day that I'm able to get up,
and I'm able to lift,
it reminds me that no matter
where I am in my life,
I can continue to make progress.
I'm in control of how
much progress I make.
I don't knock any of the
doctors for their estimations.
It looked like five years,
it looked like I wasn't
gonna be able to run
or lift weights,
it looked like I wasn't
going to have my voice back.
It looked like my mind
wasn't gonna be right.
It looked like
I was going to suffer
from neuropathy forever.
It looked like it.
But this is one of the
times where I'm grateful for
I suppose the Renegade side of me.
The same side that's the
most destructive in me
is the side that sees no limitations
and whereas before that
was fire and anger,
now it a sees no limitations in faith.
It sees no limitations in miracle.
It rebels even against that.
I won't sprint, I won't
be able to run, why not?
What happens if I try to do so?
I won't be able to feel my
toes again on my right foot?
Well, let's see about that.
I'm gonna prove you wrong.
I'm gonna fight you on that.
If I'm able to make progress on my body,
I can make progress or anything.
And Renegade knows that
rules that were given to him
limitations such as you won't
be able to deadlift anymore,
you won't be able to run.
Those rules don't matter,
those limitations don't matter.
And I can rebel against those limitations.
I don't have to live by them.
I can be who I wanna be
and I can get what I wanna
get, despite your limitations.
So long as Henry Green
is channeling Renegade,
I think it's a good thing.
Ever since I was shot
and I was able to get
my life back on track,
I made it a personal mission to go
everywhere I possibly
can and share my story
and explain to as many people as possible
that you do have this power
and this talent side of you.
And you can use it for something great,
you can use it for something good.
And that's what you should focus on doing.
And I take the ugliest parts of my life,
mainly the parts that
I'm the most ashamed of.
And I put it out there, I make it open.
I make it transparent for everyone to see
and I explain my
transition from being there
to being where I am now.
I think for myself,
my identity is formed
based upon the environment
that I have to adapt to.
Right now, I think that
I'm at my most whole
but I've always been categorized
in some way or another.
You know that I was Henry Green,
I was Renegade to somebody
or Stanley Galbraith.
(laughs)
That name, or Stanley Galbraith
or in DC I'm like the miracle patient
to people I'm different things.
And I think I've come to a
place now where I understand
that all of those different characters
that other people see are me
and now I'm not gonna work
to portray myself as one or the other.
I think for the first
time ever since the coma,
I've accepted that I'm all
one, I'm all these people.
And I'm going to not fight
to try to be one or the other
and I'm gonna be all of
myself everywhere I am.
From the New Haven, I'm
not just gonna be Renegade,
I'm also going to be Henry Green.
I'm probably never gonna be
Stanley Galbraith anywhere.
(laughs)
But I am all of these things,
I'm all of these experiences
and it would be foolish
of me to try to hide one,
take one away or bring
one up and push one down.
It's not sides of me.
A lot of people think
it's this side of you
or that side of you.
It's not sides of me,
it's just it's all me.
It's all one person.
(moody blues music)
And I'm finally whole.
My life is all one life.
When someone gets shot,
everyone wants to believe
that either they are innocent
or if it's their loved one,
they wanna believe that they're innocent.
And it's because especially
when it's covered by a big news story,
you're able to get a full
picture of an individual.
Many times when we get a
picture of a victim or criminal,
when you get the picture of the criminal,
the only side that you get,
the only story that
you get is their crime.
Their crime and possibly a
few negative characteristics
that are meant to explain the crime.
You know what I'm saying for instance,
for the shooter, they say,
"Oh, he was gang affiliated,
and he shot him and ran."
And that's all the information
that we get about the shooter.
But for myself, and probably the reason
why so many people feel
compassionate towards my situation,
is that they were able to
fully understand me afterwards.
They were able to get stories,
stories from my family's,
stories from friends
and people who I've worked with,
they were able to get a full picture.
I couldn't just be a criminal,
they couldn't make a two
dimensional picture of me
and because of that, now
I'm suddenly a victim,
instead of simply a black
on black crime casualty,
now I'm a victim, because
you can put a face on it,
you can put a personality on it.
And the only thing that's different
that I did with the
shooters, I put a personality
and I put a face and
I put memories on him.
So now, he's a victim too.
And not everyone will view things this way
because we're all we're
all a little biased.
I know that I'm both a saint and sinner,
as is anyone else.
And I think that we have
this natural tendency
to paint someone either
a saint or a sinner
because then it's easier
to hate to love them.
It's easier to do that.
It's harder to look at the
complex picture of someone
and see everything that's great about them
and then at the same time,
see their mistakes and see their flaws.
I think Have a unique situation
where I was able to survive a situation
where I would have died.
And I probably would have been labeled
as either a saint or a sinner.
But I was able to survive and
then explain my own story.
I was able to paint a gray picture,
instead of a black and white
picture, and we're all gray.
The shooter is gray, the victim is gray.
I guess my compassion for
the shooter comes from,
I think honesty with myself.
The only reason why you can
really, truly hate someone
is if you think you're nothing like them.
If you don't understand them.
But if I'm gonna be honest with myself,
he's very similar to me.
We both were really angry and frustrated
with the situation that we were in.
We both handled our anger
and our frustration in the wrong way.
I'm sure this kid grew up in
the same type of environment
that I did, where he realized
that he didn't have the
things that he wanted
or the things that he
felt as if he should have.
Maybe he's lacking some type
of love or pride in himself
that he should naturally have
or that someone should
have instilled in him.
So now he's going out,
he's trying to find a way
to be proud of himself.
He's going out and he's
trying to find a way
to accept himself and
to take back the things
that he didn't have.
And I did the same thing
and it will be nothing
short of hypocritical
for me to blame this kid
or to to make a monster out of him
when I did the same thing.
And I really wish I could just
meet him and tell him that.
I wish I could meet him
and talk to him about everything
that he's been through
so that we could find out
how to channel him in the right direction.
I wish he knew he was forgiven.
After a few years,
I've narrowed down my thoughts
of who the shooter might be.
And from what I know,
he's in jail right now for something else.
And, you know, looking at where his life
probably is right now,
actually, all the people that
I've hurt may have shot me
or are in jail or have died.
Whereas, me five years after the shooting,
I have a full time job
and I'm about to graduate from college.
I'm married with my own apartment,
and I don't really think I'm
a loser in this situation.
I would love to shine some light onto him.
If I could, and this is what I want
and I knew this initially,
when I first said, I forgive him.
I know and I knew in my heart
that I was gonna be able to run into him
and have a conversation
with him about this.
I want to,
I know that is destiny.
I know that the only way
to start changing New Haven
is to take steps like this.
I wanna meet with him
and tell him to his
face that I forgive him.
And then I wanna help him
get his life on track.
I wanna personally guide
him and help him to do that.
I want to get therapy with him.
I'm sure we both need therapy.
Shooting somebody is probably
as traumatic as getting shot.
If I could meet him,
I would love to be able to meet with him,
talk with him and share
our story together.
I think a shooter and his
victim meeting together
to forgive one another is more powerful
than a victim jailing a shooter.
I think it creates more change.
Sounds weird, but I
think it definitely does.
The thing about New Haven,
the curse about New Haven and why
the cycle of violence
continues to be perpetuated
is there's a nonstop tit for that.
Someone gets shot,
someone over here gets angry,
shoots the person who shot that person.
Someone over here gets
angry shoots the person
that shot that person and it never stops
until all family members are dead.
Then their children do it,
then their cousins do it
and their friends do it.
The only way stops is
if a person forgives.
And I wanna start that.
(moody blues music)
I can see now that without that bullet,
without Byron, the bullet, there's no way
that I would have brought all
these worlds into one place.
A bullet saved me man.
Sometimes it's the worst things in life
that bring the greatest
and most profound change.
Necessary change.
It's the climax to the plot.
The climax to the plot makes you nervous
and it sounds horrible,
but it's needed for the happy ending.
It's needed.
(moody blues music)
It's hard to see that in the
middle of the climax of course
but it's needed.
(moody blues music)
The dude who wakes up
with the gangster face
calls me crying in the middle of night.
It's like two o'clock in the morning,
he calls me bawling.
He just keeps repeating
the same thing over
and I'm like, "Yo what's good, you okay?"
And he says, "How did you do it?
"How did you do it?
"Henry how did you do it?"
And keeps crying and asking
that same question over and over.
He says, "How did you forgive him?
"How did you change?
"I wanna change, I wanna
change like you did."
And out of all the things that
I did that was hard for me,
I had to learn how to walk again.
I had to do everything over,
really I had to do everything over,
I wasn't supposed to survive
and nothing like that.
How to get my life back.
You know what I'm saying,
I had to try to get a
professional life started.
And out of everything that
I had to fight and get,
I think that was my
greatest accomplishment
because I realized at that point in time,
and I want y'all to remember this
whenever you trying to stay good,
whenever you're trying to
continue to do something
positive, people are watching you.
And it's always the ones
that are trying to plow you
that are watching you.
The ones that seem like
they hating are watching
and they're hoping that you'll continue
being that good person
'cause you know what?
You are their last hope in the world.
You're the last shot of seeing something
actually get out of here, positive.
And in that moment, when I realized
that I cracked that heart
that had all this callous
and this pain on it.
When I realized I had broke that open,
I think that was the
greatest accomplishment
I could have ever gotten,
I could have ever received.
Because I realized that
at that point in time,
the way I live my life makes a difference,
an actual a difference on other people.
You know, I know a lot of people say,
"Oh, you're making a difference."
But I was able to see it
and that reminded me every day
that I have to live my life
like the people are watching me
because they are.
And I think that was my
greatest accomplishment.
That's it, thank you.
(crowd claps)