Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Hi.
I'm Doctor Dave Robbin.
You've undoubtedly heard of me
and if not, why not?
And why are you watching
my Ten Steps to Nirvana?
I've won the Nobel Peace Prize
for psychiatry and psychology.
On top of that,
I'm a champion bodybuilder.
I once saved over a hundred
people from a sinking cruise ship
near Italy by commandeering
an army helicopter and
piloting it myself.
I've taken time out of my
busy schedule to help you.
Together, we can change your
life for the better.
Not me... Us.
You're gonna have to do the
work, and you can.
By simply following my
Ten Steps to Nirvana programme.
I was once like you
an utter loser.
Poor... Degenerate.
I was hooked on everything.
Sex. Drugs. Drink.
All the good things in life.
But take a look at me now.
I'm the man that you want to be
and you can be, by following
the same ten steps that I did.
Because who's got time for
twelve?
All we need to get started is a
mirror.
Rule One is admission.
You have to start by
acknowledging the problem.
Some of you will suffer with
this.
Some of you are not ready to
admit the truth.
That you are an addict.
Say it with me.
And that's it.
I Am An Addict
Someone's wide awake.
He's not the only one.
Do you love me?
Don't be silly.
Say it.
I love you.
Promise me you'll never
be with anyone else.
There's no-one else for me.
Why are you stopping?
It's been months now.
John would've wanted you
to move on.
No, he doesn't.
He doesn't.
John is gone
and you are here.
Can you just put me back on my meds?
They help.
But you're avoiding the problem.
Look, I want you to try
something.
Sometimes, it helps to talk to
people
who have been through similar
situations.
And tonight, there's a group
counselling session
that I would really like you to
attend.
Okay Owen, could you tell your
story please?
Um.
I know he's in a better place
right now.
Sorry. Sorry.
I just wish I could see him
for one more time.
Sorry.
I only like the frosting.
I've never seen you here
before.
Are you new?
I only come here for the free
food
and because I've got nothing
better to do on Tuesdays.
Are you uh, taking anything?
No I'm dry.
Well, tonight I'm feeling
pretty generous.
They say we're meant to forget
them.
Just like that.
But how can we do that if we
haven't had our chance to uh...
say our goodbyes?
For later.
Listen closely.
These fuckers don't last long.
So make sure you say your
goodbye quickly.
Alright?
For later.
See you next week!
Took you long.
- This place is a bore.
- John?!
- Did you miss me...
- Yes!
Hey stranger!
I need more.
No, no look. I told you
to say your goodbyes.
Besides, this shit doesn't grow
on trees.
I have to blow my dealer... semi
regularly.
I can pay you
Keep it all. I just-
I like you.
Ok, this time
make sure you say your goodbyes,
okay?
Cause, this shit can kill you.
- Thank you.
- Don't thank me.
Nutter.
We had so many good times in
this bathtub.
John.
I can't do this anymore.
But we didn't get to finish last
time.
John, you're dead. You're dead.
You died, and the worst thing...
We can't do this anymore...
John.
Stop, stop, stop...
Why are you being like this!?
I'm here!
You miss me, I miss you.
I need to move on John.
Can't do this anymore.
No.
- No, no, no, no, look at you.
- Please it's the last time.
I need to say goodbye.
I don't have money.
You're a mess!
What you doing?
FUCK OFF!
John?
Why are you here?
I didn't like the way we left
things.
I need to say goodbye properly.
Bye.
Don't be like that.
I love you.
I still do.
I've moved on.
What do you mean you've moved
on?
You said you wanted to move on.
So I did that.
Don't leave me.
Feel better? You should.
If you've reached this point
then
you've already done the most
important stage.
But admitting your addictions
is only the first step on a
journey of
discovery and reinvention.
It's time for Rule Two.
Protection.
Your ego will try and crush you
and drag you back to what feeds
it.
Sex. Drugs. Drink.
But you can protect yourself
by stopping the destruction
by refusing to give in
by beating your ego at
its own game.
That's how you protect your
qualities.
Trickle.
It all goes away, and it
feels...
it feels...
so good.
We all have to feel pleasure
from somewhere.
Scratches and picking
clutching at my flesh.
Hoping to feel something more.
But it just felt the same.
Over and over
and over again.
Bleed for you.
Bleed for me.
It's what I need.
At first...
I thought I just wanted to feed
on blood.
But where's the pain?
Where's the pleasure?
Hell, I need to be hurt.
Some pretty boys tried to help.
Some boys tried, but not hard
enough.
Some just didn't get it.
Some were just too scared.
Disappointing.
Joining others in their
festishes
certainly was an eyeopener.
Couldn't say I was a fan of the
leather.
It would be so much easier if I
were its servant.
Its prey.
"Bleed For Me" it would cry out.
I would most definitely oblige.
Till I reached the ending
we both need.
A dream.
A desire.
But just a fantasy.
Maybe, if I close my eyes
I can keep making it real.
Keep it coming for me.
My pleasure I need
so badly.
Bleed for me.
By now, you're probably
thinking...
...why should I believe him?
Look at his production values.
They look shit.
But therein lies the illusion.
I chose this place for my video
seminar
for precisely that reason.
It's different.
How can you expect to change
if you don't change your
environment?
I've seen far too many of you
losers
slip back into your old habits
because you didn't change.
You stay locked in your games
room in Mummy's basement
and then the addictions return.
Because you didn't address Rule
Three.
Change Your Environment.
It's time for change. Change is
good.
Get up off your fat ass and get
outside
and for God sake, stop playing
video games.
Good morning Kyle
the Destroyer.
You have amassed thirty days of
game play.
Please choose your reward.
Your options are:
Bioweapon attack
chickenpox outbreak
or famine.
Please choose location.
You have selected Stockholm,
Sweden.
Congratulations.
Twelve people killed and fifty
injured.
Oh, fuck sake.
And now another
chemical attack?
This time in Sweden? SWEDEN?!
Come on sheeple, wake up!
It's obviously the government,
again.
We all know they've been
developing weapons for years.
Fluoride in the water, HARP
controlling the weather.
What next?!
Fake news.
Jesus.
You gave me a fucking heart
attack.
- What you doing here?
- I was bored
Plus I wanna know the plan for
tonight.
What did you get Abby?
Shit.
- You forgot?
- Shit!
You're not gonna win her back
without a gift man.
A pretty fucking special one
after what happened.
I'll sort something.
Kyle the
Destroyer.
For one minute only
get the acid rain and viral loot
pack
for just 11.99.
You missed three calls this
morning.
- Um, I'm sorry I was...
- No let me guess...
You were playing videogames.
You know Kyle, as a virtual
assistant
the very definition of that means
you're meant to assist me...
...virtually.
Whilst you're on my time
then you'll do my tasks,
understood?
Welcome back, Kyle
the Destroyer.
You have completed fifty in-game
tasks.
Please select reward now.
Please select location.
Congratulations. Ten killed,
113 injured.
You missed the deadline?
I needed this one thing from you
and now I get a call saying the
client has pulled out?!
Look, I'm really sorry okay I'll
get on it right now.
No. You won't.
This is strike three.
You will disconnect that laptop
and you will ship it back to me.
You will not be paid for today
and your contract is terminated.
Wait, no hold on. You can't do
that.
You are a temp worker Kyle.
On a zero hour contract.
Now I have moved mountains for you
but you need to get your shit
together.
Just wait, one second...
KYLE!?
Congratulations.
You've won a bonus
round.
Please choose your
reward.
Please select
location.
- Abbie?
- Kyle?
Are you coming tonight?
- I think we should talk.
- Yeah.
Erm, I want to.
It's just, I fucked up.
I can't afford to get you a
gift.
Just come. I don't care about
that...
Okay, erm.
So should I say your place at
like six o'clock?...
Can you, can you hear that?
Look, er, Abbie?
I'm gonna have to call you back,
okay...
Abbie?!
Fourty-nine
assassinations have taken place.
Assassination
fifty...
...pending.
By now
you might feel as though you're
about to break.
But stay with me.
Feed off me.
Let me be your guide through
this journey.
You might feel as though you
can't do this alone
that you need others to help
you.
But how can you be successful
if you need others to help you
through?
Take a look at me.
Do I look like I rely on others?
No.
You're not gonna taint others
with your addictions, no no no
no.
You're not gonna use others
to fill that void.
You're gonna abide by Rule Four.
Love your alone time.
Fix yourself first.
Jason?
Hey Jason, it's time to sleep.
Dad, I'm watching streams.
Okay, don't stay too late.
Okay Dad, I love you.
Okay.
Hi everyone, my name is Valeria
and today I'm gonna show you how
I live.
Before I start it, I want
to thank everyone following me
and thanks for watching.
Jesus said "love thy neighbour"
Jesus never tried crack.
If you've made it this far
there will now be a void where
your addictions used to hide.
Losers rush to fill that void.
Losers find new addictions.
the most popular being sex.
Nothing takes the edge off like
a top shag.
One things leads to another
what starts a bit of fun to calm
down
soon turns nasty.
Soon, you are knee deep in pussy
whatever pussy you can get.
Wive's, girlfriend's, aunt's.
Fun leads to pain leads to
heartbreak
leads to prison.
It's time for Rule Five.
Replace your pleasures, and it
is essential.
Ready
Woo!
Here's one.
Hey!
Hey you!
Um, hi?
She wants to suck your dick
What?
For cash.
Becky, are you holding that
again vertically
you savage.
Our viewers want top quality.
Turn it around.
Come on, let's go get the cash.
Hey wait!
Go go go!
What the fuck!
I didn't even get my... money
yet.
Fuck!
Why don't you just do that
later?
Shut up and eat your muffin
Becky.
You're the taxi girls, right?
We're the Titty Taxi girls
actually.
We give rides, but...
- with a little bit of a difference.
- Oh wait, wait
Let me get that for the intro,
ready?
We are the Titty Taxi girls, and
we give rides
with a little bit of a
difference.
I know your videos.
I want to fuck you.
And I don't even want the cash.
Why would you do that?
My only rule.
No filming.
No... her.
Oh, charming.
No film, no content.
Which means it's absolutely
useless to us.
You've never been fucked by me.
Slut.
Bella!?
Bella?
Bella what the fuck?!
Go, go, RUN!
What the... fuck?
Are you okay?
Shit. Where's he gone?
No, no, no, no.
I'm sorry. No!
Champion bodybuilder, remember?
You too can look like... this.
If I can go from skag whore with
blackened teeth
to Arnold fucking Schwarzenegger
then, so can you.
All it takes is patience
dedication, and following my
rules.
Rule Number Six.
Get. Healthy. Stupid.
How can you expect to be healthy
in mind
if you're not healthy in body,
hmm?
Get out, get nutrition
and get your fat ass to the gym.
Don't be a fucking slob.
Shouldn't take that shit home
with you.
It's not good for you.
Yeah, well I was stuck here
stupidly late last night.
It's called a living mate.
Till it kills you.
Mate.
Do you have to chew so loudly?
Whadaya mean what, look at this
shit, look.
That's the reason why we're sat
here hotdesking.
No it's not.
You chose to be here.
- No
- Yeah
Aww you love me.
Want a crisp?
How do you do it?
What?
Well look you should be about
fifty fucking stone.
Hmmm, dunno.
Doesn't go on.
It's like
Good metabolism.
Some of us are just...
I dunno. Blessed, you know.
Body of adonis.
I dunno.
Since I came back from holiday
that scuba diving trip, it's
just...
...just been hungry
Mate, you should go see a
doctor.
Why would I go see a doctor?
I can eat what I want
when I want.
And I don't have to do any
exercise, so...
...winner winner chicken dinner.
Sorry mate.
Fucking hell, what happened to
you?
- All that food catch up on you did it?
- Don't, don't start mate.
I woke up today
and I looked like this.
I'm taking it easy.
Detoxing.
It's all that fat and sugar in
your body.
It's like going cold turkey
isn't it.
I feel so sick.
So, so sick.
Look mate.
Maybe you should just go home,
yeah?
No.
I'm okay.
Alright well I'm not gonna
torture you
I'm off for lunch.
Come join me for a drink if you
want.
Josh?
Look, go home mate. Just take a
day or two.
Well alright, but I ain't gonna
be here this afternoon.
I don't wanna see you when I get
back.
Josh?
Josh!?
Josh, you alright mate?
Fuckin' hell, stay here...
- I need the, I need the loo.
- You alright? Josh!
I'll just wait here then.
Here, Josh. You alright in
there?
Josh?
Fuckin' hell Josh.
You needed that didn't ya?
Jesus.
Oh my days.
Come on mate!
Josh?
Holy shit. Josh!?
Josh? Josh come on!
Shit!
Take time for reflection.
Every journey home requires
reflection.
This is a time to look back and
understand
that every addiction is
different.
For me, it was sex
drugs and drink.
But you might be a freak into
one of the weird ones.
If you are
you must be absolutely sure of
yourself.
Take time to yourself.
Take time to reflect on the
journey so far
and plan for the battle ahead.
And if you are one of those
freaks
that addicted to... weird shit
like setting fires or food
take time to revisit Steps 1-6
in order to be ready.
The ancient greeks believed that
life
was made from four elements.
Earth
Air
Water
and fire.
Those who are born of Earth
are nurturing and stable.
Air. Soulful and wise.
Water. Emotionally pure.
But fire?
Those who are born of fire
are compelled to consume
and destroy.
It is their nature
and nature cannot be overcome.
I was born in 1976. The year of
the dragon.
But some say that dragons
love to watch the world burn.
But they don't understand.
There's no love in destruction.
Just as there is no love in
breathing
or in your heart beating.
It just is, or you fade from
existence.
When the leaves of the forest
have fallen
and he says their branches have
twisted
the natural order takes hold
and the organism dies.
But its body still remains
taking up space.
So the Lord in Heaven sent me
I am the cremator.
Hell is a fossil.
Hell does not rain fire.
For that is our Lord in heaven.
"Then the Lord rained down in
fire and brimstone"
Ever since I was a small child
I was drawn to the flame.
Even now, decades later
my commitment to my duty has
never wained.
For the red dragon
they rest only upon the ashes of
the wicked.
Most wonder if I just live
to see the goddamn world burn
or if I love the heat
the smell of hair
the smell of flesh consumed by
flame.
But I already told you
I have no love for it.
I simply do what I was ordained
to do.
But my time is limited.
For I was given 37 years to
create entropy
and chaos.
And now, my candle burns out.
For the water snake is here
to snuff me out.
I see it dripping
and seeping and creeping
and as fast as I might boil it
away
it returns.
The water from the sky
and the water from the Earth
"All the fountains of the great
deep"
"burst forth and the floodgates
of the heavens"
"were opened"
"and every creature that had
moved upon"
"the Earth perished. Burned."
"Livestock. Animals. Every
creature"
"that swarms upon the Earth"
"and all mankind".
The red dragon breathes its
final breath.
It's time to face facts.
The medical services are not
your friend.
They don't sell a cure, they
sell a treatment.
There's no money to be made in a
cure
it's just another addiction.
How do they get you off heroin?
Methadone.
For too long you've been too
weak
and too pitiful.
For too long you've been relying
on our services to help you.
You don't need them
the only system that works is
my ten steps.
Rule Number Eight.
Don't get medicated.
Don't believe the hype.
Gonna be a bit late back tonight
one or two more things to do,
sorry babe.
I won't!
You're a creepy little cunt
aren't you?
Your call has been forwarded to
an
automatic voice message system.
Hi, you've reached Mary
please leave a message.
Hey babe, just want you to know
that
I love you
and that I won't be too much
longer
just got literally like
three more things to do.
Then I'm coming home.
Oh, things are really moving
along now.
Yes indeed they are.
You can feel it can't you, the
electricity
the excitement!
You're on a verge of a
breakthrough
and you can't afford to stop
now, no no.
Don't you fall for it, don't you
stop.
Rule Number Nine is
Don't give in.
You've got to be prepared to
stare death in the face
Just like I did.
And there, and only there
Will you truly know yourself.
I stared death in the face...
and I decked the cunt.
Hello?
It's Janet
Janet... Yeah.
I thought we were meeting up
- In person
- Nah
There's police everywhere
I ain't risking it.
Look in the envelope.
This girl I've got for you...
she's fresh.
Escaped some medical trial a few
days ago.
Normal rate?
No, no.
She's a rare find.
It's gonna cost you Jonny boy.
Well...
You did really get me a fucked
up one this time.
What happened to her face?
Delivery.
Can I get you a water?
So...
Tell me about yourself.
Your life and that...
Quick come on!
Ray!
Uh...
I'm paying by the hour here...
So...
the least you could do
is try not to be a little cunt.
Write down
three things
that you want me to do to you.
I need to drain the beast
be right back.
Hello?
I think you've got the wrong
number.
Who is this?
Ray, is that... you?
Ray?
Tell me where you are.
Tell me where you are and I'll
come get you.
Your mouth
isn't gonna be the only gaping
hole
when I'm done with you.
Ray?
Oh my God.
Look at you though! Look.
Get off!
Come on, let's go!
Come on!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Okay, come on.
You know
I don't always get things right.
And I've done lots of terrible
things.
Truly terrible things.
But I'd like to make amends.
So...
I've given you a brand new
look.
You're gonna be so popular.
And I've removed all
distractions.
Don't use all your energy up
just yet.
I've just got a call from a
particularly
horny old man who's right in the
market
for an amputee...
It's everywhere
temptation... addiction...
it takes only the smallest split
to fall back in the cage that
you crawled out of.
You will need to avoid your
weaknesses
for the rest of your life.
It will be hard but, you can do
it
I know you can because, I have
Follow me, check the list. You
flourish.
It's okay to fail once or twice
cause you know what? Even the
strongest do.
They go back, they get weirder
their risky behaviours become
more intense
to satisfy their urges.
Do not become one of them, hmm?
Rule Number Ten
Stay sober.
Stay!
Sober!
Oh yes.
Hi hun.
Yes it's... all done.
No, I...
can't come straight home I've
got an appointment I must get to
you know how it is.
I am the world's
foremost expert.
I'll be in time to put them to
bed
I promise.
When have I lied to you babe?
Don't worry yourself about it.
Just make sure everything's
ready for when
I... get... in
Okay.
Bye, love you too.
Okay, mwah.
Bye, bye buh buh-
Jesus...
wept, fuck!
Yes!
That's a good...
Is that running?
Turn that off, turn it off!
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull