( radio chatter continues )
( whispering )
STAY DOWN.
DID YOU SEE ANYONE?
GO.
( gun fires )
( grunts )
DOWN, DOWN!
I NEED A GRENADE!
ONE STEAMBOAT,
TWO STEAMBOATS...
THREE STEAMBOATS...
WHERE ARE YOU GUYS?
FOUR STEAMBOATS...
FIVE STEAMBOATS,
SIX STEAMBOATS,
SEVEN STEAMBOATS...
I NEED A FUCKIN'
GRENADE!
NINE STEAMBOATS...
( fires )
TEN STEAMBOATS!
NO, IT'S YOURS.
( explosion
sound echoes )
YOU'RE DEAD.
KENNEY,
HAVE YOU KILLED
NO.
ANY OF OURS
I JUST SAW JOKER.
WHAT ABOUT THEM?
WE KNOW SCOTT'S DEAD.
YEAH, WHO ELSE?
THEN WE'LL ASSUME
THEY'RE ALL ALIVE.
I NEED TO KNOW WHERE
QUINN'S BASE IS.
YOU TWO,
GO ON RECON.
CHECK EVERYWHERE
WE'VE USED BEFORE.
FUCK THAT.
WE CAN FIND OUT
OW!
HEY!
WHERE'S YOUR BASE?
SCREW OFF!
YOU CAN'T INTERROGATE
THE DEAD!
LEAVE HIM ALONE.
WHAT?
HE'S RIGHT.
ONCE YOU'RE DEAD,
YOU CAN'T BE
INTERROGATED.
FUCK THE RULES.
IT'S TOO HOT FOR RULES.
I'M NOT A CHEATER.
GO HOME, SCOTT.
I'M GOING TO WIN
FAIR AND SQUARE.
YOU'RE GOING TO LOSE
DUDE, THIS IS P.K.
HE DOESN'T LOSE.
LOSE WHAT?
HIS VIRGINITY?
I HEARD HE LOST IT
TO YOUR MOM.
WHAT DID YOU SAY,
ASS-FACE?
STOP IT, NOW!
I WANT A TACTICAL
STRATEGY ASSIMILATION
NOW, GO!
SO, WHERE THE HELL
WERE YOU WHEN I WAS
KENNEY WAS THERE.
YOU DIDN'T KNOW
HE WAS THERE.
SURE I DID.
OKAY, YEAH, WELL--
YOU STILL SENT ME
OUT THERE TO GET SHOT,
TO GET SCOTT TO COME OUT?
ONLY BECAUSE I KNEW
KENNEY WAS THERE AND
DON'T WORRY, PAUL.
WE'RE A TEAM.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
AFTER THE WAR?
YOU'RE COMING OVER,
AND WE'RE EATING PIZZA
WHAT MOVIE?
PATTON?
AGAIN?
YES.
NOW GET OUT THERE
SO I CAN WIN THIS WAR.
( gun firing sounds )
P.K.'S YOUR BEST
FRIEND, RIGHT?
HE'S KIND OF AN ASSHOLE.
NO, HE'S NOT.
WITH ALL HIS
OH, YOU THINK IT'S
A COINCIDENCE
THAT HE'S WON EVERY
SINGLE GAME OF WAR
C'MON,
JUST FOLLOW YOUR ORDERS.
FIND THE BASE,
THEN GO BACK TO P.K.?
THAT'S THE STUPIDEST
THING I'VE EVER HEARD.
IF WE FIND THE BASE,
LET'S JUST KILL EVERYONE
SHUT UP!
YOU THINK QUINN
DOESN'T HAVE A PLAN?
HE'S BEEN PLANNING
THIS WAR
AGAINST P.K.
FOR MONTHS NOW.
AND YOU'RE GONNA
SCREW IT ALL UP.
YOU'RE SUCH A BITCH
RIGHT NOW.
YOU'RE P.K.'S BITCH.
I'M NOBODY'S BITCH.
I'M GONNA MARCH RIGHT
INTO THEIR BASE,
STICK MY GUN RIGHT
IN QUINN'S STUPID FACE,
BLOW HIS HEAD OFF,
SHOOT EVERYONE ELSE,
GRAB THE FLAG--
AAH!
SKINNER.
WELL, IF IT ISN'T SOME
OF P.K.'S LITTLE SOLDIERS...
AND THE GENERAL'S
BEST FRIEND.
WE RULE.
( coughs )
OW!
GRAB HIS GUN.
WHAT?
YOU CAN'T DO THAT.
WHY?
YOU GONNA TELL
KICK HIM AGAIN,
SIKORSKI.
AAGH!
( winces, groans )
GRAB HIM.
A GIRL.
YOU'RE A GIRL.
SORRY.
I CAN HELP,
THOUGH.
SURE.
YOU CAN BE THE ARTS
AND CRAFTS SQUADRON.
SINCE WHEN DO GIRLS
EVEN LIKE WAR?
ACTUALLY, THIS IS
MY FIRST WAR.
GOD...
I DUNNO.
I CAN APPRECIATE WAR.
STRATEGY, TACTICS,
STUFF LIKE THAT.
LIKE CHESS.
YOU PLAY CHESS?
YEAH, I PLAY
A LOT OF CHESS.
HUH.
YEAH, ME TOO.
HM.
THAT'S FUNNY.
BUT DON'T GET ME WRONG.
I'M SERIOUS.
I'LL KILL PEOPLE.
I HAVE KILLING
LIKE WHAT?
JUST, YOU KNOW...
TECHNIQUES.
OKAY.
LET ME SHOW YOU
SOMETHING.
COOL.
LOOK AT THIS.
( beeps )
OH, YOU'RE KIDDING.
NOPE.
DID YOU BUILD THAT?
YEAH.
I MEAN, I GOT THE IDEA
OFF THE INTERNET,
YOU GET IT, RIGHT?
WHAT IT'S FOR?
A BOMB.
THAT'S THE BOMB.
( laughs )
YEAH.
UNFORTUNATELY, IT CAN
ONLY CARRY THE WEIGHT
WHAT IF YOU BROKE
THE AMOUNT OF PAINT UP
OR FIVE?
THOUGHT OF THAT.
BUT THEN THE BALLOONS
AREN'T HEAVY ENOUGH
TO BREAK OPEN WHEN
THEY LAND ON SOMEONE.
WHAT IF YOU DIDN'T
TIE THEM CLOSED?
YEAH.
JUST PUSH THE HOOK
THROUGH THE RUBBER,
AND THEN WHEN
IT RETRACTS,
THEY GET PUSHED OFF
THE HOOK AND FALL.
THAT'S AWESOME.
THAT'S REALLY GREAT.
SORRY ABOUT THE ARTS
AND CRAFTS THING BEFORE.
IT'S OKAY.
SORRY ABOUT
WHEN DID YOU CALL ME
AN ASSHOLE?
I DIDN'T.
BUT I WAS THINKING IT.
WE HAVE TO BE READY
FOR ANYTHING.
HE COULD SAP US.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN?
DIG A TUNNEL RIGHT
UNDER OUR POSITION,
A HAND STICKS OUT
OF THE GROUND AND SMASHES
YOU'RE DEAD.
THIS IS THE FIRST GUY
I'VE FOUGHT WHO...
WHO ACTUALLY KNOWS
THIS STUFF.
HE'S USING TACTICS,
HE'S USING STRATEGY.
IN A WAY, THIS IS
THE FIRST REAL WAR
WHICH IS WHY I HAVE
TO WIN IT.
BUT YOU ALWAYS WIN.
THIS IS DIFFERENT.
THIS IS THE MOMENT
OF TRUTH.
A REAL TEST OF WHAT
I'M GOOD AT.
YOU MEAN, BEING
A KNOW-IT-ALL DICK?
NO,
HE MEANS WAR.
HEY!
YOU GET PICKED LAST,
YOU DON'T TALK BACK
TO SUPERIOR OFFICERS.
WHAT THE FUCK
ARE YOU WEARING?
IT'S A BANDOLIER.
FOR SHOTGUN SHELLS.
FOR YOUR TOY
AIR RIFLE?
BACK OFF, JOKER.
HE'S OUR PRIEST.
OUR PRIEST?
THAT'S RIGHT.
EVERY UNIT
NEEDS A PRIEST.
TO WRITE LETTERS HOME
FOR THE MEN WHO HAVE
DOES HE JERK
THEM OFF, TOO?
HEY!
WE NEED TO BE
BESIDES, THESE ARE
AGAINST THE RULES,
I WASN'T USING IT
TO CALL ANYBODY.
YOU CAN HAVE IT BACK
AFTER THE WAR.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
Kenney:
SULLIVAN!
WHOA.
YOU CAN'T BE HERE.
AH, FUCK YOUR RULES,
P.K.
LOOK WHAT THEY DID TO ME.
YOU THINK THEY
GIVE A SHIT ABOUT
I'M HERE TO TALK
TO JOKER.
FINE.
BUT ONLY ABOUT THEIR
WHAT HAPPENED?
SKINNER.
HE TOOK KWON PRISONER,
AND THEN THAT BITCH
SIKORSKI KICKED
HE TOOK KWON
PRISONER?
I WANT YOU TO FIND THEM
AND I WANT YOU TO STOMP
YEAH.
DEFINITELY.
SKINNER?
YES.
DIDN'T KNOW HE
HAD IT IN HIM.
YOU DON'T KNOW
A LOT OF THINGS.
UH...
KENNEY.
THANKS.
YOU'LL GET
A SPECIAL CITATION
SCREW OFF.
WE HAVE TO MOVE FAST.
QUINN'S NOT GOING TO GO
FOR A PRISONER.
HE'LL KILL KWON AS SOON
AS SKINNER BRINGS HIM IN.
WHICH IS WHY WE HAVE
TO GET TO HIM BEFORE
JOKER, GET ME CALEB.
CALEB?
HE DOESN'T EVEN
CARRY A WEAPON.
CALEB IS A WEAPON.
TAKE WESLEY.
I'LL STAY HERE
AND GUARD THE FLAG.
OKAY?
OKAY.
NOBODY TAKES MY
BEST FRIEND PRISONER.
HE KNOWS YOU'RE SMART.
HE'S GONNA BE EXPECTING
MAYBE YOU SHOULD
JUST RUSH HIM.
CAN'T JUST RUSH HIM.
HE'S WAY TOO SMART
FOR THAT.
BUT... I KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE SAYING.
MAYBE I'M
OVERTHINKING IT.
THIS ISN'T
THE HUNDRED YEARS WAR.
HE'S ONLY GOT FIVE GUYS.
HE'S NOT FRANCE.
FRANCE.
WHAT ABOUT FRANCE?
SORRY.
I LOVE FRANCE.
ME AND MY TWO BEST FRIENDS
HAVE A PACT TO GO TOGETHER
FOR A YEAR
AFTER HIGH SCHOOL.
OH.
THEY JUST HAVE THE MOST
DELICIOUS FOOD,
AND GREAT ARCHITECTURE,
AND PARIS.
IT'S ALL JUST VERY...
QUINN,
CAN I TALK TO YOU?
WE ARE TALKING.
I KNOW.
CAN I TELL YOU
SOMETHING?
SURE.
I'M GLAD YOU PICKED ME
FOR YOUR TEAM.
SURE.
NO PROBLEM.
IT'S, UH, WORKING OUT
BETTER THAN I THOUGHT.
I MEAN, I WAS KIND
OF HOPING YOU'D PICK ME.
YOU WERE?
YEAH.
OH... OKAY, WELL,
I'M GLAD WE COULD--
Skinner: WE'RE BACK.
WHERE'S SCOTT?
WE...
GOT SEPARATED.
BUT WE GOT
A PRISONER.
I DON'T TAKE
PRISONERS.
LOOK, LET ME EXPLAIN
MY PLAN--
WHEN AND WHERE DID
YOU GET SEPARATED?
LISTEN TO ME,
OKAY?
LOOK,
THIS IS P.K.'S
WE HOLD HIM PRISONER.
WHEN P.K. TRIES
WE AMBUSH HIM
AND WE TAKE HIM OUT.
WITHOUT P.K.,
THEIR TEAM FALLS APART,
I DON'T LIKE IT.
YOU DIDN'T EVEN
THINK ABOUT IT!
P.K.'S TOO SMART
TO FALL FOR THIS.
AND I DON'T LIKE
THIS IDEA ABOUT
THERE'S NO RULE
ABOUT PRISONERS.
AGAINST PRISONERS.
IT'S PAUL,
HIS BEST FRIEND.
HE'LL DO ANYTHING
TO SAVE--
HE'D SACRIFICE
HIS MOTHER TO WIN.
HIS BEST FRIEND
MEANS NOTHING.
SORRY, KID...
WAIT!
LET'S JUST SEE WHAT
EVERYONE ELSE THINKS.
YOU DON'T GET TO VOTE
IN THE ARMY.
I'M NOT STUPID.
DID YOU EVEN HEAR ME?
QUINN'S THE LEADER.
LET HIM LEAD.
LOOK, WHEN SCOTT
GETS BACK, I'M SURE
SCOTT'S DEAD.
WHAT?
YOU'RE LYING.
SHUT UP!
KENNEY KILLED HIM
ABOUT HALF AN HOUR AGO
IN THE FIELD NEAR
THE HYDRO TOWER.
P.K. AND I
WERE THERE.
SCOTT KEPT CALLING
FOR BACKUP.
FIRST,
I'M GONNA KILL HIM.
THEN I WANNA HEAR HOW
YOU GOT SEPARATED FROM
NOW, GIVE ME A GRENADE.
NO.
YOU'RE NOT
IN CHARGE HERE!
YOU'RE A GRENADE CARRIER!
NOW, GIVE ME A GRENADE.
YOU CAN'T KILL HIM!
SKINNER,
YOU DON'T HAVE WHAT
IT TAKES TO LEAD,
AND YOU DON'T HAVE
WHAT IT TAKES
TO BEAT A GENERAL
LIKE P.K. SULLIVAN.
NOW, SEE HER?
SHE'S SMART.
SHE COULD DO IT.
BUT NOT YOU.
YOU'RE JUST STUPID.
SO EITHER SIT DOWN,
AND SHUT UP,
AND LET ME RUN THIS ARMY,
OR GET OFF MY TEAM.
SO, WHICH IS IT?
OKAY.
OKAY, WHAT?
I'M IN CHARGE.
YOU CAN'T!
IT'S NOT FAIR!
GO HOME.
YOU'RE DEAD.
THEN FUCK YOU.
AND FUCK ALL YOU
WHO'S WITH ME?
SIKORSKI?
FROST?
YEAH.
THAT WAS COOL.
OKAY.
YEAH.
YOU?
YOU HAVE ANY CONTRIBUTION
TO MAKE TO THIS TEAM?
I HAVE TECHNIQUES.
GREAT.
WHATEVER.
SIKORSKI,
TIE THE CHINK TO A TREE.
Joker:
WHAT'S YOUR NAME AGAIN?
THIS YOUR FIRST WAR?
YEAH.
WHY'D YOU COME OUT?
UM...
FOR FUN, I GUESS.
I DON'T REALLY HAVE
A LOT OF FRIENDS.
AND YOU'RE A PRIEST?
THAT WHY YOU DON'T
HAVE MANY FRIENDS?
ACTUALLY,
I'M AN ALTAR BOY.
OH.
EVER BEEN BUGGERED?
NO, IT'S AN
ANGLICAN CHURCH.
SO...
WHAT'S THE DEAL
WITH GOD, ALTAR BOY?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
WHAT'S SO GREAT
ABOUT GOD?
GOD IS LOVE.
WHAT THE HELL
DOES THAT MEAN?
GOD LOVES YOU
ALL THE TIME,
NO MATTER WHAT.
SO?
SO, NO MATTER WHAT
YOU DO WRONG,
ALL YOU HAVE
TO DO IS ASK HIM
AND HE WILL.
EVERY TIME.
( scoffs )
GOD IS SO GAY.
IF GOD TOLD YOU TO
ENGAGE IN COPROPHAGIA,
WHAT'S COPROPHA...
COPROPHAGIA.
IT MEANS EATING SHIT.
INSANE PEOPLE DO IT,
AND I GUESS DOGS
SOMETIMES.
DO YOU EVEN HAVE
THE INTERNET?
YEAH, BUT I DON'T...
THERE'S SOME DOG SHIT
RIGHT THERE.
NOW, WHAT IF GOD SAID
THAT YOU HAVE TO ENGAGE
OR GET KICKED OUT
OF THE CHURCH FOREVER?
NO, HE WOULD NEVER
DO THAT.
OKAY, WHAT IF HE
PUNISHED YOU?
YOU MADE A MISTAKE,
AND GOD SAYS "OKAY,
BUT IT'S ALL GOOD IF
YOU JUST ENGAGE IN SOME
NO, HE WOULD NEVER.
HE WOULD JUST FORGIVE ME.
( scoffs )
OKAY.
WOULD YOU DO IT
IF I SAID I'D
YEAH.
THAT'S RIGHT.
YOU COULD COME OVER,
PLAY VIDEO GAMES,
BEST FRIENDS.
YOU'RE LYING.
I'M DEAD SERIOUS.
IF YOU ENGAGE
IN COPROPHAGIA, I WILL
NO WAY.
AND I'LL GIVE YOU $50.
YEAH, RIGHT.
YOU DON'T EVEN
HAVE $50.
$50...
AND MY FRIENDSHIP.
IT'S YOUR CHOICE.
FRIENDSHIP...
OR FRESH BREATH.
YOU CAME HERE
TO MAKE FRIENDS,
P.K. WANTS TO SEE YOU.
THAT'S A STANDING
OFFER, ALTAR BOY.
THINK IT OVER.
( sighs )
YOU'RE GONNA BE SO SORRY
YOU EVER MET P.K.
YOU'RE GONNA BE SCREAMING,
BEGGING ME TO STOP.
IT'S GONNA BE THE MOST PAIN
YOU'VE EVER FELT.
YOU WON'T EVEN
BE ABLE TO BREATHE.
Jess:
SKINNER!
YOU WANNA BE LEADER,
GET OVER HERE AND LEAD.
OKAY, UH...
DO YOU EVEN HAVE
A STRATEGY?
QUINN--
SCREW QUINN!
P.K.'S GONNA TRY AND
SAVE HIS BEST FRIEND
AND WHEN HE DOES,
SHOOT HIM.
BUT DO NOT KILL HIM.
CAPTURE HIM
AND BRING HIM TO ME.
AND THEN WHAT?
THAT'S ALL YOU NEED
TO KNOW FOR NOW.
THAT'S NOT A STRATEGY.
WHAT IF P.K. DOESN'T COME?
WHAT IF HE DOES
SOMETHING THAT
HE WON'T.
OKAY, FINE.
THEN WHERE ARE WE
GOING TO POSITION
IN A PERIMETER?
WHERE IS HE GOING
THERE'S ONLY THREE OF US.
WE CAN'T DEFEND ALL SIDES.
WHAT ABOUT CAPTURING
HIS FLAG?
WE CAN'T BE ON DEFENSE--
IF YOU DON'T LIKE IT,
THEN FUCK OFF!
GO FIGHT YOUR OWN WAR!
OKAY.
SIKORSKI...
YOU AND JESS SECURE
THE PERIMETER AND WAIT
AND WHEN YOU SEE THEM,
YOU KNOW, SHOOT 'EM.
CAN'T I GO WITH FROST?
OKAY, FINE,
GO WITH FROST.
NO, NO WAIT.
I NEED FROST
AW, MAN...
AND JESS,
YOU WALK AROUND THE BASE
AND WATCH FOR THE ATTACK.
NO.
WHAT?
I CAN'T DO THAT.
YOU ALREADY TOLD ME
TO SECURE THE PERIMETER
WITH SIKORSKI.
WHY CAN'T ME AND SIKORSKI
WALK AROUND THE BASE
AND THEN SHE
CAN GO SCOUTING?
BUT THEN THERE'S NOBODY
SECURING THE PERIMETER.
CAN I BE A GRENADE
CARRIER?
WHY DON'T I WALK AROUND
THE BASE,
SIKORSKI SCOUTS,
AND FROST SECURES
I'M NOT SURE I CAN
SECURE THE PERIMETER
LISTEN!
SIKORSKI AND FROST,
SECURE THE PERIMETER.
JESS, TAKE THE GRENADES
FUCK!
NOW GO!
IF YOU DON'T
AFTER HALF AN HOUR,
COME BACK.
Kwon: WAIT!
DON'T GO!
HE'S GONNA HURT ME!
ARE YOU?
NO, HE'S JUST TRYING
TO MESS UP OUR TEAM.
WELL, YOU CERTAINLY
DON'T NEED ANY HELP
EXACTLY.
PLEASE, DON'T
LEAVE ME ALONE
LOOK,
I WAS JUST TRYING
LISTEN, JESS,
YOU KNOW FROST
HE'S TOTALLY
IN LOVE WITH YOU.
SO?
SO STAY AWAY FROM HIM.
HE'S AN IDIOT,
AND I NEED EVERYONE
YOU CAN SEDUCE
ENEMY SOLDIERS,
EXCUSE ME?
YOU'RE A GIRL.
YOU HAVE SECRET POWERS
OVER THEM.
JUST BLOW THEM A KISS.
AND THEN BLOW THEM AWAY.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IMAGINE A GUY...
QUIET!
( whispers )
IMAGINE A GUY
HE WORKS FOR EVERY
VIDEO GAME COMPANY
HE SAYS YOU CAN HAVE
EVERY CONSOLE FOR THE REST
AND YOU'D GET IT SIX MONTHS
BEFORE EVERYONE ELSE.
SO BASICALLY,
YOU'D BE THE MOST
IN THE WORLD
FOR THOSE SIX MONTHS.
PLUS--
UNLIMITED NEW GAMES.
BUT HE GETS TO CUT OFF
YOUR DICK.
OR YOU CAN KEEP YOUR DICK,
BUT YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED
TO USE ANY COMPUTER
FOR THE REST OF YOUR LIFE.
WHAT WOULD YOU DO?
WHY IS THIS GAME
CONSORTIUM SO INTERESTED
JUST ANSWER THE QUESTION.
OKAY.
FIRST, I'D FIND OUT
WHO'S NEXT ON THE LIST
THEN I'D CONTACT
THAT PERSON AND TELL THEM
TO SHARE THE CONSOLE
WITH ME EXCLUSIVELY
THEY'LL AGREE,
BECAUSE IF I SAY YES,
NO, YOU JUST HAVE
TO PICK ONE.
WHY SHOULD I
IF I CAN FIGURE OUT
FORGET IT.
ALTAR BOY,
NO COMPUTERS.
YEAH, ME TOO.
LOOK!
COME ON.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
IF I SHAVE THIS DOWN,
I COULD TURN IT INTO
OH!
A BAZOOKA!
IT'D BE LIKE...
( makes explosion
BE QUIET!
FOLLOW ME.
THE GENERAL
ARTILLERY!
OH, SHOCK.
OR LIKE A STAFF,
IF I SHAVED IT DOWN
( whispers )
YOU'RE BEING TOO LOUD!
I'VE GOT BIG PLANS
FOR THIS STICK.
KEEP THE STICK.
I DON'T CARE.
COULD TURN IT INTO
A TRIGGER FOR A BOMB
MAYBE A BOOBY TRAP.
I'M IN LOVE WITH THIS STICK.
DO YOU LIKE IT?
SHH!
I'M GLAD YOU PICKED ME
FOR YOUR TEAM.
FOR YOUR TEAM...
I'M GLAD YOU PICKED ME
FOR YOUR TEAM.
SURE.
NO PROBLEM.
IT'S WORKING OUT BETTER
THAN I THOUGHT.
I MEAN, I WAS KIND
OF HOPING YOU'D PICK ME.
YOU WERE?
YEAH.
WELL, I'M GLAD I DID.
LIKE I SAID,
YOU'RE REALLY SMART.
AND CUTE, TOO.
THANKS.
MAYBE I COULD EVEN
COME WITH YOU GUYS
OH, THAT'D BE AWESOME.
YOU SHOULD.
BUT THERE'S STILL ONE THING
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
WHAT'S THAT?
WHY DID YOU STAY AFTER
SKINNER KILLED ME?
WHY DON'T YOU GO HOME?
YOU DON'T KNOW?
NO.
YOU CAN'T GUESS?
I THINK YOU'RE A LITTLE
TOO SMART FOR ME.
WELL, YOU'LL FIND OUT.
IT'LL BE A SURPRISE.
BUT WHAT IF SOMETHING
HAPPENS TO YOU?
OH, THAT'S SO SWEET--
( twig snaps )
HEY.
DON'T MOVE!
WHO ARE YOU?
PUT THAT DOWN!
I'M LOOKING
FOR PAUL KWON.
WHY?
HE'S MY BROTHER.
OUR MOM GOT HURT,
AND SHE'S IN THE HOSPITAL,
DO YOU KNOW
WHERE HE IS?
DO YOU KNOW A GUY
NAMED P.K. SULLIVAN?
WHO?
LOOK, THIS IS A
DO YOU KNOW WHERE
HE IS OR NOT?
I KNOW HOW MUCH
YOU AND P.K. HATE ME.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW YOU.
P.K. KNOWS ME.
( grunts )
OH... OW...
I READ BOOKS, KWON.
I'M NOT STUPID.
I NE-- NEVER...
SAID-- SAID--
OOF!
THIS IS CALLED "PRESSING".
IT'S HOW THEY USED
TO KILL PEOPLE BEFORE
( coughs )
I READ IT IN A BOOK.
YOU KNOW THAT GIRL JESS?
DON'T YOU THINK SHE'S COOL?
I DON'T KNOW WHY, JUST--
JUST THE WAY SHE
LOOKS AT YOU.
I KNOW THAT SOUNDS DUMB.
THIS ONE TIME,
I WAS WALKING DOWN
THE HALL AND SHE WAS
I SAID HI TO HER,
AND SHE THREW THESE DRY
AND HER FRIENDS LAUGHED.
BUT I KEPT THE LITTLE
NOODLE THAT HIT ME.
I GOT IT IN MY SHOEBOX
BACK HOME-- YOU KNOW,
THE ONE I KEEP
MY HOCKEY CARDS IN?
JEEZ, SHE'S SO PRETTY.
IT'S HARD NOT TO THINK
ABOUT HER SOMETIMES.
YOU EVER FEEL LIKE THAT?
LIKE YOU TRY TO THINK
ABOUT SOMETHING ELSE,
LIKE A TV SHOW,
OR A VIDEO GAME, OR...
HEY.
YEAH?
SHUT UP.
OH.
HEH.
SURE, SIKORSKI.
I'LL SHUT UP-- I KNOW.
I'VE GOT A BIG MOUTH.
AND I'M JUST SO EXCITED!
EVERYTHING THAT'S GOING ON.
WE PROBABLY SHOULD
BE QUIET, THOUGH.
YOU KNOW, IN CASE P.K.'S
TRYING TO SNEAK UP ON US
MY MA ALWAYS SAYS
THE SAME THING.
"BE QUIET, ROY!"
SHE ALWAYS SAYS
AND THERE ARE FOLLOWERS,
AND THE FOLLOWERS
AND LET THE LEADERS
DO ALL OF THE TALKING,
WHICH I THINK
IS TOTALLY TRUE.
YOU'RE A LEADER
AND I'M A FOLLOWER.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE
SUCH GOOD FRIENDS.
YUP, WE'RE A TEAM,
ALL RIGHT.
LIKE THE ALLIGATOR
AND THE BIRD THAT
YOU'RE THE ALLIGATOR,
RIGHT?
WHAT IS IT?
IT'S A KID.
A...
BIG ASIAN KID.
WHAT DOES HE WANT?
HE'S KWON'S
BROTHER.
THERE'S BEEN AN ACCIDENT.
( hyperventilates )
Jess:
SKINNER!
I SAID HALF
AN HOUR!
WHAT THE HELL
IS GOING ON HERE?
UNTIE HIM!
WHAT KIND OF A GAME
IS THIS?
GET ROCKS.
GO.
PAUL...
IT'S MOM.
SHE BROKE HER ARM.
DAD'S GOT HER DOWN AT
ST. JOHN'S HOSPITAL AND
HE GAVE ME MONEY
FOR A CAB.
YOU OKAY?
LET'S GO.
WAIT!
I DIDN'T KNOW KWON
HAD A BROTHER.
WELL, HE DOES, OKAY?
LET'S JUST GO.
SHOW ME THE MONEY,
THEN.
WHAT?
FOR THE CAB.
YOU THINK I'M MAKING
THIS UP, DICKFACE?
JUST SHOW ME THE MONEY,
AND YOU CAN GO.
SCREW YOU!
WHAT'S KWON'S
BIRTHDAY?
JESUS CHRIST!
YOU'RE PARANOID,
SKINNER!
NOT EVERYTHING HAS
TO DO WITH P.K.!
HEY!
YOU'RE NOT LEAVING.
RIGHT.
( grunting )
OW!
YOU'RE FUCKING DEAD!
AH!
IS THAT THE BEST
YOU CAN DO, P.K.?
FOLLOW HIM.
FOLLOW HIM!
HE'LL LEAD YOU
RIGHT TO P.K.
GO!
IS THAT THE BEST
YOU CAN DO?
FROST, SMOKES.
SHIT!
I THOUGHT I
HE'S GONNA SEE YOU.
HE'S GONNA
SEE YOU, TOO.
NO, HE'S NOT.
I'M GOING HOME.
WHAT?
YOU'RE GOING HOME?
YEAH.
WHY?
I WANT SOME JUICE.
PLUS, I NEED A BREAK
FROM SKINNER.
SO YOU'RE QUITTING,
JUST LIKE THAT?
NO,
I'M NOT QUITTING.
JUST RIGHT NOW,
I WANT SOME JUICE.
OH.
OKAY.
DO YOU GUYS
NO!
YOU CAN'T STOP
WATCH ME.
SORRY ABOUT THAT,
SIKORSKI.
WHAT WAS I THINKING?
SHE ALMOST SEDUCED ME
SHE MUST HAVE BEEN
WEARING SOME SORT
OR SOMETHING,
'CAUSE WE'RE BEST FRIENDS,
AND THAT'S NUMBER ONE
FOR ME.
I'D NEVER...
SHUT UP.
( helicopter sounds,
radio chatters )
HEY!
WHERE'S PAUL?
OH, I'M FINE,
THANKS.
NEXT TIME, DON'T CALL ME
FOR ANY FAVORS, OKAY?
WHERE'S PAUL?
YOUR LITTLE PSYCHO
FRIEND HAS HIM TIED UP
TO A TREE
BACK IN THOSE WOODS.
HE'S STILL ALIVE?
OF COURSE HE'S ALIVE.
THEY'RE NOT GONNA
KILL HIM.
NO, BUT DID HE HAVE
RED PAINT ALL OVER HIM?
NO.
WHAT'S UP
THAT SPAZ STARTED
THROWING ROCKS AT ME.
WAIT,
WERE YOU FOLLOWED?
NO.
I DON'T KNOW.
CAN YOU PUT
THE GUNS DOWN?
SO WHAT WAS
SKINNER DOING?
WHO?
THE SPAZ.
HE WAS ASKING ME
QUESTIONS ABOUT PAUL.
WHAT KIND
OF QUESTIONS?
LIKE, WAS I HIS
REAL BROTHER.
I WENT IN THERE,
THE SPAZ LOST HIS MIND
AND STARTED THROWING
ROCKS AT ME.
ALMOST BROKE MY NOSE.
OKAY.
ANYTHING ELSE?
WHEN I LEFT,
THE LOSER YELLED,
"IS THAT THE BEST
YOU CAN DO, P.K.?"
SKINNER YELLED THAT?
YUP.
AND THERE WASN'T A TALLER
KID WITH BLONDE HAIR
NOPE.
I KNEW IT.
WHAT?
WHAT IS IT, P.K.?
IT'S HOT OUT HERE.
I GOTTA GO.
OKAY.
THANKS.
"THANKS"?
I DON'T THINK SO.
WHERE'S MY THREE BUCKS?
Joker:
WELL, AT LEAST IT WASN'T
NOW WE KNOW WHERE
THEIR BASE IS.
YEAH.
SO, WHERE IS IT?
WHAT?
THEIR BASE.
WHERE'S THEIR BASE?
HOW THE HELL SHOULD I KNOW?
IN THE WOODS.
OVER THERE SOMEWHERE.
YOU'RE JOKING
WITH ME.
COME ON!
WE NEED THIS!
HEY, SEE THIS?
I DON'T CARE
WHAT YOU NEED!
CALM DOWN.
THANKS FOR YOUR WORK.
I'LL REMEMBER THIS.
NOW WHAT?
WE GOT NOTHING
OUT OF THAT.
DOES EGYPT 1952
MEAN ANYTHING TO YOU?
NO.
CHINA 1911?
OH--
GREECE 1967
IS ACTUALLY THE
WESLEY?
THE OLYMPICS?
( sigh )
IT'S A COUP.
SKINNER KILLED QUINN.
THAT'S A TOTAL GUESS.
IF QUINN WAS STILL
IN CHARGE, PAUL
IT'S THAT SIMPLE.
QUINN WOULD NEVER
TAKE A PRISONER.
HE KNOWS IT MAKES
NO SENSE.
AND HE'D NEVER LET SKINNER
RUN AROUND SCREAMING HIS
( firing )
( Paul coughs )
PLEASE...
PLEASE,
LET ME GO.
NO.
YOU FUCKED UP MY LIFE,
SO YOU'RE GOING TO PAY
I-- I'VE--
NEVER EVEN...
THEN YOU AND P.K. DID.
WHAT DID WE DO?
BEFORE, I WAS NORMAL.
I-- I WASN'T COOL,
BUT I WASN'T A LOSER.
NOW, I AM A LOSER.
I'M A JOKE, AND MY LIFE
IS BASICALLY OVER.
I'M GONNA BE A LOSER
IN HIGH SCHOOL,
A LOSER IN UNIVERSITY,
AND A LOSER FOR THE REST
EVEN THE RETARDS
ARE MORE POPULAR
I MIGHT AS WELL
BE A RETARD.
OR HAVE A BIG SCAR
ON MY FACE.
( coughs )
CAN YOU IMAGINE
HOW TERRIBLE IT WOULD BE
RIGHT IN THE MIDDLE
OF YOUR FACE?
OR BLIND.
OR YOUR TONGUE
CUT OUT?
THAT WOULD SUCK, EH?
PLEASE LET ME GO.
I'M-- I'M SORRY
FOR WHATEVER WE DID.
NOT YET.
NOT UNTIL YOU FEEL
THE SAME WAY I DO.
THEN YOU'LL BE SORRY.
GOTCHA!
DID NOT!
DID TOO!
HEY, SIKORSKI!
YOU HEAR ME?
HOW ABOUT YOUR
GIRLFRIEND, FROST?
YOU TELL QUINN
I'M COMIN' FOR HIM!
YOU TAKE MY BEST FRIEND
PRISONER, AND YOU'RE ASKING
THAT'S NOT HOW
YOU WIN A WAR!
YEAH?
WELL, THERE'S NO
TELL HIM THAT'S
NOT HIS STYLE!
HE'S BETTER THAN THAT!
WELL,
MAYBE QUINN'S NOT
( groans )
YEAH?
SO, WHO IS?
YOU, FROST?
NO, IT'S QUINN.
REALLY?
CAUSE IT SOUNDS LIKE
IS A BIG,
FAT LIAR!
TIME OUT, P.K.!
QUINN HAD TO GO HOME.
WE'LL TELL YOU WHAT
HAPPENED, BUT YOU HAVE
OKAY!
TWO MINUTES.
OKAY, COME ON OUT!
OKAY.
I'M COMING OUT
HA!
( grunts )
( coughs )
OH, MAN, THAT WAS SWEET!
DID YOU SEE?
NICE ONE, FROST!
NO!
( groans )
P.K.!
GIVE ME COVER!
( ringing )
( screams )
AAH!
OUT!
GET OUT, GET OUT!
COME ON!
MOVE, NOW!
NINE STEAMBOATS...
GET UP!
FOUR...
FROST!
LET HIM GO,
OR YOU'LL REGRET IT.
BULLSHIT.
TAKE HIM, FROST.
TEN.
LAST CHANCE.
LET HIM GO,
OR HE'S GONNA GET IT.
HE'S BLUFFING.
HE'S GOT NOTHING.
DO SO.
DO NOT.
DO NOT!
( buzzing )
DO... SO.
RUN!
( all scream )
HE LOVES ME.
HE LOVES ME NOT.
OOF!
AH...
SO, I HEARD YOU AND
YOUR BUM-BUDDY KICKED
IS THAT TRUE?
NO, I SWEAR.
SKINNER TOLD US TO.
KENNEY TOLD ME
YOU STOMPED ON HIM,
AND HE ASKED ME
TO STOMP BACK,
SO WE'RE GONNA.
READY TO GET YOUR
NOSE BROKEN, BITCH?
THEN YOU GO CRY TO SIKORSKI
AND TELL HIM HE'S NEXT.
NO!
( grunts )
ALTAR BOY, GET IN HERE
AND HELP ME HOLD HIM.
ALTAR BOY, GE...
AAH!
OH!
HA!
AAH!
BAM!
( fires )
ONE...
SIKORSKI!
I NEED A GRENADE!
ARE YOU THERE?
SIKORSKI!
FIVE...
I NEED GRENADES!
SEVEN...
UGH!
EIGHT...
NINE...
BITCH.
AND YOU!
WHAT THE FUCK WAS THAT?
I'M SORRY.
I WAS SCARED.
YOU WERE SCARED?
IT WAS TWO AGAINST ONE.
YOU WERE SCARED
HE'D BEAT US BOTH UP?
GOD, YOU LITTLE
CHICKEN-SHIT GEEK.
I'M SORRY.
JOKER?
( grunts )
OW!
( coughs )
YOU STILL HERE?
GOOD.
H... HEY.
YOU SAY SOMETHING?
IS THAT STORY
ABOUT YOU AND JENNY...
( coughs )
...AND KAREN TRUE?
NO.
WHAT STORY?
THE ONE WHERE THEY
INVITED YOU OVER
WHO TOLD YOU THAT?
THREE DIFFERENT PEOPLE.
WELL, THEY'RE LYING.
I HEARD THAT
AFTER SCHOOL ONE DAY...
KAREN INVITED YOU
OVER TO GO SWIMMING
AT 888 SPENCE STREET.
SPENCE ONLY GOES UP
TO 880, RIGHT?
HOW LONG DID YOU SPEND
EVEN LOOKING FOR 882?
AN HOUR?
DID YOU RING ANY DOORBELLS
TO ASK WHERE...
( coughs )
...888 WAS?
THAT'S HOW YOU MUST
HAVE FOUND OUT, RIGHT?
( coughs )
SOME NEIGHBOR MUST
HAVE TOLD YOU.
THEN THEY WERE LIKE,
"LOOKS LIKE SOMEBODY PLAYED
RIGHT?
SHUT UP!
OW!
OWW!
GOD!
DON'T.
AAH!
AH!
FUCK!
SIKORSKI.
SMOKE?
YEAH.
WHERE'S FROST?
THERE WAS A BATTLE.
WITH WASPS.
HE RAN AWAY.
YOU GOT A LIGHT?
NO.
( sighs )
WHERE YOU GOING?
BACK TO BASE.
MIND IF I WALK
WITH YOU?
WHATEVER.
I JUST LOVE SMOKING.
DON'T YOU?
I DON'T KNOW.
I GUESS.
CAN YOU DO ME A FAVOR?
I DON'T KNOW.
COULD YOU GRAB ME
THAT LEAF UP THERE?
WHY?
I JUST THINK
IT'S BEAUTIFUL.
IT'S A LEAF.
DON'T YOU EVER
APPRECIATE SOMETHING
JUST BECAUSE
IT'S BEAUTIFUL?
PLEASE?
FOR ME.
( sighs )
THANK YOU.
I LOVE IT.
I'LL KEEP IT
FOREVER.
OKAY...
Jess:
SO, TELL ME ABOUT
WHAT'S YOUR FIRST NAME?
TREVOR.
THAT'S A NICE NAME.
HEY, TREVOR,
COULD YOU DO ME
I DON'T KNOW.
COULD YOU CARRY
MY CROSSBOW?
AND YOU JUST DIDN'T
GIVE A CRAP THAT WE
I HAD NO CHOICE.
YEAH, RIGHT!
WE WON THE BATTLE.
END OF STORY.
AND NOW WE KNOW FOR SURE
THAT QUINN IS GONE.
IF QUINN'S GONE,
WHY ARE WE STILL
BECAUSE A COUP
DOESN'T END A WAR.
BUT WHEN AN INCOMPETENT
GENERAL COMMITS THE COUP,
IT MAKES IT EASIER TO WIN.
SKINNER'S A SPAZ.
WE'LL JUST RUN A CLASSIC
OFFENSIVE ON HIM,
RIGHT.
LOOK, HE CAN'T MOVE
IF HE'S HOLDING PAUL.
HE CAN'T DEFEND
ON ALL SIDES.
MAYBE...
YOU GET TAKEN OUT.
BUT SOMEONE WILL PUNCH
THROUGH AND GET HIS FLAG.
WE WIN.
BUT ONE OF US
GETS KILLED?
THIS IS WAR, MAN,
NOT FUCKING HOPSCOTCH!
YOU WANT TO WIN?
YOU GOTTA HAVE CASUALTIES.
WHATEVER, P.K.,
BUT FROST IS MINE.
IT SEEMS EASY.
BECAUSE
IT IS EASY.
AS LONG AS PAUL STAYS
PRISONER, THE BALANCE
THE SECRET TO SUCCESS
LIES IN SIMPLE MANEUVERS.
NAPOLEON SAID THAT.
YEAH?
DIDN'T NAPOLEON
NO...
HEY!
P.K.!
OH, MY GOD,
YOU'RE NOT GOING
SKINNER IS MENTAL.
HE KILLED QUINN,
AND THEN HE PUT
AW, MAN, THAT THING
WITH KEVIN WAS AWESOME,
WHEN HE CAME INTO
THE BASE AND STARTED
TELLING EVERYONE WHAT
TO DO, THAT WAS ONE
SKINNER WAS BERSERK, THOUGH.
HE WOULDN'T FALL FOR IT.
AND THEN HE STARTS
TORTURING ME!
BUT THEN I BURNED HIM
AND GOT OUT, SO IT'S OKAY.
HEY, I SAW KEVIN
TAKE A COUPLE ROCKS
IS HE ALL RIGHT?
WHAT?
I HAVE SOME BAD NEWS.
WHAT IS IT?
I NEED YOU TO GO BACK.
GO BACK WHERE?
TO SKINNER.
( scoffs )
YEAH, RIGHT.
LOOK, I'VE GOT IT ALL
WORKED OUT.
IN FACT, NOW THAT
YOU'RE HERE TO TELL US
WHERE HIS BASE IS,
IT'S EVEN MORE PERFECT.
HE WON'T LEAVE AS LONG
AS YOU'RE AT HIS BASE.
I'LL RUN A RING OFFENSIVE
ON HIM AND IT'LL BE OVER.
DID YOU HEAR
WHAT I SAID?
HE TORTURED ME.
HE WAS GONNA CUT ME.
IT'LL ALL BE OVER BEFORE
HE EVEN GETS THE CHANCE
NO.
NO WAY.
COME ON.
IT FITS THE PLAN
PERFECTLY.
MAKE A NEW PLAN!
I CAN'T.
I'M SORRY.
I'M SCARED.
OKAY.
WE'LL START FROM
SCRATCH.
THIS IS BULLSHIT!
IT'S TOO HOT TO BE
WHY DON'T YOU
GO BACK THERE?
REALLY WOULD
BE FASTER.
SAY HI TO FROST
FOR ME.
P.K.'S GOT A REALLY
GOOD PLAN.
IT WON'T WORK.
IT'S NOT GOING TO WORK.
OH, AWESOME.
THANKS.
CAN YOU BE THERE
IN 15 MINUTES?
YEAH.
UH, WAIT, PAUL.
WHERE'S HIS BASE?
THE DEAD WOODS.
GREAT.
THANKS.
15 MINUTES.
WHERE HAVE YOU BEEN?
WE...
THERE WAS A BATTLE.
WHERE'S PAUL?
HE ESCAPED.
HOW DID HE--
HE ESCAPED, ALL RIGHT?
HE ESCAPED!
WHERE'S FROST?
Frost:
I'M HERE.
WHERE'S PAUL?
HE'S GONE.
HE'S GONE, AND NOW
THERE'S NO HOPE
NONE!
SO, ARE YOU GOING
TO GIVE US ORDERS THERE,
I NEED TO GET PAUL BACK.
GO FIND PAUL.
OKAY.
WE'LL GO TOGETHER.
WHATEVER.
I WANNA GO
WITH FROST.
OKAY, FINE,
GO WITH FROST.
JUST GO, FIND HIM,
AND BRING HIM BACK.
ALIVE!
COME ON.
FROST, COME ON.
DO YOU REMEMBER
THAT ONE TIME
WHEN YOU THREW
CHINESE NOODLES AT ME?
NO.
OH.
WAS YOUR JUICE GOOD?
FROST,
I DON'T LIKE YOU.
I LIKE YOUR FRIEND--
TREVOR.
FROST!
COME ON!
BYE, TREVOR.
IF YOU COULD BE THE
MOST FAMOUS, RICHEST,
MOST LOVED PERSON
ON EARTH,
BUT HAD TO STICK YOUR
DICK IN A DOG'S MOUTH,
WOULD YOU DO IT?
WHAT KIND OF DOG?
ANY DOG.
A CHIHUAHUA?
IS THAT REALLY HOW
SMALL YOUR DICK IS?
I JUST WANT
A HARMLESS DOG.
OKAY, FINE.
A CHIHUAHUA.
WOULD PEOPLE KNOW
I HAD DONE IT?
YES.
FRONT PAGE OF
"LOCAL BOY STICKS DICK
IN DOG'S MOUTH."
BUT THEN IT WOULD SAY
I WAS RICH AND FAMOUS,
YEAH, NEAR THE END
OF THE ARTICLE.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
YOUR QUESTIONS ARE DUMB.
THERE'S NO RELATIONSHIP
BETWEEN SOCIAL STATUS
HOW DO YOU KNOW?
WE SHOULD START MOVING
INTO OUR POSITIONS.
DOES EVERYONE KNOW
WHAT THEIR JOB IS?
WESLEY?
STAY HERE.
GUARD THE BASE.
PROTECT THE FLAG.
GOOD.
JOKER?
ATTACK FROM THE WEST.
I STILL DON'T LIKE THIS.
WHAT IF THEY AMBUSH US?
THEY CAN'T AMBUSH
THREE PEOPLE
COMING FROM THREE
DIFFERENT DIRECTIONS.
THEY DON'T HAVE ENOUGH
SOLDIERS.
CALEB?
GOOD.
AND I'LL COME IN
LET'S SYNCHRONIZE
WATCHES.
EVERYONE IN POSITIONS
AT 1650.
WE ATTACK
AT 1700 HOURS.
MY WATCH DOESN'T
GO UP TO 1700.
WESLEY...
YOU'RE THE KEY HERE.
IF ANYONE COMES
INTO THIS BASE,
YOU HAVE TO SHOOT THEM
AND KILL THEM.
OKAY?
OKAY.
SAY IT.
SAY, "I WILL SHOOT
I WILL SHOOT TO KILL.
I CAN DO IT.
I KNOW YOU CAN.
OKAY, PEOPLE--
1700 HOURS!
HEY, UM...
SORRY I HIT YOU BEFORE.
OKAY.
I WAS JUST...
IT'S OKAY.
I FORGIVE YOU.
OKAY.
P.K.: JOKER!
LET'S GO!
J...
THAT WAS CRAZY
WITH THE WASPS, HUH?
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU
AFTER THAT?
I WAS LOOKING FOR YOU.
I SAW YOU.
WHAT?
SHE THINKS SHE'S,
LIKE-- COOL,
SHE'S STUPID.
SHE ASKED ME TO
HOW STUPID IS THAT?
WHAT ARE YOU GONNA
EAT IT?
GOD.
SHE'S PROBABLY
THE STUPIDEST GIRL
YOU CARRIED HER CROSSBOW.
SHE ASKED ME TO!
I DON'T WANT HER
TO HANG OUT WITH US.
SHE'S NOT EVEN LIKE US.
SHE PLAYS CHESS.
SHE WOULDN'T SHUT UP ABOUT
HOW MUCH SHE LOVES CHESS.
DO I LOOK LIKE
THE KIND OF GUY
( gasps )
BANG!
OH!
YOU GOT ME.
OH, NO, I'M DYING!
HOW COME I'M DYING
SO YOUNG?
OH, NO.
NO, PLEASE SAVE ME.
I-- I SEE THE LIGHT!
OH, OH...
MEDIC!
WHERE ARE YOU?
NO...
( groans )
YES!
I'M GONNA BEAT THEM.
ALL OF THEM.
EVEN P.K.?
P.K. AND SKINNER.
I'M USING STRATEGY.
THEY WOULDN'T UNDERSTAND.
THEY DON'T PLAY CHESS.
THIS IS THE MOST
ROMANTIC THING ANYONE
THAT'S WHY I THINK
YOU'LL LOVE FRANCE.
YEAH.
I REALLY WANNA
CAN I STILL COME
WITH YOU?
OF COURSE.
WE'LL LIVE THERE.
WHERE?
IN PARIS,
THAT'S TOTALLY AWESOME.
SHIT!
YES!
HA HA!
YOU'RE MINE!
EENY, MEENY, MINEY, MO,
CATCH A CHINK BY THE TOE...
YOU KNOW I'M
HALF KOREAN,
SHUT UP!
OH!
GOOD JOB.
IT WAS SO COOL.
I SHOT HIM THREE TIMES.
HE WAS JUST STANDING
THERE BY A TREE!
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
HE WASN'T HIDING?
NO, HE WAS RIGHT
OUT IN THE OPEN.
HE DIDN'T EVEN
FIGHT BACK.
GRAB HIM,
BOTH OF YOU.
WHY WEREN'T YOU
HIDING?
I GOT LOST.
DID YOU MAKE IT BACK
TO YOUR BASE?
NO.
INDIAN BURN.
URGH!
DID YOU TELL P.K.
NO, I SWEAR...
CHARLEY HORSE.
OH!
WHY ARE YOU STILL
LOYAL TO HIM?
WHERE'S THE BIG RESCUE?
ALL HE DID WAS
THE LAME THING WITH
HE'S USING YOU.
SO STOP PROTECTING
DID YOU TELL HIM
WHERE WE ARE?
NO!
( grunts )
WE'RE MOVING.
WE ARE?
YOU'RE NOT.
I AM.
I'M TAKING HIM
TO A NEW BASE.
THE ONE THAT WE
ALMOST USED THIS TIME.
FROM TWO TIMES AGO?
YOU CAN'T MOVE.
YOU'RE NOT ALLOWED
TO MOVE.
OH, YEAH?
AND WHY NOT?
IT'S AGAINST
THE RULES.
OH, RIGHT.
FUCK THE RULES!
READY TO GET YOUR
NOSE BROKEN, BITCH?
NO--
NO.
NO...
NO, NO, NO.
DON'T DO IT!
CAN'T HEAR YOU.
PLEASE!
PLEASE, NO!
UH--
( grunts )
HEY, AFTER THE WAR,
DO YOU WANNA COME OVER
SHUT UP.
WE'VE GOT A PROBLEM.
WHAT?
THERE'S NO FLAG.
SO?
SO, WHY WOULD ANYBODY
COME INTO THIS BASE?
IT'S DESERTED.
WE NEED A FLAG.
WHAT ARE WE GONNA DO?
UH..
SOMEBODY SHOULD GO IN THERE
AND PUT IN A FAKE FLAG.
WE'LL TRICK 'EM.
YEAH.
I'LL DO IT.
I DUNNO,
MAYBE I SHOULD.
NO MAN, COME ON.
YOU GOTTA LET ME.
THIS IS SUCH
A GOOD IDEA.
I CAN DO IT.
FINE.
YOU DO IT.
SO, WHAT DO I DO?
WHAT COLOR IS YOUR GITCH?
GO NOW!
WHAT NOW?
JUST HIDE!
FROST,
WHAT DO I DO NOW?
FROST!
FROST,
WHAT DO I DO?
WHERE ARE YOU?
FROST!
( fires )
AH!
AAAH!
DON'T MOVE OR I SWEAR
I'LL KILL YOU.
DROP YOUR GUN, NOW.
DROP IT!
SKINNER WANTS TO SEE YOU.
YEAH?
WELL,
I WANT TO SEE HIM, TOO.
SHUT UP.
MOVE.
( mocking )
BYE, TREVOR...
NOT AGAIN.
SHUT UP!
STOP.
NOW YOU'RE GONNA
SEE THE REAL P.K.
HI.
SORRY I KILLED
YOUR FRIEND.
HE WASN'T MY FRIEND.
OH.
OKAY.
YOU'RE WESLEY, RIGHT?
YEAH.
OR "ALTAR BOY."
IN WAR, I'M ALTAR BOY.
MY NAME'S JESS.
YEAH, I KNOW.
WE HAVE GEOGRAPHY
TOGETHER.
OH, RIGHT.
YOU'RE THE KID WHO PRAYED
BEFORE THE TEST.
YOU CAN SIT IF YOU WANT.
SO, WHAT DID YOU GET
ON THAT TEST?
43.
SO IT DIDN'T WORK.
SO, IF IT DIDN'T WORK,
WHY DO YOU KEEP PRAYING?
I DON'T KNOW.
WELL,
THAT'S KIND OF SILLY,
YEAH.
BUT IT KIND OF
DID WORK.
BECAUSE THEN I KNEW
I HAD TO STUDY.
SO, I STUDIED,
AND GOT A 71 ON
THAT'S GOOD.
GOD LOVES ME.
LOVE IS IMPORTANT.
CAN YOU DO ME
A FAVOR?
CAN I SEE YOUR GUN?
YEAH, OKAY.
IS IT YOURS?
YEAH.
IT'S NICE.
SO, NOW YOU NEVER
PRAY BEFORE A TEST?
NO.
I STUDY.
THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S A REAL LESSON.
THANKS, WESLEY.
I'LL SEE YOU IN SCHOOL
TOMORROW, PROBABLY.
BYE.
WE DID IT.
WE BEAT P.K.
YEAH.
HE GOT SIKORSKI,
THOUGH.
OH, WELL.
GO HOME, FROST.
WHAT?
GO HOME.
BUT I'M NOT DEAD YET.
OKAY.
YOU'RE DEAD.
YOU ASSHOLE!
IS THERE SOMETHING
YOU WANNA SAY TO ME?
NO.
YOU KNOW I BEAT QUINN,
RIGHT?
I FIGURED.
I BEAT FROST.
I BEAT KWON TWICE.
AND I BEAT YOU.
I WON.
YOU DON'T HAVE
MY FLAG YET.
YOU DON'T WANT TO SAY
THAT YOU WERE WRONG
NO.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO BE FRIENDS AGAIN?
NOT REALLY.
BUT... I WON.
I BEAT EVERYBODY.
I TOLD YOU BEFORE.
I DON'T WANNA
BE YOUR FRIEND.
OH, BUT YOU'LL BE FRIENDS
WITH THAT PIECE OF SHIT?
YEAH.
BUT I'M BETTER
THAN HIM!
YOU USED TO BE FRIENDS?
BEST FRIENDS.
BEFORE YOUR DUMB ASS
MOVED HERE.
NOW WE'RE GONNA
BE FRIENDS AGAIN,
BECAUSE P.K. ISN'T FRIENDS
WITH LOSERS LIKE YOU.
SKINNER...
LET HIM GO.
OKAY.
FINE.
KWON CAN BE INCLUDED.
IT COULD BE
THE THREE OF US.
I DON'T WANT TO BE
YOUR FRIEND.
WHY?
LOOK AT YOU.
YOU ALWAYS FREAK OUT
ABOUT NOTHING.
YOU'RE A TOTAL SPAZ.
EVERY TIME YOU LOSE
A GAME, YOU GO NUTS
AND THROW THE BOARD
ACROSS THE ROOM.
YOU'RE NO FUN
TO PLAY WITH.
OKAY.
YOU DON'T WANT
TO PLAY FAIR.
SO I WON'T PLAY FAIR.
I'VE JUST GOT TO GET
THE FLAG TO THE BASE.
YOU'RE AMAZING.
I KILLED EVERYONE
IN MY WAY.
OR OUTSMARTED THEM.
IT'S EASY.
LIKE PLAYING CHESS
AGAINST A RETARD.
BUT WHY?
WHY DID YOU DO THIS?
FOR YOU.
COMPARED TO YOU,
EVERYONE'S A RETARD.
THAT'S SO INCREDIBLY
ROMANTIC.
WE'RE BOTH ROMANTIC.
WE'RE SOULMATES.
THAT'S WHY WE SHOULD LIVE
IN FRA...
GOOD BOY.
I'VE GOT SOMETHING
FOR YOU.
WAIT.
PLEASE DON'T KILL ME.
I DON'T EVEN CARE
ABOUT SKINNER.
ABOUT YOUR STUPID WAR.
I JUST WANTED
TO GET THE FLAG.
FOR QUINN.
BECAUSE I LIKE HIM,
ALL RIGHT?
I LIKE HIM AND I WANTED
TO DO SOMETHING NICE
PLEASE, CALEB.
I LOVE HIM.
( explosion sounds )
I'LL GIVE YOU
A CHOICE.
YOU CAN RESCUE KWON
AND LEAVE...
BUT I WIN THE WAR.
YOU DON'T WIN UNTIL
YOU GET MY FLAG.
OR...
YOU WIN THE WAR...
AND I'LL NEVER BOTHER
YOU AGAIN.
BUT...
YOU HAVE TO CUT KWON.
WHAT YOU YOU MEAN,
"CUT"?
WHAT?
P.K.!
SHH!
YOU HAVE TO DRAW BLOOD.
HOWEVER YOU WANT.
ON HIS FACE.
NO WAY, P.K.--
JUST TAKE THE LOSS.
WHO CARES?
WHAT IF WE CALLED IT
A DRAW, AND YOU...
NO!
JUST TAKE IT
"A!"
WE'LL TAKE "A."
( buzzes )
WHY DO YOU CARE?
JUST LET HIM SAY HE WON.
IT'S NOT EVEN A REAL WIN.
IT WON'T EVEN HURT.
YES, IT WILL!
OKAY, JUST STOP
FOR A SECOND.
THINK ABOUT IT.
WE CAN TELL EVERYBODY
IT'S NOT A REAL WIN
BECAUSE HE DIDN'T GET
YOU OWE ME THIS!
I DID EVERYTHING
COME ON, P.K.,
DO IT.
THIS IS STUPID.
YOU'RE NOT LIKE THIS.
DO IT!
( buzzes )
WHAT THE FUCK
IS THAT BUZZING?
OOF!
STOP.
YOU LOSE.
YOU OKAY?
YEAH.
IT'S JUST A SCRATCH.
SORRY.
MY HAND MUST HAVE SLIPPED
WHEN THE PLANE CRASHED.
YOU DON'T WANNA
KICK HIM OR SPIT
NO.
WHAT ARE YOU
LOOKING AT?
A LOSER, RIGHT?
EVERYBODY LOOK
AT THE LOSER.
THE STUPID
FUCKING LOSER.
OH, YEAH?
WELL, I AM A LOSER, OKAY?
I'M A LOSER,
AND I CAN ACCEPT IT.
I'M GONNA DIE A LOSER.
YOU'RE JUST PERFECT.
ALWAYS THE WINNER.
UP ON THAT THRONE
WITH YOUR BEST BUDDY.
YEAH...
YOUR FRIEND CUT YOU.
HE'S NOT YOUR BUDDY.
I NEVER LIKED YOU.
THANKS.
SO...
YOU COMING OVER?
NAH.
WHAT?
WHAT DO YOU MEAN?
I'M GOING HOME.
I'M SORRY.
I DIDN'T MEAN
IT'S AN OLD CHINESE
STRATEGY
CALLED DECEIVE THE SKY
TO CROSS THE OCEAN.
YOU LET YOUR ENEMY
THINK THEY'RE WINNING,
AND THEN YOU LAUNCH
YOUR SECOND ATTACK.
OKAY.
YOU BELIEVE ME,
RIGHT?
BYE.
OH, COME ON, STAY.
WE DON'T HAVE
WHAT DO YOU
WANNA WATCH?
MAYBE TOMORROW.
OKAY, S-SO,
I'LL CALL YOU TOMORROW!
( knife thuds )
( whistles )
( dog barks )
COME HERE.
GOOD BOY.
SIT.
GOOD BOY,
SHAKE.
GOOD BOY, SHADOW.
( gun firing sounds )