Don't mind him.
Shit!
Motherfucker!
Fucking animal!
Kwesi!
Out!
That's so gross.
Vile creature!
- What's wrong?
- It peed at the front door again.
Kwesi, Kwesi...
Come here.
You can't pee here.
You're wasting your time, hun.
That cat is crazy, or it wants revenge.
Mum, Pedro's here.
Why didn't you open the door?
Huh?
- How did it go?
- Well.
I've got everything we need
to get this done once and for all.
- Coffee?
- No need.
Who's the prettiest cat in the world?
Kwesi, what's wrong?
Stop...
Kwesi!
Free dental care is provided
to young people and children
in different schools around the country.
What do you want?
What are you watching?
Nothing.
Delicious.
Perfect.
Why don't you turn that down, huh?
Great!
You know what I dreamt?
That we were painting my room purple.
Purple?
Purple again?
You're always thinking about purple.
I don't know what purple means in dreams.
It's an ambivalent colour, I'll look it up.
I think mauve means...
Mum, stop making stuff up.
Go take a shower, Eva.
And tidy your room.
- Are you gonna throw this stuff away?
- Turn it up!
Tell me!
- Coming through.
- Sorry.
- Are you throwing all of that away?
- Turn it up.
- Why did you turn it down?
- Cos I wanted to.
- Turn it up!
- No.
- Turn it up.
- Mum!
- What's going on?
Louder!
Calm down.
Hi, ladies.
What's with the bickering?
Don't fight.
Honey.
- Mum already checked.
- OK, hun.
Hello, yes? Hi, Flor.
Again?
I won't say it again. Go wash.
- Calm down!
- Turn it up!
- Mum!
- Eva, I won't say it again.
Go take a shower.
- What are you going to do with that?
- Go.
Flor's place got broken into again.
That's so awful.
Yeah, definitely...
You OK with her throwing everything out?
It needs to be thrown away anyway.
The cat weed on everything.
Let go of me!
- Why? Does it hurt?
- Yes, it hurts. Let go.
- Why?
- You're hurting me, let go.
- It hurts?
- Yes, it hurts, let go!
- Focus, it doesn't hurt that much.
- Let go!
What are you doing, you savage?
How old are you?
Let go of her!
We had a deal.
Remember?
I don't want any violence in this house.
She's unbearable.
Impossible.
She's possessed by the same demon.
I don't recognise her anymore.
I HAVE ELECTRIC DREAMS
Puff your cheeks out.
- What?
- Puff your cheeks out!
You like the beard?
Not really.
I have electric dreams
A pack of wild animals
Scream their love for each other
Sometimes with blows
I have electric dreams
A pack of wild animals
Scream their love for each other
Sometimes with blows.
Well?
Doesn't it have an ending?
It's a poem, not a novel.
- Is that a translation?
- No, I wrote it.
- I didn't know you wrote.
- I'm starting to.
I have to go over it.
Dad, you can't smoke here.
Why not?
I'm a regular here.
Can I try?
When I live with you, can I smoke?
- Your mum won't like it.
- So?
You'll get into more trouble with her.
She's unbearable.
Why?
- Her inheritance just came in, right?
- Exactly.
The house is a mess
cos of all the work going on.
Nobody can stand her anymore.
- Hi, Martín, all good?
- Hi.
- Can I clear your plates?
- Yeah.
Why can't I stay with you over the holidays?
It's complicated.
I've just moved in with another friend.
Again?
Didn't you take a look
at the listings I sent you?
Not yet.
It went into my eye.
I think this is my last one.
I got a new mark.
Another mark?
I think the doc's gonna tell me
I have cancer.
- I need to make the most of it.
- Let's see, show me.
Yeah, there's a mark.
There.
- Bye.
Wait, you smell of cigarettes.
Here you go.
- Better?
- Let's see.
All good.
Wait, tell Sol that...
I'll swing by
so all three of us can go for a walk
and send her my love, OK?
Yeah, I'll tell Mum.
How's your mum doing?
Good.
OK.
Dad, you're squeezing me.
- Does it hurt?
- Yes.
Sorry.
- Bye.
- Bye!
As I was saying, all the walls are concrete.
You can hang some pictures up.
There's a small room, a laundry room.
The kitchen, you could put an oven here.
The bathroom.
There's a small problem
with the shower cables.
So, when you move the shower around,
try not to use too much pressure.
Otherwise, there'll be too much water
and it'll wet the cable.
It's dangerous,
but you won't get electrocuted.
- Is it safe?
- Yes, it's safe.
- And the toilet?
- It's new.
So is the sink.
Dad, there's only one bedroom.
So?
It's small, there's no room.
Where am I supposed to go?
It works for me.
Does the missus not like it?
That's my daughter.
Apologies.
The neighbourhood, is it safe?
Yes, it's calmer now,
a church opened up here recently.
So, it's a calm neighbourhood.
Don't tell me the parishioners
are the type to sing at 5 am.
No, it's changed.
They don't start before midday.
The problem is that we like our lie-ins.
What's wrong?
Nothing, I'm tired.
Nothing else?
I sent you,
like, a thousand apartment listings.
They were expensive.
He's cute.
He looks dumb.
- Let me take a look!
- He's not ugly!
He's ugly
and he's got wannabe musician vibes.
He's hot, right?
- He has a puppy!
- He looks like he'd suit Eva.
Yeah, and he has a little dog!
- He's hot.
- No, he looks dumb.
Look, I found an apartment with a bathtub.
But look at the address,
it's not even in San José.
Get it all off,
I think I've got more here too.
- You need to wear sunscreen.
- No, it's nothing.
Aren't you going to the beach?
No, we can't.
Why aren't you going with your dad?
- We're not allowed to.
- Seriously?
Shut up.
We're not going
cos Mum's busy with the house.
- Why?
- She got an inheritance.
- Who died?
- An aunt.
- Nobody knew her.
- Really?
Nobody knew her.
Shut up.
What are you saying?
What are they saying?
Pamela blows
Hands in the air, everyone!
Its head is becoming bigger and bigger
and its nose flatter and flatter.
And it's starting to grow nasty f-f-f...
fangs!
The show's about to start, enter, enter.
The pretty girl I promised you
is at the entrance.
She's 18.
She's made waves
across the whole of America.
The mysterious space grows dark
and the window is slowly opening.
And there you have it!
As usual, she comes out
and greets the audience with a...
It really is a girl in the flesh,
just like each of you enjoying this show.
Now open your eyes, my friends...
Don't let her out of your sight
because with every minute that passes,
her face...
Her transformation will be drastic,
both physical and supernatural, my friends.
I feel like the animal's moving.
Careful, careful, careful...
What are you doing?
- That's enough. Leave her.
- Diana, don't be stubborn.
I don't wanna...
What's wrong?
You know I can't take you home like this.
Calm down!
Please.
Hi.
Did you go to carnival?
Hold on a sec.
- I want a fag.
- Later.
- What a nice house.
- No, don't touch that.
Diana, that belongs to the homeowner.
Eva!
Dad, she's drunk, I can't do anything.
You've got a beard now?
- Didn't you have one before?
- No.
It makes you look older.
I think it's cos of your grey hairs.
Thanks, Diana.
- You've got grey hairs, sir.
- No need for the formalities.
That's why you look older.
I probably do look older.
Or maybe you're the ones who are too young?
I'm going to get you some water.
But it suits you.
- Really?
- It's cool, you look good like that.
- Let's go, Diana.
- In a bit...
- I'm talking to you.
- Wait till she's feeling better.
Get up!
- I think I'm gonna throw up.
- No, no!
Stop.
You like my boobs?
Lift your arm up.
You like them?
Here.
Bicarbonate and lemon for the nausea.
Stay over there.
Diana's right.
I should shave.
What's up with you?
Funny that you guys are so close, huh?
Why?
I don't know,
I've always found her a bit more...
A bit more what?
Kind of loose.
Where were you?
Why are you dressed like that?
Diana's mum called last night.
Where did you sleep?
Tell me the truth, where did you sleep?
- What's with all the questions?
- I just want to know.
Kwesi!
When were you going to tell me
where you were going to sleep?
Diana's mum called.
Am I not allowed to sleep at my dad's?
It's not even his place.
What's that guy called?
Are you throwing this away?
They're costumes from old shows.
I'm throwing it all out.
And this?
Why don't you give it to Martita?
No, I want everything out.
Konnichiwa.
That dress is too big for you.
You got those boobs from your dad.
Drop it, Mum.
I'm 16, they could still grow.
- You know what I dreamt about?
- What?
That we were on a beach and...
that we lived underwater.
Did you like living underwater?
We came across some funky creatures.
Like a vampire squid.
Water in dreams represents
memories of being in your mum's womb.
Which grocer's?
"La Luna ", on 300 south, 50 east.
- I put it on the GPS.
- This one?
- Are you sure it's here?
- That's what the ad said.
Can you carry me?
- It doesn't seem like it's there...
- Carry me, Dad!
No, you're too old for that.
Why? I can carry you,
I'm very strong.
Eva, stop.
You're already very heavy.
Look.
Yelina.
What a strange name.
I DREAMT OF YOU, YELINA
Are you sure it's here?
Maybe you noted down the wrong address?
I'm gonna see who it is.
Is that your mum?
Yes.
It's a nice pic.
Do I look like her?
Yeah, kinda.
Dove.
Everything OK?
Do you need beer for this evening?
It's fine, see you later.
I've got beer.
- OK, great, later.
- Hi, hope it all goes well.
Thanks.
Sandra is lending us a mattress.
Really?
But it's dirty.
If only that mattress could talk.
What are you looking for?
Money for cigarettes.
- Doesn't your mum give you money?
- No.
But she's got loads of money.
- It's your job when I'm with you.
- Funny.
Cheeky.
Who is it?
People who are coming for the workshop.
It's a poetry workshop, organised by Dove.
And you're going to take part?
Yes, he likes my work.
He says I have melancholic power.
"Melancholic".
This mattress isn't inflating,
it must have a hole.
Did I already tell you about the time
I had blue marks on my knees?
No, you've never told me.
I went to the doctor
and he asked me
if something had happened to me,
something serious, like a death,
an accident, that kind of thing.
I said: "No...
I'm in love."
Have you ever been in love?
No.
Hi.
- You good?
- Yeah.
You got a cigarette?
I don't smoke.
And a beer?
They're outside,
but I'll go get some ice in a minute.
OK, never mind.
How old are you?
- Why?
- Just curious.
Are you Anca and Martín's daughter?
Yes.
- How's your mum doing?
- Good.
- Is she still dancing?
- No, she retired.
OK, tell her that Diego said hi.
- Hi.
- All good?
All good.
Have you got a cigarette?
Got something to drink?
I've got Sprite and Coke.
A beer?
I do, but they're warm.
Thanks.
How long have you known my dad for?
Ages.
We used to play in a band together.
Really?
Yeah, I was surprised
when they got divorced.
He said he was looking for a place,
I'm putting him up in the meantime.
Yeah, I'm helping him look for apartments.
Really?
Yeah, it's going to be our place.
Is Dove your real name?
No, my name's José Paolo.
Why do they call you Dove?
Who knows?
What do you mean?
Why do they call you that?
A few years back,
we were out with some friends.
We'd taken some stuff.
We were heading to Coronado.
And there was this kind of ravine.
I climbed a rock
and jumped off.
I broke a few ribs and my collar bone.
So, what does that have to do with Dove?
People said
that I wanted to fly like a bird.
People say stuff.
I fell once too.
It was bad, I got three stitches.
I see.
That's nothing,
I've got scars worse than that.
Let's see.
What happened?
I don't know, I cut myself
when I was young and stupid.
Let's start the second half of the workshop
where we'll read our work
and comment on it, so...
This passage is called "Vulva".
- Vulva?
- Vulva, yes.
So...
Go on!
Licking pussy
Licking pussy is the excellent excess of sex
At 100 degrees Celsius
or 200 degrees Fahrenheit
Licking pussy, is an altruistic act
because one likes...
That's Luis, he runs the workshop.
And that guy?
That's Nacho. He's a photographer.
I don't really like him
and his pictures are kind of boring.
That's Ernesto, I don't know
what he does for a living.
He doesn't really get involved,
but he's a good guy.
And the guy over there is Santiago,
he's cool.
- Right...
- I can read "San José".
Go on.
San José was nothing more
than mere lights in the distance
An administrative constellation
Which, at night,
conceals its underdeveloped state
The rest:
Empty beer cans,
disregarded for being lukewarm
A flickering light from a car
with its doors flung open
And the devalued feeling
that we call affection.
Why aren't you dancing?
I know the basics, but I can't really dance.
You good?
Yeah, fine.
Are you done dancing?
Does your mum know you're staying over?
No.
She's gonna call me,
I'm not ready for it. Fuck!
Calm down, I'll explain it to her tomorrow.
Come here.
- You're all I have left, you know?
- What's up?
- Does that hurt?
- Yes, Dad, it hurts.
Are you sure? Focus.
OK, it doesn't hurt so bad.
See?
We're scared of pain,
but when we face it,
we realise that it's nothing.
It's not a big deal.
You shouldn't be scared of pain.
You always say the same thing,
I'm going to bed.
No, don't go, don't leave me alone.
Is this another of your...
What do you think of the girl
I was dancing with?
Pretty, right?
Up to you.
And the poem?
Was the reading OK?
People liked it, right?
Yes.
Your mum didn't like me writing.
As much as she likes to make out
that I'm the arsehole...
Dad, let me through, please.
...I wasn't, we were both to blame.
Let me through.
Stop.
Sorry, I don't want her seeing me like this.
I don't know what you see in her,
she seems like, as you say...
- "Kind of loose".
- Shut it!
And she wears too much makeup.
Occupied!
Hi.
Have you seen how many people came?
Everything OK?
To be honest, I'm kinda shattered.
No way.
- I haven't seen you like this in ages.
- Since when?
I think it was at Pepe's, remember?
I remember, mate.
Sorry, I need the toilet.
Go for it.
Fuck.
Occupied.
My dad died of cancer, did you know that?
We're all going to die someday.
No shit, man!
I'm already dead.
Listen to this, it's a great song.
Dad, no, leave me alone.
Again, now what?
If we don't cut the music,
the neighbour will call the police.
- Fucking police.
- I'm coming.
Hi, all good?
Occupied.
- Hey.
- What's up?
Have you seen my dad?
No.
Are you OK?
I feel like I'm gonna puke.
You drank too much.
I feel like I'm gonna die.
I smoked your cigarette.
- Which one?
- The one that was in the bathroom.
- What are you doing?
- Let's see.
Don't overreact.
Let me see.
What's wrong with you?
That's disgusting.
You shouldn't smoke that stuff.
Why not?
You're still growing.
So?
I don't know.
It might make you want to fly like a bird.
Are you OK?
Yes.
And you?
Give me a minute.
Not in the mood?
It's not that.
I don't like being told what to do.
I didn't say anything.
What shall we do?
Have you done it before?
No.
Well...
When you want something,
you know what to do.
I'm not stupid.
I didn't know you were sleeping.
Why are you still in bed?
Did you go out?
Yeah.
Why's your makeup still on?
Cos I was tired when I got home.
Who did you go out with?
What are you, the police?
Have you got a temperature?
Did you sleep well?
Did you have a nightmare?
Yes.
I did have a nightmare.
I dreamt that...
the house was on fire.
And that you were inside, in the kitchen.
And your hair was on fire.
On the radio there's a little chick
And the chick cheeps...
You like it? How does it look?
Yeah.
What about you, do you like it?
Go on, go have a bath.
- Kwesi.
- Mum, how does this work?
- Go take a bath.
- Kwesi, come here!
- Hi.
- Come, sweetie.
Sol, stop bugging him!
I don't want to.
Get out from under there.
No.
Sol, don't be stubborn.
Sol, leave him alone.
- Don't be stubborn.
- Ow, Kwesi!
Mum, Kwesi scratched me!
- What's wrong?
- I told her not to bug him!
What did he do to you?
I wanted to stroke him and he attacked me.
This cat is crazy.
That cat has got to go!
Where are you taking us, Dad?
It's a surprise, you'll see.
And you?
How come you're so calm?
Just because.
Right, who's going first?
Dad, are you sure
this is the right entrance?
Yes, it's the right entrance.
It doesn't look like it, we're trespassing.
No one will know, come on, let's go!
Go down!
A bit lower.
- Hold the wire down.
- Careful.
A little more...
My jumper, my jumper...
Fuck's sake.
Go on, eat that.
Leave it, Dad!
Fine.
So?
- It's nice.
- Nice, huh?
Let's go.
Look, it's on the hunt.
- Did you see that?
- No.
When it dove down.
One day, with my brothers,
we buried some knives around here.
It was under the big tree over there,
I think.
Or in those ones over there.
Dad, Eva's smoking.
It's OK.
We came here for some fresh air.
Come, sit down.
Let's breathe.
All three of us.
Take a deep breath.
One, two, three.
Hold it.
And again.
OK, let's move around a bit.
Up you get.
- Helicopter!
- Put me down!
I went to your place yesterday,
they gave me food
Rice, beans, raw tortillas
Yesterday, I was at a ball
and an old man kissed me
I called him an idiot, my sister got angry
My sister had a baby, the nutjob killed it
And the one who moves ate it.
Dad, where are we going now?
Since we're in the area,
we're gonna visit someone.
Visit?
Who?
What's this arsehole's problem?
Go on, go.
Wanker!
That dickhead, I'll show him.
- Pull your window down!
- Dad, no!
- Pull your fucking window down!
- This is ridiculous.
Pull it down!
Go get therapy, you wanker!
Fuck!
Dad, I nearly went flying.
I'm in the death seat.
- The death seat?
- Yeah, the seat in front.
So, go to the back, then, like a little kid.
Hold on tighter.
Hi.
- Hi.
- The girls and I were in the area.
So, I thought I'd swing round and say hi.
I almost didn't find the house,
but I ended up...
Hello.
Hi.
Here!
Thank you.
So, you're a translator, Martín.
Yes, I'm a translator.
What do you translate?
Birth, death certificates,
that kind of thing.
But he's also a painter and a sculptor.
You're a sculptor too?
I'm getting back into it.
- Better?
- No, it's still wet.
Sandra told me
that you met at the poetry workshop,
is that right?
- Yes, that's it.
- I love poetry.
I love de Bravo, Neruda...
Interesting.
That's old-school. We don't read that
in workshops anymore.
Of course, I don't really know.
I'd love to have the chance
to read some new stuff.
Maybe some of your poems?
You write, don't you?
To be honest, they're all just drafts,
notes, nothing that's really finished.
That's OK.
Come on, he should read something.
Nobody reads unfinished work.
I'm not expecting a work of art,
but read something.
Read.
I don't understand
why you prefer me when I'm drunk
As if I were a trapped genie
that you freed from the bottle
You didn't see the garden
that was going to be ours
Sometimes, I remember
how perfect those paths were
Where each tree was, its size
Your light.
- Hi, how did it go?
- Good.
I was starting to worry.
- Wait.
- No, she's sleeping.
Poor thing, did you guys eat?
Yes, we ate.
I'm going to put her to bed.
Hey...
Promise me something.
Don't tell Mum what happened.
What happened?
Nothing.
What's wrong?
The house felt so empty today.
I was flying,
a giant hand was pulling me down
and I was really scared.
Why?
I don't know, it felt
like there was magma underneath me,
but covered in scales.
That's beautiful, I'll use it in a poem.
Why?
The imagery of magma's interesting
because it's threatening
and soft at the same time.
I don't think I like the word "magma".
True.
The effect is a little obvious.
Mum says that dreams where you fly
are linked to sexuality.
Don't listen to her, that's bullshit.
Dad...
What?
I think it's over there.
In addition to that,
bill management, recycling, compost,
and maintenance.
If the bulb blows,
if something needs to be replaced,
that kind of stuff, someone will come
and fix it in under 10 minutes.
And then, of course,
there's the view from this apartment,
my favourite thing.
Yeah, it's nice.
I WOULD OFFER YOU THE SUN, YELINA
That place was a chicken coop.
It was tiny.
Who would live there?
It was good, it had two bedrooms.
You call those bedrooms?
And it was so expensive.
It was big.
The kitchen, the living room...
And that's why you have to pay
200 dollars for maintenance?
Never.
I liked it.
The girl was pretty.
I should've asked for her number.
You think a woman like that
would be into you?
Sorry.
Forgive me.
You said you'd stop doing that.
Why? Did it hurt?
Eva.
This lift keeps breaking down.
It must be damaged.
Are you OK?
Is there a problem, young lady?
What?
Why are you looking at me like that?
We've got CCTV here,
do we need to watch the footage?
You looking for a war?
Are you?
Did Kwesi eat?
Is there any food?
I don't know, I'm gonna check.
- He gets anxious when he doesn't eat.
- Yeah, I know.
Hey, buddy.
- Hey.
- I'm gonna cook us something nice.
- You joining us?
- No, I had a late lunch.
OK.
I'm going to go buy some cat food, coming?
No, I'll stay here with Kwesi.
I'll be back.
- What's his name?
- Linton Kwesi.
What?
Linton Kwesi Johnson, it's a Jamaican poet.
Kwesi, Kwesi...
He likes to be stroked gently.
Sorry.
I think I'm allergic to cats.
Kwesi, go on.
Get out!
This isn't a good idea.
What?
This.
This what?
- Did I do something wrong?
- No.
Don't worry.
Aren't you in love?
I don't know.
I wouldn't use that word.
What word would you use, then?
Why are you laughing?
I don't know. It's not that simple.
Don't cry.
Don't take it that way.
Then, how should I take it?
Sorry.
Where were you?
I got the cat food.
Eva.
Are you OK?
Is something wrong?
No, nothing.
Are you OK, Dad?
What's wrong? Do you need...
Mate, what happened?
Did you cut yourself?
Paper and a towel.
Put your hand under the water.
It's going to be fine.
Come on. I have to do three stitches.
Don't move. Lie down, please.
How old are you?
You look young.
As young as my daughter.
OK, maybe not as young.
Can I ask you something?
I have a mark on my tongue.
- Do you think it's cancer?
- You should consult a specialist.
- Lie down, please.
- Look.
It looks like a mouth ulcer.
Lie down, please.
All done, a nurse will come in
and clean you up.
A mouth ulcer...
You got a problem?
You got a problem, dickhead?
What? What did you say?
Dad, calm down.
- Fuck off.
- Dad, let's go.
Don't do that, you'll just make it worse.
What an arsehole.
Let's go.
You're right.
I can't do anything
to stop those things from happening.
You're old enough now to defend yourself.
Could you button up your shirt?
Why didn't you say anything before?
Please don't do that.
You should stay at your mum's
the next few days.
I've got some stuff to sort out.
How much for a song?
- Ten.
- Ten?
I've only got two.
No, keep going.
Don't pay any attention to them.
Manuel.
Mum, what are we going to do
with these pictures?
I don't know yet.
You didn't like that aunt,
why are you framing her?
- Why?
- We owe her a lot, Eva.
Yes, bless her heart.
She was self-made.
Bless her cash.
Are you not feeling OK?
You don't look so good.
I'm fine.
What are they doing?
Fucking.
Eva.
Switch it off now!
- We had a deal.
- Mum, I didn't do anything.
No violence in this house, even on the TV.
You didn't tell me what colour
you wanted your room.
Pick a colour.
I don't know, you choose.
It's up to you.
Just tell me something, give me a colour.
Yellow, white, cream, pink.
What do you want?
I don't know.
- Mum!
- Mum, are you OK?
What an idiot.
That's going to hurt now.
Electric blue.
Electric blue,
for your room.
I think I'm gonna go live with Dad.
What am I going to do with this house?
I don't know.
Should I sell it?
Do what you want.
What I want!
OK.
I'm going to burn it down.
- No, Mum.
- No, I'll burn it down.
I'm going to light it on fucking fire
and burn it down.
- No, don't burn it down.
- I'm going to.
Don't, where would we live?
I'll do what I want
so I'm gonna set it alight.
This obsession you have with your dad
and all the men that will come your way,
is something that'll pass, mark my words!
Are you OK?
I'm sorry.
I drink too much.
- I'm gonna bring you some water, OK?
- No, don't go.
Could you stay a moment with me?
I like crying sometimes.
It makes me feel
closer to my heart or something.
This is my father's room.
Oh. Yeah?
Just came here because
it was so empty, so...
You calling him?
- Yes, I don't know where he is.
- Oh.
Do you want me to leave?
No, that's OK.
How old are you?
16.
16, wow.
When I was 16, I was...
I was crazy.
Wow, you're so young.
I like being with you now.
Thank you.
It's like we are sisters, now.
All women are sisters, you know?
I think we have to unite, and...
be strong together, you know?
Eva...
Are you OK?
Yes.
I'm heading out,
should I drop you off at your mum's?
No, thanks.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'll wait for my dad.
OK.
Why didn't you tell me
you'd picked this place?
I looked in the papers
and it was the cheapest I could find.
I had to make a decision quickly.
You want something to drink?
There's only one bedroom.
- Say something!
- Say what?
- There's only one bedroom!
- Yes, one fucking bedroom, and what?
What do you want me to do?
And Kwesi?
Kwesi...
Pets aren't allowed here,
I had to take him to a refuge.
They'll take care of him there and feed him.
It's all good.
You want war?
You bastard, I'm gonna kill you.
Dickhead!
Hello?
Yes.
Eva Quesada Marín.
8-3-2-4-9-8-9-8.
San Francisco, San José.
I don't know.
I think...
From the "La Marina" shop,
it's 300 meters east.
The three-storey, blue building.
My dad tried to strangle me.
Hello.
We got a domestic violence call.
Were you the one who called?
Yes.
- It was you?
- Yes.
Are you injured?
Are you OK?
Do you need any medical assistance?
No.
- Have you been drinking?
- No.
Is that the man who attacked you?
- Yes, it's me.
- Stay over here.
If you want, you can wait in the car
if you'll feel more comfortable.
Come.
Is this man a relative?
Yes, he's my dad.
Do you live with your dad?
- No, I live with my mum.
- With your mum.
We're going to the police station
to file your report.
Then we'll call social services.
Do I need to file a report?
Yes, you should because we received
the call from you.
At a Mexican restaurant called Mero.
Have you never been?
It's delicious, you'll see.
- I've never been.
- This place is...
close to Gabi's beauty salon, right?
And when I got out of the car,
I heard a loud bang
and the patrol car reversed without looking.
Yelina!
I wasn't expecting it,
I asked him if he was going to look.
Yelina!
We're gonna go get a coffee over there.
We can't do that.
We're going down to the station first.
OK, thanks.
I can read if you want.
My name is Martín.
This is my first reading
at one of these workshops.
I have electric dreams
Where my dad, when he can't fix something,
Smashes it on the ground
He gets angry, shouts, calls names
We scream our love for each other,
sometimes with blows
That's what we are
A pack of wild animals
with dreams of humanity
Sometimes one needs several lives
to comprehend this
The rage that runs through us
doesn't belong to us.