THE PANDERERS
Yes, a simple dress.
Around 8:30.
What is your phone number again?
38-18-60
Good. Do we agree, then?
And remember: be very cheerful.
Bye, dear.
She's so sweet...
She has a beautiful voice.
We had so many expenses this week!
Two bands for three evenings...
plus overtime until dawn.
12 boxes of champagne,
2 of vodka, a box of caviar...
Everything becomes more and more
expensive, these days.
Do you want the headlines, Ma'am?
No, I've had enough for today.
I wonder where this is going to end...
I'll go and check
if everything's in order.
This is the first cigarette
of the day for me.
I swear that I won't
have another until midday.
Credito fondiario, 9800...
Mediobanca, 61200...
Credito Italiano, 1849.
- What's that?
- Buy it.
Bank of Rome,
40520.
Interbanca, 13900.
Italgas, 546.
- Buy it.
Did you sleep well?
- Yes.
Please give me another
two minutes. - There's no hurry.
Assicurazione Italiana,
269000.
Assicurazioni Generali,
43200.
What is your weight today, darling?
82 kilos and 200 grams, Gilda.
My weight rises, and my shares
fall down in the stock market.
How much was your weight yesterday?
Well, yesterday evening...-
Buy that, too!
I think 80 kilos and almost 700 grams.
I've gained more than 1 kilo and 500 grams.
Ah, so you've lost more than
1,5 kilo! - No, I gained them!
It's quite a problem, isn't it?
- Not at all...
… with the diet
I planned for you,
you'll be back in shape
within a week!
It'll be a little frustrating.
Boiled chicken and vegetables,
no bread, neither wine nor alcohol.
...and 28 700
- Please repeat, I was distracted.
28 730 at Milan. Yes, Milan.
Alright, alright, buy it.
- Buy 144, Finsid 172.
Gym, 2150.
Ifi private, 2370.
Investimenti, 2290.
The Centre, 8704.
Pirelli, 1369,
Sici 400.
Alright, that will do. Thank you.
- Can I start?
My husband is in your hands.
Please, treat him well!
You are marvellous, darling.
Stronger.
I'm not made of glass.
Relax. Don't stay so tense,
or the massage won't help.
Going to the end of the world, Miss?
It's number 25. That's there.
How much is it?
- 2000.
Who is it?
What's that, "Who is it"?
I'm Odile! Today is friday, right?
Who is Odile?
"Who is Odile"?!
I've got an appointment!
Listen, send away
the dogs, they frighten me.
A strong flavour...
I like it.
How are you going
to call it?
Well, me and my wife
have decided
not to use
exotic names anymore.
We'll baptise my cocktails
with the names of our friends,
of those who frequent our house.
this one here, mon cher,
is my latest creation.
one of those that
turned out best.
I couldn't help giving it your name.
"Cocktail Aldo Brando"
I always break the glass
when I drink.
I'd do it in war, too.
It always amused me.
In war, I've always been
with people who smashed glasses.
Davide, have you got some interesting news?
We've always been here,
even during our holidays
Naturally, we see many people
and time passes by.
I want to show you
my latest acquisitions...
for my personal museum.
It's very interesting.
I always thought that
women were totems...
cruel,
menacing, dark..
a totem that must...
be destroyed.
Yes.
Women are there to be punished.
A woman has to be punished
because she's the
intermediary between us
and the diabolical forces
of the universe.
The body of a woman
is a form which gives us life,
something enigmatic...
which, at times,
seems about to reveal...
a distant and unknown land.
I've always wondered what
the nude body of a woman means.
I believe it forms
part of a true language.
It's not actually a language.
Rather, it's silence, nothingness.
- It's silence for those who are deaf.
For those who are born dead...
for all those who don't
have space in the universe.
Why do I have to
dress myself up this time?
Well, contrary to you, I think that it's
important to know the universe well.
The landscapes speak,
have a soul.
I've traveled a lot,
especially in the Far East.
Is the girl here
Yes, she's ready for you.
Does she meet the
requirements we'd agreed on?
Yes, all of them,
don't worry, Aldo Brando.
We chose her carefully.
Go and embark
on this new journey!
Odile is expecting you.
But how did women
dress in 1954?
But what're you doing?
Look, I can walk myself!
Come on, leave me be!
Put me down! I say, put me down!
Phew!
I want to carry you.
The other one too, Odile.
Watch it...
Perfect!
Why did you bring me here?
What's all this supposed to mean?
Look, they might
see us up here, you know?
It's my little theatre.
Don't ask questions.
You just have to obey,
and that's it.
Yeah yeah, I'll obey.
But we have to make it quick.
So, what do I have to do?
I'll tell you now.
You're very nice, you know?
Don't talk nonsense.
What do you know about me?
I'm not of the nice kind...
but neither depraved.
For me it's all or nothing.
I'm just...
a torturer.
Nothing more.
Look, if you threaten me,
I'll get out of here.
You can do everything to me,
everything you want...
but you mustn't hurt me,
is that clear?
For me, my next one is
nothing but an object of torture.
You think I'm sick, eh?
Go on, say it!
Nobody knows that I'm like that.
They never found out because
in all these years of occasional love,
I managed to
camouflage myself.
I tried to be
like the others, too.
I didn't manage to.
Maybe, this time....
is my last occasion.
Look here, it's loaded.
It's enought to pull here...
and Bang!  it fires...
Do you want to know
how many wars I've been in?
Algeria,
foreign legion.
Madagascar...
Indonesia...
I was a mercenary and dealer of arms.
The risk excites me,
I can't help it.
Now I'm rich
and respectable.
You're afraid of me?
Don't be.
It's pointless.
Of course,
my criminal record is clean.
Because in this filthy world,
a clean criminal record has to be paid.
Where are you going,
stupid chicken?
Watch out, don't crush
my soldiers. Look at them...
look at them well...
because they represent
my lost dreams.
You see, I would've liked
to be commander...
in an official army.
A real commander!
Yes, it's like that...
However,
all the official armies
considered me...
nothing but a deserter.
But you won't!
You have to respect me,
you know?
I'm at your disposal.
That's what I'm paid for.
But you mustn't hurt me!
So?
Do you still think I'm nice?
Where are you going?
Stay here!
With each slap I'm giving you
I'm getting more excited.
But don't call me
by my surname, you hear me?
Call me "professor"!
Or rather, "commander"!
In that case you have to
adress me as "Miss"...
actually, as "Miss Odile"...
and besides...
I hate soldiers!
Even tin ones!
I know your story.
North africa, 1954.
Messer-Kabir.
They wanted your mother
to reveal the names of her comrades.
How do you know that?
Back then,
you hadn't been born yet.
You were born later...
when your mother was reduced
to a mere shadow of herself...
because of the tortures
they inflicted on her.
Nobody must talk to me
about this anymore.
Besides, how do you know?
Who told you?
Our host.
You've been chosen
very carefully, Odile.
Most of all...
because there was
that story behind you,
I needed you...
to be born from torture.
because I enjoy myself
this way...
I like girls who had an unhappy childhood,
disgraced girls.
I enjoy thinking about...
the tortures your poor mom...
had to endure.
It was part of the deal.
Let's make love at once.
Hold on to me tight.
That way, you can't fall.
But if you let go of me,
you'll get smashed.
I was born later.
I don't know what they did to her.
We'll catch up
on that subject soon.
But don't worry now.
Let's play!
Let's play again, Odile.
I'm dying to play with you.
You know, those who say
"Make love, not war" make me laugh.
I don't see the difference.
Conquer the hill!
The third division conquers the back...
Marching on is becoming
more and more difficult.
The objective is finally conquered.
Now...
I'm the one giving the orders!
You crushed all my soldiers
once again!
I'll punish you...
now.
I had almost forgotten her.
Well, not exactly.
Not forgotten.
You don't forget certain things.
and then, I thought that...
Anyway, it's useless thinking about it,
when you can't do anything about it.
And then... you show up...
asking me all these questions
to which I never knew the answers.
What they've done to her...
and why...
I... I...
I don't know much...
I just know that...
that she had six broken ribs...
and then... they burned her all over.
They pulled out her teeth.
The names.
They wanted to know the names.
- The names?
What names? I don't know them,
I don't know anybody!
You've responded like her.
- And you? How do you know?
I was told the whole story.
Wait a second...
I'll show you...
They used electricity on her body...
they made her feel it here...
and here, all the way
to the navel, like this!
But... who told you all this?
You didn't do anything
to prevent it, to defend her.
Your mother was beautiful...
Maybe she resembled you.
Her torturer wanted to know
the names, always the names.
But your mother was too beautiful...
even if she had talked,
he would've raped her anyway.
But who was that man?
You met him...
I want to know who he was.
I want to know.
They made her sit
in an armchair...
a special armchair
with two clamps at the arms.
Then they asked for the names,
always the names...
Then that man switched
on an extremely strong light.
Blinding,
directly in the eyes!
- Who was it?
Tell me who it was.
I want to know who it was.
- I won't tell you who he was...
but what he did.
No...
what I'm thinking
can't be true...
Why do you, of all people,
know that story?
Why you?
I always felt strangely attracted
to these things: torture,
documents,
memoirs...
That's where I find pleasure.
Who tortured my mother?
Was it you?
No.
It wasn't me.
I even couldn't say
who told me this story.
If that really is the truth...
why did you ask to meet me?
Why did you want to see me?
Take it!
It was meant for you
from the beginning.
You'll say
that I killed myself.
Don't be afraid!
I wrote it down.
There's a letter
in the pocket of my jacket.
Little blood and little noise.
It's simple, isn't it?
But one day or another,
I'll get myself killed for real,
once I find the courage.
Excuse me, my dear,
but we have many guests tonight,
many nice people.
And besides, by now I can't really
rely on servants anymore.
You're right, Gilda. These days,
you can't really trust anyone.
There you are, ma'am.
I have to think
about everything.
Our rooms mustn't look
like ordinary rooms anymore...
they should look like theatres,
like paintings of illusion.
Can a secretary
or a room maid achieve this?
No, certainly not, Gilda.
Every little detail
has to be taken care of.
And that's your task.
Who are we celebrating tonight?
- Well, there's Marcantonio...
and there's Giampiero.
Marcantonio is a little sad.
He's worried about
the oil company, isn't he?
You know, he believed Ennio
was here too, but it's too risky.
So I told him that there were
problems with the airplane.
And the judge has come?
Yes, but he's unbearable this time
He wants to be punished,
wants to suffer.
We'll never have a whip
heavy enough for him.
Yes, his crying and whimpering is unbearable...
Ah, they are just crocodile tears.
I feel more sorry for him than for the
innocents he keeps sentencing to prison.
But a lawman might
come in handy.
There's a call from Paris
for you, Count.
Yes?
Yes. I already told you
this morning
that I neither want
nor can do anything for you.
I already said no.
Who was it?
- Oh...
Tomorrow, I absolutely
have to find a tall girl,
with olive-coloured skin,
and slender like a sail.
Ginevra asked for it,
you know.
She called me
this morning from Milan.
She was quite upset,
she begged me!
Ginevra?
- Yes!
It was her who bought
all shares of Finter.
Very well.
It's a precious relation, dear.
Don't neglect it, it's important.
You must try
to keep her satisfied.
Yes, I might have
two or three suitable girls...
but it will be very difficult, darling.
Polish this vase well,
the humidity has ruined it.
"You don't have eyes to see"
as the Gospel says.
Oh Davide, don't be stupid...
It's you!
I can't believe it!
I think you'd do better
not believing it...
my beautiful panderess.
My lurid, splendid panderess.
Why at this hour? - If not in the
morning, when do you want me to come?
The rehearsals
at the theatre will start at 2 PM.
I don't want the actresses
in my bed, you know?
Forbidden flesh.
Meat for the audience.
Good for the public...
for the critics, for the projectors...
and for the “protectors” [pimps], of course.
Did you put on the coloured garters
like I told you to?
Alright like this, master?
- Alright.
Crab red, as you wished.
Is something wrong?
That's what you wanted, isn't it?
They're also wearing
bone corsets.
Yeah, it's so Berlinian whorehouse,
late 19th century, Brecht.
Or the drawings by Grosz.
- "Panderess"...
I thought you talked
more elegantly.
Panderess is an elegant word - it means
supplying love by making strangers meet.
In the theatre I'm elegant but with you,
I'm calling things by their name.
Finally a bit of freedom! Come come,
show me my mammella!
My tit, the right one,
come on, go ahead!
Madame...
- Giorgio!
Show me all the photographs, quick!
I have no time to waste.
- Right away, master!
You two, push!
You see, Giorgio...
there are no new recruits
to show you on photographs.
You already know all of my girls.
But in one and a half months,
I think I'll have some new ones,
from Tunisia or Baltimore.
Well, let's go.
Let's make it quick.
See that one?
She's an introvert, shy girl
She plays hard to get. First,
she flees from you, but then...
she always returns on her hands
and knees. Sweet, isn't she?
Who's that smart one here?
I don't think I've ever seen her.
This blonde paints herself badly.
Why does she have to put on make up?
How old is she, 15, 16 years?
- No, 32 for you, Giorgio.
I always want to
tell you the truth.
But the others
are the age they look.
Company secretary.
Horrendous.
And this one?
This one's alright.
I'd even say she's splendid.
Slender neck... employee?
Or maybe clerk?
Duchess. Do you want her?
She's very expensive though.
500 000 for one weekend.
See? This girl is a student.
She lives in the country
but attends university in Rome.
She doesn't like young ones,
she finds them insignificant.
She rather loves men
the age of her father.
Old gentlemen.
Babysitter...
This one works as a clerk,
secretary...
She has a degree in chemistry.
- Professor of natural sciences.
Daddy's daughter,
mummy's daughter, stewardess...
Ah, this one here is
absolutely irresistible, fabulous!
She likes a lot to hang out
with young ones who have little...
well, who aren't anybody,
who pay for love
with daddy's money.
Her! There she is,
that's the one I want.
Yes, no problem.
You can have her.
It's just that I'd need some time
to inform her, you see?
Alright.
But I want her!
Yes, but when?
- Sunday, at 7.
In the evening?
- No, at dawn.
A Malaysian dawn.
Conrad, Rimbaud, as well as Salgari.
She's the daughter of the chief
of a tribe of headhunters...
that way we're
closer to Melville.
and I'm Al Mayer,
the outcast of the islands.
Now it's up to you. You have to do
all you can to give him the tropics.
Our circle is getting used up. Odile,
the stewardess, the usual 2 or 3 wives
who want to buy themselves
a fur coat or a colour TV set,
as well as some failed actresses.
What do you think?
What do I think?
I believe in your
fervent imagination.
I'd like to have a group
of faithful girls here.
They should be very compliant,
absolutely innocuous.
Like these ducks.
I'd like to be able to
fondle them, to caress them.
warm them up.
I desire a young one,
healthy and new
tender like a roasted chestnut.
But...
you don't have one
like that, do you?
I thought of it.
Giusy and her collaborators
will take care of it.
Water!
Dry...
Go away! Away!
Go away, beasts!
Water!
Water! Water! Yes!
Who are you,
Stranger?
Co... the commander of...
Tell me!
Tell me who you are.
I'm...
I'm Commander Al Mayer.
I was in command
of the "Narcissus".
An armed battleship of 600 tons.
We were heading for Aden, loaded...
with guano and a thousand
muslim pilgrims on their way to Mecca.
One night a terrible typhoon,
characteristic of those areas after all,
dismasted the ship,
we lowered the boats,
and I was the first one
to leave the ship,
me, the commander,
you understand?
A hundread days at sea!
We had to fight with the sharks
over human flesh.
I myself devoured three pilgrims
and half of the boatswain.
I left the other half
to the second commander.
So you... you understand
my language, my child!
No.
We've never seen a white man.
A white man...
I'm not anymore.
I used to be but I'm not anymore.
Take me to your village.
But we are headhunters!
- Very well, so I'll lose my head, too.
I already lost everything:
my ship, my honour...
But we eat nothing but berries.
Very well... oh, excellent.
Do you also have bread trees? - Sure.
Fantastic!
- We have apple trees, too.
And cocoa plants.
- Enough, otherwise I'll gain weight!
But what's that medallion doing
on the Molucca islands? - It's St. Anthony...
That won't do, you're too sophisticated.
You're not natural, it won't do.
Ah, there it is, the village.
Cereus Candelabrus. Very good.
We live here.
It's very small.
But as it suits us, you can enter.
My two husbands are out hunting.
We're alone.
My other three husbands
are in war...
and my parents have gone head-cutting.
- And what's that?
Seanut.
The symbol of fertility.
But you'll be hungry and thirsty!
- I'll eat some head later.
For now, give me
something to drink.
I'll give you milk.
And that? What's that?
Champagne?
Is this a joke? Champagne
at the Moluccas? Put it away!
Come on, drink.
There, have some as well.
Come on! Like that...
No, wait...
from your hands.
There...
and now lick it,
like a goat...
Like that.
Very good.
Like a goat.
Yes, like this.
Very good.
And now, a moment of rhythm.
Yes...
You're like a papaya plant,
like a piston of corn,
or buckwheat.
you're wild, you're primitive,
You are primordial!
Something that transcends me!
You are...
you are obsessive!
You are the tropic,
you are...
you are like the earth,
that's what you are!
I want to be your earth,
your god, your river!
Your sacred area.
Your feet stepping on me
will evoke the great ghosts! Yes...
come, dance on me!
Together, we'll pass
the great river Nagaroa.
Yes, like that.
What are you doing?
Do you think you're in a night club?
You have to be
more archaic, more African.
more primitive.
Alright, I'll be more African.
Excuse me, dear, but your singing
has a hypnotic effect on me.
But it's the Song of the River!
- Yes, but why exactly now?
When our people fall in love
with someone, they do this:
Go ahead, act, Silvia!
What splendour,
that is still in your garments,
it is the bosom that brings relief.
What sweetness...
- "While"...
"While?"
- "While you undress..."
There, go ahead
and read if you forgot.
"While she undresses,
my teeth will bite her."
Yes... but it doesn't go well
recited like that, Silvia.
You need to interpret
and mimick more.
I have to mimick?
- Exactly. Poetry lives from animation.
What sweetness...
while she undresses,
my teeth bite her.
What are you doing?
Her saliva is like melt honey -
blessed is he
who may sack on her.
"Suck on her", ignorant!
Her breasts resemble
the eggs of the cutrix.
A bird characteristic for the Savannah.
They,
lovers who warm themselves up.
While you have
let loose your hair...
Ah, yes, finally I'm tied up!
Deep down, I've always hated freedom.
I won't be a director anymore,
never again will these
marvellous hands magically move
and guide the actors. Yes, torture me,
degrade me, tell me I'm pathetic!
You're worse than De Lullo.
Yes, punish me,
punish me!
You're nothing compared to Enriquez!
- My god, how cruel you are!
Even Albertazzi is much better
than you at directing!
No, not Albertazzi!
You're tremendous!
If Vito Molinari did Brecht,
he'd do it much better than you!
- No, don't say that. Not Molinari!
You mustn't mention that name!
You're too cruel a woman!
And now, I need
to give you some news.
Oh god, please don't!
I'm afraid of news!
Don't tell me. I don't want to know
the news. - I'll tell you all the same!
You were hoping to direct
“Galileus” at San Mignato... - Yes.
You won't.
Tell me!
- Sandro Bolchi will do it.
I could never make love
with a mediocre director like you.
You are a zero.
I love successful men.
- Tremendous!
A director who doesn't know how to
direct, does not know how to make love.
Hmm, very refined,
very cruel!
“Sorrisi e Canzoni”...
[popular Italian magazine]
never even published a picture of you.
- But how... where did you get all this?
I'll never be yours.
I'll only be
Sandro Bolchi's lover.
It's deep in the night.
It's cold.
It's very humid.
The beasts howl and I...
I'm afraid.
Yes. I'm afraid, too.
Yes, come...
Come, it's cold...
let's protect ourselves...
together...
You're my mum.
Be my mum...
my African mommy.
What's that scream? Perhaps
the buffalos that come to drink?
No, they're my husbands,
returning from the hunt.
Let's make love quickly then!
Maybe, they are giraffes,
chased by a ferocious lion!
No. It's my parents,  they are
returning from the forest with heads.
Let's make love quickly then!
No, it's an antelope,
chased by an onza...
a wild cat typical for South America!
- No, it's my tribe.
It's my tribe making war.
Yes... yes, come on,
come on...
Nonsense! It's not a tribe,
it's an ambulance!
So, did I perform well?
Are you pleased?
Can I have a role in your “Galileus”?
- "Galileus"? Let's not exaggerate.
You're gracious and pretty
but too primitive, understand?
Too crude, too archaic.
You lack culture...
and class as well.
Anyway, come to my dressing room
after the play.
Let's see if we can combine
something, a little tryout,
a test, something.
Okay?
Bye, honey, bye.
Hi Gilda!
- Hi! I see you're well.
What a wonderful dog!
Liv, how was the weather in Singapore?
- Oh, don't talk about it!
43 grades in the shade.
It was hell.
But with the air conditoning
in the hotels,
I felt in Paradise.
I brought you a little gift.
I don't know if you'll like it,
it's not easy picking a gift for you...
you already have it all.
It's one of the rarest herbs.
Perfect, of first-rate quality!
How much do I owe you, Liv?
- You didn't understand, it's a gift!
In Singapore they sell it in public,
even in front of the cathedral.
I remembered your name-day is in
a couple of days. The 22nd, isn't it?
Unfortunately it's my birthday.
You're as crazy as usual,
but that's why I like you so much.
Listen, I've had your usual room
prepared, Liv. Did you know that José...
These cocktails prepone my death.
But the story...
I'm writing about them
secures me immortality.
What about the book
you've been writing all these years?
It's almost done. In a couple
of years, my work will be finished.
I just have to study in depth
some Chinese and Japanese herbs.
As long as I haven't finished
my research,
I won't send even
the first chapter to my editor.
I'll certainly travel to Asia,
to find certain rare,
aphrodisiac roots
and others that maintain youth.
You keep on underlining
the fact that you're old...
but you know you'll be
eternally young among famous men
My name will be remembered
for this formidable encyclopedia
of odours and tastes.
They are my latest creations.
King Lear, Hamlet,
Macbeth,
Romeo and Juliet,
The Taming of the Shrew,
The 12th night...
The Merchant of Venice,
A Midsummer Night's Dream,
Othello.
My cocktails are life,
love and music.
Music to drink!
- Yes...
a music to drink!
"O, that this too too solid flesh
would melt..."
"Thaw and resolve itself
into a dew!"
My dear ambassador!
Countess...
- You really neglected us lately.
We missed you.
- I missed you, too, Countess!
I couldn't wait
to see you again.
Am I mistaken or have you
put on a bit of weight?
Unfortunately you're right.
It's the stress...
dirty politics...
But it's your job after all.
You shouldn't despise it.
I despise it precisely
for that: it's my job,
my everyday burden.
Speaking of politics... Have you
talked to Minister Navarro, Josè?
We want our ambassador
to be put in charge.
It didn't slip my mind.
Your request has been accepted.
Poor Navarro... he'd certainly
need too distract himself a little.
He spends his days
welcoming people at a castle...
full of silver chandeliers
and with wall carpets of black damast.
I'd be so happy if he came to see us.
Who knows, If he made a day trip to Rome
he might spend some
pleasant hours...
distracting himself,
escaping a little...
Yes, I should...
I should tell him about this place.
- Alright then.
To the politics
that can change the world...
And to the politics that can be changed
by the world, my dear Davide...
Excuse me for a moment.
Countess...
has my sweet Liv arrived?
I hope she hasn't missed her plane?
Don't worry, Josè.
Stewardesses never miss their plane.
To your health.
- To yours.
Josè....
I'm tired.
Why do you always make me do
the same merry-go-round? Come here.
Why do you talk?
Shut up. You mustn't talk.
You must be nothing but...
but a shadow.
Wait! Why do you
start right away?
We've time on our hands.
What's the hurry?
Promise me not to suffer, Josè.
not to suffer like
you always did,
but just a little.
Angela isn't far...
She's here, with you.
I am her.
Not, it isn't true.
You're not like her.
Turn around.
Look at her.
You look at her, too!
Don't be afraid.
Look at her.
Now, everything's different.
No, it's not true.
Nothing's different, it's always her.
You see,
it never ends. It'll never end.
I'm here.
Don't you feel me, Josè?
Josè...
Come...
What a strange idea,
recording my voice...
As if for a museum...
it gives me the creeps
What do you want to do?
Convey it for posterity?
Or don't you trust
our oath of love?
Everlasting love...
Or do you have
the intention of leaving me...
and are thus creating
one of the usual relics?
And what a sad idea to accompany
my voice with this music...
I don't know why but it's like
a kind of funeral march.
Josè! You make me laugh.
- Hear? What a voice...
The most beautiful
voice in the world.
I'll never forget it.
Never.
That's not true, Josè.
It's a voice like mine,
like everyone else's voice.
- Don't you recall what Don Quijote says?
Why did she leave me?
Because she loved someone else.
It happens to many.
What's wrong with that?
Love is never wasted, Josè.
What do you want me
to say now?
That our love will be eternal?
Alright, I'll say it:
Our love will be eternal.
That we'll never leave
each other?
Alright, I'll say it:
We'll never leave each other.
Don't think,
don't think!
I'm much better than her.
Look at me.
It's not true!
Yes, sure, I'll say
everything you want me to!
After all they're just words,
it doesn't cost me a thing saying them.
I was hoping that in all these months,
you would've forgotten her, Josè.
Forget her?
But didn't I already tell you?
I'll never forget her.
Never.
But why?
I'm here...
Give me the flowers,
I beg you!
I am the kind of woman
who loves only once, Josè.
Love is like poetry.
You know that.
Even the most banal lovers...
believe that they always
play new love games...
and that love lasts forever.
Angela...
Angela!
My love!
my love...
Josè, for me you are...
for me, you are
the one unforgettable man...
But what are you doing?
Stop it!
...like Romeo for Juliet,
like Caesar for Cleopatra.
Don't you see that I'm lonely?
- I'm the woman and you're the man.
I'm the island and you're
the sea that's surrounding me...
Come here!
You're kissing poorly today.
What's happening to you?
Today... yesterday...
What do you know
of the days?
You know nothing.
Why?
What else could I say to you
on this tape?
That you're the most extraordinary
and marvellous man to ever love a woman?
It's like that.
It's true, Josè.
I have only you.
I live just for you.
I'm the kind of woman
who loves only once.
It's time. Put on her dress.
What else shall I tell you?
I couldn't desire anyone else
now that I have you.
You know, when I'm
in the street or driving in my car,
I don't see the other men,
they don't exist.
since I have you.
You're the only man.
No one exists but you.
You're unsurpassable,
overwhelming, unforgettable...
Now call me by the names
that she would call me.
Slughi, Chiquito,
Mon cheríe...
mein Schatz,
[pet names in various languages]
Listen to the song that...
- Mo grá,
our song of love...
- Now...
the morning's greeting.
- Ours like you are mine...
and I am yours.
Now the afternoon one.
The good night.
And now the photograph.
Here it is, Josè. But I swear
to you, I don't like him.
I don't know how Angela did it,
you're much better.
You are my man.
For me,
you're the one unforgettable man.
But you've met him, didn't you?
What did he say...
when you saw him?
- He implored me.
A hundred times,
he told me that he loved me.
He even cried, you know?
He also called me from New York.
- And what did you tell him?
I told him no.
No, I swear to you.
No.
Yes, Josè...
free yourself!
Angela doesn't exist...
Angela has disappeared
into the void...
You're unsurpassable...
overwhelming...
unforgettable...
Now, you are free.
You are free and you know it.
Angela doesn't exist anymore.
She's a shadow.
You're invincible...
She's not up to you,
she's far away...
she's finished,
you succeeded!
You'll never see her again.
Josè...
You don't see her anymore,
she has disappeared.
Now, I'll make you
one of my cocktails.
Alright?
- No, Davide...
No no.
Today I want none of your complicated
concoctions but just some wine.
Red wine,
from the cellar.
Afterwards we'll make love
as God commands us.
Yes, but try not to forget
about that girl, Gilda.
What about her?
That one? Yes, she's not bad
but her hips are too narrow.
Yes, you're right.
- Besides, she's too dark.
Like beduine. We need to
find something very different.
Why not that one?
- No, not her. She's blonde.
Mrs. Gilda said:
"Enough with the blondes!"
We have to find a brunette of 18 years,
a girl from the countryside.
Hi! - How are you? - Fine.
- How was the trip? - Just fine!
What a shame.
She seemed the right type.
And how about this one?
- Yes, she might do.
Surely from Calabria.
Look what she's reading.
She seems like the right type.
Go, get her!
No, wait!
Hi mum! [Sicilian dialect]
- See how the little one has grown?
Calm down. Many more trains
will arrive before tonight.
Sure. A dark one might arrive
anytime before tomorrow morning.
Come on,
let's go to the buses.
There are girls
coming straight from the south.
Look how many peasants...
they smell like a cowshed.
- They all look like pigs to me.
piled one on top of the other...
Here, we'll find much easier
what we're looking for.
One moment...
Did you hurt yourself?
What is it?
- Look at that!
What did they do to you?
What happened?
They robbed me...
What? My money, of course!
Sickening, you can't live here anymore!
- Let's wait for the police.
Come on, don't cry!
- Chicken thieves!
Don't worry, Miss,
I'll call the police immediately!
Where did he hurt you?
It's nothing serious.
I've seen everything,
he ran in that direction!
You saw the thief?
Come with me then.
Who knows
where he'll be by now?
Cheer up,
don't let yourself go.
Come on!
Take a seat
- Give that to me, I'll handle it.
Three cognacs!
- No, I'll take a coffee.
No! I said three cognacs.
- Right away.
What did you come
to Rome for?
Don't you know
that Rome is a jungle?
In my village they said
that if you're determined,
you can make a living in the city!
Yes, indeed.
- That's why I came.
I'm going to be somebody.
There is such a lot of delinquency
everywhere nowadays...
that living in the city
is something to fear by now.
And now, where do I go?
What do I do?
Without any money,
nor friends nor relatives here?
I don't have anyone!
- Don't worry, everything will be fine.
I have a friend who can host you
for a couple of days, you'll see.
A place to stay for the night?
- Yes, at a Countess's house.
One lives really well
at her place.
There's nothing lacking,
you'll like it!
She's a real lady.
Go ahead and pay.
Am I disturbing you?
- Come closer!
Giusi told me about
your mishap.
'Tis a city of criminals!
But I'm happy to accomodate you!
- Just for one night, you know?
I don't have any relatives here.
I could make a call home, if I may,
so they can send me some money.
Not for going back,
you know...
I won't go back...
I won't go back.
I have my pride.
You're doing
the right thing, dear.
But you needn't worry,
as you can see, my house is large
enough and besides, I really like you!
Calm down, dear.
Make yourself at home.
I assure you that it's no problem,
you can stay as long as you like!
Go ahead, put down your luggage.
I'll have it taken upstairs
to your room.
Kifayesu!
- Yes, Countess?
Take her to the room
on the third floor.
Take care of her.
Thank you. I won't even unpack
my bag. I'll stay just for one night.
Don't worry about it,
stop thinking and unpack!
Unpack...
Nice...
Take this one off.
- No!
It's St. Anthony's scapular.
I'd rather die than taking it off.
Countess, why did you bother?
You shouldn't have!
It's no bother.
You must be hungry.
You're young.
- I feel as if I'm dreaming.
But what dream?
I like you, Linda!
That's all.
Moreover, I'd like to say -
one can see you have it in you...
you'll get ahead in life!
- You really think so?
You have personality,
a good sense of humor...
Really?
- Yes!
But now,
you have to do me a favour.
Excuse me,
but... I don't understand!
Me, a favour?
Of what kind?
Impossible!
How could I do you a favour?
I say that on your behalf.
My husband has decided
to help you. Talk to him.
Don't forget to tell him about
everything that you'd like to do!
He'll get you acquainted with
someone who might be useful.
Talk to him.
Davide?
You called me, darling?
- Yes, Davide.
Our new friend here wants to
confess all of her dreams to you,
all her hopes. I'd like to ask you
not to disappoint her.
Go on, tell me, dear.
What skills do you have?
Tell me, don't be ashamed. Do you know
how to dance, how to sing...? - Yes!
Not bad, you're quite in tune!
I'll call the general manager of TV.
I have his personal number.
He's a close friend of mine.
If he can do me a favour...
Usually, he never declines.
Is it the general manager?
Yes, it's me.
I have an exceptional girl here.
She wants to sing on television.
I wish you could hear her singing,
it's worth it. It's a try
you shouldn't miss.
Alright.
I'll come tomorrow morning.
He'll come tomorrow.
He's a very important man.
Very busy, too.
At this hour, he can't
leave his office.
Tomorrow he will be all yours!
Be very, very nice to him,
don't forget that!
Do everything he says.
Sing, dance...
And if he wants
to drink with you, drink!
Drink to your future,
to your success, to glory!
What time tomorrow?
- In the morning, it's a promise.
See? You are very lucky
to stay in this house, Linda.
Don't you think so?
But why that?
What question!
It's simple, Linda:
The papers will publish your photo
because you're so beautiful and likeable!
Take your hands off!
- But he's a friend!
A good friend...
Don't be afraid,
you have nothing to hold back,
he's from "the other side" [he's gay].
- Now look at me, sweetie.
Stay like that!
There!
You have a magnificent
sense of posture!
One more minute,
and we'll be finished.
Come on, get moving!
You've fallen asleep!
That will be enough for now.
You've been great, my dear.
You'll be very successful,
I'm sure of it.
Aren't I beautiful?
Thank you,
blessed St. Anthony!
You have to make it strong,
very strong, Davide.
I'm not sure if
that will be enough.
Maybe, we're in need of
something stronger...
It's better to keep this stuff
in sight, that way it's less suspicious.
It's a present from Liv,
she brought it from Singapore.
Mix it in her drink.
She'll need a lot of it.
Let's toast to your luck,
to your certain success!
I've never had champagne.
I don't like it.
- They told me good things about you.
You'll become famous, Linda!
- Thank you.
Pardon me...
I'm getting sleepy.
I'm unable to
say anything anymore.
What do you want to say?
Pardon, Sir...
- Come on, lie down, rest a little.
No, don't bother, leave it!
- No no, rest, Linda.
What're you doing?
Have you gone mad?
You...
The tiles are smooth.
You could slip.
Look.
Do you know
what a polaroid is?
Nice, aren't they?
Did you see those colors?
Your father and mother
would like them as well.
If you say one word to anybody
about what happened,
I'll send these to your parents.
I swear that I'll send them.
What are you doing here?
You want to hurt yourself...
- It's you I want to hurt, dirty pimp,
I'll kill you!
I told you
that you'd hurt yourself.
I'll leave, you bastards,
I'll tell everyone!
I'll shout what you are,
and the disgusting things
you did to me!
You're all against me,
but I'll send all of you to prison!
You, and everyone
who's in this house!
But Linda,
what words!
Why do you say
that we're against you?
You seem a little
upset to me, my dear.
What are you going to tell?
That we are fine gentlemen?
Maybe that we are chivalrous men?
Do you realise
that you're talking against us,
we who treated you
like a queen in this house?
What do you want to do?
Why do you want to leave?
Go on then!
I'LL TELL EVERYTHING!
You've been too brutal
with her.
Poor girl, she's just
a little, inexperienced fawn.
A little fawn
that wanted to flee.
Go on, take care of her.
Treat her well.
I don't want anything bad
happening to her.
You have too heavy a hand, dear.
Go on, revive her!
Give her something to drink.
Lie her down on the couch.
What did you beat her for?
Didn't you see she had enough?
- She didn't!
She brought it upon herself!
Her blood
has been shed twice today.
It's disgusting.
Daisy? Daisy!
Yes, Ma'am?
- Clean up.
What did you do to me?
Nothing, dear, nothing.
You just worked yourself up
a little too much, that's all.
If you still want to leave,
you can go now.
But no gossip.
It won't do any good.
Girls too chatty
always end up badly...
and you've only just seen
part of it.
My... my luggage!
Go upstairs and pack!
We are not your maids.
But what's there to pack?
You'll come back soon, anyway!
Is that your gratitude?
You're leaving like this,
without even taking the 100.000
lira we put aside for you?
You'd better watch out!
If you spill one word outside,
we'll find you
wherever you'll be...
and fix you a nice funeral.
A first-class funeral.
Come on,
stay here!
Don't you want to live in such a nice house?
Do you know what we'll have
for lunch today? Truffled pheasant!
Eat it and choke on it!
I won't stay here.
And if you try
to look for me...
It'll be I who'll send you
to the cemetery!
What nonsense
that girl's saying!
We'll see if she won't return.
She'll be back this evening.
She walks towards the gate.
She doesn't even turn around.
But it doesn't seem
as if she's in a great hurry.
It's inevitable, with all that
confusion in her head.
You've beaten her up too much.
She's all dazed.
Enough of that, let's go!
What is it?
Why that face, my love?
What troubles you?
This disgusting life...
That hell just before
and then...
Oh Davide...
But what are you saying, Gilda!
You're exaggerating.
Our bills were hell.
The life we lead before
was hell.
When you and I
had nothing.
When we lived like trees
and were nobodies.
Life isn't disgusting at all...
Life is incredibly beautiful...
stupendous,
always new,
incredible.
It's a paradise.
A paradise.
I'm afraid the minister won't come tonight.
It's already too late.
The evening has just begun.
-  If he doesn't come, for me our evening might as well end.
You never have confidence.
- It's not a question of confidence.
Thank God.
There he is!
What did I tell you?
- My compliments, countess.
Good evening, your excellency.
I'm very happy that you left
your major obligations
to visit us tonight.
In particular since we know
that you never have a second to lose.
I've wanted to congratulate you
in person, Countess.
Isn't it your name-day today?
No, unfortunately it's my birthday,
your excellency. Don't remind me!
May I introduce to you
the Duchess of Barkis?
Duchess.
Next week,
as soon as I arrive in Madrid...
I'll send you Morena and Luisela.
They are so beautiful, so sweet...
Can you help these girls?
They deserve it...
You see,
Madrid is too small for them.
Sure, my dear.
Send them whenever you want.
We'll organise a fashion parade
in Ischia in a month and a half.
Your two beauties will have
a fantastic takeoff there.
I'm so grateful for your help...
you know that your protegées
Cleo and Ambra...
they made their luck in Madrid.
I know, I know. It's been
all your doing, Consuelo.
Do you know that they wrote
they loved you like a mum?
Ladies and gentlemen,
since it's Gilda's birthday,
we'll all dance a waltz,
like in the beautiful olden days.
Wednesday at 5.
For the entire evening, Jane.
- Alright.
Sunday at 4.
The villa of surprises...
Our most expected guest – without
offending anyone – has arrived.
Youth itself.
The motive for all our anxieties.
the object of all our regrets.
What we never were
and never will be.
Beauty,
total and natural happiness,
the most intense,
most rare.
Hi Davide! I already told you
not to tie down the dogs!
They suffer too much
and get aggressive.
Why don't you let them into the house?
They'd enjoy themselves a lot with us!
Hey, what happened to you
tonight? You're making such faces!
Don't tell me that you expected
to enjoy yourselves with me tonight?
But why, yes.
It been you we were expecting.
Everyone of us is sure that you can
give us something more, you know, Jules?
Okay. I'm ready to give you that.
Ask whatever you want.
Ask and you shall receive. Everything.
Jules, my winged genius...
I missed you a lot.
Without you,
vice seems like a virtue
and pleasure more boring
than an old book on heraldry.
Only if you suffer without me,
you can be happy with me.
None of you will
ever get tired of Jules!
You won't have time. I always manage
to beat it at the right moment.
Davide, tell your friends
how old I am.
Tell them. It's the first thing
they need to now.
Eighteen.
My little Jules is 18 years old.
I'm very old.
Death comes closer every minute.
seconds might count like years,
you don't hear the walking death.
Watch out.
it comes on tip-toes.
But it doesn't matter to us
if death walks.
Let's have all of my kisses.
Only mine are kisses.
But Ma'am...
your breasts are marvellous.
Why keep them hidden in dark?
That's not right!
They need light.
You are a magnificent tree
who just has to offer its fruits.
Who are you?
What do you want?
My name?
What's a name?
Names are useless.
How pale you are, Gilda.
Come on, let your hair loose.
Smile.
Do you want my 18 years?
I'll open my veins
and offer you my blood.
It should be enough
to make you happy.
Just that would be enough,
the rest is already there.
I want you to kiss.
- Why us? We should be the last.
If you don't, I'll leave.
That's just the beginning.
A taste of the harmony that will
reign in this house thanks to me.
What a strong smell of incense here,
like in a mortuary chapel!
No Jules, you're mistaken.
this intoxicating smell of incense...
It's not just for the dead: it's for the living too,...
which might be sadder.
It's your decision.
For me, incense is incense.
But my perfume is stronger: 18 years
of age. They don't sell it in shops.
Come on, help me. Be my friend.
I promise to you that I'll be
all yours, with body and mind.
Undress me.
Wash me.
I'll be your food. Eating of me
will bring you some of my youth.
Everything of me
you'll discover will be yours!
Depilate me all over!
Cut my nails!
What sad faces you pull!
Are you sure that you're alive
or are you dead?
I want to drink, I'm thirsty.
- Right away.
Thank you.
Have some, too.
You're thirsty too, Davide.
And you! And you!
Now that you have
fresh and clean faces - Kiss me!
Slowly, slowly.
Do it slowly!
But don't you drink here,
don't you play music?
At Louis XIV's court,
they never ate without music.
You first, Davide -
drink to youth!
Drink slowly.
I reserved the best part of me
for you: the dessert!
Put on some suitable music
and turn down the light!
Now, do everything you want.
Absolutely everything. Eat me,
drink me, kill me if you want.
But do it quickly because
in half an hour, I'll hit the road!
She's gone.
The swallow has flown away.
Smell of blood...
"Here’s the smell of the blood still."
The little hand of Lady Macbeth.
"All the perfumes of Arabia
will not sweeten..."
"this little hand!"
What are you doing?
Are you praying?
No no, I'm reciting Shakespeare.
The little hand
of Lady Macbeth...
It helps me when
I'm in need of a bit of peace.
You were afraid, too,
weren't you, Davide?
All things considered,
it wasn't an unpleasant excitement.
But were you aware of
what could've happened?
We completely lost control
of ourselves.
We've never sunken so low.
We behaved like beasts.
But if nothing's happened...
Jules is intelligent enough to know
when to arrive and when to beat it.
Davide!
Davide! There are...
moments in which
I wished you died!
You know I've been living
for so long in symbiosis with death.
Those pigs are still here!
Why don't you send them away?
Why should I?
They do less damage here
than elsewhere.
They are sleeping.
This time, I'm leaving.
I mean it.
I can't stand it any longer.
Why do you want to leave?
The night is over.
Aren't you sleepy, dear?
We'll see the guests off soon.
See? They're all leaving.
Linda! Why did you come back?
Go away!
Get out of here!
Tell me that she stopped...
that she stopped...
Why did she come back here?
No!
I don't want to!
No...
Send her away!
Away, away from me!
What would you've become
elsewhere?
But here, you'll find love.
The sun will shine.
Subtitles by
Draxtra
thanks