Ripped, corrected and synched
by Fingersmaster. Enjoy!
Forgive me.
Do this, like you're lifting weights.
All the way, yes.
Turn it around.
Stretch out your fingers.
You have a phone call on line two.
The police.
Thanks... Freyr.
You locked the car, right?
Fuck.
This is Isafjorour.
It should be all right.
I'm joking. Relax.
Of course I locked the car.
Lif. Take a picture.
- Hello. Dagny.
- Hello. Freyr.
- Have you done this before?
- No. I haven't.
I called Gerour, she's a pathologist
and went over it with her.
I've got a checklist.
Morning.
Halla Unnsteinsdottir.
71 years old.
Lived in Flateyri.
Did she do all this?
So it seems.
Let's cut her down
now that you are here.
Boys.
Will you do the autopsy?
Gerour will do it
when she arrives tomorrow.
He found her.
I see.
Hello... Freyr.
- I'm a doctor at the hospital.
- Einar Guojonsson.
Please.
When people die like this...
Hang themselves...
Then the cause of death is
that blood is no longer
flowing to the brain.
People lose consciousness very quickly.
It's rather painless.
Almost like falling asleep.
Aren't you...
a psychiatrist?
Freyr!
Thank you for your words in there.
What you said... it consoled me.
Especially since it was you
who said it.
After all you've had to go through.
Yeah.
It's hard to imagine
how you can get over
a thing like that.
Everybody...
has to deal with something.
You do it one day at a time.
Children don't just disappear
in Iceland.
I just...
Just don't understand it.
Yet that's what happened to my Benni.
- Goodbye.
- Yes.
- Are you going to sleep in the house?
You think that's a bad idea?
Nobody's lived in that house
since the town was abandoned.
I know.
- You weren't with them last summer?
- No, I couldn't make it.
Welcome to Last Sight.
- Do you like it?
- Well...
There is a lot to be done.
- It was quite different last summer.
- I know that.
It'll all be different in a week's time.
What are you going to do
with this house?
We are going to turn it
into a bed and breakfast.
There's a lot of tourists here
in the summer.
The only guesthouse here
was booked solid last summer.
- Isn't it rotten through?
- No.
The timber's quite solid.
Try it.
- It works.
- Nice.
- There's a lot of space up here.
- Don't you think?
I was wondering...
We could have bunk beds here...
And a cozy reading corner here.
This must have been the children's room?
Yes. It looks like it.
Hey.
How are you?
I haven't seen you since summer.
Thanks for asking.
I'm much better.
I feel like I've said goodbye to him.
- I've stopped taking the drugs.
- I meet with a psychologist once a week.
He says you never get
completely over it.
Isn't this the Doctor's house,
where you stayed last summer?
Yes. It is.
I'll see you in a week.
- Yes.
- But...
If something happens
then you can call me.
I thought there was no reception here.
Well... You've to go up the hill
to get reception.
But all right.
Getting into shape, are we?
Yes.
Just...
Also to clear the mind.
It helps with that.
- Do you run?
- No.
I find nothing more boring
than running around in circles.
At least you are
getting to know the town.
You've run up and down all the streets.
You could say that.
- I live here at number 23.
- You do?
Should we have a cup of coffee?
Yes.
Let's do that.
In my profession they would say
this is a clear sign
of compulsive behavior.
I woke up here the other day and
and couldn't remember
what Benni looked like.
What do you think happened?
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, no. It's all right.
Benni was playing hide and seek
with a friend of his
when he went missing.
When eight year old boys
are playing hide and seek
they don't hide behind
a street light or a bush.
They can be very ambitious.
And then...
They searched everywhere.
Everywhere.
Back and forth.
Hundreds of people searched for him.
All over the country.
Do you have any hope he is still alive?
No, Benni isn't alive.
Benni had congenital diabetes.
He had just been injected with insulin
when he went out to play.
That means that...
if he didn't get anything to eat
for hours
then the body would go into shock.
So he would have lost consciousness.
Do you still want that cup of coffee?
Hi.
I think your wife is a bit cold.
Is that so?
I want you.
Lif.
Lif!
I'm about to fuck my husband.
Stop it.
Are you sure you're ready?
Don't you want to?
Of course.
Mom.
Hi.
- Hi.
Are you OK?
Yes, I was just trying
to get Garoar to understand
that if we want a toilet
we need running water
and we don't have it
until next summer.
So if your little prince
can't poop in a bucket,
he has to hold it in.
Crazy.
How are you?
Good to see you.
- Where were you?
- I took a walk around the area
and found the cemetery.
The cemetery?
Did you see any ghosts?
Hello.
It was great to get back to work.
Are you trying to make
the house into a sauna?
- The stove is out of control.
- You're out of control.
Isn't it amazing
that no one has lived in this house
for 60 years?
It's time for this house
to live a new life.
- New Lif.
- Very funny.
That was a lame drum roll.
Well, I'm going.
To sleep.
Good night.
I'll come with you.
- Good night.
I'll turn the generator off.
The newest scars are brand new.
Made during the last 24 hours.
The oldest ones...
They are three or four years old.
All of them crosses.
I think it's clear she couldn't have
done it all on her own.
Bjarni is here.
- The widower.
- Yes. Great.
The fact is that
the marriage was
going downhill the last few years.
Why was that?
I really don't know.
Maybe because you abused her?
Never!
Why on earth do you think that?
Why crosses?
Are you religious, Bjarni?
I swear that I never hurt my Halla.
Do you know of anyone
who could have wanted to hurt her?
No.
Once, when she woke up
lnoficed
some blood
on the back of her nightdress.
She said she had eczema.
Does the name Bernodus
have any meaning for you?
No.
Fine.
Do you believe him?
His daughter just confirmed that he
was with her down south all week.
So he didn't make the new scars.
So it's unlikely that he did the others.
Yes.
She said something else as well.
She said Halla became
reclusive and distant
when a good friend of hers died.
It often happens with people at that age
when their friends start to die.
They become depressed when they realize
their own end is coming closer.
Didn't you say Gerour
would do the autopsy.
Yes, she'll be here at noon.
So why did you check
the back of the body?
What?
I was just working late. And...
The power went so...
So I went...
Down to the cellar.
I just wanted to make sure
everything was ready for the autopsy.
Why are you so embarrassed?
Who was it
you asked him about?
Yes...
Bernodus.
It would actually be great to get your
professional opinion on one thing.
Do you have time
to go down to the station?
We found an old case connected to
the church where Halla was found.
The police chief back then
was also a prolific amateur filmmaker.
The church was disassembled
and moved from Hesteyri in 1956
after the village was abandoned.
The former villagers were not happy
about it, to put it mildly.
Looks familiar?
- What year did you say it was?
- 1956.
60 years ago.
Veigar, do you have the new pictures?
Do you think this was done
by the same person?
Yes, absolutely.
I mean...
You see how it is done.
All capitals except the E's.
The circle over the I...
I think it is obvious.
So Halla did this?
Was she from Hesteyri?
You said the former villagers were
furious when the church was moved?
I did but she was from Isafjorour.
This photo was taken a year before
the church was damaged. In 1956.
Halla Unnsteinsdottir.
Here she is. Ten years old.
Why have some of the faces
been crossed out?
That's a good question.
This photo was found at this boy's home.
His name is Bernodus Pétursson.
And here it says...
Bernodus was caught in the act
of vandalizing the church.
And he was from Hesteyri.
And moved here.
Bernodus is part of another case
from that same time.
Only five days
after he was caught in the church...
He...
Bernodus Pétursson
went missing without a trace.
He has never been found.
God, I'm tired.
- Time for a beer?
- What a great idea. Dibs on not going.
Not going-
That's life, my dear.
Is it?
- No.
- Damn.
Great.
It's completely stuck.
I can't move it.
Did you take the pin?
Garoar?
What happened?
Did you fall in the creek?
No, I jumped into it.
What are you doing with a cross?
- Bergdis Ebenesardottir.
- It is supposed to be in the cemetery.
There was a hole in the ground
like a cross had been removed.
And then I found it in the creek.
What was it doing there?
How should I know?
And what, did you leave
the beer behind?
I just...
- ls the generator off?
- Yes.
We think it broke down.
It would be nice to have
a beer right now.
Not going!
OK.
Katrin.
No, don't.
- Don't move her. Katrin.
- Yes.
- Talk to me.
- Yes. I fell.
- You fell?
- Yes.
- Where did you hurt yourself?
- Here.
- The leg.
- Do you feel pain in your leg?
- Can you move?
- Yes.
- Can you sit?
Let me see.
- Is it broken?
- I don't know.
Does this hurt?
- Yes.
- What about this?
I'll go and try to call
for an emergency helicopter.
That's not necessary.
- It's just sprained.
- No, I'll try to contact the boat.
- Let the hospital take a look.
- Yes.
- I'm going to fix the pillow.
Do you want one?
- Two.
Here you are.
Thank you.
- Lie down.
- Yes, wait.
I'll call the boat tomorrow, my love.
It's all arranged by years.
Bernodus was called Dirty.
And Unclean.
When he refused to take his clothes off
and take a shower after gym.
The scars were from different times.
It had been going on for some years.
18 crosses in total.
The poor boy seems to have been
abused for years.
The father was a drunk
and probably had mental issues.
It says here that he was
a church warden at Hesteyri
and was very angry
when the church was moved.
The school nurse wrote a report
but it seems to have been ignored.
How disgusting.
- Different times.
- Children weren't protected like today.
Nobody knew what
systematic bullying was.
His parents.
The mother, Bergdis Ebenesardottir
died when Bernodus was born.
The father probably blamed Bernodus.
Jesus.
See here.
Eight kids have been crossed out.
Halla is one of them.
Of those eight six are dead.
What?
Six out of eight dead?
- Before they turned 70?
- Exactly.
All died during the last three years.
And moreover...
All died in accidents.
Apart from Halla of course, she hung
herself. Gunnhildur Gisladéttir.
She drowned.
That was two years ago.
Jon AEvarsson.
He died of burn wounds. His house
caught fire in the middle of the night.
Sigvaldi Konraosson.
He froze to death.
He got lost walking on
Vatnajokull-glacier.
And then this one.
Steinn Gunnbjornsson.
He died in a car accident.
Eighteen months ago.
And finally, this one.
Védis Arngrimsdottir.
She was the first to die.
She fell on garden shears and bled out.
What? Were they sure it was an accident?
How do you fall on garden shears?
Could it be that Bernodus
just went into hiding somewhere?
Maybe he just fled to Reykjavik.
Changed his name.
Then he came back a few years ago
and sought his revenge.
Think about it.
The kids who are crossed out...
They bullied him terribly.
And now they are all dying
in mysterious ways.
So you are looking for a serial killer
who is 70 years old.
Sorry, I'm late.
Let's begin.
Hello.
Hello, daddy.
Is it fun?
See mommy.
Hi.
I want to show you something.
Do you have some time?
Yes. Come in.
The last pictures of Benni
before he went missing.
From the gas station at Artlinshofoi.
And what do you want to show me?
I just got this.
This is from the autopsy of Vedis,
the one who fell on the garden shears.
God.
See...
Exactly the same pattern
as on Bernédus' back.
And on Halla's back.
Could it be some sort of religious cult?
All those crosses and...
The vandalism in the church. Unclean.
Those two are still alive.
What do they say about all this?
Well, this one, Ursula Astraosdottir...
- She is at a nursing home here in town.
- Ursula?
I've met her.
I have.
She is schizophrenic.
She didn't say a word
the two times I have met her.
And then this one.
Larus Helgason.
He is a farmer in Onundarfjorour.
I haven't been able to reach him.
He doesn't answer.
Hi.
Garoar.
Hello.
Dagny.
Hi, it's Dagny.
Is it Katrin?
Katrin.
Katrin, are you there?
What are you doing?
Are you OK?
What happened?
I swear...
There is someone down there.
There is someone, there is someone.
Down there?
What happened?
Talk to me.
There was...
I went downstairs.
The door shut and I couldn't open.
- I didn't know there was a cellar here.
- Girls.
Did you know there was a cellar here?
There is a corpse down there.
- What do you mean?
- There is a child's corpse down there!
- A child's corpse?
- When will the boat come?
We couldn't get reception.
We tried and tried.
There is no signal here.
- I can't stay here anymore.
- Me neither.
We have to try to call again.
Go further.
I can't stay in this fucking
house anymore.
I mean it.
- OK.
- We can go to the Doctor's house.
Yeah?
- How are you doing?
- I don't understand this.
The whole nation followed the story.
Not like this.
A total stranger.
Why the hell would he be
obsessed with Benni?
Maybe it was a hobby.
This is a very isolated place.
But I understand why
you find it uncomfortable.
Sometimes when I try to remember him
I only see this blue coat.
It was his favourite.
- Got the stretcher ready?
- In the car.
Do you know the cause of death?
We think he drank clog remover.
Are you sure nobody lived in the house
since the town was abandoned?
I don't think so.
This child must be connected
to the former owners.
It could be anyone.
No reception.
I'm going up
to get the beds ready.
Garoar!
- Garoar!
- Yes? What?
- Did you put it there?
- What?
This is not funny!
- I didn't put it there.
- Don't fuck with me!
- Did you bring it here?
- Are you crazy?
- Watch out!
- Are you kidding?
My dear.
Hello, Ursula.
It's me, Freyr.
The new doctor.
Remember me?
I want to ask you
a few questions if that's OK.
The photo.
Do you remember these kids?
That's you.
This boy here.
Bernodus Pétursson.
Do you remember him?
He vanished without a trace.
Was never seen again.
Ursula.
Do you know what happened to him?
Benni is at the bottom.
Everything is green.
What did you say?
Benni what?
Everything green?
What is green?
Ursula.
Answer me.
What did you say?
You said "Benni".
Why?
- Benni what?
- Freyr.
- Answer me. Ursula.
You must remember it.
He said Benni hid himself
in a green submarine.
Don't you remember?
Can you take a look for me?
It's somewhere in the boxes.
Just...
I want to take a look at it.
Sure.
I'll take the first flight tomorrow.
What did Ursula say to you?
I thought she mentioned Benni
but it was rather unclear.
I have to go.
Katrin!
Katrin.
We have to get out of here.
You have to eat, Katrin.
You haven't eaten
since yesterday morning.
I don't think we're alone here.
I saw...
I saw a small boy.
This was a big mistake.
To come all this way.
It's been such a short time since...
Since what?
Since I had to...
give birth... to our son?
- Stillborn. Say it.
- Kata.
- Why do you always have to do this?
- What?
Just, it was traumatic for me too.
All this nonsense,
nobody ever thinks about that.
You didn't speak to me...
I just felt like you thought
I was never doing enough.
Why was it so important to you
that Lif not come with us here?
Answer me.
What happened here
between you two last summer?
Things were over between us anyway.
Wasn't it?
Sometimes things just develop
in their own way.
Without you being able to control it.
Hello.
How have you been?
Freyr. You wanted to look
at the police reports?
Yes.
You know where they are.
"Olafur Magnusson,
eight years old, autistic."
"Cold. Very cold fingers.
I lost a mitten.
Benni hid in the green submarine."
Hello, On.
Do you remember us?
We're Benni's parents.
His mom is here.
You remember her.
Hi, On.
What are you doing?
Are you playing a video game?
On.
We want to ask you again
about the submarine.
Oli. Wait a second.
- On, is everything all right?
- Everything's fine.
Oli, can you describe it?
Oli, you said it was green.
Oli, it wasn't a submarine,
there are no submarines in Iceland!
- Why did you lie?
- Freyr.
- On!
- Freyr, let him go.
Well...
How would the psychiatrist
describe his behaviour in there?
I want you to meet someone.
What do we have to discuss
with a lawyer?
I don't have time.
I have to catch a flight.
Hello.
- Elias Bjornsson.
- Hello. Freyr.
Can I offer you something to drink?
Water, coffee?
Excuse me.
What...
- What are we doing here?
- Freyr.
Elias has been an incredible
help to me for the last few months.
I see.
He has been in contact with Benni.
What?
It would be more accurate
to say that...
Benni made contact with me.
I don't have the time or inclination
for nonsense like this.
Freyr, you can at least listen to him.
Vilhjalmur Alvar.
Arion Bank.
Tell him I'll call in ten minutes.
Listen.
Benni is trapped.
Trapped between two worlds.
Sometimes when the end of life
is somehow unresolved
people can't reach
the next plane of existence.
Like when...
the body can't be found
or when nobody knows what happened.
The only thing that can release
these souls from their chains
is if their body is found.
And that the mystery
of their death is solved.
Is that so?
I see.
And What?
If those souls can't reach
the next plane of existence
they can get trapped.
And as more time goes by
the more powerful they become
and their problem can become obsession.
Bitterness. And anger.
They can make themselves visible.
They can travel around.
And then you who were part of his life
are in the biggest danger.
The thing is that Benni has to be found.
As soon as possible.
Or the consequences can be serious.
What do you think
we've been doing
for the last three years?
It has ruined our lives.
If I need a lawyer one day
I might contact you.
The name Bernodus.
Does it mean anything to you?
It is mentioned again and again.
But I can't explain why.
Ah, I slept so good.
Have you eaten anything?
Where is Garoar?
Isn't everything OK?
Did you fuck him here on the counter?
Katrin.
What happened?
What did you say to her?
What...
I just told her the truth.
And what does that mean?
Not everything, of course.
- Why would you do that?
- She confronted me.
Didn't we decide to wait
until we came back to town?
Wasn't she just fishing?
No. Lif.
Katrin and I have been together
for twelve years.
I know her, I saw it in her eyes.
- She won't be able to handle it.
- No.
She's such a head case.
Lif.
Look at me.
It'll be all right.
Now we just have to
look to the future.
I love you.
No.
I'll go and call for help.
"If you see this I'm at the house.
Katrin knows about us."
"Are you sure I'm the father?"
Wait!
Ursula.
How did you get here?
He's not always so mean to me.
Who?
Bernodus.
Was he here with you in the boat?
He's always with me.
Always.
We were always teasing him.
I was the only one
who saw where he went.
I never told anyone.
Never.
Everything is green.
Green?
Where is everything green?
Ursula.
Bernodus went away with the boat.
What boat?
This one? The one we're in right now?
I never told anyone.
Never. No.
Everything is green.
Green.
Ursula.
Benni is at the bottom,
everything is green.
That's what you said.
Remember?
Why did you say that?
Where is that?
Where is everything green?
Benni... Woke him up.
Benni woke him up?
Bernodus?
He shouldn't have woken him.
Ursula.
How are you feeling?
Why were you in that boat
in the middle of the night?
I saw a boy.
- I followed him here.
- Boy?
It was like...
he was asking me to follow him.
To Ursula.
Who was the boy?
I can't...
Freyr.
Bernodus.
I have seen him before.
I feel like that he is trying
to help me.
And that clairvoyant... who claims
to be in contact with Benni...
He also mentioned him.
Bernodus.
Ursula also talked about Bernodus.
I fear that I'm losing my mind.
I'm becoming like
one of my patients.
Why can't I find him?
Why can't I find Benni?
- What is it?
- I need more green.
- You should be asleep.
It's all right.
Hi.
Sorry, I was asleep.
What?
Sorry.
He has always said
Benni hid in a green submarine.
And Ursula said:
Benni is at the bottom.
Everything is green.
Bottom of the ocean?
I don't know.
Let me check something.
Septic tank?
Take a look.
Wait.
Do you still have the...
The video from the gas station?
Showing Benni?
Sure.
Here.
Let's see.
There.
I just didn't make the connection
until now.
Wait.
Those three.
They were inside the gas station
when Benni walked out of there.
And?
They eat a meal.
That's why they were there
for so long.
This one is taken
out here in the tunnel.
You can't see
what's on the trailer.
Here it is.
Hesteyri.
The search for Benni must have been
in full swing at the time.
So you probably weren't paying
attention to other news.
There is an abandoned whaling station
just outside of the village.
There they found the bodies of
Garoar Magnusson and Lif Einarsdottir.
Lif was pregnant with their child.
Katrin Porsdottir,
Garoar's wife...
She probably tried to seek help on foot.
Her body has never been found
despite an extensive search.
Lif's phone was found
with Katrin's fingerprints on it.
She had tried to call for help.
I always thought it was misguided
to try to fix up this old shack.
It's rotten through and through.
- Can you help us?
- Sure.
-- English --