Mizizi Chronicles
I'm all set here
Let's roll
Action
Hello. I'm Raj Jaiswal.
Welcome to British Raj.
Before we move on to
our next assignment,
let's meet our new co-anchor
the sexy, sultry Dilnaaz Bagga.
Hi Dilnaaz.
- Hi Raj. Hi everybody.
You know, today is very lucky
for Dilnaaz.
Not because it's her first day on the
show, but because I am introducing her.
It's a joke. It's a joke, darling.
You can smile.
First on the show, you see.
So tell me, Dilnaaz,
you have a boy friend?
That's not in this...
- Someone you date. I know that.
C'mon, don't be shy.
It's British Raj. Tell us!
There must be someone for whom
you are willing to cross all limits.
Actually... it depends.
Depends? Really?
For him, will you spend
three hours of your life...
on a movie that's beyond
your comprehension?
Yes, of course.
- Will you do it everyday for a year?
I mean, will you do it for 365 days?
Everyday? A year?
Yes, everyday.
Today we are going to meet
a warm Englishman...
who has spent 1095 hours on
Hindi films for the sake of his love.
Our correspondent Akshay Kapoor
is very anxious...
outside the Baker Street police station
to show you this exclusive.
Over to you, Akshay.
Hello Raj. I'm standing in front of
the Baker Street police station,
looking for an unusual lover.
God knows why he is hiding from us.
Let's find him.
Officer, be gentle.
Follow me.
In relation, I am your father.
The name is John Smith.
By my mother I swear, I will
pick each one of you and kill you!
This is Inspector John Smith. His Hindi
tutors include the famous writers...
of the Hindi film industry
like Javed Akhtar and K K Shukla.
Inspector, what inspired you
to learn Hindi?
I fell in love.
- Wonderful. What was her name?
Ina, Meena, Dika, Anju or Manju?
Monica! O my darling!
So Inspector, how did your
small love story begin?
Would you come with me
for the late night show?
She worked for Symphony Theatre.
Ticket window, you know.
I used to buy tickets
to catch a glimpse of her.
Eventually ended up watching movies.
In one year I learnt fluent Hindi.
And I proposed to her.
Lovers take the brides away.
Then a quick wedding followed by kids.
That's it.
So that was Inspector John Smith's
interesting filmy love-story.
Akshay Kapoor for British Raj.
Thank you, Akshay.
How do you find the Bollywood type
love-story of Inspector Smith?
Do email us.
- That's all.
That's all on British Raj today.
Whether you want it or not,
we will be back tomorrow, same place,
same time. Love you London.
Bye.
- Wonderful.
Great show. That's it.
10 pm?
- Sorry.
You and I, dinner? Together?
But Raj...
- I know, you can't believe it, right?
But your beauty has the right
to go out for dinner with me.
Dinner?
- I know.
Only dinner can't fill your stomach.
You can wait till breakfast if you wish.
I like my eggs boiled.
Don't be late. Okay?
Raj...
- Yes darling?
Work, work, work! You look good.
- Sure
Rubina, my love, your husband is
treating you well?
Stop it.
- What about you? I'll ring you soon
Kathy, my love
Looks like you're losing some weight.
Smashing
"Early morning,"
"what's come over me?"
"I don't know why
I'm walking on air"
"New morning,"
"new place,"
"new directions,
new paths,"
"I tread"
"Is it that I've gotten
a new perspective?"
"Or, were the sights unseen before?"
"Or is it that I'm walking
in a dream?"
"Early morning,
what's come over me?"
"I don't know why
I'm walking on air"
"New morning,"
"new place,"
"with new perspective,
new sights..."
"I see"
"In this humming ambience..."
"and smiling beauty,"
"I walk with the world"
"Early morning,
what's come over me?"
"I don't know why
I'm walking on air"
"Live the moment"
"If you live, you win,"
"and that's an intoxication"
"Tomorrow is a new intoxication..."
"that's worth living for"
"Drink up the wine of every moment..."
"and fill your heart"
"Early morning,
what's come over me?"
"I don't know why
I'm walking on air"
"New morning, new place,"
"new directions,
new paths,"
"I tread"
"In this humming ambience..."
"and smiling beauty,"
"I walk with the world"
Hey, who are you?
Hey, you on my balcony. Hey you!
Yes, you
Are you talking to me?
No, I talking to my favourite painting.
Of course, I'm talking to you.
Who are you? How did you
come inside my house?
You can see me? Listen to me?
Wow! That's fantastic.
Yes, I can see you, listen to you and
do many things. But not tonight. You...
Touch me
Two minutes haven't passed since we met
and you are asking me to touch you?
Can you feel this?
- Yes, I can feel this.
But right now I can feel you getting
out of my house. Who are you?
Shivani
Shivani or Akashwani,
please leave my house.
This is my house.
- Really?
Let's do something. Come, let me
leave you back at the hospital.
How did you know I came
from the hospital?
Your words clearly say that you've
run away from a mental asylum. Besides,
How did you enter my house?
You stole Mr Bolting's keys?
Come on, give me the keys.
I don't need any keys.
- Then how did you enter?
Came flying?
- Listen,
just give me five minutes of
your time. My story is very strange.
But if you listen carefully,
you might trust me.
And at this point of time,
your trust is imperative for me.
Why this favour on me? You don't have a
husband, boyfriend or a brain surgeon...
who'd listen to your rubbish?
- No. Because no one can see me.
Except you.
- What is this nonsense?
Would you like to listen to my story?
- Pardon?
Please
Will you go away if I listen to you?
- You were right.
I've come from the hospital.
- I know that.
I'm a doctor. I met with
an accident six months back.
How many did you kill?
Ever since, I've been in coma.
My body is in room number 303
of Thomwell Hospital.
Finished?
So you are a spirit? A spirit.
Well beautiful spirit, if you have
more friends, get them over tomorrow.
I don't have time today.
Now cut the crap.
Akshay sent you, right?
Akshay, who?
You will know soon. Come on.
I was kidding. Weren't you watching me?
I was laughing all the way.
Of course... I'm not serious either.
I'm also laughing away right now.
Hang on. Hello?
- Who is it?
Raj
What am I doing? As usual at this hour,
- Doing what?
Getting beaten up by my wife.
- And why so? Tell him.
You'll kill me!
Hello AK. Your friend Shivani
is sitting right before me.
She says she is in a coma. You have
only 30 seconds to end this farce.
Coming up is Shivani for you.
Shivani, your time starts now.
Hello?
- I can't take the phone.
I can't pick up things.
Did you hear?
- What did I hear?
She can't pick up things.
- Who can't pick up what?
Okay
Can you hear now?
- I could hear then too.
But I couldn't figure anything.
My ears are ringing.
Come on AK, I know you are trying
to pull a fast one on me.
And you know I'm not going
to be fooled. Please speak and get out.
Hello? Hi Akshay.
I know you cannot hear me
But your friend doesn't believe me.
AK, answer her.
- Who spoke? What should I answer?
Hey AK, dude, this is
really bad timing.
Dilnaaz will be here in five minutes,
- I'm going through bad times!
My house is being vandalized.
Can you hear?
Raj, if I don't hang up, I will be
martyred in my prime. Bye Raj.
Bye?
- Kuljeet. Relax please.
Fine
Which hospital?
- Thomwell Hospital.
Is there a ward for lunatics too?
- Shivani Dutt, room number 303
Right
Come on, let's go.
- Really? You will go with me?
If not, how will I throw you out?
- Will you go just like this?
Then how do I go?
- Put some clothes on.
Go as my cousin. Tell them you have
to meet me tonight itself,
since you got a flight in the morning.
Simple, easy and it always works.
Absolutely not. We follow rules here.
But ma'am, I was just wondering...
- Aren't you an Indian?
Yes.
- Does it hurt if you speak in Hindi?
Ms Nurse, you are an Indian. You know
the pain of separation from dear ones.
I've come from India
only to meet her.
You are like my mother.
Can't a mother breach a small rule
of this huge hospital for her son?
Only 15 minutes.
And don't touch anything!
Come.
- Let's go
Trapped
Look, she is in a coma.
She can hear what you say.
Don't overact
like you did in the lobby.
Take it easy.
And don't touch any thing! Okay?
Yes
- Have I made myself clear?
Very.
- Okay
Twin sister?
Mind-blowing!
Whose idea was it?
Mr Raj, it's me.
Neither alive nor dead.
Whoever you are,
why are you dragging me into it?
Don't know. Maybe a relationship
of a previous birth.
Pardon? Previous birth? At least you
should've got your lines written well.
But it's not your fault, you are
just an actress. Okay guys,
out with the cameras. I'm not going
to be a scapegoat. AK, show up
Listen Raj, I've told you!
No AKs or cameras here
Only I am here.
- You are right
And here's my body that's stepping
towards death everyday.
That's really sad.
- Why don't you trust me?
How should I explain? What do I do?
Do whatever you have to.
I am going home. Okay?
What happened?
Who are you talking to?
So you are also in league?
- With whom?
With her
With whom?
- With her?
- With her
Tell me
It seems you love her very much.
She is loveable.
All of us in the hospital
love her dearly.
If you wish you can sit
for some more time.
Insolent
Relax Inspector Smith.
It's absolutely normal.
It happens with coma patients. If she
opens her eyes it doesn't mean...
she is conscious.
She still is in a coma.
Look, this is her cerebral cortex
which is severely damaged. Have a look.
She is lucky, her brain stem is fine,
because of which there are movements.
She can open her eyes, but
she cannot see anything.
She cannot think or feel anything.
How long, doctor?
- Can't say
A month, a year, maybe all her life.
No hopes of her getting well,
Inspector.
The world live on hopes, doctor.
Hi
One shot from here.
- See you later.
See you
Lip stick please.
- Hi
Good morning
Dilnaaz, last night...
- You were about to ruin my life!
3idane's head wouldn't have hurt
so much. Aren't you ashamed?
You call up a married man at night
and ask him to talk to a girl.
And you don't even let her talk!
- I called you last night?
Akshay, get out of here. I'm ready
to roll. Pass the papers, baby.
Action.
- Hello and welcome to British Raj.
Today's top story;
From Spark To Fire.
An 18-year-old girl, in a fit of rage,
torched her boyfriend's brand new Porche.
Why did she do it?
Good question.
Because her boyfriend dared to come
four hours late.
What do you think, Raj?
Did Pooja do the right thing?
Or was she overreacting?
Well, you know...
- Don't you think that...
he got a mild punishment?
I mean,
don't you think she should've
set her boyfriend afire?
Pardon?
- That's not in script.
What does he think of himself?
To make a girl wait for hours alone...
in a restaurant,
is that decency?
I'm sorry.
- It's disgusting.
I say, he should be castrated,
not set afire.
Ouch
Now come on, Dilnaaz.
It's a family audience.
It happens sometimes.
Your boyfriend... I mean, Pooja's
boyfriend must've been helpless,
held up with some problem.
- Problem?
What kind of problem, Raj?
Come on, it happens...
You?
Hello.
I?
- Who are you?
Wow!
So who am I now?
- Okay, cut it out, guys.
This is too much. I told you, I'm not
going to be fooled. C'mon, out with it.
Who sent the girl to my house?
I see. So there was a girl
with you last night.
Yes... I mean no...
- That was your problem.
Hey, stop right there!
Don't come in front you camera.
What's wrong with him?
He doesn't do drugs.
Don't block...
Ghost!
- Ghost?
Am I?
- What is he saying?
You don't want to know!
- Look Raj,
I didn't fall for you,
you were behind me.
Oh my god! You are really a ghost.
No, technically I'm not a ghost.
- How dare you?
Because I'm not dead yet. Why did
you run away from the hospital?
You are trouble, I have to run.
- Trouble? I am trouble?
Mr Raj Jaiswal, this is a bit much.
Not you, Dilnaaz.
- Relax, Raj.
So this is Dilnaaz? What's great
about her? She is so ordinary.
Have you seen your face?
You are worse than ordinary.
Really?
- No, no...
Then why did you invite me
for dinner last night?
You were supposed to dine with her?
Are you nuts? I am better company.
Dinner with you? I'm not nuts.
That's it!
- Oh no!
I've had enough. I won't work
with this filthy man.
Just roll, baby.
This is reality TV.
I won't keep mum.
I will sue you for sexual harassment.
Ghost!
- I'll take this channel to court.
Hey, that's not Ms Creative.
Pack up
Ghost
No, it's not possible. Please go away.
- Raj, listen to me Raj
Raj, listen to me.
- I don't want to hear you.
Please go away. Why are you after me?
Please leave me.
Excuse me.
- What did you say?
Raj, what's wrong with you?
Nothing. What's wrong with me?
I'm just a bit tired.
I'm not mad.
- I didn't say you are mad.
But everyone there thinks I am.
- All right, let me come in.
Don't! Or you'll regret
Why?
There's a ghost in the lift.
- There's a ghost in the lift?
Raj! Listen to me.
Why didn't you allow him to come in?
- I can't hear you, I can't see you. No.
I can't see anything. It is not true!
- Why are you running away from me?
Lord, save me.
Raj, listen to me.
Listen to me.
Will you listen to me, Raj?
Come on, Raj!
Take her away from me, Lord.
I told you...
I'm not a ghost.
Go away.
You don't exist.
lt'll be bright sunshine
in Stockholm today.
It's not happening to me.
Where are you going?
- Wherever you go.
No, no.
Please... please come out... come out.
Please
Calm down... you are in control.
Hello?
Raj stop talking to yourself.
AK, I'm not talking to myself.
Wait there,
I need to talk to you.
No.
- I'll come and tell you. Wait!
No!
Move
Why?
- You mind if I drive the car?
Are we talking? Or going on a drive?
- We'll talk while driving.
AK, you're entering at your own risk.
- Yes, I know.
You know nothing.
Hello, excuse me...
I'm not your driver.
Will you come and sit in the front?
- I can't sit in the front.
I forget. The ghost is sitting
in the car.
She-ghost!
- Of course.
If you have a problem,
there surely has to be a girl.
And right now
she is sitting beside you.
No AK, she is sitting beside you.
Right here?
She is hot.
You have a great tuning
with the ghost.
Tell her to go and sit behind,
so that you can come forward.
Sit please.
Please.
- What?
Of course
What?
Shall we?
- Let's go.
Look, there's no need to
tell him the truth.
He is my best friend,
I can't lie to him.
Why not, bro? When you can talk
to nobody, why can't you lie to me?
I'm not talking to nobody, AK.
She is sitting behind us.
Why don't you tell the ghost to get off
and leave us alone for a few minutes?
I wish to talk to you. Until then
tell her to go to a graveyard and sing.
Gone?
Gone.
- Where?
You are a genius. Why didn't you
say that before?
What's up with you?
- What's up with me?
AK, please understand.
You don't believe me, right?
- Well... I do.
Last night, after you took a bath,
you met a girl.
She was with you the whole night.
- Not together, but yes...
Away. Because she wasn't a girl,
she was a ghost.
Not the spooky movie types...
- Beautiful ghost.
Very good. She also says that she is
not a ghost and she is alive.
She is comatose.
- Yes, correct. No one can see her,
except you. Very good.
At least it will take two years
in the mental asylum.
AK, cut it out! I'm not mad.
I have seen her body with my own eyes.
Every mad man says that...
- I'm not mad, I am not mad.
Exactly
You are right. I need to rest.
Let me drop you back at the office.
You are right, you badly need rest.
Go home and take rest, I'll take care
of the office. Don't worry about me.
See you.
- Yes. But don't see anybody else,
I'll get jealous.
Know what? I met Mrs Khanna
before coming here.
That gossip-monger Mrs Khanna.
She was asking about your health
I said, fine. She will come home
in some days.
I don't know why she laughed at me,
as if I was lying.
That was it. I walked away in a rage.
Oh God! Shivani, don't be upset now.
I'm telling you,
you'll be absolutely fine.
Turn that side.
Good girl
D'you know what is the greatest
strength of human beings?
Faith.
Everytime I see you,
my faith gets stronger.
I know, you will come back.
You have to, my child!
I can feel you too.
- Feel what?
Oh no, not you, ma'am...
- I'll send Bob.
And I'll see if you can feel him too.
If it goes on like this,
I'll be hauled in.
Do you believe me now?
- Is this possible?
Possible? It is happening, Raj
You still have doubts?
Hi. Can I have a coffee
and some scrambled eggs please?
Sure, whatever you want.
Yes, it's happening. But why?
You... in the hospital... in my house
...why in my life?
I don't know.
I know only my story.
But why in my life?
Do you have a phone?
- Why? You want to make a call?
Take out your phone and talk.
Thank you.
Hello? So tell me
your suspense thriller.
Just one condition. Use your heart,
not your mind, to listen.
After the accident when I came to,
I found myself in this weird state.
Since I'm an doctor, I couldn't
believe such things could happen.
It scared me, but the sight
of my mom would give me hope.
I stepped out of the hospital
with that hope...
And went to see mom.
I found that she too was losing hope.
I couldn't see her sorrow.
For days I just wandered.
Among the crowd, alone, troubled.
Finally, in search of peace,
I decided to go home...
your house, now. I was thinking that
there's no end to my woes.
And last night...
I met you. You can see me,
I can feel you, listen to you, blah
blah blah. All right, I'll help you.
Really?
Why?
- You think...
I lent you a ear to pass time?
I don't do things if I see no profit
And from you, I stand to gain a lot.
Come on, follow me.
Shivani, there are three girls
behind you.
I like all of them. Find out
if I stand a chance.
Are you crazy?
What?
Go. You don't have a choice.
I think he's really cute.
Tell me, what were they
saying about me?
Forget it.
- Why forget it?
- Why?
No chance, Raj.
- What were they saying about me?
That...
- What?
She said, you came alone
to the bar.
So?
Your clothes...
- Clothes? What about my clothes?
They're strange.
- Strange?
You know, they think you are...
I am?
- Gay.
I told you, this bar is a bad one.
Let's go.
No use being your friend.
Go back to wherever you've come from.
Why do you look at life like this?
- Because in our world,
this is how we look at life.
Do whatever you have to in your world.
Tell me, don't you use
this road everyday?
Yes.
- How many times till now?
Why?
- Just asking.
Might be a 50,000 times. Happy?
- What do you like the most here?
Are you interviewing me?
- Come on, Raj.
Many things...
- Like?
Like... like these apples.
Even the queen of England...
buys her apples from here.
And yes the coffee shop,
whose Jamaican brew is very special
And Marques Potter,
where Akshay and I used to
have a drink everyday.
Also that restaurant whose food is
tasteless but waitresses very pretty
What's so funny?
- Want to see from my perspective?
No.
Please
Okay.
- Got a handkerchief?
Yes. Why?
- Blindfold yourself
Not myself, I like to blindfold others.
And that too at my home, not here.
Don't get excited, Raj.
Come on, trust me.
Okay.
- Trust me.
You won't throw me
in front of a bus, will you?
No
Come on
Concentrate. Can you hear
the tweeting of the bird?
It's in a cage. Must be calling out to
its beloved who was separated.
What do you think?
There's a beggar outside your favourite
bar. Everyone thinks he is blind.
You also give him money. But he's not
really blind. He's acting.
And your Queen of England's favourite
apple-seller, who's quite famous,
his apples look more fresh and red.
But no one knows that...
he uses a spray that makes the apples
shine more. Don't buy from him again.
And this is Michelle,
the florist with a smile.
But she's hurt from inside,
Because her son has gone for war
in Afghanistan. It's been years,
and he has not returned yet. Michelle's
world has stopped on that turn.
And this place is called The Lamp
Of Love. You must've heard about it.
Lovers who kiss under this lamp post
stay together forever, they say.
But why'd you care?
Do you see something here too,
that I can't? Am I missing something?
Your Phone.
Take out your phone and talk
- Why?
People will call you mad.
- But I'm not mad, right?
Let people call what they want,
I don't care.
- Really?
"Whatever people wish to say,"
"let them say"
"Whatever happens,"
"let it happen"
"Why should the world bother
if a heart..."
"meet another here?"
"Whoever wants to say anything,"
"let them say"
"Just don't bother"
"No, no..."
"don't be afraid
of the world anymore,"
"don't hide anything"
"Whatever it is, it is the truth,
don't you hide from the world"
"Please come,
for a moment..."
"please sit"
"The feelings in your heart,
pour them out"
"Why should we be afraid?"
"If anyone thinks we are crazy,
O ignorant one?"
"Whatever we want to do,"
"let's do"
"Let the others freak out"
"Whatever they wish to say,
let the people..."
"say"
"They will say it and forget,"
"just think"
"So why should I change for them?"
"He who doesn't understand
changes"
"Whoever cares for the world,"
"let him care"
"Let him change"
Did we do anything wrong
last night, Shivani?
Why, what happened?
- Forget it, Raj.
You look innocent while sleeping.
- I'm extremely sorry to disappoint you.
But now that I'm up,
I've got lots to do.
I have to put your spirit back
into your body.
And I really don't appreciate you
watching me while sleeping.
Coffee, sweetheart.
- No.
Raj, it's not your cup of tea.
It's a waste of time.
Really? Do you have a better idea?
You entered my house,
got me into this mess...
and now you say it's a waste of time.
Women! What do you want me to do?
Excuse me.
Trust me, have the coffee,
take a bath and feel fresh.
I am the ghost, not you.
I've told you before! You are
not a ghost, you are she-ghost.
Okay, I'm just kidding.
Actually you are...
I am?
Forget it
- Forget it.
I am?
- Jesus! Shivani, stop being spooky...
and spare me.
You are beautiful, very beautiful.
Why did you keep doing this?
Have you ever been in love?
I do, everyday.
- Grow up, Raj.
Not that kind of love,
I'm talking about true love.
Even I'm talking about true love.
Is my love a farce?
Even I love truly.
If you think true love is marriage,
then I'm really not interested.
Have you seen Akshay?
He gets beaten up everyday.
His wife used to run after him,
now he's running away from her.
Women! Women! Women.
Raj where the?
- AK, what's up, dude?
You got a long life.
We were just talking about you.
Really?
Forget it. When will you get time off
from your ghostly encounters?
I've been waiting since morning.
Can't you even give me a call?
Pardon? Was I meant to call you?
- I see.
When I was committing the most
beautiful mistake of my life,
you were busy taking our photographs...
And now when I rue those days, can't
you even give me a condolence call?
It's your anniversary.
I forgot, I'm so sorry
I'm also sorry
Congratulations buddy.
- Mere wishes are not enough
I've organised a party at 8 tonight.
You know how dangerous Kuljeet is.
Of course.
- Be on time. And bring along...
the ghost.
I would love you come.
- She says she'd love to come.
You are most welcome.
- Not up, she's next to you.
Do come at eight.
I'll see both of you at eight.
I think you should leave.
- Is she a vegetarian or non-veg?
She can't eat.
- I see. She might like to drink?
Drinks blood.
- Dracula's sister? Any preference?
B positive.
- Don't worry, I'll organise it.
Raj, my boy! Come in.
- AK, what's up? Congratulations.
Congratulations for what?
For her?
- Kuljeet,
Happy anniversary.
Thank you, Raj. Are you all right?
Pardon? I'm absolutely fine.
Raj, did you get Ms Invisible along?
Yes, she's with me.
How are you, lady?
Is everything fine in ghost world?
She's standing here
Both of you come inside.
Raj Jaiswal of British Raj?
Not a bad show.
Who's that?
- Our family psychiatrist, Dr Patnaik.
We are happy because of him.
- So you guys think I need a shrink?
No, no. No problem in meeting him.
- Come on.
Have a drink.
- You will get advice for free. C'mon
It's okay, Raj,
I had also seen a ghost once.
In mirror.
- No. On the wedding altar.
Doctor, please have some hot samosa.
Kuljeet made them.
Have some.
No? Raj, you try one.
No, no, I'm full.
Aishwarya Rai, wherever you are,
have a samosa.
My wife made them.
Nothing will happen to you.
It's dangerous only for living being.
- Then you can eat after I kill you!
Still I can't digest them.
- Today's our wedding anniversary!
No wonder I was beaten up twice.
- I beat you yesterday, not today.
We don't need samosas.
- Okay.
So Raj, where is this
ghostly girlfriend of yours?
Right now Shivani's standing
near the window.
I got it.
Your parents are divorced, right?
Yes. How do you know?
How do you know?
- The way he swings his legs.
It's a sign. I can tell.
Such a shame! A handsome guy...
You are a virgin, Raj.
What?
- You are a virgin, Raj?
No, no!
How do you know?
His girlfriend is a ghost.
Now what do you expect?
What is this nonsense? And what
is the point of all of this?
The point is, you need help.
And only I can help you out.
Exactly.
- Yeah, right.
Now tell me, how does she look?
Not like an ogre,
she looks simple and beautiful.
Raj, you need help.
You know what you have to do?