The doctor is here.
How is he?
- Not too good today, dear.
Still, we expect that, don't we?
It won't be long if you ask my opinion.
No sleep?
- No.
Get the injection ready.
- Yes. Straight away.
Darling .. remember your promise.
At 4 o'clock he had one sixth of a gram?
- Yes, dear.
I'll give an intravenous.
- I can do it myself you know.
It should be done by a doctor.
I have had enough experience.
I can do it perfectly well.
Get him ready please.
Oh.
It's alright.
We are ready now.
He'll sleep now.
You see, I took quite
a fancy to Mr Benson.
Since he first came
up here to Liverpool.
Such a nice man.
And so good-looking too.
For a professor.
It was a mercy really he
was saved that suffering.
But it was sudden.
After that injection she
gave him, he went to sleep.
Of course, it could have
been coincidental.
All she said was 'he should sleep now'.
I thought at the time that there was
something in the way she said it.
Something peculiar. And then she
would give the injection herself.
I could have done it. I could
have done it perfectly well.
I've had a great deal of experience.
I was a bronze medal at St Mary's.
But she insisted on doing it herself.
And the injection proved fatal.
Thank you, nurse Drew.
That is the case for the
Prosecution, My Lord.
My Lord .. I call Dr Christine Allison.
Take the book in your right hand.
Repeat what is printed on the card.
She doesn't look like a criminal.
Perhaps you can tell me
what does a criminal look like?
The whole truth and
nothing but the truth.
You are doctor Christine Mary Allison?
Yes.
Dr Allison.
Are you able to tell us exactly ..
The size of the last injection
you gave Mr Benson?
No.
- Why is that?
I usually enter the amount of drugs
I give in the drug book, but ..
I couldn't.
- Why?
The bottle broke.
- By accident?
By accident.
Is it possible that you may have
misjudged the size of the injection?
I suppose it is just possible.
Doctor Allison .. I want you to
turn to members of the jury.
And tell them this.
Did you .. knowingly murder John Benson?
No.
I did not murder him.
Thank you, doctor Allison.
Just a few questions, doctor Allison,
before you step down.
I understand that you
were born in Canada?
Yes. Winnipeg.
- Your father was not a man of means?
No.
- What was his job?
He was a janitor.
- What we would call a handyman. I see.
Is this all relevant
in some way, Mr Dane?
It will become so, My Lord.
And with the help of this
janitor father of yours.
You studied medicine at McGill
University and qualified there?
My father couldn't help me.
He died when I was twelve.
I worked my way through McGill.
Having there formed a close
friendship with a teacher of philosophy?
I have many friends.
- I refer to the late Mr Benson.
Now ..
Three years ago you came
to Liverpool. Why was that?
My mother had died. I was all
alone and I needed a change.
Before you reduce us all to tears ..
- My Lord, I object.
That was a completely
unnecessary comment.
And that's a completely
unnecessary interruption.
My learned friend has a well-known
talent for being offensive.
I refuse to be interrupted
during a cross-examination.
Gentlemen!
I think we must let Mr Dane
take his own course.
Mr O'Grady?
Very well, My Lord.
I am obliged, My Lord.
And I suppose that ..
Your journey here had nothing to do with
Mr Benson working at the university?
He encouraged me to come and work here.
I see. But he didn't encourage Maria
Benson to come here, did he Dr Allison?
Who .. Mr Dane?
Mrs Benson, My Lord. To whom the
dead man had been married since 1948.
No. She didn't come.
Were they unhappy together?
We never talked about that.
- Did you not?
No doubt you had other
things to talk about.
And your conversation was not confined
to philosophy, was it Dr Allison?
In fact.
He had been your lover
before you left Canada.
Ever since then, I suggest you had
been Mr John Benson's mistress.
If you want to use those words.
- They are true, are they not?
I'd like to be clear
about this, Dr Allison.
You had an adulterous association with
this man up to the time of his death.
Yes.
And yet you acted as his doctor?
He wanted me to. He asked me ..
We agreed on it between us.
You agreed on what, Dr Allison?
On what, did you agree together?
That I should treat him. In his illness.
Wasn't there something
else you agreed upon?
What?
He asked you to kill him, did he not?
Your agreement was, you should release
him from his life whenever he asked you.
You said that it was quite easy.
- I never said that.
I only said he was my patient.
On your own admission,
your family were not well off.
No.
Therefore, money matters have
always been important to you.
I suppose so.
- Then this should interest you.
This is the probate of
the will of John Benson.
He left you all his property.
You know that?
And nothing to his wife. You stood
to gain directly, by this man's death.
Stood to gain?
I stood to gain?
- Yes! Financially.
Is that what you mean?
A few pounds he'd saved.
Some books that now seem to me as
meaningless as your foolish questions.
A pair of gold cuff-links?
Is that what you mean?
The cuff-links I gave him?
I gave them to him.
And now I've got them back.
If you are unable to go on now,
I'm quite sure we can wait.
Thank you very much,
but I'm quite alright.
Members of the jury.
You may feel that the evidence you have
heard does not support the probability.
That the overdose was
administered by pure accident.
And if the overdose was
deliberately administered.
Let me remind you of this.
It is no defence that this
man was mortally ill.
Or that he wished to die.
No-one, members of the jury ..
Has the right to bestow
the gift of life and death.
On the other hand.
If you are satisfied, that
she had no intent to kill.
But was criminally negligent in the
way that she treated her patient.
Then you will find her guilty of
the lesser crime of manslaughter.
You will now consider your verdict.
Mercy killing verdict.
What will they give you, dear?
- Huh?
I said how much did they give you?
Two years.
Mercy killing, was it?
They called in manslaughter.
You'll be out in eighteen
months. You're a good con.
You're bound to be. I mean,
you being a doctor and all.
Quiet there!
A bloody doctor, is she?
She never got down on her knees
and scrubbed out the surgery.
It will be a bit of a chance for
her when she gets inside.
A bigger change when she gets out.
I mean, you and me can always pick up
where we left off, can't we, Maisie?
I said no talking. Shut up.
[ Christine: ]
"Eighteen months."
"It didn't seem a long time
or particularly short."
"It had no end and no beginning."
"It was a timeless succession
of waking but not sleeping."
"Of collecting food but not eating.
Of cleaning floors that weren't dirty."
"And sweeping out corners
that had collected no dust."
"Of waiting for nothing to happen."
"And then, I was out in a
world I had forgotten."
"A world that didn't want me."
"As if I'd woken up from a
dream I didn't believe in."
"But which had really happened."
You've had some nursing
experience, you say?
But no diploma?
I can't recommend you without
a diploma now, can I.
Have you any special
aptitude of any sort?
No.
I'm very sorry.
Most of my patients are women.
They pay in cash or kind.
No trouble with the charming tax.
You'll find me easy to get on with.
I like redheads.
Here, where are you off to?
You haven't been planted on me by
the charming authorities, have you?
May I see your National Insurance card?
Fully stamped, I hope.
Oh.
May I see your references?
I see.
I'm afraid we're rather particular
about our girls here.
Good afternoon.
[ Door knocks ]
There is a telephone call for you.
For me?
- Well, that's what they said.
Hello.
Who?
Who are you?
You know me?
You know all about me?
Meet you where?
Are you Miss Godden?
- Yes.
I'm Miss Chandler.
'Aunt Heather' to everybody.
I phoned you this afternoon.
How did you hear about me?
Well, some people we
knew were very kind.
But it took us some time to find you.
My nephew is so anxious to see you.
Shall we go and find my car?
I put it down here somewhere.
Ah yes, there it is.
You see how small and
inconspicuous my little car is.
Yet you know, it is always attracting
the attention of the city police.
Do get in and let us drive
out of this windy town.
Where are we going?
- You'll see.
Is it very far?
These buses, they do loom up at you.
How have you been getting on?
It's been difficult for you
to find work, hasn't it.
Your nephew, he ..
He doesn't mind about
what's happened to me?
What's that, there?
- It's a red light, Miss Chandler.
How sudden they are.
No. My nephew likes to
help people in distress.
He does these kind acts quite secretly.
Now you. You've changed
your name, haven't you?
Yes, I have.
Not that it matters.
Men drivers.
This house is the devil to run.
My nephew likes it out here.
But it's the devil to run.
The servants won't stay.
You know how it is these days.
Oh, my nephew grew those.
He breeds them.
I haven't time for flowers.
I'll go and see if I can find him.
Evil looking things, aren't they.
Personally, I prefer wild flowers.
Do you come to join the family?
I think so.
Good.
There is a cinema eight miles away.
And, there is a bus into
Liverpool three times a week.
So I don't suppose you
will die of excitement.
But I haven't been taken on yet.
I've only met Miss Chandler.
Oh, then the worst is still to come.
But you look like you'll survive it.
- Thanks.
I hope you've brought
plenty of knitting.
Knitting?
The evenings in this place are longer
than anywhere else in the world.
Good luck with the master of the house.
Is he ..
Very alarming?
- Oh no.
He is really very kind.
To flowers.
Miss Godden?
I found him for you.
I always know where to look for him.
He's always in here
when he's not at work.
Of course, he hasn't much time.
But he loves his flowers.
Miss Godden is here.
This is my nephew.
I'll leave you to get acquainted.
I thought you'd remember.
Will someone drive me back.
I want you to listen to me.
- I had to listen to you before.
I was in a position where
I couldn't avoid it.
Didn't you get enough
pleasure out of torturing me?
I was only doing what I had to do.
Now sit down. Let's discuss this.
- What a sense of humour.
As far as I'm concerned,
the past is over.
I'm offering you a job.
I would rather scrub floors.
Please.
Listen to me for a moment.
I believe that I can trust you.
I was removed from the medical register.
For outrageous and immoral conduct.
Nevertheless, I can still trust you.
We are all capable of doing something
that the law doesn't approve of.
I was in a position to observe
you in a difficult situation.
You observed me?
I thought that you had
courage and character.
Give me a reference.
You can't waste your life on
the sort of job you'll get now.
You need a chance to
practice your profession.
Just what does that mean?
My wife is an invalid.
Why me?
Why have you been looking for me?
Well, she ..
Some time ago she had a car accident.
I'm afraid that her brain was damaged.
She needs somebody to look after her.
She can never be left alone.
And her life has to be
severely restricted.
But she mustn't be
made to feel a prisoner.
Do you understand that?
Where I come from, they
weren't quite so tactful.
I'm sorry.
I see no reason to dwell on your past.
If your wife is an invalid
she needs a nurse.
There are plenty around.
- We've had some of them.
All that my wife needs is a companion.
Someone that understands her.
She's quite an attractive
person in many ways.
What do you say?
- I've told you.
My car!
Liane!
Don't you pay attention
to anything I say?
Are you alright?
What a stupid way to build a garage.
I told you before. I never want
to see you in a car again.
Bring some antiseptic and bandages.
The bruises are not too bad.
Please don't interfere.
I can take care of my wife.
Your wife?
Yes.
Now perhaps you will understand.
No.
Come with me. We'll take a
closer look at that head of yours.
What shall I do?
Take them upstairs and do anything
Miss Godden asks you to.
She is going to take care of Liane now.
A little more?
Thank you very much, aunt Heather.
It's absolutely delicious.
I'm flattered.
- Thank you.
Miss Godden, how do you like
living in the north of England?
I used to practice law in London,
you know. Mostly divorces.
Actresses ringing up in the middle
of the night to ask my advice on ..
Small problems of personal inadequacy.
Lucky fellow.
Up here it's all fatal accidents
and violent crime.
I miss the south.
I've been told that the
north is more friendly.
Have you?
You know, I get the feeling
that we've met before.
You couldn't have.
Miss Godden is Canadian.
She's only just come to England.
Perhaps I'd better go upstairs
and see how your wife is.
No. She should rest.
More wine, anybody?
A glass for me, please.
Liane, you are supposed to be resting.
I'm beautiful.
That's what you're supposed to say.
I'll say it for him.
These lawyers, they always
stick up for one another.
But that's not the same thing at all.
You're like my husband.
- You're a realist, Mrs Dane.
Stephen, you have a realist for a wife.
Why didn't you stay in your room?
I'm quite alright, thank you.
In fact, I'm happy.
So many people .. it's almost a party.
Have you met my new friend, Christine?
Most charming.
Aunt Heather, don't you think you should
take the ladies into the sitting room?
You just want rid of us so you and
Mr Ebblington can tell dirty stories.
I'm afraid I don't know any.
Ah, then you'll have
a very dull time of it.
Stephen has forgotten most of
his stories. Isn't that right, darling?
He's been so busy with all
those murders and things.
Now I remember once at Curragh.
- Liane.
The house in Ireland where
I was born and raised.
I remember when the big white doors
would shut on the gentlemen.
I'd listen to what they were doing.
They talked and drank until all hours.
I remember once, my
father got so crazy ..
He brought one of the horses
into the dining room.
And I swear he gave it a bottle of port.
Oh, I'm sorry.
The whole county was talking about
Captain Ferris and his drunken horse.
Mr Ebblington.
Promise me you'll never
do anything like that.
Would you take my wife
to her room, please.
Come on, Liane. I'd like to hear
more about your house in Ireland.
Honest?
- Yes.
Really?
Come on then.
I'll tell you all about it.
[ Telephone ]
[ Voices outside room ]
Did you sleep well?
I found it difficult to get back to
sleep after the telephone rang.
Oh, I didn't hear it.
I didn't hear the phone.
You must have been dreaming.
Liane is going riding this morning.
I'd like you to go with her.
I've lent my stables to a man
who keeps a riding school.
You won't let her out
of your sight will you.
She is not to be trusted.
No. Keep away!
I can't stand men pulling me about.
I don't even let Stephen do it.
Poor Stephen.
Isn't that a terrible thing?
Why, you two haven't me. This is Roscoe.
He's from Ireland, too.
From County Cork.
A breeding ground for
rogues and rascals.
She's a great one for flattery.
Maybe it isn't flattery.
Maybe she means it.
Now that's the kind of woman I like.
Come on, Roscoe. Enough of that blarney.
Roscoe.
Can't these tired old riding-school
nags of yours go any faster?
She wants to be sailing over a
high stone wall on a stallion.
Drunk with Irish whiskey.
Isn't that what you're longing
for Mrs Dane: the Curragh hunt?
They know how to ride where I come from.
You talk as though you'd
like to go back there.
Stephen would never let me.
He's jealous of me and my father.
Liane .. turn your horse away.
Well, did you enjoy the ride, Christine?
- Yes, but I'll be stiff for a week.
It's always like that if you
haven't ridden for some time.
Would you like an apple?
- Thanks.
Well Christine, do you think
you're going to like it here?
Oh yes. This place is lovely.
It's not as nice as at Curragh.
It's not near the sea.
In Curragh, the house is
much more beautiful.
Liane.
- Yes?
You know when you stopped your horse
back there when the saw was spinning?
I don't really remember.
Do you often feel like that?
Feel like what?
Like you want to watch
something .. going around.
Christine, I don't know what you mean.
The whodunits are over there.
Unless you're looking for love stories.
No, I wasn't.
- Good. I haven't got any.
As a matter of fact, I was looking ..
Looking through my
collection of murders.
That's the worst of our trade. We tend
to make a collection of guns and knives.
Pictures of men with sad eyes.
Who finished off their wives
for the funeral benefits.
That's Smithson, the poisoner.
Do you remember him?
I'm not interested in
your cases, Mr Dane.
I'm sorry.
Most of them are rather boring.
For example, I have to cross-examine
a very astute elderly embezzler.
You'll beat him.
- Do you think so?
All you have to do is
shout loudly enough.
Yes.
Mr Dane shouting in court?
I'm sorry. Medical problems.
Your wife and I were ..
- What about my wife?
When we were out riding this morning.
We saw a woodcutting machine.
The wheel was spinning.
It fascinated her.
It hypnotized her.
She couldn't look away.
I seem to remember that's
one of the symptoms ..
Of schizophrenia. That's
the word they use isn't it.
I've read that book, too.
Would you like a drink?
- No thank you, Stephen.
Why don't you call in a doctor?
I thought you were a doctor.
I can't treat her.
It doesn't need long, technical terms
to know what's the matter with Liane.
She's just very unhappy.
I can see that.
She had a terrible experience.
I think I ought to tell you.
She was .. going home to Curragh
with her father in the car.
The road was wet and the car skidded and
hit one of the walls that they have.
The car overturned.
Liane was only stuck, but her father,
Captain Ferris was killed.
Her father?
- Yes.
Hasn't she talked about him?
She usually does.
Well, she was an only child
and naturally she was ..
Desperately unhappy.
This is more than unhappiness.
What did you say?
I've already said it.
She needs a doctor.
And what will he say?
He would say shut her up. Give her a
rest. Give her a little treatment.
I'm not having her shut up.
Well, she's not free the way things are.
- She's as free as anyone.
If you really cared about your wife.
Liane is the only person
that I've ever cared for.
And I'll do anything to
see that she doesn't suffer.
Now you go to bed. Don't worry.
I think someone should
start worrying about your wife.
To try to find out what's
going on in her mind.
Alright. Read this and try and
find the right technical phrase.
But I tell you there is only
one thing worrying Liane.
And that's the memory of a slippery
road on a wet day in Ireland.
But read that by all means.
And now if you'll excuse me,
I must get on with my embezzlement.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Christine.
You've been talking to
Stephen, haven't you?
Yes, for a little while.
He never talked to any of
the others so late at night.
You must be a special favourite.
- Oh, I wouldn't think so.
What are you reading?
Oh .. you must be very clever
to understand that stuff.
Oh, I'm brilliant.
Come on in. We'll talk.
Christine.
What did you do?
Before you came here?
Well I .. studied for many, many years.
Well, do you know what I think?
I think your talents are going to
be wasted in a place like this.
In fact.
I can't think why you are here at all.
Well, I expect I shall find
out sooner or later.
Oh, the record is stuck.
I'll have to go and change it.
You know, I'm glad that you and Stephen
found something to talk about after all.
He went out you know.
You saw that, didn't you?
Well, I hope you're not jealous.
Because he's got a woman in the village.
Liane, why do you say things like that?
Because it's true. Her name is Polly.
She runs the pub.
That's why he's been
trying to get rid of me.
Liane.
Do you know what those lights are?
Christine, do you know?
No.
They are at the seaside.
Of course, it's only a dirty
old seaside round here.
There's mess all over the sand.
Still, it's prettier.
In the night-time.
Do you like fairs?
- Oh yes.
I used to go to the fair.
We went to sell horses but
we stayed to celebrate.
Let's do it.
What, back to the present?
- Oh, it's not that bad.
Don't you think so?
There's an article in one of these
magazines I've been meaning to show you.
Christine.
- Hmm?
We'll never get away from here you know.
Either of us.
Why do you say that?
Well, you won't go.
Because there is nowhere else
for you to go, is there.
Well .. maybe there isn't.
That's why Stephen chose you, you know.
And I can't go home, either.
Not after the terrible thing that I did.
What did you do?
I married Stephen.
And why was that so terrible?
My father didn't forgive me.
We were so close.
So terribly close, you know.
Especially after my mother went away.
Captain James Ferris and daughter.
They'd invite us everywhere.
Together. All over the country.
So naturally, he got angry when
I went away with Stephen.
He won't forgive me.
Liane.
He told me your father is dead.
I know. But that's what makes
it so much worse. Don't you see?
One day.
I'm going to do what my
father wanted me to do.
I'm going to get away from Stephen.
That's what the egg money is for.
The money that aunt Heather
gets from her range hens.
She sells eggs. And I know
where she keeps the money.
Stephen won't let me have any money
in case I might try to escape.
I know. Because I know where Heather
keeps her little hoard of egg money.
And one day, when it's enough.
I'm going!
Here .. look.
He's taken it.
No Liane. No. Stop it.
It's no good, Christine.
We'll never get away.
Liane.
Have you seen Liane?
She's in the garden.
Here is the afternoon's post. See if
there is one for me, will you dear.
Here's a letter for Liane from Ireland.
Let me see.
I'll go and call her .. Liane!
Yes? There's a letter
for you from Ireland.
A letter for me?
Where is it?
Where is my letter?
- What letter, dear?
Why, Christine said I'd
got a letter from Ireland.
Oh, but Christine made a mistake. We
all make mistakes sometimes, don't we.
Ah, now where is my bag?
I must have left it in the car.
Go and look for it for me will
you dear. I'm getting so forgetful.
What did you do with her letter?
She mustn't have it.
- Why not?
I can't tell you.
I ought never to have let you see it.
If Stephen knew ..
He'd be so angry.
I'm afraid.
Don't tell him, will you.
Please, dear.
What is it you're afraid of?
That's Liane.
Liane!
She wanted to go to the fair.
The one you can see over the water.
It is all my fault. Stephen will
never forgive me. I know he won't.
Is there another car?
- Well, there's a taxi in the village.
But please dear, don't do
anything to attract attention.
Don't let everybody know.
- Don't worry I'll bring her back safe.
Hurrah!
- Sit down.
Good evening, Madam.
Could I see Mr Dane, please?
Stephen.
- Yes?
There is a Police Inspector
here to see you.
Alright. I'm coming.
Yes?
How do you do, sir.
- How do you do.
I hear there has been some anxiety
this evening about Mrs Dane.
My wife? What do you mean?
Well, this lady reported someone at the
fairground on a ride acting dangerously.
I think you were troubled unnecessarily.
She hasn't left the house.
Are you quite sure, sir?
- Yes.
Miss Godden must have
seen somebody else.
I wonder if I might have
word with your wife, sir?
Of course .. Liane!
She has been washing her hair.
- Ask her to come down will you, please.
Liane .. Stephen wants you, dear.
Just for a moment.
But I saw her at the fairground.
There was a crowd, Miss.
You've got to allow for that.
Liane.
It seems you have a double,
who's been down at the fairground.
Acting dangerously, I think they said.
Have you been out this evening?
Of course not, darling.
I've been washing my hair.
Christine went out though.
Did you enjoy yourself?
We missed you so much at dinner.
Come along, dear. I'll help you.
There. We seem to have
been wasting your time.
I'm sure Miss Godden meant to help.
It's alright, sir. We all make mistakes.
You are supposed to look after Liane.
You're not required to call the Police.
Do you understand that?
- But she left in aunt Heather's car.
My car is in the garage
and Liane is upstairs.
We'd get on better you know if you'd ..
Stop trying to find the answers to
questions that you don't understand.
[ Aunt Heather: ]
Liane.
Make sure your hair is quite dry, dear.
Good evening, Miss Godden.
I appreciate you coming
to see me like this.
I appreciate it very much.
I want to ask you something.
Don't be shy, Miss Godden.
You'll find me very easy to get on with.
It's about Mrs Dane.
Well, that's not a fit
subject for conversation.
Not when we're alone together in here.
You were with her today
at the fair, weren't you?
She's an embarrassment.
That's what she is.
Has he asked you to
say it never happened?
I avoid her company.
Honest, I do.
Half the time she's round your
neck begging and pleading.
And the other half,
she is screaming at you.
Yelling at you.
Using words I never heard.
Only in the army.
She's made you lie to
me as well. Is that it?
I wonder what you could be
talking about, Miss Godden.
I saw you with her at the fair.
Of course it's ..
It's lonely here for a man.
I was chauffeuring before.
The old girl I worked for.
She looked after me alright.
Did ..
Did Mr Dane say she didn't
go out this evening?
Yes, he did.
Well, that's ..
That's not the first
time he's done that.
It must be very confusing
for that poor girl.
I wonder if that's what
he's trying to do?
What is he trying to do?
You know what her real
trouble is, don't you?
She's kept very short of
the affection she needs.
How about you, Miss Godden?
Is that why you came down
here for your evening walk?
What's the matter with you?
Saving yourself for Mr Dane? Ha!
He's no good to you.
He's no good to you at all.
Mr Dane.
- What is it?
These plants have the most poisonous
diet. One has to be very careful.
Do you like this one?
It's called 'Liane'.
- Mr Dane.
After what's happened tonight, I think
it's best I leave here in the morning.
I see.
I'm afraid I was very rude. I apologize
if that's what you want to hear.
That isn't necessary.
- Well, what else can I say?
I don't want you to go. I need you here.
You don't need me.
You have your own ideas on
how to take care of your wife.
I'm only doing what
I think is best for her.
You lied to me and
you lied to the Police.
Well .. I had to.
Every time I see Police, I see ..
Doctors and ambulances and magistrates
signing certificates to put her away.
That's why I engaged you.
Because although you are a doctor, you
have no authority to lock anybody up.
You know Liane.
You know what it's
like to be a prisoner.
I'll never forget.
I was upholding the law.
It doesn't mean I didn't understand.
What you had to do.
I was a prisoner too, you know.
Captured in the early part of the war.
When I came out, I'd learnt
law by correspondence.
And how to make cigarettes
out of old army regulations.
But I had .. forgotten
how to take girls out.
How to go dancing.
Or even get drunk efficiently.
I didn't catch up much
on those sort of things.
When I met Liane.
She appeared to me to be all
of the things that I'd missed.
When I was behind barbed wire.
Now do you understand
me a little better?
It may seem a strange thing,
my bringing you here.
But it's beginning to work.
Is it?
Your wife is sick and
unhappy. She hates it here.
She wants to go home.
Home to beautiful Curragh.
Shall I tell you the truth.
Curragh is a broken-down ruin.
And that father she's
always talking about.
The gallant Captain James Ferris
was a drunken horse trader.
You hate him, don't you?
He's dead. Why should I hate him?
Because he made her happy.
Happy?
Yes. She was free then. She wasn't
shut in here with all your lies.
Alright. I can't deal with Liane.
You tell me.
You can deal with her.
Can't you let her out a little
without us watching?
We'll let her out.
But we'll watch her.
Both of us.
You're really clever, Christine.
Then, you are clever at so many things.
Such a nice friend for Stephen.
Turn around a bit.
Do you remember that girl
I was telling you about?
The one who runs the pub?
Polly is her name.
Yes.
Stephen is crazy about her, you know.
He is?
- Sure.
He's mine, Christine.
No-one else is going to have him.
Do you understand that?
Lend me the scissors, will you?
Do you want the scissors?
This dress is going to look
great at the races, you know.
I hope so.
I'll collect your winnings.
I'll see you at the desk.
I've never been lucky before.
- You're really good at choosing.
You know when my father
used to win a race.
He'd go and treat all
his friends for a drink.
And sometimes treat some strangers, too.
Where is Stephen?
- Well, he went to get your winnings.
He should be here.
- Well, he'll be here in a minute.
He's staying away on purpose.
- No, he's not.
There's Polly.
The girl I was telling you about.
A gin and tonic, please.
A gin and tonic, please!
I've had no luck at all today.
I think number 6. He's a bit overweight.
Hello, Dickie.
- Hello, Dane.
Have you found a winner?
- No. This is Liane's.
Is Liane here?
- Yes, somewhere.
I must get her give
me a tip for the 3:30.
I've got a hot tip ..
I want a gin and tonic!!
You know Polly's child looks just
like Stephen. Very suspicious, isn't it?
What are you talking about?
He's the image of my husband.
Look Mrs Dane. I've known
Stephen since the army.
Here's your money.
- Look at Stephen.
He's frightened that we might
find out too much about her.
Goodbye, Polly dear.
You haven't been seeing so much
of Stephen lately, have you?
He's got a new interest in life.
My beautiful companion.
They hold hands, on the beach you know.
I don't blame you, Christine.
It's his fault.
He's irresistible, isn't he.
Until you get to know him.
And then when you
look deep into his eyes.
You see that there is nothing there
at all. Have you ever noticed that?
You are afraid, aren't you Stephen?
You're afraid of what all these
pompous idiots all think of you.
Hmm?
Mr Stephen Dane, QC.
Standing up in court, in his black gown.
Wearing a severe expression.
And making all the criminals tremble.
And nobody knows the truth
about him. Nobody knows!
Take her home, please.
Here are the keys to the car.
Don't ever give her the keys to the car!
Do you think I want to
stay here with you?
You're nothing to me.
Who are you?
You're not my husband.
You don't even sleep with me.
Come on, Liane.
Alright, Christine. I'm tired now.
You know, it's not
exciting any more, is it.
[ Door knocks ]
Yes?
I saw your light on.
Is everything alright?
She got much calmer.
Good .. I had to stay and
straighten out the social situation.
Did you?
- Yes.
I bought Bill and Polly drinks
and Ebblington some dinner.
We sat surrounded by horse-faced
girls who talked about ..
The weather, and racing and ..
Horses.
We never mentioned Liane.
I see.
One thing about the English. They'll
always pretend that nothing happened.
So I've noticed.
- You didn't believe her, did you?
I've known Polly since she was a child.
Bert and I were in prison camp together.
I never quarrelled with him.
Then or since.
Liane worries me more and more.
She .. she suddenly
seemed jealous of me.
That's ridiculous, isn't it.
Yes, very ridiculous.
If she knew the truth.
You know.
It's like in the war.
When one was crossing a minefield
in the dark and one was treading ..
Delicately and waiting for an explosion.
That's what it's like living with Liane.
I know what it's like.
Do you?
The things you can't say.
The subjects that ..
You've got to avoid.
The plans you can't make.
I remember all that.
Look, we are ..
So separated now. It's like
living in another country.
And that's when they need you the most.
Does Liane?
Of course she does.
What do you think she was
shouting about today?
It's when they are so ill that
they need someone to hate.
And that's when you
can't ever leave them.
Not possibly.
Thank goodness you
were there this afternoon.
What are you thinking about?
All the things we've missed.
I brought you here to help Liane.
I think you can help me.
There is something important
I ought to tell you.
So that you can deal with
Liane when the time comes.
[ Telephone ]
I'll tell you some other time.
Soon.
Sometimes, I wish it could
be over and finished.
And I knew nothing about it.
Hurry up now, aunt Heather.
- Oh dear.
What is it this time?
I must have left my
shopping list in the hall.
But you don't need it.
You know what we've got to do.
First, you take me to the dentist.
Then we go and get my records.
Here's your list.
- Then we have tea.
Thank you, dear.
She's very nervy.
- She'll be alright.
Have a good time.
- What? At the dentists?
[ Whistling ]
Yes. What is it?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean
to have startled you.
I took the liberty of dropping in.
I understand Mr Dane wouldn't be in
his office today, so I thought I'd ..
Take him by surprise .. at home.
I'm sorry. He's not at home.
May I take a message?
- I see.
Well, if you wouldn't mind
telling him that I called.
'Ferris' is the name.
Captain James Ferris.
Wait a minute.
Are you .. Liane's father?
Yes. That's right.
- I was told ..
Oh, that I was dead? Yes, I know. That
was on Mr Dane's insistence, of course.
I am .. not supposed to see my child.
Come in.
Captain Ferris, there is ..
There is something I
don't quite understand.
Why aren't you supposed
to see your daughter?
It's a very logical
query if I may say so.
But one perhaps more properly
directed at Mr Dane himself.
I was told you were
killed in a car crash.
Yes. Well, there was an accident.
You know what lawyers are.
They'll always formulate their own
version of the facts, won't they.
In any case, I can't
complain because I ..
I agreed. I agreed to my own death. Yes.
Why?
It seems .. that Liane got it into her
poor little head that I'd been killed.
So .. out of consideration
for her, I suppose.
He thought it would be
better if I stayed away.
The shock of seeing me
might only harm her.
And you believed him?
- He was very convincing.
He always is.
But I gave my word and .. I've kept it.
Well then .. why are you here today?
Well, I made sure Liane
wasn't here when I came in.
You see, I've no choice.
Besides, I'm worried.
And I'm worried about her state
of mind. You know, a little afraid.
Of course, we Irish. We ..
We're supposed to live in a
world of fantasy, aren't we.
Are you sure you're not afraid of him?
- Of who?
Why should I be?
Of course not.
Well, I mustn't trouble you any longer.
I'm only here to sell a
mare I have at Curragh.
And get a little scrap of information
about my daughter from Mr Dane.
He'll be back in the morning.
It's a pity I can't stay.
There it is. My plane goes in an hour.
I would love to have got
another glimpse of Liane.
She's very beautiful now. Isn't she?
Yes, very beautiful.
- Uhuh.
But you know, her mother,
she was a miracle at her age.
An absolute miracle.
That is all we can produce
in Ireland: horses and poetry.
Beautiful women.
Liane should see you. She should ..
- No. I don't think she should.
Not really. Not yet.
I was just wondering.
I was wondering why he has you here.
He's a very ingenious man you know.
He never does things without a reason.
I suppose I'd better say goodbye.
I'll be glad to get back. It's wonderful
at Curragh now with the flowers out.
The gardens.
As I always say.
They ought not to be our gardens. They
ought to be turned over to the public.
Well.
Goodbye.
You must hurry if you
want to catch that plane.
Yes. Well, I'll see you in Dublin.
I'll see you at the horse show.
If there is any news, tell me then.
- You can be sure of that.
You've .. had a visitor.
Do you know him?
I used to buy horses from him years ago.
A very honest trader.
It's a terrible thing isn't it,
to do to that poor man.
Kill him off like that.
I told you Mr Dane makes ..
He makes life very confusing
for his poor wife.
But then, perhaps it's intentional?
Perhaps he wants her locked up.
Why should he want that?
Who knows?
Maybe he's looking for a new wife?
Someone .. nice and sensible.
Yourself, for instance.
Liane .. let's get out of this shop.
I want to talk to you.
Let's go into the booth and listen to
this record. And you can tell me there.
A mystery, Christine. Why did
you call me up at the dances?
Liane.
How would you like to
go back to Curragh?
Curragh?
I liked it there.
My father ..
- I saw our father today.
What did you say?
I said, I saw your father today.
It's not funny, Christine. You shouldn't
make jokes about him, poor man.
Your father isn't dead, Liane.
He came to the house this afternoon.
I'll not listen to you, Christine.
You're only saying it to make me mad.
You must listen to me. I'm telling you
the first truth you've heard in years.
Look, your father loves you and I will
take you back to Ireland to see him.
When you get there,
you'll feel much better.
And no-one will lie to you again.
Except you, perhaps?
Why would I like to you?
Back to Curragh?
Oh, I'd like to go back there.
Alright, Christine. I'll go with you.
Stephen is going to be so angry.
Can we go now before anyone finds out?
Take us to the Dublin ferry please.
We just have half an hour to catch it.
Do you think she saw us?
- No, I don't think so.
Oh good, you brought my bag.
If Stephen finds out, he'll try to ..
- Liane. Don't worry about a thing.
Tomorrow morning we'll
be safe in Ireland.
Look .. cattle.
We're here, Christine. We're at Curragh.
I'm back.
Liane Ferris is back in town.
Liane.
- Mrs O'Flynn.
Mrs Bowler.
- Liane.
Don't you see Christine?
This is where I told you about.
Isn't it a wonderful place?
Go on, there.
We're nearly home, Christine.
Straight ahead, now.
I remember every stone of it, Christine.
Sometimes, after the parties
in the village on the races.
My father used to take
me on his shoulders.
We'd walk up this hill.
And start singing all the old songs.
Where he's put me down sometimes.
And go to sleep on the grass.
I would pick blackberries or
flowers to decorate the house.
That's where my mother died.
They found her down there
at the bottom of that cliff.
It's not passable.
No, Liane no. We've got to go back.
We can't drive though here.
Then we'll have to walk.
I know a shortcut.
Please, Christine.
We're almost there.
That's it, Christine.
That's the house.
I've lost my way.
This is someone else's house.
This is not my home, Christine.
No. No, this is not your home, Liane.
We'd better go.
- I've been thinking.
There's a path round
the corner of the house.
That must be where Curragh is.
We will find it, won't we, Christine?
Yes, of course we will.
We'll look for it tomorrow.
It's so stupid of me.
What do you want?
We just came to the wrong house.
There are two ladies
here to see you .. Captain.
Liane .. Liane, don't.
Don't.
Please stop this.
So you see, Liane.
I'm alive alright.
Be quiet!
Oh yes, I'm very much alive.
I'm afraid, Liane.
It was your husband's idea.
- You've done enough!
Liane.
Is it really you, my father?
That's me.
I've come back. Do you see?
I've come back to live
at Curragh with you.
You are so silly. You've let this
beautiful house get rather dusty.
You always did need a woman
around the house, didn't you.
Someone to .. to change the flowers.
And take back the empties.
Why did you change the carpet?
Where's that one that looked
like the bottom of the sea?
You know, the one when you ..
When you lay down on it.
And looked.
Oh, I'm glad you kept
the beautiful lights.
Tomorrow I'll take it down and
I'll wash all that wonderful glass.
Come on, dear.
We'll take you home.
You don't want to make me go, do you?
You don't want them to take me away?
- You will have to go, Liane.
But I only just found you.
No, it's no use, dear.
You can see the way things are, here.
He's your husband.
It's his responsibility, not mine.
Come on.
No .. no!
Liane!
Liane, come back!
How is she, doctor?
Well, the fall didn't hurt her so much.
It's the mental disturbance
that worries me.
You'd better give her two
of these, Miss Godden.
In case she gets restless.
And you get some rest yourself.
I'll be along in the morning.
- Thank you, doctor.
I uh ..
I'm afraid I'll have to call
in one of my colleagues.
I'll telephone you tomorrow as
soon as I get in touch with him.
He thinks she may have to be committed.
Well, that's the end of that struggle.
It's a struggle.
I doubt you could have won.
But I was trying. I tried
to keep the truth from her.
I didn't want to drag it
out in front of her eyes.
How did you find us?
I heard about Ferris's visit and
I guessed you were here.
Christine, I should have told you
the truth from the beginning.
Yes.
Did Captain Ferris's charm work on you?
When he came to the
house I believed him.
He said he missed Liane.
- Missed Liane?
I told you. I met him during the course
of a criminal investigation in Belfast.
And he offered me bribes.
Including his daughter.
He sent her to my hotel room.
She was only seventeen.
When she refused to leave.
She was sick on the floor telling me
of the things that went on at Curragh.
Her mother was dead.
She lived alone in the
house with her father.
The father who was accustomed
to so much affection.
Then I married her.
Shortly afterwards,
the prosecution was dropped.
Thank you.
For lack of evidence.
But Ferris thought it was a first
down payment on his daughter.
And then he began to visit us.
It was more and more expensive to
send him back to his country estate.
Then one day he took her
out in the car. He was drunk.
They had an accident.
Liane was knocked out.
Ferris wasn't hurt.
But I told her that he died.
I thought it would free her.
Instead of which .. he became
a beautiful memory to her.
And she began to live in a ..
Child's world.
That's all.
Except that he demanded
more and more money.
He took a delight in
ringing me up at all hours.
You remember that phone you
heard and I denied hearing?
That was him.
Why couldn't you have
told me all this before?
I thought I wouldn't have to.
Sorry.
We'll have to talk
about it in the morning.
No.
No, I'm going in the morning.
There is no reason for
me to stay any longer.
Christine.
Did you see this?
Pretty, isn't it?
It's very old.
Oh Liane .. you shouldn't
have taken that.
He gave it to me.
My father gave it to me.
She didn't want him to, but he gave it.
Take these.
Why? Do you want to kill me, Christine?
Take them, Liane. They are
just to make you sleep.
It would be nice if I was
out of the way, wouldn't it?
Then you could have
Stephen all to yourself.
Take them, Liane.
Ah .. nasty.
He did give me this, you know.
That proves that he
loves me, doesn't it?
That is true, isn't it?
Yes. Of course it's true.
You sleep now.
Just a moment, Miss Godden.
Would you wait in your room?
I'd like to speak to you.
Was .. was she very restless last night?
No. Not especially restless.
You didn't hear anything
during the night?
Any movement?
No.
What's wrong? What's happened to her?
Mrs Dane died in the night, Miss Godden.
I've ..
Well, she was perfectly
alright when I left her.
What .. what time was that?
Well, I don't know exactly.
It must have been about ..
Did you .. did you give her the pills?
Yes .. two. Just as you told me.
Just two?
Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure.
I'll show you the bottle.
You can count them.
The bottle was right here.
I put it here.
I know it was here.
It's just like.
Like what, Miss Godden?
Nothing.
Death. Be not proud.
Though some have called
Thee mighty and dreadful.
Allow it no so.
I must apologise for this unwarranted
intrusion in your private grief Mr Dane.
Yes.
Your fame has already reached
this peaceful but primitive spot.
But I must introduce myself.
My name is Conson. Sean Conson.
May I walk a bit of the road with you?
- By all means.
Only the other day I was ..
I was admiring your masterful
handling of Crown versus Marchant.
Not that I claim any
erudition in these matters.
I simply read these cases as an antidote
against the total rusting of the mind.
There isn't much to stimulate
it around here I'm afraid.
Hence the national addiction to drinking
good whiskey and writing bad poetry.
I take it you're in
the legal profession.
On the very fringe of it.
That's why it's such an honour to meet
you, Mr Dane, and such an embarrassment.
I don't understand.
Who am I to unravel the mysterious
workings of the human mind?
'Caverns measureless to man',
as Coleridge put it.
And yet, that is what I will have
to do tomorrow at the inquest.
In your presence.
Inquest? What for?
Well, it isn't unnatural
to have an inquest, is it?
Especially as a post-mortem established
she died from the overdose of a drug.
I've been a coroner around
her a great many years.
Each time there is an inquest
I feel utterly inadequate.
Have you met Miss Allison?
- No, I haven't had the pleasure.
Did you say 'Miss Allison'?
Yes.
My mistake .. I thought you had
registered in the hotel as Miss Godden.
So I am.
- Ah. Quite, quite.
What's in a name?
A rose by any other name
would smell just a sweet.
Shakespeare, of course.
You don't understand.
I only gave her two of those
tablets. I'm positive of that.
I believe you.
Hello.
Having quite a little
party, aren't they.
Just listen to that.
Of course it's habitual
after a funeral, isn't it.
Go away, Ferris.
- I wouldn't take it personally.
Mr Dane. After all I
suppose it's only human.
To want to celebrate the
pleasure of being .. alive.
But of course, you're free.
You don't have to hold your
breath and look sullen anymore.
You don't have to go round the house on
tiptoe as the wife's having one of ..
Her bad turns.
I just imagine it must have
been pretty awkward with ..
With Liane there in the house. Huh?
A whiskey and water, please.
- A large one.
Ah yes, poor Liane.
Please don't think I don't
understand, because I do.
I went through exactly the same thing.
With her mother. Out with
every man in the district.
Do you know I actually ..
Once I found her in the kitchen ..
With a man I owed money to.
Of course, I couldn't
do anything about it.
On account of the financial aspect.
Yes. And then there is the other thing.
Once the dear one has departed
the fellow is free, isn't he.
To make alternative arrangements.
Isn't that so, Mr Dane?
So it's quite a cheerful sound really,
isn't it? When you come to think of it.
I mean death lifts all our burdens.
Stephen Dane, barrister at law.
Liverpool.
The doctor has told us, Mr Dane.
That your wife died of an
overdose of sleeping pills.
So I understand.
When you engaged Miss Allison as a
nurse and companion for your wife.
Did she show you any references?
- No.
Oh. You had met
Miss Allison before, then?
Yes, but I don't see what it
has to do with this enquiry.
You must excuse us, Mr Dane.
We are not used, perhaps,
to the ways of the higher courts.
So we have to grope for the
truth in our own rusty way.
Now may I ask you, how
did you meet Miss Allison?
I met her in the course of my work.
You had defended her in some case?
No, I .. I conducted the prosecution.
For what offence, may one ask?
If there is something you
want to keep from us ..
She was accused of killing a man.
Some accident?
No. She gave him an overdose of drugs.
Then she was acquitted?
No, she was .. found
guilty of manslaughter.
Of manslaughter?
I see.
Thank you, Mr Dane.
Thank you.
Miss Allison, please.
Take this in your right hand
and repeat what's on the card.
I swear by Almighty God ..
That the evidence I shall give shall
be the truth, the whole truth ..
And nothing but the truth.
Miss Allison.
The doctor has told us
that in his opinion.
Mrs Dane would have had
to have been certified.
Do you think her case was hopeless?
I have been struck from
the medical register.
And I'm not entitled to give
you my opinion as a doctor.
I see .. now, Miss Allison.
You needn't answer
this if you don't want to.
But are you a believer in what's
been called 'mercy killing'?
Under certain circumstances.
When one can no longer bear to see
the pain and agony of the patient.
You can't ever kill without destroying
something inside yourself.
I see.
Now, as far as Mrs Dane is concerned.
You say that you didn't give her more
pills than the doctor prescribed.
But I did not.
There was no-one else in the room
was there, so far as you know?
No.
And the bottle was in
your room, Miss Allison?
Yes. Yes, it was there
when I went to bed.
And gone the next day?
Yes.
It hasn't been found yet?
Now could you offer any
suggestions? For our assistance.
Think now, if you would be so kind.
I can't think.
I just don't understand it.
It's all too much like ..
What happened before.
Isn't that a rather dangerous statement
for you to make, Miss Allison?
I object, sir.
This is supposed to be
an inquest on my wife.
You're now accusing
Miss Allison of murder.
She hasn't been warned, she hasn't
been charged. It's most irregular.
Did you say 'murder' Mr Dane?
Yes. Murder.
I'm under the impression sir,
that's what is being implied.
Do you want an opportunity,
Miss Allison ..
To deal with the charge that
only Mr Dane has made as yet?
I didn't say ..
- Yes, you did.
You said it so that
everybody could think it.
Because that's what
you've planned, isn't it?
That's why I'm here.
That's why you looked
for me and found me.
That's why you waited all that time
for me to come out of prison.
Because you needed someone
that people could point to.
'We know her. We know what she did'.
'We know what happened the last time she
took care of somebody she cared about'.
I was the one person in the
whole world you needed.
Because you knew this
was going to happen.
Miss Allison, please let me
understand what you're saying.
Mr Coroner, Mr Dane
understands what I'm saying.
Because he's such a clever
lawyer. He's so brilliant.
And he's so kind and sympathetic.
He'll send you to prison and then when
you get out he'll give you a job.
Because he understands.
He understands how to use people.
And to fit them right into his plans.
And I was such a fool I wasn't clever
enough to see what he was doing.
In your own interest, Miss Allison.
I think we ought to have
a short adjournment now.
You will want to collect yourself.
We'll resume this inquiry in an hour.
You certainly gave them
something to think about.
He was afraid alright. We could
see that. I was watching him.
Oh yes, and when you
came out with that stuff.
He was very scared.
Mind you, it's not you I blame. He was
behind it. I always felt sure of that.
I don't want to talk about it.
- No.
Well, it's about time people
knew the truth about Mr Dane.
Imagine.
Keeping a man from his daughter
all these years. What a mind.
To be able to think up
a scheme like that. Huh?
What time did he say we had to be back?
- Two o'clock, was it?
What time is it now?
Hey, that's a beautiful watch.
- Yes, it was my grandfather's.
I've held on to that
through thick and thin.
How was Liane when you last saw her?
Well, you were there.
- I mean when you came to the hotel.
What?
Why did you go up to
her room that night?
What night?
Did I do that?
Well, you've got your
watch back, haven't you?
The watch she took from your house.
She was holding it in her hand
that night when she went to sleep.
She pretended that it was a
present that you'd given her.
When she was holding that watch in her
hand she was alive and now she's dead.
And you've got your watch back.
- Hmm.
Miss, what do you mean?
I mean you were there. You must
have been there. You killed her.
You don't know what you're saying.
I could tell that by the way
she gave her evidence.
She's out of her mind. She knows
not what she's says. Excuse me.
He was there!
You needn't look at me.
I didn't kill her.
Look, I just went up to tell
her to stay away. That's all.
For her own sake as well as anything.
Look can't you see that?
Look, I'm not a particularly good man.
Well. It was distressing.
Having her come out to the house
like that. Intruding into my life!
I wanted to warn her, that's all.
- How did you get the watch back?
Look, I didn't kill her!
I .. I had a couple of
drinks that evening.
When I went up I was going to advise her
to go home. To go home with her husband.
I thought it was only right.
And then when I pushed open the door,
there she was. She was lying on the bed.
With a bottle in her hand.
Empty. Empty. She'd taken a
whole fistful of these things.
Just like a kid .. like a kid.
Taking sweets. So I said
to myself afterwards.
Alright Mr Dane, but perhaps now we'll
give you something to explain away.
We'll give you, a little legal problem.
Who does he think we are?
Does he think I'm a .. a servant?
Who he can pay off if he's giving
too much trouble in the house?
So, I ..
Well, I took the bottle.
I took the bottle with me.
What are you looking at me for?
I didn't kill her!
I ..
Just a moment, Mr Ferris.
Horrible! Ridiculous allegations.
My daughter was practically
gone when l came into the room.
I saw Liane taking these things.
I'm not responsible.
I had nothing to do with it.
Stand right back.
Now move away please.
Come on now.
Christine.
Are you going to give me a lift?
-t-g-