I AM AN ELEPHANT, MADAME
BASED ON THE NOVEL "DIE UNBERATENEN"
BY THOMAS VALENTIN
Stop!
Ilse, how is this flower called?
Gropius Anaemicus Tuma
How does the proof function?
MATHEMATICS
Or else: what do we want to proof?
That the ... Koch!
mean value property
to a common group of ... Huje!
functions
in each ... Petri!
interval
belongs. Yes, of course.
Albeit here ... Ulrike!
an exception
exists.
The sine is also... Hübner!
yes, the proof that
No, it is ... Rull!
parallel.
Parallel.
To the ... Haverkamp!
X-axis.
And Rull's sentence is applied when ... Adler!
a particular case differentiable interval
followed by ... Adler. Adler!
Y = f(x)
Silence!
Yes, Y = f(x) hold the property f(a) =
= ... Karstens!
= f(b) in the interval's center at least holds one position xi for which f'(xi) = 0 is.
BREMEN
GERMANY
Yes, Gisela,
would you explain it to us?
Annoyed that I chose her.
F'(xi) = f(b) - f(a) / ...
Well?
/ B - A
True!
That's what you chalked up, Gisela.
How can it be developed further?
No Idea, not?
We're living in a society, dear Gisela,
in which in fact also ladies
have to program a computer one beautiful day.
Homework: Exercise 1 to 4 with a variant of the proof.
After the death of King Pompilius the People elect,
motioned by the interim King in the moor, Tullus Hostilius‎ as their new King.
Continue!
Whose exquisite renown over the animal kingdom and
Stotte can do this alone!
and his great war deeds distinguished him and he made the
CLASS TEACHER
Yes?
Emergency fixture of the government – Statistics about the career choices.
Does this have to be now?
Yes, Dr.
Well. Alright, state succinctly what you want to do after school.
Adler?
Export/Import.
Eve Banana!
Na na na na!
Gisela Becker?
Translator
Karstens?
Law
Haverkamp?
Medicine
Heidekamp?
City council
Hübner?
Music, at the flugelhorn: Horst Hübner.
Huje?
Zoology. What do you want to be?
Koch?
Dramatics
Korawalski?
Clochard
Korawalski!
Well then banker.
Ulrike Mom?
I'm not sure, perhaps biology.
Petri?
Computers
Rull?
I don't know.
You once wanted to become a teacher.
Got born, got holidays and died.
Satemin?
Refuse answer.
What?
I don't concur that we declare our career choice.
What is it?
First it needs to be explained what its purpose will be.
Its purpose?
The authorities need it.
For which purpose?
Go on!
Nobody can force us to support these kind of methods.
Disregarding that also our class teacher should have an interest
when we support him in his ambition to dismantle the administrative categories
who retain him and who we suffer from.
Bad grammar!
6 6 6 6 6 6 6 6
BILLA'S FATHER
BILLA
Once upon a time there was a weirdo
who wanted to paint his room every second day
for the reason that his grandmother loved to smell of fresh paint.
Or else she was sad,
screamed miserably
and lost her teeth.
However at times he was too tired
or he was ill.
Fuck Germany!
If the 11. class could ...
Müller Frank switch to the 12. instead.
Why divided loyalties? It is about exhibiting an impeccable
and it can't be based on the fact that I'm public servant within an apparatus
which I can not accept.
Loyalty towards whom? The school or the boys?
There must be something wrong when one is offered these alternatives.
There is a possibility to travel to London for 86 Mark.
Korawalski had a black eye and no homework this morning.
Did nothing change with him?
At most deteriorated.
And in six weeks are the final exams.
There are no rules to the game anymore.
From experience: a mass protest driven by notorious objectives will either
be absorbed by the Establishment or will take a party choice seat in an official and therefore harmless opposition.
Their republic of councils will also just be another new Establishment.
I have never heard something more fascistic.
The reality of this generation is to have under your guidance, Ladies and Gentlemen,
too less schools,
too few teachers,
not enough emotional address,
insufficient humour.
A lack of affection.
And it is of course foolish when they come now and claim
to have no money for the tram.
Cause the money is there obviously.
If they would be prepared to purchase one Bee Gees album less per month.
Our top-tier Germanist.
Though I suspect
the youth is focussing on money
cause this is the only language you, Ladies and Gentlemen, understand.
Afternoon dad.
Na!
At twelve?
Hm.
Where is the car?
Oh, at the garage, a mark. Bloody insurance.
Five past twelve!
The fifth class was canceled.
I see.
Ill.
Oh, who who who.
Who is sick?
It's anyway boring.
What does he have?
Bubonic plague.
Which class?
Fatzke, our top-tier Germanist. German.
Is he often missing?
No, do I know?
It's a infamy shortly before the exams. Is he often sick?
Morning.
I brought you along some sample of what I recently referred to as a renaissance of Anglo-American pop,
ENGLISCH
especially where the lyrics are concerned,
especially where the lyrics are concerned.
Precision and originality.
Besides The Bees, The Beatles, The Who, The Masters of Invention, The Small Faces,
I should like to draw your attention to
Donovan!
Correct.
Writing on the wall ...
WEIGHTED AND DEEMED TOO LIGHT
I've seen a movie yesterday.
You've seen the Warhol yesterday?
Peter!
He's taking a picture of a sleeping girl for 8 hours. Nothing happens, fantastic movie.
Among others.
The pupil of the 10th year aren't allowed to leave the schoolyard due to the 11-point program.
I must not go to the bakery during the break.
Cause if I go it has many downsides.
I could be run over.
I could strain my ankle when falling down the bakery stairs.
I could be kidnapped and be sent to Turkey.
And I could be killed like Robert Kennedy.
Besides I'd have less money and I'd beef up from all the cake.
And then I would have to sneak back to the schoolyard not to be seen.
Then I always get nervous and agitated because I'm doing an unfortunate act.
Conclusion: the 11-point program teacher-student panel is very right
not to allow 10th-year pupils to go on the street.
For we're still so callow and not trained by teachers in the dangers of going to the bakery.
I can't leave my job, would be desertion.
THE PRINCIPLE DR. HARTMANN DISCUSSES HIS PROBLEMS WITH HIS BROTHER
The situation has never been as precarious as now, never.
Imagine Nemels would be my successor
and sadly it looks like it.
His progressiveness would butcher the whole school.
Then I'll choose Violat as his substitute.
People who're always on the tail of popular trends following the latest.
He'd butcher my whole school.
That means 20 years of my lifetime,
my life.
Looks like a friendly cow from behind.
Maths isn't really your hobby.
Na, but hopefully you know how to scoop coal.
How does the gradient behave currently, Rull?
Swell!
About most teacher one only knows that one can't go to them.
And when one knows when where it's possible cause he's likable
then I doesn't do it either.
Don't know either why one should do it.
For she's a jolly good fellow, for she's a jolly good fellow!
and so say all of us!
Happy birthday to you, ...
Happy birthday to you, happy birthday dear Gisela,
happy birthday to you!
ENGAGED
BILD: Riots in four cities (Only riot and baton)
I have a request.
We'd like to discuss last week's protest with you.
Yes, of course we need to grapple with it.
I suggest: next double lesson, Wednesday.
If the topic is still interesting for you by then.
Bild makes stupid!
But we don't want to disappoint Koch.
So Koch, start.
Educational terror!
Shut up!
You haven't prepared yourself, Ladies and Gentlemen and now try to hide it.
I once more want to point out that the whole class expects you to discuss with us, Dr. Nemels.
And I'm grateful for your cue, Satemin.
The factual resumé. August Strindberg was born 1849 ...
in Stockholm.
He experienced a mentally and materially difficult childhood.
After graduating he briefly studied medicine, philosophy, natural science,
was a tutor, tried acting
and by 20 had already discovered his artistic talent for literature.
At first he lived in Sweden while his first marriage with Siri von Essen.
SCHWEDEN
SIRI VAN ESSEN
At first he lived in Sweden while his first marriage with Siri von Essen.
More than with other artists his biography is inseparable from his work.
The reason his works have so-called eternity value is due to the poets genius.
A proof is not needed for this claim, which surely is no pretense.
The reading of his books makes them superfluous.
His inner biography in keywords.
Strindberg was born son to a father from a well off middle-class family,
his mother however was a maid, servant et cetera before her marriage.
Strindberg felt through these conditions as through his family's poverty
a deep sentiment of insult.
He in fact felt drawn to socially higher status
but derided and thrown to the gutter due to his mothers descent.
From early on he showed an exaggerated, medically described as almost pathological sense of self-worth
and thus a strong urge to self-analysis.
Dear suitors!
A building plan on the North Sea island Sylt requires vivid advertising.
The company Gebhardt salutes you with a self-made promotion song.
I'm dreaming of Westerland
this beautiful town near the North Sea beach.
Where you buy a house from Gebhardts hands
the very first hands.
If only I could have such a noble house
also in Wennigstedt and
live in this modern luxury
without no any worries.
Are you interested?
Please be cavalierly, you can write us.
And everybody knows it here, the price is low at Gebhardt.
Phone
Bremen 447271
I'm dreaming of Westerland
this beautiful town near the North Sea beach.
It creates you an own world
with just a bit inmates' money.
Gebhardt Estates. Good afternoon.
Good afternoon,
you are still building on the island Sylt?
Yes, single family homes with four rooms,
kitchen, bathroom, two WCs, developable attic, terrace and garden.
These Thermopen glasses, are they actually much more expensive?
Please sign here.
Where?
First the husband.
I believe Strindberg deserves ones attention.
Strindberg accomplished tragedies of lasting significance for posterity.
His creative aptitude which rose out of the inferno of an unmistakable schizophrenia
permitted him with the methods of self-scrutiny to re-create himself and his world on stage
where many of his dramas became ideals of an epoch.
In a few year we'll have only have half of todays teachers
but twice the amount of pupils. We need more graduate students!
E.g. 6,8% of pupils of the birth year 1980 will do the A-levels in Germany
I've read at Menge.
In Scandinavia it's 22%, in France 19% down to us.
Yes that will be something we're facing.
BERLIN 1968
Rohwedder comes from Berlin.
ROHWEDDER
And you consider Gisela to be bourgeois.
What do you mean, bourgeois?
Engaged and so on.
But you complain constantly that Jochen does so eccentric things.
That's completely different, they all find her bourgeois.
Kids listen. I just fucked Billa!
Mr Violat, I just fucked Billa.
Was a virgin, so sucked. But it'll get better.
Better luck next time!
Particularly the last third of the 19th century can be called the age of imperialism
even if precursor were discernible much earlier like England's industrial revolution and its outcome.
CIVICS
HO-CHI-MINH
Stop it!
Though as said prosperity
Though as said prosperity only begins after
after which war, Koch?
After the Franco-Prussian War.
And Hübner?
1771.
The after the war following years are called Gründerjahre in Germany.
But a honest notion of the impact of imperialism is more likely to get
when realising that already at that time
the flags of the old European nations began to fly all over.
An effect of the surplus production of manufactured goods and humans.
People emigrated,
goods couldn't sell on the domestic markets anymore. Thus new markets were opened overseas:
Asia, Africa.
And obtained suppliers for the insatiable demand of raw materials.
You've constantly mention Europe, what about the United States?
Later, Satemin. We're talking now about the 19th century.
You'll have enough time for questions, Satemin.
Good Morning Mr Rull.
Good Morning Dr. Müller-Frank.
Sleep well?
Not fully. But I didn't want to miss your lesson.
Can I continue?
Yes, please.
I gorge your fish, madame.
Another time, I'll drive you to Travemünde.
I think that's stupid. You?
Nay.
Peter, there are shrimps left. That is your bag.
You have goose bumps, Gisela.
Super.
I have no mouth, madame.
Drum bin ich auch gesund.
Did you leave the ball in the car?
The dog would have broken it on the beach.
When it's raining the revolution will take place in the saloon.
Peter, shall I get you a Fanta?
I'd like one.
What?
I'm an elephant, madame.
Somebody wants to join?
I'm an elephant-a, madame.
And no ...
Can you finally stop that nonsense!
Beautiful here, not?
Actually it's weather for cinema today.
I'd like to go.
Cute, the little one.
Please, they're getting younger and younger.
It's gonna embarrassing when you're 90.
I am a Sickophant, madame. I find that blatant, madame.
I'd like to leave not too late if fine with you.
I have to visit Rohwedder shortly.
Is he in Bremen?
In a sense quite nice being 40.
One finally know what they want
and they know that one can provide it.
Question is if one wants to provide it,
if one can provide it, i'd say.
You're entering a room,
You see a girl, make out and you know it's working out.
Make out with the one over there.
Not my type.
Lame excuse.
Miss, can I have two bockwurst, please.
A mummy, nothing for us.
I bet she's called Eva.
Ask her.
Too blond for me.
Lame excuse, you only say it cause you don't dare to.
Just ask her.
Please go ahead. Nah, I'll do.
Hello, what is your name?
I'd ask louder so she can hear it.
Are you joining tomorrow?
Hegel: The state is the reality of the ethical idea.
Nietzsche: The state is organised immorality.
The one who commands decide who has to obey.
Hitler: The state is a means to the end for the race advancement.
One can substantiate this with a quote by Kikero.
Cicero!
True, it occurred to me as well at home.
I've only forgotten it.
Can somebody translate this?
Korawalski?
Sleeps.
Babara Voss, also not.
The interest of the state are to be identical with the interest of the People.
Rull, you shall sit comfortably.
But there is always the danger breaking your neck.
And then, what happens to me?
Also können wir weitermachen?
Perhaps somebody can complete Cicero's sentence.
Karsten.
Now, what do we need a continuation of the sentence for?
Be quiet!
First in latin and then it'll be translated to german.
Und jetzt übersetzen sie diesen Satz noch einmal für Korawalski.
And now repeat the sentence once more for Korawalski.
But slowly.
I've understood everything, Dr. Falk-Fliege.
Good!
Then we can continue.
Who know another analogy to Cicero's sentence?
I think we have to establish once that in our society the decisions of the community of interests
depend on the group that has the funds.
Na na na, that is really to vague.
The state is after all dependent on the people who control the economy
and the state is just an economic model, nothing else.
Now the discussion is deteriorating into very general questions.
Now it is getting .... realistic ...,
Cripes!
Korawalski.
I notice a similarity Cicero's to the Soviet Union.
Man, just go over there!
The Soviet Union, by creating a single political party,
one in which the People together...
My I ask you to stop! May I? Quiet!
Quiet!
May I ask you to please return to Cicero.
What else did you notice with Kartens analogy?
Shit, I notice!
What.
It's fucking embarrassing to compare Hitler and Cicero. Fucking embarrassing.
Man, who has earplugs?
Such people default, I'm not interested in them.
I mean there weren't any rules of the game at Auschwitz either.
Yes, back then I was a young general practitioner at the Red-Cross hospital
and believe that one had to tell the truth to the patients.
And there I've told a young lady that she had cancer.
Yes, that was the worst thing I've done during my lifetime.
Grützi together.
We're playing Dostojewski's glass 'Der Idiot'.
Mr Satimin is currently here.
My mother, Mr Satimin and me are invited for dinner at my sister-in-law.
Mrs Schniede, the wife of trade union boss Alfred Schniede sits next to me.
Dr. Nemels, the deputy vice-chancellor is here with his wife.
Dr. Hartmann, next to Mr Satimin, is also here.
He originally wanted to bring his brother but he is ill.
Such a bugger.
Everybody now as to admit what is the worst thing one did in his life.
Now it's your turn, Mrs Dr
Yes,
I remember how I met my husband, at the ball Paradox.
Oh I see, Cafe Keese.
I sat there with my girlfriend, we actually only went out of curiosity.
And then I saw Günter
who also sat there with a friend and nearly died laughing
cause the Ladies had to ask the men for a dance.
My girlfriend wanted to bet immediately that I'd never ask the young guy
to laughed hysterically, to dance with me.
I also had no desire
in a sense, but I asked anyway and made the bet.
Günter got bright red, he was terribly embarrassed.
But while dancing together I noticed immediately
that he'd fallen in love with me.
But please. What is so bad about it?
That she told the story, not lovey?
Dr Hartmann
If it has to be.
Alright.
Site of crime is also Hamburg. I sat in the tram,
must have been in '42.
Then there was still vacation from Russia.
I sat there with some friends, also officers.
We all sat there and then I suddenly saw this old woman
with a yellow star,
the first time even if my brother doesn't believe me until today.
A very old woman.
Anyway, we sat there
and she stood.
And I wanted to stand up and offer her my place.
And then I realised that my fellow officers not at all think about standing up,
cause well, then I didn't stand up either.
Günter.
Yes,
I was in the first school year. And my class theater summoned my mother to visit.
If I remember rightly I were only in school for 3 months.
And he told her:
Do you know, Mrs Dr. Your son, he's killing me.
My mother smiled and didn't understand a word.
But the class theater sticked to it.
Nah, your offspring sits in the lessons, in his corner and laughs himself to death about me.
What was entirely true.
End.
What.
Not valid!
That is completely harmless, Nemels.
Hm, I'm not sure about it.
The question is if guilt is only what we consider guilt as per the code of law
also also bewusstes antisoziales, also kriminelles Verhalten.
or as a deliberate antisocial and therefore criminal behaviour.
or
of the notion of guilt has to be understood as an existential problem.
Or not to complicate the question,
as a primal instinct that the socialised human identifies as antisocial and punishes.
Then you have to ask yourself earnestly if the guilt of a five-year old child
isn't to be considered the same as the one of Eichmann.
Or let's say Johnson.
Or whatever fashionable political references come into consideration.
Tell me Satemin, does your son seriously believe all the nonsense he spreads out there?
Hoffentlich.
Consequently the criteria for conduct can't be violence but has to be: Violence what for?
Furthermore it can't be just violence per se but the notion of violence has to be differentiated.
Again 18, again ... 18 ... my instructions. End
as the violence of the law enforcement agencies.
With water cannons and physical destruction
With the first sign of state violence we disperse, it is new and different.
The nation woke up out from their criminal indifference and must not fall asleep again.
It's part of the strategy. But the tactic demands from us to act as if.
Today is about a directed action, it is about
that the verdict of both summary trials against the pupils Fink and Mar will be reversed.
Again, don't let yourself be provoked.
Did you see that?
Well, if they want to make out on their own.
First around the Roland. Pass it on!
Around the Roland. Pass it on!
Chief Cold Coffee. Many courage.
So do you join? Yes or no?
Throw that crap away!
Then will travel.
Alright, but no violence and together.
No violence
The next thing that happened was that I was arrested by the police and taken by car to police headquarters.
I was treated fairly decently.
But I was left to cool my heels for three hours.
Very good. To cool my heels. Very idiomatic.
To be precise it means: meine Fersen kühlen
Means waiting.
A police officer searched me from head to toe
and I was asked to sign a document to acknowledge my responsibility for my actions.
Wait a second Jochen, say it once more in German.
The case is too important to just let it be philology.
So you've signed a document?
Yes and my father came and picked me up.
That is to say he's is Trapper.
Well well, sit down.
Then you don't have to be surprised that the council won't be committed for your case.
Nah Peter.
How is it at the Führer's headquarters?
Good, thanks.
What is on the agenda today?
Chemistry, History, Latin, German.
And?
Class representative election.
Don't overreach yourself shortly before the final exams.
I have already enough on my plate.
Who will be the one?
That depends on the class, Dr.
Of course.
What about Anti?
From the educational viewpoint one should probably think about Jochen Rull.
You can't be serious. He is already disruptive enough.
About violence oder The fascistic concept of society of Bremen's Chief of Police.
I hope you didn't turn over trams too, Mr Beckmann.
You're smelling of beer again.
Better a drunkard than a coal dust-lung, Miss Munk.
What does one expect from us
Six hours a day as per curriculum,
every 45 minutes another lesson.
Without sense, without logic.
Mathematics, there is maths.
There, let's see.
There we don't need one.
So there I agree. Why shouldn't one know about cars as a girl?
What should be unfeminine about it?
Robert kicked up a serious stink.
And he doesn't let me drive either though I have my license since march.
In Israel his wife would be a sergeant.
I'm interested in the problem Rull. He must decide if he joins or continues to be the clown.
When I was on the Fenner I watched out that the whole shit passed smoothly.
When did the teacher strike the last time?
When I'd be principal I'd decide that small girls are allowed at the grown-up girls toilet.
Why?
Then we could hide.
I don't feel it like, it's to daft.
Idiot!
Why don't you land one in his face, Dr. Wieland?
He can't do that, he'll end in prison.
Quiet please!
Can I assume that you made the exercises?
Rull, your notebook please.
What would you say if I'd say
that I don't have my homework with me.
Why not if I may ask?
What would you say if I'd say because the tram was late.
Tram?
What does the tram have to do with it?
If it'd have been on time I could have finished the exercise in the tram.
Until now they're still homework and tram work.
So out with it!
And what would you say if I'd say that I wanted to make the exercise yesterday evening
and suddenly noticed that my fountain pen was empty.
No ending.
When you want to pull my leg.
So do you have the homework, yes or no?
What would you say if I'd say that yes, I made them
but no, don't have them here cause I took the wrong notebook.
I'd say you've been too lazy.
Furthermore I would say that you're ill-fated, Rull.
Additionally I'd say that I have never seen such nonsense a few weeks before the final exams.
Maybe I can answer your question as follows.
The people that I usually copy maths from weren't available yesterday.
So you'll prepare a paper until monday, Rull.
About the behaviour of a curve with special attention to
Pardon me Dr. Wieland
Isn't there a directive that the weekend is free of homework?
I can tell you I'm finished.
I just don't know anymore what to do.
You're so rude and only kid around.
I get told constantly that you're an exhibitionist. What shall I respond?
They really want to achieve something grave
and you constantly backstab us.
I can't defend you anymore at all.
And then you tell every idiot that we sleep together,
Das machen 12-jährige Jungs, die kleinen Mädchen in den Hintern kneifen.
that only 12-year old boys do who pinch little girls bums.
Yes, terribly funny.
Say something for once!
Gorilla.
No
The problem with Rull is much more complex.
That he doesn't want to conform is ok.
Possibly even desirable.
But there emerges also the first question from Rull for Rull,
can a human bear it to constantly distance himself from all roles he has to adopt?
The question for me is
if I can tolerate that
an anarchist, a slob
gets the possibility to influence other young people trusted into my care
with his doubtless destructive behaviour.
I can't do that.
If
he planted corn,
he got borers;
If he planted potatoes,
he got blight.
Achtung, Füße nebeneinander.
Attention, feet side by side.
Arms ahead.
And right
and two and left and two
And now both arms
And one, two and three and four
Right
and two and left and two and both arms
one and two and three and four and once more
right and two and left and two and one
and two and three and four
and again and right and two and left and two and one
and two and three and
Thank you.
Loose up!
It's my dads birthday today.
Please forward my congratulations.
Happy Birthday to you,
Happy Birthday Rull's dad,
Happy Birthday to you.
You expect to be treated respectively but then you behave like children.
Rull, take your things and get out.
And then you tell every idiot that we sleep together.
Small 12-year old boys who've been pinched in the bum by small girls do that.
Yes, terribly funny.
I can't understand you anymore at all.
Say something for once.
Gorilla.
Ah fuck!
Gropius Anaemicus Tuma
Then prove to me objective that I'm not a Kiwi.
Kiwis are nocturnal sylvans.
They spend the daytime in self-digged caverns
and look around searching for food in the dark.
They keep their beak close to the ground
in cracks and gaps to scent or sense their prey.
They then poke their beak into the soft ground
and pull their victims out of the cover.
They eat worms, insects and small animals.
To drink they plunge their peaks almost fully into the water
and raise it steeply like a chicken.
Now prove it to me that I'm not a Kiwi.
What the gaffer says.
Difficult
I don't agree.
I think positively about disciplinary measures.
I think there should be some more imagination shown in these cases.
What's up with imagination!
He pulls our legs since months.
Nonetheless one should try to integrate a boy as Rull into society time and again.
Simply said.
Whom is he actually harming?
Generation gap
Usually these cases are handled when trusting them with responsibility.
We all know how it is about the human Van Gogh.
One, twain, three, four.
I want to hear a very peculiar word.
And up!
After all I not only carry responsibility as a teacher but as a head of the family,
as a provider for my wife and children.
And seen from this perspective the risk I take for other
should not rise due to parents complaining to the Senate
PHYSICAL EDUCATION
that certain teachers allegedly support the demonstrations.
So once again, what is Van Gogh interest in the the Potato Eaters?
I'd have to take the unfortunate consequence that you just aren't grown up yet
to honour the trust I put in you.
Thoughts are free,
who can guess them?
The third menu for me, please.
Jochen.
The menus are only available till 3.30pm.
Nut cake!
But we're already sitting here for half an hour.
But it is just a quarter to four.
Then I would have seen, don't you think?
But we've already arrive at a quarter past three.
Then the menu would have been still available.
Nut cake!
Ok then liver, or pasty.
The evening menu is only available from 5pm.
When?
Only the marked choices are available now.
Where?
Plum cake and apple cake with cream. Kale with Pinkel-sausage, potato salad, radish salad,
Bremer poult ragout and beverage of choice.
The pasty.
I'll have to ask first.
Nut cake.
May I have an ashtray?
Which topic did you choose today, Rull?
Thanks Huje.
Satemin?
On me I have a photocopy of a letter send by the head of school
to Rulls father.
Where did you get this one from?
Dear Mr Rull, in article 26 in the charter of the Free Hanseatic city of Bremen the following educational tasks are defined.
Accordingly the first educational task is to raise pupils in our young democracy
from a child to a human being
Child – friend of the humans
Quiet!
who consciously integrates into society and is prepared to take responsibilities within this community.
Do you really want to read out the whole letter?
Yes.
Also otiose I should like to mention that I voluntarily and inwardly feel committed to this statue.
The conclusion that your son Jochen violates this principle regularly
and with ever new manners is all the heavier because of it.
With earnest and greatest regret I feel compelled to inform you
that your son is in danger of being suspended from school.
Naturally I'm open for any kind of consultation this first thursday ... and so and so forth.
Yours sincerely, Dr. Hartmann
Ok well.
Shall I understand that you want to discuss a private letter by Dr. Hartmann in class?
I can't allow that.
I just want to add that we're determined to challenge Dr. Hartmann's decision.
Bravo!
Furthermore we're determined to call the school strike in case the
head of school ignores us as usual.
Halleluja!
I'm noting your proclamation, Peter.
Peter, am I a good class representative?
Not yet.
Then I should like to announce my resignation.
That doesn't belong here!
Discuss this with your class teacher, Jochen.
Ok.
Can I just now
Manifest, the fundamental rights. Article 1:
The pupils dignity is inviolable.
Article 2:
Evert pupil has the right to the free development of his individual within the parameters of the law.
Article 3: All pupils have the same rights as every other German.
Get to the point!
Article 4: Every pupil has the right to freely express and share his opinion in word, text and image.
Censorship does not take place.
That's all just rhetoric.
What do you mean with just rhetoric?
Besides I have the right to express my opinion.
... to abstract the letter and only consider the content.
To comment on the fact that Rull shall be kicked out
even though he just joked around.
Be quiet!
The manifest in which the pupils dignity is inviolable
Of course it is like that
that Jochen Rull is a pupil but we others are pupils too.
Your dignity is inviolable too, my dear.
Quiet!
Why quiet? That is no antithesis?
And if he wants to make fun of us all the time then
Yes, somebody touches your dignity.
What does it even mean my dignity as a pupil?
And second in democracy he shall be raised to a human being,
Raised?
One can't raise him with rules and regulations.
Quiet!
No, I consider this totally wrong.
and there was something about within the parameters of law and if Jochen Rull
We know how Jochen Rull behaves until now
and this behaviour justify in no way a discharge from school.
I think you .. you instrumentalise him now ... Jochen
Dr. Nemels, we've heard our opinions several times.
Can we know your opinion about this letter?
Kurz vor dem Abitur, meine Damen und Herren,
Not all graduates, dear Ladies and Gentlemen,
demonstrate on the streets.
A lot of these graduates
spend their afternoons with making homework.
They have to learn vocabulary, solve difficult maths
or possibly fill in complicated text passages.
They even have to prepare for the next verbal classes
and likewise study for the written test and the verbal examination.
Satemin.
It is not about the Individuals involved
but if the head of school decides in compliance with the authoritarian system.
In this situation the pupils demand the right of co determination.
May I make a comment as moderator?
I recognize that
and I think it is great that a group of pupils is willing to take such a big risk
in a case where it sees injustice
so shortly before the final exams.
And that they possibly hazard their own future.
Rull, you've put your hand up.
I just wanted to say Dr. Nemels.
I think Dr. Hartmanns letter is fair.
Kiwi!
Ahh Jochen, stop the nonsense.
I think it is unfair and ungrateful.
I think the fun ends here.
Dr. Nemels, do you consider the letter to be unjust?
Then please strike!
I obviously can't speak for my colleagues
I didn't even want to know that.
If I'm prepared
in eine solche Aktion einzusteigen ist für mich eine Gewissensfrage, Jochen.
to join such an action. This is a matter of conscience, Jochen.
To the topic I can only say
presumably
That there will be a meeting with a few of your teachers tomorrow afternoon.
To especially discuss these questions.
Does anybody else ...
Bummer!
Dr. Nemels, we thank you for the discussion.
That has nothing to do with it.
Leave him alone.
6 millions killed!
Yes, but not by me.
It wasn't him.
I am Jewish.
Did you do it or me, nobody of us commit it.
That's not what it is about.
Shit!
And 10 millions of ours.
Ten Million people died. In Germany.
It's exactly the same.
Forget about it.
So what?
What do you mean done it yourself? Did I commit it?
You don't do something like this to a city as Bremen.
I find it incredible.
Yes, what of it.
It reminds us of such beautiful days.
I'm only surprised that such a thing is tolerated here.
Who says it's tolerated? It was just produced.
Why isn't there any police here?
Nobody says that it's tolerated, it's just got done.
Hm, do you see any public servant here?
Das Motiv gerade das Hakenkreuz zu wählen für diese Wandbemalung.
The reason to of all things use the swastika for this wall painting.
What did you imagine?
I was to young back then, I had to follow the orders.
I don't understand that.
Who says to obey orders. Who can command me?
The symbol as sign, I think it is a beautiful sign.
What do you this what kind of sign this is?
Hm, the sign of a sect.
A sect, you believe.
I'm just not sure which one.
Do you consider it tasteful?
No, absolutely not. That means ...
It is the swastika.
Yes, why do you think the swastika is hanging there all of a sudden?
I don't know, I'm sorry.
Is it a special day today?
No.
Isn't there a party
who has a swastika in their banner?
Not that I know of.
Do you think this was created by a party or do you believe it to be a work of a single person?
A party.
Do you have a political interest?
Hm, some.
From when on do you want to be politically interested?
What do you think is the age one should be politically interested?
As early as possible.
Ich würde sagen da kann man kein bestimmtes Alter nennen.
It is because at some point it's there.
Are you on vacation in Bremen?
I consider this illegal cause of the simple reason that it creates a bad opinion about Germany.
If a foreigner, and let it be only 30 foreigner on the market square, that means 30 foreigners
will speak out against Germany.
What kind of countryman are you?
I'm from Romania.
Thank you.
Die Schande die der der die Ding da, die Rune ist für sich kein Zeichen,
The disgrace that the the rune there, the rune isn't a sign
when I may correct you, it's a rune.
Old germanic symbol.
Germanic symbol?
And we've put them all in a gas chamber, we've crippled them all. I've been a soldier myself.
But I don't want to be a soldier anymore, not even at the German armed forces.
And even if they punished me for it.
Bravo! Daft, daft!
And now you only have to add a Soviet star.
Must be something political.
Something political
Yes, there are two possibilities.
Entweder ist er Linksaussen oder ist er Rechtsaussen.
Either he is a far-left a far-right.
He's acted counter-revolutionary, it's a disgrace!
I think it's exuberant stupidity, nothing else.
Yes, there is no, nothing there
that could have been let's called it learned from the so far published Nazi trials.
If this young man would have been drafted into the Hitler Youth
Yes, but he's not.
He isn't, well, alright.
What we need are camps where this kind of guys are sent to.
Such a vandal, look at him. Look at that face.
He has long hairs,
an infamy.
And he's not washed either.
There you're standing and discuss with these people
who obviously destroy democratic-liberal constitution.
And what would you do with this young man if he'd be punished?
Hang him, immediately.
Why?
Hang him, at once.
Cause this kind gave us enough misery.
So you support capital punishment?
Completely agree.
Certainly!
Would you do it yourself?
Me, no!
Hang him, I mean.
To hang him, yes!
Have you've already been deathsman once?
No, but I was in a concentration camp.
Do you believe he's paid by a party?
The building?
No, the lad. The young agitator.
I wouldn't want to call him a lad.
Yes.
But it's a mindless act. People, who suffered below this symbol
this rune as I've said
and me, me as a Berliner, 40 year old Berliner
have to witness this once again and I was a soldier. And I've also been with the Russians
and get to know the and I don't want war anymore.
Go over to the GDR, there you can do it.
Do it there. But you're yellow.
Yes, you do it here cause nothing happens to you.
But over there, go to the GDR
and show off. Stand your ground there!
Then I'll respect you, but like this
you're only foolish boys.
This is a motion picture that wants to ridicule us
which wants to make us look farcical, ridicule the police,
you stupid boys!
In this situation in which we're now. That the left is weak, the restrictions deepen,
the conservatives gain. When you do a motion picture in this situation
which attacks all sites equally
and questions all sites.
Then there is the function, and you have to admit the function will be
people saying it's all bullshit.
Politics is rubbish, the left sucks
and the one on the Top also suck.
Shit everywhere. That especially these people get confirmed in their opinion.
Our contributor Ischt Wambouri witness the following scene
on saturday morning 10 o'clock during the shooting in the Free Hanseatic City of Bremen.
You dumb wethers.
Grandpa, don't leave the scene!
These dumb wethers.
Ne, they've told you off.
Told me off?
Grandpa, take your dog!
Me, cause I don't understand this nonsense.
Do you know what treats you right?
Clout round the ears, left and right.
Hang me maybe too?
Grandpa that are your children.
Your children?
A matter of upbringing?
There we have the gift giving.
Let's say I would have painted something else, a naked woman or naked genital.
It is a biological fact that contaminant will be segregated.
The poor boy.
Does anybody know his father?
Only a swastika.
Rascality. Not acceptable.
A partisan like Rull should be brought down..
Full stop!
I'm afraid we'd have an empty school soon.
It's not my fault I wasn't alive back then.
Somebody should have talked with the boy.
but you also have to see the tourism here.
I'm a child of this society an I fight for this society.
I'd have to leave then to Cuba.
Rull downright wallowed in his scapegoat existence.
Somewhere I've failed.
He didn't mean you, boss.
What is your suggestion?
Defect?
Join the demonstrations? Also paint swastikas on the wall?
It's about the right case in the right moment.
Do you have a special-clock that shows when?
I only know
and this isn't very original
that I wouldn't know what to do when I'd have to decide freely.
Probably Eastern Block propaganda.
But in this case there is no leeway following the regulations.
We now address the pupils committees proposal
to advise the pupils committees of other grammar schools in the Hanseatic city of Bremen
to go on strike together with pupils of this school
due to the authoritarian decision of the school administration
to discharge the pupil of class 13b.
In a manifest sent to the administration
we demand the right of co determination
in fundamental questions with concern the school community.
We're ready to take the necessary steps to convince
the administration as well as the school authority
respectively force them to grapple with our concerns.
The case is known to us all
and I suggest that we vote straightaway.
So.
Who is in favour
that we align ourselves as members of this school
with Jochen Rull?
Wait a moment
Everybody above the 10th year has the vote.
Yes please, Dr. Müller-Frank.
I know I'm a bit out of place here
and you know much better then me how to deal with these cases democratically.
However!
Regardless!
Please be quiet! Dr. Müller-Frank has the floor.
Regardless I'd like to have ask this question.
Why did Jochen Rull paint the swastika on the school wall?
I've only wanted to have asked it.
You're the best one to know!
Quiet!
Quiet! A moment!
Stop!
Wait a moment Peter, that's not the way. That is unfair.
All right, i'll bear it in mind..
Quiet!
What is this about, what is this about?
About the decision of the pupils or can we only polemicise?
Please be quiet! Silence please!
Please be quiet, kids.
This serves no purpose like this.
Klaus Rohwedder, please.
May I also say something?
Is Jochen Rull in the hall?
Yes!
Come up!
I think you can help us here!
Please explain why you choose the swastika
to expose the fascistic tendency of the school system.
But only if you want!
Leave him!
You're after all Rohwedder.
The one we read so much about in the newspapers.
I'd have a question:
Mr Rohwedder, you've been once centre forward at Almsbüddel.
What?
I'd like to know how it happened back then
that Almsbüddel won 8:3 against the HSV.
Who? Where?
Yes, Hamburg. 8:3
I've read it.
Jochen, excuse the question ...
Sure, Almsbüddel.
Centre forward.
It's quite some time ago.
No, never.
Oh
Oh, then you aren't the Rohwedder from Almsbüddel.
Could it possibly be your father?
My father, no.
When I think about it,
it must have been your grand father.
Is he also called Rohwedder?
We'd possibly be willing to judge the school strike positively
but only,  mind, after the final exams.
I'd have to convince a committee of this first.
Yes, Peter.
One doesn't have to destroy the overall form to change it.
FINAL EXAMINATION
The ones ready can bring me their notebook and leave the room.
... AND WHEN WE HAVE TO DIE.
We does not want to be mistaken for bums? We!
GERMANY MUST LIVE AND WHEN WE HAVE TO DIE.
Who cares about peace on earth? We!
GERMANY MUST LIVE AND WHEN WE HAVE TO DIE..
You prowl in parks and streets,
who can't take your senseless sloth? We!
We! We!
Who has the courage to be ashamed of you? We!
Who doesn't let their future be robbed? We!
Who sees you daub old churches,
and has to loose all respect for you? We!
We! We!
Cause somebody has to be there who not only destroys
who nurtures our faith,
who learns, who educates themselves, performs his pensium,
for tomorrow's building the world.
The world of tomorrow We already are!
Who doesn't stay forever the vocal crowd? We!
Who even says that work only ruins,
so bored so excessively dazzled?
You! You! You!
Who wants to try talking with you openly again? We!
Who of course also has their weaknesses? We!
Who even has very similar fads,
also long hair just washed?
We! We! We!
Also we are for rigour,
we also have beards.
We often go too far too.
But sometimes in good,
in silent minutes,
we're sorry for different things.
Who has not lost hope? We!
And thanks those giving birth to us? We!
But who just wants to protest,
until there is nothing left to protest?
You! You! You!