In this land there is freedom,
peace, and wealth.
But suddenly one day, without mercy...
...the nation discards
a handful of its citizens.
Resistance is futile.
One can only accept the fate...
...our nation imposes.
Kamoi, Yosuke
Time to death:
One Hour
You're not drunk enough!
Interoffice memo: I need elixir!
Shimoyama!
Yeah?
It's been a while.
What is it?
You don't remember me?
Huh?
I'm Yosuke Kamoi.
What are you talking about?
That was years ago!
I'm sorry! Forgive me!
I didn't mean it!
It was just a game!
A game?
You call that a game?
Forgive me! I'll do whatever you say!
No.
Kill me and you'll go to jail!
Jail? I won't be going there!
Congratulations on
your first day of school.
I hope you'll all study hard...
...and grow up to be fine,
upstanding people.
But first I have
something important to tell you.
Between the ages of 18 and 24,
a number of today's Grade 1 pupils...
...will die for our nation.
We don't know who they will be.
It could even be one of you.
But don't be afraid.
Those who die serve the nation.
It is a very great honor.
Do you all understand?
Yes!
We will now take attendance.
Speak right up when your name is called.
When I was 6, before I understood,
I was given the injection.
And then last year I got through
my 'period of service'.
I turned 25.
I became one of those
who had fulfilled his duty.
As you know, the 'Maintenance
of National Prosperity Law'...
...implants the fear of death...
...in the citizens of a nation at peace.
By reaffirming the value of life...
...it is the cornerstone of our nation.
All citizens,
upon entering elementary school...
...are required to be inoculated.
Mixed in with
0.1 per cent of these injections...
...is a special nano-capsule.
It is injected into
one person in a thousand.
When that person is between 18 and 24,
at a specified date and time...
...the capsule shatters
in the pulmonary artery.
There is no way of knowing
if you carry the capsule.
It could be anyone.
This risk heightens awareness
of the value of life.
It promotes civic-mindedness...
...morality...
...and the desire to be
a productive citizen.
Are you OK?
Since this law was instituted,
the national suicide rate...
...and crime rates
have fallen remarkably.
Our stagnant productivity and GDP
have risen dramatically.
It is because of the Prosperity Law
that our nation leads the world...
It's wrong!
The law is wrong!
That law stole my girlfriend's life!
The state forced a senseless death on her!
Your girlfriend...
...was sacrificed for the state.
No! There's something wrong
with this country! It's crazy!
You all think so!
Why won't anyone speak up?!
You think so, don't you?
Hey! What's going on?! Let go of me!
Help me!
Help!
Let go of me!
Hey, what are you doing?!
There is one decadent thinker
in every year's intake.
Take great care in what you say and do.
To continue...
Those young people
with the capsule in their bodies...
...receive a notification
of their impending death...
...24 hours before it takes place.
These letters are known as ikigami.
This is a service rendered by the state...
...to ensure recipients and families
a meaningful final 24 hours.
Your task following this training
will be to deliver these letters.
You are an elite, chosen by the state.
There is honor in this work.
Do it with pride.
We will now offer a silent prayer
to those on whose deaths...
...our prosperity rests.
Pray!
'Fujimoto', isn't it?
Yes, sir.
What's going to happen to him?
The state treats thought crime
in an appropriate manner.
You needn't be concerned.
From that day on,
death notifications were my job.
A job vital to
the prosperity of the state.
Honorable work, a job to be proud of.
Fujimoto...
Chief...
Good morning.
January Deaths: 65
May they rest in peace.
Only 65 last month?
That's not many.
Take care of this, please.
It's for tonight.
Make sure you deliver it.
Tanabe, Tsubasa
Time of Death: 8 p.m.
Yes?
Excuse this late hour.
Is Tsubasa Tanabe at home?
He's not back yet. Can I help you?
This is a death notification.
The subject is granted free
transportation, food, and lodging.
The family will receive a pension
from the National Prosperity Fund.
However, should the subject
commit a crime...
...the pension will go
to compensate the victims.
I don't know him!
Mrs Tanabe!
He's not my son. Go away, please.
Mrs Tanabe...
Get out.
Get out, I said!
I'm a single mother. He's my only son.
Please...
Please don't kill him!
His death will be the foundation
of national prosperity.
May he rest in peace.
Get out!
Get out, now!
Tanabe, Tsubasa.
Time to death: 23 hours, 56 minutes.
From this moment begins the last day...
...in a young mars life.
Hey!
Play it right!
Are you into this or not?
I played it right.
Have you got a problem?
Not especially.
Sorry, can we take a break?
Your face.
The look on it.
Do something about it.
Sing looking like that
and they'll leave in droves.
Like this?
Yeah. Just hold that goofy grin.
How did I get stuck with him?!
Sounds good.
Hello.
How's it going, Tatsuhiko?
Not too good.
It's Tanabe.
I'm selling you two hard.
Hang in a bit, OK?
Tomorrow's big.
Yeah.
Tanabe...
Yes?
The T-Birds' future is riding on tomorrow.
Yes.
Live TV is tricky.
Play good and you're a star.
Mess up and you're history.
It's Tatsuhiko's show.
You just stand there and grin.
He's the one who's brought you this far.
I know my place.
I'm beat!
So, Hidekazu... what are your plans?
What do you want to do with your life?
No plans.
You've got to focus,
or you'll end up like me, going nowhere.
I'm back.
Mom?
What are you doing
sitting there in the dark?
Tomorrow's our big break.
Then we'll be able to move out of here.
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
This can't be right!
I couldn't do anything...
...but accept it.
Yeah, but...
...where does that leave me?
I'm sorry!
Komatsuna Live!
Thank you! That was 'Signpost',
written by Hidekazu Morio.
Lead vocal, Tsubasa Tanabe.
Tsubasa!
Hey, don't take it all!
You always do that!
Do you think we'll ever get our big break?
Who knows?
I wanna be a star!
Careful!
You'll spill it!
Wouldn't it be great
to play in the Tokyo Dome!
50,000 people watching us!
50,000 people going wild!
Don't spill it!
Stop day-dreaming, will you!
'Komatsuna! ' 'Yay! '
Idiot!
'I wanna thank you all
for coming out tonight! '
You ate the whole thing!
You took all the pork bits!
What about you?
And the bamboo shoots!
My motivations gone!
Excuse me...
Satake, Omega Music.
My name's Tsutsumi.
Thanks.
You mean the Omega Music?
Yes.
We've been hearing about you.
Could you maybe come to our office?
We'd like to talk to you.
You mean it?!
We'd love to!
Right?
Yeah!
Uh, well...
...it's you we want to see, Mr Tanabe.
Just me?
Shit!
We've never spot-lighted a new act before.
Let's hope they can light a fire.
Thank you very much.
My hopes are high.
Right!
Yes!
See you, then.
Hidekazu!
We're going to be on
'Music Bomb' next month.
Great.
This might be my big break.
I'll pull you along with me.
Didn't you sing lead?
You're just riding
that other guy's coat-tails.
And getting paid for it.
Isn't that better than being a coolie?
What?
Hidekazu!
Come on!
Why me?!
Tanabe, Tsubasa
Time to death:
16 hours, 26minutes
Sacrificed yesterday: Kojima, Maki
May she rest in peace.
The National Prosperity Law,
on a daily basis...
...teaches us the value
and the magnificence of life.
Vote for Kazuko Takizawa!
In our schools and our homes,
we must educate for the nation!
'For a National Education! '
Fujimoto...
Good morning.
Did your delivery last night go well?
Yes, sir.
It did?
Good.
It looks like you're getting used to this.
Chief...
Yes?
Um...
What is it?
Should I be?
What?
I mean...
What do you mean?
Should I be getting used to this?
Of course.
This is important work.
But...
But what?
Couldn't we do more?
To make that last day more meaningful?
Fujimoto!
That is not for us to consider.
Interference with a subject
is a violation of regulations.
At worst...
...it could be a thought crime.
Avoid unnecessary thinking.
I'm hungry.
Hello.
Do you have a reservation?
For one, sir?
This way.
The best of everything.
Can you pay for it, sir?
My apologies!
Three hours late!
What's that idiot Tanabe up to?!
Stage fright, maybe?
It's OK. I can handle it alone.
This is serious!
No luck.
I've looked everywhere he might be.
Shit!
The instant noodles tasted better.
Isn't that the guy at the TV station?
Excuse me.
What?
Your office said you were here.
So?
I wanted to see you.
I wanted to apologize.
And I wanted to sing with you again,
like before.
You came here to say that?
I'm...
You're playing live tonight.
You knew?
Should you be here?
Yeah, I'd better go.
Sorry to bother you.
If you're in the mood,
will you watch the show?
I'll be going for it.
Tanabe!
Where were you?!
Sorry. I fell asleep.
Look, damn it!
Come on and get ready!
Smarten up!
Here he is!
Thought you'd got scared.
I am scared.
Real scared.
Sorry... may I?
Sure, sit down.
Go ahead.
Beer.
15 seconds to air!
Here we go...
10 seconds...
8, 7, 6...
Five seconds, 4, 3...
Music Bomb!
We've got all kinds of guests,
all coming to you live!
A glittering two-hour line-up
packed with music and talk!
Now, let's introduce our guests.
First...
With their million-seller 'Love',
the 'Square Pants Orchestra'!
The alluring, over-30 'R30beans'!
Here you go.
Making their TV debut, 'T-Birds'!
After commercial, to MCs.
Go.
Tonight is this duo's
first-ever TV appearance.
T-Birds!
Thank you.
Shit!
Stuff it.
Hello?
Hidekazu?
Mrs Tanabe? What's wrong?
Are you watching the show?
No.
Watch it, OK?
It's his last big moment.
Last?
He got the letter.
So in a few minutes...
Please! Watch him.
You were singing on the street?
Yes.
Singing solo?
No, in a duo.
Not really a 'duo', was it?
Well, uh...
...that's right.
I'm told you were both
sent to 'boot camp'.
Yeah, the management
sent us away for two weeks.
About a week into it...
...I was exhausted from
rehearsing morning till night...
...and I was fast asleep...
So this is it?
This is how it ends?
We could go on all night,
but we're out of time.
So if you're ready...
Right!
This is a song they wrote
at that 'boot camp'.
The ideas must have been flying!
They're all ready,
so let's hear them sing.
T-Birds, with 'Meaning'.
Now what?
Hey!
What's going on?!
I'd like...
For my last song,
I'd like to sing this one.
'Signpost', by Komatsuna.
Soon my birthday...
Will come round...
Just another candle.
My heart is torn trying to balance...
The things that push on me...
'From all sides.'
Cut to a commercial!
He's nuts!
Get his manager!
A commercial!
Quiet!
Kill all the lights except for the spot.
A signpost to now is what everyone's...
...looking for.
What is this thing called "being alive"?
Fighting?
Or staying out of fights?
What is this thing called "right"?
Not being wrong?
Or not losing track?
I want tears to age me...
Laughter to grow lines on my face...
With my love I want
my back to bend under a weight...
To be so happy it's painful...
In spite of that, because of that...
...the time to forget will come.
What is this thing called "gentleness"?
To forgive?
Or to stand firm?
What is this thing called "love"?
Just consideration?
Or concealing a doubting heart?
I want to lose to the rain...
And lose to the wind, but...
I will always point the way.
What is this thing called "being alive"?
Fighting?
Or protecting?
Every step I take now...
...will not be toward death...
...but toward life.
Every word I sing now...
...embarrassing as it may be...
...will be aimed at people's hearts...
...and be my...
...signpost.'
Tsubasa Tanabe died at his appointed time.
He was 23.
Last night another young man
gave up his life on live TV.
His song brought tears to my eyes.
The sight of that beautiful death...
...reminded me again
how important life really is.
This is the hope the National
Prosperity Law kindles in us!
Help me win this election!
Vote Kazuko Takizawa!
Please give me your vote!
National Prosperity Victim
Sings Plea For Life
Chief...
My report on Tsubasa Tanabe.
That song seems to have brought
a high viewer response.
If he'd released it earlier,
he'd have been a star sooner.
I wonder about that.
What do you mean?
I suspect when he was singing
that song at the end...
...he was fully alive
for the first time in his life.
What made that song shine...
...was your ikigami.
I don't want to think that.
Say no more.
Everyone loves melodrama.
There are even people
who grow rich selling it.
Amazing, isn't it.
Hey, Mom...
...where's our next trip?
New Year's, maybe?
Not till then? I can't wait that long!
Don't be selfish, Satoshi.
But Mom!
Sit back! You'll get hurt.
Oh, OK...
Dad?
Mom?
Satoshi?
Satoshi!
'Morning, Sakura.
Good morning.
- 'Morning! - 'Morning!
Ten more minutes.
The country is short of donors.
I don't know when your turn will come.
I see...
You'll have to be patient.
Hang in there, Sakura.
There's Sakura!
I'm back.
Sakura!
You have a visitor!
Hi, Sakura!
Satoshi? What brings you here?
Come and sit down.
Your brother wants you
to go live with him.
It's taken a while,
but finally I'm making enough money.
I'm looking for an apartment for us.
Isn't that nice, Sakura!
Now you two can combine your strengths.
Is this OK, Satoshi?
What?
Can you do this?
Sure I can!
The company's doing well,
and I'm making good money.
Enough to support you.
You've always been a big talker.
You said you worked for a big company.
Then you were arrested for selling
phony 'spirit urns'.
That was ages ago!
I've changed my ways.
The director says your marks
are good enough for university.
Impossible.
No, it's not! You're smart, unlike me.
I'll manage the fees.
Go to university. We'll find a donor,
and then you'll see again.
Satoshi...
...I don't mind staying as I am.
What?!
To tell the truth,
being able to see scares me a little.
Why?
Now I imagine everything
based on what little I remember...
...from when I was small.
Your face, my face,
all I can do is imagine them.
But what happens
if the reality is different?
What, are you crazy?
Although seeing your face
in a mirror might be a shock.
Am I really that ugly?
I'm kidding.
Oh, you!