THE ABUSIVE PRlNCE
Once upon a time
there was a princess
who made her people dream.
That was Grandmother...
and these are articles about her.
And these
are articles about Mother.
This...
is the article about me.
PRINCESS FALLS
Why don't people consider me?
Good question.
Answer that, Chamberlain.
Your Majesty, Highness,
l don't read the tabloids,
but it seems that today's
fairytale princesses
have been replaced by starlets,
show girls,
and even squalid call Girls.
Letizia, l understand you,
l too would like to be famous,
siGn autoGraphs, be on TV,
in "DancinG with the Stars".
Not me, all l want is
to raise money for charity.
Grandmother opened
four hospitals in Africa,
mother, three schools,
me...
a shed with two veterinarians,
because no one knows me.
Then marry Gherets,
he loves you,
he's the Prince of BelGium,
then you'll get in all the papers.
Not to infrinGe on your matters
of the heart, but...
No...
Dad, you just want to do business
with the KinG of BelGium.
But there's no chemistry
with Gherets.
And he has Giant ears.
He does?
l've never noticed them.
Your Gaze is as pure
as a Polynesian sea
- and deserves a Gift.
- Thank you.
This gadget is a "must".
- A mirror!
- No, no.
lt's notjust a simple mirror,
it's the i-Mirror.
- The i-Mirror.
- Ask a question.
- To whom?
- The mirror.
- How do l look? - You're
the fairest in the kingdom.
And you can even chanGe
the language.
- lt works!
- Who sells this stuff?
No one, I patented it, to make
a splash in the new economy.
- Good.
- Thank you.
- Do me a favor?
- Of course.
l left my fan in the tower,
would you Get it for me?
l'd scale Mt. Everest for you.
- Your HiGhness...
- My dear Gherets...
- Dad, have you thouGht
about my problem? - Of course!
Get moving, Anastasio,
hurry and make her famous.
After readinG hundreds
of magazines, l'm certain.
There is only one way to put a
princess on the front paGe today:
the so-called
"Beauty and the Beast" strateGy.
The princess has to fall
in love with a poor, iGnorant,
coarse and vulGar man.
His Majesty opposes it
and kicks the lout out.
The princess replies
that love is more than lineage,
there's a clash at court, Gossip
in Europe and around the world.
Result: months of cover stories
on the marriage between
the princess and the pauper.
What?
MarriaGe with the pauper?
Are you sure?
Yes, my dear, before the ceremony
we send the Groom a call girl,
we photoGraph them,
princess betrayed, marriaGe
canceled, more cover stories.
Now Your HiGhness is famous and
every charity action makes news.
What do you say?
- Call girls?
- Yeah...
l'll do it, just one problem...
Where do l find a pauper?
They're around, they're around.
l've already interviewed him.
l did some research.
LiGhts, please!
The most ramshackle country
in the Union,
its most romantic
but difficult city,
the poorest neighborhood,
its most wretched inhabitant,
and here is our gem:
Antonio De Biase.
Hey, my name's Antonio,
l was fired three years ago.
l went to my Girlfriend and said:
"Lovey, my darlin',
my life, my heart, l lost my job."
And she said:
"And your girlfriend too,
if money can't buy happiness,
imaGine poverty!"
Son-of-a gun, Ciro!
When l need money,
l'm a Guinea pig.
You know when it says
"clinically tested"?
That's me, the tested!
l eat medicine and then
tell about the side effects.
Bro, yo, yo...
l got side effects riGht now.
l say they should split
by cateGory,
l mean, experiment man-man,
mouse-mouse.
lnstead they even Get mice,
that's wrong,
because if the mice Get sick,
who do they Get, a kanGaroo?
And if they experiment
on kangaroos,
who do they Get, a walrus?
And if they experiment on
walruses, do they Get a draGonfly?
Bro, yo, yo...
Big bro, how's it Goin'?
l should go down there?
No, we'll brinG him here,
we hospitalize him
and test a new medicine.
Someone like that,
when he's not a guinea pig,
how does he get by?
Your most Serene HiGhness,
how does he get by? MoochinG!
TODAY'S OPENlNGS:
PlZZA, lCE CREAM, WlNE
METER MAID
Hello, ma'am, remember me?
l'm the espresso
machine technician,
l came to check
why it wasn't working.
lf you like,
l'll taste the espresso for free,
just to be nice,
to see if it still works.
You've never liked the theater.
And you've never come
to the country with me...
Great, my compliments, thank you!
Stop!
Wait, a lady's crossinG!
Without a "crosser-walk"
it's a tragedy!
Cool it, bro!
Thank you, Antonio,
for helpinG me across the street
every morning,
l'm such a bother.
No, l do it for "humanism"...
Oh, there's my bus,
l'll get a lift.
- Who are you?
- A relative.
Jeez, just look at uncle!
You make me so mad, Uncle.
Two things were your ruin:
women and wine.
He's always drinkinG,
he's Gotta lay off.
You Gotta lay off, Uncle,
l say it from the heart.
l don't Give a damn
about his properties,
l want him to be well.
The road's closed here,
Go straiGht on.
- Who is this guy?
- Oh, come on, Uncle.
Not the first, the second.
Okay, perfect, thanks.
Hey, what about your uncle?
lf he's Gotta die,
he's Gotta die.
Jessica!
Let's turn this off,
it's a bomb to the brain,
calm down.
No one understands me.
No one understands me!
- Cousin, snap out of it!
- How?
There were two thinGs in my life:
Manuel and tap dancinG.
Then the miracle: Gloria Cecchi
put Manuel and me in the musical.
The last dancers,
a minute and ten seconds on stage,
l'm at the heiGht of success,
l sell fruit tap-dancinG...
and what happens?
You catch Manuel in bed
with Gloria
and Get kicked out of the show.
And you say snap out of it,
but how?
- No red Grapes?
- Wrong season.
- Concord grapes?
- Next week.
You're so sharp,
as a kid you knew
everythinG about fruit:
anjou pears, fuji apples...
You invented home-delivered fruit.
Go back to your old life.
- What were you doing now?
- RehearsinG with Manuel.
- Then?
- MakinG love with Manuel.
Other stuff?
l washed and ironed
Manuel's shirts.
l can help you there!
Take my T-shirts and shirts.
lron the shirt collars high,
that's how Manuel wore them.
You can't go on like this,
you're a broken record!
Can't live by moochinG anymore.
You complain? You hire out
as a guinea pig, you're lucky.
Lucky? They call you
twice a year.
At least,
you've got a business mentality.
But loose ciGarettes are touGh,
the problem's the assortment.
We're scarce on lights
and menthols are nowhere around.
And where do you mooch cigars?
A clinic called me,
we'll see what happens,
the situation's serious,
bro, yo...
PRlNClPALlTY
KURHAUS CLlNlC
Our tests in this clinic
can sometimes cause
slight side effects,
like distortion of vision
or memory loss.
ln mice, this medicine caused
articulation narcolepsy.
- Relax. - lt only means
your arms and legs Get numb,
to revive them just do this...
But I'm sure this won't happen
in human beings. Pill time!
Let's do this,
say l want to meet him
and brinG him here.
Princess, he's not
the masseur or the pedicurist,
you have to simulate
the spark of love,
isn't it best
to run into him by chance?
The princess!
Ain't Got eyes, bro?
Plan B: random clash.
Jessica, l found a scarf,
it's awesome!
And you say I never give you
presents, you'll flip.
Highness!
Plan C,
infallible!
Grab the doG!
Nero XVI, behave!
Doghouse 7, no supper!
l'm sorry, l'm mortified,
distressed,
appalled.
- ls that your dog?
- Yes.
l didn't want to attack him,
l miGht have hurt him.
Sir, may l offer you ice cream,
as an apoloGy?
You don't have to be so formal.
l have stomach cramps,
l need to walk.
Test subject...
- Wonderful, you do it
for humanity? - No, for 700 euro.
You're a sincere man.
A sincere man is a rarity.
- What's yourjob?
- l'm a noble.
What's your work schedule?
When a person is a noble,
she's that forever.
Non-stop?
No breaks?
You catch a bite as you work!
l'll explain,
what you see here is a kingdom
and l'm the princess,
the king's dauGhter,
and that's my castle.
You own a castle?
You must be filthy rich!
You own a castle,
you're a beautiful Girl...
So, why are you talkin' to me?
Why am l talkinG to you?
lt's obvious, because you're...
so deep
and acute.
And intelliGent.
You know me to a T!
When you're pro-positive,
in moments of "optimilazation",
you hope you'll hook a Girl...
But not at your level,
so noble, superior to nobles.
You're actually "extra noble".
l was thinking a more basic type,
maybe more bubbly.
No...
actually it seems my type is...
someone like you.
You're sure, or are you kiddin'?
ls this "Candid Camera"?
You're a guinea pig, own up.
Look.
- What is it?
- My passport.
This never happens,
even your picture's beautiful.
A compliment...
"Profession:
princess."
Mer... merci, mon tresor.
l've Got...
lt had expired, you did me
a favor, thank you.
lf you like,
l'll throw your purse, shoes...
You're irresistible.
l have to Go,
but l will run into you again.
l hope not "run over"!
Just a quip...
Right.
Bye.
Even for coffee, no problem!
lf l can Get it, l will!
Ok, good-bye.
l am Jesus.
l am Jesus!
De Biase, you're next.
Call me Antonio,
it's like home here.
l am Jesus.
l took bread and multiplied it,
l took a fish and multiplied it.
- You're Good at multiplying?
- Yes.
Here's 20 euro,
squeeze another one out.
lt's your turn.
He is with you?
And with your Spirit.
lt must be fake.
- Please sit down. - Doctor,
l have to ask you something:
that medicine you Gave me,
it Gives hallucinations?
No, none of the mice had any.
Then I really was
with Princess Letizia.
The kinG's daughter?
She says l'm her type,
that l'm acute, deep...
and really intelliGent!
Suspend testing,
the medicine's lethal,
notify the who
and pump his stomach, fast!
l knew it! Hey, easy man!
l'm the court chamberlain. The
princess invites you to dinner.
Go away, you're a hallucination!
No, l must insist,
l'm the chamberlain.
First the princess,
then champagne,
- now l'll see the Madonna!
- The Madonna?
No, l'm the champaGne...
the chamberlain!
- Please, get in.
- lt's all fake,
this doesn't exist,
you don't exist.
What are you doinG? Please,
Get in.
Please...
This medicine's a bombshell,
it'll go like hotcakes!
Where are you Going?
Stay still. Let's Go!
Good eveninG, Countess.
They put a tube up my nose
that went all the way
to my stomach.
Then they pumped me
with water and salt.
l felt my food come up
and out my ears.
Can I be truthful?
lt was my own orGanic stuff
and it made me sick.
Why aren't you eating?
Your story is so intriGuing...
Princess, would you like
a little Beethoven?
Very little,
or we'll Get too full.
But, for starters,
brinG some nice pizza bread
with prosciutto
and lots of fried things:
rice balls, doughnuts
and some olives from Tuscany.
From Ascoli.
You eat those yourself,
l want the Tuscany ones.
Do you eat fried food?
When you see it, you'll eat it.
Well, we'll serve
the escargot first, alriGht?
lf they got here before us,
serve them first,
but don't keep us waiting
or we won't eat at all, riGht?
Anyway, we have a reservation,
it says "princess",
in the book of the Reserves.
Fine.
- Princess...
- Princess.
- Hey, buddy!
- Yes?
With the fried food, l'd like
a little ketchup, mayonnaise
and some barbeque sauce.
Hey, bro, you're doing fine!
- Bro, yo, yo...
- Yo?
Bro!
- Princess.
- And who are you?
- The sommelier.
- You know this guy?
- Yes.
- So, who is he?
- The sommelier.
- And what's he do?
- l taste your wine.
We pay for it and you drink it?
ls this a joke?
And look at the price:
1950 euro.
lt's not the price, it's the date.
And it's even expired!
lf you don't scram,
l'll tell your pa there.
l don't like how you work,
1 to 0 for you.
Go.
Chew out that kid,
his work's no good.
Princess...
l'm invisible to this guy.
Princess, really...
l'm sorry if l was like a hick...
No...
don't worry.
l really like your spontaneity.
l'd spend another...
thousand eveninGs like this.
l'm the life of the party,
l make quips, tell jokes,
when a guy's in the dumps,
l make him lauGh.
l don't like people to be down,
l like them up.
You have a charm...
Say it, in your own way,
no problem,
l'm ready for anythinG.
lt's mysterious.
- l Got the chills.
- lt envelops you.
Princess, maybe...
your hand slipped and found mine.
- Did you realize?
- Yes.
You did it on purpose.
Can I give you a kiss?
What, temporarily?
Right in front of these ruins?
Sure!
Come get the flesh!
Princess, l'll hurt you bad!
l'll make you see motorized
kanGaroos, the ones that Go...
The ones that Go...
A motorized kanGaroo.
Shall we order dessert?
Hey, princess,
l'll stop your cardiac zone.
Want dessert? l'll get it,
so it'll be done.
Hey princess,
remember the kanGaroos.
Mom, eat somethinG.
What's wrong?
Here l am!
What did you bring me?
lt must be a homemade pie!
Ma'am, l'll unblock you.
Push hard on the accelerator.
Ma'am, floor it!
Accelerate!
Fire!
He's a scourge of God,
his first date, he burned down
the kingdom's most antique chalet.
l don't even want him
as a fake boyfriend!
But it works, tickets
for the concert for Sudan
are goinG like wildfire.
Just think of all the charity
l can do after four months
like this.
No, after four months
with that beast,
we'll need charity ourselves.
Kick him out of the kingdom!
See? You don't care
about my dreams,
you're only interested in...
your "parties".
How dare you!
But I do.
lt's my fault, l underestimated
that boy's devastation.
He should make Letizia famous
without too much damage.
l'll take care of it
and l'll transform
the beast in, let's say...
a squatter prince.
Okay, on one condition.
That you start seeinG Gherets.
l don't say you have
to fall in love,
just spend a little time together,
talk, get to know each other
better and then if it happens...
Wow, Antonio, a princess!
Remember me
when they make you a prince!
Just one thinG: make me
the Marquise of Spaccanapoli,
so Manuel will see what he lost.
Think they'll make me a prince?
You know what l did to Letizia?
l am Jesus.
- Gotta go, Jesus is coming.
- Jesus?
You can't believe
the VlPs he's with!
Come here.
Come here, chéri.
The Princess invites you
to move to court.
- No fakin'?
- What?
- l should come with you?
- Give me your baGs.
Do you have
a change of underwear, sir?
To the palace!
You'll be in the guest
house for now.
You mean here?
Before you can enter the castle
you need to learn bon-ton.
- Button?
- Proper manners.
His Majesty wants his daughter's
boyfriend to respect etiquette.
- What?
- Etiquette.
- Before that.
- Respect.
- You said "boyfriend".
- Yes, you're Letizia's boyfriend.
- But you need etiquette.
- What's that, dude?
A group of rules, for example,
you can't say "dude",
we'll substitute it with "ooh-la".
l don't understand,
what's "ooh-la".
l don't understand you either,
so I've hired a translator.
- Professor Ruotolo!
- Here.
- What's "dude" mean?
- lt means boy.
Good dude means Good boy and
cuttin' out dude, let's go boys.
- Fine.
- Thank you.
- What's "ooh-la". - "Ooh-la"
is an expression of surprise
that can translate to "Oh, my".
lf the surprise is greater,
"Oh, my goodness",
if the surprise is excessive:
"Oh, my God Almighty"!
- Fine.
- Thank you.
l'd like to start with his look,
it's a tad vintaGe.
What did he say?
Learn to dress, you're a siGht!
Look who's talkin'!
- Fine.
- Thank you.
This way.
The classic suit,
when is it worn?
- To Get a bank loan.
- No, a suit for tea.
For me?
No, for a tea break.
Break dance, like this?
- Like it?
- Horrible.
Easy, that's for a funeral.
- No, cocktail.
- Cuddle?
Cocktail,
when you meet for a drink.
And this?
- lt's a smokinG jacket.
- No, tuxedo.
- And this?
- Tuxedo.
- No, you missed two out of two!
- l'm consistent.
You're a stinker!
You make me talk like you.
Can I ask a question, bro?
Every time a guy has a drink
he's Gotta change suits?
To get a drink at night,
l go in pajamas or penguin suit?
Ruotolo!
He asked: "When l am
in the arms of Morpheus
and feel the need
to placate my thirst,
may I quench my thirst in pajamas
or must l wear a tuxedo?"
How often we've heard
the importance of being oneself...
Not in your case.
l just Got one wrong...
- Let's Go!
- What a weirdo!
This has to Go.
lt's not hair, it's a haystack!
- l can see Letizia "zumtimes"?
- Not talkinG like that.
l still have this tiny defect.
Sometimes with an S
like the Salvation Army.
- You're a Good "babber".
- Barber with an R like Rotary.
- Say "barber".
- Babber please.
Without please!
Your school burned down
after first grade.
- l want to die!
- And l'll come to your funeral.
Have you learned etiquette?
l'm great, l'm gettin' better.
Hurry, l can't wait
to have you at court.
l'm leavinG, l have
an exhibition for Ethiopia,
you know, world hunger...
Food's Good but not drink,
they'd be in a tough spot,
not knowinG how to dress,
they have to undress, dress...
l'm learninG.
Alright, I'm GoinG.
You're hurtin' me!
Every time l kiss the princess,
a photo comes out.
You still have
these frivolous curls?
Cup.
Cup!
Tea is taken
sittinG erect, leGs together,
arms tight down and chin raised.
Only after a car crash
l'd be in this position!
Arms tiGht down!
Pain therapy might be useful
in your case.
True friends come in bad times,
but especially in good times.
Who are they?
l found them in the Garden,
they're Master Antonio's friends.
Whatjoy!
l swear on my dead
cousin's body, l missed you.
On my dead cousin's body and my
father's, l missed you even more.
On my dad's and mom's bodies,
l missed you too much.
- This is a family massacre!
- Speaking of family,
let me introduce
my cousin Jessica Quagliarulo,
l mooched off her like crazy.
No, the last time
they swiped my bracelet,
l'll say hello my way.
l got your shirt dirty,
l'm sorry.
- What are you doing?
- Spit gets the stain right off.
Just a second more.
- Am l hurting you?
- Your heel!
l'm sorry, Mr. Champagne.
Just a lot of talk...
And no drink,
where's this champagne?
Will you be staying long?
Dudes...
- Roses here! Hi, ChampaGne.
- Hello.
We're outta shampoo.
There's mail!
What's the property tax
on a castle?
And Gas and electricity bills?
Preparin' an estimate?
They're really organized here.
- Coffee?
- No, thank you. Let's Go study.
- And you?
- l'll dress and come.
Cover up and don't come.
Antonio, let's go!
Can I make more coffee?
- Miss QuaGliarulo...
- Yes.
- Hello.
- Goodbye, Champagne.
My dear Antonio, you're makinG
your debut at court tonight,
there's a charity concert.
- Will Letizia be there?
- Of course!
Okay then!
But you must learn to Greet
in a natural manner.
- Look, they're beautiful!
- They're scary, who are they?
What?
The Ambassador, His Excellency,
the Marquise of DraGo,
Serene HiGhness, and the Countess.
Say it!
- And that's, what's he called...
- Never talk like that.
Say it.
All these old fogies!
What? This is the creme
of the aristocracy.
lt's not the creme...
it's the cremation!
Now Greet them elegantly
but discretely
and especially, naturally.
Don't worry.
Hiya, bro, great!
Disgusting.
Gimme five!
Count Borromeo is asleep.
And you wake me up to tell me?
Get some shut-eye,
it's so comfy here.
Can't you hear?
Sorry!
When you're done,
we're waitin' outside.
- Just you?
- No, all of us. - Jessi too?
- Okay, see ya later.
- Take it easy!
That's enough!
You are a hick.
Okay, maestro,
if it's time to talk, let's.
You've busted our nuts
to smithereens!
This is true art,
it's pure chamber music.
Yeah, bed chamber,
we're all snoozin'.
This guy knows what l mean.
Do somethinG more modern,
like Peppino di Capri,
do you know "Champagne"?
You don't even know "Champagne"
and you call yourself a maestro!
You're not a maestro,
you're just a horn-tooter!
When you Gotta, you gotta.
Sorry they woke you up,
maybe your dead Grannie
had winninG Lotto numbers for you.
You are a boorish man,
l say this music is very youthful.
Countess,
you say "youthful", but on your lD
your birth date says
"Battle of Waterloo"!
lt's written in Roman numerals.
Where did you brinG me,
to the morgue?
l'm sorry, Count.
That boy is right,
someone finally said it.
You are always elusive,
Countess D'ArmaGnac.
Smack!
How do you find this jacket?
- l'd find it everywhere.
- Son-of-a-Gun!
The buffet!
Let's not make a show
of ourselves!
l'm losinG a button,
darn the court seamstresses!
Relax, Mr. Champagne,
l'll fix it.
- What are you doing?
- GettinG some thread.
ln a Gala evening
somethinG like this happens...
Done.
Miss Quagliarulo,
this is a miracle!
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
Letizia, my love, l was looking
for you and your father.
My father is with
the Countess D'Armagnac.
l can't bear her,
she's always on the make.
l've just been supplied
with 500 i-Mirrors,
so I thought l'd donate 499
to your needy peoples
and, big surprise,
l'll hide the last one in the
castle so you can hunt for it.
l'm off.
Fame works, the concert has raised
15,000 euro for charity,
instead of the usual 250.
Are you listeninG?
l'm worried, he's too chatty.
lt's okay if an African
Gets my job,
he's hard up
and it's an act of humanity,
but when mice steal yourjob,
that's an act of "mousanity".
lt's a question of logic.
What's yourjob?
- l manaGe my accounts.
- You manaGe a count?
That's enough!
You're an offence to savoir faire.
l don't know any Mr. Faire.
Princess, be ready for anythinG.
l say hello to anyone
l know, it's my way.
Savoir faire
is an order of Good manners.
You mustn't yell
and you mustn't eat
with your hands.
So, I can't put my finGer
in the whipped cream,
but people can spit at me?
That's enough, you hick!
You've offended my Guests,
Get out!
- Majesty...
- Get out!
Majesty...
Take it easy, bro,
we'll work this out between us.
Dad, you can't throw him out.
l... l love him.
l don't want
this troglodyte at court!
lf you throw him out, l'll follow
him and renounce the crown.
What? Your mother's crown.
Love counts much more
for me than the crown.
- Antonio stays here.
- Then keep him in the garden!
Chamberlain, he must never again
set foot in this castle!
Can I say something?
We haven't known each other lonG,
a friendship hasn't bloomed yet,
a collaboration might come about,
knowinG one another.
l'll never collaborate with you,
you disGust me!
- Sire, it's all feigned.
- No, he disGusts me really!
This man will Give me a stroke.
l'll die of a stroke!
lt's just Great here.
Who's movin'!
Don't talk with your mouth full.
Wait, when l finish...
What's the matter?
l was having a sandwich,
l saw you and...
wanted to say hello and thank you
for saying you love me
in front of your father.
You could have said itjust to me,
but l understand
you're committed to your father...
First your father, then your
horse, l never Get to talk to you,
anyway, l wanted to say
that after all...
since you're a woman
and l'm a man,
there's love,
it's stranGe there's no brood yet.
We could Go ridinG.
Do you know how to mount a horse?
You'd better give it to me
already mounted.
Can you ride horseback?
Princess,
maybe you "undervaluate".
Please.
Good boy!
You're good with horses!
Maybe...
it was mounted wronG.
- We lost the horse.
- But we found cherries.
We lost a horse
and you think about cherries.
They remind me
of when I started mooching,
it's always moving to remember
the past, never forGet that.
- Why are you barefoot?
- No, why are your boots still on?
lt's so nice
to Go barefoot on the grass.
lf l said Go topless, you might
think l was makinG a pass...
Take them off, go on!
Now l'll come down,
let's be toGether a little.
You miss me, l know you.
Little cherry!
l haven't done this
since my mother was alive.
She planted these cherry trees.
The people really loved her,
but she never told me her secret.
Maybe it was she went barefoot.
Anyway, if l owned a tree,
l'd make lots ofjellies,
because if you squeeze
the "juiz" from the cherries,
you getjelly
and you can make jelly buns,
it's a good idea.
You could even open a shop.
There's no bar around here
that can sell jelly buns,
it's a brilliant idea.
Put a sign on the castle:
"Jelly Buns".
Princess, your horse.
That's jelly!
This is a fairytale!
She'll give up
the crown for you, look.
Jessica, stretch out here,
we have to talk to Antonio.
- The princess is pretty, huh?
- What's she like?
The princess is a princess.
At first they're all princesses,
then when they do certain thinGs,
they're a wow!
- Where did you meet her?
- On Facebook?
- Did she make a friend request?
- They've friends in common?
- You know who tagGed her?
- Peppe the stable boy.
Guys, the princess
is something bourgeoisie.
- Don't talk difficult.
- She's a different social status,
because she goes from beinG
a princess, to beinG a queen.
- Automatically.
- No contest.
Like in a factory when
a dad leaves his job to his son.
Damned lucky!
What did you do?
- Where did you take her?
- Your room?
- A hotel?
- A car with newspapers?
We spent time in the garden...
With newspapers around the tree?
Maybe you don't get it,
one little kiss
and we're in all the papers,
if we did more,
we'd end up in DVDs!
Are you in love?
Besides that,
l think...
you can love without makinG love.
- He did nothin'.
- You're a jackass!
Take us to the castle
for our ciGarette assortment.
But, don't pull your usual stuff.
- Promise?
- Promise.
Let's get some sun first.
lt's my first time in here.
- Are there any ciGars? - I don't
know, it's my first time.
What's this thing?
Look in the mirror
one at a time, please.
One at a time please.
- What is it, scales?
- Stop, don't touch anything.
No cigars here.
- You gettin' a tan?
- No, just checkin'.
Here! "CiGar, cigar..."
Boxes of ciGars.
l caught you, little owl!
Was that the kinG?
l dunno, who was
lookin' at the Guy?
- Looked like him.
- Let's Go see.
Don't!
This is a Government meetinG!
And you're Governin' great!
l've had it, none of you
can come in the castle again.
Guards!
- Run!
- Easy to say!
This castle's endless.
lt took an hour
from entry to exit.
- So, from castle to castle?
- One hour.
What's this here?
Gherets, turn on
the air conditioner please?
- There's the guy
with the biG ears. - Gherets!
For you, l'd turn the stars on,
one by one.
That ridiculous Group
Going around the castle...
l found out...
His cousin wants
to be in a musical, crazy!
Have you seen the other two?
The e-normous and the e-small.
By the way,
that wretch you use to Get famous,
how much longer does he stay?
The chamberlain says
as long as he makes news,
so about three months.
l know it's all fake, but...
l'm jealous.
Of Antonio? Come on!
We have nothinG in common,
his ignorance is stellar.
He wanted to put
a siGn on the castle:
"Jelly Buns".
Are you sure
you won't fall in love with him?
lt's one of the few things
l'm sure of.
Your eyes are like the moon
reflectinG in the Pacific.
Gherets, relax.
Guys,
it was obvious!
You didn't understand?
Well, did you?
Anyway I'm just fine.
- Stay cool.
- You're okay?
Just fine.
l can't stand
seeinG you like this.
And stop listeninG
to "lndifferently".
There's always
a second chance, right?
Answer.
Sorry, is this 91457569?
You didn't get one number right!
What are we doing here?
Why don't we go?
When you want,
you make it all work out.
You showed us
we can live Great without money.
But without love too,
that's overdoing it!
You have to work hard for love
and besides, they're the wretches.
Antonio, make them respect you.
You did a terrible thing.
- You mooched on feelinGs.
- What?
lf you'd said you needed a
squatter prince, l'd have done it!
- Let me explain...
- What's to explain?
l'm tellin' the papers,
that Letizia isn't a princess,
she's a witch, she exploited me.
You'll ruin me.
So, if you don't want me
to ruin you,
l ask just one thing:
help me make her fall in love.
The way you are it's impossible,
l tried.
You have to work harder.
Give me a hand.
Give me a hand...
- We usually walk like this...
- Stop!
Lift your arms.
- Have you washed your underarms?
- Yes.
Down.
Whatever happens,
the little ball must never drop.
Everything can be done
with your arms at your sides.
- Howdy do, bro.
- No, you can't say that!
You can jump...
dance the twist...
l'm familiar
with singing and dancing.
Shout after a Goal...
- Damn!
- These thinGs are basic!
They're basic, you're right.
Good, study, apply yourself.
Sometimes, sometimes...
Good, study.
- Sometimes.
- Good!
Do you like my attire?
- Does "attire".
- No, it's your clothes.
Count, hello!
Do you like Ariosto?
l love a roast with potatoes,
Mr. Marquis.
Taste is a matter
of "up-onion".
Exceptional improvement, you have
a bent for beinG aristocratic.
BeinG aristocratic is easy,
just don't do a thing all day.
Wise observation!
The work of seduction can begin,
do you know Jacques Prevert?
- Who's he?
- A poet, Letizia adores him.
Are you up to memorizinG
all his poetry?
My memory's not so great,
how's your phosphorus?
Fine...
Antonio!
- What is it?
- l'm not so worried now.
l got pricked, there's blood.
Good, that means you're human.
Ready?
Youth in love kiss standinG up...
Youth in love kiss standinG out...
No, standing up!
Against the doors of the niGht.
Antonio, is that you?
Yes, it's me.
What are you doinG?
NothinG, you know,
l didn't have...
much "sleepfulness",
so I said: l'll sing
a couple of Neapolitan songs...
No, that was Prevert, l know.
Do you know Jacques like me?
Hot digGity!
l just love Prevert.
- You do?
- Wow!
By heart, do you know
"Chanson"?
Sure, "Chanson",
you ask if l know "Chanson"?
- l can't find it! - Hurry,
if Dad comes, he'll get mad.
Want to hear
the version that's famous
or the one on the Internet?
There's only one...
- Found it!
- Perfect.
- "What day is it?"
- Thursday.
- That's the poem!
- What day is it?
- Thursday.
- Now you're doinG it too!
What day is it?
lt is everyday, my friend...
- lt is an entire life, my love...
- lt's an entire life, my love...
- We love, we live...
We... damn!
The roses are moving
but there's no wind.
No, it's a bad, uGly cat! Quiet!
l never kick cats but
when one interrupts a poem...
ya darn tootin'!
We love, we live...
We don't know what life is,
my love,
and we don't know what days are...
We don't know anything anymore!
A poet's suffering.
l hear footsteps.
l've had it!
Chamberlain!
False alarm. The poem?
- Still want Prevert?
- Jacques.
There's a poem
that's very beautiful,
it's called "Indifferently".
lt Goes like this, more or less...
Do what you want to me,
indifferently,
l know l'm nothing for you.
Give me this poison,
don't wait for tomorrow,
because, indifferently,
if you kill me,
l won't say a thinG.
lt's beautiful.
Why don't I know it?
He wrote it after death.
l mean, he wrote the rouGh draft,
then they copied it over.
What a story, huh?
So now l know where you sleep,
where you are.
Maybe "zumtime"...
Sometime,
l'll come to say
Good moon.
Hi, ChampaGne!
Hello, does the lady desire tea
with light, delicate,
whole Grain cookies?
Am l in the hospital?
Today there's a deliGhtful breeze.
- No, spaGhetti with clam sauce!
- Clam sauce?
l see.
- ChampaGne?
- Yes!
l'd really rather have
pasta and beans with mixed pasta,
l'll make some next time.
Mixed pasta?
Pasta and beans
with mixed pasta...
- Any news from Letizia?
- She asked about you three times.
And she fired the librarian
for not finding "Indifferently".
- Next move?
- You have to disappear.
One who has things
at her beck and call
can only love one who runs,
and sufferinG will do her Good.
- And you?
- What?
Jessica!
- l adore Miss Quagliarulo.
- l knew it!
Some brotherly advice:
what can you do in this outfit?
- You look like a twit.
- What?
- An oaf.
- Thank you.
l'd like to ask you:
when's the last time
you made love?
ln 1984.
- You're in a bad way!
- You think?
- Twenty-nine very long years.
- Of cobwebs!
What did you do to me?
That's called anti-aging, now the
moustache Goes and you're perfect!
Why?
Cry!
- Cry!
- But it's just a dead canary!
ln Naples,
even a canary is family.
lt's a relative.
He shouldn't have done it!
He looks like he's sleeping,
he was sweet as pie!
- Give me a hankie.
- Here.
- Good, tear your heart out!
- The canary died!
Keep it.
- Guys!
- Save me from this nightmare.
Now they'll teach you
to say hello.
Come on!
Let's repeat:
Bro, lil' bro, big bro, my bro,
my pal, my best pal!
Go!
Bro, lil' bro, big bro, my bro,
my pal, my best pal,
cousin of my pal's pal...
Okay?
Not bad.
Did you study the insults?
lnsult number four.
You're a dimwit!
And now I'll bite my tonGue!
- Too much?
- No, Good.
Just in case,
if you want an explanation,
you need a special attitude
when you don't understand
very well, do this.
What's this stuff, bro?
What is it?
Bro, yo, yo...
- lt might come in handy.
- Good.
Love phrases? lf you like
a woman, what do you say?
You're the woman who has Generated
the most emotion...
That's what l know!
You Gotta say, like... my love!
- D'emblée?
- D'emblée, flambé... as you like.
My love!
- You okay?
- Sort of...
"My lllove" with three Ls.
- Good!
- Promoted?
ConsiderinG that
the last time he made love,
Tutankhamun was 18,
he's promoted.
GOOD MOON
My love!
Champagne, is that you?
How about some macaroni omelet?
l shouldn't, I'm on a diet.
Maybe a tad... it's with bacon?
No, sausaGe with "friars".
- Whose friars?
- Friarielli.
Champagne, you're temptinG me.
Who is it, lil' bro,
biG bro or my bro?
- Chamberlain!
- Sire!
What's happeninG to Letizia?
She's actinG strange,
always so pensive,
tell me what's wronG with her.
l wouldn't know, perhaps
problems with her charity?
l have a feeling,
and l'm not often wronG,
she's fallinG in love
with Gherets.
Majesty, your instinct
is incredible, l'll check.
After that,
l have Minister Chun Lai
who must be escorted
to the service door.
- Come immediately!
- CominG.
Pardon, I have
a diplomatic mission.
See ya!
Come on, you can do everything
with spread elbows!
Days of study out the window,
you got her laughinG
and then you left.
l couldn't keep the king waitinG.
Okay, wait another 20 years!
When will you think of yourself?
Put your hands in your pockets,
elbows wide!
- Let's have some.
- l'll get the cutlery.
Cutlery?
We'll eat it like this.
- Life is now: now or never aGain.
- Who gives a damn!
How are you eatinG?
That's not the way.
When you eat watermelon,
you gotta Get drippy,
but without gettin' stained.
You Gotta eat at 90.
- What?
- At 90 deGrees.
Bend over a little,
stretch your arms out.
You can even move
and eat like this.
This way you Get drippy,
but not stained.
The Greatest melon eaters
have scoliosis.
Besides, Jessica will never
love a guy who can't eat at 90.
- You're sure?
- Yeah!
And then, some advice,
keep your pinky finger up.
lf you eat a sandwich
with sausaGe and broccoli,
keep your pinky up,
so you can use it to pick
the broccoli from your teeth.
- lncredible!
- Sure, the old ways.
Why are you helping me?
l like to see people happy,
especially if they're
in a bad way like you.
l'm sorry for what
l thouGht about you,
you're better than
so many living at the castle.
What's all these feelings?
You're not poor like me?
My father was a laborer,
my mother's unknown, don't ask
for details, l didn't find out.
l knew we had something
in common!
l'd like to help you
for what l can.
- Are you jealous?
- No.
- We all need our own space.
- You'll be a cuckold!
Women like a little jealousy,
your woman has to be untouchable,
not to be looked at.
She's has to be a haG?
l'll explain,
all at once is hard.
Listen, these thing l said,
never tell them to anyone.
A secret.
Like we were friends?
Madame...
lnsult number 7...
You're more dimwitted
than your ma and your pa
put toGether!
And now I'll bite my tonGue!
What are you saying?
l'm nervous, it's our first date.
Wait.
What are you lookinG at? Anyone
ever tell you you're an idiot?
lf they do, call me
and we'll beat him up together.
lce cream at 90?
Prevert,
with his lyric "lonGering" says...
Damn you, hell!
We say: damn you to hell!
You're good!
The word is "linGering".
Anyway, the insult goes like this:
damn you to hell.
lt's a little bland as an insult,
it's not: l'll now bite
my tongue, bro, yo, yo...
You can Give it more substance
and it becomes...
Quiet dude, or I can't say it.
l'm listening.
You can also say:
damn you to hell and back.
- Never say "die"!
- Never.
You can add the family:
damn you and yours
to hell and back
to those who don't raise
their hands.
You don't need
a translator anymore.
Ruotolo, you're fired!
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Letizia has a crush,
but, if l were you...
l'd write somethinG romantic,
a finishinG touch.
Your own words,
you don't need all these books.
l have something for you...
- You're distractinG me.
- What a pain!
This is for Jessica, study it,
even toniGht.
lt's a musical, listen to it.
l'm crazy about Miss Quagliarulo.
Crazy, crazy...
A thousand times crazy...
Raindrops keep fallinG on my head,
it was serene
until two minutes ago,
then, who knows how,
the sky started feelinG like me
and l feel...
Raindrops on my neck
and on my hands,
tiny shivers makinG me feel,
l don't know how,
the sensation that
l'm naked among people
who don't notice,
they're cryinG.
And in you
there's a storm,
making you feel bad,
but you're free
and as you see,
you're still standing.
Someone will dry me off.
As soon as you're down,
don't move a muscle.
Good moon.
Where did you go?
l said:
l'll drop in on Letizia and...
l did.
You live here,
but l never see you.
lt's not that...
you've met some pretty Countess?
l don't like them,
they're fake, artificial...
sugarcoated.
l like women who...
touch rose petals
with their fingers, who smile,
who put their hand
to their throats.
And who...
We have to talk.
When a woman says that,
l get worried.
- You're marrying Gherets?
- No, that's not it.
Would you like to eat?
Help me out?
l'll make an omelet.
You...
Beat the eggs.
l'll cut the zucchini.
Or you can cut the zucchini
and l'll beat the egGs?
No, l'll beat the eGgs.
Maybe you'd better
break them open.
- Think so?
- l'd say...
Why don't we...
now that you're here, let's toast.
Alright.
Me too, l discovered late
you need eGgs to make an omelet.
Usually, after a toast
there's a kiss.
Why should we?
There's no photoGrapher.
What do you mean?
Every time we've kissed,
there's always a photographer.
l know you need me for charity,
because you have to become famous.
l'm sorry.
l'm ashamed, I was wronG, l know.
l was about to say it.
When? lt's been two months.
l don't want
to be made fun of anymore.
Yes, but...
now I could fall in love with you.
Now l could...
Stop this!
Why be like this?
- Because we're different.
- No, we aren't!
You've learned to be at court!
l learned your ways,
but you haven't learned mine.
lf l asked you to live my life,
how would you take it?
Like that, don't say a word,
l understand everything.
We're different.
What an ugly word "different",
it means not to love,
it's love that makes us equals,
right?
What a stranGe fate you all have,
you call yourselves reGal
yet you're so far from reality.
Antonio found out.
l know.
We failed. l wanted to chanGe him,
but he chanGed me.
Wait.
This is from Antonio.
Love is that instant
that can't wait even a second,
that chases the minutes,
even sixty times
until the time comes to see you.
Love is that silver knot
that ties eyes to heart,
insolubly.
Everything the heart looks at,
is seen throuGh the eyes
and everythinG the eyes see,
is looked at by the heart.
And now that l know
all these thinGs,
protect me, defend me,
l want to trust you
one more time,
my love.
Bro!
See who's there?
The prince!
- Oh, shut up!
- You shut up!
lt's really beautiful.
l'm glad you came to the opening,
but l gotta go now.
l decided to chanGe my life,
since we got back from the castle,
new life, diet...
The dietician said 100 grams
of bread at most, that's 150.
C'mon, just 50 Grams more!
Either you're
on a diet or you aren't.
Now it's 100 Grams.
You know what l can do
to lose weiGht?
Bring a nice Gym into the house.
Ciro, to lose weight,
don't brinG in a gym,
take out the kitchen.
- Can we take a nice photo of us?
- Go ahead!
- What?
- l told you, he's not the prince.
- Want one of me?
- You won't fit in here!
You never do what I say!
Never, never...
Remember me?
l'm the coffee machine technician,
l came here last month.
l was passing by and said:
l'll taste the coffee,
but won't take a cent.
Technician?
The technician's right in there.
l have an exclusive in this area.
Who cares?
The technician's already here.
ColleaGue...
Where should l take you?
But I...
also have a license
to taste chocolates.
To taste the best chocolate
in Naples, come with me.
This mortgaGe is perfect
for your two-room apartment.
Fine, thank you,
you've been very clear.
May I offer a chocolate?
The chocolatier is excellent.
Thank you.
l don't believe
you want to live like me.
Months learning to mooch
and you still don't believe me?
No.
l want to spend all my days
with you, all of them,
every moment,
l want to share
my breath with you.
l want to love you forever too,
but the hard thinG is to love
every day, in simplicity.
l want us to love
each other forever,
l want us to argue
over the toothpaste,
or because l don't shop well.
l want you to see bacteria
everywhere when you clean
the house,
in the bathroom, the kitchen,
and before l come in,
the bacteria looks at me and says:
that Guy's Gonna catch hell!
l want to love you forever,
l even want you to vacuum
during the Naples Games...
But only the Championship ones!
l want...
l want you off my boat,
if not l'll be GettinG it
from my wife.
Who are these people?
- Excuse me, who are you?
- The witnesses.
For the bride or groom?
For the accident, we helped them
Get the money for their wedding.
Let me say hello to the bride.
A toast!
A toast to the bride, hurrah!
The sfogliatelle,
sugar-coated almonds...
Aren't you the princess?
Yes, but don't tell a soul.
Sure!
Ciro, we won't tell a soul.
l'm a dimwit, think l'd say:
the princess is here!
Stop, wait.
Antonio, a photo!
Stop riGht there!
Excuse me, but who are you?
We're the sinGers' manaGers.
They're coming.
They took me for a hat rack!
Ladies and Gentlemen!
A great honor,
the princess made an omelet
with her own hands.
The sinGers are here.
- What?
- The singers.
So, ladies and gentlemen,
last but not least, the singers!
You are distant from my heart...
My thouGht flies to you...
l want for nothing,
hope for nothing,
but to keep you forever
by my side.
Feel sure of this love...
Just as l am sure of you.
Oh my life, oh life of mine,
heart of this heart of mine,
you were my first love,
and will always be
my first and last love.
So we'll be living in Naples?
Yes, how can the people love you
if you don't live amonG them?
But sometimes we'll visit
your father at the castle,
like for the holidays: Christmas,
New Year's, Easter, Carnival.
lnstead of cominG here
to the beach in July and AuGust,
we'll Go to the pool
at the castle,
even if the best months
are June and September.
So, we'll move into my place?
l want the kids
to Grow up in Naples.
But we can Go from time to time.
And mooch off dad.
My love...
GOOD MOON