BASED ON HISTORICAL EVENTS
IMAGE OF VICTORY
There are moments when you are trying to
to find meaning in your life.
You wonder if you have made good use of
the time God has given you on earth.
You're looking for someone to compare yourself to.
With someone who has really lived.
Sometimes you are surprised by the one,
who comes to mind.
She is the one who came to mind.
Amazing.
Of all the people,
I have met in my life,
It's her I don't know how to forget.
I know it doesn't make sense. Because he is the enemy.
But I can't erase
from my memory this image.
What made her smile?
Did she know it was about to happen?
Did she understand what I
have been searching for all my life?
After 30 years of bloody fighting, finally
a peace agreement will be signed
Between two countries:
Egypt and Israel.
The Egyptian president has taken the bold step of...
You dirty dog!
For years, we fought against Israel,
to help our Palestinian brothers.
This agreement will not change anything.
- Sadat is a traitor, and I am a coward.
- Hassanin, what is going on?
Are you still concerned?
Dinner is ready.
If there was no reason for war,
and they sign a peace treaty from such....
It was for years that I misled
people who read my articles.
I told them that war is just.
And they fought and died.
If their deaths were unnecessary,
Who is to blame for this?
Who's who!
Me!
Now I should tell them,
That our president is a traitor.
If only I wasn't such a
coward, if I wasn't so afraid....
You wrote about what you believed in.
About the king and the homeland.
You are the best Egyptian journalist.
An oak tree breaks during a storm,
And the bamboo will bend,
And then it will straighten out again.
Let's eat.
Bent bamboo. Is that what I have become?
Pathetic.
I think back to her,
To what she dared to do.
What does this say about me?
What should I do?
When I was 24 years old,
I wasn't afraid of anything.
On the last night of 1947.
HAPPY NEW YEAR 1948!
But the crowd. Come on, it's in the cinema hall.
He ordered to bring you in.
What's the job? Why the mysteries?
You will soon find out.
You like movies, don't you?
Yes, but what are the secrets?
The manufacturer will explain to you.
EGYPTIAN NEWS REVIEW
As every year, there was a
charity banquet in Cairo.
The people's beloved King Faruk
He visited backstage with the dancers,
Who entertained the distinguished guests.
Turn it off. What are you doing?
Showing the king,
As he flirts with the dancers?
Is the queen supposed to watch this?
The king cares about charity,
not the dancers.
Do you hear?
Sorry.
Do you want them to shut us down? Start thinking.
Sorry. You wanted to
to see my friend. It's urgent.
Is he the one who writes for newspapers?
Yes, but his passion is cinema.
Is he brave?
What's your name?
Hassanin.
Documents.
The Zionists are savage beasts.
They deserve retaliation.
I know Jews, they have unbridled ambition.
They consider it the land of their ancestors.
They came to Palestine from many directions.
From Europe, South America, Asia.
They are like a pestilence bearing down on us.
How will they get rid of us?
Arabs have lived in these lands for centuries.
Foreigners are colonizing our holy
Land by getting rid of our brothers.
Take a look.
From the quiet village of Hamama,
Along the road between Gaza and Tel Aviv.
These dog sons built the Nitzanim colony.
In Nitzani,
as I later learned, lived
a girl with a mysterious smile.
I had never heard of this place.
That evening I was fascinated by the passion of the
As well as the ideological fever
of young volunteers.
It showed battlefield situations,
Which were later made into films.
At first, the thought of war
was terrifying,
But for me it was an opportunity.
I was able to indulge my passion - cinema.
Tolstoy wrote,
That love and fear are inseparable.
He must not be allowed to
run in front of the trucks.
You are supposed to behave
Like soldiers, not like hooligans!
Dani! We are racing!
We'll see who gets the gifts first.
I don't know which
Is more childish.
There should be a child.
A child mother is dangerous.
- Who missed more?
- Me!
- Which ladies want to go back to the box?
- Who do you call a maiden?
Elyakim? Did you get the book
About Holstein cows?
Have a weapon with you.
We are supposed to protect these people.
Romek!
Why did they send us
These area men straight from prison?
- Will we file a complaint?
- We won't.
Better such than none at all.
Naomi, bring mattresses for the soldiers.
Listen up if you want a place to sleep!
Take a bag
And fill it with hay.
You will make a mattress.
Tie at the end,
so the hay doesn't come out.
Keep your belongings under your underwear.
I would love to put something under her underwear.
- Have you ever been with a redhead?
- It glows in the dark.
- Her hair or the lice?
- Sorry.
I used to play the violin,
I have perfect hearing. Like a dog.
- He also barks like a dog.
- I said enough!
The sea is about a kilometer away.
Do you want to take a bath in winter, crazy?
No, the coast is 50 kilometers to Tel Aviv.
- We were already in jail for desertion.
- Wasn't it worth it?
The commander can
Contact the battalion?
- Sure.
- Why didn't they give you a radio?
It wasn't. We can handle it.
- With whom?
- With the battalion commander.
Bright. I have a carburetor waiting for me
from the tractor. I'm going.
Right.
Don't stand, sit down.
Iron Gate, this is Sparrow, can you hear me?
Your son?
Nice.
He has grown up and is independent.
Do you like?
What?
Marlene Dietrich.
I rarely go to the movies.
- Do you listen to records on the turntable?
- In the dining room.
I can't feel my legs.
It hurts a lot! I can't stand it.
Stay there, we will distract them.
Fire!
To attack!
- At our place peace and quiet!
- Here too!
Habani, notified,
That the wounded must be evacuated.
The hospital is on the first floor.
Tie the body to a tree,
To deter other killers?
It's not a killer,
is still a child.
Some are skilled in the use of weapons,
But we still don't have enough people,
to keep guard and work in the field.
This is just the beginning.
Today we are attacked by farmers,
tomorrow it could be worse.
You need to bring food to the guards.
Who will take care of it?
Me.
Habani, come with me.
What about the supply of weapons?
It is still missing.
Eight cows equals 42 gallons
of milk per day? 34 for sale.
To make money,
you must have a hundred gallons a day.
It is impossible to keep children
in such a dangerous place.
Without children, there is no life.
Doctor!
Lives.
Surprised I didn't kill him?
Even a blind hen will get
a seed sometimes.
Bravo, doctor! Great job!
Ziggy?
Play as in Berlin.
Play for them.
- I don't want to disturb them.
- In what?
You said you miss the piano.
Play it. But modern.
Ziggy? More modern.
Decadent music here?
Sorry, this is not a nightclub.
Sorry, but music is music.
We will not ban it.
I'm not banning, but it's not our style.
- It's boring.
- But also important.
Excuse me, shall we dance?
Are we dancing?
I am a gentleman.
Kilometer, will you allow?
I want to dance a little.
Your name is Kilometer? Why?
It weighs a kilogram and measures a meter.
Ben Gigi, don't you dance?
Sgt. Ben Gigi.
We were neighbors, but here I am
Sgt. Ben Gigi or Sir.
Is that clear?
Get back to work.
- Shall we dance?
- I don't dance with animals.
With animals?
Yes, are you Jamus?
In Arabic, it means ox.
That is, you are an animal.
- It's time.
- For what?
Sleep.
- Ask Hadassa to finish.
- Don't.
- He dances with this soldier.
- And what?
Always looking for trouble. Always.
Radio Alexandria here.
Cigarette?
- Thank you, Mr. Hassanin.
- Just Hassanin, without you.
Have you seen Capra's "Why We Fight" videos?
I work all day. I support my family.
Capra will be our inspiration.
We will show simple people,
Who are fighting a just war.
We will shoot the news,
Which doesn't mean,
That it can't also be art.
We will show the human fate.
Are you okay?
Dreams...
We drove at night,
So that no one could see us.
We were to split up
and attack from cover.
Good morning.
Forgive me for waking you up.
I'm going to the city, coming back tomorrow.
Should I bring you something?
Enjoy your trip.
Mira...
Give me a break.
I want you to hug me.
As it used to be.
Stop. You know we don't... anymore.
Should I pretend?
To be insincere?
Sorry.
I'll tell you if I feel something again.
- I don't know what to do.
- Me too.
You told me not to do anything.
That I would behave,
As if nothing had changed, but....
What happened?
What's the problem?
I don't blame you,
But what has changed?
I don't know.
You know that you are important to me.
It doesn't matter who attacks you.
Size doesn't matter.
Habani, enough jokes.
Did you understand? Do you need me to show again?
I'm easy to flip because I don't defend myself.
Okay, hit me up.
- For real?
- Yes.
Use his power against him.
Again, but more slowly.
Do you have someone in mind?
- I think no.
- Don't think too much.
- Easy for you to say.
- Why?
Because you are Mira.
Which is to say?
Stop.
Romek, wait! You have to practice.
We'll do just that...
Jamus, this is not a brothel!
As the leader here you give the orders
- And assign tasks?
- This is not the military, there are no orders.
At the meetings we jointly
we make decisions.
Who decides on security issues?
What is it, general?
About Mira.
I know the radio belongs to the kibbutz,
But we need it for operations.
- What kind?
- Such as in this Arab village.
You need a radio,
But not girls, correct?
I wish you the best of luck.
I don't understand.
You'll understand.
Mira is different, unique.
I still don't get it.
You will see.
It's raining terribly.
I knocked, no one answered, so I'm waiting.
Elyakim has left,
and Dani is sleeping in the nursery.
Not with you and your husband?
These are the rules on the kibbutz. Will you come in?
- I don't want to disturb you.
- Take it easy.
Coffee?
Don't.
I plan to check
the area of the village opposite.
There are no soldiers there, so there should not
be problems, but a radio will come in handy.
Right. I like people with foresight.
I need your radio.
Just in case.
Bright.
Great.
- Will you give them to me?
- I will go with you.
- Mira.
- No.
- If necessary, I will confiscate them.
- You can't.
It is the property of the kibbutz.
You have to bear with me.
Is it that difficult?
At night we reached the village of Hamama.
Our commander Halif began to plan the attack.
He was the only real soldier
among the volunteers.
An interesting character. Educated
and overzealous at the same time.
The people of the village
were glad to see us.
They were counting on us to help them return
to the lands they had been farming.
I figured I would find interesting
human dramas to film.
You stick the bayonet in and pull it out.
Who ever killed a ram?
It's the same thing, but no wool.
Salman, your turn.
Do you want to tickle him or kill him?
If you want to play,
I will bring you dogs.
I joked.
Who's next?
Come.
Youssef, take a look at him,
he is photogenic.
Make an effort. Stand up as you should!
Stronger. Bring it on!
Which is to say?
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- Now?
Right.
We were to tell
about the liberation of Palestinian lands.
But each story consists of
of side stories.
Already in the first week we noticed,
That a
a beautiful tale of love.
This road is located
On the outskirts of the town.
Near the Isdud Bridge is a military camp.
From there, they send supplies to Nitzanim.
And what they produce there,
is shipped to Tel Aviv.
We divine emissaries,
We will make life difficult for them soon.
Sorry, but it stinks
More than dirty diapers.
File a complaint against them. They will be peeled off.
They are little boys,
don't pay attention to them.
It's a nightmare.
After cleaning the toilets recently, I couldn't
get rid of the stench from my hair
- And I went to take a bath.
- Great idea.
Why don't we go to the beach after work?
We'll take a swim.
I do not understand why they do not send
us mines. We don't have enough of them.
In the afternoon we are going to the beach,
So if you need a radio,
get them.
Upon my return, I want to get them back.
- Do you have someone trained?
- Yes.
Communicate to him that it is delicate.
One must be careful.
I'll see if they dig. Whether they dig deep enough.
What?
No matter.
Anything else?
You did not answer,
Whether you will return the radio in time.
You are so difficult.
You do.
What will it be like?
Do you often go to the beach these days?
Yes, why?
I will send people with you, just in case.
Will our children be taught Spanish?
Our culture?
We will be able to talk to them
in case of problems,
And our husbands won't understand us.
No problems,
we will have wonderful husbands.
Isn't the water cold this time of year?
Cold water stimulates circulation.
What is this strange word?
It's all about blood circulation.
Again, he provokes.
Any problem?
God help.
Won't you take a bath?
- We didn't take bathing suits.
- What do you guys need them for? Do you have socks?
Roll them up and place them in the appropriate
place, and then tie with a rubber band.
Are you kidding?
No. Whatever you want, the water is great.
Mira is crazy.
Why? It's funny.
Do you want to watch them naked? That's disgusting.
Sock? What do you think?
Speechless.
- Don't you take a bath?
- I don't give a damn.
Mira, wait!
Are you ashamed of your little bird?
- Stupid.
- Don't be ashamed.
You can use children's socks.
Should I leave my gun here?
- Have you started following orders?
- That's not the point.
That is, you have a little one.
- This is your chance, my friend.
- Get unstuck.
Dive in, the water is not cold.
You are idiots.
Complete morons.
For water.
Little Brain.
The little prick!
- Come on!
- Don't.
Come on!
Hello ladies.
Is the water too cold?
For you, too?
Stop it, crazy person!
Enough! Calm down! Where are you going?
Ada, help me, we will water it.
I thought you had better taste.
Stop, it's just a game.
A normal boy doesn't pick up like that.
Are you having a good time?
Yes.
For the first time since I've been in the army.
It's paradise.
Paradise.
It would have been, had we not been threatened with death.
As the poet said?
He who fears death, fears life.
Cheap Romanticism.
Get down! Don't you understand?
It's not a movie, it's really happening.
Fire!
Come on out!
Hurry! Hurry up!
Elyakim, where did the shots come from?
Kilometer, hurry up! Quickly!
I'm coming, cover me!
Jamil, hit him!
- It's a trap!
- I know what to do.
What do you do?
Why do you make them thieves?
They don't steal, they are heroes.
I know, but heroes have to eat too.
Carrying food makes them human.
A waste of time. Salman, hurry up.
We're moving, fast.
Ben Gigi to the right, Kilometer to the left.
Mosco!
Better not.
How are we supposed to work,
When they keep shooting at us?
Who is supposed to stop them?
Twelve soldiers? Is this a joke?
Yes, but a poor one. Are we idealists?
Sure.
You have to protect us.
We have children.
You are all important to us.
We placed mines on both sides.
I say. Wait, I say.
I will say what everyone knows,
But are afraid to say.
We know what commanders Avidan and Kovner are.
The situation is obvious.
A political officer, that is, a real chief...
Who is a political officer?
They have such in the Russian army.
This is someone who has more power
authority than the commanders.
He works for the government and knows its plans.
- They don't care about us one bit.
- I think it's not about politics.
It's nice that you think so,
But this is about our children.
You don't have to speak in such a tone.
I say as I wish.
It's about the lives of our children, not cows.
- Good evening.
- Hi.
Are you all right?
They are in the room, debating.
What about the cows?
How so?
Someone has to replace Mosco.
You are alone, and we have a lot of heifers.
You need a woman.
One that has experience with children.
Stop, you just
man died, have you forgotten?
Tomorrow you will not have
someone to help with the milking.
You need someone to help you.
It's Kovner.
Evening.
We asked for weapons and what?
We didn't get one.
We asked for soldiers and what?
We got one measly platoon.
- Deserters and thieves.
- Insult me, not my soldiers.
These traps are just the beginning.
First they were farmers, now they are
trained volunteers with weapons.
What are you going to do about it?
Tomorrow, the day after tomorrow,
or maybe next week,
If weather permits, meals will arrive.
And by then they will have killed us?
What will that take care of?
Is the solution revenge?
Understand, these lands belonged to them....
All the lands belonged
once belonged to someone else.
Also to you.
Such arguments will not change anything.
We paid a lot of money
To the owner of the land.
Farmers should be angry
At him, not at you.
When we were burned in the crematoria,
some of you know very well,
what I am talking about,
we understood, with all due respect
For culture and civilization,
That humans are also animals.
And animals respond to "an eye for an eye."
Elyakim.
You will return with us to Be'er Tuvia by truck.
We are reloading what is left there.
But will go with you
An armed armored car.
From now on, it will always be like this.
- The matter is settled.
- He agrees.
If we give up, we'll be thrown out there,
Where six million Jews lost their lives.
Are you okay?
- Yes.
- Don't be ashamed.
Anyone would be horrified by the sight of a
of a friend being killed.
I am not afraid or ashamed.
Everything is fine.
- Good evening.
- Hi.
Look at him hugging his teddy bear.
Don't wake him up.
I want to hear him mumble.
- He has such a sweet little voice.
- Yes.
Sometimes he says to the bear. It's cute.
- Sweet?
- Yes.
You rarely use the word.
Dear Child.
Forgive me, I forgot the book.
But it's nothing important, I'll leave you alone.
All right, they're waiting for me.
Tell him that I kissed him
And that I will bring him many gifts.
I'll be back in a few days. Bye.
Hadasa, wait.
You do well with your children.
Yerach will now be alone in the barn
with the cows. He won't be able to cope alone.
Why don't you try working there?
If you like it, you'll stay.
Good evening. I'm here to pick up the radio.
- I don't want to upset you...
- But you do.
- Sorry. If there is an evacuation....
- I will not move from here.
- I am responsible for you.
- You are a mother.
- You know a lot.
Just like Elyakim,
Who whined about it before leaving.
We need to figure out something together about the radio.
You went on patrol without him.
You took unnecessary risks.
You hoped the battalion would send you a radio,
but that didn't happen.
Therefore, I will lend you a radio.
Provided,
That you will take me with you. Agreed?
A week has passed,
Then another, then two more,
and we had nothing to film.
Good morning.
Lt. Halif hoped,
That the Jews would start attacking,
That's why he set traps.
But the Jews did not attack.
Why was there nothing to film?
Why were there no traps?
Because the truck was guarded by an armored car.
He accompanied them always.
I watched their colony out of boredom.
She seemed normal.
When you perceive in the enemy
an ordinary person, something shifts in your mind.
Since my boss and producer
Was happy with the trap film,
I decided that I would focus
on the daily lives of our heroes.
And I will show the forming love story.
This is the story of a brave soldier
Salman and Samira, a beautiful village girl.
What's up?
What kind of nonsense is this?
Has he gone completely insane?
- Who cares about these rants?
- He thought it might be interesting.
I don't pay him to think,
just for filming the war.
I want the kind of videos,
that he sent me two weeks ago.
The audience does not want a story about love.
If he doesn't like it, we'll say goodbye.
Is there a post office in the village?
No, but it's not far away, in Khan Yunis.
Send him a telegram.
Let the letter carrier get
on a bicycle, or a donkey
and takes it to the hands of
our director.
I will also write to Colonel Aziz.
I will ask him to send them reinforcements.
Maybe with this we will see some progress
and there will be something to film.
So good. Keep digging until I say stop.
Come on!
Good. Jump.
Kilometer, where are you? Practice.
- This is not a good idea.
- I want to give it a try.
If I don't like it,
I'll be back in a few days.
Good morning.
Welcome.
I am supposed to work here today.
Are you okay?
They were supposed to send me someone,
But I didn't know who.
Bright.
Remember that here work
starts early in the morning.
The cows are full of milk and their udders hurt.
Just like with a baby.
It hurts not you, me.
But I don't have a child.
There are a lot of them in the children's ward.
There is a child here, too.
How cute.
Milking consists of two steps.
The first is.
udder massage.
Massage?
Yes, take a look. Do you see?
To stimulate the milk stream.
The milk flows straight from the...
nipple.
Do you know what it is?
I know what a nipple is.
You need to press it,
to stimulate the flow of milk.
Forgive me, it's certainly unpleasant.
Why. Massaging, stimulating.
Sounds pleasant.
For the cow.
Here, quickly.
Open.
Kilometer, hurry up.
Evening.
Can I ask you something?
What do you want?
We want to go with you,
To film everything up close.
I don't care,
whether you will be filming
From near or far.
Sorry, but there's a big difference.
The story has the same
significance as action.
That's what the cowards in Cairo say.
That's what cowards say.
Cowards don't go after soldiers.
The camera is also a weapon.
Even on the eve of Passover
They don't serve decent food.
No cutlery. Do they have us as animals?
Kilometer, sit next to me.
When the party starts,
you are supposed to load your machine gun.
Remember, when the
shooting, I'll be vomiting.
- I can get you dirty...
- Stop. Grow up.
Garnet and smoke grenade.
Youssef?
Should I take up arms?
Just in case.
With a gun, don't stand behind the cameraman,
because you might kill him.
The poor man has children.
It will be better for him,
If you don't take up arms.
Once the shooting starts,
we can't stop.
If someone gets tired, he will rest
In a hideout, before shooting.
Ladies...
It will be like this...
- Why ladies?
- What.
- Because you are a woman.
- You say it in such a tone....
I didn't mean to offend anyone.
I always say that.
You have to keep watch on the water tower.
Those at the bottom will run with the news.
Good luck.
Weapons at the ready.
Quiet now, we are close.
They are about 40 meters from the fence.
Fire!
It's me, Salman! I got hit, help!
I am injured.
Help! It's me, Salman. Help!
Are we winning?
Shoot accurately, don't waste bullets.
We have a long day ahead of us.
Salman, rest assured, it's just a scratch.
Jamil, take six men
and go after them from the beach.
Do you have a wire cutter?
Hadasa!
- What do we do?
- Follow me.
Iron Gate, here Sparrow.
Phase 2, repeat, Phase 2.
Confirmed, receipt.
They go here. They are close by.
Right away.
Fire!
Habani, hurry up.
I'm in a hurry.
This is where we take shelter before we set off the charge.
Habani, the detonator.
Attention.
Done.
I don't know what happened. We are withdrawing.
It was hard to watch
at these brave volunteers
lying on hospital beds.
Especially since there was a shortage of drugs and morphine.
The saddest were the farmers,
who were expelled from the lands of the Nitzanim region.
They thought they would soon regain
their lives and return home.
Hope disappeared very quickly.
I heard that in the platoon that
had broken through to the village,
was a woman. Just as
courageous as the men.
I myself almost lost
my hero Salman.
Fortunately, his wound was superficial.
There is no drama without a hero.
Lieutenant Halif urged me to
send a telegram to my producer,
In which I will notify him,
That the film was lost during the fighting.
He was afraid they would blame him for the failure.
I told him that it was not his fault,
But I can't send such a telegram.
I have to show the truth.
I won't forget it for you.
You are a traitor.
If it's a weapon, as you said,
then this weapon you are directing against me.
I send what I filmed.
Maybe this will make them understand,
That we need help.
I'm not doing this against you.
Let's go.
Come.
Gentlemen,
If the Jews declare independence today,
We must send our troops immediately.
Our volunteers alone cannot
can handle their army.
It's a difficult situation, the king is worried.
Please forgive the frankness,
But the Egyptians will come out as weaklings
and cowards if they don't help their brothers.
The generals told the king
about what they saw on the video.
Fearing a reaction from the people, the king
ordered that all copies of the film be burned.
He also ordered preparations to invade
against Israel within two months.
I understand you.
The creation of a state surrounded
by enemies is frightening.
In cities far away from each other,
Yad Mordechai, Nitzanim,
Kfar Darom, people talk about....
I have a hard time pronouncing the word.
On evacuation.
What kind of evacuation are they talking about?
If we start it, how will it end?
It will spread
And the whole south will evacuate.
Then panic will sweep the north.
Do you want to evacuate Rehovot,
Rishon LeZion? Tel Aviv?
Where do we go from here?
- Let's hurry up.
- What did they say?
No evacuation, just children.
And the mothers?
- It is their choice. Let's help them.
- Wait.
And the meals?
They can send reserve reinforcements,
if necessary.
They figured that the Egyptians would head
toward the bridge and ignore the villages.
Weapons? Mines?
- Will they be?
- A little.
Anti-tank launcher.
- Did you argue?
- As much as I could.
But not all arguments can be won.
What?
Nothing. Sing.
Are these songs from the past?
You put me to shame.
Me?
Caution.
Pardon.
Because of you I have a mouth full of sand.
No harm done,
you always have a mouth full of pigs.
For now.
General? What do we do?
I command soldiers, not civilians.
We don't want to run away.
They will use this against us.
Are you okay?
They need drivers for convoys
to Jerusalem. They asked me.
Did you agree?
Yes, I will be gone for many weeks.
We need to talk.
Right.
It's difficult for me, and people are talking.
- I don't give a damn.
- And I don't.
Evacuate women and children, will you leave?
- What's the difference?
- I won't leave you here alone.
Alone? What do you mean?
The kibbutz is full of people.
I was talking about myself. What should I do? I love you.
I can't stand this separation.
It hurts, I don't understand it.
Elyakim, please.
I am also suffering.
Sorry.
Do you have something against pajamas?
You will consume all the hot water.
Now it's our turn.
That's not fair.
Get out, you've been sitting there for half an hour.
It takes so much to wash away the sand,
With which you sprinkled me.
Jamus is big, he needs time.
Bastards!
What do you do?
What's that? Someone is shooting?
Let's go!
Ada, it's funny.You haven't laughed in a long time.
It was worth it. You're finally smiling.
Idiot.
In a moment Ben Gurion
will declare Israel's independence.
We are not as educated as you,
Just primitive, like the Arabs.
People who are afraid to fight,
do not deserve independence.
I am not afraid, I am against the war.
What about the agreement?
With the Arabs? Ask Zigi how they
they got along in the concentration camp.
Did they hold political debates there?
- Have you ever talked to an Arab?
- I wish I had.
- Ada, took seats for us.
- For you and Mira.
He always takes a seat for her.
Now he has taken two on purpose.
He wants to separate us.
Stop, we are supposed to play.
You spend all day with him
At work, in the evening you have to too?
- I say silly things, enough of that.
- Ada...
Hasn't it started yet?
- Elyakim left?
- Yes.
Then who did you dress up for?
Take care of your love affairs, not mine.
Romance? Since when have you been romantic?
It all depends on the situation.
Quiet. This is important.
My only souvenir from home.
Family.
I wish they were here today.
And they listened to it.
We are listening to a speech by
Ben Gurion, the leader of Israel.
A country that is not recognized by
any of its neighbors.
He claims that Israel is being created
On the principles of historical justice.
But where is this justice
For the Palestinians?
What are you filming? Our humiliation?
To let everyone see our downfall?
Get out.
I don't want to humiliate anyone.
It hurts me, too. I tell the story.
Should I shoot you?
Return to Cairo.
To your beautiful life.
To beautiful words,
Which do not require action.
- I'm not hurting anyone.
- It's over.
I respect you.
But my job is to document
what's going on. Shoot.
Turn off the camera!
Abraham?
They are having a good time.
I knew you were here.
- I brought you something to eat.
- Thank you.
Are you worried?
Wondering.
What?
I wrote about you to my mother.
That there is someone... That's all.
Do you always tell her everything?
She also me. She used to have a lover.
She used to take us to the beach,
to listen to music.
We ate ice cream, it was nice.
Didn't you mind,
That she was with her lover?
I love it. I know,
That she is doing what makes her happy.
I can't believe you were okay with that.
Hurry up. I don't want,
them to see us together.
I wonder if he is with her.
Poor Elyakim.
- He is an adult. He knows what he's doing.
- They have a child.
They should be careful. So should we.
I would like to have a child. Seriously.
- Mom said...
- Look.
Egyptians dropped bombs
on the Tel Aviv bus station.
42 killed, more than a hundred injured,
many in critical condition.
Yad Mordechai.
They bomb them. They destroy everything.
Your turn.
Mr. Hassanin!
What's going on? Say.
The lieutenant asked that you
come quickly. With Youssef.
Will we be filming?
- What?
- I ask, what are we going to film?
What happened?
God is great.
I can see by your smile,
That you finally got rid of me.
Am I right?
Where are you sending us?
You are not going anywhere.
Where's the videographer?
It will come soon.
- You are being terribly dramatic.
- After all, you were looking for drama.
Everyone loves him.
You can film.
What?
Me.
Film.
Already?
Yad Mordechai is no more.
The Jews fled like rats.
Many were killed.
Do you know what this means?
With God's help
This is the beginning of the end of their colony.
Everyone is worried and waiting for help.
I understand, but at the moment
there is nothing we can do.
I organized the evacuation of women,
children and the sick.
Help will come during the attack.
We expected it
and we will do the right thing.
From now on, we talk in code.
Their army has great intelligence,
we have to be careful. Come up with something.
Cipher.
Do you know any code?
Cipher? Yes.
Which one?
- Pig Latin.
- What.
Haven't you played with it?
Dad misses you very much,
you too, right?
Yes.
You will go to him soon.
He is preparing many surprises for you.
- Let's talk.
- Have you packed your bags?
Not much of that.
You have to mix it well, because they won't fall asleep.
They will start crying and we can't cope.
They need to be broken up.
How? You break everything down.
Stop it, enough of the facades.
The situation is unbearable.
Exactly. Enough of these surprises.
We are not soldiers, you come with me.
You said we would always be together.
This is our only weapon.
You are my only family.
A promise is a promise.
It must be kept.
Sleep, baby.
Yerach take you on a trip.
Dad is waiting with surprises.
- With chocolate.
- Yes.
Remember me.
Hold it tight.
- Are you sure about that?
- Yes.
- I just...
- I know what I'm doing.
Give him a letter. If something happens to me...
How can you say that? Do you think you...
I don't think anything.
Give Elyakim a hug from me.
Enough, please.
See you in the morning.
Are you okay?
You're doing the right thing, we can't help you here.
Moving on.
Forgive me.
Hadasa!
Sleep, Dani. Sleep, little one.
Everything will be fine.
What's up?
Sorry, I got scared.
Calm. What are you doing here?
I can't get to sleep.
I came to buy sleeping pills for children.
I figured they would help me.
On the ground!
- What are those explosions?
- They can be heard from the side of the bridge.
We need to deliver the children quickly
and return to Nitzanim before dawn.
Help?
Come to me.
Sleep, baby.
Thank you.
- I just want to say that...
- I know.
If something happens to Hadas,
it will be because of you.
You will have her blood on your hands.
Do you understand?
Iron Gate, Sparrow here. Sound off.
Iron Gate here, say.
Did the package reach you safely?
I want to know if the package has arrived.
Sparrow,
The package has not arrived yet.
I will send someone to the gate,
To wait for the package.
What did she say?
They haven't arrived yet.
It's taking too long.
They should already be in place.
If something happens to them...
To the children, Ada...
Do you think something happened to them?
Why didn't they arrive?
I don't know.
It was a mistake.
Why?
I knew it was dangerous here.
I decided that when it gets hot,
I would send Dani away.
I am a bad person.
I didn't see it coming.
Me too.
I am not brave.
Ada is not as strong either,
as she appears to be.
Our moms are sisters.
Her father lost all his property
and walked away.
Then her mother started drinking.
Until she died.
Ada has only me.
She wouldn't have come here if it weren't for me.
It doesn't fit in this place.
Sparrow, Iron Gate here.
Iron Gate, here Sparrow.
The shipment arrived on time.
The birds will soon fly home.
Thank you. I am checking out.
Mira, come on!
What's going on?
Tanks, trucks, guns, armored vehicles.
They don't shoot at us.
Identify the tanks. How many are there?
What kind of armaments are they? What kind of guns?
I don't know, you can't see.
Unknown. Forgiveness.
That's a lot of tanks.
Our military
would easily destroy Nitzanim,
But the commander was not
interested in the villages.
He wanted to reach
Tel Aviv.
The commander of the artillery battery Brigadier
Naguib sat with us in the village.
He was to oversee logistics
and guard all equipment.
Me and Youssef joined the army,
To film the victory,
which the general promised the king.
But victory was not forthcoming.
The attack failed because the general
did not send scouts.
And he didn't know that the Jews had blown up the
the bridge leading to Tel Aviv.
Many were killed, some were taken
Jewish captivity.
It was a nightmare.
This was not the kind of film the king expected.
We can get started.
It was clear that we would not win this war.
And that our army must return home.
And at home, when the soldiers start
talk, it will be the end for the king.
Do you hear?
Is it already? It has arrived.
On time.
Quick! Are you all set?
Whose turn is it? Kilometer?
No. I did it last time.
I think it's Jamus' turn.
Rabbit racing?
- Habani, go.
- Me?
Right.
I'll go.
- No way.
- It's not your turn.
But I want to.
Do you want to die?
Why?
I miss the piano.
10,
9,
8,
7,
6...
Frightening.
Fire!
Get down!
Zigi, quickly!
Get moving!
Faster!
Very sorry, can't we hit
the building and get it over with?
It would have come out disorderly and without dignity.
The war is over.
Darn it! Beef stew again.
- Naomi, will you paste something in to kill the flavor?
- Please.
- What?
- You should add - please.
Not a bad time for a lesson in manners.
Okay, here you go.
Ziggi?
You can play something more...
joyful?
And what will you forgive me for?
Sorry about that one.
What is your real name?
Haim.
At last, our army was coming home.
But the king gave a clear order:
we need victory before returning.
The general appointed Naguib as commander.
Once again, I found myself in...
Nitzanim.
Iron Gate, this is Sparrow. Can you hear me?
- What's going on?
- Trying.
Iron Gate, this is Sparrow. Can you hear me?
Iron Gate? The radio is
in the sand, looking for an SOS signal.
- What are you doing?
- I hear something.
- Is the radio working?
- Trying.
- I can't film.
- And I live like that.
Did they get the SOS signal?
I don't know.
I think I got the SOS signal.
He was distorted.
They sent an SOS, we need to send them support.
Wait. Are you sure you heard the SOS?
I think it is.
Yes or no? This is important. Keep trying.
We promised them support. They are counting on us.
This is war. You don't do what,
what the enemy expects.
Even if it means sacrificing someone.
Besides, it's too early to talk
About the sacrifice, because we don't know the situation.
Try to contact them.
We are 500 meters from the main gate.
We go to the back entrance.
Where is our support?
Will it be here soon?
Take out the cannon, Abraham will move it.
- Now?
- Yes.
Remember the plan? We point the gun inward.
You shoot only when necessary.
Not yet.
Aim at the turret,
so they can see where we're shooting from.
Fire!
300 meters from the rear entrance.
We are at the main gate.
We need to neutralize the bazooka.
Forward!
Reverse the cannon!
Habani!
Done.
None of this. We're retreating, fast!
Back off!
Habani...
Habani, what about you?
Zigi?
Don't be afraid. Take it easy.
Enter carefully.
Mira, come on.
Habani, let's go.
Check if there are wounded in the trenches.
Line up in three columns.
Yerach, we need to get out of here.
Naomi, it's me Haim.
Hush, it's me.
Quiet.
- Did you film it?
- Yes, I need a new tape.
Ben Gigi...
Salman, look to the right.
Salman, don't give up.
Stay with me. Look at me.
When they start shooting, run away.
Where are the rest?
We will try to escape through the beach.
Egyptians are not barbarians,
They will take care of our wounded.
But the rest must run.
Get ready!
Shoot only if attacked.
I want captives.
In position!
Romek!
Catch Me.
God!
Support won't come?
- Come back.
- What do you mean?
I will cover you. Come back!
- Hadasa!
- Leave her alone!
No!
Hold your fire!
Enough said.
This way we will all die.
What do you do?
- It doesn't make sense.
- What?
What is pointless?
Everyone must not die. I have to...
This is irresponsible.
- Don't.
- I have to.
Clear?
Don't shoot!
Please don't shoot.
We give up.
Please!
Don't shoot.
Please. I want to talk.
Are you filming it?
- Yes.
- Zoom in on her.
- Who is shooting?
- Ammunition exploded in a burning tank.
No one is shooting.
Who did it?
- I heard the shot and thought....
- You act without thinking.
We go in there, you wait.
Do nothing without an order.
I said, I want prisoners.
The king finally got what he wanted.
A perfect picture of victory.
Our ruler, His Majesty King Faruk,
He personally led
our victorious army.
Our army destroyed the Zionist
Fort and killed thousands of enemy soldiers.
Our brave warriors defeated the enemy
Under the watchful eye of the beloved king.
What a lie!
They shot shots of the king in Cairo
Cairo and incorporated those fragments into the film.
After a year, the captives were exchanged.
We treated the returning soldiers
as traitors.
The Israelites treated their
with equal contempt and also recognized their
For traitors.
This behavior was driving me
me into a rage.
Anyone who did not fight in this war,
had no right to judge these young people,
Who were returning broken by the war.
Years later, I asked
a historian friend,
to find information about Nitzani.
In the book I got from him,
I found her picture.
One sentence struck me.
"No separation is as difficult,
As the separation of mother and child."
She wrote this knowing that she would no longer
she would not see her son.
And that smile...
As if to say:
Let's make a deal, take me
and grant me eternal life.
Eternal glory. In history and in legend.
She made a deal with death.
And would I be able to give my life
And lose those I love,
For such a deal?
For glory?
We look forward to seeing you.
I'm not rushing you.
We miss you.
But we are patient.
It doesn't have to happen today.
Haste is a satanic invention.
Love?
Do you know why I'm so lucky?
Why?
- Because you are smarter than me.
- I know.
Let's go.
- Artichokes?
- Yes.
When you were sitting here,
the children didn't want to disturb you.
But they missed you very much.
I follow them, too.
At the table, let's not talk politics.
Life is a completely different matter.
IN MEMORY OF MIRY BEN ARI
MEMORY OF YERACHMIEL YERACH BLEIBERG
MEMORY OF ALL YOUNG
PEOPLE ON BOTH SIDES,
WHO LOST THEIR LIVES
IN THE FIGHT FOR NITZANIM
Translated on behalf of Monolith Films:
Olga Krysiak