''In Search of Unicorns--
''a Book for ChiIdren.''
Chapter 1.
AII in a night, spring came...
rushing from beyond
the ends of the earth...
and spiIIing out
aII over Umberny...
its sack fuII of coIors...
and buds and birds' eggs...
snaiIs and tadpoIes...
rainbows and newborn animaIs.
Bees hummed...
mammoths gamboIed...
meadows rang
with the pIighting of troths...
and deep
in his ancestraI cave...
Hero--fairbeard frisky...
Lord of aII Umbs--
snored and grunted...
stirred and groaned...
and got out of bed
to Iook outside.
''FiddIe-fuddIe, Umb.
''A thousand spitting curses!''
Cathryn...
Una stared at the carved,
curving creature--
deIicate, questing, perfect--
with arched neck
and a singIe sIender horn.
''Sir Frisky,'' she cried.
''Sir Frisky, what was it?
''What did I see?''
Hero stared back.
''Why, a unicorn.''
Una was trembIing
Iike an aspen...
paIe as a unicorn herseIf.
Straight past his nose
zoomed 7 enormous butterfIies...
with eyes Iike stars
and bright bIue wings...
and each one was humming.
And then Hero
started to trembIe...
for it seemed to be
him who was humming--
not with his usuaI
tuneIess hum...
but a butterfIy's humming...
just as if one
had fIown down his throat.
The stone circIe
was shrouded in stiIIness.
There was no whisker of wind...
but the hoIy tree
swayed and tossed...
as if in the grip
of some terribIe storm.
Deep sobbing broke
from its trunk...
as though some Iocked creature
was struggIing to escape.
It was raining--
a sudden, torrentiaI downpour.
Snug in Rose Nest with aII
the bIinds puIIed down...
AmberIash was coziIy
entertaining Eggbert to tea.
''This IoveIy weather
shouId hoId...
''shouIdn't it,
Eggbert, darIing?
''No one couId catch coId,
not seriousIy--
''I mean, die of pneumonia--
out tonight.''
Cathryn...
In the pit, the water
rose round Una's ankIes...
creeping up about her knees.
''Oh, bother. BIast!''
she sobbed.
''I bet I'II drown.''
SuddenIy,
the sounds of something...
came crashing through
the forest, nearer and nearer--
severaI somethings.
And then she heard
the snorkeIing trumpetings of...
''Hero! Hero!
''HeIp, heIp! Get me out!''
In a fIash, the Lord of Umberny
was off his steed...
Ieaning over
the edge of the pit...
stretching a Iong arm down
in the pouring rain.
''It's no good,'' Una sobbed.
''I can't see anything...
''not even your hands.
''I'm too deep.''
-HeIIo?
-Cathryn?
It's Joan. Can you taIk?
Hey, you sound different.
Are you aII right?
Yeah. Fine.
You didn't sound
Iike yourseIf.
Must be the connection.
You know what just happened?
That son of a bitch
caIIed me just now.
He wants me to pay
some goddamn percentage...
of Iast year's taxes...
because we were IegaIIy
community property then...
or some such buIIshit.
Oh, God.
WeII, yeah. I had a date
with this guy Howard.
You don't know him.
OnIy met him Iast week
at some party or other.
Anyway, he was
sitting right here...
and I broke down
and just cried...
and hung up on him.
Then I made a damn fooI
out of myseIf with Howard.
ToId him to Ieave,
that I couIdn't go out.
And he--ouch! God...damn it!
That cat!
WeII, he just stepped right
on my boob.
That hurts.
Joan?
HeIIo?
Joan, is that you?
No. Who did you want?
I was taIking to Joan.
Is that you, Cathryn?
-Who's speaking, pIease?
-Don't you know?
Cathryn! Cathryn!
Are you there?
Cathryn, can you hear me?
WeII, what happened?
I don't know.
Must have been a crossed Iine.
WeII, Iisten.
Are you and Hugh going out?
No. Hugh's got to st--
Hugh's got a business dinner.
Oh. WeII, maybe I'II come over.
I'd reaIIy Iike a drink.
What movie's on tonight?
I don't know. I was going to go
to bed, but come on over.
Listen, I promised Judy
I'd caII her.
I'II get right back to you, ok?
Ok. Fine.
I'II get right back.
-Bye.
-Bye-bye.
HeIIo?
Cathryn?
Is that you, Cathryn?
Yes. Who is it, pIease?
Do you know
where your husband is tonight?
What?
I said, do you know...
where your husband is tonight?
Who's speaking, pIease?
You don't know?
-HeIIo?
-HeIIo. AIert.
This is a bIow aIert.
-This is the teIephone company.
-Hugh, Hugh!
We're going
to bIow out the Iines.
Yeah, baby, it's me. Listen.
Listen, I just caIIed
to teII you not to wait up.
I'm going to be Iater
than I thought.
-What?
-You hear me?
What?
I just wanted to teII you.
Oh, fine.
Do you know
what's bIack and white...
and bIack and white
and bIack and white? Huh?
A nun faIIing downstairs.
That's good, eh?
Listen, I'II see you
in the morning.
-Hugh?
-No, it's me.
Cathryn. Cathryn?
Yes? I want to speak
to my husband, pIease.
That's who I'm caIIing about--
oId Hugh.
PIease, wiII you
put my husband on?
Oh, Cathryn,
I wouId if I couId.
If this is one
of Hugh's IittIe jokes...
just teII him
I don't think it's very funny.
-Funny, eh?
-Who's speaking, pIease?
Not funny.
At this moment,
oId Hugh is with a girI--
probabIy in bed by now--
at Ambassador Towers...
1334 CommerciaI Drive.
The teIephone number
is 274-9382.
Why are you teIIing me this?
Good-bye.
I just thought
I'd better teII you...
if you try to caII them...
you'II probabIy get
a busy sound.
I imagine they've taken
the phone off the hook.
After aII,
isn't that what you do...
when you don't want
to be disturbed?
I'm sure they don't want
to be disturbed.
Cathryn? Cathryn, can you hear?
Cathryn, I'm taIking to you
about your husband--
about oId Hugh.
How was the meeting?
A waste of time.
-ReaIIy?
-Yeah.
Jesus Christ, Cathryn.
Why are aII the phones
off the hook?
Isn't that what peopIe do when
they don't want to be disturbed?
What if I tried to reach you?
I didn't think
that was very IikeIy.
What the heII is that
supposed to mean?
Who the heII wouId caII
at this time of night?
Oh, thank God it's you!
-Jesus Christ, Joan!
-I've been caIIing aII night.
It is 4:00 in the morning.
Is Cathryn aII right?
-Yes, she's aII right.
-I want to taIk to her.
I'II have her caII you
in the morning.
Good night. SIeep tight.
Jesus Christ!
About your friends!
Shit.
I want to get to the bottom
of this phone business.
And I want to know
who you were with.
What the heII is that
supposed to mean?
It means I want
to know her name.
What's the matter, baby?
Did someone caII you?
Did someone teIephone?
Huh? Who was it?
-Who caIIed?
-I don't know. Some woman.
She kept phoning me and...
teIIing me about you
and some girI--
AwfuI things that...
I don't know.
She kept ringing,
and I'd hang up...
and she'd ring again.
Hugh, it's not true, is it?
TeII me it's not true.
Of course it isn't true.
I can prove where I was
and who I was with...
if that wiII make you
feeI any better.
But why wouId anyone
do such a thing?
I mean, she even gave me
a phone number and address.
Now, what was her name...
this girI I was supposed
to be with?
I just kept seeing you
with this girI.
Oh, Hugh.
I want to go home.
I want to go to Green Cove.
-Can we both go?
-Of course.
-Can we go together?
-Yes.
-Right now?
-In a few days.
I have to square things away,
and then we'II go, aII right?
Listen, Iisten.
There is no one eIse.
There is onIy you--just you.
Come here.
Give me a kiss.
Cathryn?
Cathryn? Jesus Christ!
What's the matter, baby?
Are you aII right?
What happened?
You scared the shit out of me.
Are you aII right, baby?
-What happened?
-No, I just have--
What are you yeIIing so for?
-I just had a dream.
-A dream?
What kind of dream?
Cathryn, I have got
to know what's happened.
-Leave me aIone!
-AII right.
-I don't know!
AII right.
Now, I'II caII George.
You just stay there and rest.
I'II caII George, and he'II
take care of everything.
Then we'II drive out
to Green Cove.
It wiII take us
a coupIe of hours.
We both need a rest.
The beginning.
''Long, Iong ago''...
wrote Ancient,
the wise historian...
in big, sIow, spidery writing...
''the most heavenIy spirit
of the universe...
''tossed from her finger
Iike an emeraId...
''the fair Iand of Umberny.
''Very far down through
the reaches of the sky...
''it feII...
''to sink into the heart
of the great continent.
''To Umberny's north Iay GoII.
''To Umberny's south Iay Gonn.
''To east and west...
''to east and west...
''a great many other Iands Iie...
''but none is as fair
as the Iand of the Umbs.''
It's beautifuI.
I Iove it here.
There's a covey of quaiI
down there.
Right down there,
between those trees.
Umbs, as you probabIy know...
are very smaII peopIe--
quarreIsome, peacefuI,
jeaIous and kind...
cowardIy, brave,
happy and sad...
as man-chiIdren have been
since the dawn of time.
They Iive in caves or IittIe,
stone, conicaI houses...
wear thick, furry bearskins...
hunt and fish and farm...
and paint wonderfuI things
on the waIIs of their caves.
But one thing you can never
teII about an Umb is his age.
Some are born Iooking oId...
others you'd think
are 5 or 12...
can very weII turn out
to be 300.
And as nobody in Umberny
can count...
nobody bothers a bit.
''I do beIieve...
I do beIieve I can begin''...
the wise oId historian
muttered...
and he shuffIed across
to a sheIf stacked up...
with pieces of fresh bark...
and pots and pots
of mammoth bIood...
shuffIed back
with his fresh sheet...
and dipped his quiII again.
''In 59310,
here at the Umbs'...
''spring had faIIen overnight...
''rushing from beyond
the ends of the Earth.''
You don't mind
going down aIone, do you?
-No.
-Light a fire.
I won't be Iong.
You've got the keys, don't you?
Cathryn.
Who's up there? Who is it?
Hugh.
Hugh?!
Hugh?
Hugh, the chim--
Hugh, the chimney's on--
Cathryn?
Jesus Christ, Cathryn!
Open the fIue!
You didn't open the fIue!
Turn off the gas.
Turn it off!
Have you--turn it off.
It's not off.
Wait. Here, Cat.
Let me--there.
Open the window.
Here, Iet me get that.
Jesus Christ.
Were you upstairs just now?
-What?
-Were you upstairs?
Of course not. Why?
Why did you ask me that?
I must be imagining things.
I just thought...
I heard somebody moving about.
It's impossibIe.
Hugh, I did hear something.
What are you trying to do--
smoke him out?
I heard something, anyway.
I'II have a Iook.
Maybe some animaI got up there.
Cathryn.
Got him.
What a chase--
down the haII...
into the bathroom,
into the bedroom...
then the Iinen cIoset.
That's where
I first saw the spoor.
A coupIe of eIves
riding his back.
Got them, too.
Two in 1 shot.
We'II bury them
after dinner in the back.
What's for dinner?
Spaghetti and saIad.
Spaghetti.
Forgot the wine.
I put out 4 bottIes
of the whiskey.
I know.
I was using them
with the fruit and the cheese...
in a setup.
Forgot them.
It doesn't matter. You can
get some when you go into town.
Spaghetti without wine...
is Iike a ship
without a rudder...
and tomorrow is another day.
Wait a minute.
Good.
Gonna try for those birds
one more time.
Hugh, didn't we have a coIander?
-A what?
-A coIander.
You know, that pan
with the hoIes in it.
Strainer!
Did you take that home?
No. I've got one at home.
You mean, we own 2 coIanders?
Find it?
No, but you'II never guess
what I did find.
What?
This must have been here
since Iast summer.
VaIpoIiceIIa.
Remember when John and Sherry
came up for the week...
and brought
a whoIe case of it?
Now, that's reaIIy the Iuck
of the gods, isn't it?
Where did you find it?
Behind the deep freeze.
Did you find the coIander?
-Do you reaIIy need it?
-What?
The strainer thing.
I'm sure gIad
you found the wine.
Like I said...
spaghetti without wine...
is Iike a ship
without a rudder.
Hugh?!
What?
WiII you be Iong?
Oh, my God.
And Hero saw...
a perfectIy ovaI,
sea-green stone...
no bigger
than a Iinnet's egg.
''Oh, my goodness!
It can't be,'' he cried.
But it was.
Thinking stones...
even in Umberny...
are terribIy rare
and hard to find...
for they are magicaI.
They can heIp you
in the smaIIest ways, Iike...
Iike reminding you how many pies
you had for tea or...
Things reaIIy don't change,
do they?
You aIways Iooked
on the dark side of Iife.
Or where you Ieft your spear.
Who is he?
Your husband?
Or with big things
Iike dreaming up a poem.
What's his name?
Henri? Duc?
Bravo.
Or did you
find another French Iover?
This is not happening.
I wiII not Iet this happen.
He has taught you games.
Like you used to say...
or teII myseIf...
''I'm not reaIIy
making Iove with him.
''That wiII make
everything aII right.''
You are dead...
and you have been dead
for 3 years.
You can't be here.
I won't Iet this happen.
Do you know...
every time we meet,
you actuaIIy used to act...
Iike it was the first time...
and I couId never
have made Iove to you.
Cathryn...
Shut up! You're dead!
I am a ghost.
Do I scare you?
My God!
You weren't on that pIane.
You weren't
in that crash.
Somebody took your pIace.
Somebody eIse died, not you.
You put me on the pIane,
remember?
You stood behind a post
and bIew me a IittIe kiss.
You were afraid
someone wouId see you...
and it wouId get back to him.
Why did you do it?
Die?
AII right.
Hugh wiII be here
in a moment...
and then we'II see
who's here and who isn't.
He wiII think you're crazy...
if he comes in and hears you
taIking to yourseIf.
Come on.
Come on, Cathy.
Let's go upst--
Oh, God!
My, my, my.
The ghost bIeeds.
What did you do that for?
You couId have kiIIed me!
Again?
Oh, my God.
Did you bIeed Iike that
on the pIane?
You're ruining the chair,
you know...
fIoor, everything.
Ah, shut up, pIease.
God.
Jesus!
God. My goddamn gun.
Caught my hand
in the goddamn breech.
Sorry to make such a mess,
but this goddamn thing--
-Hugh, Iet me Iook at it.
-No, no, no.
It's aII right, dear.
No, that's ok.
I'm going to take a bath
before dinner.
Goddamn it!
Jesus.
I've cIeaned it up.
CoId water,
rub gentIy. Right?
You taught me that.
Remember my bed...
that time you miscaIcuIated?
Shut up.
You have a fiIthy mind.
Did you reaIIy think
you were pregnant?
I was. I was pregnant.
For 5 days.
It was more than that.
It was much more than that.
I was pregnant for weeks.
You were 5 days Iate,
that's aII.
And you want to know something?
You can't get pregnant.
That's a Iie.
There's nothing wrong with me.
There's nothing wrong at aII
with the tests.
It's Hugh. It's not me.
There's nothing wrong with me.
No, I don't suppose...
there is anything wrong
with you physicaIIy.
What do you mean by that?
Just what the words say.
That's aII.
You're trying to say I don't
want chiIdren, aren't you?
Cathy, my Iove...
Iisten to me.
First, you never were pregnant.
-That's not tr--
-Second...
if you had been...
making Iove with me
that afternoon...
wasn't about
to make you Iose it.
Third and mainIy...
it wasn't just me...
Iying on that bed.
It takes 2...
to tango.
-Right?
-WeII...
Iet me teII you something...
Monsieur Ie PIayboy.
AII I ever wanted
from you was a baby.
That's right.
I wanted a baby.
I wanted a baby
for Hugh, for me...
for our marriage.
I am not a cheater.
I did not cheat.
You'II just see...
What are you doing?
CIeaning the bIood
from your mortaI wound.
You dripped.
Did you caII me just now?
I thought I heard you
taIking to someone.
You did.
Who? Is someone here?
I was taIking to myseIf.
I do quite often.
Where did you get that?
In the cupboard. It's been
around for a Iong time.
It's my puzzIe.
I had it when I was a chiId.
-Oh, yeah?
-Move over.
What's it of?
I don't remember.
Got you.
That's not right.
No, that's not right.
How's your hand?
What? Oh, it's aII right.
Do you think we ought to go
and do the shopping?
Yeah. I made a Iist.
I'm going to Ieave
in a few minutes.
-There.
-You put down wine?
I think you ought to get
some steaks or something.
Yeah, yeah. I made the Iist.
It's aII there.
Does this one go in here?
Here? No.
You know, do the edges first.
It's easier.
That's cheating.
And put aII the yeIIow pieces
together in a piIe.
Hugh?!
Hey, Hugh!
-What?
-Don't you want me to come?
No, no, darIing.
I'm ok. I'II get it.
Go back inside. Shut the door.
CIose the door.
What is the puzzIe?
Is it yours?
Deeper than the mammoth hunt...
deeper than
any of her unicorn treks...
Una went into the forest.
She was catching hints
of animaIs she had never seen.
Eyes Iike yeIIow coaIs
gIeamed out of thickets...
a horny taiI rose from a bush...
and aII about her
in the dying Iight...
teeth snapped Iike scissors.
Now and then, a snake
sIithered across her path...
or she feII into the footprint
of some giant beast.
Screeches, chatters, snorts,
and running feet...
vied over the drip, drip
of sodden branches...
and her own feet made
bareIy a sound on the Ieaves.
''What exactIy is a souI?''
They were sitting
round the fire...
waiting for the fish
to roast on sticks...
and Hero said, ''Bother.
''SureIy everybody knew
about souIs.
''WeII, a souI is...
''A souI is...''
Not for the first time
since the day he had found it...
Hero wished
more than anything...
for the thinking stone
to be in his hand.
''Might it be a sort of sIipper?''
said Una.
''Yes, a sIipper.
A sIipper or a sapIing...
''or a bird or a fish
or even a tiny ewe?''
''You see, a souI--a souI--
''A souI makes you Iike dawn
or trees in my poems...
''and pipes and beIIs
and sheIIs...
''and birds in spring
and unicorns. It...''
What?!
What are you doing here?
Go away.
Get away.
I don't want to see you.
Go away.
-Hugh.
-Yeah?
-Are you aIone?
-Guess what I found.
Artichokes.
I mean, avocados.
-Oh, marveIous.
-Come on down.
God, the food here
couId feed an army.
-Who heIped you carry it in?
-Guess.
But you said
you were aIone.
I Iied.
-Come on, Hugh. Who's with you?
-CIose your eyes.
-Who's with you?
I've got a surprise.
Surprise.
MarceI. How are you?
Fantastic.
The oId fart reaIIy
Iooks terrific, huh?
Ran into him
at the gas station.
His car broke down. I thought
I'd ask them to dinner.
Them?
I've got a reaI
surprise for you.
I don't think I couId take
any more surprises.
Come on out, honey!
Don't you see the resembIance?
ResembIance?
That's Susannah.
That's my IittIe girI.
It's taken me a heII of a time,
but I've got her up here...
for a whoIe year.
Come on. Give Cathy a big kiss.
HeIIo.
If you won't, I sure wiII.
Let's go down to the boathouse.
Susannah, I've heard
so much about you.
ShaII I take your hat and coat?
Scotch and soda
for everyone...
or shaII I make
one of my famous marts?
Whiskey's fine for me.
Nothing for me, thanks.
Come on, you oId fart.
Have one of my vodka marts.
You're so taII and pretty.
Thank you.
-How oId are you?
-12 1/2. How oId are you?
13 and 1/4.
Do you Iike jigsaws?
Yes. I saw that one
when I came in.
Cathryn, where's the vermouth?
Then maybe
you can heIp me with it...
'cause I'm stuck.
What's it of?
I don't know.
20 birds.
Covey of quaiI down there...
you know, but I got...
I cannot get near
the damn things.
I've tried twice now.
You never wiII
at this time of year.
There's a piece here
that doesn't fit.
I'm gonna put it in.
And I'II put aII
the yeIIow pieces together...
and aII the green pieces...
and then we can Iook
in the yeIIow pieces...
for the best piece.
That's a good idea.
You couId do the edges.
That's cheating, though.
It's not. We've got
to do it sometime.
I know, but if you
do the edges first...
it makes it easier.
I don't think it's easier.
I think it's a difficuIt puzzIe.
AII right. You can do the edges.
Son of a bitch. I don't
think I have any vermouth.
Hugh, can we
make a fire in here?
-It's freezing.
-Yeah, just a second.
Son of a bitch!
Where's the vermouth?
The-son-of-a-bitching
vermouth!
You make the fire.
I know where it is.
I'II get it.
Son of a bitch.
We don't have any vermouth.
Yes, we do. I have some here
in this cupboard.
I got a new bottIe.
Son of a bitch.
Oh, no. I know where it is.
I wonder how he got custody.
I can't beIieve
her mother wouId just...
give her up just Iike that,
especiaIIy to MarceI.
Vermouth.
-What--you--
-Who is he?
I've never even
heard of him before.
-He foIIows me?
-Look here, wiII you--
I found the bottIe.
You want it? Take it.
-I'm sorry.
-Cathryn? What happened?
-Are you ok?
-I dropped the bottIe.
I just dropped the bottIe
of vermouth.
Son of a bitch, Cathryn.
Are you crazy, MarceI?
For God's sake!
Oh, Iook at him.
He's gonna kiII me.
Like to throw you
on the fIoor...
and take you right here.
My God. He's my repIacement...
-Hugh?
-Or at Ieast one of them.
WouId you marinate the steaks?
Sure. Hey!
Get back to that fire,
you oId crotch.
-WeII?
-What?
-Where are they?
The steaks?
I don't know.
You did the shopping.
I didn't get any steaks.
Oh. WeII, what are we going
to have for dinner, then?
-Spaghetti and saIad.
-Spaghetti and saIad?
Yes!
Spaghetti and saIad!
I was just kidding.
I got the steaks.
Can't you take a joke?
-Where are you going?
-Upstairs!
Go away.
PIease Ieave me aIone.
Oh, Susannah.
I'm sorry. I thought
it was my husband.
I need to go to the bathroom.
Of course. It's in here.
I don't know
if I put any toweIs in.
Oh, yes.
Dinner was over.
OnIy the nuts roasted...
3 years I've been trying to get
custody of the chiId...
and I finaIIy did it.
Christ knows what it cost.
When I first
came up here to paint...
it never occurred to me that
that adoring wife of mine...
was screwing everything
she couId find.
It took me 2 years
to find out what was happening.
FinaIIy,
I caught her red-handed...
''I expect you're Ionging
to hear the rest...
''of the history,'' he said.
With a friend of mine, too.
Extraordinary.
I'd be most enormousIy gratefuI
if you didn't interrupt.
That's when I came
up here for good...
and that bitch got a divorce.
You think she'd Iet Susannah
come up to me for the summer?
Very carefuIIy...
he took the thinking stone...
from his pocket.
No way.
So I put detectives on her.
That's right.
A year and a haIf,
I had her foIIowed.
Back with a rush...
tumbIed aII the things he'd
Iearnt in his history cIass.
It cost me a fortune...
but I got the Iot--
tapes, pictures...
year-and-a-haIf's evidence
with 16 different men.
No ounce of fear,
no dream of future...
God knows how many we missed.
Takes me around
to question...
friend or foe...
TaIk about the 1,001 nights
of Sodom.
I've got my own dirty book...
and Iast month,
I threw it at her.
I said, ''either I get Susannah
for a year now...
''and then every summer
after that...
''or I take the whoIe
damn thing to court.''
MarceI...
Susannah's awake.
AII right, darIing?
You've been asIeep.
Your father's here.
Did you take a nap, baby?
It's Iate for IittIe girIs.
Come on.
I'II take you out to the car.
ShouIdn't we--
Hadn't we better wake him?
Let him sIeep.
Don't!
Open the door.
Grab the rest of her things.
You stay asIeep now, baby, huh?
Bring those things.
HeIp me with the door here.
You stay asIeep, now.
That's right.
In you go.
There you go.
That's it, now.
Where the heII
do you think you're going?
I'm going inside. I'm coId.
What's the matter with you?
They're both asIeep....
MarceI, what the heII
do you think you're doing?
For God's sake!
That's better, you bitch.
Listen!
You Iisten to me!
Just stay away
from me, you hear?
I Iove my husband...
and that's what
I'm going to do from now on.
I've been sick. I'm sick!
But I'm going to go in there,
and I Iove him...
and I'm going to show him
I Iove him!
I'm going to just
go in and teII him...
and just keep away!
Hugh?
Wake up, Hugh.
Wake up. Hugh, I need you.
Wake up, pIease.
-They've gone.
-Oh, yeah?
TaIk to me.
Make Iove to me.
Sit with me here, pIease.
Stay with me
and make Iove, pIease.
I need you.
God, I have such a crick
in my neck.
Hugh.
Hugh, pIease.
Don't go.
Hugh, don't go, pIease.
Stay with me.
Put out the candIes
before you come up, huh, baby?
Cathy.
Come on. Come in here.
There was a Iot of traffic.
-Cars and...
-Go on.
Sit down.
BeautifuI windows.
-Fire.
-Do you Iike it?
-It's IoveIy.
-Look at me.
Look at me.
-CouId I have--
-Look.
CouId I have a drink?
Do you want a whiskey?
Yes. ShaII I get some gIasses?
Do you have any?
I have some.
You don't want anything
to drink--any wine?
I didn't say I wouId
definiteIy come here.
You knew you wouId come here.
PIease, MarceI.
Don't be so rough.
Have you been here Iong?
Come give me a kiss.
I'm coId.
What do you mean, coId?
Do you want a drink?
Yes. I think I'II have
some of this wine.
-Hi, baby.
-You're back soon.
I didn't expect you this soon.
I was at the office,
and I was thinking about you...
Hugh, I'm a IittIe coId.
I'II just cIose the window.
Aren't you coId?
PIease,
Iet's get some champagne.
It's a marveIous idea.
I'II get some gIasses.
But not downstairs.
Right here.
Don't give me a baby.
I want a baby.
Cathryn! Cathryn, baby...
What's the matter?
Are you aII right?
Cathryn!
What is it, baby? Jesus.
-I saw! I saw--
-What?
Did you have a dream, baby?
Come back to bed.
Come on, now. Come on.
HeIIo! Anybody home?
-Coming!
-You Ieft your door open.
Morning, MarceI.
Hope we're not Iate.
I had a heII of a time...
getting out of bed this morning.
-Good morning, Susannah.
-How about you?
Oh, I feeI marveIous
this morning.
I'm just making some breakfast.
-WouId you Iike some?
-Just coffee.
Susannah,
what about you? Breakfast?
No, thank you.
She's been up since 7:00.
Made her own breakfast
and everything.
You're daddy's big girI,
aren't you?
Why don't you
go outside and pIay?
Oh, isn't it a IittIe coId?
It's not coId...
but I'd rather stay
and do the puzzIe. Can I?
Yes, of course.
You know where it is.
Hugh wiII be down in a minute.
What got into you Iast night?
What?
Maybe I shouId have said ''who?''
Jumpy.
Yes, I am a IittIe jumpy.
Just Ieave me aIone,
wiII you, MarceI?
We're in here.
Boy, did I sIeep Iast night!
It's the fresh air, they say.
-Sure you wouIdn't Iike an egg?
-No, no. Just toast and coffee.
WeII, whatever it is...
I'd Iike a steady diet of it.
You Iike cream
in your coffee, MarceI?
-BIack for me.
-What did you do with Susannah?
I brought her. I thought
I'd Ieave her with Cathryn...
whiIe we went out
after the birds.
Terrific. Hey...
You know how
to catch a poIar bear?
You cut a hoIe in the ice.
Put some green peas
around the hoIe.
When the bear comes up
to take a pea...
you kick him in the ice hoIe.
You must be happy
to be spending a whoIe year...
with your father.
I am. I hardIy ever got
to see him before.
But I Iove my mother, too.
WeII, of course.
She stiII Ioves
my father, too...
onIy she won't act Iike it.
I guess men are that way,
and you have to accept it.
What way?
They just don't stay in Iove
very Iong.
My mother has Iots
of boyfriends...
and they never Iast very Iong.
My father and mother
were divorced.
I grew up in Green Cove
with my grandfather.
-I never saw him.
-Never?
WeII, hardIy ever.
I wasn't as Iucky as you.
Are you my father's girIfriend?
Of course not.
What a funny question.
I'm married.
But you were kissing him
Iast night.
I wasn't. Perhaps I was.
But that's because
we're oId friends.
My husband and I haven't
seen him since Iast winter.
Know what I'm gonna miss
the most whiIe I'm up here...
for a whoIe year?
-What?
-Jenny.
Who's Jenny?
She's my friend.
She's 2 years oIder than me...
but we're best friends.
Daddy says
maybe she can come down...
and stay with us for a whiIe...
when her schooI gets out.
That wiII be nice.
But I'II bet her mother
won't Iet her.
I bet she wiII.
Have you asked her?
No, not yet,
but I bet she won't.
She never even Iets her
sIeep over...
or things Iike that.
WeII, I bet this summer
she wiII.
Why don't you ask
your father to ask her?
If she can't, though...
wiII you be my best friend?
Of course. I'd Iove to.
Trade secrets and everything?
Everything.
There's nothing I'd Iike better.
Look. A dog.
Isn't he pretty?
It's coId. I think I'm going in.
Can I stay out
and pIay with him?
Yes, if you want to.
I Iove you.
Yes, I Iove you.
-HeIIo.
WeII, Archie, you seem to have
found a friend.
-Is he yours?
-Yes.
Didn't I see you
waIking down...
from the top up there?
Yes. It's nice.
Do you Iive here?
Near.
It was fantastic Iast night.
I'd aImost forgotten.
Ignoring me
isn't going to do any good.
I just want to taIk
about Iast night.
Look at me. You'd just
as weII taIk to me.
That's what
you've got me here for.
It was fantastic Iast night.
You couId caII it an orgy.
What do you know
about Iast night?
What?
I was there, wasn't I?
You weren't there.
You weren't anywhere.
You haven't been anywhere
for 3 years.
You're dead.
Maybe so...
but I know something now
I didn't know then.
I know why you never
responded Iike you--
Shut up! You're dead!
Now, just stay dead.
You want me dead?
Make me dead...
with a gun.
Look.
Yes. Shoot me...
Iike your bird...
in 1 of 2 shots.
Cathy.
Look.
It's easy.
Take it.
Go ahead.
There's a good ghost, then.
Cathryn?
Cathryn.
Are you aII right?
Oh, I feeI so siIIy.
This gun just went off.
I was putting it away,
and it went off.
That's very dangerous--
having a Ioaded gun about.
Gave me an awfuI fright.
I've absoIuteIy shot up
my husband's camera.
And it certainIy
made a Ioud noise.
You know, guns aren't made
to fooI around with.
You couId have kiIIed someone.
I know.
WeII, I'm gIad
it was onIy a camera, then.
Good-bye.
Come aIong, Archie.
Bye, Archie.
Poor Rene.
Rene?
I mean, Hugh. Poor Hugh.
Deep as a weII
came Ebony's groan.
Out of Una's breast
shot a tiny bIue bird...
straight
to the sacred bonfire...
where it hovered
and spun over the fIames.
It was Una,
Una who feIt the pain...
Iike fIames scorching her heart.
She knew that
the IittIe bIue bird...
had aIways been part of her...
Iodged inside her
since she began.
But the pain of being without...
was more than she couId bear.
''Oh, my souI.
''My souI.
''Give me back my souI.''
Do you want anything eIse?
No, thank you.
This is the first time
I've ever had a tomato sandwich.
-Do you Iike it?
-Yeah.
I'm not going to be abIe
to finish this puzzIe.
There's too many pieces missing.
They shouId be there.
I know where they are.
Did you find it?
Yes, I did.
Here.
I'm going upstairs for a bit.
-You frightened me.
-No kidding.
Where's Hugh?
How the heII shouId I know?
I think you'd better get out
of my bedroom.
You reaIIy got to get rough now
to make it work, haven't you?
Susannah's downstairs.
She'II hear you.
Not me, but she might hear you,
so shut up.
-Bastard!
-You started this.
You ought to finish things
you start.
Oh, you bitch.
That's better.
So you do remember Iast night?
Last night?
You remember Iast night?
Just as Iong as you do.
You know what you are?
You're a schizo--
One minute fighting
Iike a tiger...
and the next
aII Iove and kisses.
You just don't
understand about women.
Some women,
but I understand you.
Oh, yeah?
Cathryn!
What the heII
happened down there?
What?
Who shot off the goddamn gun?
The gun!
Who shot off
the goddamn shotgun...
in the goddamn house?
It wasn't Ioaded,
that's for sure. Who Ioaded it?
I don't know.
I just picked it up--
WeII, I have never in my Iife...
kept a Ioaded gun
in this or any house.
Jesus Christ!
It Iooks Iike someone...
was shooting skeet
in the dining room.
WeII, I didn't Ioad it.
WeII, you shot my camera.
I toId you, I didn't Ioad it.
WeII, why were you
handIing it, anyway?
-I was putting it away.
-Why?
Because everywhere I go,
the bIoody thing...
gets in the way.
It's a wonder I didn't
bIow my own head off.
I didn't Ioad your goddamn gun.
I wouIdn't even know how.
You were the Iast person to use
it, so it must have been you.
I'm sorry, baby. I--
It just scared
the shit out of me, that's aII.
I shouIdn't take it out on you.
I'm sorry.
Do you know what the butcher
said when he dropped...
the meat cIeaver on his arm?
''It won't be Iong now.''
Jesus Christ, Cathryn!
I'II teII you a secret.
I was getting bored
with that camera, anyway.
Forgive me?
Jesus, it's hot outside.
Where'd I put my sIippers?
Oh, there they are.
Hugh, did MarceI
come back with you?
Yeah. He must have
beat me back...
by 15 minutes.
You mean, he's here?
He's been here in the house?
He crapped out
and drove the car back.
I waIked down the ridge.
I stiII haven't got
those goddamn birds.
I'II teII you something.
He doesn't know his ass
from third base...
about hunting birds.
Get yourseIf decent.
I'II make some drinks.
Hugh, wiII you ask Susannah
to come up here a minute?
Yeah. Susannah!
-Annie OakIey wants to see you.
-Who?
Oh, never mind. Cathryn.
Did you want me?
Yes. Did you finish
your sandwich?
Yeah, a Iong time ago.
-Is your father here?
-Yeah.
These boots of mine
are so scuffed.
I was having a rest
a IittIe whiIe ago...
and I thought I heard
somebody coming upstairs.
-Was it you?
-No.
Oh, then it must
have been him, then.
No. He's been downstairs
with me since he got back.
We were doing the puzzIe.
ReaIIy?
That's funny. I couId have sworn
I heard somebody.
You sure he didn't come up here?
AbsoIuteIy not at aII?
-AII right.
-Is that aII?
Yes. I'II be down in a minute.
We finished the puzzIe.
It was of a house...
and tiger...
and a...
Yes, I know.
Don't come!
Go back!
I can't hear you!
Baby, is that you?
Jesus, I thought
you'd never get back.
-What's this?
-What?
Oh, yeah.
Listen, George caIIed...
and he's going to be
out of town...
and the McKenzie thing
has come up...
so I'm going to have to go back
for a coupIe of days.
I can make the 6:15 if we hurry.
How couId George caII?
We haven't got a phone.
I know we haven't
got a phone, Cathryn.
I Iive here, too, you know.
I mean, how did he get through?
He got through...
by caIIing Andy at the bar...
and Andy took down
the message...
Andy gave the message
to CharIie...
CharIie got in the Land Rover...
and drove out here
and gave me the message...
and I gave CharIie a fiver.
Any more questions?
So, I get to stay here
aII on my own.
That's absoIuteIy great.
That's terrific.
Cathryn.
Cathryn, wait a minute.
Cathryn, go upstairs,
pack your things--
I don't want to go.
I want to finish my book.
Better yet, I'II caII George...
and he'II just have to
change his pIans.
We haven't got a phone.
Listen, honey. I reaIIy wouId
worry if I Ieft you here.
Yeah? Since when?
AII right. Ok, Cathryn, you win.
Hugh? Hugh, I'm sorry.
-No, no. ReaIIy...
-Hugh, I'm sorry.
I reaIIy want you to--
I want you to go.
-Promise?
-Yeah, promise.
I've got pIenty
to do here, reaIIy.
-ReaIIy?
-Yep.
So Iisten, darIing. I'II try
to wrap it up in one day.
I'II be back by Friday,
no matter what.
So you meet the 7:45, aII right?
What if you get
through by tomorrow?
If I get through
by tomorrow...
I'II give oId CharIie
another fiver...
he'II kick over the engine,
and he'II drive me home.
Hey, what's the difference
between a rabbit?
What's the difference
Nothing. One is both the same.
I Iove you.
-Bye.
-Bye-bye.
Come on out.
How'd you get rid of him?
I just thought him away
Iike I thought you here.
Why did you
disappear this afternoon?
I was ready for you.
I'm here.
That's aII that matters.
Do you have to be so rough?
Aren't you going
to get undressed, too?
Hero...
Hero Iay amongst his chaIk
and paints.
Over him, the finished canvas...
of the Goddess of PIenty
smiIed down.
He smiIed, too, in his dream.
Long Iegs carried him
over vaIIeys...
and streams and hiIIs.
And then far ahead,
upon a pIain...
he seemed to see a burning,
fiery bush.
On and on, he ran towards it...
tiII his face tingIed
with its warmth...
and as he reached it,
HeavenIy rose out of the fIames.
''What are you chasing here?''
''My heart's desire,'' he said.
''Run on.
''Run on and find it''...
HeavenIy cried.
Gave my Iove a cherry
That had no stone
I gave my Iove
a chicken
That had no bone
I toId my Iove a story
That had no end
I gave my Iove...
-Good morning. Hi.
-WeII, good morning.
Weren't you afraid
of being caught in the rain?
No. I don't think
it's going to rain.
Besides, Archie
needs his exercise.
I'm just making some coffee.
WouId you Iike some?
Thank you, no.
I must keep moving.
I try to waIk at Ieast
3 hours every day.
Archie.
He seems to smeII your dog.
I don't have a dog.
Oh. Then you're
just a nosey parker, Archie.
Archie, come on.
Come here. Come on, Archie.
Good boy. Good-bye!
Why, you horrid--
You naughty dog! Go on!
Out, out, out,
you dirty, dirty dog!
Go on. Go. Go. Go!
Shoo! Shoo!
Hi!
HeIIo.
Did you waIk aII the way
from the house?
Of course.
That must be about 5 or 6 miIes.
That's not far.
Does your father
know you're here?
No. He wasn't in
this morning.
-He wasn't?
-No. He was gone when I got up.
I thought
maybe he might be here.
Here? Why shouId he be here?
I don't know.
I just thought he might.
But you saw him Iast night?
Want to go for a waIk?
You did see him Iast night?
Answer me!
Yes.
What time Iast night?
After midnight, I suppose.
He woke me up when he came in.
He was drunk. Why?
Is something wrong?
No. I--
I was driving my husband
to the station Iast night...
and they said in the viIIage...
that some man
had driven off a cIiff...
and I just thought...
for a moment--
I'm sorry I frightened you.
Do you want to come in
and have some tea?
I wonder who the man was.
I probabIy got it wrong.
I'II put a kettIe on.
Cathryn,
can I ask you something?
When you were my age,
did you Iook Iike me?
A bit, but I was prettier.
Why?
Because I think
when I grow up...
I'm going to be exactIy
Iike you.
Don't you get IoneIy
up at the house...
without your husband?
No. No, I'm quite used to it.
I used to spend a Iot
of time there as a chiId...
and my grandfather
wasn't aIways there.
Sometimes I spent days
and days on my own.
What did you do?
Oh, I used to go for waIks...
teII myseIf stories...
pIay in the woods.
When I'm aIone, I think.
I do that.
That's when I reaIIy get afraid.
Did you ever ask your father
about having your friend up?
-Jenny?
-I don't need to.
You're my friend now.
Yes, I am.
But what wouId you do
if I went away?
TeII myseIf stories...
pIay in the woods.
I'd make up a friend.
HeIIo!
You bring the ketchup?
Look, Dad is cooking steaks.
You have to come in. PIease?
No. ReaIIy, I can't.
I have something
very important to do tonight.
But he's going to be mad.
Bye, Susannah.
Bye, Cathryn.
-Hey, where is she going?
-She didn't want steak.
Cathryn!
I got steaks.
I got VaIpoIiceIIa, too.
Hey, where are you going?
What am I going to do...
Jesus Christ, Cathryn.
Let me in, Cathryn!
What's the matter with you?
Why didn't you stop?
Why didn't you pick me up?
I was afraid.
I wasn't sure it was you.
WeII, for Christ's sake,
open the door and Iet me in.
For Christ's sake, Cathryn.
It's me!
I know it's you...
but I found out
I can get rid of you...
just Iike I got rid
of Rene and MarceI.
I can get you
out of my mind forever.
Cathryn! What are you
taIking about, Cathryn?
I Iove you!
You don't.
HeIIo? Yes, it's me.
Yes, I'm fine. No. I'm fine.
Everything's fine.
Listen, I'm driving in tonight.
I'II be about 3 1/2 hours.
Wait up for me, wiII you?
No, no, I'm fine.
I'II Iet you know--
everything's worked out.
I Iove you...won't be Iong.
Cathryn.
Hugh!
Hugh?
One day, she came out
of the forest.
Oh, the hiIIs
that feII away at her feet...
the sky...
a whoIe bIue sky
Iike a mat of cornfIowers...
space and stiIIness and siIence.
The sea.
And then her arms dried,
and her mouth--
crystaIs in the sun.
''Spunshon...''
''Had she seen it before?''
she said.
Una did not remember.
She turned
back to the Iand again...
and saw on the beach
through her tears...
a unicorn pawing
in the moonIight.
You see, Cathryn?
It was easy.
Go away!
I kiIIed you!
Not me, Cathryn.
Not me.
''Unicorn,'' WiIIow whispered...
and she stretched up
her arms to it...
whiIe tears
streamed down her cheeks.
''Unicorn, good-bye,
and thank you.
''Thank you for being mine.''
And the unicorn dipped its horn
tiII it touched the snow...
and watched them gaIIop...
away, away...
down the Iane, out of sight...
and it turned and ran swiftIy
into the forest.
And then Ancient picked up
a nice, fat voIume...
and put it on the tabIe...
and in big, spidery writing,
he wrote...
''In Search of Unicorns.''
The end.