♪ While there is still
a heart that loves ♪
♪ While he still
listens to prayers ♪
♪ Our love would never die ♪
♪ Her paradise will
be too tired to wait ♪
♪ No tears should ever fall ♪
♪ There's nothing we cannot do ♪
♪ Because our love is sacred ♪
♪ A love that is immortal ♪
♪ Our love would never die ♪
♪ Even if paradise
gets tired to wait ♪
♪ No tears should ever fall ♪
♪ There's nothing we cannot do ♪
♪ There is no love
sacred than ours ♪
It's a girl.
Child.
She's healthy.
A healthy baby boy.
This is truly the biggest
miracle for us, Joseph.
We have waited for a long time.
We always prayed.
Our prayers were answered, Joseph.
Will we name him after the
name we have talked about before?
Your father's name?
Yes.
Nicholas Perez.
Alonso-Lopez.
I hope to live to see
him become a doctor.
He needs to pursue
the tradition of the Alonso-Lopez.
Famous doctors.
In San Miguel.
Aunt Is hang?
I will name her Alexandra.
I truly regret that her
father won't see her.
I regret it.
Never mind, Natalia.
Besides,
he can see you.
Especially now that you
even named the child after him.
At my age now,
who would think I
would still bear a child?
But Alex...
He didn't know that I was already
carrying his baby when he died.
Alexandra.
You were given to me by God.
When you grow up,
it is only Him
that you will serve.
You want your only
child to be a nun?
Please look at the camera.
Hold it.
He's such a beautiful child.
Really took after his godfather,
right, friend?
He didn't took
after his godfather,
he looks so much like his mother.
You know her?
No.
I'll have the child listed.
Sister Alexandra?
Yes, Mother?
A telegram came for you
before the evening prayer.
You will go home to San Miguel.
Why?
Your mother died.
Let's pray for her soul.
It's done.
Thank you.
Okay, sister.
We'll go ahead now.
- We're going now.
- Sister, we'll go ahead now.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Mother?
Be careful.
Let's pray the rosary first.
In the name of the Father, of
the Son, of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Dear Sisters,
The bodies of Father Fermin, and
Doctor Reynoso were already found.
They were buried
in a shallow grave,
in the northern portion
of Mount Banaag.
Let us include in our prayers,
the innocent
victims of the rebels.
The attainment of peace,
and order in our country.
Let us remember,
most especially...
Father Fermin.
Sister Alexandra?
Sister!
Paging Doctor San till an.
You have a telephone
call on station four.
Doctor a San till an.
Telephone call on station four.
Looks like you're so serious,
about the patient in room 601.
Is it because she's a nun?
Well...
It's time for her medications.
You want to give her any message?
Rose, can I do it myself?
Sure.
Doctor Lagman, please proceed to...
Ronnie!
What's the meaning.
Nothing.
How do you feel, Sister?
I'm okay.
Thank you.
You're from...
San Miguel too.
It's my hometown too, Sister.
I read it from your records.
And...
It's a coincidence.
We have the same birthday.
Excuse me.
I'm not finished with my prayer.
We met once.
At the cemetery.
In San Miguel.
I learned from the
grave keepers that
it was your mother who
you were burying then.
It's Mrs. Natalia Avila?
Sister?
By the way, I'm Nicholas.
Alonso-Lopez.
Your family is well-known there.
Famous doctors.
Why didn't you become one?
Why only a nurse?
Why?
I offered to be the one
to give your medicines.
I took the task from
my friend, the nurse,
who's in duty now.
Sister Alexandra?
After two years,
I will become a doctor.
Good night.
Hey, Nick, is that for me?
Sorry.
Not for you.
Don't tell me...
For my friend.
I'm so jealous of her.
I want to be a nun too.
Sister Alexandra?
Thank you.
Nick, please, don't.
Are you going straight
home to Santa Inez?
Aren't you afraid of that town?
There are a lot of rebels there.
One of our professors,
Doctor Reynoso,
was kidnapped,
became a hostage and then...
was killed.
Nick?
Thank you.
Thank you for this.
Sister.
I'll take those.
Okay.
We'll be going now.
Is that the patron
given by Sir Felipe?
Yes.
That image is St. Miguel.
And we call the other
one, is St. Martin.
Alright, attorney.
I really love it here in
your hometown, dude.
What if...
I live here?
I'll practice law here.
If you want,
you can get me as,
your Legal Adviser.
The retainer's fee...
You're not even listening to me.
I've noticed, you're
so preoccupied.
What if you're operating
on my abdomen,
and you'd leave your
instruments inside me.
Hey, bro?
I said, you're so preoccupied.
Yes.
I don't know what's
happening to me.
I'm in love.
I'm terribly in love.
What's wrong with that?
Nothing's wrong with that.
And that's why,
give me your first advice.
I am...
Deeply in love.
With a nun.
That's heavy.
What will I do?
Tell me.
Nick...
There are a lot of other
women in the world.
And you chose a nun?
Excuse me.
Nick?
Your mom is asking for you.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Mom?
Yes, Mom?
Nicholas, my son.
I want to ask you something.
What is it, Mom?
I hope...
Before I die,
I'd see even a...
grandchild with you.
Even for just one.
Mom, don't talk like that.
You're just 66 years old.
You're still strong.
You'd see all of
your grandchildren.
I'm too old to expect.
Tell me the truth, Nicholas.
Don't you have any
girlfriend until now?
Nicholas?
I just want to become a
full pledged doctor first.
It's just another two years.
You haven't really
found anyone yet?
Don't lie to me.
I have.
Don't worry,
when she accepts me,
I'll bring her to you right away.
I just want to give
you an advice, my son.
I hope...
The woman you'd marry,
is...
the one whom you really love.
Even if she's poor,
I hope she's religious.
Because for me,
she'd become a good wife,
if she's religious.
- Good morning, Sister.
- Good morning.
I would like to see
your Mother Superior.
Yes, she's inside. I'll call her.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for
your donations, doctor.
These medicines will
truly help a lot of people.
If you want, Mother,
we could be there,
when you give it out.
So we could also give
free clinic at the barrio too.
God Bless you, doctor!
By the way, Mother,
the hospital wanted
me to give something,
to a nun here. Some X-ray plates.
It's Sister...
Sister Alexandra.
Avila?
How are you?
I'm fine.
Here are your x-ray plates.
Nothing to worry about.
Just a mild case of peptic ulcer.
Just avoid eating acidic foods.
Thank you.
Sister?
Alexandra?
I hope you can join us in
giving free clinic to the barrio.
Let's see each other again.
Sixty-five.
What's your name?
Corazon Sanchez.
Hold this carefully.
Give him some water.
You need any help?
Forty-nine.
Okay, raise the beam.
I think this is better.
Yes.
Dear Nick,
God has not yet given me the sign
I'm asking from Him.
So I cannot make any decisions
regarding the two of us.
The sign will remove all my doubts
and fears and guilt too.
If ever I receive it,
this will also confirm,
that should I abandon
the Holy Vocation,
we really are
meant for each other.
Have patience and faith too.
Yours, Sandra.
Sandra...
Leave the convent.
It is not your vocation.
You are for me.
And I am for you.
Nick.
One question, one answer...
Do you love me or not?
- What?
- I love you!
I love you, Nick.
Wow!
So, you're not going
to take your vows.
You don't need the
dispensation from Rome because,
you're not a fully
pledged nun yet.
Sister Alexandra...
Why?
I'm getting married, Mother.
Does that man really love you?
I'm sure, Mother.
How about you, Alexandra?
Do you love him?
I love him very much, Mother.
May God always guide you, my dear.
Thank you so much to all of you.
I have learned so much here.
And I will never waste any of it.
I'll be going now.
Alexandra?
You can ride with us.
We'll just be dropping
by the health center
then we'll bring
you to San Miguel.
- Thank you, Mother.
- Let's go.
Good morning to you.
What's the meaning of this?
Where are the doctors,
who were with you at your
medical mission at the barrio?
They're not with us
now. Who are you?
I'm Anton.
The leader of the
N.P.A. in this province.
What do you want from us?
Medicines.
Perfect timing.
You're coming with us,
and help treat our wounded men.
Get down!
I only hitched a ride.
You're coming too.
Get down!
Andoy!
Berting!
Come.
The medicines.
Bring everything!
Stop!
My condolences.
Condolence.
Excuse me.
Nick?
My condolences.
I'm sorry.
I just knew about it.
Good evening, mayor.
Good evening.
Mayor!
Good evening, sir.
Mayor is here.
Mayor, good evening,
Nick, condolence.
Ivan, this is Attorney
Leo San till an.
How are you, mayor?
I'm good.
By the way, Nick.
This is Natashia.
And her sister, Vanya.
They both grew up in the States.
But we also live here.
Hello.
Condolence.
And this is Leo.
Hi.
How do you do?
Nick, you may have
forgotten my brother, Eric.
Hi. Condolence.
You know, Nicholas.
Attorney San till an.
Nobody would equal the
beauty of the Quint an a sisters,
here in San Miguel.
I'm sorry, Nicholas.
Wait.
Leo?
Do you visit San Miguel often?
Nick always brings me here, mayor.
Especially during
the fiesta season.
It's better here in town.
Peaceful.
The problem is at the barrios.
The ones far from here.
Because of the rebels?
The entire P.C. detachment.
Sketchy reports reaching
the station also indicated
that the rebel suffered
heavy casualties.
Hours later,
the same group abducted six nuns,
all from the order of the
Daughters of Virgin Mary.
They were identified as.
Mother Superior Benedict a Reyes,
Sister Felecita Sings on,
Sister Josefina Ocampo,
Sister Teresita Mendoza,
Sister Harlinda Montefalco,
and Sister Alexandra Avila.
The nuns were on their way to deliver
medicines to the indigent families...
I do not subscribe
to your ideology!
In this life,
there is no perfect organization,
and nobody's perfect!
But we can live this
life without the killings.
Don't tell me your
organization is perfect.
Your religion.
Your group.
But our organization
believes in the value of
the life of a person.
You know, Mother...
You shouldn't have become a nun.
You could've been
a priest.
You're good at giving sermons.
Go with them at their
sleeping quarters.
I'm not involved in what
you're arguing about.
I implore you,
Anton.
Anton, I am begging you.
I just got involved.
I'm not one of them anymore.
When you stopped our vehicle,
I just hitched a ride.
I was already going home then.
I was already out.
Anton, I implore you.
Someone's waiting for me.
I don't want to be here!
You will like it here.
What?
Sister, Ivan is here.
Ivan!
Natashia! You're so pretty!
And mayor is here too.
- Happy birthday!
- Thank you!
Give me that.
Here.
This is from the both of us.
Why are you late?
I had tons of work
at the city hall.
Attorney Tobias is here too.
- Mayor!
- Friend!
He has done a lot for you.
And he's Attorney Tobias.
Yes, I know him.
Nick!
Hi!
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you!
- Natashia, happy birthday.
- Thank you.
- Sorry, we're late.
- It's okay.
I had to pick him up.
I don't have a car.
It's good you made it.
Come on.
Ivan is here.
It's Nick and Attorney.
- Ivan.
- Nick!
No, thank you.
By the way, Nick.
We're waiting for your reply.
You haven't received
the letter yet?
You're going to be the new
Municipal Health Officer.
Congratulations, Nick!
Can I be your first patient?
Salsa!
Travolta!
Cha-Cha!
Cha-cha!
So, shall we start dancing?
Nick?
Okay, let's start.
Excuse us.
- What?
- Nick. Look at Natashia carefully.
Mayor!
You're still a good dancer.
You look good together.
She looks better with Ivan.
- No. They're just very good friends.
- It's just like this.
And...
It's hard to wait for nothing.
Nick?
It's more than a year that
you've wasted waiting for Sandra.
Wow.
Why don't you
accept the possibility
that she may be dead now?
Your life would be a
waste if you'd still love her.
While...
Natashia is right there.
And...
She likes you.
How can you be sure?
I just know it!
And I know that you know it
too. Don't bother denying it!
Nick?
Believe me.
You look so good together.
Sorry!
If you're going to cooperate
with the government,
we could give you amnesty.
Two more, major.
Can you show us where
they buried the five
nuns that was kidnapped
by Anton at Santa Ines?
Yes, mayor.
In the jungle.
At the foot of Mount Banaag.
Where?
Why, Nick?
She's dead.
She's gone.
Who?
She's one of them, Ivan.
Your friend?
Let's go down.
Let's go.
Natashia?
Nick?
Who are you thinking about?
Who is that woman?
She's dead.
Sometimes,
I can remember her.
But...
It's natural, isn't it?
She's the past.
Even her name,
her story,
and our relationship.
Why should I be insecure
with someone who's dead?
Natashia?
Never ever compete with
someone who's already dead.
Don't worry,
I promise you.
From this day on,
I will forget about her.
When do you want to get married?
Doctor?
Doctor, Mayor is downstairs and,
wanted to wake you
up for an emergency.
Sorry, Nick. This is urgent.
An encounter happened
at "Mat a as na Kahoy".
Major Relano fought Anton's group.
A woman got wounded
in the crossfire.
And she's critical.
Please check her.
She asked for my protection.
Over here, Nick.
Help doctor!
How long did the
gunfight last, major?
About three hours.
It started at ten o'clock until...
around 1 AM.
It's a good thing it
wasn't that critical.
No bones got hit.
But it's better,
if she can be
brought to a hospital.
So she can fully recover there.
Can we transport her?
Yes, it's possible.
Bugarin!
Sir?
Call an ambulance right away.
Yes, sir.
I think, Major,
we'd have peace around here now.
Especially now that Anton is dead,
and his group is gone.
He gave us a real hard time.
He's too slick.
Excuse me.
I'll just check the patient.
♪ While there is still
a heart that loves ♪
Nick?
You're safe now.
Take your time to rest.
Nick, help me.
I don't want to go
back to the jungle.
Help me.
Hide me from Anton.
You don't have to
be afraid anymore.
He's dead now.
He was killed in the encounter.
Don't leave me.
Have pity on me.
Help me.
Don't leave me.
- Don't leave me.
- Yes.
- ♪ There's nothing we can't do ♪
♪ Because our love is sacred ♪
♪ A love that is immortal ♪
A lot has changed with me, Nick.
Anton took me.
Even if it was against my will.
I fought him at first.
I'm not a virgin anymore, Nick.
My life was changed in the jungle.
I wasn't a nun anymore.
I forgot everything I
learned at the convent.
If you're at the den of animals,
you become one of them too.
Because you want to live.
When I saw people
getting hit by bullets...
People's brains exploding...
Blood everywhere.
I have forgotten about love, Nick.
That's why I forgot about you.
Sandra?
But when I saw your face,
my mind became clear again.
Suddenly, I remembered
that there's still love.
Nick?
Before we got ambushed
and taken to the mountains,
I already left the vocation.
I already made my farewell
with Mother Superior.
I was on my way to
our meeting place.
Nick?
Do you still love me?
In a few...
In a few days, you can
check out from here.
Are you married now?
Hi, Nick.
Hi, Ivan.
Come in.
How's our patient doing?
Sandra?
Thank you.
Why?
Nothing.
Sandra, I have good news for you.
What is it?
The military released
your clearance.
They're convinced that,
you're just a victim,
and not one of them.
Thank you, Mayor.
You can call me Ivan.
Good afternoon, doctor.
Where's Sandra?
She's in her room. Come in.
Come in.
The doctor is here.
I'm feeling so much better now.
I've recovered.
Why did you come here?
Ivan called me.
He asked me to check you.
One final check up.
But even if he didn't ask me to,
I'd still come and see you.
Sandra?
Leave now.
We don't have
anything to talk about.
Why did you come here?
And where would I go?
I'm alone, Nick.
I can't go back to
the convent anymore.
Because once you get out of there,
that's it.
Once you turn your
back on that kind of life,
it ends there.
Sandra?
I'll take you far away from here.
Nick?
Anywhere.
In another province.
In Manila. Up North.
As long as it's far
from San Miguel.
What would happen to me?
What would I do with my life?
If you're going to marry
me, why go far away?
Sandra?
We'll live together.
Not married?
You're a bastard, Nick.
You have changed.
You're right.
Two years is a long time.
But Sandra, I still love you.
No, Nick!
You don't love me.
Because if you really love me,
you'd never make me your mistress.
If you really love me,
you would leave the woman
you promised to marry.
You know about.
Yes, I know everything!
Ivan and Eric told me
everything about you and Natashia.
If you really love me,
you can leave that woman.
It would be chaos, Sandra.
And yet we can...
just live together in secret
and nobody has to know.
Leave now.
Sandra!
Nick!
I know the reason why
you don't want to marry me.
You can't accept that
I had someone else.
That I'm not the Alexandra,
whom you knew then.
It's you who changed, Nick.
Not me.
You really don't love me at all.
Natashia is pregnant.
Congratulations, Nick!
- Ma'am!
- Thank you!
Best wishes.
Thank you!
Nick? Congratulations.
Best wishes!
Congratulations.
Natashia! Best wishes.
Best wishes.
Thank you!
Thank you.
Sandra and I have plans too.
- We'll be getting married soon.
- Really?
Congratulations!
Well, it's about time, Ivan.
So that San Miguel
would have a First Lady.
Mayor.
- Congratulations!
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Mayor, I thought
you'd never get married.
Oh, my!
Mister Crispin!
- Thank you.
- Come in.
Ivan.
Thank you.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Congratulations.
Congratulations, mayor.
Thank you, Leo.
Mayor?
It's all over that you're running
again in the next elections.
Probably.
- But not yet sure.
- Who's there?
Well...
- Good luck!
- Hey, Auntie!
Nick, I'm going to
Aunt Amparo, okay?
- Wow.
- Thank you very much.
It's already seven months.
- Really?
- It's so fast. Here's Nick.
You may have a boy.
Thank you, Leo.
- Friend!
- Hey!
How are you?
- Thank you.
- I'm good.
- Hello?
- Are they there?
- They're inside.
- They're waiting for you.
Come on, and let's see them.
To whom did that come from?
From Nick and Natashia.
I'm sorry.
It's alright, Ivan.
You may be just tired.
We had a lot of visitors earlier.
How's Manila?
- This one too.
- It's too rowdy there.
Nothing has changed
from 1972 to 1985.
I mean, if it's just
about the politics.
Or are you joining
the demonstrations?
And the rallies, then
neglect your studies.
Of course not!
So, how's the...
first lady of San Miguel?
Ma'am Alexandra.
I pity that woman.
Up to now accepting her by
Ivan's relatives is a struggle.
The whole Recelis
clan spits at her.
Well, that would happen since Eric's
clan is from genuine aristocrats.
Of course, they don't
want fakes like Sandra.
Not only that, Vanya.
Imagine, up to now,
she's not pregnant.
Unlike me, I'm on my
second at my fifth month.
If I didn't have a
miscarriage then,
Ivan and Sandra
would die of jealousy.
Why don't we eat outside?
Let's drop by at Nick's
office at the city hall.
Just give me ten
minutes to take a shower.
Okay.
Just watch some movies
with the betamax, if you want.
Let me see the tapes.
Vanya!
Sister?
Don't cry.
It's the second, Nick.
I don't understand
why they don't survive.
What if we don't have
a child anymore, Nick?
You don't have any problem.
You had the miscarriage
due to an accident.
So, Natashia, next time,
you should be more careful.
The D.T.I would take care of
the honorarium for the
requisition of
resource persons, trainors,
and workshops here in our town.
A lot of our fellowmen would
benefit from your plans, mayor.
And I am confident
that would give
you a lot of votes,
in the upcoming elections.
Just the right time, mayor.
The political party supports you,
to be a candidate for governor.
Excuse me.
Have some coffee.
There's orange there too.
Good day.
This is for you.
Thank you.
By the way, mayor.
Later this three in the afternoon,
a delegation will come to you.
They're from San Vicente
and from San Cristobal.
How many are they?
Around thirty.
It would be best if you
have them prepare dinner.
I'll take care of it.
Okay.
I'll go ahead.
I'll see you.
How are you?
Fine.
And you?
Good.
How's Natashia?
Is...
Is Ivan in his office already?
He has...
visitors actually.
I need you.
Let's meet.
I would really
love to talk to you.
In another place.
Are you happy with Ivan?
If I am, I won't be here.
You know, Nick.
We've been married
for more than two years,
but nothing is still happening.
He has a problem, Nick.
What problem?
He's impotent.
You?
You and Natashia...
Are you happy?
I was forced.
Since I got her pregnant.
Sandra, when I lost you,
my world was in chaos.
There were times when,
I didn't know what
was right or wrong.
I was so lonely then, Sandra.
And she was there.
But I always had that feeling
that you and I will
end up together.
I love you, Nick.
I love you, too.
I wasn't able to go home right away
after shopping since I felt weak.
Too tired, I guess.
Sweetheart?
That's all for you.
Do you like it?
Eric, is that size okay for you?
The size is perfect!
That's a different
brand, but it's the latest.
Thank you.
Ivan?
Don't worry.
The money I used for this,
is from my savings and allowances,
that you gave me for two years.
This is not government money.
By the way,
I had caps and
jackets custom made.
We'll wear it at the
campaign for the elections.
And this came from my money too.
So, when you're already governor,
you'd refund
everything I spent today.
Just kidding.
All you thought about was
me when you were in Manila.
That's what you think, brother.
What do you mean?
I was also part of it.
Just look at this.
Sandra still remembered me.
She bought a lot.
Thank you.
Rest now,
before we have dinner.
Ivan?
I wanted to ask your permission.
Will you allow me again?
I'm sorry but I don't want you
to think that I love doing this.
But you know...
I wanted to have a retreat.
Spiritual retreat, Ivan.
I just don't know which convent
which is at Santa
Inez, or Santa Rosario.
Or in Manila?
You know.
I need this retreat very badly.
And it's perfect timing.
When I get back,
your campaign starts.
Just a minute.
Why are you being
so formal about it?
Well...
I'm talking to the next
governor of this province.
When are you leaving then?
Last Friday of this month.
How many days will you be gone?
Four.
Five days, the most.
Where is that conference?
Bacolod.
Can I come?
No.
Your diastolic is high.
Even if you'd go to Manila,
I wouldn't let you come.
More so in the province.
Bacolod is very far.
And...
You're almost due to give birth.
This is your third.
I need this baby.
Yes, doc.
You're having frequent
conferences recently.
And most of it, is out of town.
I can't do anything around
the house. I'm so bored already.
And we don't talk much now, Nick.
When you're here in San Miguel,
you're always busy.
If you're not at the provincial hospital,
you're at the clinic in city hall.
I miss you so much
already, you know.
You're so corny.
Well, cope with that since I've
watched all the drama with the betamax.
Ouch.
Our baby really kicks hard.
Maybe it's a boy.
It doesn't matter
if it's a boy or girl,
as long as it's alive.
What if I suddenly give
birth and you're in Bacolod?
Your due date is next month.
You know better than I do.
But I'm the doctor here.
I love you, Nick.
Alexandra.
You should wear bikini.
Dude, wear bikini, okay?
We should go back
here, it's beautiful.
Mike? I thought it was Jake?
Let's swim before we eat, okay?
Let's swim first!
You're going to eat again?
You're such a glutton!
You're a show off!
You always pick on me.
Nick!
What are you doing here?
But brother, what
are you doing here?
Me?
I'm just relaxing,
before I go home to San Miguel.
Actually, I'm heading
home in a while.
Why aren't you eating your
breakfast with Sister yet?
It's already late!
Who is that.
Them? They're my friends
from the boarding house.
The cutest among them
is my newest boyfriend.
It's really great that
you're here with Sister,
I'd like you to meet him.
Okay?
And you know,
he's smart! Much nicer than Eric.
And his sense of humor,
is much like yours!
You'd be laughing.
Ma'am Recelis?
Shit! You're together?
Shit!
Let's go home! Hurry!
Now we have a problem.
You bastard!
You cheater!
You've been fooling
me all this time!
That damn Alexandra!
Screw you two!
Damn you!
Natashia?
What you're doing,
is really bad for your condition.
You must be careful with our.
You bastard!
You don't even deserve
to be the father of my child!
What else do you want to happen?
- A lot has happened.
- Don't deny it!
Don't try and make
my sister a big liar!
I will let the whole of
San Miguel know that
the mayor's wife and my husband.
Let's avoid the scandal!
And now you're afraid
of your own ghost?
Eric?
Him and your damn sister-in-law!
And my husband!
Eric!
That's enough! That's enough!
She has been doing
that to you for some time.
And you'd just let her?
And your best friend betrayed you.
You didn't see anything,
you never heard anything,
and you don't know anything.
Brother, I can't understand you.
Because you're stupid.
What do you want me to do?
Kill Nick?
Kill Sandra?
- Yes!
- And then what?
I would go to jail.
Our name would be ruined.
My dreams would be destroyed.
Eric?
The person in front of you now,
someday would become the
president of the Philippines.
Brother?
You're crazy!
Are you going to eat now, ma'am?
I'll wait for Ivan.
Hi, handsome.
I heard that,
you've been working
hard preparing for
the campaign of your brother Ivan.
Eric, you're not done eating.
I suddenly felt ill.
I feel like I'm about to vomit.
Are you sick?
Bitch!
Ma'am?
Mrs. Lopez is here.
Let her in.
Please come in, Mrs. Lopez.
Natashia? It's good to see you.
You're almost due.
Come and have a seat.
You're so insensitive.
The whole province
is talking about you,
and yet, you show
yourself in public.
If you still have
enough dignity left,
why don't you just
leave this town!
You stole my husband!
Leave now.
You should leave!
You should be
embarrassed with this family!
Don't tell me what I have to do.
You have nothing
to do with my life.
I do. And it's big.
You stole Nick.
The man you stole
just so happened to be my husband.
Aren't you satisfied with one man?
Who else, Alexandra?
Who else do you bed in this town?
Are you leaving or not?
Or do you want me
to call the police?
You're a nymphomaniac!
You don't have evidence.
My sister saw you
and Vanya never lies.
Tell me every insult you want,
but I will never stoop
down to your level.
Natashia?
You're educated and all but,
you're so disrespectful.
All you say are filth.
I pity you.
Since you have done everything,
and yet, your
husband can't take you.
You're really a bitch!
Bitch?
Why aren't you
married to Nick yet?
You're just pregnant.
You bitch!
Natashia, please?
Ivan!
Open your eyes!
Please leave.
What kind of man are you?
You're tolerating
what this woman did?
She's disgusting!
She should be thrown
out of this house, Ivan!
Natashia, you're wrong.
My wife is clean.
It's just one of the black
propagandas of my enemies in politics.
They're trying to ruin me.
And you're being carried away by
news made by rumor
mongers here in San Miguel.
And most of all,
you're being like that because,
you're so jealous.
But you don't even
have any evidence.
Alright.
Give me proof.
And I will believe
everything you say,
against my beloved wife.
Your wife has betrayed you,
and you choose to be blind?
You will regret this, Ivan.
What will I do, bro?
You know, Nick...
If I were you,
I will forget Sandra.
Not because of Natashia.
But because of your child.
Give your child a break.
Have pity on him.
Imagine,
he's not even born yet,
and his life is in shambles.
Because of another woman.
Look, Nick.
For the sake of your child,
forget her.
It's very obvious.
You're not meant for each other.
A good evening to all of you,
my beloved fellowmen!
I don't know how to promise,
that's why I want to
go straight to the point.
I swear to all of you,
if you will elect me,
as your governor,
I will take care of
our whole province.
I will watch over the welfare,
of each and every one of you.
I will monitor
the peace,
and order,
of each barrio,
and town of our province.
My beloved fellowmen,
I will watch over,
everyone of you!
You will watch over us?
You can't even
watch over your wife!
Watch over your wife!
My beloved fellowmen,
let's not give them attention,
since they're from
the other party and
they just want to
ruin this campaign.
What's that?
Ma'am is leaving.
You're not leaving.
I beg of you.
Stay here.
Let's show all the people that there's
nothing bad happening between us.
That you're not betraying
me with another man.
That we love each other.
Ivan, I'm so ashamed for you.
I've done you wrong.
I really don't deserve you.
Please, I implore you.
I beg you.
I'll go down on my knees,
and I will take everything.
Even if they call me names,
and whatever, but please, Sandra?
Please forgive me, Ivan.
Let me leave.
Sandra, you will not leave me.
Set me free, Ivan.
Sandra. I'm begging you.
Ivan, don't!
You will not leave me!
Sandra, I love you!
Brother, don't!
Ma'am?
- Mayor!
- Ma'am!
Ma'am!
- What happened?
Hurry!
Let's take them to the hospital!
Let's take them!
Ma'am!
Where are you going?
Natashia! Stop it!
Ivan died!
I'm coming with you! I
want to see my friend!
Don't!
In your condition,
it would be bad for you.
Nick! Let's see him later!
When he's finally buried.
You're not leaving!
I want to see Eric!
Natashia! You heard the news!
In the news!
Eric is in a state of shock!
Damn it!
You're just making
up these reasons!
You're just going to see
that woman in the hospital!
I'm coming with you!
What else do you need from her?
I thought,
we've talked about this!
That you're going
to forget about her!
And you'd never see her again?
Why do you still need to see her?
Nick, what?
You're really crazy!
Alexandra doesn't
need you anymore!
Hey!
If it's because of the doctor,
there's a lot of better doctors
in the hospital of San Miguel!
Nick, please! Let's go home!
Turn this car around, Nick!
I'm warning you!
If you don't listen
to me, you'll regret it!
Nick, what?
What else do you
need from that whore?
Nick!
Aren't you going to
wait for Doctor Liwanag?
Not anymore.
I'm leaving so please
tell her thank you.
Yes, Mrs. Recelis.
Nurse?
I'm not Mrs. Recelis anymore.
Miss Avila.
♪ I only knew you for a while ♪
♪ But I never saw your smile ♪
Alex!
Why are you late?
Hi!
Alex! Sweetheart!
This is Alex, my best friend.
We also live together.
Alex?
Alex.
She's a woman.
Hey!
Alex.
Why, old man?
What were you
thinking? I'm a trans?
Since I have a boy's name?
I'm sorry.
I don't go to Manila often.
Olga, what mountain did
your boyfriend come from?
I don't know! Sweetheart?
What's the name of your town?
- San Rafael.
- San Rafael!
It's so quiet there, no disco.
And there's no women like.
Women like what?
Say it straight! No whores.
Alex, please!
What drinks do you want?
♪ Be brave ♪
♪ no matter where I go. ♪
Gin tonic double.
Okay.
- Hey!
- Yes, sir?
How about that girl?
That girl over there.
How much should I pay for her?
Five.
Three?
No, five.
There's no discount?
- No.
- Okay. Call her.
Okay.
Alex?
Customer. With lots of money.
Where?
There.
He may be stingy, like the
one you gave me last night.
He's good.
Come on.
He even negotiated five thousand.
Are you hungry?
It won't take long.
Alex, don't do that!
You haven't had your coffee yet.
You're drinking
all kinds of medication.
Olga, if it wasn't for
this, I wouldn't get up.
You know the time will come,
and your body would pay for that.
Okay, fine, Olga.
Tell me the reason
why I have to stay alive.
I'm all alone in this world.
And always unlucky.
Unlucky with love,
men, and career.
I think I'm the most
unlucky person in the world.
And you, Olga, you have a child.
Though you're apart,
you have the
greatest reason to live.
And what do I have?
I think the heavens loathe me.
Let's talk about something else.
Let's be both thankful and up to now
we're still alive, and breathing.
And not all people are evil.
You're just saying that, because
of that old man courting you.
I don't know if he would be
good with his promise to you.
That he would marry you.
That he'll love you
though you're a whore.
You know Olga, all men are pigs.
Last night, I was with a pig!
I think he's the most
extreme of all pigs!
Alex? A job. Looks rich.
Filipino?
White or black?
Over there.
Wow!
Wow, wow!
Don't mind him.
Okay, Alex. I'll be at the lobby.
Come in.
Sandra?
Good luck, Olga.
I hope your life would
be better in San Rafael.
I hope you'd marry a good person.
Thank you, Alex.
Promise me.
If you need me,
you know where to find me.
Thank you.
Are you sick?
This is nothing.
I'll call a doctor.
Or I could bring
you to the hospital.
I think I'll just
postpone my trip.
You need someone with you.
Don't bother.
No, Olga. Just do
what you have to.
Olga?
I'm pregnant.
- Who's the.
- I don't know.
I don't know which one those men.
I'm really so unlucky,
and now I have this.
Don't you want that?
You'd have a child, finally!
You'd have a reason to live for.
I'd have a child but
never know his father.
It's still so unlucky.
Don't be so negative.
That child could change your luck!
Maybe because of him,
your life would
take a different turn.
That may be my ride.
Is Alexandra Avila here?
Sandra?
Sandra.
You're coming with me.
Ever since you were gone,
I transferred to San Gabriel.
It's quiet there, Sandra.
Nobody would meddle with our life.
And one more thing,
nobody could come
between us anymore.
Natashia is gone.
I'm free now, Sandra.
Nick...
You wouldn't want me anymore.
I'll marry you!
Nick...
Whatever you are!
Whatever you are,
I will accept you!
We can change all of this!
Nick, we're not meant for
each other, you know that.
From the very beginning,
we're always being separated.
Not anymore.
Nick, I'm so ashamed.
I can't help you
become a better person.
I would also be a burden to you!
Sandra.
My third baby with
Natashia survived.
I want you to become the mother,
of my child.
And my future children.
I hope,
we can start again.
I love you.
I love you, too.
Alexandra.
This is the house.
Leo, take it from here?
Okay.
Oh, you see, there's Daddy.
- Say, "Hello, Daddy."
- Basil. Come.
Basil, this is Sandra.
Sandra. This is Basil.
Hello.
Cervical cancer.
That's what you have.
You said you have been
feeling this for a long time.
You should've had it checked then.
Do you have history
of cancer in your family?
My mom died of cancer.
What should I do now, doctor?
Well, you may
undergo chemo therapy.
Hormone therapy.
Operation.
But the bottom line of this,
is just the same.
Sandra?
Why?
Nothing.
Is there a problem?
Nothing, Nick.
Don't you feel well?
Why don't you tell me?
I told you, it's nothing!
Sandra?
Did something happen
to your trip to Santa Inez?
With your retreat at the convent?
Tell me, Sandra!
I can't understand you.
We're together now.
We're enjoying it.
We're happy.
Is it that up to now you
don't believe that I don't
care about your past?
Is the wedding your problem?
Are you afraid that.
I won't live up to
my promises to you?
Don't worry, Sandra.
First thing tomorrow,
we'll prepare our wedding.
I love you so much, Nick.
Okay, be careful.
You might get hurt.
Okay, go up.
Slowly.
- Nick! Let's eat.
- Be careful.
Alright.
Has Sandra
eaten too?
I haven't seen her yet.
Dear Nick,
I'm sorry. I just have to leave.
I can't tell you the reason.
Not yet.
But always remember that
I love you very much. Sandra.
He's really kind, Alex.
I just regret
that after two months, he died.
Sometimes I think about
you always say back then.
You're unlucky.
Then I say, we're just the same.
Here I am.
A widower again.
But if I think about the
properties he left behind,
like this house.
I tell myself that I
guess I'm lucky enough.
It's a good thing you
came here in San Rafael.
It's quiet here and
the people are kind.
Thank you.
Tania. Please bring
her things inside.
Okay.
Come on, go to sleep.
Don't worry, I won't leave you.
Alex, why didn't you just
tell Nick about everything?
About your pregnancy,
and your illness.
He'd help you.
I love Nick, Olga.
I don't want him to see me
suffering because of my sickness.
I don't want Nick
to see the time...
When I die.
Alex?
What I want is,
even if I'm gone,
I would still be alive in him.
Most of all, I don't
want him to get hurt.
Since what I have right now,
is my child with another man.
Tell him...
Tell him that I really love him.
Nick.
Nick. Tell.
Tell him that I love him.
That's why.
She doesn't want me to be unhappy.
She doesn't want me to get hurt.
She loves you, Nick.
Up to the last moment of her life,
your name is what she said.
She wants you to have her.
Nick?
Love that child the
same way you love her.
Treat her as your own.
What's her name?
Lara.
Basil?
This is Lara.
Watch over her.
- Embrace her.
- Watch over her.
- Slowly.
- Love her, okay?
Love her.
You sit down.
Sit down.
Protect her.
And don't hurt her.
Here's your baby.
Nice baby.
Careful.
Basil, this is your baby sister.
Love her, okay?
When did she die?
Last Saturday.
When was she buried?
Yesterday.
Why didn't you tell me?
She was adamant
with her instructions
to contact you for Lara,
only after her burial.
Where did you bury her?
I'm sorry!
- Gilbert?
- Hi, doctor.
Uncle Leo.
Basil!
It seems his birthday
party is happier now,
compared to last year.
Why are you late?
I had to do an
emergency operation.
I needed to do by-pass
with one of my patients.
Where's Dad?
He's upstairs, waiting for you.
And Lara?
They're both upstairs, come on.
Bert?
Jun.
Wait.
Basil.
♪ Happy birthday, Daddy! ♪
♪ Happy birthday,
Happy birthday! ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you! ♪
Dad!
Dad?
Basil...
Dad!
Our brother Nicholas has gone,
to his rest in the
peace with Christ.
With faith and
hope and eternal life,
let us commend him to the
loving mercy of our Father.
And assist him with our prayers.
He became God's son
through baptism and was
often fed at the table of our Lord.
May the Lord now welcome him
to the table of God's
children in heaven.
And with all the sayings,
may he inherit the
promise of eternal life.
Let us also pray to the Lord
for ourselves.
May we who mourn,
be reunited one
day with our brother.
Together,
may we meet, Christ, Jesus.
When He
who is our life
shall appear...
I will adopt Lara.
This is her birth certificate.
Prepare her adoption
papers right away.
She will become an Alonso-Lopez.
Leo?
You're the only one who'd know
that Lara is not my real child.
Be careful
with this secret.
But when the time comes,
and Lara needs to know it,
as well as Basil that
they're not real siblings,
never hesitate,
tell them.
Why?
Why do they need to know?
Leo.
Love is very mystical.
True love
is everlasting.
I love you, Nick.
I love you too.
Basil and Lara.
Since you wish to contract.
Holy Matrimony,
please join your right hands,
and express your intention
before God and His church.
Lara?
Do you take Basil here, present,
for your lawful husband,
according to the Rites of
our Holy Mother the church?
Yes, I do.
Do you give yourself
to him as his wife?
Yes, I do.
Do you accept him as
your lawful husband?
Yes, I do.
Basil?
Do you take Lara here,
present for your lawful wife
according to the Rites of
our Holy Mother the church?
Yes, I do.
Do you give yourself
to her as her husband?
Yes, I do.
Do you accept her
as your lawful wife?
Yes, I do.
Wear this ring.
As a sign of my love and loyalty.
In the name of the Father and
of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
Wear this ring,
as a sign of my love and loyalty.
In the name of the Father and
of the Son and of the Holy Spirit.
♪ While he still
listens to prayers ♪
♪ Our love would never die ♪
♪ The paradise will ♪
♪ Never tire waiting ♪
♪ No tears should ever fall ♪
♪ There's nothing we cannot do ♪
♪ Because our love is sacred ♪
♪ A love that is immortal ♪
♪ Our love would never die ♪
♪ Her paradise will
be too tired to wait ♪
♪ No tears should ever fall ♪
♪ There's nothing we cannot do ♪
♪ Because our love is sacred ♪