TOEI COMPANY LTD.
IN SEARCH OF MOTHER
(Mabuta no Haha )
Planning:
HASHIMOTO Keiichi - MIMURA Keizo
Original Story: HASEGAWA Shin
Screenplay: KATO Tai
Photography: TSUBOI Makoto
Music: KINOSHITA Chuji
CAST:
NAKAMURA Kinnosuke
MATSUKATA Hiroki
OKAWA Keiko KOGURE Michiyo
NAKAHARA Hitomo
YAMAGATA Isao HARA Kensaku
NATSUKAWA Shizue NANIWA Chieko
SAWAMURA Sadako
Directed by KATO Tai
Stop!
Calm down! Listen to me!
Cut it out!
I'm severing my ties with you!
Don't be hasty!
Let me go!
Hanjiro, it was settled last
year when the boss was killed.
What good will it do for
you to start something?
What's going to happen
to my pride as a man?
What about our yakuza code of conduct?
I received my sakazuki
cup from Boss Shigezo!
I'm not like you, a traveling gambler!
What you say makes sense, but...
Have you thought about your
mother and sister back at home?
Well, have you?
I won't let my feelings about
my family get in the way!
Snap out of it!
What's so great about being a yakuza?
We're just outcasts of society.
Unlike me, who's an orphan,
you have a family and home.
Go straight!
Lead a decent life.
No!
I'm going to get revenge for the boss!
Get out of my way!
Hanjiro!
They're here.
Let me go!
Hanji! Don't die in vain!
Sukegoro! I'm here to
get revenge for my boss!
Prepare to die!
I shall assist!
Brother! You came to help!
Don't get hasty!
You have a mother and sister at home!
For their sakes, I can't let you die!
Sukegoro! Come out!
Don't worry about me.
Kill them both.
Or we'll be disgraced!
Sukegoro! Come back!
That's enough!
Enough! Let's go!
You bastards!
Okay. I'll do as you say.
My hometown, Kanamachi, is at
the other end of the crossing.
I'm an unfilial son that
didn't attend my dad's funeral.
I find it hard to go home.
Today is the day the
departed souls go home.
You can apologize to your
dead dad and your living mom.
That's true.
What are you going to do from now?
Do now...?
I'm going to Edo.
Edo?
Did you find out where your mom is?
I heard she might be in Edo.
But it's not definite.
It's worth going there.
The ferry is leaving!
I'll go to visit you one day.
Take care.
Brother...
I'll leave the money here.
Thank you.
Brother!
They must have taken the road to Mito!
Watch where you're going!
Hanjiro is from Kanamachi.
That road is a shortcut to Kanamachi.
All right, all right.
We are going there now.
Stop complaining.
We can't go back until
we kill both of them!
Anyone who defies the boss must die!
We'll kill the both of them together.
Surprise!
You scared me.
The dance is about to start.
Go and change quickly.
I can't go yet.
I will meet you there.
See? Wasn't I right?
Yes.
What is it?
Onui is going to the
dance with her loved one.
That's not true!
Who's the young man
who came this morning?
Isn't he your sweetheart?
No man came to see me.
But I saw him.
She saw him!
Come with him!
There's no one!
Hey, you!
Is this the house of Sobei in Kanamachi?
Sobei is my father,
who passed away last year.
We don't care about him.
My mother isn't home now.
The craftsmen are...
Your older brother,
Hanjiro, should be back!
We want to see him!
He left home a long time ago!
Don't give us that!
She's a pretty girl.
Be kind to her.
But Brother... She's lying!
The villagers saw Hanji!
Take it easy...
Miss, we have a letter for him.
Will you give it to him?
Hanji, we'll give you a couple of hours.
If you're a man, don't come late.
We should just storm in and kill him!
Stop.
I don't want to be accused of hurting
an old lady and girl, to get his head.
The village is having a bon dance!
We don't want to draw attention.
Let's go.
Come!
Hanji! You're trapped!
So give up!
Let's go.
Brother! What's that?
Show it to me!
It's nothing.
You can't read, so I'll read it for you.
Give it back.
Onui, give it back.
Onui!
Give it back.
Brother! This letter is...
If I were an honest man,
I could run and hide.
Brother!
I live in the yakuza world.
I'm not a man if I don't
accept their challenge.
I'll be disgraced.
Understand?
No! Don't go!
Hanjiro!
Mom.
Where are you going?
Mom, he's in trouble.
Will you read this letter?
Hanjiro...
Haven't you given me enough grief?
You finally come home ...
And you have brought
with you a bloody battle.
I'm ashamed.
But mom...
I have to fight them as a man!
Shut up!
If that's the case...
don't be a man!
I'm glad you came home.
I'll set you straight.
I'm not letting you out.
See? That's why I stopped you.
I came home to lead a straight life.
But if they're challenging me...
Are you still saying that?!
If you insist on going...
then kill me first!
Hanjiro, go inside.
Go inside.
Go inside!
Excuse me...
Is this Hanjiro's house?
I'm sorry to scare you.
Are you his younger sister?
Isn't your name Onui?
Has he said anything
about a guy named Chutaro?
He's not here!
He was disowned a long time ago!
I know that. I'm here to...
He's not here! Honestly!
He's lucky to have a loving sister like you.
I don't have time to spare.
I don't know who you are but...
Hanjiro was disowned.
He hasn't come here at all.
Please search elsewhere.
Are you his mother?
My name is Chutaro.
I'm Hanjiro's friend.
I won't cause you trouble.
Why are you here to see him,
when he's decided to go straight?
If you really are his friend,
then please leave him alone.
If he had a decent friend...
he wouldn't have gone bad like that.
I resent you men for it.
I understand.
I understand your feelings.
I will sever my ties with him.
Please rest assured.
Brother!
Hanji...
I'm envious of you for having a family.
You have no parents?
My dad died when I was 12.
I got separated from my
mom when I was five.
So I don't know what she looks like.
I don't know what it's
like to have parents.
That is why, I...
Hanji, stay in hiding for a while.
I promise to settle it with the Iioka gang.
Chutaro!
Brother!
Please let me go!
I can't let him die alone!
Don't put his kindness to naught.
I may safely escape this time,
but the persistent Iioka gang
will keep coming after me!
Brother!
Come!
You're hurting me!
Shut up!
What's the matter?
I'm coming.
Brother!
Hanji!
Get out of here!
What's the matter?
- Did they get away?
They're coming this way.
This way?
Chutaro is with him!
Hanji!
We can get rid of them at once!
Just where we want them!
Get ready!
Don't pick a fight with him,
when he's about to go straight!
Shut up! Out of our way!
That's not how it works, Miss.
If you let him go, after
he attacked our boss,
we won't be able to survive in our world.
Move!
Before we kill the both of you too!
I'm not moving!
Miss!
I'll make sure Hanji is safe!
I can't let you two get hurt!
Don't harm them.
Get them to move.
Both of you, move.
Miss, please leave!
Go!
Brother!
Hanjiro!
Hanji!
Stop it!
Come at me!
I'll be back!
I'll get you back for this!
Hanji...
Are you hurt?
I'm okay.
I'm glad...
I'm sorry for being rude to you earlier.
It's all right.
Is there any place he can hide for awhile?
Yes, he can go to my hometown.
I'll have him leave tonight.
Good.
Hanji.
Be careful now.
I don't want to go alone!
Please come with me!
Stupid!
What happened to your
decision to go straight?
You have to appreciate
your mother and sister.
What about you?
Don't worry about me.
I'm going to Edo.
I have to find my mother.
I'll kill anyone who gets in my way.
Chutaro,
do you have traveling funds?
Thank you for worrying about me.
I have 100 ryo on me.
Brother...!
How did you get so much money?
I saved it for my mother
that I'm going to meet.
Just what I need...
I'm glad you are safe.
Will you help me write something?
That's an easy request.
One, the person who killed these men is...
...from Sakata, Goshu...
...and his name is Chutaro.
Brother...
Chutaro...
What's wrong?
Go ahead and laugh at me.
I was separated from my
mother at the age of five.
And you made me think of my mother.
I feel like a kid, yearning
for his lost mother.
I'm sorry.
When I close my eyes
and think about her...
I can picture her, even
if I cant' recall her face.
EDO
I feel silly.
Old woman, change the tune.
How silly.
Play something trendy.
That's enough.
That was good.
That was fun.
Here you go.
Okay, I'm off.
Excuse me...
What is it?
Are you trying to embarrass me?
Damn you old woman!
What is it?
Aren't you going to pay her?
What?
I'm sorry.
I was going to pay her.
I'm leaving the money here.
If you'll excuse me...
How dare he pick on an old woman.
Thank you.
You needn't thank me so much.
How old?
I'm asking you for your age.
I'm fifty years old.
Do you have any children?
I had one, but I gave him away.
I don't know if he's dead or alive now.
To add to it, my husband passed away.
That is why I'm in this state.
I'm barely making a living.
What is the name of the
child you gave away?
Do you know Kotaro?!
Is his name Kotaro?
Yes!
Then I must have the wrong person.
Oh, I see.
Were you ever in Goshu
in your younger days?
No. I've been in Edo all my life.
I haven't gone beyond the Kawasaki area.
I see...
Don't be disheartened.
I'm sure your son will
come looking for you.
So don't lose hope.
Old woman...
If I see you again, I'll give you more.
But for today, I'll give you this much.
Sir, you gave me 2-shu.
Are you sure I can have all this?
Yes... take it.
Thank you very much.
I'll be drawing the lucky number!
What are you doing?
Tsuru-1961!
The lucky number is Tsuru-1961!
Are you with the Iioka gang?
Are you the boss for Sendai-ya?
Please help us.
Yes, I will do what I can.
I don't know these men,
Chutaro and Hanjiro.
Is that so...
We heard that Chutaro
was seen here in Edo.
That is why we came here.
If you're so sure...
you don't need my help.
Sukegoro also works as a cop.
It might be faster to use his connections.
Are you saying you
won't help Iioka Sukegoro?
I'm not saying that I won't help but...
I'm busy and short-handed myself.
Please leave for today.
Boss!
He's not the only boss in Edo.
There are other
gangs we can go to.
It's only a matter of time
before we find them.
That's right. We'll find them.
While our money lasts...
Let's do it ourselves.
That's impossible.
Edo is a big place.
It could take us forever.
I'm not going back until I kill those two.
Let's pay a boss to help us find them.
Excuse me!
Who are you?
I'm Kingoro.
I know every corner in Edo.
What do you want?
Edo is not your ordinary place.
Don't waste your money.
What do you want?
Why don't you pay me
a gold coin to help you?
You win again.
Ready!
Get ready!
Place your bets!
You're awfully lucky.
Can I come in?
My name is Komata Yosuke.
I'm Banba-no-Chutaro.
Have I met you before?
Sensei!
Oh, it's you, Kingoro.
Didn't you sleep with
a cheap woman last night?
So, how was it?
I didn't get much action.
She went to the bathroom
and never came back.
What woman wouldn't reject you?
You have an out-of-date look!
You should talk.
Did you lose your
money at gambling last night?
I was sliced to pieces by
this guy at the Hosokawa den.
And was mercilessly killed.
Who's the guy who walked away with all?
He's been showing up
there a lot recently...
and his name is Banba-no-Chutaro.
Sensei!
Did you just say Banba-no-Chutaro?
Yes I did. So what?
I'm in luck!
Sensei...
He's going to bring us money.
Hey...
So he goes to the Hosokawa mansion.
Let's go back there and
wait for him to show up.
Then we'll capture him.
Then what?
We can collect ten gold coins.
Sensei, and you can get half of it.
You've got a deal.
We'll need money to
play at the Hosokawa den.
What? Kingoro is here again?
Shall I tell him you are
out and turn him away?
Wait.
There's no end to this.
I'll be firm with him today.
Have him wait.
Show them to the room.
Mom, are you going to be all right?
Shall I go?
Don't worry.
I can handle a black-mailer or two.
Weren't you going shopping with Chojiro?
The rain has let up.
You should go now.
The gardener will be
bringing the flowers later.
I'm suggesting that the
two of you take a walk.
Mom.
You should let her pamper
you while you can.
Let's go.
Bye for now.
Thank you.
Madam, hello.
You never seem to age.
You look ten years
younger than your age.
You are truly pretty.
You're not getting a cent out of me today!
Don't be like that.
And don't come here again.
Is that any way to treat an old friend?
Wait a minute.
When I was working as a maid before,
you were a local punk.
But I don't remember
ever being friends with you.
Let me set the record straight.
I have influential clients.
Don't take me lightly.
Madam, this will be the last time.
I need it as a working capital.
Please give me one gold coin.
The answer is no.
Please help me out here.
Stop being persistent.
Please don't say that.
Get out!
Madam please!
Get your hands off of me!
Stay out of this!
Madam please!
Stop being persistent!
Get lost!
Throw him out.
Hands off!
Hey, Ohama...
I'm leaving for today but...
I will come to ruin it for
Otose on her wedding day!
Just remember that!
Wait!
What is it?
Excuse me.
Ohama...
Don't let any strange people inside.
Don't make a mistake here.
Get lost.
You're Kingoro.
It's me, Otora.
I used to work as a
maid with Ohama before.
Are you still saying that?
You better cut it out before you get hurt!
I will beat her up so that
she doesn't come again.
So, will you think
about that request of mine?
Ouch!
Ohama...
I apologize for showing up unexpectedly.
I haven't been feeling
well lately, so I can't work.
That is why I swallowed
my pride and came to you.
She has no friend that
is a street prostitute!
Get lost, old hag!
Get out!
Bastard!
What do you have against me?
Don't come into my territory.
You're not getting anything from her!
I will tell her you are a
villain trying to suck her dry!
Damn bitch!
Brute!
Damn hag!
Are you this old hag's son?
Why do you pick on the weak?
Shut up!
Do you see this knife?
You'll pay for this!
That's Banba-no-Chutaro!
What?
Sensei, get him!
But...
This isn't a good place to do it.
Well, keep an eye on him.
In the mean time,
I will go and get the
men who are after him.
This isn't a show. Go.
Go on.
Are you okay?
How old are you?
My age?
Are you going to ask
me for my name next?
Wait. Take out your hand.
Are you interested?
No, that's not it.
Just answer my questions.
That's your fee for listening.
I see. Ask me anything then.
I'll tell you what I know.
Are you hungry?
If you're going to treat me to something...
Pops, can I get some 'sake'?
Here.
Thanks.
Do you have a grown son?
A son?
Do you have one?
Where is he now?
If he's alive, he'd be 25...
But he died.
I'm sorry for asking.
Please forgive me.
Wait.
You're a nice man.
Everyone treats me
like trash, but not you.
It's been years since
someone treated me kindly.
Thank you.
I'll never forget your kindness.
Don't tell me that.
You seem to have your circumstances.
Who are you looking for?
I wish I could help you...
Whenever I see a woman passing by...
I think she's my...
I've been searching
for her for a year now.
But unfortunately, I haven't
been able to find her yet.
Who is she?
She's about your age.
Is she your mother?
Perhaps...
Ohama used to tell me about
her child she left back at home.
But it happened more than 15 years ago.
Where did she leave her child?
It was long ago, but...
I think she said it was Goshu.
Goshu?
Like I said, it was very long ago.
Who knows what has become of her child.
She probably has forgotten
about him completely.
Mothers aren't like that.
Ohama and I used to be very close before.
We were like sisters.
But the past few years,
she would ignore me when she
sees me, and when I go to her
for help, she'd thrown me out.
People change over time.
That may be so, but..
A parent-child relationship is special.
Many years can go by,
but it doesn't change the fact
that they are parent and child.
They have the same
blood flowing in them.
Why don't you go see her?
She may not be my mother.
That's true.
I miss my son now.
I think I will go to see him.
Are you going to visit his grave?
Buy some incense and flowers for him.
This is a gold coin!
It's not stolen money.
As you can see, I'm a yakuza.
It's not money that I worked hard for.
It's just money I won from gambling.
It's easy money.
Maybe you can start a peddling business.
That will make your son rest in peace.
This is beautiful!
I can picture the Miss
in her wedding kimono.
It was an ordeal to raise her this far.
The real challenge comes from now.
She will be the wife of Iseya,
a top cotton dealer in Edo.
I have to do my best
to keep a good reputation.
Here.
Madam, there's a man
here causing trouble.
What does he want?
Go tell them to quiet down.
Who could be causing this ruckus?
Madam, I'm sorry about the commotion.
What was it all about?
There was a man who
wanted to talk to you.
He wanted to talk to me?
All right, I'll talk to him.
I wouldn't advise you to.
He was talking to the
street prostitute earlier.
He must be in cahoots
with that prostitute.
I'll be going now.
He sounds persistent.
He sure is.
He was humble at first.
Then he showed his
true colors and got stubborn.
Show him in.
Don't meet him.
Just have him come here.
I will scold him and send him away.
Are you sure?
I'll go get him then.
Hey, the madam will meet him!
Are you sure?
I'll hear you out.
But don't drag it out.
Please excuse me.
Aren't you going to say something?
Yes... I will talk.
What is it?
Madam...
Please pardon my
rudeness for asking this.
Do you have a son about my age?
You do?
Did you leave him in Banba of Goshu?
Did you?
I know Banba very well.
So what of it?
Do you know of an inn
run by Okinagaya Chubei?
Yes, I do.
I used to live there in my younger days.
Mom!
What's with you?
Don't get strange on me!
Please forgive my rudeness.
Who are you?
I'm Chutaro.
What? You're Chutaro?
Yes!
I had a son named Chutaro,
but he passed away.
No, that can't be true.
It's been 20 years since
we were separated.
You lost touch with me,
so you thought I was dead.
Our bonds may be severed,
but we are still related by blood.
We are mother and son,
no matter what happens.
I'm Chutaro from Banba!
Wait a minute.
You seem awfully
knowledgeable of Banba,
but that doesn't mean anything to me.
True, I got married to
Okinagaya in Banba,
and had a son named Chutaro.
I'm that Chutaro!
Will you listen to the end?
I left Okinaga-ya when
he was five years old.
Yes, I know...
When you left, Dad had bad morals.
When I grew up, I was
told he was at fault.
I didn't want to leave
my child and divorce him.
For a long time after that...
I would live in tears, looking
at the skies toward Goshu.
I'm so glad to have found you.
I would try my best to
remember your face...
but I just couldn't remember it.
I was mortified for being born stupid.
Twenty years have gone by,
trying to find you without a clue.
Enough!
You are not my son,
Chutaro, who I gave birth to.
Then who am I?
Stay away from me!
I heard Chutaro died from
an epidemic when he was nine.
I remember almost dying
when I was nine years old.
But I didn't die!
I am alive right here!
I wouldn't mistake my child!
Leave!
You can't worm yourself in!
Do you think I'm here for the money?
Why else would you be here?
You got it all wrong!
I didn't come here to
get money from you!
I'm not in need of money.
I thought if I should meet
my mother by fate, then...
I would give her this money,
if she was living in poverty.
I had saved a 100 gold
coins to give to her.
You seem to be living in a grand house...
...with many employees.
You are suspicious of people
because you have wealth.
You'd even suspect your very own son.
How I resent that...
I should be the one to resent it.
I was having a great
life with my daughter.
Then you pop up saying
you are my son, Chutaro.
Did you come to create waves?
What an awful thing to say, Mom!
- Are you still calling me Mom?!
Because you are my Mom!
I know what you're up to!
You want half my daughter's inheritance.
I've seen the good and bad side of life.
I can figure out that much.
What an awful thing to say...
Madam, let me ask you again.
Is Chutaro from Banba, not your son?
Are you saying that I'm not your son?
Yes, that's right.
I had a son, but I heard
that he passed away.
That's what I believed all these years.
Even if he were to come
and see me, alive...
I can't feel happy about it.
I didn't think that the many years apart...
could create such a big gap in our hearts.
They say the child doesn't
understand his parent's feelings.
But in my case, it's just the opposite.
You have no idea how
much I care about you.
Chutaro...
What is it?
If I said I am your mother...
What did you want from me?
Why do you want to know?
I know that you enjoy
your peaceful life now.
And you don't want me
to spoil that for you.
There's no mother who
doesn't love her child.
But that depends on the child, too.
Chutaro...
If you were searching for your mother...
Why didn't you remain straight?
Madam, don't tell me what to do.
How can you expect a parentless
child to not go astray in life?
Say I had remained straight...
There wouldn't be anyone
who would be happy for me.
I was all alone, without anything.
I'm going to hit the road again.
Hey you!
This isn't a story for you to listen to!
Madam...
I won't come here again.
Didn't you say you have a daughter?
I wish I could have met her.
I'm such a fool.
When I'd close my eyes tightly...
I'd picture the mother I
had parted with as a child.
But I had to come here and
ruin what little memory I had.
Welcome home.
Mom, who is that man?
Who is he?
There was a resemblance...
Isn't he your older brother from Goshu?
Mom, is that right?
Mom, that was my brother, wasn't it?
That was my brother!
Why did you send him away?
I adore you most since you
have been with me all along.
When Chutaro showed
up out of the blue...
I was wary of him as an imposter.
Midway...
I thought he had come
to get an inheritance.
In the end, I thought he
would ruin things for you.
How can you say that!
He is your child, too!
Otose, Choji...
Please find Chutaro and
bring him back here!
Hurry! Please find him!
Who's there?
I recognize your faces.
What do you want with me?
We're taking your life.
You should stay out of my way tonight.
Oh really?
Look there.
Do you have parents?
What? Parents? No!
Do you have children?
No!
So you have none...
Bastards!
Chutaro!
Brother!
We have lost track of him.
Maybe we should check
the next village, too.
Is this what it means to have no fate?
Mom...
I was wrong...
I was wrong.
I can sense him nearby...
Brother!
Chutaro! Brother!
Chutaro!
Dear sister...
Special Thanks to Toyo Ichi and Ichiban
Subtitled and Mastered by Cannibal King
www.KuroTokagi.com