[radio] Yo, pull out them kiddie pools and
call me up with your sizzling summer scandal.
tomorrow's the Fourth of July
but we're kicking off the celebration tonight
with fireworks at the marina!
It's going to be a scorcher!
Yo, that's my wall!
Lights up on Washington Heights,
up at the break of day
I wake up and I got this little punk I gotta chase away
Pop the grate at the crack of dawn,
While I wipe down the awning
Hey y’all, good morning
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Ice cold piragua!
Parcha. China. Cherry.
Strawberry. And just for today,
I got mamey!
[USNAVI, spoken] Oye, piragüero, como estas?
[PIRAGUA GUY, spoken]
Como siempre, Señor Usnavi.​
[USNAVI]
I am Usnavi and you prob’ly never heard my name
Reports of my fame are greatly exaggerated
Exacerbated by the fact that my syntax
Is highly complicated 'cuz I emigrated
From the single greatest little place in the Caribbean:
Dominican Republic!
I love it!
Jesus, I’m jealous of it
And beyond that
Ever since my folks passed on
I haven’t gone back
Goddamn, I gotta get on that...
Fo! The milk has gone bad, hold up just a second
Why is everything in this fridge warm and tepid?
I better step it up and fight the heat
'Cuz I’m not makin' any profit if the coffee isn’t light and sweet!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA, spoken]
Ooo-oo!
[USNAVI, spoken]
Abuela, my fridge broke. I got café but no "con leche."
[ABUELA CLAUDIA, spoken]
Try my mother’s old recipe: one can of condensed milk.
[USNAVI, spoken]
Nice.​
[ABUELA CLAUDIA, spoken]
Ay! Paciencia y fe…
[USNAVI]
That was Abuela, she’s not really my “abuela,”
But she practically raised me, this corner is her escuela
Now, you’re prob’ly thinkin:
"I’m up shit’s creek!
I've never been north of Ninety-Sixth Street!”
Well, you must take the A Train
Even farther than Harlem to northern Manhattan and maintain
Get off at 181st, and take the escalator
I hope you’re writing this down, I’m gonna test ya later
I’m getting tested; times are tough on this bodega
Two months ago somebody bought Ortega’s
Our neighbors started packin’ up and pickin’ up
And ever since the rents went up
It’s gotten mad expensive
But we live with just enough
[COMMUNITY]
In the heights
I flip the lights and start my day
There are fights
[WOMEN]
And endless debts
[MEN]
And bills to pay
[COMMUNITY]
In the Heights
I can’t survive without café
[USNAVI]
I serve café
'Cuz tonight seems like a million years away!
En Washington—
[USNAVI]
Next up to bat, the Rosarios
They run the cab company,​
They struggle in the barrio
See, their daughter Nina’s off at college, tuition is mad steep
So they can’t sleep
Everything they get is mad cheap!
[KEVIN]
Good morning, Usnavi!
[USNAVI]
Pan caliente, café con leche!
[KEVIN]
Put twenty dollars on today’s lottery
[CAMILA]
One ticket, that’s it!
[KEVIN]
Hey! A man’s gotta dream...
[CAMILA]
Don’t mind him, he’s all excited
‘Cuz Nina flew in at 3 A.M. last night!!
[KEVIN]
Don’t look at me, this one’s been cooking all week!
[CAMILA]
Usnavi, come over for dinner
[KEVIN/CAMILA]
There’s plenty to eat!
[DANIELA]
So then Yesenia walks in the room—
She smells sex and cheap perfume!
It smells like one of those trees
That you hang from the rear view!
It’s true! She screams, “Who’s in there with you, Julio?”
Grabs a bat and kicks in the door
He’s in bed with José from the liquor store!
[CARLA/USNAVI]
No me diga!
[USNAVI, spoken]
Daniela and Carla, from the salon.​
[DANIELA/CARLA]
Thanks, Usnavi!
[USNAVI, spoken]
Sonny, you’re late.​
[SONNY, spoken]
Chillax, you know you love me.​
[USNAVI]
Me and my cousin runnin’ just another dime-a-dozen
Mom-and-pop stop-and-shop
And, oh my god, it’s gotten
Too darn hot, like my man Cole Porter said
People come through for a few cold waters and
A lottery ticket, just a part of the routine
Everybody’s got a job, everybody’s got a dream
They gossip, as I sip my coffee and smirk
The first stop as people hop to work
Bust it— I’m like:
"One dollar, two dollars, one fifty, one sixty-nine.​
I got it. You want a box of condoms? What kind?
That’s two quarters.​
Two quarter waters. The New York Times.​
You need a bag for that? The tax is added.​"
Once you get some practice at it
You do rapid mathematics automatically
Sellin’ maxipads, fuzzy dice for taxicabs and practically
Everybody’s stressed, yes!
But they press through the mess,​
Bounce checks and wonder what’s next
[COMMUNITY]
In the heights
I buy my coffee and I go
Set my sights
On only what I need to know
In the heights
Money is tight
But even so
When the lights go down I blast my radio!
[BENNY]
You ain’t got no skills!
[USNAVI]
Benny!
[BENNY] Yo, lemme get a—
[USNAVI] Milky Way
[BENNY] Yeah, lemme also get a—
[USNAVI] Daily News—
[BENNY] And most important, my—
[USNAVI] Boss’ second coffee, one cream—
[BOTH]
Five sugars
[BENNY] I’m the number one earner—
[USNAVI/SONNY] What?!
[BENNY] The fastest learner—
[BENNY] My boss can’t keep me on the damn back burner!
[USNAVI] Yes, he can
[BENNY] I’m makin’ moves, I’m makin’ deals, but guess what?
[USNAVI] What?
[BENNY/SONNY]
You still ain’t got no skills!
[BENNY] Yo, Vanessa show up yet?
[USNAVI] Shut up!
[BENNY] Hey little homie, don’t get so upset
[USNAVI] Man...
[BENNY]
Tell Vanessa how you feel,
buy the girl a meal
On the real, or you ain’t got no skills
[VANESSA, speaking on the phone]
Nooo!
No no nooo!
No no nooo, no-no-no!
[Keeps saying no!]
no!
Mr. Johnson, I got the security deposit
It’s locked in a box in the bottom of my closet
It’s not reflected in my bank statement
But I’ve been savin’ to make
a down payment and pay rent
No, no, I won’t let you down—
[BENNY]
Yo, here’s your chance; ask her out right now!
[VANESSA] I’ll see you later, we can look at that lease!
[BENNY] Do somethin’, make your move, don’t freeze!
[VANESSA]
You owe me a bottle of cold champagne!
[USNAVI]
Are you moving?
[VANESSA]
Just a little credit check and I’m on that downtown train!
[USNAVI] Well, your coffee’s on the house
[VANESSA] Okay!
[BENNY] Usnavi, ask her out
[SONNY] No way!
[VANESSA]
I’ll see you later, so…
[BENNY]
Oooh... Smooth operator, aw, damn, there she goes!
Yo, bro, take five, take a walk outside!
You look exhausted, lost, don’t let life slide!
The whole hood is struggling, times are tight
And you’re stuck to this corner like a streetlight!
[USNAVI]
Yeah, I’m a streetlight, chokin' on the heat
The world spins around while I’m frozen to my seat
The people that I know all keep on rollin' down the street
But every day is different so I’m switchin’ up the beat
'Cuz my parents came with nothing, they got a little more
And sure, we’re poor, but yo, at least we got the store
And it’s all about the legacy they left with
me, it’s destiny
And one day I’ll be on a beach with Sonny
writing checks to me
[COMMUNITY]                            [USNAVI]
In the Heights, I hang          We came to work and to live
my flag up on display          and we got a lot in common
[COMMUNITY]
It reminds me that I came from miles away
[USNAVI]
D.R., P.R., we are not stoppin’
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Every day, paciencia y fe
USNAVI]
Until the day we go from poverty to stock options.
[USNAVI]
And today’s all we got, so we cannot stop
This is our block!
[COMMUNITY]
In the Heights
I hang my flag up on display
[COMMUNITY]
It reminds me that I came from miles away
[USNAVI/PIRAGUA GUY/NEIGHBORS]
My family came from miles away—
[COMMUNITY]
In the Heights
It gets more expensive every day
[COMMUNITY]
And tonight is so far away—
[USNAVI]
But as for mañana, mi pana
Ya gotta just keep watchin’
[USNAVI]
You’ll see the ​late nights
You’ll taste ​beans and rice
The syrups and ​shaved ice
I ain’t gonna ​say it twice
So turn up the stage lights. We’re takin’ a flight
To a couple of days ​in the life of what it’s like
[ALL]
En Washington Heights!
[USNAVI]
Yo, what did I say? Go fix the fridge
[SONNY]
Hells no, it was blowing fuses, sparking and shit!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Usnavi, send this boy to D.R. for summer.
Let him work on a farm so his Nikes
can get real dirt on them.
[USNAVI]
I ain't wastin' no plane ticket on this kid.
I'll be on Playa Rincon with arum and coke.
Sonny can stay here and sell Twinkies.
Sell? I'll give 'em away for free.
I'm the Robin Hood of El Barrio
[USNAVI]
Nina Rosario, what is up?!
[NINA]
Jetlag, I haven't slept all night
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
It's the watermelon of my heart!
[NINA]
Bendición, Abuela.
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Congratulations, your first year at Stanford University!
[NINA]
It felt like ten
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
You just missed your parents
[NINA]
I'm here to see you guys
[USNAVI]
So, did you kick some college ass?
[NINA]
I got mine handed to me on a silver platter.
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Please, you knew the ABC's when you
were six months old.
[USNAVI]
You registered half the block to vote!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
The future Mayor of Nuevayork!
[SONNY]
I wanna be your campaign manager
Yo miss, recognize this face?
[NINA]
Look who's a grown man
[SONNY]
Check outs te goatee
[USNAVI]
That's fridge grease
[SONNY]
Why you so jealous of my skills?
[USNAVI]
Get back to work
Stop by later Nina
[NINA]
Those recipies you sent were my survival kit
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
I had to make sure you remembered the flavor of home
Bueno, come inside, I have your sandwichito ready!
[NINA]
I'll be there in just a second
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
I'll go put the fan on
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Sigue andando el camino por toda su vida
Respira...
[NINA] Breathe
[COMMUNITY] Y si pierdes mis huellas que dios te bendiga
Respira
[NINA]
This is my street
I smile at the faces
I’ve known all my life
They regard me with pride
And everyone’s sweet
They say, “You’re going places!"
So how can I say that while I was away
I had so much to hide!
“Hey guys, it’s me!
The biggest disappointment you know.”
The kid couldn’t hack it
She’s back and she’s walkin’ real slow
Welcome home
Just breathe...
[COMMUNITY]
Sigue andando el camino por toda su vida
Respira—
Y si pierdes mis huellas que dios te bendiga
[NINA]
As the radio plays old forgotten boleros
I think of the days when this city was mine
I remember the praise
[NINA]
“Ay, te adoro, te quiero,”
The neighborhood waved, and
Said, “Nina, be brave
and
You’re gonna be fine!”
And maybe it’s me
But it all seems like lifetimes ago
[NINA]
So what do I say to these faces that I used to know?
“Hey, I’m home?”
[NEIGHBOR LADY]            [NINA]
Mira Nina                           Hey…
[COMMUNITY]
No me preocupo por ella
[NINA]
They’re not worried about me
[COMMUNITY]
Mira, allí esta nuestra estrella!
[NINA]
They are all counting on me to succeed
[COMMUNITY]
Ella sí da la talla!
[NINA]
I am the one who made it out!
The one who always made the grade
But maybe I should have just stayed home…
When I was a child I stayed wide awake
Climbed to the highest place
On every fire escape
Restless to climb
I got every scholarship
Saved every dollar
The first to go to college
How do I tell them why
I’m coming back home?
With my eyes on the horizon
[NINA]
Just me and the GWB, asking,
“Gee Nina, what’ll you be?"
Straighten the spine
Smile for the neighbors
Everything’s fine
Everything’s cool
The standard reply:
“Lots of tests, lots of papers.”
Smile, wave goodbye
And pray to the sky, oh, god…
And what will my parents say?
Can I go in there and say
“I know that I’m letting you down…”
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Nina…
[NINA]
Just breathe...
[KEVIN]
Chicos lo repito pa' que me entiendan
ciento noventa y dos, en la esquina,
al frente del McDonald's
Atención, I know it's hot
but I don't want to see any drivers without a tie.
Mija, how can you be so stressed when our muñeca is home
[CAMILA]
The mechanic called, he won't touch
another engine till we pay for last month
[KEVIN]
Then I'll get a little engine grase on my hands
[CAMILA]
Why, so you can hurt your back again?
[KEVIN]
You used to think I was sexy when I fixed cars
[CAMILA]
before all that mileage...
Mira, Uptown Investment Group...
[KEVIN]
Another developer
It's not an offer, it's an insult
[CAMILA]
Regency Bank
We're behind on all these payments
We need an emergency loan
[KEVIN]
We'll go see the bank manager Monday
[CAMILA]
Papi this can't wait.
[KEVIN]
The dispatcher called out
[BENNY]
Hey, boss, I'll cover the radio
[KEVIN]
You don't speak Spanish
[BENNY]
Five years with these drivers
[KEVIN]
You're not Latino
[CAMILA]
Excuse me? How much English did you speak when you started here?
Benny is honorary Latino
[BENNY]
There's a new voice riding the heat wave today
[KEVIN]
Just get them from point A to B
[BENNY]
I got your back
Check one two three...
This is Benny on the dispatch. Yo!
Atención, yo, attention!
It’s Benny, and I’d like to mention
I’m on the microphone this mornin’
Honk ya horn if you want it!
Okay, we got traffic on the west side
Get off at 79th, and take the left side
Of Riverside Drive, and ya might slide
West End’s ya best friend if you catch the lights
And don’t take the Deegan;
Manny Ramirez is in town this weekend
Sorry Dominicans, take Route Eighty-seven
You ain’t getting back in again
Hold up a minute
[BENNY]
Nina, you’re home today!
[NINA] Any sign—
[BENNY]  ...Of your folks, they’re on their way!
[NINA] Anyway—
[BENNY] It’s good to see your face—
[NINA] Anytime—
[BENNY] Hold up a minute, wait!
You used to run this dispatch, right?
[NINA]
Once or twice—
[BENNY]
Well check the technique! Yo!
There’s a traffic accident I have to mention
At the intersection of 10th Ave and the Jacob Javitz Convention Center
And check it, don’t get stuck in the rubber-neckin’
On a Hundred-Ninety-Second, there’s a double-decker bus wreck!
Now listen up, we got a special guest!
Live and direct from a year out west!
Welcome her back, 'cause she looks mad stressed!
Nina Rosario, the barrio’s best!
Honk your horns…
She’s smiling… say hello!
[NINA]
Hello! Everybody!
I better find my folks
Thanks for the welcome wagon
[BENNY]
Anytime. Anytime, Nina
Wait here with me
It’s getting hot outside, turn up the A.C
Stay here with me
[USNAVI]
Oye, you missed another doctor's appointment
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Mijo, would you take medical advice
from a man named Dr. Gross?
[USNAVI]
As long as you're taking your medicine
Abuela...
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
It makes my heart work better,
but in return it gives me headaches
Imaginate, with what those pills cost,
I'd get myself a good facelift
Sácalo de aquí,
mételo pacá
Y pacá, y pacá
[SONNY]
Who- who hooked it up?
Ice cold Country Club Cola Champagne!
[USNAVI]
Put that on your tab
You owe me five thousand, three hundred-
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Usnavi, I think he's trying to tell you that
he fixed the Frididaire
[SONNY]
So let's talk about that raise
Free sodas or I walk
[USNAVI]
Half price. Diet. Cola Champagne
That's my final offer
[SONNY]
Ain't no Diminicans be drinking no diet soda!
[VANESSA]
Be thankful, at least someone around
here is getting a raise!
[SONNY]
Know what? I'm starting a union
Underage cousins of bodega workers unite
[DANIELA]
Excuse me, this isn't social hours
[VANESSA]
Sorry, it's Con Edison.
I gave my mom half my check to pay the bills...
[DANIELA]
Y que pasó? She drank it away?
Vanessa, when are you going to get out
of that toxic environment?
[VANESSA]
Hi ma'am? I get my check next week, I can pay then
Yes, I'll hold.
Daniela, I know I still owe you from last time...
Carla, what's my rule?
[CARLA]
She'll do anything for you
but she won't support your mother's malfunction
[DANIELA]
Dysfunction
[VANESSA]
My lights are going to be out all week
[CARLA]
What would Jesus do?
[DANIELA]
Do I look like Jesus to you?
[VANESSA]
Yes, hello? Yes, I'm still here.
No, please don't transfer me!
Hello? Hello?
[DANIELA]
Comay, it's time to take five
and clear out that negative energy!
Get some packing tape
[VANESSA]
Anything else while I'm at it?
[DANIELA]
a Pepsi
Tough love, chacha
[VANESSA]
The elevated train by my window
Doesn’t faze me anymore
The rattling screams don’t disrupt my dreams
It’s a lullaby, in its way
The elevated train drives everyone insane
But I don’t mind, oh no
When I bring back boys they can’t tolerate the noise
And that’s okay, 'cause I never let them stay
And one day, I’m hoppin’ that elevated
train and I’m riding away!
It won’t be long now!
The boys around the way holler at me when I’m walking down the street
Their machismo pride doesn’t break my stride—
It’s a compliment, so they say
The boys around the way holler at me every day but I don’t mind, oh no
If I’m in the mood, it will not be with some dude
Who is whistling 'cause he has nothing to say
Or who’s honking at me from his Chevrolet!
And one day… I’m hoppin’ in a limousine and I’m driving away!
It won’t be long now!
(spoken)
Ay, Usnavi, help! SOS!
[USNAVI]
Good morning, Vanessa!
If it isn’t the loveliest girl in the place...
[VANESSA]
You’ve got some schmutz on your face
[USNAVI]
Another late night, eh?
Whoever you were with,
he's got nothing on these biceps
I bench press six gallons of milk
and two cases on Goya beans
[VANESSA]
It was my mom.
Actually, they shut out our lights. Again.
[USNAVI]
Coffee, whole milk. Very sweet. Little bit of cinnamon
[VANESSA]
Mm. Just like my abuela used to do
[USNAVI]
That's what all the ladies say.
I remind them of their grandma
[SONNY]
Good morning!
[SONNY/USNAVI]
[USNAVI]
Vanessa!
[SONNY]
[USNAVI/SONNY]
Vanessa!
[DANIELA, spoken]
VANESSSSSAAAAAA! I’m thirsty, coño!
[VANESSA, spoken]
Can I get a Pepsi and some packing tape?
[SONNY, spoken]
Uh, my cousin over there with his tongue hanging out,
he would like to know what a lady
such as yourself is doing tonight?
[VANESSA, spoken]
Does your cousin dance?
[SONNY, spoken]
Like a... like a drunk Chita Rivera.​
[VANESSA, spoken]
Okay… So after Nina’s dinner,
we can hit a few clubs and check out the fireworks…
[USNAVI]
Oh snap! Who’s that?
Don’t touch me, I’m too hot! Yes!
Qué pasó? Here I go!
So dope! Y tu lo sabes!
No pare sigue sigue!
Did you see me?
Freaky freakit!
What a way to begin the weekend
Sonny, anything you want is free, man!
And my dearly beloved Dominican Republic
I haven’t forgotten you!
Gonna see this honey, make a little money
And one day I’ll hop Jet Blue!
But until that fateful day, I’m grateful
I got a destination
I’m runnin’ to make it home
And home’s what Vanessa’s runnin’ away from!
And home’s what Vanessa’s runnin’ away from…
[VANESSA]
The neighborhood salon
is the place
I am working for the moment
As I cut their hair, ladies talk and share—
Every day, who’s doin' who and why...
The neighborhood salon doesn’t pay me
what I wanna be making but I don’t mind
As I sweep the curb I can hear those
turbo engines blazing a trail through the sky
I look up and think about the years gone by
But one day—I’m walkin’ to JFK and I’m gonna fly!
It won’t be long now!
Any day...
[BENNY]
Roger. Cómo? Uh... dónde estás?
Slow down. One momento.
Yo, cabrón, I'm trying to help you!
Whoa, who taught you to speak Spanish?
The drivers, dirty bastards
[NINA]
Ahá, dime
He's going to the Cloisters,
he's stuck on the Hudson
[BENNY]
Exit fourteen, tell him to follow
the signs to Fort Tryon
[NINA]
The u-turn off exit fifteen is quicker
[BENNY]
It's also illegal
[NINA]
Salida quince, haz una media vuelta, sigue derecho
[BENNY]
You gave him your directions,
didn't you?
[KEVIN]
Eyes on the dispatch, por favor
[BENNY] Yes, sir
[NINA] Dad!
[KEVIN]
You look more beautiful and even smarter!
[NINA]
It must be the bags under my eyes
[CAMILA]
Nena de mamá!
Mija tan preciosa!
Turn around, let me see my flaquita!
[NINA]
Mom! Please
[CAMILA]
Excuse me, you think you're all grown up?
[NINA]
I was hoping we could grab a few coffees
and go home for a minute
[KEVIN]
No, we're celebrating! Caridad is still serving breakfast
[NINA]
I ate at Abuela Claudia's
[CAMILA]
So? I get to fatten you up, too!
[KEVIN] We have to go by Daniela's
everyone wants to see you
[NINA] You guys!
[NINA]
Okay, I planned this whole speech on the plane...
[KEVIN]
Benny, give us a minute
[BENNY]
Nina if there's anything I can do to help
[KEVIN]
Go
[CAMILA]
Mija
[NINA]
I lost my scolarship
[CAMILA] Did you get in some kind of trouble?
[NINA] No
[CAMILA]
It's okay
Just tell us what happened
[NINA]
My grades where bellow te cutoff
so they put me on probation
After the midterms they called me
into the Dean's office
and he was like, "We have to
pul your scholarship"
[CAMILA]
But you were studying nonstop!
[NINA]
No I was working to help to pay
for books I didn't have time to read
Look, I ended up taking a leave of absence
[CAMILA]
Does leave of absence mean drop out?
Nina, look at me.
[NINA] I guess you could say I left school
[KEVIN] What?
[CAMILA] Oh my god, when?
[NINA] I didn't know what to do-
When?
March
[CAMILA]
Four months ago!? Where have you been since then?
[NINA]
Figuring out how to tell you.
Staying on a friend's couch
[CAMILA]
Like a beggar?
You lied to me! Every time I called you!
[NINA]
I couldn't work two jobs and study for finals
and finish my term papers
[KEVIN]
Two jobs? You said it was going to be one
[NINA]
It's expensive. The scholarship only covers part of it
[KEVIN]
Then you pick up the phone and say,
"Papy, I need some money."
[NINA]
You don't know what college is like!
[KEVIN]
I would have found a way!
[CAMILA]
I'm going to get started on dinner
[NINA]
Cancel tonight
[CAMILA]
You be home in an hour!
[KEVIN]
Why didn't you just ask me?
[NINA]
What could you have done?
[KEVIN]
This isn’t happening
Inútil! Useless
Just like my father was before me:
And every day
He cut the cane
He came home late and prayed for rain
Prayed for rain
And on the days
When nothing came
My father’s face was lined with shame
He’d sit me down beside him and he’d say,​
“My father was a farmer,​
His father was a farmer,​
And you will be a farmer.”
But I told him,
“Papi, I’m sorry, I’m going farther.​
I’m getting on a plane.​
And I am gonna change the world someday!”
And he slapped my face
He stood there, staring at me,
useless
Today my daughter’s home and I am…
And as a baby she amazed me
with the things she learned each day
She used to stay on the fire escape
While all the other kids would play
And I would stand beside her and I’d say:
“I’m proud to be your father
‘Cuz you work so much harder
And you are so much smarter
Than I was at your age.”
But I always knew that she would fly away
And she was gonna change the world
someday
I will not be the reason
That my family can’t succeed
I will do what it takes
They’ll have everything they need
Or all my work, all my life
Everything I’ve sacrificed will have been
useless
[SONNY]
You ready?
Let's go. One, two, three, four
What you got?
What happened?
[DANIELA]
You know me, I don't like to talk about nobody-
[CARLA]
Dani, don't! My pastor told me gossip is a sin
[DANIELA]
Jesus, perdóname
Gladys went behind my back for ten dollar hairdo
and guess what she found in her extensions?
Una cucaracha
[THEY SCREAM]
One of the big ones, with wings
[KEEP SCREAMING]
[SCREAMS KEEPS GOING]
[NINA]
I've been calling you all morning
[VANESSA]
Well, guess how confiscated my phone?
Next fall, put me in your suitcase and take me with you.
[NINA]
Ladies, do you mind if I borrow Vanessa for a minute?
[DANIELA]
And what are we, chopped chuletas?
[CARLA]
Pobrecita, you need a makeover
[NINA]
I have to go help my mom... I'll see you guys at dinner?
[DANIELA]
I'll be packing.
Tomorrow we close that door forever
[NINA]
Oh no
Alright, ten minutes
[DANIELA]
Can you believe the salon's moving to the Bronx?
[VANESSA]
Gettin' out the barrio, and headin' to the hood
[DANIELA]
What can I do? They keep raising the rent
[NINA]
Man,now who's going to mess up my highlights?
[THEY CHEER]
[DANIELA]
Ungrateful!
I mess up your highlights at a discount price
And if you visit me in the Bronx, free eyebrow waxing
[NINA]
You're the only person who touches these brows
[DANIELA]
I see. Tweezers!
[CARLA]
Ay, pero what happened to these curls?
You need some hair gel mami
[NINA]
Do not make my hair all crunchy!
[DANIELA]
You have to accept hair gel into your life!
[DANIELA] Gorgeous!
[CARLA] Linda!
[CARLA/DANIELA]
Tell me something I don’t know!
[VANESSA] Vieja!
[DANIELA] Sucia!
[CARLA] Cabrona!
[CARLA/VANESSA/DANIELA]
Tell me something I don’t know!
[CARLA]
A little off the top!
[DANIELA]
A little off the side!
[NINA]
A little bit of news you’ve heard around the barrio!
[ALL]
Tell me something I don’t know!
[DANIELA]
Bueno
You didn’t hear it from me!
But some little birdie told me
Usnavi had sex with Yolanda!
[NINA/CARLA]
No me diga!
[VANESSA]
Ay, no! He’d never go out with a skank like that!
Please tell me you’re joking!
[DANIELA]
Okay!
Just wanted to see what you’d say!
[CARLA/NINA/DANIELA]
Tell me something I don’t know!
Mmm-hmm-mmm…
[VANESSA, spoken]
What? I don’t care!
[ALL]
Ay, bendito!
[DANIELA]
So, Nina, I hear you been talking to Benny
[NINA]
And what do you hear?
[DANIELA]
I hear plenty!
They say he’s got quite a big… taxi!
[CARLA/VANESSA]
No me diga!
[NINA]
Okay! I don’t wanna know
where you heard all that!
[CARLA]
I don’t think I know what you mean…
[DANIELA]
Carla! He’s packing a stretch limousine!
[VANESSA/DANIELA/NINA]
Tell me something I don’t know!
[CARLA]
Long as he keeps it clean!
[NINA/VANESSA/DANIELA]
Ay dios mio!
[DANIELA]
Nina, seriously
we knew you’d be the one to make it out!
[VANESSA]
I bet you impressed them all out west;
You were always the best, no doubt!
[CARLA]
We want front row seats to your graduation—
[DANIELA]
They’ll call your name—
[DANIELA/CARLA/VANESSA]
And we’ll scream and shout!
[They cheer]
[NINA, spoken]
You guys, I dropped out
[DANIELA/CARLA/VANESSA, spoken]
No me diga?!
[NINA, spoken]
I should go.​
[DANIELA]
That’s a shitty piece of news.​
[CARLA]
That girl never quit anything.​
[DANIELA]
Muchacha never got a B
[VANNESA]
She got a C in gym once
I had to talk her off the fire scape
[DANIELA]
Maybe the pressure cooker couldn't take it and PAH
the lid flew off
[VANESSA]
But what the hell happened?
[DANIELA]
I don’t know…
[DANIELA/CARLA]
I don’t know
[DANIELA]
I don’t know...
[CARLA/VANESSA]
Tell me something I don’t know!
[ALL]
Qué sé yo?
[BENNY]
Yo
Does my tie look straight?
[USNAVI]
Benny, you look the same as you do every day man
Quit tying to impress Nina
[SONNY]
Whoo, you need to impress some
Old Spice under those arms.
[BENNY]
Shut up. My boss put me on dispatch today,
I need to look professional
[SONNY]
"My boss, my boss"
You're paving the way to somebody else's dream
Man, you need to strike out on your own
[BENNY]
I'm learning on someone else's dime
The day I open up Benny's Car Service
I'll know my trade inside and out
[USNAVI]
Either one of you Rockefellers wanna take
this business off my hands?
[SONNY] Heck no
[BENNY] Naw, I'm cool
[USNAVI]
Yeah, I didn't think so
[GRAFFITI PETE]
What's up, what's up what's uuuuup
Yo, c'mon, buy my t-shirt
[USNAVI]
That's your sales pitch?
Men, get the hell out of here
[GRAFFITI PETE]
C'mon, today's special, two for twenty
[USNAVI]
How about I give you nothing
and you scrub your initials off my awning?
[SONNY]
whoo, men
Look, Sonny's Secret Recipe
[USNAVI]
Ah? One dollar twenty five
[GRAFFITI PETE]
C'mon, let's trade
I got some roman candles, bottle rockets. Third of July
party starts tonight!
[USNAVI]
Contraband. Vandalism.
You got three seconds before I call the cops
9. 1
[SONNY]
Usnavi, usnavi, double check this
[USNAVI]
Take Five Lotto
Hold up, whe sold a winner yesterday?
[BENNY] Somebody won?
[SONNY] Yo, I want a cut of your cut!
[USNAVI]
I don't get a cut
Yup, the numbers match
[BENNY]
Yo, what's the payout?!
Don't tell me no five hundred dollars
[USNAVI]
Ninety-six thousand!
[SONNY/BENNY]
Damn!
[USNAVI]
Ninety-six thousand!
[SONNY]
Dollars? Holler!
[USNAVI]
Ninety-six thousand!
Danm! That's a lot of spray cans
[USNAVI]
Ninety-six thousand!
[BENNY]
Yo,​ If I won the lotto tomorrow
Well, I know I wouldn’t bother goin’ on no
spendin’ spree
I pick a business school and pay the
entrance fee!
Then maybe if you’re lucky, you’ll stay
friends with me!
I’ll be a businessman,
richer than Nina’s daddy!
Donald Trump and I on the links,
and he’s my caddy!
My money’s makin’ money,
I’m goin’ from po’ to mo’ dough!
Keep the bling, I want the brass ring, like Frodo!
[USNAVI]
Oh no, here goes Mr. Braggadocio
Next thing you know, you’re lying like Pinocchio—
[BENNY]
Yo, if you’re scared of the bull, stay out the rodeo!
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Yo, I got more hoes than a phone book in Tokyo!
[USNAVI]
Ooh, you better stop rappin’, you not ready
It’s gonna get hot and heavy
And you already sweaty—
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Yo-yo-yo! Yo!
[USNAVI]
Yo! I’m sorry is that an answer?
Shut up, go home and pull ya damn pants up!
As for you, Mr. Frodo of the Shire—
96 G’s ain’t enough to retire
[BENNY]
C'mon, I’ll have enough to knock your ass off its axis!
[USNAVI]
You’ll have a knapsack full of jack after taxes!
[SONNY]
Ninety-six thousand!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA, spoken]
Ay, alabanza!
[SONNY]
Ninety-six thousand!
[DANIELA/CARLA, spoken]
No me diga
[SONNY]
Ninety-six thousand!
[VANESSA, spoken]
I never win shit!
[SONNY]
Ninety-six thousand!
[BENNY]
For real, though, imagine how it would feel goin’ real slow
Down the highway of life with no regrets
And no breakin’ your neck for respect or a paycheck
For real, though, I’ll take a break from the
wheel and we’ll throw
The biggest block party, everybody here
It’s a weekend when we can breathe, take it easy
[NEIGHBORS]
Yo! Ma, it’s me, check my tickets!
[CARLA]
Check one two three
What would you do with ninety-six G’s—
[DANIELA] Who me?
[CARLA] I mean if it’s just between you and me—
[DANIELA]
Esa pregunta es tricky!
[CARLA]
I know
[DANIELA]
With ninety-six G’s
I’d start my life with a brand new lease
Atlantic City with a Malibu Breeze
[CARLA]
And a brand new weave!
[DANIELA]
Or maybe just bleach...
[VANESSA]
Y’all are freaks.​
[USNAVI, spoken]
Yo, I’m just sayin’...
(sung)
It’s silly when we get into these crazy hypotheticals
You really want some bread? Then go ahead create a set of goals
And cross them off the list as you pursue ‘em
And with those ninety-six, I know precisely what I’m doin’
What’m I doin? What’m I doin?
It takes most of that cash just to save my ass from financial ruin
Sonny can keep the coffee brewin’
I’ll spend a few on you
‘Cause the only room with a view is a room with you in it
And I could give Abuela Claudia the rest of it
Just fly me down to Puerto Plata, I’ll make the best of it!
You really love this business?
[SONNY] No
Tough, Merry Christmas
You’re now the youngest tycoon in Washington Hiznits!
[SONNY]
Yo! With ninety-six thousand, I’d finally fix housin’
Give the barrio computers with wireless web browsin’
Your kids are livin’ without a good edjumication
Change the station, teach 'em about gentrification
The rent is escalatin’
[GRAFFITI PETE] What?!
The rich are penetratin’
We pay our corporations when
we should be demonstratin’
[GRAFFITI PETE]
What?!
What about immigration?
[GRAFFITI PETE] What?!
Politicians be hatin’
Racism in this nation’s gone from latent to blatant
[COMMUNITY]
Oooooh!
[SONNY]
I’ll cash my ticket and picket, invest in protest
Never lose my focus 'til the city takes notice
You know this! I'll never sleep
Because the ghetto has a million promises for me to keep!
[VANESSA, spoken]
You are so cute!
[SONNY, spoken]
I was just thinking off the top of my head, I mean
[USNAVI, spoken]
Ninety-six K: Go
[VANESSA]
If I win the lottery, you’ll never see me again
you’ll never see me again
[USNAVI]
Damn, we only jokin’, stay broke then
[VANESSA]
I’ll be downtown
Get a nice studio, I'll get out of the barrio
[VANESSA]
If I​win the ​​lottery
You’ll wonder where
I’ve been
[EACH CHARACTER VERSE MIX TOGETHER]
[IT'S BEAUTIFUL]
[IMPRESSIVE]
[VANESSA]
I’ll be downtown!
[USNAVI/BENNY/SONNY]
We could pay off the debts we
​owe!
[VANESSA/CARLA/DANIELA]
We could tell everyone we
​know!
[USNAVI]
I could get on a plane and ​go!
[USNAVI/BENNY/SONNY]
We be swimmin’ in dough,​
​yo!
[EVERYONE]
No tip-toein’
We’ll get the dough ‘n'
Once we get goin’
We’re never gonna
Stop tip-toein’
We’ll get the dough an’
Once we get goin’
We’re never gonna—
[CHORUS]
[COMMUNITY]
We’ll get the dough ‘n’
Once we get goin’
We’re never gonna stop!
[WHISPERING]
Ninety-six ​thousand
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Ay, que calor. Usnavi, ooo-oo!
[USNAVI]
Something's wrong, you were off-pitch
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
It's the heat. Toma, your ham and cheese
[USNAVI]
Thanks. You know, you already brought me one
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
De verdad? My memory goes two miles an hour
I'm taking a walk, I need some air
[USNAVI]
Breadcrumbs for your birds
Stay in the shade, okay?
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Ah! I should stop by Padre Carlos's church
and light a few candles
[USNAVI]
Light one for my broken grate
I gotta go call the mechanic about that thing
Mi amor, is like you always say,
patience and faith
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Paciencia y fe
Calor… calor… calor…
Ay Mamá!
The summer’s hottest day!
Paciencia y fe! Paciencia y fe!
Ay, carajo, it’s hot!
But that’s okay!
Mamá would say, "Paciencia y fe!"
It was hotter at home in La Vibora
The Washington Heights of Havana!
A crowded city of faces the same as mine!
Back as a child in La Vibora
I chased the birds in the plaza
Praying, Mamá, you would find work
Combing the stars in the sky for some sort of sign!
Ay, Mamá, so many stars in Cuba…
En Nueva York we can’t see beyond our streetlights…
To reach the roof you gotta bribe the supa...
Ain’t no Cassiopeia in Washington Heights…
But ain’t no food in La Vibora…
I remember nights, anger in the streets,
hunger at the windows
Women folding clothes, playing with my friends in the summer rain…
Mamá needs a job, Mamá says we’re poor,
one day you say, "Vamos a Nueva York..."
And Nueva York was far
But Nueva York had work and so we came…
And now, I’m wide awake
A million years too late
I talk to you, imagining what you’d do
Remembering what we went through!
Nueva York! Ay Mamá!
It wasn’t like today, you’d say
"Paciencia y fe"
[NEW YORKERS]
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
"Paciencia y fe!"
Fresh off the boat in America
Freezing in early December
A crowded city in Nineteen Forty-Three!
Learning the ropes in America
In español, I remember
Dancing with Mayor La Guardia
All of society welcoming mami and me!
Ha!
[EMPLOYERS]
You better clean this mess!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Paciencia y fe…
[EMPLOYERS]
You better learn inglés!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Paciencia y fe…
[EMPLOYERS]
You better not be late…
You better pull your weight…
Are you better off than you were with the
birds of La Vibora?
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Sharing double beds,
trying to catch a break, struggling with English
Listening to friends, finally got a job working as a maid
So we cleaned some homes, polishing with pride
Scrubbing the whole of the Upper East Side
The days into weeks, the weeks into years,
and here I stayed
[NEW YORKERS]
Paciencia y fe…
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
And as I feed these birds
My hands begin to shake
And as I say these words
My heart’s about to break
And ay Mamá
What do you do
when your dreams come true?
I’ve spent my life
Inheriting dreams from you.
And what do I do with this winning ticket?
What can I do but pray?
I buy my loaf of bread
Continue with my day
And see you in my head
Imagining what you’d say
The birds, they fly away
Do they fly to La Vibora?
(spoken)
Alright, Mamá. Okay
(sung)
Paciencia y fe
[NEIGHBORS]
Calor, calor, calor!
[SONNY]
Uh, well, well, well. Nina Rosario
I think we both know what time it is
[NINA]
Your bedtime?
[SONNY]
No, no, no, not yet
I think it's time you open that wounded
soul up to Sonny
[NINA]
It's tempting
[SONNY]
Know what?
You need a welcome home slushee
Two parts blue raspberry,
one part cherry cola, and check this out
I mix some nerds in it... delicious!
[BENNY]
Domingo, it's all you
[NINA] Can I get a rain check on that slushee?
[SONNY] but
[BENNY]
Yo, Sonny
[SONNY]
You know, one day, you both are gonna
need my sympathy
and will I be there?
Probably
[BENNY AND NINA LAUGH]
[BENNY]
Whould you like a seat
[NINA]
Did you learn some more curse words?
[BENNY]
I'm trying but it's like two different languages you got
Dominican Spanish and Puerto Rican Spanish
[NINA]
I hear you
They spoke a different kind of English at Standford
[BENNY]
Really?
[NINA]
"Weekend," Verb
To go skiing at your cabin on Lake Tahoe
"Cabin," Noun
A blasé word for "mansion"
[BENNY]
tsk, you need to teach them some local vocabulary
[NINA]
Oh I did. Every day in the cafeteria, I was like,
"Oye, you need some fries with that?"
[BENNY]
To not knowing the language
[NINA]
I used to think we lived at the top of the world
When the world was just a subway map
And the one-slash-nine
Climbed a dotted line to my place
[BENNY]
There’s no nine train now
[NINA]
Right
I used to think the Bronx was a place in the sky
When the world was just a subway map
And my thoughts took shape
[NINA/BENNY]
On that fire escape…
[NINA]
Can you remind me of what it was like
At the top of the world?
[BENNY]
Come with me
We begin July
With a stop at my corner fire hydrant
[NINA]
You would open it every summer!
[BENNY]
I would bust it with a wrench
Till my face got drenched
Till I heard the sirens
Then I ran like hell!
[NINA] You ran like hell!
[BENNY] Yeah, I ran like hell!
[NINA] I remember well!
[BENNY]
To your father’s dispatch window
“Hey, let me in, yo!
They’re coming to get me!”
[NINA]
You were always in constant trouble—
[BENNY]
Then your dad would act all snide, but he’d let me hide
You’d be there inside—
[NINA]
Life was easier then
[BENNY]
Nina, everything is easier
When you’re home…
The street’s a little kinder when you’re home
Can’t you see
That the day seems clearer
Now that you are here or
Is it me?
Maybe it’s just me…
We gotta go I wanna show you all I know
The sun is setting and the light is getting low
[NINA]
Are we going to Castle Garden?
[BENNY]
Maybe, maybe not, but way to take a shot,
when the day is hot
I got a perfect shady spot
A little ways away that oughta
Cool us down
[NINA] Cool us down—
[BENNY] Welcome back to town...
[NINA]
Now, back in high school when it darkened
You’d hang out in Bennett Park and
[BENNY]
Usnavi would bring his radio…
[NINA]
As I walked home from Senior Studies
I’d see you rapping with your buddies
[BENNY] With the volume high
[NINA] I walked on by
[BENNY]
You walked on by—
[RAPPERS]
No pare! Sigue, sigue!
No pare-
[BENNY/COMMUNITY]
When you’re home
[BENNY]
Oh, the summer nights are cooler
When you’re home!
[NINA]
Now that you’re here with me…
[BENNY]
And that song you are ​hearing
is the neighborhood just
​cheering you along
[NINA] Don’t say that
[BENNY] What’s wrong?
[NINA]
Don’t say that!
When I was younger, I’d imagine what would happen
If my parents had stayed in Puerto Rico
Who would I be if I had never seen Manhattan
If I lived in Puerto Rico with my people
My people!
I feel like all my life, I’ve tried to find the answer
Working harder, learning Spanish, learning all I can
I thought I might find the answer out at Stanford
But I’d stare out at the sea
Thinking, where’m I supposed to be?
So please don’t say you’re proud of me,
when I’ve lost my way
[BENNY]
Then can I say:
I couldn’t get my mind off you all day
Now listen to me!
That may be how you perceive it
But Nina please believe
That when you find your way again
You’re gonna change the world and then
We’re all gonna brag and say we knew her when...
This was your home
[NINA] I’m home—
[BENNY] Welcome home—
When you’re here with me—
Welcome home—
I used to think that we lived at the top of the world!
I’m home! I’m home!
You’re finally home!
I’m home!
You’re home!
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Oh, qué calor, qué calor, qué calor,
qué calo-o-or!
Piragua, piragua
New block of ice, piragua
So sweet and nice, piragua
Tengo de mango
Tengo de parcha
De piña y de fresa!
Tengo de china, de limón
De peso y de peseta, hey!
Piragua, piragua
New block of ice, piragua
So sweet and nice, piragua
It’s hotter than the islands are tonight
And Mister Softee trying to shut me down
But I keep scraping by the fading light
Hey pana, this is my town
Piragua, piragua
Keep scraping by, piragua
Keep scraping by, keep scraping by…
Lai lo le lo lai! Lai lo le lo lai!
Lai lo le lo lai!
Keep scraping by…
Oh, qué calor, qué calor, qué calor
qué calo-o-or!
[VANESSA]
Yo, tomorrow's the fourth of July,
It's time to party! Come on,
let me teach you some new moves
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Vamos, but no bump and grind!
[CAMILA]
It's my song
[NINA]
We really don't have to
[CAMILA]
Yes we do. I dance best when I'm angry
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
It's to much nalgas
Be subtle
Pretend you're dancing on a tiny brick
[VANESSA]
Uh-uh, abuela, I shake my ass!
[BOLERO SINGER (RECORD)]
Seguiras en mis recuerdos
para siempr- para siempr- para siempr-
[THEY LAUGH]
[CAMILA]
The scratch in the record is my favourite part!
[USNAVI]
Damn, did we miss
the record scratch?
[BENNY]
Put the music back on!
[CAMILA]
Bueno, but no encores! Show up late,
you miss the hot stuff!
[USNAVI]
New Zealand Shiraz. Vintage 2008
[BENNY]
Some pastel de guave for dessert
[USNAVI]
Bendición
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Qué Dios te bendiga! Alabanza to the day!
We have to talk later al right...
[USNAVI]
So, West Village,
do I owe you a bottle of Champagne?
[VANESSA]
When the landlord saw my credit application,
he laugh
Out loud
[NINA]
Screw him. That wasn't the right place for you
[VANESSA]
No, there brick was exposed on purpose,
not because the walls were all busted
[NINA]
Don't worry about that.
We should all go dancing later...
[BENNY]
If there's AC, I'm there. Usnavi?
[USNAVI]
Actually, Vanessa and I already have plans
[VANESSA]
But you guys should come too.
The more friends the better, right?
[USNAVI]
You know it, friend!
[BENNY]
Boss!
[KEVIN]
The west side highway was bumper to bumper!
[EVERYONE GREETS]
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Mira pa'lla. Who's this handsome man?
[KEVIN]
It's my beautiful princesa
[NINA]
Hey, dad...
[KEVIN]
Excuse me, you're the princess,
Claudia is the queen
[CAMILA] And what does that make me?
[KEVIN] The dictator
[EVERYONE LAUGHS]
[CAMILA]
Damn straight
One day I'm gonna open my restaurant The Boricua
Until then, you're all my guinea pigs!
Serve yourselves, plates are in the kitchen
[KEVIN]
Ah, ah, listen up everyone. Atención!
[CAMILA]
Later honey, let's serve first,
the food is gonna get cold
[KEVIN]
Cami, the pernil can wait five minutes
Twenty seven years ago in Arecibo,
Puero Rico
I threw down my shovel,
hitched a ride into town,
and bought two plane tickets to Nuevayork
I showed up at Camila's house
with a suitcase and said vamos
[CAMILA]
That whole plane ride I was trying
not to cry, verdad?
[KEVIN]
The whole plane ride you were drinking Bacardi
[MORE LAUGHS]
[CAMILA]
Sin vergüenza!
[KEVIN]
We were Nina's age
And now look at you
You make me proud to be a Rosario
So I today I threw down my shovel again
Hitched a ride into town
and took another leap of faith
Nina, I sold the business to pay your titution
[NINA]
What?
[KEVIN]
I sold Rosario's
You're going back o Standford
[CAMILA]
Kevin, this had better be a joke
[KEVIN]
Uptown Investment takes over in two weeks
[CAMILA]
Uptown? Oh my god, they offered us nothing!
[KEVIN]
It was enough, mi vida
[NINA]
Wait. Dad. I'll find a job. I'll take night classes!
[KEVIN]
What, so you can end up,
just another girl stuck in el barrio?
[VANESSA]
Hey! Why you gotta look at me
when you say that
[BENNY]
Yo, did I just lose my job?
[CAMILA]
Of course not
I do the payroll, the banking,
your chaotic papers
We worked twenty years to
build this company
I worked!
[KEVIN]
For what, Cami?
Twenty years for what?
[NINA]
What about your employees?
[BENNY]
You can't just kick us to the curb
[USNAVI]
Your drivers are half my customers
[KEVIN]
I'm not a welfare office!
Family comes first, above everything
[BENNY]
The day you hired me you said I was family
[KEVIN]
That's business.
This is my daughter
[CAMILA]
You are all my family,
and you have my word:
we are not selling Rosario's
[KEVIN]
I'm making the damn deal
[CAMILA]
This is our business
[KEVIN]
It was in my name!
[CAMILA] Dinner is over!
[NINA] Mom!
[VANESSA]
Well, excuse me
I'm not good enough to sit with the bourgeoisie
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Con permiso
[USNAVI]
Vente abuela
[NINA] Benny, I'll fix this, I promise-
[KEVIN] Nina, stay away from him!
[BENNY]
I'll stay out of your way
[NINA]
You know I will never touch that money
[KEVIN]
So help me god,
you are flying back to California
Nina!
[CLUBBERS]
Vanessa!
[USNAVI]
Damn, this is nice
I really like what they’ve done with the lights
So, the hot club in Washington Heights
You might be right, this music’s tight
Yo, did I mention that you look great tonight
Because you do you really—
[VANESSA]
Usnavi, relax!
[USNAVI]
Relax, qué relaxed? I’m relaxed
[HOT COUPLE]
Wepa! Vanessa!
[USNAVI]
So you’ve been here before
I don’t go out; I get so busy with the store
Y cada día it’s a brand new chore
My arms are sore; no time for the dance floor
But maybe you and me should hang out some more
I’m such a dork, but I—
[VANESSA]
Let’s go get a drink
[USNAVI]
Something sweet
[VANESSA]
You know me, a little bit of cinnamon
[CLUBBERS]
Wepa! Vanessa!
[CHEERS]
[BENNY] Here’s to getting fired!
[USNAVI] To killing the mood!
[BOTH]
Salud!
[BENNY] Without so much as a “thank you!”
[USNAVI] After five long years
[BOTH]
Cheers!
[BENNY]
To finally getting Vanessa!
Man, fix your collar...
[USNAVI]
Holler!
[BENNY] To doing shots on a weekend!
[USNAVI] As long as you buy ‘em, l’chaim!
[JOSE] Hey you!
[VANESSA] Who me?
[JOSÉ] You wanna dance?
[VANESSA] Naw, man…
[JOSE]
Okay, I took my chance…
[USNAVI]
It’s cool, it’s cool, hey, if you want to…
[VANESSA] You don’t mind?
[USNAVI] I’m fine! I’m fine!
[BENNY]
Yo! Who’s Vanessa talkin’ to?
[USNAVI]
Some dude!
[BENNY]
Some dude?! That’s messed up,
she’s tryin’ to make you jealous!
[USNAVI]
Jealous, I ain’t jealous,
I can take all these fellas, whatever!
[NINA]
Benny, can we take a walk outside?
[BENNY]
And there she is
[NINA]
I’m so sorry, I didn’t know
[BENNY]
Who let you in?
Yo, this is the girl who cost us our jobs today!
[NINA]
I’m going to make it right!
[BENNY]
A toast to the end of all I know!
[NINA]
You’ve had enough!
[BENNY]
Says the girl who has it all
[NINA]
That’s not fair
[BENNY]
Well why don’t you run home to daddy?
He loves to remind me that I’ll never be
good enough for your family… for you…
[NINA]
You don’t know me
[BENNY]
Poor you...
[NINA]
I thought you were different
[BENNY]
Salud
[MEN]
Vanessa, let me get the next one!
Vanessa, let me interject some!
The way you sweat, the way you flex on the floor
It makes me want you more!
Vanessa, let me get the next one!
Vanessa, let me interject some!
The way you sweat, the way you flex on the floor
It makes me want you more!
[USNAVI]
Bartender! Let me get an amaretto sour
for this ghetto flower!
How are you so pretty?
You complete me
You had me at "hello," you know you need me
Truly, madly, deeply, let’s get freaky
Oh I get it you’re the strong and silent type
Well, I’m the Caribbean island type
And I can drive you wild all night!
But I digress!
Say something so I don’t stress
[YOLANDA] No hablo inglés
[USNAVI] Yes!
[EVERYONE'S HAVING FUN]
[A LOT OF AMAZING DANCING]
[AMAZING DANCING KEEPS GOING]
[A FIGHT STARTS]
[CONFUSED SCREAMS]
[PIRAGUA GUY] ¿Oye, qué pasó?
[USNAVI] Blackout, blackout!
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Vino el apagón
¡ay dios!
¿Oye, qué pasó?
Blackout, blackout!
Vino el apagón
¡ay dios!
[USNAVI]
Yo! I! Can’t! see!
Quit shovin’ you son-of-a
It’s an oven
And we gotta back out
This is a blackout!
Chill, for real or we’re gonna get killed!
[KEVIN]
Calling all
​taxis!
Everyone
​relax
​please
Calling all
​taxis!
[KEVIN / USNAVI]
Everyone ​relax ​please
[BENNY] Somebody better open these goddamn doors!
[SONNY] What’s going on? What’s going on?
[VANESSA]
Somebody better open these goddamn doors!
[BENNY]
[VANESSA / SONNY]
I can’t find Usnavi...
[USNAVI] Vanessa. Vanessa
[SONNY] tell him what is going on
[BENNY AND NINA CALL FOR EACH OTHER]
[USNAVI AND VANESA CALL FOR EACH OTHER]
[KEVIN]
Please find Nina!
And find Camila!
If you see my family bring them home!
[VANESSA] Usnavi help me
[SONNY] We are powerless. We are powerless
[VANESSA] You left me alone!
[SONNY/NEIGHBORS]
We are powerless
We are powerless!
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Yo! Yo! They throwin’ bottles in the street!
People lootin’ and shootin’
Sonny, they wanna see a robbery
We gotta keep movin’!
[SONNY]
Naw, man, I can’t leave
We gotta guard the store!
[GRAFFITI PETE]
They gonna bombard the store
Until you ain’t got a store no more!
[SONNY]
I got a baseball bat on a rack in the back
[GRAFFITI PETE]
I got a couple of Roman candles
We can distract the vandals!
[SONNY]
Hey yo I see some thugs comin’
Man, we gonna get jacked up!
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Gimme a light, I’ll be right back. Back up—
[GRAFFITI PETE/SONNY]
Back up! Back up!
[NEIGHBORS]
Look at the fireworks…
Look at the fireworks fly!
Light up the night sky…
Look at the fireworks…
Look at the fireworks fly!
Light up the night sky!
[SONNY]
It’s late and this grate won’t come down
Come down!
[SONNY] It’s late and this ​grate won’t ​come down!
[CARLA] Oh god ​so much ​panic! The crowd was manic
[SONNY/MEN] We are ​powerless. We are ​powerless
With everybody screaming and shoving
and shouting and slapping
We are ​powerless. We are-
And everyone’s frantic! What’s happening with you?
[EVERYONE]
​powerless!
[COMMUNITY]
Look at the fireworks…
[USNAVI]
Abuela are you alright?
[COMMUNITY]
Light up the night sky…
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
The stars are out tonight!
[COMMUNITY]
Look at the fireworks…
[USNAVI]
You’re not alone tonight…
[COMMUNITY]
Light up the night sky…
[USNAVI] You’re not alone tonight...
[ABUELA CLAUDIA] I’m not alone tonight...
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Usnavi, please promise me
You’ll guard this with your life
[USNAVI]
Abuela, I’ve never seen—
[USNAVI/ABUELA CLAUDIA]
This much money in my life!
[BENNY]
Nina there you are!
[NINA]
I’ve gotta go!
[BENNY]
I’ll get you out of here tonight!
[NINA]
I don’t need anything tonight!
I can find my way home
[BENNY]
Find your way home!
[NINA/BENNY]
Without you!
[NEIGHBORS]
Look at the fireworks…
Light up the night sky…
[ALL]
En Washington…
Look at the fireworks…
Look at the fireworks...
Light up the night sky…
[ALL]
En Washington Heights!
[END OF FIRST ACT]
[NINA]
Are you ready again?
[BENNY]
I think I'm ready
[NINA]
Ok, here we go
[NINA] Esquína
[BENNY] Corner
Tienda
Store
Bombilla
Lightbulb
You’re sure?
I’m… sure
[NINA]
Three out of three, you did alright!
[BENNY]
Well teach me a little more…
[NINA] Calor
[BENNY] Heat
Anoche
Last night
Dolor
Pain
[NINA]
That’s right
[NINA] Llámame
[BENNY] Call me
Azul
Blue
Ámame
Love me
[NINA]
Perhaps I do—
[BENNY]
Well, how do you say "kiss me"?
[NINA]
Bésame
[BENNY]
And how do you say "hold me"?
[NINA]
Abrázame
Al amanecer. At sunrise
[NINA/BENNY]
Anything at all can happen just before the sunrise
[NINA]
Al amanecer
[BENNY]
[NEIGHBORS]
Sunrise
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Sigue andando el camino por toda su vida
[CARLA / VANESSA / DANIELA]
Sunrise
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Respira
[DANIELA/CARLA/VANESSA/SONNY]
Sunrise
[KEVIN]
Nina…
[BENNY] I don’t know
[NINA] Yo no sé
What to do
Qué hacer
[BENNY]
Now that I’ve found you
[NINA]
Ahora que te encontré
[BENNY]
What will he say?
[NINA]
Qué dirá?
[BENNY]
When he sees me around you?
So how do you say "help me"?
[NINA]
Ayúdame
[BENNY]
And how do you say "promise me"?
[NINA]
Prométeme
[NINA/BENNY]
Promise me you’ll stay beyond the sunrise
I don’t care at all what people say beyond the sunrise
[NINA]
Promise me you’ll stay
[BENNY]
I’ll stay
[NEIGHBORS]
Sunrise
[BENNY]
And how do you say “kiss me"?
[NINA]
Bésame
[BENNY]
[NINA]
Bésame
[BENNY]
And how do you say "always"?
[NINA]
Para siempre…
[BENNY]
[NINA]
Al amanecer
[BENNY]
[COMMUNITY]
Al amanecer
[NINA/BENNY]
I will be there…
Al amanecer
[DANIELA]
Whoever did this, I'm gonna put a jinx on their head
[CARLA]
Dito, Usnavi, let us help you clean up
[USNAVI]
Thanks but I'd like to be alone
with my broken window
[SONNY]
I got most of the glass up
[USNAVI]
Recognize this?
[SONNY]
Bodega's first customer
[USNAVI]
First dollar my dad ever made here
Bueno, take whatever batteries
and candles we have
and take them to the church on Audubon
[SONNY]
You don't need no backup?
[USNAVI]
For what?
[SONNY]
For your soul, man
Dr Phill says that denial is
the first stage of grief
[USNAVI]
It's just a stolen register
a ripped up awning, al right,
It's just things
[VANESSA]
I heard
[USNAVI]
I still got a gas range,
you want some coffee
[VANESSA]
Nah, you got real stuff
to worry about
[USNAVI]
Listen... about last night,
Sonny was calling, abuela was alone...
[VANESSA]
My phone didn't ring once
Nobody cared if I was ok
[USNAVI]
I tried calling
[VANESSA]
I'm sorry about your bodega
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Yo, Sonny!
Sonny, you come check this wall!
I painted that shit by candlelight!
[SONNY]
Shhh, man's having female troubles
[GRAFFITI PETE]
My bad...
[USNAVI]
You got a new canvas
Tag up the whole store, have a blast
[GRAFFITI PETE]
What?
Anybody's bugging around here
[KEVIN]
Thank god
Where have you been?
[CAMILA]
Waiting here since three in the morning
for you and Nina
[KEVIN]
You should check your messages,
I've been combing the streets all night
looking for the two of you!
[NINA]
My phone died. She went dancing.
I tried to find her after the blackout
[KEVIN]
She followed your lead
She walked out the doors, same as you
[CAMILA]
Pero, carajo, who opened that door?
[KEVIN]
Camila!
[CAMILA]
Later, papi. Right now we find our daughter
[USNAVI]
Abuela!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Are you OK?
[ABUELA CLAUDIA/USNAVI]
Paciencia y fe!
[USNAVI]
Let me see it again!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
We kept it safe
[USNAVI]
So we survived the night;
What happens today?
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
A third for you
[USNAVI]
Uh huh, uh huh! Uh huh, uh huh!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
A third for me!
[USNAVI]
No pare! Sigue, sigue!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
The rest for Sonny—
And with our share of the money
And with our share of the money—
Dream of the seaside air!
See me beside you there!
Think of the hundreds of stories we will share!
You and I!
[USNAVI/ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Ayy…
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Now you can sell your store!
Open a bar by the shore!
I’ve told you hundreds of stories
About home; make some more
[USNAVI/ABUELA CLAUDIA]
More…
[USNAVI]
Yo! I know just where to go!
There’s a little beach named Playa Rincón
With no road, you need a rowboat or motorbike
To reach this beach, it’s just a stone’s throw
From home
My folks’ home
Before I was born
Before they passed on
And left me on my own,
in New York, with the grocery store
They would talk about home, I listened closely for
The way they whispered to each other
‘Bout the warmer winter weather
Inseparable, they even got sick together
They never got better… passed away that December
And left me with these memories like dyin’ embers
From a dream I can’t remember…
Ever since then it’s like
Another day deeper in debt with different dilemmas
The bodega’s a mess,
I’ll be seeing less of Vanessa
Abuela I don’t know how I can keep it together!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Remember the story of your name...
It was engraved on a passing ship on the
day your family came
Your father said “Usnavi,​
That’s what we’ll name the baby.”
[USNAVI]
It really said “U.S. Navy,” but hey…
I worked with what they gave me okay…
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
They’d be so proud of you today!
[USNAVI]
Then by the end of July
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Uh huh, uh huh! Uh huh, uh huh!
[USNAVI]
Out where the sea meets the sky!
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
No pare! Sigue, sigue!
[USNAVI/ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Think of the hundreds of stories We’ll create
You and I!
Ay…
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
We’ll find your island—
[USNAVI]
I’ll find my island sky
[ABUELA CLAUDIA]
Ay, find your island—
[USNAVI]
But whatever we do it’s—
[USNAVI/ABUELA CLAUDIA]
You and I!
[KEVIN]
I went down to the park, nothing
Any word here?
[CAMILA]
Mostly voice mails,
half of people's phones are out...
I got to the letter M...
[KEVIN]
Mira, alli está
[NINA]
Mom, dad
[KEVIN]
Start talking
[CAMILA]
Where the hell have you been?
[NINA]
I should have called, I know
[KEVIN]
Answer your mother! Where were you?
[BENNY]
Boss...
[NINA]
It's okay dad
[BENNY]
Mr Rosario, can I have a minute?
[KEVIN]
Think very hard about what you say to me
[NINA]
Just hear him out
[KEVIN]
Actually, no
I'll say this nicely
Please stay away from my daughter
[BENNY]
Sir, I've worked here since I was
practically a kid
You know me
[KEVIN]
Do you think you're anywhere CLOSE to her level?
[BENNY]
Of course not! Sir. No one is
[NINA]
Please stop calling him "sir"!
[KEVIN] You stay out of this!
[NINA] Jesus, Dad!
[KEVIN]
I taught you how to drive
I taught you how to tie a goddamn tie!
[BENNY]
And now I tie the same Windsor knot
around my collar as you
We're not that different!
[KEVIN] You know nothin about our-
[BENNY] This bullshit again
[CAMILA]
Kevin, cálmate
[KEVIN]
You will never be part of this family, entiendes?
[BENNY] Loud and clear
[NINA] Benny!
[BENNY]
Why learn the language if they
still won't hear you?
[KEVIN]
Sin vergüenza! Are you trying to shame me?
[NINA]
Yes, dad, that's exactly what I'm trying to do!
[KEVIN]
Well you've succeeded!
Congratulations, you succeed at everything-
[NINA] I'm sorry I embarras you!
[CAMILA] Oh, my god, enought
Now you listen to me…
[NINA] Mom…
[CAMILA] Carajo, I said enough!
I’m sick of all this fighting!
[KEVIN] Cami…
[CAMILA] Yapapapapa!
I think you’ve said enough
Now listen to what I say
What I say goes!
Papi, you’ve pushed us all away
[KEVIN] I’m trying to…
[CAMILA] I don’t wanna hear it!
We make decisions as a family
And throwing Benny out like that?
You sound just like your father!
We both know what a sonofabitch he was!
You think it all comes down to you…
[KEVIN]
Cami, let’s talk about it…
[CAMILA]
No no no no no!
No, you don’t!
When you have a problem you come home
You don’t go off and make matters worse
on your own
One day you’re gonna come back home
And you’re not gonna find me waiting any more
[KEVIN, spoken]
I’m sorry…
[CAMILA]
Huh. Damn right you’re sorry.​
So you stayed out all night
[NINA] Mom…
[CAMILA] I’m talking now!
You scared us half to death,
you know that right?
[NINA] I’m sorry—
[CAMILA] Don’t apologize to me
You save it for your father
[NINA, spoken]
What?
[CAMILA]
Look at your father
He doesn’t sleep when you’re gone
He’s worked his whole life to help you go farther
And he can’t admit when he’s wrong
Now who does that remind you of?
You two deserve each other!
For months you lied to us
What did we do…
To make you think we wouldn’t do
anything and everything for you?
When you have a problem, you come home
You don’t run off and hide from your family all alone!
You hear me?
When you have a problem, you come home
As long as we’re alive, you’re never on your own
Leave Benny!
Take Benny!
It doesn’t make any difference,
as long as you come home!
[KEVIN, spoken] Camila—
[CAMILA] No no no no no!
Enough lying!
Enough screaming!
I’m done trying
And I'm leaving it up to you!
It’s up to you!
I’ll see you both back home!
Enough!
[SONNY]
Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah. Let it, let it
My friend was trapped in the subway
They had to walk a mile in that
nasty dank tunnel
[SONNY] And he stepped on a rat
[GRAFFITI PETE] Ah, hell no!
[THEY ARE GROSSED OUT]
[DANIELA]
Okay...
OKAY!
[GRAFFITI PETE]
What?
[DANIELA]
I got through to Con Edison
They said it's gonna take about twenty four hours-
[EVERYONE COMPLAINS]
[DANIELA]
We can complain or we can get organized
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Then we all complain
[DANIELA]
Here, it's called a broom
[GRAFFITI PETE]
What do I do with this?
[DANIELA]
It's the Fourth of July, show some freaking spirit!
[VANESSA]
I'm catching a bus downtown for luch
Who's hungry
[SONNY]
Uh, no, they, they- no they stopped all the buses
the traffic lights are off
[VANESSA] Aggg, this is like Giligan's Ghetto Island
[GRAFFITI PETE] Tell me about that
[DANIELA]
Graffiti Pete, pon la música!
[GRAFFITI PETE]
I'm out of batteries
[SONNY] The dispatch has a generator
[GRAFFITI PETE] Ain't nobody there, man
[CARLA]
Well can't you open a hydrant?
[GRAFFITI PETE]
The popo's took my monkey wrench
[SONNY]
Yo, my sneakers are stuck to the damn street
[CARLA]
My fingernails are slipping off in the heat
[EVERYONE COMPLAINS AGAIN]
[DANIELA]
Hey! Hey!
What’s this tonteria that I’m seeing on the street?
I never thought I’d see the day…
Since when are Latin people scared of heat?
When I was a little girl
Growing up in the hills of Vega Alta
My favorite time of year was Christmas time!
Ask me why!
[CARLA, spoken]
Why?
[DANIELA]
There wasn’t an ounce of snow
But oh, the coquito would flow!
As we sang the Aguinaldo
The carnaval would begin to grow!
Business is closed, and we’re about to go…
Let’s have a carnaval del barrio!
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Wepa!
[COMMUNITY CHEERS]
[DANIELA]
Carnaval del barrio!
Carnaval…
[PIRAGUA GUY] Carnaval!
[DANIELA] Del barrio…
[PIRAGUA GUY] Barrio!
[DANIELA] Carnaval…
[SONNY / PIRAGUA GUY / GRAFFITI PETE] Carnaval!
[DANIELA] Del barrio…
[SONNY / PIRAGUA GUY / GRAFFITI PETE] Barrio!
[DANIELA]
We don’t need electricidad!
Get off your butt, avanza!
Saca la maraca, bring your tambourine
Come and join the parranda
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Wepa!
[EVERYONE]
Carnaval…
Del barrio!
Carnaval...
Carnaval…
Del barrio!
[CARLA]
Oh, me, me, me! Dani I have a question
I don’t know what you’re cantando
[DANIELA]
Just make it up as you go!
We are improvisando!
Lai le lo lai lo le lo lai!
You can sing anything!
[CARLA]
What?
[DANIELA]
Carla, whatever pops into your head
Just so long as you sing!
[CARLA]
Uh… My mom is Dominican-Cuban
My dad is from Chile and P.R. which means:
I’m Chile-Domini-Curican...
But I always say I’m from Queens!
[EVERYONE]
Carnaval…
Del barrio!
[VANESSA]
Why is everyone so happy?
We’re sweating and we have no power!
I gotta get out of here soon
This block’s getting worse by the hour!
You can’t even go to a club with a friend
Without having somebody shove you!
[DANIELA]
Ay, por favor Vanessa
don’t pretend that Usnavi’s your friend
We all know that he looooove you!
[COMMUNITY]
Ohhhh!!
[CARLA]
Wow, now that you mention
that sexual tension is easy to see!
[VANESSA]
Yo, this is bogus!
[DANIELA]
Haven’t you noticed you get all your coffee for free?
[Community cheers]
[EVERYONE]
Carnaval…
Del barrio!
[NEIGHBOR]
Here comes Usnavi!
[USNAVI]
Yo! Yo! Yo, y-y-yo-yo!
Now, now, everyone gather ‘round, sit
Down, listen, I got an announcement
Wow, it involves large amounts,
it’s somewhere in the range
of ninety-six thousand!
Atención, I’m closin’ shop!
Sonny, grab everybody a soda-pop!
Yo, grab a bottle, kiss it up to God
‘Cause Abuela Claudia just won the lotto!
Abuela Claudia won the lotto!
We’re bookin’ a flight for D.R. tomorrow!
[COMMUNITY]
Oh my gah!
[COMMUNITY (EXCEPT VANESSA & SONNY)]
Alza la bandera
La bandera Dominicana!
La bandera Puertoriqueña!
Alza la bandera
La bandera Mexicana!
La bandera Cubana!
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Pa’ribba esa bandera!
Álzala donde quiera!
Recuerdo de mi tierra!
[PIRAGUA GUY/USNAVI]
Me acuerdo de mi tierra!
Esa bonita bandera!
Contiene mi alma entera!
Y cuando yo me muera
Entiérrame en mi tierra!
[Dance break]
[PIRAGÜA GUY]
Eso es! Eso es!
[DANIELA]
Everything changes today!
[DANIELA/CARLA]
Usnavi’s on his way!
Off to a better place!
[DANIELA/CARLA]
Look at Vanessa’s face!
[BENNY]
Everything changes today!
Goodbye, Mr. Rosario!
I’m taking over the barrio!
[USNAVI/DANIELA/CARLA]
We’re getting out of the barrio!
[DANIELA]
Hey, Mr. Benny: have you seen any horses today?
[BENNY]
What do you mean?
[DANIELA]
I heard you and Nina went for a roll in the hay!
[ALL]
Hey! Ohhhh…
Benny and Nina
Sitting in a tree!
K-I-S-S-I-N-G!
Que bochinche!
Nina and Benny!
K-I-S-S-I-N-G!
[SONNY]
Hold up
[SONNY/GRAFFITI PETE]
Wait a minute!
[SONNY]
Usnavi’s leavin’ us for the Dominican Republic?
And Benny went and stole the girl
That I’m in love with?
She was my babysitter first!
Listen up, is that
What y’all want?
We close this bodega
The neighborhood is gone!
They selling the dispatch
And they closing the salon
And they’ll never turn the lights back on, ‘cause—
[SONNY/VANESSA]
We are powerless, we are powerless!
[SONNY]
And y’all keep dancin’ and singin’ and celebratin’
And it’s gettin’ late and this place disintegratin’ and—
[SONNY/VANESSA]
We are powerless, we are powerless!
[USNAVI]
Alright, we’re powerless, so light up a candle!
There’s nothing going on here that we can’t handle!
[SONNY]
You don’t understand, I’m not trying to be funny!
[USNAVI]
We’re gonna give a third of the money to you Sonny!
[SONNY] What?
[USNAVI] Yeah, yeah…
[SONNY] For real?
[USNAVI] Yes!
[USNAVI]
Maybe you’re right, Sonny, call in the coroners!
Maybe we’re powerless, a corner full of foreigners
Maybe this neighborhood’s changing forever
Maybe tonight is our last night together,
however!
How do you want to face it?
Do you wanna waste it,
when the end is so close you can taste it?
Y’all could cry with your head in the sand
I’m a fly this flag that I got in my hand!
[PIRAGUA GUY]
Pa’rriba esa bandera!
[PIRAGUA GUY/DANIELA]
Alzala donde quiera!
[USNAVI]
Can we raise our voice tonight?
Can we make a little noise tonight?
[PIRAGUA GUY/DANIELA/CARLA]
Esa bonita bandera!
Contiene mi alma entera!
[USNAVI]
In fact, can we sing so loud and raucous
They can hear us across the bridge in East Secaucus?
[CHORUS]
[USNAVI]
From Puerto Rico to Santo Domingo
Wherever we go, we rep our people and the beat go…
[CHORUS]
[USNAVI]
Vanessa, forget about what coulda been
Dance with me, one last night, in the hood again
[DANIELA/CARLA]
Wepa!
[COMMUNITY]
Carnaval del barrio!
Alza la bandera
La bandera Dominicana!
La bandera Puertoriqueña!
Alza la bandera
La bandera Mexicana!
La bandera
Alza la bandera!
Hey!
[KEVIN]
Atención,
atención
Roll down your windows
Turn up your radios
Un momento, por favor
Atención, atención
Please drive slow
Let everybody know
Abuela Claudia passed away
At noon today
[SOUL BREAKING SILENCE]
[USNAVI]
She was found and pronounced… at the scene
She was already lying in bed
The paramedics said
That her heart gave out…
I mean, that’s basically what they said
They said
A combination of the stress and the heat…
Why she never took her medicine,
I’ll never understand
I’d like to think she went out in peace
With pieces of bread crumbs in her hand
Abuela Claudia had simple pleasures
She sang the praises of things we ignore
Glass Coke bottles, bread crumbs, a sky full of stars
She cherished these things, she’d say: “Alabanza.”
Alabanza means to raise this
Thing to God’s face
And to sing, quite literally: “Praise to this.”
When she was here, the path was clear
And she was just here,
she was just here…
[NINA]
Alabanza
Alabanza a doña Claudia, señor
Alabanza,
alabanza
Alabanza
Alabanza a doña Claudia, señor
Alabanza,
alabanza
[NINA/DANIELA/VANESSA]
Alabanza
Alabanza a doña Claudia, señor
[+SONNY]
Alabanza,
alabanza
[COMMUNITY]
Alabanza
Alabanza a doña Claudia, señor
Alabanza,
alabanza
[CHORUS OF "ALABANZA" AND "PACIENCIA Y FÉ"]
[COMMUNITY]
Alabanza
[USNAVI]
[NINA]
New York Lotto, 1978
[USNAVI]
She thought it was bad luck to
throw anything away
[NINA]
"My Abuela's Front Door"
by Usnavi de la Vega! 3rd grade
[USNAVI]
I got a check minus on that thing
[NINA]
Nice handwriting
"My abuela's front door is busted up
It is falling off the...
[USNAVI]
I believe that would be "hinges." Spelled with a j
[NINA]
"The doorbell don't work
Because so many people comes over to visit
the doorknob be falling out"
The poet laureate of 183rd Street
[USNAVI]
Nina, how much is your tuition?
[NINA]
She asked me about it last night
[USNAVI]
Abuela would want you to have some
[NINA]
I have my parents, I can' take her money
But if you could spare some of these photos,
my dad would really appreciate it
[USNAVI]
I have a whole bunch of boxes inside
[NINA]
In this album there’s a picture
Of the ladies at Daniela’s
You can tell it’s from the eighties
By the volume of their hair
There you are, you are just a baby
‘Eighty-seven, Halloween
If it happened on this block, Abuela was there
And every afternoon I came
She’d make sure I did my homework
She could barely write her name
But even so…
She would stare at the paper
And tell me
“Bueno, let’s review
Why don’t you tell me
Everything you know.”
In this album there’s a picture
Of Abuela in Havana
She is holding a rag doll
Unsmiling, black and white
I wonder what she’s thinking
Does she know that she’ll be leaving
For the city on a cold dark night?
And on the day they ran
Did she dream of endless summer?
Did her mother have a plan?
Or did they just go?
Did somebody sit her down and say
“Claudia, get ready, to leave
Behind everything you know”?
Everything I know
What do I know?
[USNAVI]
I better go get the rest of those pictures
In this folder
there’s a picture
From my high school graduation
With the program, mint condition
And a star beside my name
Here’s a picture of my parents
As I left for California
She saved everything we gave her
Every little scrap of paper
And our lives are in these boxes
While the woman who held us is gone
But we go on, we grow, so…
Hold tight, Abuela, if you’re up there
I’ll make you proud of everything I know!
Thank you, for everything I know
[KEVIN]
The day I bought the business
that man took every dollar I had
[CAMILA]
Mr. O'Hanrahan.
When half this block was Irish
[KEVIN]
That polaroid is an antique
[NINA]
Dad, I just have to say something first
Benny is a good person
I hope you can trust me
Mom,
I've been thinking all day about what you said,
what dad did
If you have never quit,
there's no way I'm going to
I want to go back to Stanford and finish what I started
[KEVIN]
Camila?
[CAMILA]
Yes?
[KEVIN]
I'm asking for you support on this
[CAMILA]
So then ask
[KEVIN]
Mrs Rosario, are we ready to sell the business?
[CAMILA]
I will never be ready
But I know it's the right time
[KEVIN]
Okay
Then I'll be a mechanic again if that's what it takes
[NINA]
How can I pay you back?
[KEVIN]
When I was nine
I took some pieces of wood and made a box
I took a rag from the kitchen and an old coffee can
I walked down to the plaza en Arecibo
and shined shoes for a nickel
At the end of the day I had thirty five cents in the can
Did I spend it on candy?
Did I buy toys?
[CAMILA]
You bought shoe polish
[KEVIN]
Ah! I always had a mind for investments
Nina Rosario, Bachelor of Arts
When that day comes, we'll call it even
[NINA]
I love you, Dad
[DANIELA]
Still no power...
[CARLA / VANESSA]
Tell me something I don't know
[VANESSA]
I think that's all of the boxes
[CARLA / DANIELA]
Tell me something I don't know
[CARLA]
I'm seeing double
[DANIELA]
You always say that every time
you wear those tight pants
[DANIELA]
I got a little something something...
[VANESSA / CARLA]
No me diga
[DANIELA]
Vanessa's new address
A little birdie told me you needed a credit reference
[VANESSA]
What do you mean?
[DANIELA]
I'll cosing on the apartment
But you must invite me
for a housewarming cocktail
[VANESSA]
Where did you get this?
[DANIELA]
Usnavi swore me to secrecy...
Carla, what's my rule?
[CARLA]
She'll do anything for you,
but she won't support your mother's dysfunction
[VANESSA]
I know the rule,
I just never thought you meantthe first part of it
I'm touched
You care about me
[DANIELA]
Oye, I'm just signing the paper
You're still paying the rent!
[VANESSA]
Thank you
[CARLA]
How does it feel?
[DANIELA]
What?
[CARLA]
Spreading Jesus's love
[DANIELA]
I should have never gotten you that
"Miracle A Day" calendar
[CARLA]
Well, this is it
Make a farewell speech
[DANIELA]
It's like a band-aid,
you rip it off quick,
you don't even notice
[PIRAGUA GUY]
It's hotter than the islands are today
And Mister Softee's truck has broken down
And here come all his customers my way
I told you, I run this town!
Piragua, piragua
One-twenty-five, piragua!
Two-twenty-five, piragua!
New block of ice, hike up the price
Lai lo le lo lai, lai lo le lo lai
Blackouts are nice, blackouts are nice
Lo le lo lai
Keep scraping by
Piragua!
Sonny! Sonny, don't act like you can't hear me
State your purpose
Here's some of that lunch money
Go buy us a couple of pepperoni slices
So this is what it comes down to?
My severance package?
Money and liberty. It's what you always wanted
I'm setting you free! You're free!
No, no, no, no, no.
You think- you think Burt would ever abandon Ernie?
You think Knight Rider would
be anything without Kit?
No, he'd be taking a bus
Papa, you watch way too much TV
Can we talk about this tomorrow?
Fine. Bye. See ya
Eh! This is the end of an era!
He's got a point
How's it going?
[VANESSA]
So I got you a present
I went downtown to get it
Doing anything tonight?
[USNAVI] Cleaning
[VANESSA] Done for the day
[USNAVI] No way
[VANESSA] ‘Cuz we got a date
[USNAVI]
Okay—
[VANESSA]
Before you board that plane
I owe you a bottle of cold champagne
[USNAVI]
No…
[VANESSA]
Yeah, cold champagne
[USNAVI]
Damn, the bottle’s all sweaty and everything
[USNAVI] You went and got this—
[VANESSA] Pop the champagne
[USNAVI]
I don’t know if we have coffee cups
Or plastic cups, I think Sonny has the cups—
[VANESSA]
Tonight we’re drinking straight from the bottle
[VANESSA] Usnavi?
[USNAVI] Yeah?
[VANESSA]
Daniela told me what you did for me
And it’s honestly the sweetest thing
anyone ever did for me
Now, what can I say or do to possibly repay
you for your kindness?
[USNAVI]
How do you get this gold shit off?
[VANESSA]
Usnavi!
[USNAVI]
Yeah!
[VANESSA]
Before we both leave town!
Before the corner changes
and the signs are taken down
Let’s walk around the neighborhood
and say our goodbyes
Usnavi, are you alright?
[USNAVI]
I’m fine, I’m tryn’a open this champagne
See the twisty thing is broken
But I’m gonna open this damn champagne!
[VANESSA] Lemme see it
[USNAVI] No, I got it!
[VANESSA]
Yo, Usnavi, drop the champagne!
[USNAVI]
I mean you went to all this trouble to get
us a little bubbly—
[VANESSA]
And it’s gonna be okay
[USNAVI]
I’m sorry, it’s been a long day
[VANESSA]
You oughta stay
[USNAVI]
What?
[VANESSA]
You can use that money to fix this place
[USNAVI]
Ha ha, very funny
[VANESSA]
And it’s not like Sonny’s got role models—
[USNAVI]
Role models? Yo, what are you talking about?
[VANESSA]
I’m just saying, I think your vacation can wait—
[USNAVI]
Vacation? Vanessa, you’re leaving too—
[VANESSA]
I’m going down to West Fourth Street;
you can take the A—
[USNAVI]
What are you trying to say?
[VANESSA]
You’re leaving the country,
and we’re never gonna see you again—
[USNAVI]
What are you trying to say?
[VANESSA]
You get everyone addicted to your coffee
then off you go
[USNAVI]
Vanessa, I don’t know why you’re mad at me
[VANESSA]
I wish I was mad—
I’m just too late
[BENNY]
Thanks for coming, boss
[KEVIN]
You can call me Kevin. Look, if this is about Nina
[BENNY]
It's about you and me
[KEVIN]
She's going back in the fall
[BENNY]
Tomorrow I'ma start planning my own business
and I can't do that until I finish this
My uniform's on the counter
here's you keys
We're all squared away
I had your back, Kevin
Now I got my own
[BENNY]
When the sun goes down
You’re gonna need a flashlight
You’re gonna need a candle—
[NINA]
I think I can manage that
[BENNY]
When you leave town
I’m gonna buy you a calling card
[BENNY/NINA]
‘Cuz I’m falling hard for you
[NINA]
I go back on Labor Day
[BENNY]
And I will try to make my way
[BENNY/NINA]
Out west to California
[BENNY]
So we’ve got this summer
[NINA]
And we’ve got each other
Perhaps even longer
[BENNY]
When you’re on your own
And suddenly without me
Will you forget about me?
[NINA]
I couldn’t if I tried
[BENNY]
When I’m all alone
And I close my eyes
[BENNY/NINA]
That’s when I’ll see your face again
[BENNY]
And when you’re gone
You know that I’ll be waiting when you’re gone
[NINA]
But you’re here with me right now…
[BENNY]
We’ll be working hard, but if we should drift apart
[NINA]
Benny—
[BENNY]
Lemme take this moment just to say—
[NINA]
No, no—
[BENNY]
You are gonna change the world some day—
[NINA]
I’ll be thinking of home—
[BENNY/NINA]
And I’ll think of you every night
At the same time—
[BENNY]
When the sun goes down
[NINA]
[BENNY]
When the sun goes down
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Yo, you paged me?
[SONNY]
Shhh. Step into my office
I just came into some money and I got a business
proposition to throw your way
[WHISPERS INTO GRAFFITI PETE'S EAR]
[GRAFFITI PETE]
I'm feeling that
[SONNY]
Is enough to get you started?
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Shit, with this much cash I can hook it up
It's gonna take me all night
[SONNY]
Fine, but keep this between you and me, ok?
Alright
[BOLERO SINGER]
No te vayas
Si me dejas
Si te alejas de mi
Seguirás en mis recuerdos para siempre
Para siempre,
para siempre
Para siem—
Para siempre…
[USNAVI]
Lights out on Washington Heights
And now the crack of dawn
The blackout goes on and on and on…
Sonny’s out back, sortin’ the trash
As I think about the past with a sack full of cash
Abuela really wanted me up on a beach
With margaritas in my reach, and
Soon that’s how it’s gonna be…
Imagine me, leavin’ today
On a seven-forty-seven boardin’ JFK…
[NEIGHBOR]
The hydrants are open
Cool breezes blow…
[NEIGHBORS]
The hydrants are open
Cool breezes blow…
[PIRAGÜA GUY JOINS WITH HIS SONG]
[KEVIN AND CAMILA JOIN
SINGING "GOOD MORNING"]
[VANESSA JOINS SINGING
"IT WON'T BE LONG NOW"]
[USNAVI]
There’s a breeze off the Hudson
And just when
You think you’re sick of living here
the memory floods in
The morning light, off the fire escapes
The nights in Bennett Park blasting Big Pun tapes
I’m ‘a miss this place, to tell you the truth:
Kevin dispensin’ wisdom from his dispatch booth
And at dawn, Vanessa at the salon,
we gotta move on
But who’s gonna notice we’re gone?
When our job’s done, as the evening winds
Down to a crawl, son, can I ease my mind
When we’re all done? When we’ve resigned
In the long run, what do we leave behind?
Most of all, I’ll miss Abuela’s whispers
Doin’ the Lotto Pick Six every Christmas
In five years, when this whole city’s rich
folks and hipsters
Who’s gonna miss this raggedy little business?
[GRAFFITI PETE, spoken]
What it do? Ha ha, great sunlight this morning.​
[SONNY]
Yo cuz! We fixed the grate!
[USNAVI]
Yo, what did I tell you about this punk?
[SONNY]
You have to commission an artist
while his rate is still good.​
[GRAFFITI PETE, spoken]
It’s the first work in my new series.
[EMOTIONAL SILENCE]
[GRAFFITI PETE, spoken]
He hates it.
[SONNY]
Shh. He’s forming an artistic opinion.
[USNAVI] You did this last night?
[GRAFFITI PETE] Yeah​
[USNAVI] There goes my flight
[SONNY] What?
[USNAVI]
Graffiti Pete you’re gonna need some new cans
Here’s some money, finish up
There’s been a slight change of plans!
[GRAFFITI PETE]
Nice!
[USNAVI]
Listen up guys, you got a job, I’m not playin’
You gotta go now, tell the whole block I’m stayin’!
Go ahead, tell everyone we know!
Sonny…
Alright, go!
Yeah, I’m a streetlight!
Chillin’ in the heat!
I illuminate the stories of the people in the street
Some have happy endings
Some are bittersweet
But I know them all and that’s what
makes my life complete
And if not me, who keeps our legacies?
Who’s gonna keep the coffee sweet with secret recipes?
Abuela, rest in peace, you live in my memories
But Sonny’s gotta eat, and this corner is my destiny
Brings out the best in me, we pass a test and we keep pressin’
and yes indeed, you know I’ll never leave
If you close your eyes that hydrant is a beach
That siren is a breeze, that fire escape’s a
leaf on a palm tree!
Abuela I’m sorry
But I ain’t goin’ back because I’m telling your story
And I can say goodbye to you smilin’,
I found my island
I been on it this whole time
I’m home!
[CHORUS]
[USNAVI]
It’s a wonderful life that I’ve know
“Merry Christmas you ole’ Building and Loan!”
I’m home!
[CHORUS]
[USNAVI]
Abuela that ain’t a stoop, that’s your throne
Long after ya birds have all flown
I’m home!
Where the coffee’s non-stop
And I drop this hip-hop
In my mom and pop shop
I’m home!
Where people come
People go
Let me show all of these
People what I know
There’s no place like home!
And let me set the record straight!
I’m steppin’ to Vanessa
I’m gettin’ a second date
I’m home!
Where it’s a hundred in the shade
But with patience and faith
We remain
unafraid
I’m home!
You hear that music in the air?
Take the train to the top of the world
And I’m there
[USNAVI + COMMUNITY]
I’m home!