(lightning strikes)
(dramatic music)
(sirens sound)
- [Man] He's heading
across the field.
(dramatic music)
He's doubled back onto the road.
Let's go.
(dramatic music)
(engine starts)
(train horn sounds)
(dramatic music)
(sirens sound)
He's gotta be around
here somewhere.
Keep your eyes open.
(bird calls)
Ma'am.
There's an escaped
convict on the loose
and we're pretty
sure he came onto
your property from the beach.
He's a killer, lady.
- I haven't seen anyone.
But you're welcome
to look around.
(bird calls)
(dramatic music)
- What'd he do, bury himself?
Are you sure you haven't
seen anything, lady?
(dramatic music)
(bird calls)
- I think I saw him.
He's down there.
(dramatic music)
Hold it!
Stop or I'll shoot!
(dramatic music)
- That wasn't very
smart, Pascal.
Come on, back to your cage.
(dramatic music)
- Take it easy now,
you hear, Alex?
- Likewise, buddy.
- Don't worry, I'll see
you tomorrow morning.
Come by about 10:00.
(dog growling)
(dog barking)
- Hey, Bart, leave him alone.
Down, boy, down.
(dog barking)
Come back here.
Come on, come on,
come back here.
(bird calls)
Well, well, well,
if it isn't Lucille.
What do you keep in that?
Come on, remember old Michel?
Or have I changed that much?
- You're Michel?
The Michel?
- Now, now, I haven't seen
you since uncle Andre's.
Well you seem fine.
It is
Hey, who's the doll?
- [Lucille] That uncle
Andre's daughter.
- [Michel] Falesse?
(laughing)
Well look at her.
Why 13 years ago, you
only came up to my elbow.
I'm your cousin MIchel.
The meanie.
I always used to tease
the pants off of you.
Don't you remember?
You used to yell, Michel!
- Uh-uh.
Who cares?
Cousins are always welcome.
- Get a kiss?
- Of course.
(laughing)
- What brings you here, Michel?
- Ah, I'm just passing
through on business.
But I travel a lot for
pleasure too, of course.
(laughing)
You know how it is
when you get older,
you get a little nostalgic.
- Good morning, it
looks like your dog's
made himself right
at home already.
- Morning.
Doesn't say too much for his
master's manners, does it?
(laughing)
- [Lucille] Come on in, Michel.
I see you don't recognize Colin.
- Oh your son, no,
he's pretty grown up.
Here's to you, Andre.
Ah he's truly a great
man, you know that, Colin?
- Sure.
In his own way.
- You were too young.
Too young to really know him.
After all, you were only
five or six when it happened.
- Colin was eight at the time.
- Yep, little Colin was
just eight years old.
Not very experienced
but still old enough
to remember how the
supreme master Andre
who had survived so many
of the squalls of life,
ended up drowning like a rat.
- Colin.
You.
(laughing)
Don't talk about
father like that,
I won't permit it.
- Why so sensitive, m'lady?
What's important is you've
inherited his fortune and us.
Your underlings, who stand
always to kiss your feet.
(dramatic music)
- [Lucille] Colin.
(laughing)
I always warned him,
it was bound to get him
sooner or later, didn't I?
(dramatic music)
- Sure.
He loved to challenge the sea.
To try to master it.
He was a true sportsman.
How we all admired him.
Especially his
daughter, Falesse.
And then that morning, the
coast guard got a report
of a cabin cruiser
adrift unmanned.
Maybe the motor had broken down.
And he'd made a desperate
attempt to swim ashore.
The sea had always been his
idol and it became his tomb.
(dramatic music)
- [Man2] (Latin spoken)
- [Colin] Amen.
(laughing)
- Well look at the sort of
thing I carry around with me.
A bunch of knickknacks,
like this number here.
Why don't you try
it on for size, huh?
Picked it up at the
fair, the phono fair,
you know, in Copenhagen?
You should see the
goodies they got there.
- It's a living jewel.
- Go on, put it on your arm.
(laughing)
How's it feel?
Titillating, isn't it?
A friend of mine
went buggy over it.
(laughing)
- You're sweet.
- Throw it in here.
Kiki will be terribly tickeld.
- Kiki?
- And Kioko, we have two
vultures in the family.
I'm trying to satisfy
their appetite.
Drives him to destruction.
- They go for innards, feet,
vertebrae, sacred bones.
Real cuisine.
(laughing)
- To give a fellow like
that bones, you need
a cemetery practically.
- Practically.
- You got one?
Fascinated.
- If you really want to see
it, it's as good as done.
- Good.
- [Falesse] We found
some Etruscan tombs
right here on the ground.
- [Michel] Any gold?
- Nope, it had
already been looted.
There.
(laughing)
Think he'll get titillated?
- Why not?
(laughing)
Get in there, titillate.
You know that skull
looks like an old friend.
(laughing)
- Come on, what's happened
to your great appetite?
What is this, a hunger strike?
Come on, take it.
What's the matter?
(dog barking)
(dramatic music)
(bird calls)
- Well uncle Alfans.
(dog growling)
(bird calls)
(whistling)
- It sounded like your dog
was trembling with joy.
I bet he's met a girlfriend.
- Ah, he sure has
a way with women.
If I were half as successful.
- At titillating?
- Yeah.
- [Falesse] Don't despair,
Michel, the night's
still young, you may
have the same luck.
(dramatic music)
- A stroll in the moonlight?
How romantic.
I'd be the last to
want to interrupt you.
I'll retire.
Goodnight.
(laughing)
- "Dear Derek.
All well, road clear,
come immediately."
Okay.
Motel Hilton.
(dramatic music)
(lightning strikes)
(groaning)
(screaming)
(dramatic music)
- "Dear, Derek.
All well, road clear,
come immediately."
What does it mean?
And who's Derek?
(laughing)
- [Colin] Oh well, that's funny.
- Who's Derek?
Doesn't ring any bells.
Unless possibly it's--
- Who?
- No one.
Just a stupid thought.
(laughing)
- Let Kiki devour
it, he loves paper.
He's neglected.
(laughing)
- No it's going
to be sent to him.
It's the best thing.
This Derek knows
that Michel was here.
And if he gets Michel's note,
he won't get suspicious.
And he'll pop right down,
and we'll clear this all up.
All up.
- Another order for
soaps heads, hmm?
I'll mail it.
(bird calls)
- Ah.
Hi there, you mothers.
(laughing)
You want some too?
Yeah great bastards.
(bird calls)
(clock chiming)
Anyone home?
(dramatic music)
(whistling)
- Who are you?
- You the boss lady here?
- I asked first.
- Cigarette?
- Well?
- Name's Alex, Alex Borland.
Mm-mm.
Hey Michel wasn't kidding.
This is one beautiful villa.
By the way, where is Michel?
He said to come here at 10:30
and here he is standing me up.
Where are you hiding him?
In your bed?
- What are you talking about?
- About Michel.
And about his dog.
This is Buck's collar.
Look if Michel
and I are friends,
and Michel is your
cousin, the two of us
can be open with
each other, can't we?
- I suppose so.
Michel received a
call from London.
- An emergency,
story of my life.
- So he called a
taxi and he left.
But he did say to
expect company.
And he asked us to welcome
you, just like a cousin.
Oh here, would you like me
to light your cigarette?
- Huh?
Oh no, I don't smoke.
(laughing)
- You collect
people's cigarettes?
- It's just a thing I
have, like for women.
- Would you like to come in?
- With great pleasure.
Though I'm warning you,
you're taking a big risk.
I'm a Casanova, a dive
in the wool Don Juan
and women can't resist me.
(laughing)
- Oh.
- When I'm with a beautiful
girl, I'm like a man possessed.
I'm no amateur,
I've got technique.
You'll see.
- [Falesse] Are you
always like this?
- [Alex] Generosity
is my major failing.
(laughing)
I'll show you later.
- Get out!
- Colin?
- We don't need
parasites around here.
- That's a jealous house
boy you've got there.
- I apologize for his behavior.
This gentleman's my guest.
And no one else's.
- That was a very
impressive performance.
- Thank you.
- [Colin] The sun king
said a hearty appetite
is a sign of verility.
- The way you quote,
you must be a writer.
- No, I passed my time living.
That's a hard enough
job in itself.
- Colin is the
epitome of an artist.
He writes, sculpts, and paints.
This is one of his.
And that one, and that
one, and that one.
And he interprets Elliot
and Locker like nobody else.
Don't you agree, Lucille?
- It's shameful and disgusting.
- Must be sort of juice
stuff then, huh, Colin?
- Oh yes.
You want to hear it?
- Sure, why not?
You've made me curious.
- Yesterday's bit.
- That's a good way to keep
the kids out of trouble, huh?
To cut off artistic
drive is wicked.
- [Woman] Give me your lips.
Yes.
Oh.
Harder.
- It's a tremendous recording.
It even picks up the
pages being turned.
(moaning)
(upbeat music)
- [Man2] When a lovely
woman invites you
to madness, and the
room vertically crosses.
- [Woman] Soft music
enchants like a gentle mist.
- [Man2] Within
you, in your flesh.
What trembling, what arms.
- [Woman] What
heaven without truth?
- [Man2] What heaven,
garden of my agony?
From your veins,
blood flows to my lips
and quenches my--
(laughing)
To see you nude, is
to remember the earth.
- [Woman] The thread bare
earth, limped with horses.
- [Man2] Your belly
is a storm of roots.
- [Woman] Your lips are
the dark, livid with light.
- [Man2] Under the
tepid roses of the bed,
the dead awaiting in vain,
the hot breath of love.
You fling the covers
away, lie back,
and offer yourself, waiting
for the night to arouse
the 1,000-sorted throbbings
on which your soul feeds.
(dramatic music)
- Now why'd you do that?
To cut off artistic
drive is wicked.
Here, this is what you need now.
- You think so, huh?
Ask Colin if he thinks
this will do me.
What are you two waiting for?
You can go.
Go.
Your room is right this way.
What would you like to
help you go to sleep?
Soft music?
A book?
- [Alex] I have
my own technique.
I'll teach it to you.
(dramatic music)
- [Colin] Borland.
Do you know the praying mantis,
the role of the male?
If you don't go,
you'll play that role.
- Go away.
- You have my warning.
- You sure you're not a writer?
(laughing)
(dramatic music)
Oh no you don't.
You little bitch, so
this is your kick?
Spilling a guy's guts.
This is what happened
to Michel, isn't it?
Huh?
(dramatic music)
You killed him, didn't you?
(laughing)
- [Falesse] How dare
you touch my hair.
Only my father can touch it.
(laughing)
- And the carriage
turned into a pumpkin,
why the masquerade, Cinderella?
Golden locks.
- [Falesse] Only father.
My hair.
(laughing)
You're hurting me.
(dramatic music)
Father, only father can do it.
- My darling Falesse, with
your hair of shining gold,
soft and fine as silk.
(dramatic music)
- [Falesse] Father?
Father what are you
doing to Lucille?
Let her go.
No.
Don't hold me so tight.
You're hurting me.
No!
Why, father?
What are you doing, father?
No, let me go!
Father, let me go!
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
Why?
What are you doing to me?
Tell me.
Tell me, father.
What's this emptiness around me?
You deserted me again.
(upbeat music)
- Would you get me a reservation
on the next plane to Zurich?
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
- There's one this evening, sir.
(upbeat music)
(laughing)
- Were hung by the
chimney with care,
in hopes that Saint Nicholas
soon would be there.
The children were nestled,
all snug in their bed,
while visions of sugar
plums danced in their heads.
- [Man3] Where there is offense,
let me bring forgiveness.
- Is she fit to travel, doctor?
- All things considered, I
should think that would be
all right.
An emotional shock could
make her withdrawal further.
Although it might cure her.
That's her there.
- And ran to the window,
quick as a flash,
tore open the shudder,
threw up the sash.
When what to my wandering
eyes did appear,
but a miniature sled
and eight tiny reindeer.
The driver himself, a
right jolly old elf,
and I laughed when I--
- These bloom
three times a year.
But only in this pot.
Now why is that?
Strange, isn't it?
- That's because
plants are sensitive.
Show a plant that you care,
and then it likes to come out.
- They remind me of
the way Michel smelled.
- [Colin] Michel reincarnated
as a Chrysanthemum .
Jumping the gun a
bit, aren't you, baby?
- [Falesse] What?
- Madame, psychosis takes time.
- [Falesse] What do you mean?
You don't think
he's coming back?
- Why, don't you believe
in reincarnation?
- But that's, that's
Alex's sweater.
- Really?
I inherited it from him.
- [Falesse] Liar, take it off.
When he does come
back, you'll be sorry.
Take it off.
- [Lucille] Silence, you're
both being ridiculous.
There is no Alex.
(phone ringing)
- [Colin] Don't.
I'll answer it.
(phone ringing)
- [Pascal] Kid?
- Yes.
- [Pascal] Ah you're home, good.
Then we can have a little party,
I'm on my way.
- You're not welcome
here, bud, shove it.
(dramatic music)
- [Falesse] What's
wrong with me?
I feel a huge emptiness.
It makes me feel, I don't
know like I'm falling.
Like I'm falling, getting dizzy.
All the time, why?
Why?
I want to scream and struggle
but I don't know why.
(dramatic music)
- Kid.
(laughing)
Hello, friend, what
happened to my little party?
(laughing)
On your feet.
You heard!
Inside.
And behave yourself, huh?
I beg your pardon,
madam, I thought you'd be
expecting me.
(dramatic music)
May I?
Get up!
Move!
Ah, what's this, a
little chick-a-dee?
(laughing)
(screaming)
Oh pipe down, everybody's here.
- No!
- Everybody but you know who.
- No, Colin!
No!
- Stop, brat, or
I'll break your head.
I wasn't in jail 13
years for nothing.
I'm a specialist.
(laughing)
I heard a lot of things while
I was at the country club,
like about the blackmail
mob run by Mr. A.,
better known as Andre.
Now there was a true big shot.
- If it's money you want,
there's none in the house.
- What do you take me for,
a two-bit punk, huh, brat?
- If it's not money,
than what it is?
(laughing)
Take what you want and get out.
- The past 13 years
haven't aged you at all.
You're almost as lovely
as the night you were out
by the statue digging, just
before the cops came by
and found me hiding
in your bushes.
- Where'd you think that
up, the country club?
- Oh I thought you'd
remember, I do.
Cops might have got me, but
not before I saw it all.
Shall I refresh your memory?
How about a cabin cruiser
headed out to sea,
with no one aboard?
And the train, and how
about a beautiful woman
digging a grave
for her fellow man?
Better known as Andre.
As they say, silence is golden.
Now $100,000 for 13
years of golden silence
is nothing, why don't
we make it $200,000
and a gift here.
(laughing)
- No, let her alone.
- You and me are going to
wind up real good friends.
Here, have a slug.
I want you to be happy.
(laughing)
Coming back to the
business at hand.
I spent 13 years in jail,
never opened my mouth.
Now I could call it
quits for $100,000.
But let's think of the future.
Now for another
$100,000 I could let
Mr. A rot in peace
happily ever after.
- Now look, you, will
you listen to reason?
- You're being unreasonable.
And I've had it.
$200,000 or else the
police will come looking
for the corpse and you'll all
end up in prison for life.
Or if you prefer, you
can all end up with Mr. A
underneath the garden,
just keep that in mind.
- Could I ask you, Mr.--
- Pascal.
After the philosopher.
- This cadaver you
say is in the garden.
It couldn't' be that
you're mistaken.
It's all an unconscious
trick of your memory.
- There's one way to find out.
After all, maybe I
was drunk that night.
This way.
But if I wasn't
drunk, well let's go!
A little digging
won't hurt you any.
Especially since you're
used to it, right?
(laughing)
Put your weight into it.
Go on, dig.
(bird calls)
Give it here.
Time for you to take
a turn, chick-a-dee,
and work yourself
up a few blisters.
Get to work, no
tricks, understand?
Stay cool.
(laughing)
(bird calls)
At least your pets
know I'm right.
They can smell a
corpse a mile away.
(laughing)
(bird calls)
(dramatic music)
Okay, come on, brat, let's
see how many bones are left.
Hurry it up.
(dramatic music)
- [Colin] Is this what
you're looking for?
(bird calls)
- It's Michel's dog.
(dramatic music)
- $200,000 for this?
(bird calls)
- Will you admit that
you're wrong now?
- Shut your beak, you two.
(bird calls)
It was right by the
statue, I'm sure of it.
I'm no idiot.
I bet you think you played
it cool by moving the body
but you better think twice!
- We're not buying any of
your threats, so get out!
- Not buying?
Well then, I'm gonna have
you dig up every inch
of this estate until
you hit pay dirt.
(bird calls)
You asked for it, damn you.
(gunshots)
(dramatic music)
(bird calls)
- Kioka.
Kioka.
(bird calls)
I'll kill you!
- Colin!
(dramatic music)
(gasping)
Colin, Colin the pistol.
(dramatic music)
Colin!
Colin, watch out!
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
(bird calls)
(gasping)
- Punk brat, you
try that once more,
just once, and you're dead.
(bird calls)
Into the house.
Waiter, get us some whiskey.
We'll all have a drink then
we'll go back to digging.
Mr. A's going to pop
up sooner or later.
(laughing)
First the ladies.
You've gotta learn
some manners, brat.
All right, hurry
it up, slow poke.
My lips are getting chapped.
(laughing)
Let's all drink to freedom.
Ah, after 13 years of
prison, I got a right to.
No brats to wait on
you inside, no sir.
Ah.
Well that's water
under the bridge.
Let's have a little music.
(upbeat music)
- Hello, operator,
get me the police.
- Dumb, bitch.
Hold it, you two.
Wasn't very smart, was it?
Another trick like that,
and I'll hang you with this.
Over there!
(upbeat music)
- [Falesse] Pig!
- You.
Tie them up, one to the other.
Not too close, they've
gotta have run to function.
13 years is a long dry spell.
Oh the nights I dreamed of
having a beautiful woman.
And now I got two in one blow.
I got one for the main
dish, and one for dessert.
Problem is, which to have first?
Yeah.
(upbeat music)
Let's try the chick-a-dee.
Yeah.
(upbeat music)
I thought I warned you.
Didn't I?
You don't know how
close to death you are.
(upbeat music)
Listen, you brat, you
come at me once more
and I'll blast you.
Now why don't you
sit back and relax.
Ol' Pascal's going to treat
you to a passion play.
(laughing)
(upbeat music)
- You dirty bastard.
(crying)
(laughing)
- You enjoyed the
passion play, didn't you?
We'll have to give you
a repeat peformance.
The supporting
actress has loved it.
Come on, you loved
it, tell the brat.
She loved it.
It's good for you,
keeps you in shape.
(laughing)
Whip me up a souffle,
half a dozen eggs,
rest of us are going
out for some exercise.
Come on, let's go.
Move.
Come on, you too.
(dramatic music)
Dammit, he can't have
just disappeared.
Gotta be here somewhere.
Damn it to hell, I'm not crazy.
You'll find that
body, and by tonight.
That's if you know
what's good for you,
you understand me, brat?
Go on, dig!
(dramatic music)
Ah, here comes my breakfast.
(bird calls)
Care to join me,
chick-a-dee, you had a
real workout last night.
(laughing)
You gotta keep your strength up.
For next time.
(laughing)
You use six eggs?
Huh?
Yeah I guess that's big enough.
Hmm.
You try it first.
Is it good?
(laughing)
Lovely, fit for a king.
Say ah.
(laughing)
What's the matter,
don't you like bananas?
(laughing)
(dramatic music)
- $200,000, huh?
Now where on earth
am I going to get
that kind of money?
(laughing)
- I'll take this off
your hands for a start.
Should be worth a
couple of thousand.
Now let's see.
(dramatic music)
What's this rat hole used for?
- [Falesse] Rats.
- [Pascal] Oh.
(dramatic music)
Hmm.
And what have we here?
Well.
- [Falesse] The whole estate
is an archaeological site.
These are the remains of
the Etruscan civilization.
- Oh yeah?
You think we can maybe
include the remains
of your father?
- Those bones are
2,000 years old.
You can see that.
- Oh, I wasn't around then.
- And besides, no killer
would be about to place
his own victim on
display like this.
- I wouldn't be surprised.
Hey, what's this?
- I'd call it the kiss
of death, for you.
- [Pascal] Huh?
- [Colin] We do the
washing in here.
And it's rather obvious
washing isn't your cup of tea.
(laughing)
- Yeah, that's very good.
Kiss of death.
Yeah well water isn't
good for you but
I'd sort of like to get
the stink of jail off me.
I believe I'll take the risk.
Brat, fix me a bath.
- Yes, sir.
With pleasure, sir.
- No, no, you jerk, not
here in the outhouse.
Upstairs, chick-a-dee's
bathtub, with lots of
bath oil and a sponge,
you understand?
- No I don't understand.
Go ahead, run to the
police with your story.
If they come looking, who knows?
The body they find
might just be yours.
- [Pascal] You think so?
Then say it again.
Say it again.
You want to change your mind?
Then move.
You're lucky, brat.
(door closes)
(coo-coo clock chimes)
(door opens and closes)
- [Lucille] You mustn't
provoke him, Colin.
- Look, I've had it.
He has to go.
If we could get his gun away.
- [Lucille] Cyanide,
you should see it work.
It did quite a thorough job,
first time I watched it.
(dramatic music)
When the Germans told us we
were going to take a shower
that meant it was the end.
The shower was a gas chamber.
My mother, my
sisters, my friends,
they were all gassed.
But as for me--
(dramatic music)
- Not you.
- Go on, keep moving.
- She can have a
shower next time.
- Sure, why not?
Sooner or later.
- No, let me go.
- You should be grateful.
- I want to die with the others.
Mother.
Mamma.
(crying)
I couldn't hear them but
I could see everything
through the windows, how
they cried and choked
as the gas enveloped them.
Took only a moment.
(crying)
Let me die with my mamma.
(dramatic music)
- [Man3] Don't worry,
you'll get your turn too,
sooner or later.
(laughing)
(crying)
(dramatic music)
- It's the matter of a second.
There's not even time to react.
- [Pascal] Ah.
(laughing)
Oh.
Ooh.
(laughing)
Oh.
(upbeat music)
(laughing)
Oh boy.
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
Ah.
- Don't.
Let me go.
(crying)
- Oh yeah, oh, oh yeah.
Yeah.
Oh.
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
(gasping)
(dramatic music)
- You can relax now,
I think our guest's
grown bored with it all.
Come on upstairs,
you'll be amused.
(dramatic music)
There's nothing to fear.
- What are you doing
with that gas mask?
- [Colin] I was
playing World War I.
Over the top.
(laughing)
Come on, kid.
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
- Colin, who killed him?
Did you kill him?
- Oh no, the soap duds
didn't agree with him.
- You knew I liked him.
Yet you killed him.
You killed him because
you were jealous.
Because he's a real man
and you're only a worm.
A rotten worm.
- Thanks a lot, our only
other choices were getting
killed or going to jail.
Are you aware of that?
- Why jail?
You like to kill?
You're a sadist.
- Yes, like you.
- Sadist!
- [Colin] Go on, beat me.
- I will.
- I'm yours.
- Yes, you're
nothing but my slave.
Slave!
On your knees.
(laughing)
- [Colin] Beat me.
Yes.
- Yes.
My slave.
- Yes, yours.
- Stop it, Colin.
Colin.
Go on.
No more.
You too, Falesse.
We've got trouble
enough already.
- Well now what
are we going to do?
We can't leave him here.
- We'll do him like the others.
Don't you know?
Hmm, praying mantis?
You have a little fun and
then all of the sudden
they all wind up dead.
It's a regular ritual.
You create the problem and
our job is the final solution.
We're experts at it.
Like to help us out?
- No.
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
- Papa, no!
- [Colin] Pascal, can't you see?
(laughing)
(dramatic music)
(serene music)
(bird calls)
(dramatic music)
- Lucille.
(laughing)
It's me, Andre.
(dramatic music)
- Mr. A, that's not possible.
- Really?
It's true, I'm not a ghost.
- You're not the same man.
- I only look different
because of surgery.
There.
Very little left
of the old Andre.
You could say, as
everyone thinks,
that he did die years
ago, out there somewhere.
- Your eyes are his eyes.
- I've aged but nonetheless.
(dramatic music)
- Welcome to your old house.
- What an idea, having
me end up lost at sea.
It was very clever thinking.
- I thought it was best
after that horrible night.
- The boys were all
convinced by it too.
It was pleasant, you know,
to suddenly feel free.
- Yes, no one ever suspected.
When the priest was giving
the last rites down by
the pier, I began to cry,
along with the children.
Even I was convinced
for a moment.
(laughing)
(bird calls)
- Kiki, old pal.
You'd know me, no
matter what I look like.
(laughing)
(dramatic music)
- You hear, another
one for the birds.
(dramatic music)
- And Kioka?
- He died last year, old age.
Tell me, why didn't you ever
let me know where you were.
- I couldn't take the risk.
The police or worse the
gang might have found out.
Now that 13 years have passed,
they've forgotten me.
And with a face lift,
I'm in the clear.
Now my name is Derek Steele.
(laughing)
Mr. D.
Not wanting to stretch
my luck though,
I sent somebody ahead of me.
Michel gave me the green
light to come down.
So here I am.
- Well I'm delighted.
Oh what a lovely day.
I always knew you'd
come back to your home.
- I never once
doubted your loyalty.
And Falesse, what's
she like now, Lucille?
- I'll call her, she's upstairs.
Falesse, Falesse, Falesse.
She's no longer a little girl.
You have a lady for a daughter.
As pretty as can be.
I'll lead the way.
- [Andre] Thank you, Lucille.
- Colin, you'll never
guess who's here.
You don't recognize
my son, do you?
He's all grown up.
This is Andre.
- How do you do?
- Well amazing.
You are a big man.
Back then I thought
he was a born midget.
- Falesse.
(door closes)
Falesse.
Your father.
(serene music)
- [Andre] My child.
- No.
(serene music)
- I'm your father.
Oh, Falesse, how
I've missed you.
- No.
It's impossible.
My father's dead.
- What makes you think
that, Falesse, dear?
- [Falesse] It's true, he died.
It was 13 years ago.
He's dead, I killed him.
- No you didn't.
- I did.
- What is this?
It's me, Falesse.
I'm alive and well.
- No.
No.
My father's dead.
I didn't want to.
But I killed him, he's dead!
(dramatic music)
- Just who the hell are you?
Why don't you get out of
here, mind your own business.
- [Lucille] Colin, come
back here and apologize.
- [Andre] Never mind,
what's going on here?
I want an explanation.
(serene music)
- The night the killer
came here to the house.
I suppose his orders
were simply to kill you.
(gunshots)
But when you got away,
and he realized he'd
bungled the job, he decided
to take it out on me.
Then Falesse arrived, the
shots had woken her up.
- Papa, Papa, what
are you doing, Papa?
- [Lucille] The
brute attacked her.
- No, no.
- [Lucille] Since it was
in her father's room,
she mistook him for you.
- [Falesse] You're hurting me.
(moaning)
- [Lucille] The child was raped.
After, when I
managed to free her,
she grabbed one of those swords
hanging in your room.
(dramatic music)
And she killed him.
(screaming)
(dramatic music)
From that moment on, she
believed she had killed
her father.
I tried to get the
truth through to her.
She had a nervous
breakdown because I worked
so hard at it.
The best thing the doctors
tell me is to leave it alone.
In all other
respects, she's okay.
I did everything
possible for her.
I'm sorry, Andre,
but it's the truth.
- Such a horrible story.
(clock ticking)
(dramatic music)
- Yeah, I thought so.
You're not Mr. A.
He wouldn't try to
make his own daughter.
Get out of here, you
lecherous old bastard.
- Leave him alone, what
business is it of yours?
- So you'd take on
your own father, eh?
You're disgusting.
Slut!
- Now listen, young man,
tell me just one thing.
Where's your sister,
Lucille's daughter Ester?
Where is she?
- I don't get it, I mean
she's, well she's dead.
Tell him, Lucille.
- It's all right.
He was very attached to Ester.
- What happened to her?
- Four months after
you disapppeared.
While out riding her bicycle.
She was hit by a car.
(dramatic music)
The driver came around
too close to the curb.
She died instantly.
Right in front of my eyes.
(dramatic music)
I didn't want to stay on here.
But it was possible that
one day you might return.
- [Andre] You buried her in
the local cemetery, I suppose.
- Yes.
Yes we did.
We take flowers to
the grave regularly.
- Let's go there this afternoon.
(clock ticking)
(laughing)
- You needn't bother.
- I will though.
I want to see her.
(dramatic music)
- Ester. Radiguet, tomb 213.
Authorization of the
tomb and place bones
in the common channel,
now sign here.
- There's the mother.
(dramatic music)
This is Michel's car, isn't it?
What happened to
him, by the way?
- A couple days
ago, he took off.
Him and the other guy.
Look, but they'll be back.
- I hope so.
(dramatic music)
- It was terrible of you to
subject her to that today.
She's a very troubled person.
- [Andre] She suffered
nobly I thought.
- [Lucille] Didn't you believe
that Ester was really dead?
(laughing)
- And now I believe
it even less.
The family album, tombstone.
(laughing)
Fake mole and a wig.
A cemetery registered
altered for a fee and then
the whole thing's done.
Who would ever
think of checking?
Perfect caper.
- What are you
inferring by all this?
- I'm afraid you're going
to have to come clean.
- [Lucille] Any suggestions?
- For a start, where's
my daughter Falesse?
That's just a warning.
Come on now, Lucille.
Where's Falesse?
What have you done with her?
Why this masquerade?
Where's my daughter?
Answer me.
- She went insane.
When she killed that man.
(upbeat music)
(laughing)
- You committed her then?
- I gave Falesse every ounce
of help I could muster.
- How is she?
- Completely incurable,
so the doctors say.
- Have her brought here.
- Impossible now.
I'd be glad to go with you
if you'd like to see her.
- Impossible?
I disagree.
She's got to come here.
- Why?
- To settle this.
- No.
- Yes.
Plus she's the rightful owner.
(dramatic music)
This is her villa.
- No.
- Why not?
- It's the wrong way.
It's much too
noisy, it's vulgar.
That's not my style.
It's got to be clever.
With a touch of artistry.
Look I guarantee this
evening, we'll be free of him.
(bird calls)
(somber music)
- Falesse, my child.
- No emotions.
It's better if I handle her.
Dear, do you know who this is?
Do you remember?
He's your father.
Isn't it wonderful?
- * La, la, la, la
- My father sang.
- I liked it when Papa sang.
(gasping)
I'm very sorry, you see,
no one can touch me.
Oh the swing.
Ah.
Ester, let's swing.
Can you push us?
Papa's too busy.
He never comes and pushes,
he's always working.
(serene music)
Antoine.
He used to push me.
He's very strong.
But he was always
gentle with me.
He likes my hair.
He kisses it all the time.
He says it's made out of gold.
But the governess doesn't
like him to touch me.
There's nobody to caress
my hair any longer.
Antoine is gone.
Where did he go?
- [Lucille] He went away.
Your father doesn't know where.
Nobody knows where.
- Oh.
(bird calls)
Kiki.
Ah.
Where have you
been all this time?
Where's Kioka?
(laughing)
(bird calls)
- I used to play with
you on the swing.
(bird calls)
And Colin.
You remember, don't you?
(gasping)
(dramatic music)
- * La, la, la, la
* La, la, la, la, la, la
* La, la, la, la
(serene music)
(dramatic music)
- Come on, Eddie.
We can be a lot
rougher, you know?
So talk.
(dramatic music)
- Papa, Papa, where are you?
(serene music)
- He's not your father.
This man's nobody's father.
Leave him alone.
Go away.
Go away, everybody!
It can't be.
Tell them, Lucille.
Tell them he's not her father.
Tell them.
(dramatic music)
What's the matter?
Why don't you answer?
Is she his daughter?
Well if she's his
daughter, who am I?
Who am I?
- You're Ester.
Ester, my daughter.
You're, you're not
really Falesse.
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
- So, m'lady is really a
daughter of the governess, eh?
She's my sister?
(laughing)
And I'm her lover.
Oh incest, a couple of
children extraordinaire.
(laughing)
- Why this deceit?
Why all these lies?
Why didn't you
tell me the truth?
Was it my father?
I want to know the truth.
Was it?
Yes or no?
Well?
If it wasn't my father,
who did I kill that night?
Who did I kill?
- I don't know, it's
over and done with.
It's all in the past.
I did it for your sake.
(dramatic music)
- Just a second.
Out with the rest of it.
Everything.
(dramatic music)
Or I'll blow my head off.
- No, no.
Colin, have you
turned on me too?
All right, let's finish it.
(dramatic music)
- Antoine.
It was him.
Now I remember everything.
He did it, he raped me.
(gunshots)
- Failed, huh?
You said you'd fix it so
he never wake up, huh?
There's only one thing
you're any good for.
(dramatic music)
- [Falesse] Papa?
Papa?
(dramatic music)
(gasping)
Papa!
Help, Lucille.
Help me, Ester!
(gasping)
- Falesse, let her go!
No, leave her alone.
No, get off.
Let her go.
Leave!
(screaming)
Let her go.
Please let her go.
(moaning)
(dramatic music)
(screaming)
(serene music)
- Falesse, you've
come a long way.
But it's all clear
now, right, dear?
And there's nothing to
be afraid of, is there?
- It's all over now, darling.
And you're back
where you belong.
In your own house.
Forget that night, dear.
- Then, then I hadn't
killed anybody.
And nobody even
touched me that night.
Did they?
- It was always only
in your mind, Ester.
- The shock your
subconscious underwent
that night caused a
switch in personality.
As a result, you
believed you yourself
had suffered the
experiences of your friend.
Often in this kind of
case, they don't respond
to treatment, but
you were very lucky.
All you need now
is a little time.
(serene music)
- Forgive me, will you?
I'm sorry I took your place.
But I hadn't any idea
I wasn't really you.
(serene music)
- [Andre] I'm not through
with you yet, Lucille.
You know it's very interesting.
The night I fled through
the window, I was thoroughly
convinced I was a marked man.
Later it didn't figure
though, so I began to suspect
that maybe the boys didn't
want me out of the way
at all, all of the sudden
things started to click.
No, Antoine just wasn't
the type the gang
would use to rub someone out.
He was actually a
burden to the gang.
But he was good at one thing.
You became his
mistress and that's
when you started planning.
Taking him where you
believed no one would see
you together.
(upbeat music)
It was a lonely
stretch of beach,
where you could seduce him into
going along with you.
But I saw you.
I watched you spin your
web of sex and death.
Poor Antoine was too stupid,
too heated up to resist.
And willingly agreed to
go through with your plan.
(upbeat music)
It was simple and neat.
I'm having trouble with the
gang so why not kill me?
(gasping)
Just let it look as if
the gang had done it.
You'd be left with
the villa, the land
alone's worth a fortune,
you'd be on easy street.
But you made a mistake,
you killed your lover.
- I did it for them, the babies.
- You did, huh?
Yet you sent Falesse to
a clinic and brain-washed
your daughter and even your son.
- No.
No.
- [Andre] Murder
has to be paid for.
And it's your turn to pay.
(dramatic music)
(laughing)
(lightning strikes)
(dramatic music)
- [Colin] Mother.
- [Ester] Lucille!
(dramatic music)
Oh, Mommy.
Mommy.
(dramatic music)
Oh, God, why did she do it?
(crying)
(dramatic music)
(siren sounds)
(bird calls)
- All over, inspector?
- [Inspector] All over.
- What about Alex and Michel?
Was there any trace of them?
- They're past history.
One of the risks of the job.
The case is closed, sergeant.
I'm sorry to disillusion
you, Falesse.
It wasn't very easy playing
the part of your father
but I did it for
your sake, my dear.
Your father died in
prison three years ago.
But he asked the police
to look after you.
(bird calls)
Now that you're home
again, you can start
building yourself a new life,
and I wish you every success.
Goodbye, Falesse.
(dramatic music)