IN THE NAME OF THE LAW
This land, this lonely place left to
crack in the sun is Sicily...
... a place made up not only of the pleasant
orange gardens, olives and flowers...
... that you know of,
or think you know of...
... but also of burnt and naked fields...
... brick walls of blinding white...
... men steeped in ancient customs
that outsiders will never comprehend.
A world that is both mysterious and
splendid, of a harsh and tragic beauty.
Face to the ground!
Peppo, careful!
You?! It's you?
He recognised me.
Mafia! You?! Do me a favour!
Here you go: threatening letters, felled trees,
blackmail, the theft of livestock...
... and this morning they're killing
my cart drivers and stealing my mules.
And I'm supposed to continue trusting you?
Do me favour! Don't make me laugh!
You can tell your boss
that the mafia is finished.
And that in these parts delinquency reigns!
Go and tell him!
And tell him that from now on I will
be addressing the public authorities.
At least that won't cost me anything.
It had to be today that the new judge arrives...
Good, then we have nothing more to do here.
At your service, Baron...
Just a moment!
My friends, I didn't mean to offend you,
if you took that as a lack of respect...
- You were unwise to speak that way about
Boss Passalacqua. - Calm yourselves.
I might have been mistaken, but you
have to admit that in my shoes...
- In your shoes I'd choose my words carefully.
- Whoever disrespects the boss will pay.
- No need to worry, we know who it was.
- Boss Passalacqua has already decided.
This is your business,
I was talking about the mules.
You'll get them back... very soon.
And from us, not from the judge.
We don't need any judges here.
Good day, Sir...
Is that the coach for Capodarso?
That's it...
Thank you.
Guido Schiavi.
Do we know each other?
Someone travelling to Capodarso under
this sun, all dressed in black...
... who could you be if not Guido Schiavi?
- They're waiting for you... at Capodarso.
- But you...? - What time is it?
- Half past 4. - 90 minutes late,
but I'd wait for an entire day.
Listen, there's still time, the
train from Palermo isn't here yet.
- It's a question of patience. Are you
from the mainland? - No, from Palermo.
Good, then come with me. Within
4 hours you'll be back home again...
... then you can ask for a transfer
or otherwise resign and change trade.
Don't worry, you'll thank me when
you know my story.
Here it is!
Good luck!
He's the judge from Capodarso,
the one who resigned.
- Are you the new judge? - Yes.
- Then hurry up and get in, I'm leaving.
- My luggage, please.
- There's a ladder at the back.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Has the judge arrived?
Yes, help him get his luggage down,
I need to get going.
- Ah, it's you? - Yes... - Guido
Solari. - Schiavi, Guido Schiavi.
But please, control your enthusiasm.
Excuse us, Judge, if we're unable
to hide our disappointment.
- Sorry, but who are you?
- The Mayor, Mr. Leopoldo Pappalardo.
- The Chancellor.
- A pleasure...
We thought that after the last,
rather regrettable experience with...
you know, your predecessor?
We thought that perhaps they would send
someone more... how should I say it?
- Older.
- Exactly. Or less young.
It can be a difficult place,
and your predecessor...
I'm going, so take your luggage down.
- What are you doing? You don't need to.
- You shouldn't have to worry about that.
But they're my cases, and there doesn't
seem to be a luggage boy around...
- You're the number one authority in town.
- Yes.
- Here we value form.
- Welcome, Judge. Marshal Grifò.
- Nice to meet you.
- Do you value form, too, Marshal?
- Sorry Judge, I've been in the country, and...
Hey, the cases!
Sir, I've taken care of them.
Do you want me to take them to your house?
My house? I already have a house?
- The most beautiful house in the town.
- Yes, just around the corner from here.
I see, thank you.
See you tomorrow.
- At your service, Judge.
- We'll see you in court.
- Good evening.
- At your service. - Good evening.
- What's your name?
- Paolino, Sir.
Welcome, Judge, God bless you!
Come on up, I'll just open the door.
Come, make yourself at home,
I've prepared the room for you.
- Good evening. - No, no, give
them to me, I serve the judge.
- Here, Paolino.
- No, no! Good evening.
Good evening, Paolino.
Come in, come in.
It's nice, isn't it?
Nice, yes.
You will see that everything is here,
I hope it's to your satisfaction.
Your predecessor lived here, Mr. Pisani.
What happened to Pisani?
He just left without waiting for me.
You know, it's a difficult place.
What can I say? Mr. Pisani didn't understand
the atmosphere here and the people.
Here the people have their customs,
and one must respect them.
- The Baroness, next door. Need anything?
- No, thank you. Good evening.
- Was there anything else?
- You have an intelligent, friendly face.
You will understand how things are
in these parts right away.
So I'm happy to have you in my house,
and I like you already.
I know everyone around here,
and you'll see...
... people will take to you right away.
It won't be the same as with Mr. Pisani.
If you'll excuse me...
- My dear Lawyer!
- My dear Don Ciccio!
- On your way to the courtroom? - Yes.
- Come on, I'm heading there myself.
- Already? But it's only 10 O'clock!
- Well, once every so often...
I should be in the office
when the new judge arrives.
With time we'll calm him down, too.
- Ah, it's you. What happened to you?
Come in, come in. - Already up?
I thought that for the first morning...
You know, being tired from the journey...
- Chancellor, do you know it's already 10?
- Of course, of course. Here, I...
It doesn't matter! I'm sure that with time
we will understand one another better.
Right now you will need to find me a pair
of painters and also a bricklayer.
- A bricklayer? To do what?
- You don't see these walls? They're terrible!
If someone coughs, bricks fall down.
Go speak to the mayor.
- The mayor! May I? Attorney Faraglia.
- Nice to meet you. - It's an honour, Sir.
- I'm sorry, you've caught us at a time...
- Oh, it's nothing.
Finally, new air in this poor
and abandoned little place.
I congratulate you, illustrious judge...
... but you shouldn't have to wait
for anything from this administration.
I will tell the mayor that I
represent the opposition.
I will put the his back to the wall.
We will fight him, my dear
illustrious and amiable judge...
... and I put my body and soul
at your complete disposal, Sir.
Thank you.
Sorry, but what are you looking for?
Tell me, perhaps I can help.
- Are there many procedures like this?
- What procedures?
I mean, legal procedures that have been
left hanging for years, like these ones.
- Oh... - Good day, Judge.
- Good day, Marshal.
Can you tell me what you've been
doing in this place up until now?
There are cases that have been suspended
for two... three years!
You see, Judge, they are old affairs
that nobody thinks of anymore.
To take them out now, it would put
you against the entire town.
I am the only lawyer in the town...
... and I can tell you that
your predecessor was very wise...
... not to antagonise the natives,
their traditions...
Sorry for interrupting, but there's a
wounded man. It's Aleo, he's been shot.
- If you think it appropriate to visit him...
- And why didn't you tell us sooner?
Well, he's a criminal after all.
Put all those legal procedures back on track,
on Saturday I shall conduct the first hearing.
In the meantime, come with me. Let's go.
Make way, make way!
Doctor...
Aleo, I am the new judge.
Do you know who shot you?
- Yes...
- Come on, talk, give me a name.
Do it for yourself, for your parents.
Talk, tell me the name if you know it.
If I die, they forgive him.
If I live, they kill him...
You're his mother, do you not know anything?
An idea, a suspect...
And you others? Nobody knows anything?
Nobody saw anything?
Let's go, Marshal.
Listen up!
Ask him where he was when
the shooting took place.
Hey, Messana!
- Where were you this morning between 7 and 8?
- Being a good cop, Marshal?
- Don't mess around, answer me!
- If I must. I was with the Baron, ask him.
- Who runs the mafia around here?
- Boss Turi Passalacqua.
- The Baron? - You know how it is,
the rich people want protection.
- Go back inside, I'll see you later.
- Yes, Sir.
- Morning, bandit!
- Oh, Judge... good morning.
Looks like your girl's in trouble, eh?
- Going this way?
- Why not?
- What's your girl's name? - Bastianedda.
She's Lorenzina La Scaniota's daughter.
- And is Ciccio Messana a relative of hers?
- No, he's not a relative.
She's something, your mother. She acts like
a woman but then never wants to make love.
In this case, she was right though.
- I'll help you wash, stupid girl.
- She knows how to wash herself just fine!
If you're not careful, one day she'll
get you into a lot of trouble.
I know, she's my daughter after all.
- How old is the girl?
- 16, it's her time.
That's exactly what I was thinking.
Close that door, hussy!
And don't put your feet on the bed.
Why don't you let me marry her?
You can come too.
You would be able to stay at home all day.
I'm serious.
I've already told you no. You would just
take her away and leave me behind.
I said it out of concern for you.
Think about it.
Where are you going?
- Business.
- Vanni Vetriolo?
Things that aren't of any interest to women.
Goodbye, Bastianedda!
- Good day.
Don Peppino, aniseed!
- Did you not hear?
- No.
Aleo Calogero is dead.
Shot.
Another.
- Bye, everyone.
- Bye.
Hey!
You know where I live, don't you?
Go to my house, tell mother that I had to leave.
And that I don't know when I'll be back.
- Got it? - Yes.
- Tell her goodbye from me. Her and Father.
Scram.
- Greetings, Vanni. Where are you off
to in this heat? - Good day.
- Whose are those mules? - Mine.
- Since when have you owned mules?
Hey, come here a moment.
I want to take a look.
Vanni, stop!
Halt!
- Who's there? - Is the Baron home?
It's the judge.
Wait a moment, I'll come and open the door.
Hold on, I'll let him know.
- Excuse me.
- Come in.
- May I? Guido Schiavi.
- Yes, I know, the new judge.
- In this town everyone knows everything.
- I interrupted you, I'm sorry. - No, no...
I have all day to play.
I hear you playing from my house sometimes,
when I get home, in the evenings.
- Does it bother you?
- No, actually, I like to hear it.
At the end of the day, with the dark,
the thoughts of work can become too much.
- The music keeps me company.
- I don't imagine you'll be here for very long.
This isn't the kind of place to build a career.
- Pleased to meet you, dear judge.
- A pleasure.
I don't need to introduce my wife, I see.
Please, come through. Bring us coffee.
Come, come.
- Greetings, dear judge.
- Attorney. - Sit down.
The Baron insisted that I stay.
We were in a meeting up until you arrived.
We're glad that you took the time
to stop by, my client is very grateful.
- Just doing my duty. - My lawyer has
told me great things about you.
I see you've taken to the job with energy,
isn't that right? Doing what you feel is right.
I imagine that it won't be easy.
Yes, I find myself up against
some very serious difficulties.
- I've come to speak with you about mules.
- What mules?
Those that were stolen some days ago.
- I see you're well-informed.
- Yes, and it wasn't easy.
Because, if I may be so forward as to point out,
you didn't report the theft to the authorities.
Well, for something of such little importance...
A man was killed so that they
could steal your mules!
For this you will need to speak
to the relatives of the victim.
Yesterday another was killed out of
revenge for the death of the first.
- And I don't want to see a third.
- Anyway...
Hold on, I said that I came
to speak with you about the mules.
In fact, your mules have been
found by one of my policemen.
- You can send someone to retrieve them.
- Well, you astound me!
- Why? - That's the first time the police
have ever found anything around here.
Luck.
Nothing but luck. But I hope it continues.
See, Judge, you need to account
for the traditions, the customs...
Yes, yes, I see.
- Coffee?
- Thank you.
- You're not Sicilian, are you? - On the
contrary, I'm from Palermo? - Oh, really?
From your accent I wouldn't have guessed.
I'm Sicilian and I will
be accounting for everything.
This is why I came to you,
to ask for your co-operation, your help.
Do you know Boss Turi Passalacqua?
- Not yet.
- I can introduce you.
No one in this town will be able to help you
more than him. With Passalacqua's protection...
I see I haven't explained myself very well.
My wish is for everyone, including yourself
and Boss Turi Passalacqua...
... to be put under the protection of
the law, even if I have to do it myself.
You seem to be asking for power and
influence that I simply do not have.
- I see.
- My regards, dear judge.
Goodbye.
- How old are you, if you don't
mind me asking? - 26.
- Very young for a judge. Well done.
- Thank you.
Judge, Vanni Vetriolo is within our grasp.
- Have you found him?
- Almost, I've arrested his parents.
He's a killer, but he still loves them.
To make bail they will need money.
Within two days he'll be ours.
- You've committed an offence, do you see?
- But, Judge, Sir...
Let them out immediately. Let's go.
Come on, the judge is here.
Where is Vanni?
Your son Vanni, where is he?
It is in your interest that I ask.
If you love him so much,
tell me where he is, so that I can save him.
We haven't seen Vanni,
but my wife is dying of pain.
Return to your house,
you are free to go.
- The judge has told you to go home.
- Go on, go on.
You would think that my job would be
easy in a town like this...
I know, mine too.
- Enough! Silence! - Thieves!
- They should tear out your hearts!
- Sell outs! - May God strike down on you!
- Quiet, you!
- Want a smack in the face? - You think so?
- Yes, I do! - Stop that!
Look at Don Carletto in his gown!
It was him who wanted us to wear the gown.
And he made me put this on as well.
Loguzzo, Carmelo and Parise, Filippo.
- Do you have lawyers?
- How would we pay for a lawyer?
Sir, you will serve as the defence of Loguzzo.
Attorney Faraglia, you will defend Parise.
- Okay. - Parise, that guy will defend you well!
- You're saved, Parise.
- Next time ask the Baron to defend you.
- Silence!
Loguzzo, Carmelo and Parise, Filippo...
... you are charged with being seen together,
having some kind of physical altercation...
.. and damaging property in the process.
This offence is punishable under the article...
etcetera, etcetera...
Tell us what happened.
They are taking the bread from our mouths,
him and his parents.
They offer to work as farmhands
for 50 lire less than us.
He's a miner, not a farmhand.
But they always do this, all of them.
So the price for labour goes down.
- They steal bread and work.
- I have a wife and kids, they need to eat.
- I have a wife and kids too!
- We've been unemployed for 3 years.
- Make them reopen the mine, do your job!
- Enough! Get out!
Just a moment, Marshal. Hold on.
- You, what did you say? - Pay no attention
to them, Judge, they're ignorant people.
Come here. What did you say
Come closer, don't be afraid.
Repeat what you said.
I was talking about the mine,
it's been closed for three years.
You told me to do my job,
to make them reopen the mine. Why?
It's been 8 months since the court
ordered for it to be reopened.
No, not to reopen it, to survey it.
Just a survey.
- And we're dying of hunger!
- Judge, what about all this racket?
We've been waiting for 8 months,
they can't do anything right!
- And who does the mine belong to?
- What does that matter? - The Baron!
He closed it and doesn't want to reopen it.
He bought it all and we're dying of hunger.
- The court ordered it to be reopened!
- What happened to that order?
Silence! If there's a decree from
the court, it will be carried out.
We do not misplace or ignore
important files in this office.
Continue with the hearing.
Sir, it's your turn.
- Oh, dear Judge, we're happy to
see you visit our circle! - Thank you.
- Does everyone know each other? - Judge...
- Oh, Attorney.
- Good evening. - You've come to
speak with me, have you? - Yes.
Mayor, sit down. Please, take my place.
I get no satisfaction from playing
against such adversaries.
They're a little cold, aren't they? Things will
change, this is your first time here after all.
- Anyway, this is about the mine, yes?
- Exactly.
I see that Attorney Faraglia
has brought you up to speed.
In fact, I've dusted off this old file.
- The mine is not yours, is it?
- No, it's my wife's.
I run it, though the power
is merely delegated to me.
Yes, I know, the mine and the land.
You are very young and impulsive,
my dear judge.
The young never stop to think
that everything happens for a reason.
A profound reason at that,
my dear judge.
If the mine is closed, it hasn't
happened by chance...
... it's closed because the proprietor
has no interest in keeping it open.
And if a decree from the court has
been filed away for 8 months...
... then this didnt happen by chance either,
but because of a series of very serious motives.
As you see, in just a few words
we have exhausted this argument.
A cognac?
Two cognacs!
In that case, I see no reason why
the mine must remain closed.
Why, because you plan to carry out
this decree from the court...
... and survey it yourself?
I came to you out of trust, Baron.
There are 200 families of
miners that are going hungry.
Every day this misery provokes
all kinds of bloody brawls.
I was sure that you would
understand this problem...
... and help me save these unfortunate
people who are all depending on you.
I see I was mistaken.
That which I cannot achieve through you,
I will achieve through the law.
The law! Go and ask Boss Turi Passalacqua
who makes the laws around here.
You are wrong to have
taken this tone with me.
After all, the only person in this town
not laughing at you is me.
Do what you believe is right,
visit the mine whenever you like.
But don't bother me again, and
don't force me to write to Rome.
- I thank you for your frankness.
- Why?
Now I know exactly what I must do.
You don't know just yet.
On the basis of the survey, it is clear
that the main scaffolding...
... shows serious signs of water damage...
- I'm sorry, "damage"?
- Water damage.
... presumably caused by water from
overhanging banks of sulphur.
Prolonged inactivity will lead
to the collapse of the tunnel...
... permanently jeopardising an
eventual resuming of work in the mine.
- I have finished, Judge.
- Thank goodness! - About time!
What you do with this information
is entirely up to you.
As long as you don't use it against my client.
My work here was done with a neutral stance,
I only accepted to do the survey because...
Because you're a mining engineer, okay.
Don't worry, I will let everyone know
of your neutrality.
And if you want a piece of advice, now that
you've seen the place and saved face...
... you should leave this matter alone.
Excellent advice, and I should add,
if you plan to stand against him...
... you should know that the Baron, my client,
has people in Palermo, in Rome...
... and here.
Above all, here.
The mafia.
Good day, Sir.
Welcome to our land.
It's an honour to have you here,
for here Sir is always welcome.
A pleasure to meet you, Sir.
- Boss Gallinella.
- Sir.
Boss Parisi.
Carmine.
Tagliano.
Gambino.
Salomone...
Ciccio Messana.
Sir is very young, my friends
and I are happy about this...
... because we know that he who is
young is also pure of heart.
If Sir would like, perhaps we
could travel a little way together.
It would be a pleasure, Sir.
I would have come to Sir's
office to pay my respects...
... but the olive harvest
has taken up all my time.
Being an intelligent man, Sir will have
already realised how things go around here.
If I am to be honest, in my opinion
things are going very badly.
Things have been like this for more than
100 years, and but everyone here is happy.
Not everyone. The murder victims, for example,
the blackmailed, their families.
- And then there are the miners, farmhands...
- Every order has its weaknesses.
Besides, between men of honour
an agreement is always possible.
Sir only has to express his desires...
See, Sir, there's just one thing that
I desire and that I must do at any cost...
... to administer justice for the benefit
of all, in accordance with the law.
- What law, Judge?
- The only one I know: that of the State.
- Look over your shoulder, Judge.
- I've seen them, Sir. Your men.
You're a brave one, but the law here is
made in accordance with ancient customs.
We're on an island here,
the Government is very far away...
... and if it wasn't for us and
our severity...
... the gangs would ruin everything,
like weeds in the wheat field.
Nobody would be safe in their own house.
We are not criminals,
we are men of honour...
... free and independent
like the birds in the sky.
Then you will have to be my allies, Sir.
You know that the miners are hungry.
And you also know who killed Aleo Calogero.
Help me get the mine reopened and
hand over Calogero's killer...
... if you are indeed men of honour.
The shoves of children are caresses to men.
My words have been those of peace,
but yours have not. For that I'm sorry.
Good day, Sir.
- Jesus Christ...
- He's offended the mafia.
Jesus Christ, he's as crazy
as they come! He's crazy...
You're a gutsy man, Judge. From
today you can count on me all the way.
Unfortunately with Boss Passalacqua there's no
middle ground: you're either friends or enemies.
We are now his enemies, God help us.
Thank you, Marshal.
This is all we needed around here,
this arrogant imbecile.
- Send it! Send it right away!
- On my way home, Baron.
Within two days this will be in Rome
and his transfer will be made certain.
- Besides, now that he's disrespected
Boss Passalacqua... - A disgrace...
Good evening, Baron.
We will be done with him long before
his report on the mine is affected.
Good evening.
A disgrace...
Does it bother you?
Yes!
- Good evening.
- I had come down to here you play...
It was Chopin, wasn't it? - No...
Well, I don't know much about music.
Actually, I know nothing, but I like it.
- Yes, I know. - You know?!
- You told me. It keeps you company.
- Yes, and it keeps me sad, too.
- Me too...
- But what isn't sad in this place?
- You weren't born here? - No.
- And none of your family are here?
- No.
Listen, this morning you
disrespected the mafia...
... in town everybody knows, and
now all of them plan to ruin you.
- What should I do?
- Go. Leave, don't stay here.
This place is a graveyard. Those lucky
enough to be able to leave, should go.
- And you? - I have no reason to stay here,
nor to go anywhere else. But not you.
You are full of enthusiasm, of strength.
Leave here, save yourself.
- Baroness...
- Oh, don't call me that.
They sold me, me and all I had
for the title, and when I hear it...
Don't move, Judge.
Don't scream, Baroness.
- What do you want? Who are you?
- Vanni Vetriolo, I'm not here to hurt you.
I know that you released my folks
from prison, and I'm here to thank you.
I'm sorry for everything bad I've done,
but by now there is no putting it right.
The mafia wants me dead,
and one day or another...
... you will see me with my hands
folded on my chest.
My lady, forgive me if I scared you.
Judge, goodbye.
You are a real gentleman,
may God be with you.
Vanni, stop there!
Listen to me, Vanni!
Damn...
You're trembling. Were you afraid?
No!
Miss... Miss Teresa!
- Bastianedda, are you not dancing?
- I'm tired.
- She's already danced enough.
- You're right, I'm tired too.
Francesco!
Go on, dance.
- But I... - Go, I said.
Don't you dare disrespect me.
- Judge, welcome! - Hello, Paolino.
You weren't expecting me, were you?
- Actually no. It's my cousin getting married.
- So many people!
- I feel like dancing a little myself.
- Really? Sir is teasing me...
- Why, do you think I'm 90 years old?
- Then come, Sir, come and sit down.
Your visit is an honour. Come, come...
- Many congratulations and happiness
to you both. - Thank you, Sir.
Though I am sorry to have
interrupted the celebration.
Come on, hit it!
That's enough of your simpering.
Bastianedda.
Bastianedda... what is it?
- Something's happened, Paolino.
- What?
Ciccio Messana wants to marry me.
He's asked my mother.
Music! Come on, music!
I'm happy to see you again, Sir...
and keeping such good company, too.
Hosts and guests, please excuse the guns,
we're returning from a hunt.
- A good hunt...
- And where's the game, Sir?
Here, Judge.
A small gift for the young couple.
We have discovered the body of
Giovanni Vetriolo...
... that which, after an initial examination,
appears to have received two shots...
... that look to be the reason of death.
The shots were fired from close range.
Stated, confirmed and signed.
Capodarso, 10th of September, 1948.
- Okay?
- Yes, that's fine.
- The cartridge case! 12-gauge!
- That's what everyone has around here.
- Well, do you still need me?
- No.
Then I'm off, these shoes are hurting my feet...
Marshal! Take a look at this.
You don't have to be afraid, you'll be protected
even if you tell us. What did you see?
When they killed Vetriolo,
you weren't far away.
- You didn't see anybody? Hear anything?
- No, Sir.
What would I know about it?
Here, we work and mind our own business.
But they killed him just
300 metres from the house.
We were all asleep, Sir.
- Good day, everyone! - My respects.
- Good to see you, Sir, it's an honour.
- My respects, Boss. - My respects.
- Good day.
Good day. May I offer you a drink?
No, thank you, Marshal...
Perhaps I can offer you one.
The youth should not harbour
such dark thoughts, my dear judge...
... leave that to us men of the old world.
And allow this humble boss to
join you for a drink...
... to your health.
This morning, at the bottom of the valley...
where you and Gallinella passed yesterday...
... we found Vanni Vetriolo... dead.
Killed like a dog, with two shots
straight to the chest, point-blank range.
Now, I won't ask where you were
before arriving at the party...
... that would be useless.
But I will ask you one thing,
and you will answer me.
How do you call those men who kill
other men in cold blood? Tell me!
Vetriolo wasn't a man.
Of all his misdeeds,
this one was unforgivable...
... he killed the cart driver Parrinello.
Therefore, Judge, Vetriolo was made to pay.
Whether it was you to try him with your
array of men and useless papers...
... or two shots from a
double-barrelled shotgun...
... what difference does it make?
Justice has been done. That's what counts.
Justice... what justice?
And the men that killed him,
what do you call them?
Men of honour? No, Sir...
Bandits and killers, nothing else.
I have a son of about your age, who is
studying and who will honour my name...
... just like you honour your father's.
So forget this encounter.
When you are older and I am
no longer around anymore...
... perhaps Sir will go about
things better than this old man...
... and will understand that his
laws were just laws of nature...
... in which he honestly believed and
tried to apply in good faith...
... always as a gentleman...
... just as Sir, in good faith,
applies his own laws.
Sir, I cannot.
My respects, Judge.
What should I do?
Hand in my resignation like Pisani,
give up on the fight...
... and use the excuse that things
have always been like this?
Judge, everybody thinks it will end like
that. They're not expecting anything else.
I know...
- Oh, Paolino, what is it?
- Sir, please excuse me...
I wanted... It's just that Ciccio Messana
wants Bastianedda as his wife.
And what do you think the judge can...
Come.
Tell me everything.
I suppose her mother has said yes?
I don't know, Judge,
but Bastianedda is afraid.
I wanted my father to ask her mother
before she promises her to Ciccio.
But my father says that I'm too young.
- And that Bastianedda's mother is
a shady character. - And he's right.
Please help me, Judge. If they don't
let me marry her, I'll force them to.
- And what will you do?
- I know what I'll do.
Paolino, calm down. In one way or another
things will work out for the best.
- Oh, listen, this must be yours.
- No, that's Gallinella's.
Yesterday he came to the farm looking for it.
He said that it's very lucky.
Yes... it could well be.
So you wanted me to speak to your father?
- Oh, if you don't mind...
- Then we'll see what your father says.
- Thank you, Sir. My respects...
- Goodbye.
Paolino!
- Where have you been?
- What do you care?
Tano Gallinella...
What do you think?
Right, Judge.
Let's go, I'm coming with you.
- Be careful.
- Okay.
- Good day, Sir!
- Good day, Marshal.
It's you I was looking for.
- I keep good company, don't I?
- Exactly, and so do I.
Let's get this over with.
Listen up. Let me have a look
at barrel of your shotgun.
Be my guest.
- It's the same.
- Okay.
- Then we can go.
- Let's go.
Oh, by the way...
Here, take this, it's yours.
Get back! Get back!
- Do you know what you've done?
- Yes, and I hope that you do, too.
Let my guests pass.
"Therefore, the people, without
class distinction and conditions..."
- But it's...
- Let him finish. - It's okay.
It must mean something, though,
mustn't it?
"... without class distinction and
conditions, ask the powers that be..."
"... for the transfer to another office of
this incapable and conceited official".
Good day.
Nationals.
See that?
- Completely ignored. - You've irritated
the wasp's nest, Judge, be careful.
You're a good man, Don Peppino.
Good day.
That one will come to a bad end,
I assure you of that.
- I saw it from the first day he arrived.
- He's a crazy one alright.
It's better to stay away from him these days.
Excuse me. Excuse me!
Judge! Judge!
- Sorry, I have some very important news...
- Tell me, tell me.
- And calm yourself.
- I am calm, you know?
Tomorrow a niece of mine is coming to stay.
An orphan, poor thing... so you will have to...
- To what, Don Fifì?
- To find another place to stay.
- I'm sorry but it's essential that you...
- Okay!
Don't worry, Don Fifì, I'm going.
Ah, Judge, I almost forgot...
This arrived for you an hour ago.
Angela dropped it off, the maid
that serves the Baroness...
- Miss...
- I have very little time.
I warned you to be careful, but you've
gone and done something crazy.
Crazy and useless,
and now your life is in danger.
Something terrible might happen
to you at any moment, you know?
I tried to find out what
they're planning for you...
... but nobody is talking,
they're keeping it to themselves.
Why did you come to inform me?
I know that with you it's useless,
by now I know what you're like.
- You would rather die than let...
- No, that's not what I was asking.
And you know it.
You went out of your way for me,
you eavesdropped, spied...
Ever since that first night
when I arrived, tired, discouraged...
... and I heard you playing...
... you have been my only comfort
in this hostile and insidious place.
We've only spoken two times but
you've made me feel... less alone.
And I dared to believe that
you somehow felt the same way.
- I knew it, Teresa...
- No! We could never be together.
Good evening.
What do you think?
And you?
You?
And you...
And you?
You!
Good.
- You have decided. - And who will do it?
- Tano Gallinella. - But he's in prison.
The judge has disrespected him,
so it's up to him to deliver justice.
I leave this evening for Palermo,
within a few days Gallinella will be out.
They haven't testified and
the evidence is insufficient.
Let's move on to Paolino.
What do you think we should do?
- Paolino is working for the judge,
spying for him. - Are you sure?
I know that it was him who
recognised the medallion.
- How do you know? - I heard him
boasting about it... to Bastianedda.
Paolino is just a kid,
he doesn't know what he's saying.
He's a snake: a snake that lives to spy.
We must be certain.
Diego will look into it...
... and if Ciccio is telling the truth,
then Paolino will be made to pay.
It's La Scaniota! It's La Scaniota!
- You're too late! - They'll be done by now.
- Better prepare the confetti, La Scaniota!
- That girl is crazy!
- She's done well, she's done well!
Open up! You disgrace!
- You devils! Open up!
- You should let them marry, La Scaniota!
- They've already had their honeymoon!
- Now you have to let them get married!
And you thought she would choose Ciccio!
Get out of here, you bastards!
She wanted her to choose Ciccio!
Stop! What are you doing? Stop!
Scared?
Are you mad? Stop, I say! Stop!
- Roughly around 10 million, roughly...
- Is that all?!
Naturally the court will appoint an expert,
probably an examiner.
- Therefore, the sum...
- Forget it!
I wouldn't be able to pay 10 million,
not even if I sold my soul.
But that's the way it is, you must
reopen the mine, reactivate it...
In the report on the mine must be sent
to the government, written by the mayor...
- But I pay the mayor! - What could he
have done? The judge never took eyes off him.
So anyway, we reopen it.
Of course, the order is addressed to
the proprietor, the Baroness, meaning you...
I ran the mine, so I will be made
to answer for the sold machinery...
... the funds that disappeared,
etcetera, etcetera...
Yes, but you must have some way to
get 10 million, otherwise...
- Prison!
- A lawsuit.
Oh, no, for the love of God! You're my
lawyer, so advise me what to do.
I can only do so much, obviously,
because legally speaking...
You could secure the judge's transfer...
.. or, seeing that he arrested
Gallinella, convince Boss Turi to...
Boss Turi is going senile.
But the judge is very much aware,
because I...
... I'm not senile just yet!
Good day, Judge.
- I'm not sure if you deserve a greeting
anymore, Gallinella. - I'm free, see?
Free because I didn't do it.
Then if you're free,
it must mean that I'm wrong.
This is what the laws are for,
Gallinella.
So... good day to you, too.
And a packet of cigarettes, please.
I won't take your money. I've been waiting
to hear a reply like that for a long time!
- I just tell it how it is.
- Let me get you a drink.
No, Don Peppino,
don't put yourself out.
It's nothing. An occasion like this
deserves to be celebrated.
- You should be mayor.
- Someone bold like yourself.
Sir, may I? To your health, we hope
you're here for another 100 years.
- You rejuvenate us all.
- To your health. - To good health!
- Judge, Sir! Sorry, but is it true?
- Is what true?
About the mine. They're saying that
he'll be sued if the mine doesn't reopen.
Yes, but don't get your hopes up.
He's being sued, and the mine might
well reopen, but we must wait and hope.
- Yes, but we're going back to work.
- The mine is opening again.
Everyone in the town is saying so.
Back to work and it's all thanks to you.
- God bless you. - Yes, thank you.
But it's still early, nothing is certain.
- Judge, Sir...
- Excuse me.
- They brought this from the Baron's
house. Excuse me... - Just a moment.
I think... think that...
The envelope was open, so anyway...
- So you read what was written.
- Oh, no, I'd never do such a thing!
- But I saw that there was a card and so...
- Here!
- No! - Yes.
- He's inviting you to a party.
- The Baron is inviting you to a party.
- Yes, it seems so. Well?
Nothing, I was just thinking, it's an
honour for you... deserved, I mean.
- I see that this matter with the
mine is already... - Is already what?
Ah, I almost forgot, that niece
of mine that was coming to stay...
- Won't be coming. - Yes, she changed
her mind. But how did you know?
- Well, it was just a guess.
- So you'll be staying with me.
- Until the next niece turns up.
- What do you mean...
You can stay with me for as long as you like,
in my beautiful, comfortable house...
... with one window that opens onto the
street and another onto the Baron's garden.
You know, I can see the garden
from my window as well...
... right into the Baroness' garden...
... and I often look out in the
evenings to get a bit of fresh air.
If you'll excuse me...
- Well done, Judge! - Good evening.
- I'm pleased to see you back here.
Come, make yourself comfortable. I'll
finally introduce you to our society.
Dear friends, may I introduce
Mr Guido Schiavi, our new judge.
- Congratulations, Judge, finally
you're one of us. - Thank you.
- My wife. - In the town
all they do is talk about you.
- Oh, really? - They told us
that you were a terrible man.
Well, at the start, when people don't know each
other, there's always some misunderstanding.
Of course, but all that is now over
and we're happy to welcome you among us.
This calls for a toast! Music, please.
To the good health and harmony
of everyone in the room.
- For you.
- Thank you.
- Evening, Baroness.
- Good evening.
- Are you not drinking?
- Thank you. - Angela.
- What's going on?
- I received an invite. - Yes, I know.
But be careful, all these smiles
are frightening me.
- Listen, there's something else...
- Here we are.
My wife adores music,
but I can't stand it myself.
As soon as I hear her playing in one room,
I feel the need to move to another.
Come, I wanted to have a small chat with you.
Make yourself comfortable.
- A drink? - No, thank you.
What's this all about, Baron?
Please, sit down.
Then let us get straight down to business.
You saw this evening how people
have changed their opinion of you...
... this is because of me.
For now you have won your
case to reopen the mine.
Of course I have an appeal in the process
and am certain that I will win in the end.
- But I can't see why we can't be friends.
- That's all I'm asking for.
- I came looking for your co-operation.
- Exactly, co-operation.
- See, you help me and I help you.
- Yes, but... - Please, let me finish...
Just the other day one of us was talking
about the increasing cost of living.
To live well these days,
you need to own rivers of cash.
- Are you sure you wouldn't like a drink?
- No, thank you.
As I was saying, the cost of living...
I can't remember who, but someone was
complaining about the government wages.
The Chancellor, yes.
It must have been him, the poor man.
It's terrible that the government
pays its staff so poorly.
Besides, we know how difficult it is
to justify extra spending...
So someone, I can't remember who,
mentioned...
... that in some cases there are funds,
let's call them extra-government bonuses...
... that thanks to which, even the
most modest of salaries can balloon...
... things suddenly become,
in a word: possible.
And it's right, more than right.
- Don't you find, Judge?
- No.
- This was what you had to tell me?
- Young man, let's be clear about this...
- I thought we were clear already?
- No! Obviously not enough!
Only yesterday I received a letter,
a letter regarding my wife.
Read it!
- There really is no way to save you.
- Enough of your preaching, Reverend!
As you see, none of us stay clean for long.
We're all the same!
Then I will not reopen the mine!
And you? How much do you want to
walk away from this matter?
How much do you want to leave me in peace?
And to leave my wife in peace!
- Guido, what happened? - We must not
see each other again, Teresa. Ever again.
Guido...
Forgive me, Teresa.
I will never forget you. Goodbye.
Judge, the prosecutor has arrived
from Palermo and wants to see you.
- Where is he?
- At your house, Judge.
Good evening, Teresa.
- What was that?
- Nothing, nothing, just a poacher.
Baroness, don't go out there,
it might be dangerous.
Close the door!
- You missed him, didn't you?
- He was walking too fast...
You damn imbecile!
Now what do you want from me?
If you even breath a word
of this to anyone...
- Did he see you? - No. - So what are
you afraid of? It was an order from the mafia.
- Nobody will suspect us.
- Yes, but the mafia...
- Get out!
- Murderer.
- Murderer!
- Be quiet! Will you be quiet?
Murderer! No, I want to scream it for
everyone to hear! Murderer! Murderer!
Get out of here, you! Out!
Judge, the workers are
on their way to the mine.
Word spread that the case is won
and that work will start again soon.
Call the marshal, hurry. We must
stop them on the road to the mine.
Stop!
Stop, I tell you! You're jeopardising
everything! Stop! Wait!
- Get back, that's an order!
- What order? - The case is won.
- They already told us. - We're going
back to work. - Everyone knows by now.
- Get back!
- To your homes! Orders from the judge!
- Orders from the judge?
- Why?
I knew he was in with that lot,
that's why he was at the Baron's party.
There you go, done.
- How does it look? - Just a shock.
If you need me, I'm at your disposal.
- Goodnight.
- You know why I've come, don't you?
- I have an idea.
There are two types of young magistrate...
.. those that are broken down
and those that stand and fight.
- I belong to the second category.
- Exactly.
Stop! Get back! Get back!
Get back! Get back!
We want to work!
Come on, sit back down.
Excellency! Excellency!
- They're knocking by house down.
- Get me the marshal. - Yes. Marshal!
That the atmosphere is always going to
be hostile, that's a fact...
... but it's also a fact that you,
my esteemed colleague...
... haven't made any friends or allies
in the process, everyone is against you.
Everyone, poor and rich, good and bad.
You have just cause, but it's clear
that this isn't the place for you.
- You called, Excellency.
- So, will this racket never end?
- There are only a few of us, Excellency.
- Come on, don't make excuses!
- Fire your gun in the air!
- Of course, Excellency.
That there is a man you should
recommend for a promotion.
I was thinking of you, not the marshal.
See, from a human point of view
I can't praise you enough.
Get back! Get back!
- Enough! - We want to work!
- Miss, return to your house.
Though, I repeat, this is
not the place for you anymore.
I won't berate you because there's
absolutely no reason to.
You heard the miners before.
Under these conditions, I can't do
anything else but order your transfer...
... and as soon as possible.
A transfer. You realise that to transfer
would mean victory for the mafia...
... that with my transfer the reputation
and influence of the Government..
... would be most definitely
lost in this place...
... and that my successor would
have absolutely no power here.
I'm sure you've considered all of this,
and yet you're still telling me to leave.
I cannot, I would prefer
to leave the career itself.
It's useless to keep trying to
break down walls with one's head.
I give up...
I will hand in my resignation, instead.
I understand how you must be feeling,
but please think about it before deciding.
- I've already decided.
- Goodnight. - Goodnight.
Guido.
Teresa...
- I'm free, Teresa. I'm leaving.
- Take me away, I'll come away with you.
Well then, Chancellor,
finally you're rid of me.
What are you saying, Judge?
I feel... inconsolable.
I can see that...
Wish better fortune to my successor.
Thank you for everything, Marshal.
I'm sorry to leave you with this mess.
It's good that you're leaving, Judge,
you're still so young...
Dont worry about me, nothing to be done,
everything will go back to the way it was.
A shame...
I felt important with you by my side.
Paolino.
- Is it true that you're going, Judge?
- I'm on my way now.
Well done, Paolino, I'm happy you
came to say goodbye. How is your girl?
She's just outside, ashamed to come in.
Hey! Hey, Bastianedda!
Bastianedda, come here!
Don't be silly, come here.
Bastianedda!
Give her a kiss for me.
- I hope you're not jealous, eh?
- Of your, no.
- Whatever happened to Ciccio Messana?
- Thank God, nobody has seen him since.
Well, goodbye Paolino.
I'll be sure to write.
- And let me know when you get married.
- Goodbye.
Judge! Judge, Sir!
- What is it now?
- A murder.
What does that matter to me, Marshal?
I'm finished with this place now,
hand it over to my successor.
Who?
- Who?!
- Paolino.
Down there... dead.
- What's going on?
- Have they gone mad?
What's all this ringing?
Now that you're all here,
I should tell you that this is a trial.
Half an hour ago,
shot by a double-barrel shotgun...
... the corpse of Paolino was discovered.
He was 17 years old and
has never hurt anybody.
You killed him, instead of
helping me carry out my task...
... you have treated me as a threat to
your world of laziness and ignorance.
You killed him, you who have done
nothing but create problems in my task.
You, who have opposed me if
and whenever you got the chance.
Who have scorned and ignored me...
... accused me of being a disturber
of your peace!
You, men and women, who have
cowered in fear...
... even in front of those who are
trying to catch your child's murderers.
You have broken the law, even
when it was put there to protect you!
You have killed Paolino
because you prevented me...
... from administering justice and from
encouraging people to respect the law.
Of course, only one of you has
actually shot the boy...
... one who is perhaps listening
to me right now...
... and one who will never be punished
because he is protected by your fear.
You, men of the mafia,
and you, Boss Passalacqua...
... you, who are in your own
way wise and just...
... you, too have preferred your
bloody and cutthroat laws...
... that condemn he who disrespects
and protect he who does the condemning...
... laws that allow you to live and
slaughter one another like beasts
Now I've finished.
For the first time since I arrived here,
we're speaking face to face.
I know very well, by now,
what to expect from you.
And you now know what
to expect from me.
Because I will remain here, in this town
for as long as it is necessary...
... and will do my duty until the
very end, with or without you.
Until a blow from a shotgun...
... sends me to keep Paolino company.
Isn't that right, Boss Passalacqua?
You have spoken harshly, Judge.
More harshly than anyone here
has every spoken before.
But to me you have also spoken justly.
My men and I came here today,
not to listen to your words...
... but to punish Paolino's killer...
... and deliver justice swiftly,
in our own way.
But I was thinking of my
son while I was listening...
... and thought that he would have
been proud to hear you speak like this.
I will tell my friends that the time has
arrived to return to the law once again.
Perhaps all of us killed Paolino in some
small way, but just one man shot him.
And I will deliver him to Sir to be
tried under the laws of the State.
Go on.
Francesco Messana, you are under
arrest in the name of the law.
In the name of the law...