In front of you,
you can see the Colosseum.
- One of the 10 wonders of the world...
- Fausto!
Entirely built
thanks to foreign workforce.
In its center there's a cross,
as a statement of faith...
It's there... there...
is it true that the lions
used to eat the Christians in here?
Yes, haven't you heard
what the guide said?
The lions
ate 30 Christians a day.
At those times they were tough...
Further on you can see
the Arch of Constantine...
The "Emperor of the compromise."
A compromise with the Christians...
Another important monument,
also built by the slaves.
After all, even today they don't...
Well, you know...
even my mother, who is 85...
voted for the communists...
and make no mistake...
I didn't even have to convince her!
The old, glorious Catholic world...
of which you spoke
about at the congress...
...that world is dying, dear Fausto!
Dear Andrea,
Marxist Catholics like you or others...
are very few nowadays!
There's no one here...
Calm down... they'll come, you'll see...
They didn't even see them
at the hotel...
Your cappuccino is getting cold.
Why do you mix it with a spoon?
There's no sugar...
I take it with no sugar...
Can I have a couple
of cigarettes, Italo?
What's the point of going to visit
the Pope if the workers are not here?
I'll tell you what, if they don't come
I won't move from here...
- Who?
- The workers.
Well, listen... in our headquarters
we agreed that the workers' delegation...
would have joined us
at St. Angelo Castle.
or even at the Vatican...
Dear Italo, don't be annoying
with your concerns about the unions!
Well, I'll be straight with you,
Mr. honorable.
I don't give a damn about going to see
the priests without the workers!
- Thanks again!
- You're welcome.
Let's go Toppy...
Listen...
Don't write "husband..."
just write "my dear Sandro..."
Honeymoon?
We are here for the "Holy Year..."
I'm sorry...
What did she say?
She told me to say that I'm sorry...
You see, madam...
these are valuable items...
you gotta be careful...
How much is it?
800.000.
Please pack it for me.
Come!
- Hello Sandro!
- What happened? What did you do?
What is this?
It's a present for my father, I liked it
a lot, you'll see, it's very nice...
Let's take a walk, should we?
I tell the taxi driver
that he can go then...
No, father...
I don't want
to get married with him.
He's ugly, ignorant, and...
He's right! Marry me instead!
I am good looking, rich and intelligent!
Here I am!
What about those balls?
The Pope had to defend himself
from the barbarians...
who were pretty tough...
Fausto is coming...
He's always coming at the right time...
Hello Fausto.
Hello, hello Eugenia...
Here you go,
I couldn't change these 50.000.
Give them to me...
Listen, Eugenia...
I gotta talk to you...
Did you understand
that Italo wants us to bring...
also all the workers of our hospital
to the Vatican with us?
How long have you been here for?
For about half an hour...
Where were they?
Listen!
- I didn't even see them...
- There's not that much to see...
Could you
take a picture of us please?
You just have to press here,
it's all set.
Thank you.
Oh, I'm sorry...
with the castle in the background!
Come here.
"How many are they in the chapel?"
"Don't ask me, but ask your lady!"
Please take another picture!
The folders of the group
of the Hospital "Mater Dei..."
Fausto Santini.
Journalist.
Don Andrea Porini.
Maura Farina.
My sister.
Welcome.
Sandro Tacchini, surgeon.
- Doctor...
- Giulio Purini.
Sister Eugenia...
Sister Teresa...
Luigi Saitti.
Head physician.
Adelio Cicca.
Dear honorable...
Father Carlo.
Come Italo... we didn't say hello.
Vera Saitta.
Good, dear. Thank you.
Bullotti Italo.
Trade unionist.
A trade unionist...
Ahh, the troubled world of labor...
Come with me...
Here...
Can the head of the delegation
please follow me?
The head of the delegation...
You go, Luigi.
Together with the honorable.
Alright.
Everybody agree?
Of course.
Tell me how it ended up
with the workers...
They didn't want to come in the end!
Let's not say this to the others...
Please...
In the speech of the Holy Father...
We could hear some kind of new tone...
...and we could also see it in the
touching and meaningful ceremony...
that we attended earlier on...
in which...
Tell me, Monsignor, how come
you have files about everyone of us?
It's a precaution for the safety
of His Holiness the Pope...
The silver spanner...
as a symbol of the meeting...
We just aired...
"The News."
Look how nice my present is...
The story in this movie
is a fictitious one...
I think it's time, Eugenia...
The characters, unfortunately,
are not...
We're going to the Pope!
It's such a nice building...
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
How nice, it seems like a living room.
I pushed this button...
It's the right one.
Because it says "up."
And "up" in English
means "going higher."
It is better if we keep the presents
in our hands...
it's only a couple of floors.
That's good... because the lift
makes me uncomfortable...
"Vatican cable radio."
Let's relax...
The Pope won't eat us...
In any case, it's so exciting...
"Music of our times."
Don't smoke!
I think it's forbidden anyway...
everything is so neat!
You see Teresa, you can smoke in here...
Will it be you talking
once we're in, professor?
- Why?
- "Catholic Action."
As you wish, doctor.
But it's better if the presents
will be given by Vera.
What did she say?
She said she agrees.
Did you hear Camilla?
"I think it's right!"
- It's extraordinary.
- I also understand what Camilla says!
It seems like we've made it...
we lost the workers along the way!
What do you say?
I didn't think that things
were so easy in the Vatican...
"Do not anxiously go after
the comfort of the body"
"but think of the eternal season..."
Andrea, will the women
come in a separate way,
or will we go in all together?
We'll go in all together.
"Our missions."
What does "floar" mean?
"Floar" means "flower..."
Why does it says "60 flowers"?
Where?
Well, no...
That is "floor..."
It means "level."
So...
"Flower" means "fiore"
and "floor" means "piano."
Well, honorable,
we can't be at the 82nd floor!
It's an American way
of counting the floors.
We are talking of inches here...
Inches...
Oh, well...
Honorable, will you be the one
reading the message to the Pope?
Oh, no!
Let's have a youngster reading that!
Or maybe Rosa can do that!
She knows it by heart!
I'm not really sure
about this inches thing...
Take a look, now it says 112.
We've been here for at least 6 minutes.
It's not 6 minutes!
It's been maybe 1 minute! 2 minutes max!
Whatever...
Let's get ready: we'll be there soon.
I think we're probably
at the level of the cupola.
Carlo, come here.
Come and see.
"Sacred music of our times..."
Who knows if there are
restaurants in here...
There are canteens...
In any case I arranged something
for the lunch...
"Jesus sees... and Andrea provides!"
Study. Study, Rosa!
- Do you want?
- No, thanks.
Oh, another one!
Listen, Eugenia.
Of course Luigi couldn't help
but pushing those buttons!
Who told him to do it?
I hope
he didn't put us in trouble.
Listen, Gullotti.
Do me a favour.
If you wait a moment you won't die!
You're giving me anxiety.
You're not telling me
that there are 333 floors, are you?
- How tall is the cupola?
- We gotta do something!
I'm so distressed.
Let's not make jokes here...
First of all...
Are we sure it's moving?
What?
- What?
- The lift. The lift of course!
- The lift.
- Yeah, the lift...
Well, according to this we should be...
...at the 473rd floor!
Oh, come on... enough of that...
Do not touch anything.
It's going to be embarrassing
if we make trouble...
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
"This is the Vatican cable radio,
broadcasting for all the listeners"
"...a program about
all the churches of the world."
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
Please do something,
cos' I don't feel well.
Nothing is happening...
Push the alarm button.
Uncle...
We've been in here
for more than 15 minutes now...
It's better to push the alarm button.
God is testing us...
What are you saying?
What's the meaning of this?
It's hard to breathe in here...
Let's not make it dramatic,
dear Italo.
It is indeed easy
to breathe in here.
Let's bang all together every time
the light of a new floor is on!
So that they will hear us for sure.
I agree.
It doesn't have to be all of us
doing it... only the men can do it.
Andrea.
No, no, no... stop it!
- Who's taking a look at the light?
- Me!
Take a look at the light Andrea,
it's better...
It's better
if we all take a look at that.
Rosa.
- This is good fun!
- Now!
Now!
Harder!
Come on!
Well, let's try to be reasonable.
Let's examine the situation.
I think the best thing to do is to wait.
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
Bullotti, it's better if you put
your jacket back on.
"Good afternoon."
Otherwise you'll catch a cold
when we get out.
"Music from the new world."
Look!
The message for the Pope!
Hey, there is water here!
Just say that you are joking...
Where? Where?
I was joking.
That was a joke.
Vera...
made a joke.
Good Vera.
Well...
Let's make ourselves comfortable.
Andrea.
Let's ask around for some opinions.
No thanks, I'll stand.
You know what I think?
I feel very calm.
Let's relax
and see what we can really do.
Carlo.
You start.
I don't know...
I wouldn't know...
I'm not an expert of this...
I think it's just a common accident.
There is no issue that can't be solved.
No, Giulio, don't sit there!
The ampullas are there!
Sit on the other one.
They searched us.
Motherfuckers! Open it! Open it!
Open it! Open it! Open it!
The workers! The workers!
I want to go back to the workers!
Stop it Italo, calm down! We're not
going to solve anything like this...
- Shut up! Shut up!
- Italo!
- Do something!
- You're hurting her!
Move away! Move away!
Oh my God.
Italo...
Jesus... Jesus...
Eugenia...
Italo...
How is he, how is he?
He's OK... he's OK.
Here, smell this.
Stand him up.
Vera, help me.
Lie down, Bullotti.
The pillow.
- Just like the lizard...
- What?
Just like hay that burns...
Let's hope he's not hurt too bad.
All this is confusing...
- The old folks fell asleep...
- What?
The numbers...
If there are bombs on the tracks...
No one is backing off...
The leaders are not coming...
The fascists...
Poor Italo, he's delirious...
Watch out with that glass...
you'll cut yourself.
And it's better not to touch
anything anyway... give this to me.
The comrades...
Me too...
We are comrades...
We just needed this...
Look, Giulio...
The guns...
What?
The flags...
Maybe the lift is broken
and it keeps on going up and down.
Calm down Bullotti, be strong.
Well, in that case sooner or later
they will have to notice that...
Or maybe it's just a bad joke...
that doesn't really make me laugh...
By God! There's an injured person!
What does God have to do with this?
Who took his socks off him?
Did you try
to push the alarm button?
We pushed all of them.
Do you want to smoke?
Let's go in the corner
otherwise we'll bother everyone...
I'm sorry, can I also have a cigarette?
Maybe it's better
if we smoke in turns.
Uncle, I can't stand this anymore...
Vera, I told you already to be patient...
can't you see that I'm talking?
- You can talk to me, dear...
- Well, never mind.
"If you were born poor, after you die
you will be treated as a rich."
"If you were born rich,
you will be treated as poor..."
"A concept by Saint Barnaba."
We need something bigger...
Vera
take my present.
- Italo is dead.
- Jesus, how can that be?
We also have the paper cutter...
It's better with the cutlery...
gold is more resistant!
Did he die?
Just like on the trains...
are you scared?
No, please shut up.
I'll help you with that...
Leave it to me, dear...
Are you really sure?
Poor Italo.
Dead?!
Come on!
The trade unionist
is not feeling well...
Harder!
Come on!
Italo is not breathing.
He seems dead.
All together!
Now!
Damn!
- Did you cut yourself?
- Maybe it's the buttons!
What are you doing?! Are you crazy?
You'll break everything that way...
Give this to me.
If we manage to get to the cables,
we solve it.
- What we need is some paper...
- A piece of fabric?
We are trying to repair the lift.
So?
Honorable.
I don't know if that will be enough
as insulator.
Let's try...
There's no light!
Stop it!
You dumb idiots, can't you see
that there's no light now?
Mama! Mama!
So?
Well, the light went off though...
Yes it did...
They got to the contacts...
Leave it, Vera. You'll cut yourself.
They'll come off
when they open the door.
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
Do something, Sandro.
I'm having enough of this.
Well, don't tell me...
What about them?
Let them pray...
Let's go and talk to the honorable.
Think about our son!
I have to pee.
Vera, why don't you come here and pray?
You also, Giulio, it wouldn't hurt you
to pray, you know?
I don't believe
neither in saints nor Epiphany!
Why should I pray?
I really have to pee...!
You lout!
Well done!
- Shut up, you idiot!
- How dare you!
How dare you, you piece of shit!
Look here!
Giulio!
Giulio, Giulio!
Calm down.
Calm down, Giulio, leave it.
Let's try to be reasonable.
They can't take such things.
- They're old fashioned...
- Listen to those communists!
You're really educating them well,
these youngsters...
They learn bad behaviour in school...
Through this holy unction...
and His mercy...
may the Lord help you...
in the grace of the holy spirit...
Amen.
May He grant you indulgence
for your sins and save you...
and may His love lift you...
Amen.
Brothers, let's play for our brother
Italo and let's say all together:
"Hear our prayer, Lord."
May the Lord visit this infirm, and
comfort him through the holy unction.
Let's pray.
"Hear our prayer, Lord."
May He, thanks to His power,
keep him from evil...
"Hear our prayer, Lord."
Leave it, Maura.
We'll lose our balance.
May His grace comfort
all the sick ones, let's pray...
Honorable.
I can't help but thinking
that someone is spying on us...
Godless!
Stop it! Let them work!
You communists are very pragmatic...
when it's for your own good!
"Communists"? How dare you?
Teresa, do you enjoy
being trapped in here?
Did you find anything?
Everything seems to be welded.
...or it might even be
one single piece...
in any case, touching the ceiling
I could hear the vibrations...
Excuse me, Eugenia...
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
"Pilgrims rosary..."
- Do you want a piece?
- No, thanks.
I really can't stand
salami without bread...
Look, this is sticking out!
We have to lift it,
maybe we could find a way out...
Sandro, make them move those packets.
Vera, move to the other side...
Well, at least we found something.
Eugenia...
Take a bit of this.
Bad smell?
Take off your veil... you're sweating...
I can't. It's forbidden.
I'm sorry, Eugenia.
I'd really like to know
who's gonna pay for all these damages...
They're breaking everything.
What can you see?
Nothing.
It's all dark.
Well...
if it's dark,
it means that the night came...
There's air coming in...
There's some kind of whirlpool.
So...
I was telling you... a movie
can be aesthetically magnificent
but if it doesn't have
the moral requisites...
our duty is to advise against it...
- What do you mean?
- Well, out of many movies
that I had to see last year
because of my job as a critic.
Only about 20
were really advisable for families...
Who knows...
I probably read your articles many times
without knowing it was you...
How do we relate
to the workers nowadays?
Do we tell them the story
of the communists eating the children?
For example I think that...
Today... Marxism is changing...
And what about the violence?
We have to try
to stick together for now.
Andrea is Marxist...
but he is also a Christian.
Well, a Marxist dressed up as a lamb...
They're being ironic about us...
What a barbaric act...
Well...
If we're not careful, they'll let us
come out of here with no presents...
My present won't be touched by anyone...
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
"If you have no home,
the Bible will be your home."
"If you have no bread,
the Bible will be your bread."
"If you have no job,
faith will comfort you."
What is it? Are we there?
Stop it! Stop it!
In the name of God and
the Church, I exorcise you!
He's possessed! He's possessed!
Leave this body!
Carlo, come on!
Oh my God...
He's gone crazy.
Poor Carlo.
I had been
looking at him for a while...
You son of a gun!
Pig! Pig!
You want this?
Take it!
I'm sorry Carlo...
You'll see... it's better this way...
It doesn't matter...
While the men work...
Let's try to gather what's left...
Rosa.
Adelio, please... leave it...
Let's eat first, should we?
You could also turn, you know...
Stop it with that thing!
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
Stop smoking those cigarettes,
they're awful!
Maybe... but it's better than nothing...
Andrea, why are you Marxist?
Well...
I've read a lot...
Listen, Andrea...
let's be straight...
I observed you a lot...
If you get me out of here...
I'll make you rich, in maximum 2 years!
You know that my father
is rich and demented.
Fausto, my friend... please...
why don't you rest a while?
Well, my dear...
maybe you can trick the others,
but I won't buy it!
You got it?
Leave me alone, you idiot...
take a rest.
Listen...
In a while we won't be able
to think straight anymore.
There's no food anymore...
Jesus Christ, while establishing
the communion of the flesh said...
"Take this, all of you,
and eat it... this is my body."
This...
Honorable...
Eating did me some good...
What are you writing?
This is Fausto's.
He's writing
everything that's happening.
Give this to me!
How dare you?
- It was on the floor!
- So what?
Why did you write
that we'll all end up like Hitler?
It's a novel...
Asshole!
He's thinking about novels, this one...
Leave it...
It's dry.
It's useless.
Leave it...
I heard a noise!
Like some kind of voices...
No, no...
It was coming from here...
Thank goodness!
They had to hear us
sooner or later!
We are happy,
because they noticed that we are here!
What an adventure, damn!
What a mess that we did!
What are we doing with Italo?
What are we going to say?
Was Italo's name on the list?
There was, but then again...
there wasn't.
There was only written
"trade unionist."
Rosa.
Where is my veil?
Oh... help!
Help!
Help! Help!
Maybe I was wrong...
There's no hope...
This isn't fair...
You bastards.
I don't wanna die!
Keep an eye on Sandro...
I have to put this back, I'm sorry...
I'm not crazy...
I'm not crazy!
I know...
Let's take a decision
all together...
We're all aware that he's crazy...
It's terrible...
Yeah, I'm in.
We have to survive...
not for ourselves but for our faith...
Let's be realist.
Giulio.
Mind your own business!
You can vote as much as you want...
This is murder.
7 are in favour...
Are you dealing with it, Andrea?
What's the matter, Luigi? What's wrong?
I feel unwell.
I feel unwell...
Really, really...
Leave Carlo alone.
Take me instead.
I'm about to die.
The Lord will forgive you.
The uncle is sick!
Just like the time
when he had the heart problem.
Shut up you little tart...
Bitch! Bitches!
You're all bitches!
Let's moisten his lips.
Oh yeah... with what?
You are the bitch of the bitches!
Bitch!
Me?
What do I have to do with it?
You have hell between your legs!
Bitch!
Andrea...
look at what he had
in his underpants...
We'll give them to the poor...
That was
a close shave, dear Carlo...
"Do not anxiously go after
the comfort of the body"
"but think of the eternal season..."
Let me do it...
The numbers...
The numbers... the numbers... move away!
The numbers! The numbers!
We gotta stop the numbers...
We gotta stop them!
The numbers! We gotta stop them!
Leave it! Leave it!
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
We gotta make sure we're ready...
Look at him.
He's reading... reading his Bible...
The matter is clear...
We just need to know
who will be the next one...
You got it, finally!
"Vatican cable radio."
Let's free the priest...
It's all written...
There's no stopping all this...
This time it's going to be me.
It's either us or him...
Let's wait until the others are asleep.
Don't you worry...
Fausto...
Sandro, what are you doing?
Nothing.
Just sleep.
Is Maura sleeping?
Yeah, she is indeed...
You should also sleep...
I was thinking about the uncle...
Who knows where he is now?
Sleep.
He's in everyone of us...
Are you afraid?
...finding the door...
I gotta find the door...
the closet, the table... the chairs...
I gotta put the chairs there...
They don't have to let him in...
Domenico!
I was wishing...
I am like...
What do you want to do?
What do you know about all this?
If you don't tell me, I'll kill you.
Leave it, you idiot, just sleep...
I kill you!
Ahh! What is it? Oh God...
It's painful... it's painful...
What is it? What is it?
It's so painful! Oh God, it's painful...
What is it?
Do not touch her.
She could lose a lot of blood...
Here he is... the Marxist!
Shitty Communist!
It was you killing her, assassin!
No, you are the assassin!
What is all this?
He doesn't want to talk, the bastard!
Talk!
Give me the lighter, Maura.
I'll make his memory warm.
Well, I've had enough...
He doesn't know anything...
I'm thirsty...
I've done it for you too...
you idiots!
I'm thirsty...
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
Have mercy on us.
Once again...
Once again!
I would have done that...
He was sleeping!
He was sleeping...
Sandro!
He was sleeping!
My face. My face!
Adelio!
"Be honest with your family..."
"Submissive at work..."
"Easygoing with authorities..."
"A concept by Saint Fulgenzio."
It's good.
Eat it.
You will never eat me...
Will you?
Sleep.
- Come here, Fausto, come.
- "Praised be Jesus Christ."
"This is the Vatican cable radio,
broadcasting for all the listeners"
"...a program about
all the churches of the world."
Is it painful...
...to die of starvation?
I don't know.
I know that you...
...will help me...
I finally got it, you know?
What?
Thank you my Lord...
He will make us all saints...!
You bastard... don't you see she's dead?
"If you will be a good Christian,
you won't surrender to compromises..."
"and you will not be tempted
by other ideals..."
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
No!
Camilla no!
Help...
"Vatican cable radio..."
"Praised be Jesus Christ."
"Glory to the Lord,
and to the men of good will..."
Help!
Somebody help me!
Somebody help me.
Help!
Help.
Help me.
My child is dying!
Help.
You idiot...
...get out...
I want to get out...
Sister Teresa.
Your Eminence.
This is a great day for us...
A great day of a great year!
Bullotti Italo.
Father Carlo.
Sister Eugenia.
Luigi Saitti.
How beautiful is the Vatican!