(Man, speaker) Attention,
we apologize to all the passengers.
For the delay incurred
Because of the labor union protest,
Eurostar train 9406 Rome-Milan,
Will depart from platform number 10.
(EXCERPT: "FORBIDDEN ENCOUNTERS"
BY P. PIGEONS)
- Hello? It's Andreoli, who is it?
- I'm Iris, the secretary.
Tell me, miss.
The tender is here this morning,
his answer came
On the committee table.
But is the minister aware of it ?
Yes, the minister said.
To visit him in his office.
No, no, no ! I don't do antichambers
In the corridors of ministries !
If the minister wants me,
he knows my address.
- Do you understand ?
- Damn, what a character !
- Do you always wake up in a bad mood ?
- Yes, yes, I have a bad temper.
Miss, let me go, the train is leaving.
- Goodbye, see you tomorrow.
- Goodbye.
But how,
After 30 years you still don't know me ?
Yes, it is as I said.
Papa ?
- Papa, Papa !
- Are you talking to me?
I'm sorry, I made a mistake.
Do you think so? "Papa" ?
Miss, now that you understand
That I am not papà,
why are you coming after me?
Me? I'm just looking for my carriage to Bologna,
number 8.
Number 8 is mine,
I'm going to Bologna, too.
Good, so we make the journey together
and keep each other company.
Run, the train is leaving,
walk faster.
Miss, my carriage is this one.
Miss, this is my pace, the briefcase is heavy
and the umbrella bothers me.
- You run, go, go !
- You could have told me.
- Don't be polite, just give me the briefcase.
- What! I don't give the briefcase to anyone.
- Excuse me, don't you trust anyone?
- No, I don't trust anyone.
- Why ?
- Because I don't trust anyone.
I trust no one.
- Help me ?
- I just wanted to help you.
I do not need help,
Get your hands off me.
- Oh.
- For God's sake, who touches it!
Where did this come from ?
- But who is she ?
- (Controller) People, into the carriage !
Slowly, wait, wait.
I'm coming, I'm coming, I'm coming.
- Here I am.
- Here we are .
- Come, I'll give you a hand.
- No, I do my own thing.
- "Aridaje" with this bag.
- Then give me the umbrella.
- It makes me slip.
- Yes hold on to me.
- Gosh, the knee !
- I'm sorry, is he hurt ?
Yes, miss, I hurt myself.
- Very bad.
- Sorry.
- It's not my fault.
- For goodness sake, what's you got to do with it? God!
It is mine, I alone am to blame.
Why are you shouting? If I knew,
I would not help you.
Miss, you would have done your duty.
- Too bad you realized it to late.
- Come, I will help you.
- Come.
- (Armando) Did you see what she did to me?
- (Armando) I banged my knee.
- Are you hurt ?
- (Armando) A tremendous evil.
- Do you know her ?
- No, I don't knows her !
- What did she want from you ?
- Briefcase.
- The briefcase ?
Yes, the briefcase.
Under the guise of helping me,
"Give me the briefcase," she said.
- You think she wanted to...
- I think nothing and know nothing.
She asked me three times for the briefcase, though.
kind sir, today on the trains
are travelling professionals.
Beautiful, attractive, they chat
And you don't know how it turns out.
Nothing gets to me.
Even if they are attractive, I don't trust them.
- is this my suite.
- Here it is, yes.
- It is suite number 2, in the centre of the train.
- Good.
No one will bother you today,
the train is half vacant.
Why is it vacant ?
With these annoying strikes
people are afraid
of being left halfway.
Well, and aren't you right ?
Let's hope well.
Oh.
Travel.
I'm telling you, people who travel
Is an impossible thing.
Ah.
(Male, speaker) We inform you.
That the crew
is at your disposal and wish you a safe journey.
oh, thank you,
that's what I need.
No one's disturbing me, I'll can do my notes.
Ah, that's good.
Notepads.
And the speech.
Here it is.
So.
Intervention first.
Dearly beloved.
...Defendants,.
Here we go, into the tunnel
and they even turn off the light.
But I say to you !
(Armando) Well, what's going on?
(Armando) Who came in?
(Armando) Oh there, sorry, but who are you?
- It's me..
Here she is again, and what are you doing here ?
If you don't mind, I'll settle in here.
What, "If you don't mind ?"
This is a private suite.
- Is it a private  suite ? I didn't know.
- Yes.
Ah, you didn't know ?
Be patient, you don't have a ticket
with a reserved seat?
Yes, but there are some guys,
who are basketball players
they were bothering me.
Really, do you think so ?
Young people are a nuisance.
Well, what does that mean ?
I mean it's more fun for you to
take a trip with young people
than come and be bored
with an old man like me.
Old ?
Who said you are old ?
All right, never mind.
Spare yourself the compliments, please.
- No compliments.
- Eh, no.
I'm just saying that some young people
sometimes they are so boring !
It is a matter of opinion.
Is yours this ? Well, let's respect it.
- Can I smoke ?
- "Can I smoke ?" your is already smoking.
Smoke away, I smoke cigars.
- Ah.
- Yes.
"Italian Locomotives in the World."
If you don't mind, Can I a take a look.
What is it ? Ah.
- Don't miss the mark.
- No.
There is a sign.
Ah.
(Federica) Ah.
Don't tell me you're interested
in steam locomotives ?
Oh, when I was young.
Everything is now electrified.
They are old steamers,
But they give a feeling of great power.
Yes.
It must have been very romantic
riding on those trains.
"Locomotive Dakota"
"A project
of Engineer Armando Andreoli."
"for the Brazilian Railways."
Don't tell me
That you are the engineer Armando Andreoli ?
Yes, miss.
If you don't mind,
I designed that locomotive.
It is fantastic !
So you have also been to Brazil ?
Brazil, Costa Rica, Nicaragua.
You can be say that I worked for the railways
since I was born.
- How wonderful !
- Yes.
I am very happy to make this trip
with such an important person.
My name is Federica,
can we call each other ?
No.
- Why not ?
- Because I don't see any reason, sorry.
What is this trend?
We barely know each other,
in Bologna we say goodbye,
I don't see the reason
For which we must call each other by name.
Excuse me.
- Will you stay long in Bologna ?
- Ah, I don't know.
- I have a conference, depending on how it goes.
- Ah.
Are you married ?
Yes.
- Isn't your wife coming with you ?
- No.
- Why ?
- I am a widower.
Ah.
Where are you staying here in Bologna ?
How, where do I stay ?
As in,
Which hotel are you sleeping in tonight ?
If you permit, I will not tell you.
Why ?
Because I have a bad temper
And I am also wary.
Ah, excuse me.
Wary of me ?
Not just you, I distrust all people
I don't know,
And because I don't know you,
I don't see the reason
For which I must tell you.
Where I am sleeping tonight in Bologna.
But what is the harm ?
What's wrong with that ?
It's that I don't know if I'm sleeping in Bologna,
Because if there is no strike,
I leave on the first train to Rome.
What if there is a strike ?
If there is a strike ?
No more questions,
I have to absent myself for a little while.
Where are you going?
I am going to the toilet.
- Do you go to the toilet with your briefcase ?
- Yes, with the briefcase.
- Why?
- Just like that.
- May I?
- Please do.
Here you go, thanks.
(Armando) Oh,
this one still thinks about the briefcase !
Excuse me, do you know what time it is ?
- Are you a basketball player ?
- Yes.
It's time for you to wake up, young man.
But who are you ?
Couldn't always be predicted
what was happening, you know ?
Do you think that when we were laying out the tracks.
40 degrees in the shade,
the monkeys, mischievous,
From above the tree branches,
They would throw coconuts on our heads.
There was a lot of tension
In the camp at night,
Because we were surrounded by Indians.
We were afraid to do things
That were not part of their culture
and their way of life.
Fear.
Did you know that when we built
the bridge over Rio Negro,
we were infested with piranhas.
We caught an anaconda.
We opened his belly
And inside was a live monkey.
What an extraordinary life !
I wish this journey would never end
to always listen to your stories.
Unfortunately, our journey is over,
dear young lady.
We arrived in Bologna
and we have to prepare ourselves.
"Come on, boom."
Eh, I have told you the whole story.
Unfortunately, I don't know
whether I have made all the necessary notes
to make my presentation tonight.
Let's hope for the best.
Engineer, engineer !
- Engineer, your umbrella, engineer !
- Who is ?
- You forgot your umbrella.
- Oh, thank you very much.
Where are you going ?
Are you going straight to the congress ? Where is it ?
It is in the Main Square,
the City Hall.
Ah, it's near my little hotel,
The Clock.
There are no more cabs,
can I come with you ?
Can you come ? I am already late.
Is the Clock near the municipality ?
- All right, come.
- Thank you.
Let's go quickly, though, it's late.
Excuse me, Miss, if this is unlawful.
What are you doing alone in that little hotel?
I'll meet my fiancé
who lives in Trent.
Ah, I get it,
You meet each other halfway.
Yes, we have to decide
the date of our wedding.
If you have nothing to do,
come and have dinner with us.
Having dinner with you, are you kidding ?
Boyfriends want to be alone, don't they ?
Yes, we have been engaged for five years,
But when we are alone we get so bored.
Hmm, but if you are so bored,
why did you decide to get married ?
Sometimes it comes down to marriage
Just when one should break up.
Ah, you got it !
It happens.
We are here.
Here we are, then goodbye, young lady.
- Goodbye.
It was a very interesting trip with you.
- I we hope to meet again in Rome.
- Rome is big, miss.
- I don't think so.
- Never say never.
Never say never, eh.
However,
It was a pleasure for me as well.
I wish you all the best
for your marriage.
Here,
Escort the young lady to the hotel.
Please be quiet.
Thank you.
The commencement of work on the highway
is again under discussion.
Due to the massive intervention of supporters
of the doubling of the railway line,
of which we have here in the hall
a notable representative.
Engineer Armando Andreoli.
Silence, silence !
(Together) Get out, go outside.
Silence !
(Man) And always him.
Silence, silence !
Silence !
Engineer ?
But...Miss, what are you doing here?
My fiancé phoned me,
arrives tomorrow afternoon.
- I had nothing to do...
- Sit here.
- Thank you.
- Can't you see that everyone is looking at you ?
- They stopped.
- I thought.
they froze as soon as you entered.
I thought I would visit you
here at your convention.
Yes, you thought wrongly,
because I don't own the congress.
Everyone here is agitated, everyone is in turmoil.
Yes and no that they make me have the response.
(Speaker) A moment of attention,
Engineer Armando Andreoli,
author of the project
which is now in the hands of the Minister,
Will make his speech.
Now he's calling me.
Come, engineer, come.
Go away, go away !
What am I coming? "Come."
Can't you hear them ?
Please have a seat, don't worry.
- Engineer, go, don't be afraid.
- What did you say? Afraid?
I am afraid of no one.
Of course I'm going.
- Here I am, here I am ready.
- Go!
I obey, I obey.
- Go home.
- Enough !
- (Man) Go away, shame !
- (Man 2) Go away, shame on you!
(Man 3) Go back to Rome !
Go steal somewhere else !
When in the postwar period,
Europe found itself at a dramatic crossroads.
of making the huge choices,
including transport on tyres
and rail transport...
of this historic... of this historic...
of this historic concern,
I say that I have never had
neither doubts nor uncertainties.
The are many interveners, and I see them here,
they have come here affected by bad ideas
to contest my truths.
Here is the evidence !
The evidence ?
The evidence is here in my speech.
Everything is here, everything is written.
My proposals
are of national interest.
Not of private interest !
Not of interest to your constituents
Paid to support to the last extreme
your business interests
without showing any respect
for those who disagree with you.
(Man) Enough with the lies, stop it.
(Man) Get the fuck out of here!
- Do not respond.
- Of course I won't be responding.
- Because I'm leaving.
- No.
- Yes, yes, I'm leaving.
- Please.
I don't want to stay
not a minute longer here.
- Finish your presentation.
- Come on, let me through.
Don't you understand that these animals
are shouting and screaming
to be filmed on television?
(Armando) I am ashamed to have come.
For heaven's sake,
I'm leaving, goodbye.
Engineer, don't give up.
- Why do you want to give them satisfaction?
- What are you saying? What do you want, too ?
- Let me go.
- Why do they do this ?
When that bastard was still in diapers,
I went to work overseas
not to bow my head to them.
(Armando) I am not like him, rascals!
(Armando) They took the bribes.
To challenge me !
You old fart,
I would have smashed your face in.
- What do you want to do ?
- I'll break your face.
Let's fistfight,
I'll show you who the wrecker is.
Go back to Rome !
Go back to Rome !, go !
Do as your bosses tell you !
Your bosses, fill the streets with cars,
infest the air
Until we all die from poisoning.
- He brought his geisha.
- What?
Who's geisha?
Geisha will be you, you fool.
I work,
I'm not taking bribes like you.
(Federica) Engineer.
(Man) We scared the shit out of him,
we scared him.
The usual illiterates, scoundrels, thieves !
Curse to me and when I joined
to this convention.
I didn't have to...
The briefcase, the briefcase !
Here it is, engineer.
Do you know that you are unpredictable ?
Thank you, miss.
You were very helpful to me.
I must thank you very much, Miss,
for your assistance
this evening it was
so uncivilized and degrading.
you were better off with your boyfriend.
- No, I feel sorry for you.
- Here.
How could anybody face
such people who were so rude?
- Hmm.
- Are all congresses like this ?
But no, miss, I came here
to present my project.
I knew straight away when I came,
that no one would listen to me.
Because they had it all planned.
They had prepared everything
against me.
Do you know that you are right ?
- They didn't want to let you give your speech.
- No.
Perhaps they were worried that you would make
a too convincing proposals.
- Rascals, delinquents.
- Where are you going?
- Uncivilized !
- Come here.
Did you see that guy?
He wanted to punch me in the face.
- It is better to leave those people behind.
- Yes.
Of course,
let this evening serve as a lesson to me.
- I will never set foot here again.
You are right.
The most important thing now
is to go home without delay.
You know what I'll do, miss?
I call a cab, go to the station
and I take the first train to Rome.
- At the station ?
- Yes.
- Do you want to leave like this at night?
- In a way you're right.
You know it's not acceptable here ?
I did not make reservations at any hotels.
There is not a room
even for the price of gold.
I have an idea, there is a small hotel nearby.
It is a little hotel,
surely they will find you accommodation.
- Really ?
- Yes.
Are you sure that here
they won't refuse us accommodation?
- Then you don't trust what I say.
- May I?
- Let me do the talking.
- YES.
- Good evening.
- Good evening, miss.
How can I serve you in ? Good evening.
The gentleman cannot depart
because of the strike.
We stayed in three hotels,
But it is sold out.
- Do you happen to have a single ?
- Look at this.
I don't know, there's the trade-show,
the dental conference.
Unfortunately, all the rooms are occupied.
You don't even have a single ?
Nothing, miss,
this is a small hotel.
The rooms we have
are all booked.
- So.
- Wait a minute.
this evening a french couple should arrive
- "Yes ?"
- "Let's try this.
If by 10 p.m. they don't show up,
the room is yours.
- Thank you.
- Then we just have to wait.
- You can have dinner in our restaurant.
- Good.
I am sure it will be a wonderful experience
and enjoy our culinary specialities.
(Armando) That's a good idea.
(Hotelier) Forgive me, every time
there's a thunderstorm the lights goes out.
(Hotelier) Luigi,
Escorts the guests to the restaurant.
- (Armando) Yes, let's go.
- (Federica) Let's go.
- Ah-ah, nice !
- Hmm.
Thank you.
Leave it, I'll do it.
- Do you ?
- Yes, I like to do that.
Ah, I like pork sausage.
- Do you still want one ?
- Yes.
Thank you.
- Some puree.
- Yes.
Do you like Bolognese specialities ?
I don't eat them,
only once a year
you can even taste it.
- It's delicious, it's tasty.
- Go easy on the meat.
It is not good for
those with  high nitrogenemia.
What do you know about high nitrogenemia ?
I'm a nurse,
work at Holy Spirit.
Yes, I know she is a nurse,
but the fact that I have high nitrogenemia
what do you know about that?
Why did you lie to me?
Did I lie to you? When?
On the way,
when you left
from the train suite,
your mobile phone rang
and I answered it.
- And who was it ?
- It was a voice from beyond.
It was your wife.
My wife? What about my wife ?
Why did you say you were a widower?
This is why?
You see, Miss, during that trip,
I was making the notes
To make the speech in Bologna.
She would interrupt me and ask,
he would ask me, he would ask me again.
To cut a long story short
I said I was a widower, did I do wrong ?
No, but do you always do this
with all the women you meet on the train?
No, don't say that.
This is the first time
such an encounter has happened to me.
It must be something
that was deduced by your subconscious.
What does the subconscious have to do with it?, sorry ?
I don't know, perhaps unknowingly
you want to get rid of your wife.
No, no.
Ours is a marriage
that has lasted for 40 years.
We love each other like the first day.
Why you do not believe me?
- If you say so, I believe you.
- I do.
That's it.
Here it is.
It's here.
Gentlemen, I'm sorry,
right now...
- I heard, the French have arrived.
- Correct.
- So ?
- The room is no longer available.
Don't you have something to accommodate me ?
- An armchair, a chair?
- I am terribly sorry, sir.
- I can only offer you a couch.
- Very good.
- Perfect.
- What a couch! He'll sleep in the room with me.
No, no, let it be.
If the young lady agrees.
No bother, I have a big bed,
We will not bother each other.
No, no, no,
The couch is fine with me.
No, no way,
he sleeps in the room with me.
(Armando) Ah.
If the young lady agrees,
I would take advantage of it.
- Well.
- Do you have any identification?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
- I have my passport.
- Good night.
Good night.
Excuse me, do you realise
what you say and what you do?
- I always know what I am doing.
- Yes ?
Yes, what? No, I'm fine now.
(Armando) I have a warm bed,
a warm quilt, I'm really comfortable.
Are you going to Africa with the Red Cross?
No, no, give up, look.
No, it's fine, we'll talk about it,
I'll be home for breakfast tomorrow anyway.
Is that alright?
Bye, Alessandra, good night.
Good night, dear.
- Thank you, Federica.
- You're welcome.
Why is your wife going to Africa?
Ah, she has been
involved in aid to the Third World,
for the Red Cross.
How come you didn't tell her
that you were in the room with me?
Well, these things you
don't say over the phone,
because it can be misunderstood.
you're is right.
- Are you comfortable in the bed?
- Ah.
- How grateful I am to you!
- Are you sure you're alright?
I heard you say
that your head was cold.
Well, because there was
so much rain today!
My head is freezing.
Look under the pillow.
- Under the pillow ?
- Yes.
What ?
Oh there.
- What a beautiful nightcap !
- Do you like it ?
Beautiful, is it yours ?
No, it was a surprise for my fiancé.
- Ah-
- But you can wear it now.
Eh, no, that's not proper.
What do you care?
Put it on, he didn't come anyway.
- Really?
- Yes.
Well, you know what ?
I feel sorry for your fiancé,
I'm really going to wear it.
- Ahh  !
- It looks great on you.
- Do I look good?
- Yes.
- It looks really good on you.
- Nice, warm.
Well, it suits you just fine,
but you're fine with everything.
You'll wear it with a lot of distinction.
- Really ?
- Yes.
You have beautiful blue eyes.
I hadn't noticed.
Actually, I hadn't noticed it either.
Oh, God, it's already 11 p.m.
and the lights still haven't come back on.
Yeah, and we can't watch
the television either.
That's better, so we can talk a little.
Yes, it's better, but I was saying that
because TV helps me sleep.
Every time I see television
I fall asleep.
Can't sleep ?
Yes, yes, I sleep well, all right.
Would you like me to read you a good poem?
- Ah, poetry ?
- YES.
- I like poems so much, I love them.
- I always read them in the hospital to patients.
They are as happy as children.
- Yes, really ?
- Yes, they like it.
- Ah, read it to me, what is it ?
- Do you like Prévert ?
Prévert is my favourite author,
his love poems are exquisite.
(Armando) A beautiful poem,
what a beautiful idea!
- "When."
"When the little lion has breakfast,
the lioness becomes young again."
"When fire claims its share,
the earth blazes."
"When death speaks to her of love,
life quivers."
"When life speaks to it of death,
love has a smile."
What is he doing, sleeping ?
- Need anything else?
- No, thank you very much.
Federica, breakfast has arrived.
- Finished showering?
- (Federica) I'll be right there.
- Please, have a seat.
- Thank you.
- Oh, sorry.
- Oh, you're welcome.
- Did you make a mistake?
- Did I make a mistake?
You made a mistake, this is my room.
Isn't this room 223 ?
Yes, it's 223.
- This is not the one you were looking for.
- How is it not mine?
I booked this room
in my fiancée's name,
Ms. Federica Pescatore.
Do you know you are right ?
This is the room
Of Ms. Federica Pescatore.
So what are you doing here?
What am I doing here?
Yes, what are you doing here?
No, I am not doing anything here.
It is as if I were not here.
It's a pure coincidence, that I am here.
- (Federica) Engineer, who are you talking to?
- To your fiancé.
Ah.
Um.
Hi, weren't you supposed to arrive in the afternoon ?
Never mind when I was supposed to arrive.
Rather you, explain to me what you are doing
in bed with this gentleman.
I mean, you arrive so suddenly
and you raise your voice?
Do you want to make out that it's my fault too now ?
(Armando) Listen, sir,
don't get any wrong ideas,
because I could also sleep
In an armchair.
It was the generosity of the young lady
who told me:
"No, you sleep in my bed",
but that was because it was me.
Excuse me, take a good look at my face.
I am closer to 80 than 70.
What does it matter, what are you saying ?
What does age matter?
Look, Miss Federica,
perhaps you can better explain to the gentleman
how things went.
That's it, anyway,
now I'll get dressed right away.
Don't worry,
and then I'll also leave in a flash
Here, I'll get my briefcase.
Pardon.
You must tell me who it is! But who is this?
Meanwhile, this is a gentleman.
In fact, he is a great gentleman.
If you really want to know,
Is a famous engineer.
He is a designer of steam locomotives.
Here I am.
I was very fast.
I want to take my troubles from you.
To you, young lady, I want to express
all my gratitude
for your generous hospitality.
Sorry to have disturbed you.
What disturbance, engineer ?
It was a great pleasure.
- (Federica) Aren't you going to answer?
- (Giorgio) Do I have to answer as well?
(Giorgio) Federica, I am used
to the fact that you are unpredictable.
(Federica) This is the way I am,
take it or leave it.
(Federica) Leave me !
La 231, accompany the gentlemen to the room.
This is perfectly fine.
- Oh, good morning, sir.
- Good morning.
Did you sleep well?
Well, never mind,
let's say I slept.
Rather, how much do I owe you for the room ?
Nothing, sir,
you are a guest of the young lady.
- Yes?
- It's all on the boyfriend's account.
- Really ?
- Eh-
Ah, well.
- So.
- here is your passport.
Thank you, this is for you.
- Thank you, sir, have a good trip.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
- Goodbye, sir.
Let's all hope for the best.
Hopefully.
- (Hotelier) Hotel Orologio.
- Listen, porter.
I am that gentleman
who stayed overnight in your hotel
in the room
of Miss Federica Pescatore.
Yes, sir, did you forget something ?
No, I wanted information.
After my departure what happened ?
All quiet,
sir, don't worry.
Ah.
Do you already know Miss Pescatore?
Is she a client of yours ?
No, it was the first time
she was sleeping over.
Ah.
Um, tell me, concierge, in confidence,
her behaviour
don't you find it a bit equivocal?
You should know better, sir.
No, because my suspicions are...
This sudden arrival of the boyfriend,
you know, I wouldn't want them to disagree.
Did they try to extort you?
No, no.
Not exactly extortion,
but if the young lady
asks her for my address,
you say
that you are not authorised to give it to her.
- All right, sir.
- All right.
I thank you
for your generous tip.
- Have a good trip.
- Not at all, thank you.
Take care, eh.
Heh, oh.
That...
Some intention was there.
- Thank you.
- Welcome back, engineer.
(Armando) Here.
- Here.
- Thank you.
- Yesterday we waited for you all evening.
- I know, I had to stay.
- My wife?
- And upstairs, she's working with the Countess.
Erm, the little crusaders
and the black gentleman, as usual.
- (Luisita) Good morning, engineer.
- Hello, Luisita, everything OK here?
Here is the Italian Red Cross in action.
- How are you doing ?
- Good, thank you.
- Oh, John.
- Good morning, engineer.
Sorry we invaded your house today.
- We had an expedition.
- For goodness sake, it is your job.
Do your work, where is my wife ?
- She's over there with the Countess.
- Good.
Hey there, guess what ?
It's me, here I am !
- No one can understand...
- Alessandra, I'm back.
An incredible journey,
an adventure I must tell you about.
- AFTER-
- After ?
- I finish the call and I'm all yours.
- After that, do whatever you want.
- Hello? Hello?
- Go, dear.
(Alessandra) Consul ?
(Armando) Here we go.
- Everything done ?
- Excuse us, engineer.
Make yourselves at home,
for goodness sake.
- (Armando) By now.
- Engineer, lunch is ready.
I'm really hungry,
but the lady hasn't finished yet.
Now, in a little while...
I was expecting it yesterday
And instead it only arrived this morning.
He says he has so much to tell me,
Who knows what it will be ?
- (Contessa) Everything is ready here.
- Goodbye.
- Hello.
Luisita ?
- (John) Ma'am.
- Yes ?
I'll pick you up tomorrow
with the Consulate's car.
(Alessandra) Perfect.
- The engineer is waiting for you.
- Luisita, accompany the gentlemen.
Armando ?
(Armando) I couldn't wait.
to return home
to tell you about this adventure,
it's an incredible thing!
At the station she calls me: " Papa."
Inside the train
she enters my private suite,
giving up the company
of basketball players, oh!
She says: "But they are boring,
I prefer to be with you."
Tell me, but what is she like? What is she like?
Ah, she's beautiful.
She is very beautiful.
She works as a nurse
at the Hospital of the Holy Spirit.
She says she is enrolled at the university,
but I think this girl
to supplement her salary...
Ah, but then this is a long story.
- Very long.
- It feels like an adventure novel.
Let's go over there and have a drink, come on.
While you finish telling me,
I'm waiting for the phone call.
I couldn't wait to come back
to tell you about it.
More than just long! Just listen.
During the whole journey back,
I said:
" Now that I'm going to tell Alessandra..."
- "Love, can I have my usual drink?
- Yes.
This happened because I was forced
to stay in Bologna.
- Yeah.
- There was the storm, there was the strike.
I looked for a room.
All the hotels were full,
there was not a single vacant room.
I found one from a French dentist.
If they didn't come, they'd give it to me.
Instead, at that moment at the most beautiful
the French dentist arrived.
The director came to me and said:
"Look, the room is occupied."
"I can give you a couch."
"A couch ?" she said,
"Are you crazy ?"
"He's sleeping with me."
Well, she was very nice this girl.
Yes, yes, she was very nice.
But did you understand
what I told you ?
Of course I understood.
Well, I slept with her,
I slept the whole night with her.
Armando, I understand.
- I got it !
- As long as you understand.
Eh, I didn't even want to tell you.
I said: "Alessandra is going to get jealous."
- My love...
- No, eh ?
- Jealousy ?
- No.
After so many years I know you too well.
So, listen,
right now I really have
some very big worries
to think about.
So excuse me.
- Look, I put on my pyjamas....
- Shh.
(Armando) Ah...
Hello ?
Oh, it's you at last.
I've been waiting for hours for you.
Yes.
I wanted to tell you that I checked
the whole list of antibiotics.
They're all expired.
A disgrace, believe me,
a great shame!
- (Armando) Alessandra, Alessandra ?
- No, no.
(Alessandra) For the rest
we are quite covered,
I mean, the other medicines are there.
It is late, I almost.
- (Alessandra) Hmm.
- Huh ?
- Yes.
- Yes, No, for the medicines...
If not let's make it daytime,
I know these phone calls.
I received a fax from Milan
which I will now read it to you.
You guarantee us
the sending of the following vaccines.
- Just a moment.
- YES.
So.
I'm going to the bedroom,
it's not over yet, you'll see.
"Cholera, malaria, typhoid..."
(Armando) No, on that side there
no temptation.
(Priest) Not even with the thought?
Eh, with the thought, you know.
Because it's so sudden,
perhaps driven
more by curiosity than anything else, that is.
After all, it's been so long
that I no longer have any stimuli, I have no reactions.
Not even with my wife.
So much so
That we sleep in separate rooms.
- Meanwhile, this is not your wife.
- Eh-
Did you ever meet that girl again?
No, no.
You see, it doesn't seem to me that your adventure
contains anything shameful.
I am rather concerned
that you still think about it, huh?
You may go.
(Priest) Should you find yourself again
in similar situations again,
always think of your wife.
- Do not doubt, Father.
- Praised be Jesus Christ.
Behold, praise be to jesus.
All right, Velardi, now I'll tell you everything.
- In the meantime, have a drink.
- No, I'll help myself.
I want plenty of vodka.
Do you think so ?
Have you heard from our doctor ?
He serves himself.
We forbid everything; he eats instead,
He drinks and smokes like a Turk.
I am a doctor, not a sick person.
- Am I right, Mary?
- How clever.
- Is there a tournament ?
- Eh, yes.
- Hello? Yes, he's here.
- He has not told you.
I'll put him on right away. Engineer, it's for you.
- Who is ?
- Ms. Federica.
Another one like that, though...
- It's Federica, what shall I tell her?
- Well?
- Tell her I'm not here.
- I said you're here.
- What are you afraid of?
- Eh!
- Answer.
- Come on.
- Hello ?
- It's Federica.
Ah, Miss Federica.
I thought you wouldn't be in touch any more,
it's been a while.
How come? You found me, huh?
- I found you.
- Yes.
- What are you doing, engineer?
- What am I doing?
Well, I'm at home with friends.
- You?
- What floor do you live on?
I live on the first floor, why?
Ah, yes, I can see the lights in the windows.
- Yes ?
- Yes,.
What, you see the windows?
Why, where are you calling from?
I'm down here, in front of your house.
- Alessandra, she's down below.
- then have her come up.
- What, have her come up here?
- Eh.
But no!
(Armando) Excuse me, Miss,
why are you calling me from down there?
I'm just passing by.
I'm on my way to the hospital
for the night shift.
Ah, well, then good work
and thanks for the call.
Goodbye, Miss.
No, wait a minute.
I am free tomorrow,
we could meet up.
Tomorrow?
Look, Miss, I have a lot to do.
Why do I have to see you?
- I have something very important to tell you.
- I cannot come.
- Armando, Armando.
- What is it?
Don't make it so long,
give her an appointment, no?
Hmm.
Miss,
if this is very important,
OK, let's meet.
Where can we meet ?
Come tomorrow to my house at three o'clock.
Ring the intercom, Via degli Ausoni, 7.
But is it your name on the intercom?
No, it says: "Tango School."
- School of...?
- Tango.
- Tango ?
- Yes.
(Armando) What is it?
Don't ask too many questions,
I will explain tomorrow.
All right, Miss,
at 3 o'clock I'll be at your house.
Goodbye.
"Tango school," she says.
Crazy things.
Does it seem to you that a man of my age
goes to tango school?
Here.
(Armando) "Tango School."
She said, "You ring the intercom,
but no one answering.
What is this, a freight elevator?
(Armando) Oh, here we go.
- Hello.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Does Miss Federica live here?
Yes, are you Federica's papà ?
No, I am not her papà.
- I am Engineer Andreoli.
- The engineer.
- Come in.
- Oh, thank you.
- What a pleasure.
- (Armando) Yes.
- (Armando) Federica is always talking about you.
- Really? Where is Federica ?
She just woke up because she did
night shift at the hospital.
- Ah.
- Vega, come in, give me your coat.
No, no, I'd rather keep it.
"One, two, three"
Excuse me, does Federica sleep here
in the tango school?
Yes, we sleep upstairs.
We share the flat with three girls
to save on rent.
This is Mercedes, she's from Argentina,
she gives tango lessons here.
Bend your knee,
you have to feel my body, that's good.
Mercedes, the engineer has arrived.
Oh, engineer, finally.
Good morning, engineer.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Please, have a seat.
- Thank you.
- (Mercedes) Here, pay no attention to it.
(Armando) No, I'm waiting for Federica.
No, it is broken.
- No, it's fine.
- Gloria, take that chair away.
- I'm so sorry.
- She told me that later.
- You're right.
- Sit here, so sorry.
It is nothing, nothing at all.
Like this.
- (Mercedes) Do you like tango ?
- (Armando) Do I like it ?
I'll tell you, back in the day,
in all modesty I was a great dancer.
Today, you know, they don't do such dances any more.
Today they are dancing to rock.
- Yes, it's true, young people are dancing to rock.
- "What the hell!"
Not doing exercise anymore,
venting their emotions by jumping around,
moving to the rhythm of rock.
- Unfortunately.
- But nothing to do with tango.
- Rock is puritanical.
- Puritanical, why?
Because the man and the woman
they dance separately.
- Oh, yeah.
- Tango is much more sensual.
Yep.
I don't quite grasp the concept,
what do you mean?
I mean that in the tango
there is physical contact,
the man and the woman
always remain close.
(Mercedes) He feels her body,
she feels his body.
(Mercedes) It is a carnal relationship.
She teaches him
that sensual love and death
always go together.
Ah.
Sorry, but I had never made
any of those thoughts.
I'm saying this against my own interests, though.
Sensuality cannot be learned in school.
- One has to be born with this gift.
- Not that one.
- Like Federica, for example.
- Why does Federica also...?
Yes, she helps me when she can,
she pairs up with my students.
- You should see her.
- I can imagine.
- No, you can't imagine it.
- Of course not!
There she is.
- There he is.
- Oh there.
Federica, look who's here ?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Federica, I'll give you back your engineer,
he is very nice.
- I know. Good morning, engineer.
- Good morning, Federica.
- Show him how you dance the tango.
- No, another day.
- We don't have time today, do we?
- No ?
- "Adios."
- "Adios, Senorita ."
Where are we going ?
We can stay here,
so we can dance the tango.
- No, let's go somewhere quieter.
- Yes?
We must be alone,
I have something very important to tell you.
He told me: "If you have been
all night in bed together"
"and he didn't try,
then your engineer is an asshole."
No, "asshole" ? Now let's take it easy.
Let's just say I'm a decent person.
You can see that for him
makes no difference.
Of course, he is young.
Some young people talk like that,
but when they have reached my age
then they will understand.
But no!
He says in these cases
age has nothing to do with it.
I agree with him.
Excuse me?
And you agree with him?
Yes, if you let me talk,
I want to explain to you that age
is an irrelevant factor
in romantic relationships.
But how is it irrelevant? Come on, now!
You're telling me ?
To a man of my experience ?
But if you always interrupt me !
Am I interrupting you?
You're interrupting me, sorry.
Instead you have to listen to me
because you don't understand.
- I don't know what?
- you don't know.
He doesn't know that if a man my age,
suppose he is in bed with a woman,
also the most beautiful in the world,
the most attractive, the most exciting,
he lets her go
because he is afraid to attempt the encounter,
because he understands that she has her own troubles.
Did you or did you not understand
what I mean?
- I understand, I understand.
- Oh!
I'm not dumb !
- Then why do you say it's not true?
- Well, my fiancé didn't believe it.
He made a scene
And screwed up the wedding.
- Oh, really?
- Yes, really.
Do you understand why
I wanted to see you urgently ?
Yes, I understand, it's serious.
But.
Excuse me, Miss,
why did you have to say it so urgently
me?
Who was I supposed to tell ?
Who was there that morning
in bed with me?
Miss, you wouldn't happen to be
you and your fiancé
did you and your boyfriend agree that
maybe by imagining
that I took advantage of you?
Or by accusing me of being
responsible for this drama ?
My fiancé and I agree?
But for what reason ?
Well, don't tell me.
The reasons could be many.
The need for money, for example.
What would I know?
You could ask me for a loan
or even damages.
It is you and your fiancé
who have to tell me what you want from me.
What do you want ?
You may have great experience,
but you haven't understood a thing.
Oh, no? Then you explain to me
what I didn't understand, please
- There is little to explain.
- Yes?
I was tired of my boyfriend and I'm happy
that it all went wrong.
Well, but then at this point
I breathe a sigh of relief.
Oh there, look at that pizzone!
Thank you.
And what do you plan to do now ?
- Now I am finally free.
- Well ?
- We could be together every day.
- What's the point?
Listen, engineer,
but when I speak you don't understand
or do you pretend not to understand?
I still don't understand for what reason
you and I have to see each other.
(Federica) No reason,
if there is harmony between us
and a relationship is born...
(Armando) What harmony, what relationship?
Will you explain it to me?
(Federica) There's nothing to explain,
if two people want to see each other, they see each other.
(Armando) How, do they see each other? Excuse me.
Why do you want to see me?
Who am I to you?
- (Alessandra) Armando !
- Alessandra.
Who are you quarrelling with?
No, Miss Federica
accompanied me in the car.
Don't just stand there on the street, bring it up.
But.
yes, only a couple of minutes
because I have the night shift.
- What are you doing?
- Yes, let's go, come on.
- Let's go.
- Eh, slowly.
Good evening, Federica.
Good evening, madam.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
We've already met over the phone.
Yes, I know, dear,
but it's good to see you
and to finally meet you in person,
then I didn't know you were so beautiful.
Thank you.
What a beautiful house, beautiful !
- Who knows how much you pay in rent.
- No, no rent.
The house is my wife's.
You see, my papà gave it to us
when we got married.
- Yes.
- Come, come.
- Sit there.
- Thank you.
- Have a drink.
- Thank you. She has to go to the hospital.
- She's on the night shift.
- That's right, I'm already late.
- Eh.
- But why ?
- She's just arrived and you take her away from me ?
- I know.
- Duty calls me.
- Listen.
But you have to promise me
to come back really soon.
Certainly, madam.
I hope you don't mind
if I steal your husband from you sometime.
- Here he is.
- You're welcome.
In fact, I have so little time to devote to him,
poor love.
I'm always caught up
by all these duties of mine.
I know, it is very noble what you do
for Third World hunger.
Please, there is nothing noble
in what I do.
You see, Federica,
I've had the good luck, or the bad luck,
to be born into a very rich family.
Then I look for everything
To make it up to me.
That's it, kiss.
- Bye.
- Bye, thank you.
Bye.
- Good luck.
- Bye, Armando.
See you.
- (Federica) Goodbye.
- Bye.
Did you hear that?
"Bye, Armando, see you."
Well, what are you looking for?
Women today are like that, aren't they ?
- Well, but I am surprised.
- But don't be so jurassic !
Instead, listen,
late as it is, where have you been?
Give me your hand.
- Hand in hand.
- But why?
- Like children, in the park chatting.
- Oh, too cute.
Then she offered me a pizza
which stuck in my stomach.
Pizza? Poor love!
Come, I'll make you some chamomile tea.
The staff are finished,
but I'll gladly make it for you.
(Armando) Thank you.
Now that you have met her,
you have seen her properly,
what do you think, Alessandra, of her?
- What impression did she make on you?
- What impression did she make on me?
She is really beautiful.
Perhaps, you know,
she's a little bit strange for my taste,
but with that body...
She is also honest in appearance.
On the other hand, she is a nurse,
and works all night
to earn a living.
She says she's a nurse,
but what do we know about who she really is?
Oh, look, Armando,
you have such suspicions,
you are adult enough
to know what to do, aren't you?
- You ask for information.
- Yeah.
Look, wait for me, huh.
- Good morning, are you a relative of the injured person?
- No, I don't know him.
- I was asking about a nurse.
- Ask Sister Costanza.
- Bottom right.
- Bottom right ?
- (Armando) Sister Costanza?
- Yes.
- Excuse me, Sister.
- Are you visiting someone?
No, no,
I came here to do some research,
but as I am here in the hospital,
I wanted to ask about a nurse.
- Which nurse ?
- Her name is Federica Pescatore.
I'm not sure,
but they told me she works here.
Yes, Federica Pescatore works here,
she works the night shift.
- This morning she left at 8 o'clock.
- Then it's true that she works here.
- Of course.
- Ah, good.
- Excuse me, who are you?
- Um, I'm a relative.
I have known Federica since birth.
Do you know that everyone in the town talks about her?
She has a great passion
for medicine.
Yes, and now, being here in the hospital,
how does the young lady conduct herself?
- She is the pillar of this ward.
- Ah.
She works at night to earn more money,
but the truth is that she's in love
with these old gentlemen.
- You know what I mean.
- Yes.
- They want my blood, Sister Costanza.
- Do you hear? Do you hear?
They want to take away my blood,
But I am afraid.
- If Federica doesn't come, I won't do it.
- Do you hear that?
- All right, she's coming tonight and I'll take it from you.
- Thank you.
Here, everyone is so fond of her.
After all, she does some really...
She washes them, she shaves them,
she takes them to the bathroom.
- I don't tell her !
- And nice what I hear.
Yes.
- It's rare for a young person as beautiful as her.
- Yes.
Well, actually, it is a bit strange,
because she's so beautiful and young!
I ask her: "How do you spend your nights
with these old gentlemen"
"instead of going out and having fun ?"
Yes, that's what I thought too,
but for such a young lady,
beautiful and stunning,
isn't that very strange behaviour ?
Yes, indeed it is a bit strange,
but which one of us doesn't have oddities?
- Don't we?
- Allow me, sister.
- For the little chapel, some flowers.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, that was very kind.
- Thank you, thank you.
- (Armando) Duke ?
- (Duke) Yes, engineer.
Juraschi, take into account
Of the axial stress,
Between the rim and the rail.
He will see what he combines next.
- Yes.
- Hello, Research.
(Luciani) Yes, he is here, good.
- Ah, Luciani ?
- (Lucians) Yes ?
Call a taxi, I'm going home.
Miss Federica is downstairs,
she came to pick you up.
- (Armando) Really?
- (Lucians) Yes.
(Armando) Federica ?
"Who is she?
She is a niece of mine, on my wife's side.
"Who is that?"
- Congratulations, engineer.
- " Why do you care?
Federica.
Armando.
Why the surprise ?
Today is a special day.
I have a little present for you,
for your birthday.
No, no, Federica,
you don't have to do these things.
Come on, don't do these things.
For Saint Armando
you got me a beautiful pen.
What should I do in return?
Come have lunch with me.
It is I who should be delighted
to invite you to lunch,
but sadly, you know, my wife.
Not at all, today is a special day.
She cooked a turkey,
and a cake with candles...
- Invite her as well.
- Champagne...
Oh right, we'll ask her.
- (Luisita) Hello, Andreoli residence.
- Yes, it's me, is my wife in?
No, she's having lunch at the Embassy,
she told me not to wait for her.
Then don't set the table
because I'm dining out too.
- YES.
- Let's have lunch together.
Then come with me.
- Yes, I'll go with you.
- (Federica) Run.
- Don't run, don't run.
But blessed child.
I am so happy
to be with you all day!
Me too, but I don't know what happened.
You see, my wife, because of her job,
she has to make sacrifices, some renunciations.
She has great obligations,
but all for human welfare.
That's very impressive.
- When does she leave for Africa?
- I don't know, she needs to know today.
Do you mind if she leaves ?
Do I mind ?
I'm alone,
so what am I doing in the house alone ?
You're there.
Yes, dear, I am there,
but that is something else.
Forty years of marriage,
that's no joke.
Why, sorry,
is our relationship a joke?
No, now all jokes aside,
where are we going to eat ?
Here we are.
(Armando) Ah, Santa Maria in Trastevere.
Did you choose the 'restaurant'?
(Federica) Yes.
I know this restaurant.
- How come you chose this one?
- And a surprise, come on, Armando.
- If you please, you are our guest.
- Guest of whom?
- Who are they?
- They are my parents, Papa and Mama.
Papa and Mama ?
Where ?
Federica, Federica ?
(Federica) Mamma, papà.
" Papa-
- Hi.
- " Mama, papà, look who's here.
- Good morning.
How do you do, my pleasure.
- Delighted.
- I am engineer Armando Andreoli.
- Sit down, Armando.
- Yes.
We know who you are.
Every time she phones home,
Federica tells me a lot about you.
Oh really? I didn't know.
With Federica
there are always surprises.
You see, I wasn't supposed to be here today,
but at my home.
Today is his birthday,
but he has made himself available and spending time with us.
Well, then you stay for lunch with us
and all the best!
I'm turning 55 on Monday.
Well, time passes for everyone, madam,
but you look so young.
Well, she looks very good, too, however.
Are you passing through Rome?
Yes, we came to buy
a second-hand car.
In fact, we just took a little trip
just to try it out.
But let's be honest,
we also came to meet you, you know.
Our curiosity was overwhelming.
Mamma
Well, after what happened
in that little hotel in Bologna...
- Mamma, don't insist.
- No, she must insist.
Go ahead, ma'am.
See, this is another little surprise.
- What did you tell mamma?
- (Federica) I didn't tell her anything.
I confided
with an aunt of mine and she talked.
That was wrong, you did wrong.
What are you on about, excuse me?
About our chance encounter ?
We met by chance,
a coincidence,
a matter of no importance.
What are you talking about?
(Father) The engineer is right,
she's a chatterbox!
That's it.
She went to talk to relatives,
friends and the whole town heard about it.
That's it.
What has the town come to hear?
Eh, that the fiancé has left her,
that the marriage is no longer taking place,
now Federica is dating someone else,
and she has this new relationship
with an engineer.
Is the engineer me?
- (Armando) Ah, that's it.
- (Federica) Yes.
Look, the report that Federica says
is nonsense.
- Thank you.
- And it's all made up, it's incredible.
Engineer, I am a modest clerk,
but I'm very open-minded.
In my daughter's personal affairs
I don't want to get involved in them.
She is a daughter who has always given us
so many concerns.
- What concerns, mama?
- So much, ever since she was a child.
She had typhus,
didn't want to take Communion,
a very different girl from all the rest.
She doesn't listen to anyone
and we now dare not oppose her.
She always does everything on her own.
Also this relationship with her,
we have to know more about you.
I don't know, if it's serious,
if you're thinking about an engagement.
I don't know.
Federica, did you hear what your papà said?
yes, no, papà, for the time being
the engineer and I will see each other.
(Federica) We have a beautiful relationship,
and we're going out together.
In the future, maybe, who knows?
That's right, precisely what ?
What is certain?
Papa, nothing is certain.
Eh.
(Federica) For the moment
we see each other for now.
In the future, maybe we will get engaged.
Oh, my goodness!
Engineer, are you not feeling well ?
- (Father) How are you, engineer?
- Huh?
- (Father) How are you?
- I am perfectly fine.
Only I was thinking
that I have to leave.
No.
- (Armando) Yes, I have to go.
- But Armando?
Eh, yes, I have to go.
I can't stay, I told you.
- I shouldn't be here.
- Armando?
No, no, you sit here
and stay with papà and mamma.
We said what we had to say to each other,
We have said it.
I thank you for your invitation,
you have been very kind.
Excuse me, but I really
really have to go.
- Armando ?
- (Armando) I have to go, I'm leaving.
Papa, mamma, eat.
Nothing happened; that's just the way he is.
Sorry.
I have never been so ashamed,
not even when I was in school.
Armando, stop.
- Armando, please stop.
- Yes, yes, yes, I will stop.
I really want to hear what you want,
so what do you want?
I know, I was wrong, but let me explain.
But what do you want to explain ?
There is nothing to explain,
it's all clear.
You hooked me on the train,
then you had me found
by your boyfriend in bed with you.
Today at the restaurant with Papa and Mama,
can you believe it?
- What are these plots, these deceptions?
- No plot.
I did it to make
peace with my parents.
Ah, so you make them feel at ease ?
By saying I'm the boyfriend ?
Me, at my age ?
They live in a small village,
they are simple people.
You cannot understand
what kind of relationship there is between us.
But enough ! What relationship?
There is no relationship.
You must leave, you must disappear.
- Do you understand?
- Is this the love you want for me?
Who told you that I love you ?
These are all things you put in your mind.
You made them up out of your own imagination.
All right, if you deny it, then explain to me
why when we are together
we love each other so much.
Do we love each other when we're together?
But if we always quarrel!
No, no, no !
Enough, enough!"
- What, enough ?
- Yes, enough, enough.
I am not an asshole
as your fiancé says,
I say, " Leave
and don't let me see you again."
Oh, if you come after me again
or call me, I'll call the police.
- Understand ?
- Armando.
- Armando, come here.
- Taxi, taxi.
(Armando) Come on.
- (Federica) Armando.
- Go away !
Armando !
Coward !
Scoundrel !
May lightning strike you down !
Luisita, put things down here and here.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Alessandra.
Hey, Armando.
- "Hey, Armando."
- Hello.
So ?
- Have you decided ?
- Yes, I decided.
- I leave tomorrow morning at 11 a.m.
- Why ?
Well, you know, there's the hospital to reorganise,
I just couldn't get out of it.
What about me? Are you leaving me alone ?
But darling, with all the love I have for you,
however, I too am entitled to my space.
- Yes.
- Do you think so ?
- Besides, you have yours too.
- Hmm.
- (Alessandra) Luisita, then?
- spaces.
- (Alessandra) Did you put the lingerie away?
- Yes, madam.
Take care,
don't make me worry.
- You already know, don't worry.
- Cholera and malaria.
Cell phone.
- Is it mine ?
- Yes.
- Yes, Engineer Andreoli, who is it?
- I'm leaving.
- The plane is leaving.
- Federica?
- You make the call, OK?
- Tell you what.
- I'm coming.
- I'm glad you phoned me.
We broke up arguing
and I take this opportunity to tell you that I'm sorry.
(Countess) Look.
(Armando) I want to be at peace with you,
even if we won't see each other again.
(Federica) I called you about this, that's why,
give me one more chance.
- I would like to invite you tonight to a party.
- Why?
So I tell you that we won't see each other again
and you invite me to a party ?
Don't get angry now,
do you remember my friend Mercedes?
What kind of party is this?
It's for charity,
for Mercedes and her family.
If you come to the party, Armando,
you will get a free membership
to the tango school.
(Armando) I don't want
any membership !
I'm not coming to the party.
- Will you listen to me ?
- No!
I no longer want to be involved
in your affairs.
- Who wants to involve you?
- Don't raise your voice to me, you know !
Come on, Armando,
don't start fighting right now.
- I'm about to take off.
- Go, darling.
Bye, darling, don't be mad, eh.
- Yes, love.
- Bye-bye.
- (Alessandra) Bye.
- Bye, love.
- (Federica) To whom did you say: "Love?"
- Hi. Ah !
Why do you care ?
I told my wife
she's leaving for Africa.
So I'll see you tonight
and we will dance together
a tango you'll never forget.
No, I don't tango with anyone.
Goodbye forever.
Bon voyage, love.
Bye, Armando.
Come back soon.
Oh, ouch.
What a kick !
Ah, another one ?
- Are you kicking me ?
- Yes.
beautiful, isn't it ?
That's it, eh.
(Armando) Oh there, there.
(Armando) I love it, I love you.
beautiful
Completely black.
So beautiful!
Federica, he called on the intercom,
your fiancé is on his way up.
Who ?
- Your fiancé?
- I don't know anything about it.
- I swear.
- But how?
- You called him.
- (Federica) No, I swear.
- You made an arrangement.
- (Federica) That's not true.
Armando, come here, I didn't know.
Where did this happen to you ?
Eh, from Federica, at the tango school.
It was a sudden thing.
It's as if the blood
boiling in your head.
It's terrible, I didn't sleep all night.
I had palpitations, I couldn't breathe.
Of course, you've got yourself
in a state of excitement, friend.
I had strong feelings
which were a long time ago
so many years since I had felt them.
Hmm.
- Why didn't you take advantage of it right away?
- The fiancé had arrived.
Fuck, what's the fiance got to do with it?
Exactly, that's where you had to end it.
I don't know why.
- Actually...
- (Velardi) What are you doing, crying?
Yes, I'm sick.
Oh, you haven't fallen in love, have you ?
oh.
Who is speaking ?
Tell the Minister
that the engineer is very sorry,
and he is in bed with a fever,
he cannot come.
No.
Oh.
Sorry, engineer, you haven't eaten since yesterday,
at least have some tea with biscuits.
Luisita I,
I'm breathing heavily and drinking tea ?
I don't want anything, go away.
Leave me alone.
Since.
Hello ? Ah, Miss Federica.
No, the engineer is not here.
No ? And who am I ?
Give me the phone.
"She's not here."
Hello, Federica ?
That asshole left again,
when shall we meet?
Has the asshole left ?
I'm coming tonight, let's dance the tango.
No, tonight there are too many people.
Let's meet at breakfast time
and we'll be alone.
- Alone ?
- YES.
- My friends are not here
until this evening.
Let's eat something here,
I want to be alone with you for a while.
I too need so much
to be alone with you.
Come soon, I'll be waiting for you.
- Come.
- Of course, I'm coming, yes.
Luisita, draw me a hot bath.
Lily foam, scent of Arpège.
- Throw in a couple of rose petals.
- Whatever you want, engineer.
- Yes.
- Have some tea.
Tea? The tango!
I am so happy !
Go and prepare my bath.
Oh there, hooray!
Oh, my, my!
- What, are you impressed ?
- Yes.
Tango !
Armando mio, hold me tight.
Yes, my love.
Yes, I'll hold you, my beloved,
I've come just to hold you.
Papa, Papa!
(Armando) (Just call me papà.)
(Federica) My daddy isn't here anymore,
my papà has died!
- What, papà died?
- (Federica) Yes.
When ?
He died yesterday,
they phoned me half an hour ago.
I have to go,
they're taking him away, I have to go!
Now that he is dead,
you have become my papà.
Yes.
(Armando) Uh, another flight of stairs.
- (Priest) Excuse me.
- Who is it? Ah, please.
You are welcome.
What a disgrace.
Are they taking him away soon ?
Yes, engineer, they are taking him away.
- (Woman) Yes, yes, they'll take him away.
- (Woman 2) Yes, engineer.
Armando, Armando.
- (together) Engineer, they're calling you.
- What?
- (Woman) They are calling you.
- Armando, what are you doing there? Come up.
Shall I come up?
Coming up.
Here comes Papa.
Papa.
Papa, look who's here.
Armando, aren't you going to say hello to my papà?
- (Mother) Engineer?
- Who is she?
Ah, madam.
- Did you see that misfortune?
- How did it happen?
How should I know?
We were over there, he was fine.
- He was fine and suddenly...
- I feel awful!
- What is it?
Come on, Armando, they're taking Papa away.
Let's go now.
Let's go, let's go.
My daughter is left alone, engineer.
Take care,
love her very, very much.
Now that papà is gone,
when are you planning to get married?
- Well...
- We'll get married as soon as the mourning is over.
- What mourning, what mourning ? Get married right away.
- It's not up to me.
- With whomever? Aren't you the man?
- Yes, madam.
Ma'am?
Call me aunt and give me a kiss.
- Don't you ?
- We're going now, aunt.
- That's it, yes.
- Bye.
- We have to go.
- Bye, love.
- Bye.
- Take care.
- Take it easy.
(Mother) Bye.
(Woman) Listen, but your daughter
where did she find this engineer?
(Woman 2) But he seems like a good Christian,
your daughter has settled down,
what more do you want ?
Goodbye, Armando, goodbye.
What do we do now? Don't we eat today?
Thank you, Armando.
- And what?
- Of everything, I feel happy next to you.
Listen, Federica.
Now that you have calmed down
from this great pain of yours,
and we are about to consummate
this wonderful night of love,
please for the future,
do not spoil
this imminent pleasure of being together
By saying meaningless things
- Why, what did I say?
- You mentioned marriage.
I understand, Federica,
That you said that
To reassure your mother and relatives,
but you shouldn't say these things.
You shouldn't say
even in jest
But I wasn't joking,
I really want to marry you.
There, do you see !
Do you see that you are talking without thinking ?
I have been married for more than 40 years,
I'm getting married ?
I know.
you desire me now
and tonight you want to be with me.
Yes, beloved.
I yearn for you.
I look forward to this night
to be with you,
But I am still married.
Who cares? We'll run away.
We'll run away? Where do do we run to?
There, you see that ?
Do you see the nonsense you talk ?
What nonsense ? You can everything.
Go to the bank,
take all the money you have,
then sell your property
and move far away from here,
On a desert island in the Caribbean.
That's it, yeah.
I take all the money in the bank,
I sell my properties
And we are going to live in the Caribbean.
- Yes.
- Olé.
Eh, good, good.
And then ?
Then you file for divorce and we get married.
So you put poison in my coffee
And you become the owner of everything.
Did you plan this
you and your fiancé ?
Ah, is that what you think of me ?
That I want to put
poison in your coffee?
Listen, dear.
I have tried with all my might
to banish this ghost,
but I was unable to do so.
I have been wary
from the very first moment.
You said it today.
It is my heritage that you are interested in.
You never cared about me at all !
- Ah, that's right.
- YES.
Where are you going ?
Listen, you old hypocrite.
Because you are stubborn
And I can't make you understand
That I am sincere,
I'll tell you just one thing.
- Take it or leave it.
- Leave.
What?
Leave !
Then go away, go away !
Leave, leave,
I never want to see you again !
Get out ! Leave, leave, go away !
- Oh, Oh !
- Go away !
Damned be the day
on which I met you !
- Oh!
- Oh.
- Is this going to Rome ?
- Yes.
Please open.
- Excuse me, commander.
- Yes.
Has the private plane from Mozambique arrived?
- That's us, we've just arrived.
- Armando, Armando.
- Alessandra.
- Love.
I'm back.
So are all the problems solved there?
All resolved.
Any help is a drop in the ocean.
If you only knew what pain, what immense pain,
with all these human skeletons
asking for help.
Look, a real shame
for the so-called civilised world.
Then, my love, I want to tell you something.
Listen, I want to confess this to you.
I didn't tell you from afar
because I didn't want you to worry.
You see, when I saw
the fever continuing to rise,
and I found myself
in the presence of death,
in a solitude
very extreme, very painful loneliness,
then, I understood then, Armando,
That the only thing in the world,
that is really important to me, is you.
Love.
No.
It's not my fault.
It is not my fault.
Then you have fallen in love with her.
God, God
(Mercedes) (Do you like tango ?)
(Because the man and the woman
dance separately).
(The tango is much more sensual,
I mean...)
- (Federica) Where do we go now ?
- (George) In the hotel, at Dad's.
He has just arrived from Argentina,
he is so anxious to meet you.
- Will you accompany me?
- You couldn't have a better partner.
- Now.
- papà is a great dancer.
- Will you accompany me ?
- You will arrive together.
I will be in the church waiting for you,
don't do as you normally do.
- Yes, but let's leave right away.
- Have you decided where to go?
Far away, as far away as possible,
where I've always dreamed of going.
(Federica) On a desert island
in the Caribbean Sea.
Hold.
- A small coffee, please serve it to me outside.
- (Waiter) All right.
A ristretto coffee.
Thank you.
(Woman) She's coming.
Alessandra ?
Where are you ?
Luisita ?
Luisita, but is there no one there ?
Where are you ?
Luisita ?
Why did you prepare only one place setting?
- Yes, engineer.
- What about my wife ?
She has left.
- Did she leave?
- Yes.
She went to Piedmont to her sister.
She left you a letter.
(Alessandra) (Dear Armando,
I left for Turin this morning).
(I'm going to my sister's and I'll stay with her
I don't know for how long).
(In fact, you see,
I can't accept the idea)
(that you have fallen in love
with your young friend,)
(I just can't do it).
(I need to think
and I think you need to as well).
(Maybe we'll talk again.)
(Sorry. Alessandra.)
Engineer, rigatoni all'amatriciana.
Amatriciana ?
Eh, put.
I'm not hungry anyway.
But how can I do without her ?
(Alessandra) ( That's when,
I understood it then, Armando,)
(that the only thing in the world,)
(which is really important to me, is you).
Alessandra.
Yes, Andreoli, who is it?
(Alessandra) Armando, it's me.
Alessandra.
Finally.
So I'll see you tomorrow morning?
Yes, I have already left.
I arrive precisely in Turin,
and see you at the station.
Platform number 7,
the Saint Moritz carriage, number 9.
Armando, after so long
I'm very excited, so you know?
And I'm really excited, Alessandra ?
Listen, are you still thinking about her?
- Who her?
- Come on, don't pretend!
- You know who I'm talking about.
- Alessandra, it's been a long time.
The story with that woman
ended before your departure.
I haven't heard from her
since that time.
I want to believe you.
I love you, Alessandra, I love you.
I love you so much too.
Goodnight.
Good night, dear.
- See you tomorrow.
- Good night, see you tomorrow.
But that was crazy business.
"Still thinking about that one ?"
Excuse me, thank you.
- (Child) Mother.
- Engineer.
- Who is ?
- Giorgio.
- The fiancé, remember Federica?
- Eh, gosh !
Federica's infamous fiancé,
yeah, right.
- Where are you going?
- To Turin to meet relatives.
- Ah, is that your son?
- Yes, he's my son.
- Eh!
- Is Federica in the cabin ?
- Federica ?
- Eh.
That's my wife, she's German.
What are you talking about?
I was there that morning.
She was at the door,
Federica arrived in a Rolls-Royce.
You entered the church, what happened?
True, then once in front of the altar
she changed her mind and left.
- (Giorgio) She ran away.
- She ran away?
Yes, she ran away
with my papà to South America.
With your papà?
Look, with Federica
it's no wonder.
The man didn't matter to her.
In fact, she preferred
your papà's money.
Your papà is very rich, isn't he?
My papà rich?
He never had a lira.
He has done a thousand jobs in life.
He has always made do.
Do you think he is now an entertainer
on a cruise ship in the Caribbean.
But what about ?
In the Caribbean ?
She did it, eh.
- Did you see them again?
- No.
Every now and then they send some postcards,
in fact, I should have one here.
- It arrived today, here it is.
- Oh there.
(Armando) Are they on this ship?
They dance in pairs.
Tango.
Goodbye, engineer.
- Best wishes.
- To you.
- Goodbye.
(Armando) (Ah, Federica.)
(What have you done?)
(EXCERPT: "FORBIDDEN ENCOUNTERS"
BY P. PIGEONS)