--== McEphie ==--
Are they here?
No, not yet. But they will be soon.
How soon?
There are only a few dances left.
Hopefully more.
God willing,
we'll make it through the night.
This?
I won't need that in the forest.
We're leaving too many things behind.
We're taking too many things
we don't need.
Come here a moment.
There isn't enough time,
we have to leave...
Come here.
Listen well.
If there's one thing we must bring,
it's our faith.
Son, you have to be with me.
But I am with you.
It's one thing to be with me,
and another to believe in me.
We have to get going.
Why did you stop?
I thought I heard something.
- Where?
- Put that away!
There's nothing wrong, my child.
Let's go.
Mother!
Let me see if anyone is inside.
- What was that?
- The floor.
But otherwise, it's usable.
A bit of work
and it will be good as new.
Looks like it was abandoned
centuries ago!
Must be the Spanish!
It will be easy to fix the mess
they left behind!
We're already running out of wine.
So, what are we going to do here?
How long are we going to stay?
We'll try to live here.
We shouldn't worry
about wine and tobacco,
when the rest of the land
is in conflict.
Have some wine.
We'll get through this.
No, thank you.
Lunch is ready!
What are we having?
Potatoes! What were you expecting?
Tonight, we'll eat meat!
It's a good thing I brought these.
I thought they were for planting.
Yes, I will plant them!
I only need a few leaves
for your wound.
They say that these herbs
become healthier and more potent
if grown in the forest.
They come from the forest anyway.
They were once wild plants
discovered by our forefathers
a long time ago.
Bear it!
As they say,
if it hurts, it will heal.
What was in the forest,
and how did this happen?
This is a great forest!
I saw trees far greater
than the ones around us.
I saw one
wider than this whole house!
I think...
...I could walk several days and nights,
and I still wouldn't reach
the other end of the forest.
I've heard that at the end
of the forest lies the sea!
I'd like to reach the sea one day.
I think I'm more of a fisherman
than a hunter.
There are a lot of big fish
in the sea!
- Sometimes I dream about the sea.
- You don't like the river?
You caught our dinner from the river.
Of course! I like the river.
This forest's river.
The water was so cold!
There were so many fish.
I could fish every day
for the rest of our lives,
and the river
wouldn't run out of fish.
We'll never have meat?
Of course we'll have meat!
For example,
on special occasions,
like when we have fiesta.
I promise. One day,
I'll bring some meat home for us.
We need to dig up this soil.
What about the owner?
No one owns land
that's been abandoned.
- Should I start a fire?
- Don't!
Someone might notice us.
I lost my way.
Come inside.
You must be starving.
Mother!
I woke up in your hut.
I had some of your potatoes.
I was so hungry that
I finished everything in the pot.
Well, the hungry always find
something to eat.
I never got to meet my grandfather.
But my father told me
many stories about him.
My favourite is about
how he fought with snakes.
Snakes!
Don't worry!
There aren't any around here.
I'm not afraid of them.
Like my grandfather.
You see... his vegetable patch
in the forest was taken over by snakes.
He couldn't even
get close to the patch.
Neglected, it became overgrown
with weeds.
So my grandfather said,
"These evil snakes cannot reign
over my property!"
So he sharpened his sword
and with a friend, marched to the forest.
As they approached, they could hear
the angry hissing of snakes.
It seemed the snakes knew
they were coming.
Frightened, his friend
quickly climbed up a tree.
From the top, he could see
how my grandfather fought the snakes -
severing their heads with his sword,
or pounding them into the ground
till they were dead...
When he finished killing the snakes,
he gathered them up
into a huge pile taller than him!
Afterwards, he collapsed
from exhaustion.
Later, they extracted
all the bile from the snakes
and distributed it
amongst the villagers.
A form of medicine!
It cures many ailments.
You know how my grandfather
was able to do all that?
Because he had an amulet!
A pebble: round, smooth,
and black, which he found
inside a coconut on Good Friday.
It wasn't from
any ordinary coconut tree.
It grew in the middle of the forest
all by itself.
He gave the amulet to my father,
but people say
that lightning will take it back
if the keeper does bad things.
Then the lightning puts it back
inside another coconut in the forest.
Where is it now?
One day, I'll find it.
Mother...
Did you see her?
Why did you leave?
Why are you crying?
Boil some water!
Son! Where are you!
Father, I'm here!
Stay there! I'll come over to you!
What are you doing here?
I was looking for fruits.
Fruits?
I can give you sacks full of fruit
if you just ask.
Let's go home.
Your mother is worried about you.
- Why aren't you eating?
- I wanted to have fruit for dinner.
Nobody has fruit for dinner.
This is what people eat for dinner!
Are there as many people
as there are fruits in the forest?
Where do they live?
Listen, son...
If you only ate fruit, when you go
to bed you'll have stomach ache
and you won't be able to sleep.
Then you'll cry all night.
The witch will hear
and she'll come for you.
Mother, is the witch
human like us, or an animal?
Child, listen.
You're more talkative
than the birds!
A good boy does
what his father and mother say!
That's right...
Witch or no witch,
you have to be a good boy.
- Right, my child?
- Yes, Mother.
Let's go inside.
Yes, Mother.
I'll heat up your dinner.
What do you see in the night sky?
Wow, it's really beautiful tonight!
The evening star is as bright as ever
and it's right above the trees.
It will disappear in a while.
I can't see the night
as well as you do.
What do you mean?
In the town,
there are many people like us.
And many houses too.
It is good to live in a town
but the problem is
when people quarrel with one another.
I'll tell you a story.
There was once a town
near the forest.
The people were happy as there were
lots of animals to hunt in the forest.
Every day, they had meat to eat.
But people from another town
heard about it.
So they started to hunt
in the same forest.
Soon enough, the wild animals
started to become scarce.
So the two towns quarrelled
with each other.
Until... they hunted one another
rather than the wild animals.
In the end... they all died.
Because there were no more people,
trees started growing in the towns.
They grew into forests.
The animals grew in number
and roamed freely
with no people to hunt them down.
Your son woke up early!
He must be feeding the chickens.
I don't hear him or the chickens!
Your son is missing!
He's not a baby any more. Leave
him be. He'll be around somewhere.
Son!
Where are you?
I hear the Americans.
They're close. Listen.
He was so big and tall!
He came out of the river
and the sun was looking down on him!
His hair was the colour of the sun
and his body was bathed in light!
Your eyes hurt
if you looked at him for too long!
I was so afraid,
I ran away as fast as I could!
I got lost on the way home.
Father's back!
Something is going on in the forest.
Haven't you noticed?
Well you, little boy... You saw the man
in the river bathed in sunlight.
Because you have
the innocent eyes of a child!
Strange things
have entered this forest.
Your failing eyesight
sees many things.
I see them!
I feel them!
Both terrible and wonderful things!
You encountered the giant wild boar?
- Something even worse!
- The witch!
Much worse than that!
It's the evil army
that's been taking over the town.
Now they're here in the forest.
You're scaring the boy.
Listen. Don't worry.
The Saviour
to whom this forest belongs
will destroy the evil outsiders!
You saw him in the river, right?
The one bathed in light,
he will protect us and the forest!
We must find the amulet that lightning
has hidden back in the forest.
The time has come
for someone to find it!
I will find it.
I will make my grandfather proud!
Its power will save us.
Let me tell you
about my brave grandfather...
How he fought snakes
with the amulet in his mouth!
- Snakes!
- That's enough!
It's not good
to speak of snakes while eating.
Son! Where are you?
Father, I'm here!
Father!
Father...
Let's go home.
Mother...
Where did you come from, boy?
Up there?