Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
And we're
back from our commercial break.
When we left off
we were talking
to Chris in Fort Lauderdale.
Chris, are you still there?
Chris?
Annie, is Chris
still on the line?
Ugh.
I don't know
what to believe anymore.
I mean, I feel like there's...
I feel like I'm going crazy.
All the evidence.
All the evidence says
that I'm not.
Okay, Chris.
Just tell us, again,
what's going on
so that people
who are just tuning in,
they can catch up to speed.
Well,
things have been coming
up missing and reappearing
in places I don't leave 'em.
I'm waking up
in the middle of the night
and my nightstand's
always knocked over.
Blinds ripped down.
And they'd be these bruises.
Bruises keep popping up
on my legs.
It has to be aliens!
Sol?
Yeah?
Ask Chris,
what's his work schedule?
Annie, you don't
have to be nervous.
You can ask him.
Ask him, please.
Chris.
Chris, I don't mean
to cut you off.
But do me a favor
and tell me something.
What?
I wanna know
about your work schedule.
My work schedule?
I'm not really working much
right now.
I drive rigs.
Big rigs for a water company.
About nine months, I think.
Okay, Chris, then so
you've been taking uppers
for like nine months?
And then now you quit because
you're on break, right?
Yeah.
But I don't really...
Well, Chris,
unfortunately for me
but fortunate for you,
you're not being abducted.
What? What?
Chris,
you're sleepwalking.
Sleepwalking?
You're sleepwalking.
No.
Your body
has created an addiction
to these stimulants
and you've been on them
for like nine months
and then you just stop.
No, no, Sol.
That's not, that's not right.
Well, okay, Chris.
Well, just continue cutting
back on the stimulants
and you'll be fine.
You know, no more bruises,
tipped over furniture.
I'm okay.
And voilà, you'll be back
to normal.
And with that, folks,
Annie's giving me the signal
that we are out of time.
Tune in tomorrow night
to see what
our brilliant Miss Annie
has in store for us.
So until then,
drive safe,
sleep tight
and keep an eye to the sky.
Seemed
a little off today.
Yeah, I haven't been feeling
right for the past few days.
I have these spots
that popped up on me.
No idea where they came from.
My heart was like
jumping around.
I went to the doctor,
he puts me on this heart
monitor for a month.
So I have to just wait
and see what happens.
But it's strange.
But enough of that.
Now,
with you,
what's wrong with your accent?
What're you having
a problem with it for?
Look,
I'm just not comfortable
doing it.
I appreciate you trying
but I'd appreciate it more
if you didn't.
Well, you know I'm
gonna keep pushing you.
Yeah, you wouldn't be you
if you didn't.
Well, on another note,
what tipped you off about
this last caller
being a sleepwalker?
Well,
my dad, he used to work crazy
work hours when I was little.
Sometimes, 25, 26 hours straight
just hopped up on coffee.
Oh.
One day he lost his job
and we started noticing
weird things.
Like, his tools would be
out of place
or the fridge door left open
or the car keys in the toilet.
In the toilet?
But the weirdest thing
was he had these bruises
all over his legs,
so one night,
I stayed up pretty late
reading my mystery stories
and I heard footsteps down the
hall.
It was my dad.
So I follow him to his room
where my mom's dead asleep
and as he walks to the bed,
he slams his legs
into the night stand.
So that's the whole thing,
that's it, that's the story.
20 years I've been
dying to get a real story
and as soon as it looks like
I have one,
you knock it right out
from under me.
But overall, a good night.
Well, yeah, that's true.
And no worries.
I'll be digging up a really
good topic for tomorrow.
Yeah, I'm sure.
But in the meantime,
go home, get some rest, or
you'll be coming in here
with bruises on your legs.
That's true.
All right, all right,
I will, I know.
Hey, guys, I don't mean
to break anything up.
I was told to get
the studio prepped
for Fabian's morning show.
Yes, sir, boss man.
I guess that's my cue, so.
Would you drop this
off at the break room?
Will do.
Thank you.
Of course, sure.
Wow.
Goodnight, Annie.
Goodnight.
Good show tonight.
Thanks.
Hey.
That's not good
for your car, you know?
Huh?
Just letting it
idle for so long.
I read online it starts to
build corrosion in your...
Oh, oh, I'm sorry.
I get it.
Strange guy by your car in
the middle of the night.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, look, I'm Jared.
I live like one door
down from you.
Watch you
almost every night.
Oh.
Oh, no, no, no, I
didn't mean it that way.
It's a bad choice of words.
Look, I work
customer support online
but I work it from my house
and I'm kind of a night owl so
I take the graveyard shifts.
I usually pop out
at like one or two
and I see you pull in and
you fumble with your things
as you go to your door.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
I know Sol.
I mean, I don't know him,
know him.
I mean, he was friends
with my grandparents
and I knew he sold you
his place out here, so.
Oh, really?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Sorry.
I guess that just me.
So, Jared?
Jared, yeah.
Nice meeting you.
Likewise.
I just, I thought
it was kinda weird.
You know, you pulled in a
lot later than you usually do
and then you just
kinda sat here.
Well, yeah,
I might have zoned out
for a minute
or something but...
What time is it?
What?
- What's wrong?
- No, wait.
Wait, what's wrong?
Kidding me?
Is everything
all right?
Yeah, yeah.
It's fine, it's just...
I just don't remember
driving home.
I remember heading to my car
and then you knocking
on my window.
Highway hypnosis,
have you heard of it?
That's what it is.
Like, I drove from here
to Miami and back
on one cup of coffee
and I can't remember a thing.
I can't remember
why I drove out there.
I think it was for my training
or something.
Annie?
Oh, yeah.
- Sorry.
- Hey.
Look,
how about we get you
to your apartment?
I guess so, all right.
Look, Jared, I'm fine.
You don't have to do this.
Annie,
at least let me fail at
being a gentleman on my own.
Oh yeah, I know.
Just trying to be nice, right?
Anyways, here we are.
Yep.
Here we are.
Here you are.
Thanks.
It was nice
to finally meet you.
Yeah, nice meeting you.
Hey,
this is against
my better judgment
but would you like to come in?
Just have a coffee
or something?
Yeah, sure.
I've got time.
Okay.
Cool.
This is it.
Water
is what gives us life.
It's a precious, limited
resource which is vital to our...
It's funny.
What?
This.
I never expected it
to be this messy.
Really?
It's like a bum became
a crime investigator
or something.
Okay.
There goes the point where you
begin failing as a gentleman.
Oh, no, no,
I don't mean it that way.
It's, it's refreshing
to see a woman
that's so involved with her
work.
Hmmm.
I can tell you're not
knee-deep in the latest fashion
or running to the bathroom
every five minutes
to fix your face.
Okay.
Have you ever successfully
given a woman a compliment?
All right, look, wait,
you got coffee, right?
Yeah.
How about I make us a pot?
Sounds good.
Looks like
you're all out.
Is ice water just as good?
Mm-hmm.
You know,
that was
an amazing show tonight.
Oh, you listen?
Friends with Sol.
Kinda.
Yeah, I listen.
I mean,
a lot of people think
Sol's pretty nutty but
I think he's right
on the money sometimes
with a lot of his stuff.
I mean, that's...
That's clearly
why you work there, right?
I mean,
you have to believe in all the
extraterrestrials and UFOs.
Oh, no, no, no.
Me believing in these show
topics isn't a part of my job.
I was actually hired because
I don't believe in this stuff.
Well, how does that
make sense?
Well,
'cause I'm there to
disprove the little stories,
weed out the hoaxes.
Find logic in the bigger ones.
All right,
I can see that.
It's kinda like religion.
Like how some one would
rather be preached to
by a former atheist turned
Christian
than someone who's been a
believer in God their whole life.
There's just something
more powerful
in the words of
skeptic-turned-believer.
It's kinda genius, actually.
Especially once they
make you a believer.
Try and get some sleep, Annie.
To stay hydrated,
we must drink half of our
body weight in water a day
and that's why you should
drink Arch Filtered.
Our water is naturally
purified using the same process
that occurs in natural springs.
You know what's on them
satellites come crashing down?
Diseases.
Diseases we ain't even
got a name for.
Space germs.
Can't
nothing live out in space, man,
not even germs.
There's no atmosphere.
Odell, give my quarter back!
Sit done, Smokey,
you'll get dizzy again.
This machine has had it.
Give my my quarter back, Odell!
That's why I loaned you
that quarter in the first place.
Hey,
brother, do you speak English?
Oh gosh.
All right! All right!
I'm coming, I'm coming.
Hey,
did you hear or feel
that a few minutes ago?
No, sorry, look Jared, I'm
still a little out of it, okay?
Look, I just came by
to check on you.
I came out to have a smoke
before I started my first shift
and I saw your car
was still here.
So I figured maybe you
called off after last night.
No, what time is it?
You making a habit of this?
It's 6:49.
What?
Shit, I am so late!
Okay,
look, Jared, I'm super late.
I have to get to work
right now, okay?
Sure.
I'll talk to you later?
- Sure.
- Okay, bye.
Hey.
Thank you for being a
gentleman last night.
Sure, just being
a good neighbor.
Sorry.
Try to feel better though.
Okay, I will, thanks.
Hey, Sol, I'm sorry I
slept through my alarms.
I'm getting ready right now.
I'll be there as soon as I can,
okay?
Calm down, take a breath.
You're not in trouble.
We were just a little worried
when you didn't show up.
I know, I was just, I
don't know, I must have...
I just had a weird night, that's
all,
but I'm getting ready right now
and I have a great
story for tonight, okay?
All right, all right.
Stop apologizing.
Just get yourself together
and get down here.
Okay, all right, thank
you Sol, see you soon.
See you soon, kiddo.
Taking a look at our
seven day forecast,
we've got plenty of clear
skies headed our way
starting with today at a
high of 87, a low of 81,
bringing us into a little
cooler night tonight
with a high around 69 and
continued clear skies.
And speaking of clear skies,
Janis, I don't know if you
caught that
surprise meteor shower last
night.
We've had photographs
flooding in from
our viewers in Gulf Breeze.
Really beautiful stuff.
Well those are some
beautiful pictures, Stan.
Can't beat surprises like those.
And to continue the subject
of the sky,
our next story involves
strange sounds
heard from the sky
this morning.
The story has piggybacked
on the meteor shower
and is one of the top
trending topics online.
Have you seen this?
Or better yet,
have you heard this?
The authorities' emergency
lines and new stations
have been flooded with
reports of strange noises
being heard all around the world
and just as close as our
backyard here in Gulf Breeze.
That's right, we've
experienced a first time taste
of "the sound" this morning.
Our own news station
believed it to be a hoax
until researched proved this
is not to be an isolated event.
There's more on this story at
11.
Oh, come on.
Let's see.
"Gateway to Hell Found."
"Superpowers."
How is this not on the news?
Okay, so I've never done
a blog before.
This is my first one,
so here it goes.
So the other night I
heard this sound, right?
Yeah, so I heard this sound
and it was about three
o'clock in the morning
and I thought it might be a
plane but it was continuous.
I had never heard
anything like that before
so I did some research.
I found a video online
that was from Berlin
and I'm in Michigan but it
was the exact same sound.
Leave a comment if you know
or maybe you heard it too.
I can't be the only one.
I heard the sound again tonight.
I caught the tail end of it.
It must've literally just
stopped.
My boyfriend thinks
I'm screwing with him
but I know I heard it again.
If anybody else did, you
know, send me a message
or comment or anything.
Just let me know
somebody else heard it.
Okay,
I have finally caught it.
It's, I mean, it's like 3AM.
But I finally caught it.
I've been waiting up every night
and I've finally caught it.
So I'm gonna
show you guys, all right?
Here, here we go.
All right.
I don't know how he's sleeping
through this, it's crazy.
It's like, it's louder
than it's ever been before.
You guys must be able
to hear this.
It's like this crazy metal
sound.
Damn it.
Hey.
James.
Hey, Annie.
You know I don't usually call.
But Sol said that you would
be here like 10 minutes ago.
You know we can't do the show
without you.
I know.
I know, I know.
I'm right around the corner,
okay?
I'll be there
in five minutes, okay?
Hey, Annie,
is everything okay?
No, yeah, it's fine.
I'm just...
Stanton Road?
How the hell did I get here?
Um, yeah,
I'm okay.
I'll see you guys in a second.
Yeah.
Hey, Annie.
Hi.
Hey, James, watch this,
watch this.
Boo.
Seriously?
So we had a case of
Sleeping Beauty, did we?
Oh yeah, ha, ha,
really funny, very.
I don't know,
I don't know what happened.
I think I'm just in some
kind of funk right now.
Well don't go getting sick on
us.
You are what makes the
program interesting.
Hmmm.
I have to check in on
studio one.
If you don't need anything
else, that is, sir.
You're good to go.
We'll see you after the show.
All right, kiddo.
Annie.
Feel better
and if you need anything,
just let me know.
Will do.
Talk about a crush.
How're you doing, kiddo?
Ugh, all right, I guess.
Just a little out of it, it
seems like.
How so?
I don't know, like
me oversleeping today.
I mean, I knew I was tired
but four hours?
And then I'm constantly thirsty.
And what about now?
Yeah, all the time.
Just, I don't know,
and last night I don't
remember driving home.
I remember being home,
sitting in my parking lot
but nothing else.
Oh, and thanks for not
telling me about Jared,
that neighbor guy.
He came to my car,
knocked on the windows.
Scared the hell out of me.
Gosh.
Annie, how can you
not see what's going on?
What do you mean?
Lost hours,
oversleeping,
dehydration.
Yeah.
This all speaks of...
alien activity.
Ugh.
See, I knew I couldn't
tell you this.
I knew you wouldn't
take it seriously.
But I am being serious.
I mean, what other
explanation could it be?
Oh, let's just save
it for the show, okay?
Great.
Okay, look.
We have a few songs left
until we air,
so I stumbled upon a great
topic for tonight, actually.
I had something yesterday
but this is way better.
There's been reports
about this strange sound
being heard thousands
of miles apart
and nobody knows what it is.
Not the NSA, not NASA,
not the government.
Nobody has answers
to what it is.
Well, it sounds like we
have a good show on our hands.
You have no idea and
it's all right here.
Tell you what, why
don't you get yourself
a strong cup of coffee,
get one for me
while you're at it
and I'll look at
what you have here.
Cool, sounds good.
Oh.
I have a recording of
the sound right here.
And we're going to play it.
Hey, when did we get that?
Huh?
When did we get that?
Oh, this?
The station got a new
sponsorship from a water company,
so naturally they want to
put their product everywhere.
Mm-hmm.
Well, folks, we're back
and we're ready to hear
what out audience has to say
about what can only be
described as "the sound."
So, we'll be opening up
the lines for your calls
and I believe Annie has
our first call ready to go.
Mm-hmm, first we have Jack
from Cocoa Beach on line one.
Hi, is this Jack?
Yes.
This is Jack.
And you're calling in
about the sound,
so go ahead
and tell us about it.
Yeah, yeah, the sound.
Here's how it went down.
A few weeks ago,
me and the buds,
just camping out one night.
Well, we saw, I don't wanna
freak anybody out or anything,
but man, we saw
some crazy shit, man!
Well, Jack,
what did you see?
Well.
So,
we're like camping out and
sitting around the fire
and, like, all of a
sudden, out of nowhere,
I mean the sky just lights up
and it was just awesome!
So glorious.
And then, all of a sudden...
Something doesn't sound right.
Recheck his facts, please.
Okay, Jack,
so a few weeks ago
you and your buddies
were camping
and taking plenty of hits
off of who knows what,
when a crazy spaceship took off
but what you saw
was a space shuttle
off the coast
of Cape Canaveral, Florida.
- No way.
- And with that, folks,
we'll be right back.
Aren't you the one
who is supposed to be
screening these calls, Annie?!
I'm sorry.
I just thought he had
such a convincing story.
I thought you would
want to talk to someone
who had a firsthand account
of the sound.
All right, now that
we have had our laughs,
can we get back to business?
All right, our next caller
is Mary from Gainesville.
Well, folks, we're back
and we're ready to hear
what our audience has to
say about "the sound."
Okay, Mary from Gainesville.
Mary, are you on the line?
Hello, Sol?
I'm a first-time caller
and a first time listener
but I just had to tell you,
I know exactly what that sound
is these people are hearing.
Fill us in.
That sound is
the good Lord's trumpet
calling his faithful to
Paradise.
Well, folks,
there you have it.
Now wait a minute, Sol,
I'm not done speaking.
Th good Lord is
calling his faithful
before the end of days.
So they can be saved.
Well, Mary, if you're correct,
have you heard
the good Lord's trumpet?
Well.
Hello, Mary?
Well, folks, I guess she
heard the good Lord's trumpet.
Well, in order to minimize
the crazies calling in,
we think you should have
a little more information
and our program director, Annie,
has dug up
some pretty interesting stuff.
So we will let her tell her
tale and open up the lines.
Annie?
It's over to you.
What are you doing?
I'm not reading the stories,
I just give them to you.
- Payback.
- Eh?
Payback.
No.
Sorry, folks,
I caught Annie off guard
but she's collected
her thoughts now
and she's ready to go.
Over to you, Annie.
Okay.
This is Annie.
And...
Within the last week,
authorities and emergency lines
and news stations have
been flooded with reports
of strange noises being
heard all around the world
and the first big report
to break national news
happened last week in Nevada.
The second was in Berlin
and the third was in Michigan.
Upon further investigation,
local authorities
were unable to pinpoint
an exact location of
the source of the sound
due to the wide range
or reported locations.
Again,
many people believe it's
just a wide-scale hoax.
After a bit of digging,
I found that these
sounds have been reported
as early as 1991
but there were less people
actually reporting it.
And then just two days ago,
all reports of the sounds
stopped
except for one place,
right here in our quiet
town of Gulf Breeze.
The sound was heard
for the first time
this morning around 3AM.
And with that, we would
like you to tell us
what you think we could he
hearing under the stars.
All right, Annie, now
before we take our break,
Annie told me that she has
a recording of the sound
and we're gonna play it
for you folks right now.
Um, uh, um...
All right, folks,
there you have it.
What do you think it could be?
Give us your thoughts
when we come right back.
Two things,
one, you did amazing
like I knew you would.
Thank you.
It felt good.
And two,
game's over.
I want a real phone call
when I get back.
Yes, sir, boss man.
Seriously.
No, yeah, I know, will do.
"Under the Stars,"
this is Annie speaking.
What are you
calling about tonight?
Hello?
Okay, I'm going to hang up
if you don't say anything,
caller.
Hello.
Yes, hey.
This is Annie and you're
with "Under the Stars."
I need to talk to you
about the sounds in the sky.
I know what it is.
What it really is.
The Arch Corporation, it's them!
They are the ones
that are make...
Okay, sir, please calm down.
So you say you know what
the sound really is.
Can you explain?
Listen, I
don't have a lot of time.
They are the ones that
are causing these sounds!
It's like, I don't know, okay?
I don't know exactly but
it is making the sound.
Okay, sir,
before I can put you on,
I need just a little
more information, okay?
Listen to me!
I work, worked for them!
I escaped!
They are keeping something
there at the facility
that is not human!
It is pissed!
It is dangerous!
They have been
doing experiments on it
and there's no telling
what it's gonna do!
I know what they are, okay?
Okay.
Okay, I'll put you through.
We still have a little time
left.
Can you tell me
what the sound is?
The sound is a physical
phenomenon caused
when something tries to
cross over into our world
through the tears.
The sound is...
You're hearing matter being
translated into our world.
You are hearing them come over!
Who's "them?"
I was a lead engineer
hired to work on a device
codenamed "Project Harmony."
I saw something cross over
when I tried to turn it on
and that's when it
made the sound.
Okay.
I'm putting you
through now, okay?
Just...
Just a second.
You have a creepy caller
on line four.
He wouldn't give me his name.
All right, folks,
and we're back
and Annie has a caller
on the line that
apparently we really
need to talk to.
All right, caller,
who am I speaking with?
This is John.
Well, welcome to the
show, John, you're on the air.
Everyone listening
must pay attention!
Remember these words!
The Arch Corporation,
Project Harmony.
A device was built as a
result of Project Harmony.
This device replicates a
singularity here on Earth,
manufacturing...
space time.
Okay, I don't who where...
Annie.
Annie, we're losing him!
Annie!
Um...
Our signal's fine.
It's being cut from his end.
What the hell is going on?
Stay calm.
The backup lights
will be on in a second.
A fire emergency
has been reported
in the building.
Proceed to the nearest exit
and vacate the building.
Do not use the elevators.
Sol!
Who are
you, my brothers and sisters?
Telling you that
we are not alone.
I want to remind you all
today that we are not alone.
We are not alone today.
We have never been alone.
We will never be alone.
"Why?" you ask.
"How?" you ask.
You see,
my brothers and sisters,
we are in the presence
of He who is called "I Am."
The first and the last.
The Almighty.
We are in the presence of God!
Do you believe Moses was alone
when he parted the Red Seas
to save his people?
No.
Oh my Gosh.
Do you believe
that David
was alone when he slayed Goliath
to defeat the Philistines?
No.
Do you believe
that Noah was alone
when he loaded two
of every creature
on this green and beautiful
earth on to that ark?
To rescue them
from the Great Flood?
No!
Okay.
So things are starting
to get really weird.
I mean, like, really strange.
I haven't heard the sound
in awhile but,
like, the other day,
I clocked in at work
and the next thing
I remember is leaving.
I don't remember any of it.
I mean,
that's eight hours
of my day that's just,
just gone.
Just nothing,
I don't remember any of it.
Yeah.
We just talked
about this.
You ramble on the internet
like some sort of freaking
psychopath and just...
I'm sorry, this
is actually happening though.
I'm not crazy.
No!
Nobody's coming to get you.
This is getting really old.
But I don't know
what's going on!
I don't know what's going on.
I mean, I can't explain
any of this.
Do you need to talk to
some sort of freaking shrink?
Whatever.
Sorry about that.
Just, if...
I'm really scared, so if
anybody knows anything,
you know, let me know, please.
Message me
or leave a comment.
Maybe you're going through
the same thing, I don't know.
So my boyfriend left me.
We're together
for five years and
he just ended it
like it was nothing.
It's not just,
it's not just him though.
Like, my boss.
My boss has been
really weird.
It's not me.
It's not me, it can't be me.
Everyone else is being weird.
They're being weird.
You know,
they're telling me things
that I'm doing
that I can't remember.
I think I'm getting sick
because I keep throwing
up this black stuff.
I don't really understand.
Is anybody else
going through this?
I'm really scared and I
don't know what's happening.
Please, comment or mail me.
Anything, I just,
I don't know what's happening.
I figured it out.
I figured it out, I did, I did.
You know, me losing time and
just everyone acting crazy.
It's aliens.
It has to be aliens.
It is and it's them trying
to get into your brain.
Can't get in.
Bye.
If they can't get in,
then you're safe.
So I'm safe.
They're not gonna get me.
No.
They can't get in.
Hey.
Hey, what's up?
Sorry to bother you.
Is your cable acting funny?
Mine's under the fritz for
like the last half hour or so.
What?
I don't know.
I hadn't had it on
since I've been home.
Would it be too much
to check to see if yours
is the same as mine?
- What's?
- Um.
You look flustered.
Did I, uhh...?
I didn't scare you, did I?
Like bad timing?
No, it's...
Sorry, it's okay, I'm just
a little, a little on edge
- but you can come in.
- Sure.
It's fine.
You can have a seat
if you want.
Or you can just stand.
We interrupt your program
to bring you
this breaking news story.
A grizzly murder scene
has been discovered
at the water filtration
company in Emerald County,
just two counties over.
Local authorities are
looking for this man,
33 year old John Maner,
believed to be
- armed and dangerous.
- Seems okay.
Yeah.
Like I said, it comes and goes.
But
we're asking our viewers
with any information
about the whereabouts of...
You want a drink
or something?
No, no, I'm covered.
Okay.
Are you sure you're okay?
Uh, yeah.
Hey, you haven't been feeling
strange or anything, have you?
Me?
No.
Aside from a bad burrito
I had the other day,
I'm feeling pretty good.
Why, you getting sick?
Okay, listen.
Okay.
You need to promise me
you won't call me crazy
or anything, okay?
Sure.
I wrote this
before I came home
but I wasn't in control
when I was writing it.
We just had
this weird phone call
about this topic
I stumbled on and,
you mention earlier, like,
strange sounds being heard
all over the place, you know?
Right.
Okay, so, I talked to
this man on the phone and
I'm starting to write these
numbers and words but...
It's like I'm just on
autopilot or something.
This isn't even my handwriting.
You get a weird phone call,
you write these notes down
and then you black out?
I don't know, yeah.
I just have, like,
these gaps in time...
Time gaps.
I don't remember anything.
Can I have a look?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Whoa.
This is weird.
Do you see something?
Yes and no.
Do you have a pen?
Yeah.
Here.
This is an anagram.
The letters in the sentence
have been reorganized
so for the untrained eye,
it doesn't make any sense.
Okay.
But if you
rearrange the letters,
one of the sentences
I get out of it
is, "They want to colonize."
Yeah.
I don't know.
The rest is
a little more complex.
It's like a big puzzle.
You just gotta figure
out where the pieces go.
And these numbers, here,
they mean something and
I think it has to do
with whatever you wrote down.
Look, I'm not the best at this
but I think I know somebody
that can figure it out.
Okay.
Whatever this is,
some part of you didn't want
you to know what it means.
Oh God,
you start sounding like Sol.
No, no, no, no.
Seriously, let me take these
and I'll get this figured out.
I trust you
with this, okay?
Okay.
"Sorry, the blog you are
looking for does not exist."
What?
Shit.
"Sorry, the blog you are..."
"Sorry."
"Sorry, the blog you are looking
for..."
Jared!
Hey.
Where are you going?
You look different.
What did you find out
about the notes?
I'm just going
to the dumpster.
Come on, Jared, it's really
not the time to joke, okay?
What did you find out?
Where are my notes?!
You're Annie, right?
Yeah.
And you're Jared.
And you've been to my
apartment two nights in a row.
So now, if we're done
stating pointless facts,
I really need you to tell
me what you found out, okay?
Or give me my fucking notes!
Just hold on.
You really don't know
who I am, do you?
Look,
Annie,
I'm really sorry.
I've been forgetting
a lot of things recently.
What do you want me to do?
If I've done something
to you, I'm sorry.
Looks like you're all out.
Is ice water just as good?
They're telling me things
that I'm doing
that I can't remember.
It's aliens.
It has to be aliens.
It is and it's them trying
to get into your brain.
It's the water.
How many
did you have of these?
None.
Maybe since yesterday.
Okay, good.
This is going
to sound strange but
don't drink
any more of these, okay?
Sure.
Sol.
I need to get to Sol.
I know what to do.
Oh my God.
Hey, hey, hey.
Where's the fire?
Sorry, sir, I didn't see you.
James?
Yeah, I know, it's different.
Yeah.
I don't know.
This morning I just woke up
and just felt,
new.
Sorry, where are my manners?
Oh, no, thank you.
It's ice cold.
Yeah, thank you but no.
Annie.
Sol?
How are you today, Annie?
Sorry, I was just looking
for...
Didn't mean to scare you.
Sol?
No, it's find.
I just need to talk to you,
okay?
Wait.
I think you were right
about everything you said.
I think everything
I had going on
has to do with...
Aliens.
Just get ahold
of yourself, Annie.
Stay hydrated, you'll get
back in the swing of things.
Where's
your coffee, Sol?
That's something, isn't it?
No more marks on me.
No more heart monitor.
I have to get ready
for the show.
They have everything ready
for me to go.
What do you mean?
I haven't even
prepared anything.
Look,
there are bigger things
going on right now, okay?
You need to listen to me.
Things have changed, Annie.
I want to go into
a different direction
with the classics
and current events
instead of all that alien stuff.
You're not Sol.
Oh my gosh.
Hello?
Annie.
It's Jared.
I remember,
I remember everything.
What happened?
Listen to me.
I'm locked in the back room
of my place.
Why?
Why are you locked
in your bedroom?
Because there's men
in your apartment.
Just listen, Annie.
I don't have much time.
I don't know who they are.
But I found out it has
something to do with the water.
And they have
the same bottled water
that's in the bottles of
water I've been drinking.
Annie?
Annie, are you still there?
I'm here.
I'm in one of the stations.
It's different.
You gotta get out of there.
You gotta get out of there
right now.
Did you hear me?
Okay.
What about those notes?
Listen,
the numbers you gave me,
the numbers in your notes,
I think they're coordinates.
It's...
30.44,
33 degrees north
by 87.214 degrees west.
I'm not sure what's going on
but those numbers hold
some kind of answer.
What're you doing here?
What do you want?
Jared!
- Oh no!
- Oh no.
No!
Jared, can you hear me?
Oh no.
Hello, Jared?
Jared, can you hear me?
Hello, Annie?
Is everything okay?
Annie?
Are you there, Annie?
Annie.
Annie, wait a minute.
I just want to have
a word with you.
Damn it.
Oh shit.
Open the door, Annie.
No!
Please?
Get away
from my car, James!
Don't you wanna be
one of us?
James.
Don't do this, please.
Don't do this to me, you
don't have to do this...
Open the door, Annie!
Open the door!
Annie.
Annie!
Open the door!
Annie.
Join us.
Okay! Okay!
Okay.
The numbers.
Those numbers.
Make a right turn
in 200 feet.
This must be the place.
Your destination
is within half of a mile.
I shouldn't be here.
33.
97.
21.
14.
Three.
Your destination
is within 500 feet.
Four.
Three.
Seven.
Two.
One.
Where am I?
Your destination
is within 100 feet.
You have arrived at your
destination.
Oh my God.
This is it.
This is Dr. John Fox Maner.
November 12th, I think.
It's...
It's a site that I woke up at.
I don't know where I am.
I don't know where this is
but it's a remote location
that I know Arch is using.
This is not, this is not just
me.
People have been
disappearing every day.
I've seen it happening
around this facility.
There's people that disappear
and then they come back
and they're not
the same person.
I don't know where, I
don't know how I got here.
I'm trying to find answers
and I know they're here.
This form is
documents that I've seen,
I've seen this work,
I've seen these notes.
I don't know
what they're trying to build
or what this is
supposed to replicate.
It's not anything that
has been done before.
What's that?!
God!
What is that?
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org