Mhm! Mhm!
Mmm.
Mm?
Mm.
HAPPILY EVER AFTER
UNHAPPILY EVER AFTER
A COUPLE OF YEARS AGO...
Hi.
What are you doing?
I'm waiting for you.
-Are you OK?
-Yes.
I just came to gather strength.
I still want to go a few
more times.
-Really?
-Yes.
Mmm. No.
-Why not?
-People can see us.
-So? They'll cheer us on!
-No.
I don't want to go...
-ever!
-Me neither.
I don't want to work
with the accountant!
Quit, baby.
No, I mean it.
Are you going to support me?
-What's wrong with that?
-Nothing.
I'd love it.
-I have a surprise for you.
-What is it?
Promise me something...
That no matter what...
we will always make the next day
better that the last.
Love each other so much
that you are a bit of sun
and a bit of night.
Be together
through the gray mornings.
Laugh and watch
how love defeats time.
You are married now.
Let's go!
I love you, María José!
María José!
Where are my pants?
You've been wearing
the same pants for a week!
Your pants already
stand by themselves.
-They're my favorite...
-But they have a hole
in the crotch!
Baby, who would look
at my crotch?
You're right about that...
there's nothing to see.
-Lower your pants, you look old.
-And you look like my mom.
I'm taking your car.
-Why? What about yours?
-It's in the shop.
Why did you take it there?
I said I'd fix it.
-Three weeks ago!
-Yes, baby,
but I'm closing stuff at work
and I have a lot to do!
I have to help the accountant!
But you help her
more than you help me.
Baby, come on!
Centennials...
Are you ready?
Let's go to school.
Stop it.
Kids, go to the car
while I say goodbye to dad.
Yes, let's go.
Here.
Go to the car
while I say bye to mom.
-I heard you.
-OK, last one...
-Well done, baby!
-Stop!
Go ahead, princess.
Don't talk like that
in front of the children.
I'm sorry, baby.
-I'm very stressed out.
-Why?
María José...
Maybe América
won't make it to the league.
Alfredo...
América always makes it
to the league.
You're right.
OK,
you'll need to take the bus.
The bus?
María José, me taking the bus?
-What's wrong with it?
-How...?
-García!
-Accountant!
I'm behind on
the sheet balances...
-I know!
-Yes, of course.
-I need my coffee.
-Of course, ma'am.
No!
-Latte, lactose...
-Of course.
-...two sugars.
-Latte, light, sugar.
Desy, sit on the front.
María José!
María José, please...
Take me to work.
I'd love to,
but we're running late.
See you later.
Say bye to daddy, kids.
Bye, daddy!
Ouch!
We're here live
on El Heraldo Televisión,
Alejandro Cacho,
Paulina Greenham.
Yesterday was an amazing show...
-Here.
-He's talking to you.
Thank you.
Last night, women
received awards from the...
Did you like your surprise?
Yes, baby!
Thank you for the food...
Well, your anniversary
is an important date.
Yes, baby.
How could we forget
such an important date?
Alfredo, it's in two days.
But we're celebrating today.
And you're one to talk.
You almost killed me and you
didn't even say you're sorry.
It was both our fault.
Both our fault? Sure!
I'm sorry for putting
my foot under your tire!
It's fine, I forgive you.
-Quit the attitude.
-María José, don't start.
-I'm not liking you...
-...since the day started...
-Enough!
-Shut up!
This is your 20th anniversary
and I think
you need to celebrate.
Yes, baby but...
we don't have money
to celebrate right now.
-Oh!
-What is it?
Wow! Baby...
Wow.
Look at this,
"Happy Anniversary..."
"A trip to the beach".
It's just what I need.
But you're going too...
It's the hotel
of our honeymoon.
We saved our allowances,
the money grandma gave me
for my 15th birthday,
everything Jorge won
with his bets,
and Nina's savings.
That's how we paid for it.
-No way.
-It can't be.
At least we're on
the same page about this.
It's right.
So, what do we tell them?
We have to tell them.
Centennials...
It's cool
that we're all friends.
Mhm.
Guys, what you did for us
was really beautiful,
-thank you so much, but...
-But daddy has to work.
Yes, the month is ending
and I have a lot of work.
This is not a question.
You have to go on this trip.
But you can't stay alone,
who'll take care of you?
-Grandma!
-My girl!
So precious!
How are you? I'm sorry,
I know you're celebrating
and I didn't want to intrude
but... the kids invited me.
Baby,
I didn't say hi, I'm sorry!
Since you're going
to the beach,
I bought you some sunblock.
Because you always
burn your ears, Alfredo.
And if I don't take care
of you...
who will?
Right?
Pull your pants up, Alfredo,
you look like a plumber!
There.
Thank you.
I don't know
whether to feel angry
or proud of you.
-They are just like their dad.
-Or like their mom.
We're like the both of you.
Go with God,
have a safe trip
and a good return.
Thank you!
In the name of the Father
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Take care, son.
-Yes.
-Take care.
-Just relax.
-And try not to kill each other.
Wait!
Don't come back until you love
each other again.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Saguaro Airlines welcomes you
to Puerto Peñasco, Sonora.
A lot of people
get sick on planes.
Sure, but because
they get dizzy not drunk.
Yes...
What are your names again?
María José Márquez
and Alfredo García.
García, Márquez...
Like the writer.
Sorry, yes.
THIS RESERVATION
HAS BEEN CANCELLED
SEARCH FOR RESERVATION
THIS RESERVATION
HAS BEEN CANCELLED
-You're not on the system.
-No, that can't be!
There must be something wrong,
call your manager, please.
-I am the manager.
-Fuck!
I used to manage Hibris,
Mexico's biggest
international company.
And I went from manager to VP
because I could find solutions.
-Yes...
-Shut up!
I have a solution.
The honeymoon suite.
Welcome.
-Your bag, please, sir.
-Yes, thanks.
No, thank you.
We're planning on
remodeling the suite
but some other things
have come up and...
we haven't done it.
Tomorrow we'll take out
the boxes, brooms,
and the dust, I apologize.
-Hey.
-Yes?
What's the Wi-Fi password?
No Wi-Fi up here.
With caps on?
No, I meant
that there's no Wi-Fi up here.
Oh, OK.
OK but...
apart from these little details,
everything works great.
Look,
the hot tub is still there.
Too bad it's broken.
Oh, and the AC...
is also broken.
Yes...
Apart from that...
everything works great.
Sometimes we have
power outages.
Tomorrow we'll fix
all these little details.
See you, thank you.
Look!
-Hello?
-Happy anniversary!
Good morning.
How was the trip?
Everything was fine,
thank you.
Majo, how's my son's foot?
Fine, ma'am, everything's fine.
Well, I'm just here cleaning up
your house
because it was really dirty.
I'll let you talk to your son.
-Hi, mommy.
-Alfredito.
Don't forget to put on
your sunblock, please.
You're in
the middle of nowhere,
there are no hospitals,
no doctors,
-and you even get fevers.
-Yes, mommy.
So cool, the weather is amazing.
Shit!
♪ Here's your baby ♪
♪ Your bitch from the future ♪
♪ Hard, hard ♪
♪ Bitch from the future ♪
♪ Here's your baby ♪
♪ Your bitch from the future ♪
♪ Hard, hard ♪
♪ Bitch from the future ♪
♪ Here's your baby ♪
I'm sorry, ma'am, I apologize.
I forgot to explain
the thing with the water...
No, it's not a thing.
There is no water.
No, there is...
From four to five
in the morning
and sometimes at six p.m.
But only for 15 minutes.
It's a phenomenon.
Well, you're scamming my kids.
Because they spent
all their savings on this.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
I swear that tomorrow
everything will work perfectly.
Despite being
the honeymoon suite,
in 20 years
everything falls apart.
OK, I want less apologies
and more action.
To the left, to the right.
You're fine, tomorrow
you'll be good as new.
Let me see what I have here.
Never mix bacanora
with eggnog and chiltepín.
It's to die for.
I'll give you
a cocktail of Meloxicam,
Celecoxib,
Parisiprodol,
and a bit of Tramadol,
that will make you feel...
No, you know what?
I'm feeling better already.
Drop your pants!
-No, Doctor...
-Drop your pants!
It's fine.
Bend over, it's fine.
Relax!
Here we go.
I'll count to three.
One...
Good morning.
Nice day, huh?
Yes...
A lot of sun.
BEACH TOURNAMENT
García...
Hi, accountant, how are you?
I'm waiting for the...
Right, sorry.
-The balance!
-Right!
I'm sorry,
I forgot to send it.
There are so many things here.
Could I send it later?
-I'm...
-Later?
If you need it now,
I'll send it. Of course.
-Send it right away!
-My pleasure.
-It's been days...
-See you,
say hi to everyone
in the office for me.
-Sure, bye!
-Have a...
Yes!
-Shit!
-Auch!
I'm sorry!
Sir, are you hurt?
No, I'm fine, don't worry.
Thanks.
I work here, do you want me
to take you to the doctor?
No, really I'm fine.
It didn't hurt at all.
OK then.
Thanks.
What happened?
A risky move playing volleyball.
Oh!
You have to come closer,
I'm stealing
the other room's Wi-Fi.
-Hi, dad!
-Hi, baby!
What happened, dad?
-Did my mom hit you?
-No, baby!
He got hurt playing volleyball.
Volleyball?
But you get tired playing chess.
Alfredito, look at your ears!
-They're sunburnt!
-Yes, mommy.
Why aren't you fighting?
Is grandma wearing my silk robe?
Yes, she's very happy.
How's the trip,
are you having fun?
Is the hotel the same
as your remembered it?
Exactly the same, baby!
Excuse me, it's hot.
Yes.
-Oh!
-What was that?
Shit!
Don't move him.
Mom, what happened to him?
-We can't stay here!
-I want my money back!
Calm down, please.
We don't want to ruin
your holidays,
just for tonight,
in memory of Mister Tolstoi...
vodka on the house!
Fine...
How can you drink
in a moment like this?
What's the problem?
I mean, may he rest in peace,
but this is free alcohol.
I talked to him.
No wonder he killed himself.
-Hi, how are you?
-Hi!
How's your face after
the ball hit?
That was your risky move?
Stopping the ball with your face
-is a risky move.
-Of course.
Did you go to the doctor?
It was hard...
No, I'm fine, thank you.
That was brave,
because it was really hard.
-Thank you.
-Happy anniversary to you!
Happy anniversary to you!
We all wish you...
It's a gift from your kids,
and they sent a note.
"So you remember this day...
forever".
-Sir.
-Sorry. Yes.
-Let's go.
-Yes.
I'm sorry...
I... Yes...
How long have you two
been together?
Too much.
OK...
we'll let you celebrate.
Congratulations!
There isn't much to celebrate.
Baby!
Baby, wait!
It was a joke, of course
there's plenty to celebrate.
-Like that old woman's ass?
-Old? She's so young.
Really, Alfredo?
On our anniversary?
You're right.
Maybe there's nothing
to celebrate.
We were going to make every day
better than the last.
We made good things...
I think we're
just fooling ourselves.
And there's only one solution
for this.
Divorce.
Really?
Is that what you want?
It's not that I want it!
We're hurting the kids.
Look at everything they did
so that we would stop fighting.
I'm sorry.
What do we do now?
Can you sleep on the couch?
Yes.
I'm married to
the hottest woman in Mexico!
And I to the nicest man
in the world!
At least someone
is having a good time.
Happy anniversary.
Same.
Happy anniversary!
What are you doing here?
Didn't you sleep on the couch?
When did I switch places?
-Hello?
-Happy anniversary!
-Good morning.
-How was the trip?
Majo, how's my son's foot?
Well, I'm just here
cleaning up your house
because it was really dirty.
I think your mom
has Alzheimer's.
-Hi, mommy.
-Alfredito.
My love.
Don't forget to put on
your sunblock, please.
Shit...!
♪ Here's your baby ♪
♪ Your bitch from the future ♪
♪ Hard, hard ♪
♪ Bitch from the future ♪
♪ Here's your baby ♪
♪ Your bitch from the future ♪
♪ Hard, hard ♪
♪ Bitch from the future ♪
-There's no water!
-No, there is.
-From four to five...
-And six to seven,
and the plumber,
you already said that.
And I told you
that you're scamming my kids,
because they spent
all their savings on this.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
Despite being
the honeymoon suite,
in 20 years
everything falls apart.
You're fine, tomorrow
you'll be good as new.
Ouch!
But you said
the same yesterday.
I don't remember it.
Let me see what I have.
Never mix bacanora
with eggnog and chiltepín.
It's to die for.
I'll make you
a cocktail of Meloxicam,
Celecoxib,
Parisiprodol,
and a bit of Tramadol
that will make you feel...
Wait...
Drop your pants, man!
Drop your pants!
Bend over!
One...
One daiquiri, please.
García, I can't believe it!
Good morning.
I sent you the sheet...
You haven't sent anything,
-you're so irresponsible!
-You don't have it yet?
That's weird,
I sent it yesterday.
-Come here!
-Lady, what happened?
-Sure.
-Don't let me down!
Say hi to everyone...
I can't leave the front desk.
I can't be under the sun,
my skin is very sensitive.
-Shit!
-Again, shit!
Who's that?
Mister Tolstoi.
Didn't he killed himself?
Lady, don't say that.
I work here.
Do you want me to take you
to the doctor?
The Russian is alive!
What? Didn't he kill himself
yesterday?
It's like I lived
all of this yesterday.
Hi, dad! What happened, dad?
Did my mom hit you?
Alfredito, look at your ears!
They're sunburnt!
Mom, why is my dad so pale?
-Kids, what day is today?
-What do you mean?
It's your anniversary.
Oh!
Happy anniversary to you!
You must've done something.
I did something?
Why do you always blame me?
Sorry, I'm used to it.
"Used to it."
Mmm...
-I know what to do.
-What?
We'll go to sleep,
and tomorrow
when we wake up,
-everything will be fine.
-Brilliant idea!
-Hello?
-Happy anniversary!
Uf!
Ladies and gentlemen
Again, it's not up to us.
Saguaro Airlines doesn't fly
every single day.
But if you want, I can book you
a flight tomorrow
to Mexico City
at 10 in the morning.
It has to be today.
I'm sorry, sir.
You don't know who I am!
Less apologies and more action!
This is insulting
to our rights as passengers.
I swear I'm not with this lady.
How are going to get
out of here?
-Let's relax.
-Relax?
Do you think someone will drop
from the sky
and come down to save us?
Tsst, tsst.
You need to get out of here?
So we're going to stop...
But chill.
It's 10,000 dollars.
We have...
-How much do you have?
-Yes, um...
-3000?
-Yes, and on the card
I have $17,600.
Withdraw in batches of 3000,
or the ATM
might swallow your card.
And... my ring.
I won't need it anymore.
It's pink coral
and it's hand made.
I don't think it'll be enough.
Please!
We just want to see
our kids again.
Fine...
come on!
Just because
I have a heart of gold.
Mm.
This is safe, right?
Of course! The safest.
Excuse me,
I think we should get off...
Alfredo, don't be afraid!
The pilot said it's safe!
And I believe him
but look at that...
What's wrong?
Why are you nervous?
-Is it the money?
-Yeah!
-It's my cousin's.
-Oh!
What does he do?
He's a farmer.
A farmer of what?
Stop, you're surrounded!
-Damn!
-"No name"
-and "Silver doll".
-I told you!
Shoot!
You don't have
permission to take off.
-Mom! I told you!
-Don't be a scaredy-cat!
Speed up!
Don't let them catch us.
You really are weird!
Did we lose them?
We did!
We're going down.
Plane going down!
We hit it, plane going down!
No!
-Hello?
-Happy...!
-Your mom.
-Did you hang up on her?
She won't remember it anyway.
Alfredo, we need to find
a solution for this.
We did the same yesterday
and see what happened.
I think we're cursed.
Yes...
there it is.
What did you see?
A tiny winged being.
Who winked?
A being with wings.
Fine.
We're cursed?
It's a spell that you
brought upon yourselves.
Can you help us?
You didn't listen to me
the last time,
how dare you come here
and ask for help?
Not even the toad
can help you.
Or maybe it will...
if you find it.
Help each other out.
It's not something
you're looking for.
It's something you find.
What did she mean?
Alfredo,
I don't think she knows.
I think we need
to go find the toad.
Do whatever you
want, I'm going with my kids.
When you can't find
a solution, find an exit.
-Oh!
-Ouch! Ouch!
How long does the bus take?
Emm, not much,
about two days.
One day by car.
But the roads are dangerous.
It's rabbits mating season
and they're everywhere.
Huh.
Are you stealing my meds?
-No.
-OK.
Do you have a car?
-Yes, but it's the hotel's.
-Give me the keys.
-Excuse me?
-Give me the keys!
-Miss, I can't...
-Give it!
-I can't!
-Give them to me!
Please?
It's a black...
Jeep.
"The alvarius toad has been
considered a magical being
with great powers
for many centuries".
No, move away!
No, please, no!
No! No!
No!
Let me go! Let me go!
No, no, no...
No!
Hi, dad!
What happened, dad?
Did my mom hit you?
Fine...
Just because I have
a heart of gold.
Hey...
Have you considered
another means of transport?
Because the airplane
is too flashy.
-Is the engine broken?
-What happened?
The engine is broken?
How are going to get back?
For real?
Hey, where are you going?
Hi, dad!
What happened, dad?
Did my mom hit you?
I fell asleep under the sun.
And what happened to you, mom?
Baby, if I tell you,
you won't believe it.
Alfredito, look at your ears!
They're sunburnt!
Yes, mommy.
Is the hotel
the same as your remembered it?
-Let me see!
-Hey!
This girl can't stay still.
Nina, do that again.
Ouch!
Do you remember what you said
when we were getting on the cab?
-No.
-That we shouldn't get back
until we loved each other again.
That's it.
-That's it!
-Yes!
That's it.
What was that?
HOME
Good morning, beautiful baby.
How's the love of my life?
I'm great, my love!
-Hello?
-Happy anniversary!
Thank you!
-How was the trip?
-It was wonderful!
You know how much
I enjoy being with your son
and how much I love him.
Majo, are you feeling well?
Don't over do it.
Are you sure of this, my love?
Baby, of course!
I always do it.
And I can go through anything
with you by my side.
That's so cute!
Really cute! One...
Fuc...!
See? We all have
a reason to live for.
You just have to find yours.
Love will save the world.
Damn Russian,
you're really buffed.
Can you put sunblock on me,
my dear?
Of course, darling!
-García!
-Hi, ma'am, good morning.
You're so irresponsible!
You said you'd send me...
I'm with my wife and my only job
is to make her happy.
-Bye.
-García!
That was so sweet of you!
It's sweet you find it sweet!
Sorry,
that almost hit you, right?
Hey, be careful,
you almost hit my wife.
Sorry.
I'm sorry!
Look, Nina...
See how mommy and daddy
love each other!
Look.
-Ew, yuck!
-You're weird!
We're in love.
-What was that?
-It was Cupid, honey.
-Yeah.
Happy anniversary!
How long have you been together?
Twenty years.
But they'll never be enough.
Never enough!
Hey...
-What if we try?
-No.
Sure?
-Maybe it works.
-What...?
Baby, this has been one
of the happiest days
of my life but...
I'm so tired,
you understand, right?
Of course, my dear.
I'll always understand you.
Well...
Good night, my love.
-I love you so much, my dear!
-I love you too.
HOME
-Hello?
-Happy...
anniversary!
-See? I told you.
-What?
What do you mean what?
We had to...
Do you think that'll help?
In memory of Mister Tolstoi...
vodka on the house!
-Oh!
Cheers!
More!
No, I'll be on top.
Oh! Oh, God! OK.
-No, wait.
-Now what?
-Wait.
-What is it?
-Wait just a little.
-What happened?
Alfredo junior is distracted.
You know what? No.
Not this.
I'm done!
We'll take this seriously.
Yes.
-Oh!
-Baby, you're bleeding!
-I don't care, kiss me!
-OK.
Alfredo, I'm getting wet.
-Good. It was about time.
-No! It's water!
Make it stop!
Oh!
María José?
Why!
-Cover it!
-I hate it!
Come on, it's not a big deal.
It is a big deal.
For a man this is
a very tough thing.
Not tough enough.
Sorry.
Happy anniversary to you!
Hard, hard
Bitch from the future
Here's your baby
Drop your pants!
Please try to not die today.
You have no shame.
I gave you the best speech
and you still killed yourself.
-Hello?
-Happy anniversary!
I give up.
What do we do?
Why don't we just relax,
take a few days,
take it easy and let it flow?
I don't understand.
What do you mean?
I've been working nonstop
for 20 years,
we're on the beach,
we don't have to go back home,
it's any working man's fantasy!
Plus when I relax,
I have the best ideas.
A 40% tip.
Thanks you crazy bastard!
Whatever you need
whenever you're here.
García! You haven't sent...
I can't hear you!
There's... And...
Can you hear me?
Sorry, it almost hit you.
Don't worry about it.
I have good reflexes.
Hey!
Thank you!
Oh!
I'm sorry, Russian, you must've
died a lot of times.
I can imagine.
Thank you.
You're not ugly, Russian.
Screw it!
I'll give you something
to live for.
What's your name?
Yes, I'm María José Márquez,
you're Tolstoi what?
Oh my God!
This one...
This is the first time I...
No, wait!
Wait, it's just that
I haven't done this in a while,
not even with my husband!
So, I need like...
to prepare a little bit more,
because if you and I
knew each other a bit more
I'd be more relaxed,
because I'm really tense!
And I don't...
Wait!
Damn Russian!
This is Jorgito,
as handsome as his dad.
I just need to know
who his dad is.
This is Desy, my teenager.
Here she was in a good mood,
although her face says
otherwise.
And my princess Nina.
The apple of my eye.
The most beautiful thing
in my life.
Do you always talk this nice
about the people you love?
Yes.
No, sorry...
-I can't.
-Sorry.
Will your mom
support her too?
Baby...
-Listen, please.
-No! Don't even think about it!
I don't care
if you sleep with her.
I almost did it with the Russian
before he killed himself again.
What?
You forgot about the call
with the kids.
If you want to get out of here,
don't do it for me,
at least do it for them.
Alfredo, I'm sorry
for blaming you for everything.
We are both responsible.
It hasn't been easy to leave
my job to take care of the kids.
I liked my job.
I didn't ask you
to leave your job.
You didn't ask me
to keep it either.
Actually, you're lucky.
I'd love to stay all day
at home with the kids.
I don't like what we are now.
Me neither.
What do we do?
Keep trying.
-Hello?
-Happy anniversary!
Ma'am, don't wear my clothes.
I study Russian.
Nice and up.
Yei!
Drop your pants, man!
Ready?
Ready!
Hi, dad!
Happy anniversary to you!
One, two, three.
To know the world...
Come on!
To know the world
and everything in it.
Are you OK?
Are you talking to me?
Yes, are you OK?
Yes, everything's fine. Thanks.
A few things here and there,
nothing major.
Everything's fine,
thanks for asking.
Yes, all good.
This way, please.
Don't worry.
That rat is dead. Relax.
This way, please.
This is the problem.
They were supposed to send
some Japanese electricians.
But they haven't arrived,
I'm not sure why.
Damn, it looks hard.
What? Don't say that.
I told your wife I'd fix it.
And with all due respect,
I'm scared of her.
I don't blame you.
But deep down
she's a good person.
You know what?
I can help you.
Do you know about this?
I took a class once
in high school.
I built a little machine.
So I think I can do it.
Yes.
Yes...
Where is the library?
Thank you!
-Wanna play?
-I don't know how to play.
You don't have to, just come!
Come on!
The soup is cold.
♪ Here's your baby ♪
♪ Your bitch from the future ♪
♪ Hard, hard ♪
♪ Bitch from the future ♪
♪ Here's your baby ♪
♪ Your bitch from the future ♪
Doctor Orozco...
-I didn't know you were a man.
-Good morning.
Drink this.
-Have we met?
-You could say so.
-Damn...
-That's what happens
when you mix
bacanora, eggnog and chiltepín.
It's to die for.
Doctor Orozco...
have you thought about
learning how to give shots?
Now that you say so...
I've always wanted to have
a wave runner,
to get girls.
And then?
That's it!
We're not going to win.
What do you mean?
Let's go! Come here!
When I was manager in...
It doesn't matter.
Listen up. We are going to make
a plan to beat them.
The best ones
in the best positions.
Everyone else,
stay out of the way.
Elizabeth, go to the back left.
Be careful with
the one in the green bikini,
because you know how she likes
to score next to the net.
If we do this together,
we'll win!
Less apologies and more action!
Come on!
"The Japanese are the best".
This is easier than I thought.
This is very interesting.
♪ Hard, hard ♪
♪ Bitch from the future ♪
♪ Here's your baby ♪
♪ Your bitch from the future ♪
Centennial, come here.
Have you ever listened to
the Rolling Stones?
The Beatles?
Or Juan Gabriel?
This is good music.
Mom, stranger danger!
Ouch!
Come on.
Yes!
Huh. Done.
The problem
with the light is solved.
How did you do it?
Less apologies and more action.
-García!
-Good morning.
-Why haven't you sent...?
-Right, your balance.
You know what?
I won't send it.
-What?
-Wanna know why?
Because I don't want to.
García, you're so rude!
-Ma'am, don't get upset.
-A terrible employee...
It's bad for your health.
And the next time you want
coffee, go get it yourself.
-García!
-Walking helps varicose veins.
-You're insulting me!
-See you, good day.
What did you just do?
I think I quit.
-No!
-Calm down.
I didn't like my job anyway.
Oh!
And I think you
don't like yours either.
Yes and no.
I studied Tourism in Mexico City
because I wanted to get
to know the world.
But I've been stuck in
this hotel for 10 years now.
I don't have the attitude
nor the money to do it.
Yes...
-You know what?
-What?
If you really want it,
you can do it.
You think?
Let's go check
the water problem.
Yes, sorry.
And that trophy?
We won
the volleyball tournament.
The hot tub is working!
And the AC.
And we have hot water.
And you bought new jeans.
Who are you and what
did you do with my husband?
Come here.
How much was this?
Very expensive.
-Alfredo...
-What?
We don't have to pay
anything else.
Cheers, baby.
I remembered something.
I like managing people.
The truth is you've always
been good at it.
The only thing I can't do
is saving the Russian.
I have a plan,
although I'm not sure.
You speak Russian?
I want to tell you
that the world is a bear.
The soup is cold.
There are
many reasons for living.
What did you say?
Something huge.
I was in love...
and she broke my heart
and now I can't keep living
anymore.
What did he say?
-Something about the heart.
-Is he sick?
I'd never seen such beauty.
Marry?
Marry...
I think he likes you.
I told you we kissed,
but it was nothing.
Damn Russian,
you're in love with your ex
but you kissed my wife.
You're one to talk!
You kissed Carmen.
I'm sorry but I didn't kiss her,
she kissed me.
But you didn't move away,
you could have.
-María José, when you arrived...
-She was there...
You didn't see that she...
The Russian!
I got you!
I got you! I got you!
It's slipping.
Damn Russian,
you're too heavy!
-Don't let go!
-No!
No!
Too bad,
we'll try again tomorrow.
-What?
-What happened?
Did he die?
-Yes.
-What about me?
You too,
but you're alive now.
Ah...!
Answer.
Hello?
Yes, mommy,
I'm wearing sunblock.
No, mommy,
I don't miss you because
I feel like we've talked
for the past 100 days.
What are you doing today?
I'm fixing the light,
the water,
and the hot tub.
It'll take me like half an hour.
And you?
There's one thing I want to do.
A silly thing.
Look, we know it's not easy.
And that you do it
to help out your families.
Because you just said
that your heart is good,
but have you ever considered
that there are better ways
to do it?
He's right.
-He's right.
-He is?
Let's give them the money.
Why don't we just give them
the money?
And you...
Less apologies and more action.
MANAGEMENT
IGNACIO, TO KNOW THE WORLD
AND EVERYTHING IN IT
Carmen!
I know you've
always wanted this,
how would you like to be
the new manager?
Are you kidding?
No, I'm serious! Really!
And that was the exact moment
when I couldn't help but wonder,
do women really want
some prince charming?
What for?
Or do we actually want someone
who makes us feel...
enormous!
I HOPE YOU LIKE IT
SEE YOU AT 7 P.M.
-Hi.
For my favorite guests.
Who are these from?
Cheers!
-Have fun.
-Thanks.
Cheers.
I love you.
Hi.
How are you?
Bravo!
Let's go dance.
They really are a cute couple,
right, Bicho?
Yes, you look so in love.
Thank you so much.
How long
have you been together?
Twenty years.
Plus two dating.
Twenty years, Bicho,
we can make it.
Of course we can, my Bicha.
How do you do...?
We keep surprising each other.
Bicho, surprise me!
I'll surprise you
my whole life, Bicha.
Hey, girl, that's a good song.
You know what, Alfredo?
I think
we're fooling ourselves.
What do you mean?
I want you to make love
to me right now.
Here?
People can see us.
OK.
They'll cheer us on.
I'm a little sore, that's weird.
My foot no longer hurts.
I'm sore.
And my foot is OK?
My foot no longer hurts.
Hello?
Hi!
Hi...
Nina, baby,
where's your grandma?
She's asleep.
I touched her last night
with my magic wand
and she watched
The Fire Lieutenant.
I'm sore.
My foot no longer hurts.
HAPPY ANNIVERSARY
Dad, the accountant called.
Go get your
final paycheck on Monday.
Damn, dad...
I think you got fired.
I can work.
And I can stay here
and take care of the children.
And I can go home
because it's getting late.
-Good night.
-Bye, mom.
Thanks!
Who
will help me with my things?
I will!
My bag, my suitcase.
Hey...
I want a brother.
UNHAPPILY EVER AFTER