[Music]
[No audible dialogue]
[Screaming]
REDD INC.
(Reporter) A scene
Of grisly murder.
It appears that the headhunter serial
Killer has finally been caught.
Thomas Reddmann
Was arrested earlier today
For the murder of Bloom incorporated
High flying public relations guru
(Anchorwoman) The Headhunter is
Responsible for the vicious axe murders
Of six corporate heads,
Decapitating all of his victims.
You’re favorite
Serial killer and mine
Is found guilty
Or not guilty.
I'm humbled that my psychic
Gifts were able to help lead
To the arrest
And conviction.
(Woman) My father worked
Very hard to get to the top.
He didn't deserve
To die like that.
I hope he rots in jail!
(Man)
This is a good outcome.
Thomas Reddmann
Will be incarcerated
For the rest
Of his natural life
At the Lansdale Clinic.
(Doctor) Mr. Reddmann
Is very sick.
Under the guidance
Of Doctor Lansdale,
We know we can
Make a difference.
(Man) In an escape attempt last
Night at the Lansdale Clinic,
A fire broke out which took the
Life of inmate Thomas Reddmann.
The circumstances of the
Escape attempt remain unclear.
However, it appears that
Reddmann was viciously attacked.
The good news is Thomas
Reddmann, the headhunter,
Is dead.
So, you did well
In high school,
Dropped out of college
And have what,
At best, can be described
As sporadic job history.
There's nothing here that
Suggests you would be an asset
To Fulber Incorporated.
At all.
I'm-I'm really just--
I'm just looking
For a chance, you know?
I just can’t see this
Working out Annabelle.
We have your
Details on file.
We'll be in touch
If circumstances change.
No, you won't.
[Beeping]
[Scottish accent]
Annabelle, its Les.
Listen, your private show
Numbers are a disgrace.
You're a Bullet Girl, honey. Try
And act like it. This is your job.
Your titty little
Tease act is cute,
But I expect your numbers to go up,
Otherwise I'm gonna have to let you go.
Hello.
You wanna see these'?
Do you like that'?
Do you enjoy?
What you do?
Of course.
Can't you tell'?
But do you feel you're achieve
Something with this job?
Oh, this is no
Boring old job, baby.
Where do you see yourself?
In five years time?
I'm-I'm sorry, what'?
Would you like the opportunity?
To right a terrible wrong?
I don't even know
What that means.
I'm out.
I've got
A job for you.
Later, weirdo.
So many douche bags.
[Exhales]
[Shouts]
You've got the job.
What's this'?
What the fuck is this'?
(Man)
Hey,
You awake?
Listen, don't get
The wrong idea.
I'm trapped, too.
Who are you'?
[Machine whirs]
What'?
[Whispers]
Can somebody tell me?
What the fuck is going on'?
I don’t know.
But it's not good!
We have to get out.
We have to.
Stop it.
Stop it, all of you.
Hey, stop it!
We're all connected
To... to something?
We're just gonna hurt
Ourselves more.
[Man shouting in pain]
[Shouting continues]
Let's try the desks.
One, two, three.
[Gasps]
He got you.
He got all of you.
[Laughs]
He's dead.
[Whispers]
And so are we.
We're dead.
We're all dead.
We're already dead.
Gotta get
Back to work.
Gotta get the pages done.
Can't miss a deadline.
Guy.
Guy Marr.
Jesus, it is him.
He's been missing
For over a month.
We were all
In court together.
The Reddmann
Headhunter homicides.
I arrested
Thomas Reddmann.
I led the defense team.
I assisted the police
With their investigations.
You're Sheena, right'?
The psychic.
And who are you'?
You're the psychic.
Shouldn't you know that'?
I was an eyewitness.
And I was
An eyewitness, too.
The Internet stripper.
How could I forget'?
And that man
Led the prosecution.
[Man shouting]
[Door slams]
[Typing]
[Gasps]
Oh, shit. Oh, shit, it can't be.
Drink.
Please.
Some office rules.
Three toilets
Breaks a day.
Two social breaks.
Finish all
Meals provided.
Complete all tasks.
You will begin by transcribing
These legal manuals.
Start at page one,
And don't stop
Until I tell you.
My name is Redd.
I'm your new boss.
[Door closes]
I identified his body.
So, how is he?
Still alive?
[Typing]
I can't do this.
Why'?
I don't have my glasses.
I can't see without them.
I get headaches.
Just do something.
Show him you're
Doing something.
That looks
Really painful.
It's not that bad.
I can't believe we're
Stuck in a cube farm.
Cube farm'?
An office job.
I have been avoiding them
For so long, and now.
[All typing]
We'll be okay.
Really?
I have no idea.
It just seemed like the
Right thing to say.
Shit.
Come on, this is crazy.
He's just fucking with us.
No.
He's breaking us.
[Door slams]
Looks like you're
The big winner.
Incentive.
You can stop for now.
Start again first
Thing in the morning.
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh.
I didn't say
You could start.
If you obey the rules, tomorrow
You’ll have some food.
Fuck you!
Really?
I'm sorry, Redd.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, please.
I'm.
[Groans]
Mr. Marr
Should know by now
That I run
A tight ship here.
I am firm,
But fair.
Isn't that right, Guy'?
Firm but fair.
Sorry, Redd.
Sorry, boss.
Now, what the rest
Of you need to understand
Is that with every
Act of insubordination.
Comes a warning.
I'm sorry, Redd!
[Groans]
After the fifth warning,
I review the employee's
Ongoing value to my company.
Please. And that
Was number five.
Please, Redd, please!
Please!
[Women shout]
Right.
[Shouts]
Stop!
[Crying]
Please, stop!
And how did
You do today'?
Let's take a look
At your work.
I don't have my glasses. I can't
See properly without them.
Really?
Yeah.
No glasses'?
Just a moment.
[Crying]
Try those.
Come along.
Better'?
Better, thank you.
No excuses then.
You've got a lot
Of catching up to do.
[Cutting]
Toilet break time.
Five minutes.
I'll be waiting.
[Exhales]
[Crying]
Oh, for fuck's
Sake, Hale.
Keep it together.
[Whispers]
Hello?
Is anybody there'?
[Knocking on Door]
Shit!
Time's up!
[Knocking]
I said time's up.
I'm ready.
[Keys clinking]
You took your time.
[Groaning]
That's your first warning.
It's nothing personal,
You understand.
What's down there'?
Any sign
Of where we are'?
You must have
Seen something.
Anything at all'?
[Yelling]
Oh, holy shit.
Bad dream?
Yeah.
Oh. Bad everything.
I thought this place
Was a nightmare.
This place
Is a nightmare.
I don't need to go
To the bathroom.
[No audible voice]
You are the same
Annabelle Hale
Who was a witness at the
Thomas Reddmann trials.
Yes.
You said,
"I saw Thomas Reddmann
Holding the axe.
"He was covered in blood.
Shelly Bloom's body
Was on the elevator floor."
That's right.
That's what I said.
Decapitated.
I misspoke.
You said, "The decapitated body
Was on the elevator floor.
Correct?
Hm. You also admitted
That you did not see
The killing blow.
Your words.
You did not see me
Actually use the axe.
No, I-l didn't.
Well then.
That will be your task.
That's your job, Annabelle.
To find
The real killer.
Because I'm
Telling you now,
I am not the headhunter.
[Door closes]
Mr. DeMeyeFs body was slumped
Against the conference room table.
His head had rolled
To the other side.
I heard a wheezing behind me.
And when I turned around,
there wasn't anyone there.
I..I walked in
And Mr. Ketc...
Was sitting there,
And I called the police.
Edward.
I don't even know what I'm
Supposed to be looking for here.
If we were really
Investigating a case,
We’d be looking for patterns
And inconsistencies.
But we're not
Working a case here.
The killer is in that
Office right there.
What we need to do
Is look busy,
And stay alive.
Thanks.
Patterns
And inconsistencies.
[Man shouting in pain]
(Redd) Rules are made
To be followed, Marcus!
(Marcus) Please! No, no, no, no!
You don’t follow them,
You know what happens!
Please! No!
[Whispers]
Who's Marcus?
Wait a second.
Marcus Conlon.
The judge in this case.
He's been missing
For months.
Why would he
Wanna hurt Conlon?
The dude sent him
To the Lansdale Clinic.
Padded walls and all the
Barbiturates you can swallow.
It's basically a medicated hotel.
No, it isn't.
The Lansdale Clinic,
The part you can see
Is exactly as Annabelle says.
But Lansdale,
[Marcus shouting]
He has certain ideas
About the criminal mind.
Certain procedures,
Chemical and surgical
That aren't
Strictly legal.
And the results?
They vary.
Surgical?
[Whispers] He's got
Scars on his head.
Did you notice?
That when Guy stabbed him,
He didn't even flinch?
Yeah.
He can't feel any pain.
Whoever Thomas Reddmann was
Before the Lansdale Clinic,
That person is gone.
We need to talk to him.
We need to make him see sense.
No, Sheena, I don't think
That’s a good idea.
[Door bangs]
Shit.
Hello, workers.
You know what you're
Doing here is wrong.
Don’t you, Thomas?
Can I call you Thomas?
You know my name.
Sheena Oleary.
We're all people.
We all have friends
And family, just like you.
[Scoffs]
Like me'?
You're not a bad man.
You don't really
Want to hurt people.
That man'?
In the other room'?
You don’t want
To hurt him either.
Perhaps I do.
Perhaps said person
Has earned a lot of pain.
I think that we should
Get back to work.
What about Guy'?
What about his
Friends, his family?
[Broken voice]
His children?
You say you're innocent, but you
Killed a man, for God's sake.
Calm down.
You're disrupting
Your co-workers.
Sheena, Redd's right.
You are a murderer!
I said calm down!
[Groans]
[Grunts]
This is no way
To start the day!
Let's get this clear.
I am not a murderer.
I am a Regional Manager.
Find the real
Killer today,
You go home today.
Take six months and you'll
Be here for six months.
Remembering that for
Every second you waste
A vicious murderer
Will be walking about
Enjoying the freedom
You’re currently not.
For God's sake!
That went well.
No, no, really. It was
A really good idea.
Some of you could
Have backed me up.
If we all appeal to him,
He might let us go.
[Blows]
I know how he did it.
Did what'?
How Redd faked
His own death.
It wasn't his burnt remains
At Lansdale fire.
It was someone else.
He must have severed
His own left arm
Knowing it was all we could
Use for DNA analysis.
It was a setup.
So, he escaped
With another patient
And used him
As dead meat'?
Chopped off his own arm'?
I told you. The Lansdale
Clinic changes people.
Oh, fuck!
Jesus, William,
Are you okay?
(Redd)
William.
Is there a problem
I can help you with'?
Hmm'?
Hmm.
It's fine. It's just
A little splinter.
Mmm, yes, they start small.
But the infection
Can spread.
You don't want that.
Ha!
Found them.
It's in deep.
[Groans]
There.
[Groaning]
Got it.
There.
Right.
Now, just remove
The fingernail.
No, don’t look at them.
They can’t stop infection.
Do it.
Now, get back to work.
And remember.
My Door
Is always open.
Oh, fuck, William.
(Shelly) They need to get out more.
Get a little style.
It's a quagmire of bad ties and
Cheap cologne around here.
Anyway, I'm heading
To the airport now.
So, you know what you
Have to do, so do it.
Why are we stopping here?
There isn't even any--
[Whizzing]
[Voice-mail voice]
End of messages.
[Whizzing] Why are
We stopping here?
There isn't even any--
[Whizzing]
End of messages.
(William) You making
Any progress?
No, not really.
You?
[Man shouting in pain]
(Redd) That’ll teach
You to be civil.
[Shouting continues]
I'd like to smell
Her hair one last time.
My wife.
Her hair smelt great.
[Shouting continues]
I hope someone's
Feeding my dogs.
What are their names?
Reasonable and Doubt.
I regret
Not getting back
In contact with my mom.
It's been years.
We didn't get along.
[Shouting continues]
You know what
I really regret?
I didn't get to tell my stupid
Boss to shove his job up his ass.
I honestly thought
I had the boss from hell.
[Whispers] I think that
There’s a way out.
The women's bathroom. There's a
Gate that could lead outside.
Can you open it'?
No, but I'm trying.
[Door bangs]
Shh.
[Door closes]
Does anyone else have a
Funny taste in their mouth?
Yeah, like a...
Like a chemical taste.
We're being drugged.
Do you think he's gonna do
Something while we’re asleep?
We have to stay awake
No matter what.
[Clanking]
[Spraying]
[Keys clinking]
[Machine whirring]
I'm glad we don't have
To look at him anymore.
You can always
Channel him later.
Let's just keep
Focused and stay alive.
There's no reasoning with him.
He's a psycho.
As opposed
To a psychic, right'?
(Edward)
We should get to work.
As long as we continue with our
Tasks, we buy ourselves time.
[Knocking on Door]
[Groans]
This isn't
A guessing game.
Times and dates,
Detective.
Neatness.
Punctuality.
Accuracy.
Facts.
[Shouts]
At this rate we'll all
Be dead in two days.
Sheena, have you
Found anything yet'?
Let's just say it's...not the
Ideal working environment.
(Rudy) You mean for
Someone like you.
For any of us.
What number
Did I just type'?
I'm not getting into a
Guessing game with you.
That's all you do.
You just guess and you
Hope you get lucky.
I'm not having this
Conversation with you.
Well, then talk to me.
I'm not sure that I
Believe in what you do.
But if you can get
A message to someone,
Then you need to
Do that, like now.
Are you fucking serious?
(William) You got
Any better ideas?
I mean, it can't hurt.
Right?
I think that
You should try.
Please, try.
Okay.
[Door opens]
(Redd)
The truth.
So easy to grasp,
Yet so hard
To hold onto.
Some people are
Naturally skeptics.
It's part of their job
To question everything.
Many are too easily convinced
By what they see and hear.
Seeing believes.
Others view the truth as
An accumulation of facts.
Evidence
Which cannot be denied?
And then
There are those
Who view the truth?
As a piece of clay
To be worked.
An art form.
Another way to lie.
Sheena O'Leary.
A renowned
Psychic and medium.
She recently
Helped the police
On the headhunter
Homicides case.
One could ask
Why you chose
To lend your powers
To this particular case.
I've assisted
The police on many cases.
You did very well out of this
One, though, didn't you'?
Really made
A name for yourself.
You helped identify
The big, bad headhunter.
Had nearly
Everyone convinced.
My gift is often
Misunderstood.
Gift'?
You call it a gift?
That's interesting because,
And correct me if I'm wrong,
But a gift is something
Normally given for free,
And you, you charge $5.95
A minute for your gift.
You claim
You can see
Into the future.
Correct?
I can.
At times.
But you didn't see this
Coming up, did you'?
[Yells]
[Whimpers]
You can't see
Anything, can you'?
Can you'?
No.
You won't be
Needing these then.
[Yelling]
[Yelling continues]
Wasn't so hard, was it'?
[Yelling]
No! Redd,
She’s suffered enough!
No!
Now she's suffered enough.
[Crying]
[Sobs]
[Opens drawer]
[Closes drawer]
Right.
Get back to work.
[Door closes]
(Annabelle) We 're all
Gonna die in here.
[Crying]
Like that.
We're all gonna
Die in here.
[Crying]
We're all gonna die!
[Clanking]
[Machine whirring]
[Door opens]
What a messy
Girl she was.
You, uh,
You want me...
Yes, Mr. Tucker.
Spick and span.
Okay.
[Trembling voice]
This job sucks.
Good job, Mr. Tucker.
Most impressive.
I'm just happy
You’re happy.
That's the attitude.
If only that attitude were more
Evident in your other work.
In fact, I'm afraid I have to
Express extreme dissatisfaction
With the work of the
Group as a whole.
A company which
Does not get results
Cannot sustain itself.
And a company which
Cannot sustain itself,
Has to start reevaluating
Its workers' positions.
It's time for
A performance review.
Right.
What I want is for you to
Think back on that day.
The day you saw me.
Why were you
At the building?
I'd been out drinking
The night before.
I was hungover and I was
Late for a job interview.
[Elevator bell]
You say I was grinning.
That's how I remember it.
And then I heard
Someone screaming,
And I realized
It was me.
I had to get a delivery to
A small publishing house.
I remember
Seeing this girl
Who looked?
Out of place.
Who I now know
As Annabelle.
And then the elevator
Doors opened.
[Screaming]
You looked terrified.
Like you were in shock.
I'd been tracking the
Headhunter for months.
I was pretty sure I knew where
And when his next kill would be.
I just didn't know
Who it'd be.
I entered the lobby
And there you were.
I told you to put
The axe down.
After a moment
You complied,
So I decided to use
Non-lethal force.
I took you
Into custody.
I did my best to have
You acquitted, Redd.
Rest assured of that.
Did you really?
The prosecution's evidence,
It was overwhelming!
Guy Marr and the police asserted
That I decapitated Ms. Shelly Bloom
In the lift.
Correct?
Correct.
And nobody saw
The actual killing
Because the lift's camera was out.
Also correct?
Yes.
I think you missed
A key piece of evidence.
Are you aware that the lift in
Question was custom built'?
No.
But you are aware
Of Miloan brand elevators?
This black line
Is the height of the
Miloan brand elevator.
But this red line
Is the highest point
In the custom-built
Elevator.
Our elevator.
Okay.
Do you know how much pressure one
Has to use to decapitate a person?
No. No, I don't.
Because when
The masked murderer
Decapitated
Ms. Shelly Bloom,
The prosecution asserted
That he used his axe.
Like a guillotine to sever
Skin, sinew and bone
By using an extraordinary
Amount of force.
Like this.
No, no, no,
Redd, please.
[Shouting]
[Hinges squeak]
[Door closes]
Thank God.
What happened in there'?
Are you okay'?
Who's Peter Bava?
What?
There's an
Inconsistency here.
Peter Bava.
He's listed as an alibi witness but
His statement was never taken.
Maybe it got lost.
That's what I thought, too, but the
Statement is listed as evidence
And the documents been removed.
Edward.
Do you know?
Peter Bava'?
Hang on, this is. This is your
Signature at the bottom, right'?
Edward.
Is that your signature?
It looks like it, but.
Well, it either is
Or it isn't.
What are you hiding?
Nothing.
This was all
Along time ago.
Do you know how many cases?
I've worked since then'?
Why should I care about?
Any other case but this'?
(Rudy) Redd could’nt have
Killed Shelly Bloom.
What'?
No, no, no,
I'm not saying that.
I just. I wanna know
Who Peter Bava is.
No.
He didn't have enough
Room to swing the axe.
(Annabelle)
Edward.
What are you hiding?
After I arrested
Thomas Reddmann,
The media
Was all over me.
Detective Crandell
Catches the headhunter.
But Reddmann
Was so calm.
He had total faith
In the system.
He had weak alibis
For all the other murders.
He was always at work.
And when he wasn't in the office,
He was nowhere he could prove.
But the second
Killing, he.
He had an alibi
For the second.
The headhunter killing
Of October 14th.
Redd was firing
An employee
For having
A bad attitude.
That employee was a man by
The name of...Peter Bava.
I asked him
If he was certain
That the date he was
Fired on was the 14th.
And he said,
Yeah, man,
Check it out.
He gave me a letter
Of termination.
Seriously.
I framed it.
The day they fired me
From this place,
That was the greatest
Day of my life.
Come on, Peter.
That guy was fucked up.
Any detective that
Works the streets
Knows that if you've got 80% percent of
The evidence, you can find the other 20%.
Well, I had 80% of the evidence.
More, even.
I kept telling myself we had the
Right guy until Peter Bava.
But I've always
Known there's
A special place in hell
For me for what I did.
Then I got shot on the job
And I ended up in this chair.
It felt like
I'd paid the price.
So, we're all here
Because of you.
(William) Because you
Are incompetent
Or just because
You’re corrupt?
Oh, now you're
Calling me corrupt?
You withheld evidence.
I'm no expert, but that sounds
An awful lot like corruption.
It was just
One witness.
I only withheld
It's all so fucking
Easy to judge now.
But At the time there was
So much pressure on me,
I had to make
An arrest.
Oh, fuck me.
Edward.
Is there something
You want to tell me'?
Redd.
We can talk
About this.
With this new evidence,
I could get you a retrial.
But it's not
New evidence, is it'?
It's evidence which was
Deliberately withheld by you.
Please.
Oh. Ah!
Oh!
[Cutting sound]
What is this'?
What are you doing?
Shh.
[Panting]
Oh, is that--
Is that my blood?
Shh.
[Panting]
Is that my leg'?
Is that my fucking leg'?
[Edward shouting]
So, what's the verdict?
Judge Conlon'?
One leg or two'?
No! Please!
[Shouting]
No!
[Door bangs]
Yes.
[Knocking on Door]
Redd.
Why aren't you asleep?
I...I was.
I need to go
To the bathroom.
You people need to learn
Some self-respect.
I really.
I really need to go.
It's always something.
Five minutes.
Okay.
Let's do this.
Times up.
Shit.
[Gasps]
[Clanking]
Shit.
[Whispers]
Oh, my God.
[Grunts]
[Gasps]
No!
You're not meant
to die!
You're meant to suffer.
Haven't you
tortured him enough?
You just don't
get it, do you'?
I'm an innocent man!
All you people
had to do was your jobs!
Pay a bit of attention
when you're an eyewitness.
Do a bit of research when
you're defending someone.
Don't hide the evidence!
If you folks
had done that,
you wouldn’t be here!
[Groans]
Ah!
[Gasps]
[Saw whirs]
I'm out!
I'm fuckin' out!
Wake up!
Hey, hey, hey! Wake up.
Wake up. Wake up.
Wake up!
Wake the fuck up!
Yes! We're getting
out of here.
What'? We're getting
Where's Redd?
He's knocked out in HR.
Wake up! It's okay. I'm awake.
It's okay.
Thanks.
Oh, for fuck's
sake, come on!
Okay.
Well,
get back to work!
Just bring
fucking everybody.
I'm gonna leave
the phone off the hook.
They're coming.
[Bang]
We need weapons.
Yeah.
Are we really gonna kill
this guy with stationery?
We're gonna try.
[Banging]
[Whispers]
Where is he'?
I don't know.
Fuck.
Run!
(William)
There.
Run, run,
run, run!
He's heading for us.
Guilty.
I was an innocent man.
Then Dr. Lansdale
turns me into this.
Tell me, Miss Hale.
In my position,
what would you do'?
You're right, Redd.
It's not fair
what happened to you.
All I wanted was for
People to do their jobs.
Do what they
Signed up to do.
Except we didn't sign up for this.
None of us did.
So, you can take
Your fucking job
And shove it
Up your ass!
Oh, fuck!
I'll hold him off. Go!
Don't you come?
Any closer.
What about Rudy?
He's as good as dead.
[Whizzing]
Oh, my God.
Oh, shit.
What a waste.
I'm afraid I'm going
To have to let you go.
Annabelle.
You've got to understand.
This is nothing personal.
I mean, when you think about it,
Am I really the bad guy here?
I get rid of corrupt CEOs and I'm
In the wrong. I mean, really?
I make the world
A better place
One head at a time.
You know the plan for Bloom was no
More complicated than the usual.
You just wait for the corporate
Bitch to get on the elevator,
And then you catch her
On the next level down.
And that is
When things turn ugly.
Why are we stopping here'?
There isn't even.
Redd had to fuck
Everything up
By being on the exact
Same elevator.
[Siren blares]
Sometimes you learn
To improvise.
Getting away
Was the easy part.
[Screaming]
In a weird way, we do have
A lot to thank Redd for.
He did introduce us
To each other.
It's a shame office romances
Rarely work out, huh'?
[Groans]
[Sirens blaring]
[Shouts in pain]
(officer)
Put your hands up!
Put your hands
In the air!
Put your hands up!
Get on the ground!
Get on the ground now. Put your hands
Up and get on the fucking ground.
Get down now!
[Mixed voices]
(woman) Her BP's spiking
Off the charts.
It's okay,
I've got it.
And she's out.
Good.
Did you see that?
Back there'?
Yeah, I wish I hadn't.
There were bodies
Everywhere.
Did it make you horny?
No.
But it made me want
To get back to work!
[Gasps]
[Alarm clock beeping]
[Exhales]
[Beep]
Annabelle.
Ready for tonight?
I must be the best
Agent in the world.
They're all gonna be looking
At me and judging me.
I don't know
If I'm up for it.
Sweetheart, it's not
Gonna look good.
You've got to get out of your
Apartment and face this eventually.
I know.
[Grunts]
I'll call you later.
Get dressed.
I'm coming over.
Okay.
You can do this
Because you are
One tough bitch.
[Buzzer]
Hello'?
It's me, darling.
Come on up.
Hi. Lock the Door! Lock
And close the Door!
Sorry, love--
Look what
You made me do.
Oh, poor Annabelle.
Such a disappointment.
I thought we had
An understanding.
I really liked you.
We both kept our
Mouths shut and then
All of a sudden you go and write
A fucking book about us'?
I mean what
Were you thinking?
Huh?
[Knocks on Door]
Whatever happened?
To discretion?
I got my hands on a copy of
Your grubby little manuscript
From a very
Reluctant publisher.
Dr. Lansdale
Transformed Redd.
He created
The boss from hell.
[Laughs]
This is my favorite.
"William, on the other hand,
Was a self-made psychopath?
Arrogant and deluded. "
[Bangs on Door]
Now, Annabelle, I don't
Know if you've heard this,
But there are a lot of people who are
Very dubious about the scribblings
Of a stripper, so I'm gonna
Do you one last favor.
I'm gonna kill you.
They will wonder why you didn't
Turn up to your own book launch.
Come back here and find
Your decapitated body,
And see that actually
You weren't crazy!
[Yells]
[Edward screams in pain]
[Clap of thunder]
Help!
[Screaming]
Help! Somebody!
He's trying to kill me!
Help.
Get behind me.
[Thundering]
[Yells]
Please, no.
Get away from me.
Job well done, Miss Hale.
You may need some shoes.
Meanwhile
I have a pressing appointment
With Dr. Lansdale.
I'll be in touch.
[Baroque music]
[No audible dialogue]
(woman) And here she
Is now, the author,
Annabelle Hale.
[All gasp]
I'd like you
To meet William Tucker.
The real headhunter.
So.
Questions?
♪♫ Vicious freak ♫
♪♫ Your skin mystique ♫
♪♫ Feeds my body's craving ♫
♪♫ I feel my spirit ♫
♪♫ Dispossessed ♫
♪♫ Desire's overtaking ♫
♪♫ Hunted like an animal ♫
♪♫ Messing with my dreams ♫
♪♫ Twisted sums ♫
♪♫ Then nightmares some ♫
♪♫ But there's pleasure
In the screams ♫
♪♫ Hey ♫
♪♫ Hey hey hey ♫
♪♫ Lying in
The broken shards ♫
♪♫ How beautifully
They cut me ♫
♪♫ Wounds that heal
But leave a scar ♫
♪♫ Dark and deep
As black seem ♫
♪♫ After all
This rippin' apart ♫
♪♫ I'll put the pieces
Back together ♫
♪♫ Violently restrained
By my addiction ♫
♪♫ With this tearing
At my heart ♫
♪♫ I gonna break
Towards the daylight ♫
♪♫ Silently contained
By this attraction ♫
♪♫ You make me
Lose my mind ♫
♪♫ With your dirty
Pretty lies ♫
♪♫ You make me
Lose my mind ♫
♪♫ With your dirty
Pretty lies ♫
♪♫ Recklessly romantic ♫
♪♫ Tainted by the fantasy ♫
♪♫ These delusions
Are ecstatic ♫
♪♫ So just take
What's left to me ♫
♪♫ After all
This rippin' apart ♫
♪♫ I'll put the pieces
Back together ♫
♪♫ Violently contained
By this dangerous game ♫
♪♫ You make me
Lose my mind ♫
♪♫ With your dirty
Pretty lies ♫
♪♫ I'm gonna lose
My mind ♫
♪♫ From your
dirty pretty ♫
♪♫ Dirty pretty
Dirty pretty lies ♫
♪♫ So just take
What's left of me ♫
♪♫ Just take
♪♫ I'm gonna lose my mind
Just take what's Left of me ♫
♪♫ Just take
What's left of me ♫