All characters and events portrayed
in this film are fictitious.
In memory
of Pavan S.N.B. Shankar Rao
Bro, Sreenu will be on a roll
this time too.
Apparently, he snagged 50 lakhs
last time.
If only we could get that Delhi
contact.
He has direct contact with
the match fixing batch.
That's why we will manage with
Ranga's information.
First finalise Ranga's commission.
How can we be sure of his word?
Earlier, we helped him with a
girl problem. He won't scam us.
Okay!
[Mobile alert]
What happened? What did you get?
Oh! Super!
[Mobile ringing]
- What's the ratio?
- Mumbai 1200, Chennai 750
-Call me when Chennai bags the rate
-Okay!
[Mobile ringing]
Hello?
Why is Chennai not picking up?
Match is favourable to the
other side, sir.
[Mobile ringing]
- Hello?
- Playing 10 lakhs on Mumbai
Okay!
Come on
Betting 10 Lakhs on Chennai.
Bro, you've been placing all bets
on Chennai. Are you sure?
We are going all in this time!
His bowling is trash.
What are they even playing?
[Mobile ringing]
[All mobiles ringing]
I'll send the money by morning.
No problem at all.
Hello, super guess. How did you
guess that Mumbai would win?
I'll send it bro.
He's been taking loans from us and
using you to avoid repayment.
He makes empty promises.
You don't say a thing.
Both of you are putting
on a great show.
- What is this?
- What happened?
No one but you can make upma this
hard in India.
At least get me some buttermilk!
You have taken loans from
everyone in this town.
Your dad is acting like
he doesn't know anything.
What happened?
Looks like even the ladies have
been trained well at home.
Who told you to lend him the money?
- Did you ask me while lending it?
- No
I had no idea you lent him
the money,
Then why are you asking me now?
Do what you want with him,
I won't interfere.
Kill him if you'd like.
I won't say a thing.
But, if you cause a scene here...
...I'll file a harassment case,
and put you behind bars.
Instead of living shamelessly here,
if you deal with your shit outside,
We'll at least consider you human!
What do you mean?
Can't you understand
a direct statement either?
If you pack your things and leave
We will think of you as a beggar
scrounging around for food.
If I leave now, I'll not come back.
Finish the remaining upma and leave.
I mean there's a
little bit of upma left.
I thought why be wasteful with food!
Screw my life!
Did you think we left?
If you leave the house,
Who will return our money?
I'm telling you; I will pay you.
If you don't repay,
we will sell your organs.
How do you plan on repaying us?
Trust me, give me a week's time.
I will pay you back somehow.
How long will you keep fooling us?
We won't leave you today.
Okay. Is there any proof
that you gave me money?
Come, let's go
to the Police Station.
Tell them you won a lakh betting
in IPL and that I am not paying you.
If it comes to that,
we are prepared for anything.
We'll come again tomorrow.
When and how will you repay?
Your IPL betting idea crashed.
What you will do now?'
[Mobile ringing]
Hello!
I urgently need 10,000 rupees.
Hello, who are you?
I have pictures of you and your
boyfriend being naughty.
I'll bring those photos
to your home.
Please don't do that,
I'll give you the money.
♪ Use your brain
and steal all the cash ♪
♪ Money is all you need,
everything else is trash ♪
I lent you 25,000
rupees out of pity.
You've been beating around the bush
to return it.
If my husband finds out,
he will kill you.
Then forget about the money.
What do you mean?
If you ask me again, I'll tell your
husband that we have an affair.
♪ Use your brain
and steal all the cash ♪
♪ Loot it if you can, steal it silly
and simply escape ♪
I know your family doesn't know
that you smoke marijuana.
I'll delete your video for
50,000 rupees.
Should we book a guest house
in Bhavani Island?
Let's book a guest house
Who the hell are you?
Dude, I have everything.
All your sex chats and nudes.
I don't care. Keep it with you.
Fool, looks like he won't listen
until I show up at his house.
You used to live
in Benz circle, right?
Yes, why?
Aren't you Kishore's girlfriend?
Don't worry!
I get it now.
All the photos and videos you
took together are safe with me.
Please don't be loud,
that was all before my marriage.
Didn't you get married last week?
Then...
What do you want?
♪ Steal ♪
♪ Simply ♪
♪ Cheating is a
valuable skill. ♪
Do they think the
world belongs to them?
♪ Betrayal is what quenches
your thirst, my friend ♪
♪ Whatever you do, whatever you see,
money is what makes a human ♪
♪ This is an innate talent,
don't try it if you are clueless ♪
[Mobile ringing]
It's been a month since
you asked for a week's time.
If you don't settle it by tomorrow,
we'll kill you.
♪ This world is a bottle of poison ♪
Where's my treat?'
- I'll take a shower and be back.
- Okay, make it quick!
I need to take it all in one go,
then I can repay them and relax.
Why is she taking so long?
If her husband comes,
he will give me the treat.
I wonder where she keeps the money?
Why repay them when I can
take this money and settle down?
Let's run away with this!
The flat is fully furnished.
The owner does not stay here.
Apart from selling the furniture,
you can do whatever you want.
That's not how you do it.
You can't build biceps that way.
Follow what I do if you want
to be built.
Oh! As if this guy is Hrithik
and the other Tiger Shroff.
Why is this old guy working so hard?
What's happening inside?
They are doing whatever they like.
The ones who know, do it well,
the others do what they can.
Then why don't all of them
appoint a trainer?
It takes a lot to establish a gym.
How can you expect a trainer?
Young men don't come here.
Girls and aunties use it casually.
Can I train them then?
Sure, sir, why not? Our president
needs to approve though.
- Hello, young boy.
- Hello, sir!
So, you are the new tenant
in flat number 303?
Yes, sir!
So, what do you want?
I have some experience.
So, I thought I could be a
trainer in our gym.
It's a good idea.
But everyone here is a lazy idiot.
EXCEPT ME!
I've lost it now...
But I used to have a
sculpted physique in college.
Then you must be
aware of fitness addiction,
That's why I am asking you, sir.
What will you get if you
train people here?
It will be like a hobby.
As long as there isn't a salary
involved, you can go ahead.
I can cozy up to this Tinder
aunty, this winter.
Wonder how she agreed so quickly?
Hope it isn't a scam.
I hope this is the right address!
What if your husband comes
and surprises us now?
- Why are you talking about him now?
- To get into the mood!
I'll do something and get rid of
my husband.
Should we run away together?
You can go if that's what you want.
Give me the address.
I'll visit whenever I find time.
What? I want to run away with you.
How much money can you bring
if we run away?
The 5 lakhs in my savings.
I'll finish it in two months.
After that you will have to earn
and provide for me.
If not, I'll run away from you too.
This is much better than
providing for you.
Find a rich girl for your needs.
Exactly!
That's what I'm doing right now.
- First time?
- Sir?
- Is this your first session here?
- Yeah.
- What's your name?
- Chitra.
We all have issues.
Depression is it's by-product.
Depression damages us
more than actual problems.
So, you may not find solutions here.
We can find ways to deal with
depression, if we discuss it.
Let's fight depression together!
LET'S FIGHT DEPRESSION TOGETHER!
We'll start the session
with my friend An and.
Hi
I fell in love
with a girl in college.
She looked breath-taking!
I decided I'd do anything
to make her happy.
I also went to the US for her.
But I got to know that her marriage
was arranged with someone else.
I would've been relieved if
what I had heard was a lie.
I returned to India immediately.
It's not about her getting married
to someone else.
I'm not able to digest the fact
that she is happy without me.
I could have tolerated it
if she despised me.
I realised she never loved me.
I couldn't stand that.
So, any progress?
Since I've been here, I've heard
a lot of issues...
Some bigger, some smaller than mine.
Most importantly, I understood that
I'm not alone in this.
Chitra?
No problem.
Relax.
And take your own time.
How's the session, Chitra?
Hi!
Now, the session
will start with Chitra.
Chitra!
It's been a while since you've
joined this program.
There is still no improvement.
If you want to get rid of your pain,
please share your story with us.
Can I forget it?
My name is Chitra
I don't even know
who gave me that name.
I'm an orphan.
I've been unable to share my sorrows
since an early age.
I grew up in Mother Teresa's home
in Vizag.
I did my schooling there.
After my education,
I came to Hyderabad for a job.
There, I met Ajay.
I was alone until then.
But after I met Ajay...
I was so happy.
He fulfilled all my needs.
Happiness!
Family!
[Door-bell ringing]
Where is Ajay?
We planned to come early
and go to the movies together.
But Ajay is stuck at work,
He told me to go home and get ready.
Oh, I see.
You just came back home.
Don't worry, I'll do it.
It's okay aunty, I'll do it.
- I'll do it, get ready to go.
- Okay
[Mobile ringing]
Yeah, Ajay.
I'm not Ajay, I'm a Sub-Inspector
at Gachibowli Police Station.
There's been an accident.
A man has been found dead.
We checked the belongings
found at the spot.
The victim seems to be Ajay,
your husband.
Chitra?
Uncle...
You'll keep thinking of him if you
stay at home all the time.
Start working to get a busy life
for some time...
To forget Ajay.
Ajay died in a car accident
within 6 months of our marriage...
My life turned into a nightmare.
I've lost all hope ever since.
We are sorry for your loss, Chitra.
Hope she takes this route.
I'll hitch a ride, get into her car.
And then weasel into her life.
Sorry, I didn't realise it was you.
- You can go ahead.
- It's okay. Get in.
- I don't want to trouble you.
- Not a problem, please come.
Thank you.
Actually, I'm sorry for your loss.
It's okay.
[Mobile Ringing]
Hello?
Hello madam, we're calling
from Jeevan Bheema insurance.
This call is in regard with your
husband's insurance policy claim.
Can you please talk to
my father-in-law about this?
You can find his number
in the documents.
- Thank you.
- It's okay.
Please stop there on the left,
I'll get down.
- There?
- Yeah, there.
- Yea.
- It's okay.
Thank you.
What have you been up to?
You've been loitering
around of late.
You seem very busy all the time.
Did you bump into someone else?
Are you jealous?
Yeah, I met a girl called Chitra.
She attends the depression classes.
Sadly, her husband died just
6 months into their marriage.
I tried to trap her for my expenses.
Yesterday when I was in her car...
I overheard her husband's insurance
details, the pay-out could be a lot.
So, if I entrap her,
we can enjoy with her money.
What do you think?
Sounds like a solid plan,
but will she fall for you?
Not everyone is as easy as you.
But I will not give up that easily.
Everybody looks financially
weak there.
Except for her!
She looks like a rich girl.
That's why I chose her.
I have to attend that morose
group session again.
I'll have to go early
and focus on her.
Good morning, all of you.
This session has been cancelled
since Madhusudhan sir is sick today.
He will meet all of you
in the next session.
I'm sorry.
Hey, it's you!
Are you okay?
Fine!
- Get in the car.
- It's okay, you can go on.
It's okay, get in.
Care to join me for a coffee,
if you don't mind?
- Two cappuccinos.
- Okay, sir.
- Is that okay with you?
- Yeah.
I don't know how to open up
about this.
My ex-girlfriend is the reason
for my current state of mind.
Ah.
It's her birthday today.
No matter what I do, I've been
unable to forget about her.
It seems like I can't move on.
How is she happily married
to someone else?
Is it that easy to feign love?
Is it that easy to hurt someone?
Is it that easy to forget someone?!
Huh?
No.
I'm reminded of her everyday
in the quest of forgetting her.
Her betrayal is painful.
Most importantly, I'm unable to
erase her from my memory.
I feel conflicted, internally.
Does everyone feel this way?
Or...?
Hey!
It's okay!
Don't worry.
Why are you upset when
she is the one at fault?
I am baffled because of this.
She is happy with someone else but I
constantly pine for her.
This is what I've been trying
to tell you.
You know she is happy with
someone else...
Yet her memories taunt you.
You have to end this, you know!
It isn't easy to forget someone.
You will regret crying over her
to this extent.
It's not worth it!
Okay, it's getting late.
I have to leave.
- Thanks for the coffee.
- Thanks for coming.
To hell with my life!
Keeping this act up is brutal.
I wonder how long it will take?
Get the receipt.
She only started talking to me
after I started crying like a baby.
Finally, you are on track with her.
Do you even know how hard it is to
ensnare a woman like that?
No one is better at entrapment
than you.
That knowledge helps me
put up with all this drama.
If I were a fool that dies for love,
I'd be dead many times over.
What's the plan?
The seed is sown. Now we wait.
Hello! That's my phone.
My name is An and.
- I'm Chitra.
- Chitra from the depression group?
- I'm An and. We had coffee yesterday.
- Yeah.
Actually, that's my phone.
I dropped it somewhere.
I've been looking
for it all morning.
Finally, you answered my call.
Yeah, I just found it
under my car seat.
Oh shit, It fell in your car?
It did not occur to me.
Tell me where you are, I'll come
there and collect my phone.
You know Xenex
at Madhapur 100 feet road?
I'm over there.
[Mobile ringing]
Hey bro, how are you?
I was fine until you called me.
I don't know what will happen now!!
You should be
in the Intelligence Department!
I should stay as far as possible
from you.
Good joke.
But, I have a task for you.
- I need something for motions.
- To stop or to start?
Of course, to start.
- I'm talking with a customer.
- Oh!
To stop them of course.
Give me one full sheet.
If you take a full sheet,
something down there won't work.
I'll give you two tablets. Take one
in the morning and evening, each.
She's already depressed.
She'll die if I give
her two tablets.
I'm talking with the customer.
Now tell me,
what if I won't do it?
Are you still talking
with the customer?
I'm talking to you this time.
What if I won't do it?
You still want to discuss options?
You know about me, right?
I don't know pleading,
all I know is blackmailing.
If you don't comply...
I'll call your wife.
My wife? What will you tell her?
I think revealing your Facebook and
Gmail passwords would be enough.
If you try to cleverly
change those passwords...
It's not a big deal for me
to figure them out again.
Chill, I was just trying
to clarify a few doubts.
How can I say no after
the conversation we just had?
Tell me what to do.
[Mobile ringing]
Why are you behaving like this?
When will you move on?
Will you leave your friends
because your girlfriend left you?
Why are you doing this?
If you do all this for love,
people will think you are mad.
- Move on, man!
- Hello!
Hello? Sorry ma'am.
Finally, I'm so happy that he found
someone that understands him.
Honestly speaking,
you are so lucky ma'am. Nowadays...
A guy like An and...
- Bro, one condom packet.
- Flavour?
-Strawberry
-Oh my god!
I mean what I'm trying to say is..
An and is a very flavourful guy
- Phew, good save!
- I can talk about him all day.
He loves everyone.
I mean he values love genuinely.
Kudos to you,
for understanding him and his love.
I thank you from
the bottom of my heart.
This is all I need.
Now I can die in peace.
- I'll tell An and to call you back.
- Please don't tell him all this.
Thank you for waiting.
I'm extremely sorry for
troubling you.
No problem.
It's okay!
I wouldn't have been able to
find my phone if it fell elsewhere.
Is everything all right?
You look stressed.
Actually, my car is out
for servicing.
I've been trying to book a cab
but no luck.
Come with me, I'll drop you off on
my bike.
Uhh...
Why do you look sceptical?
Can't I offer a little help?
You've given me a ride in your car
multiple times.
You returned my phone safely.
Don't over think it.
I'd like to do
something for you.
Come with me, I'll drop you.
Let's go!
Chitra, it may sound silly but...
I used to go on this bike
with my girlfriend.
She would hold onto me tightly.
She has a whole life ahead of her.
She needs a partner.
True! You have to talk to her
and change her mindset.
-Chitra
-Uncle
- I want to talk you about something.
- Tell me.
The same old topic
of your marriage.
It's not fair for you
to remain alone this way.
Yes Chitra,
you can't stay like this forever.
Try to change your perspective
on getting remarried.
Please try to understand.
No Chitra,
you can't ruin your life.
[Mobile ringing]
See, my plan started working.
Hello! Chitra, tell me.
I need a tiny favour!
You can ask me anything, tell me.
Actually, my car broke down
while travelling with my in-laws.
I remember dropping you
around here last time.
So, I thought your house
would be nearby.
Yeah, yeah. I live around here.
- In that case...
- Hope she doesn't want me to fix it.
Yeah, tell me.
If you don't mind,
could you try to send a mechanic?
Where are you now exactly?
I'm... at...
I'm at S.R. Nagar Post Office.
Okay, give me five minutes.
I'll look into it.
Do you have a car?
Oh no! That's my husband's car.
He'll kill me if he finds out.
I don't care, I just need the car.
Yeah.
Hi!
It broke down unexpectedly.
Let me drop you guys home.
No... Not necessary, the mechanic
will be here soon. Don't worry!
I've spoken with the mechanic, he'll
get it done and bring it home.
Let's go.
Uncle, are you okay with this?
It's alright!
- Sorry, for intruding on your time.
- It's okay, I was free.
What do you do son?
- I'm in the construction business.
- Oh!
I have a friend who does the same.
Shit! Did I get caught in the act?
He might be a useful contact.
Who? That Venkat Rao?
His construction has always
been shoddy.
Seems like this guy is doing well.
Why does he need Venkat Rao?
Aunty is an angel.
She saved me!
Son, take that left
Yeah, I know uncle.
YOU KNEW IT?!
I meant, this
side is residential
area, the other is
commercial space.
Ohh!
-The upcoming third building
-Okay
Thank you so much!
-Thank you son, come home someday
-Sure uncle, I will come.
Chitra!
Yes, uncle?
You said the car wasn't fixed yet.
How did you come home?
An and dropped me!
He was nearby, so I called him.
Oh. Looks like he is
a very good guy.
Yes, he is a very nice person.
- Okay.
- Okay, uncle.
- Hello, An and!
- Hi, uncle!
Sit down.
What's happening?
You said we needed to talk?
Yeah, we are thinking of
getting Chitra married.
- Shit, did he find someone else?
- Take it.
So, I think it would be better if
that person is someone she knows.
- I wanted to know your opinion!
- I never thought of it that way.
- Don't you like her?
- No, no. I like her.
What's the problem then?
Please An and...
Chitra is finally happy again
when she is with you.
So, I thought only you can
make her happy.
The last stage of my plan is here.
An and, handle this with care.
I need some time uncle.
Okay.
[Mobile ringing]
Hello, Chitra I need to meet you.
They think my marriage is
their responsibility.
But I'm not interested in
getting married.
- So, what did you tell them?
- I said it's your choice.
I have a positive opinion of you.
But I'm not sure about my marriage.
I just want to do this for them.
If you really want to marry me,
let's do it.
But, even after our marriage,
I will take care of my in-laws.
Taking care of them
isn't only your responsibility.
Not only will I be a husband to you,
but also a son to them.
That is my responsibility.
No, uncle, We've already decided.
It is our duty to take care of you.
Yes, uncle, let's stay as we were.
There is no need to change anything,
please.
When we need to be taken care of,
we'll surely call you.
Until then you don't need to
worry about us.
Thank God, he finally said it.
No, uncle, I did
all of this for you.
What is the point of living apart
when we are in the same city?
Yeah, uncle, why?!
Don't worry, we
live in the same city.
We'll visit you every weekend.
Hey, morning.
- You're up so early!
- Yeah
There was no need for this.
I could have done it myself.
I promised that
I'd take good care of you.
Go ahead and freshen up.
I'll prepare breakfast.
I'm getting late for work,
I'll leave.
Bye!
[Door-bell ringing]
What do you want?
I heard you just moved in,
thought you might need a maid.
What can you do?
I can wash clothes.
We have a washing machine.
I could clean the house.
We have a vacuum cleaner for that.
I could cook.
I prefer ordering online.
I can wash the dishes.
Don't you want that too?
Looks like you're jobless.
Go ahead and do the dishes yourself!
- This man ruined my day.
- What the hell?
What is your name?
-An and
-Okay
Are you new around here?
Yes
Recently married?
Yeah
Does marital life feel
strangely new to you?
What is this?
She's more rotten than I am.
- What's your flat number?
- It's 606.
If only she knew me before...
Hi!
What is she still doing here?
Gosh! Looks like she won't leave me.
I should not deviate from my plan.
You knew my marital history.
Why did you choose to marry me?
Was it out of pity?
I felt sorry for you initially.
After getting to know you,
there's been only love.
If I felt only sorry for you,
I would have just consoled you.
I married you,
because I love you.
What is this? Why is
she getting handsy in the lift?
Don't do that.
Oh, control...
Why is she tempting me this way?
What is she targeting me?
Hey, Chitra.
Let's go for a coffee?
- Hi, sir.
- Oh, hi!
You look good when you smile,
you should do it more often.
Thank you.
The London client called.
What's the update on that project?
Yeah! It's almost about to get done.
- Goo...
- Sir, wait.
Sir is saying good.
Thank you.
We're just about to get coffee.
I could have said it myself.
With pleasure, sir.
Boo!
Did you get scared?
This is too much Chitra,
what's all this?
You should've told me,
I would have brought it.
- It's okay.
- Give it to me.
- I can carry them.
- I'll bring it next time.
What is she looking for?
Anything special today?
- I have a meeting at the office.
- This early?
Unexpected US call.
Last minute!
Okay give me ten minutes,
I'll make breakfast.
Don't worry, I'll have it
at the office.
- At least have coffee.
- I don't need anything, see you bye.
-Bye
What was she intensely
searching for here?
What could it have been?
Locker keys are here.
Should I take this and run away?
No, I might get caught.
What is this?
Toy car. Why did she hide it here?
A pen drive!
What's in it?
This is Khalid speaking.
Varma sir told me to speak with you.
Tomorrow evening, Ajay will be in a
red colour Audi on Gachibowli road.
Make it look like an accident
and kill him, to avoid suspicion.
Okay.
Ajay died in a car accident.
[Doorbell ringing]
[DOORBELL RINGING]
What took you so long?
I was in the washroom.
What happened?
I forgot a file; I have to get it.
- I'm getting late, I'll leave.
- Okay.
Is everything alright?
Yeah, why? What happened?
Nothing!
Shit! She took the keys.
Ugh!
Shit!
When I was in college...
I fell in love with a girl.
I can't forget her even after
the breakup.
I'm unable to forget her.
Don't worry.
It was her mistake, right?
I called her for a coffee,
to execute my plan.
Will you have a coffee with me?
How stupid was I?
And you wanted to scare her?
I don't know how to say this.
What can I start when my
life seems like its ending?
Is it that easy to feign love?
Who would meet at a graveyard?
How stupid of me!
Yesterday, I met uncle.
Why did you drag the old people
into this?
It's not just your responsibility,
to take care of them.
The plan was to steal her property,
in the name of love.
The plan backfired and now
I'm stuck in a murder mystery.
Make it look like an accident
and kill him...
and avoid suspicion.
No one is as street smart as I am!
How did I fall into this,
without digging into her past?
What is she planning?
Why did she select me?
I came all the way from Bezawada,
in high spirits.
Stupid fellow!
How was your day?
It was alright, what could happen?
Good!
By the way...
Why don't you message me even
once during the day?
Why don't you message?
Umm, message?
Tell me!
WHY DON'T YOU MESSAGE ME?
She'll kill me
for not messaging her.
I'm asking you.
IM ASKING YOU!
Why don't you message me?
Are you busy the whole day?
Or do you think that I'm busy?
I was free but got busy...
Or it was because you are busy
and might not be free.
So, I didn't message.
Oh god! I got confused.
Huh?
I mean, I thought you would be busy.
Why did Chitra kill Ajay?
What is her plan?
What is she doing?
I'm not even educated enough
to understand these documents.
My husband is out of town.
As if, he'd do something if he's
in town.
Okay, I also need a small commercial
break, from this tension.
We'll arrange cash.
You need 3 photographs?
Okay!
Hi An and.
Hi, hi uncle.
Yeah, okay. I'll talk to you later.
How are you?
I'm fine uncle.
Its good.
Look, An and is also here.
Yeah, he just arrived.
- Yeah, okay.
- Hi, aunty.
Okay.
Chitra.
Oh!
She's here too.
She is downstairs.
I am dead for sure.
Apparently she didn't know
that you were coming?
No aunty, she didn't know.
Okay.
Would you like to have tea or
coffee?
No, aunty.
I'll have a glass
of water, that's it.
Okay!
Both of you are here today without
each other's knowledge. Why?
What's the matter?
My karma, uncle.
We just spoke about you yesterday.
So, I felt like seeing you.
That's why I came to meet you.
Coincidentally, Chitra is also here.
The devil has arrived.
What is this suddenly?
- It's been a while since I visited.
- Oh
Aunty, some of my packages...
Are still getting delivered
to this address.
I came to collect them.
I changed the address just now.
They'll come to the right address
from now on.
'Wow, she is putting up
a great show!'
Should we leave?
Yeah!
- See you later uncle.
- Bye!
I have a little work,
I'll be back in 2 hours.
Okay, it's alright.
- Should I get something for you?
- Nope. I don't need anything.
Okay.
Why is she going out on a Sunday?
- Hi Sam.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Fine. Fine.
Check all the files if you want,
properly.
If you have any doubt,
please call me.
I strictly want it to be very
confidential. Just between you & me.
And I don't want anybody
to come in between...
Gosh! The devil has returned.
Did she see me there?
I wanted to cover your eyes
and make you guess who it was.
Like what I was dealing with wasn't
enough.
What are you doing?
I don't know either.
Read this.
What is this?
Insurance papers.
Insurance papers?
Read it properly and sign it.
We are calling from Jeevan
Bheema Insurance...
We have to talk about your
husband's insurance amount.
Insurance on my name?
That means, I'm also...
Huh, goddammit.
I planned to get away with
her dead ex-husband's insurance.
Now I am stuck in this trap too.
Should I sign now?
Of course.
She'll kill me either way.
Next page.
I'll going to have water.
Would you like some too?
No.
Who are you?
She's going to stay here from today.
You'll take her to the
office every day?
No.
To take care of the household work!
I've been taking care
of all that work.
Exactly.
That's the reason behind hiring her.
Why should you be bothered
with all that?
Look at all the love
you have for me. Bitch!
Nice to meet you,
What's your name?
Dhanamma.
My name is An and.
You can start from tomorrow.
No, she's going to be staying here.
Is she staying nights too?
Living here 24/7.
Apparently living here 24/7.
Okay, okay, nice, nice.
Cool.
Go ahead then!
Why did she hire her?
I thought I could escape but she
took a policy on my name.
I should live here
while I figure a way out of this.
If I step out, she might
get me killed in an accident too.
I should only step outside
if it's absolutely necessary.
Did she stab me?
Oh, it was her leg!
Get it off me, you imbecile.
'A newly married wife...'
'...within 2 months of marriage, '
'Planned to kill her husband,
for insurance money.'
Why sort of content is this?
'You'll be shocked
to know the reason.'
Bad timing in my life, I guess!
Hey.
Relax, relax, it's me.
It's just me.
What happened to you?
Nothing, nothing,
I was having a nightmare.
Let me get you some water.
I must have fallen
asleep here last night.
Why did you sleep here?
You might kill me
if I sleep next to you.
I'm asking you!
I felt cold in the night.
I thought you'd be disturbed
if I turned off the AC.
So, I came out and slept here.
You've been very thoughtful.
Okay, I'll get ready to go to work.
Whoa! Is she trying to kill me?
Which curry would you like to have?
Your wish.
I was asked to make
whatever you prefer.
Brinjal.
What kind?
Make stuffed brinjal.
Okay, I'll make that.
Oh god, is she a sorceress or did
someone perform sorcery on her?
The way she looks,
the way she walks.
Scary!
She deliberately hired this maid.
When she saw me at her
in-law's house
She must have suspected something.
That's why she placed the maid here.
Something is fishy.
Her first victim was
a software engineer.
At least she plotted against him.
There's no need to plot
against a fool like me.
She could kill me pretty easily.
I should find a way to escape.
That witch must have slept by now.
This is the right time.
[Doorbell ringing]
Hi!
She is not at home.
I didn't come for her.
She's not at home.
Only the maid can help you.
The maid...
Dhanamma! Aunty needs something.
What do you want?
Do you have chilly powder?
Yes.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Hmmm.
Did she really fall asleep
or is she acting?
Or even worse is she
plotting her next move?
I have no idea.
Dear God! Please watch
over me tonight.
Please.
Looks like she's really sleeping.
I should also crash.
My life has turned into a joke.
Instead of being turned on because
there's an aunty next to me...
I'm scared for my life!
How pathetic am I?
Shit, I never even dreamt of
a situation like this in my life!
Why are you telling me all this?
Because, even if I tell you, you
can't communicate
it with anyone!
As long as this witch is here
It'll keep getting harder for me.
I should do something and
get out of this place.
[Mobile ringing]
Tell me
I need a knock-out drug
that can be mixed with milk.
Condoms, please!
You need condoms?
Not condoms, any knock-out drug.
I'm talking to the customer,
not you!
- Condoms?
- Yes.
You want it every day?
How?
Please attend to me first!
What's your budget?
You are asking me for money?
Send something nice.
I think you should listen to me...
I'm not going to
entertain your questions.
Got it! Where do I send it?
How do I send it?
I need to tell you something
Actually, I married you...
...for your money.
Everything that I told
you until now, is a lie.
Yeah, I know.
I joined the depression group,
to trap you.
I know.
She knew this too?
I thought you could be of help.
I acted accordingly.
Oh, my freaking God!
That's the extent she can go to!
My cheap plans and I
never stood a chance against her.
I don't feel like all that has
happened is fair.
That's why I'm planning
to leave the house.
You've fallen into this trap now.
You can't go back
on your own whim.
From now on, whatever we do...
We should do it together.
Okay?
Together?
What do you mean?
I knew you were a fraudster,
the very moment I met you.
All the plans you
hatched to ensnare me.
I know all about that.
And the thing which I know and
you don't, do you know what it is?
I know that you know
everything about me.
Only if we plan together...
We can figure out
a way out of this.
Okay?
Did she get caught too?
What actually happened
I've faced a lot of
hardships since childhood.
I thought this office
would end my troubles.
I met Ajay there.
Ajay?
What are you doing here?
I was just finishing up with work.
I caught Ajay making
a huge mistake.
Just a moment.
Something isn't right
about your story.
Please tell me the truth.
Good.
You caught me!
It was just a small doubt.
That's why!
In fact,
it wasn't Ajay who got caught
It was me.
I cannot accept your apology.
If you can't do it, tell me!
I will find someone else.
- Give me two day's time, sir.
- What two days? TWO DAYS?
Sir, by tomorrow we'll finish it.
- What tomorrow?
- You there! Show me!
Rubbish, this will
take only two days?
All of you are a bunch of fools!
You! Come to my cabin!
What are you doing Chitra?
Shit!
Please, don't tell this to anyone.
I'll give you how much ever
you'd like.
What's all this?
What exactly are you doing?
I've been copying
our project proposal details.
If we leak our proposal...
They will make a better proposal
and submit them to the client.
They are paying me for that.
But our company will face a loss.
So? Why should I care?
If we do this right,
we'll get 40 lakhs.
You've made me your
accomplice already?
That's not what I meant!
How much do you want?
Just tell me!
15 lakhs!
Is that enough?
Okay!
We started forging
office files together.
Is it okay?
It's safe right?
Completely untraceable.
Not just cybercrime,
even CIA can't catch this.
Trust me!
If need be...
We'd delete the agreements
from the server as well.
After that
I started making more
than I could ever dream of!
Ajay earned a lot too.
We created an offshore account
with the help of a C.A.
We made sure all the money
went into that account.
Later, we would
transfer it to our accounts.
We started selling off
other teams' information too.
We planned it precisely.
No one suspected a thing.
I'd signal Ajay at the right time.
Guys, let's go for a smoke?
Ajay would keep them distracted
until I signal led him again.
My life is much better now.
I used to be broke.
My salary was never enough.
Now I feel like I have
all that I need.
Should we get married?
I mean it, Chitra!
Okay!
You agreed instantly?
I was sharing
all the money until then.
I thought if we were to get married,
I would get all of it.
I could keep everything.
I thought if I saved up 10 crores,
I can run away to some place.
If I didn't accept his proposal,
he could have threatened me.
So, in the name of marriage,
I secured some time.
That's a valid reason
to get married.
What happened next?
Sir!
Good morning sir!
What the hell is going on?
The application that
we planned to release...
was released by another company,
10 days before our launch?
For God's sake, it's a big hit!
Uhh.. Sir, that...
I don't know how and who did it!
How could you not know?
Someone from our side
leaked the project.
- No, sir.
- I want them immediately.
Sir, actually...
How is it...
Our boss...
Do... do... do...
Do you know
what is happening in the office?
The application which we were
executing...
Someone else released it
with the same features.
How is it...
- Ah...
- What actually happened?
HOW DID IT HAPPEN?
The case has been filed.
The criminals will be caught soon!
You all may go. Please, get out!
GET OUT!
Hey!
How is the new car?
What is this?
I got it for us, Chitra.
Good, my son. Nice car!
Did you take a loan?
No, Dad!
A client gifted it for
my work on a project.
Oh! Nice.
Do we really need this now?
We can't raise suspicion
at this point.
If they suspect us,
our life will come crashing down.
Who will suspect us now?
Your dad was suspicious just now.
Won't others follow suit?
It's okay, I'll take care of it.
Don't ruin my mood like a fool.
I can't be as mechanical as you.
- Just do whatever you want.
- Chitra!
Ajay, started losing it.
All in!
I call!
Fuck!
[Mobile ringing]
Hello!
I'm out with friends,
I'll come home later.
Why are you always drinking Ajay?
When will I drink if not now?
Hello?
Drink guys! Won't you drink
even if the tab is on me?
Ajay
You are drinking every day.
Don't create a scene.
What will happen if I drink?
What do you mean by that?
You've been drinking every day.
And those weekly visits to clubs?
Is it necessary?
This is the time to have fun.
Should I do it after
retirement then?
If you keep spending this way,
it's bound to raise suspicion.
Try to understand.
If you blurt this all out someday,
we will end up behind bars.
All my hard work will go to waste.
Why are you shouting?
I'm a part of this too!
Don't over-react.
You keep all your money.
I'll do whatever I want with mine.
We never thought we'd get caught.
Ajay, as I told you...
I can make sure
you never land another job.
- Sir.
- Stop!
What do I have to gain from
doing something like that?
Now...
Everyone does things,
for their own benefit.
Even I'm a human being,
just like you all.
So, according to the deal
you make with me...
I will react.
Didn't you understand?
Otherwise, the crime I caught
on tape will be sent to the police.
In such a horrible situation...
This is a great deal.
No one will be this generous.
Like, God sent.
Forty percent.
40 for you, 60 for me.
Everyone is
a self-centred bastard.
I thought it was just me until now.
Although, women are no less.
It's hard to suspect and
catch women when they cheat.
This is a deal of a lifetime, Ajay.
Our company secured a
30 crore project from Rushaba.
If we sell that project to
Seoul's Okama company.
They'll give 20 crores instantly.
Super deal!
This time the share will be
70 for me, 30 for you.
Okay, I'll do it.
But only I'll deal with it.
Don't let Chitra know.
Oh!
Okay!
Thank you, sir.
Do it right.
Where's Ajay?
He didn't come, sir, he's on leave.
Leave?
Sir!
Recently, Ajay has landed
a lot of money.
He seems to be
enjoying a lot, sir.
I suspect he's up to something, sir.
I'll take care of it,
you can go.
Okay, sir.
We've been offered a huge deal.
It's valued at 30 crores.
If we give it to the other company,
they'll give us 20 crores.
I've already finalised it.
I spoke with Ajay too.
He wants to do it without you.
I know that he is incompetent.
I want you to do this.
Yeah, I will do it.
Done!
This is a one-year project.
I never thought Ajay
was capable of hiding such a thing.
Why did our boss
offer it to Ajay first?
I had no control over the situation.
They transferred the money
to the offshore account.
Give it to me in cash.
After the project is done,
I'll delete all your videos.
After that...
You will be a free bird!
I couldn't trust anyone.
I was trapped.
I couldn't let this go out of hand.
Our company made a blueprint.
We copied it secretly and
sent it to the Korean company.
One crore was deposited
in our offshore account.
Hello!
Was the money deposited
in the account?
Just 5 minutes ago, sir!
Why didn't you tell me?
You called me before.
Okay
Encash it immediately
and send 60% to me.
Yeah. Okay!
Ajay needed money.
He checked his account.
The 1 crore promised by the manager,
was not credited to his account.
Our manager didn't call him.
He opened my mail to check.
I didn't know that
he knew my password.
He found the message from the bank.
That was it.
He knew that
I took up the job secretly.
One large, please.
What's up, Ajay?
You are a scamster!
You kept me in the dark
and got her to do the job.
What are you talking about, Ajay?
You are a fool to trust her.
You would have gotten your fair
share if I did the job.
Now, she will take it all!
I won't let you get away
with what you did to me.
I will see to your end.
Ajay was very aggressive.
My manager feared that we would
get caught due to this.
Will you join hands with anyone?
It was with me first,
it's him now?
What are you talking about?
I know that you are dealing
with that manager by yourself.
You thought of it first. Remember?
Yes, I thought of it,
but I didn't do it.
YOU DID IT!
There's a lot of difference.
Ajay, Relax!
After this project,
I'll give you a share too.
What's the big deal?
Who wants your share?
I can do it too.
Anyway, you are doing well with him?
Do whatever you want with him.
You don't need me.
You only care for money.
You don't care about emotions.
Hello. Hello. Hello.
Calm down!
You can't talk about emotions.
I know what you've been doing
with all the money and alcohol.
What?
What do you mean?
I mean all the money
that you spent on those women.
You don't have a clue.
You bloody...
Are you spying on me?
Try to remember...
Two years ago,
Priya from our office...
I know how you used her
and destroyed her life.
I let it go because
it was your weakness.
Why did you stay with me
despite all this?
Why?
You wanted to use me.
I won't let you get away with this.
Ajay! Ajay! Ajay! Please!
Please! Wait a minute.
Think about your parents.
You didn't take care of them.
Now you'll destroy their future too?
Why are you so concerned about them?
Why are you trying
to bait me with emotions?
They got married,
and gave birth to me.
They had to raise me.
Most useless parents!
They didn't do anything for me.
I made all this by myself!
Taking care of them
is already a big deal.
Bloody losers!
I don't care about them anyway!
I'll be watching you both!
Ajay would refuse to understand.
That was clear.
This time, I had no choice.
Nothing seems wrong for people
already on the wrong track.
Ajay cannot be a part of our plan.
We'll get caught before the pay-out.
If Ajay is involved, we won't get
even 10% of the pay-out.
Eliminating him is justified.
Anyway, Ajay was
squandering all the money.
And there was a chance
he would expose the matter at hand.
If he were dead,
you could get the 40%.
Isn't that why you killed him?
That wasn't the only reason.
Think about it
This is the only option.
I have all your videos.
So? You agreed to it?
Did Ajay give me another option?
That's also true
This guy's name is Khalid
Professional killer
If you inform him
about Ajay's movements...
He'll finish him off
at the appropriate time.
Varma sir asked me
to speak to you.
This is Khalid speaking
Ajay will be on the Gachibowli route
tomorrow evening in a red Audi.
Make it look like an accident
and kill him, to avoid suspicion.
Okay
(A car met with an accident
in Gachibowli today...)
(Police said that the person
in the car died on the spot)
(The deceased's name is Ajay)
(The victim was a software employee)
Come.
Sit.
What happened, sir?
You wanted to see me urgently?
There's a small change in the plan,
Chitra.
What is it?
Percentage!
You are alone now right?
The society will be watching you.
So, I'll be taking Ajay's share too.
You can also live peacefully.
So, keep 10% with you.
Transfer the rest to me.
What the f...?
One moment.
Tell me, sir.
Khalid! Did you record it?
I did sir!
Varma sir, asked me to talk to you.
Ajay will be on the Gachibowli route
tomorrow evening in a red Audi.
Make it look like an accident
and kill him to avoid suspicion.
Now he is blackmailing me,
with the call recording.
Please, take your seat.
This is absolutely unfair.
We've lost the right to use
the word unfair a long time ago.
Don't you think so?
I understand you
want to keep Ajay's share.
What is this 10%?
My Guru once told me...
90 is my lucky number.
So, if I give you 10%,
everything will work in my favour.
So...
Don't drag this matter out.
You are a smart girl.
When the amount is
transferred to you.
Encash it and give it to me.
Or else, I'll ensure everyone
hears your sweet voice on the call.
That's alright but,
why did you marry me?
Everything was clear with Ajay.
Why didn't I leave their parents?
That's another doubt
you have, right?
After Ajay's death...
I wanted to get rid of them.
That was the plan.
I was thinking of a way out.
Then Ajay's father,
came to me with an envelope.
This is Ajay's insurance cheque.
Keep it with you, uncle.
Why would I need it?
It might not be of help now,
but it might help later.
When later?
You might not like it now.
But it's necessary.
You might not be able
to forget Ajay.
It's not right for you to take
too long.
You have to get married again.
No, uncle!
Don't say that!
I would like to find you a nice guy
to marry...
And hand this money to you.
That's all we need in life.
This money belongs to you, uncle.
You have to keep it
for your financial security.
If something happens to me someday
What will you do?
We won't need 2 crores anytime soon.
This isn't the age
to enjoy it either.
What can we do with this money?
I'll hand this money over to you
as soon as you get married.
You'll be sorted for life.
That will make us really happy.
They made up their mind,
to get me married.
I'd be stuck if I
married a man they chose.
I knew your malicious intentions
the moment I met you.
I thought if I married you...
I could throw some money at you
and leave you.
All my problems would be solved.
Do I look that stupid to you?
[Mobile ringing]
Chitra?
The project is done.
I need the money in two days.
Or else, you know what could happen.
I have to pay the
manager right away.
Paying him is not the problem,
But will he leave me alone later?
Okay, I'll pull you
out of this mess.
In exchange I'd like a share
out of whatever you may get.
Get me out of this and...
I'll give you however much you want.
I don't need a lot,
just give me 50 lakhs.
I'll get 20 crores,
I could give you more.
I don't need that much,
just 50 lakhs is enough
If I ask more, you may
plan to kill me. I'm not greedy.
Okay. Tell me the plan.
Yes! I got it!
First, call the Korean company guy.
Tell him that you'll finish
the project by tomorrow.
Ask them to transfer money
to your account by tomorrow evening.
Make sure they transfer it to
your offshore account.
Should we encash it immediately
and give it to the manager?
- Will you let me finish?
- Sorry.
Go on!
You inform this to your manager.
Transfer all the data today.
Okay!
[Mobile ringing]
Hello, Chitra.
I'm copying
the project files tonight.
We have to give to
the company by tomorrow.
I just spoke to them.
Super!
[Mobile ringing]
Hello, Chitra.
Come to my cabin.
Quickly!
Give me the hard disk.
By tomorrow evening...
Give me the total amount.
Okay!
Thank you.
See you!
(Give me the disk. By tomorrow
evening, give me the total amount.)
Now if he tries to set me up
I'll set him up.
Only the office matter
has been sorted.
He won't be able to
use it against you.
But we still have to deal with
what happened to Ajay.
I have a solution for that too!
Okay. I'll get 20 crores in my
account by tonight.
Speak to your manager.
Ask him to meet you at the building
under construction at Narsingi.
Tell him to collect the cash there.
What will we do if we
give him all the money?
Across the street from there...
There's another building.
I'll use a pair of binoculars
to keep an eye on you.
He'll come there and exit his car
to come upstairs
As soon as he reaches
the floor you're on,
Pretend to be dying
and fall on him.
Didn't you get it?
Apply fake blood to your dress.
It should look like someone
just stabbed you with a knife.
Now the real story begins.
The bag next to you will be empty.
He'll think someone must have
killed you for money.
He'll assume someone knew that
you were coming with money.
That they killed you...
And ran away with the money.
This will be a massive shock to him.
He will have no choice
but to run away.
That's my plan.
How is my plan?
It's perfect!
He'll assume I'm dead.
He won't even think about me
anymore.
Even if he suspects something later,
he will keep his mouth shut.
Call your manager.
[Mobile ringing]
Hello!
I'll get 20 crores in
my account by tonight.
Before the toll gate, at the
ring road...
You'll see an under-construction
site
On the 7th floor.
Be there at 11 o'clock sharp!
Ohh...
I understood.
You were going to say okay..
- Ohh...
- Bye
Done.
- Everything ready?
- Yeah!
His car is here.
He's on the first floor.
He's on the second floor.
He disappeared suddenly.
Hello?
What happened?
I'm dying here.
I saw him on the third floor,
but then he disappeared abruptly.
What?
I don't get it either.
What do we do now?
You stay there, I'll check it out!
I can't wait anymore,
should I go and check?
Chitra! Stay back! Don't go!
Chitra!
Hello?
Hello...
Hello... Someone killed the manager.
What?!
[City police sirens ring]
- Hello?
- Pinky pinky ponky...
- Friend is a donkey!
- Hey, who are you?
Can't you recognise my voice?
Hey, it's you! Where are you?
Did you get the promotion?
That's not my girlfriend
to come at my beck and call!
I know of a way to earn it for you.
Will you do it?
What is it?
I'll send you the location.
Be ready tonight!
A Location?
Ok send it!
[Mobile alert]
-Yes Khalid
-Sir, the job is done
Good!
Sir, the police are here
just like you said?'
Then what are
you still doing there?
Sir, when can we meet?