I've prayed for them
every day of my life, but
when you came I begged
you to leave. I am not ready.
Isaiah, the prophet.
Help! Help...
Come on, come on!
No, no, no!
CALL VOICE MESSAGE.
VICTOR. CALL ME.
WE ARE WAITING FOR INSTRUCTIONS.
YOUR FATHER ASKED ABOUT YOU.
Where are you? You took
me, you didn't let us stay.
They blocked all the entrances, and
no one told me what was happening.
Please answer me!
Yes, it's very strange, even though
it's already two o'clock in the afternoon.
Be careful, people are
so panicked, it scares me.
WHERE DO YOU WANT TO GO?
Idiots! Your father will
kill you if he hears that.
OK, fine, I trust you, you take
care of it, but don't
let him find out,
if not, it's no longer a surprise. Okay?
OK, I don't want to
send you a long voicemail
telling you what to do.
I believe you, okay?
Kiss.
Hello?
Hello? Is anybody there?
Hello? Yes! Hello!
Hello, who's talking?
Banish.
Banish? What is that?
Nickname. Not important.
You don't need to
explain it to me, buddy.
Tell me, where did
you get this frequency?
He wrote on the wall.
I tried it.
Written on the wall. Okay.
Are you alone?
Yes.
Give me an honest answer.
Anyone following you?
Are you going alone?
Listen, I haven't
seen anyone in days,
this is not for fun.
OK, OK, that's fine. I'm
just asking as a precaution.
There's something stalking
us that I'd better avoid.
I stay on this frequency.
Where exactly did you find it?
In an abandoned building.
This building is very large and has
several rooms and storage space downstairs.
But it's been looted.
Yes, I know which building you mean.
I was nearby.
Did you find anything?
Yes. A can I can't open.
You don't have a knife or
something else you can use?
I'm not a Boy Scout.
It's okay, at least you can.
I really want a steak sandwich.
With fried potatoes and eggs.
Stop, this is torture!
I could eat a dog now.
What's your name?
Where are you now?
Sorry I haven't introduced myself.
I'm Demian.
I'm in a building.
I heard noises and preferred
to wait until the area was quiet.
It's been days since I
last talked to anyone.
What does it sound like?
Noise, screams and gunshots.
I've been where you are.
But the situation is very bad.
Dangerous, better wait.
Where are you now?
Can you give me a hint?
Demian?
I don't know, they
evacuated us to the west.
I'll tell you where exactly, but
please, drop everything and come here.
Don't do it if you're not sure.
Hi! Are you there? Answer.
Hello, what happened?
Sorry, I have to maintain radio silence,
I heard voices and had to move.
Where are you now?
I'm heading your way.
This will take time, I
have to take a detour.
Are you still in the warehouse?
Yes, I'm still here.
Okay.
Do you have a car?
No, mate, that's a luxury.
Why do you ask that?
Well, I have a car.
But the battery is empty.
Is it true?
Sorry about the battery.
Do you want to go on holiday?
I just want to get out of here.
But there is a blockade.
With the military everywhere,
this will be difficult for you.
But there are some
warehouses north of your position,
maybe you can find
batteries or something there.
But why do you want to go?
There's nothing there.
I don't care.
I understand.
Help!
Give it back to me!
Hello Bannen, can you hear me?
Hello Demian!
Where are you?
I still need time,
I have to take
a detour, a lot of movement.
Yes, me...
I have to leave the building.
I'm so scared!
Bloodsucker? Damn.
Listen, don't
believe their voice.
Yes I know.
I thought it was someone, but...
I also do not know.
That's why I'm telling you.
Where are you now?
I had to jump over the
wall in the other direction.
Now I'm in a greenhouse.
Have you strayed too far?
Two blocks, more or less,
far from the road.
Yes, that's great, mate.
This is getting complicated.
Keep your head down, okay?
I will pass this creature.
At least I have a gun.
Demian?
Yes I'm here.
So you have a gun?
Do you know how to use it?
I tried, but I couldn't.
What do you mean you can't?
Have you checked
to see if it's loaded?
I don't know.
Have you prepared the weapon?
Listen, there's usually a
button next to the handle.
Can take out the bullet magazine.
Check the cartridge.
Then plug it back in and
make sure the fuse is on.
There's a button here.
Now pull, like in the movies.
Done.
Now I understand.
You're Charles Bronson.
When I was little,
I always go to my
grandparents' house.
I love camping in their park.
I went on Sunday.
I love it when it rains.
That's another life, my friend.
Yes.
Time passes quickly.
And suddenly you wake
up and see everything
so it's like hell.
Banish, did you hear that?
Yes, what is that?
"Nephilim," he sounded
like the powerful type.
I find his voice very calming.
No, no, you're crazy.
You don't know me.
Banish, did you see it?
No, I just heard it.
In my opinion, there is no
point in continuing to fight.
But you have to do something, right?
Yes, they definitely do.
Oh okay.
Are you sure
one of those existentialist,
nature-loving hippies, right?
You're an asshole.
Listen, let's get some quiet for now.
I'll contact you later.
Understand. Understand.
Hello, your father told
me you two had a fight.
I don't want to interfere,
and I won't interfere.
But why do you always fight?
With all the love you
have for each other.
He already knows you
have good intentions.
And you, you know him.
He was as stubborn as a hedgehog.
That's what he
always told you: "If
you know how I
behave, accept it."
That's how it is. Just let
it go and stop being angry.
Let's not argue anymore, okay?
Banish, do you hear me?
Now seems like a good
time for you to move on.
This situation confuses you even more.
Drop it!
Give me your weapon!
I've dropped.
The backpack.
This only I have.
Come on!
Give me the backpack! Come on!
Fuck!
Bastard!
You shot me, you bastard!
Come on, you have to help me!
Fuck!
Wait! You can't
leave me like this!
Please help me!
Do not leave me!
Help!
Please stop!
Who are you? Hah?
What are you doing here!
Jesus?
Isaiah.
Is that you, kid?
Kid, I thought you'd
never come back.
I'm worried about you.
You left without warning.
You want to leave me alone?
- Forgive me.
- It's okay, nothing happened, right.
Hey, tell me, how's your sister?
Did you see it?
Good.
Good? Just that?
Yes.
He asked about you. He is fine.
Good. Now you're here.
I thought you'd never come back.
Sorry, dad.
It doesn't matter.
Come on, eat.
It's still warm.
You're hungry!
They don't give you anything.
Drink it.
Slow. Don't rush.
You'll get used to it.
The water is the same everywhere.
What a night you chose to come.
Just look at the sky.
You're right, my son.
The sky fell, with it all our gods.
Asking for something to be done.
They are as hungry as we are.
- I don't understand.
- You remember that,
How did you pray when you were little?
You scream, "They're
coming, they're coming!"
But in the end there is
nothing special about them.
You used to live in luxury and
now you're crawling on the ground.
You're mortal, we make
you do something special,
but out of necessity.
Previously we didn't
know how to find ourselves.
But you need us.
You want us to believe you.
The sky is falling because of us now.
Do you think we'll need you?
Each of us finds what
we need within ourselves.
We live in Eden! They took him!
When you find a janitor, you
can ask him what you want.
And you're fulfilled?
Depends on what makes life.
Whether it's your
dream or your nightmare.
Yourself.
I found this under the bridge.
I'm having trouble reaching it.
I almost lost a leg.
You don't know
how hard it is to fight.
Look!
- It's worth it!
- What do I care about money!
- What is the point?
- This makes me happy!
Do you want to feel it?
Your sister knows.
That's why he left.
He goes with them.
And now I'm a grandfather!
Singer grandfather from heaven.
What's his name?
Who?
Your daughter.
I will take you.
Demian!
Demian, are you there?
Yes I'm here. What is it?
Hear. I'm in one place.
A workshop, I don't know.
I found the battery.
Is it true?
Have you tried it? Can?
I've tried it.
Still have some burdens.
I'll take it to the car
and we'll see if it starts.
Don't rely too much on it.
But hey, what do you have to lose?
There isn't any.
Where are you now?
Are you close?
I'm very close to the warehouse.
But I'll go the other way.
We can meet in the car.
Okay.
Go to the south side.
There's a back door there.
Go out, then go right, there is a dark alley.
Then go straight for 50 meters.
There you will find the car.
Good guy, change and you're done.
Banish. That's you, isn't it?
The acid is leaking.
This won't work.
Sorry friend.
IT IS NOT SAFE TO STAY HERE.
There is a way out.
This won't be easy.
But you have to prove
to me you're worthy.
If you're ready, let's go now.
From here, straight forward.
500 meters.
Then you go left.
You will see some grassy areas.
Go straight towards the forest.
Go.
Trust me, okay?
I'll take the other tunnel.
This is my way of distracting you.
If you see us together, it
will be easier to catch us.
See you at the exit.
Help!
Help me!
If we are lucky, we
might catch a rabbit.
We might catch a rabbit.
Have you ever eaten this?
No.
You're really funny.
The water in my mouth ran out.
I haven't eaten anything for a long time.
Maybe we'll catch
one and cook it.
Wait a minute, I want to pee.
Let's go, buddy. Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Why are you called Banen?
It's a nickname, you say.
When I was little I often
read science fiction comics.
There's a character named Brian Bannen.
My father always called me Bannen.
And you make it a habit?
I always feel like
I'm someone else.
And who are you?
Vaña" "Aguará Guazu".
A type of long-legged
fox that lives in swamps.
But this one has something special.
Do you know which one?
He wants to be human.
He talked about almost all the animals.
Alligators, tapirs, birds.
“I want to be human,
I want to be human.”
Everyone looked at
him as if he was crazy.
That's not possible.
A sparrow flying by heard him.
He said, "I can help you."
"I know someone, a
wizard, who can help you."
"Where does he live?"
"In a shack at the
end of the road here."
"Good, good!"
So he ran.
And when he arrived, he stood in the hut.
And inside it is Aivaguá.
The witch's name, Aivaguá.
He is cooking something.
When he reached
the door, he slipped in.
Aivaguá looked at him.
He said, “you told
me you could help me.
"I want to be human."
And he tells her, “but
it comes at a price.”
"Will it work?" he asked.
- "Your ears!"
- "no, my ears are very beautiful!
I can't just give it to you!"
"Your feet!"
"No, I can't give you my feet."
I'm the only animal in the
swamp with long legs, the only one!
"Your fur!"
"No! No! No! I won't give you my
feathers! Not my beautiful feathers!"
So the witch asked
him further, and he
refused. Everything!
He rejected them all.
Finally Aivaguá
got tired and said:
“You really want to be human?”
He said, "Yes! I
want to be human",
but I can't give you
what you ask for!
"I can't!"
The witch looked at him like
that, intently, for
a few moments.
He said, "If you can't
sacrifice what hurts you",
just for convenience,
then I'm very sorry.
I ask you never to
ask for my help again.
And something else:
You will continue to
dream of being human.
"And this is how you die."
And you?
Have you sacrificed much?
This is strange.
I have memories, but...
I know I've never lived it.
You don't have a weapon?
Could I see it?
Victor.
I don't know if you got
a reception, but I left this
message for you in case
you get one someday.
There is nothing left.
I don't know how
much longer we can last.
I hope.
You are okay.
You find peace.
I really love you.
I apologize.
I have to find out
who you really are.
I have to get you out of there.
You.
You...
You're a parasite.
How about you?
Who are you?
I like things the way
they are right now.
I have this place.
I went out to plant seeds.
And you?
Do you know who you are?
I always know who I am!
I accept it!
May I ask for your help?
What?
Will you give me one?
My darling, where are you?
Are you lost?
Come on, we're all here,
at your father's house.
All your friends are here.
Come on, your father really
misses you, and your son too.