INTRUDER IN THE DUST
Subtitles by Seglora
Say can I get my shoe shined?
Not today,Mr
Where is the shine boy?
Where are they all at?
Seems to me I ain't seen one darkie
on the road since yesterday
Ain't you heard?
No,heard what?
One of the Gowrie boys been shot dead
Gowrie? Shoot at Gowrie?
Now who would do a fool thing like that
Shot in the back by a nigger
It's him,it's the sheriff
Bring him in
I'd never thought he'd do it
He is here,the sheriff is starting,come on
Come on
Knock it off again,sheriff
Knock his head next time
Don't bother the sheriff,
the guards will do it for him
You boys get on out of here,
get on back to barber shop
You got a flat tyre,sheriff,
somebody tried to slow you up?
Maybe,somebody don't know me,anyhow
All right,Lucas,come on
You, young man!
Tell your uncle I want to see him
Want to see who?
Lawyer Stevens,John Stevens
He wants to see a lawyer
-Lawyer?
-He ain't even needing an undertaker
I told you boys once to get on out
of here,I ain't going to tell you again.
What, Chick,you are perspiring,
you are wet through
Where have you been?
In the Sunday School,the pictures show
doesn't start until six o'clock
Perhaps there are other attractions
Gosh,I'm hungry!
Is that a proper way to behave?
-Sir?
-Coming in here,without a word of greeting
-No,Sir
-This is your home
Yes,Sir
-Well?
-Hello,ma
Hello,father
Hello,Uncle
Paralee
-Yes,Sir?
-Bring the chicken in again
I don't know if there is any left
Apparently she's upset today
I don't see why,she is not
the lady of that murderer
-Or is she?
-No,neither is Chick
Now Chick suppose you explain
where you've been
Nowhere in particular
Nowhere in particular is
a mighty large place
I reckon you can do better than that
-May I please have the salt?
-More coffee,Paralee
You waited outside
the jail with the riff-raff
from the pool hall and
the barber shop,didn't you?
Well,did you see what
you'd expected to see?
They didn't do anything
They just stood there that's all
I want you to stay home
until this thing is cleaned up
Over,finished and done with
It's happened before and
it's bound to happen again
Nothing for us to get excited about
I have to run up to Memphis
for a couple of days
and this is been the way it is
I don't want to have to worry about
you too,you understand!
That apply to Aleck too
-Yes,Sir
-I told him but he don't listen to me
He listen to Chick,I ain't no
friend of his,I'm just his Ma
Everybody is going to
stay right here at home
All this fuss and nonsense simply because
Your friend Lucas Beauchamp really
seems to have done it this time
Yes
They're going to make a nigger
out of him once in his life any way
What,Chick!
Let me talk to him
-What in heavens name
-Why?He hasn't finished his dinner
It's terrifying,I know it
but we got to face him
He just doesn't like his napkin up here,
makes him feel not quite grown up
-But he isn't
-He'd better not be
Let me go up and talk to him
Tell him I said to him to come
down and finish his dinner
whether he is hungry or not
Paralee,or Craig tell Aleck to
put my suitcase in the car
Tell me what happened?
Why did he have to do a thing like that?
Who knows?
We'll never really know
Your friend Lucas Beauchamp
He is not my friend!
Chick,you mustn't take this so seriously
I'm not
I can't help it
But why,tell me why
I don't know
You must tell me,Chick
I don't know if I can
Try,you're old enough to try.
And maybe I'm old enough to understand.
It was quite a while ago
Went hunting with Alexander
On the old Edmond's place?
Yes?
It was  November,pretty cold.
We were hunting rabbit.
We hadn't jumped one all morning
Alexander!
My gun!
Get the pole out of his way
so he can get out
That was just about the first
time I saw Lucas speech
Come on to my house
Take his gun.
Then I realized we were
hunting on his land
I remember you'd told me the story
His grandfather was a slave
He got this land as a gift
You told me why
Because his grandfather was the
first cousin to the man that owned him
So grandfather,to father to son
came to Lucas Beauchamp
It was 10 acres,all his own,smack in
the middle of whole plantation
It was Lucas Beauchamp's land
And Lucas Beauchamp proved it,
every step he took
His land and his house
Strip off
There was something else,
just what I'd expected
Side meat and greens
He made me the dinner
that was cooked for him
What's that for?
Pick it up!
Pick up his money
Give it to him
I was so angry.I was so awfully ashamed
He knew what I did not know
What I didn't have sense
enough to understand
He knew all the time,and I didn't
That I was his guest in his home
Now go on and shoot your rabbit
And stay out of that creek
Then I could hardly wait for Christmas
I went down-town and bought Lucas
Beauchamp four of their best cigars
a package of snuff for his wife,Molly
That was to pay him his
seventy cent with interest
The next day he made me take it back again
That's a home-made molasses,
a gift from him to me
That was worse this time,because
he had a white boy bring it to me
This time it had to be finished,
once and for all
Out of what you paid me I saved a quarter
a week and finally there was enough
Enough so he couldn't pay me back
Enough so he wouldn't if he could
Mother helped me
We bought a dress good enough to wear
on Sundays,head and set for his wife Molly
I thought that Lucas would have to come now
Take off his hat and say
Thank you,Mr Mallison
But he didn't
I saw him in the town just once after that
He didn't even see me
I wasn't there
He didn't even see I wasn't there
I thought now it's finished,it's all over
Then I heard,you see, his wife was dead
Been dead when I sent her the dress
He was grieved
I reckon you can be sad and prouder
and even lonely,and sad of black skin too
I went to see him,not to his house,
I wouldn't be caught that way again
I picked neutral ground this time
Fraser's store
He came by there any Saturday afternoon
They were watching him,
two of the Gowrie boys
One of them was  Crawford Gowrie..
The other was Vinson the younger brother
You,brummie,big headed,bare headed nigger
Get out of here, Lucas!
Get out of here, your fool!
Take it easy,Vinson
Don't be a fool
I didn't go after him,couldn't,
I don't know why
Maybe because Vinson Gowrie
was white, and I was white
Lucas Beauchamp was not
Right in these woods on a Saturday
afternoon a few weeks later
He killed Vinson Gowrie,
shot him in the back
And yet he thinks I'm his friend.
Well,come on
He wants a lawyer.
-Is that all?
-He asked for you
Uncle John,can't you go right now?
What's the hurry?
Chick...
Nothing is going to happen
They never start anything in the day time
They'll be ashamed to see
each other's faces
Suppose they are not?
They'll wait for the Gowries
They won't do a thing without the Gowries
and the Gowries are going to bury Vinson
before they do anything to
anybody that isn't a Gowrie
Then they'll come and drag him
out of jail and hang him up
No,the Gowries are not much
good except the fish and fight
And rise enough corn
to boil up some whiskey
But it's Sunday,even for a Gowrie
and they wait for Sunday's passed,
for midnight at least
Suppose they don't
Then there is  a steel door
and sheriff Hampton
It's his job
Not yours and not mine
But you are going to see him,aren't you?
There isn't much I can do for him now
Uncle John
-All right,I'll go
-I want to go with you
All right,after supper
-But suppose they come..
-Suppose of them?
Lucas should have thought of that
before he shot a white man in the back
Come on finish your dinner
Good evening,Mr Lillie
Alone aren't you?
Those Gowrie folks got George to do
before they can get into town
Maybe they'll decide to stay
at home on a Sunday night
By Jove no,they are set for this Sunday
He ought to thought of that
before taking to kill a white man
on Saturday afternoon
I agree
My wife is not feeling well tonight,but
tell them to holler if they need any help
I expect they know they
can depend on you,Mr Lillie
You see he has nothing against Lucas
He'll probably tell you like some other
don't like the white folks,
and he believe it
all he requires is that Lucas
acts like a negro
Which he believes what must have happened
Lucas blew his top and murdered a white man
Now the white folks are going
to take him out and burn him
No hard feelings on either side
In fact Mr Lilley will be probably one of
the first to contribute cash money
to Lucas's funeral and support of his
widow and children if they had any
- What's that?
- Someone of Mr. Lilley's friends
-Good evening.Mr Legate
-Evening
Mr Stevens,you had to get
mixed up in it too
Seems like you can't let life act alone
I'm his lawyer,Mr Tubbs
Will here won't even shut
and lock the front door
I'm doing just what the sheriff said
He is saying me aside and it is a night
to resist and is just what I going to do
Does the sheriff think that gun and
funny papers are going to stop the Gowries?
I don't suppose to stopping by myself,
I've got you,and you got a pistol
Me? Me getting in their way for 75$ a month
Better for everybody if them folks
just took him as soon as they
laid hands on him yesterday
But they didn't and I don't think they will
Don't mind me I'm on duty
doing as best as I can
I've taken an oath of office too
How am I going to live with myself
if I let a posse of no good Gowries
to take a prisoner away from me
And don't think nobody
don't make me admit I like it
I got a wife and two children
What good in my tomb if I get myself
killed for taking a hard stand
Look
Look at them,they ain't asleep not a one
And I don't blame them
when a mob of white men
is going busting here with pistols
and cans of gasoline
Well,it won't be the first time,
and the law of black cats look alike
-Entitled to a cell?
-Serious orders
I don't know what the
next white man he figures
he can't risk going to kill
somebody and going to think about it
I've taken the blankets off
Maybe because he won't be here
long enough to have to go asleep
Well,old man you played the devil this time
Then you can take my case?
Take the case? What do you mean?
Depending before the judge?
I'm going to pay you,
you don't have to worry
I don't defend murderers
that shoot people in the back
Let's give it a trial,we
ain't come to it yet
Now I want to hire somebody,
don't have to be no lawyer
To do what?
Is you or ain't' you going to take the job?
I'd already taken your
case before I came in here
I am going to tell you what to do as
soon as you tell me what happened
-Never mind that
-Mind?
What I want is..
You tell the Gowries to never mind
when they bust in here tonight
So you don't want the job?
No,but I'll do it just the same
Now tell me exactly why
you killed Vinson Gowrie?
Was it to that kind of trouble at
Fraser's store two months ago?
I was there Uncle John,
I'll be your witness
That's Lucas's trouble now,he's
got too many witnesses already
Well?
There was two white folks,
partners in a sawmill
in this way they were buying
lumber to the sawmill on credit
Who were they?
Vinson Gowrie was one of them
Lucas has it not occurred
to you that if you just said
Mr to the white people and
said it like you meant it
you might not been sitting here now
So I am to commence now?
I can start off by saying Mr to folks
that drag me out of here
and builds a fire under me?
Nothing is going to happen to you
Nobody takes you if you
got a good pair of hands
Sure of hands,is home in bed
It's a point of Mr Wilbur Legate to sit
downstairs and throw away the shotgun
I ain't querying any Will Legate
The day you hunted? The man that can hit a
running rabbit with a 30 30 rifle?
Them Gowries ain't no deer,they might be
carrymouse and panthers,they ain't no deer
All right,I'll stay here with you till
the morning if it makes you feel better
Now go on
Vinson Gowrie was doing a lumber deal.
Who was the other man?
Vinson Gowrie was the only
one what's public here
And he got public by being shot
in the back in broad daylight
Well,that's one way to do it
All right,who's the other partner?
What was his name?
Some other man
He was stealing a load of
my lumber every night so
How do you know?
I've seen him
All right,and then what?
Now you answer me some questions
Is you or ain't you going to take the case?
You haven't got a case,you look
at the suspicious and took a pistol
and went straight in a wrong between
two white men,what did you expect?
What else did you expect?
You don't want justice,you want mercy
Well?
Well,what?
The rest of it,what happened?
That's all
Then I tell you,you went to Fraser's
store again and met Vinson Gowrie
You told him that someone was robbing
you,he cursed you and called you a liar
Whether it was true or not,naturally,
he would have to do that
Maybe he even knocked
you down and walked off
And you shot him in the back
Never nobody knocked me down
So much the worse,
it's not even self defence
Now you listen to me
I'm going to get you
tried in another county
Persuade the District Attorney
out there since they don't you
that you are an old man,never
been in trouble before
You plead guilty and ask
the mercy of the court
And hope they send you to a penitentiary
where you will be safe from the Gowries
I'll made this offer once
and I'll  make it again
Do you want me to stay
with you in here tonight?
I reckon not,they kept me up all last
night,I'm going to try to get some sleep
If you stay here you'll talk
to the morning
Right
How do expect to get me help from anybody?
I don't want help,I paid my way
You won't pay your way out of this
You broke it
You might bring me a can of tobacco
If them Dowries leave me time to smoking
Tomorrow,we don't want you
to keep you awake tonight
You aren't going to help him,aren't you?
Of course I am,whether
he wants me to or not
As for change of venue,pleading guilty
Then they tell you what really happened
I know what happened,
he killed Vinson Gowrie
no matter what provocations and
he probably had plenty
Nevertheless he's killed a man
But there was something he
wanted, started to tell you
I know the answer to that too
He was going to tell me a lie
he knew I couldn't believe,and ding his
lawyer,I had to defend like it
No,I know what's happened and the
only cure for it,come on,let's go home
I might take him the tobacco
That can wait for morning
Chick,your father told me before he
left to see you didn't go anywhere
I know
Then you get home as fast as you can
Yes,Sir
What again?
I forgot something
Let it rest till the morning
Oh,let him get it tonight
I am afraid if he leaves to the
morning he might get trampled on
Let open the gate,I intend to
give him through the bars
All right,what do you want me to do?
-Go out there
-Go out where?
The Gowries buries into chapel
What?
That's nine miles out of the bridge
Then first right hand turn up the hills
All you got to do is going to look at him
Me? Why should I do such a thing?
Come here
Because my pistol is a 41 colt
All right,suppose it is,then what?
He wasn't shot with no 41 colt
What was he shot with?
What kind of shot was he shot with,Lucas?
I'm going to pay you,name your price and
anything within reason and I'll pay you
But why me,why do you call me,
what can I do about it?
Because you ain't clattered,you can listen
but a man like your uncle he ain't got time
He is too full of notions
Tell me what you want me to do
They bury at the Caledonian Chapel
Up in that part of the county,
up in the night?
Even the sheriff won't go up
there unless he is sent for
And you want me to?
Anyway I have to be back
at midnight or the Gowries
I know about the Gowries
Even midnight will be too late
I don't see how I can make it
I'll try to wait
Wait! What did he tell you?
Nothing Mr Gowrie
You have been up to see him twice
Why not? Why shouldn't I?
He killed my kid brother
And I'm here to see that nobody
stick him over the county line
where we can't get at him
You tell me what you went up there for?
He asked me to bring him some tobacco
Tobacco?
We buried Vinson this morning,and
do you know how he was killed?
Tell me what he told you
He said it wasn't his gun
He is a smart nigger,I'd say the same thing
So he told you it wasn't his gun
If I were Lucas or any
other ignorant murderer
I'd claim the exactly the same thing myself
That's just what Crawford Gowrie said.
Where?
Outside the jail
And the Gowries are there already
And you come to me,and I say
no more that what a Gowrie says
It's true,in the matters of life and death,
a man's vocabulary is almighty small
-Oh Excuse me,Good Evening,Miss Habersham
-Good Evening
Where as in the matter
of Miss Habersham's truck
in dreadful collision to
a worn out rooster
which your neighbour Mr Winston swears and
contends is of high pedigree stock
Worth at least 7 $
There are all the words in the world
Why if he had to shoot a white man,
did he do it up there in deep mine?
He couldn't picked the worse place
for himself in this whole county
Maybe not in the whole world
But if he had to do it there
why did he pick the Gowries?
And if he picked the Gowries why did
he have to shoot him in the back
Maybe he didn't
Maybe we might find out if we
went up where he was buried
Chick,now tell me,what did
Lucas asked you to do?
Maybe the sheriff could do it
Do exactly what?
Dig him up
-What?
-To get the bullet out and look at it
Why in heavens name?
To see that it comes from a 41 colt
Dig up Vinson Gowrie out of ground he's
been prayed and consecrated into?
Violate a Gowrie's grave to
save a black from punishment?
I'd rather tell old man Gowrie
I want to exhumes his boy's body
to get his gold out of its teeth
Even if Lucas' story were true,
even if every word of it were true
even then we couldn't do it,not you,not me
not sheriff Hampton,not the governor,
not the President of the United States
It's Chick
I'll let you not going to do it tonight
I didn't say I was
It's Chick with Ryebow
Let him be
Go ahead,go ahead,if you want to
That Lucas being so smart,why
did he has to do a thing like that
Go ahead,do you what you just want to do
I ain't going nowhere
At least not very far
Where are you going?
-Far enough
-Where is that?
Where I don't have to see or hear
anything that have happened tonight
I am going after more
feed if you go that far
Chick
What did Lucas tell you?
He said it was not his pistol
I know and then what?
He wants me to pick up the body
Well?
I can't even if I could you know
what Uncle John would say
I got a flash,I got my car
Can you get some tools,a pick and shovel?
Going to no good,
he will be burned just the same
just exactly the same for you
could not doing anything about it
How far is it?
Caledonian Chapel is on the
hill beyond the bridge
Then we do need a horse
We? Do you expect to come,Miss Habersham?
We'll park at the bottom of the hill,
then we use the horse,he'll make less noise
Can you drive?
I am not supposed to go
I know,neither is Mr Stevens
neither is the sheriff,or the governor,
or the President of the United States
For that matter neither am I,
but somebody got to do it
Come on
Don't go across the bridge
it will make noise
Go and cross the creek
What's the matter?
He smells quicksand
A mule coming down the hill.
Who's that on the mule?
-I couldn't even see it was a mule
-I couldn't see anything
Suppose he saw us,suppose
he knows he can catch us
Maybe he had carrying things
Here it is
There is no need for any pick
So much the better
Got to excavate,I'll help
All right,Aleck,give me a hand
We need a crowbar
And rope.We forgot the rope
It's empty
Well,you would not have come
here at four o'clock in the morning
with a tale like that if it wasn't so
Looks like he might be innocent
He could have killed Vinson Gowrie
but he never dug him up
Because Vinson wasn't buried
until Sunday afternoon.
By that time Lucas had been locked
up in that cell for almost six hours
-Sheriff if we don't..
-Vinson isn't in that grave
But officially he is
By the county records he is
So you want me to dig
him up again officially
Gowrie grave,Gowrie ground
Who is going to get old Hubb's permission?
Aren't you the sheriff?
But you're the lawyer
You're the talker
And tell him what?
That we are trying to save
the black skin of a man
who was found with a
fired pistol in his pocket?
Standing over a dead Gowrie?
It will take more than a lawyer to do that
If we are going up to that
graveyard without permission
We'll wait till it's broad daylight
We didn't and what is going to happen
to Lucas Beauchamp in the mean time
That's an iron door,Miss Eunice
There is a key to it
Meaning Mr Tubbs is only a man
Will Legate had 12 gates
and a shotgun inside,Mam
If enough Gowries are that keen,
enough work and they are keen
You mean if they are enough to get together
they make up a collected minds
they'll pass even Will Legate and his
12 gates and the shotgun
We will back before then
And if you are not?
He is doing the best his
judgement tells him to,Miss Eunice
You can't ask more than that
If you mean these two children and
me we are not asking anything
It's Lucas you got to trap for or cow to
No,Miss Eunice,it's none of us up to
do anything before we had some breakfast
Drink your coffee,that's a full
swelling of Mr Hampton's style
What I like to know how
the same Lucas Beauchamp
could convince me he was guilty and
convince you he was innocent
And you too
What I would like to know
what Chick and his buddy
would have done if there had
been a body in that coffin
I don't know,I hadn't thought about it
I did
Put some sugar in it child
You? You were out there too helping
digging up a white man's grave.Why?
Was it because Miss Habersham made you?
Never made me,I didn't even know that I
was going,to tell you suddenly,there I was
Why didn't I believe Lucas?
Why didn't he trust me a loyal to the truth
You are a white man,worse than that,
you are a grown white man
Yes,I've heard that before too
I heard Aleck's grandfather tell
Chick and Aleck that once
Do you want to get anything done,
don't bother the men folks with it
They are too clattered up with facts
Get the women and
children to working on it
Is that what you meant?
Why don't you drink your coffee
yourself so we can get started
It's more than that
there is a wall going up between us.
Lucas can't see through it and I won't
Maybe that's wrong
We're the ones who can't see through it
because we are the ones who are blind
Will Legate!What are you doing here ?
Morning,Miss Habersham
It is broad daylight,I got 2 miles to
walk before I can feed them
-You see?
-Who is on guard?
I'll wake Tubbs and give him a shot gun
Oh,it is all quiet over there,
I wouldn't left if it hadn't been
Are you too sure..
Miss Eunice let's finish breakfast
and get started
Mr Hampton is right,Miss Eunice,
and so are you
They'll pass even Will Legate sooner or
later when there was enough of them
But there is one thing that would stop them
Long enough,anyhow
And that is somebody without a gun
A lady
A white lady
All right but I am not going to sit
there all the morning doing nothing
so the gaoler's wife will think
she has to talk to me
I'll go home and get some mending
to do and feed the chickens
Maybe Aleck will drive me
I don't know Mum want me..
You gone this far you can go a
little further,you and me,both
I reckon so
Yes and..
Who can eat more than two eggs?
Well,we won't have the county
the sense to stay home anyway
They'd rather have
We are too late,they
are going to get him
No,not these people, I haven't seen
any of the Gowrie,not yet anywhere
-Suppose ..
-I reckon that
They are just going to town
to see something happening and wait
for the Gowries,just to wait,that's all
But suppose
Suppose we'd stop supposing
and denying either
to get out there and do what we have to do
All right,boys,jump to it,let's get
to work done and get out of here
What is going round here,sheriff?
I am going to open this grave,Mr Gowrie
No sheriff,not that grave
Yes,Mr Gowrie I am going to open it
Get back to the car boys
Never mind boys
I ain't going to hurt you,I'm
talking to the sheriff here
The boy ain't in that grave
Don't tell me the name of the fellow
that proved my boy ain't there,sheriff
It's empty
I saw it last night
Grab those shovels,sons,
they belong to the county
If we bust one,it's nobody's
business except the grand jury
What have they done with my boy
Mr Gowrie I think you knew last night
that something was wrong
You knew that Lucas would be
dead some time after midnight
or as soon as you could have got into town
But you stayed home,why?
Why,Mr Gowrie?
Uncle Charles I found some tracks come on
Here,I found them again
Here,here was the animal was hiding
And there was it stopped
Alec said it was a mule
Aleck whom? Oh
Sure,the other detectives
Yes,but did he say who it was
Somebody who couldn't or
wouldn't let Vinson rest
Had to take him out and hide him somewhere
Anywhere so we couldn't look
at the bullet and name a gun
Somebody who knew that Vinson was
never shot with Lucas Beauchamp 41 colt
It is Vinson's partner in the
lumber deal whoever that is
Because Lucas won't tell
at least not to his lawyer
You think his partner
Who is Vinson's partner?
We ain't found Vinson yet
Set your dogs to find him
Never mind the dogs
they'll trail and they'll catch anything
that ever run or walked either
But my boy never walked away
from here and never left no trail
Hush now,Mr Gowrie the man that carried
him walked all by himself from here on
And in dreadful terrifying hurry
before two boys and an old woman
who came down that hill and discovered
him at work,so he had to do it
Hide what he had to carry
and do it fast,sure and quiet
There will be no more trace
not for long time
A well or a river
-Or sand
-Yeah,what sand!
Right over the bridge,the horse
wouldn't cross last night
Quicksand
No,lawyer,put a man in
quicksand,my boy in quicksand
A man who would do a
thing like that would..
Gowrie give me a hand
Get the rope up the hound dogs
You cut a branch,any branch,
anything get him out of there
Watch it boys
Come on boys
Hurry with that branch,come on let's go
Three or four down here
Give me your hand now
Here,I found him,I've started on him
Hang up
Here,bring it on,give me the pole
Pull,pull
Easy boys
Pull
Easy boy
That's it
That's it boys
My boy,get my boy out of there
All right,boys,pull,pull now
Easy boy
Right over here boy
Here we are
Put him right here
There we are
That's Vinson all right
John,let's get him away from the road
At least get him back in the
wood so they won't see him
Steady,they all passed by now anyway
They are all in town by now
Well they had to do it too hard,
just a three and a five
Well,Mr. Gowrie,when you reckon
you don't  get somebody?
He's got to  wait on his brothers certainly
Where is your act Robert,
planting corn this morning?
Don't say that they are waiting
to be called up for jury duty
Get out of your way,Miss Habersham
I'm very comfortable the way I am
There is one way take and move
her and chair out in the yard
Or else I could do this
Please bring your step out of my
light so I can straight my needle
Miss Hamersham,I'm not touching you,you
are an old lady,but you are in the wrong
You are fighting the whole county
But you are getting tired,and when
you do get tired,we are going in
I'm going for the 80
and I'm not tired yet
Go home.
Everyone of you
Go on home
You're ought to be ashamed
I've never seen no man shoot Vinson Gowrie
But you must know who shot him
Don't you realize you'd never be safe
Not until we know who is,
not until we find him
Not until we put him right here in
your place,on this bunk,in this cell
You are a lawyer,you know the law
Can you put a man in jail if
you never seen him fire no shot?
Your case is slightly different
Can they take him out of
jail and maybe burn him
if there are only suspicions and maybe..
Listen,you were standing over a dead man
you had a recently fired
pistol in your pocket
Do you call that just suspicion?
-It was Saturday
-I know that
Why did you carry a pistol?
-Mr Carruthers
-Give it to you?
Sold it to me
-All right
-He always carry it on Saturdays
But he was a white man
So that's why,I see
When you dressed up on Saturday
you wear the pistol exactly like old
Carruthers did,just as simple as that
Downstairs in the office they got my pistol
And my hat and the toothpicks,
do I get them now or..
Lucas,last night I was wrong,you were
right and Chick was right,and I was wrong
Today I'm trying to save your life
not for your own safe since you've been
throwing it away but for my own safe
So I won't carry it on my conscious
All right
-What would you be satisfied with?
-The truth,nothing more
There were two white folks
partners in the saw mill
And one was Vinson Gowrie,
yes,and the other?
I do not sleep much nights.
So I taking to walking
Not because you suspected
anything of course
I've taken to walking and in the
dark I come near the saw mill
And then I see the light
coming straight at me
Just like I told you that there were
two folks partners in the saw mill
And one of them was dealing with lumber
every night maybe or every night he could
And he's seen me
So I know that was the end of it
Then I hear the mule
This your lumber?
Who drove that truck?
You see who drove that truck
I knew that was not him neither
Next Saturday afternoon I am on my
way over to Fraser's store
I see my Saturday supper
But I missed him
Two miles later when I come in sight of
Fraser's store there was Vinson Gowrie
He wanted to know before he beat
me just who's been stealing the lumber
Then I told him I ain't decided yet
He told me,he reckon he has
to beat it out of me then
He never did
I don't know if it was a rifle
It could have been a rifle
But I've never seen who fired it
He could have picked me out and
shut me up but he picked Vinson
Do you know why?
Because the murderer watched
you every step of the way
He saw you fire the rabbit
and missed,it was his chance
He murdered the man from
whom he stole the money
to see you lynched for
that very same murder
So he would be safe and you
and Vinson would be dead
The scheme should have worked
by every reason of geography and psychology
and the past 200 years of
this county system
In fact it did work
Except once long time ago
and partly by chance
a white boy fell into the
creek on your property
Hello,sheriff
I don't know what you have done with Lucas
but we got something out of Vinson Gowrie
Lies just right back at his breastbone
Fired by some kind of rifle
Who fired that rifle?
You forget I've not seen no rifle
But certainly you must know
or suspect or even guess
Not personally I do not want to send
any man to jail I ain't seen personally
Lucas,why don't you trust me
There is no need to
Listen to me,it wasn't your pistol,true
you did not move the body
down to the creek,true
But you try to explain the truth to a mob
who has been waiting down there
all night for something to kill
Don't you see you are not going
to be safe until we catch the murderer
All right I'll show you how to catch them
Put your right fake in the right trap
How do you propose to do that?
Give me my hat and let me go home
Can't do that
Sure we can on the strength of
this you are a free man now
But you walk out this jail and
you won't be alive 10 minutes
And you would be lucky for less
Shall I ask the sheriff to get your hat?
And the pistol and my toothpick
No,come on
I think I got to be be hiding  in there
You won't have to stay here much longer
we are going to get this whole
thing settled before dark
All right I don't mind
I've had lots of company
So I see
Lawyer
That the second time you've
been up seeing him
Yes
What can you actually do for him lawyer?
Don't we treat you better
Save his life
You ain't been paid enough
money to be able to do that,lawyer
I've been paid nothing,there are
some things you don't do for money
I'm going up to my office and
phone the District Attorney
to get him to release this man,today so
he can go home and finish his planting
Wait
So you are taking the case that is going
to defend him hope to get him out
-Yes
-And you call yourself white folk
-Mr Gowrie
-And my brother was killed by that nigger
-Lucas Beauchamp is innocent
-Not in this court
I've seen a piece of evidence that
I know would even convince you
They don't believe you
One of them does,the question is which one
-But he will be cleared out of the county
-He might
But there is one thing
he is bound to do first
He was frightened last night when
he had to dig out of his grave
the body of the man he shot, carrying
downhill to find a place to bury him again
All by himself furiously in the dark
One man against the whole
weight of the earth
What a hard that must have been
And now today every hour that
has happened since Saturday noon
must be gone together in his brain
They don't know it out there,but he does
He is lost,he is finished
He is running through his last
few pennies of freedom
And I reckon he is going to
spend the only way he knows
On revenge
You don't carry a 33 rifle
do you,Mr Gowrie?
No
Do you know anybody that does?
Yes
Sit down Mr Gowrie
Don't sit down if you don't care to but
at least get away from that window
You sent for me
You phoned me set up a
warrant see who killed my boy
He'll be here
Sooner or later before the day is over
he will come to kill Lucas Beauchamp
I don't see Lucas Beauchamp neither
Now you do
-Is that his wife?
-That his wife,she is dead
Two years now
Maybe three
Mine been gone twenty five years
The day the twins was borne
Raising all them boys by yourself is hard
Five boys
That wasn't shot with no 41 colt
Come on out here you black nigger
Wait a minute
Get out of the way
You need help
I don't want no help
I'll do it myself
Pa,you ain't got no business here
Pa,get out of the way
Put down that gun
Is this the gun that killed
your brother Vinson?
Is he the one,sheriff?
That's right,he is the one
The man who killed his brother
Ask him
Is that right,Nub!
That's right,he killed him
They are running away
There is more than that
No,that's all,there is nothing left to do
than to admit that they are wrong
So they are riding away
It's worse than that
Then they are running from Lucas Beauchamp
-No
-Yes
They won't even wait to
buy him a can of tobacco
to show him getting for
all the trouble he cost
Then what's the hurry? They know they
got the rest of their lives to do that
From coffins,so they wont have to bury him,
they are running away from coffins
Not from Lucas and not from coffins
Well,they are running,you can't change that
No,I can't change that
They are running away from themselves
Hi,Miss Eunice what's the hurry?
I got to get home to my chickens but
if you ever get trouble again let me know
You see,we were in trouble,
not Lucas Beauchamp
It's all right,Chick
-Is it?
-It will be all right
So long some of us,you,Miss Habersham,
and Aleck and maybe me
or even so long one of us,
someone of us doesn't run away
-Uncle John
-Chick
It's a fine Saturday afternoon
why don't you go to the ball games
Lucas is coming here
Well,he is a gentleman,he won't tell
me in the face I was wrong
Come in Lucas
Young man you seldom go fishing lately
I'm waiting for you getting nice new ...
You are welcome whether
it is frozen or not
Have a seat Lucas
I believe you got a little bill against me
Not me I didn't do anything
That boy there is the reason
you are walking around today
All right,I'll pay him
You can't,he'll be practising
law without a licence
I'll pay your expenses then
The only expense I had
was having this fixed
-How much?
-2 $
2 $
That don't seem that much to me
First I'm a farming man use a law man
I don't reckon it is my business
to try to learn yours
-That is one dollar in four bits
-Never mind that
That makes it out four bits in pennies
I was aiming to take them to the bank
but you could save me the trouble
-You want to count them?
-Yes,but you are paying,you count them
There is 50 of them
This is business
As long as you are paying your debts
,go and see Miss Habersham
15,20 I ain't much of a visiting man
You could bring her some flowers
I've had no flowers to speak
of since Molly died
Chick's mother will fetch
some of your garden
You owe her that much,Lucas
She is the only lady anywhere that
ever held a jail full of threats
All right,anything more to satisfy you
Just one thing more
Why didn't you tell me the truth?
That night in the jail
Would you have believed me?
No,what what are you waiting for now?
My receipt
They don't see him as though
it never happened
They see him
No,they don't know that he is even there
But they do same as I do,they
always will as long as he lives
Proud,stubborn,insufferable but
there he goes keep on my conscience
Our conscience,Uncle John
Subtitles by Seglora