INVISIBLE WAVES
That's for Noi?
Oh, yes.
You know her too.
You're going to ask her to marry you?
Tonight.
Compliments of the boss.
I still think this place is creepy.
I hate seeing those machines.
Something smells great!
Dinner's almost ready.
I meant you.
Let's skip dinner...
... and have dessert now.
Oh, but I think you'll enjoy dinner more.
You've been working too long
for my husband.
You're starting to talk like him.
I have to stir the sauce.
I love it when you talk like that!
Seiko, the sauce will be ruined
if I don't stir it.
That's okay.
I like my sauce medium-ruined.
Well, that was delicious, darling...
... as always.
Did you have enough?
I might have room for something more.
I made chocolate mousse.
Oh well, there's room for that too.
I'll get some more wine.
Okay, darling. You're the boss.
Oh, wait a minute.
Actually, you're not the boss.
Oops, sorry darling.
Come on, get the mousse and hurry back.
Oh, I like this.
Let's turn it up a bit, okay?
The neighbors won't mind, will they?
I have only one neighbor.
She won't mind.
You don't look like
your father at all, you know?
You still don't have a TV?
What do you do when you're alone?
I sleep.
But how do you know
what's going on in the world?
I already know.
There's always war.
You are so cynical, darling.
Kiss me.
Are you drunk?
Why? You gonna take advantage
of me if I'm drunk?
You still have to eat your mousse.
Good morning.
W RESTAURANT
The restaurant's closed.
Go home.
Good morning, boss.
You want some cigarette?
No, thanks. I don't feel so good.
Go home and pack.
Kyoji!
You have a good vacation.
Hello.
I am Kyoji.
Do you know me?
No, I don't know you.
But I know why you're here.
You are a little bit early.
Come worship first.
I'll be with you later.
Did you pray?
No.
Why not?
I didn't come here for that.
I see.
You came here for this, I believe.
I think so.
Everything you want is inside there.
The ticket, the money, the documents.
I'll send you more money...
... when you're in Phuket.
This is very important
Your life now depends on it.
Lizard's contact number is inside.
Lizard?
Yes, from now on...
... he's the one you'll have to contact.
Any problem...
... contact Lizard.
Remember, Lizard.
Only Lizard.
He's your man.
Your only contact with the past.
Can you give this to the boss?
Okay, I'll take care of it.
Have a good life.
Are you really a monk?
My father was.
Hi, Maria.
Oh, you're back.
What did you do
to your apartment last night?
It smells horrible!
Leave the door open.
Can I wash up at your place?
Sure, go ahead.
I'll make dinner tonight.
So, you're leaving tomorrow, huh?
That's a big surprise.
Are you all ready.
I guess.
My boy's always ready.
What do you think about leaving?
I'm going to miss you.
I know.
I'll write to you.
From the ship?
Okay. I'll wait for that.
Hello? Are you Lizard?
I'm leaving now.
Bon Voyage.
When I get to Phuket I'll call you.
Have a good life.
Can I help you, sir?
I think you got the wrong room, sir.
I can show you your room.
Follow me, please.
Wha...? What the...?
What in the...?
May we have your attention please.
Universal Cruise will depart
Hong Kong shortly.
May we have your attention please.
Universal Cruise will depart
Hong Kong shortly.
Lunch will be served shortly
at all of our restaurants...
... Galaxy Cuisine, Tropical Cuisine,
Planet Café, and Moonlight Diner.
Please enjoy your dinner
at the closest restaurant to your cabin...
... or at any of the restaurants as you wish.
May we have your attention, please?
In a few minutes
there will be an emergency drill.
This is the mandatory procedure
for all cruises with passengers.
It is for your own safety.
When the drill is heard,
please gather in the lobby.
We will then divide you into small groups
for a twenty minute-lecture...
Not afraid of dying?
What?
You don't go to safety lecture.
So...
I thought maybe you are not afraid to die.
How about you?
What?
You're not afraid?
Oh, I am afraid to die, yeah.
Why are you here?
I... I need some air.
Me too.
Yes, I can tell you need air.
You look like... ah...
... you are seeing a ghost.
A ghost?
Hey! What are you doing here?
Who left you alone like this?
Where's your mommy, huh?
Nid, mummy's back.
You.
Good morning.
Your baby?
You left your baby alone?
No. I left her with you.
With me?
But I am a stranger.
I was sleeping.
So?
So... is that safe?
I only went to the pool for a few minutes.
What time is it?
I don't know... Between nine and noon.
Where's your husband?
He should take care of the baby.
No husband.
No husband?
Not really.
Not really? Why?
Why what?
Sorry, not my business.
He's just not here on this ship.
You are here just with your baby?
My boyfriend is a very busy man.
This trip is a gift to me.
You enjoy traveling alone with your baby?
It's okay.
You alone too?
Yes.
You want to take a swim?
No. Not really.
Good.
What?
I want to swim.
Not long.
Please.
Thank you.
What is her name?
Nid.
- What's your name?
- Noi.
Noi?
What's your name?
My name is Kyoji.
Okay... Uncle Kyoji.
Let's go swimming.
Open it!
Why'd you lock me in here?
Hey, is somebody out there?
Hey!
What are you doing?
Good afternoon, reception.
Can I help you?
Err... Yes.
I am calling from 96M.
I am in the room.
I cannot get out.
You cannot get out from inside?
Yes, inside the room.
You cannot get out from inside the room?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Do you have your room key, sir?
Yes I have key...
... but I cannot use my key
because I'm in the room.
- In the room?
- Yes.
I want to get out.
Do you want to get inside the room?
Or you cannot get out from inside the room?
No, no, no... I said I'm in the room.
- lnside the room?
- Yes.
Just get someone down here
and open the door, please.
- You want to get inside?
- No.
- I'm inside the room.
- That's very strange, sir.
Normally people cannot get
inside the room. We've never...
Good afternoon, sir.
Hello? Is this room 96M?
Hello.
I am still in my room!
Have you sent anybody here?
Can you identify yourself?
We'd like to know who you are.
- Me?
- Are you the guest of the room, sir.
I am Kyoji Hamamura...
... in room 96M!
96M?
I've just called to tell you.
Do you have your key?
Yes!...I have my key!
You can't get in your room?
Or you can't get out of your room?
I already told you everything!
You mean you locked yourself inside?
Come and let me out, please.
Well, let me see what we can do, sir.
Hey! Excuse me!
I am in room 96M.
Uh... Could you help me?
Uh... I cannot get out.
Hey!
Someone in there?
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Ah, I can not get out.
Please help me.
Somebody called.
Please. Please.
You can't get out from inside?
Yes. Yes.
Just a minute. I'll go get someone.
Yes, please.
I called the receptionist many times!
You never came.
Sorry, sir. We are busy at the moment.
Busy?
Thank you for your help.
Oh, it's okay.
Be careful of the door.
Thank you.
What was wrong with my door?
Well... seemed like the lock snapped, sir.
- Snapped?
- Yes, some kind of accident.
Maybe old lock.
Accident?
I don't think so.
I think someone locked me inside.
- Someone?
- Yes.
Who, sir?
I don't know.
I think old lock, sir.
But should be okay now.
Will there be anything else, sir?
You can go.
Excuse me.
Kyoji Hamamura!
I can't believe it! It's really you!
Do I know you?
Know me?
Don't you remember me?
Oh! I'm hurt!
Sorry.
We went to school together!
Really? The same school?
You have such a bad memory!
Come on...
- Not exactly.
- Where you headed?
I have to go and meet someone.
But you're meeting me!
It's a lot more exciting!
You don't look too happy to see me.
Well, I'm a bit busy.
You really don't remember?
Sorry...
Hideki!
You haven't seen me for fifteen years...
... and you tell me you're too busy to chat?
So how are you?
I can't believe that of all places
we meet again on this ship.
Even the sea can seem so small.
Hideki?
Yes! Now you remember?
And how is your brother?
Married? Kids?
To be honest I still don't think
we know each other.
But you are Kyoji Hamamura, right?
Yes, but...
From Osaka, yes?
Yes. But now I live in Macau.
Macau? Wow! Great.
We went to school together?
Yes. Now you remember?
Those were the days.
Sneaking off to read manga
on the way to school.
- In Osaka?
- Yep.
I never went to school in Osaka.
I don't think I am who you think I am.
You're Kyoji Hamamura!
Maybe you know another
Kyoji Hamamura that looks like me.
How could that be?
But I remember you...
Really, you got the wrong guy.
No, no. I'm sure it's you.
I still don't think we know each other.
But you are Kyoji Hamamura, right?
Yeah, but...
I'm sure it's you.
How are your kids?
Are they wearing braces yet?
Look, I don't know you.
Must be my mistake.
I told you.
Sorry about that. So long.
Uh, no, no, no. No wine.
Sorry, sir. What are you going to have?
Have anything non-alcoholic?
- Are you Japanese?
- Yes.
Just a moment.
Everything we serve is non-alcoholic...
except the alcohol, sir.
I guess that's true.
Okay, give me milk.
- Milk, sir?
- Yes.
Such an innocent drink
for someone like you.
Someone like me?
I don't mean to be rude, sir.
I mean, you seem a very experienced man.
I don't understand.
Forgive me, sir.
I make no sense.
That's why they put me here.
You enjoy your cruise so far, sir?
To be honest, no.
I see. That's why you come
to the bar so early.
Why did you decide to take
this cruise, sir? Vacation?
Not really. Somebody arranged it for me.
I see. Like you won a prize?
No. Well... yeah. Something like that.
Sorry for asking too much, sir.
You like your job here?
To be honest, no, sir.
No?
In fact, I hate it, sir.
Why do you do it then?
Well, this may sound strange to you...
... but I'm doing it to atone
for the sins of my life, sir.
What?
Yes, well, you see, sir...
... I was a very troubled teenager
and caused my folks many worries.
Troubled?
Yes, sir.
Drugs and stealing, things like that.
A bad ass, you know, sir?
But then I wised up.
I decided I'd do something unpleasant
as punishment for my past.
I see.
My folks had been so nice to me.
They never punished me and I got spoiled.
So I took this job to punish myself.
Now I never get to see anyone...
... but it's probably for the best
I think I understand.
May I ask you something, sir?
Go ahead.
Did you love your father, sir?
My father?
Did you think he was a good man, sir?
Good man?
Maybe.
But... I wouldn't know much
about being a good man.
I am not such a good man myself.
Maybe my father was better than me.
I think you are a good man, sir.
How long will you keep
punishing yourself on this ship?
I am not sure, sir.
I do like the sea.
The sea?
You don't find it boring?
No.
I like the feeling that
the sea isn't judging me.
I just look at it, and it just looks at me.
Strange...
What's that, sir?
It judges me all the time.
Hello, Uncle Kyoji.
Uncle Kyoji
Want to dance?
Hi.
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
You look awful!
I'm sorry.
Want to dance?
What about the baby?
We all dance together.
Okay.
It's getting late.
I will take Nid back to the room
and go to sleep.
I think I'll stay here for a while.
Goodnight, Uncle Kyoji.
It was nice dancing with you.
- Good night.
Hey!
Hey, Noi!
Yes?
Can I have your number or address?
If you don't mind.
Well, I will be in Hong Kong...
You have a phone there?
Yes, a mobile phone.
That's fine.
Do you have a pen?
You can write on this.
Oh, I love it when a man gives me money.
Turn around.
Okay, finished.
Thanks.
- Bye.
Don't spend my number!
I will not.
Hey, Mister.
Where you going?
I don't know, actually.
You looking for girls? Or food?
Maybe a hotel. Cheap hotel.
No problem. Phuket many cheap hotels.
No luggage?
No. Just this.
Hey, hey. Wait, wait wait.
Flower for you.
Welcome to Thailand and Phuket!
Thanks.
Check, please.
Please...
This is very good and cheap place.
This woman is Wilai.
She take good care of you.
Wilai!
Hurry!
Hello, welcome.
How many nights you want?
Oh, I don't know. For a while.
I give you good room.
Five hundred baht a night.
You pay for tonight now.
Okay.
Oh, sorry, I don't have Thai money.
It's okay. What do you have?
- Hong Kong dollar?
- Hong Kong dollar.
It's okay, give me hundred.
Here's your key. Room 33.
No, no. Not that one, sorry.
There.
Tonight. You want sightseeing?
I take you a special price.
- Here, this is my card.
- Thank you.
You call me if you want go outside.
Oh, sorry, sorry, mister. I forget!
I take flower.
Welcome to Phuket!
Excuse me.
Hey!
Excuse me. Do you have stamps?
No, you can buy at 7-1 1.
Oh, okay.
Hello, my friend.
Over there.
Hong Kong money, Mama.
500.
500. No commission.
Excuse me.
Where is room 33?
Hello.
Hello?
Excuse me.
Did you see anyone come down here?
Who?
Someone. I don't know.
No, I don't see any.
Can I change room?
What's the problem?
Er... Bad bed.
Bed?
No need to change the room.
I come fix for you.
Okay.
Hello.
Why do you call me here?
I told you not to...
Sorry, boss. I'm in trouble.
I was robbed.
You were robbed?
Yes, last night.
In Thailand?
Everything's gone. I have no money.
I have nothing.
I lost Lizard's number.
That's why I call you.
Are you still in Phuket?
Yes.
Alright.
I know some people down there.
So I'm going to make a few calls, okay?
Call me back in two hours time.
But call me at the restaurant.
Do not call this me here, get it?
Thanks, boss.
You take care, now.
Forty baht, forty baht. Who took it?
Did anyone see it?
It was right here.
Who took the forty baht?
Uh, I'd like to make
a collect call to Hong Kong.
The number is 231 18081. 8-1, yes.
For Mr. Wiwat.
Kyoji Hamamura.
- Hello?
- I found someone to help you out.
He can meet you at 4.
He can lend you some money...
... and may be help you
with some other things.
Do you know the Pearl Hotel?
No.
Well, it's very well-known.
Just ask around, okay.
He's going to meet you at the hotel bar.
How will he know me?
Just get there on time.
Okay.
Boss, uh...
I don't know if I want to live here...
We can talk about this later.
Right now you have
to stay away for awhile.
How's everything over there?
Everything's fine. I can handle it.
You go out and get your money,
eat some crab, fuck a Thai girl.
Just relax, okay?
Okay, boss.
Kyoji.
Everything will be all right.
Look, how many times do I have to tell you.
Put the beet root on top of the lettuce.
What would you like to drink?
You talking to me?
No...
... I'm talking to the pineappple next to you.
You are Kyoji, aren't you?
You are...
Your boss sent me.
So, what's it gonna be?
Err... milk.
Of course.
A glass of milk, please.
You are Japanese.
You expected a Thai man?
Sorry to disappoint you.
You from Japan?
Yeah, but enough about me.
You don't look so good, man.
Well, I have had some trouble.
So your boss told me.
Anyway, cheers!
What did the boss say?
Not much.
To give you money. Take care of you a bit.
He told you who I am?
Why, is it a secret?
C'mon, man, don't be so paranoid.
You're not in Hong Kong anymore.
Why worry so much?
Guess I'm just tired.
Bet you are. You look like shit.
The boss told me
you might settle down here.
Maybe open a restaurant.
Don't know yet.
That was the original plan.
Well, it's not a bad place.
I gather you're quite a good chef.
Did the boss tell you all this?
Who else?
We are not so different, you and l.
I know what it's like to be in your shoes.
I was there once myself.
Your boss is very generous.
That is, if you're loyal.
Did you get the job done?
I guess so.
Good. Then I guarantee the boss
will take good care of you.
I've never known such a big-hearted man.
That is...
... as long as you're loyal to him.
He also promised me freedom.
Freedom, yes.
Do you like karaoke?
I don't sing well.
Ah, but it's not about singing anyway.
It's a great invention...
... probably the best thing
Japan's ever given to the world.
Think about it.
Karaoke's such a great concept.
The music itself is empty...
but when you who hold the microphone
you're the one who fills it with substance.
Want to?
No, thanks.
Sure? C'mon.
Really, it's okay.
Alright then.
I hope you don't mind if I do.
I want to give you a welcome song.
Hope you enjoyed that.
It's my gift to you.
Yes, thanks.
Well, I guess you're anxious to get
your stuff and get back to your hotel.
Yes.
Very well.
It's not a lot...
... but since it was kind of sudden,
it was all I could get today.
Come back here tomorrow
and I'll give you more.
Tomorrow, same time?
Yes, that okay?
It's fine.
Good.
And this milk?
Oh, don't be silly. It's on me.
Oh, thanks.
Alright man.
See ya. And get a haircut!
I guess you want the top floor.
Where did he go?
You!
What are you doing up there?
Where?
On the truck.
Truck?
Are you all right?
What happened?
I don't know.
How are you?
Fine...
You want to come down?
Down?
From the truck.
Thank you.
What happened to you?
You look like you need help.
Where is Nid?
She's sleeping at the hotel.
You're going to be alright?
Yes...
... I miss Nid.
She misses you too.
You want to go see her?
Yes.
I have to go change first.
- You know?
- Yeah.
You have to change.
I have to change.
Okay.
Hello.
Hello, Khun Noi.
(Note.. Khun is like Madame in Thai)
- Yes?
- Somebody waiting for you.
Somebody waiting for me?
Yeah.
In the lobby.
Okay.
You go ahead. Room number 29.
I'll be right back.
There you are.
Hello again. Long time no see.
Time for a city tour!
It's hot out there.
Who are you?
What?
You are Lizard.
You're not so stupid after all.
The boss sent you to get rid of me.
Nah.
He sent me on vacation, just like you.
You were on the cruise?
I've been babysitting you, my man.
Why?
Not because I like you, that's for sure.
Why get rid of me? I did my job.
And what job was that?
Screwing Madame Seiko?
He was going to get rid of me
no matter what.
Why?
You must be the stupidest
smart guy I have ever met.
Okay...
... Iet me tell you
a little fucking fairy tale, alright?
There was a man.
He had an affair with his boss's wife.
He got caught.
And just to save himself...
... he agreed to kill the woman
he'd been fucking.
By the way...
... this man was a real selfish bastard.
Did he think killing Madame Seiko
would solve his problem?
Did he think it would be that simple?
Anyway...
... we are writing the ending
of this tale as we speak.
Remember what I said about loyalty?
Once you break it there's no going back.
Sorry.
What about Noi?
Well, all I can say is...
... you weren't supposed to meet her.
She was also sent on vacation.
Just to clear things out
at home first, you know?
You're a real trouble maker, aren't you?
Creating problems for yourself
wherever you go.
Even at sea!
She's the boss's girl?
None of our business.
And the baby?
Would you shut up and let me sing?
Now you're going to shoot me?
Well, I could...
... but I'm a bit tired tonight.
So I'm just going to ask you nicely
to step into the sack.
Then you'll shoot me.
Actually, I'm not going to do anything.
My boy there will do it.
And then throw me in the sea or what?
You really are a good guesser.
Eventually they'll find my body
and it might lead them to the boss.
You don't think we're just going to
throw you into the sea, do you?
These boys may not look it...
... but they're experts in their field.
Sorry, man.
I actually kind of like you.
Then again...
I've done this to people I liked before.
Okay!
Kindly step into the sack.
The stupider he gets the more I like him!
Why did you make me do this?
I'm so fuckin' depressed.
I need a microphone.
Hey, Mister Ghost.
Did you sleep well?
As a dead person,
I have to say you look quite healthy!
I was just reading about
my own death in the paper.
When I kept this I didn't know that
I'm keeping it for you.
Were you sad?
Did you cry?
I was a bit upset.
Just a bit?
Well, my mind is very well-trained,
you know.
But last night when I saw you,
I really thought I see a ghost.
But you didn't seem so scared.
I wasn't.
Why not?
You're not afraid of ghosts?
Not if you were the ghost.
And when I thought you were dead
I kept asking you to come back and see me.
Well... I'm here.
Are you hungry, darling?
I'm fine. Don't worry about me.
Now that you have come back to life,
and you have come back home.
What do you want to do?
I haven't come back to life.
I'm not going to come back to life.
Why don't we have dinner
somewhere nice tonight?
I'd love to... but I have a friend to visit.
So soon?
Why wait?
Hey...
... you never wrote to me from Thailand
like what you said you would.
No time to buy stamps.
Hello, darling!
Hello honey. Are you still jogging?
Yes, I'm still here but I'm going back soon.
Listen, I'm cooking some Thai food tonight.
You're going to cook?
- You'd like that?
- Great!
- Anyway, see you at home. Bye.
- Okay. See ya!
It's already loaded.
I'll get it.
Is he dead?
Let me in.
How did you get up here?
There are ways.
Step back.
You know, you look great tonight.
Are you going to
a dinner party somewhere?
This... is my dinner party.
Would you like some wine then?
I want to talk first.
Sit down.
Listen, I have to stir the soup...
... otherwise it's gonna get burned.
No.
Come on.
What do you think I'm going to do?
Attack you?
I'm not going to do anything. I promise.
Stop.
Kyoji...
Don't you trust me?
Of course not.
Oh well...
... then why don't you stir the soup for me?
Okay?
Smells good, doesn't it.
- Listen, why don't you have some cigars?
- No.
Just stay there.
Did you enjoy your vacation?
Don't try to be funny.
So you've come to kill me?
Yes.
Why didn't you stay away?
Why do you want to start up trouble again?
Because you must be punished.
You know, I like you.
You were quite a fine cook.
You are also a pretty good chef.
But you are an evil man.
Evil?
Pretty harsh word.
You didn't have to kill me.
It was bad enough that
you hired me to kill your wife.
But you also betrayed me.
Betrayed you?
As far as I remember...
... you were the one who was
fucking my wife behind my back...
... for months.
And now you come to me
and talk about betrayal?
You could have just killed me
for having the affair.
That, I would understand.
But I murdered someone!
Because of you!
Murder!
Okay, calm down.
We had a deal.
Yes, we did.
And then you broke the deal.
I didn't know I was going to be killed.
Well... it's cause and effect.
You do something bad and then
something bad happens to you in return.
Simple as that.
Exactly.
And that is why I am here tonight.
I'm the something bad
that's gonna happen to you now.
Hey, cigar?
No.
Well?
It's fine.
It's great.
It's pretty good.
I am in love.
That's why I've been so happy lately.
I'm not the type of person
who's afraid of death...
... but right now...
... I really want to enjoy
my new happiness...
... with my girl.
That's for Noi?
Oh, yes.
You know her too.
You're going to ask her to marry you?
Tonight.
Are you going to shoot me with that gun?
It's gonna be messy.
No, I've brought something else.
That's better.
Very appropriate for a chef.
It's the same bottle I used to kill Seiko.
You sure you don't want some wine?
No.
You know, we don't have to do this.
All can be forgotten and all can be happy.
I can never be happy again.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
Hey, darling, come here!
I can't.
Come on!
No, really I can't. You stay inside.
Nid just said something...
Oh my god!
You!
Hello Noi.
Well, I guess there's no need
for introduction.
What are you doing here?
Kyoji just came over to help us
make some soup. Right?
With that gun?
Why are you doing this?
Does she know?
Not everything.
What?
What is that?
It's for you.
You got that for me?
Yes.
But you're not supposed
to see it until after dessert.
It's beautiful.
What's going on?
Is this some kind of joke?
Yes, it's a joke.
It's not funny.
I'm sorry.
I have a weird sense of humor.
Would you like some wine now?
Oh sure.
Honey, would you pour us
some wine, please?
Maybe we can see you
some other time soon.
Some other time.
Do you have stamps?
Stamps?
Hello, old friend.
I was waiting for you.
To tell you the truth,
I'm really lazy tonight.
Not in the mood
for this sort of thing at all.
How about karaoke?
That's exactly what I was doing...
... when the boss called.
You are very loyal.
That is one thing I'm proud of.
Good for you.
I have nothing to be proud of yet.
You plan to go back home and sleep?
And tomorrow start a new life?
Not exactly.
I'm just going to take a walk.
There is no home to go back to.
You know this walk
has to end sometime, right?
I know.
And it will end soon.
Yes.
But will you let it end?
How many times
have you crossed this water?
A lot.
Will you miss it?
I guess either I will find out now...
... or else I'll never know.
You sorry you didn't get your revenge?
I realized I have nothing to get revenge for.
No one really hurt me.
Not even the boss?
No...
... he just didn't let me know
certain things...
... that I should have known myself.
You could have killed him tonight.
Sure, I could've.
I wanted to.
Why didn't you?
He seemed so happy. Very happy.
That's your reason for not getting revenge?
Who do you think deserves to live more?
A happy man...
... or a homeless ghost?
I see.
In a way, I envy you.
About what?
I always wonder what the end will be like.
You're about to know.
You think it really matters?
Yes, it does...
... but I'm in no rush to be sure.
Right.
It's getting late.
I don't want to keep you.
It's my pleasure.
But...
... I guess it's gotta end sometime.
Any last words?
Could you mail this postcard for me?
I'll leave it right here.
No problem.
Have you put a stamp on it?
It helps.