In order to set up a holding company,
you're required to provide
your retina scan, fingerprints, and DNA.
What's the DNA for?
'Cause you can get your retina
and fingerprints transplanted.
VEGA'S FILMS HAVE MADE
$112,000,000
Mr. PATRYK,
what do you intend
to spend the funds on?
PATRYK...
We won't pass together. I'll go first...
and you'll follow on my mark...
you'll follow me, you hear me?
You'll manage.
Don't look down.
Don't look...
Don't think about it...
Don't look down.
- Mom!
- I'm good, son!
Everything's fine.
Very well, son.
Your turn. Slowly, slowly...
On your knees...
Yes. Proceed slowly.
Hang on.
Don't look... Look at me...
Look at me... PATRYK...
Don't think about the height.
Look at me.
Move slowly.
Like that.
Nice.
Wait.
Listen... I wouldn't have let you go
if I hadn't known you'd manage.
You can't move back,
or you'll fall.
You must move on.
You can do it.
Because you're the best.
I believe in you.
Do you?
Yes, son.
Do you really?
Yes, I believe in you, son.
I believe in you.
Come.
Almost there.
Why don't I have a father?
- Why are you asking?
- All children do.
He's gone to the States for work.
He hasn't come back.
I'll find him, when I grow up.
Stay here.
Mom, please! Let me out!
I'll never say that again, I promise.
- What are you writing, grandpa?
- A movie title.
- What movie?
- The one I've seen at the cinema lately.
In this notebook,
I write down the title
of every movie I see.
The date of its production,
its cast, and the director's name.
Wanna go to the movies?
- Pick the flowers.
- Why?
There you go.
Now you can afford the tickets.
Will we come here again?
This is Elżbieta.
Your father's new wife.
I brought you a gift
from your dad.
These blocks are very expensive. They're
worth a few of my monthly salaries.
I'll unpack them.
Put them in two bags.
Mix them with Polish blocks.
And I'll sell them as two sets.
- Where are the spaceship's wings?
- They're here somewhere.
When I grow up,
I'll take care of you.
You won't have to work ever again.
You're already taking care of me. Son.
Thank you.
- Grandpa...
- So he's gone?
Mom, I'm to recite a poem
during a school ceremony.
Don't worry about it.
We'll cover it with a sweater.
And remember:
- you're the best.
- At what?
At everything.
When I grow up, I'll marry you.
Okay.
- Take it off.
- Do I have to?
Everyone's wearing shirts.
You look odd.
Soldier... I look into your eyes...
and remember your noble struggle
for the glory of our homeland...
What have you done? You've ruined
the whole performance! So much work!
I want to borrow it.
HOW TO MANIPULATE
This one!
This car, please.
- You want it? I'll buy it for you.
- I don't want it.
- Don't be shy. I'll get you one.
- No.
- Take it. Auntie wants to buy it for you.
- Why not?
- I don't want it.
Okay.
Come.
Why didn't you want that car?
I wanted to see what she'd do,
if I did something unpredictable.
Know what, mom?
Make me some soft-boiled eggs.
Okay.
Or fried.
Or hard-boiled.
You know me too well.
Yes!
Diego!
Diego Armando Maradona!
I'll be a new Maradona!
I'll be the best soccer player
in the world! We'll be rich!
I told you! I told you, Pacio, didn't I!
Yes! Yes!
I'm done playing.
- Why?
- 'Cause I won't be the best.
What are you gonna do?
I'll make millions in another way.
Perhaps, I'll become a rock singer.
Or my hair
in the 7 colors of the rainbow.
This way, or another,
I'm doomed to be successful.
A rock singer. Great.
Hi.
- Hi.
- What's that?
- What do you think? King Diamond.
- Don't you listen to metal?
This is Ole from Sweden.
He wants me to go there with him.
Pacio...
It's my chance to make a lot of money.
You'll stay with Aunt Gosia.
I want a pentagram etched on the front.
And an inverted cross on the back.
You know what I'll buy you
with all the money I've made?
- What?
- A computer!
- I'll be the first kid in class that has one.
- Yes!
Can I have this cassette?
Mom!
Why should I pay for it,
if they can pay me?
- I wanna buy games from you.
- Which ones? - All of them.
I wanna sell them.
Will you help me set up my stand?
Maniek is a hacker. He has a modem and
gets the latest stuff for the entire Fair.
- Hi.
That's all for today.
- See you.
- Copy this.
Show some respect.
What's up?
I want to cut off the entire Fair
from computer novelties.
I'll pay five times more than they do
for exclusivity.
We need the new stuff
before the weekend.
State your price.
There's no good price.
From now on, you'll buy them from me
no sooner than on Saturday.
And remember: I'm like a shark.
- What'd you mean?
- I can't tell a friend from food.
- What's new on the list?
- There you go.
See if the cheese is good,
so that Kubuś won't get the squirts.
It's okay.
This is the future.
5-10-15?
Computer animations.
I'll learn how to make them,
and I'll earn a fortune.
I'll make an intro for them.
Okay.
With us is PATRYK, the maker of the
computer-generated intro we've just seen.
- Is it difficult to make?
- A 3D animation is like making a movie.
Objects are your actors,
you plan the camera movement,
set the light, select the textures of the
materials you overlay the objects with.
- Who taught you that?
- I'm self-taught.
PATRYK has just been entered
into the Guinness Book of Records
as the youngest creator
of professional computer-generated intros.
What are you doing?
I have no heart to whack it
with a hammer.
I'm waiting for it to drown.
Your father is coming to Poland.
He wants to see you.
Shall I let him?
Let him give you money
for a new computer.
He hasn't given a shit about us
his entire life.
The only thing he sent you from America
was Lego blocks and powdered milk.
Let him feel responsible now.
What do you like, PATRYK?
I make computer animations. I'm planning
to buy an Amiga 3000 computer.
When I have it, I'll start making
professional intros for television
- and earn a lot of money.
- What will you have?
Tiramisu.
- Same for me.
- Very well.
Help me buy that computer.
How much is it?
4,000 dollars.
I can send you the money
in two months.
- Anything from my father?
- No.
He was to have sent
the money two months ago.
- Write him.
- That he let me down again...
And that I don't want to see him again.
Pacio...
I'll take out a loan.
I'll buy you that computer.
The loan has worked out so bad for you,
because we've had
a redenomination in Poland today.
Meaning?
A currency reform introducing
a new monetary unit
to replace the old one.
One new Polish Zloty is
an equivalent of 10,000 old ones.
It's processing really slow.
10 seconds will take a week.
In September, I'll take my new animation
to the TVP. We'll start making millions.
I hope.
Or we'll have huge problems.
I'd like to show you my animation.
Great, but my priority is to secure jobs
of those working for the television.
Perhaps I could do
an extra job for you.
- We're not seeking cooperation.
- I thought... - I must be going.
Another thing worth mentioning
in terms of the narration style
was the application
of black-and-white photos in the movie.
But a director of Spielberg's caliber
could afford
- this type of innovations in the cinema.
- Where did you find this review?
- What do you mean?
- What did you copy it from?
- I wrote it myself.
- Impossible.
- The bitch thinks I stole it.
- How can she?
I don't know. Keep watch.
I have a great idea.
We'll take out a loan.
We'll buy a stolen vehicle
and resell it for profit.
- Will you give me a receipt for the money?
- Sure.
And I'll write
in it the car's been stolen.
Don't worry.
The money's no longer yours.
Okay.
- Where's the car?
- There's no car. - How come?
- Kazek took the money. He's off the grid.
- Pay it back. I took out a loan.
- What do I have to do with it?
- You recommended him.
We've been in the same school
for 5 years.
You shouldn't have given him the money.
I have a friend who knows a mafia guy.
They say he hates redheads.
Perhaps, he'll help us.
There's one more important thing.
He has red hair.
We'll take him to the woods.
Where's my money?
Ask the Wołomin gang.
What do you mean?
Uh-huh...
I get it.
They said the money's not good enough
for them to go to war with Wołomin.
Okay, since he couldn't be kidnapped...
I'll go see his mother.
- You had my son taken out to the woods.
- Your son and Wołomin robbed my son.
I get it.
But it's not right.
Let's find some solution
together, like mothers.
How?
You sell baguets, you can
pay me off in monthly instalments.
Cheers.
If you wanna have a drink,
bring your buddies home.
I don't want you to drink
out in the bushes.
Want some?
Are you coming with us
to booze at Zegrze, Kulpa?
We'll take my Syrena.
- What about your trash?
- I'll bring a can for it tomorrow.
Wanna go to Zegrze like this?
My transmission's blown.
I can only drive in reverse.
Look at that bum.
Let's search him.
Give us the mullah.
- Shut the fuck up and give us your money.
- Okay, he's had enough.
- He has this.
- What's this key for?
A locker at the Central Train Station.
I have a hunch. We'll find
a million dollars in that suitcase.
What's in there?
Fucking grunt.
Wanna make a million dollars?
Start dealing drugs.
I know a guy who has amphetamine.
Wanna start dealing?
Got it? How much?
- Two.
- Got a lot of it?
No dealing outside my club
without my consent.
I started dealing amphetamine.
This is for you, mom.
Thank you, son.
I no longer have anyone
to borrow from.
Can I go to Sweden?
There's a school trip.
- Let's steal some perfume.
- No way.
Fuck you.
Sweden, Karlskrona
Open your backpack, please.
You'll come with us.
I'm an interpreter.
- Tell me what I should do.
- Tell the truth.
Okay.
I confess.
I stole that perfume.
What's gonna happen to me?
Will I go to prison in Sweden?
The Swedish police assume the crime
was committed on Polish waters.
You'll be deported to Poland.
The local police will take you over.
You'll make the return trip
in a detention cabin.
Do you confess?
Yes.
Sign here.
God must've been watching over you.
Why?
They've changed the law
regarding forced entry
and aggravated larceny.
Last month you would've gone
straight to jail.
And now?
You'll be awaiting trial at home.
Jesus...
thank you for saving me from jail.
I'm begging you to forgive me.
I'll never do it again.
Jesus, I fail at everything.
I no longer know what to do in life.
I'm begging you... tell me...
I did something stupid.
I got drunk and made a mistake.
I don't want to waste my life.
Will you ask the school
board not to expel me?
If I convince them...
what will you do with your life?
I'll make movies.
What movies?
The first time I killed a man,
I threw up.
The second time, I had lunch.
Cut! Awesome!
The fuck you're looking at?
Got a problem, punk?
Next time, remember
to say 'excuse me'.
Excuse me.
Punk-ass sucker.
Dump the piece.
The dude will call the cops.
Fuck off.
Ugh...
- Yes?
- Did you film me falling in that cool place?
Great,
'cause it was fucking awesome.
Let's split.
- Don't confess to anything.
- Hey! No talking!
Alcohol recovery center
It wasn't us. He was more drunk
than us. He confused us.
Do you know where you are?
Homicide Department of the police
station at Malczewskiego Street.
Can you call my mother
and tell her where I am?
- She must be worried.
- Had we found anything on you,
you would've been
at Rakowiecka by now.
Do you know how they treat a man
with long hair there?
- Like a woman.
- Do I look like a gangster to you?
Thank you very much,
but I can't help you.
Why?
Because in Poland a family name
can't be spelt with "V", "X","Y".
Ma'am,
next week I'm leaving
the country for good.
I'm begging you, change my name.
No one can pronounce
'PATRYK Krzemieniecki' in America.
And you'll never hear of me again.
Since you're emigrating...
What name do you want?
PATRYK Krzemieniecki.
He's gone.
From now on my name is
PATRYK Sebastian
Vega.
PATRYK Sebastian Vega...
I've read your mock matura paper
on the Renaissance.
I gave you an 'A'.
I want you to read it out to the class.
A huge palace emerges before my eyes.
I open its double-wing door
with a screech.
I pace along the hall,
peering into the rooms of Rej,
Kochanowski,
Górnicki,
Janicki,
Skarga, Szymonowic.
Today...
I will visit all of them.
First, I call on Kochanowski,
grieving over his deceased daughter
while writing a threnody.
I grab a bottle of liquor
and pour him and myself a drink.
I sit down next to him
and we start talking
about his trauma of losing his child...
I'm drawing the shots for the first
scene of my movie.
What if I placed several dozen
cameras around the protagonist,
had him filmed simultaneously, and then
merged the shots into one whole?
Let's begin your final exam in Polish.
Here are your questions:
"What is courage?"
I move my hand along her naked body.
I slide it toward her crotch,
where two droplets
of her juice are shimmering.
I lean over
and kiss them away.
I can feel her quiver
under the warmth of my breath.
Her greedy eyes
are begging me to continue.
I plunge my tongue inside her
and start moving it around.
Casually at first,
then rhythmically,
savoring her pungent taste...
And this is what I call courage.
Mom!
Ewa!
Look! These cunts have stolen my idea.
- What are we gonna do now?
- I'll apply
to the directorial department.
Have you seen "The Serpent's Egg"?
No.
Does the name Ingmar Bergman
ring a bell to you?
Know what? Ingmar Bergman...
is a director I watch as part
of the "Cinema Masters" series.
I know directors and movies
you've never even heard of.
The exam is over.
Best of luck to you.
This movie is...
a visual orgasm for me.
I already know which school
I wanna go to.
I wanna be like Agent Clarice Sterling
from "the Silence of the Lambs".
I've come to enroll for the exam.
You're late. The resocialization
department is no longer accepting.
Come back next year.
I have invented
a brilliant murder scene.
I drive needles into the victim's body,
and hang an electric heater over him
which causes the guy
to bleed out slowly.
The recruitment office
wants to draft you,
because you didn't get into college.
- I'll create a character for them.
- What character?
A chronic alcoholic.
I'll check in a mental hospital
and play my role in front of a doctor.
I'll stand in front of the army
medical board and inform them
I'm undergoing a psychiatric
treatment as an alcoholic.
You're seeing the board on Friday.
Today is Wednesday
No one will check I've been
in rehab for just one day.
I started drinking...
in elementary school.
Every time I got...
a poor grade...
or something bad happened...
to me.
I had to have a drink.
And you've had a drink today,
haven't you?
Sadly, yes.
Sir...
try not to drink at least
until the end of the week.
How many times did you answer "yes"?
8 out of 10...
But this test seems a bit exaggerated.
Amazing...
That professional hit woman is amazing.
Who's gonna play her?
There's that actress
from "Radio Romance"...
Małgorzata Foremniak.
What's up?
- Foremniak.
- What?
That actress, over there on the bench.
Wait a second.
Hello.
Sorry to bother...
My son... has created a character
of an assassin for you.
Don't be surprised, then,
if one day he'll call you with an offer
to act in his movie.
Why doesn't he come see me
in the theater this Friday?
With the screenplay.
Seriously?
- Hello. This is for you.
- Thank you.
I've shown your screenplay
to Waldemar Dziki.
He's a film producer.
He's read it and the dialogs shocked him.
I'm not surprised.
What do you intend to do
with this screenplay?
Give me a million dollars, and I'll
turn it into an Oscar-winning movie.
- I can employ you as a secretary.
- That'd be cool, too.
Black coffee for me.
Two spoonfuls.
Spoonful's like a spoon for soup?
Nevermind.
I've no time for such petty shit,
so stop wasting my fucking time.
You sound like an American movie hero.
- Let me write something as an experiment.
- Like what?
You and your team are working on a new
series. I want to write one episode.
Take it...
That's not...
Fuck! You can't do that!
Get out!
You can't do things like that...
Okay... Take it then...
Why not?
Maybe I have it.
Maybe I don't.
Yes. Yes, ghost. Fucking kill me!
It's not working out for you?
PATRYK,
Marek Miller,
my friend, a journalist,
and an originator.
We've read your episode...
and fired the screenwriting team.
You'll write the series.
PATRYK Vega, it's a pleasure.
What did you get your degree in?
Sociology.
It gave me humanist education,
and led me to journalism.
To get in, I invented a book
entitled "Who Let the Journalists in".
In one fell swoop, I met
the most influential reporters. Yes...
My mentors are the three "K's" -
Krall, Kapuściński, and Kąkolewski.
I lecture in a reportage school.
Postgraduate studies based on
a master-apprentice relationship
where students gather materials
for the lecturers' true works.
Yes, the lecturers' true works.
Isn't it plagiarism?
But...
Such a straggler, such a...
nobody from God knows where.
And still, you can ask...
such matter-of-fact questions.
You've convinced me.
- I'll study the same thing.
- What's that?
Sociology and journalism.
I'll do two majors in one go.
And whom do you want to be?
Neither a sociologist, nor a journalist.
Sociology will give me sound education
that will be a back round
for my film-directing work.
And your reportage school
will teach me
to professionally
gather materials for my screenplays.
I promise I'll pay my tuition
next month.
I have a full-time job as a secretary,
doing day and evening
courses at the same time.
How do you manage to study, then?
Actually...
I'd like to request an individual
course of study for me.
I want to do a 5-year MA course,
and a postgraduate one
in 2 years, dean.
But you'll have over 20 exams
in each session.
I know.
In our lectures, we'll retrace the history
of the philosophical thought...
Well... perhaps not all of us.
There's a locker in Auschwitz
that contains 20,000 prisoners' accounts.
We'll read them all. What for?
In the 50th we'll find a statement
of a prisoner that claims to have survived
the longest roll call
in the history of Auschwitz.
After a breakout, they were forced
to stand up for two days,
and many of them died.
150 accounts later,
we'll find an account of a prisoner
who also took part in that roll call
but stood at a different spot.
By collecting all those accounts, we'll
be able to recreate a panoramic scene
told not by a writer,
but prisoners from all over the world.
Why are we doing this?
To create an Auschwitz chronicle.
An Auschwitz chronicle, yes.
We'll spend a few weeks here.
Questions?
Can I sleep in Rudolf Hess's study
with the view of the gallows?
I think it's a very positive place.
I might fall in love here.
Why?
The closeness of death
makes you appreciate life.
There's strong energy here, but I feel...
things have turned around over the years.
Now it is a space
where nothing is trivial.
Everything you experience here
becomes...
extremely intense.
Everything.
Magda, our new secretary.
Who am I, then?
A journalist.
You'll make reportages for Polsat
about children
from dysfunctional families.
When do we begin?
These are the conditions they live in.
The eldest girl has a brain tumor.
But no one comes to treat her.
Hey.
What're you doing, kid?
- Interesting.
- What?
The world doesn't look
like Warsaw, after all.
Is that so?
In 2 hours you're shooting the mother
of a child murdered in the woods.
Awesome.
Wait.
What if I shot the lady's statement
at the scene of the crime?
- It'll be too dark.
- Get a flashlight.
- What?
- I'll illuminate your face.
Tell us how your child was murdered.
Bartek was walking down the road...
when he approached him from the back...
and stabbed him with a knife.
He knocked him down to the ground...
and kept stabbing...
several times...
He dragged him to the bushes...
My child...
He killed my child...
The murderer killed my child...
My child...
I have nothing to live for!
How did you feel then?
Yes?
Kill me! I don't want to live!
He killed my child!
Doesn't it move you a bit?
The mother ended up
in a psych ward after the interview.
But we have a good story.
Borsukowa's sleeping with a guy
from the homicide department.
Perhaps you'd like to meet him and get
some materials for your screenplay?
Sure.
Bitch! What have you done?
- Leave me alone!
- Slut! I'll fucking kill you!
- It wasn't me!
- I'll kill you!
I'll fuck you up, you hear me?
- It wasn't me!
- You whore!
- Leave me alone!
- I'll kill you!
- It wasn't me!
Leave me alone!
- You killed him!
- Get off me! - I'll fuck you up!
- I'll fuck you up, you hear me?
- Jacek, a gentleman to see you.
Jacek.
It's about the screenplay.
It wasn't me!
Who's that woman in the hall?
Michałek's mother.
A 4-year-old boy
drowned in the Vistula.
She commissioned
her boyfriend to murder her kid.
Cheers.
Then, the Lord beheld our work
and was content,
but when He asked about our wages,
He sat down and cried.
Do you know what they call
the homicide department?
A dust factory.
We do a lot of good work
that nobody needs.
We're the last romantics.
Why romantics?
A typical investigator...
from the homicide department
is a divorcee, an alcoholic
with a pet dog
that doesn't fetch.
Officially, we don't exist.
Cheers.
We have a 95% crime detection rate.
We've solved the biggest cases.
Kredyt Bank. Dębski.
But the chief's just decided
our department is redundant,
because the number of undetected crimes
in Poland has dropped.
So what do you need
for your screenplay?
Nothing.
I wanna make a movie about you.
We have a meeting with the Pruszków
gang. Why don't you come with us
- and see what it looks like?
- Won't they mind?
- No.
- You'll pose as one of us.
When?
Now. Come.
- Have you been long with the homicide?
- 2 months.
- Where did you come from?
- Narcotics.
- At Cyril and Methodius.
- Cyril and his methods...
They hanged me on a nail there.
Oh... there comes Cieluś.
He's too afraid to approach you.
Cieluś offered me
a 3-million-dollar bribe.
- And?
- I knocked 3 of his teeth out.
Seen from the side, one can't tell
a difference between you and the bangers.
But these are just appearances.
There's a barricade between you.
An invisible line
that nobody crosses,
as there's nothing beyond it.
Do you know why you can't be bribed?
Even thugs don't respect a corrupt cop.
And you're afraid of losing your job.
For it, you've sacrificed
your health, kids, wives.
You have no life without it.
And now you've saved mine.
How?
I just realized
with you I can legally do
extreme things
unattainable to ordinary people.
Barnyard banditry will never
give me such a kick.
Overdue alimonies.
You're calculating wages, not benefits.
Why the fuck do you need a calculator
with so many zeros? It's decimals...
- Have you read it?
- Yes.
What do you think?
It's deeper than Pasikowski's "Hounds".
- Do you think he could make this movie?
- I think it should be you.
No one knows those guys better than you.
No one else will understand
what it's about.
But...
Will anybody give money... to a director
without a film school diploma?
Well...
it may be a problem.
Since you can't make a feature film,
try making a documentary on those guys.
And who'll give me money for that?
You need to pitch it
to the editor-in-chief of the TVP,
Andrzej Fidyk.
A guru in film documentaries.
How can I get to him?
I have no idea.
You're a journalist. Figure it out.
A journalist, yes?
Polish Television documentary
department.
Hi, PATRYK speaking. I've changed phones
and lost Andrzej's number.
Can you give it to me?
Write it down.
- Yes?
- Hello, director.
My name's PATRYK Vega.
I'm a reporter.
- I have an invitation for you.
- For what?
For vodka.
Will you show your faces?
No.
It'd blow our cover.
Anyone will?
See this projectile?
A lucky one.
Why?
It misfired,
when I tried to blow may brains out.
I'm commissioning the whole series.
12 episodes.
- Will you let me shoot it?
- There's no way the TVP will agree...
to have a series produced
by someone without experience.
You'll be an originator and an associate
director, but I must find you a director.
Our operations will be
followed by a camera.
Each TV crew member will have a status
of a police assistant.
They will act as unarmed police officers.
They can take part in all police
operations at their own risk,
including interrogations and arrests
made by SWAT officers,
for which we'll equip them
with bulletproof vests.
We'll tint the windowpanes and film
with hidden cameras.
- We'll be able to watch them at will.
- How come you have the cheek
- to interrupt a cameraman while he's filming?
- Cut him some slack.
And you lost them.
We'll have to stage those scenes.
We'll shoot from several angles.
If I can't be a director,
at least give me a camera.
What camera?
A foolproof one. Automatic.
One that I could use by myself.
We've a racketeer that extorts
protection from people in Radom.
He calls a fitting dealer and threatens
to rape his daughter, or burn his wife.
If he doesn't pay.
We're watching the phone booths
in the busiest spots in Radom.
We expect he'll try to blend in,
after he makes a phone call.
- We're waiting for our contact, now.
- Pull over. I need to pee.
Watching public phones makes no sense.
There's one in the clinic, too.
The guy could easily
make a call from there.
- Nero to Bajbak.
- What is it?
We're locating our contact.
- Where's he calling from?
- The clinic at 57A Struga St.
Fuck. That's the clinic. Back up.
Stop! Police!
Stop, or I'll shoot!
Moron!
Go, go, go! Go!
He went there!
Get the fuck out!
- I'm elated.
- Why?
I'm experiencing something unattainable
to 99.9% of the people.
There he is! Stop!
Motherfucker!
- Relax. Relax, Ania...
- You fucker!
- Calm down, Ania.
- Fascinating. - What again?
I'm in my early 20's, but it's only now
that I know I have him in me.
- Whom?
- The killer.
It was the brain's chemical reaction.
An adrenaline rush that made me
ready to kill that guy.
Now I believe a mother can lift a car,
if her child's trapped under it.
- Who's that guy?
- His father-in-law's gone missing.
A councilor.
Divers are searching the local ponds,
to no avail, though.
The boys are interrogating the son-in-law.
Perhaps, he knows something.
Give me the headphones.
I don't know where my father is.
Maybe he's gone away, or has a mistress.
That day I was busy playing
with my child.
My relationship
with my father-in-law was very good.
- We liked each other.
- That's what I'd say.
If I were the killer.
I think he killed his father-in-law
and dumped the body.
Pull over here.
We'll be filming the house
with a telephoto lens.
Come here.
They've just brought the son-in-law in.
When he saw you with a camera,
he went to dig out
his father-in-law's body at night.
Hold it.
He moved the barrel with the body
a few kilometers away.
The pit was discovered
by mushroom pickers. Here.
I like the brain.
Hi.
I wanted to see you,
because of my impact on your life.
Because you saw me with a camera,
you'll spend 25 years in prison.
It was self-defence.
How?
My father-in-law was a beloved
councilor for the villagers.
He built roads for them.
But at home...
he turned into a monster
who beat up my wife...
with a vaccuum cleaner hose.
He used to take the toilet seat
to his bedroom...
so that we wouldn't use it up.
I was alone with a 1-year-old kid.
He attacked me...
because I'd turned on a water boiler.
I choked him during the fight,
because he threatened
to kill me and my child.
I panicked.
I wrapped the body in plastic foil.
I dismembered it with an axe
in the garage...
put it in a barrel... and hid it.
If you'd reported it, you'd be charged
with involuntary manslaughter.
After what you did,
you'll go to prison...
for a model...
premeditated murder.
Is there anything I can do for you?
Can you pass a message to my wife?
Sure.
You can count on me.
You fucking scum, you'll rot here
until you die, dig it?
Confess to murdering him.
Fuck the punk. I'm done talking to him.
It's Christmas Eve.
I'm going out to buy my woman a present.
Stay with him until Metyl comes.
Care for a drink?
One more?
Tell me, did you whack him?
Tell me. Just me.
I won't tell anybody.
It's Christmas Eve.
Consider it a Christmas present for me.
Did you whack him, or not?
Just cut the shit and talk to me.
I...
How?
I grabbed a knife...
while drunk...
We fell out...
I stabbed him...
Horrible.
Now they're gonna drag
me to court on Chrismas
to have me testify in your murder case.
Opala shot his pregnant
girlfriend while drunk. In the lung.
I visited her in the hospital
and convinced her
to testify she shot herself
during the argument.
Sławek will get a proposition
he can't refuse.
- He'll have to leave the police.
- What'll he do?
Kill himself, I guess.
A war broke out in the USA. Planes flew
into the Twin Towers and the Pentagon.
We don't know what's going on.
There are thousands of casualties.
We keep receiving tragic news.
"We keep receiving tragic news".
What a dumb-ass!
She shouldn't work for the radio,
if she can't control her emotions.
Whom to believe?
Where's the kid?
Where's the fucking kid?
Why?
- Do you really have to work on New Year's Eve?
- Yes.
- I feel disgusted.
- By what?
The whole human race.
Seeing those people
out the window makes me sick.
Those morons are shooting firecrackers,
when I'm creating something that'll
- change the history of the cinema.
- You need a doctor.
My cousin dreamt of making movies,
and now he's shooting porn.
Take it, for fuck's sake...
THE END
I don't want to be a bitter guy mopping
floors in the TV station all his life,
knowing he is a genius,
but somehow the world ignores
and rejects his ideas.
If I fail to make a debut movie
within a year...
I'll relinquish my plan
to make movies at all.
And what will you be doing?
I have a strong need of self-affirmation.
I'm seriously considering
becoming a serial killer.
- Whom will you kill?
- Bad guys.
In a way I won't get caught.
I'll be constantly changing
my modus operandi.
- Me and my multiple personalities are all ears.
- I'm already scared.
You have no film school diploma,
or family connections.
Little chance to get millions for a movie.
- So there is a chance?
- Yes.
I've found money for your movie.
On condition you turn it
into a 5-episode series as well.
No one except me believes in your movie,
and selling the series to the television
will allow the ATM company, which puts up
the dough, to make a profit.
I'll remember that day for the rest
of my life. The trip to the set.
Entering it.
The first time I'd say "action".
- Eat the sugar.
- It'll stay under my eyelids forever.
Time to finish, dears.
We're gonna shoot.
Marek...
it's my first time
on the feature film set.
Does the director say "camera"?
It's usually the set manager, but...
you can do it, too.
Thanks.
Camera!
- Rolling.
- Action!
Have you been drinking?
Where's the kid?
What about your A.A. chip?
- Where's the kid?
- You were to stop drinking.
Where's the kid?
Cut!
"Steal it, and I'll shot your knee"?
THE FIRST VEGA'S FILM EARNS
$458.000
A message for a thief.
- Is this your ride?
- I bought it in Austria
with the money I made on a movie.
Are we going to the reception?
- Hi.
Will you give me a ride home afterwards?
Why afterwards?
Now.
How can you come to the set
and provoke me with your erect nipples?
Without a bra?
Have you seen a bra that'd fit my boobs?
I must wear sports ones.
I like small boobs.
I'm on period.
Gosia...
I've seen 5 autopsies.
Whom have you brought to the party?
I just gave here a ride.
I missed you a lot.
Let's go to your place.
- What happened?
- John Paul II has died.
Let's kneel.
- Not good.
- Yes. I loved him so much.
Not good, because they'll declare
a national mourning,
and the premiere of my movie
will be canceled.
The premiere is irrelevant.
Something more important has happened.
Yes. More important.
Besides, the movie sucks.
Why?
Not intellectual enough.
There are three things that matter in art:
the truth, the meaning, and...
the final message.
There's truth in it.
Who cares?
Hi.
- We haven't been introduced. PATRYK.
- Hi.
I know who you are...
I've been trying to arrange re-shoots
for your City Police series for Friday,
but the spokesman said no.
Oh, I'm Kasia.
Want me to help?
How?
- Who's the City Police spokesman?
- Adam Gradoń.
Which precinct are you
trying to get the permit from?
Mid-town.
Call their chief,
tell him you're Adaś's cousin,
and you have his approval to film,
and that he told you to discuss
the details directly with the chief.
I can't lie.
Think of it... as some sort of...
adventure.
Yes. Okay.
Hello, Kasia Słomińska
from the Pleograf Studio.
I'm calling from Adam Gradoń's office.
Can I speak to the chief?
Hello, chief.
I'm Adaś's cousin.
He gave me his approval to film
in the City Police station.
He told me...
to discuss the details with you.
The shooting is scheduled...
for Friday, 11 a.m...
Yes...
Sure, I'll greet Adaś from you.
Thanks a million.
- How did you know he'd agree?
- My job's about manipulating people.
Is Dziki in?
Yes.
You're the third best Polish movie
of the year,
but your debut won't yield any profit.
It was viewed by only 150,000 people.
No one can predict
what the cinema audience will do.
Americans say that making movies
is second only to building space shuttles
- in terms of risk.
- I'll be the first
to learn to predict the audience.
In making movies it's not enough
to press blue, yellow, or red buttons
to produce a million views.
We'll see.
I made a movie no one cared to see.
Now, I want success.
I'll choose your station's
best-selling actors
and I'll make a blockbuster
for many people to see.
Okay. Let's do it.
Or not.
I'm indisposed.
Get me the assistant director here.
Have him shoot for me. I'm going to bed.
Wait, wait...
The producer is coming for inspection.
Get me the sound guy with a stick.
Krzychu... come, come, come...
Record.
Camera!
Action!
Play it in a loop.
When the producer comes,
she'll look for me on the set,
and then she'll leave.
- Where's PATRYK?
- At the buffet.
Camera!
Action!
He's back shooting.
Camera!
Action!
- He's not here.
- He's with the 2nd unit,
- a kilometer away from here.
- Okay.
If he's busy, have him call me
after the shooting.
Okay.
I bought a 1.5 liter whisky mug.
I don't feel like running to the fridge
- each time.
- Seriously?
We're going out.
- Where?
- The Old Town.
What? Jaup... jaup...
The color of Trzebiatowska's
shoes sucks.
She doesn't keep her curls
throuout the scenes.
VEGA'S FILMS HAVE MADE
$1,924,000
I can't drink anymore.
I need to change something
in my life.
And...
What're you gonna do?
I'll start doing coke
to be able to drink more.
Docent I an exclusive celebrities' dealer.
From now on, he's gonna be my supplier.
- What's up? How much?
- 10 grams.
Kasia, I snorted 10 grams in one night.
I snorted 10 grams in one night.
I haven't slept in 3 days.
Every time I close my eyes,
my heart stops.
I'd jump out the window,
but I live on the first floor.
Kasia...
Honey...
I love you, you know?
But... I don't know...
If I come to you now, and...
start patting you on your head,
you'll never get out of it.
I'm dying, sir.
Half of my body is numb.
We must hurry to the hospital.
The readings are good.
It's all in your head.
Kasia, I haven't slept in 4 days.
I have agoraphobia.
Now I know why Kurt Cobain was
sitting in a closet before he died.
It's not food poisoning, mom.
I've overdosed on cocaine.
I haven't slept in 5 days.
Help me.
You've always known
when to bang it out full blast, son.
- What kind of beans have you taken?
- I don't know.
You could've hurt yourself.
Don't do it again.
We'll give you something
to knock you out for 8 hours.
Stay with me.
See if I keep breathing.
How long have I slept?
30 minutes.
Give me another one.
How long?
3 hours.
Get me a third one.
I filed for the annulment
of my marriage, but...
Until I get it,
I can't receive Communion,
and it's...
very hard for me.
I'm finished as a director.
I don't know what to do in life.
What was all that for?
There's a streak of failures behind me.
I don't think anyone will ever
lay out money for my movie.
So many years and nothing's changed.
I feel the same.
- Feel what?
- Disdain for people.
They make me feel like an alien
born on a wrong planet.
I know I'll never...
understand them,
and they won't understand me.
A service is starting...
Perhaps you'd like to go
to the church with me?
Go alone.
You'll figure something out, honey.
I'm sure.
VEGA'S FILMS HAVE MADE
$4,102,000
Bye.
PATRYK?
What's up?
I'm Niesiołowski's assistant,
that MP.
There's a lady that advises politicians.
She reads people and predicts the future.
Crap.
Niesiołowski owed one guy a million.
He asked Aniela what he should do.
She told him not to do anything,
'cause the guy'd vanish into thin air.
And a week later he got killed
in Smoleńsk.
There's something foul about that woman.
Her life is a streak of misfortunes.
Both her sons are sick. Her dog is sick.
When a helicopter crashed outside
Katowice, it crashed into her balcony.
When there was a fire in a factory,
all her paperwork burnt,
so she can't get her pension.
You've convinced me.
- How can I get hold of her?
- By phone only.
Hello, Aniela, PATRYK speaking.
I got your number from Mateusz.
Hello.
- I'm a film director, and...
- Uh huh...
I don't know what to do in life. The film
I made turned out to be a failure.
Yet another one in my life.
I feel like I'm finished.
I don't know...
Shall I change my profession?
Egypt will soon shut off. Tourists
will no longer visit the pyramids.
That movie was a gate.
Had you not made it,
your life would've taken
a different course.
But now you'll achieve success.
I can see crowds coming
to see your movie.
- What's the movie gonna be about?
- There'll be many movies.
The one to attract crowds?
You'll make a movie about wicked women.
It'll fill up the theaters.
Then you'll make one about doctors.
I can see crowds there too.
Why you?
My sweetest one...
No...
Florian's been paralyzed.
How?
I don't know...
He started walking sideways.
First, his hind legs gave in...
Then, the front ones.
Now, he doesn't move at all.
Help him...
My... my love...
Help him.
I don't know what it is. A neurological
problem, perhaps. Or a spine trauma.
Maybe his spinal cord is damaged.
He has to be rolled over
from side to side, every hour,
so his lungs don't collapse.
- Okay.
- And do air cycling with him for an hour
to prevent his muscles from declining,
which happens very fast.
- For how long?
- I don't know...
People put dogs like that down,
because they can't manage.
Is medicine helpless?
Conventional, yes.
But I know a woman who helps
animals in this condition.
She used to have cancer herself.
She was granted a gift that helped
her recover. Now she heals herself.
I'll get a CD with a pep
program for Florian.
It'll heal him.
You are surrounded by space doctors.
Fulgent figures approach you.
They lay their hands on you.
They begin to heal
all your neural connections...
Can you feel the cosmic energy
pass through you?
Yes, Magda. Thanks a lot.
- Hi.
- Hello...
I've been carrying him for 4 hours.
He can't pee, hasn't pooped for 14 days.
Magda told me a medium from the U.S.A.
will come to Poland.
Worked as a PhD for NASA,
then she went through a transformation
by the healer John of God in Brazil.
I'll see her about my spine.
I can't move.
Come on, let's dance.
This is the highest card
as regards finances.
In that time you'll make a fortune.
The ghosts said you should
hang it up in your bedroom.
They will protect you.
This is an old Jewish method
from kabbalach.
Write the name of your enemy
on a piece of paper.
Put him in tinfoil.
Give him food.
Wrap him up.
And freeze him in a freezer.
This way
you'll cut yourself off
from all your enemies.
What are you doing?
- Don't touch it. It's very important.
- Okay...
I just want to tell you...
Tomorrow at 10 I'm going to my parents.
For Easter.
- Yes?
- Hello, Aniela.
PATRYK speaking.
Have you been able to foresee
whether I should go on vacation this year?
Yes, but I can see
you'll have an accident.
- What accident?
- You'll be riding in a black car.
I can see a bend
in a road through a forest.
There will be three males
in an oncoming car.
Good I've put on
a loose sweatsuit for the road.
You've taken a different route.
A shortcut through the back country.
We'll skip the traffic.
Dad?
Dad!?
You killed my father!
Fuck... I was supposed to go...
to Radom and have some
Easter poppyseed cake...
but it won't happen...
My life's just ended.
I killed a man and I'm going to jail.
No...
You know what I felt?
Your spine?
I'll never be safe without God.
I can...
secure myself, hoard the riches.
But one second's enough to lose it all.
Kamil!
Father's alive!
- Dad!
- He passed out.
Dad!
I don't know, mom!
Some chav.
A common bald chav.
Yes.
The Volvo has broken in half. The pedals
are gone. It's a miracle nobody got hurt.
Let's go to church to say our thanks.
- How?
- The firefighters will give us a ride.
I want to sign up for exorcisms.
First, you must see a psychologist.
If you get qualified,
you'll speak to Father Grewkowicz,
who'll decide what'll happen next.
What is it about?
Suddenly, I felt safe.
So far, I've been like a house
with a deactivated alarm system.
With doors and windows opened wide.
I let everything inside.
I stopped thinking on my own.
I consulted everything with a seer.
Each petty thing
related to my existence.
Over the last 3 years,
I've opened myself to bad energy.
I think it revealed itself
through a head-on collision
- that God saved me from.
- Tell me about it step by step.
People like that may be convinced
they're pure love.
But they never know
who advises them from the other side.
It is not God. He doesn't act this way.
If God wanted us
to know the future, He'd show it to us.
It always works the same way.
You get pieces of true information,
fall for it...
and follow it blindly.
Then, you start rolling down
a steep slope towards destruction.
That's what the evil spirit wants.
What you've experienced might've been
a result of strong mental suggestion.
But if it resulted from spiritual
interference...
you won't cope with it on your own.
Holy Spirit, come...
And open my heart...
And fill my heart with your love.
Holy Spirit... Your breath
has the power to transform me.
You must sever all contacts
with those people.
And attend the CRR.
- What's that?
- Charismatic Renewal Retreat.
I'm no good for that. I don't function
well in a group. I can't stand bigots.
The exorcisms have lit a fire in you...
But if you neglect it...
it will die out.
During today's liturgy, we shall pray
for the charismatic healing.
Let each of you
pray to the Holy Spirit
for whatever you want.
Come, Holy Spirit.
Please, come to us and heal us.
I'm sorry, but I can't believe in this.
I have too many reservations.
I can't believe
you'll suddenly visit me, Holy Spirit,
and heal my spine injured in the crash.
As a human being, I have too many
limitations that tell me it won't happen.
You know that we are sinful,
you know that we stumble,
but in spite of that, all the time
we count on your help,
- we count on your support...
- Okay...
I'll switch off my sober mind
for a moment.
I'll reject my prejudices and believe
that you can come and heal my neck.
It's the middle of summer
but it's freezing in this church.
- He moved.
- Are you sure?
I wasn't at the beginning,
but look.
- I see you got a new dog.
- No, it's the same one.
Come.
I have understood that...
I won't have to believe
in God ever again.
I just know
He's out there.
I could feel a physical force
adjust my cervical verterbrae, and...
the church turned into a freezer.
Honey...
it's hard to listen to things one has not
experienced themselves, but...
I'm so happy you're no longer hurting...
that I let you have a drink tonight.
I... will never...
- drink again.
- You won't?
God let me take an elevator ride
to a different level.
I'll quit drinking...
smoking... I'll lose weight.
I'll eat regularly.
Huh...
And you know what else?
I have never...
thought I will...
talk shit to a stranger...
through a lattice. But now, after 20 years
I'll go to confession again.
I can't absolve you.
A civil divorce is irrelevant.
You're living with a woman... whom God
still considers another man's wife.
So...
I'll never be allowed
to receive Communion?
The only solution is to have
the marriage invalidated by the Church.
My wife's been trying
to accomplish that for 7 years.
Gosia used to work with me in a hospital.
I want to remain anonymous.
Sure.
I'll let you see the movie
before I release it.
VEGA'S FILMS HAVE MADE
$52,000,000
What did you do specifically?
I performed 976 abortions.
When I got pregnant, I was afraid
I'd be punished with a sick child.
I promised myself not to ever do it again.
What does abortion look like?
Is the child being scraped out?
The woman gets an abortion pill,
and she gives birth to a child.
And...
What happens with the child?
It's taken out to a different room
in a bowl and placed on a windowsill.
Alive?
Yes.
It's left there
without food or drink until it dies.
How long does it take?
The record-breaker took over ten hours.
Okay, 15-minute break.
Then we'll go back to scene 127.
PATRYK...
I can't do this movie.
Why?
My parents are doctors,
and this screenplay is... gruesome.
But... it's based on doctors' accounts.
Yes, but... it discredits the entire
healthcare system.
- I can't do that to them.
- PATRYK...
Eleven actors refused to act in your film.
Are you sure you want to do it?
You're the best-selling director.
This may ruin you.
I am confused, Jesus.
I don't know what to do.
Everyone tells me
to quit making this movie.
I'm begging you.
Tell me what you want.
You are the Lord of life.
You are the Lord
of the beginning and the end
of every man's life.
I'm giving you all those praying here.
My Lord, I'm giving you
those who are close
and those far away.
I'm giving you those who love you
and those who still don't love you enough.
I'm giving you those who believe
and do not believe in you.
I'm giving you all those
who live in sin.
SAVE A BABY'S LIFE
And those blessed with your grace.
I'm giving you my brothers and sisters.
I'm giving you all those
whose lives you crave.
Okay, Jesus... I'll make this movie
in the teeth of everything.
Vanquish death and give them new life.
That picture will burn
a hole in people's brains.
Father Waldemar Maliszewski.
I am a police chaplain.
We met on the set.
- I married actors in your movie.
- Oh...
I remember.
God bless you.
Hell broke loose on the Net.
Pro-abortionists' hate is paramount.
The opening box office will be low.
Come on, honey. I don't think so.
When will the box office results come in?
Speak.
Thanks.
- And?
- 711,000 viewers over the first weekend.
VEGA'S FILMS HAVE MADE
$77,000,000
- What? - The best opening of the year!
- Awesome.
Wait.
Yes?
Really?
Yes... Sure.
Okay.
Bye.
You'll never guess.
My church marriage has been annulled.
We can get married in church.
What a day!
Now that you want to enter
into sacramental marriage,
hold each other's right hands.
Before God and the Church,
repeat after me
the words of the marital vows.
- I, PATRYK...
- take you, Katarzyna, to be my wife...
and I promise...
to love you,
to be faithful to you,
to be your honest husband...
and to remain by your side...
till death do us part.
So help me...
Almighty God
A mighty God
in the name of the Trinity...
and the Holy Saints.
If I'd gotten it earlier,
I wouldn't have appreciated it.
Communion?
God granted me that only
after I had matured in faith.
- Body and Blood of Christ.
- Amen.
Do you know the pain
of losing such a small child?
This woman has recorded a message
for the kidnapper of her child.
I want to meet her.
Do you know the infinite fear
and despair of not knowing his fate?
There are...
two types of parents.
One, like my husband,
who respond to their child's
kidnapping by saying... "Too bad...
What's done is done...
Gotta move on with your life."
And the other, like me,
who keep searching for their child
even 20 years later.
How have you coped with it?
I've known I must be strong for him.
Because if he's found,
he will need me.
It's just like...
trying to take a bone away
from a rabid dog.
It has to end with painful bites.
Are you ready to make this movie,
and lose everything?
What do you mean by "everything"?
Your family, your wife, your kids,
your house... money, your career?
You're exaggerating.
Camera!
Action!
Cut?
- Cut. Who's that?
- I don't know, but that's our prop car.
Cut.
There are attractive women
who don't look good in the camera,
and average ones
that the camera tweaks 1,000%...
But the camera loves you.
You could have a career.
My name is Vega. PATRYK Vega.
- You look taller in the pictures.
- I have a good sense of humor.
164 IQ, and... I'm a millionaire.
If I were taller,
it'd be unfair to other men.
Come to an audition.
Give me your number.
Incredible.
- What?
- I wasn't even supposed to be here.
I've come for a moment to deliver
the car for my father, who's just fainted.
Is it a wrap?
Off to the hotel.
If you send this message,
I won't be able to help you.
Duh...
I'd like to invest
in a residential complex in the US.
- Find me some nice apartments.
- Sure, brother. Great decision.
America is the land of smiling people.
I spoke to the diamond Jew.
He can get you a diamond crown.
You could wear it for the premiere
of your new movie.
God is begging you
to stop engaging
in the futile deeds of the dark.
During the Eucharist, it came to me
you should not make your new movie.
Our Lord doesn't want it
to be made.
I will have a record number of views.
If the Lord does not build the house,
the work of the builders
is useless.
Prosperity comes from God.
Nothing gets more stupid
than refusing to fulfil our Lord's will.
I'm not gonna back out
of making that movie.
DIRECTED BY PATRYK VEGA
VEGA'S FILMS HAVE MADE
$91,000,000
I've never had such bad reviews.
Box office results coming in.
Speak.
The movie has been a disaster.
Unbelievable.
Considering all the pressure
to get it done,
I would've bet my head on it.
My last penny.
As if... someone has built
an invisible wall to block it out.
Come with me.
Leave the phone.
- It's tapped.
- What?
You've taken up
a slippery topic in this movie.
- They're eavesdropping on my conversations.
- I know.
- But why?
- They wanna lock you up.
I'll set you up with someone
who'll tell you what's going on.
You're not recording, are you?
Is my phone really tapped?
You've got bugs everywhere.
What do you mean?
In your cars, in the house...
They want to set your wife up
with a stud
who'd sway her to testify against you.
Honey...
your biggest enemy is your mind.
THEY CAN HEAR US
I'm not going to save myself
for myself, Jesus...
But for you, I can do it...
Stop it...
I'm so ashamed to be here...
I'm sorry...
I'm sorry, my Lord...
Deliver me...
When will you transfer the money
for the apartments?
Right away.
- Jacek Masalski is here to see you.
- Did he have an appointment?
No, but it's important.
Let him in.
Hi.
You're doing business
with a guy from the States?
Why?
I've heard you're gonna lose that money.
You want to buy a residential complex
for your kids there. He's a thief.
He's gonna rob you. It's a bogus
transaction. And so is the lawyer.
I know... the amount...
you'll lose.
Correct?
That guy has ties
to the old Pruszków gang.
He's been a professional con-artist
for 30 years.
A whole team are working on you.
And he is...
- grooming you for 3 years.
- Grooming?
Feeding the victim.
He's softening you
with watches, diamonds...
cars, which he uses to rip you off.
For a sole purpose...
of eventually robbing you
of everything you have.
- Do you know how they're gonna do it?
- Uh-huh.
You'll buy the estate.
Then, they'll tell you
something's gone wrong.
And you have to pay a little extra.
So you will.
Then, they'll tell you to pay
a little more to make it awesome.
Yes...
And then, they'll rob you
of fucking everything.
I knew a guy from So pot
whom they conned out of 30 rocks.
He never got over it.
He went back to his 5,000-zloty salary.
Finally...
he committed suicide.
See you later.
Jacek...
thanks.
There'll be no transfer.
I know you want to rob me.
You've put so much effort into it,
and now you have to kiss
your money goodbye. Poor thing.
How much longer will it take?
Clean.
How clean?
Your house, your car. Both clean.
Whoever told you you were tapped
was full of shit.
Old mistakes - no.
New ones - yes.
I'm sure I have many more to make.
But I'll never allow...
the evil one...
to sneak up on me again.
I want to ask you...
to renew our marital vows to Jesus.
I can feel it's important for us.
Dear spouses,
3 years ago,
you entered into sacramental
marriage before God,
tying a bond in Jesus Christ
for your entire life.
Then, you vowed to love each other,
remain faithful,
cherish each other,
and persevere in the marital bond
till you're parted by death.
As a sign of your will to fulfil your holy
obligations even better,
hold each other's right hands,
and answer the questions that I will ask
you on behalf of the Church.
You know,
I was in a grave.
They almost buried me.
God saved from demise once again.
- I thought God would punish me for that.
- God never punishes us.
He lets us bathe in His mercy.
He's waiting for us with open arms.
But the first step is on us.
Because we are not puppets.
And God gave us free will.
So far, I've been behind the wheel
in my life.
VEGA'S FILMS HAVE MADE
$112,000,000
I looked at God only when I needed Him.
Now, I'm handing the wheel to Him.
I want to work for Him,
not for myself.
Do you think God wants me to stop being a
movie director and do it in a different way?
Listen to yourself.
And answer this question yourself.
You've wanted to be a director
since you were a child.
Who gave you that dream?
Who put it in your heart?
Who made you a movie director?
Who prompts you the content
of your screenplays,
when you're praying for anointment?
Who made it all work in your heart?
Put it together?
And made you a craftsman?
I'll never be able to tell the story
of God's masterpiece here in Poland.
It's impossible due to the market
and budget limitations.
You know, the only bird that dares
to attack an eagle... is a raven.
It sits on it and pecks.
And what does the eagle does?
- Uh-huh?
- It doesn't fight back, or fly away.
It just rises higher and higher.
And finally the raven gives up,
because it sees the altitude
is way too high for it.
Can you hear me?
Slow down, and soar higher.
Am I supposed to stop working?
Not at all.
Slow down
to perfect every single detail.
Make beautiful works.
Complete in every way.
A tabernacle of God's Word.
Increase the level
through the power of our Lord.
Do you know what the scammers
made me realize?
What is it?
I'll always be around scammers
and greedy folks.
To become independent,
I must have my own money
for making movies.
I've matured enough to stop making
money for myself, and make it for God.
- Not a bad divine trip, isn't it?
- Yep.
I, a dude focused on making money
in life,
have reached a point where I pray to God
to give me control over talents.
Infinite resources that I'll manage wisely
and effectively to create our Lord's works.
This kind of money can't be made
in Poland. Not even in the UK.
This is Victor.
He used to work for the GRU.
There is the good CIA,
and the bad CIA.
I've my man in the good one.
The money you're looking for
is on Wall Street.
We'll get you the financing.
Our cut...
is 200 million dollars.
- You want to steal it?
- Yes.
You'll get a hundred.
We need 2 months
to see the deal through.
I'll make my last movie.
But...
last in your life?
In Poland.
I'll never be able to make a masterpiece,
unless I find a sufficient budget.
And in order to accomplish that,
I must start making movies in English
with Hollywood actors that will be
distributed all over the world.
How much do you need?
A lot.
So?
- Shall we go ahead with it?
- No.
No?
I don't want a single dollar out of it.
There's no such money
that'd make me break the seventh
commandment and betray Jesus Christ.
God opens amazing new spaces for me.
I'll set up a movie holding
in several countries,
where I'll operate in dollars,
pounds, euros, yens, yuan,
and Swedish crowns.
God has a sense of humor.
I prayed and I know
how to obtain the funds.
I'll finance spreading the Word
of God to Islamists that support ISIS.
Uh-huh.
I'll get the money in Qatar.
From the guys whose airspace
has been blocked out
for financing ISIS.
They have Al Jazeera.
Do you understand...
God's genius?
- It's a Trojan horse.
- If they don't cut your head off.
Prosperity comes from God.
It's a gift for you.
See how generous our Lord's been to us.
Where we started...
The road we've walked...
Now my mom drives a Porsche.
One can't get bored with you, son.
Thank God you grew up
without your father.
He would've made you
a completely different man.
A different child.
You wouldn't have achieved
what you have,
or become who you are.
I never was a child.
I was born a grown-up man.
And I suffered for the lack
of my earthly father.
It had an impact
on my relations with women.
I had no role models because of him.
And almost ended up in prison,
as I was growing up without the sense
of security that fathers give.
Only now have I understood
that I've always had...
this Father by my side.
The Father...
that has always protected me.
Fought for me...
And saved me...
even when I was an animal...
dwelling in a dark den
the evil one had lured me into.
I owe it only to God
that I'm on my way to Qatar.
I can jump into the fire with him.
And I know I won't burn...
and flames won't devour me.
Write me,
when you get there...
Pacio.
Mr PATRYK,
what do you intend
to spend the funds on?
I want to be number one.
INVISIBLE WAR
WRITTEN, DIRECTED AND PRODUCED
EXECUTIVE PRODUCER
SPIRITUAL CONSULTANT
DIRECTOR OF PHOTOGRAPHY
EDITED BY
MUSIC BY
SOUND
PRODUCTION DESIGN
COSTUME DESIGN
MAKE-UP
2ND UNIT DIRECTOR
1ST AD
CASTING DIRECTOR
STUNT COORDINATOR
PROMOTIONAL PHOTOS