INVINCIBLE LOVERS
On August 11th Vassilis escaped
from the orphanage
to go back to his grandmother,
at the village...
Whatever you say...
whatever you say...
...I'll do it, yes,
on my honor I will...
...whatever you say...
He traveled by truck at night
all the way to Isthmus.
Tripoli.
270. (drachmas)
I'll go before I see you get
tired of my kisses...
...I'll go before I see you with
a brand new flame...
...I'll go first, even if I break
my heart to pieces...
...I'll be the first to go so I'll take
all the blame...
...aaah, all the blame...
Adder!
No-no!
Adder and whip snake!
No!
If only an adder bit you...
Welcome!
- Whose are you?
- Panos Apostolopoulos' (son).
- Where to?
- To my grandma.
My blessing.
[Traditional folk song- Tsamikos dance]
[Traditional song]
Why are you not talking to me?
You know if there's a garage around?
A phone number perhaps?
Hey, listen...
Listen...
All right, thank you very much.
'Bye.
Go on, sleep.
I'll just sit here and not talk to you.
I watched a film last night.
My husband, the woman said,
is a gambler, a scoundrel, a burglar,
a swindler.
One night
he got a bullet in the eye.
Ah, says the man who listened,
is he blind now, then?
No, she says, he's dead.
Are you from this town?
Nah...
Well, save your breath,
don't talk so fast...
- This one.
- Have a seat.
How far are you going?
I'm going very far, got it?
Addio, miss.
There we go again...
Morning!
Welcome.
- And you'll have?
- A chocolate.
Ah, that's too little money.
You'll have a lokum (Turkish delight).
No, thanks.
Come!
Thief!
Lay off, dumbo.
Pal!
You won't talk?
Hey, listen...
Voyager!
Where are you headed?
Come, I'll take you there!
Come on, I'll drive you!
I'm out of petrol!
It's the truth!
Eat your meal.
What's with these hands?
Come inside!
Sit down!
All of it!
ORPHANAGE
"SANTA SOPHIA"
To Student Vassilis Apostolopoulos
Orphanage "Santa Sophia", Athens
Sender: Maria Dimopoulou
Kostis Palamas 36  PATRAS
- I am Vassilis.
- Welcome! Come in!
Enter.
Won't you kiss your sister?
I would suggest you stayed for the night
but we're leaving on holiday tomorrow.
Come here.
- Say good night!
- Good night.
Good night.
A whisky.
Vassilis, my boy, what will you have?
Spoon sweet?
Some ice-cream?
What shall I get you, then?
Whisky on the rocks.
You see that?
This has been happening
for quite some time now.
Vassilis?
How are things, then?
Fine.
Thank you.
A social worker, right?
A social worker.
I read about a new film
where an angel falls in love and
wants to become a mortal.
So they say that, this angel can only
be seen by the audience and children.
The audience for sure.
Yes, because children...
when you're facing a child
you feel that...
someone is actually by you.
" I am Vassilis".
You fathead...
So, you can speak, can you?
Farmer...
I've been sleeping in fields
for 3 days now.
Tonight we're going to a hotel,
you hear that?
What is this?
"Invincible lovers".
The farmer got himself some
food for thought!
Get inside! Get inside!
Fathead!
(With a head) like an airport!
Pour me some.
Whisky!
Thanks. A little more.
Put the cap back!
Will you teach me how to whistle too?
Where do you place your fingers?
Come!
Hey filthy!
Hey drunkard!
To the bathroom, quick!
My money!
Come inside!
It was "Scherzo Tarantelle"
in E minor, by Wieniawski.
Jordan stared into her eyes
with that look that only he knew
how to give her...
Lilia... Yes, Jordan...
Without answering, she put the
phone down with a single move.
His hands touched her fiery skin...
"Jordan", whispered Lilia...
I'll do whatever you ask me to...
I want you to get pleasure...
and give me pleasure, too...
You got it bad.
...I can see this wreckage...
...my empty life...
...and the thrashing around...
...Stay with me tonight...
...even for just this once...
I know nothing about you.
At times I wonder why
you don't talk to me.
Why did you leave?
Grandma!
Dumbo!
- Morning!
- Good morning!
Winter found Vassilis in Tripolis
He works in various jobs for his living
On Sundays he goes for a walk
[Church Liturgy]
That's all I'm asking...
...that you remember me...
...that's all I'm asking, dear heart...
A special request from Kiki,
this is for Takis.
If Takis is listening,
please give her a call.
You're the right person for me...
To me you're life itself...
...and my secret yearning...
On the night of his nameday Vassilis
decided to go back to his village
At daybreak he left Tripolis
English subs by never4ever for KG
(January 2015)