For many thousands of years ago,
there was an awful weapon
and the war has been invented.
Don't be impatient, Iksay. The news you
are waiting for is just around the corner.
We have been hunting in the next few
days. There are no traces of the game.
Gasellerna is gone, as well as the
badgers, fallow deer and wild boar.
There is only a buffalo, but how are
we going to be able to attack them?
Don't worry, the great Zot does not
allow us to starve to death.
Unfortunately, the ground is shaking
a long time, the last couple of days.
The animals are in fresh danger, and
hide in the woods.
What is it that makes you feel sad?
I need to select the tribe's new
leader.  "As you have made up your mind?
I'm too old. Someone else can take my
place.
An able and courageous man, who is
able to take advantage of your wisdom.
- Calm down, Vood.
- I want to be, Ela.
Do not weary yourself before the hunt.
Vood like to be a leader, but he
could not restrain himself.
For a woman to have more discipline
than him. How is he going to be able
to lead others?
You were like his.
A wild ungbuffel as well as rain,
thunder, lightning, and wind.
By the time you've been with a man.
It will be the same for the Vood.
"I'm not convinced of that, Ra.
Are you thinking of someone else? Speak
in Iksay, and I need to know about it.
- Ela to convince me.  "It goes
against tradition.
Vood, your woman's children. It is he
who must take the lead.
Iksay! Iksay! The wild boar. Many of
the.
, In the valley, beyond the area.
"What are you waiting for!
Vood, you are not a leader yet. Wait
here with the others.
Ra, the Zots, the name, then I ask
you: If the hunt is successful?
Human beings are often more dangerous
than the animal.
- You speak obscurely. What do you mean?
Be careful. Others are looking for prey.
Please pay attention. I'm with you,
no matter what.
"What is it?
- Rogh! Rogh!
- Why is the shout you get?  -
"Hide you in the cave. Don't cry.
Calm down, calm down.
Iksay.
The death of the. B.
Great Zot, take Iksays of the spirit.
He was a beloved leader, a great
hunter.
You are punishing the modlöse, and
the rewarder of the good.
To receive his spirit. We want to
thank you.
When the sun rises, in line with the
tradition of
will be of you in the lead for
the Zots strain.
'No!'
Vood is not fit to be a leader. He
was murdered in Iksay.
He needs to be punished.
That's enough!
What are you waiting for? To take him
out.
Vood, have come into contact with
his own people's blood. He does not
belong to our tribe anymore.
- Vood will be hunted as prey.  -
, Ela is right!
- Today, Ela is our leader.  - ,
Ela! Ela!
Run!
Watch out!
Please help!
Mom!!! Mom!!!
Vood!
- Who are you?  I is institute of
technology.
I wish to welcome you as the future
ruler.
- How do you know my name?  'Our
name is written in the stars.
"Where have you come from
linköping institute of technology?
"From a land beyond the stars.
My family worships the Efferon, god
allowed the earth to shake.
He wanted to see the one I left in
the middle of people. Now, I am one
of you, Vood.
It is a Vood.
Vood, have returned to the fight.
To provide you with the. As you have
said, " the two of you. You no longer
belong to the Zots strain.
- Create the.  - , Ela has already
beaten the Vood.
Vood, have been given a new coat of
arms of a god. Vood is invincible.
What are you waiting for? To kill me,
as Iksay, and Ra.
Vood kill you. Vood is the bathroom.
- Recognize him as a leader.  "No.
Vood to follow god's will. He was
forced to kill the Iksay, and Ra.
With this, the Zots tribe is
invincible.
If Vood. The fire god says it is.
Otherwise, be angry with him. The earth
is shaking, and everything is burned down.
Who of you recognize me, don't like
their leader?
Bring him to me!
This time, I will save your life.
For six days and nights, be sure to
stop at the apes ' land.
No weapons, no food and no water.
We'll have to see how to do it.
God gave me a weapon. The one who
follows me will get a like.
- Vood!
It was god's will that I might find
the perfect weapon.
We are going to be a tribe of the
conquerors.
Others may not work for us. Others
may supply us with food.
We will be the rulers. We are going
to show that the hero wins.
We are going to introduce a new law.
No one can be against us.
We have to be ruthless to everyone. It
will be a pity if those who refuse to obey.
Vood! Vood!
Please follow me."
- Stop! What do you want?"  -
"None". There is some wear.
Wait.
To rest of you. Put yourself in there.
"What is it?
- Don't worry. It will make you happy.
It is in the right here.
This.
Run! Run!
- The pain is gone.  "As a good
thing.
- Iza. My name is Iza.  - , Ela.
Iza belongs to the sages, the Mogos
of the tribe. She is the Mogos's.
In our village, one to the sun and beyond
the forest. In the big lake, on the beach.
Now, the need to Iza to go.
Wait.
Ela will go with you.
Now, when we are able to blend with
the black stone and no one can stop us."
It is in god's arms.
Only we know the secret. To reveal it
to anyone.
Clock has it right. The black stone
makes us mighty.
Yes, we will be invincible.
And, Vood, will be our leader.
I can't wait. I would like to fight,
and to force all into submission.
The time is now. In the morning start
your day with.
Iza!
Spring.
Hurry up, you, Ela!
, In the valley, there is a
buffelhjord.  The stop.
Kill!
Stop.
"We have won!!!
- Vood!
Vood will save your life. From now
on, Vood you, the leader.
You owe him the obedience of faith.
All of you are chasing belongs to him.
But the life of god. No one can take
someone else's prey.
So dies the one who sets himself against the Vood.
- Submit your. If Vood.
Speed up you, Iza.
Iza is a very sick and
tired. It can't be done.
"I can't be bothered.  "Come, beyond
the forest, we are safe and secure.
Go ahead of time.
- Iza! Did you feel bad?  "No.
Here, take my hand."
Put yourself in a.
However, it is, of course, Vood.
To see the way.
Com.
Forward.
Take those twigs.
We are going to enter.
Clock in, he's all yours.
"There are no more of them. ,
We.
, Who was a man with a lion's head?
- Vood. We are among the Zots strain.
We live in the mountains and beyond
the stars. As a little hunting together.
His father, the great Iksay, led by
the us.
"But you did not love each other? "No.
Vood's heart became proud and cruel.
For he will despise the tradition. I
realized too late just how dangerous he is.
- It is he who has hurt you?
"Yes." Vood don't want to have rivals.
He wants to kill me." He's got a new
coat of arms, and the tribe's compliance.
My father will help you, Ela. You are
assured of the Mogos village.
- Stay as you are.  Damage to him.
He is a child.
Don't be afraid. My name is Iza, I'm
a friend of yours.
"What is your name?
- Daal.
Voods of the tribe in need of powerful
warriors. You are going to bear a child.
You are all men and all men belong to
you.
If they are healthy, strong, and
faithful our god is.
The god who gave us this: "the
power of Darkness, the light and the fire
of the ruler.
God Efferon.
Efferon. Efferon.
To have a look. Behind every fire
there is a nomads.
In two of the phases of the moon, all
the strains belonging to the Vood.
Look it up, Vood. You
are able to get rid of
a powerful king, but
watch out for the Ela.
Ela will be put to death.
No one can withstand this new
weapon's power.
"What has happened?
- A bear attacked us.
Have a look, there is the Mogos of
the tribe.
Iza!
"It is up to you.  Thank You,
Oria.
- Father.
- Iza.
Eat.
Well.
Iza said that you were wounded by a
man from your own tribe.
The wound is open. You'll get the rest on
here. Hospitality is a sacred value for us.
Thank You, Mogo. It makes me feel better.
Your daughter has been caring for me.
I've heard of Zots tribe, who live in
the interior.
It is said that in the day ye eat the
flesh of animals, as well as the city
of the tribe.
The hague, the tribe is no more. The
man with the lion-head took it.
The man called Vood.
I don't understand. This has to be
one of them.
Why do Vood come into contact with
the city of blood?
Vood is much worse than that of Rogh,
with the sharp teeth.
Vood is more ferocious than the brown
bear with its strong claws.
He has killed up to Iksay, and Ra,
and the wise men.
He was trying to kill me.
Unfortunately, the dominate, is often
to the bestial instinct of the human being.
In each and every one of us lurks the
evil one.
That makes brothers of enemies.
We have to fight against the enemies of
his wisdom and the power of persuasion.
"We should love, not hate.
- Do you think it is possible to, Mogo?
Anything and everything is possible.
The mighty Efferon, you've given me
this weapon.
With these weapons, I will conquer
the land that has risen out of the water.
The land of the long shadows, in the
country, which is always greened.
With these weapons, I will conquer
all, and the honor of your name.
Hurry up and enter.
The village lies beyond the forest,
on the lake shore.
If my eyes don't deceive me, and so
is the Ela of the village.
And this time, he couldn't get away.
- I'm going to have to kill him.
Let's go.
Ela would like to have a variety of
weapons. Elah to fight against the
Rogh, with the long teeth.
No. Mogos tribe has no weapons.
We don't need any weapons.
But the beast is destroying the
Mogos village, if not the Mogo to defend
themselves.
We can't go against the grain of our
nature. The weapons are the bad guys.
Unfortunately, the arms, to
bloodshed, and that is a bad thing.
"Life is sacred to us.
- Iza, which is why he does not want to understand?
Mogo is the way. Mogo talk sense.
Ela, do not be Rogh. Rogh time has
passed.
Rogh but Vood is coming soon, and
Vood does not go their way.
Vood, may stem the blood flow.
Mogo hasn't done Vood ill. And Vood
does not Mogo bad.
Rogh.
Mogo, you can't let the beast kill
the women and children.
"You need to stop it.  - , Ela
is right.
Let's go. What do you consider to be
the right one.
Where is the Ela? Where has he been
hiding? Bring him here dead or alive.
Find him and kill him.
Watch carefully over her. She might
know where the Ela is hiding.
Stop.
You can't do anything for her.
We have to find him. He will have to
move.
- Search for. He can't have gone far.
"In way of you.
Com Ela, before it's too late in the
day.
Com.
From now on, Vood you, the new leader.
None of you for a long time. Not even
in your life. It all belongs to the Vood.
Glory be to Vood, and the greatest
warrior.
- Vood.
- Vood!
In honor Vood, honor, your king."
- Glory be to Vood!
- Vood!
The women stay in the
village and work. They
are subject to the
institute of technology.
Able-bodied men to come with us.
Now, we know that there is food in
abundance here.
It is here, the people, were to be
serve.
I will leave the village in your
hands, the Clock. The warriors are
replaced every six mo.
- They don't hang out with them.
- Put your trust in me. If you
continue to chase the Ela?
Why is that? The eagle kills the
snake, only when it dares to show itself.
Don't touch them. They are a group of
viruses.
We need to walk away. The wounds and causes
of death. Everything in here is tainted.
The Fort here.
Great Vood, there is a need for more
men in order to wear off all of the iron.
Soon we will have more and more of
the men.
"You did that on purpose, your a
fool.  "No.
Get up.
To work.
We will have to do many of these
things.
It is wise Mogo does not come to an
agreement.
If Mogo is the way he knows that his
ideas are the only functions in the wild.
But freedom is found in Mogos words
are just words in the wind.
Ela is right, but the Mogos heart is
heavy.
Let Mogo take off his eyes of the
blood.
Please keep in mind: the Weapons you
can give you the freedom back in the day.
However, in the morning, they can
deprive you of it.
We can't let him go. To stop him, Ela.
He has made his choice.  "But
he will not survive in the forest.
If he stays, he needs to offer up
their ideas.
Mogos wisdom is more to it than that.
His selection is worthy of our respect.
- Stay as you are, old-timer.
Where are you going?
From everywhere and nowhere.
I'm looking for berries to eat and
water to drink.
- What is the tribe you belong to?
- Vildkaninernas of the tribe.
And in the forests, and all of the
other animals.
"You're lying. If you run with
us?  "I have no reason to be.
You are a provocateur. That's what
you are.
Have a look at this
weapon. It is the symbol
of the god of Efferon.
The case of the knee.
"What are you waiting for?
- Case upon his knees.
- A kiss to it.
- Do as he says, the old-timer.
If.
You asked for it, your old man an
idiot.
Now, are you, Voods slaves. I am a
leader.
What was yours is mine.
I have dominion over life and death.
Thanks to this weapon, forcing you to
bend down.
You need to be working for me, if you
want to stay alive.
Collect all of the fresh men, and
take them to the volcano.
Where do they dig up the black stone
cornerstone in place, the day and the
night.
If anyone dares to rise up...
- A good one.  Is the Voods
weapons?
No, but it Vood do not expect an
attack. He is full of confidence.
Speed.
- I'm asking you...
- don't Try to escape again.
Now you are in charge of the women.
If anyone tries to escape will cost
you your life.
To work.
You guys are the chosen ones. You
guys are the warriors that can't be beat.
Efferon has chosen you, that ye should
honor the Vood, and for the people.
Vood takes you higher and higher. One
day we will become masters of the world.
What is Taag?
- Vood, why don't we?  "What do
you say?
Vood can be satisfied. We have taken
a lot of people.
We are the rulers of the valley. No
one will dare to rebel.
When you quit the exercise of its
power, it is the beginning of the end.
We are living in the battle. War is
our purpose in life.
What can it be used a weapon to
silence?
"Everybody hates us, Vood.
"No," they will fear us.
We can't stop it. Don't forget, Ela.
As long as he's alive-
-we are in trouble.
I was his slave. Its origin is lost.
I had to be obedient to him, but for
now, I want to take revenge.
"In what way?
- Vood is a cunning and slippery.
However, he has been a sore point:
the fact that Vood is doing what, as
a whole, in order to prove his power.
- Don't trust her, she's lying.
"No," how does it benefit me to lie?
If you want to get revenge, you'll
see that he's coming here either.
- What is your plan?  I just want
to challenge him.
Go to the Vood is now. You are
clever, to convince him.
- Do you trust her?  "No.
However, Vood must know that I am
here.
Where is my father?  He would
have preferred to go.
He didn't want to see his the tribe
to fight.
However, you have to fight, Iza.
Along with me, to Vood.
As for the others, do what you
do.  "It is a suicide.
Our boys are not warriors. Vood has
been one of god's weapons.
The weapon is man-made.
Vood, have a lot of strain. How are
you going to stop them?
Neither the number of the men or
their guns scare me.
They are different, and Iza. For
them, life has no value.
They love to kill. It scares me, Iza.
"We must put a stop to them.
- You'll also spills the blood of the.
What is the difference between them?
I can understand why my father left.
Maybe I should do as he says.
Watch the Ela, this is what the tree
is.
We can't be beat Vood, with a few
boughs, and Daal.
- Why did you stop?  "I have won.
The war was over.
You don't think so. It's just stupid.
They have horrible weapons, and
fought to kill.
When you're on the ground, undoes the
top stomach in the er.
Step right up and start all over.
"You are too hard on them.
- It is not enough.
You are blinded by your father's
ideas. Why, do you not?
My father made his choices and I make
mine.
I would like to help you out. I was
thinking of stopping by.
"Can't you not sleep?
- I don't get tired.
But now I'm going to sleep.
Vood!
He is a boy, and three women. The
women don't count.
You can easily kill him. A dozen men
will suffice.
"I would also like to fight. Where do we go?
- Impatience is associated with passion.
There's a dangerous feel to it. The
suspect, Ela you?
No, I don't think so.
Go back to the village. Let's say I accept
the challenge and are going it alone.
Tighten it a little to aim for.
Say to yourself, "I'm spike, and I'm
going to hit the target."
I am in the lead. To meet the goal.
Well.
Don't even think about the next day.
Iza fight by your side.
We can do it, you'll see.
Ela! Vood, in the morning. Alone.
"All Right, Linköping Institute Of
Technology. Go to the others now.
"But Ela...
Go back to your seat and pay
attention.
Stop Ideas!! He is our friend.
Sorry, Iza, and in the darkness he
looked like one of the Voods men.
What are they, and Iza?
Tracks, and the Jeda,
which the men of our tribe.
"What has happened? How did you
get here?  We managed to escape.
Vood, forcing us to work. In two days
we have been wandering without any food.
It is better to die, and Iza, than it
is to be Voods of the slave.
- Please help us.  Yes, if you'll
help us to beat Vood.
No, no, you stay here.
Ela! Ela!
Where are you Ela?
Ela!
To stay there.
- Vood! Vood!  - , Ela!
Look it up, Vood!
Here I am, Vood.
Vood!
- You must hurry!
- Vood!
Stop. Please come back.
Coward, to attack.
Ela.
You won't Spli.
But one day, there will be another
Vood.
Remember, in Ela: a Weapon can give
you the freedom back in the day
"but in the morning, they can
deprive you of it.
Violence gives birth to violence.