In Cairo, a muezzin calls
faithful Muslims to prayer.
It's the same call that sounds
five times a day, every day,
in cities across the world.
Nearly a quarter of the people
on earth respond to it,
'God is most great'
the muezzin calls.
'I testify
there is no other god but God.'
Muhammad is the messenger of God.
'Come and pray.
Come and flourish.
'God is most great.
'There is no god but God.'
In the unfolding of history,
Islamic civilisation has been
one of humatiy's grandest achievements.
A worldwide power
founded simply on faith.
A spiritual revolution that would
shape the nations of three continets
and launch an empire.
For the West, much of the history
of Islam has been obscured
behind a veil of fear
and misunderstanding.
Yet Islam's hidden history
is deeply, and surprisingly,
interwoven with Western civilisation.
It was Muslim scholars who reclaimed
the ancient wisdom of Greeks.
While Europe languished
in the Dark Ages.
It was they who sowed the seeds
of the Renaissance,
600 years before the birth
of Leonardo da Vinci.
From the way we heal the sick...
to the numerals we use for counting...
cultures across the globe
have been shaped by Islamic civilisation.
But all this, began with the life
of a single, ordinary man,
and the profound message he proclaimed
would change the world forever.
His name was Muhammad.
To Muslims, the life of Muhammad
is a story revered.
In its mysteries
as much as its certainties,
there are beliefs held sacred.
Whatever we can tell
about the Prophet, of course,
is screened through the filter of what
has been preserved over the centuries
and what people
have wanted to preserve.
It's very difficult to pull out,
from all these different sources
that are very adoring,
the ordinary human being...
We do know that Muhammad was born
in or around 570 AD
in the sun-blasted Arabian peninsula.
A land of savage scarcity
whose Bedouin tribes were locked
in a constant state of tribal war.
While still an infant,
Muhammad's parents gave him
his first taste of life in the desert.
Muhammad was from a town, Mecca,
but he was sent off
to live with the Bedouin
because the people
even the town of Mecca
felt that the Bedouin were the holders
of the deeper cultural Arab values.
And the Bedouin view the towns people
as having lost their really authentic
roots in Arab culture
and the poetry and animal husbandry
and all the things that they do so well.
By the time Muhammad was six,
both of his parents had died
and he was taken under the protection
of his uncle, chief of his clan.
Being an outsider
gave him a singular perspective.
He'd been orphaned early
and developed very early on
a passionate sense of concern
for those who are left out of society.
To be orphaned in a tribal society
where clan and family relationships
are your keys to everything...
success, status, honour, dignity...
is to face what it really feels like
to be marginalised.
That obviously had a very deep
impression on him as a young man.
In some ways, it was detrimental,
of course, to grow up without parents.
But in other ways
he was so adaptable.
He had many parents.
He had many fathers.
He had many mothers.
So it made him a child of everybody.
Muhammad's clan, like Arabs
all across the Arabian peninsula,
would share the stories that had been
told and retold for generations.
Pre Islamic Arabian civilisation
was largely an oral culture
and there was tremendous respect
and admiration
for people who could
express themselves orally,
especially those who could recite
poetry almost at the drop of a hat.
Some of the most important people
in a tribe were the poets.
They sang of the glory of the tribe.
They told the story of the tribe.
To the Bedouin,
the word had a mystical importance.
Poets linked the tribe to its ancestors
and celebrated values older than memory.
Poetry was the sinew
that bound the Bedouin together,
celebrating their victories,
lamenting their defeats.
The poems themselves,
like the poems of Homer,
both celebrate
this great heroic ethos
and yet intimate,
in the deepest way,
the tragedy that, um...
this war... this ethos of constant
tribal warfare brings to people.
Warfare and conflict were
the grim realities of a dangerous time.
Muhammad's uncle taught him
the skills he'd need to survive
in a world where even a prophet
would wield a bow and arrow.
In a wilderness punished by the elements
and bereft of water,
rivalry over a single well could
provoke a blood feud for generations.
A real rivalry. Real battles,
and sometimes quite bloody.
So the allegiance of individuals
was the family, immidiately,
and, a larger extent, to the tribe.
Without the tribe's protection,
no one could endure.
Scattered across the peninsula
were countless factions,
all embroiled in bitter struggles,
each defending its precious
grazing lands, trade routes
and most importantly, its wells.
You have to understand
that most of the lands are dry.
So, water is something that
everyone always considers precious.
For those of us in climates
that are more heavily watered
it's difficult to understand the depth
and the centrality of the symbol of water
in societies that are desert
and in which it only rains
once or twice a year
and in which a little water makes
the difference between life and death.
Each clan had its own separate
gods and totems.
To water and wind,
fire and night.
They were kept
in the caravan town of Mecca,
in a shrine of wood,
stone and cloth.
It was called the Kaaba,
the Arabic word for 'cube'.
Pre Islamic Arabs
worshipped a number of spirits.
They were generally nature-oriented spirits
sometimes associated with natural features.
Like trees or rocks or springs.
And the Kaaba in Mecca was
one of a number of these sanctuaries
centred around
a particular cluster of deities.
It was said the Hebrew patriarch
Abraham himself
built the Kaaba centuries before
and that a sacred black stone it held within
had fallen from the sky.
In these turbulent times,
the Kaaba provided a rare place of peace.
Only here would the Bedouin
submit to a temporary truce
before returning to their conflicts
of the open sands.
There was this one place
in the middle, around the Kaaba,
which was, from even pre Islamic times,
a place of... a sacred enclosure
where all people
had to put down their arms.
This, of course, facilitated trading
because it meant that you couldn't
carry on your feuds, when you
were doing your buying and selling
The spiritual and economic
importance of the Kaaba and Mecca
are pretty hard to seperate as far
as the pre-Islamic Arabs are concerned.
The Kaaba made Mecca
a vibrant centre for trade.
Here were found Arabian incense,
exotic perfumes and Indian spices,
Chinese silks and Egyptian linens.
But perhaps the greatest treasure
to be found at Mecca
was the rich mixture of cultures.
They were people who came through town
who had all kinds of interesting
experiences to relate of faraway places.
The local religion was mixed.
There were Christians, there were Jews.
There were also the Arabs of the desert
who followed an animist type of religion.
Muhammad's world was a centre of trade,
connecting the Mediterranean Sea
to the Indian Ocean,
linking the ageing empires
of Byztantium and Persia
to the great bazaars
of India and China.
Muhammad became a merchant.
In fact,
he had a great flair for trade.
At the age of 25, while leading
a caravan northward to Syria,
his talents caught the eye
of the shipment's owner,
a wealth widow named Khadijah.
She was so taken with Muhammad,
she proposed marriage.
Ah, Khadijah. Well, I think
she was a mentor as well as a wife.
A very strong lady
who had her own business
and Muhammad was helping her out.
So, it was a wonderful partnership
and I'm sure he learned a lot from her.
He had a tremendous amount of contact
with merchants coming from
different parts of the world,
passing through the Arabian peninsula.
I think he was a very intelligent man,
very open minded,
and he was able to communicate
with a great variety of people.
He must have had
great charisma as well.
Muhammad had a way with people,
and with resolving their disputes.
Once, when the Kaaba
fell into disrepair,
the clan chieftains quarrelled
over who would have the honour
of putting the sacred black stone
back where it belonged.
Before violence could erupt,
Muhammad proposed an equitable solution.
United in the effort,
the four leaders shared the weight...
and the honour.
In gratitude, they invited Muhammad himself
to replace the secret stone.
He became known as Al Amin,
'The Trusted One'.
There are all kinds of indications
that he was tremendously interested
in religious questions.
This is obviously not something
that an ordinary person probably
was interested in in those days.
He talked to...
sages, Arab sages.
He talked to Jewish and Christian sages
who lived in the area.
He used to go up
into the rock hills around Mecca
and meditate, think about things.
And at some point
he had this extraordinary vision
which is spoken about
very evocatively and allusively.
In a cave above Mecca,
Muhammad had an experience that would
be the defining moment of his life.
An angel was said to appear before him
in the form of a man,
instructing him to recite
in the name of God, the Almighty.
For Muhammad, it was an encounter
as profound as it was deeply disturbing.
You get a sense
of what it would be like
to be a normal person in society...
perhaps unusual in the sense
of your intensity for things
like social justice and finding out
what the meaning of life is,
but not being endowed with anything
that would seem miraculous by your friends.
And all of a sudden
having this voice come to you
and then come OUT of you as you speak it
and recite it to other people.
And that is the beginning
of the prophetic career of Muhammad.
The months to come
would bring more revelations...
powerful words of a lyrical quality,
more beautiful than
the most exquisite Arabic poetry.
Above all, Muhammad was to bear
one message to his people,
a simple yet radical proclamation.
That there is only one God.
The central tenet of Islam is the oneness,
the indivisible unity of God.
Not something that is simply...
that one pays lip service to
but something that is absolutely
the most important concept.
Divine unity is more
than saying there's only one God
and there are no other deities.
It's only thinking about one thing.
So, to be thinking about possessions,
to be thinking about status,
to be thinking about power,
are all intellectual idols.
The implications were staggering.
One God meant one people.
No more tribal divisions.
To the poor and unprotected,
the prospect was revolutionary.
Seems to me that
one of the most important things
in his early teaching
that isn't often talked about
is the strong social justice message
that he delivered.
In Mecca at the time
there was an increasing separation
between the haves and the have nots.
He insisted that this was not to be
and that we should share the wealth.
It was this social justice
message that, i think,
really got him a hearing
among many of the folks.
So coming with Islam
it was a new order, a new way of life,
and it was a beautiful way of life
because everybody was equal...
black, white, men, women, children.
So it had that type
of universal appeal
which I think was the reason
why Islam spread so rapidly.
Many were moved
by Muhammad's message
as he began to speak out
in the community.
It had the suppleness and symbolic depth
of the great pre-Islamic poems
that had been created by this people
and that had given
these people in Arabia
such an Extraordinary ear
for verbal expression,
where verbal expression
was the commanding cultural force.
Some people called him a poet.
There's a Qur'anic sura
basically saying...
Muhammad is not a poet.
Poets speak through desire.
This is not the voice of desire,
this is the voice of God.
Muhammad's following began to grow.
They called themselves 'Muslims',
for those who surrender to God.
They set out to preserve the message
Muhammad had brought.
This was the beginning of the Qur'an.
The Qur'an was revealed orally
but very soon people realised
it had to be written down
in order to make sure
it wasn't corrupted
and the original message
was maintained.
From a very early date, and it's
very unclear when that date was
because no early manuscripts
of the Qur'an survive,
people began copying it down.
The Qur'an is a revelation
of spiritual teaching,
of both ethical and social guidance.
It was revealed, and remains,
in Arabic.
What's so extraordinary
about the Qur'an is its naturalness,
so that it can say
the most powerful cosmic things
with a sense of intimacy,
so that power and tenderness come together
constanly in the Qur'anic language.
With words alone, the Qur'an delivers
its vision to the faithful.
Its imagery conjures
a picture of the afterlife
that resonates with all the power
of traditional Bedouin poetry.
Imagine yourself in the desert...
surrounded by dust,
by the glare of the sun.
You wear cloaks to cover your body
because the wind will just
sear your skin right off your face.
And you walk into an oasis.
The temperature drops dramatically.
There's a quiet there.
The wind is no longer howling.
Everywhere you look
you see green and colour.
The world of water and paradise
are symbolically tied to one another.
And the Qur'an can conjure that up
with just a few briefly chosen words.
Yet for all the imagery of paradise
in the Qur'an,
there was no easy description of God.
The mystery would remain.
It's very difficult to talk about God
without reifying God,
reifying to make God into a thing,
or anthropomorphising God,
to make God into a projection
of our own human self.
That's why Muslims don't like sculpture,
for example, traditionally,
because they believe
there's that danger.
The Qur'an avoids that
by constantly shifting the pronouns
so we can't really reify God and get
an image, a physical image of God.
Rather than a physical image of God,
or of Muhammad,
it is the beauty of the Qur'an itself
that is celebrated in Islam.
Islam developed in this context
where pictures were not favoured.
The Qur'an as it was revealed
was God's representation on earth.
And Muslims felt
from a very early time
that the only just representation
of God's word was the Qur'an itself,
not any picture of... God, certainly not,
because you couldn't represent God,
and certainly not a picture of Muhammad,
because he wasn't divine.
At certain times and places people did
make images of the Prophet Muhammad.
But these are not religious images,
these are not images
meant to be worshipped,
they are not images
of a saint or of God.
They're images of Muhammad
as a historical figure.
He's sort of given honour by having
a very bright blue background
or a white cloud near him
but he's not otherwise distinguished
from the other characters in the story.
At other times
people did represent the Prophet
but always with a white cloth
over his face, to hide his face.
So there were different
approaches to doing this.
But in all of these,
these are not devotional images.
You're not supposed to look at them
and pray towards them.
You're to learn more about
the history of your religion,
with the emphasis on history,
from them.
As Muhammad's community grew,
so did the opposition.
People, of course, were sceptical
and said "Look, if you're a prophet,
where's your miracle?"
"And the prophets
in the Qur'an...
"Moses had miracles,
Jesus had miracles.
"Where's your miracle?"
And the Qur'anic answer
to that challenge is...
"This is the miracle...
this Qur'an.'
But that wasn't miracle enough
for the people who defined themselves
by the gods of their ancestors
and the totems of their tribe.
Their doubts increased.
The idea of life after death
appalled them.
So, the Qur'an presents people
as really being sceptical.
"You mean to tell me that after I die
"and my body has gone back
to the elements and I've been putrefied
"that I'm going to be
put back together again
"and brought back to life?"
That, of any of the messages
in the Qur'an,
that struck the people of Arabia
as being the most hard to believe.
Muhammad also spoke
of eternal damnation for the unjust.
He used the language
of apocalyptic imagery,
talking about
the signs of the end of time...
when the mountains crumble,
when the skies are rolled up like scrolls,
then you will know what responsibility
you bear for your actions.
There are references to those
who are unjust going to the fire.
To the non believers,
the divine reckoning Muhammad invoked
was an outrage...
His dismantling of their heritage
and customs, deeply unsettling.
It was a threat, in several ways...
to their social order,
to their age old traditions
and an economic threat
because of the importance
of the pilgrimage shrine
of the Kaaba in Mecca.
As Muhammad's following increased,
the social fabric of the caravan city
began to unravel.
Business suffered as pilgrims and traders,
worried for their safety, left town.
The tribal leaders decided
Muhammad and his message
must be removed, permanently.
They didn't want him taking over and
horning in on their control of the city.
They made things very difficult for him,
perhaps even plotted his assassination.
They tried to keep him from the Kaaba,
doing all they could to run him out of town.
They demanded Muhammad's uncle remove
his clan's protection from the Prophet...
which would clear the way for his murder
without the threat of retribution.
But his uncle refused.
The battle lines were drawn.
Nothing short of tribal war
would settle the conflict now.
Muhammad is clearly asked to do
extraordinary things...
to tell the Bedouin to give up
many of their notions of multiple gods,
to give up their attachment
to their ancestors
and their tribal warfare
in the way they had.
Things that... could and did make him
the object of scorn, persecution
and, um... attack.
Muhammad's followers were forced
from the marketplace and starved.
Those without clan protection
were tortured and killed.
In 619 AD,
Muhammad's wife Khadijah died...
and his uncle as well.
Gone were his first great love
and his only protector.
Here at last was the opportunity
his enemies had been waiting for.
But in the lush oasis town
of Yathrib, north of Mecca,
a refuge opened
to Muhammad and his people.
Clan rivalries had become
deadly in the town
and they desperately needed
a peacemaker.
They had heard that Muhammad
was a very trustworthy man.
They'd heard he had great arbitration
skills, and they thought...
"Let's get him here to help out."
So they invited him.
Muhammad agreed to travel to Yathrib
and settle their disputes
in exchange for a safe refuge
for his people.
For Muhammad's followers,
leaving the place of their ancestors,
their families and tribes
was the ultimate test of devotion.
In doing so, they began
a new community, a new tribe.
For the first time, they were
bound together not by blood,
but by faith.
In the course
of a single caravan journey,
Islam marks its true beginnings.
Their journey is known as the Hijrah.
622 in the Christian calendar
marks the Muslim Year 1.
Muhammad's goal
among the people of Yathrib
was the same as his larger mission...
to bring unity and peace
with his message...
He was asked to be
a Solomonic figure,
to mediate tensions between tribes
that seemed intractable.
As his work succeeded,
the town would become known
as the City of the Prophet...
Medina.
Muhammad's great task in Medina
was to try and bring together
these various groups,
to try and forge
a community of believers
in a way that would bring people
together in a sort of harmony.
To the divided clans of Medina,
Muhammad offered a vision of solidarity.
But even as he spread
the word of Islam,
he didn't challenge
the beliefs of other faiths.
Islam sees itself in relatlonship,
to the earlier revealed religions
of Judaism and Christianity
and treats them as people of the Book.
It believes that God had revealed himself,
his word, to mankind many times...
to Moses, to Jesus,
for example, and...
but each time
people went astray.
Throughout the Qur'an we have
a sense of the humanity of Muhammad,
his humbleness as a person
and the extraordinary challenge
of the mission he was given
by this divine revelation.
As the Muslim community grew
in Medina,
a life of simple devotion
and ritual developed.
A freed Abyssinian slave,
named Bilal,
was the first to call believers
to prayer at Muhammad's house.
Allahu akbar.
It was the first mosque.
The call to prayer has within it
the first Islamic Pillar
which is the affirmation
of God's unity...
"La ilaha illa Allah"...
that beautiful phrase
which many Muslims chant
over and over in their mind,
or vocally,
to constantly remind themselves
of the unity of the God.
And the unity of what
we should focus on in our life.
Allahu akbar.
La ilah illa Allah...
Praying together is a good thing.
It cements the idea of belonging
to a movement, to a religion,
to an organisation, to a community.
The result is something
very, very powerful even to watch,
even for a non believer
or someone from another religion.
We carry out physical
gestures of prayer, in worship,
that unify our body
and our mind and our soul,
all at the same moment of bowing
and touching our head to the ground
toward that exact centre.
What could be
a more powerful symbol of unity?
It's said that, while he was in Medina,
Muhammad received a revelation,
instructing those in prayer to face
in the direction of the Kaaba in Mecca.
Though filled with pagan idols,
it was still the shrine of Abraham,
the first believer
in the one true God.
But even as the Muslims
were praying toward Mecca,
their enemies there
were rallying in force.
Their goal...
to wipe out the Muslims.
Muhammad 's people
began to gather arms.
Though the Muslims prepared
as best they could,
they were outnumbered
and outmatched.
They mustered a force of only 313,
mostly old men and boys,
with few weapons...
while the approaching Meccans were
heavily armed and a thousand strong.
For years, Muhammad had tried to bring
Islam to the people of Mecca peacefully.
Now it was time to fight.
Muslims faced their own tribes,
brother fighting brother,
son against father.
Yet they came armed
with a powerful weapon...
a passionate belief in their faith...
Muhammad's troops fought
with every confidence
that God's will was guiding them.
They fought three
very, very bloody battles.
At one point, the entire young Muslim
community was on the edge of annihilation.
For three years, the Muslim army
held out against staggering odds.
As word of the fighting spread,
other Bedouin tribes saw God's hand
in Muhammad's victories.
One by one, the peoples of the desert
began to join in his struggle.
The Muslim army grew
and tide began to turn.
The Muslim forces advanced
to the outskirts of Mecca.
It was a furious siege
that lasted for nearly a month.
Until, finally, the city
fell to Muhammad.
In 630 AD, the terrified people
of Mecca braced for the onslaught.
Muhammad's army was returning home,
now 10,000 strong...
The vanquished knew the terrible fate
that awaited them.
According to the modes
of tribal warfare,
the Meccans could expect
a big revenge.
The men are usually killed.
Women and children
are sold into slavery.
There's little pity
for the loser in a tribal war.
Of course, that's standard
around the world.
But Muhammad had a surprise in store
for the fallen city.
When Muhammad came into Mecca
and not only did not carry out
a bloody revenge
but actually embraced the very Meccans
who had fought him for three years
and attempted to annihilate him,
it was very shocking
to the people in his milieu.
So, within the very founding
of the religion
one finds episodes
of great generosity...
often extraordinary acts
of kindness and mercy.
But not all of Mecca
escaped Muhammad's wrath.
Flush with victory, his troops
marched straight to the Kaaba.
Seven times
they circled the shrine,
as those who had come to seek
its protection appealed to their idols.
But it was not the pagan people
Muhammad come to destroy.
It was their gods.
He raised his staff
and the tribal gods of his ancestors
smashed into dust.
When Muhammad entered Mecca
and entered the shrine,
and destroyed
the idols in the shrine,
this is of great cultural
and symbolic importance in Islam.
By breaking the idols,
he was breaking apart
the tribal system
in which each tribe really had
its own independent deity.
This was schocking to the Bedouin.
This was saying, the gods
of our fathers are being destroyed.
In some sense, you are saying that
our fathers themselves were deluded.
How can you say this in a tradition
in which relationships
to one's father and tribe were primary?
So, this act of iconoclasm, then,
is seen as an act
of prophetic violence
that has just as much importance
in Islamic tradition
as Moses's breaking of the tablets
when he saw the idolatry at Mt Sinai
or Jesus's casting of the money sellers
out of the Temple.
The Muslims turned to the north,
They continued west, into Egypt,
and quickly across North Africa,
fortifying the coastline
of the Mediterranean.
Only the seas stopped them.
Its growth was so explosive
from 622, Year 1
of the Islamic calendar.
Within 50 years,
people whose fathers
had been camel herders
were now governing
one of the major empires in world history.
Within 200 years
it extended from Spain to China.
The Muslims absorbed
the Sasanian Empire of Iran
and two thirds
of the Christian Byzantine Empire.
By now the empire was larger than Rome.
It stretched from Morocco in the west
to the Indus River in the east,
where the border of India is today.
How had it happened,
that so small an army could conquer
an area so large, so fast, so easily?
Islam's success in expanding
into the central Middle East
then across North Africa
was due in large part
because people were fed up
with previous regimes.
So the idea that Muslims were going across
the world saying that "Convert or Die"
is really not accurate, not at all.
They didn't have a heavy hand,
they didn't rule with a heavy hand.
They allowed the conquered people
to maintain their administrative structures.
They allowed the Christians and the Jews
to maintain their religious law
and to be governed by them.
And so, in many cases,
conquered peoples did not feel
the presence of the new regime
very heavily.
Certainly for individuals who felt
themselves exploited or downtrodden
by an oppressive and even
sometimes parasitic priesthood,
the idea of Islam being a religion
essentially free from clergy
must have seemed very attractive.
It's the times that create
the movement and sometimes the men.
The Roman Empire had collapsed.
The Byzantine Empire
wasn't strong enough.
There was a need for a new vision,
a new way of looking to life
and i think what happened
at that time,
Muhammad's mission filled the void
that the societies wanted.
They really wanted some sort
of solidarity in their lives.
The lessons of the Qur'an,
so successful for the Muslims
in Medina and Mecca,
were playing out on a global scale.
As the conquest swept through Syria,
the Muslims held their friday prayers
in the church of St John the Baptist
in Damascus...
allowing its Christian congregation
to continue their services on Sunday.
Side by side, the two faiths shared
the same building, in peace.
As the Muslim community grew,
they bought the old church
from the Christian congregation
and built a huge mosque on the site.
With Byzantine artisans, they decorated it
with golden mosaics of an Islamic paradise.
The Great Mosque of Damascus would
become a model for new mosques to come,
all across the empire.
The Arabs transformed
their conquered lands,
maintaining, improving
or expanding the infrastructure.
In Tunisia,
building on Roman ruins,
they devised an ingenious system
of water purification,
using gravity to separate
fresh water from sediments.
Part of this system
were these two enormous basins
that they built
outside the city walls.
The clean fresh water
would flow over into the larger basin
where it would then be distributed
by pipes to the city.
This is, you know,
hundreds of years before
anyone in Europe ever thought
of having running water.
All over you find schemes
for bringing water from the mountains,
where there was more water,
to the plains,
where there might be less water.
They resurrected
elaborate irrigation systems,
filling the old stone aqueducts
with precious water.
Agriculture flourished
as life-giving staples like wheat were
introduced to the Mediterranean region.
In just 100 years,
Muhammad's vision had transformed
the spiritual and political map of the world
and his followers had established
an empire larger than Rome.
But Muhammad
never lived to see it.
In the 11th year
of the Islamic calendar,
632 AD, only two years
after the taking of Mecca,
Muhammad died.
Medina fell into despair.
For days, the city was consumed
with sorrow and ceremony.
He's known to have said that
he wanted to be buried very simply
with no marker over his grave.
He didn't want people
to worship his grave.
That would interfere
with their worship of God.
God had spoken to them
only through Muhammad.
Now that the Prophet had left them,
perhaps God would as well.
Muhammad's death set up a crisis
in the young Islamic community.
The question of succession was the first
thing that really occupied people's concerns.
At this point there was
a divergence of opinion as to how
the community should
go about choosing a new leader.
According to the Shi'ites,
a faction, the Shi'a of Ali,
Muhammad had indeed designated Ali
his son-in-law and cousin, as his successor.
The opinion that came to be
the majority, or Sunni opinion
held that Muhammad had not appointed
a successor during his life
but had said "After I am gone,
choose one from among your peers,
from among the elders."
And from the house there came out a man
who would be his successor, Abu Bakr.
And he addressed the people
and said...
"If you worship Muhammad, know
that he is dead"
"If you worship God, know
that he lives forever. "
Here was the secret to Islam's strength
and profound influence...
the unifying power of one God,
merciful and compassionate,
the power of one people,
bound by a common faith.
Muhammad did not lead the
conquest of create the empire to come
The transforming power
of his message did.
Out of that message would spring
a font of knowledge
that would transform humanity,
as Islam continued to spread
its reach far and wide.
Awaiting the Muslims
would be a new age.
They would be destined
for enlightenment, for new horizons,
and a clash of great powers
the like of which
the world have never seen...
During the 7th and 8th centuries AD,
a powerful new faith
was about to change the world...
the faith of Islam.
Its followers launched a conquest
not only by the sword
but with the power of ideas.
Two hundred years after
the death of Muhammad
his message, and the new Arab empire,
were transforming three continents.
Now comes a new empire,
a political new configuration,
driven by a religious,
newly defined civilisation.
This new civilisation,
expanding beyond its own dreams
within a period of very short time.
Literally, the largest empire
civilisation had ever known.
The Arabic word for conquest, futuh,
literally means 'openings'.
Islam sowed the seeds of its faith
to the four winds
and a world of opportunities
opened before it.
But the vast empire's spiritual core
remained at its birthplace...
the holy city of Mecca.
From every corner
of the Muslim world
the faithful embarked
on the traditional journey to Mecca,
a sacred pilgrimage
known as the Hajj.
The pilgrimage became a central devotional
and ritual feature in Islamic life.
In fact, since the life
of Muhammad himself,
the pilgrimage
has symbolised,
probably more than
any other Islamic ritual activity,
unity among all people
and equality.
The Hajj set humanity in motion.
For the first time
since the reign of Alexander the Great,
cultures and caravans now flowed freely.
Borders closed for a thousand years
opened...
Both ideas and goods went
back and forth over incredible distances.
Since every Muslim is enjoined
once in his life to visit Mecca.
It means that there were caravans
carrying goods and pilgrims
and ideas and people.
And they all met together
in Mecca once a year,
then things
would radiate back home.
So if an invention
was discovered in Samarkand
it could be, within the year,
known in Cordoba.
Where pilgrims trod,
traders soon followed.
Muhammad himself
had been a man of commerce
and now the spread of his message
brought with it the spread of trade
and the Islamic way of life.
Trade was incredibly important
in the Islamic world
simply because
of its geographical position.
It was, and still is,
between what we call the West,
and what people
always called the East.
So it was a natural land bridge
connecting China to Europe.
In only two centuries,
Islam had extended its reach
from Spain
all the way to the edge of India.
It took nearly a year
to travel from one end
of the Arab empire to the other.
At its heart was a fabled city of wealth.
It was called Baghdad.
The palaces of ancient Baghdad
have been lost over the centuries
but in its glory
it rivalled ancient Athens or Rome.
It was a magnificent
architectural achievement,
the pride of Islam in a new age.
One visitor left this account.
"All the exquisite neighbourhoods
covered with parks,
"gardens, villas
and beautiful promenades
"are filled with bazaars
and finely built mosques and baths.
"They stretch for miles on both sides
of the glittering river."
But what made this
the greatest city of its time
was more than just what met the eye.
It was the company it kept.
Scholars made Baghdad
the jewel of the world.
Certainly from the 8th century on,
Baghdad was the centre of learning
in the Islamic world
and all major innovations either came
from Baghdad or quickly came to Baghdad
Because the best people came
to Baghdad, the best thinkers,
the best philosophers, the best artists.
The empire's meteoric growth
had left its new leaders overwhelmed.
They had staggering engineering
and logistical problems to contend with.
Solving them would take
the greatest minds of the day.
Under the new empire now,
you're responsible for public hygiene,
you're responsible for the marketplace,
for the goods being sold in the marketplace.
All of this require some
basic elementary science.
This new civilization
having a need for science,
really stems from the need
to run that empire.
The best minds rose to the call.
The finest were welcomed
at a centre of scholarship,
Baghdad's renowned House of Wisdom.
It was a magnet for
scholars and intellectuals
who came and worked
in the academies.
There were public libraries
associated with the palace
and scholars came
from all over the empire.
There were scholars from Iran,
there were scholars from Byzantium.
Some were Christians,
some were Muslims, some were Jews.
And all of these different...
sort of threads of human knowledge
So, the net effect of this
is that you've got
human individuals
from radically different cultural traditions
being thrown into the same crucible.
The challenge that greeted
these scholars was daunting.
The great works of the ancients,
had to be transformed
into a wholly new body of knowledge.
Competition for jobs developed
within a new intellectual elite.
And from there on, every single
scientist is competing for that job.
They were competing among themselves
almost just... in the same way
that modern bureaucrats and academicians
will fight among themselves.
Scholars were dispatched
across the empire
to locate as many ancient texts
as possible...
the first international
scientific venture in history.
Unlike their Christian counterparts,
Muslim thinkers saw
no insurmountable contradiction
between their faith and
the laws governing the natural world.
So they embraced Aristotle and Plato,
writers the Christian church
considered blasphemous.
So this is the time
when we begin to see
scientists, bureaucrats,
what have you...
going and seeking
from whatever civilisation
that had any sciences before,
be it the Greek, the Indian,
the Persian, and so on.
From the Hindus came
mathematical concepts that guide us today.
It was the scholars
of the House of Wisdom
who developed the system
of Arabic numerals, still in use.
It is they who translated and transformed
the writings of the Greeks
and made a gift of them
to the modern Western world.
The Renaissance
had its beginnings in Baghdad.
They managed to assimilate
quite a lot of the rich legacy
of the Hellenistic world,
translate it into Arabic, initially,
which was then made available
to all other participants
in the new Islamic civilisation.
Arabic emerges as the language
of learning throughout the region.
This is a very significant development
in human intellectual history.
Having amassed the knowledge,
the Muslims began to challenge it.
This was perhaps
their most important contribution.
The scientific process was born.
They wanted to know why
a very intelligent Greek scientist
whose texts they were just admiring
and they were verifying it...
Why would he make a mistake
in the first place?
So they began to dig. Was it because
he didn't have the right instruments?
Or is it because he didn't have
the right methodology
to use the instruments
for the verifications of observation?
It is this spirit, you see,
this spirit of questioning,
the spirit of saying that we
have to build science constantly
on a systematic, consistent basis,
where we make a physical proposition
of how the universe ought to be run,
and the mathematical representation
of that physical universe ought to match.
Now you begin to have what i call
the birth of the new Islamic science.
Algebra and trigonometry,
engineering and astronomy...
Countless disciplines
integral to our lives today
trace their roots to Islamic scientists.
More surprising, perhaps,
were their innovations in medicine.
At a time when Europeans were praying
to the bones of their saints
to cure their illnesses,
Muslim physicians developed
an innovative theory...
that disease was transmitted
through tiny airborne organisms,
the precursor to the study of germs.
They determined that sick patients
should be quarantined and then treated.
This is the basis of the institution
most fundamental to medicine today...
the hospital.
Funded mainly
through religious endownments,
Muslim hospitals had separate wards
for patience suffering
from different kinds of disease.
Even mental illness was treated.
Their studies of anatomy
were so sophisticated
that they remained in use
by Muslim and European physicians
for 600 years.
Muslim scientists were especially
intrigued by light, lenses
and the physiology of the human eye.
The father of optics
was a muslim named Ibn al-Haytham.
His work with lenses eventually led
to the invention of the modern camera.
He produced the first treatise
that ventured to explain
how the eye actually sees.
A thousand years before the West
dared to take up the practice,
Muslim doctors were removing
cataracts surgically,
clearing them from the eye
with a hollow needle.
But for all this knowledge
to transform and illuminate an empire,
it had to be copied and shared
across a hundred different cities
in the Islamic world.
For this, there was a new invention,
one that is still fundamental
to learning and knowledge today...
paper.
Around the year 700 to 750,
when Muslim armies reached Central Asia,
they encountered paper
for the first time.
And, very quickly,
the Muslim bureaucracy
started using paper.
You find that within
50 years it's in Syria.
Then a few years later
it's in Egypt.
Then it's in North Africa.
Then it's in Sicily,
then it's in Spain.
And that's where Europe
learned to make paper.
They learned to make it
from the Arabs.
We begin to have people
with family names like Papermaker.
So, in other words, it was not only
that paper was available.
It must have become
a very, very widespread industry.
And hence the acquisition of books
must have also become very easy.
With the wide use
of books and paper,
hundreds of scribes,
some of whom were women,
were kept busy transcribing
the translations and new writings
of the Baghdad scholars.
All of this knowledge
that's being acquired from the Greeks
and from the Indians
and from Central Asians
is all beingswritten down
in books on paper.
And these books are being copied
and re-copied and sent around.
We know, for example,
that there was a street of booksellers
with more than a hundred shops,
each one with paper
and books for sale.
And this is a time when,
you know, in Europe,
a monastery would be lucky
if it had five or ten books.
While the monks of the West
were hoarding their wisdom
on scraps of expensive parchment,
paper enabled Islamic civilisation to spread
its newfound knowledge far and wide,
creatingu single community,
linking three continents.
So, the chief distinction, therefore,
of Islamic civilisation,
in addition to the fact
that it made new leaps of originality,
New transformations in traditions
of learning and everything else possible,
is the fact that it enabled human beings
to consider the possibility
of thinking about the globe
as a single unit... humanity.
In all the broad empire,
there was one place the Christian world
could experience the lifestyle
Muslims now took for granted...
southern Spain.
Here, on the European continent itself,
Islamic culture
would begin to have an effect
on the European civilisation
around it.
A thousand years ago,
the Spanish city of Cordoba
was a centre of learning and culture
that rivalled Baghdad.
Today, Cordoba's narrow lanes
hearken to its medieval past.
During the Dark Ages,
this was the most prosperous and
sophisticated metropolis on the continent.
It had streetlights and paved roads,
libraries, hospitals and palaces.
This was a city of light...
a Muslim city.
We have descriptions of it
by people coming and saying
"All these flowers
everywhere, open streets,
"this wonderful light
comingtown..."
Northern cities were dark.
Cordoba had running water.
People lived in big houses.
In contrast, in Paris, people lived
in shacks by the side of the river.
The glory of medieval Cordoba is here,
in what is now the great Roman Catholic
cathedral in the middle of town.
But the Cordoba Cathedral of today
began its life as a mosque...
one of the grandest
of the Islamic empire.
The Great Mosque in Cordoba
was simply the biggest mosque
in the biggest city
in southern Europe.
When you climb the church tower
which used to be a minaret,
you look out over
this expanse of roof.
Complete with
flying buttresses,
popping up out of the middle
of this massive mosque.
Many, many people came to visit it,
to view the wonders of the mosque,
which had rib vaulting.
The kind of vaulting
which is like this
and which,
100 years later,
but not at all a coincidence,
appears in the Gothic cathedrals
of northern Europe,
in Lincoln Cathedral
in Chartes Cathedral in France.
Where does that come from?
Obviously, influenced by the Great Mosque
of Cordoba in the south of Spain.
For the occasional
European Christian traveller,
Cordoba was the one opportunity
the climpse the Islamic world
What they saw, was shocking...
Most of Europe at that time
languished in poverty and squalor.
Cordoba was a pageant
of prosperity and enlightment.
In the 10th century
there was a Saxon nun
with the unpronounceable name
of Hrotswitha
who called medieval Cordoba
"the ornament of the world".
She was very, very taken
with the place.
and she was a Christian nun.
As Europeans made their way from the
cold stone of their northern castles...
into the glorious
Muslim cities of Southern Spain,
they couldn't help
of being impressed.
In the green hills above Granada,
was a palace of startling elegance.
A shining example of the richness
and sophistication Islam brought
to medieval Europe.
It's called the Alhamra.
The Alhamra is, perhaps
the most famous example...
...of the Islamic architecture
to most Westerners.
It is the best remaining example of...
...what a medieval Muslim palace
would've look like.
How far Muhammad's followers had come
from the life of desert nomads.
How distant they felt from the rest
of the European continent they now shared.
Christian Europe, due north,
was struggling on through the Dark Ages.
a tragedy in Jerusalem would put
Muslims and European Christians
on a collision course.
Jerusalem was ruled
by an Egyptian caliph,
an infamous man named al-Hakim.
But at the dawn of 11th century,
Clinically speaking, I suppose,
today we'd regard him as a madman,
as simply insane.
For 200 years, the Christian holy
places in Jerusalem...
...had been respected
and protected by Muslim rulers.
In 1009, the Egyptian ruler al-Hakim
broke with that tradition.
He ordered the holiest church
in Christendom destroyed.
And, horror of horrors,
he burnt down the Church
of the Holy Sepulchre in Jerusalem.
Nobody knows quite why he did it,
and you can have
your own theories about it,
but the fact of the matter was
that that sent shivers
of terror and anxiety
through Christendom.
In a way, of course,
el-Hakim was the one exception
and proved the rule for Christians
that Christians had been
speaking of for centuries,
of Muslims as intolerant, mad,
slavering heretics
who simply could not be...
...expected to abide by the
rules of civilised human beings.
The fact that al-Hakim's succesor
rebuilt the Church
of the Holy Sepulchre...
it was done by 1048
with Byzantine help...
didn't cut any ice.
There was this perception now
that things were not going well
in the Holy Land.