Christ has risen from the dead
Trampling down death by death
And upon those in the tombs
Bestowing life
Christ has risen from the dead
Trampling down death by death
And upon those in the tombs
Bestowing life
May God arise and His enemies scatter
May His foes flee before Him
Christ has risen from the dead
Trampling down death by death
And upon those in the tombs
Bestowing life
This is the day
that the Lord has made
Let us rejoice and be glad in it
Christ has risen from the dead
Trampling down death by death
And upon those in the tombs
Bestowing life
Lift up your heads, O ye gates
And be ye lift up,
ye everlasting doors
And the King of glory shall come in
Lift up your heads, O ye gates
And be ye lift up, ye everlasting doors
And the King of glory shall come in
Open the door.
Father, even if God comes down,
we won't open.
I said, open the door.
We won't open,
even if the sky falls.
Open the door before I grab you
and finish you off.
I will smash your bottle
over both your heads.
Open the door!
His Holiness doesn't get it.
Father, you have your head
in the clouds.
I'll tell you what, Father,
how about you take off
and come back later?
We might open then.
Forgive me Lord.
Have mercy, Father!
Christ has risen from the dead
Trampling down death by death
And upon those in the tombs
Neighbor, don't think I'm stealing.
I usually knock on the door
for permission.
I did knock, but no one was there.
Our sister says the food is sour.
Sour?
What do you mean by sour?
I'm not sure, but it tastes acidic.
I'm sorry you don't like it.
But that acidity comes
from the wine sauce.
It's how it should taste.
What did you say?
Did you say wine?
Yes, wine.
White.
So you are telling us
our sister was drinking alcohol
without us knowing?
It wasn't exactly your sister
but the chicken
who drank the alcohol.
That's how it is then!
You're going to pay for this.
Are you aware of that?
I'm to blame, I'm very sorry.
I should have warned you.
These two glasses
are on the house.
And we'll top them up.
Neighbor,
it's time this lemon tree got pruned.
You'll see, after I do it,
the lemons will be this big.
Neighbor!
Neighbor
Neighbor...
The other day,
I had an urge to go hunting.
As I was lurking for boars,
I look up
and see a large eagle,
its wings spread, each 2 meters long
whirling around,
as if looking for something.
I look closer
And what do I see?
A giant snake coiled up.
Suddenly,
the eagle brings its wings in
and swoops down on it,
like a rocket.
Before it grabs the snake,
I put a bullet in it,
it drops dead next to it.
The snake lifts its head,
stares at me, then at the eagle,
then back at me,
lifts its head up,
does like this to me
and slides away.
A few days later,
I was sitting home bored.
I told my wife I was going out.
I took my rifle and went hunting.
The sun set,
it started to get chilly.
I had a dozen partridges
hanging from my waist.
I said to myself: Let's go home.
I get to my Jeep
and find it slanted like that.
The rear tire completely flat.
Then, I hear a noise
in the bushes.
I point my rifle,
thinking it's a hyena
coming out to eat me.
Let's get it before it gets me.
I had only one bullet left.
I point my rifle
and right before pulling the trigger,
and who do I see?
The snake.
That same snake.
It comes towards me,
my gun still pointed at it,
passes by me,
and goes straight for the flat tire.
It opens its mouth
and puts it around the valve.
It breathes in and out into the tire.
Inhale and exhale.
It blew into it
until it became hard as a rock.
Then, it looked at me,
lifted its neck,
did like this to me
and slid away.
Neighbor,
now I'll go home, make a barbecue,
with a few glasses of Arak.
Come join me, neighbor,
you're most welcome.
You, come over!
Piss off.
Neighbor...
I've never pissed this much
in my life.
I cannot stop.
- Thief.
- Trained by you.
- Piece of shit.
- Your shit.
- Filthy.
- Your filth.
- Drunkard.
- Just like you.
- Thug.
- Your upbringing.
- Rotten.
- Your stink.
- Scumbag.
- Your scum.
Welcome.
Welcome to Paris.
- Welcome.
- Thank you
- Welcome to Paris.
- Goodbye
Welcome
Thank you
Hello, sir. How are you?
- Are you unwell?
- No.
Any headache? Heart, stomach?
Numbness in the legs?
Are you taking any medications?
- You're thirsty maybe?
- Yes.
- Are you hungry?
- Chicken or beef?
- Chicken.
- Pasta, Tabbouleh, both?
- Both.
Some dessert with that?
Panna cotta, tiramisu, chocolate?
Chocolate.
- Coffee or tea?
- Coffee.
- Do you have any allergies?
- No.
Central for number 7.
We are at the corner
of Vaucanson and Vertbois.
We have someone who's a bit tired.
He was reported to us.
He's alone now, but he's okay.
We gave him water and food.
We're off.
Over.
There you go.
- Enjoy.
- Thank you.
Is that all for you?
Great.
We'll pass by later in any case.
Ok, see you later, sir.
Enjoy your meal.
Are you Bridget?
We are looking for Bridget
Mr. Suleiman, thank you
Thank you
for sharing this project with us.
As you know, this is the type
of project that interests us.
This is a film
about the Palestinian conflict.
You know we have a certain sympathy
for the Palestinian cause.
It's not that you've made a film
that's too didactic
or exotic about Palestine.
But we could almost say
your film is not Palestinian enough.
It's not for commercial reasons,
because this kind of film
...doesn't make money.
That's not why we make them.
We make them only
because we're trying to be useful.
However, this project
doesn't correspond
...with our editorial policy.
We were under the impression
that it would take place in Palestine,
...but it might as well be anywhere.
It could even take place here.
Therefore, I don't think
we'll be moving forward.
Of course, we would have loved to.
Despite our initial excitement,
I'm afraid it will be a no
from us on this project.
Did you understand what I said?
Do you get it?
2 meters 60.
90.
3 meters 90.
- Hello ma'am.
- Good Morning
We came to check your terrace.
Everything looks good.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Have a good day.
It's in compliance. Let's go.
Please guys, please
Our beloved homeland, Palestine.
Guys!
Please listen to me.
Please listen to me, guys,
please listen
But if we go on clapping this way,
time will be up
before anyone gets to speak.
So please,
a little calm.
One clap will do
That should be enough, trust me.
This much.
Agreed?
Hey,
what's up?
No, I'm here.
Waiting for a meeting
with an American producer.
Well, she's not American,
I don't know where she's from.
It's for a project
on the conquest of Mexico.
For the 500th anniversary
of the conquest.
About Cortes, Moctezuma
and all that stuff.
But they want to do it in English.
In English, can you imagine?
They want the Spanish
to speak English.
And the indigenous to speak
in Nahuatl or any other language.
They don't care.
So they'd sound like:
"Hello, my name is Hernando Cortes
and I want to conquer you."
It's going to be terrible, really.
But I won't do it. I'll tell her no.
I'm here with my friend Elia,
Elia Suleiman.
He's a Palestinian from...
No, he's not a Palestinian from Israel.
He's a Palestinian from Palestine.
Yes a Palestinian from Palestine.
Yes, Palestine.
Listen, we'll talk later, ok?
Sorry, I'll call you later, bye.
Hey Gael.
- How are you?
- Good, and you?
- Good.
Listen, excuse me,
but I want to tell you something.
You Palestinians are a weird bunch.
The whole world drinks...
in order to forget.
You're the only people
who drinks...
in order to remember.
Cheers.