We ate at
only the best restaurants
in the waterfront
of little old New York.
Well behind the best
restaurants anyway.
Half of this garbage
can belonged to
me and my mother.
Everybody knew that.
That's ma working on a steak bone.
As for those mongrels
thinking they're gonna
push us out of the away
that was a large mistake.
Although I do not
admire the expression.
It was strictly dog-eat-dog
on the waterfront.
It was also at times
quite a bit of fun.
Wasn't just a salami.
It was a thrill of a chase.
The hide and seek that I liked.
And also my old friend
captain was getting pretty old
and couldn't grab
for food anymore.
I like to hide
in the old warehouse.
It was cool and quiet
and also happened
to be where I was born.
Sometimes I wondered
if it was wise to bring
my mother back there.
She was your kind of a sad look.
Then I began to get a glimmer
of maybe what made her sad.
It was what those
other dogs barked at me,
from a safe distance for them.
Things like where is your father?
Ask your mother if you dare.
You don't even know
who your old man is.
Well, being his mother
didn't wanna talk about
the sad situation,
I went to see my
old friend captain.
Captain knew everything
that went on
waterfront, so I asked him.
When captain got to his feet,
you know it's serious.
The last time he got up an
epidemic up this temper spread
through the waterfront like
fleas to a muscovites beard.
The time before two cargo
ships burn to the waterline.
I got a little scared.
Well I asked for it and I got it.
Both barrels.
Captain said I was
old enough to know.
My father was a great dog alright.
Champion regent royal.
How's that for a handle?
He had cornered my mother,
father her children,
without benefit of clergy.
And then melted into the
crowd never to be seen again.
Now I understood what
those other dogs meant
when they called me 'a dirty,
no good, son of a black and tan'.
I made up my mind.
First, to tell my mother
that it didn't make a whisk
of a difference to me.
Second, I'd find
my father and kill him.
Mother wasn't home
when I got back,
I laid down and waited for her.
She never came back.
I won't bore you
with my troubles journey
for the next two
weeks but I'll say this.
Without sleep I covered
every square-foot
of the city of new
York looking for my mother.
I never found her.
But I did find something I
never knew existed.
The Bowery,
the Bowery, the Bowery!
Only at the Bowery do
you see the most amazing,
the most fantastic attractions.
Such as the Patagonia
fire-eater, also the human...
what a place and tough.
So tough that down herein
Bowery during high-mass,
they allowed smoking
in the last three rows.
Such noise, such excitement,
every day was a clambake.
Everybody looked as happy as sin,
even in the place
they called the mission.
Get out of here!
I could not believe my eyes.
Here in a Bowery were
dogs who looked just like me.
But they were living like kings
and you'll never guess why.
Because they were dogs
who fought each other,
not for fun and not for food.
But for the sport
of their masters.
I remember captain telling me
about these professional mutts.
With my mother gone I had
to find my own way in life.
How to make these men in
the saloon notice me?
Come on. Come on.
Easy, easy.
Atta boy.
Where did he come from?
Some nut has
her dog days of course!
Attacking masterful,
look at the way he is
breathing now. He's dead game.
He doing pretty good there.
Why Don't we
toss him in with masterful?
It'll give him a chance
to sharpen his teeth on.
Who bet
against a champ now?
- Me.
- You on!
For home...paddy
Hold on, hold on.
Gentlemen hold on.
There will
be no free and easy fighting,
here at Corbin's place.
That is unless Corbin
gets a bet in first.
Here he's no Corbin, take that.
Nobody owns him.
It looks that way.
Well, we can't take him, can we?
Looks like
he might be
a real scrapper, Corbin.
Now aimless fighting
is a sin, gentlemen, you know it.
We only fight dogs for a record
or to establish a championship.
Look at him!
He isn't a scrap.
Here is a great
piece of dog flesh.
Young but as finely potent as
the handle of St. Peter's harp.
He's mine, I saw him first.
I kinda
like this dog myself.
Just a minute gentlemen,
just a minute.
I make the arrangements here.
Patch, come on follow
me and bring the dog with you.
Gentlemen.
We are about to
participate in the first,
the only,
the original dog lottery.
Come gentlemen, for $1,
you can buy a chance
on this magnificent
specimen of bull-terrier.
Where does the money go?
You're aren't the first man
who doesn't pay his
bar bill on Saturday!
Elsa, I had a dream
about you last night
- Really, honey?
- Yeah.
What?
In this dream you were
found in an alley
with your head kicked in.
Really, Patch? Why?
Because you wouldn't
give me a dollar
when I asked you for it!
Oh, really Patch!
You have hidden charms, Elsa.
Not to my friends.
I shall pay this back
with interest and affection.
You can skip the interest.
Thanks honey!
Thank you, sir. Anyone else?
Number 16.
That's me, Mr. Corbin.
Gentlemen, the winner is Mr.
Patch McGills.
You going to Patch McGills,
you hear?
And you're going to be
the toughest fighting dog
on the Bowery.
And you're gonna
do exactly what I say
or I'll beat your
brains out twice a week!
Understand?
Ah, Patch Mcgill.
It was just what I
wanted my master to be.
Tough. As tough as
I'd have to be to fight.
When Patch Mcgill
snuck a lose dollar,
he'd walk right through
a solid brick wall and get it.
I like him,
he was my kind of people.
Now we're broke.
I spent my last
hard-earned dollar on you.
We're gonna need money.
Now you wait here
until I come out for you.
When I take you inside
you give out with a personality.
If you want to eat next week.
Patch!
Ha-ha-ha!
Hi, baby!
You
came a little late for this.
I gotta get
on the palace gardens
before five so I
can actually guard it.
Ah, I tell you there's nothing like
watching a woman
pretty up her face.
Ha-ha-ha.
You've been working, huh.
I got a surprise
that is gonna knock you
right our your little slippers.
You finally took a job?
- Oh, anybody can get a job.
- Yeah, anybody except you.
I, I've been waiting
for one thing.
A business on my own.
And opportunity
is finally knocking.
What kinda business?
The kind that puts me in
coarse cigars and you in furs.
Pick up a check,
quit your job and live like a queen.
- As missus Patch Mcgill?
- As missus Patch Mcgill.
Ha-ha!
I couldn't think
of anything worse.
- All I need is 20 bucks!
- 20 bucks!
Yeah, well you're
not gonna get it.
Now look honey, why make trouble?
You always end up
giving it to me anyway.
Well this time I'm not gonna.
If you don't give it to me,
I'll break you all to smash.
You just try it.
I don't suppose you
wanna watch anymore at that.
He asked he again for the money
and she turned him down cold.
So he used a little psychology.
He grabbed her by the
throat and slammed her
right up against the wall.
That convinced her.
I'll never understand people
because what happened next,
you wouldn't believe!
Ah, Patch!
You're a real strong boy!
Only when I'm near you.
You're like fire in my veins.
Well, aren't you gonna
ask what business I am in?
Oh, Patch!
We'll get there in the end.
Right now I’m having a good time.
No, I mean it.
I don't take money
from girl's for fun.
This money is gonna buy food,
equipment, finest training.
- For what?
- For a dog.
- A dog?
- Yup.
You give me that money back.
Now wait a minute
this is a bull terrier.
The finest I ever laid my eyes on.
I don't care if it's a solid gold
ten-carat greyhound!
I'm not slaving every night
at the palace gardens
to keep a dog and bones.
This is a fighting dog.
For 20 bucks I'll
fight him myself.
I can make $500-$1000 a fight.
Well, who does he fight,
diamond Jim Brady?
Other dogs.
What other dogs got
that kind of money?
People. People pay to watch
why I can make a
fortune on wildfire.
That's what I'll call him,
wildfire.
Did you ever see a
fire start in the grass?
It goes wild,
sweeps right on through.
And that's what he's gonna do.
He'll sweep right on
through to the championship.
Where did you ever see any grass?
They grow down on the
floor at Corbin saloon?
Would you like to see the dog?
You got him in your pocket?
Mabel Maycroft, meet wildfire.
I'm gonna manage
him to the championship.
You'll party that 20 bucks
of your in the thousands.
That's the ugliest
thing I've ever seen.
What did she expect, a peacock?
Good boy, wildfire!
Alright, you can take a rest.
I never had any trouble
fighting on the waterfront.
But this professional
fighting was different.
This was tangling with
dogs who fought to win.
Because if they lost,
they were dead.
That's the best
steak money can buy,
13 cents a pound.
Pure bottled spring water.
I don't want you
drinking out of gutters.
You might get
typhoid or something.
This has all the germs removed.
Drink it before any dust falls in.
Now on you got two choices, kid.
You need to be champion or dead!
Five weeks later
I stepped into the ring,
back at Corbin's bar.
In a room filled with rum,
smoke and money,
the local sporting gentry
had come to my first bout.
Which most to them
figured to be my last.
Well Patch and me,
we figured it different.
Remember what I told you.
Don't waste your breath
barking or growling.
Don't chew up any
fancy spins or slices.
Just drive in and get him.
Turn the tables,
you are three-to-one.
Quiet, quiet, quiet.
Quiet!
The betting is now closed.
And there will be no
drinking during the fight.
For a purse of $100,
paddy Corbin is most happy
to being you that always
dangerous canine fighter.
Ruffie's cantanker!
And the challenger,
a newcomer to the Bowery.
Patch Mcgill's wildfire.
Are you ready to go?
- Ready.
Face your dogs.
Make ready.
Fight!
- Jeremiah Edward E. A.
- Would you say that man
was good or bad?
I'd say he was good.
But it would be easier
to prove that he was bad.
When I take that,
take that for example.
It took man to teach
a dog to fight for money.
I never heard of a dog
that had a daughter fight for her.
That's where you're wrong.
Dogs still possess a spiritual
wealth that men have lost.
Would 50,000 gather
to bet their soup bones
that one man could kill another?
I don't get you.
Well look at it this way,
do dogs follow the leader?
Do they drink because
everybody drinks?
Do they paint themselves blue
because blue is fashionable?
Bah! They do not!
They're proud,
self-reliant individuals.
Would you mind wetting
the bottom of that a little?
I mean man, man is the handler.
He sees in dogs the
qualities he has lost.
But does he respect them? No!
He exploits them.
Just as he is
exploiting his own soul.
Watch out, watch out!
Here comes the winner.
Carney, see if you
can find some caviar
on the free lunch table.
- Okay, Patch.
The money, Corbin, the money.
First in a long line
of prizes for Patch Mcgill.
The drinks are on me, boys.
I fought twice a week after
that for almost four months.
Toast to wildfire!
I was the talk of
the sporting world.
The hottest dime since bock beer.
There is no need to
show you any the fights,
they were pretty brutal.
And I might add, we now had
those two great organizations,
the American humane
association & society
for the prevention
of cruelty to animals,
better known as the SPCA,
well deserving of your support.
Honey, you're looking
high up on a horse.
Right, wildfire?
High up on the
dog was more like it.
Patch, you look like a real swell.
Patch, watch out,
you'll spill some liquor on me.
It's eight years
old bottle in Bonn.
You'll smell like a debutante
at 3 o'clock in the morning.
Well, just don't spill
the chase around me too.
These are my best clothes.
Honey stop worrying.
In a couple a seconds
you'd be throwing them
duds out of the window.
Why, Patch Mcgill?!
What I mean is I...
I got you a little present.
- For me?
- Yup.
From a guy who thinks you
to be the last thing every night
and first thing every morning.
Oh, Patch.
You shouldn't have.
Just my colours.
- Do you know what I feel like?
- No.
A rich caterpillar.
Honey, I have never
seen anything like you.
Just like you've stepped
out of a store window.
Yeah! Right through the glass.
Patch.
I bet that there's not
another woman in the world
with a man like you.
I knew you couldn't go
on being a bum all your life.
I knew you'd turn
out good some day.
Well, honey as long
as I can keep on fighting
you're gonna live like a queen.
I'm gonna buy you the
best duds money can buy.
And you got such
a good taste that I...
well, I hate to criticize.
- Criticize what?
- Him.
What's wrong with him?
Well if there's anything I hate,
it's a gaudy dog.
Listen to the rich caterpillar.
Some nights when
the bourbon and Mable
Maycroft's cheap perfume gota
little too heavy in the air...
I would sneak out.
I always had the hope
of finding my mother,
but I never did.
And I always had the
hope of finding my old man,
for a different reason.
And I couldn't understand
never meeting him,
because he was called
'champion regent royal'.
Yet the only champion
I knew was a rough, tough,
experienced murderer
called masterful.
My next opponent.
To the memory of masterful
and a new champion, wildfire.
Gentlemen, the drinks
are on paddy Corbin.
Hurray!!
Looks who's coming in?
The heavy weight
champion of the world!
John L. Sullivan!
And a good evening to you,
gentleman.
Thank you,
for your kind reception.
Now come on boys
get out of the doorway,
come on, this is no
place for the likes of you.
John L. Sullivan,
now I can die happy.
Well, it's an honor
to have you, John.
The house is yours.
What will it be?
No, no, no money, no money.
Well, bring me the
biggest schooner of beer
you've got in this place.
Uh, filled with bourbon!
Well, could it be that Corbin
sis always this popular?
Or is there some
special event going on
that has escaped me noticed?
Patch Mcgill's wildfire
just took the title away
from the masterful.
Well, now, that's the
kind of dog I can understand.
Where is this champion?
Tell him John L. Sullivan would
like to shake him by the hand.
That's John L. Sullivan,
a prized fighting champion
of the world.
Now you walk down and look
him right straight in the eye.
Wow!
You are the only thing
on earth I've ever seen,
I wouldn't wanna meet in the ring.
Put your hand up there, boy.
Come here.
Send him back here
and I'll buy him a drink.
- Patch!
- Hi honey
well, what's going on?
If I'm not being too inquisitive.
Money's going on, that's what.
Real money.
Ever thought of retiring?
Traveling around
the world on boats.
Eating squat at del Monaco's.
Buying your weight in chocolates
or anything you wanted?
Yeah, Patch.
Are you in trouble or something?
Trouble?
Why, Mabel honey, you're looking
at the most successful
financial operator on the Bowery.
Yeah, what are you
doing with all my things?
Investing them.
Honey, I need capital.
Everything I own
and everything you own.
We are partners.
You bought six more dogs?
No, no, nothing like it.
This is the only
dog in the world for me.
Man's best friend.
Honey, you remember about
three months ago in the same room
when I told you
opportunity was knocking.
Yeah.
Well this time,
it's busting down the door.
Honey, this is no dog.
He's a walking goldmine.
In fact, I'm thinking
of renaming him. Pay dirt!
But he's the champion,
you're makin' money whether...
enh, small potatoes.
This is going to
be the real big killing.
Probably mine.
What made this
incredible performance
worth listening to was
that I didn't know
what was up myself.
I was curious as to how
we were all going to retire.
Alive!
- This goes too, uncle.
- Yeah I counted it.
But one thing bothered me.
I couldn't figure out why I,
the champion,
was a five to one underdog.
If you'll pardon the expression.
There was something
about this whole thing
that began to give me a chill.
Sorry for your
trouble mister Mcgill.
Nothing to be sorry about, uncle.
This is the happiest
day of my life.
Here's my money, Corbin.
You can take the bets on it.
I get five-to-one.
Do you really want
to do this, Patch?
Why not he's a champion, ain’t he?
Well, the champion
take on all comers?
In his class, yes.
But not destruction.
A good big man can always
beat a good little man.
Destruction is good.
And besides he's a heavy weight.
And he'll eat him alive.
Well, what's a little weight.
I'll take skill
over weight any day.
It's you who do the talking.
But it the little
one will do the fighting.
I don't seem to recall your face,
but put your money up
if you wanna talk with me.
I earn my own money,
I don't have dogs do it for me.
Ah, gentlemen, gentlemen,
settle down, settle down.
I'll take your money
and I'll arrange the bets.
Well, you know,
there's something about him
that a man has to like.
This is the one where
we get rich, so make it quick.
Here comes destruction.
This was quite
a dog I had to lick.
He looked as if he had
been sired by the devil.
And bred to the killing of tigers.
His mouth was as big as my head.
Looked like a freight
train with ears.
Don't let him bother you,
wildfire.
He's a pushover,
slow muscle-bound.
Why I know three cats who
licked him in the past month.
All he's got is an ugly face.
Just don't look at it.
Go get him, wildfire.
I was sure gonna try.
Not for Patch Mcgill
and his miserable money but
there's something called my life.
Maybe I was selfish.
But I kinda enjoyed livin'!
Quiet, gentlemen, quiet.
The betting is now closed.
And the fight will
be underway in a minute.
Now as this fight
is exclusively for money
we'll forget the formalities.
Ready, destruction?
Ready.
Ready, wildfire?
Fight!
Cur! A sneaking yellow
live red street dog cur.
Could've beaten him if you tried.
E tu, brute.
Fed you and housed you
and nursed you like a king.
And now you put your tail between
your legs and sold me out.
Everything I worked
hard for is gone.
You mean everything he worked
for and I worked for is gone.
You never worked an
honest day in your life.
Shut up!
That dog's got more character
than you'll ever have.
It was the first kind thing
anyone said to me all day.
I felt like waging my tail.
Except that I was hanging
from it at that time.
So long Patch, and don't
ever come near me again.
And just to make sure you don't,
I'm going to marry a policeman.
It's all your fault, you mongrel.
I had about one bite left in me.
And I found the perfect
place to use it.
I could hardly see.
And my legs felt like
I'd borrowed them
from some other dog.
But I knew I was
through in the Bowery.
I'd better get out
when I was still alive.
Right back where I started from,
the waterfront.
A whole year had gone.
I was just as far from finding
my mother or my father.
I was too tired to think.
I only wanted to lie down,
close my eyes and
forget the whole world.
Maybe forever.
What was the use of anything.
Sometimes I wish the dog catchers
and caught me a long time ago.
You'll probably saying to yourself
who is this ugly old devil?
That's exactly what
I was saying to myself.
Nolan is the name.
Jeremiah Edward
Emmett Augustus Nolan
I take care of all
the animals around here.
I'll admit most of them cantake
better care of themselves,
if they're just left alone.
There.
Horse meat, horse meat.
Shouldn't be too tough though.
His last race he
had finished second.
If it runs out the
money we don't serve it.
That's the kind of
fancy estate this is.
Here is what's your
doctor ordered for you.
It eases the pain
it prevents infection,
and he gives me a chance
to get a clearer view.
Well, eat a little, sleep a little
and then we'll
see about the future.
But don't get lonesome now.
If you do, don't bark.
No, I'll be back eventually.
Oh and most important of all,
under no circumstances
leave this room.
The terrible tempting
is to run back home
and that can only mean trouble
for man and beast alike.
I liked him.
He was the first man I'd met in
months who treated me like a dog.
I still didn't know where I was
but it seem like a nice,
clean, friendly, quiet place.
I told you to have my
daughter meet me, she didn't.
I asked her to send
the gray mare, she didn't.
I asked the gardener's to
trim the hedges, they didn't!
No one, I'm tired of trying!
All of you get up to
the big house in an hour.
Well, it was a clean place anyway.
The next day I had
my appetite back
and felt like an animal again.
Nolan was showing me around.
I've lived here almost
since I was a boy.
I know every foot of it.
Alright dear.
That's where he lives, Mr.
Wyndham.
He's got everything
in the world but peace.
So stay out of his sight,
wildfire.
Until he comes back to being
the old Wyndham he used to be.
I'm presuming of course that
you'd like to stay around here.
Would you like to be Nolan's dog?
Could you've said no to
a man with a face like that?
If you could, you re a better dog
then I am gunga din!
Course if you do stay you won'tbe
the only dog on the premises.
Oh! No,
no, no. See those buildings?
They are the kennels,
Wyndham's special pride.
One of my jobs is to see that
those dogs live better than I do.
They are Saint Bernards.
Ever seen a Saint Bernard?
No, probably not.
They are kind of like
draft horses with racoon coats.
Only the fact that
they're named after a Saint
prevents me from telling you
what I really think about them.
Well, Nolan.
What do you got there?
A dog, as you can plainly see.
A white dog,
should you be colorblind.
Wildfire.
Wildfire!
Theson of the pits, a fighting dog.
Retired.
What do you think of him, tattle?
Not what I think
of him that counts but
what the old man thinks of him.
Well, I'll keep him out
of his sight for a while.
Yeah you're better.
The old man will throw
another one of his fits if
he found a fighting
dog hanging around here.
He might even get
a little mad at you.
So he might.
You're the boss,
Nolan, you tell him.
You make him like it
whether he wants to or not.
Do me one favor though.
And what would that be, tattle?
Just tell me where
you want the flowers sent.
Boy, that's a mean dog, Nolan.
No sense of humor.
Probably kill somebody
before he's finished.
I had been called
mean and vicious before
but nobody ever accused me
of not having a sense of humor.
I was prepared to
dislike mister tattle.
Now never mind, Tom tattle.
He is just young, full
of young talk and big ideas.
He's right about one thing though.
You've got to keep out of
sight for a while down here
in the barn
whatever you do wildfire,
at whatever cost,
stay away from those
Saint Bernard kennels.
Naturally when I had the chance
where do you think was
the first place I went!
You re right!
Those with dogs?
They must put
something in the food!
The puppies were
bigger than I was!
And the way they lived.
Like one my
early dreams of heaven.
Saint Bernards!
For saints their commons
left much to be desired.
Quiet!
That's when I heard a voice.
Unmistakably British it said,
'in here old chap
and shake a leg'.
It took all my self
control to sit there
staring into a face
that looked like something
that fell off a totem pole.
But as it turned out
he had a kinda style
about him grew on you.
Said his name was Jimmy jocks.
And he was the housekeeper
of mister Wyndham's daughter,
miss Dorothy.
Speaking of Mr. Wyndham...
Where did that white dog go,
the one that was attacking
the Saint Bernards.
He just disappeared, Mr. Wyndham.
Did
you see him, Nolan?
I saw no dog attacking
the Saint Bernards.
Well I did.
Findhim and get him off this estate.
I don't care how you do it.
This isn't a home
for stray mongrels.
Oh, I am sure he is harmless,
Mr. Wyndham.
And I'm sure I don't
need your advice, Mr. Nolan.
Just find them before I do.
You re not crazy enough
to think you keeping that
fine fighting dog, are you?
What if do?
Just thinking
of you, Nolan.
You're too old to take
a chance at getting fired.
Tattle,
the reason I'm been about here
as long as I have
is because when I was your age
I was working hard instead
of talking so much.
- Now let's get busy.
- Sure, Nolan.
I guess I can ever
hope to be as smart as you
until I am a real old man.
Take it easy, old timer.
And if you do get
cut blame it on me.
I can handle Wyndham.
That Tom tattle
made my hackles rise.
Well anyway I head out for
a couple hours with Jimmy jocks.
What a big brain that jocks was!
These words I never
heard people say.
He had been all over
the world and seen everything.
Wonderful things like,
perfumed French poodles
and Chinese fire hydrants.
We struck up quite a friendship
Jocks didn't care much
for the Saint Bernards.
But at the same time
he didn't want to
tangle with one in a fight.
You'd have to be a furrier
to find their throats.
The things that Jimmy
jocks taught me...
Did you know that dogs
were here before people?
That we invented such
well known phrases as, 'puppy love',
'putting on the dog'
and 'bulldog determination'.
That my Latin name is,
now get this, cannis familiaris.
Things Jimmy jocks showed me.
One day the sun was warm
and the air smelled like a
department store at Christmas.
And we had just polished off about
half a crate of Wyndham's
finest strawberries.
Jocks was in a good mood.
Expansive, he'd have said.
He told me I reminded him about
great terrier named
'champion regent royal'.
That was my father's name.
Champion regent royal.
No wonder I never found
him on the Bowery.
He was no fighting dog at all,
but a different kind
of a champion, a show dog.
Jocks then took me to a place
I'd never seen or heard of before.
It was called the trophy room.
After jocks left I stayed
there a long time alone.
Looking at the prizes won by dogs
of the most superior breeding.
I thought about my father,
the most superior of them all.
I knew now I'd never
get close to him.
He lived in another world.
I Don't know who you are,
but you couldn't stand that
way unless it was bred into you.
You must be one of Mr.
Crawford's new terriers.
If you are, he's certainly
improving his stock.
Don't tighten up, I just
want to get a good look at.
Oh, I know,
I'll bet you are the white dog
father was complaining about.
Holy Toledo!
Three of them.
Jimmy jocks!
They will kill him!
My only hope was that
they fought like gentlemen,
because I didn't.
It's alright, Jimmy, it's alright.
It's alright, Jimmy.
Do I shoot him now
or would you rather do it down
by the stable?
Father, three of
those monsters attacked
poor little Jimmy jocks.
They would have killed...
these are three of most valuable
Saint Bernard's in the world.
And I don't intend to have
any stray mongrel tearing
at their throats.
Come on,
Nolan, let's get it over with.
I'll be no party to the
shooting of a defenseless dog.
Well then I'll do it myself.
Father, stop talking
like Simon Legree!
Well, it's interesting
to see what kind of people
I have working for me.
Well after 40 years
you should know.
Why don't you tell them
whose dog it is, Nolan.
It's my dog, sir.
I brought him in as a stable-pit.
He's a fine animal, sir.
A pit-dog.
A fighting dog a trained killer?
No longer, sir.
He's intelligent, has a good heart
and we've become friends.
In the future
I'll see that he gives you
no cause for further trouble.
Well, you get rid of him in
one hour or I'll shoot him on sight.
The dog will be out in an hour.
And I'll go with him.
Father what's the matter with
you? He might really leave.
Let him.
Let him think of
himself and his job
if he wants to waste
it on a street dog.
Let him.
Put those Saint Bernards back
in the kennel.
Come on, boy,
come on, come on, let's go.
I'm not overloaded with
conscience but I found a friend.
I couldn't see letting
them lose a lifetime job over
a drifter like me.
No, no, no.
You don't have to be a martyr,
go running off to save me.
You don't realize it, of course.
But it's not your fault
that all this has happened.
How do you like that?
Not only does this guy treat me
better than anybody I ever met.
But for the third or fourth time,
this is exactly what I'm thinking.
I wonder if somewhere
back in his family tree...
no, no, it was too improbable.
But still...
you know, wildfire.
Mister Wyndham is a self made man.
He Rose from the waterfront
all by his own ingenuity
and the sweat of his brow.
Yes, like everybody in America,
he had the dream of getting ahead.
You get to a day,
when you can sit back,
take it easy and enjoy
the fruits of your labour,
immaterial things and friendships.
And most important
of all the luxury of time.
Time to do all the
little personal things
you've always wanted to do.
Like reading the classics,
trying to grow a blue Rose,
learning about
good wine and may be,
doing something foolish,
just for the fun of it.
Well, after working
all through his life
to the day when he
could enjoy himself,
he suddenly collapsed.
With a heart attack.
He's had four in
the past two years.
Yes, those business trips
were in truth trips to a clinic.
If he has another attack
he could die...
Tomorrow or next week.
Or next year.
I'm the only one who
knows of his misfortune
and that bothers him too.
I am a source of irritation to him
and every time we get
together we seem to argue.
I don't want to live myself
to see the day he drops dead
in one of those arguments.
So, it's best I go.
That's the third Brandy
you've had in 10 minutes.
No, no,
it's the sixth in 20 minutes.
What's the use of a
man working hard all his life
to be able to buy the best
Brandy if he can't drink it.
But father...
Dorothy, I'll drink what
I want, when I want it.
And do what you want,
and scream when you want,
and be bullheaded when you want.
Well I hardly have the time
to live my life for a dog handler.
Or a daughter?
I'll run this house and
this estate the way I want to.
Well, I bought it and built
it and I paid for it.
I thought you built it for mother.
It was hers when she was here.
Father ask Nolan to stay.
- Absolutely not.
- I'll ask him for you.
He had no right
to bring a dog here,
especially a street mongrel.
A pit-dog, trained to kill
other animals before their time.
But that dog isn't a mongrel.
You didn't see him posing
in front of the
trophy room mirror.
He looked like royalty.
Well, I could enter
that dog in a show
and win a ribbon with him.
You...
I bet you $50 that you couldn't,
I bet you $50 you couldn't
even win the third prize.
Or if that pooch could win
the booby price,
I'd give up drinking.
I'll make you an even more
interesting bet than that.
How interesting?
If he wins a ribbon,
both he and Nolan stay.
Daughter, that's a bet.
I had about as much chance
at winning a ribbon in a dog show,
as I had of swimming
the English channel
maybe less.
There's his mother's boy.
My first shave.
No comment!
Some things your best
friends wont tell you.
Now, wildfire, let's learn
how to be a real show dog.
It's discipline, boy, discipline.
Now assume the position
of a real champion.
Stand up. Up!
Alright then you lazy
thing just stay there.
Well, well maybe you can point,
like a hunter.
Point.
Point at what?
Besides pointing ain't polite.
Stand up!
Hey fellas, after all
you can't make a fencing
mask out of a steely door.
Well, that's a little better.
Oh, you aren't trying hard enough.
And don't try to make
up it won't do you any good.
Terrible, it's terrible.
So it was terrible, sue me.
Special foods to fortify me,
build me up and
make my coat shine.
Breathing exercises
and how to walk.
Six weeks for junk like that
but two good reasons
kept me going.
Just won't let me be friends.
He's a little nervous and edgy,
he'll get used to you.
What a crazy thing to do.
Betting your job this
mutt will win a ribbon.
The bet was no choice of mine.
I'm turning in.
Nolan...
I want you to know I'm sorry
to be taking over your job soon,
but that's life.
The old make way for the young.
Sorry to take Nolan's job?
If I ever saw a guy happy,
it was tattle.
That was the first good reason
I had to go through
with the dog show.
Maybe all the other
dogs would drop dead
and might win something.
Nolan can keep his job.
And the second reason... him.
He took to standing out
at night and watching me,
as if he was trying
to figure something out,
maybe wondering
when he was scheduled
for that last fatal heart attack.
Well maybe he was hoping
Nolan would throw
me out and apologize.
Nolan never would.
The old guy was so honest,
it was stupid.
Somehow the day finally came.
And there I was
at my first dog show.
I'd seen some pretty
wild specimens in my time.
But some of these took the cake.
I began to get an
idea of what happened
to some of those characters
who didn't know what was up.
They were entered in dog shows.
136, is that right?
- 136.
- Here, here come on.
- There, in you go.
- Go on in, prince Galahad.
Obviously the wrong cage I hoped.
Prince Galahad, oh no!
Now relax, Galahad.
You're as good as any out there.
And don't you forget it.
A lot of things are
riding on you today.
My faith, Nolan's job,
and the honor of Wyndham.
Now do your best.
All she left out was,
if you need anything bark.
And then it happened.
A dame just swaddled in class.
Miss ladyship, the second
of the canford estate.
About three miles she told me
from the Wyndham place.
Well we fell into
some nonchalant chit chat
about fleas and
dog biscuits and such.
It was then that I noticed
something going on
in the front of my cage.
Good morning,
miss Wyndham.
Good morning, Mr. Oakley.
- Nolan.
- How do you do, sir?
I haven't see
you at any of the shows lately.
Possibly because
I haven't been to many.
I see. I didn't know
you were raising bull terriers.
I'm not,
this is just one that Nolan
and I happen to... to inherit.
Prince Galahad of Wyndham.
You have no parents
listed for him.
Oh, well, you se... unfortunately
the records were lost in the fire,
but he comes of a good line.
Your word is good
enough for us, Nolan.
Thank you, sir.
Let's take a look at him.
What a cornball this guy was.
I could have been a
mongrel for all he cared.
I bet he was he was
just hoping to sneak a look
at miss Dorothy's ankles.
They were pretty well covered up.
Miss Wyndham,
you are not seriously
entering this dog in this show.
I certainly am.
You don't know much
about this breed, do you?
Is it necessary to know anything?
He's a good dog.
I paid my fee and entered him.
Miss Wyndham, don't you realize...
I'm not interested in your opinion
until he gets up there
on the judging stand.
And if you're angry with me
don't take points
away from the dog.
Miss Wyndham, I'm an honest judge.
Above everything.
As if I didn't
have enough troubles,
now I was responsible
for a love affair.
The next thing I
expected here was that
if I didn't win a ribbon,
every third baby born in New York
would be thrown in east river.
It's enough to make me nervous.
Well, good luck in the show,
Galahad.
Here, here's a little something
to keep you from getting hungry.
There, good hunting, chin up.
What I really need was about
two shots of rye that
they poured at Corbin's saloon.
Well maybe what I needed was...
At least, the flat heads
could have looked
at me a little longer.
Pretend like I was worth the time.
It would have made Nolan
and miss Dorothy feel better.
I had a good mind to
take a bite out of that
imported tweed seat of Oakley's.
Your attention please,
third prize in the bull
terrier judging
miss ladyship, the second
of the conford estate.
Second place ribbon
goes to cavalier,
of the well brow kennel.
And the blue ribbon winner,
for best of breed,
miss Dorothy...
prince Galahad,
of the Wyndham estates.
Holy Toledo!
Talk about the fix being on!
What a phony decision!
The things a guy
will do for a doll
congratulations, Nolan!
Nolan!
Oh wonderful, beautiful dog.
If you were a man,
I'd marry you tomorrow.
I could hardly wait
to be reincarnated.
Why you entered prince
Galahad on this local show,
I couldn't understand.
He was way out of his class.
One look at him
would tell any judge
that he was a winner
before he ever stepped
into the judging ring.
- Really?
- Really.
He's the best bull terrier
I've ever seen since...
Since champion regent royal.
Champion regent royal, my old man.
Even the experts
said he was perfect.
Well maybe that blue ribbon
I won was really on a level.
Wildfire Mcgill
butcher boy of the Bowery
was now prince Galahad Nolan.
Darling of the society
show dog circuit.
I can hardly wait
to tell Horatio Alger.
I don't know what to say Mr.
Oakley,
except that I misjudged you.
I am sorry.
Oh, that's quite alright,
miss Wyndham.
Will you have lunch with me?
I'd be delighted.
- Nolan?
- Thank you, sir.
A more stupid exchange
between two people
obviously in love
you can hardly imagine!
It comes from too much education,
reading love novels written
by al mead spinsters.
Now on the Bowery
she would've kissed
him and lifted his wallet.
And he'd have gotten
roaring drunk on credit.
And beat up every man
that as much as looked at her.
Now that's real love.
Well I'm as surprised
as you are that he did so well.
I just wondered if we
could set him up in a kennel.
There is one empty.
He could get good care
like the other...
no, no absolutely not.
No, he's still nothing
but a street dog.
Get him off the table.
Father!
Down wildfire.
Well you were something
of a street dog yourself,
sir, once, weren't you?
Nolan, so help me out,
get rid of...
Father, he's in the right
to be taken care of.
I don't need anybody
to take care of me.
I was talking about the dog.
He has better manners
than both of you.
And what must he do to satisfy
you win the grand national?
Oh shucks!
Winning the
neighborhood dog show...
George Oakley would
give you the world
if you smiled at him.
Hardly qualifies this Bari
tramp as the champion.
Father George Oakley
didn't give me those ribbons,
there were two other judges.
And George said he is
the most perfect bullterrier
he's seen since
champion regent royal.
That name again.
The son of men who want to get in
this plan again myself.
You're the most stubborn
man I've ever known.
Well please, miss Dorothy
I'm sure he doesn't mean to...
He's been like this for a year
shouting, criticizing, hating
everything he doesn't own.
Well you don't own this dog.
And before Nolan and
I are through with him,
you're going to be begging
for a chance to hold his leash.
He's going to win
the grand nationals
at Madison square garden.
Whenever I went outside
for some air at night
I could almost always
count on him being there.
Watching me.
We all had our problems,
but it came to me that
Wyndham's was the biggest one of all.
He couldn't hate everybody
and everything as
much as he pretended.
He was a self-made man
and that was something
I could appreciate.
So I decided to
stick my neck way up.
If I get chopped off
I can only say I asked for it.
Would you care to go for a walk?
We walked for about
10 to 15 minutes.
He didn't say a word.
Once in a while he
just look down on me.
As if he was trying to make
up his mind about something.
What do you know?
The old boy was so
sure I'd go with him,
he had a couple
a dog biscuits ready.
Well I hear you were quite a dog.
The terror of the Bowery,
wasn't that it?
Taking a chance on getting
killed twice a week,
just to keep a Bowery
barman's spending money.
Does life mean that little to you?
Of course, I couldn't answer.
But if I could.
I would have said that
dogs are no different from men.
They do what they
can to stay alive.
And when they run out
of cleverness or courage,
one day they turn up dead.
Pit-dog, huh? A fighter.
You know what it means
to suddenly face death,
don't you?
Doesn't seem to bother
you in the slightest.
It occurred to me
maybe there's something
that I could learn from you.
What's a man come
to when the only one you...
Let himself look
to for help is a dog.
Come on, boy.
Come on.
Get him.
Get him out of there.
Come on.
We walked for miles.
And I listened
to him talk for hours
no one ever noticed this.
And I got this to say about him,
underneath all that
shouting and bluff,
he was as great
a guy as I'd ever met.
He wasn't afraid of dying.
His mind was so full
of life and ideas.
But he felt cheated because
his body was short
changing him with time.
That was a pleasant
evening old boy.
Why Don't you go to bed?
But I had problems of my own.
I just couldn't get
that miss ladyship,
the second, outta my mind.
It was 3 miles to the canford
estate as the crow flies.
Unfortunately I was born a dog.
Over hill and Dale.
Through shot and shell.
Anything for love.
Dames, they want
you to climb mountains,
swim oceans, go through fire.
When you finally get there,
they say
why don't you go home clean up.
But you can always tell.
Sometimes they change their mind.
Oh, well.
Two weeks went by like that,
I never got any sleep or any rest.
I suddenly found my life
belong to a 24-hour company
called 'the Wyndham-
miss ladyship-
Nolan-miss Dorothy-corporation'.
Buyers and sellers of
that miracle product wildfire.
Come on, boy.
You've slept long enough we've
got a hard day ahead of us.
Oh, Nolan.
- What are we going to do?
- I don't know.
- He must be sick.
- Sick?
No temperature, no infection.
Maybe he is homesick
for something.
Where he came from
I can surprisingly say that
he never want to go back.
- I know!
- What?
He's in love.
Why don't you say he wants to
study the piano
or something sensible.
Well, he has all the symptoms.
And who would he be in love with?
The queen of Romania?
I don't know but look at him.
Do you know what's
really wrong with him?
Worms!
An inferiority complex.
He probably thinks
a dog from the Bowery
has no right in
Madison square garden.
- Now who's talking nonsense!
- Isn't it odd?
Neither one of them
was talking nonsense.
They both hit it
right on the head.
It was enough to make
me feel ashamed of myself.
I sure wish that I could
find my mother somewhere.
She'd make me feel better.
You know, sometimes I wonder
if we're not being foolish.
Even if he gets in the
big dog show in the garden.
You know who he has to face,
Don't you?!
Champion regent royal.
That's the news
I was waiting to hear.
Suddenly I felt great.
The world wasn't
big enough to hold me.
What a wonderful feeling.
I was finally gonna get my chance
to kill my father.
Come here, boy.
Come on.
Bring it here, boy.
Come here, boy. Yeah.
Come on, boy. Come on, here.
Go inside.
Go on.
I see you and the
old man out for a walk
that's good.
The old fella needs
somebody to talk to.
You're quite a dog, wildfire.
Quite a dog.
Why Don't we be friends, huh?
Okay, I don't have
Nolan's touch with dogs.
Maybe I did something.
They just sore at me,
I don't know.
Can't hold it against
me forever, can ya?
I made a mistake, I admit it.
Come on shake.
I didn't like that tattooed
smile on tattle's face.
The guy was trying
so hard to be friendly.
What could I do?
There...
It was easy, wasn't it?
You and me we're
the same breed, wildfire.
When we something we want,
we go after it.
Relax.
All your troubles are over.
That cloth
smelled like Mabel
Maycroft's lousy perfume.
It was just as burning.
What happened next
I only learned later.
At the time I was strictly
or as they come back,
which translates roughly
to fractional chloroform.
When I heard that tin pan piano
I knew I was back at Corbin's.
And I knew I was in trouble.
I don't know the exact
price that tattle got for me
but I can only guess
to be somewhere around $40.
Back to the dog-eat-dog
circuit and Patch Mcgill
right where I always dream
that I'd get you some day.
Right here in Patch Mcgill's fist.
How does it feel, you mongrel?
Fortunately I
couldn't feel a thing.
Ransom!
Mr. Mcgill, prefers
it to be called an award,
for finding your dog.
Oh, I have no hand in it.
I'm just a messenger.
He told me to tell you,
you could take it or leave it.
But $2000?!
There won't be $2000,
there won't be as much as $2!
I'll see Patch Mcgill...
Very good gentlemen, very good.
The animal means nothing to me.
But I shouldn't say that.
Because he does
mean something to me.
He's a grand piece of dog flesh.
And he's entitled
to a decent home.
And I think you're going
to have to give it to him.
But apparently
not... wait a minute.
Just a minute there.
- $2000...
- Cash, Mcgill says.
Don't give him the money, Mr.
Wyndham.
I love that animal but this,
this is criminal.
I want that dog
back and they know it.
I'll be there tonight.
Well if you don't like...
Never mind the directions,
I could find that
place with my eyes shut.
You can hear the screaming
of the dying dogs a mile away.
Oh, they were not dogs,
they were customers who
had their credit cut off!
Well, thank you gentlemen,
you've taken a great
weight of my mind.
And I am much obliged too.
I can't say more than that.
Good day to you gentlemen,
good day to you.
Excuse me,
I'm looking for someone
with the name of Patch Mcgill.
I happen to be that gentleman.
May I inquire who is calling?
Wyndham is my name.
Well, Mr.
Wyndham, what's your pleasure?
Glass of beer,
introduction to one
of our sweet young ladies or
is this a business call?
- Business.
Ah the most charming
word in the English language.
Shall we retire to
the conference room?
Yes, yes, by all means.
I hope you brought
it in small bills.
No, I brought it in person.
This is a personal quarrel,
gentleman, an affair of honor.
Good for you, sir.
We'll see you in
a little while, Galahad.
We got many things
to do before the show.
You relax.
Let judges do the worrying.
I don't have to tell you
how important this is, do I?
Win this show and
you're the champion.
Yes.
Now you just forget all
about the ribbons, old boy.
Have your self some fun.
It'll mean more when you're ready.
You know maybe when
the shows over with,
I will find you a girlfriend.
What a guy!
It was a tough choice.
All these people whom I owed
so much wanted me
to win the gold cup.
And I wanted to do one thing
that will lose it for me.
Kill my father.
A choice got tough
every time I looked across
into miss ladyship's eyes
and so that I was thrown away.
The more I looked at her
the less I hated my old man.
After all if it hadn't been for him
I wouldn't be here, would I?
I mean I wouldn't be
fighting for the championship.
Making a lot of
nice people happy in
trying to win the
paw of a fair lady.
I bet he's a pretty
good gaffer at that.
It may be enough to
take away his cup from him.
Why not be noble
about the whole thing?
Noble and smart.
Well, he was at last, my old man.
Pretty good old gaffer.
On not him, what a character.
Arrogant? Cocky?
A real wise guy.
So he's a champion, well so what?
Well, that did it.
Was no woman safe around this guy?
Let Nolan and Wyndham
win their own cups.
I had unfinished business.
Keep that mutt away
from regent royal.
This dog is too expensive...
Oh is that so?
Well if you want
to keep him valuable
take him out of the show.
Because after the show,
he won't be worth anything.
Nothing!
He took the words
right out of my mouth.
Ladies and gentlemen.
If you will allow the judges
to tally up their scorecards,
we will announce the winner
in the bull terrier class
for the championship of America.
All these nice people had come
to the garden to see a show.
Well they were sure gonna see one.
They were about to
see which dog was the best.
Bowery style win, lose or draw.
I was going after my old man.
The final decision,
in the bull terrier competition.
The winner and new champion,
prince Galahad of Wyndham.
- Nolan, congratulations.
- Thank you, sir.
- George.
- Mr. Wyndham
congratulations, Nolan.
It's wonderful, isn't it?
This was the moment of truth,
the time for the kill.
Everything inside
me said go get him.
But suddenly I just couldn't move.
Maybe it was the way
he took it on the chin.
A champion even in defeat
and I understood then
why my mother had loved him.
I taken away his championship
and he would never
know I was his son.
That seemed punishment enough.
A funny thing.
I came wanting to
teach my old man a lesson
instead I had learned
a lesson myself.
Where did those guys get
off making fun of the champion.
We all have to lose some day.
They would murder him.
My old man sure
needed a friend now.
And I was his boy.
Holy Toledo!
Me and my old man,
we sure started something.
I had crossed the Rubicon,
there was no turning back.
I had to enter my
invitation to all the things
most men and most dogs want.
Security, social prominence
and the love of a beautiful girl,
with dull...
Easiest catch I ever made.
Came in low and fast.
Yes, sir.
Homerun of a very first twist.
Well, now settle down,
take it easy.
You've got no worries at all
from here on, none whatsoever.
Now, stand back in there
you fellow stand back.
You've got a new visitor.
Yeah, a regular marathon runner.
As soon as he catches
his breath he'll
probably tell you all about it.
Wrist full of male.
In less than two minutes
I'd gone from the
top of New York society,
the pinnacle dogdom
all the way to the bottom
as Jimmy jocks would say
'sic transit Gloria Mundi'.
All the paths of glory
lead but to the dog catcher.
The only part that hurt
was a thought of passing
my last moments.
With a scurvy as bunch of mongrels
as had ever been picked
up on the streets in New York.
They looked like something
that had escaped from
madame tussaud's waxworks
on a very hot day.
I'm certainly glad my
mother couldn't see me now.
Mother, at long last I found her.
I was so happy I almost
forgot we were behind bars
and heading for that long
slow walk to the gas chamber.
If only the mounties
would arrive in time.
Listen, did you happen
to see a white bull terrier,
he was about so long
and about this tall?
Seen him? Well he's coming
running down through here
as if he's trying to make to
post office before they closed it
but I timed it perfectly.
I drew, back and I
bagged him on the wing...
You got him in here?
Locked tight.
But, but, he is the champion
bull terrier of America.
No kidding! My first champion.
Will you unlock...
The gates here, let me have him.
No, I'm sorry I can't do that.
It's the city orders
against dogs running loose
on the streets.
Oh, yes, yes. How much?
Are you trying to
corrupt a civil servant?
Certainly.
Good! I've got 10 dogs in there.
Make you a deal for
the whole lot of them.
Two bucks a piece.
Here's 50.
What you going do
with the other nine?
Why?
For another buck a piece
I'll taken them off your hands.
Mister,
they are yours for nothing.
Well, off to the hunt.
Tally ho!
Come on, our pilot's gone.
Come on, boy.
No, don't worry about
what happened back there.
That was one of the
greatest sights I ever saw.
Oh, I see you picked
yourself up a friend.
Well, bring her along if
you like that little old lady.
That, that's good enough for me.
Come on, come on, boy.
Come on, girl.
Oh, miss ladyship.
What a lovely girl.
Am I glad to see you.
You know, I think we
may have the makings of a
nice little family here.
Miss ladyship,
I, you know I think,
you not only found
yourself a husband but...
Wildfire, you,
you know, you kinda look like,
like around the eyes, maybe,
maybe we got ourselves
a mother-in-law, too
well, wildfire, girls,
come on let's all of us go home.
Here we go!
Congratulations father!
- There are two boys and...
Three girls.
How about that!