Production company TOR presents
film by Janusz Majewski
JEALOUSY AND MEDICINE
based on novel by
Michał Choromański
starring
featuring
music
sound editing
scenography
costumes
make-up
executive producer
photographed by
directed by
Are you that industrialist,
Widmar?
Yes.
What's this?
It's for you.
Anonymous documents.
Wait!
Stop!
"Of Adultery"
You poor cuckold,
I send these memories
instead of a will, as a farewell.
Once yours, Sophie D.
These are insults!
It's a libel!
You called, my lord?
I did. Why do you let strangers
into the garden?!
Some rascals are hanging about here!
What rascals?
What strangers?
- I've seen no one, Mr Widmar.
- That's exactly the problem!
How dares she?
One awful woman!
Yes, fine.
Goodbye.
Bye.
You're leaving?
I changed my mind.
- Was someone here?
- No.
Are you sure?
- I thought I saw a doctor.
- Really?
What a terrible wind.
It shall make all the patients
leave this world in a week!
No, thank you.
Of course...
It may even wreck
healthy people lives.
Would you agree, doctor,
that medical ethics is very different
from the regular moral sense?
Different from general moral principles?
I don't think so.
But I do.
Physicians always lie to patients.
That must become a habit
in private life as well.
- What do you mean?
- You don't take sugar?
I beg your pardon.
Excuse me. I have a lot on my mind.
I should go back to work.
That's a pity...
Come visit us again some time.
Thank you.
It was said it was the appendix,
then - women's health problems.
But I've heard it was something
quite different!
If that's true
and Widmar knows nothing about it,
that means she cheated on him
when she'd already become his wife.
I counted on fingers.
One day me and Widmar
went to the movie theatre.
They were screening "Love Manoeuvres"
with my favourite Żabczyński.
We were a bit early and adverts
were still on, which Widmar hates!
I know this world,
bright days, golden dreams.
Your smile,
the sparkle in your eyes...
They keep us in here
like we were a flock of sheep.
Who cares about that?
You're the one, the only one!
Forgive me all my sins!
Prophecies that have never come true!
So many routes and words...
Can I have a chocolate, please?
Can I have a chocolate?
Here you go.
IS YOUR SKIN ALIVE?
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
She must be a swimmer.
Have you seen it?
Her one arm
is lower than the other one.
POLISH NEWSREEL
International Equestrian Contest
at Łazienki Racecourse in Warsaw
brought a great success
to Polish equestrians.
Despite strong rivals,
they won the cup.
- Swimmers have uneven arms?
- I don't know.
She may be a bureaucrat then.
Contestants drank champagne from
the cup to cheer for the winners.
If you don't enjoy it here,
we can leave.
You irritate so easily today.
Also women should take part
in defending the country.
They can join defence training voluntarily.
The title, the estate
- it's nothing.
I've been looking for kindness, grace
and straightforwardness all my life.
And you've got it all.
No, I can't believe it.
A prince falls in love with
a Cinderella only in fairy tale.
Life can be a fairy tale, too.
In real life a prince asks about
the marriage portion, about position.
Only children believe in fairy tales.
Let's go back, like in the olden days,
to the fairy tale land.
Turn my life into a wonderful
fairy tale with your love!
What's happened?
Fire!
It's locked!
That way!
Excuse me.
I reckon it's your glove.
Thank you.
Now I know
you don't care about me,
you must know you're leaving me
for no better woman.
- What do you mean?!
- I want you to know.
That lady lived with
every second man in this town.
Everyone knows
everything about her.
Can't you see?
She's cheating on you.
Maybe even the moment we speak?
But you all deserve it!
You think I've been faithful?
Everyone knows
I've made you a cuckold!
Wait!
Very well then.
You'll be sorry.
When I left the hospital,
I wanted to forget those sad events
as soon as possible.
I went dancing with my friends.
I didn't expect
to see Mrs Widmar there.
Please, help me.
Help me.
- What's happened?
- She's fainted.
Excuse me.
It's too soon to dance.
It can cause haemorrhage.
Please.
Excuse me.
He was so disarmingly trustful
and naive,
that I wanted to shout
above people's heads and the tables
and tell him everything I knew
about the hospital and operation.
- Good morning, doctor.
- Good morning.
- Here are the certificates of death.
- Very well.
- Good morning, doctor.
- Good morning.
Doctor!
Am I really not worse?
Why there is still leakage
from my knee?
That's nothing.
You're not worse.
Everything's going to be just fine.
Good morning!
Doctor, a gentleman has been
waiting for you for half an hour.
Excellent.
We might need to amputate
that poor fellow's leg.
Yes?
Excuse me.
Thank you.
You're the gentleman
who's been waiting for me.
Yes.
Let's move to my office.
Have you come as a patient?
Not exactly.
More as a husband
of one of your patients.
What can I do for you?
Doctor...
I owe my wife's life to you.
I'd like to know
the course of the operation.
The course?
The best possible one.
Was it really the appendix?
Of course.
If we had done the operation a day later,
it would've been too late.
I don't want you
to get me wrong...
I'm sure you remember
I was abroad back then.
When I came back,
it had all been over.
My wife never talked
about the details of her condition.
But you must be aware that
it became clear during the procedure
that your wife had been suffering
from other ailments.
What sort of ailments?
Women's health condition.
Quite common, nothing serious.
I can't understand,
why you're so interested in the past.
There's nothing strange about it.
Are you telling the truth?
I beg your pardon?
You must tell me the truth.
I beg of you.
Like only a man can ask another man
in exceptional situations.
I'm not a man, I'm a doctor.
Excuse me but I should be going.
They're waiting for me
in radiography room.
I can see why you're anxious.
However I assure you
your wife is perfectly healthy now.
Let bygones be bygones.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, doctor.
- What's new?
- Another one from the crash.
Those cars are like a plague!
It's worse than tuberculosis!
Dear Willi, I owe you a letter.
But today I particularly feel like
sharing my problems with you.
That patient's husband
came to see me today.
The one we'd operated on when you'd
visited me during your vacation.
You're familiar
with the story of that operation
and its significance in my life.
Although you still
don't appreciate it, I'm afraid.
Willi!
Willi, my dear!
- I'm so happy!
- Me too!
- How was your trip?
- Very good. However...!
I'll speak Polish in Poland.
Shall I?
- You look pale.
- Oh, no.
You seem tired though.
You're right.
I skipped vacation this year.
- A telephone call for you.
- For me?
You should've said I'm not here.
Doctor Otherone speaking.
What a horrible voice.
She must be an old witch.
I'm very sorry but I can't come now.
My assistant will see you.
Fine.
I'll be right there.
Such a strange voice.
She should be young, attractive,
naked... and in bed.
- You said it was an old witch.
- That's a possibility.
I should go.
She's in pain.
- Do you want me to go with you?
- No. Wait for me in here.
- Shall we dance?
- Sorry?
Why didn't doctor Otherone
come to see me?
I'm him.
I see...
What's wrong?
I'm in pain.
- Where does it hurt?
- Here.
Lift your nightgown, please.
- Is that painful?
- Very.
You've got a fever.
How high?
38,5°C.
It's nothing serious.
It's the appendix.
You can't be operated on now.
We must wait for the attack to pass.
No food,
just a few sips of bitter tea.
Operation?
The procedure is as easy
as childish games.
I'm all alone in the house.
I'm very scared.
My husband left abroad.
I'd like you to take me
to your hospital.
It won't be necessary.
Stay in bed for a few days
and then we'll see.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Doctor!
Goodnight.
At that moment her face changed
beyond recognition.
I felt she was the most beautiful
woman I'd ever seen in my life.
But the weirdest thing of all
was that I'd never cared
whether my patient
was pretty or not before.
That's right, my friend.
The position of a woman
in our time is so strong
that it's dangerous and sick.
Women are good for nothing
but for making love to.
At least for me.
Is that your opinion?
A man will never believe a woman
is doing whatever she wants with him.
If only it was something good!
I've met many scientists
and artists
who gave up half their ambitions
influenced by their wives.
All the same,
it's both meaningful and sad
that men are the only ones
who disagree with me.
Women mostly admit I'm right
in their minds.
Well...
Can you remember our conversation
about that woman, Willi?
I'm starting to feel that Rebecca
is my doom.
I can always see her image
in my mind's eye.
I see her face everywhere.
I see the unique line of her stomach
which I mentioned to you.
The next day was calm.
Caregiver Paweł
was running errands for your wife.
He even got two bouquets of flowers
your wife asked him to buy
to cover the smell of gasoline
that annoyed her.
Of course
it was some kind of a delusion.
I couldn't smell gasoline.
The nurses had already fallen out
with the missus.
- They weren't too fond of her.
- As usual.
I worked night shift that day.
I was in the office,
studying before my pathology exam...
Open the window.
Cold compress.
Hello?
It's Rubiński, doctor.
Who?
I don't understand.
- Number 101.
- 101?
Mrs Widmar.
Get her to the operating theatre.
Surgical instruments?
You'll be fine.
These are for some other procedure.
I'm scared.
Doctor!
Don't be.
I'm going to shave you.
Start with the anaesthetic.
Breathe in calmly.
Easy.
She's fallen asleep, doctor.
What time is it?
Do remember that.
It's 02:16, doctor.
Lancet.
The first cut always
soothes the surgeon's nerves.
It looked like a pleasant job.
It was like artistic inspiration.
It didn't occur to me
something wrong might happen.
For the first 8 minutes, every stage
of the operation was successful.
- What's the time?
- 8 minutes, doctor.
Oh, la-la!
Look at this...
It's the third time.
Encapsulated.
Yes, sir.
Scissors.
Fool!
I need the patient to breathe easily.
Scissors!
Fool!
The patient must breathe!
Ether.
We have none.
Get the sterilized instruments.
Scissors.
Get her tongue out.
Fool!
Yes, sir.
The tongue.
Forceps.
Forceps!
Endoscope.
And don't jump around!
Get the grip!
His shouting really made us
get a grip.
I made no more mistakes
passing him the instruments.
I was trying to see something in
the abdominal cavity, but I couldn't.
Of course I understood
there was some kind of complication.
That it's no longer the appendix,
that we're operating on genitals
but I didn't know why.
You found out afterwards though.
The director said it was a cyst
but if it really was - I'm not sure.
Have you got any assumptions?
Any suspicions?
Try to remember a detail,
which you could use as a hint.
Truly...
I remember nothing.
It happened so quickly that
I don't even know, how it all ended.
It's dawning. We must've been
operating for two hours.
When you're doing trepanation,
you need your brain.
When you're operating on a woman,
you need to think about genitals.
- Boruch, dad is crying again.
- Dad has got a smoky chimney.
- You're lying!
- No, you are!
Where have you got so dirty again?
The sweep threw me into the chimney!
You crazy girl!
Anielka, Boruch!
Get back home.
Dad, he hit me.
My Boruch...
Why did you hit her?
I'm going to make you suffer for it.
She bit my leg!
I'm not sure about that anyway.
Maybe it's just my imagination.
Gold, what are you talking about?
I can't understand a thing.
I don't want to offend you.
What if those are just presumptions
of an old, blind tailor?
Hello?
Yes, it's me.
You can go now.
And remember about the lining.
Dear God, why did you punish me
with such children?
I see...
- Get back into the house now!
- I'm not coming!
Do you recognize me?
Tell your father I'm waiting for him
today afternoon at my house.
No, tell him I'll be in Esplanada
at 6 p.m.
- It's that café.
- I know.
- Don't forget though.
- I forget nothing.
Listen to me, Gold...
I think it's all
a disgusting joke of yours.
Don't even say that, Mr Widmar.
No.
Why did you grow old so soon, Gold?
Look at me - I wear well.
Admittedly, I'm only 50.
What about you?
Me?
I'm 38.
- What?
- 38.
Let's go back to our business.
What will it be?
Do you agree?
I do agree but I can't do it.
Listen to me, Gold.
You've always been sewing for me.
That's true.
We've known each other
for 10 years.
But I still don't know,
if you have a wife.
Perhaps you don't know
what suffering is?
No!
There is no suffering.
All I want is the truth.
The truth.
Can't you see?
No suffering, Mr Widmar.
Gold! I think you're simply
blackmailing me.
Mr Widmar, don't get me scared.
Waiter!
Why are you looking at me like that?
Why are you covered with plumage?
Do you sleep in your coat or what?
Perhaps you sneak
and visit some ladies as well?
Get under their duvets?!
My dear Mr Widmar,
don't get upset.
Calm down, please.
Well?
What do you say?
Mr Widmar, I can't do it.
I cannot agree.
If you were sure, you could...
- What?
- You could do something foolish.
- How can I help you, sir?
- What's that smell?
It stinks of agony in here.
I can't smell it, sir.
Mr Gold, you've got kids.
You need money.
If you have it,
you can make your son an engineer.
Well?
I'll give you an answer tomorrow.
- What are you doing here?
- Greetings, doctor.
- Are your lungs better?
- Thank you.
You keep on bravely.
Anielka, Boruch!
You should stay in the house
when wind is blowing so strongly.
It could make your lungs burst.
And then all of your blood
would get out through your mouth.
It's easy to get a cold.
And only bastards know
how to get better.
Has your uncle come back
from the power station?
- No.
- Yes!
The question is,
which one of you is lying?
I never know!
Dad, why are you so slim?
Are you a little boy?
I'm surely not a little boy!
I'm just slim.
I know!
You're humpbacked then.
I'm not humpbacked.
I'm simply slim.
You must be a dachshund then.
Boruch, please,
you leave me alone!
- Good evening.
- Is it?
What's the matter?
- What should be the matter?
- Nothing is the matter.
But it doesn't justify saying
"good evening".
Come in.
I'm glad you're here.
Boruch, wash Anielka's hands.
Get ready for the supper.
I'll burn you
with boiling water today!
You'll see!
I'll tell daddy!
Look!
The dachshund.
Boruch!
Good heavens!
You're a rascal, not a Boruch!
Trust me, it's all the same.
Everyone wants to earn money,
when one can.
Say yes, otherwise you'll starve
together with your children.
I won't be able to help you,
if I get sacked from the station.
Yes...
I see.
I'm off then.
Would you like to become an engineer,
Boruch?
- What's 7x8?
- 9.
You'd be one poor engineer.
Isaac!
- Come back, Isaac.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing's wrong.
- Come back.
Isaac, I was thinking...
You're ginger.
What of it?
Boruch looks just like you.
Abraham,
I hereby give you my word.
I never fancied your wife.
I didn't even lay my eyes
on your late wife.
Forgive me, Isaac,
but neither her nor I were ginger.
Excuse me.
I'll go now.
I'm going to shoot you...
- Is the missus asleep?
- The missus?
She's gone to the hairdresser's.
I'd like to see that hairdresser.
She didn't mind the weather?
It's not raining.
It's just the wind.
Yes...
You're right.
Left!
Higher!
That's fine.
Good morning, dear sir.
The thing I feared the most
has happened.
It's you.
What happened?
The director of the hospital informed
me today my contract is off.
- His motivation was stupid.
- I'm sorry.
Did you manage
to go through the archives?
There's nothing there.
It only says there had been
a cyst which was removed.
Bloody hell.
- I think I know what it was.
- Well?
I've come to a conclusion
it must've been eccyesis.
What's that?
Ectopic pregnancy.
Right. 9 weeks...
Everything's clear.
- Pardon?
- It's nothing.
Do you swear that's true?
No, I told you
it was just my presumptions.
We should leave. It's not
a good place for a conversation.
No, that's too much!
Some details are symptomatic.
For example her complaining about the
smell of gasoline that wasn't there.
Typical compulsions during pregnancy.
- Doctor!
- The weather is awful!
I have been witness
to 12 haemorrhages today!
I'm answering
to another call right now!
Dear Lord!
Have you seen that?
I almost got run over!
It was BMW 327.
6-cylinder motor!
2 carburettors,
overhead-valve engine!
True devil!
- It's time for me to go, too.
- Just a second.
What are the possible complications
of such an operation?
Complications?
Sometimes it's infertility,
psychological trauma
- especially relating to sex life,
susceptibility to putting on weight.
- I see.
- Goodbye.
Boruch, wait!
Wait for me!
Boruch, get down!
You're a rascal, not a Boruch!
What are you doing?
You're peeping at me, you bastard!
I'm not a bastard but a postman.
- Where are your letters, Mr postman?
- That's it!
Don't tell anyone you saw me here,
will you?
HAIRDRESSER'S
What are you doing?!
Nothing. I just wanted
to give her a teddy bear.
Get stuffed with that bear!
Philanthropist!
Wandering and scaring children!
- I just...
- So many perverts walk the earth!
That lady...
That lady in the window
threw some sweets for me.
What lady?
Which window?
On the second floor.
Listen to me, children.
Listen carefully.
How did she look like?
Boruch, you must have seen her.
- Did she have long red hair?
- No. She was blonde.
She had pink sacks in the front.
Is that your tailor again?
He's a repulsive old man.
- Why repulsive?
- I don't know.
He smells like he was going
to die in a minute.
Or like he was already dead.
Like I was dead?!
Greetings, sir.
It's you.
Is there something
you'd like to tell me?
- Mr Widmar, I made my decision.
- Bravo!
- Do you agree to do both?
- Yes.
Splendid!
- Have you hired a thug?
- I did.
- Who's he?
- My brother.
- Your brother?
- Yes.
- And a twin, too, huh?
- No, it's my older brother.
I mean he's younger but he looks like
he's older because he's well-build.
He works at the power station.
- Power station?
- Yes.
Hold on a second...
- Is he ginger?
- How did you know?
See?
I know everything I should.
- How much does he want?
- It's up to you.
Will that be enough?
- You're a good man.
- Forget it.
- Would he like a drink too?
- Give it to him.
What about that other problem?
We'll go, for sure.
Perhaps tomorrow.
Why not today?!
We shouldn't.
Lady was there today.
- How do you know?
- Boruch told me.
- But he said the lady was blonde.
- What do you mean?
Maybe he doesn't know
what he's talking about...
Listen, Gold.
I you're lying and making it up,
you'll be sorry.
I'm not making it up.
You'll see for yourself.
Come and visit me tomorrow.
At 6 p.m.
HOMELAND
I see you're a regular customer here,
Mr Gold.
- Don't even speak like that, doctor.
- Alright.
- The usual?
- Yes, please.
Why are you
paying us visits so rarely?
- We met 2 days ago.
- Do feel welcome.
Today and whenever you feel like it.
No...
We shouldn't see
too much of each other.
What's wrong?
It's the draught.
I thought you were cold.
It's easy to catch a cold.
I'm warm enough.
- Mrs Rebecca plays beautifully.
- She does.
She's been practising.
- Shall we?
- No, thank you.
You're not staying for a supper?
I'm very grateful but I'm expected
at the hospital. I should go.
- Shame.
- Forgive me.
Come and visit us tomorrow.
I wouldn't.
Not every day.
- The wind doesn't stop.
- That's true.
Excuse me, have you got a light?
- I don't smoke.
- That's a pity.
Rebecca...
Stop!
Stop or I'll shoot!
- Is something wrong?
- No.
Listen, doctor. Two haemorrhages.
I bet it's the wind.
- One nurse is not enough.
- I'll do anything you ask for.
A second nurse?
Not a problem.
Where did that bump come from?
- I was hit.
- By a car?
No, with a bat.
Whatever you do, don't get in the car.
They get so many people injured.
About the haemorrhage,
I'll deal with it myself.
Why tire the nurses?
Nurse, make sure
doctor doesn't exhaust himself.
He's been working too much lately.
One more thing!
If there's a patient
with a gunshot wound, do wake me up.
Was it doctor Otherone shouting?
- When?
- Out in the street.
Of course not.
I saw him walking off home.
I'm sure it was him.
Why are you laughing?
It's nothing.
Get me some water.
- What kind of meat is it?
- Poulard.
- It's a young hen, isn't it?
- Yes.
Very spongy and tender meat.
Poor hen!
Are you all right?
I'm not going to eat that,
it's disgusting!
Don't you like it?
Why?
I just don't!
Expect me tonight.
I need to talk to you.
Fine.
- Was the operation very painful?
- Just a little.
- You're still gaining weight?
- I'm trying to stop it.
Yes, of course...
Why didn't you tell me the surgeon
warned you about putting on weight?
Do you still find
the smell of gasoline irritating?
Didn't I tell you about that?
- But you do love me, Rebecca.
- I do.
You'll always love me,
won't you?
Always.
Why don't you want
to tell me the truth?
I'd forgive you, I'd bear it,
just tell me!
Confess, Rebecca!
My little one,
what do you actually want?
I don't understand a thing.
Will you tell me or not?
What was it
with the unborn child?
What child? I have no idea
what you're talking about.
No idea.
About that either?
After the operation you can be
infertile for the rest of your life.
You don't understand that either?!
It must be true then.
Women are mutilated
after such procedures.
You'll no longer be a woman!
You won't be capable of love!
Poulard.
Is anyone here?
- There's no one in the house.
- Our dad is.
- Which one of you is lying?
- He is.
Yes, it's me.
- Where's your father?
- Dad is dead.
Father is in his shop,
your grace.
Greetings, sir.
You've got a very talented son,
Mr Gold. He'll make a good engineer.
- Boruch, what's 7x8?
- 9!
You stupid boy!
- I'd like to speak to you.
- Come into my shop, please.
Every woman has weed
under her skirt!
Be quiet!
Gold, I've come to a conclusion
we should go there right now.
- No...
- Yes.
- Get dressed.
- I can't go, Mr Widmar.
Boruch, this gentleman is sitting
on the ironing-board.
- Dollars will get you even to America.
- Boruch, the gentleman is crying.
Our dad has a lantern
in his stomach!
Mr Widmar,
I'm not sure whether
it will happen today or not.
It could end up
with your beating today!
Dear sir, can you see the light?
Let go of my arm!
I can see it.
Dear Lord...
Let's go.
Come on!
Don't do anything wrong though.
How can I help you?
- You're a keeper in this house?
- Indeed.
Please tell us,
where doctor Otherone lives.
No one lives here permanently.
There was an accident
in the hospital.
We're looking
for surgeon Otherone.
You should've said
there was an accident.
He lives on the second floor,
to the left.
Don't tell him we talked.
You'll go first
and knock on that door.
- No...
- You will!
- You'll go right now.
- Never, never.
No...
Or else I'm going to...
You and everyone...
With lead shots, get it?
Lead shots!
I can't, Mr Widmar.
Poulard!
I'll do anything.
I'll go anywhere you wish.
Just don't shout like that.
You'll go first.
Mr Widmar...
You will!
Who's there?
I've got a gun.
Gold...
- Have you seen it? She's not there.
- I have.
It's good she's not there.
Very good.
Nothing to be glad about.
Have you seen a scarf?
What scarf?
You've lost a scarf?
You fool!
There's my wife's scarf
on the railing of the bed.
Yellow scarf!
- My God...
- Listen!
Listen to me, Gold.
I have no doubt now.
Even if she's not here today,
she'll come tomorrow.
And you're going see to it.
I'll wait for you at home.
The moment you see my wife,
let me know immediately.
- All right.
- I'll give you the money upfront.
You don't even have to
come back here with me.
I'll find...
my way round.
Doctor!
I know where your bed-sitter is!
Are you alright?
Would you like to sit down?
No...
I'm not ill.
I only wanted to see the director.
- He's operating at the moment.
- You'll have to wait.
Thank you.
Is that your wife who's going to have
her appendix removed?
That's none of your business!
I...
I have no wife.
Nurse, is director operating?
He's been removing appendix
for an hour.
- For an hour?
- Yes.
- I wanted to see the director.
- He's operating.
- How long is it going to take?
- It's his third one day.
We've got 4 more.
What a sick day!
Doctor!
Don't you get it?!
It was abscess!
It had moved right under her heart.
What happened?
She died on the operating table.
Excuse me.
You've been waiting
for the director for so long.
Can I help you as a doctor?
Thank you. I wanted
to talk to him strictly privately.
I beg your pardon.
It's enough for an old doctor
to look at the patient
and he already knows
the source of the suffering.
What would be the diagnosis
in my case?
Unfortunately very common.
There's not one man
who doesn't suffer from that.
Really?
What would you prescribe
for that illness?
What would I prescribe?
Time.
Time heals all wounds,
Mr Widmar.
Yes...
Thank you.
God...
Dear Lord...
Don't punish anyone
with misfortune.
Don't lead anyone's wife
into temptation.
But, good God, let one talented son
of Israel become an engineer.
And let the father of that engineer
go to America!
To have many clients
and do great business!
Not wander the city, as if he's some
broker, to spy on someone's wife!
God...
Dear Lord,
listen to me just for a minute...
Why didn't you come yesterday?
Don't be angry at me, my dear.
I've missed you so much!
I couldn't.
He was with me the whole evening.
- He was home yesterday?
- Yes. Why?
I thought he was here yesterday.
That's not possible.
I can't take it any longer.
You're inconsiderate towards me.
You know I'll do anything
you want or tell me to.
Why don't you speak to him?
Or let me do it.
I didn't come yesterday because
I was talking to him.
Were you? At last!
What have you told him?
That there's someone else.
Someone I love.
And that's why
I couldn't be with him now.
- Did you tell him you meant me?
- No.
But I think he knows it's you.
Even if he doesn't,
he must suspect it.
We should prepare him for that.
You know he has a heart condition.
Do you see, my dear?
My little one...
- You'll never leave me.
- I won't. Never.
Never!
I wish I could believe that!
I'll show you!
I can't bear it any longer.
I'm going to discover nothing.
Nothing...
Was it you who turned off the light?
It obviously wasn't.
- What happened then?
- The bulb must've blown out.
The power is out in the whole town.
I'll take the flashlight.
Why are you getting dressed?
What time is it?
You're distracting me.
You don't treat me well.
I forgive you this time as I've
already forgiven you your past.
- Even the Uhlan.
- Which one?
You know which one.
We've met thanks to him.
He was the reason
you got into the hospital.
Don't remind me of him.
I have no idea how that happened.
He was young and immature.
You should've waited for me.
You do know
I never loved before.
I have to believe you.
Otherwise I'd stop loving you.
I must be trusted.
I never lie.
It's got very late.
I should go.
My scarf.
I must've left it here.
Turn it off.
Promise me you'll speak to him,
once and for all.
I promise.
I'm so tired because of work
and everything else.
- You'll never leave me?
- Never.
Never.
Bye.
See you tomorrow.
- Where?
- Here again.
I'll be at 6 p.m.,
I'll tell you everything.
I'll see you to the door.
Stay here.
I better go alone.
Bye.
- You in a car, doctor?
- I can't see why not!
I always go by car.
There's been an accident.
A man's experienced electric shock.
Director!
I'm glad you're here. The patient
in room 7 has suffered an attack.
Where have you been?
Where do you go every day
at this hour?!
- I've been to a movie theatre.
- You're lying.
- Do you love me, Rebecca?
- You know it only too well.
Why do you need to ask?
So you're not cheating on me
with the doctor?
My little one,
you're being silly.
I must be trusted.
You can see I find him boring.
He's here every second day,
hardly saying anything.
Why are you torturing yourself?
Can't you feel I'm being faithful?
Of course...
You've never been unfaithful.
And you never will be.
Am I right?
Promise me.
I won't.
Never.
How could I have suspected you?
I should've trusted you!
Forgive me!
Rebecca.
I'm sorry!
I'm sorry.
You shouldn't be.