Starring:
THE ONLY WAY OUT
Directed by:
The movie was filmed in
Postojna Cave (Slovenia).
During World War II, German occupying
forces used the cave to store
nearly 1,000 barrels of
aircraft fuel, which were
destroyed in March 23, 1944
by Yugoslavian Partisans.
This story was losely
based on that event
and any similarity with
real persons was accidental.
For the first time,
we have to be careful
about the object we
are about to demolish.
We have a strict order not to use
too much explosive in the Cave.
Because it is a wonder of nature.
-It would make a nice tomb for us.
Seems that the fuel is stored
in some unimportant part.
We are here.
The Germans have
walled up the passage.
That's why they don't guard it.
But there is an
underground river here.
Some parts, called siphons,
are completely submerged.
The fuel storage is 4 miles away,
at the tourist entrance.
Do we know the quantity?
-Approximately 50 wagons.
Has anyone of you been in the Cave?
I know only the entrance
near the railway.
Maybe we have to go through the
undercurrents. -Why through there?
Better that we go through this
hallway. It is faster and safer.
Damn, this is a nasty action.
Four men in the dark
with new commander.
We should think of men.
I've told you already that the passage
has been walled up. -We will break through.
No one has ever passed through
the undercurrents. -I know that.
I'm going to see the security officer.
We go as soon as I come back.
You shouldn't talk to
the commander like that.
I just don't know what came over me.
Let's forget about it.
I was with Maria last night.
She asked me where I would go.
I didn't want to tell her.
She told me: "Watch yourself!"
Why would she tell me something
like that? -She loves you.
Have you ever loved someone?
Not as much as I should have.
When you are with a woman,
you wish the war is over.
You know, her fingers are...
...long, long as blades of grass.
I was a master shooter with marbles,
when I was a kid.
This one doesn't count.
Let's go over there to
smoke our cigarettes.
You go. I'll smoke here.
So, white bread diet again?
I wish it is white.
We have a little time left,
let's smoke our cigarettes.
Let's wait for the commander.
Let's not!
Who knows what the new one is alike.
And this I will stash away.
This way,
at least my tobacco would be dry.
Hand me the lighter.
It is reliable, but almost empty.
Down there, you have 50
wagons of fuel, you could use.
If we live in some other time,
now it would be a proper time
for a prayer and confession.
But, since we are, what we are,
let everyone thinks what he wants.
Look at Jozha. He still smokes.
It must be that you come up
with something. -Me?
This time - nothing.
I don't like this rain.
The undercurrent will raise up.
Rudy, you cigarette butt is the shortest
and my the longest. It means something.
Means what?
-Nothing. I was joking.
Four butts - all grouped together.
Everything ready?
Yes, for now.
Our mission is crystal clear:
the fuel must fly sky-high,
or our asses are on the line.
Stay together.
If someone gets lost...
-...let him yells: "Ooya!"
Be careful and agile.
We must go through water.
Have you protected the explosive?
Silly me! You have been in many
similar missions, haven't you?
Depends. Most of us have
been in more than 30 missions.
And you, comrade commander?
OK, let's smoke a cigarette now.
We have done that already,
comrade commander.
Is that so?
Now he knows about our cigarettes.
-Ah...
Good start!
Keep the necessary distance.
Jozha...
Come out, comrades!
I played this for you.
Are you insane?!
Acting like a fool!
I just wanted to check
electric installations.
Don't be afraid.
They cannot hear us.
The fuel storage is a
couple of miles from here.
So, this means that the Germans
can turn on the lights in the Cave.
No, not the entire cave at once.
This switch, turns the lights
on, 200 yards behind us,
and this one,
200 yards in front of us.
The tourist bureau was thrifty, taking
care about economical use of lights.
You mustn't do it again without
my approval. Understand?
Yes, comrade commander.
They built a strong wall,
as we predicted.
Let's try to break through.
Shorty, let's start!
-Wait!
Impossible. A concrete wall.
Who knows what's behind it.
And they could hear us.
Explosion could crumble the hallway.
Going through the underground
river would be insane.
It has been raining for days.
The water level must be high.
Make a decision.
I was told that there was one siphon
through which we might be able to pass.
It's our only chance.
Let's go.
This newbie doesn't
want to hit the wall...
...with his head.
Let's go.
Take care about the explosive
and protect your flashlights.
Jozha and me, we are going ahead.
You three wait here.
When you hear my whistle,
you come along.
Wait here! Commander and
Jozha have gone to see around.
Give me the matches.
I don't have it.
I don't know where I put it.
Wait! The water is rising.
It has risen a lot.
We shouldn't go any
further or we would drown.
Stop talking! Hurry up!
How would we go back?
The same way.
Only faster.
The Germans will chase us.
Come on, Rudy!
-Don't you see the water level?
We have a new commander.
What is he going to think about us?!
And now what?
And if that is 50 yards long?
You're insane! I won't go!
I won't commit a suicide!
Who doesn't dare, just go back.
Be my guest.
We've slipped through.
The shore is near.
Good work, comrades.
We've managed to get here
for less than a half of hour.
I doubt that we would be able to
penetrate the wall in that time.
Jozha?
-Huh?
What about the explosive?
- Everything is in order.
Tomo? -The same.
Even the cigarettes are dry.
We can smoke a cigrette now.
-I would prefer a snack.
Here, Rudy... Have a smoke.
If you have finished your
cigarettes, we can move on.
Should I go ahead with a flashlight?
I would choose this way.
-I don't think so.
I don't see anything on this chart.
But I do not agree with you.
-Comrade commander...
This passage is narrow and
has a dead end, I'm sure.
I think we should go that way. The
Germans has probably walled up this one.
Germans did not built another wall.
No discussion any more!
Follow me. We don't have much time.
Hollow and rings like a bell.
He pretends to be a wise guy, huh?
-He is sure that he knows.
You're gonna spent your flashlight,
comrade commander.
We will try your way.
We are wasting our time. We should
have broken through that wall.
What are you trying to say?
-Nothing.
Then stop talking!
If you have soiled your pants, don't go!
-I shouldn't have come!
Enough! Go back!
He's gonna destroy us, for sure.
Turn off that lamp.
Why are you looking at me?!
Let me be.
Turn off the light.
Jozha.
Jozha!
-Huh?
What is this?
-I don't know.
Probably some lights
from one of the halls.
We are still far away
from the entrance.
This is probably "Concert Hall".
Rudy and Shorty stay with the gear.
The rest of you, follow me.
Shorty...
Listen, Shorty...
"Turn off the lamp.
What are you looking at!"
Now we have turned off everything.
Tell the Krauts to turn off, as well.
There are 3-4 guards.
They have a kitchen there.
They have a radio, as well.
What could that be?
Some sort of a guard exchange post.
Maybe that is the storage.
Impossible. The storage is
much deeper, behind the bridge.
Let's eliminate them.
Eh, Tomo...
Three Krauts doesn't
worth 50 wagons of fuel.
Go back and bring
those two and the gear.
Shorty, forgive me, please.
I don't give a damn.
Forget it.
I'm dreaming.
I see a bright sunshine of Africa.
-Why are you talking about sunshine?
No reason.
Just wanted to tell something.
I'm sick of all these rocks.
I wish I could see a daylight,
just once more.
Don't worry.
You'll see it.
A man could be afraid
of some weired things.
Could be, but mustn't be.
C'mon, the commander is calling.
According to this chart,
we should go through this hall.
Yes, this is "Concert Hall".
It's a shorter way.
Now we have to take a longer detour.
We just have to reach the railway.
I recognize this part of the cave.
Can you...
Can you find the detour?
-Yes, I can.
We have to cross over a hill.
I think they call it... uhm...
They call it...
Calvary, or something like that.
We move. Absolute silence.
And now the Calvary!
In the name of the Father, the
Son, and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Oh, Jesus Christ,
your torment is upon us now.
Little fish...
Little fish.
Nice little olm.
What a nice little olm.
Don't be afraid. Come here now.
Are you a fish... or a man?
Little fish. Little fish.
Why are they shooting?
-Maybe they saw us.
Impossible. They would light up
the cave and sound the alarm.
Forget it. Move on.
Come and get it!
(Speaking German)
(Radio warning)
Hey!
Put out the cigarette, now!
Calvary.
Shorty...
I've decided.
I can not stand this
uncertainty any more.
As soon as we reach the target,
I will go into action. -Why you?
The commander will choose.
-He must choose me!
You mean, because of this.
What's he saying?
-Nothing.
Give him the lighter.
He doesn't have any matches left.
This one is not for everybody.
I'm gonna steal it, for sure.
After the war,
I will make a lighter like this.
Yeah, just go ahead.
I'll keep this one, for now.
Pay attention now!
What is it, Jozha?
I've found the detour.
And the railway is close by.
One route leads back to the bridge,
and the other,
straight to the entrance.
This has been like a
tourist walk, so far.
Now it's over with tourism.
Keep quite and alert.
(Speaking German)
So, here you are, birdies!
And now the showtime.
What a beast's lair!
It's OK, comrades.
We predicted something like this.
It is the entrance, so there will be
no significant damage if we blow it up.
This will make a nice little fire.
-Keep quite and get to work.
Jozha, keep watching the guards.
-Yes, commander.
Shorty, you will go and...
-...and me.
All right.
Tomo and Jozha will cover us.
In the case of a fight, we shall not
retreat until Shorty and Rudy return.
I'll fix it to explode
in a half of an hour.
Half an hour?
No. Two hours.
We need that much to escape.
I'm going to have a closer look.
A bit too cautious, our new pal.
He could say two days.
Who knows. Maybe he's right.
Yeah, why not...
I'm so tense, I could explode myself.
Stop whining!
If you had a britches,
you would have soiled yourself.
Not that one!
Use a chemical fuse, you bungler!
You always think only
how to fill your belly.
You're lucky to be with us,
so no one would know.
No, not that one.
Use the other one, instead.
Their garrison is full of soldiers.
I don't know about this side.
Don't worry. When they reach
the cave, we will be far away.
Are you planning to stay?
Taking your boot like that.
I wouldn't do that.
-Something pinched me.
Don't do that, bro.
They could smell your stinking feet.
-Quite!
If they spot me,
you should eliminate the guards.
Don't worry, Rudy.
Light me.
Hey, gimme that!
Later. Now I know that
you will cover us properly.
Here. Take this to comfort you.
Well... Ready?
We're ready.
Let's go!
Stay hidden and don't turn any light.
Yeah, now I wish to be a bat.
It is mined!
If they spot them,
shoot in the searchlight.
(Speaking German)
See, it's only a cat.
-Yeah and we almost open fire.
Come, kitty, kitty...
If they spot me, I'll start to meow.
Come to me, kitty.
(Speaking German)
Someone is there!
We can forget the explosive now.
They will find it.
I'll light up the fuel.
Give me the lighter. -I'll do it.
Give it to me! -We'll go together.
-Go back!
Cover me!
Rudy will light up the fuel.
We have to wait for him.
Rudy!
It's burning!
(Krauts yelling)
Rudy! Over here! Rudy!
Here! Take this, Krauts!
Rudy!
Rudy! Shorty!
Shorty!
Rudy! Where are you?
Rudy!
We must go back!
Try to awake him.
The Krauts could be here any second.
Is he wounded?
-I didn't see any wound.
Probably just a concussion.
Strange that they haven't turn on the
lights. Maybe damaged in the explosion.
What about him?
Nothing yet.
I hope that they would not cut us off.
-The flame has blocked the way for Krauts.
Nevertheless, we don't have much time.
What's going on? Where are we?
Shorty! Shorty!
Rudy!
Oh, it's you. Where is Rudy?
Shorty, can you stand up?
Are you wounded?
-I don't know.
What about Rudy?
-In such a flame, even stones burn.
What? You left Rudy behind?
-You called him. Did he answer?
I didn't see him fall.
-What do you think?
I thought I saw him running. And
then it exploded, and I passed out.
Listen, Shorty...
Give me a straight answer:
Are you sure that he is alive?
Maybe he crawled under
those moist rocks there.
We cannot hesitate any more.
We completed the mission.
Who did complete it?
He did complete the mission!
What could we do?
-Let's try to find him!
Wait!
Krauts!
Go back!
Here.
Get moving. Go!
(Speaking German)
Wait!
They go back.
-It's Rudy!
What are you trying to say?
He's alive!
-How do you know that?
You don't know that.
Take it easy.
We don't know why are they
going back. -It is clear why.
Only five of us entered the cave.
Dogs can smell live and dead people.
So, this is how you think.
If the Germans don't start
to shoot, then... -Then what!
To sit here and wait?
-Yes, damn it!
Or would you rather
take us to attack them?
We did everything we could.
What sort of a man are you?
I haven't heard a single shot.
Would it be better if you did?
Maybe they have captured him.
Rudy would never surrender.
What if he was unconscious, like me?
We couldn't do anything about it.
-Why not?
We were sitting here like some
old ladies. -I'm going alone! -Stop!
Stop right there! What makes you think
that you are better than the rest of us.
We've been in trouble many times
before and we never left a man behind.
Enough!
They are going to the bridge.
Why did they return to the storage?
-Why did they come here in the first place?
I don't know.
-I do.
Listen.
My orders were to complete the mission and
to save the men. And you want to ruin us!
Retreat! That's an order!
Hurry up! Or they would cut us off.
They are coming. Fire!
Go cross over the bridge. Hurry!
Comrades! This is my fault.
Go, cross the bridge.
I will cover you.
Go now!
I'll shoot better if I'm alone.
Go after him.
I order you to go!
This is my fault. I'll cover you.
I give the orders around here!
-But, commander...
Go, when I'm telling you.
Soon, it would be too
late for both of us.
This one is for Rudy!
Fuck you!
Shorty!
Watch yourself, Shorty!
Comrades...
I'm only holding you...
-Don't talk, Shorty.
Throw some grenades.
Keep them there.
This was all my fault.
Don't talk now.
Lucky for us, the
siphon is not too long.
Maybe they are still
here in the dark.
Sergeant!
Collect this as an evidence.
-Yes, sergeant.
Comrades!
The dawn is near.
The sky is clear.
This will be a beautiful day.
Yes, it's a daybreak.
Any moment now.
Go and bring a stretcher.
I regret...
I've kept Tomo's lighter
and I wouldn't be able...
...to return it to him.
We'll put you on a stretcher.
You will feel better.
Stars...
Like marbles...
It is not good to remember...
Forgive me...
I was rude with you.
Well, you know...
New commander...
I understand. Don't talk now.
You need to rest.
It was my fault.
I put you all in jeopardy.
Forget it.
Don't talk about it.
Who knows who's fault was that.
Don't be angry with me...
...but I still think
that Rudy is alive.
I would like to smoke
a cigarette with you...
Shorty. Shorty.
Shorty!
Take him down to the checkpoint.
Leave the gun. I'll follow you.
Tomo...
He asked me to give you this lighter.
Thank you, comrade commander.
Rudy!
Rudy, it's me.
Hurry! They are going to the wall.
We will go through the understreams.
Finally!
Let me go first, this time.
What about the others?
-All out and safe.
I wonder...
What is it, Rudy?
You wanted to ask me something.
I wonder why Shorty isn't with you.
He couldn't come.
Is he badly wounded?
We carried him.
He didn't suffer for long.
It was during the night and he said:
"It will be a beautiful day."
Translated for Karagarga by
Quigley (12.2013)