Towards the end of the 19th century,
Christians from around the world...
emigrated to Jerusalem, convinced
the end of the world was nigh...
and the second coming of Christ
was eminent.
This story is dedicated to them.
Mr. Storm!
What a surprise! Welcome!
How are the children getting on in
school? Are they learning anything?
-Indeed...
-I thought so.
What brings you here,
if I may ask?
Well... it's like this...
-It's so...
-What is it, Storm?
I have something to tell you.
I'll tell the vicar...
Some of us plan to build a...
A mission-hall.
A mission-hall? Surely not.
Building a mission-hall?
Heresies are spreading
throughout the land.
-I thought you were my friend.
-Don't take it like that.
I've not been an eminent preacher,
but to take the office from me...!
The mission-hall will be
a fortress against apostasy...
and the sects that threaten our land
with conversion and desolation.
Forget all that...
The mission hall shall be a place where
people can be addressed more directly.
-Where you can explain the difficult...
-Haven't I spread knowledge?
Haven't I warned
against unbelief?
I must be singularly inept
when the school teacher...
a farmer,
I have taught you everything!
And now you think
you are on a pair with me.
We have to protect the flock
against the wolves.
Wolves?
I haven't seen any wolves.
I know they are on their way.
If so, is it you, Storm,
who opens the door to them.
Ingmar! Big-lngmar!
The jetty has collapsed!
The children are on it!
No! Don't go into the water!
-It'll be the death for you!
-Come back, lngmar!
Ingmar!
Big-lngmar! Come back!
It'll be the death for you!
You're crazy, lngmar!
Come on, children!
lngmar!
Look out for the log!
You must take me home.
Take me back to the farm.
-You won't make it. It's too far.
-I want to see lngmar.
I must talk to my boy.
And the angel took John
to the top of a high mountain.
and showed him the holy city,
The new Jerusalem,
descended from heaven,
from God,
filled with God's whole glory.
And John saw how the city shone...
like the most precious jewel.
The city wall was of quartz.
It's good that you came.
Come closer to the light, children,
that I may see you...
After your mother's death, I thought
that I would live long enough
so both of you could fend for yourself.
But...
Karin...
In this envelope
is all the money I own.
It's for lngmar.
I want you to keep them
until the boy has grown up.
Yes, father.
And you and your husband...
If he can stay sober...
shall run the farm
until lngmar is old enough...
to buy it back from you
with that money.
Yes, father.
Ingmar, my darling boy...
The people in this parish
have always needed someone
who can lead and support them.
That's what they are used to.
When you are a grown man, it will
be your turn. Do you understand?
Remember, lngmar...
One day the people here
will need you.
Promise me
never to let them down.
If the boy doesn't like it
he can go to hell!
Go to hell both of you!
I make the decisions
'round here now!
-Karin!
-Good day, Karin.
-Good day, lngmar.
-Good day, Storm.
Well, you know how things are...
-Yes, we do.
-Well, things have gotten much worse.
I don't want my brother to suffer.
So I'd like to ask you...
if he can live here with you
until things are better at home.
-Of course, but we are not well off...
-I'm sorry to ask...
Of course lngmar shall live here!
I can't imagine
a better place than here.
It is an honor
to help an lngmarsson.
I'll bring his things over.
Thank you very much!
Farewell, lngmar.
May I have it back?
-Eljas! Give it to me!
-It's useless!
Elias! Elias!
What have you done with lngmars money?
Come down at once.
Do you hear me?
Come down!
Come down at once!
Elias?
What have done with the envelope
containing lngmar's money?
When you shouted...
it was as though your father
came rushing towards me.
Hello, lngmar.
You know that Tim and I are
very happy with each other.
So now...
we've decided
to get married in the autumn.
Therefore we'd like to ask you
if you wish to return to
the farm to live with us?
-Come and dance, lngmar!
-I can't.
Come on now!
One, two, three, one, two, three...
-No, I can't do it.
-Sure you can! You're so boring.
-Mom can dance with me!
-I'm too old for that for such things!
-May I go to the dance?
-You'd be back too late.
-But everyone else goes!
-Very well, if Ingmar goes with you.
-But I haven't planned to go.
-Why must you always be so boring?
Well, then I'll go.
What is it, mother?
-What is it?
-Look yourself.
Ingmar is practicing
for the party.
Don't worry Gertrud.
It will soon be over.
May God have mercy on us.
Oh Lord. We meant no harm.
Karin!
Karin! Karin!
Tim! Tim!
Tim!
-I can't go any more!
-What happened?
My legs don't carry me.
I think I'm paralyzed.
Tim...
is God punishing us?
What is it, lngmar?
I must keep what I promised dad.
What do you mean?
I must work and earn money...
so the farm
can be mine as planned.
I'll try to get the sawmill
in the forest working again.
-Hello Gertrude! How are you?
-Good, thanks.
-How cold it has become.
-Yes...
-Have you heard from lngmar?
-Not a word.
Ingmar isn't one to write letters, but
if you want we can get a word to him.
Yes, thank you.
Amen.
And finally, we will sing
"Jerusalem, thou exalted city".
Excuse me...
May I say a few words?
Well... if it can't wait?
I would like to tell you
and the congregation...
about the storm last summer,
when...
we all stayed home
and feared for out lives.
We longed to come to the mission-
hall and hear word of God...
but we couldn't go out
because of the weather.
Then the spirit came over me
and began to speak.
I thought it was strange...
that a simple man like me should be
given the ability to speak like that.
But then I thought although
you are a schoolmaster...
you are but a farmer yourself...
I see... So you wanted to talk
here tonight, Mats Hök?
-Yes, if you nobody objects...
-No, we've finished for today.
-May I not say a few words?
-No, now we sing the hymn.
Mr. Storm!
I think you should ask for our opinion
before silencing Mats Hök.
Is that what you think, my lad?
Let me tell you that I am the only one
who has something to say here.
I heard Mats Hök
preach that night...
It was magnificent.
Everyone here would
enjoy hearing it.
If I let Mats Hök preach tonight...
you'll want to preach next Sunday,
and then Tim will want to go!
Why shouldn't Mats or anyone else
be entitled to preach as you do?
I have a suggestion...
Donors of money to build the
mission-hall should be asked first.
When we built this mission-hall...
we agreed it would be free for all.
Not like a church, where only
one man may proclaim God's word.
Here is the key to this building.
I hereby part with it.
I have finally understood that
everything I wanted to keep out...
I have instead let in.
May I ask how long you're
planning to stay, sir?
I have yet to decide,
but I expect to remain for some time.
Well, here it is.
I hope you will find it suitable.
Perhaps I should show you around,
if you're new to this parts?
Thank you, but as a young man
I worked nearby.
-In that case...
-By the way...
Old lngmar died in an accident
down by the river years ago.
It was tragic. He was a great man!
It was a misfortune for the district.
-Who has taken over his farm?
-His daughter and her husband.
-Did he not have a son?
-He's also called Ingmar, of course.
He is as resolute as his father.
But now he's obliged to
slave away in the forest.
-I see.
-Do you want to get hold of him?
His fiancé
lives down by the school.
That won't be necessary.
Thanks anyway.
-Would you like some supper?
-I am tired after my travels.
Goodnight.
Dear lngmar...
I think of you. How are you coping
up there in the forest?
Have you got the sawmill working?
I guess you're working all the time.
Your father would be proud
if he could see you.
Things are much the same...
except that Father is upset after
the quarrel in the mission-hall.
There is a newcomer here.
A preacher from the United States.
It must be cold where you are.
I wish I cold warm your hands
and look after you.
I wish we could be together
all the time.
You have no idea how I miss you.
Every day I come to this stone
and pretend you are with me.
It's been such a long time.
It all seems so unreal:
The dance and the storm...
I would be so glad to hear from you
and to know if you think of me.
You have no idea how I miss you.
It's so dull without you.
Why don't you write?
I feel sad and angry.
It's because I miss you.
What does it matter?
You'll never get this letter anyway.
Satan doesn't wear horns
so you can recognize him.
Satan is among us!
We must turn our back on all
who would tempt us to sin.
-What's your name?
-Gunhild.
Come ahead.
I want to talk to you, Gunhild...
May I ask you...
When you dressed up like that
to visit the house of God...
was it for the Lord's sake,
or your own?
-I just wanted to look nice.
-The Devil's deludes the weak.
Gunhild,
that is the root of all evil.
Adornment means temptation
and destruction.
We must deny everything
that leads us away from God.
Fleshly desires are sin.
The wages of sin is death.
But God's gift is everlasting life.
-Oh Lord help us.
-May the Lord have mercy upon me.
Deliver me from evil...
for thine is the kingdom,
the power and the glory...
for ever and ever.
Amen.
Open your heart.
God shall hear your prayer.
Listen when God speaks. Listen...
God has heard your prayer, my child.
Stand up
No, that's enough.
We're leaving.
He's a false prophet.
Christ said: "He that loveth
father or mother more than me"...
"is not worthy of me."
"And ye shall be hated of all men
for my name's sake."
"But he that endureth to the end
shall be saved."
"The kingdom of God is nigh.
The Lord shall return."
"He shall judge both living and dead.
He shall punish the evil."
But those who are saved
shall know the splendor of Heaven.
All of you gathered here today
shall follow me.
For God has sent me to help you.
I shall help you to salvation.
-Can I help you?
-What?
You can hold that
so I can the shaft in.
My wife says you have begun
preaching in our mission-hall.
God sent me.
-All the way from America?
-God moves in mysterious ways.
Let me explain. When I got to
America, I bought a factory.
I got on well with my workers...
but they were envious and
accused me of deceit and theft.
I ended up in prison and
spent a long time there:
I was an innocent man, wrongly
convicted, yet I enjoyed it...
for there I could live
a life of righteousness in solitude.
For the first time I attained
utter closeness to God.
When I gained my freedom again...
I resolved to combat the evil forces
that ruin men on earth.
I joined a lady named Mrs. Gordon
to live a Christian, righteous life.
Soon another joined us and another.
Things went better and better.
Thirty of us now live
in a house in Chicago.
We share everything,
help and watch over each other...
relating in a purely Christian manner.
Tim...
In the short time I've been here I've
heard so many good things about you.
I've heard of your difficulties...
and what a burden it has been
to run the farm on your own.
But if you want to achieve something
great, you need to join with others.
Every day...
Every day, Tim, I hear God's voice.
He says to me:
'' Soon...
''Soon we shall build a new
Jerusalem... together!''
-I thought I might be able to help.
-We haven't asked for any help.
-I gather you are ill.
-I have not walked for six months.
I have come to pray for you.
You might have heard that I can
heal those who have faith in me.
-I have the faith that my father had.
-I'm sure that God can help you.
You have always tried to live in
righteousness. Let me pray for you.
Let God manifest his greatness.
O Lord Jesus. Here is...
Do not spurn what God hath sent.
A great mercy
shall be visited upon this house.
Greta! Come here!
Don't go there, Greta.
Come here!
Greta!
Help me, God!
Help me!.
Help me...
Help me, dear God.
No! Greta!
Greta!
Thank you, God!
Thank you for sending this holy man
of God to help me.
I thank you
from the bottom of my heart.
Some of the children at school have
begun to preach Hellgum's doctrine!
Hellgum has told them to serve God
rather than play.
They are to convert everyone
and struggle against the devil.
If I contradict them they say:
"How long will you remain sinful?"
Worst of all, some of them
have left their parents...
-and joined Hellgum's group at the
lngmarsson farm. -At the farm...?
Hellgum has founded a community there.
They call themselves Hellgumians.
-What about Karin and Tim?
-They are among the most fervent.
Hellgum has torn families apart.
It's brother against sister, friend
against friend, man against wife.
Those belonging to his faith...
cannot live among sinners and devils,
and the hounds of and Antichrists.
-What do you want us to do?
-Well...
People in this parish
have always had a leader.
Now that your father is gone
and... I...
I have lost my influence...
Hellgum has aquired
a hideous power.
Now is the time for you to show
that you are an lngmarsson.
Hellgum has even
talked to Gertrud.
Gertrud would never
let herself be converted.
Well...
I don't know...
lngmar!
Dearest lngmar!
-Welcome, lngmar!
-It's been a long time.
Is there somewhere
we can speak privately?
It's lovely to see you again.
We've waited for you
to come and share our joy.
-What are these people doing here?
-Father would be glad to see...
the new Jerusalem
come down from heaven.
-Father wanted us to tread God's path.
-But not Hellgum's path.
Hellgum saved Greta's life by
healing me so I could walk again.
I remember the doctor said
you would walk again...
-once the shock had passed.
-Wait until you meet Hellgum.
Wait until you meet Hellgum.
You will join our faith, Ingmar.
I hear you are at odds
with the whole parish.
-We avoid those who tempt us to sin.
-What about me?
You shall follow our faith.
Hellgum will convert you.
I see. Unless I convert to your faith
I cannot live in this house?
There's another matter...
what about the sawmill?
-It's the only way I can earn money.
-We love you so much, Ingmar.
-What about the sawmill?
-Talk to Hellgum.
-I'll certainly talk with him.
-It's for your own good, Ingmar.
Maybe you and Hellgum
could be partners?
Tim?
You have said nothing all this time.
I'm asking you directly:
Is Hellgum to have the sawmill?
How you become such a coward
that you cannot answer?
If you oppose God,
Hellgum shall have it.
Thank you.
So that is my incentive to join you!
-He didn't mean it like that.
-I know what he meant:
If I don't convert to your faith,
will I lose my home and the sawmill.
Speak to Hellgum first.
-Where is he?
-With Gertrud.
She could decide tonight
to join us.
Ingmar, is that you?
You're back!
Gertrud...
-It's been a long time.
-Yes it's been a long time.
I never thought I'd see you again.
-How has it been for you up there?
-All right.
I've been working a lot,
but it's been all right.
How are you?
I'm also all right.
The winter has been long.
My sister says you plan
to join the Hellgumians tonight.
Is it true, Gertrud?
-Yes, it's true.
-You mustn't do it, Gertrud!
I have to, God is forcing me.
It is not God who is forcing you.
Have you told Storm already?
-Not yet.
-You mustn't do it, Gertrud.
If you do, Hellgum will only let you
meet those who share his faith.
I realize that.
Are you aware that it means...
-That we can never meet again.
-You could also join.
How can you say that?
How could I join a mad swindler
who is taking everything from me?
-Think it through carefully.
-I've been thinking the whole winter.
-Think again!
-Let me go! You are crazy!
Yes, Hellgum drives me mad!
This has got to stop!
-What do you mean?
You'll never join the Hellgumians!
Ingmar! Wait!
She should never have gone
with you to Amerikal
You refused the doctor to help!
You killed my sister!
She left me and the children
to join your damned sect!
Satans priest!
-You don't know what's good for you!
-Damned preacher!
She is dead!
You refused to let the doctor
help my sister! You killed her!
You have taken the life of my sister!
She's dead!
Damn preacher!
You killed my sister!
Enough!
Get out of here, both of you!
lngmar, what have you done?
Good God!
This cannot be!
Help lngmar first!
-He was trying to kill you.
-He chased my assassins away!
Stop, lngmar!
Let me bind your wound.
God bless you, Ingmar.
You saved Hellgum.
-Go away. Leave me alone.
-Tim and I are sorry for what we said.
I was about to tell Hellgum
to give you the sawmill.
-You can give it to him.
-I'm sorry, lngmar!
I thought you were trying to kill him.
That's what it looked like.
How could you think
your brother was a murderer?
Ingmar, don't cast away
your life like this...
before God and your fellow men!
I'll do anything to give you back
the will to live.
There is one thing you can do.
Tell Hellgum to leave at once
and not show his face here again.
There's something
I must ask you to do.
It's something I promised lngmar
I would do.
Won't you look at me?
I'll leave soon but wanted
to say a few words to you.
Last year, when you moved out
I began to be very fond of you.
My long was so great...
But not even once
did you visit me.
-It was if I didn't exist for you.
-I didn't want to meet you...
until I had earned a little money
so I could propose.
I thought you had forgotten me.
You have no idea how much
I suffered all winter.
And then Hellgum came...
He was kind and comforted me.
He said my heart would be utterly at
peace if I gave it completely to God.
I got so angry
with you yesterday.
I was afraid
I wouldn't be able to resist you.
That the struggle within me
would begin again...
And then last night I heard
you had helped the man you hated.
I could no longer resist you.
I could no longer do anything
that would keep me apart from you.
Gertrud...
Well, dear brothers and sisters...
Hellgum has something very important
to say to us all.
My dear friends.
I must tell you...
Yes, I'm leaving you.
Already today.
God spoke to me last night.
God has been merciful to us.
For a long time
we have enjoyed His gifts.
He has let me live among you
in this paradise.
But now time has come
for new tasks and new challenges.
-I must leave.
-What about us?
Continual sacrifice
is the way of God.
But I know that I am
responsible for you before God.
I will not abandon you
to the devil...
or let you drown
in the river of brimstone.
For there is hope for salvation...
in Jerusalem
Jerusalem!
That is where God is calling me.
His holy city Jerusalem.
And there is hope for you!
Today...
God will call all those...
who are to follow me
to Jerusalem.
Are we to abandon all we own
and move to a foreign land?
Not foreign land!
God is sending us to the same land
to which He once sent Jesus.
Where shall we live?
How shall we support ourselves?
-He's saving us from Armageddon.
-I'll go first and arrange everything.
Mrs. Gordon and our American brothers
and sisters have already moved there.
You'll have to sell
your goods and chattels.
-Strike off the fetters that bind you!
-Hallelujah!
We shall walk
where Jesus walked.
We shall build a paradise! The glory
of the Lord shall manifest on earth!
We shall be redeemed. Amen.
Amen.
Now concentrate your minds.
Say not a word to each other.
God calls those
who are worthy of him.
You must be completely silent...
And listen.
Listen.
What God's voice
tells you to do...
is what you should do.
Lord Jesus,
here are your children.
Choose those you wish to call
to the Holy City.
Choose those who are
to meet You.
Those who to see You
appear in the heavens!
Speak to each
and every one of them.
-Let my cry come unto Thee!
-God, hear my prayer!
-Lord, thank you!
-I hear God's voice!
The Lord is calling me!
-Thank you... Thank you...
-Karin... Karin?
Perhaps God deems me unworthy.
He thinks I love our fields
and pastures too much.
Be quiet, Tim, and concentrate.
Listen!
Can't you hear the angels' harps?
O God, take me under Your wing.
The harps precede God's voice.
Do not leave me in hell!
Don't leave me on my own.
Now! Yes!
I shall also go.
God is calling me!
I have been called!
What am I bid for this cushion?
No bids?
Sold for 20 ore
to the lady over there.
It'll be something
to remember the Ingmarssons by.
Then we have two silver bowls.
Twenty-five ore! Thirty!
I wonder who'll buy the farm.
A rich farmer said he would.
His daughter will get the farm as
a dowry if Ingmar marries her.
We continue with a cabinet.
Seventy-five ore! One crown...
People say the farm can be yours.
It would be the best thing you
could do for us and the parish.
It is what one loves the most that
should first be offered to the Lord.
Then perhaps we can continue.
The forestry company bids 26.000.
Sven Persson...?
-27.000.
-Then I bid 29.000.
-30.000.
-32.000.
What do you say, Sven?
-33.000.
-Let's get this over with, 40.000.
No.
Are you sure?
I quit.
Well! The lngmarsson farm
goes to the forest company.
Their bid is for 40.000 crowns.
You'll never get a better offer.
Do you accept
the forest company's offer?
-I think...
-May I say something?
The forestry company will demolish
the farm and plant trees instead.
A disappearance of the lngmarsson farm
will be a disaster for the parish.
But Sven Persson is a farmer.
He wants to carry on farming here.
So let Sven Persson
buy the farm for 33.000.
It is more than you
expected anyway.
We accept
Sven Persson's bid instead.
Thank you. Everything will
remain as it was, I assure you.
Good luck!
May I ask you something?
Do you intend to live here yourself?
No, I'm marrying off
my daughter Barbro.
It's for her and
her husband-to-be.
Then there will once again be
an lngmar lngmarsson on this farm.
Then I must congratulate you.
We have been antagonists
in this matter.
If God doesn't want you
to follow us,
I thank him that he lets you
take care of the farm.
Go home and
tell Gertrud the truth.
That I betrayed her and
sold myself to get the farm.
Tell her to put me out
of her mind forever.
God...
O God,
take this terror away from me.
help me out of this sorrow!
God, help me.
Help me out of this!
I don't want revenge.
I want no evil in me!
Help me!
Remove this sorrow from me!
-Can I help you with anything?
-I need to talk to the bridegroom.
I see...
Just a moment.
Excuse me. There is a woman outside
wishing to speak to lngmar.
Say that lngmar is dancing with his
bride and cannot talk to others.
Wait a moment!
Ingmar?
There's a woman outside
who wants to talk to you.
I'm sorry to disturb you
on your wedding day.
Ingmar...
Last year, when I decided
to join the Hellgumians...
I had given my heart to Christ...
but I took it back in order
to give it to you.
It was wrong of me.
I betrayed Christ and have in return
been betrayed by my beloved.
No, it's not that way.
It isn't God's plan to punish you.
It's not punishment, it's to show me
I made the wrong decision.
It isn't a punishment...
I'm so happy.
I don't miss anything.
All my sorrow has been
taken from me.
Ingmar,
I shall tell you a secret.
I have met him.
I have seen Jesus.
He has taken my sorrow from me
and I love Him.
Now I cannot love another
in this world.
The real purpose of my visit is...
I have a present for you.
Something that is yours.
My mother bought a cushion at the
auction and I used it as a pillow.
One night when I could not sleep,
I found something hard within it.
I found a package that rustled
when I touched it.
I pulled out the package and
found your name on it.
I realized it must be the money
that Elias hid.
Here is your inheritance, lngmar.
Oh God!
So this is your revenge!
-Why do you call it revenge?
-What else should I call it?
-Why didn't you bring it at once?
-It was for your wedding day.
-Had you come earlier I'd have bought
the farm and married you. -I know.
Now it's too late.
It was too late anyway, lngmar.
It was too late a week ago.
It's too late, now
and forevermore.
Ingmar, you had a choice.
You didn't love me enough.
You can always come back
if you change your mind.
Can't you stay? I beg you!
-Aren't you coming, Hans?
-I can't.
Last night I looked out over
the fields and thought:
"Can the hills of Jerusalem be
more beautiful than these? "
Then, when I saw the river and
the mountains beyond, I thought:
"Our Lord cannot pour fire and
brimstone over all this? "
The way I reckon,
he must have liked it...
when He made it with
His own hands.
Don't forget the big bag!
We'll soon be there.
We'll be ashore before long.
Do you see that white city?
That is Jaffa.
Look, there's our land!
Welcome dear friends...
Welcome Karin!
Hello Hellgum.
You have a beard!
Welcome to the Holy Land!
Welcome, Gertrud!
Mrs. Gordon could not be here
but she awaits us at the colony.
Go to the railway station.
Our train departs in an hour.
You should have your papers ready
and show them here.
Over here, on the right.
Everyone at the colony
calls Mrs. Gordon "Mamma".
It feels natural to do so.
The English word used is: "Mother".
Use the tip of your tongue:
" Mother".
They speak English, so I'll interpret
until you've learned the language.
We've arrived. Here's the colony.
Here are your American and German
sisters and brothers.
This is my husband.
Tim is my name.
This is little Greta.
That's it.
Dad's little girl...
We are so happy to be here.
He has a cousin in Wisconsin.
He's not very big.
Maybe you've met him.
He is a blacksmith.
Let's go in.
Mother is waiting for us.
We can get the luggage later.
Here is Mother.
Then Mother said that you can come
up to her office one by one.
You can then donate your savings.
Here are the dormitories.
The men sleep for themselves
in this hall here...
The women sleep over here.
But can't the families...?
We can live together, can't we?
The women sleep with their sisters,
the men with their brothers.
-But what about the children?
-They sleep with the other children.
They get to like it after a while.
I'll show you where they sleep.
Greta, you're going to sleep
with the other children.
They're very nice children.
Daddy will go with you and show you.
-Where have you been?
-Down by the school.
People say you row there every
evening and sit on a rock.
Let people say what they want.
You must realize that it is no fun
for a wife to hear such talk.
A wife who has bought her husband
can expect nothing better.
I had a fiancé once.
I was very much in love with him.
One day I told him there
was a curse on our family.
Any children I had might
not be healthy.
He became terribly frightened.
From that day on he would
have nothing to do with me.
It was so humiliating.
I decided to live in solitude
for the rest of my life.
My father wanted you me to marry.
He began sending suitors to me.
In order to put a stop to it all...
...I asked for the impossible:
I asked for you and the lngmarsson
farm. I just wanted to be left alone.
Tim and Karin had the farm and you
were going to marry Gertrud.
I realize that this has all
been a game for you.
I didn't understand
what I had done...
until I heard that Gertrud had left
her parents and gone to Jerusalem.
Since then I have had no peace.
I never wanted to wanted
to make anyone else so unhappy.
Now I see that you are tormented.
I feel that everything is my fault.
No, I am to blame for
my own guilt.
If I had done to you
what I did to Gertrud...
would you have forgiven me?
No.
Then perhaps you understand
what it is like for me.
I wanted to help her!
Am I a murderess now?
I'm not to blame!
You are! You are!
Can we not send for a doctor?
We must send for one.
You know we cannot.
It's forbidden!
Only Mother can help. If He hears
her prayers He will show mercy.
Do you still believe God
is protecting us?
How could you say such a thing?
-Why would he send us here to die?
-Hold your peace, Sister Gertrud.
O God, forgive all those
who hate and insult us.
Mat Thy Son descend to earth
and become a part of us.
Dear God...
May Jesus come and redeem us.
Can you keep a secret?
Jesus is coming.
-But not today?
-No, tomorrow.
I thought Jesus had forgotten us but
I realize He allows us to suffer...
because the last days of
the world are at hand.
That is why God has lacked the power
to vanquish all evil and lies.
Jesus will return.
Soon He will descend from heaven.
That's why we were all summoned
here. We are about to meet him!
Gertrud, Gertrud...
I was worried about you, lngmar.
You are never usually away so long.
I worried that you might
have hurt yourself.
Come. Try to rest awhile.
Try to drink a little.
-It smells disgusting.
-Do you want me to die?
You have drunk nothing for days.
You must drink.
It's from the cistern.
-It is filtered. It is all right.
It is safe to drink.
Just take a little sip.
Will nobody help me
to get clean water?
Am I to lie here and die
with nobody to help me?
We are all helping as best we can.
There is no better water in Jerusalem.
Well, it does! Were you not with me
when we looked at the mosques?
Yes, I was with you.
In the Mosque of Omar there is a well
in the grounds.
It is Jerusalem's only clean well.
that has good water.
-Why do you think that?
-It has it's source in Paradise!
The Garden of Paradise is down there.
Forest, trees, flowers and birds.
A river of clear and pure water
runs through it.
It's all in her imagination,
poor girl.
They have asked for you
in the kitchen, Sister Karin.
-Can you attend to her?
-I shall do my best.
Try to get her to drink something.
Brother Gabriel...
Please persuade Sister Karin
that the water in the well...
is the best water in the city.
She won't get me any!
I'll go to Jerusalem and fetch you
some of that water.
Don't do it! It's only because I'm so
thirsty that I talk so much.
The well is holy for Mohammedans.
They'd never let a Christian in.
-I'll dress like a Mohammedan.
-A Mohammedan?
You must be mad!
I could ask the old cobbler next door
if I could borrow his clothes.
-Is he here today?
-Yes, he is.
-I'll do it this afternoon.
-It's dangerous. They'll kill you!
Do not fear, Sister Gertrud.
-How will you carry the water?
-I'll carry a large jar.
There are many people about
at this time.
Nobody will recognize me if I'm
dressed as a water-bearer.
But inside the Damascus Gate
it will be harder.
But I know how to force my way
through the crowds...
I might be recognized
at any time...
It is so kind of you to
get me some water...
I pass by the prison, with many
policemen standing outside.
-But you quickly go past it.
-Yes, but I think they recognize me.
I run with the heavy jar.
They pursue me but
I escape in the crowd.
At last I'll enter
the temple grounds.
I can see the well and I hasten
to join the other water-carriers.
I dip my jar into the
Well of Paradise...
and fill it up with the purest,
clearest spring water.
And then I think: "As soon
Gertrud drinks this water"...
"she will recover."
Then I finally reach home
with the water.
Will you not taste the water from
the Well of Paradise, Sister Gertrud?
God bless you, Brother Gabriel.
You have saved my life.
Do you want more?
Give some to the others,
so they may recover.
The water is only for you.
Don't you want to taste it?
Yes, I'd like to.
Telegram.
Thanks.
Barbro... I have some
sad news for you.
What has happened?
Your father is dead.
Well...
This is news of great import
for both of us.
We have been granted our freedom.
-Now we shall get divorced.
-Why do you say that?
Now father is dead, there's
nothing to stop us.
Never!
I want you to go to Jerusalem
and bring Gertrud home.
You must do it
for Gertrud's sake.
And for my sake, that I may once
again have peace of mind.
Be glad you can make amends
for your wrongs.
I'll do as you say.
I shall do my duty towards Gertrud.
-But I don't want to divorce.
-You must understand something:
I can never be the wife you need.
I cannot give you healthy children.
They'd be blind idiots.
-There's a curse on our family.
-Do you really believe that?
It's hopeless, lngmar.
We must divorce.
That's the way it is.
That's what I want it.
Go to Jerusalem and fetch Gertrud.
Try to forget me.
Good God, what have they done
with our dead?
What have they done
to my little Greta?
My dear... little child...
My dear little Greta...
We knew nothing of this.
Had I known, you would never
have been laid to rest here.
Hello?
Hello!
But Tim...!
They have dug up our dead.
They lie under open sky.
-I'll fetch Sister Karin.
-No, my heart hurts too much.
Promise me...
Promise me that little Greta will be
properly buried in hallowed ground.
I don't want her to think
she has a bad father.
And let me lie beside her.
Tell Karin that I want to wear
my wedding ring in my grave.
Well...
How are things in Sweden?
Fine.
Do folks back home think of us?
Some of us have thought of you
every single day since you left.
And your wife? Is she looking after
the farm while you are away?
Is she a good housewife?
I couldn't ask for a better one.
Have you got any children?
No, we have not had any children.
Barbro and I are to divorce.
What are you saying, lngmar?
None of our family
have ever divorced.
We are already legally separated.
-But what do you have against her?
-Nothing whatsoever.
-Is it she who wants to divorce?
-Yes, it is her wish.
I'm glad that Father is dead
and has been spared this.
It is indeed good he is dead.
He has been spared a great deal.
So you are here
for Gertrud's sake?
In my struggle to keep the farm
in the family...
I abused Gertrud's trust.
I abused her most
precious quality:
Her love of others and
her trust in them.
I heard rumors that she was
loosing her mind down here.
I have come to shoulder
my responsibility.
Don't think you can come
and ruin Gertrud's life again.
Whose life has been ruined
by whom, Karin?
It's been a long time.
-How are you?
-Well. Very well...
Your mother and father say hello.
Thank you.
What is the purpose of your visit?
I want to see how things are.
If you think you can take me back
to Sweden, you are wrong.
I gather you have been ill.
Even very ill.
Don't bring up the past.
You have no right to do that.
I'm doing fine. I've never been
so happy as I'm now.
My love for Jesus is complete.
No wonder Jesus stayed here.
God knows what He would have said
had he been here today?
Perhaps: "Except ye become as children
ye shall not enter into My kingdom. "
Since I came to Jerusalem, I have
almost felt like a child.
I have childish faith in people,
even in our persecutors.
-I feel the same way.
-Do you really think he would say:
"Except ye become as children
ye shall not enter into My kingdom"?
What would your answer be?
I would say:
"Lord, we love everyone as children. "
-What would Christ say?
-Nothing. Just...
"Except ye become as children
ye shall not enter into My kingdom. "
Then I would begin to understand what
He means and I would say:
"Lord, I have also
become a child. "
"For I no longer feel the
yearning I used to."
"For my beloved
is but a playmate. "
"A sister with whom
I pick olives. "
"No, Lord, I am not a child."
I cannot enter into Your kingdom.
"I cannot quench the fire
in my heart."
I love you, Gertrud.
As a man loves a woman.
I can not help it.
Forgive me... forgive me...
Bear down...
as hard as you can!
Here it comes.
It'll soon be over...
-What was it?
-A boy. A cute little boy.
He's not cute at all.
He is blue all over!
His eyes are swollen.
Can't you see?
He looks strange.
I knew it. I knew it...
Nobody must ever know about him.
He's an idiot and blind with it.
I knew it...
Nobody must ever see him.
-Have you seen Brother Gabriel?
-He went to Jaffa to buy grain.
Ingmar, I can't wait anymore.
I have to tell someone!
I have met Christ!
-The Lord has risen again!
-Gertrud...
Tell me exactly where
you saw him.
Gertrud...
I think I've found him.
Have you found Him...?
After you told me what you saw,
I went looking for him.
Ingmar...! So you believed me
in spite of everything...!
Have you ever seen such a face?
-No, I haven't...
-I knew He would return!
You must show me where He is!
This very evening.
I can wait no longer.
How lucky you are, not having had
to wait as long as the rest of us.
You look tired, lngmar.
Your conscience has troubled you
for my sake but it was God's will.
It was God's mercy that guided you to
Jerusalem at just the right time.
We go in here.
Are you sure this is the place?
Yes, this is where I saw him
with his disciples.
One expects pomp and splendor...
but simplicity and poverty is
the way Jesus teaches.
Do you see?
Do you see His disciples?
Yes...!
It's Him!
You can see he is no normal man.
He is going to speak!
I can't wait to hear his voice.
Why doesn't he tell them
to stop that?
Has He nothing else
to teach them?
Was he the man you saw yesterday?
Yes.
Did my happiness cause you such
pain that you had to show me this?
-I shall never forgive you.
-I understand...
But I had to do what was right.
Why did you have to take
my faith from me?
Why could you not let me keep it?
There are visitors waiting outside.
You must attend the little one.
I'll say you have a cold and they
had better not risk catching it.
They'll hear the child crying
unless you keep it quiet!
It's all right. They've gone now.
You think you're so clever?
I know there were no visitors.
-You wanted to make me hold him.
-I'll take him out again if you want.
No. He's fallen asleep. He can
stay here until he wakes up.
-What do you with him him at night?
-He sleeps in the barn.
Do you let him sleep there
like a kitten?
I didn't think you cared. He
can be in here if you want.
I think we'd better change him.
You're not holding him right.
No wonder he's crying.
I'm as good at caring for children
as you are.
-His face is turning blue!
-People say I'm good with children
But if you're quite sure
you know best...
Here you are.
See...?
I doubt that other mothers
with healthy children
feel as much love for their infants
as I feel for you, you poor mite.
Eva...
lngmar must never know about him.
Do you understand?
Not until he has married Gertrud.
Mother advises you to
return home immediately...
Tell Mrs. Gordon...
that I shall leave the colony.
That I'll leave Jerusalem.
And tell her that I wish to take
Gertrud with me.
I can't tell her that. Sister Gertrud
will never leave with you.
I know what you think, Karin.
But please translate word for word.
My brother says he'll go.
Gertrud is very ill.
She has not been well for some time.
People are talking about her. She is
destroying the colony's reputation.
Tell Mrs. Gordon...
that if she lets Gertrud
go with me...
she'll have one problem less...
and the colonies' reputation
will remain intact.
And tell her
that I need Gabriel as well.
I'm leaving, Sister Gertrud.
Ingmar needs medical care in
Sweden. I'll take him home.
-He always gets what he needs!
-He also wants you to come along.
Never!
Consider the matter,
Sister Gertrud.
-Mother wouldn't allow it...
-Ingmar has spoken to her.
If he thinks he can take over
my life yet again, he's wrong!
You must forgive him, Gertrud.
Consider how much he loved you.
Had you seen him
at the auction...
you would have seen how much he
suffered and how he loved you.
You must forgive him, Gertrud.
Our Christian faith is based
on forgiving each other.
Otherwise you will never
be able to love another.
Wait, Brother Gabriel!
I forgot to give you the letters
for the folks back home!
I need to talk to lngmar.
Ingmar, there's something
I must tell you.
I received a letter from home.
There's something you should know.
A boy has been born on
the Ingmarsson farm.
I thought you should know
before you set off for home.
-Was it Barbro who wrote to you?
-No, it wasn't Barbro.
Farewell, lngmar.
Farewell, Karin.
-Farewell, Sister Gertrud.
-Farewell, Sister Karin.
-Farewell, Brother Gabriel.
Gertrud! Gabriel!
Welcome!
My dear girl! Welcome!
My dear child! Welcome home!
My dear child...!
-Gabriel!
-Hello Mr Storm.
-Storm...
-lngmar...
Come in!
Pray forgive the intrusion.
You must be Gertrud.
And you are Barbro, I presume.
I won't stay long, but...
-Is lngmar here?
-No.
-Do you know where he is?
-Yes...
-He went up to the lngmarsson farm.
-Why should he go there?
He couldn't bear to wait
any longer...
even though you are legally separated
and he shouldn't return.
You seem to think nobody knows
you have born a child.
But everyone knows.
Everyone knows... even lngmar.
May I ask you...
if you love lngmar?
No. I no longer love lngmar.
Go now...
he is waiting for you.
Where's the boy?
lngmar is here.
He took him to church.
Good day, Barbro.
We were waiting for you.
What are you doing here
with the boy?
How dare you? You know you are
banned from the Ingmarsson farm.
It's my duty to ensure
he is properly baptized.
I heard you had hidden him
as though he did not exist.
I had no choice.
He is entitled to be baptized
and given a name.
Don't give yourself problems
for my sake.
I need to know what the boy
is to be called.
Perhaps Barbro has
a name in mind?
His name is lngmar, like that of
all the first-born Ingmarsson sons.
Now you think you are kind to me, but
I must repeat what I have said:
The boy cannot
be called lngmar...
for he is both blind
and an idiot.
-Let's hear what the doctor says.
-You can see he's ugly and sick.
Children in our family come
no prettier than this.
But you can see he is blind.
What on earth makes you say that?
I'll give you some eyewash. The
swelling will be gone in a week.
His eyes will be as clear as
those of other children.
In that case, let us continue
with the baptism.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
Lift up your hearts to God.
O Lord Jesus,
baptism has been ordinated by Thee.
As he said to His disciples:
"To Me is given all power in heaven."
O Lord, Thou art my rock,
my redeemer and my sole comfort.
On my narrow path of pain
I have lost my dear ones.
But I fear nothing, for I know
that Thy love is eternal.
I thank Thee for leading me
to the Holy Land.
Here, in Thy light,
I find salvation.
Here in Thy light I find Thou art
utterly close to me.
Here in Thy Jerusalem.
Amen.
Subtitles transcribed from VHS
& retimed by: THAFTN