You think you caught
me sleeping, don't you?
No.
No one in the village
sleeps in the day.
Except once in
a while in church on Sundays.
This is a normal village,
you see?
Just like any
village anywhere,
only it is
in Sicily.
My people live simply.
Work hard.
They plant seeds
when they should,
and with God's help,
those seeds grow as
they should.
And it follows
that in due time,
we harvest our crops
and our babies.
Crops and babies.
A normal village.
That is, this was
a normal village,
but not since
the trouble came.
Jessica.
The new midwife.
A bit of fluff,
a lock of hair,
a fleeting smile,
a wisp of a girl.
A wisp of an American girl,
one of nature's more
formidable accidents.
What has she done
to my people?
Well...
(HORN BEEPING)
She has reshaped
the course of business.
(HORN BEEPING)
Be still, darling.
FATHER ANTONIO: She has
hopelessly tangled
communications.
My sister's best teapot.
WOMAN: Beppi?
Beppi, have you
seen my teapot?
Uh...
FATHER ANTONIO: And because
of her, property owners are
denied their lawful rights.
(HORN BEEPING)
She has caused
the downward curve
in our farm programs.
(HORN BEEPING)
Of all the husbands,
there is only one you
could point to with pride,
His Honor, the mayor
of the village.
But then, as has been said,
to fast when you're
not hungry, what is it?
Meanwhile, every other husband
is dreaming of
a banquet.
Oh, Lord, we are in trouble.
Hello, Father!
I'll talk to you later.
Hello, Jessica!
Where are you going?
Signor Risino.
My fist consignment on my own.
Oh, your first test.
Every woman in the village
will be watching
to see how you do, my child.
Does that worry you?
I'm a good nurse, Father.
Yes, but it is not as a nurse
that my people will judge you.
Ah, yes, I know.
Jessica Brown Visconti.
Girl midwife.
A most unusual midwife.
Because I'm an American?
Oh, no,
not at all.
I'm not a Sicilian
and they accepted me
as their own.
But there are
other things about you,
unusual in a midwife.
Jessica, do you mind?
Why did you
come here?
Oh, I don't know, Father.
Oh, it's all right.
You don't
have to tell me.
Oh, no, no, I...
I really mean
I don't know.
You see, all my life,
I've been
making plans.
As a student nurse,
I planned to be head nurse.
Then one day in the corridor,
on the second floor of
the Passavant Hospital
in Chicago, Illinois,
I met a young medical student,
Carlo Visconti.
So I had to make new plans.
We were married
in his mother's home
in Palermo,
and everything went
just as we planned,
the wedding, the reception,
setting off together
on our honeymoon.
The only thing we didn't plan
was the tree that had fallen
across the road,
and Carlo
was driving much too fast.
He died
and I came out of it
without a scratch.
After that, I didn't
make any more plans.
So, when your letter came to
the hospital...
Well, here I am.
Ah, that's Priscilla.
They told me about her.
"Priscilla, to Father Antonio,"
"in gratitude for his help,"
"from the boys
of the third company,."
"Fifth Army, USA."
Yes.
Your American boys are,
are so generous,
so enthusiastic.
And our girls were so pretty.
Oh, well.
That was then.
Have you ever thought of
marrying again?
Of course I have, Father,
but I've been too busy.
Uh-huh.
Let's see,
let's see.
What single men have we?
For one,
there's Beppi Toriello,
the messaggero municipale,
who owns the wine shop
with his sister.
You mean the teapot?
- You know him?
- Mm-hmm.
You're right, you're right.
No, no, no,
he won't do at all.
Then, now, there is
Edmondo Raumo.
Who?
The marchese.
But no, no, no,
he's not right,
he's not right.
He's not like his father.
- He's all wrong.
- Really?
Why, Father?
(CART APPROACHING)
Then there is, uh...
Gianni!
Hello, Father.
How are you?
I'm well, Gianni.
This is Gianni Crupi.
Signora Visconti.
- Did you say Signora, Father?
- I did.
Signora Visconti is our new
midwife, from America.
Midwife, you?
To take care of other
people's babies?
What a waste, Signora.
I hope your trip
was a success, Gianni.
You've been gone, what?
Two weeks?
Anyway, a long time.
Too long, Father.
Yes, Nicolina
must think so, too.
She must be waiting for you,
Nicolina.
Uh-huh.
- FATHER ANTONIO: Gianni!
- Huh?
Oh.
And Signor Risino must be
wondering where I am.
It's going to be a lucky baby.
The first face it sees in
the world will be yours.
Well, it might not be
if I don't hurry.
If it's a boy, he'll wait.
FATHER ANTONIO: Jessica.
And one more thing.
Gianni Crupi
is very fortunate.
He's going to inherit
all the Lombardo farmland
one day.
Old Maria Lombardo
thinks of him
as her grandson.
And as a matter of fact,
he's going to marry
her granddaughter Nicolina,
- in a few weeks.
- Nicolina.
Ah, yes, the gentle,
pretty little girl.
Yes, with the strong,
big grandmother.
Don't worry, Father,
I'm not that lonely.
I won't cause trouble.
My child, you are trouble.
- Mama, Mama!
- Yes, dear.
Father, pray for me.
I will.
Ever since you came I've been
praying, for everybody.
Gianni!
Nicolina!
Hi, Gianni.
Rosario.
Oh, Gianni,
where have you been?
Having fun.
Gianni.
Oh, I have missed you so.
(CHUCKLING)
What took you so long?
My dear child, I was bringing
to terms the sharpest
olive dealer in Messina.
Did you get him?
When I finished with him,
even your stiff-necked
grandmother would be pleased.
Gianni!
NICOLINA: Gianni, don't.
GIANNI: Why not, little one?
NICOLINA: Someone will hear.
GIANNI: Then don't struggle.
(CLEARING THROAT)
Gianni, I meant what took you
so long on the curve
by the wheat field?
I saw you talking with
Father Antonio and Jessica.
- Who?
- Signora Visconti,
the American girl.
Isn't she pretty?
I didn't notice.
- You didn't?
- Why should I?
A married woman?
What is she to me?
She's not married,
she's a widow.
A widow?
Really?
Then her name is Jessica.
Gianni, what are you thinking?
I was just wondering
how she must feel.
Who?
Jessica, the midwife.
To have known a man's love,
to have his arms around her,
his mouth on hers,
then not have it anymore.
She never did have it.
Her husband was killed on
their wedding day.
GIANNI: Oh...
A virgin, huh?
(CHUCKLING)
Signora Lombardo, we came
about the midwife.
You told us that we
should go and watch.
I mean, help the midwife.
You know, Signora Risino
is in labor.
Oh, Signor Risino, not yet.
There's nothing to
worry about, though.
I hope you're not gonna bother
your wife now.
- No.
- Thank you.
This is not the time
for a husband.
Later, after the baby comes,
yes, but right now,
it's your wife's
time and mine.
You understand?
Well, then you
go back to work.
I am hungry.
Now you know better than that.
You know you'll just
be in the way.
Now go back to work.
Why not?
Oh, it's just a scratch.
Go back.
I want to see my wife.
All right.
Go ahead.
Holy mother.
What are you doing here?
I came to see you.
I don't know.
What for?
Well, the baby, I mean.
What's the matter?
Do you think I don't know
how to have a baby?
Who do you think had
the other eight?
You?
Signora Visconti?
Tell him to leave.
ANTONIO: Does it hurt?
"Does it hurt?"
Throw him out!
Come.
To leave his work
in the first place.
Why?
He's never done it before.
Why this time?
Signora, can you come down?
I want to
tell you something.
JESSICA: Now go!
Shoo!
And don't come back.
I'll send one of the children
to let you know.
Now, go!
Go, shoo!
Shoo!
Well, we can't blame her.
She put him out.
Yes, but did she have to?
We are not here to
judge her looks,
but how good
a midwife she is.
But Signora Lombardo,
what if she's good?
She won't be.
Why should she?
She doesn't have to.
Would you work the bakery with
your husband if you were as
pretty as the midwife?
Of course
you would not.
She washed their faces.
So neat.
No dust.
Hmm.
Smells good.
(BABY CRYING)
Already?
She usually takes days.
We came to help.
She had no trouble?
None.
She always did before with
the old midwife.
(GIGGLING)
WOMAN: Bella always
had trouble before
with the old midwife.
(BABY CRYING)
Do you love babies, Signora?
I will love my
great-grandchild.
I will love the baby of my
granddaughter Nicolina
and Gianni Crupi.
And I love them all.
They're so wise.
They come into the world
knowing at once
where food is
and how to get it.
Thank you for wanting to help.
Well, Signora?
I was wrong.
Do you think she's good.
- Worse.
- Worse?
She's good, she's honest
and she loves her work.
She's impossible.
How did it go?
- Fine.
- Did anything go wrong?
Not a thing, Mamma Parigi,
everything went beautifully.
Ah, that's what I heard.
Oh, well.
We have other things wrong
in the village this morning.
Oh?
Let me take that.
Oh!
Hey, heavy, isn't it?
You must be so tired.
You were smart to grab me away
from all the other ladies
who wanted my
services as housekeeper.
You certainly
gave Maria Lombardo
and those other gossips
a shock.
I heard all about this.
But how could you hear?
When you're as deaf
as I am,
you make
a special effort.
I knew there was something.
Old Crupi's got
blood poisoning.
Who?
Old Crupi.
The gardener
up at the chateau.
He's the uncle
of that boy Gianni
who's going to marry
Maria Lombardo's
granddaughter.
You met Gianni, didn't you?
That boy, Gianni...
If I were only 55 again.
What about the uncle?
MAMMA: He cut his hand.
Gianni stopped by to ask you
to go and have a look at it,
but don't you do it.
Can you reach the cups?
Blood poisoning or not,
Crupi's an old grouch.
The coffee, Mamma Parigi.
Hates doctors.
Probably hates midwives
even worse.
Won't pay his bills,
won't even die.
Ooh, he's so mean.
Ah, there.
All the same, I'd better go up
to the castle to see him.
(SCOFFS) He'll throw you out
for your pains.
- Signor Crupi?
- That's right.
Hello, I'm Jessica Visconti.
Is that so?
The new midwife.
There must be
some mistake, Signora.
I am not having a baby.
A pity, sir.
However, I came about
something else.
Your nephew, Gianni.
My nephew Gianni is an idiot.
That may be,
but he left word asking me
to see to your hand.
It's already been
seen to by me.
Oh, please.
Won't you let me?
No.
I won't let you
and that's that.
Are you afraid of a bill?
Are you really
that stingy?
Yes, I am, yes!
JESSICA: Are you afraid
I'll hurt you?
That's right, I'm afraid of
that, too, yes.
Now, please
leave me alone, will you?
Go, hmm?
All right, I'm sorry to have
bothered you.
Uh, Signor Crupi?
Aren't you supposed to be
the best gardener around here?
I am the best
gardener anywhere.
Really?
CRUPI: Why?
Oh, I don't know.
Putting all those
tulips and stock
and wallflower
in the same bed,
mixing all those colors.
CRUPI: What's wrong with it?
It clashes.
Clashes?
You talk to me about clashes?
Come back here, come back here
and look at that.
- Look at that, Signora.
- Wow, really?
You know what they say about
my borders, Signora?
The richest borders
in the whole of Sicily,
- that's what they say.
- Ah, really?
And then those rich borders
are every color
of the rainbow.
I've had tulips as red as
a drunkard's nose,
with iris as yellow
as the sun right beside them.
I have red geraniums,
white geraniums
and blue luberias.
Blue, mind you!
All on the same border.
Uh, that...
That can't be a garden
you're talking about.
It sounds more like a jungle.
Jungle?
You're too ignorant to know
that it's the most
beautiful garden.
Beautiful to
the eye, to the heart.
There is the bee to think of
too, you know?
He uses flowers for food
and he likes
variety in his diet,
just like the rest of us.
Just as we do,
to begin with, buttercups,
for main dish, chrysanthemums,
for dessert, zinnias.
I plant my gardens more
for bees than for people!
They're a lot
less ungrateful.
And God knows they are more
intelligent, hmm?
It's only infected,
nothing serious.
But I'd like you not
to use it for a few days.
You tricked me, hmm?
Yes.
Signor, I'm not a doctor,
but if you don't mind,
you don't look
like a well man.
I am not.
- Well, then would you...
- No, no, I would not.
I suppose you expect
to be paid
for this?
Certainly.
How much?
To be allowed to come back
to see your garden.
(GRUMBLING)
That's too much.
Then consider
the account paid in full.
However, if you
happen to be passing by,
you can
always come in, hmm?
I am here every day.
Thank you.
I'd love to.
- Mm-hmm.
- (VESPA STARTING)
Goodbye, Signor!
(CHUCKLING)
Hey, Rosario,
how does it look?
You think we have
enough lights?
That's right,
if the bride gets
a look at the groom,
she could change her mind.
Do you think this hem
looks crooked?
Oh, why bother?
If Gianni is like Musudino,
the dress will be in shreds
by wedding night, anyway.
Really?
Why?
Because men are so nervous.
- About what?
- (WOMEN LAUGHING)
(HORN HONKING)
MAN: Whoa, here she is!
Here's Jesse!
- Hey, Jesse, I need you!
- Over here, Jessica!
Hey, Jessica, we've got two
weeks to celebrate
before the wedding!
Let's make every day count.
Nicolina, are you home?
In the bedroom upstairs,
Jessica.
Oh, you did come!
Of course.
We are all in here.
I can't stay,
but I had to give you this.
- Oh, thank you.
- Good morning.
How wonderful you look,
Nicolina.
Yours?
Yes.
Yes, it's mine.
Yes, it's beautiful.
The way you
are beautiful.
(GASPS)
Jessica!
I want you to have it.
My husband gave it to me
to carry to my wedding.
And I will be happy to
carry it to mine.
Thank you, Jessica.
You must hold your husband's
memory lightly
to give away
his gift so easily.
Why?
Does it dishonor the dead to
believe in the living?
Of course not.
But we have customs here
about accepting gifts
from strangers.
We cannot accept yours.
But Jessica is my friend.
Yes, I am your friend,
but I'm also a stranger.
However, your grandmother
knows that I didn't
mean to intrude,
just as I know she didn't
mean to offend.
Yeah.
Take her gift.
Goodbye, Nicolina.
Bye, Jessica.
Thank you.
Why did you give in like that?
I changed my mind.
Are you beginning to like her?
No, I'm beginning to
hate her.
Because she
puts you in the wrong?
I... We haven't all day.
Bring the other pins.
There she is again.
Don't let her get
away this time!
Pour some wine for her.
You have to toast
the bridegroom, Signora!
A toast to the groom.
JESSICA: A toast, to you.
And a kiss to the groom.
Oh, no, no.
Go ahead, what are you afraid
of, he's not gonna bite?
Signora Lombardo,
I think you should see this.
MAN: Woo! Save some
for wedding.
Show him.
Just think of him
as one of your babies,
a boy baby.
Hey, she was right to be
afraid, look at you, Gianni.
FATHER ANTONIO: Aren't you
a bit early, my children?
Your wedding is not till...
Jessica!
I was just congratulating
the bridegroom, Father.
His friends insisted.
That's right, Father.
When a man gives up
his freedom,
he's got to get
something for it.
Will you have some
wine with us, sir?
No, no, no, I have to make
final arrangements for
the wedding
with Signora Lombardo
and then I have...
I have an appointment
up at the castle,
so I'm sorry, eh?
Another time.
Meanwhile, have fun.
But not too much fun.
We will, Father!
- Goodbye, Father.
- Bye.
Hey, Jessica, don't forget,
I'm picking you up
for the wedding.
I'll wait, Rosario.
MAN: Goodbye, Jessica!
- Bye, Jessica, byebye!
- Goodbye!
Don't forget, I'll pick you up
for the wedding!
- (BELL RINGING)
- (DOGS BARKING)
Good morning, Annamaria.
Good morning, Father.
Is the marchese in?
No, he's off in the woods
with his dogs.
All right, then, Annamaria,
I'll wander out.
Perhaps I'll run into him.
Father, don't ask him any of
your favors today
if you can help it.
He's in one of his
mean streaks.
- Who said so?
- Oh... Ooh.
Mother of God,
how did you get here?
Through the back way, why?
Oh, excuse me, sir,
I only meant that...
All right, Annamaria, get out.
I mean, get in.
Hello, Father.
Want to take a walk?
I have something
to tell Crupi.
All right.
Why the honor for your visit?
Need another
donation for the church?
Yes, I do.
How much this time?
Or am I being too crass?
Not at all.
As a matter of fact,
I brought a little list.
Quite the little list.
If I recall,
I said no to everything
on your last
little list.
Yes.
I remember.
Item one.
Old Bugianni
died last month.
His wife cries because she
cannot afford a headstone.
What good is a headstone
to a dead man?
No, no headstone.
Next.
You must go to the wedding of
Nicolina Lombardo
and Gianni Crupi.
You know I never go to church
anyway, so the answer is no.
I will not go to the wedding.
What is next on your list?
The mortgage for
old Vantorte's farm.
Yes.
A wooden leg for Old Spani.
Oh.
FATHER ANTONIO: Maria Lombardo
is the matriarch
of Forza d'Agro.
- You owe it to her.
- No.
What decent thing
won't he do now, Father?
He won't go to the wedding of
your nephew
and Nicolina Lombardo.
(SCOFFS)
Of course not.
He's afraid it might make
somebody happy.
It's sad to think that you
look so much like his father.
I'm not my father.
(LAUGHING) Oh!
And yet you were
like him once.
Was I?
I forget.
Well, I must be off.
See what you can do with him.
Me?
Why me?
Because you're an obstinate
old man and he's getting
more like you every day.
You are right.
One like me is enough, huh?
Oh...
(DOGS BARKING)
(GROANING)
They don't pick
themselves up for me
the way they used to.
My boy.
In all the years
I have tried
to be your friend,
I have never
given you advice.
But now, open your windows
to the light.
Unlock the doors.
Step out.
You mean people are splendid,
and I shouldn't
sit in the dark
just because a group
of cowardly dogs
who call themselves fascist
dragged my wife
into the night
and shot her like an animal.
That was a terrible thing.
Forget it.
You are quite right,
I must remember that.
Is there anything else
I can do for you?
Yes.
You can go to that
damn fool wedding.
All right.
On one condition.
That you go, too.
Me?
Or I won't.
Oh...
Well, well, going to
a wedding, what.
(HORN BEEPING)
(ALL CLAMORING)
And another thing.
The way she rides that Vespa,
it's vulgar.
She smiles all the time.
She has that soft,
sweet voice.
And the way she walks.
Her body.
Oh, I beg your pardon, Father.
Her shape.
It's disgraceful.
Her legs alone are a sin.
The sin is yours, my friend.
You're jealous.
You're all jealous.
Jealous, me?
Where did you get
such an idea?
All right, now.
Enough.
ALL: Excuse us, Father.
Now, my daughter,
it's time we had a talk.
You are all upset
because of Jessica.
She's making
you unhappy, very unhappy.
You want to be rid of her.
I don't blame you.
Obviously, she's
a terrible midwife.
Oh, no, she was wonderful.
Well, she was.
Ah, yes, but perhaps...
Perhaps that was an accident.
There have been
other babies since.
She must have been terrible
with them.
No, no, she was not.
She was good.
Oh, yeah?
Yes, then you want to
be rid of her because...
Because she makes eyes
at all the men, eh?
She uses her... Her smile.
Her soft,
sweet, voice.
Her... Her shape
in a sinful manner.
No, she does not do
any of that.
- No?
- No.
Ah, then it is the men.
It is the men
who make eyes at her.
- Yes.
And of course, they...
They withhold their
attentions from you.
Oh, no, they don't.
I don't know about the rest of
you, but for me,
it's more
attentions than ever.
But then, what's wrong?
I'm so tired.
And not only that,
but every time.
Musudino pays attention to me,
he's thinking of her.
How can you tell?
They close
their eyes, Virginia.
Oh, my goodness.
Well, if the situation
is this painful,
then you must
tell Jessica to leave,
but you must tell her why.
And you must tell
your husbands, too, why.
Then we can do nothing.
(LAUGHING)
Excuse me.
I was thinking
of something funny.
A story Tuffi told me.
It's a story called Lysistrata
about a group of women
who lived a long time ago.
Their husbands kept
going off to wars
and they didn't want them to.
So they decided to
deny themselves
to their husbands
and pretty soon,
their husbands stayed home.
You mean the women
denied themselves?
This couldn't happen here.
In Sicily?
Never.
But this happened in Greece.
They had a strike.
A kind of...
A sit up strike.
But it's a wonderful idea.
Don't you see?
Deny yourselves, no babies.
No babies, no midwife.
It solves
the problem.
It's perfect.
We must all stand together.
- We better put it to a vote.
- Yes, a vote!
- Let's go, vote!
- A vote?
You must tell them.
Bring them back
to their senses.
But I am on their side.
You, Maria?
Have you so little trust
in Gianni Crupi?
Oh, this girl, this Jessica.
She is a fire.
She is burning the heart of
every man in the village.
It's not her fault.
Why must she be punished?
She is not being punished.
You do not kick the fire
that burns your house.
You just put it out.
It's against nature.
Nature will survive.
It's a sin.
A denial of life.
Not life.
Self.
It's self-denial, which
makes it a virtue, Father.
Maria, these
are just words
and you know it.
You also know,
as do all of you,
that a wife has
no moral right
to deny her husband.
Therefore, there is
nothing more to be said.
But you'll say it.
I am older than you
and I regret that
I've led you astray, but...
I can hardly wait
until Musudino starts
whining around.
If I say yes,
it means no more babies.
That's right, no more babies.
And no more...
No more.
But it's Saturday.
Lucia!
All right,
all right, I vote yes.
And Nicolina, too?
Will she be with us?
Yes.
I vote yes.
And her answer will be yes.
Strike!
All the women
called a strike today.
A strike?
That's interesting.
Against what?
Against sex.
Hmm?
Never mind.
You mean Gianni is not to
make love to me at all?
Only for a time,
only for a time.
After all, you'll be together,
you'll have fun
and laughter together.
There's a great deal
more in marriage
than just physical love.
That is something
that you learn later
to enjoy more fully.
You've got a great many
years ahead of you, Nicolina.
And if Gianni loves you,
he'll wait until you're ready.
But I'm ready now.
I ask this of
you now, Nicolina.
It will be even more difficult
for Gianni.
But it's good for a young man
to learn self-control.
He'll be all
the better for it.
Now, will you promise
me this, Nicolina?
NICOLINA: I will attempt it,
Grandmother.
Well, the attempt
of a Lombardo is often
better than
the accomplishment of others.
I know as long as you're
under my roof,
you'll keep your promise.
You may find me wiser
than you think.
Don't forget, while Gianni
is dreaming of
possessing his wife,
he has little time
to dream of anyone else.
Many wives have
discovered that.
But there is no one else to
dream about.
I wouldn't be
so sure about that.
That's another discovery many
wives have made.
- Grandmother?
- Yes?
Are you thinking
about Jessica?
I know she's beautiful,
but Gianni wouldn't.
- He loves me.
- Oh, love.
Love is for Sundays.
Never forget,
no matter how much
in love a man may be,
he still scratches an itch.
You've got a lot
to learn, Nicolina,
and the rest of
your life to learn it,
but for now, for now,
you promise me this, huh?
Yeah?
Yes.
I guess.
That's good.
That's very good.
MUSUDINO: Open the door,
Lucia!
I'm going to eternity,
you understand?
What do I care
where you go to sleep?
Take your silk off
and go and sleep in the oven.
Why did I wait 'til
after nine children?
Why didn't I think
of this before?
(LAUGHING)
This is not the first time
it happened, Filippo.
You won't believe this,
but it happened
a long time ago,
in Greece.
A story called Lysistrata.
FILIPPO: Come to bed.
As it seems, there were
these women,
and their husbands
kept going off to war,
so they decided to have
a strike, and pretty soon...
- (SMACKING)
- (SHOUTING) Oh! Filippo!
- (SPEAKING SOFTLY) Filippo...
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(SPEAKING IN LATIN)
My children...
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(WHISPERING)
No, that's
the marchese's chair.
What?
GIANNI: You can't sit there,
it's the marchese's chair.
Come.
There has been a promise of
marriage between Gianni Crupi
and Nicolina Lombardo,
both of
this parish,
to take place
this coming Saturday.
This is the second
publication of the banns.
My sermon today is
inspired from the epistle of.
St. Paul to the Ephesians,
chapter five.
"Let women be subject
to their husbands,
as to the Lord:."
"Because the husband
is the head of the wife,"
"so also let the wives
be subject to their husbands
in all things."
Father Antonio was great.
But I tried, see?
You must try harder,
and just remember tonight,
when he climbs into bed,
I'm behind you
all the way.
He did nothing
but talk of you.
And this is the first time
in 30 years my uncle
said anything good
about anybody.
He is a mean old man.
Oh, no, he's a wise old man.
Good morning.
Ah, how are my children?
Come on, everybody.
March.
Antonio.
You look well,
Signora Lombardo.
Oh...
What's worrying you?
Nothing, nothing, nothing.
And you, my dear, you look
like a girl of 18.
Really?
Nicolina?
Your wedding comes
closer and closer,
I'm so happy for you.
Oh, thank you, Jessica.
Nicolina!
Gianni, come.
Goodbye, Jessica.
Come.
Goodbye.
Hey ho!
(VESPA STARTING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Drink.
I don't want to get drunk.
I don't want
to get drunk, I...
Oh, it's a proud day, Father.
I only wish my Roberto
had lived to see it.
Your Roberto would have
outdrunk them all.
Yes, outdrunk,
outshouted and outloved.
Oh.
Come on, let's dance.
Come on.
It's all right.
They're not married.
It's Edmondo!
- Good evening.
- Why, you came.
- Hey, Father.
- What a pleasant
surprise, my son.
Not at all.
How could I miss the marriage
of my goddaughter,
to the nephew of my
old friend Crupi?
By the way, where is
my old friend Crupi?
He had a small errand to do,
but he'll be along.
He'd better.
Signora, will you have
a glass of wine with me?
Of course.
Just look at my wife.
You're jealous, Luigi?
Jealous?
Not at all.
Had the American
girl been here,
Nunzia would have been
on the sidelines.
When I left, Jessica was
dressing to come.
Waiting for that.
He was supposed
to pick her up.
(KNOCKING)
Oh, Signor Crupi.
But I thought...
Where's Rosario?
Drunk, if he has any sense.
Aren't you ready yet?
Hmm.
Is that for me?
Of course it's for you.
Oh.
Well, good.
Then you can have this.
- Ah.
- Ah... (CHUCKLING)
Oh...
- Okay?
- Okay.
(COUGHING)
You'll catch cold.
Come on.
- Oh, oh, oh, oh...
Wait a minute.
- Hm?
For you.
(CHUCKLING) Oh.
And so I won't catch a cold.
This is how we do it.
We go.
My children,
I have no words of wisdom for
you, no warning.
Not even a wedding gift.
Only a wish.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
* It is better to love
* It is better
if you would
* It is better than
be loved
* Than be loved if you could
* To be ever in love
* It is better
if you do
* It is better to give love
* Than have love
given to you
* For the gift of love
comes with giving
* And you'll have
a life full of living
* It is better to love
* It is better
if you could
* It is better than
be loved
* Than be loved if
you just would
* It is better to love
* It is better
if you would
* It is better than be loved
* Than be loved
if you would
* To be ever in love
* It is better
if you could
* It is better to give love
* Than have love
given to you
* For the gift of love
comes with giving
* And you'll have
a life full of living
* It is better to love
* It is better
if you could
* It is better than be loved
* Than be loved
* If you
just would *
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Oh, look at my
old friend Crupi!
Never mind. Forget her.
Come on.
I told Rosario
not to bring her.
I know, Rosario told me.
How did Old Crupi know?
In the village,
everybody knows everything.
Isn't it so?
I've never seen her before.
Does she belong here?
That, my boy,
is quite a question.
(GRUNTING)
My Roberto always said it
wasn't a good wedding unless
there was a fight.
But I don't like it.
What do you expect
of a village
that sleeps with
a volcano for a pillow?
(CRASHING)
(GRUNTING)
Guess what?
What?
More wine, Jessica?
Should I?
It's up to you.
Then I shouldn't.
How did you know my name?
Father Antonio told me all
about you.
I'll take the wine.
Like what did he tell you?
That every man
in this village wants you.
Oh, that.
But he didn't tell me
which man you want.
I don't want any of them.
Oh! (CHUCKLING)
Do you mean to tell me
that not one of those 10
muscular young fellows
in there has caught your eye?
Being young
isn't all that good.
It's much better
when you're older.
- Yes.
- I mean, you've got all that
gray around
and I don't know,
your mind is better when
it's older, or it ought to be.
And your feelings are finer.
So I am the one you want.
I thought so.
But why else did you bring me
out to the garden?
Whenever you're
ready, my dear.
Are you tired, dear?
A little, but if
you'd rather stay...
Oh, no, I was just marking
time, waiting for you.
Thank you, Pascale.
Antonio.
Oh, yes, of course.
(LAUGHING)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Mm?
Mm-hmm.
Ooh, I love wine.
All right.
Your name is Giuseppe
and you own fishing
boats in Taormina
and in the morning,
you're going off
with your fishing fleet
and you won't be back
for several weeks.
What else about you?
Nothing.
Except that I am a lucky man.
Because you're going away
in the morning?
Because I met you tonight.
Oh.
Are you sure you're
a fisherman, Giuseppe?
Of course.
Why not?
I don't know.
It sounds...
Dull, I don't know.
And you don't...
If you know what I mean.
Fishing?
Dull?
You mean it's exciting?
If you go after game fish,
a fighting fish,
a fish worth taking.
Oh, yes...
Oh, yes, it's exciting.
It is not a rich man,
or a poor man,
who catches a fish.
It is a lucky man
who knows how to wait.
Oh...
That's so cruel.
Cruel?
It is the fish that
comes to the hook.
The hook does not
seek out the fish.
But the fish
hasn't got a chance.
What does the fish
need a chance for?
If I don't take it,
what would it do
with its life?
Poor fish.
What?
Never mind.
Ooh.
I almost forgot.
Are you married?
No.
Engaged?
Mistress?
(LAUGHING) No.
Ah.
Then nobody's gonna get hurt.
(MEN SINGING)
Luigi, it's late.
Close the shutters
and come to bed.
And that's why
the wives were urging their
husbands to get drunk.
So they wouldn't be able to...
Oh-ho!
That's right.
And it's going to be oh-ho
every night for months.
You too, Nunzia?
Me too what?
Are you a part
of this conspiracy?
Certainly.
I'm a woman, am I not?
You most
certainly are.
What are you looking at?
A woman.
A most desirable woman.
Who?
You, Nunzia.
Luigi!
You've taken on
the delicious savor
of forbidden fruit, Nunzia.
Luigi, I...
I think you've gone mad.
The Rubicon has been crossed,
the drawbridge raised.
I must confess,
I find you at this moment
extremely desirable,
whether it is the moonlight,
the midwife,
something has been done to me.
There is this deliberate
challenge to me as a man.
I can't explain.
There is no need to explain.
Oh, Nicolina...
Quiet, Grandmother
will hear us.
She will hear nothing that she
does not expect.
But she will, she...
- Gianni?
- Huh?
Not now.
Why not?
I'm sleepy.
You've never been less sleepy
in your life.
We must talk!
We must talk reasonably.
Intelligently.
Like two sensible people.
Oh, Gianni.
No, we can't.
GIANNI: Don't fight,
little one.
I love you.
NICOLINA: Yes.
I promised Grandmother.
Not under her roof, I said.
Nicolina.
Nicolina, let me
tell you something.
All girls are afraid at first,
but afterwards,
they like it
very much.
Trust me, don't be afraid.
Afraid?
Who is afraid?
- Gianni, I have an idea.
- Yes?
Let's go to the orchard.
The orchard?
Now?
- The orchard!
- Shh!
You want to leave a soft, warm
bed for a cold, hard orchard?
Oh, yes, oh, please, Gianni.
Please, love?
I want our first night to be
under the stars,
under the moon,
on the soft grass.
You want to sleep
in the orchard?
Then that's what we'll do.
Your shoes.
Come on, crazy one, hurry up.
Hurry up.
(ROOSTER CROWING)
NICOLINA: Gianni?
GIANNI: Hmm?
NICOLINA: My hand
looks no different.
GIANNI: Did you
think it would?
NICOLINA: The trees
are no different.
The sun's no different.
Nothing's different.
Only me.
Oh, Gianni.
I'll never be the same again.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
And then finally the bride
and the bridegroom left.
Oh, that bridegroom.
With his eyes like
slowburning fires.
The girl's lucky.
The boy is a prize.
But eyes or no,
not only that...
(SMACKING PILLOW)
Ooh, Jessica!
Do you have to be so noisy?
Oh, those feathers crashing
together inside there.
Anyway, you certainly had
the best of it last night,
vino and amore.
Me, I only had vino.
But when I saw you walking out
with the marchese.
You mean Giuseppe.
Giuseppe?
Who is Giuseppe?
He was the tallest,
the most handsome,
the one with the eyes,
and the cruel mouth
that isn't
cruel at all.
That's what I am saying.
The one who led you
into the garden.
Him I saw, the marchese,
Edmondo from
the chateau up there.
Giuseppe is the marchese?
There are girls
all over Sicily
who are looking for him.
But not here.
Never with a girl
from here before.
But I suppose he broke
his rule for you
because you are a stranger.
Mamma Parigi,
are you sure the man I...
The man you saw me with last
night was...
Was the marchese?
Of course I'm sure.
When it comes to man,
at least I still got the eye.
And speaking of men, there was
something going on last night.
The husbands all drunk
and the wives
all happy.
Mmm. Those women are
up to something...
And it's against you,
and it's
about to explode!
I can hardly wait.
You won't have to.
But why didn't you tell me it
was a strike, against me?
It would only have upset you.
But why didn't you
stop them, Father?
These women are fighting for
the most important things
in their lives.
Their husbands
and their homes.
I couldn't stop them.
You think that
they're right to do
a thing like this to me?
They are right to fight for
their homes, yes.
But why?
What wrong have I done?
You are here, my child.
You are what we call
the occasion of sin.
The temptation
to the husbands,
the torment to their wives.
No married man has touched me.
No, but you are in every man's
dream, and that is what their
wives can't forgive.
But what if
I want to stay, Father?
You are right to.
Then what
do I do?
That is something
no one can tell you.
It is up to you.
Yes, of course.
Thank you, Father.
But why didn't you tell me it
was a strike?
What difference does it make?
You kept your promise,
didn't you?
Oh, yes, I did.
Well, that's nice.
I hope you're not sorry.
Of course not.
Good.
You'd better take
that grass out of your hair.
- Anything else?
- Oh, yes.
Some brown yarn.
His socks are full of holes.
Well, she begins early.
But she looks tired.
Didn't you sleep well?
Oh, yes, I slept beautifully,
but the night was short,
as you know.
As we all know.
I'll say.
Oh, you should see him.
I fail to see the humor.
As for you,
Signora Casablanca,
have you any idea
what you have done?
Oh, have I ever.
Do you really think it's funny
that she has betrayed us?
Sabotaged us?
Humiliated us?
Us, Virginia?
Why not us?
Well, I don't know about you,
but I haven't had to lock my
bedroom door lately.
All right, go ahead and laugh.
But if it wasn't for me,
some of you
would be crying by now.
I was the one who first saw
the danger of this Jezebel,
this American midwife,
and I was the first
to see her evil plan.
I was the first one
to see that she was
going to use her
devil-inspired body to steal
every man in this village.
Good morning, ladies.
Father Antonio told me about
your strike,
and I was going to leave.
That was before
I heard you.
My devil-inspired body.
What quaint words
you use, Signorina,
for your dirty thoughts.
As for stealing
your men,
I'm innocent
and you know it.
Still, you've tried to get rid
of me because
you thought
I might be trouble.
Well, ladies...
You don't know
what trouble is.
Such insolence.
* Oh quelle belle Jessica
* Oh quelle divine bambina
* In all the world
no replica
* Of Jessica, of Jessica
* When Jessica
comes into town
* That little town
is turned around
* And everything is
upside down
* With Jessica around
* For Jessica
has laughing eyes
* Her tantalizing air
* For Jessica
has tender lips
* And honeycolored hair
* Oh
* The baker cannot
bake his cake
* The farmer
leans upon his rake
* They're feeling
so romantica
* For Jessica, for Jessica
* Oh quelle belle Jessica
* Oh quelle divine bambina
* They're feeling
so romantica
* Because of Jessica
* La bella Jessica
* Che bella Jessica
* Voila
* Eccola
* Oh Lord
* I must confess to it
* I must have made
* A mess of it
* Cannot be the fault of thee
* So
* It must be the fault of me
* The ladies in the town
are right
* The gentlemen
are downright right
* And Jessica is also right
* But everything
is wrong
* My little town
* Is turned around
* My quiet little town
* My little town
* Is upside down
* With Jessica around
* Ah
* The ladies in the town
are right
* The gentlemen
are downright right
* And Jessica
* Is also right
* But everything is wrong
* I cannot blame the men
* Amen.
Oh, perfect.
Perfect specimen.
Exquisite proportions.
The legs, perfect.
The body, faintly mottled.
I waited long time for this.
Good afternoon, Jessica.
I've never seen anything
so perfect
and I've seen quite a few.
Now, wait a minute.
You can't always tell the male
from the female, you know?
But I didn't have the
slightest doubt this time.
A real hairy old grandfather.
What?
TUFFI: A spider.
Where?
TUFFI: Oh, it's gone now.
Are you interested in spiders?
No.
No, I'm not, but...
I'm glad to hear you are.
It's my life work.
I'm writing a book.
About spiders.
Their qualities, their
patience, their cunning.
The infinite delicacy
of their handiwork.
Consider, madam, a web.
A dangerous weapon
of infinite beauty and grace.
Oh, I could spend
a whole life with them.
He's coming.
- Ladies.
- Luigi.
No, no, no, Nunzia,
I mustn't be disturbed.
I must be alone.
To encapture this
afternoon's experience.
It was unique.
It was staggering.
Well...
Poor thing.
Too bad.
The American girl?
Naked as a grape.
(BOTH GASP)
A spider?
(LAUGHING)
Oh, Luigi, Luigi.
How sweet of you.
And now, my love,
I have some news for you.
You are going to
be a father.
What do you think of that?
- A... A father?
- Yes.
(MUMBLING)
Luigi! Oh!
Luigi! Luigi!
Wonderful, wonderful,
wonderful!
Bravo, Tuffi!
Tuffi, you are a true
son of Sicily!
It was the first
shot that got the bird.
Bravo!
No, you idiot!
You're in too deep!
GIANNI: I'm planting them
in two inches.
- Hmm?
- GIANNI: The way you said.
No, no, you're choking
them to death!
All right, all right.
He's killing all my flowers.
Well, that's too bad.
Now, you just stay down.
I keep telling him every day,
for four weeks,
he never listens.
He doesn't want to listen.
He won't learn.
You'll have to
help him again, huh?
All right.
You're the only
one who listens to me.
Nobody else does.
Nothing does.
My legs.
I tell them to get up,
they don't move.
How can they not move?
When I still have so much
living here to do.
You see how you
have weakened me, hmm?
With your soft ways?
Why do you do it?
Why?
Who else would put up with
your rotten disposition?
I have the disposition
of a saint
and God knows
I am more interesting.
Now go on, go to that boy
before he kills my flowers.
Go on, go on.
I want to sleep.
Don't do me any favors,
but if tomorrow, you should
happen to be passing by...
I'll be passing by.
(SIGHING)
(WIND HOWLING)
- What do you think?
- Terrible.
It couldn't be worse if you
planned it that way,
which you did, of course.
Did I?
Will you ride me
home on your Vespa?
No.
Why not?
Because, everyone would see
and that would
make it too serious.
Now, the way to plant.
Look at this, your
uncle and I have
both told you
time and again
not the blue over there
but over there.
GIANNI: Then show me.
JESSICA: The way to plant.
Deep, but not too deep.
The rows
straight and neat.
Well, well, Gianni, so soon?
I'm going away
for a week or two.
If your uncle needs anything,
see that he gets it,
and I'll take care
of it when I return.
But don't tell him that,
he's a stubborn old fool.
He should have gone to
the hospital weeks ago.
- If he had...
- If he had,
he would
have died weeks ago.
Ah, you're an
authority on dying.
No.
My best subject is fishing.
Really?
It shows how wrong
I can be.
I would have
thought you an amateur.
I am.
But I learn quickly.
How lucky
for your friends.
Mm-hmm.
Gianni, come on, come on,
if you're going home
with me on my Vespa.
Gianni!
Remember me to your wife!
(BLEATING)
(MEN SHOUTING AND LAUGHING)
(HORN BEEPING)
Look out below!
Ah!
Tomorrow, Jessica?
Why not?
Gianni, you're late.
Father Antonio and Grandmother
finished supper hours ago.
I waited for you.
Nicolina, we...
I told you to keep this woman
away from my house.
- GIANNI: Nicolina!
- I mean it.
Get her away!
Stay and have supper.
No, but I'll see
you tomorrow.
That is, if you're
allowed out.
Arrivederci, Gianni!
Gianni!
You come in here!
GIANNI: Mind your business,
old woman.
Nicolina!
Gianni.
I want to talk to you.
Save it for
the church, Father.
Nicolina!
(NICOLINA SOBBING)
Where is my supper?
Oh, Gianni, please don't be
mad at me, oh, please.
Let me know when it's ready,
I'll be in the barn.
Oh, Gianni!
And fix the bed
in the spare room.
Oh!
The thing is...
I don't know
what to do about it!
I don't know either.
But I'll try.
Of course, I...
I can't be sure that it will
work, Father.
But on the one hand,
I have Edmondo.
On the other hand,
I have the girl.
And I can't help feeling
that Edmondo could
save the situation
and she in turn
could save him.
So I have to try.
Even though I...
I know it's risky.
All right, Father, not risky.
Crazy.
Pretty, isn't it?
Beautiful.
Will you do it, Edmondo?
I don't know.
From what you say, it seems to
me the girl has done a good
thing for the village.
Brought a quickening of
interest, a spirit, a zest.
I agree she...
She has brought
life itself
to the village.
And you still want me
to throw her out.
Yes, I do.
And you won't
give me your reason?
No.
All right.
As soon as I get back...
I'll throw her out.
Now, tell me more about her.
(WIND HOWLING)
So don't worry, when your baby
comes, I'll be there.
Well, I wanted to be sure.
You can be sure.
How many
pregnant women so far?
Counting Signora Tuffi, three
positives and four probables.
Seven scabs,
all coming in secret
and all bringing presents.
Oh.
Here comes another one.
Who is it?
She can't be coming here.
(KNOCKING)
I'll get it.
Signora Visconti,
I have a present for you.
Never mind the present.
Who is the man?
My brother Beppi.
Your brother!
My brother Beppi,
as messaggero municipale of...
Signora!
Signora Visconti.
As messaggero municipale
of this area,
I have been instructed to
read this to you.
Jessica, if you want to fight
this, I will help you.
Marquis Edmondo Raumo...
Orders said
Mrs. Jessica Brown Visconti
to vacate such house
within 15 days from
the date hereof,
signed Marquis Edmondo Raumo.
Legally, the marchese
has the right,
but I can find ways.
VIRGINIA: Why, how dare you!
For you, Jessica,
I will do anything.
So that's how it is with you.
She's a hussy.
Shameless.
Shocking!
Unspeakable!
- Beppi, I am talking to you!
- Oh...
Where are you going!
I'm going to
the wine shop.
Why don't you go to hell?
(LAUGHING)
(BELL RINGING)
What is it?
What do you want?
Ah, it's you.
I came to see you.
What can I do for you?
Come inside.
It's perfectly safe.
A fisherman always leaves it
up to the fish,
remember?
Please.
Sit down.
I'm not tired.
As you like.
Now, what is this?
Ah, I see.
I want to know
why you've ordered me
to leave my cottage.
I own it.
- JESSICA: I pay rent.
- Promptly, too.
Then why must I move?
No special reason.
I won't give it up.
Then you don't have to.
Someone asked me to do
something, I did it,
and that's that.
- Drink on it?
- No.
Afraid?
Yes.
All right, then go.
Still here?
How nice.
- Please.
- (SIGHING)
Giuseppe, or Edmondo,
or whatever your name is,
why did you lie to me?
I don't know, really.
It was automatic.
When I lie,
you want the truth,
when I tell the truth,
you want a lie.
Now which?
I'm glad you see
the injustice of it,
especially since
I did not remind you
of the lies you told to me.
What lies?
I told you no lies.
You gave the impression that
you love being in my village
gathering babies,
when all the time
it was the fathers
you were gathering.
Oh, now, wait.
That was only after,
and it wasn't serious.
Ah, it was a joke.
Now, I like jokes,
but not jokes against
my people,
by intruders.
Or perhaps I am being unfair.
Or perhaps you are sincerely
and wonderfully in love
with Gianni Crupi,
Antonio Risino,
Pietro Musudino,
Filippo Casablanca,
Beppi Toriello, no?
Aren't you forgetting
your gardener?
Old Crupi, too?
I thought you were just using
him as a blind for your affair
with the nephew.
You give me
too much credit, Giuseppe.
Not at all.
I know talent when I see it.
Well, good for you.
And now that your vote is in,
that just about
makes it unanimous.
I'm sick and tired
of you people sitting around
deciding whether or not
I'm good enough for you.
Well, now it's about time that
I decide whether or not
you people
are good enough for me.
You want to know something?
You're not.
Beginning with you.
(WIND HOWLING,
VEHICLE APPROACHING)
Jessica!
I thought Gianni
would be here.
No.
He did not come home
so I thought...
Was he with you?
No.
Jessica...
Don't take him away from me.
You can if
you wanted to.
I don't know how to stop you.
But please don't.
What do you mean,
don't take him away?
I don't want him.
I don't want any of them.
Aren't you women
ever going to understand
that I am not the one
to be afraid of?
It's yourselves.
And instead of being afraid,
you ought to be ashamed.
How can you doubt
the men you love so easily?
Don't you trust them?
Oh, never mind.
Nicolina, you don't have to
worry about Gianni.
You never did have to.
Come on,
I'll take you home.
(KNOCKING)
Jessica, my uncle is dying.
He wants you to come.
- Gianni.
- Nicolina.
Let me come, too.
Where is she,
where is she, where is she?
I didn't hear you,
what was that?
I said, where the hell is she?
Lie still, lie still.
She will come.
Is he in pain, Father?
No.
What do you know about it?
(SCOFFS)
These idiots
think I'm dying.
Don't push me!
They're in for a surprise.
Yes, yes, but I want you to
rest now.
I want to see my garden.
Later, but rest first.
I haven't time
for later.
Help me, help me, lift me!
What's wrong?
My garden?
Jessica?
Yes. The storm.
I want to see it.
Help me, help me...
The fruit
of 60 years.
My garden, all gone.
Well, I'll just
have to plant it again.
We'll do it for you.
Will you?
Will you really, Jessica?
Exactly as you had it.
Flower by flower.
You'd better.
Don't forget,
I'll be up there watching.
Father, can you pray me
on up there, huh?
I'll do my best.
Well...
Maybe you ought
to get a head start.
Edmondo.
Yes?
Am I...
Am I really dying?
Tell me the truth.
Yes, you are.
Exactly.
And half dead as I am,
I am more alive
than you.
Wake up, boy.
Wake up.
Jessica?
I'm right here, Crupi.
Lie still.
Don't talk.
What do you mean,
don't talk?
You know nothing
stops me from talking!
(PRAYING IN LATIN)
(SOBBING) Crupi!
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
No, we're sorry,
but we're off to Rome
to forget it all.
It's nice of Maria Lombardo
and the others
to send their apologies,
but we've been hurt in our
feelings in a terrible way.
Tighter with that buckle,
don't you think, Father?
Ah, good for you.
Finished with
the trunk, Jessica?
Then let Father Antonio
close it for you.
Jessica, isn't there
anything I can say?
Jessica, we are not forgetting
our poor dead husband's
picture, are we?
Excuse me, Father.
Did you
say something?
Did I interrupt you, huh?
Hmm?
- Don't go to Rome.
- MAMMA: Why not?
Why shouldn't we go?
Listen to me, Jessica.
I made a bad mistake.
I was the one who asked
Edmondo to put you out.
I just wanted you two to be
together again because...
Because I was sure.
That is,
I felt that he is...
I hoped, but I was wrong.
It takes a big man to admit it
when he is wrong, Father,
and we forgive you.
Shall we lock the trunk now
so we can go, Jessica?
Won't you stay?
Because of me?
Oh, Father, of course not.
The women?
Not the women.
Then who?
Oh...
I don't know.
I think I know.
It's the marchese.
I was just going to say that.
- It's the marchese!
- What?
Oh.
I was afraid you had gone.
We were just leaving.
Come, Jessica.
Wait, please.
I'm sorry to break in
this way.
I'm sorry about many things.
But, well, the way you feel
about babies
is how I feel
about promises.
I like to see them
taken care of.
What kind of promises did you
have in mind, marchese?
- Come, Mamma Parigi.
- Hmm?
- Out.
- Out, why?
Oh...
You promised to help restore
my old friend's garden.
What are you
going to do about it?
JESSICA: I have never...
EDMONDO: Are you going to
keep your promise?
JESSICA: Yes, I suppose
I have to.
EDMONDO: But Jessica,
it must be done my way.
The way and Crupi had the
colors mixed together,
it looked like a jungle!
JESSICA: Well, that's the way
we wanted it to look!
And I think a jungle
is the most beautiful
garden of all...
Hey... Mmm.
(PLAYING SLOW MUSIC)
(PLAYING UPBEAT MUSIC)
(MUSIC STOPS)
(PLAYING SLOW MUSIC)
A son has been born
to Signor
and Signora Luigi Tuffi.
Congratulations.
Huh?
(MOUTHING WORDS)
Two sons have been born
to Signor and Signora
Luigi Tuffi.
Peppi, two boys!
Two boys.
(THUDDING)
Just slipped.
Mother and sons,
and father...
All doing...
All doing well.
The text
of my sermon today is,
when the fruit
is ripe,
it is time to reap.
You will please join me
in a prayer of thanksgiving.
We thank thee,
almighty Father,
that after
an unusually dry beginning,
thou has showered us
with the rain
and sunshine of thy mercy.
Our once-barren fields
are now teeming
with abundance,
thanks to thy infinite wisdom,
and we ask thee
to continue to keep
thy fatherly eye upon us
as we
prepare to gather
this great harvest,
for without
thy help,
we can go wrong, Father.
Oh, how we
can go wrong
* Oh quelle belle Jessica
* Oh quelle divine bambina
* In all the world
no replica
* Of Jessica, of Jessica
* When Jessica
comes into town
* That little town
is turned around
* And everything is
upside down
* With Jessica around
* Oh quelle belle Jessica
* Oh quelle divine bambina
* In all the world
no replica
* Of bella Jessica