SPRING
Sus, get up.
Good morning, darling.
Get up, darling.
FOR MUM
Here.
Good morning. - Hi.
Why did you sleep in the same bed?
Susana was having nightmares.
Done.
Wash your face, Susan.
Oh man.
Go wake your sister up.
Hey! - Stop daydreaming!
I gotta work. - Get in.
I'll walk. - I'll drive you.
How you doing? - Good. You?
Hamdulillah.
Where are the girls? - At school, where else?
You're looking good. - Thanks.
New watch? - No, it's really old.
Eyes on the road! - I just haven't worn it for ages.
From Murti? - Of course! What do you think?
He's a good man, Murti.
He treats you like a queen. - Typical Arab man.
It's nice. - Yeah, alhamdulillah.
Hamdulillah.
No, the one before Real City...
This one? - Yeah, that one.
You like it, huh? - Turn it up!
Drive Sadah!
Good morning.
Sorry I'm late. My colleague is off sick.
Amir, hi. - Hello.
That's the one.
You need to...
sign here, please. - Yep.
Perfect.
Here, the fee exemption form.
Are they your girls?
The girls on the photo. - Yes.
Really?
Wow, they're adorable. - Thank you.
They really look like you. I can see you in all of them.
Right, I'm going to photocopy this.
We don't need this, it's the old one. - OK.
My friends play some traditional music... - OK.
They play the oud... - Nice.
Do you play too?
I play the flute, but I haven't played for ages.
I thought you might like to come to the party with me.
We could have a drink and watch the concert together.
I don't have the time, Khaled. Sorry.
"No time. Sorry." - No time.
Good morning, Maryam. - Morning, Abu Jamal. How's it going?
Hamdulillah.
Have you booked the flights? - Yep.
It's still warm. - Grab the garlic sauce.
When is your flight? - Thursday.
That's not so bad, is it?
No, but I've gotso much to do before then.
Buying presents? - Yeah. Presents, and loads of paperwork.
Be happy you get to see the sun!
I am, it's just the difficult circumstances.
Let me know if you need any help. - Sure.
Seriously. Don't hesitate. - Yeah, I'll see what I get done.
I'll take care of everything.
Open sesame.
Are the boarding passes on your phone? - Oh...
Have a good journey.
Thank you, thank you.
Say hi to all the family from me. - Will do.
And kiss Beirut for me!
Have a last look at your car while it's still nice.
Oh, you'll be fine.
And the parcel for Jibril. - Yep.
I registered your visit. Don't forget to take your ID.
Alright. See you.
Bye.
What's the point?
Hi.
Maryam.
I know.
We've seen each other before.
At the wedding.
It was a while ago, you were wearing a blue dress.
Yep.
I handed in your parcel from Sadah. - Thanks.
She's really sorry. - It's fine.
Did Murti fly over with her to Beirut? - Yeah, it's his uncle.
It's crazy getting in here.
Getting out's even crazier.
What do you do in here all day?
Sit around.
Read.
Exercise.
I'm doing an apprenticeship as a locksmith.
Learning to break into places?
I'm also in this group with a priest.
Or pastor... no, he's a priest.
Sorry.
He's the only person who understands what's going on here.
I'm trying to do my A-levels, and he's helping me with that.
A-levels? - Yeah.
Cool.
Jibril.
Jibril...
It's a nice name.
It's nice the way you say it.
Don't you speak Arabic? - Only a little bit.
My dad didn't really want us to...
speak Arabic.
He wanted us to speak German, so we felt like we belonged.
I can speak both.
That's you.
But... I can still learn it.
I brought you some chocolate. - Thanks.
I was hoping it was for me.
I have to get going.
Are you gonna come again?
It was an honour, Jibril.
Thanks.
When one door closes, the other will open.
Have a nice day. Thanks. You too.
Have a nice day. - Bye.
Shall I...? - We're about to eat.
But not the yellow stuff! - Right.
What do you want? - Rice.
Do you want the rest?
No?
Not that much!
Not so much. - Stop!
That's enough.
Peppers too, Elin?
How was your day?
What did you do? - Nothing special.
How was your day at Dad's?
Chilled.
So you watched TV all day? - No.
What did you do then? - We went out.
We played... - Then what?
I told you, we went out.
You had a good time then?
Did you clean for him after that?
No!
Seriously, Sus. Don't lie to me.
Stop fighting all the time. - We're not.
Just tell me. I want to know what you did. - No.
You're my daughter. - So?
Are you my daughter? Yes or no.
And my father is my father.
I don't want you vacuuming for him. - What's it to you?
I wanna know what you've been doing. Sus! - Man!
Give me that. - Can't I keep it?
No, give it to me, please.
Want a cup of tea or something?
I could make some peppermint tea.
I'll go upstairs in a bit.
She said she'd call tonight. - It's already 9:15.
She won't call anyway.
I can't imagine my daughters not talking to me...
Do a better job than me then.
You can see what she's like when she gets back from her Dad's.
She's close to him.
That's just how it is.
Girls are always close to their dads.
Mine is the same. That's the way it is.
SUMMER
Morning check!
Say something.
How's your Arabic coming along?
Not great.
Did you even start? - Not really.
You can't be bothered?
How are your kids?
Susana's giving me a tough time, but they're good.
Yara's Arabic is really good.
Really? - Yep.
And Susana? - She can't be bothered.
She's more into her private life. - The old one?
Susana's the oldest one, Yara's the middle one.
Twelve. - Susana's twelve, yep.
Pretty old.
The coffee should be over there.
Mr Martin, is the coffee on? - Yep.
Let's get started then.
It's nice to see you all here once again.
Let us give thanks for the companionship,
and for what we talk about, think about and feel.
May the Lord be with us. Amen. - Amen.
I just got this article.
We talked about relationships in our last two sessions,
and about our desires,
and Mr Martin, you found something interesting.
So, Mr Martin, do you think relationships stand a chance in prison?
Yes and no. Maybe a tiny percentage of them work out.
But generally, speaking from personal experience,
no.
Do you have a girlfriend, Mr Böhm? - Not anymore.
It lasted for a year.
Then we split upafter I got put in prison.
Did you split up by mutual consent?
Yes, we...
She came here for a long-term visit,
but we decided a two-hour visit once a month wasn't enough.
Imagine seeing your wife only two hours a month.
So we said we'd take a break for the time being.
And what happens when I'm out is another story.
Your cornflakes are ready.
Mum's eating your cornflakes! - So?
Cornflakes thief!
Good morning.
How's it going? Did you sleep well?
We're having breakfast.
Cornflakes.
Wanna speak to him? - I do!
Susan.
I'm Jibril.
I guess your Mum told you about me.
Good. Yeah, put her on. - OK.
Hello.
Yara.
Yara! With an "R".
With an "R"! Yara.
Give me the phone!
See you sometime soon.
You too? - Yeah.
Here. - Good morning.
"Good morning!"
Hello? I'm Elin.
Give it to me.
They're sweet.
They're laughing at me.
Bye.
No, thanks.
Just try it, a few vitamins will do you good.
Yummy.
They're really nice. - Yep.
I like them too.
Where'd you get them? - Downstairs.
Have you heard from your cousin?
Samira? - Yeah.
She's marrying some loser.
He's got no job, nothing...
I'm sure she knows what she's doing. - What's that supposed to mean?
He's a waster.
How can she marry someone who's such a failure?
If she's happy, she's happy. - "Happy", what does that mean?
Mum, she's in love.
Love blossoms over time, my child.
It's not something that's just there.
A man needs to be able to provide for his family.
But she has a job.
Does she have to work to provide for him then?
But she loves him.
And that's enough, is it?
Sometimes it is. - Well, it's not.
You can fall in love very quickly,
but true love grows and stays with you, like me and your father...
he loved and respected me, we got through a lot together.
God bless him. - God bless him.
No ice cream!
You're back already?
I thought you were at work.
Oh God, what are you wearing?
Are you serious? - Yeah...
Why do you look like a clown?
You've eaten all the ice creams. Yara! - Leave us alone!
We're allowed.
You clown!
Fuck.
Did you have an ice cream too? - I didn't.
Hey, did you eat four ice creams?
What are you doing back already? - I didn't go in.
You got all dolled up for that? What's your game?
What? - Leave me alone!
What's up with Susana?
How should I know? She's always like this. - She's not.
Sure she is.
Talk to me. - I didn't go in.
Oh, you didn't, did you? That's good to know.
I don't want them eating ice creams before dinner, OK?
The state of this place!
How about a smile?
How was maths? - Good.
What does that mean? - I got a C.
Hey! We're over here.
How was your day? - Good.
Shall we do something fun? - The funfair!
The funfair? - Is Maggi coming?
Us four and one of my students. - How old?
He's a grown-up.
Brilliant.
You too? - Yeah!
Come over here then.
She's allowed on too, right?
How much for three children?
And Khaled?
Are you going on with them? - Me?
Yeah!
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome on board.
Enjoy your ride on the carousel and...
have fun!
How are we all doing? Are you feeling it?
Okey dokey, let's pump it up to the top!
Hello, Maryam Abdul-Karim speaking.
I'd like to speak to Mr Issa.
Gabriel Issa.
He's one of the prisoners,on ward 4.
2-4-6-3-6-8-7.
Yes.
Thanks. Bye.
Thanks.
Last time I got four.
Yeah, I haven't figured the machine out yet.
It's fine.
Open the present, it's for you.
Looks like someone already did.
Yeah, I wrapped it up really nicely,
but, yeah, they...
...ripped it a bit. They always do that.
Yeah, they opened it.
Open it.
Later.
I want it to be a surprise when I'm back in my cell.
OK?
I wanted to come last Thursday.
Where were you?
In the car.
What? - You alright?
I'm good. You? - Yep.
I'm good.
Did you just have a shower?
Nice.
Why are you so far away?
You know what you looked like up there at the wedding?
Like King Kong!
Don't, or we'll get thrown out.
Well, I will. You won't.
That's enough.
What are we doing here?
Sorry.
I didn't mean to meddle.
I'm just worried about you.
You just got rid of one bastard, but not his debts.
Don't worry, I won't bring another bastard home.
But I do worry.
Where's this gonna go next?
I can see how you're acting weird.
You never let me do my thing.
Do your thing?
Deal with your shit yourself then.
I know it's totally stupid, but I'm in front of the building.
Seriously.
I had this mad yearning for you today.
She's on WhatsApp again.
Sorry, but I have a life. - And we don't?
You're our mother, that's your life.
That's precisely the problem. - Yeah...
So? What's been happening?
What do you want to know?
You're looking good.
You are, wallah!
Tell me.
It's good.
Give me money.
Money? What for? - To buy something.
I saw.
What do you want to buy?
Sweets.
Thanks.
OK, bye.
Take your sister with you.
Does it feel good? - Yeah.
What are you gonna do now?
Go on holiday, of course!
Good evening.
How's it going?
Sorry?
I'm good, I'm just watching...
"The Eyes of the Heart".
Crazy.
You understand everything.
It all turns pretty dramatic after that.
Right.
They're not allowed to be together anymore.
Yep.
You're so cute.
You just are...
I'd love to kiss you now.
Hello?
Are you still there?
Did you hear what I just said?
Well? - I miss you.
Really.
Why are you moping around the place?
I'm fine.
At least do some bums, tums, thighs.
What a machine!
AUTUMN
Can't you walk a bit slower? - This is slow.
It's not slow, it's fast. - It is slow!
He's not gonna open up.
Why not? - Something about some bills.
What bills? - I dunno, bills.
Why's he not opening?
What's that? - My code.
Do you know the code too? - No, only I do.
Do your code again then. - Go on!
He's not gonna answer, forget it.
He's at home. He'll answer in a bit.
Get off.
You're so annoying. - Look who's talking.
Just go up and knock, OK?
If you hadn't taken my phone off me I could've called him.
Hello? - Yes?
Could you open the door, please?
Get in.
Bang on the door, he might be asleep. OK? - Yes!
I was told to say hi.
Who by? - Murti and Sadah.
Those two...
They never come and visit me anymore. - They're busy.
They're always travelling.
Sure, travelling... still in China?
Dubai.
How are your A-levels going?
I stopped that.
I dunno... I'm gonna do something else.
I might study architecture.
You can't do a degree without A-levels.
Who says I can't?
How are your daughters?
Good.
Great.
Nice.
They're asking about you.
Seriously?
Cool.
They could come visit me.
Why not?
Fuck.
Hello, Mum.
Hello. Sorry.
Come on. Susana!
Put the tablet away. - OK.
I'm so sorry, Mum. I really thought he was at home.
Was it hard work?
Are you tired? I'll make you some tea. - No.
Can I get you anything?
No, I'm alright. Don't worry. - Bye.
Sorry. Bye.
I know it's totally stupid, but I'm in front of the building.
Seriously.
I had this mad yearning for you today.
I'm here.
Can you feel it?
Cell inspection.
Where's your phone? - I don't have one.
You know mobile phones are not permitted.
We must assume it was smuggled in and you have violated the house rules.
It will have consequences regarding your release.
We were all set to taking steps towards your release next week.
We were going to review your situation,
and take steps towards your release if the assessment was positive.
But that's all down the drain now.
There's nothing we can do? - No.
You've been here for three years now.
Everything was going well.
You've been working regularly, your urine samples have all been negative.
No complaints about your behaviour.
We have a plan. You have prospects.
Say something.
Right. I get it.
Just go then.
Wanker.
Shut it!
Fuck off.
Hey, babe. It's me.
Why aren't you picking up?
You hear they'reconfiscating mobiles on 4B?
Yep. You're a bit late though, they took mine yesterday.
Serious?
Thanks for the chocolate.
All white today.
True.
You cool? - I'm cool.
Everything's cool.
Everything's been cool for three years, just three to go.
Cool every fucking day.
It's all good.
What's going on with you? - Loads.
Eid al-Fitr is coming up.
We decorated the whole flat yesterday. It looks so stupid.
Murti brought so much junk back with him. Proper junk.
For the kids.
Murti's back? - Yep. The day before yesterday.
You don't give a shit about how I'm doing? - Huh?
You don't give a shit about how I'm doing?
What's wrong, Jibril?
What's wrong with you lot, more like.
I just sit here waiting for shit.
I'm a bit stressed right now.
School's starting again.
You're stressed?
About what?
I am, yes.
That's why you don't pick up? - Yep.
And they don't visit me... - I only don't pick up if it's you.
Thought so.
You're absolutely...
spot-on.
Go then.
What's wrong, Jibril? - Go.
Seriously, what's up? - Go.
Say hi to Murti and Sadah.
I'm here now, Jibril.
Has something happened?
You like hanging out with my friends, huh?
Yeah...
We're going to a spa together next week.
I don't want your chocolate, to be honest.
I'll take them with me, no worries.
Go.
Move it.
You're pissing me off.
Fucking prick.
What can I do for you, Mr Issa?
The phone thing... it's really shit.
Did you have your disciplinary meeting?
Yep. - And?
It didn't go well.
I want to call my girlfriend.
Miss Abdul-Karim? - Right.
Yeah, but...
What do you mean by that? - I dunno, Jibril.
I dunno. I need some space.
Whatever, I need to get out.
You need to get out? I need to get out, Maryam. Fuck you.
Mr Issa.
That's not possible.
What's the problem?
I dunno.
Why didn't you tell her that they...
confiscated your phone?
I wanted to, but it's...
It's not that easy.
You're doing good, yeah?
You can do whatever you want, and just go,
while I'm left waiting here like an idiot,talking to your fucking mailbox.
I wish you had never come.
Because she has to...
OK. Right, bye.
Good morning. - A very good morning.
I passed B1.
Congratulations.
I actually came to ask you... - Persistent, huh?
Huh? - Persistent.
It means "pigheaded". But not in a bad way.
I'll take it as a compliment then.
I don't know what's up with me. But it's not you, it's me.
Sorry for being such a dick.
OK...
I was just...
acting like a wanker.
I dunno.
I dunno, Jibril.
Bye.
Great to see you.
Let's get married.
What? - Get married.
But I'm in jail.
Are you serious?
What about your mum?
She's gonna freak out.
The things you come up with!
WINTER
Wow!
My princess! Cake?
Are you nervous?
Yeah, a little.
Really? - Well...
Shall I put some make-up on you?
He's lucky to get you. - Definitely.
You've only got 20 percent battery. - Put it on power-saving mode.
I managed to get off work early,
glad I made it.
That must be the imam.
Hey, Sus. Put that away.
Now!- Give me those toys.
As-Salaam-Alaikum. - Wa-Alaikum-Salaam.
Please come in.
Right. Now we're going to speak to Mr Issa.
On the phone.
He's going to ring any second now.
OK. Let's wait.
This is certainly unique.
You don't often get marriages like this one.
But...
Hello.
It's me.
Shall we get started?
Yep, let's get started.
Hello, brother Jibril. How are you?
Good, I hope.
I will start with a small reading.
Maryam, daughter of Abdul Karim Majid,
I will now ask you
if you agree to marry brother Jibril Issa.
I do.
Excellent.
The witness... the brother is present.
The vows have nowbeen taken on one side,
and now, for you to be tied in holy matrimony,
we need to hear the same vows from you.
Yes!
Al hamdulillah. - Hamdulillah.
I hereby declare you man and wife.
My sincere congratulations.
To finalise the marriage, I will pass on this ring to you.
This is now your ring. - Thank you.
Turn around, please.
PLEASE LEAVE THE ROOM IN THE CONDITION IN WHICH YOU FOUND IT.
ONLY USE BED LINEN YOU HAVE PROVIDED.
My colleague will call you.
You've got till 7 pm.
How are you?
You cooked? - Yeah.
So, this is it. - Huh?
This is our room.
I'm not all that hungry.
I'll just quickly... - Do it later.
Let me just get everything ready.
PLEASE WASH UP CROCKERY AND CUTLERY AT THE END OF YOUR STAY.
Come over here.
Hi. - Hey.
The food.
Can I give you a hand?
I'll lay the table.
It's all... plastic.
Let's go eat.
Sorry.
Yummy.
I'll soon be two-thirds through my sentence.
It'd be coolto see each other more often, right?
Did you speak to Murti about the job?
No.
I haven't had the time.
Yes?
OK.
Time's up.
NEW YEAR'S EVE
A new year is about to begin...
Why don't you take a selfie, if you know how it works?
Don't be so cheeky.
Firstly, one of you.
Oh yes, very nice.
I'm gonna do loads of fireworks!
You?
Let's go. - It's nice...
Move it! - Hey!
Let's go.
Chill.
They're Maggi's.
It's gonna be fun.
Hey!
Right... - Little goof.
Look after her, OK? - Yes! Let's go.
I'm serious about the fireworks, OK?
Let's go!
Come on, let's go.
Do your coat up, Yara.
Yes!
This one's for you. - Hey, I heard that!
You can make a wish.
Love you. - You too.
Bye, Maggi. - Bye, sweetie. See you next year.