This Golden sword should
be kept in the hands of a good person
should it fall in to the hands of
an evil person...
the outcome could be terrible
- Who's there?
- Open the door!
- Who's are you?
Open up!
- Open the door
- Yes
What can I do for you?
I am here on a matter
of great importance
I was told you have a rare sword,
called the Gold Sand sword
I came here especially to see it
I am sorry, but I have sent
the Gold Sand sword to the Ting Hsiang Ren
Why didn't you give the sword to me?
I could have paid you
a great deal for it
I would never sell it
So you're a man who
looks a gift horse in the mouth
well forgive me for the
grief I am now going to cause you
Get him!
If you kill me you will never
get your hands on the Gold Sand sword
I think you should hand it over
otherwise...
The Black Bat
will do something nasty
You want to get your hands on that sword,
but I tell you that will never happen!
If you don't take it out at once
I will kill you
- Hurry, where is it, well?
- Not here
Kill him!
Master we have made a thorough search
we cannot find the Gold Sand sword
It seems he really has given
the Gold Sword to the Tings
Let's go to the Ting's place
Strange, where is he?
Go!
Master, master...
Master, what happened?
Ah Cho, did they take the
Gold Sand sword?
No, no
I hid it
That was close...
Hurry over to Ting Hsiang Ren's house
and give him the sword
you must not let the Gold Sand sword
fall in to the hands of the Black Bat
If Ting Hsiang Ren
refuses to accept the Sword...
then give the sword to his son
Ting Yeh
You give him the sword
You must give the sword to his
son Ting Yi
Master, master...
Master, Madam, it's bad
What's so urgent?
I am sorry for this rude intrusion
So it's the famous Black Bat
What can I do for you?
I heard that the gold Sand Sword
is now in your possession
I would like to take a look at it
Gold Sand sword?
What is the Gold Sand sword?
You're telling me you never heard
of the Gold Sand sword?
So your coming here was
to get your hands on that sword
Sorry to disappoint you
but that sword is with Master Lee
I just came from Lee's place
he did not have him so I killed him
What?
You killed him?
I kill who I please
You can't scare me.
I am not a coward afraid of death
The Gold Sand blade is not here
but if it was I would not give it to you!
You don't know a good thing
when you see it
Madam, I suggest you hand
over the Gold Sand blade now
or else I will massacre
your entire family
Do we have that sword here?
Madam, this isn't your concern
go to your room, hurry up, go now!
Wait!
No one leaves this room until
I get the Gold sand sword
Black Bat, you have gone too far
Men!
No use
Thank you for your guidance master
You must remember that martial arts
is for spirit, mind and body
don't use your martial arts
to gain power and glory
Student understands
when you go back you
will be given a precious sword
you must use this sword wisely
Yes
- Take care my two brothers
- Please
Your third brother, might run in to
some problems on this trip home
you three should follow him
and keep an eye on him
help him if he gets into difficulties
but don't bring him to any harm
- Understood
Third brother,
wishing you a safe trip
it's second brother, greetings
Master has high hopes for you,
so I want to see how god you are
You words are very strong
I don't see what you're getting at
Enough talk, en guard.
En guard!
Second Brother why do you
force me to fight
Stop talking, are you afraid?
Well... please forgive me
Second Brother, my respects
Please
Sister, it's you
what are you doing here?
What do you mean by this?
You just leave without saying a word
we have been together so many years
have you got feelings for me?
I need to return home now,
I will come back soon
There's no need to explain
unless you can tell me
the date of your return
then I will not let you pass
Why you doing this?
I you promise and tell me
then I'll let you pass
Do you know why I have to go?
Watch out!
Wait!
If you don't wait, I'll hurt you!
Sister, don't be like that.
Go back to master
I'll return very soon
Sister, forget it
- Father where is uncle Ting's house
- Over there
GOLD SAND TOWN
This is the house
Why has it become like this
Hold this, I will go and ask
Uncle...
isn't this the Ting's house?
You must mean Ting Hsiang Ren...
it's so sad, their whole family
were murdered
How could they all have been murdered?
Well I'm not too sure about that
By some stroke of good fortune their son
Ting Yi was away studying martial arts
and escaped the massacre
This world we are in
is so unfair
Sir, could you tell me why
their whole family was murdered?
And who killed them?
I am not too sure about it...
some people said it was
the work of The Black Bat
but there are some others that
say it was done by Chow Yi Lung
Chow Yi lung, sure it's him?
I couldn't say
since I did not see the massacre
I think it's best
you ask someone else about it
Father, what shall we do now?
Thank you
Daughter, wait for me at the Inn,
I will be over shortly
Father, who is The Black Bat?
He's an infamous pirate warlord
he's totally ruthless
but nobody knows his true identity
Brother Ting seems to be safe
We must try to find him
You two have not seen each other
since your engagement
We must get revenge for the Uncle Ting
- You go now
- Alright
Your turn
Waiter!
Listen!
What are you men doing?
Hurry, go and serve her,
are you deaf or something
What would you like to eat?
We have buns, dumplings, noodles
and pickles the works
That's more like it
Just bring me a pot of tea
You afraid you cannot afford the prices
Don't worry miss, I'll treat you,
come and join me
I think that girl fancies you
Do you know where's she from?
I didn't order that!
Our lord ordered it for you
Take it away!
There's no need for that,
we are all friend here
That's right, all friends here
I told you to take it away
didn't you hear me?
Don't get your knickers in a twist
Feed your dog with it!
Have a drink
Take it back!
Give you back!
Looks like your trying to test me
Very well
Good kung fu
What, can even win
on home ground
Stupid bitch, don't you
know my reputation?
How can you say that,
when you are trying to bully a girl
- My lord
- Get out of the way
Bitch, you've got real guts to
come out to Gold Sand town
Don't think just because you
out number me that I am afraid
You've got a big mouth
Stop it!
That's enough!
Father!
Shi Fong,
you have been making trouble again
They bullied me
Go and apologise to them
Gentlemen, the young lady extends
her apologies to you all
Your name good sir?
I go by the name of
Yu Xiao Cheng
Oh you're the famous Knight,
Master Yu
- Your reputation precedes you
- Not at all
My name is Fan Ta Kwai
This inn belongs to master Tso
please come in and take a rest
Thank you
Master Yu, this way please
- Waiter... get their things
- Yes
Please
You know him?
Everyone knows him
He had a feud with the chief
a few years back
So what's here doing in Gold Sand town?
Looking for revenge?
The way I see it...
there could be 2 reasons...
The first reason is to get
the Gold Sand sword
the second is to take revenge
for the Ting family
How is connected to the Tings
I heard that his daughter
is engaged to their son
I think that fiery girl just now
must be Ting's son's fiance
The Tings are all dead,
is his son hiding like some turtle
I hope the room is to your satisfaction
- Thanks
- I'll be going
Father, the men here are all scoundrels
they are a bad lot
Right, be on your guard
So what's our next move?
Once we find Ting Yi
then everything will be fine
Where shall we start looking for him?
I am sure he will come back here soon
isn't that our young master?
Young master, young master...
you're back
What happened?
The worst
That night a man dressed in black
brought six men with him
He insisted master give him
a Gold Sand sword
where in your house
would you find such a sword
The master said
I don't have the gold Sand sword
but he did not believe
then they both stared to get angry
Master got his sword and struck
the man n black
Master's blade was unable
to penetrate the man
then the 6 men with him
said invincible armor skill
then those six men killed everybody
Master was no match for them
and madam was killed
two of the servants also died,
I too was cut by them
Look
I came to, the next day
The house was deserted
and quiet
I just sat outside
waiting for your return
Do you know who that man was?
I did not know him
and the six men wore masks
I only know that they all wore black
Master called him The Black Bat
Black Bat?
- Who is he?
- No one knows
Young master, he has many
associates in Gold Sand town
the Tso Sheng Inn is
run by his associates
I must find him
not to avenge my parents
would be a sin!
Father
Help!
Leave me alone
Help me!
Please save me, save me!
Shi Fu, catch them!
What happened?
Talk?
We could not find it
You should have questioned him
why did you kill him?
He's just a common thief,
he deserved to die
Master Yu everything alright?
This man is not a thief,
Shi Fong, let's go outside
Damn
Bastard got away
Who was that person who
saved the old man?
I'm checking
Thank you for saving me,
may I know the name of my savior?
I would like to reward you
There's no need for that,
The Inn you were staying at
is a bad place, do not go back there
Be on your way before the sun rises
if you go back I fear you might be killed
Yes, yes, thank you kind savior
That's enough of that
quick be going
- Hurry you better get going
- Thank you
Damn it!
I need to kill those two busy bodies
I think you should consult with
Lord Tso, see what he thinks about it
- Mind your own business
- Yes
- Wine
- Yes, waiter, some wine!
2nd brother, two strangers came recently
the old man is Yu Xiao Cheng
I think he's looking for the Black Bat
to get revenge of the Tings
I already guessed that
So what are we going to do about him?
Father and daughter are top fighters,
I fear we are not their match
Let's invite them here for dinner,
that should do it
Dad are we going to the dinner party?
Of course we are going
This dinner is hosted by them
I don't think the food will be good
That's beside the point
I must attend
Father...
I want to go with you
You cannot go,
Tso Yi Lung is my enemy
3 years ago at Mount Kwun Lun
he was defeated by my Wind Chasing Blade
No he wants payback
What I really want to discuss with him
is the matter of the Black Bat
Father I insist that I come along
That's impossible
What if something should happen to me,
who's going to take revenge for me?
Do you understand what I'm saying?
If for whatever reason I fail to return
you must find your fiance and tell him
Who is it?
Master Yu, I have been sent to
escort you to dinner, are you ready
Good, I am ready
Father please be careful
and come back quickly
Don't worry, wait for me here,
don't forget what I told you
Go in
What can I get you sir?
- Some beef noodles and Wine
- Yes
Beef noodles and wine
My dear friends, my name is Ting Yi
I am form the Ting family, my
family was exterminated by the Black Bat
If anyone knows
the whereabouts of the Black Bat
as a reward I will give you half
of my families estate
Are you really
the Young Master of the Ting house
Who are you?
I'll wait for you outside
I have important news for you
That is enough for today
Friends, if anyone knows the whereabouts
of the Black Bat, please contact me
I, Ting Yi must get revenge.
- Waiter, your money is here
- Thank you
Where are we going?
You're a hard man to find
My master instructed me to give
you a precious sword
- What precious sword
- The Gold Sand Sword
The Gold Sand Sword,
where is it now?
Follow me
- it's in here, I'll go fetch it
- Be careful
Take it easy
Young man are you alright?
Uncle Ting, I am fine
Madam, thank you
No need for that
I am Yu Xiao Cheng's daughter
my name is Yu Shi Feng
You are Uncle Yu's daughter?
Where is Uncle Yu?
He's gone to the Tso's fortress
he could be in danger
- Could you go there with me?
- Of course I can
Let's get going
Hand over the Gold Sand sword!
You've got some nerve
Try asking him yourself
Rotten Kid,
you know a few moves
After them!
Wait
Chief, Master Yu is here
- Master Yu
- Chief Chow
Please
Come..
Brother Yu, please...
Good kung fu
Cheers
Brother Yu, we noble men
don't do bad things
You won that fight 3 years ago
So what is it that
brings you to Gold Sand town
- I am looking for someone
- Who?
Master Ting
I heard that he was killed
That's correct
Such a pity, such a noble upstanding
man like him to be killed by bandits
I was told this was done by
the infamous Black Bat
isn't he you senior brother?
My advice to you is to not get
involved in this matter
it does not concern you
If it were not for Ting's son
would you even care about this matter
You have a fine way of putting things
I think Black Bat is not your boss
so why do you cover for him
Master Yu is a fine person
Serve the wine
So you must settle this matter
with the Black Bat?
He's right
Black Bat knows King Kong palm
and Invincible armor styles
and the mystery style
I fear that you are not his match
A jack of all trades but master of none
I would like to meet with him,
tell me where I can find Black Bat
Tell you...
I am not that stupid
TSO HOUSE
That is the Tso mansion
I can't go in as I am a local
You two go in,
I'll wait for you here
Wait for me here
Master Yu. allow me to give you
some good advice
leave Gold Sand town
as soon as you can
Don't listen to all the rumors,
that is all I have to say
Brother Yi Lung, we noble men
don't do such despicable acts
I come here to avenge
the death of my old friend
as you have no connection
to this matter
please step aside and
let me do my own investigation
You talk really big
You are now in my territory!
Let me enlighten you
The Black Bat is not here
he is in the mountains
you came to the wrong place!
Thank you for enlightening me
brother Yi lung
I will leave now
Yi Lung,
is this how you treat your guests?
I thought you might
try and pull a stunt like this
If I was afraid
I would not have come here
What are you going to do?!
Going to do?
Black Bat is my senior, his affairs
are also my affairs
Ta Kwai, attack him!
What do you think you are doing?
Attack! attack!
- They're fighting
- What now?
Jump!
Gold Sand Sword
Kill him!
Stand aside!
Kid, I'm keen to test
your Gold Sand sword
Father!
Tso Yi Lung,
did you kill my parents?
How should I know
who killed your parents
Shi Feng,
take uncle away from here
Let's go
Tso Yi Lung,
I will be back to settle this score
Until next time
- After him
- Stay back
I want that Gold Sand sword
in my possession, damn it!
Second brother
Senior brother
Even you are here
Senior brother, we got grief
Ting's son has shown up
and he's got the Gold Sand sword
and he's out for your head
I am no longer interested,
just ignore the boy
This lad is a martial arts expert
he uses the Gold Sand sword
to get his revenge on you
I have killed so many people
in my lifetime
He is the only descendant of Ting left,
let him go, forget about it
But if you don't kill him
he will kill you
Well if he does come looking for me
then he will go to an early grave
Stop bothering me
What about the Gold Sand sword
don't you want it?
Is that sword really so powerful?
- Without a doubt
- Yes
If senior brother does not want
the sword perhaps...
you would allow me to get it
Don't be too eager
Yes, yes
Forget about it
Senior brother, we're leaving
Brother Ting Yi
A penny for your thoughts
I can't find my enemy
I can't relax until I find him
You must be patient
I think you have something else to do
Shi Fong, the only thing that matters now
is to find my families killer
nothing else matters
Say... do you think Tso Yi Lung
could be the Black Bat
Ah Hsiung said he has seen Black Bat
let's ask him if Tso is Black Bat
Right, why didn't I think of that,
let's go and ask him
Good, let's go
Come back and play
Master Yu, Tso Yi Lung is coming
and he has lots of men with him
Your three days are up
I think you best leave today
Unless you can force out
The chief is coming
you tell that to him
Chief, Master Yu refuses to co-operate
Then we better enlighten him
Brother Xiao Cheng...
Brother Yi Lung,
you're taking this too far
Brother Xiao Cheng, do you want to know
the whereabouts of Black Bat?
If you can tell me
I'll leave here right away
On one condition,
you leave the Gold Sand sword with us
Your terms are too unreasonable
The Gold Sand sword
is not mine to give away
and even if it was, I would never
give it to the likes of you
I'll tell you this,
I could have killed you
I let you live a few more years
you know martial arts,
but you didn't learn your lesson
I... am sorry
it's a fierce fight
- Ah Hsiung, is he Black Bat?
- No... no he's not
Talk!
Master Yu... please spare me
Where is Black Bat?
He... he lives at
The Kingdom of Doom
Brother Yi... wait for me
Why are you following me?
I want to help you
This is my affair, I will do it alone,
I don't need any help
Black Bat, is a martial arts expert,
I am afraid you cannot beat him
If I do not go
I will be so worried about you
Thank you
My families martial arts
is considered one of the best in the land
should I manage to kill him
then I would re establish our name
I can't use other people
to avenge my family
I would not feel right,
Shi Fong, go back, I'll go alone
Shi Fong, don't be sad,
everyone has their own destiny
Don't be upset, I'm going
- Shi Fong
- Father
Don't be sad...
we will secretly follow him
Ferryman!
Ferryman take me across
I'll pay you extra
Ferryman, why do you stop?
Money, give me money
You want money, how much money?
One thousand tales of silver
One thousand tales?
Fine, once I have found the man I seek
I'll pay you what you want
Who are you looking for?
The man I seek is named Black Bat
what do you want with Black Bat?
I have urgent business with him
If you want to see him,
you have to pass me first
Let's go
if he can do that
why did he need that ferryboat?
Please have pity on me
Friend, I am blind,
please help me cross the bridge
Would you like me to help you
cross the bridge?
Thank you
Who are you?
Tell me!
I'm just a blind man
You're lying, tell me, who are you?
If you don't tell me, I'll kill you
I'm telling the truth,
I am just a blind man
So you're not blind!
Get out of here before I kill you!
Is this the way to Doomsday road?
Warrior..
I know the reason for you coming here
Revenge is a dish best served cold
but not in your case
I think you should forget about it
I must avenge my parents
If you insist on going through with it
you'll have to pass me first
So you are also
one of Black Bat's fighters?
Wait
Black Bat!
Black Bat come out!
Black Bat if you have got the guts
come out!
Black Bat come out!
So you must be
Ting Deng Cheng's son?
Let me tell you that I have retired
for you to have passed my three tests
you must be quite a good fighter
but you are still no match for me
you should turn back now
like a good boy
so that the Ting's
may have a next generation
You talk nonsense
Don't bite off more than you can chew
I've been through so much to get here
it's either you or me!
Father, mother...
I have tried my best to avenge you
You will never leave
the kingdom of Doom alive
Father, is he alright?
Will he...
Don't panic,
let's get him back to the inn
Father, take care of yourself
I can take care of myself
you two go and enjoy yourselves
Go
What's wrong with you?
You asked me to bring you here,
now you're here you don't want to go
look your boyfriend is going away