JL RANCH
Good morning, chickens.
We have to talk, Dad.
Hope this ain't a conspiracy
to keep me from my breakfast.
We're just trying to save you
from yourself.
And we're running out of time.
I could use a quiet breakfast.
Okay, me first.
As long as I get my say.
Fine, you won't let us save you,
then let us save this ranch.
You sound just like your mother.
Don't change the subject!
-The Bed and Breakfast.
-Oh, Rebecca.
-What?
-We've been through all this.
No is the answer, no.
What exactly do I do here, Dad?
Remind me, what explicitly
is it that I'm in charge of?
It's Lynnie comin' home today?
-No.
-Lynnie coming...
-Got youon a knife's edge.
-Lynnie's coming home?
It's the finances, Dad.
I'm supposed to help us
keep from going under and under
is exactly where we're going.
I can't control the weather, honey.
The drought doubled hay prices,
dropped our margin down to nothin'.
I told you not to buy that new tractor.
How was I to know Jimmy T.
was gonna bail,
leave us with the full weight?
A ranch is full of risks.
-We'll ride this out.
-Couple of months, Dad...
And we're not gonna be able to
afford to feed our own stock.
Regan, are you on board
with this B&B nonsense?
That cedar house
is your family home.
Yeah, I know, Daddy,
and that's why
I have an alternate proposal.
-I am never gonna get my breakfast.
-Okay, listen.
Regan and Jerry can afford
their own house, Dad.
I drove nails, girls,
in that porch
when I was eight years old.
I'll make the decision who lives
in that house.
This is an asset
that we need to exploit, okay?
The B&B can help us
create a brand
that we can monetize.
The only brand we need
around here is the one I put
on the hind end of a calf.
-Good morning, Grandpa.
-Oh, here we go.
We got eggs.
Yeah, breakfast. Thanks, boys.
He had ol' blue eyes up
with the chickens.
Now look, Daddy, you're right.
The cedar house is my home
and I don't intend to leave it
but we don't need to turn our ranch
into an amusement park.
There's another way to get even.
Are you listening to me?
All right. All right, Regan, what is it?
Sell Parcel 14 or maybe Parcel Six...
and we wipe out our debt.
Those parcels are our land...
which we ain't sellin'.
I know that you mean well, Regan,
but selling dirt is a one-time solution.
Hey, it's not gonna generate
any income after that.
What if we need money again?
What are we gonna do?
-Jerry proposed to me in that house.
-Oh, here we go.
And my babies took
their first steps inside it.
You know, the only thing holding
you and Jerry back
is dad's generosity.
This could be the best thing
that happened to both of you.
You know, it's easy for you
to talk about bootin' me
and my children out of our home,
because your own daughter
won't even...
Don't even, don't even go there.
Daddy, where are you goin'?
Daddy, come on back here
and eat a proper breakfast, please.
I will make it for you.
It's all good.
You never listen.
Good morning, Grandpa.
Hey, Ty.
What are you grinning at?
Nothin' like a hearty breakfast
to start the day. Huh, boss man?
You got a sadistic aspect.
Are you aware of that?
What did you have for breakfast?
Some of my wife's perfect little,
beautiful chilaquiles, yeah.
I ain't interested.
I'm sorry I brought it up.
Let's go. Haw!
Go. Go.
Keep your eye on Big Redhead.
I'm on it, John.
Yeah, I see
that ol' trouble maker, John.
Round 'em up.
Come on, boys, round 'em up.
Haw!
When Rebecca gets something
in her craw...
boy, she keeps chewin' on it
and chewin' on it.
Just a little swelling. No abscess.
Oh, that's good. Here.
But Regan stood right up to her,
toe to toe this morning.
Yeah, I don't think Rebecca's ideas
are half bad, though.
So, she got to you behind my back?
No.
No, no, I'm neutral like Canada.
-Besides, none of my business.
-Yeah.
Switzerland.
Neutral like Switzerland.
John! Hector!
Wolf!
That's it, that's it now.
It's $50,000 fine
if you kill a wolf, John.
Wolves cost me
more than that this past month.
Yeah, but it's the law.
You used to be sheriff, didn't ya?
Back then,
the law was closer to common sense.
This ain't that.
-Where is it, Tio?
-Tree line.
Some of them wolves
are tagged, John.
Think about it.
You'll have Parks and Wildlife
all over you like stink on pigs.
Get outta here!
I see you again,
I'll make you into a coat.
Hey, how ya doing there?
All right, sir.
Darn it!
-Sorry about that.
-That's alright.
Yeah.
There's your county.
Some people still hunt their food.
Yes, sir.
Anyways...
this land I was talking about was...
Well, the boundary...
It starts just about right here,
this fence and it goes
north and west
all the way
that Forest Service firebreak.
Yes, sir, we'll get
the boundaries to the Capitol
by the end of day.
Well, gosh darn. I sure appreciate
that extra work, Frank.
-Yes, sir.
-That is Frank, isn't it?
-Yes.
-See, I knew that 'cause...
one of the boys said you'd meet a guy,
Frank, who's got a...
a wedding anniversary
coming up soon, is that right?
-Nine years, nine years.
-That's the man.
Not too many people respect
that institute of marriage anymore.
Here you go.
Mr. Peterson, sir...
My daddy was Mr. Peterson,
my name is Tap.
Tap, sir, I can't take this.
Listen, let me tell you
something. I...
I enjoy giving gifts
to people I respect,
and what I will not like is
if you don't spend every dime
of that on that young lady.
Yes, sir.
See this, this land back here
it all belonged to my family.
In time, it was stolen from us.
I mean, you could understand
how an old man would feel about that.
Yes, sir.
Well, I appreciate your work.
I look forward to seeing you again.
Far cry from the big city, I guess.
Never been myself.
I don't like the traffic.
I guess that's kinda funny,
a driver who don't like traffic.
But that's why everybody calls me.
See I know all the backroads,
all the shortcuts...
Do you mind?
I haven't been home in years,
so I would like to spend
some quiet time with my thoughts.
-Yes, Ma'am.
-Thanks.
I will have one of the guys
put it in your pickup.
Thank you, sir.
All right.
Makings of a fine spread.
Now what is the occasion?
None of your business,
Ethan Peterson.
Thank you.
Speaking of business, Rebecca,
how are things at JL Ranch?
Never better. Thanks for asking.
Yeah, that's a welcome surprise.
-Is it now?
-Yeah.
'Cause Daddy and me...
we heard different.
Well, you must have manure
in your ears.
As well as in between 'em.
Excuse me, Ethan.
Oh, boy.
Same ol', same ol'.
Have a seat.
Morning, Miss Rebecca.
Sheriff, is there a problem?
Yeah.
Tail light's out.
No, it's not.
What do you want, Henry?
I heard Lynnie was comin' home today.
Yeah, well, you never know with Lynnie.
Where'd you hear that?
I got my connections.
I might not be quite as stealthy
as your dad was when he wore
the star, but I get around.
I bet she's been
through some changes.
School and all, city life.
You must be excited.
I'm scared to death.
You? Scared?
From what little she did say to me,
it's looking like she wants to open
things up about her dad,
maybe seek him out.
Well...
only natural, I guess,
after all this time.
Yeah, well, make one big mistake
and it just follows me,
and follows me,
and follows me, you know?
You have always been a loving mom.
I'm sure Lynnie can see that...
now she's older.
No, your real mistake
was choosing him over me.
Please, you weren't even
in the picture then, Henry.
-Shut your face.
-Well, in my heart I was.
Always.
What'd your dad say about it?
Oh, you know him.
Never says more
than there's necessary.
"All will work itself out."
That's what he always says.
I'm a good sounding board
if you need one.
Thank you, Henry.
I appreciate it. I wish there
was something you could do.
Try me.
I gotta get going.
Don't you have a job to do
or something like that?
Okay. Well...
I'm gonna let you off
with a warning this time.
-Okay.
-You just remember...
I'm always watching those tail lights.
Get outta here, Henry.
Hello? Anybody home?
Hello?
Anybody home?
Grandpa?
Howdy.
Who are you?
My name's Terrence.
Lookin' for John Landsburg.
I need a job.
And you just walked
into this house?
Yeah.
What's the matter with you?
Didn't your parents
teach you manners?
Nah, they weren't around much.
Well, if you're looking
for my grandfather,
step out there
and the first hand you see,
ask them where the office is
and then wait.
Might it be a long wait, Miss...
John Landsburg's granddaughter.
And it could be all day.
Well, John Landsburg's granddaughter,
it just so happens I got all day.
Cowboys.
-Hey, John, Lynnie's here.
-Who said that?
I just dropped her off this morning.
-She at the house?
-That's what I heard.
-Hey, Lynnie!
-Grandpa.
Hey, kid, how ya doing?
-Hey, Grandpa.
-Hey, honey.
-Oh, it's good to have you home.
-I missed you.
You got your same room waitin'.
-Yeah?
-It ain't been touched.
Hope you're going
to stay a little while.
-Hey, Hector.
-Hey, girl.
There's a man waitin' for you
by your office.
Says he's lookin' for work.
He walked right into
your kitchen without askin'.
Well, ain't that nice.
There's your mother.
Go to her.
Go to her, Lynnie.
I'll take that, Miss Landsburg.
-Hey, Mom.
-Hey, girl.
Didn't think you'd make it.
Seemed like it was time.
Well... come here.
She looks good.
All grown up.
Yup.
Howdy.
Enterin' my house
without permission.
Layin' about.
Not the best way
to get yourself a job,
if that's what you're lookin' for.
You must be John Landsburg.
That's right.
Ever worked a gather before?
-Let's talk inside.
-Won't be necessary, sir.
Mr. Landsburg,
you been served.
Served what?
Well, ain't you a little snake.
Sorry to be
the bearer of bad news.
I mean that.
Get out of here, son.
Go back where you came from.
How can they take private property
that's bought and paid for?
They can't, can they?
We need to see the deed.
Where is it?
I don't know, I'll look around.
All right, you find it.
Thanks, Paul.
I'll call when I know more.
Hey, Grandpa. Mom said dinner
will be ready in half an hour
if you wanna go get washed up.
Is everything all right?
Fine, honey.
Especially now that you're home.
I'll... I'll make myself pretty.
Uncle Brady.
Hey there, City Lights.
Long time. You grew up real nice.
-Lynnie!
-Aunt Regan.
Hey. Hey, bud!
-Hi, Tyler.
-I'm so happy you're home.
Hi, Hayden. Who is this?
-That's Devin.
-Devin, you've gotten so big.
Careful, Devin.
City girls are known to be
a little tricky.
-Dinner's ready.
-Grandpa.
-Careful now.
-Oh, watch out.
Easy does it.
Because they were two shellfish.
-I didn't find that funny at all.
-Let me ask you,
has anybody been paying
attention to Devin.
Go easy on the collective us.
...you gotta build that muscle.
Grandpa, I gotta say the ranch
looks as good as the day I left.
Thank you, Lynnie.
Boys...
I remember
when your cousin Lynnie
roped her first deer.
Oh, yeah?
It dragged her through the mud
for about 50 yards.
If Becca hadn't yelled to let go,
she'd still be hanging onto that rope.
How old were you?
I don't remember.
Nine, maybe?
She let loose, jumped up,
stood straight up,
proud as can be, ran to her mother,
wrapped her muddy arms around her.
She was a dirt ball.
Stubbornest little girl I met.
Probably take after my father.
Not that I ever met him.
What do you think, Mom?
Would you call my father
a stubborn man?
How come you hardly ever visit?
Busy, Devin.
I like living in the city,
traveling and I had
a heavy course load in college.
So, why was it you stayed away
for so long?
Your big sister knows why.
Past is the past.
You're home now.
And that's all that matters.
I'll drink to that.
-Here, here.
-Water, I hope.
Absolutely. Nothing
but for the past 13 months.
-Good boy.
-Hey, it's great.
Good for you, son.
-Thanks, Pops.
-Good boy.
-Cheers.
-Good work.
When your great grandma
and grandpa...
Nellie and Jeremiah, when they first...
saw this land, they said,
"This is the most beautiful
place on God's earth."
There was almost nothin' here then.
No roads to speak of.
And they... they built...
this little stone house.
And that's how they survived
the first winter in that house.
They survived storms of all kinds and...
and fires, predators.
And they brought the first calves
up into this area.
Little by little...
they made this ranch.
They saw it was good and they said,
"This is for our grandchildren
and their children."
They passed it down to us.
I've seen some of the world, Lynnie,
in the service and such.
I ain't never been happier
much anyplace else.
I don't have to go nowhere.
Now...
Who wants some pie?
I do.
I know you do.
I want some pie.
I know it's not my business, sugar.
You're right, Aunt Regan,
it's not your business.
Go easy on your mother.
This is hard on her, too.
Hey, guest of honor doesn't do dishes.
What's going on here?
Just showing my appreciation.
By all means, carry on then.
Well, you can take over for me.
I can do that.
Thanks, Regan.
You...
look good, Lynn. Beautiful.
Don't bother.
It's not a happy place for me.
I don't want to be here
any longer than I have to be.
All right, then why are you here?
What do you want?
You know what I want.
We have been over this 1,000 times.
Your father took a walk
long before you were born
and hasn't been seen since.
Biggest mistake of my life.
My father was a mistake?
A mistake that led
to the greatest blessing of my life.
That doesn't cut it, Mom.
It didn't when I was a kid,
and I'm not a kid anymore.
No, you're not.
Honey, you are a beautiful,
young woman.
Just stop with the down-home syrup.
I got enough of that
with Grandpa's speech.
Hey, girls.
Lynnie, you must be tired
from your trip.
You better get some shut eye.
Chores start at 04:30.
What are you talking about?
No freeloaders here, darlin',
you know that.
You gotta pull your weight.
You'll get paid a fair wage
like everyone else.
Sundays off for church.
Say good night to your mother.
She and I got some business
to attend to.
Go on, sweetie.
-Cut a trail to bed.
-Good night. Mom.
Night, Lynn.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.
Hey...
give it a couple of days.
Let's get some air.
That kid today...
served me with papers
from the Bureau of Homeland
Management.
They're trying to seize a chunk
of our ranch.
What?
How are they gonna do that,
eminent domain?
They have to make an offer,
set a court hearing.
They say they're not renewing
our lease.
What lease?
We don't lease. We own
every inch of this property.
I know. That's what I don't get.
What part of the ranch
are they talking about?
107.6631 West.
That's Parcel 14.
The southwest side.
Butcher Hill.
Where the big well is.
Yeah, the big well.
That well recharges the ponds,
provides all the water for the ranch.
And half the others in the valley
during drought times.
So...
that's what this is all about.
Water.
Oh, thanks, man.
Hey, darlin'.
Wanna come give her a try?
Go on now.
She was rejected by her momma,
so if we don't get a bottle in her soon
we might lose her.
As I remember,
you had a way with the cows
when you were little.
Okay.
All right now, come on, sugar.
That a girl, that a girl.
That a girl. Easy, easy.
Okay.
That a girl.
Pack it in, Lynnie.
You put in a good day's work.
How did it feel?
I'm going to go into town,
you wanna come?
No, I'm wiped.
-Okay.
-All right.
I'm proud of you.
I'm proud of you, honey.
-Grandpa, Grandpa...
-Hey, kid.
-Grandpa.
-Take it easy, take it easy.
What is it, champ?
Just slow down, take a breath.
I got a B on my report card.
Dad says he's taking us out
to rejoice at the impossibility.
I don't know what that means.
That means work well done,
that's what it means.
Congratulations, Son. Here.
Yeah.
Dad said you have
a meeting in town.
Yeah, a long boring meeting.
Why don't I give you a ride?
We'll take my truck.
Go tell your daddy.
Can we talk?
-About what, honey?
-I don't know.
Something's goin' on.
I wanna know about it.
Let me finish up
and I'll get back to you.
-Daddy...
-Nothin' for you to worry about.
I know grandpa's ready
because he has his rifle.
Why do you got your gun, Grandpa?
Well, ain't we huntin' for tacos?
You don't hunt for tacos, Grandpa.
You don't?
What do you do with them
squirrelly creatures?
-You eat 'em.
-Eat 'em.
Oh, boy. Get in. Get in the truck.
-Come on, guys. Buckle up.
-Everybody in.
-Grandpa?
-Yeah, Ty?
Why do you bring
your rifle everywhere?
Well, Ty, nature's unpredictable.
Most days are calm,
but you should always
be prepared for storms.
Besides...
we got precious cargo on board.
Ain't that right, Jerry?
I don't know about precious.
Well, they ain't too ugly.
Get in there.
All right, everybody in?
Would you tell me the truth
if I asked you to?
Yes, always.
There's something going on
with Daddy
and he won't tell me what it is.
You have to ask him, Regan.
But he told you.
I deal with a lot of things
on this ranch that don't involve you.
Nah, this is my home, too.
The Bureau is trying to take
Parcel 14,
and they say that our lease is up,
and it's not to be renewed.
I thought we owned all this property.
We do which is why
it doesn't make any sense,
but the big well is on that block.
Wait, what?
The big well is on 14?
I thought it was on nine.
No, it used to be on nine,
but when we granted the easement
to the Forest Service
for the firebreak,
the boundaries shifted.
Well, I didn't know that.
Well, the point is
the big well is on 14.
We lose 14, we lose our water.
Well, it's all
some bureaucratic snafu, right?
We're gonna find out.
But you can't say anything
to anybody, you hear me?
Why would I say anything?
I'm hungry.
Martha, hi, how are you?
Honey...
Where's my bundle?
Here we go.
I want a quesadilla
with extra cheese.
Well, you earned it.
This is your night.
I'm getting five.
Hey, one quesadilla at a time,
young man. Come on.
Hi, Mom!
Hi, baby.
What was that?
Did you tell her?
Yeah, she took it pretty hard.
Check and see if anybody else
had been served.
I'm gonna do one thing
with the kids and I'll join you.
Okay, you tell Mabel I said hey.
Don't get cute.
Hey, John.
I want you to do
something special for Devin.
-Oh.
-Little... Little celebration.
How about a sundae,
with some rainbow sprinkles on it,
some whipped cream, cherry.
I'll pretty it up nice.
-That'll do it.
-John Landsburg.
Aren't you even gonna say hello?
Laura Lee.
I haven't seen you in town
for a while, Laura Lee.
Yeah well, technically
I'm still a resident.
I believe I can come and go
as I please.
Well, I ain't pryin'
into your personal.
And you retired
as sheriff of this town
a while back, didn't you?
-Peace.
-Come, sit down.
Come on, sit down.
Well, maybe for a second.
So, I hear you're having
a little trouble with your land.
Is that so?
Where'd you hear that?
Well, you know me,
gossip is my middle name.
But if there's nothing going on,
then I didn't hear anything.
-Things aren't so bad.
-Really?
I'm happy to hear that.
I do care about you, you know.
Well, this is something
of a reversal.
You puttin' aside hostilities.
Well, you know,
that was the echo of old times.
Yeah, sometimes those echoes
can be tricky.
Our echoes were pretty tricky.
So, how's your parents' house doing?
Tap Peterson's interested
in takin' it off my hands.
You and Tap are talkin' business?
You gotta go where the money is.
I was thinking of selling
some land myself.
Really?
Maybe to the Bureau.
-Really?
-You have any connections there?
Why would I have any connections
at the Bureau?
Well, you always seem to know...
all the players.
Can't help you.
I'm late.
Okey-dokey.
Nice to see you, Laura Lee.
Nice to see you, John.
Evening. How are ya?
How you doing?
How are ya, sweetie.
You see Tap working the room?
I ran into Laura Lee Schaefer
at the Hash.
That harpy.
Every time I think
of the two of you together...
Well, don't think about it then.
She seemed to know our troubles.
-How?
-Got me.
But she told me
that Tap's interested
in buying her parents' place.
She's never gonna sell that.
Maybe not.
But Tap, the Bureau, Laura Lee,
I think it's all connected somehow.
-Really?
-I got a feeling.
Hey.
I'd like to call this meeting to order.
Look, I've sent pictures,
I've sent vet bills,
I've even sent 'em fur samples
and all they ever tell me
is the wolves are protected.
Don't worry, they're not gonna
listen to you. Nobody else does.
Are we going to be reimbursed
for our losses or not?
Not as long as the greenies
are in bed with the feds.
Which they are.
-That's right.
-John, you've had wolf trouble,
would you like
to speak about that?
Well, I believe that we should
get this whole valley
declared a wolf sanctuary
and put in for eight-figure subsidies.
Pencil me in for some of that, John.
Yeah? Well, give me your number.
But, you know, we had this,
this Senator Archer.
I don't know what he's doing
down in Washington, D. C.
behind that desk.
I'll tell you what he's doing, zero.
Well, he should be out here
with his constituency
seeing what we're faced with.
What do you think, Tap?
The governor's your golfin' buddy.
Oh, yeah, yeah, he was but...
last time we played I beat him
like a red-headed stepchild.
He won't pick up my calls anymore.
But I tell you what.
I do have some friends there
and I guarantee I will
get in touch with some of 'em.
You're going to take care of that?
I just said I would.
Any other business to come
before the meeting?
You all know what happened
in Washoba County.
The Bureau came in there
and condemned three ranches.
Eminent domain, whatever that is.
And all the ranchers in that area,
they all folded...
just stepped back, let em' take it.
That ain't gonna happen here.
No way.
We gotta stick together
or they'll take
the whole valley from us.
-Absolutely.
-That's right.
Anybody here been approached
by the Bureau recently?
The Bureau wouldn't come down here
and try to pull any of that stuff.
They know better.
Meeting adjourned.
Okay. Will see you.
Tap.
Yeah?
Can I have a word?
What do you need?
Has the Bureau
of Homeland Management
approached you in any way?
Been by your place?
Nah.
Yours?
What do you know, Tap?
I believe that I know...
that you're about to get
what you got coming.
Oh?
Yeah, see, you know
funny thing about getting old...
the past sometimes fades,
but sometimes it gets a little stronger.
And the bad thing about that
is that you can't do
a darn thing about it.
But you are doing something
about it now.
Yes, sir, I am.
That land...
you're about to lose...
the land your grandfather stole
from mine.
I'm going to do everything
I possibly can...
to get that land back.
No Landsburg ever stole a thing
from a Peterson
and you know as well as I do
that your grandfather
sold that land to the government
and my grandfather
bought it from them fair and square.
No, he leased it.
The deed to that property
has been in my family
for 100 years.
Hundred years.
If it was that simple, I imagine
all you have to do
is just show me that deed.
You're lookin' for trouble,
aren't you, Tap?
I was born for it, John.
A lot of people don't know that.
But I know...
that you do.
Hey, boys, what's the good word?
Just...
couple of good ol' boys just...
lying to each other
like they usually do.
You take care, buddy.
Sorry to bust that up.
Looked like you were getting ready
to have a bit of a good go.
There'll be another time.
-Thanks, Flo.
-I'll take one of those, Flo.
Seat taken?
It is now.
What?
I still remember the first time
I saw you drink a beer.
-Oh, yeah?
-County Fair.
It was the year you won
the barrel race at the rodeo.
You were a sight to behold, girl.
So strong, graceful.
And so much younger.
You're still
a beautiful woman, Rebecca.
All right.
So, how's things with Lynnie?
My goodness, how do you think
things are with Lynnie?
No idea she was going
to be so angry.
You should come clean with her,
Rebecca.
It'll be better for you both
in the long run.
Oh, you think so?
I know so.
Well, thanks for that, Doc.
I appreciate that.
No charge.
You've been very good to me, Henry,
you know that?
We should do something fun.
What do you say?
Riding or I don't know.
Anytime.
I got an ice cream
with rainbow sprinkles, Grandpa.
Rainbow sprinkles, holy smokes.
Did you get...
get any sugar in that?
-Yeah.
-Yes?
That's no good.
Here, double up.
-Sit on your brother.
-Get up there.
-Sit on me.
-All right, squeeze in.
I ran into John Landsburg tonight.
Oh, good. Were you drivin'?
I hope it was that big truck.
It's a little late
for being funny, isn't it, Tap?
What can I do for you, honey?
I don't think that you should
go through with this.
Oh, you don't think
I should go through with it?
No, it's not going to end well.
I thought that you
and John were...
were done.
It is.
It's just that if John doesn't know
what's going on now,
he's gonna know real soon.
No worries, sweetie,
he already knows.
I told him to his face today.
Why would you do that?
Listen, let me explain
something to you.
When my grandfather
lost that land with the water on it...
it tore the man apart.
And he got a bit drunk...
and then he went ahead
and torched down
every building on the property.
And next, thrown in jail.
My family just got robbed.
And now I... I got a chance
to make things right.
And there's nothing
that John Landsburg can do about it.
And for you, my dear,
you'll get your money
when the deal is done,
but you gotta
keep that mouth of yours shut.
Is that understood?
What kind of beers
you got on tap?
We got Red Rocket,
Cutthroat Porter,
and Black Tooth on tap
or the list of bottles on the menu.
You don't remember me, do ya?
Can't say I do. Should I?
Happens all the time.
I go places with Clarence
and nobody ever looks at me.
Well, I can't blame them.
You know Clarence,
he leaves an indelible impression.
You remember him, right?
Big fella,
fancy boots.
What can I do for ya?
I'm working right now.
Well, you missed
your deadline, chief.
It's time to pay up.
Look, I always honor my debts,
but I'm a bit short right now.
I'll need a couple of weeks.
Download your daddy's financials
onto this.
You do that and we're square.
My pop with a computer?
You might as well ask for the keys
to his space shuttle.
That's real funny, chief.
What kind of computer
does Rebecca use, hmm?
Look, we wanna know
who your daddy owes money
to and how much.
So tomorrow, I'll be back.
Maybe I'll get myself a beer then,
but you might not even notice me
'cause I'll be bringing
Clarence with me.
You.
-Terrence, ma'am.
-You worm, you process server.
You better get outta here,
get off this property.
You're trespassing, cabrn.
Who sent you?
What are you doing here?
You got nerve coming down here.
I'm looking for your grandfather.
Well, you found him.
Let him up, Hector.
Got any more bad news
for me, son?
I'm looking for work.
That's getting a little old.
Mr. Landsburg, I do need work,
I'm flat broke.
You seem like a fair man.
Who hired you
to deliver those papers?
You have to be registered
to serve in this state.
-You okay, Lynnie?
-I'm fine, Brady.
You sure, girl?
Like you care, Mom.
You registered...
or not?
I am. I got the papers
at the courthouse in the Capitol.
You didn't get 'em
from Tap Peterson?
No, sir.
I don't know the man.
I just, I need a job.
Well, assuming
that you can work cattle
better than you can fight,
you got a job.
You start tomorrow morning, early.
-Hector, get him settled.
-Boss.
-Hector.
-Thank you, sir.
Dad.
No references,
no discussion with your CFO.
-You hire a total stranger.
-That's right.
Why?
He just lied to me again.
I'm sure he knows Tap.
Then get him the hell out of here.
If we keep him close,
we got a better chance
of finding out what he knows.
About what?
Tap Peterson is using
the Bureau of Homeland Management
to come after our property.
-How the hell can he do that?
-Brady...
-Are you gambling again?
-No.
What does that have
to do with anything?
Well, just tryin'
to put the pieces together.
Yeah well,
I ain't one of 'em, Pop.
-Where are you going?
-A little road trip.
Well, I'm coming with you.
You need to straighten things out
with Lynnie.
Maybe it's time
you told her the truth.
Tell me about my father.
Okay, so...
I focused on guys your mom's age
or up to five years older
'cause I figured
why waste a bunch of time
on a bunch of younger dudes
and if they're too much older,
it's kinda creepy.
Jeremy, what've we got?
I checked...
databases, birth records,
high school yearbooks,
I checked rodeos
and county fairs.
I came up
with nine likely suspects.
Lynnie?
-What is it, Mother?
-Hey, what are you doing?
I'm talking to a hacker I hired
to try to find my father.
Hi. Hi, I'm Jeremy.
Goodbye, Jeremy.
You don't need to do that.
I'll tell you
what you need to know.
I think we scanned and digitized
everything back in '05.
Look, here we go.
Well, that is
my grandfather's signature.
Hang on, zooming in.
Well, this ain't right.
My grandfather
couldn't have signed that.
Look, if we leased
there would've been renewals.
Show me the records
for the renewal payments.
Well, actually, I can't.
Oh, you can't.
It seems that there was...
a clerical error in your favor.
According to my supervisor,
the Bureau was unaware
that you stopped
paying on your lease.
Or that it had even expired
until... until recently
and in most cases,
the Bureau would take legal action
for any back payments owed, but...
you were granted a reprieve,
we're just not renewing
the lease.
Don't that sound
like a bunch a bull to you?
It does to me.
Let me speak to your supervisor.
Let's do that.
Right now.
I was 17 and he was a year older
than I was.
Your grandpa and grandma
had told me not to mess with him,
stay away from him and...
But I was young
and stupid and rebellious, so...
-Was he cute?
-Oh, yeah, of course he was.
Your grandpa knew
that he was into bad things.
There was a reason that
trouble followed him everywhere, but...
but I took your father's side
and yeah,
he was attractive and strong-willed.
You got that from him.
But...
he didn't have much character.
And at the end of the day,
sweetheart,
character is all that matters, okay?
So, what happened?
Well, your grandpa
caught us together...
threw him out hard and told me
never to see him again
and I didn't.
A month later I found out
I was pregnant.
And I went looking for him,
but he was gone.
Left town, disappeared forever.
Apparently.
Mom, what was his name?
His name is Caleb Peterson.
He's Tap Peterson's boy.
Well, with all the bad blood
between our families,
I really couldn't stand the idea
of you knowing that Tap Peterson
was your granddad.
I need to meet my father.
I need to find him.
We have looked for years,
your grandpa and I.
Don't the Petersons
know where he is?
They have always said no.
So, we just stopped asking.
If he's alive, I will find him.
I love you, baby.
I know you're in a tough spot,
Mr. Landsburg, and I sympathize,
but I can guarantee you
this is not a forgery.
You've won some awards.
Yeah, if you like,
you can file a complaint.
We can try to dig up
the original in D. C.
But if what you tell me is true,
I suggest you produce
your own copy of the deed,
signed and notarized, of course.
Let's do both.
Just to be sure.
And I'd like a printout
of that deed in your computer.
Agent McCarthy will help you
file the complaint.
You have to fill out a form
for a copy of the deed.
You can't just print one out?
Again, I sympathize,
but rules are rules.
Have a nice day.
Yeah, it's Jennings.
Guess who just paid me a visit.
John Landsburg. Call me.
DEED
-Hey, Daddy.
-Hey.
What are you looking for?
The deed.
The original deed to Butcher's Hill.
Butcher's Hill?
What we used to call Parcel 14.
I got deeds and titles
to everything else...
but Butcher's Hill is missing.
Well, you want me
to help you find it?
No, I'm done. It's not here.
Grew legs and walked away.
You mind puttin' this
back together a little bit for me?
Oh, yeah, sure, Daddy.
Yeah, I'll tidy up.
Thank you, thank you, sweetie.
Watch your step now.
I would never turn my back
on my family.
I mean, in the end...
family is all you got, you know?
Whoa.
I know I've held back
from you, Henry.
And I thought it was
about my past and...
who I was, but it's not.
It's about fear, plain and simple.
Fear of taking
that next step with you
and it is... It is still there.
I'll never hurt you, Rebecca.
I brought you out here
for a reason, Henry,
and it wasn't just for the ride.
I'm sorry.
Well, what am I doing here?
Tap Peterson is trying
to take our land from us.
Tap and the Bureau.
And we're running out of time,
running out of options.
Can you please stop him?
Well, that depends,
Miss Landsburg.
On what, Sheriff Whitlock?
If Tap Peterson
is doing something illegal
to take your property
and I can prove it,
or at least
find probable cause
then yes, I can stop him,
I'll be glad to do so.
But I take the star
and my oath of office seriously.
Just like your father did.
Oh, God. So, that's it?
You're gonna hide behind the law?
No, I'm gonna uphold it.
Your father wouldn't have it
any other way.
Neither would you.
Don't be so sure, Henry.
The sheriff,
that's your mother's boyfriend?
I don't know,
I've never seen her date anyone.
Where's your father?
I don't know you well enough
to talk about that sort of thing.
You seem a little hostile
towards your folks.
You don't know anything
about my family.
-I know they care about you.
-You think so?
Shoot, my daddy never looked me
in the eye his whole life.
He just sat in his Barcalounger
drinkin' blended Scotch whiskey.
-And your mom?
-My mom, she worked two jobs,
hated her life,
hated everything about it.
I don't even think they noticed
when I left.
Grandpa gave it to me.
It's my grandmother Elizabeth.
She was a beautiful woman.
You take after her.
You know I'm going to LA,
the first chance I get.
Why don't you go now?
What's stoppin' you?
Well, it sure isn't you,
if that's what you think.
John Landsburg
durin' daylight hours?
Isn't there work
to be done somewhere?
I just spent three hours
looking through real estate records
at the courthouse.
No luck?
-What's this?
-Got somethin' for you.
Really?
Duke Ellington at Fargo, 1949.
-Wow!
-It's a good one?
Oh, it's a classic, John.
What a thoughtful gift.
It was in the attic.
I just thought... you might like it.
That guy at the Bureau...
playin' games,
givin' me the runaround.
Oh, boy.
You're one big knot, John.
How's that feel?
Nice.
If you try to jump
through every hoop
the Bureau puts in front of you,
you will be on a walker
before you ever get anywhere.
I know he's lying.
I gotta fight him out.
Can't let him on my land.
I'll never get 'em off.
No, you're right, you won't.
And they'll kill you in court,
take all your money.
You'll have nothing left.
I know what my mother would say.
What?
Someone needs a good spanking.
-I like your mother.
-My mother's always right.
Hello, Terrence.
Is Mr. Peterson here, ma'am?
Well...
He's in his study but...
Can I speak to him?
It's really late.
It's important.
Mr. Peterson, sorry it's so late.
Hey, son,
how's your grandpa?
You're a real McCall, you know.
He's as well as can be expected.
He just finished
his first round of chemo.
Have a seat.
Without your help, you know,
he would be...
dead by now.
You know, we...
we do pray for him every night.
Thank you.
I'd sure like to know
what brings you
to my house at this hour.
Is there something
I can do for you?
What am I doin'
at John Landsburg's ranch?
Well, you're workin' there...
until I tell you not to.
See, I'd like to...
know everything he's doing.
Always wondering that...
that little college girl
that got out there?
Lynn.
What about her?
Well, I mean she is sure...
a cute little thing, isn't she?
If you say so.
If I say so?
Well, I'd like you to...
just kinda stay away from her,
all right, son?
Why is that?
Well, mainly
'cause I just asked you to.
Just stay away from her.
It looks like it's going to snow.
You oughta be heading home,
don't you think?
Goodnight, son.
Goodnight, sir.
NOTICE OF SEIZURE
Daddy.
Forty-eight hours?
Yeah, seems like Tap can't wait.
Well, there's got to be
somethin' we can do.
Bed and breakfast, sell a parcel.
Maybe you were both right.
Yeah, but it's too late
for all that now, isn't it?
I gotta get my hands
on that deed.
Somebody took it.
But who?
Sweetie.
Rebecca's got her mother's fire,
but you got her heart.
You got her heart, honey.
I miss her.
That's for you, thank you so much.
Have a good day.
Hey, where you goin'?
To see my granddaddy,
Tap Peterson.
What? Now?
Lynnie.
Gosh darn it, girl.
Are you kidding me?
Oh, gosh.
Sorry to interrupt the concert
but I think it's time you and me
did something crazy.
I'll get my boots on.
Excuse me.
Look...
outside of the ranch...
Hi, I'm your granddaughter.
Excuse me?
Your son Caleb Peterson
is my father.
Well, where did you come up
with a story like that?
I want to find my father.
That's nice, but...
see we're gonna have
a little problem here because...
I really don't want to talk to you.
You're a Landsburg and...
I don't like talking to Landsburgs.
They give me indigestion.
You're a coward,
and your son Caleb, my father,
is just a chip off the old block.
Look, young lady,
I don't much care
what you say about me...
but my son...
is not a coward.
I'm sure he has reasons
for running off like he did.
It's a pretty good thing, too.
But let me tell you something
there's no way on God's earth...
that I'll let me son run off with...
any one of John's daughters.
None.
But I happened, what about me?
Collateral damage.
Hey, hold it.
Hold it, hold it.
Come here a minute.
Okay, you can go now.
Lynn, what's going on, baby?
What happened?
Talk to me.
I'm here, honey.
Okay, come on.
What are you doing here?
How did you get in my house?
Easy there, Mr. Jennings.
You can't do this.
I'm a federal agent.
You're a pencil-pushin' bureaucrat
and a liar.
You're gonna lose a lot more
than just your property, Landsburg.
Hey, wait, wait, wait. John, wait.
Listen...
do not get him riled up.
The last time you met,
you got him really riled up.
Don't even say anything.
Nod your head.
Okay, good.
You know, John, come on.
Just don't shoot him.
He didn't mean any harm.
He's just following orders.
That's right.
-Whose orders?
-Charlie Lincoln in Washington.
Never heard of him.
He works for Senator Archer.
Come here.
Sit down.
Keep talking.
Charlie said to get that parcel.
So, I took the signature
from the original deed
and I pasted it into the fake
and uploaded it into the system.
All I had to do
was backdate the file
to match the time frame
and the personnel
to when we originally
digitized the records.
Where's the deed?
Shredded.
How much did you get
for ruining a man's life?
Promotion to GS-15.
How's Tap Peterson involved?
Come on, you can say it, just,
just come on.
Tap owned the pillar cliffs
along the river.
Senator Archer wanted that land
for the Bureau to designate it
like a monument to himself.
The only way Tap would
get rid of that property
was to trade it for yours.
Some lady brokered the deal.
Schaefer or Shaffer.
Laura Lee.
Okay, that's it.
We're good, John.
We'll see ourselves out.
And we thank you
for your cooperation, Mr. Jennings.
And then you said to him,
"You can say it, come on."
Yeah, yeah, come on.
Come on.
Look, we got company here.
Henry.
I heard an ugly rumor out
of the Capitol.
Some supervisor at the Bureau
got himself threatened at gunpoint.
No kidding.
Know anything about that?
Not a thing, Sheriff. You?
Nope.
I guess it must just be
a rumor then.
I heard something, too.
Not just a rumor.
A supervisor admitted
that the deed they have on file
is a forgery.
Do you have any proof of that
other than your word?
No.
But you do have my word.
John that's not evidence,
that's respect.
I guess respect's not worth
what it used to be.
No, sir, it is not.
But it's important to me
though that you know how I feel.
I appreciate that.
You got to know,
I need to be there tomorrow,
when the Bureau comes.
Sure.
All right.
Hey, John.
This is a surprise.
No, it isn't.
Do you want a drink?
No.
Fixin' it up to sell, huh?
No, I'm not gonna sell
this place.
It's too many memories here.
Your daddy ran me off
a couple of times.
Well, serves you right
for sneaking into
an innocent girl's bedroom.
I guess you were never innocent.
No.
Why'd you do it, Laura?
Why help Tap destroy my family?
For the commission, John.
Girl's gotta eat.
You know...
there's always a place
for you here.
If you need it, John.
Senator Archer...
must be really desperate
for a legacy to risk all this.
Well, all politicians want stuff
named after them.
They have bigger egos
than movie stars.
Has to be something
more than that.
Yeah, of course, it's money.
Tap and the honorable Senator,
they own an energy company.
So, they're gonna build
a solar power plant on your dirt
with a nice federal subsidy.
They don't need my well for that.
No, your water's gonna be
diverted
to restore a salmon run.
Thank you, Laura.
I appreciate your candor.
You're welcome.
I did mean what I said
about there's a place
for you here.
Look...
guilty people should make amends.
Or they'll pay for it
somewhere down the line.
Yeah, if you believe
that sort of thing.
Tap has been spoilin'
for this fight
his whole life, you know.
Be careful.
You armed?
No.
Well, won't you come on in.
I think Lynnie deserves
to know who her daddy is.
We've kept it from her,
you know, for good, for bad.
It just doesn't matter anymore,
does it?
I loved your son.
I loved him.
And he said he loved me.
I never ran him off, ma'am.
He was a liar then.
Caleb wasn't a liar.
I never heard from him again.
I never heard another word.
Not another single word
from him ever.
What kind of person does that?
He's a coward and a liar.
He lied to me.
Your dad called and said
he caught you guys
together again and...
then knocked Caleb on his butt.
He told me what he did.
Things got a little heated,
got a little out of hand.
I told him to get his butt
over here,
he said he was going
to come over
and do the same to me.
Momma never let him out the door.
So, I guess she saved you all...
both some unwanted trouble.
John, maybe but not me.
How is that?
John Landsburg...
trespassing my property was...
was not a threat.
It was an opportunity
to take care of things.
So, I ran in the house
and got my shotgun and...
just waited on him
in the dark there.
Well, see, the dark has a lot
to do with this story.
So, pretty soon
I see your daddy come...
honkin' up that driveway and...
I yelled, "Hey, John."
He didn't say nothin'.
Don't turn his head, nothin'.
So, I shot.
It wasn't John.
It was Caleb, my...
I shot my son...
Caleb.
But I guess it says something.
It was meant to be.
'Cause you were a Landsburg...
and I was a Peterson.
I'm very sorry, but...
you tell your daddy...
Tell him I'll come by tomorrow
and get that land.
-Excuse me.
-Hey, cover for me?
There's a meeting down at the
courthouse.
I got to be there.
Okay.
Come here.
Howdy, Brady.
You got them financials for me?
You can have it back,
but there ain't nothin' on it.
I don't care who you work for.
I won't do it.
Leave my family alone.
Hold this.
Beat him, don't kill him.
I'm not much for asking for things,
as you know.
But the Bureau is coming
to take a piece
of my ranch tomorrow.
To do it, corrupt officials
altered documents
my grandfather signed
a hundred years ago.
I lived here all my life.
Like my daddy,
my grandfather most of his.
My family owns every inch
of that land they're trying to steal.
They're trying to take the water.
You all know what that means.
They take our water,
we're bankrupt.
That's trouble for all of us.
So, I'm asking you...
I'm asking you to stand with us.
To stop the Bureau
from tearing down our fence,
from seizing our well.
Stop them from
robbing our family of its legacy.
But this is a community thing.
This affects us all.
Well, you're asking people
to risk their lives, John.
Look, if we allow corrupt men
to thumb their noses at the laws
that we live by,
who will they come after next?
You, Dr. Taylor? You, Elaine?
I buried my brother...
my mother...
my wife...
on that land they're trying
to steal.
John...
I got my own family
that I gotta worry about.
Come on, babe.
I can't risk their future
by standing out there with you.
None of us can.
I'm sorry, John.
Well, I appreciate
everyone coming.
It's good of you to be here
to hear me out.
This is all my fault.
'Cause I took the deed.
I took the deed and I gave it
to Laura Lee Schaefer.
Why?
Laura Lee came to me.
She said she heard
we were having money problems
and she had a solution.
You sell the parcel,
save the ranch.
Save my home.
She told me she needed to see
all the deeds for the buyer.
And you believed her?
I didn't know
she was working for Tap.
And I didn't know she took one,
until you told me
the deed was missing.
I'm so sorry, Daddy.
I'm so sorry.
What's goin' on?
I was just tellin' your sister
that she can have no part
in this today.
She's got the boys and Jerry
to think about.
What are you gonna do?
I'm going with him.
No one's goin' up there but me.
There's nothing in this world
you could do to stop me.
Us, Daddy, us.
I don't want you girls goin'
and that's it.
But this is our ranch too, Dad,
and we'll decide what we do.
Like old times?
-Flashin' on desert storm.
-Right.
Just don't get any sand in it.
Okay, boss.
Well, look at you.
This ranch is who we are.
I'll be damned if I ain't
gonna be a part of that.
Son, there might not be
much ranch...
come day's end.
Well, not without a fight.
Never was there a family
with less sense.
Okay, go get yourself cleaned up.
All right.
We'll make a camp right here.
-All right.
-We'll camp.
We can tie those horses
to the well head.
Got ya.
All right.
Want me to build a fire, boss?
Better hold off on that.
Stay right there.
This is private property.
In 25 minutes,
this land and that well
will belong
to the federal government.
We can wait.
Well, maybe I'll stick
around then, too.
-Where's the sheriff?
-I haven't seen him.
Morning, Peterson.
Okay, let's set up over here,
you guys.
What are you doin' here?
Figured you wouldn't mind
a few of those Bureau guns
aimed at me.
You don't fire that thing
unless I tell you.
-Copy that.
-Grandpa.
I actually don't own a firearm.
I'm a firm believer in gun control.
Well, then you stay
behind me, girl.
Here, you take this, Lynnie.
-Yeah.
-Put it over there.
Okay.
Everyone take cover.
-Brady, over here.
-All right, Pop.
Hector, with the girls
and stay there.
Got it.
What you're doing is wrong.
The deed you've been shown is a lie.
It's a forgery.
Tap Peterson knows it's a forgery.
He arranged it.
It's a bunch of garbage.
Now, I don't know
how many of you
have shot anyone.
It's not a great feeling.
But I can't let you on my land
and I will do what I have to,
to keep you out.
You don't know who I am,
most of you.
But the people around here
will generally tell you
that I mean what I say.
And that's just who I am.
Who are you?
What kind of family
do you come from?
We live and die for the land
that our fathers gave us,
that's who we are.
Ronnie Tiwwit.
Are you going to shoot us?
Are you?
Really?
Put down your weapons!
Never.
How's that?
Daddy.
-Hey, boys.
-Hey.
Hey.
Hey, baby.
They all came because they
remembered
everything you've done for them.
-All right, you get safe now.
-All right.
Okay, Hector, take Brady.
Get right over there,
right behind him.
You better move
some of them trucks.
Hey, man. We're ready.
Oh, you are ready, man.
It's so good to see you, Martin.
Thanks for coming, guys.
Get over there behind that truck.
Bring those cars out up
in this direction.
The National Guard
will be dispatched shortly.
If you do not lay down
your weapons
and disperse,
you will be arrested.
Take Mr. Landsburg into custody.
I gave you fair warning.
Don't you dare move.
Get in position, you guys.
Daddy, look.
Hey, you see that?
THIS LAND IS OUR LAND
Stand down now.
Come on, boys,
put your weapons down.
-Guys.
-That's the sheriff.
Guys, stand down.
Come on, out of the way.
I'm from the Capitol, step aside.
John Landsburg.
John.
Judge Gibson from the Capitol
has granted you a stay.
The Bureau can't take any action
against the Landsburg Ranch,
pending further investigation.
Put those guns down now.
We are a part
of the same community.
Nice work, everyone.
-Nice work.
-Come on, let's all go home.
Back out. Back in the cars.
Back down.
How'd you do that?
I can be pretty persuasive
on the right occasion.
Yes, you can.
Thanks for...
Thanks everybody for coming.
That's right. You're all invited.
You, too.
I'm glad you came, man.
I'm so glad you came.
Your great grandma and grandpa,
Nellie and Jeremiah,
faced many challenges
to pass this ranch down to us.
But they were strong,
they worked hard
and they never gave up.
And we're not about to either.
JL RANCH