(dramatic music)
(static buzzing)
(jazzy dramatic music)
♫ You are my sunshine
♫ My only sun, my only sun
♫ You make me happy
♫ When skies are grey, when skies are grey
♫ You'll never know dear
♫ How much I love, how much I love
♫ Please don't take my sunshine away
♫ You are my sunshine
♫ My only sunshine
♫ You make me happy
♫ When skies are grey
♫ You'll never know, dear
♫ How much I love you
♫ Please don't take my sunshine away
♫ You are my sunshine, my only sunshine
♫ You make me happy
♫ When skies are grey
♫ You'll never know, dear
♫ How much I love you
♫ Please don't take my sunshine away
(dramatic rock music)
("Star Spangled Banner")
Hello, and good morning
to you, ladies and gentlemen
of the City Admissions
and Citizenship Council.
I'd like to extend a special greeting
to Councilman Harrington who supports me
fully and is my sponsor in this matter.
The presentation and review materials
(ominous organ music)
that you find included in your package
are to establish the legitimacy
of my bid for citizenship
in the fortified city proper.
With me I bring the
requisite citizenship fee
paid for five years in
advance and a profitable
and equitable business,
Maximum Productions.
Now I know that many of you are familiar
with the types of film that I produce
or you may have heard
he just peddles in smut,
et cetera, et cetera.
I would argue however that
with advent of the Rising,
profits must be realized
in infinitely diverse ways.
(dramatic ambient music)
(camera humming)
Fuck.
(dramatic rock music)
[Johnny] Poor guy, he owes.
Like so many of us out here in The Sprawl.
But he owes Max.
In The Sprawl, you don't get a tombstone,
you don't get a eulogy, you
just hope to die on film.
(dramatic rock music)
This isn't an execution.
It's entertainment.
(dramatic rock music)
I'm Johnny Sunshine, I'm a titan.
I'm a hurricane.
The soft whisper of a razor blade on skin.
I use many tools to entertain
and this one, not bad.
If I slide my blade above his floating rib
and tease the lung just a little
(coughing)
(heavy breathing)
it erupts on me.
The blood that cools against my skin.
Gently now.
(coughing)
(heavy breathing)
No tombstone for this one.
But he's a narc, he owes Max,
and the cameras are always hungry.
(dramatic rock music)
(door creaking open)
(ominous music)
(door creaking shut)
This is what really sells, the kill fuck.
I don't know who he is,
and I really don't care.
So long as the money comes, he goes.
Don't worry, I'll make the most of him.
(ominous music)
(gentle guitar music)
I keep a cocktail under the armrest,
my own blend of ecstasy, Sodium
Pentothal, and Belladonna.
Keeps the mind subdued
but the flesh willing.
[Man] Fuck.
(yelling and gagging)
[Johnny] Disgusting.
What are you doing?
You crazy fucking bitch,
what are you doing?
[Johnny] Let's see.
The fuck!
[Johnny] Ah.
Fuck you, hey!
I'm talking to you!
- Let's see.
- Fucking talk to me!
[Johnny] Hmm, I remember that one.
I'll kill you, oh my God,
I'm gonna fucking kill you.
(gentle guitar and vocal music)
[Johnny] Oh yeah, one in the
pink, and one in the stink.
Mm-hmm.
What are you doing?
(gentle guitar and vocal music)
You crazy fucking cunt,
what the fuck do you want?
Talk to me!
[Johnny] Oh.
Zap to the clit.
Every girl should try this one.
Favorite.
Ooh, this one hurts.
So many devices.
(gentle guitar and vocal music)
[Man] Hey fucking talk to me,
what the fuck are you doing?
[Johnny] I enjoy the
anticipation, the choosing.
The feeling part comes later.
♫ I don't have the words to say I love you
(gentle guitar and vocal music)
Oh shit.
(ominous booming)
(eerie music)
I'm gonna make you a star.
This is what sells.
The kill fuck.
(heavy breathing)
Max needs his money.
And I get off.
This is what sells, this is what sells.
(moaning and heavy breathing)
(eerie music)
This is what sells.
I have to have it, I
have to have the blood.
(man yelling)
I have to have it.
(moaning and yelling)
(yelling and moaning)
(eerie music)
Where are you going?
(man yelling)
(panicked breathing)
(gurgling)
(eerie music)
[Johnny] Porn star and killer for hire.
I fuck and I murder.
I am Johnny Sunshine, and this is my life.
(ominous music)
Hard music, hard sex, and hard drugs.
The only way we can feel like we're alive.
We're all junkies of one sort or another.
We all have our addictions.
Subdermal injection right
into the bloodstream.
No needles, no pain, no remorse.
(dramatic rock music)
Since the Rising of our
killing, a victim or a zombie.
It all started when I was a little girl.
(eerie rock music)
One day the dead just
stopped staying dead.
Zombies were among us.
Why call them anything else?
Corpses that feed on the living.
[Little Girl] Daddy, Daddy.
[Johnny] The world went straight to Hell
(screaming)
[Demon] Come to Daddy!
And stayed there ever since.
(energetic rock music)
(static buzzing)
Why the snuff?
Because it makes me rich,
because of the amazing
defense that only money can buy.
I do what I have to do to
stay on top of the game.
Look, this isn't a fairy
tale, and I'm not the bad guy.
The Rising was the great equalizer, man.
No more wolves and sheep,
all that's left are sheep.
(eerie music)
Sick, feral, predatory sheep.
Some breathe, some don't.
I get the ones that do
breathe what they want,
and they want the sickness, the violence.
(static buzzing)
The Rising hasn't just
affected the stiffs out there.
It's affected the living
too, I do what I have to do.
I was born right on time.
(dramatic rock music)
(static buzzing)
(dramatic ambient music)
(camera humming)
(growling)
[Johnny] They are dangerous,
an ever present menace.
(dramatic rock music)
It's always the same,
there are no surprises.
A chance meeting, the familiar dance.
(knife slicing)
(groaning)
(yelling)
(growling)
(groaning)
And the inevitable end.
The world gets a little smaller.
(dramatic rock music)
Jeff, is it?
Welcome to the big city Jeff,
and welcome to my movie set.
Lose the clothes, this
isn't Shakespeare, Jeff.
I've got a few ground rules on my set.
I don't care if you have to
smoke it, shoot it, snort it,
use the fluffer or jack it
off, keep your dick hard.
You keep it double wrapped, you don't want
a post-mortem infection
ending your new career.
Alright, what we're doing in this scene,
you're gonna approach
the stiff from behind,
I want you to be aggressive, I
want you to be mean, alright?
You're going to enter her violently.
I want it bloody, I want it mean,
I want it very aggressive,
you hear me, Jeff?
Good.
When you come to the end
of your business, alright,
I want you to grab her
by the back of the hair
and you just bash its
fucking head in, okay?
I want it bloody, I want it messy,
I want brains all over
the wall and all over you.
Keep your eyes and your mouth
closed when that happens.
You got it?
Let's get out there, time is money.
Go get 'em, tiger.
(dramatic rock music)
(sighing)
(heavy breathing)
(squeaking)
(dramatic guitar soloing)
Mm, there are maggots
in my money shot, Dennis.
God damn retards.
(giggling)
(panicked breathing)
Move.
Nasty bitch.
(panicked breathing)
Hey Sunshine, what you got for me?
Female, average build.
Pretty cute.
Yeah.
It's fresh, too.
No blemishes or anything.
Ah, very nice.
Got any tape?
Oh yeah?
- Is the man in?
- Yeah, he's in the pit.
Come on.
(muffled rock music)
A new one for ya.
[Max] Yep, she'll do.
Take her in the back with the rest.
Dennis, get your bitch
ass over here and help me.
Come on, let's go!
Quit it, open the fucking door.
(dramatic rock music)
(growling)
Johnny Sunshine, my
favorite piece of ass.
That creep still taking pictures of you?
Yeah, can't seem to
take his eyes off me.
Nobody can, but I'm with you,
if he's gonna be taking
pictures, he should be paying.
I can have some of the boys...
Don't sweat it, I can
take care of myself.
- Fine.
- You want the tape?
Only always.
(muffled rock music)
Wow, hot stuff.
(laughing) You cut his tongue out, classy.
Who's your co-star?
Didn't catch his name.
Never do.
Same price as always?
Same price as always.
Are you on for the show tomorrow?
Yep.
(muffled rock music)
(dramatic metal music)
Raid, I want you to
bring down the two cases
from the warehouse and
keep an eye on things.
Yeah.
Oh, you alright?
(man mumbling)
Raid, one of the unfortunates
that breed Max's money.
I guess I love him, as
close as I can get, anyway.
He and his sister Dez here run
Max's entertainment efforts.
I ended up with Raid, but if
Dez had swung the other way,
who knows?
(energetic rock music)
Ah Raid, only attracted to the dead,
or the living dead.
So we make due, the spice
helps him, numbs him, I think.
We do our work, dream of
life high up in the city,
and watch each other die.
(dramatic ambient music)
What's this?
Well, bar's closed now,
there's nobody left to kill.
Figured I might as well
give it back to you.
I've been a good girl.
I haven't spilled blood
in here for awhile now.
(muffled rap music)
Why is that?
Respect.
And your ass.
Hell, Johnny, it's
just another speakeasy.
Yeah, but it's yours.
Well, yours and his.
A girl's got to draw the line somewhere.
Don't kid yourself.
You know there's no lines.
Not anymore.
[Johnny] Friends and enemies.
[Dez] The living and the dead.
[Both] Everything else is just meat.
(dramatic rock music)
And that, Officer Stein, is the deal.
I delivered you your muse, your obsession,
your precious Johnny Sunshine.
And you walk away with enough money
to leave to the force
and buy your citizenship.
(sighing)
Yeah, Max.
Did alright.
Sounds a little like horse shit to me.
(gun cocking)
From your very next breath,
you're operating on a level
you've never experienced
before, Officer Stein.
Alright, just making sure
that you're the right guy
to be doing it, and I gotta go to work.
Time is, you know.
There's one more thing,
perhaps I should say two more things.
The long haired fucking
boyfriend that works at my bar?
He'll need to be eliminated.
Your little photos have made
Johnny rather suspicious.
He'll come here looking for that.
Let him take a pinch, let him have a hit,
he'll expect it, but take
him out here, and do it soon.
The other one of the triad of their
little trio is his sister, Dez.
She's the little dark haired
bouncer down at the bar you've seen.
She needs to be taken care of too.
That way there will be nothing
that stands between you
and your precious Johnny.
Are we clear?
(sighing)
I'm clear.
One more thing.
Don't do her until the camera's rolling.
Everything hinges on that footage.
You can leave your bloody
past in The Sprawl.
Put some panties on her or
something, something real nice.
Now it's time to go.
(dramatic ambient music)
[Johnny] Stupid fucking zombies.
Sometimes I think I only do this
only because it isn't popular.
Nobody wants to fight them,
but everyone wants them dead.
Or worse.
(eerie rock music)
(dramatic metal music)
Raid lost out, he got the opposite.
A legitimate love for the dead
that transcends his
human genetic imperative.
A cursed necrophile, like a maggot.
Maybe the ultimate joke on evolution is
that we are all something else's meat.
(static buzzing)
(eerie rock music)
The zombies aren't even people man,
just meat, there for the taking.
Sometimes I think they
know something we don't.
(static buzzing)
Sometimes I see it in their eyes.
The pain and the hatred.
There's awareness, it's
in there somewhere.
(static buzzing)
(dramatic rock music)
(ominous electronic music)
[Johnny] Just look at her.
Supple.
Warm and unaware.
(screaming)
Pump enough drugs into their system
and even torture seems like fun.
(ominous electronic music)
I hate them.
(choking)
I want to hurt them.
I want to use them up
and throw them away.
I live for it.
(man yelling)
(speaking quickly)
I can't scrape it off
my skin so I embrace it.
(man yelling)
I become it.
I make it my own.
(man yelling)
(ominous electronic music)
(choking)
(heavy breathing)
(intense metal music)
(man yelling)
(choking)
(intense metal music)
(man yelling)
(man yelling and groaning)
Who the fuck?
(eerie music)
[Johnny] I've gotta let
this thing into a routine.
(dramatic metal music)
Hmm.
Used that one recently.
This has been awhile.
(dramatic metal music)
Right there will be nice.
(stapler impacting)
(gasping)
And there.
(stapler impacting)
And right there.
(dramatic metal music)
(whimpering)
Mm.
I need the blood.
(dramatic metal music)
I love to watch them shiver.
I need something more.
But what?
I need to take another route with this.
(whimpering)
Sweet, tender meat.
I think I'll get a slice.
(dramatic metal music)
Hmm, penetration.
A little lube.
Fucking cunt, I'm gonna fuck
this bitch with something bigger.
I need something to slide in.
And out.
All the way out.
Ribbed for her pleasure.
So this cunt wants to
get her pussy fucked?
Well now her pussy is fucked.
(intense metal music)
Just a tickle, tickle.
(yelping)
(ominous vocal music)
Tickle.
(yelping)
(ominous vocal music)
(screaming)
This is what sells.
Just another kill fuck.
(shower water trickling)
(ominous ambient music)
(intense metal music)
Where have you been?
Moving a body.
[Johnny] Took your sweet time.
Yes I did.
Sorry if I smell like corpse.
It was alone.
I know.
(man mumbling)
♫ Reminding me of the
necessity of sobriety
♫ Still fighting that cancer,
still searching for an answer
♫ To questions that I do not want to know
♫ And perhaps I should give up
♫ Because maybe I don't wanna
know how to kill this parasite
♫ Oh baby, I think I might
♫ Carefully remove it
with pinpoint precision
♫ So I can finally have my way with it
♫ Still I made the decision,
time to make the incision
♫ And having my way with this pain
♫ Is better than I ever
could have envisioned
(dramatic string music)
(gasping)
(eerie music)
[Raid] Students have secret names.
The undead have voices of the hound.
(dramatic rock music)
Maybe it really is the end of the world.
(dramatic string music)
(mysterious rock music)
(dramatic metal music)
(growling)
They are not affected.
The crowd doesn't care.
They've seen it all before.
You don't survive The Sprawl
if you aren't one of the hard.
One of the frozen.
But still, they come
just like everyone else.
Like me.
(growling)
(intense electronic music)
(chainsaw buzzing)
(growling)
(intense electronic music)
(reciprocating saw buzzing)
(growling)
(intense electronic music)
(drill whirring)
(growling)
(intense electronic music)
(groaning)
(grunting)
I am a titan.
(eerie music)
I am a hurricane.
I live for this.
Every perfect moment.
(dramatic string music)
(metal clanking)
("Star Spangled Banner")
As we all know, the federal
government is incapable of
delivering the kind of support
this city desperately needs.
It's up to the city to
raise the funds we need
to maintain security in
these dangerous times.
Regulation is a dead concept
and the moral opposition
has all but disappeared.
The entertainment industry
is virtually untapped
within the walls of the city proper.
The lights, get the lights.
[Man] Sorry.
Sorry.
[Man] No, pan to the chart.
[Man] No, no, pan to the chart.
Pan, what's on the list?
[Man] I can't see the list.
[Man] Where's the light?
I can't see.
Oh shit.
Pan to the chart.
[Man] I'm not moving the fucking camera.
[Man] Show the chart.
[Man] You two are fucking fired.
(intense metal music)
It's closing time.
Wake up, dead boy.
- Hey, come on.
- Hey.
It's time to go.
Motherfucker.
Get the fuck out you piece of shit.
(intense metal music)
Looking good, doll.
Just another day at the office.
Got started a little early.
Didn't have a choice, the
dead don't punch a timecard.
I guess they don't.
Well we do.
You know, most people,
death just doesn't become them.
Something's lost in translation.
I don't think you'd lose it,
there's something about you,
your nose, cheekbones, skin.
No, you'd look good dead.
Don't even think about it,
you couldn't get it up if you tried.
Fuck you, Johnny, if
it wasn't for the porn,
guys like me, be glorified pest
control, like a fucking cop.
Raid, if it wasn't
for the thought of you
savagely penetrating my rotting corpse,
I don't think I could ever die.
Careful, Johnny.
(intense metal music)
(muffled rap music)
[Dez] I'm done.
Thanks, Raid.
How's my business?
Adequate.
Adequate?
How's the bar take?
The usual.
How's spice sales?
Flows, spice flows.
So I suppose my health
inspector came by?
Yeah, he was happy.
[Max] So we passed inspection.
Flying colors.
Good.
You want anything for the bar?
Red Dead, Private
Punishment, Kinky Ferret.
Get it from Sam this time.
Now speaking of the spice,
got a larger than usual
shipment coming in.
I want you to handle it personally.
Can do.
Now you know you're on
your last legs with me, Raid.
You don't fuck this up.
This is the time and the place.
It smells a little funny
because he's a cop.
His name is Stein, he's
dirty and he's in my pocket.
Never heard of him.
Is there a reason?
You have a fucking problem with it?
Then pour me another drink?
Yes sir.
(dramatic rock music)
(dramatic ambient music)
(gun cocking)
(phone ringing)
Yeah?
[Operator] Please enter
a tone to accept charges.
(phone beeping)
Yep.
(muffled talking on phone)
Yeah, first part's done, it's finished.
[Max] Now you just need the
corpse lover out of the way.
Mm-hmm.
(muffled talking on phone)
You set up the meeting.
Yeah.
I'll take care of the pre-vert.
[Max] You'd better get it straight.
(ominous ambient music)
Shitty day, no different.
Change up our equipment.
Say the production's down at the force,
so we got a 50 year old
phone, 50 year old gun,
something's always wrong in production.
Went out last night and
got a call from the family.
A zombie raid.
(ambient screaming and gunfire)
We were too late, always too late.
(dramatic ambient music)
I took the smut perv's offer.
Gonna die in a clean, well-lighted place
alone in the big city.
There's a fine line between
discipline and obsession.
I've chosen to cross it.
(reversed speaking)
Obsession.
(dramatic ambient music)
(camera humming)
(beeping)
(dramatic rock music)
(groaning)
(squishing)
(dramatic ambient music)
(gun cocking)
[Stein] Yeah?
You Stein?
Come on in.
How's the weather out there?
Shitty, like always.
I need a sample.
Coming right up.
(dramatic rock music)
Have a taste.
Roll 'em up, buster.
Hmm, care for a pinch?
Mm.
Yeah, you got a subdermal?
Nah, little old fashioned grinder.
Right here.
[Raid] Ooh, that is antiquated.
(dramatic rock music)
It's hard to find shit
like this these days.
Certainly not at your local gas station.
If you could, we
wouldn't be in business.
(splattering and gurgling)
(intense metal music)
(groaning)
(grunting)
Yeah.
(dramatic ambient music)
Hey there sweetie pie,
this used to be your pre-vert boyfriend.
Observe the lack of face.
Meet me at Big Tom's wood
shop, Detective Stein.
(dramatic ambient music)
(static buzzing)
The cops are nothing.
Their hands are tied
patrolling the streets,
whacking zombies and cleaning
up all the fucking murders.
That's why Stein came to
me, you know, he wanted out.
And the timing.
The timing was perfect.
Sails of the great Johnny
Sunshine have started to wane.
So what do you do when the shit
hot slayer isn't so hot anymore?
(static buzzing)
You feed her back to the sheep, of course.
And Stein was more obsessed than most.
A 50/50 split in the most
profitable snuff film ever made,
The Fall of Johnny Sunshine.
And I orchestrated the whole thing.
Anybody would have taken that deal.
Stein just went fucking mad.
(static buzzing)
(ominous ambient music)
Knew you'd accept my invitation.
Too bad your friends couldn't be here.
Guess they're busy,
sucking on fucking maggots.
Let's do it.
(reversed speaking) Let's do it.
(intense metal music)
(whimpering)
(grunting)
(intense metal music)
("Star Spangled Banner")
Taxes on the considerable
revenues my business
already creates are not
enforceable out here in The Sprawl.
Why the majority of my
recession-proof profits
come from inside the city walls,
with no foreseeable decrease in demand.
The Dark Endearment and Slayer,
Coming of the Champion series have vaulted
Maximum Productions into the
international film market.
I'm sure you're all familiar
with the disturbingly popular
Johnny Sunshine anthology
which has recently plateaued
in both urban sprawl
and city proper markets.
Now make no mistake, ladies and gentlemen,
she's still a superstar but I'm the one
who knows what you really want to see.
(dramatic ambient music)
(grunting and heavy breathing)
You like it in the butt?
Ugh.
Fuck yeah.
(moaning)
Stars and stripes, baby,
stars and fucking stripes.
(grunting and moaning)
You ready for a chocolate mustache, huh?
Probably bite my dick off, wouldn't you?
(gasping)
Gonna have to break your fucking neck
with my fucking dick in your mouth.
It's pretty sense
and real.
(gasping)
Oh yeah.
(grunting and moaning)
(ominous ambient music)
(sighing)
Wake up.
Guess I know what I have to do.
Wake up!
Don't want you to miss the
biggest show of your whole life.
Supposed to wait til the
camera was rolling to fuck you.
I just couldn't help myself.
Now what are we gonna do to occupy
our time while I get my second wind?
(dramatic ambient music)
(grunting)
You can't imagine what it's
like watching a creature
so beautiful waste such a gift.
Hmm?
Ready for the ham sandwich?
(grunting)
(coughing)
(laughing)
You're not a killer, you're a whore.
And that camera that exalts
you makes you a whore.
Ready, ready?
(grunting)
Oh no, no don't fade.
Oh, my little angel, don't fade.
Oh, my goddess. (Laughing)
You see this set up is
taking a little while, right?
I mean, you've gotten
photos, you've seen going on,
and you just walked into
a pretty little spiderweb.
Pretty little spider.
Oh, no?
Eyelids, keep 'em open.
We're gonna do this right.
(coughing)
(belching)
Come back to me, come on.
You know in this world,
you're either a zombie,
a killer, or a victim, huh?
I used to think that you were a goddess.
Some thirsty angel walking amongst us.
A slayer, like me.
But you're not smart enough, no.
No, not fast enough.
Not tough enough.
And the biggest difference of all,
no testosterone.
(intense metal music)
You know what you are?
You're a fucking write-off, that's right.
And the man's got you fucking wrapped up
and I'm getting 50/50 on this shit.
Are you ready?
(intense metal music)
(moaning and heavy breathing)
Just another
cheap kill fuck.
(intense metal music)
(screaming)
Open your eyes, this is
the apocalypse culture.
(mysterious guitar music)
(muffled metal music)
[Woman] The hell happened to you?
Occupational hazard.
Got a fresh tape.
Uh, Max isn't here, I have a...
Same price as always.
[Woman] Here you go.
And this one's free.
Thanks.
(muffled metal music)
[Johnny] Max made me what I am, a star,
a star maker, a zombie hunter.
I knew it would end this way.
I knew it from the very beginning.
But because they will say
you have killed the king,
I am the king.
[Johnny] So when Max sold
me out, I did him a favor.
Look around you,
Johnny, flesh is a prison.
[Johnny] No tombstones.
So.
[Johnny] No eulogy.
Fuck regret.
[Johnny] I let him die on film.
(gun firing)
(dramatic vocal music)
(intense metal music)
(dramatic clanking)