'The real deal. The real deal, that.
'The champion.
The champion wife of the world.'
'Sorry.
'Hang on, hang on.'
'Mission accomplished.
'Mission accomplished. Number one.'
'Go.'
'Go away.'
'Cheese.'
- 'Three, two, one, go!'
- 'Cheese.'
'Matty Burton!'
Hey, you.
Hey, you, Mimi.
Yo. Yo, Mimi.
How you doing? How you doing?
Eh? All right, beautiful?
Yeah. Where's Mama?
Where's Mama, eh?
It's all sticky. Yeah, it's all sticky.
Yeah!
Daddy have some of your toast?
Have some of Mimi's toast? Daddy eat it?
No? Daddy gonna eat it.
Eh? Daddy can't eat any of your toast.
I got boobies.
I've got to get rid of my boobies.
- I've got bigger boobies than Mummy.
- Oh, is that right?
If Daddy keeps that talk up,
there'll be no booby off Mummy for a month.
- Oi, come here.
- What?
Come here.
Get here.
Thank you.
- I love you.
- Good.
After this fight, I'll take you out
somewhere nice to eat.
Sounds good.
Anywhere you wanna go. It's your choice.
We can go to Nando's.
- Berni Inn.
- Wow!
- Harvester.
- You spoil me.
You deserve it, kid.
Matthew! Mia's right there. It's a bit weird.
Oh?
Mimi?
Come here, baby.
There you go, look. Let's turn you around.
- This is so wrong!
- Don't look at Mummy and Daddy.
You watch the birdies, look. There you go.
Matty, you lost your father recently.
He was with you in the corner
for your first 33 fights.
What difference will it make
when you walk to the ring?
Will his thoughts be in your head?
Yeah, definitely.
I'll fight in honour of my father.
You know what?
No disrespect to his pops an' all that,
but it wouldn't matter
if he was here or not, he'd still lose.
Every single person
who goes against me goes down,
regardless of who's in his corner.
You should show Matty more respect.
Respect for what? What's he done?
His father was part of boxing folklore.
Surely that's wrong.
All right, go on.
What do you wanna say about your dad?
It's, er... It's fine.
I'm just so grateful
that before he passed away,
I was able to bring the title home
and also I've got a beautiful daughter.
I'm just glad that he was able
to hold her before he left us.
Has that given you extra motivation?
It's another person in my life to protect.
It's just that extra bit of fire.
Having that bit of extra motivation
is gonna help me.
This is his most important fight.
It's the most important fight
of my life, apparently.
Matty, you're fighting Andre The Future.
This is billed as "The Future Is Here".
Do you feel like you've been written off?
If it's all about the future,
the past is gonna bite him on his arse.
This guy's losing all the time,
and he won this on a default.
It's my duty to go out there and defend it.
He's never been better.
He knows he didn't earn it.
He is not the true champion.
I might not be the best technical boxer,
but I'm the world champion.
A true champion defeats his opponents.
They don't pull out because of an injury.
He's not a true champion.
It will be interesting to see
who's around him
after he loses on the 22nd.
I'm gonna knock him out, take that belt home.
We're gonna dance on his grave
and celebrate his life.
Ooh!
Go on, Matt. Go on!
Shall we wrap that up?
Thank you very much for coming down.
- We'll see you fight night.
- Come on, Granddad!
This belt is mine.
Last time you're gonna feel that belt.
Hey, look at me.
What are you looking at them for?
Look at me. You ashamed to look at me?
You want me to look you in the eye?
I'll look you in the eye. There you go.
I'm gonna take your head off.
This is a life-changer for you.
Understand that. It's a life-changer.
Hey!
You're not asleep, are you?
Eh? You're wakies.
You're wakies, eh?
Ah, my baby.
My baby girl, eh?
What's Daddy gonna do?
What's Daddy gonna do, Mimi?
Eh?
Eh? Shall I whup his arse?
Eh? Shall I smoke his boots?
Shall I? Shall I take him
into the deep water and drown him?
Yeah?
Eh?
I love you.
Phwoar.
You've tinkered, haven't you?
Yeah, you smelly bum-bum.
Come on, let's change your bum.
Yeah.
Slow-mo. There, there, there.
- Feel it?
- Yeah.
There's the shot. Relax on it.
There he is.
Sit down on those hooks.
Again.
There he is. There he is.
Spring back in with that right.
Time.
Here.
Nice.
Another one in.
Exhale. Nice and slow.
Slow it down. That's it.
Come on.
Been eating Mimi's treats?
It'll come off in the bath.
Let's go. Eight.
Sharp stuff.
Three, four, five, relax.
And now to the scales, the WBO
middleweight champion of the world,
Matty Burton.
- 11 stone, 4 pounds.
- Matty! Matty! Matty!
Yes! Come on!
'Andre, your best chance
'is because he's, according
to you, over the hill.'
'The best of him is gone,
but I could beat the best of him.
'What is the best of him? Please tell me.
'The best of him ain't touching
the lowest of me.'
'From my point of view, Steve,
look, this fight is about experience,
'and he's never gone in deep in his career.'
'You're going down.
It's a life-changer for you.
'I ain't lost a single fight, right?
I've had 18 fights, 16 knockouts.
'He's a sluggish fighter.
Just stands there, takes beats.
'What's there to fear or respect?
People are gonna go, "Matty who?"'
Here he is. You all right, champ?
- Yeah, mate.
- Give us your bag.
- Thanks.
- I'll get it in the car for you.
Come here.
Don't worry, we'll look after him.
- See you, Jackie.
- All right, ta-ra.
- Take your time, bro.
- Thanks, mate.
Emma.
Look at me.
When I come back through that door
in a few hours' time,
I'm still gonna be champion of the world.
Number one.
I've just gotta do this. It's what I do.
Yeah.
I'd better go.
Can you knock him out quick?
I wish it was that easy.
I love you.
Good.
Spread your fingers. Okay?
- Thanks, gents.
- Good luck.
Thank you.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
entering the arena, the champion,
the one and only Matty Burton!
Punch his lights out!
Come on, Matty!
Okay, bring him out.
We love you, Matty!
Yeah, you can't run away now.
Come on, Granddad. What do you say?
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
it's Big Fight time.
This is a contest of 12 three-minute rounds
to decide the WBO middleweight
championship of the world.
In you come.
I gave you instructions in the dressing room.
Life-changer.
I say "break", you break. Touch 'em up.
- You ain't tasted pain.
- Best of luck, gents.
He's got no class. Here you are.
Hard work's done, mate.
Homework's done. Do what you do best.
Matty! Matty! Matty!
Get on that jab. Don't chase him.
Keep your shape.
Get on that jab.
- I slipped. I fucking slipped.
- Two, three.
Judge Steve Watson scores the contest
115-113 in favour of the winner.
And still...
...the WBO middleweight
champion of the world,
Matty Burton.
Matty! Matty! Matty!
- Hey.
I fucking did it.
- Ow, ow!
- Sorry.
Oh, you did it.
Don't cry, baby.
Don't cry.
It's over.
Do you feel legit now?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Good.
What do you want?
Do you know what I want?
I just want a nice cup of tea.
You're champion of the world.
You can have anything.
- And you want a cup of tea?
- Yeah.
A nice sweet cup of tea.
Okay.
Ow! You keep squeezing me.
Sorry, I just wanna touch you.
Oh, God.
Oh.
I'm very fragile.
Look at your face.
Aargh! Oh, f...
Oh, God.
Matty?
God.
Oh, God.
I need an ambulance.
He's a boxer. He's been in a fight.
I don't know.
Er, Sheffield, S17.
Okay, okay.
I'm still here.
This one.
It's in.
Right.
- Ready?
- Mm.
It's okay, baby. It's okay.
Hey.
We're home.
Let's get you inside.
Come on.
You're home.
It's okay. Come on.
Sit you down.
- Yeah?
- Mm.
- Get you a cup of tea?
- Yeah.
I want you to try and point them forward
so they're pointing towards the steps
That's good. I know it's hard work.
Lovely. Well done.
It's a lot to concentrate on.
Forwards again.
What I need to check first
is that we can actually get
this leg of yours up onto the step first.
What I'd like you to do
is you just pop this leg here
up onto the step.
Pointing forwards again.
Do it like we do it at home.
- What?
- Do it like we do it at home.
- Show them.
- Yeah.
Yeah?
Well done.
That's lovely. Hand on the banister, though.
Lovely. Well done.
That's it. Got the leg position. Good.
Well done.
- Brilliant.
- Good. Put your hand forward.
What are you doing down here?
What are you doing?
- Training.
- What for?
A fight.
Who are you fighting?
Um...
Black man.
- A black man?
- Yeah.
What am I gonna do with you,
eh, Matty Burton?
I don't know.
Let's take you upstairs.
- Yeah.
- Come on.
I'll take that.
Um, what's her?
It's Mia.
Oh.
Who her dad is?
You are, Matthew.
Oh.
How long?
Um...
From the moment she was conceived.
Basically, all of her life.
We made her. Do you understand?
No.
Am I gonna have to teach you
about that as well?
What?
That is your little girl.
Oh.
What his name is?
She's called Mia.
- Mia.
Made her.
100%, yes.
I made her.
We did.
- I'm pregnant there.
- Oh?
- Who's that?
- It's Darren from the gym.
He's wrapping your hands before the fight.
- Him my friend?
- Yeah.
Who's him?
That's Mia, when we brought her home
from the hospital.
- Eh?
- Yeah.
- Do you remember?
So little.
- Who's that?
- Mia.
- Yeah. Ah, that's your dad.
Yeah. Remember my dad?
I do.
Er, he's in the ground now.
Yeah.
- Robin.
- Yeah.
- There's more Mia.
- Mia.
There's lots of her.
- One of my dad.
- Yeah.
This is us wedding.
Oh, yeah.
- That's you.
- Yeah.
Um.
Her beautiful.
Thank you.
Keep up with the compliments,
you might get a look in later.
Oh, is something waking up down there?
Hello, you.
- Oh...
- Yeah.
It's okay.
- Yeah?
We got married here.
Yeah?
- Do you remember?
- Mm.
Do you remember?
Um...
You don't, do you?
Yeah.
It's here.
Who's that?
That's Jackie.
- Right.
- He's in your corner.
Oh.
Who's him?
That's Richie. He's your trainer.
Right.
And my dad.
Yeah, you know him.
Yeah.
Who's him?
That's Matt.
- I'm Matt.
- No, you're Matty.
- That's Matt.
- Yeah?
Matt.
- That's me.
- Oh.
Yeah.
Are my friends?
Where are they?
That's a good question.
Mm.
# Like a diamond in the sky
# Twinkle, twinkle, little star
# How I wonder what you are
All right, sweetheart?
Er...
There you go, angel.
Emma?
Emma? Emma?
Yeah.
All right, sweetheart.
Made you a cup of tea.
Aah.
Thank you, that's lovely.
Yeah?
Ah.
It's cold. Did you forget to boil the kettle?
Um...
Yeah, I think...
I think you might have forgot.
Oh, and it's still got the teabag in.
Next time, you just need to boil the kettle,
and then when you've made it,
just take the teabag out...
Matty, look up there.
My team.
- Yeah.
- And my dad.
Do you remember coming in before the fight?
Yeah.
And my friends.
I'll see you later, son.
Watch your fingers.
Hiya.
How are you doing?
Yeah, we're good, thank you.
Good.
- How is he?
- He's there. Ask him.
- Is it all right if I just say hello?
- Yeah, 'course it is.
Hello, mate.
Who he is?
- My friend from the picture?
- Yeah.
We go way back, mate, me and you.
- Where you been?
- Busy at the gym.
Why you not take me to the gym?
Um, yeah, all right.
- Can I take him to the gym.
- Yeah.
I'll be in touch with you
and we'll go to the gym, all right?
Don't forget me.
I won't.
See you later. It was nice to see you.
Um...
- C-c-can do... do the nice...
- No, Matty!
- I want to do the nice thing.
- No.
Um, but... um...
- Can we do the nice thing?
- I know it's nice, but no.
- Can do...
- It can't just be when you want it.
It's got to be right for both of us.
Right.
'Bryte's looking to finish this.
'He's looking to take him out.'
'It could all be down
to this last three minutes.
'It has been a tremendous fight.'
'Oh, what a last round that was.
What a last round!'
'Judge Steve Watson
scores the contest 115-113
'in favour of the winner.
'And still... the WBO middleweight
champion of the world,
'Matty Burton!'
'Bryte believes he's been robbed,
'but for Burton it means so very much.
'He has survived a tumultuous last round,
'and he's still champion of the world.'
'Did you feel old tonight?
It's been a long career.'
'I knew that it was probably my last fight.
'I don't wanna make any announcements.
I wanna go home and just talk to my wife.
'But, you know, Steve, if I'm honest,
I think this is the last time for me.'
- 'Is this a retirement statement?'
- 'Honestly, Steve,
'I think I knew a long time ago.
'I think I knew when I won the title.
'I can't... It was hard to find it
for this one, if I'm honest with you.
'It was hard to find it and, um...
But I got through it.
'What I had left, I gave tonight.
I haven't got no more.
'Yeah, as far as I'm concerned...'
Emma?
'Don't take this from me now.
'I won the title. Nobody gave me credit.
Please don't take this from me now...'
Emma!
I had an accident.
Accident again.
It doesn't matter.
- Come on.
- Accident again.
Yeah, you have.
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right, don't worry.
I...
- Accident.
- Get you changed.
Yeah.
Oh, well.
Where are you, my baby?
I feel so alone.
I need you to come back now.
We need you to come back now.
Can you hear me?
Do you want me to give you a hand?
You keep missing bits.
I'll do it.
All right. I'm walking away.
Hey, what's happened?
What's happened? It's okay.
What's going on? It's okay.
Shh.
It's okay, Matty.
Eight letters, second letter A.
Ridicule, five letters.
- Six or a two.
- No, five or a two.
'Welcome to the show.
'My first guest, Ben, is back here today
to confront his nightmare ex, Jemma.
'He says after their 12-year relationship
ended just weeks ago,
'she has harassed and threatened him...'
'He's on the show.
Give him a round of applause.'
Shut up.
Matthew, where's Mia?
Where is she?
I left her in the play pen. Where is she?
Matty?
Are you listening? Where is she?
- Hey!
- Listen to me.
She's not big enough to get out by herself.
Where is she?
Come here, Mia. It's all right, sweetheart.
It's all right. Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm so, so sorry.
It's okay.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
It's okay, it's okay.
I'm sorry.
Oh.
Oh, you silly cow. You silly cow!
Emma?
Hungry.
I hungry.
Um...
All right, mate?
I just like a little bit of milk with mine.
Um...
Phew, yeah.
All right.
Oh.
There you are.
Um.
There.
Where are you?
Up here, yeah.
Er...
Pictures, yeah. Pictures.
Pictures.
In here.
Yeah.
All the pictures.
Ah.
Pictures.
Of you. Pictures of you.
'Thank you to the fans,
thanks for everything,
'everybody who's stood by me
through the years.
'I don't think I'll be seeing you again
anytime soon.'
'Matty! Matty! Matty!'
Matty.
You're not Matt. Matty.
Matthew.
Matty.
I'm Matty.
Double it.
Good. Double it
and put a right hand after it.
Steady.
Nice.
I'm sorry I left you, kid.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know what to do.
I got frightened.
'Hi, this is Emma.
Sorry I can't get to the phone.
'I'll call you back as soon as I can.'
Hello?
Hello, Emma.
Richie!
All right, mate? Long time, no see.
What are you doing here?
He needs us, mate, big time.
Hi, love.
You all right?
Yeah.
Hey.
From... from the picture.
My friend.
- Yeah.
- What's your name?
It's Jackie.
That's him.
Jackie.
You know my girlfriend?
Emma.
She's my wife.
If you see her,
tell her I'm looking for her.
I will, mate. Yeah.
Tell her I want her to come home for me.
- And my daughter.
- Okay.
My daughter, um...
She's a baby now.
Mia.
Yeah.
If you see her, tell her, um...
I saw her under the water.
Will you do that for me?
Yeah.
Are you gonna leave me as well?
No, mate.
No, I wanna stay the full visiting hours.
- Good.
- Yeah.
Here. On here. Right.
Hello, my mate.
Do you wanna come and do
some pads with Manny?
Do you remember how to do it?
Yeah.
Hold the pads for Manny, eh?
Manny, do some pads.
So, open your hand up.
- Push.
- Manny Pacquiao.
Push. Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
Pacquiao.
Looks like him, but he doesn't hit like him.
- Push 'em.
- Is that all right? Okay.
- Yeah.
- You do some pads now with Manny.
Yeah?
All right, Manny.
Manny Pacquiao.
Manny Pacquiao, that's it.
Right.
Um...
Oh, er...
No, no, no.
Get back in line.
Matty? Matty? Shh.
No, don't do that. Don't do that, no. Shh.
Mate, mate, come and sit down.
Come and sit down.
Come and sit down over here.
- Come and sit down.
- I want back home.
- Eh?
- I want... I want Emma.
Yeah, we'll get Emma.
I'll ring Emma for you. I'll ring her.
Come and sit down. Time, boys. Time.
That's it. Now come and sit down.
That's it. Go and get some water.
Do you wanna go out and get some air, mate?
She's not coming back.
She is, mate.
I'm doing the best I can.
Oh, mate.
Come here.
I know you are, brother, eh?
Come on, let's get your coat
and get you out, yeah?
Get some air.
Er, Jackie?
What if she comes back when I'm gone?
She's got a key.
Oh.
Okay.
My dad's not here, Jackie.
No.
He's still alive in you, isn't he?
And in your Mia.
Why she's, um... punishing me?
No, mate, she isn't punishing you, is she?
She's just taking time
to get her head together, that's all.
Thank you for being my friend.
Oh, mate, it's my pleasure, innit?
I'm just sorry I left you for so long.
You can't look after me forever.
No, you're right, I can't,
but we'll make sure you're all right.
People will think we're married.
I wouldn't marry you, mate. You're too ugly.
Let's see if you
can just relax that right hand.
- That's good.
- # I want you
- He's bossy.
- He looks bossy.
# Yeah, I want you
Come on, kid.
# Cos nothing comes close
- One more.
# To the way that I need you
# I wish I could feel
# Your skin
# And I want you
# From somewhere within
# It feels like there's oceans
between you and me
# Once again
- No power shots.
- Don't knock him over.
# We hide our emotions
# Under the surface
# And try to pretend
# But it feels like there's oceans
# Between you and me...
Right, we train hard, my wife will come back.
Yeah.
- Well, you're definitely training hard.
- Yeah.
# I want you
Keep your eyes up. Keep your eye on the ball.
# And I always will
- Right.
- And then left.
- Left.
Brilliant. Good lad.
In the middle there. That's it, perfect.
Now let it go out gently.
Don't let it rock back.
Controlled.
- # It feels like there's oceans
- Strong.
# Between you and me
- Ten.
- # Once again
Bring 'em up, bring 'em up.
- # We hide our emotions
- Slow.
- Clench the fists.
- # Under the surface
- # And try to pretend
- Practise. It will become second nature.
# But it feels like there's oceans
- # Between you and me #
- Team Burton, number one.
Bang it out.
- Good lad. Boom!
- Yeah.
Right, come on, then.
Let's get you a drink
and go on to something else.
- Yeah.
- Good man. You're doing great.
- Yeah, my mate.
- You see the improvement?
- Oh, yeah.
- Nice one, champ. Let's go.
Mia.
- She's a small baby.
- Yeah.
With a little bit of hair.
I think sometimes when you hear yourself,
it then becomes clear.
- Just try and listen to how you sound.
- Yeah.
'Emma's my wife.'
- 'Um... She's beautiful.'
- That's not... Is that me?
Yeah, that's you.
'Beautiful, soft.
'She's my... love of my life.'
- Okay.
- It's true.
So let's maybe just overexaggerate
the sounds in the words: love of my life.
Love...
of...
my...
life.
Love of...
my life.
- My...
- Yeah?
Love of my life.
- Your go.
- Your go, mate. I've just been.
- Go on. Don't try to fiddle me.
- Um...
Don't be cheating.
- Matty.
- Yeah?
- You got a visitor, mate.
- Oh?
- Cheers.
- Here, my friend.
Some great pictures.
Er, yeah.
Um, that's my dad.
Um, that's me.
Jackie, Richie.
He's my dad and, er, Matt.
Not Matty.
Um, this is my team again.
Had, um, accident.
Um, Richie's gonna fix it.
This is my wife.
Emma, um...
Beautiful.
She's gone away for a bit while I fix myself,
but she's coming back,
um, one day.
And Mia.
Very soon.
Thanks for letting me in.
Welcome.
- I was worried.
- What for?
Because of what happened.
The fight.
What I did to you.
Did we fight?
Yeah.
Who won?
You.
Number one.
Er...
I just wanted to say to you that, um...
I'm really sorry for what happened.
I didn't mean to hurt you.
And if I could take it back...
It was out of order, saying all those things.
I was naive, just trying to sell tickets,
be the bad boy,
and I'm ashamed I said the things I did.
The Future.
Future is here.
Mm.
Hello?
Hi.
Er, yeah. Shall I get him?
Hang on.
- Matty?
- Yeah?
Telephone.
- Hello.
- 'Hey, you.'
- Is that you?
- 'It is me.'
Oh.
Um...
I miss you.
'I miss you.'
When are you coming home?
'I love you.'
I love you.
Um, I'm training very hard.
'I know you are.
'Richie's told me you're doing really well.'
Um...
What else?
Um, I saw you under the water.
Um...
I'm better now. Um...
- 'Are you?'
- Yeah, I'm very strong.
'Good.'
Um...
Who are you with?
'I'm with Mia.'
Oh.
- My Mia.
- 'Your Mia.'
- Um...
- 'Our Mia.'
Yeah.
When you see her, will you tell her
I saw her under the water?
'I will. I'll tell her.'
- Okay.
- 'All right.'
Um...
- When are you coming home?
- 'I'm not sure yet. I just...
'I need some time to fix myself.'
I'm waiting for you by the window.
'I'm gonna have to go now, Matthew.'
Um, wait. Um...
What else? Um...
Something else.
Er... how are you?
'Fine. I miss you.'
I miss you. When are you coming home?
'Soon, baby.'
Okay.
I'm very strong now.
'Good.'
Um, something else.
Um...
To tell you. Um...
Just come home
cos I'm waiting for you by the window.
I'm doing very well.
'I have to go now. I love you so much.'
- I love you.
- 'Bye, baby. Bye.'
Okay, bye.
Oh, um...
There's something else.
Um...
Oh, well.
Er... she's not coming today.
- She'll come.
- Yeah.
- I need to just give her time.
That's all, mate.
My belt.
Yeah, man.
Richie.
Put... Put Emma on again, Jackie.
Yeah, man.
She were dancing with my dad.
There we go.
Oh.
Best ever.
Who's best ever? Best ever?
Um...
- Who's the greatest?
- Muhammad Ali.
Muhammad Ali.
Cos he made you laugh as well.
You know what I mean?
- He was bigger than boxing, wasn't he?
- Yeah.
I'll get you some money sorted out.
- It's all right. That's on me.
- Are you sure?
That's good of him. No charge.
- Oh.
- Yeah, that's fine.
These boys wanted a picture.
Is that all right?
- Future world champs.
- Yeah.
- What weight are you?
- Lightweight.
- Are you?
- Lightweight, yeah.
- Look here, Matty.
- Big enough.
Here, here. Look at me.
- See you at the do?
- 100%, yeah.
- See you.
- Thank you.
- See you later, pal.
- All right, mate.
- Take care.
- Thank you.
- Shut this door, Richie?
- Yes, please. Yeah.
Are you all ready for your big night?
- Yeah.
- Good man.
There you go.
Smart, mate.
- How do I look?
- Smart.
Good.
Let's get your jacket on.
- Get your arm in, your hand.
- Yeah.
There you go.
Come here.
Very dapper.
Gonna be a lot of people out for you tonight.
Ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's do one.
Looking dapper, man.
Thanks to everybody for coming
to what's gonna be
a celebration of Matty Burton.
We're gonna celebrate his life.
I wanna take you back to that night
when he retained his title.
What a memory that was.
What a fight that was.
Weren't it fantastic? That was brilliant.
That was Matty as we want to remember him.
Let's welcome him to the stage,
our champion, the man you've come to see,
Matty Burton.
All right, Matty.
I want to, er...
Where's Andre?
Andre Bryte?
There's him.
The Future.
I want to say to you,
I don't blame you for what happened to me.
I don't blame boxing.
I love boxing.
It made me who I am today.
I'm glad this never happened to you.
Because I don't want anybody...
to go through what I've been through.
Because it's been hard.
I want to say
a special thank you to my friends,
to Richie and to Jackie,
for looking after me.
I thought you'd left me but you came back.
I love you and thank you very much
for being in my life.
A few weeks ago
I tried to end my life.
I wanted to die.
I jumped into the water.
In the water
I saw my wife
and my baby.
It made me want to live again.
I lost my belt
in the water.
It's just a belt.
It doesn't mean anything,
compared to the people I love.
I don't want to lose them.
Every day I train hard,
get my mind sharp,
and keep training.
I hope that...
the people I love the most
come back to my life.
Um...
Thank you.
Well done, Matty. We love you, Matt.
We love you, Matty.
Well done. I love you.
You did good.
Trying to remember what you're trying to say.
It's gone.
Excuse me, Matty. Big fan.
Any chance of a selfie?
- Course you can.
- You're a star.
You've had a lot of selfies today.
- You get better.
- Thanks, mate.
Thank you, mate.
What did you hate most about training?
Tyre.
- You hated or loved that?
- I hated it.
Yeah.
Hey, you.
- Is that my baby?
- Yeah.
It's my baby.
Oh, it's you.
Er, wait.
Love of my life.
- Don't leave me.
- I won't.
Don't go anywhere, will you?
I'm not going anywhere.
# But I believe in love
# And I know that you do too
# And I believe in some kind of path
# That we can walk down, me and you
# So keep your candles burning
# Make her journey bright and pure
# That she'll keep returning
always and ever more
# Into my arms, O Lord
# Into my arms #
Change!
Got a big mouth, he has.
He used to shout at me.
Then I punched him in the head
and he stopped it.
- Sorted him out.
- All right, kiddo.
That's nice. Nice movement, nice feet.
# And one by one
Say when.
# I watched them run
# They were my friends
# A frozen eye
# And one by one
- # I saw them crying
- Fast.
- # They were forever
- Do that switch. One, two, switch.
- That's it.
- # To be leaving
Change.
Who's in here? Who's in here?
- Happy with that?
- Cheers.
Good man.
# Nothing is remembered
Daddy.
- # Nothing ever said
- There's my baby.
- Yeah, Daddy.
- It is Daddy.
Daddy.
- Who loves you?
- Daddy.
Yeah, you bet.
Give us a kiss.
- Mummy.
Take you home, baby?
Yeah.
# A broken horse
# And one by one
# I watched them run
# They were my friends #