This film was produced
without public resources.
[The month of June begins with]
[a lot of humidity]
[in most parts of the country.]
[I declare officially open the FIFA]
[Confederations Cup 2013.]
[As from tomorrow, bus and subway]
[tickets will become more expensive.]
[In São Paulo, the bus,]
[subway and train tickets...]
[...will go from R$ 3,00]
[to R$ 3,20, as from today.]
[Goal! Brazil!]
[The protesters]
[are walking around...]
[If the fares don’t go down...]
[Ole, ole, ola...]
[This coverage was the winner]
[of the Esso Award 2013]
[It’s just wonderful.]
[It makes you want to kill yourself,]
[commit suicide...]
[Just jump on the rails,]
[it’s easier.]
[The buses take long time to arrive,]
[the amount of people inside...]
[I can never get a seat, I never travel]
[seated when I take the bus.]
[Depending on the bus,]
[I think it’s really shitty.]
[Excuse the word...]
[But it’s the chaos.]
[Regarding the urban trains,]
[we do suffer.]
[Considering it’s the year]
[of the World Cup in Brazil,]
[we’d think there would be]
[some investments,]
[but it’s not the case.]
[None of the politicians are brave]
[enough to leave their cars]
[and take the public transportation,]
[and be there with the people,]
[in the heat, sweating.]
[I believe the fare,]
[either R$3,20 or R$3,00,]
[is too expensive]
[for what is offered.]
[It’s out of the question.]
[I hope this will change some day.]
[I’ll die dreaming,]
[I don’t know if my generation will be]
[here to see this change.]
[Haddad, you asshole,]
[bring the bus fare down!]
[It’s too expensive!]
[It’s R$ 0,20...]
[...making the businessmen]
[richer and richer.]
Watch out, because
the Crazy-men Party will emerge!
JUNE
[Come out to the streets!]
[Come against the raise!]
[The MPL, Free Pass Movement,]
[is a social movement, horizontal,]
[autonomous, disconnected]
[to political parties,]
[that fights for a truly public]
[transportation model.]
[The movement started]
[with the popular uprisings]
that happened especially
in Salvador and Florianópolis,
against the raise of bus fares.
[The rebellions in Florianópolis,]
[which were known as “Fare Wars”,]
[achieved victory]
[for 2 years in a roll.]
[The people on the streets]
[revoked the fare from rising.]
[And in 2005,]
[at the World Social Forum,]
[several cities that were impelling]
[fights for public transportation]
[got together and created]
[a social movement]
that could represent
all these fights.
It was the Free Pass Movement.
The organizations such as
the Free Pass Movement
aren’t primarily directed
towards the State.
[They talk about the society,]
[to the society itself.]
That’s groundbreaking.
The MPL declares itself
to be anti-capitalism.
The movement is not really interested
in the topic of urban mobility.
For them, urban mobility is an excuse
to build a revolution, that’s curious...
I know them because many
are students at our university.
[It seems to me they act]
[very intelligently.]
Instead of presenting general agendas
in their political discussions,
[like the end of capitalism]
[or topics of this nature,]
[they aim towards a specific symptom,]
a symptom that shows
the system’s irrationality.
[This...]
[...is the third great act...]
TUESDAY, JUNE 11TH
[that will stop the city.]
[It’s not only São Paulo]
[that is fighting]
[against the fare increase.]
[I started covering]
[the protests on Tuesday,]
[the first day]
[of protests this week.]
And I saw very different
groups of people.
There were some people connected
to political parties
and others who were there protesting
because they identified with the cause.
[Why are you here protesting?]
I can’t find a reason
not to be here, actually.
It’s amazing that everyone
is finally coming to the streets
[and is protesting for their rights,]
[which will only come when]
[there is pressure from the people.]
This is the State’s responsibility,
it is written on the bus itself.
There are ways to achieve, at least,
the free tickets for the students,
and then, afterwards,
the total gratuity in transportation.
I’m surprised society thinks a protest
in favor of a public cause is strange.
Everyone is paying for this increase,
including the police.
I have a car and I’m here.
I think everybody should be here.
Because cars generate
a lot of traffic,
and car owners wouldn’t use their cars
if public transportation were good.
The first arrest done
at the demonstration on Tuesday
[happened right next to me.]
[He was a cyclist, who crossed a lane]
[the police was trying to clear]
[for vehicles use exclusively.]
[He was thrown on the grass]
[by six officers.]
Oh, my God!
[Many protesters didn’t want violence]
[and never attacked the police.]
But a few people at the front
[led an attack against the officers.]
[The police struck back]
[and they engaged in conflict,]
especially when the protesters arrived
at the Terminal Parque Dom Pedro.
It’s interesting to analyze
the police repression on Tuesday.
[Because the act was very peaceful until]
[we got to Terminal Parque Dom Pedro.]
[And we have entered]
[the Terminal Parque Dom Pedro]
[in other occasions]
[over the past years.]
We agreed on a specific route
with the movement’s leadership.
[But they didn’t]
[follow the agreement,]
because there isn’t really
a leadership unity,
there are many people presenting
themselves as leaders of the movement.
The shock troops surrounded
the Terminal Parque Dom Pedro
and didn’t let us inside.
[A very strong repression started]
[and the people got very motivated]
[by the fight and didn’t want]
[to simply go back home.]
They talked about anarchic-punks,
but those who were there
knew it was actually
the Black Block.
I frankly don’t know how associated
they were with the MPL.
But they were there.
The Black Block is a tactic;
it’s not a political group.
[This new tactic puts a question:]
[What is more legitimate,]
the violence against people,
committed by the police,
[or the destruction of public]
[and private properties?]
On that day, some had masks
on and wore black,
[and they knew about]
[the history in Seattle, Genova.]
[They knew the anarchic-punk strategy,]
[especially the anarchist one,]
[which was applied that day.]
Our tactic force had to act,
precisely,
because they were attacking police
officers at the Parque Dom Pedro.
We negotiated with the police
when we were at Paulista avenue,
trying to hold back the repressions
like the ones that had already happened;
a lot of people were hurt.
[Everything was going well.]
[We got to Paulista avenue without]
[any sort of complications]
[among the protesters.]
[But the police clearly set an ambush]
[waiting for us at the MASP.]
[We were supposed to close]
[the act at MASP,]
[but they started to shoot and throw]
[bombs before we could get to MASP.]
And then it happened,
what everybody already saw.
[You'll have to throw bombs]
[all night long!]
I believe what is happening
is a historically know phenomenon,
but which has huge singularities.
There is a mismatch
between the citizens
and the institutions
that represent them.
Everyone has the right to reunite
in a public place
without needing
someone’s authorization.
Isn’t it your job to see
that the law is followed?
Yes.
Is the law being followed now?
You are keeping the citizens
from coming and going;
you are throwing
tear gas bombs on people.
Is this justice?
What if it was your
son marching here?
-Would you throw a bomb on him?
-I don’t know.
All that I know is that you people
have set buses on fire,
broken vehicles, hurt officers,
written on buses...
-Did I set fire on buses?
-I don’t know. I don’t know.
Must I pay for somebody
else’s crimes?
But that’s what you’re telling me.
You are justifying your actions.
Should I pay for
the crime of someone else?
I was hit with a bomb
in the face, you coward!
There was a sort of guide
on the Internet,
explaining how to cope with
the tear gas, something like that.
And it became viral on the Internet
that the best way to deal with
tear gas was to use vinegar.
[Vinegar.]
[Vinegar is the new Anthrax]
[Vinegar]
He was holding a substance
that he claims to be vinegar.
It will pass by the police
inspection for confirmation.
[The vinegar became a joke.]
Being arrested before even
getting to the protests,
because you are holding vinegar,
doesn’t seem to make sense.
Vinegar.
You can stand right there
with your hands back!
[What?]
[Am I being arrested?]
Stand right there
with your hands back!
[Vinegar is the new Anthrax]
It’s easier to make people cry
a little with some tear gas
then to be in a situation like that,
which everybody saw, including Folha.
A police officer in the position
of maybe killing someone,
[because he was attacked]
[by a bunch of people]
[and he was carrying]
[a 40 caliber pistol,]
[which is not the proper weapon.]
[He shouldn’t even have]
[been alone at that place.]
[Stop! Stop!]
Go on ahead!
Lead the march ahead!
Brazil only had two big movements,
at the most,
which were the “Diretas Já”,
Direct Elections Now,
[and the impeachment of president Collor,]
[both were big public manifestations.]
But the country doesn’t have a tradition
of public manifestations.
If you take France, for example,
there is a tradition that lasts.
If the French destroy
subway stations in France
they’re doing it for the cause.
If people break subway stations
at Paulista avenue,
they are seen as lazybones, who don’t
want anything to do with work...
Maybe if we were French, we would be
fancier and be called activists.
This is interesting.
Let’s look at the guidelines
of protests around the world.
[Chile: 400 thousand people]
[on the streets asking for free,]
[quality public education.]
[Israel, Tel-Aviv: they asked]
[the State to regulate]
[the costs on habitation.]
[Spain, the Indignants:]
[true democracy]
[and the chance to oppose]
[the economic system]
[that was destroying the country.]
[Tunisia and Egypt: besides the ideas]
[of democracy and dignity,]
[it was also about a well-fare State]
[that doesn’t exist in those countries.]
[All of these movements asked for]
[something very clearly:]
more democracy.
THURSDAY, JUNE 13TH
[Come out to the streets!]
[Come against the raise!]
[Hands over your head!]
[R$ 3,20 is a robbery!]
[On Thursday it was]
[a completely different scenario.]
When we left
to do this coverage,
we had already read some
statements by the police,
saying the demonstrators
wouldn’t be left so comfortable
to protest like they wanted to.
Many people were arrested.
Look over there.
-They got Luisa!
-Where?
Over there.
Let me go!
Go back! Go back!
My friend is there!
My work colleague is there.
All we are looking for
is our rights!
And these shitheads wearing
uniforms keep hitting us!
They aimed the fucking
pepper spray in my eye!
[They walked from the Municipal]
[Theater to Consolação street,]
where the conflict began.
Actually, it wasn’t a conflict;
it was more like a massacre
coming from the police.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
What happened to you, Ma’am?
-How old are you?
-67.
-What’s your name?
-Maria Bernadete.
-Tell me, Dona Maria, what happened?
-I was shot with a rubber bullet.
They are going to shoot
in this direction.
I will file a police report.
The movement said they
would stop at Roosevelt square,
but that’s not what happened.
Thursday was pure brutality.
Cowards!
Murderers!
Stay here,
because here is safe.
Safe?
It’s safe.
São Paulo is a safe city.
During the entire time, on Thursday,
I saw the police hitting people,
shooting, throwing bombs towards
people who were shouting:
“No violence!”
I was surrendered,
you son of a bitch!
I was surrendered!
I was surrendered,
you piece of shit!
Giu, was shot
in the eye, man!
-Who?
-Giu.
We were walking up Augusta street
when we ran into the shock troops.
I just stood there,
I was wearing my identification
from Folha around my neck,
I didn’t have my cell phone
because it ran out of battery,
and I didn’t say
a word to any of them.
[Then a shock officer stepped]
[ahead of the others,]
who were holding shields,
and pointed his gun at me.
[That had happened]
[several times that day,]
[so I didn’t really think]
[he’d shoot me.]
But he shot.
[Did you see]
[him aiming at you?]
I saw it.
I saw him aiming at me,
but I never thought
he would shoot.
Because they had aimed
at me before that evening,
but no one had shot.
I was there doing my job.
And I am a woman...
I could never have imagined
that a uniformed policeman
would shoot me in the face.
Our police force is well-built.
The police force was destabilized
by the lack of communication
[with this group.]
We were surrounded.
At a certain moment,
when we got to Consolação street,
I remember looking to one side
and there was the shock troop,
at the other side
there was the cavalry troop,
looking ahead
there were bombs coming.
The order was disrupted, therefore
the series of police interventions.
Fucking rich kid.
Shut up! Shut up!
[From day one,]
[we had many protesters arrested.]
[Many protesters who were]
[simply walking in the streets]
were taken to the police station
and charged with crimes
they hadn’t committed.
-Excuse me. Excuse me.
-What did he do?
He assaulted the troops.
Excuse me.
In Brazil, the public system
is totally under-prepared.
Schools, hospitals...
The police couldn’t be different.
Stop right there!
Stop!
Get back!
Get back and wait!
[You can see by their reaction]
[they didn’t receive proper training.]
Their nervous reaction
doesn’t make sense.
You can see they’re under prepared.
[Maybe they’re “well-prepared”]
[when no one is watching,]
when they are in the suburbs
and you can’t see what they’re doing.
What you saw here is the same thing
that happens every day
[with groups]
[that aren’t middle class.]
It’s the same thing, but this time
the middle class was filming.
These fuckers are filming us.
[If you have records]
[of this kind of behavior,]
it surely doesn’t reflect the attitude
of most officers
who were at the marches
of the Free Pass Movement.
[The State Government,]
[the shock troop,]
the police, they all clearly
attempted to checkmate the movement
and tried to stop people from going
to the streets at any cost.
This movement
is organized by whom?
By a tiny little group of vandals,
whose actions are clearly criminal.
Are they linked
to a political party?
We must investigate
to verify what’s the origin.
Tomorrow there will be more!
Tomorrow there will be
a lot more!
Tomorrow there will be more!
Tomorrow there will be
a lot more!
On that week,
the media played a role
as important as the violence
from the police,
in terms of creating outrage.
The press reflected the huge indignation
the public opinion
developed towards
minority movements.
We’ve gotten used to minority movements
in the last ten years.
Any 50 people can stop Paulista avenue
if they are labeled as “social movement”.
That’s a way of making the city
hostage of organized groups.
I think the editorials
of Folha and Estado de São Paulo,
on the next day,
will become historical,
considering the repercussions
they caused.
They were demanding more repression,
saying the State was being weak,
affirming Paulista avenue
should be taken back.
Well, the press demanded things
to be done the right way,
and the police translated it
on their own terms.
The translation was
“Now, it is our time to play”.
Then, when the police started to play,
the public opinion became revolted,
and this was also
reflected by journalism.
I think journalism and the public
opinion have walked side by side.
The media accepted the situation;
because there was no way
it could go on denying
that the movement
was taking huge proportions.
The media could
no longer be against it.
But they supported the movement in a
way that wouldn’t hurt their interests.
That’s exactly
what Arnaldo Jabor did.
One day he said it was vandalism,
it was abominable...
They are the violent imitation,
of a 50’s socialism imitation,
that the ancient
left still stands for.
This middle class insurgents
aren’t even worth R$ 0,20.
And the other day he says
“It’s great that
they’re out on the streets”.
At first sight, this movement
seemed like a pointless provocation,
that many were mistaken
to criticize, including me.
I don’t think the press was mistaken
in neither of the two opinions
that were adopted.
At the first moment,
the press wasn’t asking for violence
towards peaceful protesters.
And at the second moment,
the media was right to denounce
the absurd violence of the police.
Are you going
to put Datena on the film?
Wasn’t our question clear?
“Are you in favor
of protests with riots?”.
That would be a better way
to put the question.
2.839 people said they are
in favor of this kind of protesting.
It’s very interesting,
because these anchormen are normally
addicted to public opinion.
The viewer that calls us is seeing
everything calm in the image;
he may misinterpret the question.
Ask the question like a suggested.
They don’t go against
the public opinion.
If the audience wants to know
about the police,
they’ll talk about the police.
When Datena started seeing there was
another side to the history,
he was smart enough to...
I can tell the people are so angry
about the ticket fare increase;
it doesn’t matter if it’s the bus,
the subway, the train.
People are so angry they will
support any kind of protest.
If the media hadn’t changed sides
after June 13th
and hadn’t convoked the entire
country to participate,
MPL wouldn’t
have achieved victory.
I noticed it by the people
in my everyday life,
colleagues from work,
who up to that moment
only talked
about the vandalism.
I couldn’t tell them
I was participating in the marches.
I always managed a way to go,
but I couldn’t tell them.
After June 13th, I mentioned I had gone
to a march and it was suddenly cool.
[What you see there is the vehicle]
[of Record network on fire.]
[You’d tell me is the destruction]
[of the network’s assets.]
[But I see it differently;]
[I think it’s a great sign.]
[Come out to the streets!]
[Come against the raise!]
[No violence!]
[There is something very new,]
[which already became very common.]
It’s the power new medias
have on convoking people.
[That’s very new]
[and it’s extremely important.]
[In São Paulo, the turning point]
[was in a moment]
[when there was criminalization]
[against the movement.]
The movement peacefully
took the streets,
the journalists and protesters
were severely hit by the police.
[And the society got to see that,]
[it ran the social networks.]
[It was the citizens who changed]
[the way the history was being told.]
[With their phones, their cameras,]
[they documented independently]
[and spread pieces]
[that had quality and importance.]
[The material they had shot]
[was largely broadcasted.]
At that moment everything
was empowered in the country,
including the importance
of citizen journalism.
[The Media Ninja]
[is not a secret organization;]
[it’s a proposition]
[for a network of collaborative]
[and independent journalism.]
An event was created on Facebook...
The entire country...
It’s happening in Rio,
in São Paulo...
The TV and the media
are distorting everything.
[The social networks]
[became crucial.]
[More important]
[than sharing your opinion,]
is becoming the channel through
which opinions are spread.
It has always existed, what differs
are the ways to do it.
At the Bastille,
how did the people reunite?
Here in Rio, in less than 15 hours
a huge march was organized
for the funeral of Edson Luís,
a student murdered by the police.
The huge march was done
without the Internet,
but there was the radio,
the telephone...
mouth to mouth
and things like that.
At the end, those
differences correspond
to the means available
at each time,
but all these means
have always worked
and new means
will go on working, I hope.
MONDAY, JUNE 17TH
[Some say the protest on Monday]
[had 100 thousand people,]
but we heard the police talking about
over 1 million people on the streets,
in the entire city of São Paulo.
Oh, fuck, the people are out!
[We made it very clear]
[the manifestation really was]
about the R$ 0,20.
It was about the fare increase.
It makes a huge difference
in the budget of my outskirts!
I’m here for him.
So that he can have quality
transportation in his future.
What a coincidence,
there is no violence
when the police isn’t here.
People are right.
They are acting like a family,
fighting for rights
that belong to them.
I agree with them.
Especially when
there is no violence.
We got a call that the National
Congress was being invaded.
I thought “Oh, fuck“.
I felt so much adrenaline that day,
as if it was the Bastille.
That’s why I went
to Palácio dos Bandeirantes.
If they were going to force
governor Alckmin out,
I wanted to be there to see it.
São Paulo represents
the main economy in the country,
that’s why it drives
a lot more attention.
MPL always knew that if one day
we organized an uprising in São Paulo,
like it was done in other cities,
it would spread around the country.
[We are part...]
[...of a national fight,]
[...of a world fight.]
[We can’t stop now.]
[We will only stop]
[when we get]
[1 million]
[2 million]
[3 million]
[20 million]
[people here]
[to tell the politicians]
[that it isn’t right]
[what they do]
[with our money,]
[with our health,]
[with our education.]
[Tomorrow it will be bigger!]
They just invaded
the National Congress!
Aha-Uhu, the Congress is ours!
Monday I got very sad.
I was surprised with the amount
of people on the streets.
At start, I thought
it was very positive,
but I was worried when I left.
At that day I saw lots people
carrying the national flag,
organized groups
giving away national flags,
anarchists, the Black Block,
some political parties...
There were a lot of groups
that hated each other that day,
and they were all there together.
I saw a total scattering
of the main agenda.
I could barely hear people
shouting about the transportation.
While I was at the manifestation,
I thought it was beautiful.
But when I got home I saw many
people posting worried comments on-line
about the political right
trying to co-opt members,
saying they didn’t like
what they’d seen,
that the movement had lost focus.
But I got home
with my soul cleansed.
[The police declared]
[it was a preventive measure.]
TUESDAY, JUNE 18TH
[The police intelligence identified]
[a new attempt to invade the building,]
[after the acts that happened today]
[in other Brazilian cities.]
[Thank you, Brasília.]
[It is now 6:12PM.]
Now..
we will
meet
with the other fellows.
For that,
we will
turn
the next left.
Everybody together
and organized.
Today the city will stop.
Tuesday was a true popular
uprising in the city.
[The movement couldn’t...]
[ensure a route]
[for the march.]
We didn’t mean to go
to the City Hall.
When it's over...
Don’t go outside!
Tell everyone not to go outside!
You must gather everyone
in the great hall.
They are going
to turn over the car.
Pay attention!
We resisted as much as we could
from calling the shock troop.
But the situation
in the building is unsafe now.
So, unfortunately, the shock
troop is getting in position...
Excuse me.
[I was in the building]
[when City Hall was attacked.]
I could clearly see
the police had stepped back.
At a certain moment,
only the municipal guard was there.
The government really meant
to hold back the protesters
who were trying to invade the building
using only the municipal guard.
But then the situation in that area
got out of control.
City Hall warned the police.
I too got a text message
from a Secretary warning me
the shock troop was coming.
The protesters were heading
to the Municipal Theater to invade it,
and the shock troop
took 2 hours to get there.
-Have you ever done this before?
-Never. It’s the first time.
-What does it feel like?
-This is our money, from our taxes.
-What are you doing? Stealing?
-No, I’m just breaking stuff.
I don’t take anything.
I have an old TV at home.
-And who deserves what you’re doing?
-The governments deserve it.
[There’s this ideologically]
[violent group.]
[They think]
[that’s what must be done;]
they must strike
[institutions]
[that represent capitalism.]
[This group got mixed]
[with people on the streets,]
[people who live on the streets,]
[delinquents around the city.]
They took advantage
of this situation.
The police was totally absent.
If people thought
the police was violent,
[they saw what it was like]
[without the police.]
WEDNESDAY, JUNE 19TH
We’ve been talking with Mayor
Fernando Haddad during these last days.
[We will go back to the R$ 3,00 fare,]
[so that the city can move on.]
I got the City Counsel
together this week.
We must reopen the discussion
about the consequences
implied in the decision taken,
for today and for the future.
6 years ago everybody
thought it was crazy,
and now people are discussing
it on the streets, at the bars.
If I were a transport businessman,
I’d frankly think twice before
crushing the people to get more profit,
because the people
are very aware of things now.
We’ll have to cut back
some investments,
because the companies
can’t afford the fare reduction.
The State will bear these costs
by adjusting the investments,
holding back in some other areas.
We’ll drink beer to celebrate...
THURSDAY, JUNE 20TH
People go out to the streets
for very different reasons.
This scattering allows
certain movements,
which are a bit more organized,
to take on the streets
with different convictions
and clash against one another.
No fascism!
No political parties!
In June 2013, nobody on the streets
put their differences aside,
for the benefit of common purpose.
On the contrary, people got out
on the streets
bringing all their differences.
Talk to yourselves,
you bunch of losers!
If the people on the streets
are side by side,
but they have
different political opinions,
which sometimes are incompatible,
surely the differences will appear,
and there will be violent episodes.
You’re a bunch of bourgeois!
You don’t make any sense!
-I don’t represent a political party!
-So what?
No violence!
Hey, let the girl talk!
Thief! Thief!
Fascists! Fascists!
You won’t go through!
Morons! Morons!
Opportunists!
A political party
won’t solve this problem.
Don’t oppress!
You’re being oppressive.
There was no oppression
to freedom of speech.
There wasn’t?
How can you oppress someone
because they held up a flag?
The movement has no owners,
my friend.
By your speech, you want
the military dictatorship back!
What about this riot?
People are almost killing themselves.
They don’t seem
to understand one another.
Each day there are
more isolated groups.
Before it was everybody together.
We didn’t agree with many
of the causes that started to appear.
Many conservative ideas
started taking over the marches.
But we always understood the protests
should be centered
on the decrease of the fares.
It’s only natural that
a huge popular mobilization,
especially one that turned out
to be victorious
and revoked the fare increase,
will motivate
other manifestations to flourish,
and many other topics
will be taken to the streets.
Groups of kids
who are not usually political
[participated on the demonstrations.]
Then they became orphans,
in a certain way,
but they kept on going.
But there were also groups
with very bad intentions.
This Thursday at the Paulista avenue
there were skinheads,
“the white supremacy”, neo-Nazis,
people from the extreme right
who were trying
to co-opt these young kids.
When it became evident that there was
a huge level of discontentment,
and you had the right
to show your discontent,
people stopped repressing
their opinions.
All the demands appeared
on the streets,
in a spectrum going from the extreme
political left to the extreme right.
I’d say that’s very natural,
it means that politics
has regained the streets.
Let me ask you:
who is here in the protest
because of the bus fare?
Raise your hands.
Who is here for the rest?
Renan, Sarney,
get out of this country!
Feliciano,
my asshole has no religion.
It’s missing focus.
They all want different things.
It’s education for one,
corruption to another...
Another one is about the PEC 37.
It doesn’t work out if everybody
wants to approach all topics
at the same time.
I think this is going nowhere.
Flags! Flags!
How much is it?
-R$ 20
-R$ 20?!
What are you protesting for?
I’m against this law...
this constitutional amendment
they are planning to do.
-Which one?
-PC... PC 37
What is the PEC 37?
-PC 37!
-What is it?
PEC 37 is a project
for a constitutional amendment
that limits
the investigation activities
to the members of the civil
and federal police,
no longer allowing the Public
Prosecutor’s Department to proceed
with police investigations not only
as the one entitled
for the criminal prosecution,
but also as the one which holds
the right for the investigations.
PEC 37 is...
Oh, my gosh...
It’s a...
How can I say?
Then what happens?
They go out
to the streets to protest.
And these protests
seem a little shallow.
They protest for education,
health, against corruption.
These are protests of people
with no political instruction.
PEC 37 wants to blind us
for these robberies,
these crimes that the government makes,
well, not the government,
the people
at the House of Representatives...
They want to blind us
for all of that.
But that’s the short version.
It’s very complex.
And I’m also here
for the health system.
I’m doing this
because I’m Brazilian,
even though I’m going
to London in September.
I’m a Brazilian citizen
and I’m outraged
with the fucking corruption!
Fascist!
Then respect
your country’s constitution!
No political parties!
We’re going down
a dangerous path, guys.
-No, we aren’t.
-It’s a dangerous path.
The dangerous path
is to be manipulated.
We no political parties
we’ll go back to dictatorship.
That’s what
we’re fighting for!
They may not like the politicians,
I don’t like them either.
They may not like president Dilma,
governor Alckmin, mayor Haddad,
but there hasn’t been invented
another way to mediate
the State and the society,
if not by politics
and political parties.
Attention: the national broadcast
of radio and television is now open
for the declaration
of president Dilma Rousseff.
WEDNESDAY, JUNE 26TH
Come rain! We’ll get wet!
And wet we will fight!
My friends,
All we Brazilians
are following closely
the manifestations
occurring in the country.
It isn’t lack of resources;
it’s not lack of money.
There is lots of money.
The World Cup is producing
millions and millions.
And the worker
is the one who suffers.
We want these criminals
in the police in jail!
I trust this moment we’re living.
It’s a slap in our face,
as strong as we deserve it.
For those who can’t stand
the traffic in São Paulo anymore,
join our fight!
In reality, everybody
has causes for dissatisfaction.
But those who really feel it
in their skins
the matters related
to transportation, safety,
are the lower classes
living in the outskirts.
I like it when the people
from the outskirts say,
“the outskirts
were never sleeping”.
Because the idea that says “Brazil
was sleeping and now it’s awake”
makes you think everyone was well,
laying in their golden beds...
The outskirts were never
sleeping in golden beds.
Of course I didn’t like this
talk of “Brazil has awoken”,
because I’m part of a Brazil
that was never sleeping.
And there is something else,
the bullets are not rubber
bullets in the outskirts.
I think many mothers,
when they heard about
rubber bullets in protests downtown,
must have thought, “we’d rather have
rubber bullets here too,
my son would still be alive”.
The people from the outskirts
always go to the streets.
Even before the protests,
they did monthly manifestations
on behalf of the transportation,
habitation.
The truth is they don’t stand out
as much as a protest in Paulista avenue.
If the outskirts manifestations
were at Paulista avenue,
I’m sure the bullets
wouldn’t be made of rubber.
It’s complicated
at the outskirts.
You can go to hospital’s doors
and see what it’s like...
[A 11th grade kid]
[can’t write or read.]
Some may say I exaggerate...
We are a country that lost
55.000 people murdered last year.
It’s a lot of people,
over 50.000 people murdered.
[The placid shores of Ipiranga heard]
[The blaring shout of a heroic folk]
Fight! Fight!
People have the power!
Our political system has shut out
the society and is closed around itself,
there is no longer
a polarization of positions,
when you can tell clearly the ideology
in the power from the opposition.
So, what we have is a mismatch
between a political system
that works based
is this governability agreement,
and the people on the streets with
a huge variety of political opinions,
that are not reflected
in the political system.
We are living a very
strong political emptiness.
For the first time,
after the dictatorship ended,
we have the depletion
of a political cycle,
without forming
another alternative cycle.
It was very clear to the authorities
that none of them could represent
what was happening
on the streets.
Nor PT or PSDB could present
themselves as representatives
for the protesters.
[We’re in an island.]
[It’s a blue island,]
[an illuminated island,]
a fantasy island.
It’s like there is nothing
happening outside.
WEDNESDAY, JUNE 26TH
These kids got ahead of us.
[The kids are out on the streets]
to show how fragile
are the institutions.
[They are the true democrats]
[and they are worried about]
[the fragility of the official]
[institutions caused by our mistakes,]
[the mistakes]
[of the Federal Supreme Court,]
[mistakes of the executive branch.]
[Because we are unable]
[to deal together with rules]
that show the independence
of each branch of power.
We are under a threat.
[The prove is that people,]
[tired of waiting for our actions,]
[took the streets.]
I don’t recall any episode
in Brazilian history
[in which you had]
[a huge mass of people]
[marching towards the national]
[congress to break it.]
[And the police couldn’t do]
[anything to prevent it,]
[only deviate the protesters]
[to another side]
[so they would set something]
[else on fire.]
[So they set]
[the Itamaraty building on fire.]
[Now we can see fire.]
What we are living
today is a reaction.
All actions have a reaction.
They had it coming,
people are reacting.
The politicians
are generally like that,
they can smell the demands
on the streets
and they follow it to try
and understand
what the people are asking for,
even if they don’t agree
with any of that.
The people answered they
were happy about the country.
Why, then, all this
dissatisfaction exploding now?
[Another day of efficiency]
[in the congress,]
[like we had never seen before.]
[The protesters who fought for]
[the rejection of PEC 37]
[are now singing]
[the national anthem.]
[The senators approved the project]
[that makes the crime]
[of corruption hideous.]
[I have a question.]
[The protests will start in 30,]
[40 minutes, out there.]
[Are we going]
[to close this session?]
[As the House president,]
[I can answer you]
[that we’ll be here]
[all night if needed,]
[as long as the manifestation]
[is out there.]
[Step carefully.]
[If you can’t deal with the ants,]
[don’t poke the anthill.]
[My government has been fighting,]
[alongside the national congress,]
[for the oil royalties]
[to be used 100% in education.]
She says the royalties
will go to education.
Who will control this?
Who guarantees
it will go to education?
The protesters react like that
because they think the people
in the power are cynical,
because the movement
was actually against them.
The congress recognizes
the legitimacy
of democratic manifestations,
like the ones that happened today.
I personally gave orders
to the legislative police
not to repress
the popular manifestation.
The police are protecting
me while I’m here.
That’s very embarrassing.
Even in the worst moments
of revolutions around the world,
people protested against
the executive branch,
never against the legislative
or judiciary.
Where did we go wrong?
Hey, police!
Go fuck yourself!
If they don’t understand
that what is at stake here
is politics as a profession,
as a business,
then there is a real risk.
We will live in bitterness
not only because of our impotence,
celebrating with our vote
and mockery our distance
from the political system.
We will begin living a series of
tensions that won’t have an outlet,
a channel out.
That’s very bad,
it could produce destructive
results to everyone.
THURSDAY, JUNE 27TH
Guys, the idea is this:
we go together,
and come back together,
peacefully, from the Mineirão
soccer stadium, ok?
All those in favor
of going to Mineirão,
raise one of your hands.
Is this a joke or what?
They can afford the World Cup,
but not education.
In what measure the Confederations
Cup motivated the manifestations?
It was an influence not only
because the world press was here
and it was a good chance
to show the movement to the world,
but also because the sumptuousness
of the new stadiums
horrified the Brazilian people.
How can they build a stadium
in the FIFA standards,
as is the Brasilia stadium?
It is absurd.
Like you said, it’s like
Taj Mahal in Brasilia,
a city that doesn’t even
have soccer.
And they can’t build a hospital
in these same standards?
People have to accept that the best
hospital in Brasilia is the airport...
We must stop with this nonsense
of thinking soccer
and politics don’t mix.
That’s the most reactionary speech
you could possibly make.
That’s the speech João Havelange
made all his life,
the one he used
to support dictators.
Could be either Videla
or Médici, or Geisel.
“I don’t mix soccer with politics”.
Does your lack of political
consciousness allow you
to act like a barbarian then?
No. Things always get mixed.
You eat your
breakfast politically;
so you can only imagine
a soccer team,
which is capable
of mobilizing the country.
[Regarding the World Cup,]
[I want to make clear]
[that the money spent on]
[the arenas came from financings,]
[which will be properly paid]
[by the companies and governments]
[who are profiting]
[with these stadiums.]
The name of the true president
of Brazil, today, is FIFA.
FIFA got to our country and set
a State inside our State.
And that’s it.
It’s not possible!
Is it right to make
fools out of the people?
In 2014, we’ll all be out there
saying “vote for me!
I’ll be your representative
at the House of Representatives”.
[How are we representatives?]
What does hideous means?
Hideous means disgusting,
[something that makes you]
[want to throw up.]
Corruption kills people
at the doorsteps of hospitals.
in the highways.
Corruption steals the future
of an entire generation of Brazilians.
The politicians have never
denied they are criminals;
we are the ones
who are cowards.
We should be whipped by
them every day at 6:00 PM.
All of us, all the workers,
all the honest people
in this country,
should bend over before
them and get hit.
Because of all
we let them do...
Somehow I consented these
men to remain in power,
to leave the people
in misery.
I consented through my silence,
for being coward.
I think these men are right,
they ought to rob us,
because we are too coward.
We’re a very hypocrite society.
We give R$ 1,00 to a bum
but we don’t want to know
who turned that guy into a bum.
It’s the fucking revolution!
Revolution!
I see in this moment one of
the most important moments
in our history.
Today, thousands of people
occupy the streets.
There’s a clear
lack of leadership.
It’s a sign of renouncement to
the old way of making politics.
[Soccer, as sport in general,]
[is a symbol of peace among]
[the different cultures.]
[Brazil deserves to make]
[a great World Cup, and it will.]
When the supporters continued singing
a cappella the national anthem,
and the players singed together
while standing in the field,
something special happened.
I even wrote a column about it,
titled “The anthem’s fuel”.
SUNDAY, JUNE 30TH
[The placid shores of Ipiranga heard]
[The blaring shout of a heroic folk]
[The sun of Liberty in shining rays]
[Shone in homeland's sky at this instant]
[If the pledge of this equality]
[We could conquer with strong arm]
[In thy bosom,]
[O freedom]
[Our chest defy death itself!]
[O beloved,]
[Idolized homeland]
[Hail, hail]
[Brazil, an intense dream, a vivid ray]
[Of love and hope descends to earth]
[If in thy comely,]
[Smiling and limpid sky]
[The image of the Southern Cross blazes]
[Giant by thine own nature]
[Thou art beautiful, thou art strong,]
[An impavid colossus]
[And thy future mirrors thy greatness]
[Adored Land]
[Amongst a thousand others]
[Art thou, Brazil]
[O beloved homeland]
[Of the sons of this ground]
[Thou art kind mother,]
[Beloved homeland]
[Brazil!]
[In the democratic game,]
[the winner could become the loser]
[in the next 5 minutes,]
[or maybe nobody wins anything.]
Because the conflicts
are bigger than the solutions.
But I believe that,
in a very peculiar way,
[it could be a good change if we started]
[complaining about what’s wrong.]
Fuck the World Cup!
[40 million people.]
[We made a lot of progress]
[in the last 20 years,]
[thanks to the past governments,]
[the Brazilian society,]
[the democratic constitution.]
[This didn’t just magically happen.]
[We’ve been taking]
[more and more Brazilians]
[from extreme poverty conditions.]
[Now, this people want more.]
[There is the dream of a society]
[that goes beyond the consumer market.]
[Today, we can say we have]
[less social disparities,]
[and that reflects]
[on people´s right to consume.]
However, the public schools
still reproduce social disparities.
[The health system still]
[reproduces social disparities…]
Get out of there!
Get the fuck out of there!
[We will resist!]
You're discrediting
the popular wisdom
if you think the people mix victory
in sports with political needs.
Even in the specific moment of victory,
they don't mix the two things together.
It doesn’t mean the governments
don’t try to take advantage
of the situation, though.
Whether you're a conservative,
ultra-liberal, extreme-left,
anarchist, environmentalist,
ruralist… Nobody is satisfied.
Everyone feels the structure in power
needs to go through profound changes.
There were almost 1 million
people in Rio de Janeiro...
I don’t know how many thousand
in São Paulo, in Brasilia...
[We got so close!]
I think Brazil suffers
from premature ejaculation.
We were there, had some fun,
and thought,
“Is this what
revolution is like?
I’ve had enough,
I’m leaving.”
[The referee has whistled!]
[We’re the champions]
[of the Confederations Cup!]
[The month of June]
[brought out the need]
[for everyone to stop]
[and rethink themselves.]
[The political parties, the unions,]
[the mainstream media, the police,]
the political system...
everyone must stop
and balance things.
[To believe!]
[It’s time to unite and believe!]
[Tomorrow it will be greater!]