Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
You all right?
- Yep.
- How is boarding going?
- Better than home.
- Well,
it's just for the weekend.
- So that's all for her?
- Yes.
That's, what,
a year's worth?
It's two, maybe three
weeks, at a guess.
She drinks that much?
She does.
I thought you hated your mother.
Hate's a strong word.
Where's she sleeping?
She's bringing a nurse with
her. She has a broken leg.
Where's she sleeping?
The nurse is in the spare room.
- So she's where Mum was?
- She will want the sun.
Sam.
Sam, we're here.
Here. OK.
Come on.
So two people are gonna
die in that room now?
No. She's not coming
here to die, Sam.
She's coming here to get
better and to meet you.
She'll go back eventually.
Her bell still works.
Ooh. You all right there? Ooh.
You sold the horses.
They've gone to someone who
can afford to look after them.
What about Grace?
I'm not selling your mother's
horse, Sam.
She'll be lonely.
Well, we'll just have to give
her more attention then, eh?
Dad!
- Samuel?
- Sam.
Come closer.
- Turn around.
- What?
I want to take a look at you.
Do the girls like you?
Yeah.
Where is Sarah, my nurse?
- Not sure.
- And Robert?
- Dunno.
- Fuck.
I'm afraid I'm gonna have to as
you to take me to the bathroom.
The bathroom?
You do have one?
Believe me, this is far
more humiliating for me
than it is for you.
Go on, then.
- What?
- Leave.
- Blood of Christ.
- Body of Christ.
Right.
What do you think
of New Zealand?
The 4ft I've seen seem nice.
And Sam?
Sam looks like his mother.
Yes.
I'm surprised you've
sent him away.
You always said
it ruined your life.
Keeps him out of trouble.
I need you to read this.
Hey!
Don't be a bitch
and cry about it.
You missed a good party.
- Tracy Turnbull was there.
- Yeah, well,
- I'm not missing the next one.
- She has got the best tits!
This tastes like shit.
That's cos gin's not supposed
to be drunk straight;
- it's for cocktails and mixes.
- So is your mum.
So,
how much does an alcoholic
drink, anyway?
Two cases in two weeks.
- That's like a bottle a day.
- That's impressive.
Does she shit her pants?
- What?
- Nah, I'm serious.
You're a dick.
A kid drowned there once.
How?
Put rocks in his backpack and
tried to swim across the river.
Really?
Man, why would you
do something like that?
Maybe he wanted to.
♪ Kia mate ururoa.
Kia mate ururoa.
♪ Ko te haka a t -matauenga
♪ a Tkai taua, a T@@-ka-riri e.
- ♪ Takatakahia!
- ♪ Hi!
- ♪ Werowerohia!
- ♪ Ha! ♪
- Yes, boys!
- Numbers.
Numbers, numbers, numbers!
Looking wide. He's looking wide!
- Brother!
- Go, go, go! Get him in!
- Get him in!
- Come on, boys.
Go, go, go.
- Here! Wide, wide, wide!
- Come on, go. Go, boys.
- Fucking mama's boy.
- Get up, Sam!
- Go, go, go!
- Get him back up.
- Get him back up!
- Let's go, boys! Come on, boys!
Come on, boys!
Let's get it together! Come on!
- Tackle!
- Get up! Get up! Get up!
- Cover. Cover. Watch.
- Here!
- Watch. Watch.
- Let's go! Let's go!
Tackle! Get in below!
Get in below!
Ooh!
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Hey, Sam!
Get him off me!
- (WHISTLE TRILLS, CROWD SHOUTS
- What are you doing, man?
If you miss any rubbish,
it'll be in your bed
when you get back.
I won't be in England long.
Sarah will be here
the whole time.
I'm heading over to James'
for most of it anyway.
No, you aren't.
- What?
- I want you here
with your Grandmother.
You don't wanna hang around her.
- I don't have a choice.
- Really
Sarah's gonna need your help.
I have to sort out Ruth's trust.
It's easier if I do
that in England.
- She's your mother.
- Yes. I need to be there.
It has to be sorted now.
I'm not looking after
that old bitch.
She is an old bitch,...
but you're gonna help look afte
her, whether you like it or not.
She's the one thing
stopping us from going broke.
If you're gonna drink my booze
which I assume you are -
stay away from my
whisky. All right?
- Sure.
- And no parties.
- I mean it, Sam. No parties.
Not after last time.
I'll crucify you.
- All right.
- You'll be fine.
- Hmm?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you for offering to help.
I didn't.
Right.
Well, the main thing is her leg.
The bones were completely
severed when she fell,
and her skin can't handle
the plaster, hence the splints.
I'll just need your help
with moving her, really -
keeping her company,
giving me a break.
Look, I'll help, but I don't
wanna talk to her.
OK.
Hands here. OK?
Up here. That's it.
And one, two, three, lift.
There you go. Good.
- Thank you so much for coming.
- Oh. Not at all.
Um
Ruth?
- This is Reverend Matthews.
- Good morning.
Is it?
I thought you might
like to talk.
Why did you think that?
Forgive me. How can I help you?
Well, I'm here for you.
So we could just...
enjoy a cup of tea,
get to know each other.
I don't really do tea.
Or I could offer you communion
and absolution.
How do you mean?
Well, if you've got something o
your mind - regrets, perhaps -
then I can absolve you
I don't have regrets.
Right.
You should come
back another time.
We can talk about a deal, maybe.
Excuse me?
I can make a donation to your
church. Which church is it?
- Anglican.
- Now, I'm not judgmental.
I'm happy to work with
anyone for a clean slate.
- How much would it take?
- Ah.
500?
A thousand?
A thousand it is.
Look, no...
You do deals with the devil,
Madam, not with God.
Oh, come on. A cheque
is a far more honest transaction
than listening to my
regrets and shame.
Please take it.
You can't just buy your
way into heaven.
What can you offer me, then?
Well, if you don't
have faith,...
then nothing.
Well, then, fuck off.
Out!
You can't
speak to him like that.
I'll speak to
whom I like how I like!
You hit him!
- You're going to hell.
- I'm already there.
- Hello.
- Hey, Dad.
Sam. Good to hear from you.
Um, can you talk?
Yes.
- Is everything all right?
- Yeah, uh,...
- it's Mum's birthday.
- Yes.
I know.
- Are you going to visit her?
- I've got something planned.
That's great.
And Ruth?
How's she?
I think she just assaulted
someone.
Sounds like everything's
normal, then.
- Yeah. Yeah, no, it's fine.
- I told you!
Look, I'm...
I'm in the middle of something.
- Sure.
- I'm sorry. I need to go.
- OK.
- Is that OK?
- Bye.
- All right. All right, bye.
- Where are you going?
- Down the back of the farm.
- I need you to stay with Ruth.
- I can't.
- Yes, you can.
- I've got plans.
Stop sulking and go look
after your grandmother.
She's gone off in
a huff, has she?
Something like that.
So,
what shall we do?
What?
Perhaps you could show
me around the gardens.
- We could take a walk.
- A walk?
In my chair, you idiot.
Or maybe you could read to me.
I think I'll take a pass
on all of those options.
Excuse me?
I'll bring you food,
I'll take you to the bathroom
until Sarah gets
back. But that's it.
Please leave.
Just testing.
- It works
- Mm.
- Yes?
- I need to go to the bathroom.
Fight!
Argh!
You win. Round two. Fight!
- I'm hungry.
- What would you like?
Anchoveta on toast.
You'll have to make
me some more.
- Haven't you had enough?
- Oh, no, deary. Not nearly.
Gin to here, water to here,
and a squeeze of lemon.
Gin to there, water to there?
You heard.
So that's half gin
and half water?
Are you retarded?
Jesus.
Can you come here, please?
- Jesus!
- Don't ever water it down.
Now go and make it properly.
Shit.
Give me my gin,
you little shit!
Don't you dare!
Would you like another shot?
I would. Thank you.
Tell you what -
I won't move.
Finished?
Seems I have run
out of ammunition.
Go away, girl.
Go away!
Fuck off!
Ruth.
What were you thinking?
Shut up and help me
up, you little fuckwit.
How is your leg?
Fine.
Where's Sarah?
No idea.
She seemed upset.
- Maybe she won't come back.
- Oh, she'll come back.
She wants to save my soul.
Fat chance.
Sam, you are a bloody
shit. A bloody little shit.
So are you.
At least you're a fighter.
I'll go see where Sarah is.
Stay. Please have
a drink with me.
Why did you come here?
Can we not have
some small talk first?
Sure.
- Why did you come here?
- Oh, Christ's sake.
I needed a
I needed a holiday.
You have a broken leg,
and you and Dad hate each other.
No. I don't hate him.
I sent him away to boarding
school from the age of 5,
and I never told him
who his father was,
but I don't hate your father.
- What do you want?
- What do I want?
I want one more passionate
love affair.
Well, that's gonna be hard,
considering your
current situation.
You have no idea.
Now finish your drink.
- No. I'm not thirsty.
- Oh, come on.
We're not gonna have
a decent conversation
if we don't get drunk. Give it
to me. I'll show you how.
Ah. See?
Happy?
Can you do it again?
Enough.
I don't like this room much.
Must be rather painful
having me occupy it.
It is.
I'm sorry.
You didn't try to drink
with her, did you?
I did.
Well,
you're an idiot, then.
How does she do it?
She has the constitution
of a goat.
Is she all right?
I'm gonna take her into the
hospital later for a check-up.
I need your help.
- Uh-
- I wasn't asking.
- Sure.
- Let me, um
Let me look at that for you.
Relax, please.
Is she always like this?
I think it's got worse
since she hurt her leg.
- But you left me with her.
- Yes. Well,...
sometimes there's only
so much one can take.
She really drunk you under
the table, didn't she?
It's the gin. It's awful.
Why did you come here with her?
I don't really know.
What's all this?
I've been putting these
together for her.
She hates me doing it.
She looks like she's
had a lot of fun.
That's one way of putting
it. She was really there,
on the front lines,
taking photos.
- Really?
- Can you imagine?
Coming!
- She's up?
- She's always up early.
I said I'm coming.
Most people like sunsets.
I love the sunrise.
- Yeah, it's nice.
- Nice?
Please read some more.
This light allows
the imagination in.
Even these unkempt gardens
hold some magic.
One more hour, and they're
just overrun and crap.
Those photos.
You took them?
Your father hasn't told you
much about me, has he?
He said you were a photographer
and that you went to war.
- I did.
- Which ones?
Most of them, I suppose.
Thank you, Sarah.
I love the
games we humans play.
- Games?
- Each morning,
she brings me a cup
of tea, in the hope
that I will reach for it
before I reach for my usual.
- And you don't go for it?
- Of course not.
But I pretend to be grateful.
- Why?
- That's the game we play.
Are we gonna play games?
Well, then. We shan't.
Perhaps you can get some of you
friends over to sort out this
mess.
No, I don't think my friends
are gonna wanna clean up
these gardens.
- Why not?
- Cos we're all drunken louts.
You sound
like my kind of people.
- Can you knock!?
- Sorry.
What do you want?
She asked me to get some
new clothes for you.
- Why?
- She said you dress like shit.
Come in.
- Hmm.
- Turn around.
- I'm not turning around.
Shut up, turn around,
and tuck yourself in.
Women appreciate a man who
takes pride in his appearance.
How do you feel?
- I feel like a dick.
- Well, you don't look like one.
No. I... I think it could
improve your sex life.
- What do you mean by that?
- What do you think I mean?
- Well, I'm not-
- Of course not.
You just haven't had sex yet.
- I'm not a virgin!
- I never said you were.
Hello, Sarah.
What do you think?
- Oh.
Very handsome.
- (SEATBELT CLICKS, KEYS JANGLE
- What are you doing?
- Taking you to the doctor.
- Where are your flannels?
Excuse me?
We're not leaving until you
have your flannels on.
Well, I guess we're
going anywhere, then.
There's a little healing
going on, but not much.
- What do you mean?
- Things are going slowly.
Could I walk again?
Not like you used to.
Is there anything else?
Perhaps we should think
about putting in a catheter.
It will limit your trips to the
bathroom and take away any
unnecessary movement from
the leg. That could help.
- Sarah?
- It might be a good idea.
What happens if I
meet someone,...
we have a few drinks.
Do I have to spell it out?
You will have to abstain
from sexual intercourse.
Mm.
Listen to me very carefully.
I will walk again,...
and I will never have
a fucking catheter!
OK.
- What was it like?
- What was what like?
War.
War is It's simply a waste.
A senseless bloody waste.
Some boys like you get to live.
Others don't.
Tell you what -
I think we should have a party.
- That sounds like fun.
- Mm.
- With who?
- Your drunken louts.
Ah, no.
I don't think that's
a good idea.
- Why not?
- The place will get smashed.
Dad'll kill me.
Well, your dad has always
had a stick up his bum.
Why doesn't he want
you to have fun?
Mm. Ruth!
I did something dumb last time.
What did you do?
- It doesn't matter.
- Go on. Spit it out.
Mum was sick.
Dad wanted to cheer me up.
So we threw a party.
And I got drunk and
decided I wanted to...
drive to the hospital
at 3 in the morning.
But I crashed,...
badly. I
totalled Dad's car.
- You were OK?
- Yeah.
But then one of my friends brok
a tap and flooded the house.
It was carnage.
Perhaps I want some carnage
right now.
Hello?
Hi. Is Robert there?
Is that you, Steven?
- Steven?
- Yes.
Darling,
it's your lawyer.
Hello, Steve?
- Hi, Dad.
- Sam.
'Darling?'
- Who's that?
- She's a friend.
- Really?
- Yes.
- I hope you're having fun,...
- Sam.
...while I look after
your mother.
It must be 3 in the morning.
Do you want to talk
about this now?
- No. Not really.
- I'll be home soon.
I'm almost done here.
I loved your mother, Sam.
I miss her every day.
Sure.
- Sam.
- Anyways,
I was just ringing to say
that we're having a party.
Sam-
All right!
So, write down your order,
in terms of alcohol,
and Sarah will
go out and buy it.
- I will?
- In return,
I want you to clean
up these gardens.
As you can see,
they're a disgrace.
It's a lot of work,
- Miss.
- Yes.
So, how much
booze are we talking?
How much do you want?
- Three kegs?
- Deal.
Really?
But no fucking about.
I'm expecting a proper
job from you,
or you get nothing.
- Oh yeah.
- Choice.
It's cheaper than
a gardener, I suppose.
I'm enjoying the view.
You're such a tart.
Oh, shot!
Whoo-hoo!
- Let's go. Let's go.
- Yeah, bro.
It always surprises me that
your father came here.
This was Mum's dream.
And he wanted to
get away from me.
Why didn't you tell him
who his father was?
I wasn't ready.
And when I was,...
he wasn't interested.
- Who was he?
- Some fool.
Have you ever been
up here at sunrise?
Once. Mum and I brought
our sleeping bags up,
and we slept under the stars.
I'd like to do that once
before I head back.
Is that right?
You don't think
I could handle it?
Oh, I never said that.
What?!
Hey, don't point that shit
at me, man - seriously.
Oh, it's not loaded, you pussy.
Fuck off.
Seeing someone
shot is not pleasant.
I've seen boys younger
than you with their brains
decorating their
best friends' chests.
Now, hand it over, and
I'll show you how to use it.
- Go on, then.
- Mm.
OK.
This is gonna be interesting.
Pull!
Oh shit!
Again!
Cheers.
- Is that her?
- Yeah.
She was hot. I would definitely-
You're talking about my grandma.
Right. Sorry.
- Holy shit.
- What?
Females are arriving,
and there's some pretty
good-looking ones too!
Bullshit. Really?
Sorry. Excuse me.
Oh, guess the word got around
- Hey. Um...
- Hi. Where are you from?
You're not from around here.
Oh, it's you.
Are we making too much
noise or something?
Oh, wouldn't that
make me a cliché?
Old woman who wants peace
and quiet.
So what's the problem, then?
There's no problem.
- You said you wanted carnage.
- I did.
But a little bit of
sophistication wouldn't hurt.
Oh, we don't do
sophisticated carnage.
Obviously not. Look.
Why don't you just go outside,
find a girl, seduce her?
You're not gonna get laid
wheeling an old woman
around a party.
Are you afraid of something?
What? No.
Do you not wanna
be seen with me?
- No.
- Good!
Uh-oh. LAUGHS: You are a shit.
Don't you
- Hello, love.
- Hello, handsome.
- Don't be a hold-out.
- Eh?
Offer her some smoke.
It isn't polite to
bogart a joint.
Do you want some?
I've had better.
- Sarah?
- Absolutely not.
- Hey.
You having fun?
Yep.
Can you scratch her eyes out?
I'm not doing your dirty work.
Shall we dance?
- You could drop me.
- No, I won't.
You better not.
I can take it from here.
Ruth.
We'll see you at the hospital.
OK.
Um,
I'll have the pathology
results tomorrow. OK?
Thanks.
I need a cup of coffee.
Do you want one?
- No, thank you.
- Sam?
I'm fine. Thank you.
How are you?
- I'm all right.
- I should have been here.
We were
fine without you.
Oh yes. Well, obviously not.
How are you feeling?
I'm all right.
I shouldn't be here.
It's up to you and Dad, I guess.
It's up to me.
Uh, I got you a present.
Don't go overboard.
The taint of rubber...
adds a certain charm.
You said you didn't
wanna play games.
I don't.
Are you dying?
Well,...
we're all dying.
I wanna know.
Yes.
- Why didn't you tell me?
- Would you have spoken to me,
if you knew?
Can I ask you a question?
When you crashed your
dad's car at the party,
- did you do it on purpose?
- What?
You heard me.
The hospital just called to
say they're moving Ruth
to the hospice.
Can you stop by and see her
on your way back to school?
Nope.
I'm worried he's gonna
try and keep her there.
Aren't you her nurse?
Your father's not interested
in what I think any more.
- Well, he's in charge.
- She doesn't want to die alone.
- That's why she came here.
- Really?
Doesn't she have
friends back home?
- Not really.
- Well, that's not surprising.
- She's afraid.
- Well, that's her problem.
Mum didn't wanna be alone.
She wanted me to be with
her when she died,...
hold her hand as she passed.
And I promised her I would.
And then she started to go, and
it looked like she
was in pain,...
started making all
these funny sounds.
I couldn't bear it.
I was scared, afraid,
so I left.
And she died without me.
I'm a coward.
- You're not a coward.
- I got stoned at her funeral.
I haven't been to
her grave since.
I didn't know she was
dying until she got here.
- Right.
- That's why I had to go back.
I should never have
allowed her into our lives.
I made a mistake, and I'm sorry.
The doctors want her to stay
in the hospital. I agree.
It's for the best. She won't
come back home, OK?
I really don't care.
Sam!
Away, old man;
give me thy hand; away!
King Lear hath lost,
he and his daughter taken.
A man may rot, even here.
Men must endure
their going hence,
even as their coming hither.
Ripeness is all. Come on.
And that's true too.
Mr Stevenson?
Dude.
Stevenson. Stevenson!
What are you doing?
Stop. Stop it!
Stop it! Stop it!
Awesome!
You're expelled, Stevenson.
You hear me?
You're gone!
Aren't you supposed
to be at school?
I got expelled.
I'm proud of you.
All the best people
get expelled.
I was expelled, you know.
- I'm sure you were.
- Twice.
Let's go back home.
Goodnight.
Yes.
Can you not see it
from his perspective?
He's been through
a lot. I thought
Yeah. But perhap...
Yes, I understand that rules
are important - it's just
Well
Thank you.
Fucking idiot.
She has to go back.
That would be a shame.
You've thrown away
your education.
For what?
I'm asking you a question.
What were you thinking?
Sending me to boarding school?
- Is that what this is about?
- Two months after mum died.
Sam, we spoke about
this. It was for the best.
Was it for the best to leave me
alone and go shag your new
girlfriend in England?
I have never betrayed
your mother.
If you care so much about her,
why haven't you been to see her?
Not having a father doesn't mea
you can be a shit one to me!
I thought you would be better
off without me, Sam.
I'm sorry.
They're deciding my fate.
We don't need to do any more
tests - you can tell by the lack
of urine that her
kidneys are failing.
What can we expect?
She'll start to feel more pain,
and gradually,
her lungs will fill with fluid.
Her breaths will become
longer, and...
she'll die. She should
be in the hospice.
She's staying here.
She has a nurse.
OK.
I'll leave you something
for the pain.
Thank you.
Sam, take my shoes off.
I want to feel the grass
under my feet.
Can you help me stand?
Please.
Oh, it's good.
Just let me go.
I definitely won't
be going home.
Well, England's crap anyway.
I love you, Sam.
I wish you didn't.
But it's true.
Sam.
There's one last thing
I need your help with.
Anything.
I'm doing this for you.
Through the suffering, death an
resurrection of Jesus Christ,
may almighty God free
you from all punishment.
The body of Christ.
I've still got it.
Yes. Yes, you have.
Ruth?
Is it time
for our little outing?
Yeah.
I never thanked you for
cleaning up the garden.
Well, she bribed
us with alcohol.
Oh. You know,...
she threw a knife at me once.
- Really?
- She was drunk.
Missed my head by an inch and
stuck in a knot of wood in the
door.
I was just trying to
get her attention.
- She threw a cup at me.
- And?
- And she didn't miss.
- Well, you probably knew her
better than me.
She never told me
who my father was.
I don't think she knew.
That sounds about right.
If you've got something
you wanna say to her,...
now is pretty much
your last chance.
I mean, she's not gonna
argue back now.
You're like your mother, Sam.
She was the strong one.
The kind one.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull