Oh, damn.
You'll find Captain Kraft up there.
- Thank you, soldier.
- Get down.
Shh, shh, be quiet.
Is this trench 17-A 154?
Yes.
Lieutenant Von Przygodski,
reporting for duty, sir.
Go put the soup on, Schultz.
Would you like to come down here?
Is it absolutely necessary?
The... It is custom.
Yes. Follow me, would you?
Welcome to the front, Lieutenant.
Yes, very smart, I'm sure.
New boots.
What do you expect to find here,
Lieutenant?
Fame and glory, of course.
I'm a Prussian.
Military background.
My father was a colonel.
- Heroism is my destiny.
- Is it?
Is it'? Very good.
Ugh, God, you ought to be shot, Schultz.
If you want heroism you should
try some of Schultz's soup.
Follow me.
You can almost smell the enemy's breath,
- can't you, Lieutenant?
- Yes, sir.
War is one of the most fascinating aspects
of human nature.
Did you know that?
Listen. The men, sir.
They seem to be cheering.
Enthusiasm.
It's enthusiasm for battle.
Captain Kraft!
The war is over, Captain!
Do you still want fame
and honor, Lieutenant?
Yes, sir.
But it's an Allied trick.
They'll do anything
to distract us from our cause.
The war will never be over
while we are losing.
This is a trap!
Attack! Attack! Attack!
War is over!
It's over.
He's awake!
Excuse me but where am I exactly?
I'm... I'm awfully sorry...
My regiment.
I need to rejoin my regiment.
Where?
But we found this helmet in your hands.
We thought you were one of us.
Lying to us, eating our bread,
drinking our milk!
Sleeping in our beds!
With our pillows!
Our hero.
Looking at our girls!
Excuse me.
I have a problem,
I have to get back to Berlin.
If you want to go to Berlin,
that train is the best bet.
It was not like this before.
Not here, demonstrations, surely?
Demonstration after demonstration.
All of you, stop whatever you are doing
before it's too late!
Hmm, but Berlin
will always be Berlin. No?
And we shall look the other way.
- Pretend it isn't happening.
- Yeah.
♪ It isn't wrong to be prepared
To fight a'
♪ Together to unite
If we believe a'
♪ In giving everything
Our heart and soul a'
♪ Until we reach the goal
We should achieve X
♪ It shouldn't matter
If we're brown or white a'
♪ Yellow or black as night
To anyone a'
Go away.
Don't, it's the only thing I brought back.
- God's sake!
- Come back!
Leave me alone!
Find your own pigs!
How do you expect to win a revolution
if all you're interest in is food?
Leave me alone, find your own pigs.
[{dogs bark] Relax!
Good morning!
Mufti?
Mother?
Uh... ex... excuse me?
Excuse me'?
Mufti?
- Hello?
- Sorry,
all the rooms are taken.
But I think we could find
some space for your pig.
- Aunt Hilda!
- Paul.
Paul... oh, my God.
Oh, Paul, what happened?
- Yeah...
- We thought you were dead.
No, I'm not dead.
I'm very much alive.
Yeah. But... but... but...
How long have you been alive?
Ever since I can remember.
Look, what is going on here?
Paul is back. Paul is back.
What a mess! What a mess!
Yes, it was a mess, explosions usually are.
Your mother is going to faint
if she sees you.
Where 'vs Mutti?
She can explain it better than I can!
She, um... she is at the...
at the Turkish bath.
What on earth is she doing there?
An activity she took up
at the end of the war.
It's called working.
Working?
- My mother is working?
- Yes, Mutti is working.
Paul“ -Aunt Hilda.
Aunt Hilda, I want those people
out of my room before I get back.
But... but Paul!
Bravery!
And fill it up for me, please.
Okay.
Oh, yes, he was, he was.
They wanted to award him the Iron Cross
but I told them not to bother,
to keep their medals for the war efforts.
Oh, here she goes again.
I personally prefer Paris in May.
Oh, my God!
The hallucinations are coming.
What hallucinations?
Of my poor Paul.
I often see his face
in front of me with this...
sensitive, bewildered, calm expression.
Mutti?
He always used to have...
Paul! Paul!
The War Department lied to me.
- The War Department?
- Yes, they said you were dead
and I had to believe somebody.
You've been gone
for quite some time, you know.
Well, and awful lot's happened to me,
hospitals, that kind of thing.
Oh, my God!
You've been dead
for so many months and now...
My God, you could have chosen
a better way to resurrect.
Some men have no heart, dead or alive.
- I've brought a pig home.
- A pig.
It's just a family quarrel,
it's so boring!
- Come on now, let's go.
- Oh, my boy,
if your father hears
that all you brought back
from the war is a pig,
he'll have another stroke
- of paralysis.
- Another what?
How long has he been like this?
Since the end of the war,
since the proclamation of the Republic.
The blow was too much for him.
He chose that particular chair,
he refused to let go of it
and only after we changed it
into a wheelchair,
he started to cooperate.
It's a shame he won't recognize you.
Vati!
- No, no, no, no.
- It is worth a try.
Vati! You see,
I actually think he's just pretending,
he won't admit defeat. You know.
Father, we may have been defeated
but we haven't lost the war.
Sold-out politicians
stabbed us in the back.
Attack! Attack! Attack!
Paul! Paul!
Oh! Cilly.
To what do we owe this unexpected visit
of our house-keeper socialist daughter?
Is this Paul's breakfast?
Yes, of course it is.
'
take it to him.
No, I'll take it for him.
- Cilly, please let it be...
- No, no, no, I can do it.
She didn't even say hello.
These lower classes.
The charm.
So, you're back.
After three years.
How sweet.
Why have they turned this place
into some kind of sordid guest house?
I'm very happy to see that
you're the same senseless idiot
that you were before you went to the war.
The war wasn't quite what I expected.
This is no sordid guesthouse.
This is Pension Przygodski.
Like Kempinski. "Przygodski."
You say it in the same breath.
By the way, did you know that
I'm one of the working class's
most popular artists?
Well, I know you sing in the streets.
Well, we can't all be war heroes.
You should join us, you could
play the military parts.
Oh, don't be childish, I'm an officer.
Silly me to forget.
Paul! Oh, excuse me.
Paul, please come on.
Let's try if it fits.
Times may have changed,
but appearances still count for so much.
This really isn't bad, you know.
I always thought that Uncle Heinrich
was very much taller than me.
He shrank when they made him a captain.
I think the responsibility
was too much for him.
Yes, yes I know.
I have to patch up
the bullet hole.
Shh.
- Morning.
Who is that?
We don't know,
but we think he has something
to do with tax.
How do you feel, Paul?
- Does it fit?
- Oh, it looks beautiful...
just like the old Paul I've dreamed of.
Take those down to the table.
Are you all right, my boy?
He's trying very hard, isn't he?
Yes, but I really don't think
it's the best job
for an officer.
We've got to find something better.
Paul, your mother's very worried about you.
Did she ask you to tell me that?
Oh, no.
I'm worried about you too.
I don't seem to be able to adapt
as easily as everybody else.
Let me say that you don't seem
to be settling in here
as easily as we'd hoped.
No, I don't, do I?
If it's a sacrifice
for my mother to work here
it's an impossibility for me.
All right.
Perhaps a military situation
would be more suitable.
- I have a friend who has a...
- Oh, please, Major.
You've done quite enough
for our family as it is.
I'm capable
of finding my own employment.
Number one, are you all right?
You ready, number two?
All right, hurry up!
- Oh, you are the sixth bottle?
- Yes.
Come here.
- The employment officer...
- I know who sent you,
- save your breath. Name?
- Przygodski.
Przygodski. Come on! Help him.
This is your bottle.
Keep it clean and tidy.
Bring it back on Friday.
No bottle, no wages.
Get in there.
Line up.
All bottles, line up!
- This isn't...
- Hey! Get in.
- Come on, quickly...
- Ow!
Uh. Hello? Help.
Um. I can't breathe very...
It's going-
All bottles, line up.
Hey, come on.
Stop pretending you're
champagne. Alexanderplatz.
Put them left side.
Put them right side.
Hurry up! Come on!
Hey, there, sixth bottle!
What's the problem?
Line up there.
Come on, that way.
Go on.
Morning, Paul.
Oh, good morning, Major.
How did you know it was me?
I'm a major, Lieutenant.
You didn't think I could fail
to recognize the contents
of any bottle at 50 paces, eh?
Isn't this a little undignified?
Well, certainly inconvenient.
Then I really think
you ought to consider my...
I heard there was a painter...
Good morning, Major.
I'm sure he's involved
in the black market in some way.
I heard there was a painter.
Yes, that's it.
Actually, he's involved in...
Paul, tell me, how's your new job?
It's all right.
Bit confining, I suppose.
Come. Do make yourself useful.
Here are some flowers which came for Eva.
Take them and put them in her room.
But in a vase.
Gitta, down.
Please stop it. Gitta.
What are you doing on my bed?
I can explain. My aunt...
The old lady with the curly hair.
Uh. These arrived
and she wanted me to...
These flowers.
Would you please put them over there?
Yes, of course.
I am sorry.
I am very sorry.
Is that your bottle blocking the entrance?
Yes, it's my bottle.
- Would you move it away, please?
- Yes, of course.
Uh. I am sorry.
Gitta, come on. Gitta,
Gitta, here. Gitta, come.
Come. Have some food.
♪ I wonder why you
Keep me waiting I
♪ Charmaine, my Charmaine a'
♪ I wonder
When bluebirds are mating I
♪ Will you come back again? a'
♪ I wonder
If I keep on praying I
♪ Will our dreams be the same a'
♪ I wonder
If ever you think of me too s'
♪ I am waiting
My Charmaine, for you a'
I have nice legs.
Don't you think?
- Cilly?
- In person!
Imagine you're now at the front,
blood, horror, explosion,
and a little soldier's whore
comes to warm you up.
You take her slowly
as you would sip a cup of tea.
- A cup of tea?
- Well, coffee then.
When I was a little girl
I imagined that you would come
and take me like some great crusader.
You'd ride back on a white horse,
and then you'd make love to me
on the floor... or in a boat...
or in the middle of the city
on the Victory Monument.
There was no victory.
Aren't you sentimental?
Didn't they teach you how to kill?
No, not really.
And you're behaving like an actress.
Like some sex-starved,
irresponsible, immoral slut!
Well, I certainly hope so.
But it's not getting me any place, is it?
Just imagine we're in Venice, on a gondola.
Somebody's serenading us while
we're going down the canals.
What are you looking at?
Stars.
I've forgotten
how beautiful they are in truth.
That's not the only thing you've forgotten.
Yes, the stars are twinkling in the sky.
And you, my little warrior,
are suffering from shell shock.
Well, I tried.
But just keep looking up there.
Someday you may see
another beautiful German star.
Me.
Night.
Hello again, my dear.
Are your services available this evening?
Be in your room then.
- Oh.
- Shall we say in ten minutes?
Paul, would you be so kind
and help me with these packages, please?
Sorry, hope I am
not bothering you too much.
Thank you very much.
Come on.
Gitta, come on.
Over there. Thank you.
Paul. Won't you stay
for a moment?
I'm really rather busy. Sorry.
Please.
Sit down.
Very well.
- A little tea perhaps?
- Yes.
Gitta, please. Stop.
If they're such a nuisance,
why don't you get rid of them?
Oh, no.
I couldn't possibly do that.
Gifts from old lovers must always be kept.
No matter how cumbersome.
Sometimes I think the larger the gift,
the more ineffective the lover.
What's the matter?
And why are you looking at me that way?
I saw you last night.
Picking up men.
Can I explain something?
I too had hopes, ambitions,
I thought I knew who I was...
who I'm going to be.
As you see.
- Aren't you ashamed?
- Ashamed?
I think shame belongs to another decade.
There's no such thing.
You shouldn't be ashamed
of your bottle either.
It's a wonderful hiding place
until you find yourself.
- [Flaughs]
- f laughs]
See. You can laugh.
You should do that more often.
Becomes you.
Do you think it'll ever be the same again?
No.
Come on, come on, move it.
Faster. Faster. Faster. Faster.
Excuse me? Uh. Von MUller.
Oh, I know who sent you here.
The boss is up there.
Um, excuse me'?
Major Von Mijller sent me.
Yes. Come here, would you?
Captain.
- Do I know you?
- Przygodski, sir.
{Hermanrfl F> r2.
But you were in the war, weren't you?
- Yes, sir!
- Saint Mihiel?
- You were with explosion.
Yes, that's right, sir.
- Are you still alive?
- Of course I am, sir.
And ready for duty.
Well it's very good to have you back.
Very good to be back, sir.
- We didn't lose the war, did we?
- No, sir.
We're going to win the peace, aren't we?
Sir!
- A lot of things to accomplish.
- We have, sir.
Do you realize that the future
of Germany lies in these hands?
Yes, sir.
You may have the chance
to share my balcony.
- Follow me.
- Sir.
I will show you such things, my boy,
as will change the entire
philosophy of your life.
We have the chance to realize
the dreams and ambitions
of our forefathers and to rid our society
of the garbage and grime of our times.
That war should be banished from the world.
It's not only absurd,
it involves the atrophy
of some of the finest and the essential...
essential things of mankind.
Captain Kraft, my hand.
It hurts.
Yes, but it hurts me too
when I think of our fatherland
overrun by vermin.
Quick.
Come on. Door. Door, help me.
We have a great opportunity, by the way.
We're going to set those Reds
in their place. From here.
From our underground headquarters.
It's gonna be into the trench,
over the hill, and into the battle.
Well, what do you think of it?
It's wonderful, isn't it?
Nietzsche.
Look, you see?
Goethe.
- You've read all these?
- I have no time to read.
Read? I have other
people to do that for me.
Taking notes. The books
are just there for inspiration.
Do you like music?
Listen to this. Listen.
Mm_.
- Do you recognize it'? Hm?
- Um...
It's Wagner.
Ring des Nibelungen.
I can see it now.
Masses of blond-haired, blue-eyed subjects
with our name on their lips
and our beliefs in their hearts
waiting for us...
to give them that great idea.
The idea that will transform
the human race.
- Hmm.
- What idea?
I don't know yet.
People are working on it.
But we must let nothing stand in our way.
- Especially women.
- Women?
Do you realize that a passionate woman
can destroy the greatest warrior?
Do you remember
what Josephine did to Napoleon?
- What?
- She...
What does it matter?
We're rewriting history.
From here, we shall spread the tentacles
of our organization through
every street in this city.
Through every city in this country,
and through every country in the world.
Door.
Propaganda.
You can stay here if you want.
Thank you very much.
- You swine.
- I beg your pardon?
Because of your rosy cheeks,
I know you think
you are pretty enough.
YOU!
You've ruined it. Uh.
And if you wish to address me
you'll do so correctly.
My name is Lieutenant Paul
Ambrosius von Przygodski.
Do you think you can jump into our bed,
Ambrosius? I show you! You! You!
Otto.
- I... I...
- He's broken my nose.
No. No.
Paul, would you leave us please?
Outside, if you wouldn't mind.
Who's... a naughty... boy then?
Hermann, forgive me, please.
I didn't mean to.
Hermann, please!
- No! No! No!
- Don't you know
- I can't stand violence?
- No, no, no, no.
You know I can't stand violence.
Sorry about...
Otto, his nerves are...
his nerves are shattered.
It's the pressures of terrorism, you know.
He'll be staying with us...
for a while.
Until he's himself again.
The things he said, they are...
they are foolish.
You mustn't take any notice of him.
Mustn't let anything stand
in our way, must we?
Especially trivialities.
Yes.
I hear Paul is progressing
really quite well.
It seems the young man has found
just the right niche for himself.
You kill the goose...
and I'll make the stuffing.
- No, no, no, no.
- Why?
You kill the goose
and I'll make the stuffing.
No, no, no, no, no,
you kill the goose and I...
- I want to make stuffing.
- Will make the stuffing.
Please, keep it.
Please... oh, you're hopeless.
I'll do it.
Uh.
Oh, go away, go away, away, give it.
Oh, no!
Oh, no, poor thing.
Wait, wait, wait, I'll go.
Oh, Oh.
Merry Christmas, Mutti.
Mother, this is Captain Kraft.
- Hi.
- How do you do?
- Aunt Hilda, Captain Kraft.
- Nice to meet you.
How do you do?
I'm so glad you could come,
I... I had the feeling
Paul was trying to hide you from us.
I'm so glad he feels fine
in his new position.
Paul is one in a million, aren't you?
Yes, he is.
You must excuse us, but we were
just trying to slaughter a...
Oh! No...
Perhaps I can be of some assistance.
- Can I?
- Yes! Would you please?
It will be so kind of you.
Hmm.
I... may not eat meat but I do
know something about animals.
All right. Come here.
Oh, no.
She said yes, I said no, and then I made...
Excuse me, I'd just like to say
that the colonel's contribution
to the war will not be forgotten.
- Hear, hear. Well said.
- Beautifully said, thank you.
Nor will the contribution
of the esteemed Ms. Eva.
I thought I donated to help
celebrate Paul's new life.
- Yes!
- I'll drink to that.
To Paul.
They tell me you don't eat meat?
Not a bite.
That reminds me of an old comrade of mine
from Minsk.
He had the same problem.
Do you abstain for religious reasons
or are you just a mistake by nature?
The only religious abstentions
I have are to religion.
Oh, that sounds
like a line out of Vaudeville.
You know what I gave up
for lent? Religion.
No, no, I take it back.
Lacks taste.
God died in this country, my dear.
Oh, Oh, really?
That must've been some funeral.
Cilly, please,
this is not one of your shows.
Shows? But you invited
all these clowns here tonight,
I thought this was everybody's show.
Isn't it?
Cilly. —Lt's all right, Paul.
We, who are in command,
have to suffer greater hazards
than the idle conversations of women.
Do you think you know a great
deal about women, Captain?
- Excuse me.
- Hermann...
I hope you'll excuse me.
Oh, Captain Kraft, please.
Come back sometime,
you're always welcome here.
Yes, I know where you are.
I'll see you later, Paul.
Paul, I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- Please excuse me, Mother.
Paul!
Paul.
- You cannot just...
- Please, Cilly, not now,
this is none of your concern,
this is none of your business.
Come back here.
You've been gone for months now,
at least you can tell me where you live.
No, I can't, it's military secret.
Well, what about us?
Cilly, there comes a time
in every man's life...
when he has to avoid making
the same mistakes as Napoleon.
Paul, you're slipping off
of the deep edge again.
Not at all, it's...
it's just that I'm coming very close
to my life long purpose.
What purpose?
Well, I'm not sure yet,
but people are taking notice.
I know Hermann isn't quite
as clear as he ought to be,
but at least he hasn't given up
like everybody else.
And I need something positive, Cilly.
Shell shock, it's gotta be shell shock.
Hermann?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I shouldn't... I shouldn't have
done that, I'm sorry.
Don't leave me, Paul.
It is a sad state of affairs,
- when standards drops so low.
- Yeah, you're right.
- Where are we going?
- Hmm. I know.
What is going to
become of us, I don't know.
And the young people, where are they going?
Mutti.
Mufti.
Where have you been so long?
I'm not sure.
And... how are you?
As usual.
You can't keep running, you know.
Yes.
It's just that...
something is missing.
Everything I've been told...
my background...
all of it...
it's so meaningless.
Where is Cilly?
She is working at the Lijlzower Lampe.
♪ Young ladies who plan
And scheme to get rich a'
♪ Will become horror maids
Only married to one man X
♪ Hot girls like me
Likes it better to be a'
♪ Not tied down, fancy free
My own aristocracy X
♪ I'm restless like a sailor a'
Chair. Here we go. Good.
♪ I looked another twenty I
- Concentrate. Turn.
- J' He's good enough ♪
♪ He's old enough a'
♪ To fall in love a'
- And.
- J' With me ♪
Excuse me.
Should I ask for an autograph?
Nice.
Come on, get your coat,
I've got a couple of hours
before the next show.
I'm really glad, you're here.
My monument with our pigeons.
Thanks.
- Welcome home, lieutenant.
- Don't call me that.
Why not?
I don't know, seems to be
bothering me recently.
Anyway, aren't you gonna ask me
how I've been.
I don't have to, I could just
tell by looking at you.
How have I been?
Suffering, complacent.
Like a suicidal wildebeest.
Oh, but you can be happy now,
because now you can say that
you knew me way back then.
Way back when?
Way back before I was famous.
What happened to politics?
They used to call me the child prodigy
of the revolution,
but the revolution was a little
slow in coming so, I moved on.
Yes that seems to be my problem.
You got a lot of problems.
How's your shell shock?
And now, the supreme moment of the evening.
The wicked child of present day
Germany, Cilly Taboo.
[{crowd applaud]
♪ It's after hours
The old cafe X
♪ Will close its doors
The same old way I
♪ People gone, the ashtrays full
And I'm alone ♪
♪ Why is it, it's always me
Left here by myself, you see X
♪ A little tired of waiting a'
♪ With the chairs upturned
Feeling spurned I
♪ Don't let it be too long X
♪ 'Til the man of my dreams
Comes along a'
♪ Let him be handsome
Let him be strong a'
♪ But don't let him be
Too long X
♪ My favorite gown
This new perfume a'
♪ A special dance
A haunting tune I
♪ I wait for him to find me
But there's some delay a'
♪ My hopes, my schemes
Seem only dreams I
♪ He will not come today
It seems a'
♪ But somehow I just
Cannot tear myself away X
rSolsay.“
♪ Don't let him be too late a'
♪ A man who'll appreciate X
♪ A girl with good taste
But with no time to waste I'
♪ So don't let him be too long 3
♪ Don't let it be too long X
♪ 'Til the man of my dreams
Comes along a'
♪ Let him be handsome
Let him be strong a'
♪ But don't let him be too
Don't let him be too a'
♪ Don't let him be too long a'
And more!
Bravo!
- She was great.
- I can assure you she, uh,
she's only in love with her work,
- she's hasn't seen a man...
- Glenn will take her.
What? You Will?
She'll be one of the greatest things
to hit Hollywood since, uh, Al...
- Jolson!
Taxi! Oh, my fur.
Oh, thank you.
- —Taxi! Taxi!
- Taxi!
To the Schwanenwerder.
JUST go!
Well, did you like it?
It wasn't quite what I expected.
I... I wasn't really trained
for that kind of thing.
You're so much adaptable than me.
There doesn't seem to be any measure now.
Everything's so improvised.
Day by day, moment of...
Everyone's kind of floating.
Hmm?
Soafing.
Through the sky
with the freedom of the birds
who've just learned how to use their wings.
God, you're dramatic.
Don't you feel it?
I feel useless.
There's nobody here but us.
Look! It's got everything.
It's got seventy rooms.
Dogs, cats, horses, silverware, servants.
- And a prince.
- A what?
Oh, a prince.
He comes with the house
but he won't bother us.
He told me that he'd give it
to me as soon as I was ready.
We can put the bed here.
What are you doing?
I'm taking off my clothes.
It's easier to make love that way.
Cilly, please.
I have waited for the past three years.
I don't intend to wait any longer.
Haven't you got any sense of decency?
This is somebody's home.
- Don't you love me?
- That's not the point.
I don't think we should play around
until the Kaiser returns.
You gotta be kidding.
No it's just that...
Germany today is no place
to raise a family.
Well, who's talking about a family?
I just wanna make love.
Why do you have to complicate things?
Why is it the only thing
that women think about is sex.
I mean, what happened to...
What happened to families,
and children and parents?
Oh, they died. It was in
all the papers last week,
didn't you read it?
I don't have much time.
It's a little warm in here, isn't it?
Let's go upstairs.
Good morning. Good morning.
- Slept well?
- Very.
- Water warm enough?
- Just right, yes.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you, thank you.
Are you the, um...
The prince.
- Yes.
It's a wonderful place you've got here.
Yes, we like it.
- Have you been prince for long?
- A
, my life.
- Any kings in the family?
- Five.
Oh, really?
Two of them were murdered
by their brothers.
- Any particular reason?
- Not really.
They were just found making love
to their mistresses.
Max.
Oh, Cilly. I'm sorry
to come so early.
You should be. Do you have
any idea what time it is?
Okay, come on up.
Agents have no respect
for personal relationships, God.
Cilly, aren't you going
to catch cold like that?
- What do you want, Max?
- Cilly, I have a job for you.
One that could fill
this whole house with dollars.
Does it look like it needs it?
No... but you do. I do.
There've been some Americans
at the club last night.
They did find you sensational.
They want to see you right away.
- But I mean, now!
- But I can't!
But they are thinking
of taking you to Hollywood.
Hollywood?
I think I'm clean now.
If you could pass me a towel.
I'll be on my way.
Yes, of course.
Thanks.
I've known Cilly for a very long time.
Since, uh...
But you're not anymore that...
You're gonna kill me, aren't you?
- Good evening.
- Hello.
This is the third evening
you've been in here.
She has left my dear, it's too late.
I really can't understand
why she'd leave without telling anybody.
She didn't give a shit about you.
I have the impression my dear friend.
That we've met before.
Lieutenant Von Lipzig,
the Academy. Class of '17.
- Von Lipzig?
- Mm-hmm.
I'm stationed at Eden Bar.
Baroness von Semering's regiment.
Who?
It's actually quite pleasant, you know.
The money is excellent
and the dress is more than suitable.
You look as if you're free tonight.
How perspicacious.
Yeah.
I wonder if you'd do an ex-alumni a favor.
You see my lady companion
turned up with a friend.
And I'm somewhat annoyed tonight.
I haven't got enough blood
for both of them.
Perhaps, you can join us at the Eden.
Excuse me. The Baroness
would like to see you.
If you'll excuse me.
Come in.
You dance quite well.
Champagne?
Dom Pérignon, my favorite.
Dancing, music...
champagne.
The best way to forget...
until you find something
you want to remember.
Have you got a military education?
Yes, my father was Colonel Von Przygodski.
Any other credentials?
Languages?
There's one thing I don't like...
poor fantasy in speech.
It lacks charm.
And you don't seem to lack anything.
How's your French?
Oh, I've spent a great deal of time
in one of their hospitals.
Why all the questions?
Let's call it an interview.
A recruitment if you like.
Isn't that a term the military use.
Yes, I suppose so.
I'm the head of a regiment of sorts.
The gigolos.
Yes, the lieutenant told me.
All you need is a battlefield.
Right there.
It's for you.
Frau Aeckerle will be very happy.
And surely other people will be too.
You may leave now.
Thank you.
Would you...
Would you care to dance?
Oh.
- Hello.
Frau Przygodski, how are you?
Oh, yes, you like our hats?
Frau Von Kaiserling.
I'm sorry dear friends I cannot stay.
You see I've had a slight mishap.
My husband, the general,
he died of stroke this morning.
But Helga that's terrible.
But he was so healthy.
Yes, I know and all his life
he wanted to die with a bullet.
But then we can't always have
what we want, can we?
My condolences. I propose
we have a moment of silence
to commemorate the departure of a man
who was a fine, fine soldier.
We're going to have
a moment of silence, Gustav,
for Helga's dead husband.
Oh my God. What was that?
It's my son.
He's almost a man.
Mutti, sounds awfully close,
I think...
I think you should go back.
And leave you alone? Never.
Left wing idiots.
Fighting everywhere.
They don't even respect the dead.
Move faster. Move faster.
Oh my God. Oh my God.
- Just a few more yards.
- Faster, God. Faster. Faster.
Faster. Faster.
They're shooting, they're shooting!
Oh, they're shooting.
Over here. Come on hide.
Push him out of the way. Hide.
Gentlemen, advance to the left.
- Mutti, go back, quickly.
- Only if you come with me.
Please, you come with me.
This is a military funeral and somebody
- has to look after the widow.
- Yes, I need a willing officer.
Paul, please. Paul!
- —Don't worry, Mutti.
- It's so wonderful...
- I'll take you...
- to find a...
safely to the grave.
Look out! Look out!
Just help him out.
Behind the cover. Hide.
Yes, sir, I'll do that right away, sir.
Come back, come back, please!
Come back, come back!
It is a coffin.
Come on! Just a few more yards.
Thank you, lieutenant.
I don't know what I would've
done without you.
Yes, did you see that?
Yes, he finally got his bullet.
How unfortunate that he should die
when he had someone like you.
Fatherland was his pride.
Yes.
Must've been a great honor.
Don't be afraid, I'm still here.
Bravo, Kaiserling, you are very brave...
Call me Helga, Paul.
I should be so alone.
Of course you won't.
- Will you help me, Paul?
- Of course.
Of course.
Do anything I Say?
Um. Of course.
Of course.
- Do anything I say?
- Of course.
Charge lieutenant.
Charge! Mount. Mount.
Charge lieutenant. Charge!
Mount! Attack! Attack! Attack!
Victory.
It's wonderful.
Yes.
It's absolutely wonderful.
I feel like a puppet.
Is it not enough that I'm staying with you?
Do I have to be subjected
to this embarrassment as well?
Just relax, Paul.
Try walking. Just walk.
Yes, not so stiff in the shoulders, hmm.
Just lose. Yes.
Now try a little bit a of tilt
to your head. Just a touch.
That's better. It's marvelous.
Now, try putting your hand on your stomach
as if you had a gastric ulcer,
and smile. Like this.
How do I smile
with a gastric ulcer. Look...
Do, let's stop this.
I feel uncomfortable.
Don't be ridiculous.
Now, how can I present you in public?
You have to have the right image.
You have to be elegant.
I don't want to be presented in public.
Just relax, dear.
I'll play a little music,
stay just like you are.
♪ In dreams
I kiss your hand, madame X
A tango?
I've always dreamed
of doing a tango in this house.
Just feel the music, Paul.
♪ I'm begging for your lips I'
♪ I haven't any right, madame X
♪ To do the things I do a'
♪ But when I hold you
Tight, madame a'
♪ You vanish
With the night, madame a'
♪ In dreams
I kiss your hand, madame X
♪ And pray my dreams come true a'
Oh, Paul. Dance with me.
Come dance with me, Paul.
Come share it with me.
Come, Paul.
Come here, lieutenant.
Don't you think it's a bit late
for giving orders Frau Von Kaiserling.
Could've learned together.
I don't think so.
You're making a fool of yourself.
I see.
Very well then.
Look at me when I talk to you.
Now get out, lieutenant.
Thank you.
You know what he is now?
A gigolo my dear.
My God. Imagine that.
- That is true.
- Told you...
no good would come of him.
- Yes?
- Frau Von Kaiserling?
Come in.
Thank you.
- My name is Captain Kraft.
- Please.
Um. I'm here looking
for a comrade of mine.
I understand he's being staying
with you for a while.
I'm afraid you're a bit late, captain.
- Bit late? Why? Where's he gone?
- I don't know.
Ah, Paul.
- Hermann.
- Been a long time.
We've been watching
your progress with interest.
- Haven't we, Lothar?
- Yes.
We had great ambitions for you.
Really.
We've been a bit disappointed frankly.
Seems you prefer courting elderly women
to caring about the fatherland.
You got charm.
Have good looks.
Your country needs you.
Well I see your surroundings
haven't changed.
We shall have you in the end.
I shall have you.
- Gigolos and such.
- The son, of course.
Oh, did you notice?
Gone for nothing.
As I look around me
and I see the lower races
that have swarmed into our country
over the last decade.
I ask myself, who are they?
And are they German?
'Course, they're not.
You see, in a sense,
our intent is not to unite Germany,
but to unite the German people.
The purity of our race
that was sucked from us
by the so called victors of the war.
From our lookout posts all over the city,
we can watch the degeneration
of our society.
But are we just gonna stand by and watch?
No!
"No!" No!
No! No!
Are we gonna allow our country,
our heritage, our women,
to be... to be used
as a breeding ground
for genetic mediocrity,
are we gonna allow them
to do that? No!
No! No!
"No! {Crowdl No!"
We must put a stop to it
before our own physical fitness
and our mental lucidity is jeopardized.
We will not let them get away
with it will we?
No! No! No!
And are we gonna show them
our superiority, our strength,
- and our unity?
- No!
Yes.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
- Yes!
- And what're we gonna do?
- Fight.
- Fight. Fight. Fight.
Why am I surrounded by idiots.
There's been in a lot
in the papers recently.
I think this man from Munich
is a strong influence.
- Maybe.
- Mm.
But I don't think so.
Mm. No, but listen to me.
I think there is far too much.
Propaganda.
♪ Sometimes I wonder
If hearts are broken a“
♪ By little love words
That are left unspoken I'
♪ I always tremble
When you are near me I
Oh.
♪ I'm looking for a ray of hope
To cheer me a'
♪ I hope to keep
My kisses warm a'
♪ Until we meet in shadow form I
♪ In dreams
I kiss your hand, madame... a'
Very good. You've improved.
You're a little better yourself.
I hear you're quite good
at your new occupation.
By the way, I have a new husband now.
Any general we know?
His name is Antonio Jose Felipe de Roberto.
Is his nose broken?
I beg your pardon.
Doesn't matter.
- Where did you find him?
- Argentina.
So the tango has become your lifestyle.
He is one of the richest man in the world.
He's got an awful lot of coffee in Brazil.
By the way, we've bought you off the night.
I'm booked?
Yes, room 217.
Uh, Helga...
My room.
I may be a gigolo, Frau Von Kaiserling,
but I'm not a whore.
Let's not split hairs, shall we?
After all it's not like
we haven't been bred.
Besides, there's an extra
100 dollars there for you.
And the husband?
Actually, it was his idea.
You see, he's desperately
in need of an heir.
He's obviously incapable
of providing one himself.
So I convinced him
that no substitute would be
quite so appropriate as an officer
of Prussian descent.
Thank you.
Besides, it's a good excuse
to see you again.
- A very expensive excuse.
- Of course.
But I'm paying so dance.
Thank you.
Does he have to stare like that?
One of his conditions.
I don't think so.
Paul.
♪ Just a gigolo
Everywhere I go I
♪ People know the part
I'm playing a'
♪ Selling every dance
Selling each romance I
♪ Every night
Some heart betray s'
♪ There will come a day
Youth will go away X
♪ And what will they say
About me? I
♪ When the end comes, I know X
♪ They'll say Just the gigolo I
♪ And life goes on without me a'
Good evening, Father.
What are you looking at me like that for?
You know it's easy for you to talk.
I mean you had it made.
Everything you could ever have hope for.
War, famine, pestilence.
You had it all. I mean,
it really wasn't difficult
to be somebody under those conditions.
I don't know why but people don't seem
to want that kind of thing anymore.
All they think about is forgetting.
And most of them have already forgotten
what it was they were supposed
to forget anyway.
And the only thing about the past
that they do remember is that
there was something back there
that they weren't supposed to remember.
I mean it really doesn't matter
whether they remember it or not
because they've forgotten it anyway.
You see what I mean?
Meanwhile I'm at the Eden.
I know what you're gonna say.
It's not really the sort of career
that you can walk down
the street and brag about.
Being a gigolo, I mean.
But most of the people
that I pass the street,
I mean, they don't care anyway.
They don't know the difference.
And if they did care, they'd start a war.
And I'd be back in action.
You see I have got it all sorted out.
You will be proud of me, Father.
Get out while you still have a chance.
Go somewhere, anywhere.
Marry a rich American.
You can always get a divorce.
They do that over there a lot, you know?
I'm very tired, Mother.
I'm going to bed.
- Cilly's back in Berlin.
- Why?
She's getting married to a prince.
When?
Saturday.
I see.
♪ Why you're giving me
Those jealous eyes S
♪ What you're thinking of me
Isn't true a'
♪ Stop accusing me
Of living lies 4'
♪ When I'm loyal
And faithful to you X
♪ Maybe you are merely teasing a'
♪ Acting jealous
For some reason a'
You look wonderful.
- My dear.
- Oh, hello.
- Well, lieutenant.
- Congratulations, sir.
- I'm glad you could make it.
- Thank you.
Well, well, well, I think
we're a little tired
of shaking hands, aren't we?
Why don't the pair of you enjoy yourself.
Thank you.
Oh, Grisella, my beauty...
I knew you'd come.
- Did you?
- Yeah.
Comet's like you always visit
the stars every couple of years.
I saw your film two and half times.
Let's go.
Well, if it isn't our gigolo.
What are you doing at a function like this?
Oh, we're moving up
in the world, lieutenant.
People are thinking it's about time
they got to know us.
Congratulations.
Hello, captain.
Enough pleasant young ladies
and gentlemen around here for you?
- Thank you.
- Oh, incidentally,
there's a friend of yours here from Munich.
Perhaps, you would like to see him.
This is my wedding and you're my present.
And besides now I can afford you.
- Can you?
- Yes.
I'm very expensive.
That ought to do for a couple of hours.
♪ Johnny I
♪ Reserve tonight for me a'
♪ Keep it exclusively a'
♪ For me alone a'
Otto.
I'll do my best, but we need more people.
How many men have we got
at party headquarters?
Not many. There'd be more,
if we would have been notified.
- Where are the Reds now?
- Nearing Savignyplatz.
Okay. I'm out.
Sorry.
I have to leave tomorrow morning
at 8:00 to start in a film.
And then?
Back to Hollywood.
I see.
It's not sure though.
Congratulations Cilly.
From revolutionary to princess.
I told you I was a star.
Why don't you stay with me?
Just for tonight.
- After all, it's you I married.
- I have my duties to think of.
Why don't you think about your heart?
Well, if you should comeback...
and if you should want to see me.
I'll be at the Eden.
If you find the Baroness ahead of time...
I'm sure you'll get a reservation.
Igunshoq.
The Nazi's did it.
- Is he one of ours?
- I don't know.
- He's one of ours.
- No! He is one of ours.
Save it.
Well, well, well.
It's destiny.
Well done, lieutenant.
Take him to party headquarters.
Full military honors.
We'll make him one of the party
whether he likes it or not.
That's what we need.
An elegant death.
Why to the party headquarters?
He's not one of ours.
Don't worry.
We'll make him a hero.
Oh...
My son.
But why are you dressed that way?
These things on all his clothes.
He would never have worn such colors.
Are you absolutely sure he was one of you?
One of the best.
One in a million.
Was it a bullet'?
Through the heart.
♪ Just a gigolo X
♪ Everywhere I go a“
♪ People know the part
I'm playing a'
♪ Paid for every dance
Selling each romance I
♪ Every night
with some hot dream I
♪ There will come a day a'
♪ Youth will pass away a'
♪ Then what will they say a'
♪ When the end ends, I know a'
♪ They'll say, just a gigolo a'
♪ And life goes on without me a'
♪ Just a gigolo
Everywhere I go I
♪ People know
The part I am playing a'
♪ Paid for every dance a'
♪ Selling each romance a'
♪ Every night some heart
And some dreams a'
♪ There will come a day a'
♪ Youth will pass away a'