Internet, TV, video games:
According to a
National Health Institute study
youths spend
five-and-a-half hours a day
in front of a screen:
The bombing horror goes on,
the toll approaching
a chilling 1,000 dead:
There was shoving and punching,
and what for?
To take 50 refugees:
JUST A BEGINNING
Perhaps due to
the Obama effect,
Sarkozy
is fast-tracking
the thorny issue
of diversity:
Faced with
the looming crisis,
inequality cannot
be tolerated:
As the president said,
that affects the basis
of social cohesion:
Liberty, yes,
equality, yes,
fraternity:
Question mark:
The aim is
to put some sense
into the nonsense:
Faced with this
flood of images,
I think we have to stay a bit angry,
because looking at TV,
there's good reason:
The debate on
schooling children
aged
two and three
has been
relaunched
by the Ministry
of Education:
In front of the Senate
finance committee
on July 3,
here's what Xavier Darcos said:
Is it really logical,
when we are so attentive over
the good use
of state funding,
to make people
attain a masters degree
when their job
is mainly giving kids a siesta
and changing
their nappies:
I wonder:?
WITH THE CHILDREN
OF THE JACQUES PREVERT KINDERGARTEN
HEADMIS TRESS
TEACHER
Now then, me, when I close my eyes,
there's something in my head:
I can't see anything at all:
Me:
yum, yum, yum!
I see something delicious:
What about you?
And you? And you?
What's in your head?
- I've got a brain:
- A brain: Very good:
What have you got
in your head, Inès?
A memory:
You've got a memory:
Abdheramène?
- In my head:
- Yes?
- There's papa:
- Papa's in your head:
I've got papa and mama:
Watch carefully: IsmaeI:
That's magic chalk:
It's not magic chalk:
That is an object:
What's it called? A candle, Hamet:
The candle is going to help us
try and answer the questions
we're asking ourselves this morning:
It's moving!
Are you ready?
Shall we light it?
That means we're going to try
and answer the questions:
That's it: It's starting:
- It's not a birthday:
- No, it's not a birthday candle:
It's a candle to help us think,
not a candle for a birthday:
It helps me think:
It's helping you think?
When I ask you to do some work
you need to do something
in your head:
We need to?
- Make our memory work:
Make all that work up there:
That's got a name:
We call that? You have to:?
- Think:
- To think:
We certainly need to do that;
to think:
When you think,
when you think with your head,
can anyone see you're thinking?
- Can you see it?
- No:
How do I know
what you're thinking?
You must open your mouth:
Open your mouth to do what?
To, to let it out:
To let it out:
And to let something out,
we have to:?
- To? You said it:
- To speak:
- And to eat:
- You also use the mouth to eat:
- And hands are for taking:
- You're right:
Mustn't speak with your mouth full:
There was a lot of anticipation,
even from the parents,
I can tell you:
Coming out, they all said:
"How was it? What was it about?"
Some said what they thought:
- Others can't have expected it:
- Did they say that?
I couldn't hear the kids well
because the parents chimed in with:
"Tell me all about it:"
They're curious to know
what happened, what was said:
What about you?
It was great: Jonathan said:
and I think it was the best moment,
Jonathan was making out that,
you know,
"I'm not interested:"
And then at one point I said:
Can anyone see when you think?
All together, they said no:
So I said: Then how can you show
what you're thinking about?
How can I see, Jonathan,
He said, I can't remember
exactly how:
"You have to let it out:"
Like that: "You have to let it out:"
That was great,
because he'd said something earlier
as if he'd really worked out the path
that goes down as far as the mouth:
Then Yanis said:
"You have to speak:
"Letting it out is words:
You have to speak:"
Did she bring coffee?
Coffee? There isn't any coffee?
There's none left:
There was just a drop:
I want some coffee:
Never mind:
- What time is it?
- I think it's time to go in:
Let's go, back inside!
This morning
we're going to do philosophy:
What does that mean,
doing philosophy
with you? What does it mean?
- Talking:
- We're going to talk, good:
What else? Yanis?
- Use our brains:
- Use our brains: What else?
- Thinking:
So,
I now declare
the philosophy
session
open:
So tell me,
are you adults or are you children?
- Children!
- Why do you say that?
Because I'm little:
My parents are big:
Little ones do work, grown-ups too:
Little ones do work
and grown-ups too:
I can do some things:
- What things?
- I can do my posters:
Can papa or mama,
or the teacher do things
that you can't manage to do?
He can do photos:
Who can do photos?
- Papa and mama:
- And you can't do photos?
Why not?
Because I'm not big enough:
Because what?
- Cos they're big:
- Because they are big:
Listen carefully, GabrieI, listen:
Is there anything
that you cannot do now
but you'll be allowed to do later?
- Yes:
- Everything:
Are there things,
Abderahmène, Matthis,
that you can't do now,
but that you'll be allowed
to do later? Anissa?
Rosemay, what d'you think?
Is there anything you can't do
that you'll be able to do later?
William, anything to say?
Naomy?
Well there, nothing!
And when I say nothing:
It was very unsettling
because it was dragging,
because I was getting nothing:
At all:
I was waiting, thinking;
"something has to emerge":
But it was just blanks,
nothing at all:
Because they didn't have
anything to say:
I've got tiny little feet:
It doesn't matter:
You can do it: Come on!
I'm the princess!
Come on!
Hurry up:
We've got tiny little feet:
Kyria, can you lend me the shoes?
I'm barefoot, because on the carpet,
we go barefoot:
I'm the most beautifuI:
We are beautifuI princesses:
Oh yes, I'd love to have a prince:
Don't write;
draw what you're thinking
in your head:
I think I want to marry my love,
I want to marry even though
I'm little, that it?
Good: Want to say anything else?
Go on, I'm listening:
Because I,
because my papa and mama,
they're not married,
I want to get married for them:
Can I say her name?
- Yes:
- She's called Laura:
Thank you, Yanis:
What did you think about, Shana?
- Little princesses:
- Why's that?
Because I like little princesses
who are kind:
And that's Azouaou:
Why did you think
of drawing Azouaou?
I don't know:
I don't need any help, it's fine:
She thought of you:
She was thinking of you
and so she drew you:
I'd like to know why
she thought of you:
Because I'm not her sweetheart
anymore:
And yet she draws me:
He was your sweetheart?
And you don't want that?
I'm not your sweetheart anymore!
Stop it, Azouaou!
Why were you thinking of Azouaou?
Was it for all those reasons?
Was it because you like him?
That it?
You're allowed to:
You're allowed to like him:
No matter if he doesn't think
the same as you:
You're allowed
to think differently:
When we see the drawings,
we'll see if we all think the same:
But you drew very well what
you were thinking:
- There's a lion:
- A lion? Oh, yes:
Yesterday, I was watching
Nicolas Sarkozy at home,
and my mama said to my papa
that he was in prison:
Sarkozy in prison?
That's news to me:
I want to say something:
What did he do then, this man?
- Yes, Anissa:
- I saw Sarkozy at my place too:
- He came to your house?
- Er:yes:
Nicolas Sarkozy came to your house?
- Yes:
- Really?
- I want to speak:
- Naomy?
He's our colleague,
of papa, of mama, of my brother:
He's a colleague
of papa and mama?
Yes, of ours:
WHAT IS A LEADER?
He's on the news, Sarkozy:
Yesterday he watched my papa,
and after, after,
and after on the balcony at home,
I watched, a big limousine:
He had a big limousine?
And what does he do, this man?
For the money:
- For the money?
- Yes:
Take it easy, get in line:
I'm going to ask you a question:
What is a leader?
A leader?
At schooI, are there any leaders?
- No:
Leader, that goes like that:
- Where do they do that?
- In the green thing:
What's the green thing?
- It's the soldiers:
So then, are soldiers leaders?
Soldiers are not leaders:
Would anyone here
like to be a leader?
- Yes:
- You'd like to be leaders?
- Who wants to be a leader?
- Me!
When I'm big, after I want to marry,
I want to put on my suit myself,
I want to buy a Twingo with myself,
after, after:
In my Twingo:
That's all very interesting:
In my Twingo,
I'm going to take Matthis for a ride:
You're going to take Matthis?
Will you be a leader
when you're big?
No, I'll have a leader, a leader:
You'll be a leader? Why?
Because she says like that,
my mama:
Does anyone want to be
the President of the Republic?
GabrieI?
Go on, GabrieI:
- Don't know what to do:
- You don't know how?
Kyria, would you like to?
What should we do?
The same thing? So then, here we go:
They know why they're doing it,
what's expected,
but they maybe don't know how:
- To express it:
- To explain it:
Whereas kids
who haven't done much philosophy,
when you ask them
they've maybe got more:
When I somersault it hurts my butt:
We don't do somersaults in the yard,
we do them on gym mats:
So they're more neutraI,
so they're forced to really think:
While these ones
are already thinking about things,
why ask the question? You see?
- Maybe that's it:
- Yes, that's it:
Yes, Florian:
He doesn't want to lend them:
Let him play with it a bit:
From the start, when you said
they're doing philosophy:
What use is it?
For thinking:
But I wanted us to go further:
- "A" first:
- The "A" first:
Good, nice and pointy, great:
- After?
- The "B":
There, you've drawn a verticaI line:
Good:
Good, keep going, the:
- Very good:
Good: Not bad at all:
"A, B, D", after it's the:
- No, no: Look:
"E":
- Good: After, what letter is it?
- The "H":
"H", very good:
After, what letter is that?
- Like Naomy:
- Yes, like Naomy:
You're right:
- Which one like Naomy?
- "N":
- It's the:?
- The?
- "N":
"N", good! I didn't hear you:
Good: And now I can read it:
ABDERAHMENE:
D'you see what you've done?
Are you pleased?
Do you recognise your name?
Great: Put your things away:
I don't see any danger,
we can carry on:
Let's hide in a corner,
I saw something move
It's no time for playing around:
Let's go closer:
WHAT IS A FRIEND?
Azouaou and Theo are friends:
How did you tell
that they were friends?
Cos sometimes they hold hands:
And then I hold hands
with someone else:
And do you have friends?
Who are your friends?
My friends are: IsmaeI, Kyria,
GabrieI, Azouaou and Naomy:
I like Kyria:
Do we like friends
the same as sweethearts?
- No!
- Yes!
I can't hear a thing:
Friends, you play
with them,
and sweethearts kiss each other:
On the mouth: Then get married:
They get married?
Do you kiss your friends?
Yes, on the cheek,
you can kiss them:
Yanis, he said on the cheek:
- And sweethearts not the cheek?
- On the mouth:
What do you think?
- Miss:
- Myron?
I want to give mama a big kiss:
- Are you her sweetheart?
- Yes:
- Really? She doesn't have another?
- No:
Can Myron
be his mama's sweetheart?
Kyria said I'm her sweetheart:
Can a mama be a friend, a mama?
- No:
- Why not?
Mama kisses me on the mouth:
- So are you her sweetheart?
- Course not:
She's already got one; papa:
Can friends get cross
with each other?
I agree:
No, he doesn't agree:
Can friends get cross
with each other?
Can they argue?
- Yes:
- Yes or no?
- Yes!
- Wait, let Abderahmène explain:
You know, last time with William,
I had an argument with him:
- You stayed cross with him?
- No:
- I want to say something:
- Yes, Yanis:
Well, my papa, well,
he no longer speaks to
a friend of his:
Can you stay cross long
with a friend?
My papa, he, he speaks to him,
he speaks to him now:
My papa has a friend,
he's called Kadour:
And why is he papa's friend?
Because yesterday,
the police caught him:
What did Kadour do?
Because: he didn't have
a driving license:
So? Since they were friends,
what happened?
Did anything happen?
He went to Algeria alone:
He didn't have a ticket:
What did papa and Kadour do?
Papa has a license
because he's nice:
He still speaks to him:
He still goes to his house:
Can brothers and sisters be friends?
Can you be friends
with your siblings?
Rosemay, what do you think?
Are you friends
with your sister Manon?
Is she your friend, Manon?
Why not?
Let's play fighting:
I'm not playing:
Sherazade, is Halima your friend?
I'll tell you a secret:
Leave Yanis alone:
Halima, is Sherazade your friend?
Is she your friend or your sister?
She's my sister:
Is she your friend too? Why not?
What did you say?
Yanis listen,
she says she's her sister,
she says she's not her friend: Why?
Have you only got boys for friends?
There's no room:
Can girls be friends?
Abderahmène is a bit squashed in:
Yes or no?
Do you know?
I'm going to get cross:
Hello, mama?:
It's me, I'm at schooI:
We're playing:
See you later, mama, bye-bye:
I'd like to see mama, for reaI:
I'm not kidding:
Yanis, off you go, mama's here:
Jonathan:
Bye-bye:
Inès; since I don't see you often,
I forget:
Inès, off you go:
Bye-bye: Anissa:
We coloured-in a fir tree,
and the older ones,
they coloured a Father Christmas:
Is that all you did in a day?
NO BATHING, WALKING
OR SKATING ON THE ICE
How come you can see
my hand on the screen?
Because there's the light:
- Because what, Naomy?
- Because the light:
What about it, the light?
- Well, your hand:
- What about my hand?
Look what happens
if Théo stands up:
What happens?
- We see his head:
- Why is that?
Is that it?
Will it light? Yes:
Being intelligent,
what does that mean?
Mama is intelligent:
Why is mama intelligent?
Because she never puts the Nutella
in the fridge:
in the fridge?
- Intelligent means:
- Yanis?
Sit round properly please:
It's better to draw
than play video games,
otherwise you're stupid:
Is it true, when you play
video games you're stupid?
- Do you think:
- You learn nothing:
Also Hélène,
she doesn't stop playing the star:
The star?
Why are you talking about that,
given today's question?
Because she thinks she's beautifuI
with her pink coat:
What's that to do with intelligence?
Well, Madonna sings well:
My brother said to me:
When you act the star
you're not intelligent:
When you act the star,
well you act the bighead:
You might think you're a star,
but no one cares
when you take yourself for a star:
Because sometimes I've seen in:
where they sing, and it was a girI,
and she got undressed
and you saw her all naked:
Is that intelligent or not?
Why not?
Are adults more intelligent
than kids?
No, because they say:
"You know nothing,
you know nothing:"
We know some things:
Are adults smarter than kids or not?
- My papa is less intelligent:
- Why d'you say that?
Because he didn't know
that Nutella doesn't go
in the fridge,
it goes in the cupboard:
He puts the Nutella in the fridge
so he's not smart?
- It melts:
- It gets cold:
What could he do now
to become intelligent?
I know what he could do
to be intelligent:
We just have to ask someone
to find a solution for the Nutella:
- Does anyone have a solution?
- Me:
- Kyria, you have one?
- In the kitchen cupboard:
Kyria has found a solution:
Do we stop thinking
when the candle goes out?
No, we think about other things:
WHAT IS FEAR?
Why are those characters not afraid?
Cos they're superheroes:
Nightmares can be a little bit
too scary, but not dreams:
Do you remember this?
- It's a question mark:
- A question mark:
Does he think or reflect, Santa?
Myron, when we think about a thing,
can we have it right away?
Théo,
can we stop thinking?
Yes:
We stop?
Does that ever happen?
- Do we learn by thinking?
- Yes:
You agree?
We learn about God when we think:
Do you like thinking or not,
Abderahmène?
When I used to do philosophy,
I always used to ask myself why
we lit the candle in the afternoon:
It's a good question:
Let's begin, the candle is lit:
To have a sweetheart,
you have to flirt:
I don't like schooI:
Boys and girls are the same,
because:
They're the same because:
They want to make love:
They want to make love? Meaning?
You're asking
more and more questions,
and you need to think even deeper:
We should just do the class
and we'll see if we're able to think:
What is death?
There are countries that are dead:
What are you talking about?
It's cos of the newspaper:
The paper always talks about death:
Why do they always talk about it?
They say things that are not good:
On TV,
when the news: we see fires:
The TV, the TV is hot:
Why do you say that?
Because when I see,
when I touch the TV,
it's already hot:
There was the news,
there was a car,
it went where there was a train,
there was the bus,
and after it made an accident:
There's someone
who killed something
in the residence just next door:
What did he kill? Myron!
Where there's the nursery schooI:
Who killed what?
There was a guy with a pistoI,
and do you know what he did?
He fired:
Really? Then what happened?
Then they started a fire,
the firefighters came
and the police too,
and the hospitaI:
I'm not very happy when people die:
Why are you not happy?
Because I don't want
my mama to be dead:
I don't want my granddad to be dead,
or my other granddad to be dead,
and not my grandma to be dead,
or my other grandma to be dead
and I don't want my cousin
to be dead
and my other cousin:
Why don't you want that?
You've got it all:
Because I don't want to be alone,
because then I'll get lost:
We were talking about
the man who died:
- What can you tell us?
- He was little before,
then he grew, he was four years old:
Then he was big, he was like that:
10 years old?
Then he was
very, very, very old,
and then he died:
Gently, gently:
Just like the big boys, my God:
Come on, come and see, Abde:
Bring the bike, we're off:
Stop cycling, we're going home:
They say they don't have any choice,
but to hear their story,
we had to film with hidden cameras:
The supermarket trash cans
have just been put out
and 5 people
are already upon them:
Their kids get food from the trash:
What's written?
"A":
There's "A", there's "B",
there's "D" and there's "E",
there's "R",
there's "A", there's "H",
there's "M", there's "E",
there's "N" and there's "E":
ABDERAHMENE:
To go up into junior class,
to go into junior:
No: Passing into junior class:
Come in, hello:
Take a seat, let's begin:
Come along, sit closer,
let's make a little room:
Come here, my love, closer:
Hello, thank you:
I'm losing my notes:
First off, thank you for coming
this morning:
It's a pleasure working
with your kids:
At the start, it's a lot of effort
for the teacher:
Then the more we move forward,
the more the sessions
are driven by the kids,
and now I take much more
of a back seat,
listening to what they have to say:
The program won't be stopping,
I'm pleased to say
it's being renewed next year:
That's where
I'd really like to thank you,
because without your kids,
there would be no program:
It's through the children
that the philosophy program
can grow:
And it wouldn't happen
without the families either,
since we ask you
put a huge amount of faith in us,
and a huge amount
of faith in your kids' words,
because they say many things
you can't controI:
Thank you very much:
I'm quite moved:
We thank you too,
because without this,
we couldn't have continued at home:
There were some very important,
interesting themes,
notably death, which we didn't
quite know how to broach,
and bringing that home,
talking about it with the kids,
that helped us as parents
to discuss it with them:
It was a good follow-up
from schooI to home:
So, thank you:
"France is changing,
now when there is a strike,
no one notices: "
The words of N: Sarkozy today
at his party conference:
A circuit of more than 5 miles,
180 guys on bikes,
and thousands of spectators
on the way:
It's one of the biggest
sporting events,
the Tour de France:
The first stage started out
from Brest a half-hour ago:
The riders are on the road,
and the vacationers too:
Traffic authorities are bracing
for a very busy day:
"Do You Love Me Or Not?"
Do you know why
we're here again today?
We're going to do philosophy:
What does that mean,
doing philosophy, Inès?
We're thinking about things:
- Thinking:
- We're going to think:
- Listening:
- We'II listen:
- Asking ourselves questions:
- What do we ask about?
About love:
Today it's love,
but it's not always love:
Well?
- Sometimes we change topic:
- Sometimes we change:
We think, we ask questions
on the world around us,
in which we live:
So, today's question:
- Here it is:
- It's love:
What is love?
Love means that
the papas, after,
are in love with the mamas:
Love,
well,
it's something
that is good, but
people who are in love, well:
Inès, she says love
is something good;
do you agree with that?
- What d'you think?
- It's good:
So Shana, why's it good?
Because there are people
who are married
and afterwards they're happy:
It's not good to get married:
Why's that, can you tell us?
Because, you don't have
to get married always:
- Why shouldn't you marry?
- Yes!
- No!
Stop talking: I'm speaking:
Go on, explain:
You shouldn't always
get married because
you should do it once,
and after, when you're not married
all the time,
you get married again:
The papa and the mama,
if they're married,
they'll fight with each other
to get the baby:
Then they'll fight,
and then the mama
will get angry and she'll say:
"Well then, I've changed my mind,
I'm moving out
and we're getting a divorce:"
You can't love
for a lifetime because
if they fight over the baby,
then they'll get divorced,
and it's the other one
who'll take the baby
and he'll chose another sweetheart:
A girI can be in love
and a boy is not in love:
Yes, that can be:
It's the girls that is in love
with another girI:
Are you nuts?
Why do you say that, Abderahmène?
Do you mean that girls are in love?
- Is that possible or not?
- Not possible:
It's not because if you're in love
with a girI, you can't marry:
You have to be in love
with a boy that you love:
You want him to be handsome,
but if he isn't you don't love him:
You have to fall in love with a boy:
You see?
It's the code:
Wait, wait, wait; what did you say?
- It's the code:
- What is this code?
Like the highway code:
Like the highway code?
So it's the code of what?
It's the code of love:
It's the code of love?
Can anyone tell me
what this code of love is?
Kyria?
I'm not in love with Abigaëlle,
I like Abigaëlle:
You're not in love with Abigaëlle,
but you like her:
Abigaëlle is a little girI, right?
She's using words
that are a little bit different:
She doesn't love Abigaëlle,
but she still likes her:
Explain us that:
Explain that to us:
Because a girI
can't be in love with another girI:
In what way do you like Abigaëlle?
- Have you got a sweetheart?
- Yes:
- Who's that?
- Yanis:
You don't like Abigaëlle
the same as Yanis?
Inside you,
how does it feeI liking Yanis?
She likes Yanis, that's all:
- Yanis likes me too:
- He likes you too:
It's him who gives me
the most kisses:
Oh, kisses again!
We haven't talked about that:
- She annoys me:
- Why does that annoy you?
Because:
She always looks at me:
- She comes next to me all the time:
- And that's all?
How do you show
when you're in love?
You do little tummy tickles:
- You turn red:
- Why do you go red?
Because you've got a heart
in the tummy:
Because we've got a heart
in our tummy:
Some old people don't love anymore:
A grandma and a grandpa:
Go on, my dear:
:They love each other,
and sometimes they don't:
Can grandpas and grandmas love?
- Can they be in love?
- No:
No?
Why not?
Because grandpas
and grandmas are old:
That means
they're still in love, Azouaou:
In Algeria,
I've got my grandma and grandpa:
I've been to see them often
with my papa and mama,
with my four-wheeI-drive:
Are grandpa and grandma
still in love?
No:
Because my grandpa and grandma
don't want to be in love:
I say that's not true:
I'm telling you it is:
If Azouaou says that's how it is,
then it's true:
Wait, wait!
Wait, hold on a minute:
I'm older than Shana
and I'm older than you:
Shana!
He's telling you that Azouaou's
grandma and grandpa are in Algeria:
So what?
So, you listen:
It's none of your business:
Listen to Azouaou:
Wait, wait:
- He went to see her:
- In the bled:
What's that, the blade?
The BLED:
The bled, sorry: What's that?
- The bled is Algeria:
- It's Algeria?
I agree with Shana,
but I don't agree with Azouaou,
because those two have to agree
since they're sweethearts:
They should say sorry for love:
They don't want to forgive:
If they don't say sorry, then,
they're not sweethearts:
but if they say sorry, they are:
If we don't say sorry,
we're not in love:
And we look for someone else:
Inès said
that if we forgive each other,
we can still love:
Do you think that's true?
Yes or no?
- Do you agree or not? What:
- I agree:
But since Shana
doesn't want to forgive me,
I'll shout at her in the yard:
Azouaou can give
a bouquet of flowers to Shana:
What are you on about, Kyria?
You're talking rubbish!
Shana? Are you going to forgive him?
Last time you told me:
"Will you still be my sweetheart?"
And now what do you say?
What? Little apple?
- I didn't do anything!
- Yes you did!
I didn't do anything!
- Yes!
- No!
I've got a good idea
for us to forgive:
I've got an idea:
Find a flower and give it to me:
No, he doesn't need to:
They're filming you:
He breathed in
and got it all up his nose:
How d'you make bubbles?
- With the straw:
- Yes, but how?
- He blows:
- Oh, he blows:
- Where does he blow?
- Like that:
He blows:
We've got objects
that float and sink,
we're going to see
why they float and sink:
There we saw just a stapler
and a little boat:
We're going to have
to look outdoors,
and amongst the objects
in schooI and in the home:
We have to find those that float,
and those that sink,
and find out why:
I LOVE YOU JOCELYNE
You know Abderahmène?
Well he said
there's no such thing
as girls who kiss girls:
Then I said: I like Abigaëlle,
but I'm not in love with her:
That's right, she's your friend:
She's your paI, but not your love:
Then Pascaline said:
"Who's your sweetheart?"
And everyone said: "Yanis!"
Do you love mama and papa
more than Yanis?
What?
Do you love us more than Yanis
or him more than us?
I love you more:
Is that so? Why's that?
Because you're nice:
And Yanis isn't nice?
Yes, he's a little bit nice:
He's very nice but before he hit me:
Really?
Yes:
That's not very nice:
Can a sweetheart hit his friend?
No:
My name is Alice
I've got my head in the clouds
A rabbit with a watch
Birds that speak and weep
I'm Alice in Wonderland
Alice, I'm afraid in my sleep
In nature or the sky:
It's true that Aimé Césaire is dead:
Aimé Césaire?
- Do you know him?
- She said Aimé Césaire:
Do you know who he is?
Césaire?
- He died in Martinique:
- Tell us who he was:
Mama told me:
Mama talked to you about him?
Aimé Césaire
who died in Martinique:
Because I saw the picture
when he was dead:
Death means,
for example, when there is a fish
and a boy sees the fish that is dead
he says to a papa:
"Papa,
"Leave it, it's sleeping:"
"No, Gaston, it's dead:"
Death, we're:
we're not allowed
to get ourselves killed:
If someone attacks us, we're dead
forever and the other one
goes to prison:
Someone who's dead
is someone
who doesn't breathe anymore,
who doesn't move anymore:
Their eyes are closed:
Even deceased people are dead:
Deceased and dead,
is it the same thing?
- Not the same:
- Deceased:
- No:
Deceased:
What does that mean, being deceased?
Who wants to explain?
N'Dickou, what does it mean?
Someone who's deceased,
he's dead in a coffin:
Is it the same thing or not,
deceased and dead?
Is being dead and deceased the same?
It's not the same, it's just that
when you're deceased,
you're in a coffin,
but when you're dead,
you're not in a coffin:
It's the same:
Yes, it's the same:
What about a coffin,
what's that for?
You don't go in the grave,
first they put the person
in the coffin, and then
they put the coffin in the grave:
If someone is dead
you can still give gifts:
Gifts on the grave:
Well, that's different:
I don't agree with Shana because
when you put gifts on a grave, well,
you're dead forever,
you're dead under the ground,
forever:
Gifts to put on graves,
what are they for?
- Nothing:
- For praying:
Praying, tell us what you mean:
Shana, you must learn to listen too:
It's not for anything:
It's nothing, it's just decoration:
You have to decorate with flowers:
What are the flowers for?
Sometimes they take necklaces
and bracelets to pray:
To pray: What's that, then?
Praying is for speaking to God,
and so God,
he raises up people
who we want to be still on earth:
You mean he brings them
back on earth?
On earth, she said:
When we die, we're buried,
and after we go to
the paradise of our God:
When you die it means
it's for a long time
and then you go to heaven:
Because in heaven
there's the Virgin Mary:
- Who's that?
- Yes, she's flying:
- She's a goddess:
In heaven there's the Virgin Mary
and Father Christmas:
And then you are an angeI:
Our souI goes to God, not our skin:
It's our souI:
What's that, our souI?
It's an invisible thing that's blue:
- It's invisible?
- And it comes out of our tummy:
I'll ask you a question,
listen carefully:
When you learn that someone's dead,
how do you feeI
in your body
and in your head?
When someone dies, it's maybe
someone's grandpa, mother,
or their father:
We're sad because it's our mother
or our father:
And then, next,
it hurts us in our own hearts:
- What if your mama died?
- I'd kill myself:
D'you agree with him?
He says that if his mama died,
he'd kill himself:
What do you think of that?
Hold on, he'll explain:
I'd like to see
what it's like to be dead,
the problem is you can't get up:
Then, his papa will be alone:
He'll stay
with the 2 little sisters:
But he'll think of you,
he'll miss you:
I don't agree with Yanis,
if his mama kills herself,
and he kills himself,
we won't be able
to learn anything more
with the passing of life:
You won't be able
to learn more about passing life:
But I see with my eyes:
- But if you're dead:
- My souI goes to heaven:
If you're dead you see nothing:
Yes I will, but my souI will go
with God and I'll see like God:
No, you won't:
Cos your eyes will be closed:
You can die with your eyes open:
Yes, but you still can't see:
I don't agree with Yanis:
If his mama died
and he was going to kill himself too,
afterwards he'd be dead forever:
I'd rather his mama died
and that he stayed with his father:
He'd stay with his father,
you hear that?
That way his mama's in his heart
and he can always
think of his mother:
That's it, they're capable
of staying with the topic,
bouncing it around
even with the other kids' comments,
reacting,
knowing if they agree or not,
and building an argument,
so some kids can do it:
There's lots going on
with the parents,
kids are saying to me:
"I talked about that
with mama in the car,"
"I talked about:"
So I think the parents understand
they're also involved here
and it's important:
It'll also help them to answer
questions they are asked at home:
I think some parents
prepare for it long in advance:
You can see it
in the more considered views:
- I said it's just the teachers:
- OK, just teachers:
But when teachers scold their kids
at home, cos teachers are mamas,
does it mean they don't love them?
I don't want to be filmed dying:
What d'you do? Can't remember?
- What?
- I said we talked about love:
I'm just asking: I'd like to know
why you got told off:
Whose it not going well with?
Teachers? Supervisors? Parents?
When grandpas scold you,
do they love you?
Aunts and uncles?
Doesn't Aunty love you?
No, I didn't say
my aunts and uncles,
Just the teachers:
You didn't answer me:
Teachers don't have to love the kids:
When you're told off,
they don't love you?
Next year, what are you going to do
if you're told off?
Next year's one is strict:
- I'll put up with it:
- You'll put up?
Unless they beat me:
What d'you want to do
in philosophy next week?
What topic? What do you
want to talk about?
What topic would you like?
What use are mamas and papas?
They only seem to watch TV:
What use are you, then?
- That's it, what use are kids?
- Me, playing or drawing:
No, but for me:
What use are you to me?
- I can't hear:
- For playing Lego Batman:
I'm there so you can play:
But what use are you? Nothing:
Wipe your mouth:
- What use are you?
- What use is having kids?
They don't make you happy:
Don't make you happy? Why?
Cos you're always telling us off:
The next train for Melun
is currently at Cesson station:
It will pull into platform 1 B:
Departure scheduled for 11:09:
Thank you for your attention:
Difference means that
sometimes it's old people:
It's handicapped people,
things that are different,
animals are not like us too:
For example, elephants;
they've got four feet:
And humans have got:
They've got 2 feet:
They've got 4 feet,
their legs, they've two of them,
and the front ones, they're hands:
- I don't agree with Yanis:
- Why not?
I think Yanis is talking nonsense cos
he thinks he's seen some films:
It's not about films,
we're trying to see if animals
are people like us:
We're the same, except different,
because they've got
blood like us, but
we're the same as them
except they're not the same:
It's both:
Animals are more hairy
than parents:
More hairy than parents:
Sometimes, the difference is also:
- No, it's:
- Shut up!
Go on:
The difference is women and boys:
Sometimes boys
have got long hair, sometimes boys:
There are boys with long hair
like girls:
For example, Florent,
but it doesn't mean
that he's a girI
because he's got hair:
It's because it grew
and he couldn't cut it:
And we know he's a boy?
- His voice:
- The voice is also a bit different?
When my mama
gets angry with my papa,
she shouts, but:
but in fact,
she hasn't got a soft voice:
Are men and women
the same or not?
Not the same:
Because women have babies:
Boys don't:
My mother and my father
are almost the same
but not a lot:
My father is brown,
my mother is brown:
Are they different or the same?
They're the same:
Can you name anything
that is different?
Go on, give an example:
What is being different?
My sister, she's white,
and my mother,
she's black:
Sometimes,
we're not the same colour because
if there's someone who's white,
the babies will be white:
My mama and me,
we're the same colour
because we look similar
and we're the same difference:
It's the same difference,
the same colour? Explain that:
Are you different or the same?
- Everything's the same:
- Everything's the same?
OK:
In my family, there are just
three of us who are black,
but there's one who's mixed race:
That term there,
mixed race; what does that mean?
It's black mixed with white
and it makes coffee:
My sister is not the same as me
because I'm a bit mixed race,
and she's a lot more
mixed race than me,
because I'm the same as my father:
I don't like being black,
I like to be white:
Why's that?
Wait, wait:
She has to tell us why:
Then you can speak:
Because I don't like black:
Why is that?
Because:
Do you have a reason?
Do you have an explanation?
No? Yanis?
I'd like to be white and not black:
Why would you like to be white?
Stop it, Shana:
Because white people, well,
they're nicer:
Do you agree with Yanis?
- So, explain it to me:
- Yes or no?
It's that I didn't
really understand:
I love my brother the way he is,
even my mama and my papa,
and my dog:
Black people are stronger
than whites:
Because IsmaëI,
he's a class below
he's stronger than Sébastien and me:
Théo says IsmaëI is black,
so he's stronger:
Do you think it's because:
Sébastien is little:
:his skin is another colour
that he is stronger than him?
Because Sébastien is that big,
he's big like us:
Maybe he's ill,
that's why he's small:
You think it's an illness?
- No, he was born that way:
- If you're little, you're ill?
- If you're little, you're different?
- Yes:
Different from the big ones:
My father, you can see
that he's handicapped:
Your papa? There are handicaps
that can be seen?
Are there things he can do
the same as you?
- Yes:
- Like what, for example?
He can:
He can open the:
He can't walk like me but
he can move like me:
He can talk like me,
and he can also
read me stories when I:
You said he can't walk,
then you say he can walk
like you:
- That's not what I said:
- Say it again:
I said he can't walk like me,
but he can do things like me:
He moves like you:
He moves like me, she said:
Yes, but he can't move his legs
like you:
That's enough!
He can read like me:
Go on, Louise, go on:
He loves me the same as I love him:
He loves me the way I am:
I love him the way he is:
Discover Jolina Ballerina:
Ready, liftl
Your new dance partner:
One, two, three, arabesque,
and splitsl
Learn dance steps
with this book and CD:
Jolina Ballerina,
become a real ballerinal
I'd like to know something:
What did the poor to do to be poor?
Good question:
People who are poor,
they live outside,
they don't have a home:
It means you've nothing,
just bread and water:
You've only got?
- Water:
- Only water?
- You sleep at the station:
- I know about the poor,
I know a poor person and
he eats leftovers from the trash:
Poor people,
they're outside in the storm,
and the storm is scary:
- It's good to be rich:
- Why's it good?
You can buy everything:
What can you buy?
Food, a car, a motorbike:
and a tent:
Are you rich or poor?
I'm poor:
Well?
- I'm poor:
- You are poor?
Does being rich just mean
having lots of money?
- Yes:
- How else can you be rich?
With your friends,
because if I was rich,
it wouldn't mean anything to me:
When I'm with my friends,
I feeI good:
Bums,
they've got friends,
but they don't have
anything to eat:
Listen:
But they, the bums ask,
they're invisible
and they ask for food:
No, bums aren't invisible:
Because if we don't
give them anything
they'll die,
and if we bring them something,
if we bring them
a little something, then:
That's why they're mean
with people at times,
because they're our friends
and we give them nothing,
so they're mean:
When we give them something,
they're not mean:
Give a coin to the poor,
you go to heaven,
when you're really kind to people:
Because the last time I gave to:
I said to my aunt:
"Look, a poor man:"
She said: "Shall we buy him
a sandwich?" and I said yes:
Then we bought one
and gave it to him:
We don't have to give:
You give money to people,
they'll just buy stuff:
You're mean:
No, they should buy
their own stuff:
You're nasty:
That means you're nasty:
Yes, you're nasty to others:
Can we help them?
They can buy stuff themselves:
In Melun,
I saw a woman asking for money,
she had nothing in her pot:
She had nothing at all:
We were at the station,
where the trains are,
we were going down the steps
and we saw a lady:
She was praying because she wanted
some money, then she said:
"Can you give me some money,
"Can you give me some money:"
My mother and father
didn't even give any money,
and I said to mama: "But mama,
"papa, why don't you
give that lady any money?
"She's poor:"
They gave nothing and said:
"We don't care: We have
to go now or we'll be late:"
Well done!
No, I'm just kidding:
If I hadn't any money
and was poor,
after I couldn't buy
myself anything:
Can you imagine
being in that lady's place?
We'll stop there today:
We can carry on thinking,
but it's very hot,
I think you all might drop off:
- I'm sweating:
- OK, let's go:
- I'm so hot:
- It's very, very hot:
Yanis, Louise and Eastland,
I'm sorry but that's unacceptable:
Come, I want to talk to you:
Leave me alone, Théo:
Will hitting her
solve your problem with Louise?
Yes or no?
- I don't know:
- You don't know:
Are there other ways
to solve a problem
other than hitting children?
Are there other solutions?
Look at me:
What do you think?
You're a big boy now:
So:
Is hitting her the way
to solve things?
Yes or no, can you tell me?
What could you do to sort it out?
- I don't know:
- Well, think:
I don't know:
Apart from hitting, what can you do?
- Nothing:
- What are we learning?
What are we doing here together?
You often don't agree,
you and Louise:
But in philosophy class
do we hit others?
- What do we do?
- Nothing:
Nothing?
Don't you talk to each other?
In philosophy, don't you talk?
Look at me and tell me the truth:
What do you both do in philosophy?
I don't know:
You talk:
She says something,
you reply:
You don't always agree,
but in life we don't always agree:
When we don't agree
do we hit?
That's not the solution:
First, you talk about it:
OK?
Run along:
I want to focus
on the fact that our children,
if we have stuck to it
in our two schools,
and if we made an effort previously
to retain this contract,
it's because we think it matters
and it's a plus for the kids:
If they decide to stop it, so be it:
But that means
we're giving our pupils
nothing extra,
either in partnership or finance:
The priority
is the children's well-being:
FREEDOM?
When you're in your ma's tummy
you're not free:
When you come out
of your mother's tummy,
then you're free:
You are alive, sometimes:
Because you've just been born
and you can't come out in a hurry:
That's why babies kick,
they want to get out:
But you have to wait a long time,
9 months,
for the baby to come out:
- When it comes out, is it free?
- Not free:
Why is it not yet free?
Because when you're grown up,
you're allowed to do
what you want, but not everything:
You still have
the baby in your body:
Because you're a baby,
but after you grow up but it's like
you're still a baby, you:
Even grown-up,
there's still a baby inside you?
- Explain this baby part:
- A part of us is baby:
We have a baby inside ourselves:
We still have a part of baby
inside our bodies:
And when you grow up?
When you're adult?
Have adults
got a part of baby in them?
No: They've got a child part,
but when they were like us,
they've got the baby part
and when they're adults,
they've a part of the body like us:
What does that change
in terms of freedom?
Before, I wasn't free,
because I was still little,
I was 4 years old:
My brother's never free cos he's 6
and what's more he's not even big:
So your brother's not free:
Do you think one day he'll be free?
- Yes:
- When?
This is the month
when he has his birthday
and he'll be 7 years old:
And at 7, will he be free?
For example, my brother's 10
and he can't go out:
So your brother's not free?
No, he's not free:
Anissa, we can't hear
each other while you talk:
Me and Naomy
were in the yard, Naomy
and Shana went
into your classroom,
they were going to look for cakes:
But you too, as well:
Shana asked for,
do you know what Shana asked for?
Yes, I know:
She said:
"Come on, we'II look for some:"
Yes, but after, we were punished:
We weren't punished
for a long, long, long time:
Yes, I know we weren't
punished for a long time:
We were punished
an almost long time:
Yes, I know:
When you're punished,
does it mean you're not free?
Yes, you're not free, you stay put:
They were punished,
so they weren't free,
if I understood right:
And you were sent outside:
When you're outside,
you're not free either?
Yes, you're free:
But after:
But once you were no longer
punished, you were free again?
- Yes:
- No:
No, because we're watched
all the time:
You can't even do what you want:
When you're in the yard,
are you free?
There are grills
and we're not allowed out:
That's because once we're adults,
we'll be allowed to:
No wonder there are grills,
the teachers are worried
we'll run off and get lost,
if we go out of sight:
- Then the mothers cry:
- The mamas weep:
So are you free or not, outside?
Outside, we're free:
We're with our friends:
Azouaou?
One time, there was a boy,
he was big,
he was in my sister's class:
He climbed up the grills,
and he climbed and he climbed
up the schooI fence
and he left the schooI:
And so why do you think
he did that?
- Cos he wanted to be free:
- He wanted to be free:
Will you be free one day?
Yes, one day we'll be free:
- Yes, certainly:
- Yes, it's certain:
Why certainly?
If we're never free
it's because the parents are nasty
and they're not free:
We're not free
cos we're not grown-up:
Are adults free or not?
No, sometimes not:
Why? What d'you think, N'Dickou?
Rosemay?
Are papa and mama free?
My papa isn't free
because he has a long job to do,
and he has to do all the work:
Do you agree with that?
When at work, you're not free?
I agree:
You think so, Jonathan?
IsmaëI, I agree:
- To have days:
- Wait, I can't hear you:
To have days when you don't work,
well, we know there are
days of frost:
Days off!
Days off, yes, when you're tired:
For example, I, tomorrow
my papa isn't working:
My papa explained to me that
when you work, you earn money,
and you're free:
Am I free?
Yes:
You're not free
because you ask your kids:
Cos you've a baby in your tummy:
Cos I've a baby inside,
I'm not free?
Yes:
Who's stopping me be free?
The baby in your tummy:
Does it decide for me?
No, it's you who decides for it:
In its place:
It decides in place of me?
No:
Tell me: Inès?
Is she pregnant?
- Miss, are you pregnant?
- Yes, look:
Yes, it's a boy:
You know it's a boy?
She's got two boys:
Because I just want boys
so I said a boy:
So it's up to you?
It's a boy:
That'll do, that'll do:
Mouths closed:
Quiet down:
That it?
Shall we concentrate again?
I'd like to go a little further
with what you've said:
You said adults are free:
Well, you didn't all agree:
I'd like to know if I'm free,
and if mamas and papas are free:
Are they allowed
to do all they want?
No:
- Yes:
- Because they're grown-up:
Can grown-ups do what they want?
Yes:
Not everything they want, because:
No, not everything they want,
cos if you write on a wall,
the police, there's them too:
And if you do anything
really serious, you go to prison:
When you're grown-up,
and you're a big person,
well then after
you can do what you want,
but not just anything:
I'd like to know, is it normaI
for things to be forbidden?
- Yes, it's normaI:
- No:
It's cos you're not grown-up?
And cos parents, sometimes, are
afraid if something happens to us:
I'm not afraid
if things happen to me:
Inès?
Boys aren't scared of things:
Don't start that again:
When we're on vacation,
once I went on vacation,
I woke up, I opened the door,
and I left:
You left?
I went to my aunt's place,
then after, I went out again:
- You went out all alone?
- Yes:
Are you crazy?
My aunt's house
is next door to mine:
The houses are just opposite:
So you're allowed to go
from one to another?
You're not allowed:
- He's not allowed:
- Yes, I am!
What do you know?
He goes with someone:
What if there's a thief?
There's no thieves
at my place on vacation,
no, no, no,
I don't agree, there's no thieves:
- What if there is one?
- There aren't any where I go:
What if there's a thief
who buys you candies
and says to you,
come with me,
he takes you home
and cuts off your head?
When I went away
there were no thieves:
One last thing:
There are laws about this, maybe?
If there's a thief,
he puts you in the back of his van
and cuts your head off
and puts you in the woods:
But those guys don't have trucks:
They tie us up and take us away,
once they took my grandma:
So,
we're talking about obedience,
it makes me think of rules
and the law:
You know what a law is?
Louise said everyone has them:
No, not in every country:
- Yes, there is:
- No:
There aren't any in Africa:
Why's there none in Africa?
Because in Africa, they're poor:
And poor people don't need rules?
I've got a villa in Africa:
Kyria?
They're naked in Africa:
One time in Africa,
there was someone
who disobeyed something
and then, and then he was thrown,
they made a fire,
and threw the person in the fire:
It was a hell of a thing:
No one ever did it again:
Kyria, then we'll stop:
Freedom is when there's a little boy
who says to his mama:
"I don't want to stay in France,
I want to go to another country:"
And when the mother says no,
well, it's a no,
and when she says yes,
he leaves for another town,
and the little boy is happy:
That's good: You began a conclusion:
Freedom means?
I say that freedom is when
you can be on your own a little bit,
breathe a bit, and be kind:
It's when you go outside alone:
When you go outside alone, Yanis?
It's when you can do what you want:
For me, freedom is when
you come out of prison:
When you come out of prison:
Any other ideas?
N'Dickou last and we'll finish:
I wanted to say
when, in Africa, or SenegaI,
when they said
they didn't have any clothes,
well I have a villa:
They said they don't have
any clothes,
well we've got clothes in our villa,
and mostly we've got maids:
- You've got?
- Maids:
- What?
- Housemaids:
What's that?
Housemaids is when:
- Oh, maids!
- That's it, maids:
Tell us what that is:
Well, over there, sometimes
in the evening when I'm scared
they give me:
they give me chocolate
because I was scared:
They bring it on a tray
to not dirty the bed:
So they're people?
Yes, they're people:
But they're Senegalese:
I try to talk to them
but they don't understand me:
Are the housemaids free or not?
Yes, sometimes they go out
on their own
to buy things when they're told to,
and sometimes they buy us candies
at the souvenir shop:
- Are they adults or children?
- Adults:
Are they allowed to be free?
Yes they're allowed,
they're allowed to walk around:
But sometimes I'm free
all the time over there,
I'm always going out alone:
In SenegaI, you're always free,
but not when you come here?
Yes:
Why that difference?
It's interesting:
Sorry, we should've stopped:
What's the difference
between that country and France?
- It's normaI:
- Why's there a difference?
Because France,
they say sometimes that
it's a great country,
but SenegaI is still
a medium country:
But over there, I go where I want,
I go as far as Dakar beach,
and I also go
even farther than Dakar:
You can go to Dakar beach?
Yes, I can go to Almadies:
- That's cooI:
- Alone?
To Dakar beach?
Now the workshop is over:
On one side, you draw
a moment of your life, a situation,
when you're free
and on the other, a time
or a place where you're not free:
What's freedom to you?
Going where I want to go:
I'm not free
when I'm dusting the furniture:
She's not free
cos she was forced to steaI?
Why did she steaI?
Why did she steaI the bread?
Afterwards, there's
the police who came:
It was them
and they put on the handcuffs:
I don't think all the time:
Do you like it when you're thinking?
Why don't you like it?
Because
it takes too long:
OK, that's a reason:
N'Dickou, do you like thinking?
I like thinking:
- Why?
- Because afterwards, it:
I like sleeping:
After it gives me
some ideas to do something:
Hey, N'Dickou!
That's a good reason, too:
Yesterday, I couldn't stay awake:
My brain helps me to think,
my head helps me think,
it's not tired
and I talk all the time:
So you like it: Shall we go on?
I really, really, really
like thinking:
Why do you like it so much?
Because dreams,
it's the same as when you think:
It's beautifuI when you dream:
I don't like it
cos you force us to think:
- Who forces you to think?
- Teachers:
How do they do that?
Cos we're always doing philosophy:
And you're forced to?
All the girls at schooI
force me to think:
They say: "Think:"
What don't you like?
That the girls force you to answer
or that you're forced:
I tell them: "You're not in my body,
you can't controI me:"
Are you made to think?
Are you forced?
Boys don't force me:
They say:
"Don't think,
you won't bug the girls:"
D'you mean teachers or the girls?
All the girls get on my nerves:
Take it easy:
We can't hear each other:
When we're no longer in the class
and we move up to primary,
we'll no longer do philosophy
and we won't be able to think:
Do you agree with that?
Do you think that
when you leave this schooI:
We'll no longer do:
When I was 4,
I didn't understand, but:
You didn't understand:
When I started to be 5,
I understood,
but I don't know if when I move up
to primary if I understand:
Next year,
I won't be here anymore,
and I want to do philosophy
and I like doing philosophy,
because I like to think:
But next year
can you try and carry on thinking,
without us?
Yes, I could think,
because my parents
are going to do philosophy with me
because we'll have a candle:
Next year,
we'll have lots of regrets:
Why will you have lots of regrets?
Because this schooI,
we'll miss it a lot:
Why do you say that?
Because I like being here:
Cos primary is going to be harder:
- Is that right?
- Yes:
It'll be harder, maybe that:
I won't forget the teacher, anyway:
- It's over:
- No it's not all over:
- It is:
- No,
next year in September:
- We won't be doing philosophy:
- I know:
But for the little ones,
it's not completely over:
It is,
cos the little ones won't do it:
When the little ones grow up,
they'll be like us,
and when they do philosophy, well,
they might be able,
they'll be able think:
In the sand pit
with Abi and N'Dickou, me
and Louise and Léa were talking,
but at first there was only
Abi, me and N'Dickou,
and we were talking
about death and love:
From the age of 4,
these kindergarten children
attended philosophy workshops
in a public school:
JUST A BEGINNING
Subtitling TITRA FILM Paris