Yang Chae-young... Yang Chae-young!
What a know-it-all! Serves you right!
Who said that?
You insolent punks.
Back to your seats!
Don't just stand here like that.
Let's go.
Yo, Yang Chae-young.
Happy that you're switching schools?
Don't you go around saying crap about me.
Watch out when you're out at night...
Hell... you startled me.
I'm all right.
You promised not to hit me again.
Don't breathe a word about the fight we had.
Seriously.
Keep your promise!
Justice High
I'm here.
It's quiet here, isn't it?
It's our exam week.
Hey, pass it...
Shoot! Scores!
Chae-young took the midterms last week, right?
Yes.
Since it's our exam week this week
she can join us starting next week.
Yes, ma'am.
Please look after Chae-young.
We had an episode of school violence recently.
It's a bit chaotic around
and everyone is still a little wound up.
We had a big fight here last week
that ended with a student being suspended.
Mr Yang, please look after Chae-young.
Of course, well...
There were some bullies
who kept picking on her.
She should've ignored them...
They just got into a bit of an argument.
Nothing to worry about, ma'am.
You didn't have to explain everything.
What? Did I say you were in the wrong?
I never said that, did I?
Think about it. This school has bullies too.
Rather than confronting them
you can always choose to ignore them.
You mean I should just ignore them?
- No, I mean...
- Dad.
If you let them get away with it once
you're giving them permission
to run roughshod over you.
When adults ignore bullies
they are indirectly enabling them.
I swear if you get into one more fight, I'll...
- Not again?
- Chae-young..
Nature calls.
But you just went earlier.
Take a walk. Just five minutes.
We both know you'll take half an hour!
- I'm going shopping!
- Sure, go ahead.
Repeat yourself. What did you just say?
If I help you to cheat
it'll affect everyone else's grades.
That's not fair to them.
What? "Not fair"?
Hell, who says that anymore?
You're a real retard, aren't you?
- You... moron!
- Hey.
Move aside.
Come here.
I said, come here.
Jong-gu, we were asking you nicely.
How dare you turn us down flat.
You friggin' twerp.
You sound like some old fart.
"You must be fair to everyone taking the exam."
Bloody hell! You're asking for trouble!
Hell... don't you think I know it?
What was this?
But what about the other students?
What the hell are you saying?
Hey, what? Speak up.
It's not fair to those who studied hard!
Bloody hell. He startled me.
My ears are buzzing. What should I do?
You friggin' scumbag!
My, aren't you honest?
We have a Mr Prim And Proper here.
Friggin' retard! Bloody rat!
Moron! Retard! Idiot!
Stop hitting his head.
What if he dies on us?
Hell... he makes my blood boil.
He's trembling like a leaf.
Did he pee his pants?
Crazy witch.
Pull his pants down and check for yourself.
Don't be ridiculous.
- That's enough.
- Are you in love with him?
He looks pathetic enough as it is.
What is this? Four ganging up on one.
My... is this a scene out of a friggin' movie?
Hey... is she your wife?
She's taking a video.
Who are you?
Hand over that phone right now.
Hey, get up.
She ignored me.
Hey! Hand it over, you witch.
Are you deaf? Get up now.
Are you friggin' nuts?
Don't you hear what we said?
Why? Want me to add a flush to those cheeks?
Being cocky gets you dead, you retard!
Let go of me!
Don't frown.
If you get wrinkles, it's game over for you.
You witch!
Hey, move aside.
You sure you want to do this?
M-My weiner... hell...
You friggin' witch!
Get over here!
You bloody witch!
Behind...
Be quiet!
You guys tanked the exam. So pipe down.
Sit down, now.
Hey, Yang Jeong-hak!
Yes.
We have a new student.
Chae-young, introduce yourself.
Hello. I'm Yang Chae-young.
Let's be friends.
Be nice to her
and help her settle in.
- You hear me?
- Yes.
Chae-young, you can have that empty seat.
Class President, what's for first period?
- Science.
- OK, good.
So you're the new kid in my class?
Want to go to the cafeteria? I'm buying.
There's a cafeteria on the first...
Yang Chae-young, wait up.
Hey, come here for a second.
Come over. Now.
Why?
- Come closer.
- Closer?
Pretend you don't know me.
I just wanted to thank you for yesterday...
That won't be necessary.
You piqued my interest
with what you said about fairness.
That's why I stuck my nose in.
If you really want to thank me
just stay away from me, OK?
My company abandoned me.
My wife abandoned me too.
Sir, it's closing time.
This bar is abandoning me too.
It's only 10.00pm!
What kind of a bar closes so early?
Hey, let's go...
Let's not come back here.
Let's go. Come on.
We're not coming back here.
Let go. I have something I need to say.
Your food is terrible. I'm...
not paying for it
- Let's go.
- You should pay for what you ate.
Lady!
- You should pay...
- Shut it!
I'm not bloody paying for it.
- Sir, you should pay.
- Get your hand off me!
- What do you want?
- That's enough.
What's this?
Hey, attention!
Attention.
- Attention!
- Jong-gu!
- Attention.
- Hey, stop it! Let's go.
You brat.
We shouldn't have come here.
Let's go.
Hey! Newbie!
Me?
"Me"?
You're a cocky one.
Don't you see this?
So you really are a crazy witch.
Did you hit my girls?
I exchanged a few words with your minions.
My minions?
Are you tired of living, you friggin' witch?
So bloody rude.
Just hand me your phone while I'm being nice.
My phone? Why do you want my phone?
Isn't that a violation of privacy?
Show some respect, newbie.
You aren't acting like a senior should.
That's why you're not getting any respect.
What's this?
Let go of me, you friggin' skank!
Sae-na, are you OK?
So you don't know your place either.
Birds of the same feather indeed.
Hey, pin her down.
You still don't get it, do you?
Want me to upload that video?
We're so sorry, Sae-na!
Morons. You're deadmeat!
You said you're a senior.
So I'll let you off this time.
Yang Chae-young.
Teach me how to fight.
I hate repeating myself.
Don't follow me.
My dad died when I was little.
My mum runs a diner all by herself.
We get a lot of difficult customers at night.
Last night, one of the customers
was giving us a hard time.
And there was nothing I could do about it.
What has that got to do with me?
Just call the police.
Please teach me how to be strong like you.
So you can fight back
and wind up at the police station?
Don't be stupid. Just call the police.
I don't want to hurt anyone.
I just want to protect my mum.
"Justice without power is hollow."
"But power without justice is merely violence."
Master Choi Bae-dal said that.
Right, there's a biographical film of him.
Have you seen it? Fighter In The Wind.
No.
Oh... I see.
Anyway, karate is not about
hurting people, but protecting them...
- Dad.
- Yeah, Chae-young.
Is the dust giving you a sore throat?
Wear a mask.
Come on now.
The academy gives a GV
to anyone who brings in a new student.
A GV?
This?
Come on.
Gift voucher. I brought him here.
Of course, I have it right here.
Here.
Not funny.
OK. Here you go. Take it.
You know you're really cheap, right?
What?
I'm going out.
The bottom line is...
sign up now
and you'll get 50% discount
for the first month.
Application Form
Jeongdokwan Kyokushin Korea Federation
Yang Chae-young.
What?
No, I mean...
If I do taekwondo, I'll be strong like you?
- This is karate, not taekwondo.
- Oh, karate.
Dad taught me how to kick
as soon as I started walking.
If you want to be like me, give it a try.
Or whatever.
Hey there!
We'll start training tomorrow?
Jin-hyeok, since you became
the president of the student council
the atmosphere in school has gotten much better.
Thank you, sir.
When Baek Gang-shik made trouble
you handled his victim well
and we managed to keep it within the school.
And it all went away quietly.
I didn't do much.
It was just a fight between friends.
I hated seeing that happen.
By the way
the student council is doing a good job.
I feel reassured.
When Gang-shik is back from his suspension
please keep an eye on him.
- OK?
- Sure.
Don't worry, sir. I'll talk to him.
I'll get your recommendation letter ready.
Just maintain your school grades.
Sure.
By the way, how is your father?
Principal's Office
What a pain. That bloody fogey.
Joo Hae-seong!
How can you sleep now?
A new student walked all over me!
Sae-na, I can see under your skirt.
Hell...
You pervert!
Be more careful. You're practically flashing me.
Hey, Lee Sae-na.
I heard all about yesterday.
You wound up on the floor.
I bet it was humiliating.
If I were you, I'd quit school.
Park Jin-hyeok, shut it.
You don't want to rile me.
Oh, just relax.
Hey! Aren't you going to do something about it?
Hey, a junior really did hit you?
Of course, you dweeb.
How could you laugh about it?
The school's going to be turned upside-down.
What's with you today?
Who was it?
Who humiliated the mighty Lee Sae-na?
Keep that up and you're a dead man.
All right, fine.
- Jin-hyeok.
- Yeah?
Let's meet that crazy newbie tomorrow.
OK.
Summon her here.
What?
She'll come if you summon her.
You're the student president after all.
OK.
Come on, come up. A little more...
Master...
OK. Seven!
Come up now!
This is the best way to improve endurance.
Master, may I take a short break?
Is this really relevant to karate?
Of course, my dear student.
Your current fitness level
is a joke. OK?
- Just do what I say, please.
- But...
I said a thousand times.
- You've only done 12.
- But...
Ready, go!
Master, wait.
- You'd better do it at once.
- Master.
Wait a minute! Hold that position.
- Don't move.
- OK.
- Chae-young.
- What?
- Help him with the splits.
Let's get it done. Sit against the wall.
Sit down!
- Spread your legs.
- Wait.
This is killing me...
If you fight this, your muscles will tear.
No, wait...
- Wait, no.
- Come on!
Chae-young, wait!
Don't be a baby! We're just getting started!
But it really hurts...
Breathe through the pain. This won't kill you.
OK? Relax.
One, two, three!
How can you do this?
It really hurts, Chae-young!
- Hey.
- What?
When you can't avoid it, what do you do?
You learn to enjoy it.
Hey.
It'll hurt even more tomorrow.
Hurry. We're late.
Run!
Come on!
Y-Y-You're to go see the student council.
Me?
Says who?
The president of the student council.
And why are you the one telling me?
Why does the president want to see me?
M-Maybe it's because you're a new student.
Where's the student council office?
This way!
This way, you dummy.
Sorry, this way.
Let her in.
Come in.
Come in, it's OK.
- Come in.
- You wanted to see me?
Yeah.
Yang Chae-young.
I was wondering why you got transferred here.
You got into pretty serious trouble
at your old school.
What's this? You broke someone's arm?
Did you hit him when he was sleeping...
What's this about?
You really have no manners, don't you?
Right?
You're quiet today.
Where's that sharp tongue of yours?
Why? Are you scared of these boys?
Not so formidable after all, huh?
You don't know what you did wrong, do you?
I'm your senior but you walked all over me.
My dear senior.
You swore at me, demanded I hand over my phone
and hit me first when I did nothing.
I hit you first?
You hit Ye-eun and So-yeon first.
They hit my classmate first
because he wouldn't help them cheat in an exam.
Four of them ganged up on him.
I just advised them not to do so.
So what did I do that was so wrong?
Hey.
It wasn't nice to knock her down.
"Wasn't nice"?
Hey, do you friggin' mean that?
Y-Yang Chae-young.
Just apologise to her and go.
I'm sorry for what happened yesterday.
Can I go now?
I haven't had lunch yet.
Lunch? Bloody hell.
Are you kidding me?
Then, I'm off.
Go.
Hey!
Who said you could go? Bloody...
I did.
Just go.
Hey, you just let her walk out?
You're making me lose face.
- Lose face?
- Yes.
They ganged up on a student
because he wouldn't help them cheat.
You'll be losing face if you take their side.
- What?
- Hell, this is embarrassing.
Again?
Athletes need protein
but all we get is black bean noodles.
What are you talking about?
Here's your protein right here.
Eat up.
- Master.
- What?
I see you giving grade school kids a ride home.
Do you have a lot of grade school kids here?
Of course.
We have so many young karate practitioners.
Sure.
Two. Just two.
It doesn't matter how many, right?
Karate is an Olympic sport now.
Sheesh. If our students were selected
for the national team, I can't even...
But...
there's something more important at hand.
Not again? We're eating!
Never mind that. Just eat.
Your noodles is going to get soggy!
Got it. Be right back!
Why do you keep to yourself in school?
I mean, I'm an introvert
and I'm lousy at fighting.
- But you...
- What about me?
You're so cool and pretty
and good at fighting too.
I think many kids would want you as a friend.
It's too much of a bother.
Getting to know people and making friends.
It's a hassle.
Whoever it is you meet
sooner or later, you have to say goodbye.
Right?
So why bother?
So don't try to be my friend.
I'm always by myself...
when I go home after school.
I envy the other kids
who have friends to walk home with.
They'll part ways eventually.
But...
I still think it means something
even if you have to say goodbye later.
"It was fun walking home together."
"I'm glad we got to walk together."
That's how I would think.
It's really lonely to walk home alone.
I'm embarrassed for you.
You walk like you just got circumcised.
Don't come to the dojo today. Rest at home.
And put on some of this ointment.
No, I'm OK.
I'll use the ointment and be at the dojo.
Your muscles need rest to heal.
Listen to me.
Thank you.
I'm not giving it to you, so bring it back.
Is it tasty?
Bozo.
Are you coming tomorrow?
Let's drink ourselves senseless.
I have no money, dude.
It's on me, bro.
Just thank me very much, OK?
How do you have so much money?
You don't get much allowance.
Come on.
I have money to spend
even if my dad doesn't give me any.
I have my ways.
What are you looking at?
That's the crazy witch.
Bloody hell, she's no match for me.
And all that fuss.
I didn't notice it before but...
she's kind of cute, isn't she?
Are you listening?
What did you say?
Hey, wait a minute.
What about that?
- Get it together!
- Yes, sir.
If you do good work...
- Happy?
- Sure.
You like that?
Sir.
On that note, I'll start the party.
Where are you?
Why are you calling me when you're already here?
Come in!
He's here.
Turn it off.
Turn it off!
Hey.
You know why we're here tonight?
To celebrate the return of Baek Gang-shik
from Busan.
Yeah.
What's the big deal about hitting a guy?
Now...
let's drink to celebrate Gang-shik's return!
Cheers!
Bloody hell!
Drink!
You're not drinking?
Is Sae-na still after Hae-seong?
Come to me.
I'll treat you better than Hae-seong does.
You stupid?
Sae-na only has eyes for Hae-seong.
Right.
What?
Am I wrong?
Hey.
We used to fight
only when someone picked on us.
They'd hit us, and we'd hit back.
That's how we used to do things.
I don't understand what you're doing anymore.
I'm just playing a bigger game.
Stop bringing up the past.
Did you join a gang?
I've talked about it with Kim Sang-jin.
I have money to pay the initiation fee.
What?
Initiation fee?
Hae-seong.
Let's play in the big league!
You're taking this way too far.
Initiation fee?
- What the hell...
- You twerp.
Why are you walking all over me these days?
Snap out of it, moron.
Don't do anything you'll regret.
If you talk about joining a gang ever again
I'll kill you.
Go to hell, you moron!
If Dad were still alive
our lives wouldn't be this hard.
Your dad did the right thing.
I'm proud of him.
Does that even matter?
He's not with us now.
- I'm home...
- Gosh.
Oh, my pretty baby girl.
I said I don't want to see her pictures again.
Why are you so dumb? She left us.
Why do you miss her?
Chae-young.
You shouldn't say that about your mum.
Your mum is not a bad person.
She loves you very much.
Maybe she does.
But...
she loves money even more.
She's not to blame.
It was all my fault.
She's not my mum.
You can come back to visit Dad when you want.
Don't be stubborn. Come with me.
You want me to abandon Dad like you're doing?
What did he ever do to deserve this?
What did he do?
You know how crazy he is about karate.
He spent all our money to open a dojo.
Now he's heavily in debt. You know that?
You're really not coming with me?
Just go, Mum.
Just go and be with that rich guy.
I'll stay with Dad.
You're really your father's girl.
You two live together then.
Mum, don't go...
Mum...
You should've let me know right away, bozo!
Sorry, I didn't know
he was already in the room.
Hell.
Hey, Sang-jin!
Oh, Park Jin-hyeok.
Hell, I'm liking your school.
Hot girls out there and a room of your own.
Have you done it with a girl in here?
Why didn't you call me before coming here?
I told you I'd stop by soon.
Friggin' punk. Are you my boss now?
That's not what I meant.
I was just messing with you.
Don't be such a wuss.
Hey, I hear you've been learning boxing.
How did you know?
Min-seok from your gym told me.
He told me you pulled a dirty trick on him.
Oh... Min-seok?
We sparred twice and I kicked his butt.
He didn't say squat to me.
He's all talk.
It's no use talking only, right?
No doubt.
Are you Baek Gang-shik?
Hey. Say something in Busan dialect.
Are you my boss now?
That was pretty good!
I love the way he speaks.
- Jin-hyeok.
- Yeah.
You told me you got this school covered.
But, bloody hell...
you should take your boys in hand.
Is that the right attitude a lackey should have?
Hey, you're a good fighter?
Want to go outside with me?
No.
- I don't mean to...
- Hell, Jin-hyeok!
You said you want to join us
but didn't follow up.
Do you have the initiation fee ready?
Almost. I'll send it to you soon.
Time's running out.
I'll be starting my career once I graduate.
But you got nothing. Right?
Right.
What is Hae-seong doing these days?
We need that crazy guy.
I can't believe you're the number one here.
Hae-seong has never been number one.
I've been taking care of things here.
It's been a while since I saw Hae-seong.
Anyway...
I'll have everything set up for you, all right?
Just join us.
Hey, let's go.
I'll let it go this time on Jin-hyeok's account.
Glare at me one more time
I'll gouge your eyes out.
It's so hard to see you, dude.
Are you a celebrity or something?
So, what brings you here?
Are you still mad at me?
It was so frigging long ago. Be a man.
If you have nothing to say, I'm off.
Join the gang.
I'll hook you up with my boss.
Who's your boss?
Gangbuk was united the year before.
By my boss.
After he graduated
he completely reorganised the gangs.
They're even getting paid now.
It's amazing how much money you can make.
You get a lot of money from the gambling tables.
And, hell...
there are no lack of horny old farts.
You can hook them up with chicks...
Bloody hell, aren't you taking it too far?
There's no one who can do what you do.
- Join us.
- Sang-jin...
If you join the gang, you'll end up in jail.
Let's not see each other again.
Your boss, Jin-hyeok...
He's joining us.
So, see you around.
You friggin' retard! Hey.
You still don't get the picture?
Still don't get the picture? Know your place.
Don't you frigging drag me down!
Sorry.
Hey... I saved you from getting expelled.
I cleaned up your mess!
You better not forget that.
We must get the collections done soon.
Let them in.
Right...
Hey.
Bring this bozo to me.
He needs to be taught a lesson.
Jeong Jong-gu, you friggin' loser!
What's up?
What's up with you lately, moron?
Hell... what do you want?
"Hell"?
He said "Hell". Can you believe it?
You friggin' loser.
What the...
What the hell? Let go! What's this?
- One, two...
- Hell!
Hey, wait.
Wait a minute...
You friggin' schmuck.
Hey, wait...
Hell! You bloody son-of-a-gun!
Hell...
Go to hell!
Bloody hell!
Hell...
Ouch! My arm's going to break!
Hell!
What are you doing?
Let go, you bozo!
Bloody tosser.
You're a dead man today! Loser!
Yang Chae-young is not here.
- Don't get cute.
- Come with us.
You're a dead man, loser.
You're Chae-young's friend, aren't you?
Good afternoon.
What are you doing?
Jin-hyeok wants to see him.
- Jin-hyeok?
- Yes.
- Why?
- He...
Why are you grabbing him like that?
Are you a cop now?
We need to talk.
Stay right here, loser.
What?
You're getting on my nerves.
Hey.
Are you insane?
I don't care what Jin-hyeok said.
Let him go.
We need to talk.
But Jin-hyeok said to bring him to him.
Why?
It probably has to do with Yang Chae-young.
Are you guys part of it?
I heard four students ganged up on him
because he wouldn't help them cheat.
If we don't take him to Jin-hyeok...
Hell! I must have been too nice to you.
Did you forget who I am?
I didn't forget, you moron.
See that? He's no match for me.
I know who you are. You're nothing.
See that? See how I brought him down?
Is this him?
Jin-hyeok's waiting. Let's go.
Jeong Jong-gu!
Are you going to skip karate practice today?
I heard we had a crazy witch in school.
Is that you, Yang Chae-young?
Are you crazy?
I'm your senior. Bow to me.
Not you guys again.
I'll say it nicely. Let him go.
We can't. Jin-hyeok's orders.
You can try to take him.
You said it.
She's one crazy skank.
Where the hell do you think you're going?
You friggin' skank.
It's not over yet!
Does it hurt? You want more?
Baek Gang-shik!
It's OK.
You didn't do anything wrong.
See you later at the dojo.
Hey, wait. Come here.
Jeong Jong-gu? I like your name.
Hey, are you close to Yang Chae-young?
Yes...
Where are you going to meet her?
"Justice without power is hollow."
"But power without justice is merely violence."
Master Choi Bae-dal said that.
That's him.
Karate sounds like a Japanese martial art
but it actually originated in ancient India.
It was brought in during the Tang Dynasty
so it's also called tangsoodo.
We do not rely on weapons to inflict damage.
"Kara" meaning empty. "Te" meaning hand.
Dominating your opponent with bare hands.
That's karate.
- I'll sign up.
- Sign here, please.
You get a 50% discount for the first month.
Can I start today?
You're full of passion.
Sure, then...
Let's see.
Here.
Change into this.
The locker room is on your right.
Hey, Jong-gu.
Here.
Yang Chae-young, nice to meet you.
Why is he here?
It's because...
He told me to come here to be strong like you.
I did?
- That was what you said.
- When?
You did. Nice to meet you.
Aren't you one of the school bullies?
What are you doing here?
I'm not with them anymore.
I really want to learn karate.
You were really awesome earlier today.
Sure.
When did I say that?
You did.
When?
Earlier... Jump rope. Let's jump rope.
Hey!
Why didn't you greet me?
Don't you know me?
Hey... hey!
You may be a good fighter, but I'm your senior.
Have some manners.
I'm not the only one who thinks
you're a thorn in the side.
What are you doing here?
Do you have something to tell her?
Run along then.
Joo Hae-seong!
She disrespects the senior students.
Are you OK with that?
Hey, don't do this in public.
I'm off.
Hey!
What?
You've changed.
You don't answer my calls.
You get impatient when I talk to you.
Do you...
Sae-na...
Hey, Joo Hae-seong!
You knew all along, don't you?
You know I'm in love with you.
I'm madly in love with you.
But you...
Sae-na.
We've been friends for six years. Yeah?
I'd hate to lose a friend.
I'm off.
Chae-young!
You're so persistent.
No, I mean, today...
Fine, I'll walk back with you.
Thank you, but...
It's no big deal.
Let's just walk without the chit chat.
No, I mean, today...
Sweetie!
Dad.
What brings you here?
I was just passing by.
- Jong-gu?
- Hello, sir.
Hop on. I'm going to the dojo.
No, sorry.
My mum fell sick.
I was trying to tell you I can't make it today.
I see. Gosh, you're a good son.
Take good care of your mum. See you.
- Bye, sir.
- Sweetie, get in.
Let's walk back together tomorrow.
That won't be necessary.
Leave me alone.
Let's walk together tomorrow...
- See you tomorrow.
- Bye, sir.
Take care!
Hi.
You're alone.
Can I help you?
Ball...
Belt...
Honestly, why are you here?
To learn karate.
It's the truth.
You box?
Yeah. I used to box in middle school.
Does everyone look weak because you can box?
Hanging out with your clique
and bullying the weak.
Nothing wrong with that, huh?
- That's...
- Go one round with me.
No, Chae-young.
He just signed up a few days ago.
No, it's a good idea but...
Go easy, OK? Go easy.
Chae-young, this is...
Yes, this is so wrong!
Is it because I'm a girl?
No, I mean...
- That's not why.
- I...
I just started learning karate.
Yes, he just signed up.
You can box or do whatever you want.
But sparring is sparring.
So here and...
there's off limits. Fair play.
Ready.
Fight!
Easy, easy!
Go easy on him...
Are you OK?
Chae-young!
Even when you can
sometimes you must not.
"Power without justice is merely violence."
Don't you know?
Give me just one more week.
What? Your boss wants me?
Of course I appreciate it!
I'll have the money soon, Sang-jin. So...
put in a good word for me, please.
OK, bye. I'm counting on you.
Baek Gang-shik.
Can't think straight after a girl beat you up?
Hurry it up.
Get the collections done by this week.
Come here.
I'm opening the door.
No Smoking
Here it is.
Show me what you've got.
So that I know I can trust you.
I'm sorry!
Don't forget next time, OK?
And just leave that crazy witch alone.
I know what I'm going to do.
What are you doing?
What the hell is this?
May I sit with you?
It's time to go play.
Come with me.
Let's go.
Turn right.
Hey... clench your teeth.
Bloody loser!
You're the only one who didn't pay.
He's such a twerp.
Bloody loser.
I'm saving up for my mum's birthday gift.
"I'm saving up for my mum's birthday gift."
"Not for Daddy, for my mummy darling."
Hey, twerp.
He was saving up to get his mum a present.
So?
Cut him some slack, you tosser.
What did you call me? Hell...
Did you think I would do that?
Bloody hell.
This moron is full of crap.
- You friggin' loser.
- Hey...
Hell, you startled me.
Hey...
Just get out of here when I'm being nice.
What is it? You need to take a crap?
- Go poop somewhere else!
- Cut it out.
Bloody hell!
Jong-gu, can't you leave us alone?
I don't want to rough you up.
You bloody moron.
Why are you always picking on the quiet kids?
Do something to him.
Bloody hell.
You bloody schmuck!
Aren't you persistent?
Hey, Chae-young is not here.
You don't want to mess with us.
What's wrong with you, retard?
I said stop.
You bloody schmuck...
- Hell!
- Are you crazy?
Gyeong-nam, go get our homeroom teacher!
- Hell.
- Hurry up!
Hey, what are you doing?
Do you want to date me?
Are you hungry now?
You startled me!
It's you.
Why are you so early?
Where's Chae-young?
By the way...
what's with your school uniform?
Did you fall down or something?
No.
What else could it...
You got into a fight?
I wish I did.
As it is, I just got beaten up.
What happened?
Tell me.
I wanted to help my friend, but I couldn't.
Master.
When can I be strong?
I'm sick of being beaten up all the time.
I can't do anything on my own without help
and I always get beaten up. I'm pathetic!
Jong-gu.
Everyone gives help and receives help.
That's how things are supposed to be.
There's nothing pathetic about it.
I want to give help too
for a change.
It's impossible to suddenly become
a good fighter.
If you want to do that, mixed martial arts
might be better for you.
But...
I'll teach you a useful karate technique.
With enough practice, it's powerful.
So it all depends on you.
What do I need to do?
Practise until you master it.
What's this technique?
Hand!
Hand?
That's it.
How?
Karate chop.
People usually think of
using a fist or a palm to attack.
There's an attack using the edge of the hand
called the karate chop.
Softer than a fist so it requires much practice
but the narrow area of contact
inflicts double the damage!
An expert's karate chop
is no different from the blade of a sword.
Right? I like green onions too
- Same here.
- Put the noodles in.
It's not that I don't want to go.
I can't. I'm going for training.
Are you trying to get into a sports school?
Why are you training?
What sort of training?
Are you trying to get into a music school?
Why karaoke out of the blue?
This is not out of the blue.
Anyway, I'm off. Have fun!
Chae-young...
- What are you doing here?
- I was...
It hurts where you hit me yesterday.
So I couldn't sleep...
- You look fine.
- No, I...
Here and here.
My thighs and back are all bruised.
I didn't hit you there.
Really?
You don't have to apologise.
Just buy me dinner.
Bye.
Hey, let's walk together.
One thousand times.
One.
One thousand times, really?
Two.
Three.
You need to do it a thousand times.
Four. Oh!
I thought you quit.
I'll train hard, sir.
Please teach me.
Sure.
Get changed in the locker room.
Five.
Osu!
Osu.
Ouch!
Back into it.
I got ice cream!
- Why?
- Here.
Here.
Say "ah".
Honestly, I order it because you guys love it
but I'm sick of black bean noodles.
Same here, sir.
Hae-seong likes it too much!
I see...
He eats so slowly because he's savouring it.
- Does he?
- Of course.
Did you buy a roaming plan?
I'll do it at the airport.
I'll be busy, so I won't be calling you much.
You'll be busy drinking, you mean.
Sweetie, you know me too well.
Drinking is like a prerequisite for adults.
- Just go, you'll be late.
- OK.
- No eating on the mat!
Make sure you lock the door, OK?
Right, Chae-young.
Run the washer.
- Got it.
- Wait.
Are you having your finals this week?
Dad.
You're late.
Boy, I'm late! Bye. Wait!
You guys.
Look after Chae-young, OK?
- Yes.
- OK! Bye!
- Bye.
- Have a safe trip.
You don't have to come for practice
until he returns.
- Then...
- Really?
I want to be here every day.
I have nothing to do at home.
Jong-gu, what about you?
Same here. May I?
Of course not, you schmucks.
Hey.
Am I asking you for money?
Did I ask you for money?
I'm giving you money, you schmucks.
So what's there to think about?
Hey.
You only gave me five minutes
to copy your answers in the English exam.
You wanted me to flunk, don't you?
Try copying all the answers
with just five minutes on the clock!
You friggin' schmuck! You try doing that!
You bloody son-of-a-gun!
That friggin' English exam.
This is all your fault, scumbag!
Hell, I broke a sweat.
Get up!
Anyway, change seats in maths class. OK?
He's very poor at maths.
Don't you get it?
You studied so hard, share it with me!
Hey! I'm Park Jin-hyeok, mind you.
What?
You want to mess up my life?
If that happens, you guys are dead.
If I mess up the final exams
you won't get to take the KSAT.
You know why?
Because I'll cut off all your fingers.
- Jong-gu.
- Yes?
The exams are over. What are you doing tomorrow?
Nothing.
Oh, you want to watch a movie?
Good. My friend gave me three movie tickets.
Three tickets?
He gave me three tickets, not two.
Right.
Hey, the three of us could go, right?
Sure.
I'll pass.
No, wait...
What do I do with the spare ticket then?
I have no one to give it to
and it's going to expire soon.
- Right?
- Yes.
No, I'll pass.
Chae-young! Sorry...
Won't you catch a movie with us?
Yeah.
Let's go together.
The president was a zombie.
Wasn't that awesome?
He didn't fall, so he must be a zombie.
- That's right.
- No, I think...
The gate to the Blue House was open.
Right? He didn't die in the end.
They must be making a sequel.
Chae-young, you must be hungry.
You're eating a lot of popcorn.
I'm not hungry, I have popcorn.
Wait.
Who's stomach did I hear rumbling
during the movie?
That was...
It was you, right?
- Not me.
- It's all right.
- It wasn't me!
- OK then, let's have dinner.
How about rice cakes or...
Udon? Anything but black bean noodles for me.
Why spend money? Let's just go home and eat.
Wait! How about this...
We do karate, right?
How about we play a game? Loser buys.
Right now?
Hell.
You see that? The rim moved!
This machine is really weird!
This machine is no good.
Something's wrong with it.
This is nothing like karate, right?
A deal's a deal.
It's Jong-gu's turn now.
Isn't my score high?
It's low.
That post is lower than the one at school.
I've never been here.
I see.
Give it a shot. Don't give up.
Well-done, Jong-gu...
Jong-gu, you twerp...
Is there a punching machine here?
Let's make this the final game.
This is so wrong.
Jong-gu. Where are we?
The most delicious kimchi stew place in Korea.
It's not too expensive, right?
- It's free.
- Free?
Yeah. Because we know karate.
Hey.
You should've told us it's your mum's diner.
You never told me
it was your dad's dojo either.
You guys must be hungry.
This is the first time
Jong-gu has brought his friends here.
Please help yourselves.
OK.
- Mum.
- Yeah?
This is my senior at school.
We go to the same karate dojo.
- Hello.
- My, you're so handsome.
Please take good care of Jong-gu.
Sure, ma'am. For sure, yes.
Mum, this is Yang Chae-young.
She's my classmate and my master's daughter.
How do you do.
My, what a lovely young lady.
Thank you for being friends with Jong-gu.
Thank you.
Eat lots, OK?
If you need more, just let me know.
- Thank you for the food.
- Thank you.
Jong-gu.
You eat such good food every day?
I envy you.
My mum was always telling me
to bring my friends here.
Thank you for coming here with me.
Thank you, Senior.
Jong-gu.
You can just call me Hae-seong.
Hae-seong.
Have some meat.
- Hae-seong.
- Yeah?
Why do you act all chummy
with Jong-gu and me?
Hey, it's not an act.
I really want to be friends.
But why?
What do you mean why?
We do karate together.
You guys are nice and fun.
You shouldn't look for fun here.
You're friends with those school bullies.
Jong-gu gets bullied by people like you.
You know that, right?
You know why they beat him up
and pick on him for no reason?
It's their idea of fun.
That's not what any decent person would do.
I...
I was in the school's boxing club
back in middle school.
I had a flair for it and even won a few medals.
I was a decent boxer.
But...
my coach was a drunk who beat me every day.
So I quit after two years.
I kind of lost my way after that.
I got into plenty of fights.
In the third year of middle school
there was a kid in the class next door
who was ostracised.
He killed himself.
The bullies who tormented him...
were my friends.
One transferred to another school.
And the other got away with just a suspension.
But someone is dead because of them.
I really wanted to mend my ways after that
but...
I didn't know how.
The one thing I know how to do was fight.
And so I fought.
So...
when my friends called me...
I just joined them.
I didn't have friends
like you and Jong-gu around me.
I want to be a good person, not a thug.
Chae-young: You asleep?
Jong-gu: Not yet.
Chae-young: That was a great dinner.
Chae-young: Thanks.
Jong-gu: You're very welcome.
It sure is nice to have a mum. I wish...
Chae-young: Really enjoyed it. I'm beat.
Chae-young: I'm going to bed.
Jong-gu: Yeah, good night. See you tomorrow.
Here.
I quit smoking.
What?
You've changed a lot.
What is it that you want to tell me?
Starting tomorrow, our school...
belongs to Gangbuk gang.
How did you get the money?
I passed around the hat. Why?
Park Jin-hyeok.
What is it you want?
Why would you want to live like this?
Bloody hell.
Just ride off on your high horse, scumbag!
I know your school grades are crap.
You think I don't know?
I know you cheated on the exams.
I'll get right to the point.
Sang-jin wants you at the general meeting.
I don't get why he likes you.
You'll be there?
Tell him I won't be there.
Thank you.
I'm warning you not to bring
that gang stuff into our school.
Or I'll make them sorry.
Bloody hell...
I'll make you sorry too.
You've been warned.
Bloody hell!
Hey.
Who are you to tell me what to do?
Who are you to ever tell me what to do?
You piece of crap, let's fight!
Hey, schmuck.
I can't even think straight right now.
Stop yapping and just take a swing at me.
Bring it on, bozo!
If I win the fight
Yang Chae-young is dead, you schmuck.
You friggin' schmuck.
Go to hell!
You friggin' loser! Lowlife rat!
What do you think I've been doing?
You think I'm still the old Park Jin-hyeok?
You piece of crap!
Bloody hell.
Hell... how dare you disrespect me?
How dare you!
You think you're a good fighter? Loser!
Bloody hell!
You fancy Lee Sae-na, don't you?
I know you like Lee Sae-na.
You think I don't know?
That's why I stayed away from her.
You need to grow up.
You friggin' scumbag!
Hell...
Lay a finger on Yang Chae-young
and I will kill you.
Bloody hell...
Bloody hell!
98!
More!
99!
Straight!
100!
You're doing better.
- You've been working hard.
- No more.
Let's do 100 karate chops.
I'm not a robot.
I'm tired too.
You won't do it?
- No, I mean...
- Don't do it then.
No, I'll do it. Wait.
What happened to your face?
You told me you wanted to turn over a new leaf
and you got into another fight?
Easy, easy...
All done.
Looks like I'll have to get injured more often.
You've been saying no.
- But here you are.
- What's that?
What happened to your face?
What's with you?
You're actually worried about me?
Hey, do you really like Joo Hae-seong?
He's such a show-off.
If you're just going to be talking crap
I'm leaving. I'm busy.
What's the rush?
Sit. Come on.
Hell...
These are my mum's pills.
Very potent sleeping pills.
Because of my old man
my mum can't sleep without them.
That friggin' scumbag.
Lee Sae-na.
- What?
- Do you really...
Do you really want Joo Hae-seong back?
I want you to do something
Hi, I'm Sae-na.
I've been thinking and I think
I've been too mean to you.
I'd like to talk to you.
Can you come
to the student council office for a bit?
I just want to make peace with you.
Could you drop by just for a moment?
Please.
Come on in.
Chae-young, thank you for coming.
What's going on?
Suddenly, you want to apologise to me?
Come, sit down.
Sit.
Chae-young.
I'm sorry about the other day.
I apologise for being rude to you too.
No.
No matter what the girls said
I shouldn't have taken sides.
I'm so sorry.
I was too mad to think straight
but after hearing what Hae-seong said
I realised I was wrong.
I hear Hae-seong goes to your dad's dojo.
You two must be really close.
He's very athletic.
But we're not that close.
I see.
Can I tell you a secret?
I told him I had feelings for him
but he turned me down.
You two seem like a great match.
Maybe he doesn't see me as a woman.
No way, you're so pretty.
Really?
Well, the heart wants what the heart wants.
I know he doesn't fancy me
but I can't seem to give up.
That's how it is.
Have some tea.
Right, yes. Thank you.
- You know what?
- What?
You're more nave than I thought.
Yeah.
What the hell?
Sheesh. I'm leaving!
What's wrong? You look like a mess.
Wait. We have tissue paper somewhere.
Where's the tissue paper?
Lee Sae-na, why didn't you follow through?
That must hurt.
But you're not the only one who's hurt
so don't think this is unfair.
I hear you like taking videos.
It's your turn to be on video today.
- I have big news.
- What?
Gang-shik told me they're teaching
Yang Chae-young a lesson today.
Jin-hyeok is going to beat her up.
It's her funeral today, dude!
It's long overdue.
- You're here.
- Hae-seong.
What's wrong?
I think Chae-young may be in trouble.
Someone from student council called her.
And now her phone's turned off.
- Student council? Who?
- I have no idea.
I overheard some guys saying
they're going to do something to Chae-young.
Incoming call: Hae-seong
- Yeah.
- Park Jin-hyeok, where are you?
Come to school, moron.
This is your last chance.
Get the job done.
Hae-seong.
Answer the phone, Park Jin-hyeok.
- Hae-seong.
- Park Jin-hyeok...
Hey!
We need to go now.
Joo Hae-seong, where are you going?
Where's Chae-young?
What is this?
Are you here to fight me?
Where's Chae-young?
You shouldn't have made things so complicated.
Hey, scumbags.
Nobody leaves here without my permission.
Hey, take them down.
What the hell are you doing?
Are you taking turns? Just go at him!
Hell, get up!
Hey!
Get him!
Friggin' schmuck!
Hell!
- What's this?
- This is karate!
Hell... stay still!
Sorry about that but I told you to stay still.
Stay still.
Just stay still.
Chae-young! Chae-young!
- It's locked!
- Park Jin-hyeok!
Baek Gang-shik, that bloody moron.
Park Jin-hyeok, you call yourself a human?
Call the police.
You want to see her face get shredded?
Put the phone down.
You think I'm bloody kidding?
I said, put it down.
Put it down.
Come here for a second. A little closer.
Come on.
Kneel.
I said, kneel!
Why did you do this to me?
Why the hell did you do this to me?
Do I look like a pushover?
Do I look like a pushover, you piece of crap?
You scumbag! Friggin' loser!
Do I look like a pushover, you scumbag?
This is all your fault, you hear me?
Hell, you have a death wish?
Bloody hell!
Scumbag!
Everyone has been disrespecting me.
I'll show you who I am today.
You lowlife rat.
I know who you are.
You're a hypocrite.
Are you deaf?
You shouldn't even have been born
you lowlife trash!
You friggin' schmuck!
Who are you to diss me?
Friggin' loser!
Die, you piece of crap!
I'm Park Jin-hyeok.
Hell, I said I'm Park Jin-hyeok.
Bloody hell...
Go to hell!
My dad always said...
You crazy witch.
"Justice without power is hollow."
"But power without justice is merely violence."
You deserve this beating.
Go to hell.
Hey, Chae-young...
Are you OK?
I should be the one asking you that.
I'll take care of you.
Guys... are you OK?
Wait. Wait a minute.
Hae-seong.
Get up.
- My leg.
- Easy, easy...
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
You were out for a while. Are you all right?
Just worry about yourselves.
Jong-gu, are you all right?
Are you OK?
Let's go.
Let's go, Chae-young.
Just go.
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, what about you?
- Are you guys hungry?
- A little bit.
Hae-seong, could I get your number?
I couldn't call you earlier.
You don't know my number?
- Why not?
- That's why I couldn't call you.
Incoming call: Gangbuk's Kim Sang-jin
Then, could I get Chae-young's number?
Is he dumb?
It's true. Master is divorced and single.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I think she's right.
He goes shopping alone every day.
Really? He's totally my type.
Your type?
He's so much older than you!
That's not good.
You can't say that anymore.
Age shouldn't matter.
What?
"Justice without power is hollow."
"But power without justice"
"is merely violence."
Master Choi Bae-dal said that.
In karate, what's most important
is to dominate
not to attack.
Karate is not a skill to attack someone
but rather, to dominate your opponent
with your bare hands to protect yourself.
Now ladies, learning karate
will help you lose weight fast.
Let's warm up first
with a simple dance.
OK.
Osu!
Dad...
Hang in there.
Be nicer to him.
He's working so hard for you.
This is none of your business.
Sir.
Yes, dear student.
May I go to the bathroom?
I'm almost done. Can you hold it in?
OK.
So, the bottom line is
sign up today
and you get 50% discount for the first month.