--== McEphie ==--
For latest releases visit https://moviesnipipay.co
You're an embarrassment.
What will people say?
That I'm a bad mother,
and that's why this happened?
You shithead,
I send you to school.
It's all for nothing.
You can't smoke here, ma'am.
You better not tell your sister.
Her tongue is loose, like her vagina.
If you don't want the entire world
to know…
don't tell anyone.
Laing.
-Pork blood stew, miss.
-Miss, what do you need?
Where have you been?
Don't start. I'm not in the mood.
I told you not to leave dirty dishes here.
Give me a break!
I only have two hands. I'm swamped.
Kalel, don't just stand there.
We have so much work to do.
Clear the table.
You're so tense.
-It's from too much work.
-Do you feel it? Right here.
It's the middle of the day,
and you're flirting with my friend.
Are you taking her seriously?
Just go back to your stall, Mameng.
They need those ingredients.
GOOD NIGHT, WORLD.
LET'S GO TO SLEEP.
Kalel, where's the blow dryer?
Hey!
What an ass.
Are you listening to me? Where is it?
How should I know?
-You were the last to use it!
-Was that necessary?
You're so careless!
You're the one with panties lying around!
You leave my panties out of this!
Stop this at once.
It's his fault.
Going somewhere?
Yes, I already told you.
Danny's going to pick me up.
Now?
Yes.
Mameng placed an order
for three kilos of spring rolls.
Just ask your boyfriend
to give us a hand here.
I can't!
-Such a slut.
-I said no.
You're an idiot.
You want me to hit you back?
What the fuck are you doing?
Show your sister some respect!
-She started it.
-Jerk.
What have I got to do with it?
It's our day off, but we're still working.
What?
I'm exhausted!
Excuse me. Do you think I enjoy this?
I am killing myself
just to feed the two of you!
You ungrateful wretch!
Stop being a slut!
There are better men out there.
All you do is have sex with Danny!
Do you use condoms?
Must I tell you everything I do?
Pardon me, madame,
but you can be a real idiot sometimes.
Fuck.
You might get pregnant again.
-Fuck this life!
-Life says fuck you too!
Come back here when you're dressed!
Did you tell her?
Sis.
Hurry.
Take this.
Ma, I'm leaving.
Go straight to school.
Here.
Text me.
Ms. Torres.
Please repeat what I said.
You're not listening.
Who are you texting?
Kalel, are you okay?
You seem a bit off today.
I'm just not feeling well.
Are you and Sue having problems?
No.
Why are you avoiding her, then?
She kept calling me yesterday,
asking if you were with me.
You haven't even fucked yet,
and you're breaking up?
Have you made out with her?
Make-out extreme!
I got to mash her boobs!
Did you check out her breasts?
Her nipples are pink, right?
Eloisa's are really dark,
like Oreo cookies.
They're as big as the original Oreos.
What's a guy to do? They're delicious.
She lost our bet. I won.
Here.
Hey!
Want some?
Come back here!
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Tell me.
You figure it out.
Your good night pic has 1,000 likes.
Who are these people?
My fans.
For real?
You can bid them good night,
but you can't send me a reply.
Why are you stalking me on FB?
Am I not allowed?
I thought I was your girl.
Look, I'm sorry.
I had to do a lot of errands for my mom.
-Can I have a kiss?
-Jerk.
It's just a kiss.
We're in our uniforms. Give me that.
Special trip, please.
Let me know when you're home safe.
LET'S JERK OFF TOGETHER.
IS THAT REALLY YOUR DICK?
WHAT'S YOUR ASL, BRO?
ARE YOU GAME?
Get up. Your father's downstairs.
Hurry. He can't stay long.
You finally found time.
I didn't have a choice.
Thanks.
You kept pestering my secretary.
Kalel, sit down.
What happened to you?
Only gay men end up with that.
Are you gay?
Where did you get it?
He won't answer.
I sounded like a broken record,
but I got nothing.
Where's that soup you made?
My stomach is aching.
You're done talking to him?
I'm hungry.
Did you let someone butt-fuck you?
Thanks.
It's hot.
Look, a sports car!
Isn't that Kalel's father?
Get inside!
Is that still a thing?
It used to be expensive.
You can get it for 4,000 in Manila.
-Kalel.
-Bro.
Your turn.
I want to go home.
Then, go.
Aren't you coming with us?
Caloy will text us if his dad leaves.
We already bought beer and munchies.
Do we have enough?
Yes.
One more.
Good stuff.
Just like a rock star.
Can I talk to him?
Bro.
Bring the lighter.
Are you sure you just want to talk?
What are we?
Humans.
Idiot.
Okay, we're idiots, then.
Be serious.
What I meant was,
are we just friends,
or more than that?
You want out?
Stop playing games. You're such a child.
So we're not humans nor idiots,
and I'm such a child. So, now what?
Stop it. Do we have a problem?
You can be sweet at times.
And then suddenly, cold and uncaring.
Earlier, you seemed to be
in your own world.
You were paying more attention
to that girl.
What was that?
You want my life to revolve around you?
I just want what we used to have.
I want to feel that I'm important to you.
You don't have to say it.
I know something has changed.
So?
You're just going to ignore me?
Ma.
-Where have you been?
-What are you doing?
We were working on a group project. Why?
I kept texting, but you never replied!
That phone is just a waste of money.
Just because I didn't reply
doesn't give you the right
to go through my things!
-They're mine.
-Where did you get these?
They're very expensive.
Are you using drugs?
Are you selling drugs?
What's going on? People are sleeping.
Mind your own business. Get out!
Fine!
Why are you doing this?
What did I ever do to you?
Stop being so dramatic.
Not everything is about you.
I'm the one with HIV!
Shut up. Someone might hear you!
Wait.
You have HIV?
I told you to mind your own business.
You're both shouting.
Of course I can hear you.
Shut your fucking mouth, you stupid twat.
If this gets out,
I will hang you upside down!
Why are you mad at me?
You're a gossip, that's why!
You gossiped about your own abortion.
Stop what you're doing.
Get your tuition money from your father.
Why me?
Who should go? Ruth?
He's not her father.
I don't want to.
What?
-I don't want to!
-Why?
What do you mean, why?
I don't want to go there.
-What's the reason?
-I just don't want to go.
Why don't you like going there?
You're lucky he's sending you
to a good school.
Be thankful that he was the one
who got me pregnant.
If it had been one of my other boyfriends
who were all assholes,
you wouldn't have gotten anything.
Believe me.
You were never lucky with men.
So why do you like Mon?
Yes.
Come on!
You bitch!
Bitch! You like it big.
All we desire is your embrace
And forgiveness
Lord, our Father
Nothing compares to the joy
And love you bring
Lord, our Father
Opel, get us a box of buns
and some orange juice, please.
We'll have snacks.
Excuse me. I'll get your food.
Give this to your mother.
How are you?
May I kiss your hand?
Please bless our son Enzo as well.
Enzo, let me hold him.
-Didn't I baptize him last month?
-Yes.
Oh my, he has grown.
Sorry, were you still talking
to your guest?
He's my friend's son. He just dropped by.
Father, I have to go.
-Mother's waiting.
-Aren't you going to eat?
I'm still full. Thank you.
Father, let's take a selfie.
All right.
Here.
What's this?
I read on the Internet
that it's a great help
to those with your illness.
Their viral level dropped because of it.
Google it.
Thanks.
Do you like it?
I'll give you a discount.
You can't stay long.
Why not?
I just got here.
Keep your voice down. They're sleeping.
Just go without me.
Take care, bro.
Are you still mad?
Are you free after class?
Can you come with me?
What did you want to show me?
Are you in a hurry?
My mom might get angry.
This won't take long.
Are you sure this is okay?
Yes. My parents are in the province.
They won't be back until tomorrow.
I'll get you a drink.
You sure have a lot of awards.
Have you counted all of them?
Wait.
Sue, what are you doing?
I realized why you were avoiding me.
-I haven't given in to you.
-Wait.
-It's okay.
-I'm leaving.
Just relax.
Sue.
Let's see if you can escape from this.
What's that?
Fuck, where did you get that?
I've always wanted to do this.
You have no idea.
You want this too, right?
What did you do?
You don't want this?
Are you crazy?
Fuck! Stop it!
Why did you bite my lip?
Kalel, wait.
Kalel, come back! You asshole!
Dinner's ready.
What's that?
Nothing.
Let me see. Why are you in cuffs?
Are you in trouble with the police?
What did you do?
You idiot. Did you kill someone?
You're so full of shit. Me, kill someone?
So what's with this?
It's nothing.
-Tell me.
-Nothing.
My friends were just fooling around.
Give me your hand.
Shit, Kalel,
I thought you were a good boy.
You really are my brother.
Let's go.
Come to the table
before the food gets cold.
Stack them properly.
This is heavy.
Just a minute.
Here.
After class, go straight to the eatery.
I have to go to the market,
so I need you there.
Okay.
It might spill.
Here.
Is that her?
-What?
-Is she your lover?
A lot of people
have already seen you with her!
Wait a minute.
You bitch!
Stop fucking my husband!
Fuck you! Don't you dare attack my mother!
Mon, you better fix this.
Let's go home!
Get inside!
Get inside, or I'll punch you!
You think you're so tough?
Bring it on, bitch!
That's enough.
Go home!
Leave, you piece of shit!
Fuck! Come back here!
Ma, he's not worth it.
Yes, let it go.
Idiots!
We loaded everything in the tricycle.
What am I supposed to cook in the eatery?
You should have unloaded it!
My father is looking for the handcuffs.
They're here.
Does he know what happened?
If he knew,
we wouldn't be talking right now.
He would have sent you to jail.
I'm sorry.
Sorry, my ass.
Wait, Sue…
Bro…
are you and Sue still together?
We're just taking a break.
Are you sure?
Someone saw her at the Leopards party.
She was making out with a varsity player,
Balmaceda.
You didn't know?
You better investigate.
Sue could be playing with you.
Don't be a fool.
A witch?
She doesn't look like a witch.
More like a ghoul.
So early!
Sit, Kalel. Let's drink.
No, thanks. I have homework to do.
Busy?
Come on. Just this once.
You saw how embarrassed I was earlier.
Let's drink as equals.
Just call me Edith.
Let's get wasted, you motherfuckers.
Come. Sit. Drink.
You like getting drunk?
Okay, then.
Edith, can I ask you something?
Go!
Why do you have such bad taste in men?
You shithead!
They're all assholes.
You're such a sucker.
Don't be an ass.
I'm still your mother.
Don't make fun of my love life.
I thought we were drinking as equals.
Oh yeah. That's right.
But stop shitting on my parade.
My love life is my business.
Did I ever meddle in your love life?
Isn't your boyfriend a drug addict?
He's not an addict. He just has a vice.
So meth is just a vice now?
Fuck you.
-Who's the sick one here?
-Look at her, Mom.
So?
Let's be happy. Drink!
You're so arrogant.
Stop that.
You'll just end up fighting.
Let's just drink!
Drink up, asshole.
You are one horny motherfucker.
Not as horny as you, shithead.
-Fuck you.
-Aren't you going to ask her?
Never mind. Just leave her be.
If she wanted me to know,
she would have told me.
You're such a bitch.
She's already drunk.
Didn't she say we can ask her anything?
-You're so gullible.
-She might tell you.
-Don't bet on it.
-I'll ask her.
-Yeah, right.
-I'm going to ask her.
Edith, wake up!
Ruth wants to ask who her father is.
Fuck you. Stop it.
There must be a reason
why she's not telling me.
Your father is a priest,
and yet she told you.
So my father is probably worse.
Maybe he's a dog.
Fuck, maybe that's it.
Edith was fucked by a dog.
Shithead!
You look like a dog. Son of a bitch.
-Hit me, and I'll throw this at you.
-Fuck you.
You're an idiot.
Are you sure you're leaving your wife?
You might end up changing your mind.
Yes, I'm sure. And you?
Are you really leaving your kids?
Don't worry about them.
They're grown-ups anyway.
They can live on their own.
If you only knew how much I love you.
I love you too.
-Let's leave now.
-Kalel! You're still awake?
Where are you going?
I left a note at the altar
for you and Ruth.
Just read it.
I left money for the rent
and for the eatery.
Use the money wisely.
Why are you leaving?
Mon is leaving his family for me.
Fuck.
That's why you're abandoning us?
I'll be back.
When?
Fuck, Kalel.
You're old enough to understand.
You know everything I've been through.
He truly loves me
and is willing to fight for me.
It's time I give myself a chance.
We have to go before Osang tracks us.
Go back inside.
Take care of yourself and the eatery.
Otherwise, you won't have anything to eat.
You idiot. Why didn't you stop her?
Were you able to stop her before?
Fuck.
This is all Mon's fault.
Where is it?
-On the altar.
-Where?
The altar.
Shit! She beat me to it!
Danny and I were going to elope.
I'd already packed my bags.
Fuck!
Where's my allowance?
Here.
Here's more.
Are you sure?
Don't you want it?
It's taking so long. Maybe she went home.
Just wait.
Maybe they have a group project.
Group project?
We should have gone to her house.
Bro. Here she comes.
I told you, bro.
She's with that stupid Balmaceda now.
Dumb jock.
We weren't going to tell you,
but someone saw them in Twilight,
the motel near the market.
I have a discount card there.
Hey, Kalel.
Bro, sorry,
but we heard there's a video.
Is that true?
Yes.
It shows Balmaceda eating Sue's pussy.
Fuck!
Balmaceda is a jerk.
He was caught with a gun during a retreat.
Really?
Fuck, he should have been expelled.
You know, guys,
can we not talk about them?
We're drinking!
Let's just have fun!
Another round!
Let's order more?
But we have school tomorrow…
Kalel wants to drink! Let's party!
-What happened to your brother?
-Beats me.
Gross.
What a mess.
What a weakling.
He can't keep his liquor down.
Don't drink if you can't handle it.
Lights?
Get up! You have school today, right?
Clean up before you leave.
Is that my shirt?
I'm going to return it.
I haven't gone home.
You moron!
You're never going home.
He's staying with us.
Why?
Because I said so.
Go upstairs. You'll be late for school.
What a loser.
What an amateur.
So gross.
Are you taking the medicine I gave you?
It's so itchy.
Did you apply any ointment?
Just virgin coconut oil.
Did it help?
Not really.
I'll prescribe an ointment.
You need another blood test
to check your CD4 count and viral load.
We can only help you if you help yourself.
We arranged for counseling sessions,
but you and your mother never came.
If I kiss someone,
is it possible for her to be infected?
You can't transmit HIV with saliva
unless the patient's infected blood
comes in contact with an open cut
in his partner's mouth.
Even then, the risk is still small.
Why, did you kiss anyone recently?
What did I say?
You have to be honest
if you want me to help you.
She bit my lip, then she sucked my blood.
As I said, the risk is still low.
But it may be best
to have your partner tested.
Kalel, don't you have
any other activities to do?
Kalel, I need more plates.
Can I have my allowance?
What allowance? I'm broke.
How will I eat later?
Do you ever think about how we'll eat?
No money, but they have meth.
What did you say?
Fuck you!
You son of a bitch.
-Shut up!
-I use my own money for that.
Don't cuss my brother!
I don't ask for money from your sister.
-You should set him straight.
-Shut up!
Here.
That's all I have.
Borrow money from your classmates.
I'll pay them later.
Asshole.
Fuck you!
Get out of here!
How will you pay his classmates?
You sold everything!
Asshole! Did you not benefit from that?
Your brother is the asshole!
And he's sick!
-Don't mention that.
-I can hear you!
Fuck you!
Get the hell out of here!
This is our house!
Here. Now, get out of here!
Put him in his place!
Here, guys. Check these out.
They're in mint condition. Be careful.
Guys, I said be careful.
Come on. Buy it.
I'll get this. How much?
I bought that for 300 bucks.
I'll let you have it for a hundred.
Great!
Shit, Caloy. This is just 20.
That's all the money I have.
-You owe me 80.
-Fine.
Bro. I'll get this.
Yes!
This is your collection.
Why are you selling them?
I just have too many comics.
-Kalel, bro!
-I have no space for them at home.
Hey, Je.
So you haven't heard?
Sue has been absent for two weeks.
She's sick.
She was rushed to a hospital in Manila.
What's her illness?
She probably busted her pussy
from fucking Balmaceda.
Do you know what hospital she's in?
How much is this?
Those are 100 each.
Expensive. And the small ones?
Also 100 each.
Is there no discount?
Nothing's cheap nowadays.
Miss, where can I find Sue Evangelista?
She's in room 804.
-804. Here?
-Upstairs.
Is that for me?
It's good you came to see me.
I'm so bored. I have no one to talk to.
Where are your parents?
They'll be here after work.
What's your illness?
Just a fever,
but it got worse.
I'm okay now.
Why?
Did you miss me?
Don't worry.
I'll be back in school next week.
Come closer.
Are we back together?
I thought you didn't like me anymore?
I can like you again.
What about your boyfriend?
What boyfriend?
You're the only one who came to see me.
You even brought me an apple.
So we're back together.
Come closer.
I miss you too.
I want to kiss you, but it's not allowed.
I might infect you.
Did you miss me?
Of course. Don't you believe me?
I'm not wearing anything underneath.
Have some water.
Bro, your girlfriend's so high.
Jerk. Stay away.
Get lost.
Relax.
We should just enjoy ourselves.
You're back together?
What about Balmaceda?
Maybe they were just fuck buddies.
No.
Sue's raunchy…
even though she looks
like the Virgin Mary.
Show some respect.
What's your problem?
What's that smell? You're all too young!
Stay out of this.
We don't mind you doing drugs downstairs.
You're too serious.
I come bearing gifts.
-What's that?
-Open your mouth.
-What?
-Open!
Asshole!
Body of Christ.
Fuck, Danny.
You, open your mouths!
Wait, won't we get arrested for this?
Idiot!
Only people who live in slums
get arrested.
What?
Stop asking questions. Open!
You're next.
No.
Here!
You, Tiny. Come here.
Tiny, you'll get two.
Is this it? I don't feel anything.
Just enjoy it!
This is beautiful.
It's a different world.
He keeps saying
that he will stop gambling.
But as soon as he has money,
he heads straight to the casino.
He even steals money from my piggy bank.
One morning, we woke up
to find the TV gone. He had pawned it.
The other day,
they almost killed each other.
My brother cut his hand
trying to stop them.
Fuck…
I wish they would just split up.
I'm tired of them.
I have HIV.
You have AIDS?
You're so stupid. He said HIV.
How am I stupid?
Pipe down, you two.
I didn't tell you right away
because you might find me repulsive.
You might start avoiding me.
You're being silly. We're like brothers.
Even when we grow old,
we will still be there for each other.
That's why we call each other "bro."
That's right.
We're like a family.
We share everything.
If one of us has a problem,
it's everyone's problem.
No one gets left behind.
Guys,
make sure this doesn't get out.
Promise me.
Of course.
Coach.
You should try out for varsity.
You have what it takes.
Okay, Coach. Thanks!
Guys!
Coach told me to try out for varsity.
You guys should try out too.
Can I have a drink?
-Here.
-I'm not thirsty.
Let's go.
We have to go, bro.
We'll just see you later.
I'll send you a text.
And congrats!
Sue.
Hey, are you okay now?
Is it true?
Do you have AIDS?
Who told you?
A lot of people. All our friends know.
I have HIV. I don't have AIDS.
That's the same.
No.
I'm not sick.
Not yet.
What about me?
Won't I get infected?
It doesn't work that way.
Are you sure?
Even if I bit your lip?
Maybe that's why
it took me so long to shake off my flu?
The doctor said the risk
of infection is low.
But if you want to be certain,
we can have you tested.
Fuck, Kalel!
What if I also infected someone?
Jerk!
What's going on?
-I said, stop!
-Why?
Enough!
Stop!
He started it.
What? What's your problem?
What possessed you to spread rumors
that your classmate has AIDS?
It's not just me, Sister.
But you started it.
If I were Mr. Fernandez,
I would probably punch you too.
That's slander!
Why don't you ask him if it's true?
Is it true?
Idiot.
Get out.
You too, Miss Consolacion.
But, Sister,
there's talk among our students
that he might have infected
his girlfriend.
She's also a student here.
Infected?
Why?
Are you and your girlfriend having sex?
I don't understand.
Why is this happening here?
This is a Catholic school!
Did you get tested?
Don't.
Fuck you!
-Is that him?
-Leave him be.
Stop here.
Sis?
There was a commotion earlier.
What happened?
Your landlady came earlier
with village officials.
They told your sister to leave
because you were several months
behind in rent.
But your sister put up a fight.
Even her boyfriend beat them up.
The landlady punched your sister.
Is there a Ruth Anne Fernandez here?
This is the traffic bureau.
Try next door.
Thanks.
Is there a Ruth Anne Fernandez here?
Ruth Anne Fernandez?
She was brought in earlier.
Just today, right?
Ruth Anne Fernandez.
Sir.
Thanks.
Put it inside. I'll eat later.
What's her name again?
Ruth Anne Fernandez…
Here it is. Ruth Anne Fernandez.
But she's in no condition to talk.
Come back tomorrow.
Why? She's my sister.
She was high on drugs
when she was brought in.
That's probably why she was violent.
Will she be released tomorrow?
Tomorrow's Saturday.
You can post bail on Monday.
Bail?
How much would that be?
I don't know.
Come back tomorrow with your parents.
Let them take care of it.
Sir, is it possible--
Come back tomorrow.
Bring your parents with you
so they can take care of things.
May I talk to Father?
He's inside the confessional.
What time will he be done?
It depends. If there's a long line
of people who want to confess,
he just stays inside.
Father, it's Kalel.
Where's Father George?
He is sick. I am filling in for him.
I need to speak with him.
About what?
I need to talk to him.
Come back some other day.
Please, child.
There's a long line outside.
You should go.
I'm his son.
I have nowhere else to go.
Kalel is here.
Sit down.
Are you hungry?
You can have it. I have no appetite.
Eat slowly. You might choke.
Fuck this arthritis.
That's how I eat meat too.
I slice the fat off.
Why are you here?
We were evicted.
We haven't been able to pay our rent.
Where's your mother?
She ran off with her boyfriend.
My sister is in jail.
The police said perhaps tomorrow--
How much do you owe?
Rent is 8,000 a month,
but we haven't paid for five months.
My bones are so painful.
There's an envelope near the TV. Get it.
How much is in there?
Give that to your landlady for now.
Next week, come back here.
We will pay the full amount.
I need to post bail for my sister.
Kalel, your sister
is not my responsibility.
She's not my child.
What's important is for you
to get your home back.
I don't want to live there anymore.
Where will you go?
You can't stay here.
I thought you weren't coming.
Would you like to eat first?
I'm not hungry.
I've been sending you messages.
It's good to finally get your attention.
Are you really up for this?
Just stick to our agreement.
Of course.
Is Kalel your real name?
Aren't we gonna leave now?
I'll just finish my coffee.
I'll wait for you outside.