Sir, the Inspector has gone for rounds.
Yes, sir.
Okay, sir.
I’ll inform, sir.
Yes, sir.
The same address.
- Sir, SI has come.
- Sir.
Greetings, sir.
The Government will not take action
against the wish of the people.
- Sir, K3 police station.
- That was said by the Prime minister.
At Madurai airport,
he met the press reporters...
... and said he will appeal
to the supreme Court.
- Greetings, sir.
- Is this the guy?
- Yes, sir.
Hey, get up.
Sir, I didn't do any mistake.
Tell them to leave me.
(Indistinct chatters)
Sir has gone out for rounds.
Don’t know why, the Inspector asked us
to come urgently.
Did he tell anything?
No, sir. We enquired him our best.
But, he didn’t say anything.
Okay,
Get me his FIR, immediately.
Sir, it’s Aminjikarai, K3 police station.
Sir just came in.
"Honour killings" often takes place
in the villages...
The accused, himself came
and surrendered, sir.
We have sent the corpse to autopsy.
Okay, sir.
Okay, I’ll inform, sir.
Right now, we’re at Aminjikarai,
the murder spot.
We will ask the people
who have witnessed the murder.
I was tying the flowers there.
The man who is dead,
was coming by the side.
A guy came in high speed and lynched him.
He fell down unconsciously.
Heeding loud noise, I came out
and saw, what it was?
Don’t know what was the issue.
A person was lynching another person.
Have you seen the murderer
anywhere before?
No, I haven’t seen him before.
Didn't anyone stop,
when the incident happened?
He is lynching with a knife.
You’re asking, didn't we stop.
What would you do?
Will you stop him?
The news we received so far,
the murder has surrendered in the police station.
Police are investigating intensively
to find about the deceased.
For Panimalar news, this is Prabhu
with Cinematographer Iniyan.
Thank you, Prabhu.
The current news...
Police suspects this murder would’ve been
executed because of illegal affair.
The brawl between the murderer
and the deceased…
…was the reason for the murder,
said by the local residents.
In this regard, the police are
intensively investigating.
♪Three wheeled vehicle,
There is no route, left out♪
♪No charge for the pregnant women
to travel ♪
♪Poverty is plentiful
Thousands of worries ♪
♪We are living in the midst of it ♪
♪Three wheeled vehicle,
There is no route, left out ♪
♪No charge for the pregnant women
to travel ♪
♪We have the address
of the whole Chennai in our palms ♪
♪When the first day of the month comes,
we fear a little ♪
♪A tea and a bun is the happiness
of an automan ♪
♪We will tell you the address
of the dead end too ♪
♪Three wheeled vehicle,
There is no route, left out ♪
Shankar, you have mentioned
all the leader names in your auto stand.
This is “Thanthai Periyar” auto stand,
Here all are leaders.
Hey, it’s a woman's auto.
Hey, how about going to room?
Get the job done and call me.
Sister, I feel like puking.
Stop, let me get down.
Sister!
Do we women look so cheap?
Go to hell.
♪Before brushing the teeth,
we will take a ride to Pallavaram. ♪
♪We will halt at Koyambedu
in between time ♪
♪The billionaire Ambani, ♪
♪And the poor man♪
♪Both of them are
a great ride for us. ♪
♪Three wheeled vehicle,
There is no route, left out ♪
♪No charge for the pregnant women
to travel ♪
♪Three wheeled vehicle,
There is no route, left out ♪
♪No charge for the pregnant women
to travel ♪
I regret, why I took up the ride.
Hey, Madurai bus has arrived.
Come, dude.
Let the passengers get down soon.
Brother, switch on the light.
Brother, Guindy!
Anyone getting down in Guindy?
Brother, arrived at Guindy Kathipara.
Sister, Guindy has arrived.
Hello, boss!
You asked for Guindy, right?
Guindy has arrived, you may get down.
Brother, this will not go to Vadapalani,
It goes via Mount road to Parrys
and then reaches Koyambedu.
- Those who have to get down at Guindy, get down.
- Malar, we’ve reached.
Brother, wake up.
Don’t sleep.
Come.
- Sir, come
- Sir, come.
Hey, give way.
Sir, come I’ll take you.
- Sir, come on.
Where do you want to go?
Auto is ready.
Sir, come let’s go.
- Sir, where do you want to go?
- Hey!
- Sir, come.
Come in our auto.
Sir, come.
- Sir, no need.
- Sir, come.
- Sir, give me my bag.
- Get in
Sir, come.
Come, sit here.
We’re not going by auto.
We’re going by bus.
While leaving, I was cautioned
that auto guys will pester.
- Are you going by bus?
It’s right.
Hey, you don’t have bus
at this hour.
You’ve to go only by auto.
Wait and see.
I’m also watching you
for past one year.
You came by cycle, then a moped,
now by bike.
Don’t you see the auto is parked,
coming in between and taking the ride.
- Hey, move away.
- You will become a big shot, in future.
- Brother, do you need an auto?
- Hey, uncle.
It’s my ride.
Come!
Wow, it’s Audi A4!
Wow, what a car!
Kathir!
Hey!
Hey, don’t you have sense?
Have you informed your home?
I didn’t say, sir.
Dare to give a mocking reply.
Where have you to go?
To Choolaimedu.
- Hey!
- Sir!
- Someone drop them and come.
- Sir, I’ll take them.
Come.
- Every day, these kind of nuisance arrives.
- Hey, come on.
What to do?
Come on.
Sir, you didn't turn on the meter.
- No, I haven’t.
- Sir.
You need to go to Choolaimedu, right?
Give me 300 rupees.
What 300 rupees?
Sir, I was told 150 rupees
will be charged.
What?
150 rupees?
Who said?
For earning 100 or 150 rupees,
are we awake the whole night and driving auto?
It’s 300 rupees,
give me or else get down.
- We will give.
- Okay.
Tell him.
Okay, sir.
I’ll give you, let’s move.
That’s good.
Sir, have it.
Just a minute.
Have it.
You said 300 rupees.
Hey, it’s actual meter payment,
you can leave.
What happened?
Unable to connect the call, wait.
Hey!
Who are you looking for?
Mari!
Looking for Mari brother.
- Are you from Madurai?
- Yes.
Mari brother!
The Madurai party has come.
They have come from Madurai college.
Brother, they’re waiting for you.
- Not even 16 years, but talking about love.
- Greetings brother.
Has the bus arrived early?
Yes, brother.
Bus came early than the schedule.
Okay, come let’s go.
Anand.
- What brother?
Take the vehicle.
Okay, brother.
Come.
Shanmugam brother!
This is the house.
Come Mari, are they the one
you spoke about?
Yes.
Open the door.
- Come in.
- Come.
Mari, I too observe,
the people who you bring...
...stay for two to three days
as if they stay in lodge and leave.
Will these people stay
for some days?
Brother, will everyone who come here
will like the house?
If they like, then they will stay.
Have I ever kept balance on rent
or advance?
- No, I can’t blame you on payments.
- Then, open it.
Get inside.
Mari!
Water crisis is here.
Have you informed them?
I’ve informed everything
and brought them here.
I’m feeling sleepy,
going to take rest.
- You go.
- Okay.
Close the gate and leave.
What?
Do you like the house?
All your required things
will reach you tomorrow morning.
This is the safest place.
No one can easily identify this place
and come here.
Don’t think and worry about anything.
Be happy.
Enjoy.
Malar!
Kathir!
Hey.
If I tell you one thing,
you shouldn’t feel bad.
Kathir!
If a girl elopes from a house,
they say the girl is strayed.
Her name will never change till
she proves herself by living happily.
You go for a job
and earn money.
When we both return to our village,
people should respect us by looking at our stature.
After achieving,
we can have this…
Sorry, Kathir.
Are you angry?
Kathir!
Okay.
Sir.
Tell me.
-Where have you sent the boy and girl?
- Sir, I didn’t send them.
- Tell me.
- Sir, I don’t know.
Why did you brought up the girl
so chubby?
To mesmerize the rich guys like us, right?
- Sir, not like that.
- How much money do you need?
- Sir, don’t speak bad.
- Tell me, where they’re?
- I’ll give you the money.
- Sir, I didn’t bring up my daughter immoral.
Tell me.
Sir, you’ve mistaken.
- I’ll kill you.
Hey!
- Sir.
Hey, take off your legs.
Take off your legs.
How dare each one of you
is coming home and hitting him?
If your son has eloped with her,
either leave them or kill them.
Instead coming and creating ruckus here,
is not right.
Leave now.
- Hey, if it’s your daughter, will you tell this?
Be quite, all these ruckus
is because of you.
If you had nurtured your daughter perfectly,
will anyone come and question us?
Hey, get lost from here.
If I give a signal,
the entire colony will come and kill you.
Brother, they might come.
Come, let’s go.
Or else I’ll lodge complaint
in the police station.
Don’t stand here, leave now.
Get up.
Hey, you get up.
Hereafter if you favour her,
I’ll hit you to death.
Then you have to go,
where you first wife has left.
Being second wife to you, rather I should’ve died.
My children are suffering.
Dude, I don’t know what will you do.
You kill her and bring back my son.
This is a bad name for our ancestry.
We should get rid from the root.
Tell me.
I’ll tell you.
They have gone to Chennai.
Where in Chennai?
At Choolaimedu.
- I don’t know anything more.
- Choolaimedu!
Hey, let’s start to Chennai.
Kathir!
How long to knock the door!
Hey, this is not like your village.
The water container has arrived,
go and fetch the water.
Use well water only for household.
Hey, you bath and do washing near the well
and throw covers inside the well.
Don’t know what to say about you all!
Hey!
Wow, Yamaha RX 135!
Hey, Kathir!
Come on.
Not leaving a car or bike.
Looks like the crowd in “Alagar” river!
How to fetch water in this crowd?
Sister, I’ll take one pot of water.
Malar!
- Stop.
- Go away.
You fetch the water.
Hey, are you calling him for support?
We’re all waiting for one pot water only.
- Sister, I've come from outstation.
So, you've come from outstation
to fetch water?
I'm residing in this street.
(Indistinct chatters)
Hey, no!
You made me to get caught
and laughing now?
I said, don't hit me.
You said, you'll take care of
me like a queen.
Now, you let me to fetch water.
You're also the same
like any other male.
Fraud.
Henceforth, you must go to bring water.
I'll not come.
Won't you switch on the motor, on time?
- Who's turn is this week?
- It's mine, Anbu.
- Then, you'd have switched it on.
- I had work the whole night.
Go and switch on the motor.
Shantha, why didn't you like Ramu?
Shanta, why didn't you like Balu?
Ramu and Balu is confusing.
Today, I should astonish him
by my acting.
Dude!
- I'm coming.
- Dude!
Welcome, uncle.
Dude, I've got a furious chance
to showcase my acting.
You say like a starving dog
got a dosa.
I was called for an audition
for a new film.
Known I'm addicted to lentil snacks,
you're going to pressurise me...
...and prove your talent, isn't it?
God bless you.
Arya is the hero.
It's a friend character.
- Friend of Arya's father?
- No, a friend to Arya.
To Arya?
Shall I act?
Jaishankar, sir!
What's lacking in my friend?
Doesn't he have knowledge,
charm, tone and good thoughts?
Just wait, don't be panic.
You might pop up in emotion.
Just wait,
Dude, is Arya acting in
any period film, recently?
No, it's a college story.
- College film?
- I'm studying in college with Arya.
Arya is in love with Shantha.
I'm helping him in his love.
Shantha has become old, Samantha was also
outdated and she left to Andhra.
You're shouting as 'Shantha' now.
Hey, oldey!
First, get rid of these
old style costumes and accessories.
Let's see whether you can
do better in acting.
If I wear all these, people respect
me, 'the Square star'.
Who gave you the title, 'Square star'?
It's me.
Who is giving to whom?
Everyone is titling themselves.
So, I preferred this title myself.
Don't you feel ashame?
If I feel shame,
I can't get an Oscar, dude.
First, go and see your family in Arcot.
Instead, he is going to America
to get an Oscar.
Look here, I'll get two Oscars and
appear before you, who teased my acting.
On that day, we both will
hang and die.
Go.
Do you feel jealous of this film?
Next film is with Director Shankar...
- Why do you tease him?
He is pityful.
He has become mad on cinema.
Kathir!
Kathir, get up.
Mom, let me sleep.
Where am I?
Malar!
Is it 11 o'clock?
Malar, don't cry.
I'm sorry.
In sleep, I thought I'm in home
and my mother is waking me up...
I'm hungry, Kathir.
I'll get you now.
Just five minutes.
I'll get you.
He bought us lentil snacks and
shown his acting, irritating to the core.
Hey!
Who is he?
Driving like he didn't have RC.
Didn't I tell you, I took a ride with
a couple in love?
- Yes.
- That's him.
Is it him?
Arumugam brother, who is this guy?
He is the new tenant next
to your house.
Brother, it's long time
since I asked for idly.
Take the idlis soon.
- Just wait for five minutes.
- Okay, sir.
- 'Come on, my dear village girl'
- You'll be banged with broomstick.
Brother, two tea.
Two tea.
- Wash the glass well with water.
- He is my neighbour.
He is sitting here.
He looks like a rogue.
Why is he running?
Do you want auto?
- Give me.
- Here it is.
Have you seen him anywhere?
- Hey, I knew him.
- Where did you see him?
He came in my auto
along with a girl.
I dropped them at Burma bazaar.
Where is Burma bazaar?
Do you've Google map, brother?
Burma bazaar.
Where the blue line ends
is Burma bazaar.
- I dropped them there.
- Come, let's go.
I'm from Melur, Madurai.
She is from my neighbouring village.
We both studied in the same college.
We fell in love.
It came to my father's knowledge.
We belong to different caste.
She is from lower caste.
My father didn't like it.
He blazed her along with her family.
It's a great thing, she survived.
I don't know what to do.
That's why, I tied her nuptial knot
in the temple and brought her here.
Who is he who came now?
He is my maternal uncle.
My mother's brother.
They have known this place.
If caught, they will not do
me anything.
But, they will kill that girl.
We can't stay here, anymore.
We will vacate the house and go.
Brother, I spoke with my friend
regarding the job.
Hey, stop blabbering.
If you want to go...
Where will you go?
Did you say only the area
or given the address too?
I told only the area, brother.
That's why, they have come here
in search of you.
You eloped from the hometown
and hiding here.
For what sake, did you call him?
Instead of this life, it's better to...
Don't know who all will
come, searching.
Should I suffer because of you?
Accompanied by a girl,
He is saying to leave...
Why are you afraid?
If they don't find the person
in a area, they won't come here again.
Don't be afraid.
I'll take care.
Will you give me a tea?
There is no milk.
It's our house.
I can have whenever I want.
I'll come often.
Hey!
They won't come, hereafter.
I'll take care.
Be bold.
Take care of her safe.
Shall I leave?
Bye.
Brother, it seems he
will take her.
It'll not work, right?
I've contact with all the
colleges in Tamil Nadu.
Yes.
Whoever elopes with the girl,
I'll get the call, first.
Yes, that's routine.
But, they will come and enjoy
for two days and abandon the girl.
- Then, I'll take over the girl.
- Yes.
- But, he is in deep love on this girl.
- Is it?
That's why, going beyond a week.
He will leave.
Malar.
Get up.
What?
Are you surprised?
I'll give you surprise
every year, like this.
This is a big surprise to me.
My birth date is today
but my birthday is on next month.
Sister, please wait.
- I'll go to ATM.
- Okay, go.
Dude, shall we have a tea?
I'll buy you.
Hey, come on.
Master, two cups of strong tea.
- Two cups of tea.
She is very stingy.
Why is she buying me tea?
Let me see how long it goes.
Dude, your shirt is excellent.
I bought it four years ago
and washed four days ago.
You're the first woman to say
that khaki shirt is looking excellent.
You want to ask me something.
Instead of going around,
ask me straight away.
Saying this and that...
Dude, I saw Anbu at
Saidapet sub- jail, a few times.
The lawyer comes to the auto stand
and takes money from him.
What's his problem?
I was dubious on you.
You look after your job,
don't poke unnecessarily in other things.
If so, I'll bang you.
Do you know how happily
that family lived?
You can't find a person like his father,
wherever you search in this world.
If anyone see the love in his family,
they would feel jealous.
Are you good?
Mani, come on.
Why have you come here?
I went to your house,
sister said you are here.
That's why, I came here.
Manickam, give the invitation to him.
- Take it, brother-in-law.
- Is it your daughter's wedding?
Yes, come along with your family.
You must come two days before.
What are you doing, dude?
I'm studying B.Sc., Agriculture, final year.
- Okay, dude.
- What, Mani?
Names of kin isn't mentioned.
They are staying away from
the family for five years.
Are they staying away or
you kept them away,
...since they aren't rich?
You've kept them away,
that's the fact, right?
Five hundred houses are there
in our village.
Fifty houses belong to our clan.
Though we belong to upper caste,
we are a small clan.
We should be like the goats
in the shed.
If a kid is missed in the shed,
the wolf will kill it.
♪A house is a like a nest of the parrot♪
♪The relationship of two parrots in it ♪
♪Our home with Kith and Kin ♪
♪The next generation is the answer ♪
♪We will be together like a beautiful music ♪
Dad, is it only for mom?
Not for me?
Brother, look at him.
Only after your mother stepped
in the house, our family got fluorished.
Whatever, the first
preference is for her.
♪We will live with love and enjoy♪
♪A house is a like a nest of the parrot ♪
♪The relationship of two parrots in it ♪
♪Our home with Kith and Kin ♪
♪The next generation is the answer♪
♪If there are no relationships ♪
♪If we don't need bonding ♪
♪It's like the sea without waves ♪
♪What if we have tempers? ♪
♪What are our cravings? ♪
♪Our relationships are divine♪
Greetings to all!
- Greetings!
- Welcome!
- Are you all good?
- We are good.
- Take this.
- Thank you.
Parasu, I want to talk with you.
An auspicious occasion is going on,
I wish to talk about an alliance.
Your daughter and my son
is studying in the same college.
Though you were low
in status than me,
...my son likes your daughter.
What to do?
So, you discuss in your home
and tell me a good decision.
I'm happy that you attended
this occasion.
You can leave.
I'm telling you to leave.
- Whom are you talking?
- Hey!
Brother-in-law, he is a MLA.
He is asking for a bride.
Though there is difference in
the caste, it's a wealthy family, right?
Hey!
He is MLA!
His grandfather came to our backyard.
His father came to the entrance
of our house.
He wants to sleep in my house.
Is it enough if he has
money and power?
Shouldn't he have a stature of dignity?
He has come to ask my daughter.
Hey, Uma!
What, brother?
Will you accept your son
to marry my daughter?
Why are you asking this, brother?
Hey, do you like my daughter?
Yes, uncle.
Your wedding is on next auspicious day.
Hey! Stop.
How long to wait?
When my head honcho came
and asked for bride,
...your father has denied him.
We are poor too.
When your father denied him,
Will he give me if I ask?
Already, when a girl went missing
in your clan, your father tortured our guys.
- Better, marry that guy.
- No, I can't live without you.
- I'll die.
- No, Deepa.
We can't live together.
They will not let us to live.
Don't perplex your mind.
We are different.
We can't live together.
Tell me now,
I'll come with you.
- Mom!
- Anbu! Look at your mother!
Since the cloth strangled the neck,
the blood vessels were cut...
...and the brain lost it's functioning.
She is in coma.
- Oh, no!
- No chances of her to recover.
She will be like this till her death.
Sorry.
Oh, no!
Mom!
Come soon, I have work in home.
How if you feel shy for this?
Dad!
Oh, no!
On the eve of engagement of his son,
he married a lower caste girl...
...and was living in Chennai.
If you get shocked just for this!
Still there are many more like this.
Parasuraman has killed his daughter.
- Look at that.
- This case is under investigation.
The people of that area is panicked
on this honour killing.
Stella.
Go for the ride.
You're the first in the order.
I'm not going.
You go.
- Should I go?
- Yes, you go.
Sir, come.
Have it.
- Give me three thousand rupees.
- Already, you have pledged the watch,
And yet to redeem it.
Meanwhile, you’re pledging the ring.
Is it your's?
- Yes.
- Because, many theft jewels are coming.
Don’t mistake me.
- No, sir! It’s mine.
Am I right?
- Yes, true.
- Nothing
Okay.
- What, sir?
- Come, Anbu.
Don’t you know who will bring
theft jewelry?
It’s my duty to ask.
That’s why, I asked.
What, dude?
Brother, I came to pledge the ring.
Is he known to you?
Yes.
I can believe and give him, right?
- Known guy, the guy next door.
- Okay, then fine.
It’s okay, if you say.
Take it, Rs.3000
This month due, I’ll pay
next month after incentive…
Brother, I’ll leave.
Okay.
Kathir!
Where is your ring?
Hey, look here.
New Axe spray has been launched.
- The fragrance is good, right!
- Kathir!
Have you pledged it?
Then what to do?
Have to pay the rent.
Kathir, where is the rice?
Isn't there rice in the bag?
That is!
Hey, I told at the shop.
I think he had missed it.
When you know to buy body spray,
don’t you know to buy rice?
Hey, what you…
I told him, he didn’t pack it.
Okay, you arrange these things.
I’ll go and get it.
The money we had is over.
Now you have pledged the ring,
later you’ll sell.
You will pledge the chain
then you’ll sell.
Then?
I’m getting afraid, Kathir.
Hey, did I say that I’ll not
go for job?
Yesterday, I went to Taj Coromandel.
I went to DLF.
Wherever I go, they are asking for certificates.
We’ve not got that.
What should I do?
Kathir, now too we’re eating
with your father’s money.
Not with your money.
Kathir, I like you very much.
I’m burdening you,
which I can understand.
Kathir, forgive me.
The money what you earn is not important.
The belief that you’re going to job
is enough.
Go to a job.
Go to any job you get.
I’m working in Axis bank.
Getting sufficient salary,
though everything is there.
I’m looking for a bride.
Though the money increases,
my tress is receding.
♪Half of those lives
are hanging in the sky♪
are worth like sandal♪
♪Half of those lives
are hanging in the sky♪
are worth like sandal ♪
♪ The city on the coast of Bay of Bengal
Whoever comes can survive ♪
♪It'll not ask for whereabouts ♪
♪Millions of dreams live
in the breeze of river cooum ♪
Dude, two auditions every month.
- Better teach me to drive auto.
- Come, I’ll teach you.
♪Millions of dreams live
in the breeze of river cooum♪
- Did you find them?
- No, brother-in-law.
I’ll send you a saree, drape it.
I don’t know where to go.
But, I want to travel with you
throughout my life.
Sir, Don’t you understood if I say?
I would’ve told you before
if I liked you.
♪Leaving the Kith and Kin,
a clan is yearning ♪
Sir, it's okay if you don’t treat
the women equally,
But, don’t look at them
in abusing manner.
♪They tie a cloth on the feet
and lay tar on the road♪
♪They drive on the road,
a car worth several crores of rupees♪
♪ The city on the coast of Bay of Bengal♪
♪Whoever comes can survive♪
♪It'll not ask for whereabouts ♪
♪Millions of dreams live
in the breeze of river cooum♪
♪It plays dice rolling you and me♪
♪Millions of dreams live
in the breeze of river cooum♪
Affection is flowing like1500 volts.
I feel the lost happiness
has come back to me.
Hi!
Don’t worry, dude.
Dude, it’s our responsibility to get
you married to his sister.
We solemn the self-
respect wedding for
bridegroom Sadha Thomas
and bride Vaishnavi...
...On behalf of Dravidian movement.
Wishing them, "long live like Tamil".
I’ll not consider you as my sister.
I’ll kill you.
♪Who do we ask
what will happen and when?♪
♪A bud will be craving
to blossom as a flower♪
♪To pinch it, a counterfeit cat
will be waiting aside♪
♪There is no property for us
except our foot and hand♪
♪But there is caste, religion, upper and lower,
there are hundreds of differences inside♪
♪The city on the coast of Bay of Bengal♪
♪Whoever comes can survive♪
- Yesterday, your wife was smashing you.
- Brother!
She will fear if she see me.
♪Millions of dreams live
in the breeze of river cooum♪
There is a small stainless steel glass
in your house, right?
It has fallen down, it seems.
The yelling you get is audible till the street.
♪Millions of dreams live
in the breeze of river cooum♪
♪It plays dice rolling you and me♪
- This month rent.
Brother, I got a job at Taj Coromandel.
- Good, dude.
- Sister, give me two plate idly.
- Sit down.
Give them idly.
Okay, sister.
Hey, petrol price is getting hiked.
- Brother, have it.
- On our way, let’s fill up the petrol.
Hey, dude.
We missed the way and
came to Taj Coromandel.
Hey, here Idly will cost Rs. 2000 to 3000.
- Have to pledge the auto, I guess.
- Brother, don’t tease me.
Brother, eat.
Working at street shop and exaggerating
as if working in Taj Coromandel.
Brother, just leave it.
Hey, you went for interview there,
what happened?
I did the interview well.
But, they rejected me since
I don’t know to speak english.
What nonsense,
you talk in front of me.
You don’t know English?
The teacher in Madurai,
he himself doesn’t know to speak English.
Then, how can I speak?
For that, why are you looking sober?
Buy a quarter everyday and come to me
in the evening for two hours to learn English.
I’ll teach you English.
- Okay.
- Brother, don’t tease me.
You eat now.
Anyway, If I eat here,
It'll upset my stomach.
I’ll come and tease you, tomorrow.
- Brother.
- What, dude?
Tell me, If you know a better job.
Is he Ambani, having ten ships,
seven choppers and nine flights...
...and also having ten petrol stations.
Ask him, he will give you a job.
Hey, will you work in petrol station?
Petrol station!
That’s better than this job.
Okay, I’ll do.
Be ready at tomorrow morning.
Hefty money will be collected
in petrol station.
- Will he be trust worthy?
- Yes, you can trust him.
Brother, he is my neighbour.
Then, it's okay.
Ask him to take up the work.
Okay, brother.
Brother, Check the meter.
Take it.
Eat.
Just a minute.
This is my first salary earned.
I've spent my father’s money a lot.
But, today...
I stood till my legs are hurt,
...shed sweat
and when I got the money,
I felt so happy.
I feel more happier than you.
Eat this.
Cheers!
I'm holding a glass.
- That is...
- I'm having many thoughts.
- Hold this.
- Why? Why?
It's all a free booze.
Don’t know what it is!
My body is like…
Holding on the gun
and filling up the petrol, right?
Feeling pain in hand..
Taking pills is of no use.
Pain will not be relieved.
Hey, trickster!
Do you want to booze?
Hey, not that.
Okay, go.
Really?
Stay in limits.
Only this little.
Is this enough?
Brother, this is very less.
Pour some more.
Very less!
Brother, drinking this is like bite of an ant.
Brother, pour some more.
I only know how I competed with others
and bought the liquor.
- Enough?
- Brother, pour some more.
Hey, if I pour for you more.
Then it will be like a snake bite for me.
- Is that okay?
- No, need.
Add some water and drink.
Brother, it's enough.
I didn't add the water, yet.
Give it to me.
Why is he opening the jug?
Is he going to fill the jug and drink?
- You crook.
- Hey.
Hey!
The intestines may burn.
Drink slowly.
- Is he competing with us?
- Drinking without diluting.
Hey!
Gone?
- He will take over us.
- Hey,
I can't afford to buy alcohol again.
He is drinking heavily.
- Dude!
Brother, why are they bursting crackers?
My father will buy crackers
for two lakhs, every year.
I’m the only son.
I’ll burst the crackers as a single guy.
The whole village will wonder at me.
I'm fond of my father.
For that, if he blaze malar in home...
...it’s wrong, isn't it?
Who is bothered about caste?
Will my caste give me the happiness
like living with Malar?
Malar is very pitiful.
She is also suffering along with me.
It’s our first Diwali, post marriage.
Working in petrol station
for just Rs.500 salary.
I told that I'll take care of her lika a Queen.
It’s not possible, I think.
Very pity.
Wonder, what am I going to do!
Only after watching this businessman,
We remember Diwali.
Do you know, I’m a fan to his dance.
Dude, he is a legend.
Hey, dude!
I bought a dress for Vasanthi's son.
Don’t know in which bag I kept it.
Look in the Orange coloured bag.
It must be there, check it.
It's okay, if it isn't there.
Give me, I'll keep it in the auto,
Enough, it’s getting late.
I’m leaving.
Kathir, what shall I cook for dinner?
Anything is okay.
My husband is sincerely going to work.
Should I not cook what he likes!
- what I like!
You mean, what I like?
What I like?
You didn’t agree to do, what I like.
Are you okay, for today?
Hey, go away.
Always thinking of the same.
Hey, Kathir!
This is our first Diwali,
post marriage, isn't it?
Look here.
This year, we don’t have money.
Next year, let's celebrate grandeur.
But, if you had married
among your relatives...
...They would’ve given money
and jewels to you, right?
You too would’ve been happy.
But, I wouldn’t have got my Malar.
For me, Malar is my happiness.
Shall I leave?
- Hey, Kathir!
- Brother.
Come here.
Brother, tell me.
We’re leaving to our village.
Have it.
- Brother, why?
- Have it.
- I’ll be back in 4 to 5 days.
- Brother, I don’t want.
Hey, have it.
Buy new attires.
Don’t worry about anything
and stay happy.
Hey!
Thank you, brother.
Kathir, Happy Diwali.
Brother, don’t make fun of me.
Use my bike for going to work.
Kathir, don’t drive fast,
drive slowly.
- Okay.
- Hey!
Don’t make fun of me.
Take care.
You enjoy.
Hey, come.
♪I caught fire... ♪
♪And I went into flames ♪
♪If I hug you,
everything will be doused ♪
♪I was roaming like an ant
which tasted honey ♪
♪If you laugh, that's my world ♪
♪My body is filled with the finger prints ♪
♪My mind floats like my weight
has been reduced ♪
♪Slowly... slowly... slowly... ♪
♪I caught fire... ♪
♪And I went into flames ♪
♪If I hug you,
everything will be doused ♪
♪The waves will not end
till the ocean exists ♪
♪I'll not leave you till I live ♪
♪When I get time to be alone ♪
♪My youth which was calm,
awakened when you hugged ♪
♪When you touch, my life trembles ♪
♪Enjoy as I get wet ♪
♪When both hearts are cooling ♪
♪It's the permission granted by god ♪
♪You enjoy it ♪
♪It's the space to die ♪
♪I caught fire... ♪
♪And I went into flames ♪
♪If I hug you,
everything will be doused ♪
♪Let you be known by the fingers too
like known by eyes ♪
♪Let my body know everything
about you like your attires ♪
♪The roof on the broken wall
It's the palace of love ♪
♪The magical brush writhing
to draw me in you ♪
♪Twenty fingers and two hearts
It's a pleasure when twining ♪
♪Even the sweat is elixir,
this is also the grammar of love ♪
♪It's fragrant when having it ♪
♪I caught fire... ♪
♪And I went into flames ♪
♪If I hug you,
everything will be doused ♪
♪I was roaming like an ant
which tasted honey ♪
♪If you laugh, that's my world ♪
♪My body is filled with the finger prints ♪
♪My mind floats like my weight
has been reduced ♪
♪Slowly... slowly... slowly... ♪
♪I caught fire... ♪
♪And I went into flames ♪
♪If I hug you,
everything will be doused ♪
Kathir!
♪I was roaming like an ant
which tasted honey ♪
♪If you laugh, that's my world ♪
- Hey, Kathir!
- Hey.
Kathir!
Driver, better runaway.
Someone call for an ambulance.
Malar!
Hey, move away.
Give way.
Kathir, nothing will happen to you.
Kathir!
Doctor, Kathir!
How is he now?
Has any elders have come?
Oh, no!
I advised him.
(Indistinct voices)
He didn’t listen to
what we said and left.
You departed from us.
Now, it cost him his death.
Get the signature from her.
- Okay, Doctor.
Mam!
Kathir!
Sign in this form.
How is Kathir, now?
Tomorrow, the Chief Doctor will come
and tell you.
Transfer the patient of bed 3 to normal ward.
- Doctor!
Okay, sir.
- Doctor, Kathir!
- Yes.
- Which patient is she asking about?
- Kathir, an accident case, sir.
You mean the accident patient,
who’s skull got opened?
Yes, doctor.
Good improvement.
Don't worry.
But, he needs to be in ICU for observation.
Maybe a week.
He will be fine.
Okay, don’t worry.
Don’t worry.
Doctor has said he will be fine.
It’s been two days since you came here.
Go home, refresh and come.
- I’ll take care of him.
- No, I’ll be here.
It's night duty for me, I’ll take care.
You go.
Mam, Where is Malar house?
- Sir, this house.
- Arumugam!
- Come and see here.
- Sister, what happened?
Mam!
Any problem?
The police has come.
Who is Malar here?
Come out.
- Since the police has arrived, it must be big issue.
- What, sir?
- Mam.
- Any problem?
Sir!
What happened?
You come to the hospital.
Sir!
Hope nothing has happened to Kathir?
Nothing.
You come.
Sister, come this side.
Can you accompany me?
(Mourning song)
- (Mourning song)
- Kathir!
(Mourning song)
- (Mourning song)
- Don't allow her to leave, kill her.
Hey!
(Indistinct voices)
Listen to me,
be calm.
Kathir!
(Indistinct voices)
They have brought Kathir.
(Mourning voices)
I brought you up with utmost affection.
You left us all.
Kathir!
Look at your son.
Our son left us.
Kathir!
Leave me.
I’m going.
Kathir, I’ll also come with you.
- Kathir!
- Hey, you too come.
My son-in-law is asking for
a companion to die along.
Leave me.
Kathir!
You leave from here
or else they will beat you to death.
Listen to me.
Kathir!
Hey, to have relationship with my son,
you brought him here and killed him.
I’ll witness you.
You will be wandering with someone
for the sake of money.
I’ll witness you here itself.
INTERMISSION
Every year, I'll give you
a surprise like this.
Why did you bring her here?
Is this necessary for us?
She asked for a help and I sent you.
Instead, you brought her again.
We are struggling to lead our life.
Do you want to get her
along with us?
She is pityful, dude.
If you'd have seen the incidents
happened there...
...you will not talk like this.
Kathir's relatives would've
beaten her to death.
When looking her face,
I reminded of Kathir.
If I wouldn't have given bike
and money to Kathir,
He would've been alive, I think.
I feel guilty that I'm also
a reason for his death.
I found her parent's contact number
and called them.
Her aunt attended the call.
She said, she is not our daughter.
We disown her and disconnected the call.
How can I leave a girl, abandoned?
That’s why, I brought her.
Are you seeking remedy
for your father's act?
I think it's an unnecessary job,
take care.
Are you seeking remedy
for your father's act?
I'd have died.
I'd have died when Kathir was hurt.
There was a chance of life.
I thought he will come alive
for my sake.
But he deceived me.
I thought of seeing
his face finally and die.
But I couldn't.
We both came to live happily.
His father's words shouldn't come true.
I must live.
My Kathir is with me.
I must live with his memories.
This shouldn't happen to
anyone, brother.
At this young age...
Yes.
- Take the things, outside.
- Okay, brother.
Brother, what about the mat and pillow?
It's a lucky mat.
Take it carefully.
Anand, take it carefully.
Can't you take it safely?
It slipped, brother.
What are you going
to do now, Maari?
I got a call that the guy is dead
and the girl was left alone.
Oh, no!
It was disheartening.
Brother, move away.
I've rented out the house
to many people.
But, such an incident
has never happened.
It's painful.
Somehow, they are related to us.
That's why...
Switch off the TV.
Why?
Switch it off.
Brother, it's we who brought them here.
If anything happens to them,
we will be questioned.
We are responsible.
Why is she like this?
They will all come together.
If they ask the guy is dead,
what about the girl?
So, we have to protect them.
I've seen a house in Ramalinga nagar
near to my house.
I'll send her safely along with
her parents when they come.
Until then, who will take care
of her other than me?
What are you doing, brother?
I'm playing cricket.
Can't you see what I'm doing?
Seems like you're playing
a game with cowries.
Reply to my query.
I made her to stay here.
My relative girl.
Her husband is dead.
Who else is here other than me?
Who is related to whom?
If you're a middleman,
you should do only your job.
Instead, you're vacating the house.
Dude, it's my duty to protect that girl.
Oh, we will take care of everything.
Shut your trap and go.
I'm replying patiently to your queries.
Who are you to question me?
If anything happens to her,
who will answer?
Uncle.
Take your hand.
Everyone is talking philosophy.
As if they are perfect.
Hey, granny!
Won't you shut your mouth?
- Uncle!
- You always suppress me.
You talk like a big cheese.
Is that girl a relative to you?
When you dragged her hand,
she must have come if she is your relative.
Did she come?
Fraudster.
What's this, dude?
You're rocking!
Do you think no one can ask you?
I'll ask you.
Do you think women are cheap?
Will you go with him?
Is he your relative?
Tell me.
I'm asking you.
Will you go with him?
Hey, you go away from here.
Else, I might yell at you.
This is the job I'm doing
for many years.
It seems, you're starting only now.
Let me see, where and how
will you help her to live?
My clan is everywhere.
I'll see to you later.
House owner, yesterday
two policemen came.
Hereafter, guys will come and enjoy.
This house will become a lodge.
And both of you will go to prison
for doing business with women.
Then, these guys will be
the middlemen for this business.
Hey, whom do you call as middlemen?
- Get lost.
- Brother!
- Hey!
- Henceforth, if I see you here...
- Brother, come. Let's go.
We got a customer from
SRT college, Salem.
The girl looks chubby.
Anbu, we can't let this girl
stay here at this stance.
He'd have taken her.
You denied that too.
Anbu, I'm saying strictly.
That girl shouldn't stay here.
If you don't like what I say,
better you too vacate the house.
Don't mistake me, Anbu.
Many families reside here.
I don't know any other way, Anbu.
I'll give you surprise
every year, like this.
You're a big surprise to me.
You wander with someone
for sake of money.
Let's go straight to my sister's house.
Let her stay there for four days.
We will see later.
Okay.
Shankar, you left your wife
and children in your hometown...
...and roaming with a girl here.
Moreover, you want her
to stay in my house.
If your brother-in-law knows,
he will kick me out of the house.
I didn't expect Kamatchi
to talk like this.
Let's try for ladies hostel.
- We have some rules, sir.
Either there should be an ID proof
or certificate.
Else, we need a recommendation
letter from the working place.
Without these, no one will admit.
We are going around with a girl
in an auto at this odd time.
I'm feared.
Hey, the police is coming.
Greetings, sir.
Why are you here now?
That's nothing, sir.
Have to go till airport.
The customer is coming.
That's why, I'm waiting, sir.
Why have you covered the auto?
It's snowy, isn't it?
That's why.
Oh, you've covered the auto
since it might shiver.
We will leave now, sir.
We ride the auto
from this stand, sir.
We will leave as soon as
the customer arrives.
Sir!
- Senthil!
- Sir!
- You go to the station.
- Okay, sir.
Sir!
Raji dear, I got a phone call
from the IG office.
Suddenly, I'm scheduled night shift.
I'll come in the morning.
Okay?
Lock the door.
Be careful.
Sir, she isn't that kind of girl.
Please, sir.
Listen to me, sir.
Is this Royal lodge?
Inspector Paramasivam, speaking.
Is Room no.143 available?
Very lucky room.
No, sir.
Sir...
Along with a girl.
Clean it up.
She isn't the kind of girl you think.
Sir!
No, sir.
Listen to me, sir.
Please, sir.
Sir...
Believe me, sir.
She is pitiful, sir.
Sir...
Take the vehicle.
Sir, I plead you...
Hey, you...
I told you to take the vehicle.
- Hey!
- Sir.
Have you gone too far?
No, sir. I'm nearby.
- Come immediately.
- To the same autostand?
Raji, the programme was cancelled.
I'm coming home.
She seems to be a good girl.
Take care.
Take it, Anbu.
You come this side.
It's dawn.
Sadha is not attending the call.
If someone notice us, it'll be a shame.
Sadha is coming.
When he is coming?
Coming too late and cool.
You...
Hey, do you've sense?
How many times to call you?
Can't you attend the call?
Sorry, I kept the phone and was sloshed.
The house is ready.
Come, let's go.
Dude, take the vehicle.
Dude, follow me.
Where are they rushing at this time?
- Only their children have to study.
- Our children should rear pigs.
Still how long?
The house owner is bit tough.
I'll say whatever I wish.
Don't care.
Come.
Come on.
Uncle, this is the house.
The rent is Rs.3000
- I finalized it for Rs.2500
- Excellent!
Five months rent to be paid
as an advance.
We will pay.
The middleman has to be paid Rs.2500
Isit?
Dude, is it okay?
Let's give.
The middleman is my friend.
I'll get you time.
He will accept.
- Okay.
- I'll talk to him.
- Dude, thank you very much.
- It's okay, dude.
You can't get this kind of house
in this area.
Okay.
Sister!
She looks like an alien
made of airbag.
- Is she the house owner?
- She is the councillor.
She will kick me out,
If knew about me.
- I need to piss.
- Wait.
- Greetings, sister!
Sadha, to whom is the house?
The house is for them, sister.
Don't look like that, sister.
It's love marriage.
It's been two months.
He is with me in the auto stand.
Good guy.
He belongs to my hometown.
You...
Sister, that's nothing.
He doesn't know to drive.
He has no experience,
that's why got hurt.
Look here, dude.
I'm very strict.
I must get the rent by
10th of every month.
Okay, sister.
You must come home by
11 o'clock in the night.
I'll lock the gate
and take away the key.
Then, you've to sleep outside.
Similarly, if any noise emerge upstairs,
I'll throw you along with all the things.
- Is it okay?
- Okay, sister.
What a condition!
Who is he?
Dude, Introduce me.
He is my uncle.
My uncle, sister.
Tell me your contact number.
Why?
To lift you if any problem arises.
Sir, I'll stay back in auto.
You come and pay for the ride.
Hey, dude!
Hey, blue shirt!
Believe me, sister.
Open the door.
I told everything and brought them here.
Get inside.
I think, this place will be safe
as of now.
Many families stay here.
You talk with the children.
Move along, casually.
If possible, try to forget everything.
Call me immediately,
whatever you need.
I'm leaving.
Leave this house,
else you will be spared.
Drunkard, how hard are
you hitting me?
I'll hit you like this
if you don't give me money.
Get lost by falling
in pond or lake.
Why should I die?
You go and die.
Hey, I'm telling you, right?
Some people die but you aren't.
Hey, what's the noise there?
You go and die.
Won't you suppress?
- Sister, look at him.
- Get in.
I said get in.
I'll be peaceful only if he dies.
This has become routine for you.
He is hitting me, everyday.
Open the door.
Hey, moustache!
The onions are looking small.
All onions will look small
if it's in your hands.
- Sister!
- What?
You told me to deliver
the water can.
I'm knocking the door for long time
but no one is opening.
Open the door.
Sister, I'll keep the water can out,
I'll come and take it in the evening.
Dear, open the door.
Open the door.
I'm knocking the door.
I'm calling you.
Eat.
You...
I said, eat it.
Dude, on TV programme today,
It's predicted for my sign
that I'll be out of trouble.
So, I'm going to be happy
like a new born baby.
- Hello!
- Hey, fraudsters!
Where are you all?
How dare you cheat me?
You should be here in ten minutes.
Come on.
'The flowers are blossoming
for my sake'
Who is on the phone?
The house owner.
Her face is changing
like an angry potato.
Wonder, what will happen.
Hey, you leave.
Who is she to you?
She is crying without eating.
What's your story?
Say something and manage her.
Sister!
Her aunt is dead.
She thinks of her and crying.
Sister!
I'll tell you the truth.
- What are you going to say?
- Hey!
We are different people.
She is a lower caste girl.
We fell in love
when studying in college.
My father didn't like it.
He tried to blaze her in their home.
Since we have no other way,
we both eloped.
It's okay if whatever happens to me.
But, nothing should hurt her.
So?
Will you abandon her?
No, sister.
Still our clan is searching for us.
If they see us together,
they will lynch us.
Does caste still matters?
I too had an inter-caste marriage.
Who is that generous person!
Hey!
Not that, I just tried to say
that you've a generous mind.
It's true.
Who will come?
No one can come here.
I'll take care.
Do you know who I am, right?
Azaghu Rani.(Beautiful queen)
The councillor of this town.
You must stay here only.
This is my fort.
Let me see, who is coming here.
Get inside.
Go.
Hey, why are you standing?
You too get inside.
Then, let me go.
You stay back.
I need to talk with you.
Where are you driving the auto?
At the stand.
Which stand?
At auto stand.
Where is your auto stand?
♪This is the song to my rhythm and poetry ♪
♪Yeah... ♪
♪Singing to my rhythm... ♪
♪This is the song to my rhythm and poetry ♪
♪The deer has trapped ♪
♪The bull fight with the veena ♪
Where are you?
Come home, immediately.
I'm coming, sister.
What happened, sister?
Nothing is in home.
How will you lead a life?
I'll give a day time.
All things must be in home.
Go out.
Okay, sister.
♪Turn away... ♪
Musical line from the film,
"Velipadinte Pusthakam"
Nothing is here.
He said he will take only two things.
You traitor!
I've seen a hero becoming
a billionaire in a song.
But, he made me like a hero
acting in *** film.
At least, he left this
since it doesn't fit him.
♪ This is the song to my rhythm and poetry♪
-♪ Yeah...♪
Haven't you left yet?
I've got all the things.
You must have that fear.
♪ The deer has trapped
The bull fight with the veena♪
♪ If you want to have a house
Wrestle with an elephant♪
Where are you?
Come Immediately
♪ Whatever happened is happened ♪
♪ Whatever lost is lost
Turn away... ♪
♪ This is the song to my rhythm and poetry♪
-♪ Yeah...♪
Where are you?
-I'm coming, sister.
♪Singing to my rhythm...♪
♪ This is the song to my rhythm and poetry♪
-♪ Yeah...♪
Where are you?
♪ Singing to my rhythm...♪
♪ This is the song to my rhythm and poetry♪
-♪ Yeah...♪
♪ Singing to my rhythm...♪
Who is at home?
What?
Who are you?
Whom do you want?
Malar...
It's been a week since we moved here.
I don't know who she is.
Better, enquire someone else.
Dude, you won't leave a job
without completing it.
How did you let her go
without killing?
I'll leave this place only
after killing her.
I was very afraid that the job
will be issued based on the marks...
but they have given
based on experience.
Get on, come.
Sister told that you've
come in search of job.
Kathir's uncle has gone to
the old house in search of you.
So, don't go anywhere
for a few days.
Ask me if you want anything.
I'm coming near the auto stand.
Come and pick me up.
Hey, where did you go?
Where will I go?
I went for a ride.
- Hey, stop.
- What?
I'm waiting for you since morning.
For me?
Yes.
Didn't you get any ride?
I got the ride but I didn't go.
Aren't you well?
Why? I'm good.
Shall we both have tea?
Tea for me?
You seem to be different, today.
No.
Do you need money?
Get lost.
Wonder, she feels shy.
An information to you..
Hey, crazy.
This doesn't suit you.
- I'm watching you, for few days...
- Hi!
He has come.
You leave.
- Be seated.
- Hey, wait.
I'll come.
Sister!
Anbu, come immediately
to the Shrusti hospital.
What happened, sister?
- Sister, what happened?
- Anbu, you've become a father.
Oh, gosh! My gold!
I know, that's the luck of my house.
Everyone will give birth
to a baby boy.
Okay, Malar is inside.
I'll pay the bill and come.
You go and see her.
Nurse...
You have to take utmost care
of her at this time.
Sir, sign where it is mentioned
as 'husband'.
Sign it.
What are you thinking?
- Anbu, buy all the tablets immediately.
- Okay, sister.
Doctor has told to take
all the tablets from today.
Malar, you need not cook today.
Take rest.
I'll bring you food.
If the drainage is blocked,
will I come and clear it?
I've sent men.
They will come.
- I've to tell you...
- Don't tell anything.
Please, don't tell anything.
Don't want this baby.
Abort it.
You too have a life.
Don't say anything like this.
I was afraid what my life would be
without kathir.
Now, Kathir is with me.
I troubled you more.
Just few days, then my child...
We will go somewhere
and lead a life.
I've more respect on you.
Have you seen?
Serve me too.
Take it without dancing.
Cheers!
Take it.
- You have, dude.
- I told you to have it.
You have it.
If you don't booze, else I will.
Cheers!
Let's have fun.
Tell me, sister.
I'll come, sister.
Okay, sister.
Dude, I'm going home.
Finish the game and go.
You carry on.
Hey, stop.
What?
You're going since someone called.
Take it.
- You have it.
- I don't want, uncle.
Go.
Why are we boozing?
When I knew she is in a problem,
I sent you along with her for protection.
I'm a goof.
For that sake, will you go
around her always?
Hey, don't talk rubbish
before the guys.
What, uncle?
Nothing, it's our family matter.
I'll take care. You go.
We have lot of problems in our family.
You don't have time for that, right?
How happy we all were.
Idiot, he came...
He is dead now.
You have a life.
You must live it.
It's shameful.
You're close with that girl.
What's the relationship between
you both?
Tell me.
Don't know.
You asked you want Kathir, isn't it?
♪ A cloud is drizzling in my heart ♪
♪A desire has blossomed in me,
what will happen, henceforth? ♪
♪Like a merry-go-round,
my heart fights around♪
♪ A cloud is drizzling in my heart ♪
- Anbu
- Sister.
Here is the fish gravy.
You eat it.
- Okay, sister.
- Tell her to eat too.
Who is that in the photo?
My brother.
Where is he?
Abroad.
Okay, you eat.
Don't forget.
Malar, you too eat.
How many times to tell you
not to keep hot water at the entrance?
Hey, be careful.
How many times
will you puke a day?
How will you be healthy?
- It'll be alright.
- What happened, sister?
She is puking all the time.
You can't take care of her
and I too can't.
Better, ask her parents to come here.
Only your father is a problem
not her parents, right?
Tell them to come.
It'll be alright.
Hey, father is ready.
He thinks of himself as
dance master Prabhu Deva.
Won't you sit without shaking your legs?
- Don't shake.
- Where did I shake?
- It is shaking on it's own.
- You're sitting before an elephant.
Be careful.
I found out who you are.
Oh, no!
So, it's confirmed
she is going to thump me.
You've proved that you're a good father..
When you knew that your
daughter is pregnant
you came to see her
without any ego.
That's where you proved
that you're a good father.
I've become a grandfather!
Dude, I've become a grandfather.
Hey, you are a grandfather, already.
Why are you over reacting?
Be quiet.
I too had love marriage.
But, I'm not gifted enough.
When I was pregnant,
my father didn't even visit me once.
Would have you been pregnant
for about 20 years?
- Don't you stay quiet?
- Be calm.
Hey, what are you performing?
Look at that performance.
She is giving variety of emotions,
learn from her.
It's okay.
- You stay with her till her delivery.
- Okay.
Sister, he can't stay here.
He is very busy.
If he goes today morning at 6,
He will be back tomorrow morning
at the same time.
- Immediately, he will leave again to job.
- Malar!
Your father has come.
Cook tasty food.
Okay, I'll go to the Corporation office.
I didn't get a father like this.
- Hey, Aadhar faced!
- Why are you hitting me?
When she asks you
to stay for six months...
...you too nod your head
for sake of food.
Don't you have sense?
Leave it.
She was astonished by my performance.
He has acted in the climax of
Raja Harishchandra drama...
...for her to get astonished.
Get lost...
She is a goof who believed
your performance.
You are a dolt.
That means?
You mean to say as Hollywood artist.
Definitely, he is a goof.
♪ Glittering in the fire♪
♪ I'm floating like a dry
leaf in the waves♪
♪ I'm the poem which lost the grammar♪
♪ It's the raga starting with the last word
of the song that ends. ♪
♪ The cloud drizzles in my heart ♪
♪ A desire has blossomed in me,
what will happen, henceforth? ♪
Don't cry, Fathima.
Nothing.
Be careful.
She is very much afraid.
Please, talk to her.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
Think of your newborn.
You'll get rid of all the fear.
♪ Shall I melt down?♪
You sleep on cot.
The floor is too cold.
♪ The wound the past gave me
is still with me...♪
♪ What's the spring calling for?♪
♪ My heart will not bear ♪
♪ Where in this world is the river
and waterfall which climbs the mountain? ♪
Dad, why have you come
with a fish?
Dad!
I went for an audition.
I saw this fish on the way.
Since you're pregnant
and you cook well too.
In order to taste your cooking,
I bought this.
Do you like acting very much?
It's forty years since I came to Chennai
from my native.
In these years, I went to my native
just four times.
Once, for my wedding.
I came to Chennai the next day
to attend an audition.
Later, I went to attend my first night
fixed on an auspicious day.
Later, when my daughter was born.
Then, I went for her wedding.
Those who came along with me
have become superstars.
Unless I become a star like them,
I'll not leave from here.
I swear!
If only worries are life,
the earth won't bear...
It's the film, "Thanga pathakam"
acted by Sivaji Ganesan.
I attended the audition
for this film too.
Srikanth has acted in that film.
That character has to be
played by me.
The relationship is a cuff...
Dear!
Already came once,
I was alright, then.
I'll bring you fresh food.
Uncle!
I'm calling you.
What happened, uncle?
Son-in-law, I was awaiting all these days
to act in films.
Today, I've played a good character
A father character.
Daughter is getting fits.
I panicked and I tried to save her.
I'm the father who never lived
with a family.
I didn't know what to do.
Without any movement,
I was staring at her.
She was blabbering in pain as, "mom".
Applauds in theatre.
It's enough of my acting.
I'll go to my native.
I'm going to live with
my wife and children.
I don't want this cinema.
Dad!
Dear, I think it'll be good
if dad stays with you at this time.
He takes care of me like a father.
You go.
She tells that
you are like her father.
Take care of my daughter well.
♪ The cloud drizzles in my heart♪
♪ A desire has blossomed in me,
what will happen, henceforth? ♪
♪ My mind is spinning like
merry-go-round ♪
- Anbu, come here.
- I'm coming, sister.
What are you doing there,
instead of sitting with your wife?
- Be seated.
- Sister!
♪ A desire has blossomed in me,
what will happen, henceforth? ♪
Malar!
Kathir!
Kathir?
What happened, Kathir?
Where did you go,
leaving me alone?
Look at me, Kathir.
Look at our child.
Look, he is hitting me.
Look at me, Kathir.
- Look at our child, Kathir.
- You're good.
No, Kathir.
Dear, you're good.
- Why are you speaking like this, Kathir?
No, Kathir.
- Anbu is taking good care of you.
The life you lead now is right.
Remain the same.
That's good for you.
I'm leaving.
- Don't go, Kathir.
- Kathir, don't leave me and go.
I'm living for your sake.
Don't leave me and go, Kathir.
Kathir, don't go.
Kathir!
Kathir came in my dream.
He said, you're taking good care.
He said the life I lead now, is right.
You have a life.
I don't want to ruin it.
I'll leave.
You're too generous and good.
Forgive me.
'Mortuary'
You will wander with someone
for sake of money...
My son-in-law is asking for a
companion to die along, come on...
Hey, I told you on that day,
you'll come to streets for sake of money.
Have you come?
No...
I know.
No, leave me.
Leave me.
No...
Why did you do this?
I can't say that you left
without trusting me.
Even when you didn't know about me
you came along with me.
What's your confusion now?
You say you want Kathir,
He is my brother.
The relationship whom I lost.
I too want to see him.
Until something good happens
to you, I'll be with you.
I'll be fine.
I'll get a good life.
Look here, according to me
I'm just a watchman to this house.
That's all.
Don't get confused, be happy.
That's good for you and the child.
This is the safest place for you.
Please, understand.
Welcome, sir.
Greetings!
Coming 15th is my wedding with Stella.
I'm inviting you all
with this single invitation.
Alex, sir.
- Everyone should attend, definitely.
Greetings, sir.
The invitation seems to be small.
Will the feast be grand, at least?
Don't worry, buffet is arranged.
You can eat as you wish.
Is it buffet?
No worries, then.
We will come two days before
and eat well.
You're most welcome.
Washing the vessels is the duty
of the maids.
You will come, isn't it?
You don't worry about anything.
Tell us, whatever help you need.
- Sure.
You're great, sir.
You made Stella to fall for you
taking ride in her vehicle.
Where is this Church?
- Okay, let's go.
- Don't you know this?
If you go in the opposite lane
to Nagesh park, a CSI Church is there.
- That's the Church.
- Sir, will there be drinks?
- Bye.
- Be seated.
- Kumar's wedding is also on the same date, right?
- Let's take care of it.
Sir, is there alcohol?
Shall we go?
- I'm leaving.
- Sir, don't forget the alcohol.
- Definitely.
- Bye.
He seems to be a good guy.
- Sister.
- Brother!
Mother's health is critical.
The doctor is saying something.
Bring dad.
I'm very much feared.
Before something happens to her,
let her see dad, once.
Mother's pulse rate is going down.
Hope you understand.
Try to come soon.
Dinesh, where are you?
I'm at Gummidipoondi.
It'll take two hours to come.
- Is it?
- Uncle has come out on parole.
We have to go to native.
Come soon.
Will you come to Anbu's house, then?
- Okay, I'll come home.
- Okay, bye.
- Bala sir, got the parole?
- Yes, got parole.
I'm leaving.
Hope you know the parole rules.
It's given for 30 days on conditions.
So, ask him to sign at the local station
everyday at 10 o'clock.
Okay, sir.
If not signed in the morning,
the parole will be cancelled.
- Okay?
- Okay, sir.
Okay, take care.
- Call me, if you need anything.
- Okay, sir.
Let's go.
Sister!
Brother!
I'm bringing dad.
Coming by Dinesh car.
Will reach in the morning.
Don’t cry.
Give the phone to dad.
- Dear!
- Dad!
Dad!
Give the phone to mother.
Mom, speak to dad.
Dhanam!
Come on, dad.
This is the house, dad.
Be seated.
Stella, tell me.
Do you remember,
today is my wedding.
My friend's wife.
You will come for wedding, isn't it?
- Yes, we are leaving.
- What about him?
We both are coming.
She will be here
till the baby is born.
Dude!
Stella's wedding today.
It's getting late.
Okay, let's go.
Dad, my friend's wedding today.
I'll go and come back.
The car will arrive late.
You take bath and get ready,
let's go.
We will be back, uncle.
Prepare food for dad.
We are going to our native today.
I've told everything to sister.
She will take care.
♪The garden of my God ♪
♪I blossomed as a flower,
that's enough for me ♪
♪His foot, is my bible ♪
♪I'll praise him everyday, henceforth ♪
♪Lord Jesus, your glory is enough, ♪
♪I'll win the world ♪
♪Your word is my life, ♪
♪My good saviour ♪
♪Crucified lord! ♪
♪ The wounds are your foot ♪
♪ You will live where sorrows exist ♪
♪ Shine upon me with glory ♪
♪ Oh, my lord! ♪
♪ My lord who redeems from my sins ♪
♪ You know my pain ♪
Both the witnesses
come to the stage.
- Yes, father.
- I'm her brother.
The first gift must be our's.
Come on.
Where is Alex?
You traitor, you got engaged with Alex
and married to someone else ?
Don't tease me.
Sorry, brother!
Can't identify you with the wig.
- Be quiet.
Stella, you're rocking by
covering his bald head with wig.
Come, let's take a selfie.
♪His foot, is my bible ♪
Shall we leave?
I thought you will not come.
♪I'll praise him everyday, henceforth ♪
♪Lord Jesus, your glory is enough, ♪
♪I'll win the world ♪
♪Your word is my life, ♪
♪My good saviour ♪
♪Crucified lord! ♪
She is struggled a lot.
Let her be happy.
Dinesh has come.
Let's leave if dad is ready.
Hey, look there.
Dude, they are still searching.
You can't find Malar, anymore.
Dinesh, you said it'll take
two hours but came early.
Just stop the routine of giving
a month's rent for three months.
Else, vacate the house.
- I'll give on time, sister.
- Go...
Oh, no!
My dear Malar!
What will I do?
Malar!
What will I do, my dear?
This has happened.
I did a mistake.
I've become the reason
for your death.
Anbu, I didn't expect your father
would be a murderer.
Just now Malar said,
Anbu's father has come.
I felt happy.
Though Anbu married a lower caste girl,
you've come to see her...
...when you knew she is pregnant.
He stood like a dumb person
when I was speaking.
He kept everything in mind
and killed her like this.
A murderer!
Malar!
He had killed the mother
and the child, together.
Will he be forgiven?
Hey!
He takes care of me like a father.
This is the safest place for you.
What's this?
Why did you do like this, father?
Poor girl she is.
Didn't your casteism obdurate yet?
"Honour killings" often takes place
in the villages...
...but this murder which happened
in Chennai had caused a great chaos.
The public at Aminjikarai
is in a state of fear.
Regarding this murder,
at the spot of the incident...
'Caste will kill man!'
'Religion makes man a beast!
- Thanthai Periyar.'