Germany
European Championship
starts.
Turkish boxer Serhan vs
champion Alex Muller.
Serhan Kebabcilar is the new
candidate of golden belt.
Alexander Muller won golden
belt one month ago...
After the match
with Maurizio Martino.
Turkey
This is an important day
for turkish boxing.
Serhan grew up in Germany
and he is boxing for us now.
Use your left... damn!
Don't forget to use it!
Two boxers began
to close up at the moment.
- This is a hard match.
- Don't forget your left!
Muller got a fist
but couldn't take point fists.
And now this is Muller's time.
- Two boxers are relaxing now.
- Always use your left.
This is black panther Muller,
on the other side Turkish boxer Serhan.
First round is up. Boxers are
taking tips for the second round.
Second round started.
Boxers are trying each other
for points.
Muller seems ambitious.
Serhan giving fists
from left and right.
Serhan got an important fist now.
They are fighting for golden belt.
They are still trying each other.
All fists from Turkish boxer.
- Faster, harder.
- These are mortal fists.
Two boxers in a life match.
Serhan got German now,
come on Serhan.
Come on, great!
Come on.
Take him from two sides!
Serhan almost fell him down.
And German is on the ground.
Thank god.
Referee counting for Muller.
Three... four... five...
Seven... eight... nine...
- Knockout!
- Serhan is the champion.
Golden belt goes to Serdar.
Champion is
the Turkish boxer Serhan.
My dear son.
Nice news. You can
win this turkish, Maurizio.
I'm fit, after a couple of matches
I'll be the new champion.
And a Turkish can't be a champion
in Europe.
First round starts.
Italian Martino vs
Joe Jackson from US.
They are boxing for
European Championship.
And winner will box with
champion Serhan.
Black boxer using his long arms.
And Martino knows him.
Martino prefers closing up
and giving fists.
Martino tries to get rival's guard.
And he hits the American.
One... two... three...
four...
Five... six... seven...
eight... nine... knockout!
And the winner is the Italian Martino.
Thanks for reporting.
May I shoot some pics more?
We have to shoot champion
with golden belt.
Is it easy for you?
So if there is a new match?
If there is somebody
I'm ready.
Incoming of the match is
420.000 Deutsche Mark.
Please sign it.
And it's the net after taxes.
Have a nice day.
I'm a legman, as Serhan's father,
you have contribute?
I don't speak without money.
You got a wealth.
Germany gave luck to us.
There is no poverty anymore,
my son.
You are the champion,
we are the rich.
You have best contribution
for my championship.
Son, you have talent.
You have fist, you have heart.
And now the whole world
knows you, son.
New matches for golden belt
will come with more money.
These are the best days our lives.
And my mother? My brothers?
Are they happy, dad?
Do they have money?
Do they have peace?
Don't think silly.
We send them some money,
that's all.
Money is happiness.
I want to get back, dad.
Speak with him.
You are his trainer.
You are so hard.
You have to be easy
and compassionate.
He has to fight.
For money, for wealth!
We came here like animals,
going out from cage.
We forgot our humanity,
our identity, our land.
Germans only saw us
like machines.
In fabrics, in laundries,
in mines...
We got in all shits that
never get by kind Germans.
They made prisoners us
for money.
They said "money is
master of the world."
They took us away from
our religion, our land.
Isn't it?
Don't you answer?
When we have enough money
we'll be back.
I won't be a hard worker
in my country!
You fool! Stupid!
You can't work clear!
Take it up!
Come on.
- Don't you see? It's heavy.
- Look at your own work!
If you make it again
I'll kick you out!
Don't try it again bastard!
Wanna try?
Come on, you think a man yourself?
Champion's brother.
Come on!
Come on you bastard!
God! The chain!
Run like hell!
Hook it, come on,
give him a rope!
Hook it. We'll die.
Help, my god, help!
Give him the hook!
Are you ok, Serdar?
I'm ok.
Let him go.
Look up your works.
You lazies!
Behave them like a human!
What the hell is this?
Tank felt down on us
and Serdar saved us.
He wounded and chief
doesn't let us to help him.
Grouches again. Look chief,
if you make it again...
But work stopped, sir.
He never knows the wealth
of people's life.
'Cause he is not human!
Ok, stop. If you make it again
I'll discharge you.
- Are you ok?
- I'm fine, sir.
Ok, you are free
till tomorrow.
Serdar is a strong guy
and has a golden heart.
Shut up! Work!
Hurry up!
- Oh, dad!
- My daughter.
What happened?
Are you wounded?
Unimportant accident.
Serdar is my college hood friend dad.
We couldn't meet for years.
- 'Cause he...
- I left school, sir.
Cause I have to look up
my mother and my brother.
Your dad?
He went to Germany
with my brother 15 years ago.
His brother is a boxer who was champion
on the match yesterday.
I think Serdar
isn't a usual boy too.
He saved his friends today,
everybody loves him there.
I think his brother is the same.
We're proud of him as Turkish.
They can't share this happiness,
Serdar has to work hard.
I'm sorry, Serdar.
If you need anything
I'll be glad to help you.
I don't need anything, sir.
I have to go now.
Serdar, you misunderstood my dad.
Look son, I was a sportsman.
I grew up without family too.
But I'm not you.
You told him, dad.
No, he is a honor person.
I wish I had a son like that.
Here you are, sir.
- And you?
- Thanks.
Cheers.
For champion.
He is not champion.
I'm the champion,
I'm offering you a match.
We will arrange the date.
You can't behave like that.
You old man, get out.
What the hell are you saying?
Let me!
You fuck...
They have to make a match
urgently.
Come on, boxer.
Come on, you champion.
You are a coward. You're going
to your country because of me!
- If it needs I come there too.
- Wait for me, Italian.
When I'm back
I'll change your face.
Don't worry, fuck face!
I'm waiting for you too.
Lick my balls, Italian!
Fuck up, you champion!
- I'll show you!
- You'll creep, Italian.
- Let's speak with his father.
- Good idea.
- Cheers.
- For my championship, honey.
I don't know how we'd arrange
this match in Turkey.
Don't worry, Osman.
We'll arrange it.
Saloon is important,
all TV channels will be there.
We'll get million dollars
with all bets.
If the match is in Turkey
you'll have a wealth.
- And match will be like our way.
- Ok, arrange it in Turkey.
- Thanks.
- Martino!
Match is ok,
it'll be in Turkey.
We'll go next week.
- I'm the champion.
- For champion.
Come here, sweetheart.
They are coming, mom.
My father, my brother are coming.
They'll come here, mother?
I'll see my brother, my dad.
- I miss them.
- I miss them too, my son.
You are my one arm
and Serhan is my other arm.
- But your dad...
- He is our heart, mom.
I hope everything begin new.
Serdar?
- Hi.
Wanna come?
Where?
Don't you like my car?
Come on girl, find anybody
to get in your car.
Huh... what a rude boy.
If I find you again...
I'm a stupid girl.
You're right,
for ex I'm a young too.
You?
I'm on your service, miss.
I'm a playboy.
Come on, you pineapple.
Pineapple?
You are happy today, Serdar.
You won the lottery?
My dad and brother are coming.
- It's wonderful.
- Thanks.
Hey, champion comes
with a lot of money.
He is the European champion.
And when he is the world champion
he'll be rich like Muhammed Ali.
It's a kind of lottery too.
And you will left work, Serdar, hm?
Money is nothing.
What are you doing?
Come on! Work!
- You are a fool.
- I'll kill you bastard!
Come on!
Chief! Boss' calling you.
I was waiting for you,
please walk slow.
I promised myself
not to call you again.
But I waited for you again.
And I left my car too.
Come on, hurry up.
Let me please.
Let my way sister.
So, new comers?
Let me sit, you are rude.
You're not used
to these vehicles, hm?
You're used to luxury cars,
used to money.
I know you're angry
with my dad.
But he loved you
and you misunderstood him.
Speak low, sister.
Watch your way.
Your voice's like a door bell!
You can't speak to me
like that.
Easy, turn your side.
You like it, huh?
Ok, money.
- One person?
- Yes.
- I don't have money.
- I don't use money.
- What?
Are you a big boss, sister?
You woke up my baby!
Is it my problem?
Take him to sleep again.
You rude!
I know your kind of girls well.
You sat near of nice boy,
you sucker.
I can't put up with your sadness.
I want to excuse you
on behalf of my dad.
But you behaved me so rude.
You could say me clear
"I don't want you."
I tried to close up you
for years.
But you didn't want me.
Please be honest with me.
What did I do to you?
You didn't close up me
for years.
First I thought I was a child...
But when I grew up
I fell in love with you.
I don't have a mother
and my dad only works... he works.
And I came for you.
Maybe you could love me too.
You're crying.
I don't care.
I said you're crying.
I said I don't care!
Please don't cry.
Why?
I don't wanna see it.
I love you!
I love you, darling.
Me too.
- You're welcome, Osman.
- Mr. Osman!
Brother!
You're welcome, my husband.
Your son is there.
- My mom.
- My son.
What a nice scene.
- You honored us, my son.
- You are champion, brother.
Ok, silence!
You saw the champion,
now go away.
Contract boy!
He is foolish like his son.
He became mr. Osman in Germany.
My ass, mr.!
He forgot his old days.
- This is my golden belt.
- I'll be a champion, too.
- Where is Serdar?
- He almost came.
- Tea?
- No.
- You spoke to him?
- This is not the time.
So, I'll say...
- These are for you.
- Thanks.
Look at me, my son.
You'll go to match in Turkey.
With Martino, we arranged.
It's better for us.
This is our country, it's guaranteed.
It depends on you, trainer.
It's an important match.
There will be some big money!
The winner will go
to World Championship.
It's more important than money.
I trust you, my son.
They came.
Thanks.
- Brother!
- My brother!
Welcome, dad.
This is my trainer, mr. Hulusi.
Welcome, sir.
Look at me, Serdar.
This is the golden belt.
You honored us, brother.
You are a lion.
He is a lion
but you are a mouse.
Your brother conquered Europe,
he earns a lot of money.
And you? You're giving
poverty to your mom.
We are a family, dad,
and you are master of it.
Have you ever thought about us
till now?
You insolent!
- How you speak with me..
- Easy.
I cooked something for you.
Do you have a feast banquet?
Come on, let's celebrate today.
Let's go to a luxury place.
- Please let me...
- No, you'll come too.
You silly, don't you know
how to use it?
Unmannerly boy.
It's my fault.
You are coming from cave.
This is not a place for us,
please let us go to home.
Shut up, you asshole.
Please mom, only my dad
knows "manner."
Let's go.
He is right, dad.
You are so rude.
Let's go.
You are false,
this is your family.
Family? You saw they are wild.
I'm only interested in Serhan.
I can't understand my dad.
Aren't we his children?
He passionates only with money.
After years he is still the same.
This is his way.
He is a hard man
but I love him.
We love you too.
It's enough, you drunk too much.
Come on trainer, you funny.
Come on trainer. You are funny.
I'll go to house too,
but with bitches.
You are drunk,
you are saying bullshit.
So this is your problem?
To have fun is my right.
Wanna come with me?
No, I'll go to another place.
So, have some fun!
What a "kind" guy
anyway, never mind.
Come here, ladies.
Come on dance, you nasty.
Play it again!
What the hell is this?
Don't you see?
I'm dancing with bitches.
- Is this a disco?
- Come on, up your ass!
Get out!
What are you saying, you suckers!
- Hey, be careful.
- It's so late.
You are the father of Serdar
but be kind.
What will happen
if I'm not kind?
This is not Germany!
- We'll call the police.
- Police? Call your mom!
Ok, it's enough!
Enough?
- What's that?
- Your dad's quarreling.
Let him go!
He is our dad!
Are you ok, dad?
Get off your dirty hands!
This is my lion. This is my son!
Here you are, sir?
I'll meet with mr. Nevzat.
- He is upstairs, sir.
- I'm his old friend.
Please come in.
Hulusi! My friend, you're welcome.
- Thanks, my friend.
- Where were you?
You're right, I'm here for you.
You're welcome, sir.
It's a pleasure welcoming you here.
This is a nice place,
thanks for your kindness.
It will be a nice journey for us.
I was wondering, Turkey
is a nice country.
You like it, sweetheart?
It's a fantastic place.
I will match here and we'll
have a nice holiday here.
Harder!
You have to be faster!
We came to Turkey
to arrange this match.
Martino must listen to us.
Boxing means money.
And money always earns
by us, by mafia.
We have to arrange it
for bets.
I spoke with Martino.
He won't lose the match.
Hello,
we want to meet you.
Are you legmen?
No, we are fan of you.
Turkish people are so kind.
Sir, would you want to say
something before the match?
Newspapers say golden belt
will be Turkey's again.
Turkish sport-lovers
will see a wonderful match.
And championship case:
2 months ago German Muller...
Got golden belt from me as a deposit.
Golden Belt is mine forever.
To shoot a movie
with winner will be sensational.
It will be a box office movie.
Ok, get ready, we will shoot it
with winner.
- I came here for you.
- You always come for me.
Your life will go like that
by waiting me.
I'll always come exhausted to home.
Will you get used to it?
I can't give you a rich life.
So, please think twice.
I love you Serdar
and it's more important than everything.
You are still a baby
who imagines the dreams.
Please come to us tonight,
my father will be glad too.
I can't, this is
the match day of Serhan.
When I was young
I couldn't win this belt, son.
But you won it
and you have to save it too.
Get this match.
You are fit.
If you hit strong, you'll get it.
Ok, you are ready son.
Come on, time is up,
crowd's waiting for us.
- Good luck, son.
- Thanks, sir.
And the day is today.
This is the most important
boxing match in Turkey.
European Championship
for Golden Belt.
Turkish Serhan Kebabcilar
vs Italian Maurizio Martino.
They are getting ready
for the first round.
And referee calls them into the ring.
Match started.
Martino prefers to stay far...
And Serhan wants to be closer.
They are trying each other.
Martino begins his fists...
And also Serhan replies to him.
Martino began to hit harder.
This is Serhan's hard times.
He's surrounded.
They are more careful now.
Serhan trying to get
to Martino's guard.
Martino is in front of ropes, now...
And he began to reply
harder, now.
Be careful, son.
This is Martino's left.
Now, this is Serhan's time.
Don't close him, Martino.
Faster! Faster, son.
Martino earns some points, now.
Also Serhan earns, too.
And round is up.
They are relaxing now.
Don't get excited, son,
always hear me.
When you saw him ready
give him your left.
Don't close him up, Martino,
you have to stay far.
Always try beneath,
you'll win.
And this is the second round.
Martino entered faster, now.
He earns a lot of points.
Faster! Faster,
even more than a second.
Serhan closing up
but he can't save his own guard.
And Martino begins again.
Serhan can't make anything.
One fist
and another one.
Serhan is a blind mood now.
Referee has to stop the match.
But Martino doesn't stop.
Left and right,
he doesn't stop.
And Serhan felt down.
- Referee counting now.
- One... two... three...
- Four... five...
- Serhan trying to get up.
- But he can't get up.
- Six... seven...
- It seems impossible.
- Eight... nine...
- My brother, Serhan.
- I can't take breath.
Knockout!
Let's go to hospital urgently.
- Champion.
We are sorry,
we lost him.
It seems he got a poison.
We took him in operation
but unfortunately lost him.
He was poisoned?
This is a murder.
I don't wanna believe it, Serdar.
I don't wanna accept
he is dead.
Shut up! Enough!
Enough!
If it's better quarrel me
if it's better cry.
Please don't be sad anymore.
How would I say you don't want me
to my children?
You never saw me
as your wife during these years.
This is not truth?
Are you still accusing me?
What a woman you are,
you poor disher woman.
I went to Germany
because of you.
- And you are using our son...
- I'm so sad, my son is dead.
- You gave me a bad luck.
- But I won't have a bad luck.
It will your destiny,
I'm leaving this home.
We are sorry, Serdar.
- Thank you, bros.
- We wish RIP for him.
Get out, you lazies!
He is dead and that's all,
now work!
Let me go!
Come on, get up!
Get up I said, fight!
He is stronger than his brother.
True, he saved workers last day.
He can take vengeance.
What are you talking about?
His brother was killed,
this is an organized work.
I'm sorry sir, he doesn't have respect
even for dead.
Don't care about it son, come on,
let's speak with you.
It was hard to take it again
but it's mine again, now.
Even if it costed a life
it's mine again.
It was your right, honey,
nobody can't take it from you.
I'll win all matches
to be the world champion.
I'm not afraid to kill!
Somebody wants to meet you, champion.
- Hello.
- We came for an opportunity.
- For what?
- We want to shoot a movie with you.
- Movie? But I'm a boxer.
It'll e easy for you,
we'll pay well.
We only need 3 months
if you accept to stay in Turkey.
Seems nice but my honey will act too.
- Sure.
- Ok, deal.
You'll begin from last point
of your brother Serdar.
But I'm not a sportsman.
I don't know anything about boxing.
We arranged everything, son.
I'll support you.
And don't be sad again,
you can pay it after match.
Therefore you can take
your brother's vengeance.
This is a kind of heritage of him.
You have to be like him,
Serdar, you'll be the best boxer.
Ok, give your hands.
First, you have to be muscular.
Than we'll work on the technique.
Action!
- Angela.
- Martino, sweetheart.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
No break,
you'll sweat.
You have to sweat!
You'll run until you'll be of steel!
Run! Run like hell!
You'll believe this work,
you'll believe in me.
You won't be human anymore!
You won't feel like a human!
When you won't be human anymore,
you'll be ok.
- Rest.
- Ok.
Well...
- We are together tonight?
- Sure, darling.
Now... go!
You don't believe me,
you don't believe in work!
If you won't success
let's leave this work, son.
You must success, Serdar.
What happened?
You were a honored person...
You're not, Serdar.
That I knew?
Are you afraid?
Ok, I'm going to stay alone
with your fear.
Stop, don't leave me alone.
- Believe me. I'll win!
- I love you.
Action.
- You are so beautiful, darling.
- I love you.
- Cheers for love.
It's for you, sweetheart.
It's more important
than the golden belt, for me.
You'll see the golden belt
will be mine forever.
I love you, Martino.
I'll be the world champion.
Stop, congrats, bravo.
I'm the greatest.
Box is the hardest sport,
needs more passion.
Begins with athleticism,
stops with force.
You have to be
a complete sportsman.
You'll work more, son,
there is no other way.
You can't win today,
if you want let's stop.
No, let's continue.
I'll play for my wealth.
Ok, time is up. It's ok for today.
This is an antique
turkish revolver.
Ok, I'll buy it.
Darling, this is your birthday gift.
Congrats, mrs..
Don't use one arm,
use 'em all.
Don't stop,
do it faster.
Now here we are again,
you have only 25 seconds.
You'll be a sport god,
you have to believe it.
It's almost done,
you'll be the greatest Serdar.
You'll be the invincible champion.
Right, right, harder.
You'll hire your left
for the time.
Don't lose your timing.
Bravo, wonderful.
Ok, ok son.
You are ok. Your first rival
will be the American Jackson.
My god, please save my son.
Black thunder
And the match starts with the gong.
Turkish boxer Serdar
vs American boxer Jackson.
Serdar seems relaxed.
Winner will go to
the European Championship.
Two rivals are poised.
American tries to earn points.
But Serdar's careful.
Faster!
And Serdar's beginning
to earn points.
American wants to go beneath
but he got two fists above.
Serdar's working serial.
He hits than far,
hits than far.
Use your left!
And with Serdar's left
American felt down.
- One... two...
- Referee counting.
Four... five...
- He is trying to wake up.
- Seven... eight...
Nine...
- Knockout!
- And the winner is Serdar.
- Turkey!
I won, I don't know
what's the lost.
Ok son, you are ready for the match.
Your new rival is German
Alexander Muller.
Muller came here to win you
then match with Martino.
You have to win, son.
You have to be faster to win, son.
Faster! Faster!
Turn me, hit now. Faster!
Serdar vs Muller now.
Muller seems faster.
- But Serdar's closing up to him.
- Finish him! Finish!
Serdar has a wonderful technique.
Muller trying to resistance...
But it seems impossible.
And Muller felt down.
Come on Martino, close up to girl.
I'm afraid, darling.
- I'm anxious for the last match.
- Don't be afraid, darling.
I love you, Martino.
These are the best days of our lifes.
Stop, cam is going to this side.
Well? You like it, boss?
Serdar's got the Spanish too.
Serdar is black thunder!
I'm going too.
What? Are you going?
You don't have money anymore.
You are now a poor man.
Kook at me, be careful
or I'll slap you.
Come on, why don't you try?
If you don't have money,
you are nothing.
Even you don't have the energy.
Never call me
if you don't have money.
So long... "man."
- We are ready, sir.
- Ok.
This is the European Championship belt.
It's mine, I'll be the world's best too.
Write it as it
to your newspapers.
Movie is ended, thanks folks,
thanks champion.
I thank you too, my friends.
Cheers to everybody.
You came to see me?
We are offering a new match,
Martino.
With whom? Is there anybody
who can make it with me here?
- Serdar.
- Who is he? I don't know him.
He's brother of the dead boxer.
I want 100 millions,
for less it's impossible.
- Ok?
- Your check is ready.
Ok, let me know the date.
We'll let you know.
- So long.
- So long too.
- Turkey gives us luck.
- Cheers for boxing.
- You won't accept this match.
- Why? I'm invincible.
Serdar seems professional too.
He won 4 matches, it's serious.
What a success! I won 34!
Daddy, don't be sad for me.
- Martino can lose this time.
- We can arrange the match for Martino.
He doesn't work for months,
he is not fit anymore.
Look up your work, trainer,
and rest is our work.
Serdar's father is poor now
and we'll earn millions again.
You'll be the world champion, Serdar!
So we are here again, Osman.
Do you wanna leave this poverty?
What will you do?
We'll pay a lot of money
and Serdar won't go to the match.
No,.. no! You will be faster.
It'll be an easy match,
I always trust myself.
You only think about my pay
in America, that's all.
We are with you
but we need guarantee too.
I'm afraid for the match.
I don't wanna lose you.
Don't be pessimistic.
You are the source of my force.
- I'll cry.
- No, don't cry, never.
I'll win this for me, for you,
for my family.
- And vengeance feelings?
- I don't have vengeance feelings.
I only feel for win,
this is a no merciful fight.
After match, there will be
a new life for us.
I believe you sweetheart,
I won't cry.
My god, please save my son.
And this is the biggest match.
"Black thunder" Serdar
vs Maurizio Martino.
This is the day for
Europe's golden belt.
- Are you ready?
- Yes sir.
I'm fit! I will blow him up today.
He will kiss my ass,
nobody can't take my belt.
- Ok son, this is your time.
- I'll win, sir.
- Ok, son.
- I'll do it, sir.
Let us alone, trainer,
I'll speak with Serdar alone.
Listen, don't go to this match.
I lost everything,
I'm lonely.
I'm your father,
understand me?
You are my last hope.
Serhan's dead, I don't wanna lose you too.
Martino is a professional,
you don't have the experience.
He'll kill you too.
You listen to me,
I'm your father.
They won't do any murder again,
I'll take my brother's revenge.
They're playing dirty games
but I'll blast this champion.
I said you won't go to the match!
My son...
Please forgive me.
Money stole everything from me.
I hate myself, go to the match.
Go and win! This is the time for believe,
show it to everybody.
My son, please say one time
you forgive me.
And time is up.
The winner will go
to the world championship.
Turkish boxer Serdar...
And "Italian stallion"
Maurizio Martino.
And round starts with gong.
Martino trying Serdar from far.
And Serdar began to reply.
They are speaking with fists.
Don't close him.
Serdar closing up to Martino.
Martino trying to get Serdar's guard.
Martino using his experience.
Don't close him!
Serdar seems more successful.
Martino staying far
and Serdar trying to catch him.
And Martino's time,
he is working beneath and up.
He earns points
and Serdar trying to save own self.
- Come on, Martino.
- Get him, Martino.
Faster! Faster!
This is a fight!
Serdar is incredible.
Therefore first round is up.
The two boxers are relaxing now.
Watch his right.
He is faster, stay far Martino.
Try to pull him close.
Close up.
And the round starts with the gong.
Boxers seem so exciting and angry.
Martino's right
and Serdar felt down.
Serdar trying to wake up.
Serdar's in a hard position.
And he got up.
Serdar's got a left fist.
Faster, son! Faster!
Martino attacks like a tiger.
Hit! Hit!
And round is up.
You're wounded
but it isn't important.
Continue like that,
hit to his eyebrow.
And round starts with the gong.
Serdar always replying to Martino.
Serdar's left eyebrow is bleeding.
And Martino's nose is bleeding.
These are Martino's serial,
he earns points.
Hit him! Hit!
Serdar's preparing for his last shot.
And Martino felt down.
- Get up, Martino!
- Three... four...
- Five... six... seven...
- Turkey, Turkey!
Eight... nine...
Hit! Hit!
Faster, faster!
Come on son, finish him!
"Brother, save me brother"
"I don't want to die"
Three...
Four...
Five...
Six...
Knockout!
All handshakes for Serdar!
The golden belt goes
to Turkish boxer Serdar.
This is the honor day
of turkish boxing.
Brother, brother!
My father is dying.
Father!
Did you forgive me, son?
I love you, dad.
My father...
You are so strong,
you have a big passion.
I know your sadness, son,
they never back again.
But I'll always be with you, son.
May I call you "father"?
The end