Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
five, four, three, two, one…
Happy New Year!
I love you, baby!
Congratulations, baby! Huh?
- Going to varsity.
- Yes, that's me.
- When did you get the text?
- They've just sent it.
-Let's get out of here.
It might get worse
than it already is.
Guys, he's scared!
Happy!
Mmm-mm!
Huh-uh! Please stop!
-Damn!
Wow! Varsity.
Aunt, I passed!
I got three distinctions!
Can you believe it?
Wow!
Finally, I can get rid
of that school uniform.
Oh! By the way, you need to send a
deposit along with my matric results.
My girl.
Isn't there a cheaper school
Not this again, Aunty.
I told you there is no better school
that offers a Degree in Acting.
Acting again?
But you said if I pass
you going to let me go.
Yes, because I thought you'd realise
that there's no money in acting.
Well, that's what I've chosen.
Then that means we
have to move to plan B.
But you've never told
me about plan B though.
That's because I didn't
think we'd needed it…
but the way you are carrying on
we will definitely need plan B.
You remember that stokvel,
Hope of Glory that fell apart?
Yes.
Well I took all your varsity
savings and invested it there.
I'm leaving.
Aunt, you took my tuition money
and invested it in Hope of Glory!
Who does that!
Kedibone!
I was hoping for a great
return on my investment
so I could give this house a facelift
and also pay for your tuition.
Okay, now how will I go to
university if there's no money?
Are you saying I should
stay at home the whole year?
Am I homebound doing nothing?
I've been working at
Checkers for 16 years.
I spoke with my manager
and he said I should bring your
CV and you can start working.
Me?
Work at Checkers?
If you start now, you'll have a huge
pension fund by the time you retire.
That's not going to happen.
I'm not going to
work at Checkers!
Kedibone!
Stop acting like a spoilt child.
You know the situation.
There is no money. It's gone!
My goodness! Huh-uh!
Really!
Argh! Uh!
You know sometimes I
wish my mom was here.
Coz I wouldn't be going
through all of this.
Like… I just want
to study, baby.
I don't want to be a statistic,
I want to leave the township
and just further my studies.
-Baby.
Listen…
You will go to varsity. Okay?
-Hey?
You seem to forget that I
can make anything happen.
Look… I never want
to see you cry, baby.
Understand?
Just trust me and
all will be fine.
I need this student
loan, please!
- My sister.
- It's a bit too late, hey.
I can't help you.
I know, but I really
need your help…
- I can't afford to take a gap year.
- It's already too late.
I'd kill to have a car
like this, bra. Eish!
- Cool!
There's no jitter
here, do you hear.
Because it's a German machine.
Your dad left you a
good inheritance, hey!
Convertible! Coupe. Woah!
I just wannt study, baby.
You will go to varsity. Okay?
I am totally going to beat you.
There! Take that!
Hey, Mrembula.
What's up, buddy?
Hah! Take that!
Mrembula…
What's up, brother?
I sold my car.
I had to, man.
Kedibone…
varsity…
Mrembula, are you telling
me that you sold your car?
Because of a girl?
Huh?
Mrembula sold the car
that his father gave him?
The whole BMW 325i is gone.
How much did you sell it for?
- Twenty five.
- What!
Twenty five thousand?
Have you lost your mind?
Huh!
You're telling me you sold your
whole inheritance for Kedibone…
for R25,000?
You know what that car is?
That's a classic.
You and Mrembula
are couple goals.
You're my role model.
Themba… sell his car?
- He would never do that for me.
- Bottom line, we're going to varsity.
Yes! First years. First years.
How much do you still need?
Ten thousand…
Okay, listen…
Mrembula said he'd
give me R25,000.
So, I will give you R5,0000
and we will both be short.
Kedi…
- Are you being for real?
- Yes.
Kedi!
Oh…! Kedi!
This is the car I was
telling you about.
We call it Rosary.
Rosary?
Yeah, you know that thing…
Mother Theresa?
Say a short prayer and
it'll get you to work.
You see?
Here's the key.
If you fix it…
you can drive it.
Are we good? Yeah. Thank you.
Sure!
Mrembula bro…
Look at this!
Hey! What's all this?
I'm tired of being friends with guys
who can't think with their heads.
Go to hell!
Can you fix this car or not?
Yeah, the starter just
needs a bit of attention.
Well then stop complaining.
Friends like you
are draining, bro!
From a BMW to this!
Just stop right here.
Right here.
Yoh, Babe! This
feels like a dream.
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
Don't worry about it.
As long as we're happy.
Calm and relaxed… I'm happy.
Yeah but baby, you didn't have
to sell your father's car.
Don't worry about it, baby.
We sold that car
for a good cause.
Look where you are now?
But baby… this one is so old.
-What?
Which car? This
one? This is Rosary.
Give me two months
with this car.
You'll see when I
pull up in here.
-I'll show them flames.
You will even get new friends.
-And besides…
I'm getting a Lamborghini
with your first paycheck.
- With my paycheck?
- Yes.
Thank you.
I love you.
-I'll call you.
Baby…
-You must drive safe.
Love you.
Babe!
My sister relax.
Gents, let's help.
Don't worry. We got this.
-Let's go, king.
Ah!
Let's go.
Where did that lady say we are
supposed to leave the trays?
Um…
I think there where
it says 'Out'.
Right there.
By the conveyor belts?
Yoh, friend!
-It's like a dream.
-Yoh!
Why is it doing that?
Okay…
They go in there
to get washed? Yoh!
Mmm!
What's wrong?
Eish…
It's just that, like…
I'm happy being here but at
the same time, I'm pregnant.
I mean, I am going to show soon…
and we eat a lot…
You'll be fine, don't
even worry about it…
Oh, don't stress about it.
Are you still my best friend?
Of course. Best friend.
That's my best friend.
Cute… Who are you?
Look at her hair,
that poofy thing.
Who did that?
It's Neo from Zone
6 in Diepkloof.
So, are you telling me
that's your actual hair?
- No…
- Yeah.
They crotched her and added
extensions plus a wig.
Okay, wait, guys.
Are you telling me that total nobodies
just joined this conversation?
How is this any
of your business?
You don't know me,
right? You don't know me?
You… tell me… where you from?
I'm from Soweto.
How are you this pretty
and you come from there?
Yes?
Right? Because there are no
beautiful girls in Soweto?
Hold on, guys!
Is someone gonna shut this bitch
up because she's been talkin...
Okay!
Jeez, guys.
So, are you First years?
Yeah… and you?
Do we look like
First years, doll?
I'm sorry.
Be careful of the
Fuck boys on campus,
they're a little tricky.
I like you.
We'll see you around.
Bye.
Why are you defending them?
They're not your friends.
Yes, but you don't
know them either.
Did you come with them?
You also don't know them.
Let's go.
Let's go!
When I try to start
the car… nothing.
So I ask Kedibone to
help so I can kick start.
Just before she starts to push…
some guys came to the rescue.
Come on, bro!
Doesn't she use this
car as her Uber?
So if you have to kick
start, she must push.
- Huh-uh. Push?
- Yeah.
No man, c'mon.
Mrembula there's one thing I
don't understand about you.
How can you…
give up your whole inheritance for
a girl you haven't even slept with?
Not once. Not even once!
Msithi, don't talk shit.
You know very well I'm
waiting for her to turn 21…
then I can deflower her!
Why do you act like you
don't know what the deal is?
When she turns 21? Yeah.
What if you die before then?
Should I…
deflower her for you?
-Three thousand… per month.
- So expensive.
- R1,500 a month?
- Where are we going to get this money?
- Buy airtime. We need to call them.
To go and see them
requires taxi money and…
Hello…
- Hello.
- Hi.
I overheard you are
looking for accommodation.
Hi.
Are you a student?
No, I used to be.
But now, I am an
acting lecturer.
Oh, Acting? Me too.
- I am a First Year student.
- Seriously?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
A young Thespian. Huh?
Lesbian?
- No. Thespian.
- Thespian!
I can already see you transforming
into the different characters…
and bringing light and shade
and dynamics to the roles.
-You go Thespian!
Yeah. That's fantastic!
So, where do you stay?
Um… for now we stay at home.
Yeah. We don't have enough
money to pay for res.
Oh…and these ones are expensive.
These are all just exploitation
of the African child.
Huh?
My friend owns the
Bannister Hotel.
Next to it, there's
free accommodation.
Free?
It's like a backpackers.
- What is a backpackers?
- Backpackers?
I can show you if you want.
Yes.
Here it is, ladies.
Come in.
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm.
No man!
Why aren't there any windows?
You know living in
the city is expensive.
Okay look, if someone moves out,
you will get one of the other rooms.
Woah!
And who's underwear is this?
Ah… these underpants?
Let me move them.
Um… Yeah.
- I can help you get settled...
- No, thanks.
Please give us a moment…
to… um, to…
to discuss this.
Oh, you want…
-some privacy? Okay.
Okay…
I'll see you around then.
-Ah!
Woah!
Friend, you're so extra.
It's my birthday week.
What do you want from me?
Ah, I'm gonna get so drunk.
Anyways, let's toast
to being fabulous.
No! Toast to me…
This is about me. Why the fuck
would we toast to anything else?
- Okay, okay, we'll have it your way.
- Yeah!
And I'm not going to serve them
because they think they are
better than anyone from Soweto.
Ha! Why are you
being so negative?
I'm sure they tip well
with all that money.
Their table is yours then.
-And we'll share
whatever they tip you.
-Babes, it's my dad.
- He's on his way.
- Okay.
Hi Franco.
Let me help.
-You're going to be fine.
Hey!
- Hey.
- How's it going?
- How are you?
- Sharp. Where's my daughter?
Um… she just quickly
rushed to the bathroom.
She's not feeling well.
You drink girls drink a lot.
- Daddy.
- Hi, baby.
My little dolphin.
Ah, dolphin.
Are you okay?
I don't feel well.
Here, have some water.
Yeah, drink.
Daddy, I want you to
meet my new friend.
She saved me!
Oh, it's the girl
with the pretty hair.
I think you need to
go home now, dolphin.
Amanda, please come and
take her to the car.
Make sure Njabulo takes
you home, he's in the car.
Take her bag and everything.
Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
You must stop drinking
too much, baby girl.
You're so funny.
- Let me get the bi...
- I have to…
I really want to thank you
for saving my little dolphin.
Argh, it's not a problem.
She just wasn't feeling
well. That's all.
Has anyone ever told
how beautiful you are?
No…
But thank you… Sir.
Huh-uh. Call me Franco.
Sorry.
Ah! You don't have to be sorry.
The person who has to be sorry is
the one who made this gorgeous…
beautiful, stunning paragon
of human perfection.
Huh? Clean after drunks.
No, no, no. I need his address.
I want to find where he stays.
I want to know his parents.
- I will deal with him. Huh?
- You're so funny.
- What is your name?
- Uh… Kedibone.
Can I call you crayfish?
Uh… okay…
Let me get the bill.
Crayfish…
-I owe you one.
Three, two, one. Tada!
Daddy, you got me a car!
-Mmm?
Crayfish, come. Come
celebrate with your friend.
We'll catch up at lunch, okay?
Great.
I got a car!
- How about we ditch school?
- Yes!
- And we go shopping.
- Yeess!
But I have class soon.
Dude, dude, it's Monday. Everyone
in there is hung over. Let's go!
Okay, but I'm broke.
Don't worry. It's
on me. Come on!
It's my treat. Let's go.
I'll pay for everything.
- Dolphin's got a car!
- I've got a car!
Let's go, baby.
Let's go, Crayfish.
-Friend, come!
Uh-uh… you stay.
Go to school. School is cool.
Beautiful girls.
Okay, so let's get back to this.
When you say virgin…
you mean like virgin?
Virgin, virgin?
Yeah…
Like never used
a tampon, virgin.
Girl, do you know what
your vagina looks like?
Yeah.
Does your man know what
your vagina looks like?
Yeah, but…
I am waiting until I turn 21.
That's cute.
Let me tell you
about my first time.
It was super romantic.
There were flowers, champagne.
His parents are super
rich, obviously so…
He booked us out
this hotel room.
The sex itself was terrible.
But the experience
was just wonderful.
Okay and…
What does sex feel like?
Sex is amazing!
Sex is like…
it's like God floating down
from the heavens on a cloud
and whispering sweet
sensations into your ear.
But most guys…
Most guys don't know how
to make you come so, girl,
you gotta get on that dick and
grind and you grind and you grind!
I swear, it'll be amazing.
Eish! That sounds…
Sounds… rough.
You know what.
My first time…
I know Mrembula is
a very gentle guy.
- Hmm-mm.
- So he's gonna…
kiss me.
And he's gonna
unbutton my shirt.
Uh-huh!
And he's gonna
suck on my titties.
Geez, you've got this thing down
to like, every clothing item.
And then he is gonna…
Put his penis
inside your vagina.
I'm tired of swimming.
I need to go home now.
Thank you so much
for everything.
I will take you home.
If you don't mind.
Okay.
Thank you.
Let's go. You'll
be safe. Trust me.
Ah… Crayfish.
So…
this is it?
Yeah.
It's way smaller
than your mansion.
You don't have to
be embarrassed.
You have a roof over your head.
Yes, but one day…
You know, I'm gonna buy myself
a life away from this place.
And you know what that day could
be much sooner than you think.
- What do you mean?
- I want us to be special friends
and have a special friendship.
Franco…
What exactly do you want?
You know what, close your eyes.
Close your eyes.
Just wait!
Patience. Patience. Patience.
Don't open your eyes yet.
And now, open…
What's this?
Possibilities.
Here…
It's yours. Take it.
- Uh, Franco, no I… I can't.
- No, no, no.
You can't be rude.
Don't be rude.
It's a gift. It's yours.
Ahh…
Yeah…
Spend it however you like.
Do your hair, your
nails, the works…
Have fun with it.
Okay?
Later.
Jesus Christ!
Woah!
Beauty.
What is this?
It's a phone.
Yeah but…
I've got a phone.
Yeah, I bought it for you.
I already have a phone
and it works fine.
Huh-uh! This one
is also yours. Huh?
One more thing…
I won a cellphone.
You gotta be kidding me!
You won a cellphone,
just like that?
No way!
- Congrats, baby.
- Thank you, baby.
Actually, I want you to have it.
There we go, there we go!
Beauty.
Go for it, go for it, go for it!
Ah, this palette is so amazing!
I should have
gotten one as well.
And these colours are gonna
look so good on your skin.
Fuck it, you are beautiful!
Like I forget and then I
look at you, I'm just like,
"Oh my God, you're beautiful."
And can I tell you something?
Rich people love beautiful shit.
Beautiful cars,
beautiful houses.
Beautiful fish. Great.
Fantastic.
I swear to God, Kedi…
with that face…
You'll have the rich
falling over you.
Opening every door for you.
Will snatch that face…
get you a good weave.
Don't do that. That
doesn't look classy.
Afterall…
I want to get you a rich man.
Take you out of poverty.
Woah!
Comrades are really funny, hey.
Seriously man, I'm telling you.
If the tender is
for R200 million…
and Mbaks wants R50 million…
give it to him.
Just give it to him.
How else are you going
to get the next tender.
Hey, cheers guys!
-Cheers!
- All the best.
- Oh, politicians are very funny.
Oh, they are very funny.
- Hello, Bra D.
- Hello.
Quick word with you?
Sure. What's wrong?
Uh…
Bra D, I wanted to know if…
anyone has off days
so I could work
during that period?
You want to work overtime again?
Yeah, I need it Bra D.
Your dad used to
say the same thing.
"I really need this overtime."
And when I warned him
about overworking himself…
He said one day, he
would buy this place.
Is that why?
Ah… No. Bra D.
Bra D, I'm saving up for lobola.
Huh?
You want to get married?
Yes, I do.
Oh my boy…
That's a beautiful thing.
You can work the extra hours.
Just make sure you
don't break your back.
Remember, after the wedding,
you still need to
consummate the marriage.
- I hear you Bra D.
- You know what I'm talking about?
Bra D…
- Thank you Bra D.
- Do you have the experience?
I need to go and
fetch this car part
that Msithi's been
nagging me about.
Okay.
Thank you.
-So…
I swear to God, I
am gonna tag you.
Two thousand likes by the
end of the day, darling.
I promise!
Okay? Average.
Hey, Kedi…
Is that not your friend?
-Can you see your likes?
Come… see your likes.
That is a beautiful
picture. It's pretty.
So… who has to come up
first and show us something?
Kedibone.
Why don't you come up?
Let's show them something.
So we sit down.
We lock our toes.
And we lock our hands.
And we lock our eyes.
And on my count…
One…
Two…
Three…
Let me not into the
marriage of true minds.
Admit impediments.
We tried our best but
you're not forgiving us.
Love does not insist
in its own way.
Your name is Martha
and you will work in that factory
for a duration of six months.
After which you will
pack all your belongings
and go back to those very
valleys and mountains,
where you will be greeted
by smiles and giggles.
From the children you've
left for a whole six months.
And they will be
expecting gifts from…
from that Johannesburg.
But as you step
onto your doorstep…
you realise that all those gifts
that were promised by Johannesburg…
were intangible.
That's it. That's
it Kedi. Well done!
Nice one.
Rise of the African child.
Good. Okay, I'll see
you guys next week.
- Alright, have a good one.
- Bye, Sir.
Kedibone…
May I have a word with you.
I was wondering if…
-I can meet you in
the dressing room…
Once you've gotten your things.
Just something that I
wanna talk to you about.
Okay… um…
-Dressing room…
I'll see you there.
Okay. It's this side.
Hi, Franco…
Yeah. I know, I know.
Can I just call you later?
Bye.
Rise of the African Child.
It's a big play, you know.
It's important to us Africans.
And Kedibone…
you're perfect for this role.
It's as if it was
written for you.
You'll see.
It's going to be wonderful.
You're perfect.
Just perfect.
So, aren't we talking anymore?
- Friend…
- No!
Don't "friend" me. I
can't get hold of you.
When I call, you don't answer
'cause you're busy with Franco…
Wait, let me get my phone.
I'm good, right?
I'm good.
I think need the gym.
I must get a personal trainer.
And you could be the one.
-Me? -Yes.
- I wish. Yoh!
- I'm telling you.
I'll pay you.
Look at that.
Huh?
Yes…
There we go.
Thank you.
No, thank you.
-For being a good friend.
It's okay.
I'll wait.
I'm a patient man.
Huh?
Take care.
Yeah.
-Okay.
The old man is exhausted!
-I need to go now.
- Look after yourself okay.
- Okay.
Have fun.
Enjoy it.
-Thank you.
Alright…
What's up, Crayfish!
Woah!
Hey, hey, hey!
Yoh!
We're celebrating,
because I found an agency.
- Mmm-hm.
- Agency?
Mmm-hm, acting agency.
Oh okay, so…
Those people who send you…
- To television stations?
- To auditions.
- Yeah…
- And then they're are going to tell you
if you got the gig.
Those type of things.
-Okay. Okay.
Got you.
Babe.
The necklace?
Is that real?
No, baby, I got from China Town.
It's so cheap.
It cost about R20.
Yoh, no. It looks like…
Like the real thing.
They really know how to make
these things these days.
Ah, you know how
the Chinese are.
-I know them.
Don't worry we'll be alright.
Soon we'll be able to
afford to eat crayfish.
Hey? As well as…
Lobster, huh?
The high life things.
Fuck it, you're beautiful!
And can I tell you something,
rich people love beautiful shit!
After all, I want to
get you a rich man.
Take you out of
poverty, you know.
- Good day.
- Hi.
Take a seat.
How can I help you?
Ma, I actually came to…
I want Kedibone's
hand in marriage.
I… I want to make her my wife.
Hah! That will never happen.
This child!
No, that can't happen.
- Why not?
- No ways.
Please hear me out.
Kedibone…
I love Kedibone.
Are you ready for marriage?
Or you think marriage is a joke.
- I am ready.
- Okay, forget that.
I'll pretend that I'm Kedibone.
Propose to me so I can see if
you're as ready as you claim to be.
Mmm!
Okay… um…
Uh…
Put the ring on my finger!
Kedi…Kedibone.
K… K… Kedibone Ma… Manamela.
Are you just going to
keep calling her name?
And not state your intention?
If you're going to
propose to Kedibone,
you need to be confident.
And not stutter,
Kedibone, Kedibone!
I will allow you
to marry Kedibone
but don't do what you
just did ever again.
This won't work.
Go and practise!
Use a mirror and make sure you know
what to say when you talk to Kedibone.
Go, go, go!
It's a surprise.
Wait a minute, wait a bit.
Stand right here.
- Okay, now I'm nervous.
- Okay. Ready?
-Ah!
This is yours.
Fully paid and all.
Welcome home, Crayfish.
What!
This is so…
Look at my view!
No frickin ways!
Phew!
Hmm.
Do you want a taste
of this crayfish?
Yes, Crayfish.
Yes.
-Ah! -
- Isn't there a lift?
- We're already here my guy.
We're going to get fit here.
I am already fit.
I was born fit.
So, baby, what do you think?
-Ah!
-Yeah! You did well.
-Ah! The view!
Look at the Jozi skyline.
-Ah, wow!
So, tell me…
the agent put all
of this together?
Yes, baby. All of it.
Marble floors, marble
kitchen, everything.
- Just for you?
- No, baby, with Tanya.
This other girl from
school. She is so cool.
I also want this
for myself one day.
Wow! Yeah!
Tony Montana views.
The world is mine!
I'm telling you.
I'm telling you. Hey, hey!
Are you jealous now, Msithi.
We're here on the
December 16 holiday.
And I can't wait for us to make
great memories, right here.
- Right here?
- Mmm…
- Like… now?
- Mmm-hm.
Msithi…
Go kick start the car,
we're leaving soon.
- I have to go.
- Okay.
Bye, baby.
I'm telling you Msithi
the first three weeks…
I couldn't sleep…
Thinking about how these rich
boys might try and get with Kedi.
Yoh!
At least she got a
decent place now.
The one she used to
live in was trash.
Yeah, yeah. I agree.
She's in heaven now
compared to where she was.
Tell me something. Is she
only staying with her friend?
Of course.
And the agent is paying rent?
Yeah, that sounds
just about right.
Have you met this agent?
What business do I
have with the agent?
Have you met him? Do
you even know his name?
- Who are you talking about?
- The agent.
Msithi, how am I
supposed to know?
What's with all these questions?
You should've asked Kedibone!
I don't know anything about
agents and how these things work.
Okay, then. Don't
get so emotional.
Delivery for Kedibone.
Kedibone?
That's me.
Rise of the African Child.
You know, Dineo…
This is a big play.
And you are just the right
person for this role.
You and only you are
perfect for this role.
It's as if they wrote
this play for you.
Yes?
I thought you said
you'd call me.
Look, my plate is kinda
full right now, so… yeah.
But do you know what, I really
need this class in order to pass.
I don't know, Kedibone.
You know exactly what
I'm talking about.
I saw on Instagram you are
looking for actors and models.
Well, I'm studying
to be an actress.
Oh, okay.
Uh… tell me…
What kind of acting do you do.
Well, I am acting on a
stage play at school.
And they gave me a lead role…
w… which I lost but I'm
gonna get it back soon.
Tell me, what are you busy with
next weekend. Are you are available?
I'm definitely free!
- Hello.
- Hello, Sir.
Uh… I would like to make
a withdrawal, please.
Okay please insert
your card there.
Please enter your pin.
Okay, so… how much
do you want to draw?
All of it.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Please hurry up, my sister.
So, where do I get the script?
Don't worry where you are going.
They will have a script
for you my angel.
And how much do you pay?
Let me tell you.
Eighty thousand rand.
For starters!
Eight… Eighty thousand…
My girl, I'm telling you.
Plenty more where
that came from.
Okay, this is all of it.
Twenty thousand…
as you requested.
Am I gonna get my
lead role back?
Yes.
-Ah! -How are you?
I called you here because I want to know
who you've invited for the ceremony.
I've already spoken
to Gheminah about it.
She said she'll invite
the friends from varsity.
Okay, but don't forget
about the cousins.
And the rest of the family.
This is a big deal.
I won't forget about them.
It's just that I wanted
to lay low because
you know, it's a surprise.
I'm aware that it's a surprise.
I know how to keep a secret.
What I want to know is do you have
the funds to make this possible?
Financially I'm sorted.
I even got overtime
pay from work.
She's also found an agent. Everything
is going according to plan.
Hey! Wow!
Thank God for that agent.
He's a gift from above.
Oh, now I'm convinced
that this acting thing…
You know… it's working for her.
I'm also going to see if we can
extend an invitation to the agent.
You see, now you're talking.
The agent needs to bear
witness to everything.
- You know what I'm saying.
- I hear you loud and clear.
Okay then…
I'm preparing dinner now
and you're not invited.
Please…
Okay Ma'am, on another note…
I think you have
a hidden talent.
Could you hit me
with one more note…
- before I leave.
- Hey!
Okay girl, outside.
Make sure you get the job done.
He can have you, okay?
Uh, uh, uh!
What's this?
How are you going
to work like this?
Go get changed.
Hurry up and start drinking.
Ooh, I can't deal
with ghetto girls.
You okay?
- I think she wants some.
- She should. Definitely.
It'll make you feel
so good. Trust me.
Have just a little. I cut
a little line just for you.
It's a nice small one…
It's good, hey?
-Did you inhale?
I feel like I'm
getting a nose bleed
Fuck!
Don't forget that you're paying.
Yes. Yes.
You see…
-Hi… -Who's this?
- Karabo.
- Oh, Kedibone.
Yeah, where are you? I'm
still at your house and…
I need my money.
Listen, I'm at the airport now
getting ready to go to Cape Town so…
You said you'd give me R 80,000.
When are you going to give it to me?
Let me send you…
- You wanted your R500.
- Five hundred ra…
- What!
- Please don't stress me.
I'm tired and I'm late
for my flight, bye.
No, but you…
More lemon, please.
Thank you.
Kedibone.
- How are you?
- Hi, Sir.
Don't call me sir.
We're not at school.
Let's dance.
No, I can't dance because
these heels are killing me.
I'm not used to them.
Oh!
Can I join you?
Do you need some company?
I'm actually waiting for my friends
they just went to the bathroom.
They'll be back for their seats.
I'll see you around then.
Shots?
I don't do tequila shots.
Look around, it's a
nominations after-party.
Loosen up a bit.
Yes, but do you see
that old man over there?
- That old man?
- Yes.
Tequila did that to him.
He's an old man.
You can't compare the two.
Come on.
Okay fine.
Yeah!
Ah ha…
You know what, actual…
here's another one.
To your nomination.
So, you do know who I am?
Smash, the whole country
knows who you are.
- [Smash laughing]
You know how to do
your thing. Yoh!
What is your name, buy the way?
I'm Kedibone.
Kedibone?
- Yeah.
- Oh.
I haven't seen you around, um…
are you… new to the
acting industry?
Yeah, I'm studying
acting actually.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I mean I am chilling with
actors, colleagues, producers.
How are you gonna get to know anyone in
the industry if you're chilling here?
Okay…
Give me your things.
Friend, call me back.
I think…
I think something is wrong.
I think I am having
contractions.
Okay…
Yoh!
Should we leave this joint?
Yeah, but he's my ride.
Who?
Him.
Him?
You're gonna leave
your life in his hands?
Seriously?
Can I Uber you home,
wherever it is?
Let's just go.
- Okay.
-Msithi.
How…
how do you get back in the game?
Let me school you.
When you're making
love to a woman…
Step one.
Step two.
Aye! Nicki Minaj.
Ah! Face forward, back is mine!
- Slow.
- Hey, man!
The aim is not to rush…
- No, man!
- …remember you're in charge.
- Hey, man!
- When you get to the 4th round.
You do the Thuso Phala shake.
Then you release.
I got this!
Aye!
Ah!
Where did you get this?
It's on a wall in my house.
I know it's in your
house… I mean like…
like where's the…
where did you buy it?
Online photo of the day…
just like blew it up
and put it on my wall.
-I'm sorry it's not my...
-Relax.
Oh, that's why.
Ah!
Yoh, it's the Gqom party
vibe. Take me to Soweto!
Yes, yes! Oh yeah!
Ah…
You know what, dancing is not…
- You're going to hurt yourself.
- For everyone.
You need a degree for this shit.
- Yoh!
- Come here.
Huh-uh, huh-uh, Smash.
What?
What, what, what, like…
I have protection.
It… it's not that.
Wait! Don't, don't…
It's…
It's not like you are
virgin or something right…
coz that would be some
really fucked up shit.
-You are?
No! Shit! Really?
I'm just waiting for
somebody who really loves me.
You know and…
Someone special.
Well, you're…
special…
to me.
Trust me, trust me. Listen.
We're here…
in this moment right
now for a reason.
Huh… Uh-uh.
Stop.
Please.
I so… I…
I just don't wanna do this.
-I'm not ready.
I love you.
I mean I… I could love you.
- I love you.
- I will love you.
-I will…
What are you saying?
Kedi…
I love you.
-And I… will always love you.
What… What are you saying?
- Come on.
- Huh-uh. Huh-uh.
Hmm-mm!
If you…
If you really, really,
really love me then…
you'll wait.
Alright.
In the family…
Are you sleeping for real?
Hey, Babe…
Smiso.
Smiso!
You, get up!
- Are you kidding me?
- Oh shit!
Are you serious?
Babe listen, when did you land?
Fuck you!
Now I know why
your phone is off!
You were busy with this whore!
In my house! Babe, I had…
- I had an awards ceremony.
- Get your hands off me!
You!
Get your things and get
the fuck out of my house.
Now!
Pamela, leave her.
Don't… You're don't have
to talk to her like that.
We are supposed to
be getting married.
I am pregnant with your child
but as soon as I turn my back
you fuck around like this!
What is wrong with you, Smiso!
I can explain.
Are you still here!
Get up and get out!
Get the fuck out of my house.
Get the fuck out of my house!
Don't talk to her like that.
Leave me alone!
Get the fuck out of my house!
Baby…
Eish! Shit!
Kedibone…
It's going to be alright.
Don't be scared.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Okay.
We should go to bed.
S… Step…
on…
Please! One line, one line.
Please!
Okay. It's time.
No wait, wait. Please!
Well, you're pregnant.
Fuck!
Eww Kedi!
Eww!
Fuck!
Are you gonna tell
your boyfriend?
It's not his?
So… what's the plan?
Kedibone…
What's going on? I'm in
the middle of my lecture.
I'm pregnant.
It's not mine.
Dexter, a girl
always knows, okay.
No… No, she doesn't.
I want an abortion.
Um… okay.
- Let's do it.
- I'm broke. I only have like… 2000.
- And I need 7000.
- Yoh! I don't have that kind of money.
So, this is your cousin?
- Yes, I am the cousin.
- Yeah.
So you're claiming
that's my child?
Franco…
I did everything
you asked me to do.
We'd go to fancy parties. Do my
make-up, dress up and then show up.
This how you treat me?
From being a crayfish to just
being pollution in the ocean?
Is this how you see me now?
You know what?
I didn't send you…
to be a porn star.
Do you hear me?
Hmm? Busy entertaining
other men. Hmm!
Like a whore. After everything!
After everything I
have done for you!
From me.
I sacrificed every
single thing for you.
I sacrificed my youth and
my beauty for you, Franco.
You took my virginity.
And you took my money.
What did you do with all of it?
I paid for tuition.
And I have to eat.
How much are we
talking about exactly?
Uh… Five thousand.
Are you mad!
Then I'm keeping it.
If the family finds out
about the pregnancy…
they will come for you.
I'm coming with.
Let's go.
Mavis, car keys!
The biggest whore in
the fucking world!
- What?
- We know you slept with her father.
How could you do this to me?
Don't you… Hey! Hey!
Don't you dare touch her!
-I need a drink.
A drink like alcohol?
- Yes.
- Now?
Just drive.
- How's things Msithi?
- Good thanks and yourself?
I'm good, can I have the usual.
Alright, sharp!
I got a nice surprise for you.
Check this out.
Who this is?
Don't forget that you're paying.
Touch is a move and
a move is a price.
No man, is this not Kedibone?
- Yes, that's her.
- Mrembula's girl?
- Yers.
- Where did you get it?
- Instagram.
- Oh, I see…
You've got data, hey.
She's a slay queen now?
- Thanks.
- Cheers!
I'm going to the bathroom, okay
- What's up man.
- I'm good, what's up?
Why are you checking
out my girl.
- What's up with that?
- What?
- Oh! Oh!
Chill man, let me
show you something.
Don't forget that you're paying.
Touch is a move and
a move is a price.
Hey, he saw you!
Where did you get this?
It's on the…
You know what, forget it.
We're leaving.
Oh, baby.
I'm not asking you.
I'm telling you.
Kedibone are you cheating on me?
- What?
- You heard me. Answer my question.
Are you cheating?
No, baby.
What are you talking about?
Explain to me why
there's a video of you…
twerking on some random guys…
On that guy's phone
back at the restaurant.
So you are accusing
me of cheating?
Seriously, Tebogo?
I'm at school every day but
you're accusing me of cheating!
You know what, it's fine.
I can tell you've
found someone else.
What!
- You've found someone else.
- Someone else?
- You got a new girlfriend Tebogo.
If you want to break
up do it like a man.
What are you on about?
I'm trying and…
Here I am thinking
I have your support.
You're not being fair, baby.
I'm sorry.
Sorry. It's just…
It's just that the way that
guy was looking at you…
Next thing…
I see someone who
looks like you…
Babe…
Cheating on you is the
last thing on my mind.
Tebogo.
- Look at me.
- Please don't lie to me.
Please don't lie to me.
I would never lie to you, baby.
I would never lie to you.
Oh, Msithi?
We need to talk.
And Tebogo?
I need to talk to you alone.
What is it? Is everything okay?
Are you cheating?
- What?
- Cut the crap!
Don't act all innocent here.
I see your promiscuous ways!
Me, promiscious?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I have been seeing you
with these celebrity guys.
Driving Lamborghini's with big
bellies and high blood pressure.
I am the dealer that side. You don't
think they tell me these things.
You know…
All wanted to do in
this industry was…
just to make it.
But then you meet…
Can I call you crayfish?
A young Thespian.
I saw on Instagram that you are
looking for actors and models.
So you do know who I am?
To meet mercy people and then…
They sell you the world…
What's this?
Possibilities!
And you, Kedibone…
You're perfect for this role.
So, how much do you guys pay?
Eighty thousand rand.
Just for starters!
I mean I am chilling with
actors, colleagues, producers.
How are you gonna get to know anyone in
the industry if you're chilling here?
And then they just wanna
use you for your looks.
Great fit!
Woah!
I didn't know how I was
going to tell Tebogo.
I mean…
He paid for my tuition…
by selling his inheritance!
I know.
I'm sorry.
I'm not the one
you're cheating on.
You need to apologise
to Mrembula not me!
Yes, I know Msithi.
Can I use your phone?
I wanna call these other girls.
They wanted to come fetch me and…
I just wanna cancel
my plans, please.
You're sleeping around…
but you can't afford airtime?
Thank you.
Msithi?
Stop!
Bloody cheater!
You have reached the
voicemail box of…
Yeah, Cray, Cray.
You put me on voicemail.
Hey!
You took me for a ride.
And played with my heart.
You know, Crayfish…
I gave you everything I have.
I was there for you emotionally.
Financially.
Physically.
And you just drop
me automatically.
Hey Crayfish… Crayfish!
You hurt me Crayfish.
Cray…
Eish!
Woah!
Life is tough!
Hey!
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you very much.
-You know this one's
for you, right?
Smash, Smash, Smash, Smash!
Can I have a word?
What!
I've meant to give you a call.
It's just I realised I
don't even have your number.
You already got what you wanted.
Listen…
I came to apologise.
I should have said that I'm…
engaged.
You must think I'm a dog.
Dogs are cute!
You are evil, Smash!
Hey, come on, I…
You raped me.
Rape?
Kedi, I didn't…
I didn't rape you.
We both got back…
You raped me, Smash.
Hear me out. Hear me out.
I genuinely wanna help you.
You said you wanna
get into the industry.
I wanna hook you up. I wanna…
- I want you to meet my people.
- You know what.
- Get into his book…
- You're wasting my time.
Kedi…
Smash! Smash! Smash!
Hello.
I brought some baby clothes.
Thank you.
Themba.
Come get the baby.
So…
How's life been treating you?
Fine.
I'm sorry.
Hi, baby.
Okay where are you taking me?
Yeah, but how must
I know what to wear
when I don't know
where you're taking me.
Baby, come on, you
know I hate surprises.
Okay, okay fine.
Cool.
Ah! Crayfish!
I don't like how things
ended between us.
- I know your birthday is coming up.
- Don't touch me!
Yoh!
I bought you something, hey.
Voila!
You bought me a car?
This is not just any car.
This is a machine.
I'm fine. You can keep it.
Ah!
Since when?
I'm moving out.
- Where to?
- I'm going back home.
Am I a joke to you?
I will tell you when to leave.
I'm the one paying
for this apartment.
Do you hear me!
And you still owe me.
One last round.
- Where do you think you're going?
- Don't touch me!
- Get off me!
- You're my whore, I own you.
Now shut up!
Kedibone!
Baby…
He's the agent I told you about.
Agent?
Kedibone what's going on here?
- Huh?
- Guess who's in trouble now.
I'm sorry, baby.
Here's the story young
man, listen carefully.
I know this looks bad.
But I'll save you the heartache.
Kedibone?
There's a lot of women out there
and they're still gonna hurt you.
I know because I was once
a young man like you.
They'll hurt you real bad.
You see how full of
fish the ocean is?
Crayfish there,
crayfish all over.
And you know what you did?
You chose one crayfish and…
And you put it in the fridge.
And left the door unlocked.
What did you think
was going to happen?
I opened the door and helped
myself to some crayfish.
And it was appetising.
I must say, your
crayfish is delicious.
Never tasted anything better...
-Tebogo, please.
Tebogo you're hurting him.
Tebogo stop!
Let him go.
Let go of me!
Tebogo no, no no…
Please don't kill me, I'm sorry.
Let's talk about
this. C'mon man.
Let's go.
Tebogo you're hurting
me, let me go!
Tebogo you are hurting me.
Let go of me.
- Shut up!
- Baby, I'm sorry.
Baby, I'm sorry.
Baby, listen, I'm sorry.
- Get inside.
- Please.
-Kedibone Manamela.
My pure innocent woman.
Virgin!
You!
Jesus!
Your dad left you a good
inheritance in this car.
-He did!
I just wanna study, baby.
- Baby, please.
- Don't touch me!
Tell me about your agent.
It's really not what you think.
Kedibone Manamela!
- Baby, I'm sorry.
- Jesus!
I'm sorry, baby!
You are sorry? Are you
sorry for my father's car.
I love you, baby.
Baby, no!