BIRDS CHIRP
BABY GURGLES
VOICES CHATTER
Charlotte? Come and see Jen's baby.
Hello. Hi.
How are you?
I'm good.
We're having a little nap.
So, how are you finding it?
Great. She is a little joy,
honestly.
Do you want a hold?
Oh, no, I couldn't.
Yeah, go on. Come on.
There we go.
There.
There, that's it.
Yeah.
Aawww. She likes you.
Really? She's not normally this good
with strangers, honestly.
Oh, she can be
a right madam sometimes.
I bet you're looking forward
to getting back to work.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm back in June.
Erm...
But you know what, I think
I might just stay at home,
do the whole mum thing instead,
you know?
What about your career?
Of course. Yeah, I know,
but, erm...
Well, now Tom's been made partner,
I can kind of relax a bit.
Tom's been made a partner?
Has it... Has it not
been announced yet?
Oh, sorry.
Hmm.
Oh, bigmouth strikes again, eh?
OK.
Oh.
Oh, sweetie.
Come back to Mummy.
Oh!
I'm so, so sorry, Charlotte.
Please, send me
the dry-cleaning bill.
It's fine.
Charlotte, do you have a minute?
Sure.
Bye, Charlotte, nice to see you.
You too.
Yes. Yeah, that's better.
Has she got any teeth yet?
Yeah, she's got two.
Come on, baby. Yes.
Show us your little teeth.
Oh, lovely little smile. Yeah.
She's a happy
little girl, isn't she?
This is shit!
Of course I can market
over Mina, I just did.
Well, then stop trying
to feed me such utter bullshit.
Well, what's the procedure?
We went through a procedure.
It's constructive dismissal,
that's what it is, Simon.
I was promised equity in the merger
and now you're trying
to get rid of me.
I've been here three years
longer than Tom.
Look, he wouldn't even be in
a position to sell the agency
if it wasn't for my input.
Why are you doing this to me?
This is my world.
Plea...
Right.
Fuck.
VACUUM STOPS
I don't expect you.
I can see that.
What have I told you
about smoking in my home?
I'm sorry.
I said smoking was unacceptable.
Do you remember me saying that?
Yes.
OK.
Well, as I've warned you before,
I don't want you
to clean for me any more.
OK, I not charge you this week.
It's not about the money,
Maya, it's about trust.
I really need this job.
You should've thought about that
before you polluted my apartment.
I want you to leave, now, please.
SHE SPEAKS OWN LANGUAGE
Maya.
Maya, hold on.
Look...
You do a good job.
Just...
please use the terrace
if you want to smoke.
What's that?
Is mine.
Well, it's not, is it?
It's mine...
and you're going to
give it back to me. No!
I knew it was a mistake
not going through an agency!
SHE SPEAKS OWN LANGUAGE
LIFT: Doors opening.
OK, Miss, I'll see you next week.
Maya, Maya, Maya,
hold on, hold on, hold on...
I have a headache, that's all.
OK, well, well... Let's go inside
and sit down for a while.
You've had an accident.
It was not accident.
You give me pills
and then I need to go.
You, uh... You can keep
the champagne.
Is very kind.
SHE LAUGHS
Are you all right?
You...
are so unhappy.
I have to go now.
I think you should sit
and rest a while longer.
I not stay here so you feel better.
SHE SPEAKS OWN LANGUAGE
I think you...
Maya. Maya!
Maya! Maya.
Maya.
May...
Oh, bloody shit.
Maya! Maya, come on, Maya!
Oh, no.
Oh, God.
SHE SOBS
LIFT: Going down.
Doors closing.
CENTRAL LOCKING BEEPS
Shit.
LIFT ACTIVATES
(Fuck.)
SHE GRUNTS
CENTRAL LOCKING BEEPS
NURSERY RHYME ON RADIO
SOFT CRY
# Row, row, row your boat
gently down the stream
# Merrily, merrily, merrily
merrily, life is but a dream. #
BABY CRIES
That's it...
Come on.
Have some more?
Have some more.
Yeah...
DOORBELL BUZZES
BUZZ
WHISPERS: OK, OK, OK.
Shh.
DOORBELL BUZZES
Yes?
There you are.
I've been calling you from the cab.
'Well, then, let me in.'
Look, Tom...
..now's not a good time, OK?
'Come on.
'We can talk about it.' I'm sorry.
I'll call you.
'Charlotte...'
BUZZER
Please, can you stop doing that?
'Not until you let me in.'
Look... I can't.
'Why not? It's freezing out here.'
BUZZER
KNOCK ON DOOR
Hey.
I told you. Now isn't a good time.
I feel terrible.
I've been at a client lunch
all afternoon,
and all I could think about was
getting over here.
I'm on your side.
I swear, I thought they were going
to make you partner as well.
It was only when...
..David asked me to take over your
accounts that...
Look, you know, I did as much as I
could do, but...
But I want you to know...
..that I am with you with this, all
the way.
I'll do anything. I don't care
what it is, I'll do it.
Really? Mm-hmm.
First thing tomorrow morning, I'm
going to hook you up with Sally,
my head-hunter. She's brilliant.
There's nothing you can do, Tom.
Yes, I can. I really can.
Look, Sally will get you
a brilliant job, she's...
I couldn't care less.
It's about the baby.
What?
I know how horrible it must have
been for you, and...
You know, especially on top of everything
else that happened yesterday, but...
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry,
but I swear to you on little Grace's
life that I had no idea Jen was
going to bring her into the office
yesterday.
She did it on the spur of the moment.
I need you to leave, now, Tom.
No.
No...
We need to work through this.
The last thing I want is for all of
this to get in the way of us.
And...
I've got a free pass for
the whole night.
Come on.
What are you doing?
If you don't leave now, I'm going to
call your wife.
Right. I tried.
What a waste of time.
DOOR CLOSES
SHE CRIES
OK.
Mmmm.
Oh, what's this?
Healthy...
OK, what...?
Hang on. Mmm.
Softer, softer.
OK, bye. Thank you.
LIFT: 'Going up. Doors closing.'
'Doors opening.'
Shit.
BABY MURMURS
BABY CRIES
Shh, shh, shh.
Shh, shh, shh, shh.
I'm sorry.
I know. I know.
Ssshhhh.
Shh, shh, ssshhhh.
Sorry.
I'm so sorry.
And we've got a pink rose.
And rose rhymes with no-o-o-ose.
And pebbles. Clip-clop, clippety-clop,
clip-clop, clippety-clop.
It's like a horse's hooves.
Clip-clop, clippety-clop.
Shh, shh, shh, what's the matter?
Hmm? What's the matter?
What else should we look at?
Shall we look at the river?
See the river.
Can you see any boats?
Can we see any boats?
Oh!
BABY BURPS
Oh, oh, oh, dear.
Dear, dear.
Oh, dear, dear.
Oh, what a lovely baby!
Oh, I startled you there.
So sorry about that.
Oh, aren't you a beautiful
little girl?
Just like your mummy, eh?
Thank you. What's her name?
Um... Rosy.
Oh, that's a lovely name.
Agnes. I'm just saying hello to
the new neighbours.
We're moving in next week.
So, hope to see you again soon.
Bye-bye, Rosy.
Rosy.
Yeah.
Given the circumstances,
I want nine months gross
and I'm keeping the car.
OK.
Six months plus bonus.
And I want this resolved as soon
as possible, Simon.
Thank you. Bye.
BABY CRIES
What's the matter? Eh?
'Good evening, you're through to
the NHS 111 service.
'Can I take the number you're
dialling from, please?'
I've got a baby here and she's
really burning up.
'OK, if you could just let me have
that number you're calling from.'
Can you not help me? She's really sick.
'I'm afraid I must have that number first.'
BABY WAILS
God. Shh, shh, shh, sshhh.
It's OK.
Hi. All right?
You remember your Auntie Charlotte,
don't you?
Oh, two kisses now, eh?
You look fucking terrible, you do.
A nice pad, though, eh, Char?
Oh, my God, look at that view!
Come on, love, let's have a look.
Are we all right going out, Char?
Yeah. Come on, kid, let's have
a look.
Oh, my God!
It's gorgeous, isn't it?
Whooooo!
We're in London for the weekend.
Ah.
Let's have a look.
Well, she's all right.
I don't understand.
She was burning up before.
Yeah, well, babies get temperatures
all the time, it's no big deal.
I'm sorry, I didn't know what else
to do.
Well, even know-it-alls like you
can't know everything, eh, Char?
She's beautiful, isn't she?
She is, yeah.
Ah.
Little pudding.
There you go.
Ta.
So, she... She had cancer?
Yeah, breast cancer.
How old was she?
32.
What, and she had no other family?
No, not that I know of.
So, you've decided to take
the kid on?
Well, it was the least I could do.
I wish you'd contacted me sooner.
It just happened so quick,
we didn't even have time to tell
the authorities and whatnot.
I was worried she'd get taken
into care.
Right.
You want to stay clear of the
Social.
Be careful, yeah?
Thanks for the clothes.
That's all right, they were just, you know,
sitting in a cupboard, doing nothing.
It's a great help.
And it means a lot.
Um...I stink, can I borrow
your shower?
Yeah, but don't go using
all the hot water, young lady.
Yeah. You girls think money
grows on the bloody trees.
What are you up to?
I'm playing with my sister.
She's not your sister,
she's your cousin.
I want her to be my sister.
Why's that?
So I can play with her every day.
I think Rosy would like that.
Shit.
Hi.
Hiya. I saw you drop your box.
What? You know, on telly.
The old CCTV.
Can't tell you how much I love
this flat, Char.
It's amazing.
Are you all right?
Um... Yeah, yeah.
I've, um...
I've, I've left something at work,
I've come all this way home.
Can you just mind Rosy for a bit
longer while I go and sort it?
Oh, you are joking, aren't you?
We've come all this way to see you.
I'll be really quick.
Oh, it's fine.
It's not like I'm not used
to you running off, eh?
Look, OK, tonight, when we get back,
I promise we'll sit down and we'll
have a good drink and a natter.
Right.
Stop by the chippy on the way back,
yeah? Yeah!
DOOR SHUTS
PHONE BEEPS
PHONE RINGS INSIDE
RINGING CONTINUES
RINGING STOPS
DOOR OPENS
Can I help you?
I didn't mean to barge in, I'm...
I live in the new apartments and...
I've been having trouble with
vandals.
Right. Well, I thought you might
have the CCTV footage.
What building would that be?
Westhill Tower.
OK, let's take a look.
Sorry about this place, eh?
Throw these flats up,
don't bother sorting out security.
They haven't even built us
an office yet.
I can't give out footage to
anyone except the police.
Oh. But I tell you what,
you report it to them,
and I'll see if I can get a picture
of the little bastards.
Great. I'll do that.
Thank you.
CAR LOCK BLEEPS
RADIO: '..naturally in middle age.
'Described as revolutionary,
'it can help thousands of women in
their 40s and 50s who are currently
'unable to have children.
'River police have recovered
the body of a young woman
found floating in the
Thames at Erith.
VOLUME INCREASES 'The unidentified woman
is believed to be Eastern European,
'and officers suspect
her death may be linked
to illegal sex trafficking
in the capital.
'In other news, a Metropolitan
Police spokesman
has admitted that it acted
unlawfully by failing...'
RADIO OFF
PHONE RINGS
ENGINE STARTS
LIFT: 'Doors closing.'
'Going down.'
Cor, about time.
Roger's been waiting ages,
he's found your vandals on the CCTV.
She's beautiful.
Just like her mother.
I need to put her down.
Hey, good girl.
Hey, there's a good girl.
LAUGHTER IN OTHER ROOM
Yeah. I suppose you were
born a stone's throw away
from the Stretford End.
My old man supported them,
didn't he?
Here you are, sit down, Char.
Roger's having Stacy's.
You were so long, I had to give her
a sandwich and put her to bed.
It's only fishcakes.
Oh, don't bother me,
I am Hank Marvin.
One fish is bigger than the other,
so I'll give you more chips, right?
Is this the only vinegar
you've got, Char?
Yes, sorry.
And you forgot the gravy. No,
actually, down here in civilisation,
we don't do gravy on chips.
Oh, right.
Well, in that case, I better get us
a drink to wash it down with, eh?
Nice try with Westhill Tower.
Unfortunately, I spent a year
manning a checkpoint in Basra.
Kind of teaches you to remember
where you've seen a car before.
So, then, seeing as it's
so posh down here,
I thought we better make it
champagne.
What's this? Drinking the evidence?
What? Nothing.
Here, give it here.
You'll do someone an injury.
You don't mind, do you, Char?
There's loads of bottles in
the fridge.
No, it's... I just don't want any.
Oh, come on, sis.
No, really, I'm fine. Right, Rog,
pour Char a glass, will you?
Come on, you should be celebrating,
you've had a payoff.
Wow.
That really is something to
celebrate.
INAUDIBLE
I was out with this mate of mine,
terrible he is,
can't handle his drink at all.
We've had, what, seven, eight pints,
and he has thrown up all
over himself.
Jesus! Seriously, right there in
the middle of the pub,
he is all over the place.
He's going, "Oh, my wife's going to
kick me out," you know,
"She said if I come home like this
one more time we're finished."
I said to him, "Chill out, pal.
"When you go home, have a £20 note
in your hand and say some geezer
"threw up on you and gave it to you
for the dry-cleaning."
So, he goes home, wife takes one
look at him, tries to chuck him out,
he goes, "No, no, no, no, no.
"When I was on the train home,
some geezer threw up on me,
"gave me a score for the
dry-cleaning."
She goes, "But you've got 40 quid
in your hand."
He goes, "Yeah. The other 20 quid is
from the geezer that shat in my pants."
You... You're full of shit.
No, straight up.
So, um...
So, what's the deal with
these vandals then, Char?
What? You know, the vandals.
What's been going on?
Oh, something went on in
the car park a few days back,
but I found it all on CCTV.
Oh, here you are,
let's have a look, then.
We can do if you want.
What do you reckon, Charlotte?
No. No?
No, you're right.
Save it for the police.
Let's have some more of this.
I know what you dodgy southerners
are like, eh?
Trying to take advantage of
young defenceless women.
No, no, you can trust me.
Yeah, right.
No, seriously, in a bad situation,
I'm the kind of guy you can rely on.
What do you want?
What do I want?
I want the toilet.
It's down the hall, you nutter.
Lovely.
What's the matter with you?
I want him out of here.
Oh, I knew it.
You're jealous, aren't you?
You don't know what you're getting
yourself into.
Don't you give me that
concerned sister bollocks.
Look, listen!
He is trouble. Oh, Jesus.
You can't handle a bloke liking me
instead of you, can you, eh?
He's trying to intimidate me.
You don't half rate yourself,
Char, always have done.
You think you're too good
for the rest of us. No!
You called me once in two years
and I come running down like a twat.
You're a stuck-up,
self-centred cow.
You didn't even care
when your own dad died.
I paid for the funeral.
You didn't turn up for it, though,
did you? I was in Cape Town!
You didn't show up for the whole two
years that he was ill, either, Char.
OK. OK, I accept
there are issues...
You're too fucking right there's
issues...
But, please!
Please...
Listen to me.
We have got to get him out of here.
And then we're going to pack our stuff,
we're going to go back up North...
..and we're going to see each other
all the time, I promise.
What, you want to move back home?
Yes! Piss off.
Look, I'll explain everything...
DOOR OPENS
Everything all right, ladies?
Yeah, sound, Rog, yeah.
I was just negotiating getting us
another bottle of champers.
Ah, splendid. Well, come on then,
give us a hand clearing this lot up.
Oh, no problemo. Good boy.
Done with yours, Char?
Here.
Ta. Did you wash your hands?
I'm proper house-trained,
I'll have you know.
Yeah, right. I'll bet you're a right
dirty bastard.
Well, I can be if you want me to be.
DANCE MUSIC PLAYS
Here, open this then for us.
Coming up...
BOTH: It's Dare.
# Never did no harm,
never did no harm... #
Come on then, Rog, hurry up.
CORK POPS
Bloody hell, that went nearly right
in my face! Get it down you.
Go on. Here you are.
Tune! Ooh-ooh! Ooh-ooh!
Yeah!
Not in my home! Not in my house!
All right, Char. Jesus,
I'll smoke outside.
Mummy, it's noisy.
Oh, sorry, sweetheart.
Me and your Auntie Char, we were
just having a little bit of fun, eh?
Come on, let's get you back to bed.
Come on, darling.
That kind of anger could get
a person into trouble.
KNIFE GRATES
MUFFLED CONVERSATION AND LAUGHTER
GLASS CLANKS, LAUGHTER
MOANS AND GASPS
You looking for this?
You don't need it, you know.
I'm here to help you.
Get the fuck out of here.
Ssshhhh. You'll wake the baby.
Look, I'm not being judgmental.
I'd hate for the police to get hold
of the CCTV footage
and spoil everything for you.
What's in it for you?
30 grand.
Well, I'll need time to get it
together.
No, you've just had a payoff.
Yeah, but it'll take a few
days to get into my account.
Bring the money to the office,
Thursday morning.
I'll delete the footage right in
front of you.
What about the memory stick?
Yeah, yeah, that as well.
Don't do that.
I'm just giving myself another
option.
CAMERA PHONE BEEPS AND CLICKS
What do you mean?
Well, if you dick me about,
I could always take the kid as well.
Right.
Thanks for the chips.
Fishcake wasn't great, but hey-ho.
Oh, yeah. Your car.
What? I'm having your car as well.
Give me the keys.
Um...
Well, I'll need it on Thursday to
come to your office.
Fuck me, you've got an answer for
everything, haven't you?
All right.
But bring the paperwork with you.
Money. Give me some money.
I haven't got much on me. But you're
minted. Give me your wallet.
For fuck's sake!
MUSIC PLAYS
Ah, this is epitome, this.
This is banging, man! What is it,
Blaupunkt or something?
I don't know.
Yeah, that's the thing,
they don't badge them no more.
Can't nick 'em no more, either.
Off you go.
VOLUME INCREASES
CASH MACHINE BEEPS
MACHINE WHIRS
MUSIC STOPS
DOOR OPENS
That's all I could get.
All three cards?
The corporate one's blocked.
Fair dos.
Give me the stick first.
Still got it all on the hard drive,
remember.
Yeah.
'Can I help you?'
Hello, boss. Has your breakfast menu
started yet?
'Breakfast starts at 6.30, sir.'
All right, I'll get a...
..Chicken Royale and a chocolate
shake.
'Any fries with that, sir?'
Sure you don't want anything?
My treat.
That's it, boss-man. 'Thank you.'
What did you do with it, then?
What? The body.
What did you do with it?
Dump it somewhere? Burn it?
No.
What, then?
The river.
So, it will turn up, then.
It already has.
Yeah, they always do.
It's something to do with the currents, you
know, they never quite make it out to sea.
My uncle used to work on
a Woolwich Ferry, you see.
Uncle Frank.
Lovely bloke.
Committed suicide.
HE SLURPS
Of course, you know the funny thing,
don't you?
I never would have found that footage if
you hadn't come sniffing round the office.
We never bother checking anything
unless it gets reported.
HE LAUGHS
Hey, this is nice, this, isn't it?
I need to go home, now.
Don't be like that.
Look, you've had your money.
Take me home.
Just trying to be friendly.
You're going the wrong way.
I'm going straight to work. You can
drive yourself home from there.
You don't want to do that.
I'm going to have to.
My shift finishes in 15 minutes,
and if I ain't there when Ravi gets
in, he'll grass me up.
Well, what about your bike?
It's well over 20 minutes
from your place on a bike.
I'll pick it up later.
Well, I need to get back to see
to Rosy.
Sarah's there. What's the biff?
Look, why don't you forget about
work?
We can...
We can hang out.
I can go back to the bank and get
some more money out.
Look, I'd love to,
but if I don't show up,
they'll know something's wrong.
And this could get very messy if
we're not careful, babe.
No, the best thing we can do is
act normal.
I mean, all right,
you've made a mistake,
you're trying to put it right.
It's all good. But not everyone's
going to see it like that, are they?
So, it's very important that we don't
attract any attention to ourselves.
What the fuck?!
Fuck.
Open this door.
Open this fucking door!
Shit.
Fucking loser...
Come on, you. Get up!
What? Now, did you tell him where
you're from last night?
What? Did you tell him where you're
from?
Oh, for God's sake, Char,
just leave it, will you?
Look, it's important nobody knows
I'm moving back up North.
Now, look, I'm being serious.
We are leaving in 15 minutes,
so get up!
What, you want to move back today?
Yes! I can't put you up, you know.
Well, I'll book a hotel!
Stacy. Stace.
Stacy, love. All right, trouble?
Eh?
How do you work this thing, Char?
Have you not got any instant?
Look, we haven't got time for this.
I can't go anywhere until I've had
my coffee.
I will buy you a Starbucks.
BANGING Open the door!
Open this fucking door!
Let me in! Is that Roger?
Right, I'm not having this.
Sarah, no! No! Roger, mate...
Don't, don't, don't!
Roger...
Get over here! Get here!
Fucking bitch!
Did you think you could just burn it
down and it would go away? Did you?!
I don't know! Did you?!
You fucking bitch, trying to mug me
off, you fuck!
Where's that memory stick?
Where's the stick?!
You don't know who you're dealing
with, you stuck-up Tampax mug!
Try and burn me out, try and make
me disappear like your cleaner?
Fucking bitch, get off me!
You fucking touch me?!
You fucking bitch!
You are fucking... You are fucked!
Where are you going?!
You're going nowhere!
Give me that stick!
I want it now! I threw...
I threw it away. Bollocks you did!
SHE SCREAMS
It's in my coat! It's in my coat.
What pocket? Fuck!
Give me that stick!
What difference does it make?
You can still have the money!
It makes a lot of difference now.
I'm taking the baby.
What? I know people, and that is
50 large in my pocket.
I will give you 50...
I'm having all your money!
I'm having the motor,
I'm having the baby!
So, just do as you're told and you
can go back to your nice shiny life.
There's nothing you can do. It was
never your kid in the first place.
It's mine now.
We...
We can work this out. Yeah?
The first time I saw him was when
he burst in this morning.
And you've never met him before?
No.
Never heard her talk about him?
No, I don't think so, no.
Did you notice anything else out of
the ordinary about your sister when
you came to stay?
ROSY GURGLES
Who's this?
It's my sister, Rosy.
Hello.
You want your mummy?
Here's Mummy.
Thank you.
It's OK.
Ssshhhh.