Once upon a time, there was a girl
who lived in a small town.
She had friends.
A boy who loved her.
But she had secrets.
And she wasn't free.
You want something to eat?
I'm not really hungry.
I have just the thing for you.
Works for me every time.
I forgot earlier.
I had to get another credit card.
-I got you one.
-Thanks.
So, yeah, who are you?
My name is Lindsay, aka Lady Bug, aka...
Some call me Bug, some call me Lady B.
What's pure happiness?
Pure happiness to me is
in the eye of the beholder.
I mean, only you can make yourself happy.
Motherfucker...
That's mine.
Get the fuck off.
Get the fuck off my hair, bro.
You disrespectful little shit!
Hey, man. What's your name?
Marcus.
I'm Trey.
Well, I don't really know
who I am at the moment.
-I know who you are.
-Who am I?
-You're my guy, bro.
-You're my guy, too.
I won't forget you, bro.
I can find happiness
in the smallest things,
or the biggest.
Hey, Mom.
Where are you getting all that money from?
I'm working. Just trying to save up.
Well, where you been working?
Where they paying you that kind of dough?
I'm just working, Mama.
You're just going
to keep it all to yourself
and you're not going to give none
to your poor mother?
You're fucked up, Mom.
I ain't know I raised such
a selfish bitch. Come on. Give it here.
Mom, stop!
If you ain't gonna share,
then you're gonna have to
get the hell out of my house.
Fine.
Well, then go on.
When do you feel most free?
When do I feel most free?
I feel most free...
probably when I'm laughing.
'Cause laughing is uncontrollable.
And, with my homies, I'm always laughing.
There's not much to do in this small town.
So, I'm like, it's either I laugh
or get high, or party.
So macho, T. Damn.
Bug!
Guys, who is all in there?
-Okay. Okay.
-Let's do this shit.
-Get your ass up in the car.
-Let's go, Captain.
What's up, Bug?
Are we late picking you up?
You know it.
What are we about to do, y'all?
We're about to smoke.
-Yeah.
-That’s what we about to do.
-I already knew. I already knew.
-You already knew.
Look at that.
-Look at that glow.
-Oh, man. Come over here.
-That light!
-Right. That glow.
That is everything, bitch.
Get up in there.
That glow.
What's up with your mom?
You guys know, right? She wallin', always.
Nobody gives me hugs, though.
-Hey.
-Good to see you.
-How you doing?
Aren't you looking fresh as fuck?
It feels fancy to me.
-That's bougie.
-She's classy.
It's us in this fucking town.
I dare you to howl.
Shit's fire.
-Where'd you get that even?
-At thrift.
-You thrift?
-Yes.
If I had a son, yo...
Brother, obviously
just fucking rose up...
Oh, my fucking God.
You're saying it doesn't...
Both including Munich and chocolate malt.
Yeah. Yeah.
-Hey.
You good?
Yeah. Of course.
Then why're you over here like a creep?
Pure happiness.
You got these questions written down?
This is fucking...
Pure happiness.
Just doing my own thing.
Thinking about the void.
"The void," what's that?
What have we been doing? You know,
we used to have a purpose.
You would wake up, go to school,
come home, go to bed,
and it's all for something.
You know, what the fuck
have we been doing now?
Absolutely fucking nothing. You know,
we're fucking here every single week.
You know, I wish we could just
get in the fucking car
and drive the fuck out of here, you know?
Start a whole new thing.
Bah.
You said, "Bah."
-Bah...
-Let's just fucking go.
We've seen the same shit our whole lives.
-I wish...
-Let's just fucking go.
-I'm serious.
-"Let's fucking go."
I'm serious.
Powerful. There's a lot of power
behind this fucking man.
-Let me see this real quick.
-All right. You got it.
-Hey.
-What's up, Bug?
This fucking town
is sucking our souls dry.
We need to fucking go.
Can you hear me out here?
We gotta get the fuck out of here.
We gotta get the fuck out of this town!
-Okay, Bug.
-There ain't shit for us here!
Y'all really just want to just fucking go?
For real?
Yeah. Let's go to the fucking city.
How good does that shit sound?
-Fucking hell.
-All of us together, let's do this shit!
Let's fucking go. Get up!
We're going now?
My mom would beat the shit out of me.
-You wanna go?
-Okay.
That right there is
God's way of telling us.
That van has its window rolled down.
-I could boost it, man.
-Do that shit.
All you gotta do is you get
the red with the blue.
Hey, look, I watch YouTube videos,
all right?
-Okay.
-Stop it. Stop it.
Go.
Shit. Got it. Got it!
Hurry up. Hurry up. Hurry up. Hurry up!
-Let's go.
-Here we go.
-Yay!
-Yes. Yes.
You all gave me...
Honestly, Bug, you gave me
these small-ass joints.
-"Just trade it to her."
-Okay?
We really just stole a fucking van.
Nah, I don't want to know...
And so, she left on a journey
with the boy and her friends.
The road was full of new places.
Enchanted.
And she felt something
she may have never felt before.
Wait. Wear them horns
on your head like this.
Wait. Stand right...
Which way do you look at?
What's pure happiness to you?
Happiness.
What is happiness for me?
It's a feeling. It's an emotion,
it's something that you can't necessarily
hold in your hands,
but still it has so much impact
on how you live, how you breathe,
how you think.
Did you not examine it?
You're first. Okay. Truth or dare?
I hate you guys.
All right. I dare you
to get up on this table
and sing "Mary Had a Little Lamb."
Okay. I'll make the beat.
I've been waiting for this moment.
All right. Five, six,
seven, eight. Hit it.
Please, sir.
-Please don't dance on the table.
-I'm sorry.
Sorry, ma'am.
Hey, five seconds, switch,
and you got it. Here we go.
What do you pick? What do you pick?
Truth or dare?
Truth.
All right, truth. 'Cause we did
kinda get a little wild.
All right. Let's calm down.
-Let's calm down.
-You got any "truths"?
Just corny ones.
Like, you think you ever been in love?
Yeah, absolutely. I love all y'all.
Nah. Nah, nah, nah.
Not that love. Not that love.
Not that love. Not homie love.
Do you believe in falling in love?
I don't know if you can fall in love,
because, like, I'm not... I don't know.
No! It's too much, too much, too much.
-Too much, too deep, right?
-I don't know. I...
Yeah, too... Yeah. No. I love hard.
So, that's what it is. I feel like you...
Yeah.
Yes. Yes, I am.
Would that person know it?
No.
No. She won't.
Who's paying for this, though?
Y'all, I got us.
-Hey.
-Hey, let me look at that.
Hey, you must be a...
How are you feeling about this trip?
I don't regret it.
-That's good.
-We out here.
We out here.
That's good. Yeah. I don't know.
I hope everyone's on board
with this shit, though. You know?
I ain't going back. Fuck going back.
Shit. My bad, bro. I'm sorry.
Hey, bro, you scared
the shit out of me, man.
Yeah. Bad for the smoking, man.
It's all good. It's all good.
It's what heathens call it, right?
I guess you're right.
-Man, you scared the shit out of me.
-Shit.
-Take my shit.
-All right. All right. Okay.
You from out here, bro?
I'm on a road trip with my family.
We're trying to go to the Grand Canyon.
Shit. I've never been to the Grand Canyon.
Don't go!
That shit ain't nothing
but a hole in the ground, man.
-Yeah.
-Shit's over-rated.
Yeah.
Honestly, I'm out here
with my friends, too.
We were supposed to go
on this crazy-ass road trip to the city,
but I think I'm gonna go home.
Yeah? Why? Why's that?
I'm not built for this.
In the moment,
I thought things would be different.
Now I just wanna take my ass home.
It's understandable, man.
Sometimes in life,
you have too much expectation.
Yeah.
And when reality hits you
and everything's settled,
you know, then you sort of figure it out.
You don't even look like the smoking type.
-Word?
-That shit's crazy.
No shit.
I'm faded.
You don't say that
'cause I got the cowboy boots on?
-I think it might be the boots.
-It might be the boots.
-This don't go with the boots.
-No.
But I'mma tell you something, though.
Sometimes it's just the little moments.
When you take a moment,
you enjoy the view, you know,
and just count your blessings.
Shit.
I'mma tell you something that
these grown folks
ain't going to tell young bucks,
'cause it's too harsh of a reality.
You don't ever have it figured out.
Fuck.
You just get older.
Honestly, when you put it that way,
I think you're right, man.
I moved to LA from El Paso, Texas.
I'm a military kid,
so I lived all over the place.
If I were to build
a relationship with someone,
or a friendship or whatever it was,
in a year or two, they'd end up leaving
and moving somewhere else.
That's always the saddest part.
The losing the friends.
It's time to dip.
-Dip, like...
-Like...
Y'all going back?
We can't... We can't do this no more.
Do what?
We were on this path of
y'all trying to find yourselves,
or whatever y'all got going on,
but for real, we gotta go.
Why can't you go back home with us, bro?
I can't go back, y'all.
There ain't nothing for me.
All of y'all are going.
-You going?
-Yeah.
For real, y'all?
You're just about to bounce?
There's a point in every journey,
in every adventure,
when you've travelled so far
that you've lost sight of both
your home and your destination.
It's in those dark moments
that true explorers are tested,
boundaries pushed.
It's when companions turn back,
the chaff falls away,
and you're left to find your own path.
Well, the girl refused to turn back.
They had to press on.
What is pure happiness to you?
Pure happiness is...
just looking in the mirror
and just being comfortable with yourself.
Wait, wait, wait. No, no, no.
What's going on? What's going on, Trey?
Do you got...
-I'm about to die.
-You're not gonna die, Trey.
You're not gonna die.
It's gonna be okay, Trey.
It's gonna be okay. It's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be okay.
All right.
Highly over-rated.
It actually tastes like freedom.
-No, no, no.
-Real shit. Don't fucking shit at me.
That's the last shit to say, bro.
I'm on some real shit and I would like
to thank you for buying me this,
because I feel very amazing,
and off that, I'll take a big bite
just for you.
Lady Bug guaped up,
got the unlimited credit card.
Where did you even get that credit card?
Can you get my phone out of the car?
It's in your purse?
All right, got you.
You know, the consistency of the fries,
it's, like, quite astonishing.
-Shut up. Shut up.
-Quite astounding. No, no, no...
...like your hand about to fall off.
Hey.
-What's up, my bro?
-What took so long?
Here.
Hey, did you grab my phone?
You were out here the whole time.
-You didn't even grab the phone.
-It's in the front seat.
-All right.
-Is my book still in there?
Yo, check it.
They got actual humans in there.
-It's like some animal shit.
-Step the fuck back.
-They look hungry.
-Yeah, man.
-I said step away from the vehicle.
-They're starving.
-The little girl is starving, bro.
-There's a little girl in there.
I'm not gonna ask you again.
Hey, man, this is all humans, man.
-Like, you really signed up for this shit?
-I'm not gonna ask you again.
They're people, too.
-Yeah, they're really people, too, man.
-Boys, take your friends
-and step away from the vehicle right now.
-Yo, yo, calm down.
Yeah, you're a real fucking tough guy,
aren't you?
-Yeah, I am.
-You see something on my fucking face?
Have you guys ate something?
-Step away from the vehicle, boy.
-Yo, chill, chill.
-"Boy"?
-Yeah, "boy."
-Don't fucking touch him.
-You gonna hit me with the "boy," man?
Hey, man, days like that,
that's over with, man.
We're really trying to move on
from that, man.
Don't hit me with the "boy"
'cause I'm not a boy.
"Move on from that"?
I told you to move on.
Get the fuck away from this van.
-You're being aggressive for no reason.
-Step away.
All I'm saying is, I'm not trying
to be aggressive, bro.
-Fuck this. We don't gotta...
-Let's go.
Hey, cop, calm him down.
-Get in the car.
-Hey, I'm not resisting, I'm backing up.
Bug.
Bug, you awake? You awake, Bug?
What? What's up?
-You good?
-Yeah.
What's up?
Do you love me?
The fuck?
Why the fuck are you asking me that?
Do you?
I can't do this, go to sleep.
Go to sleep, Marcus.
What do you think about
her and Trey's relationship?
There is... I mean,
they're just friends, you know?
They're just friends. I've...
It gets me tight.
-You got that one out, huh?
-Yes.
That was like... Sounds like you're angry.
-That wasn't angry.
-This is crazy.
You don't know me angry.
The air feels different.
Who would've thought, like, 10 days ago
we'd have been on this shit.
They keep always fucking littering
on this fucking shit.
Pick it up.
"Bulltown Rodeo."
I haven't been to a rodeo before.
Yes, a fucking rodeo.
Hey, we should go to this.
Bug, we should go. You know, the rodeo
and the shit with the bulls?
-Yeah.
-Yeah, baby.
-We're fucking late.
-For real.
-It is cold as fuck.
-Where's all the people?
This shit is nice, like,
what the fuck is this shit?
This is the rodeo.
Hey, what's up, man?
I like your horse.
She nervous?
No, I wouldn't say she's nervous.
I don't see no bulls.
-Didn't the sign say bull, bull riding?
-It did.
I think it's coming up.
Shit.
Dang.
-So majestic.
-She taking off.
Yeah, she's hard.
It's crazy how she really know
what she's doing,
like, she's controlling it.
See how fast that thing going?
That's crazy.
That's Hallie.
She was county champ last year.
-Y'all do this a lot?
-Yeah. All our lives.
Y'all ain't from around here, are you?
-I'm Taylor.
-I'm Annie.
-I'm Trey. Nice to meet you.
-Hi.
-Nice to meet you guys.
-I'm Marcus.
I'm Lady Bug.
This what y'all do around here?
I mean, this is kinda it. We just kinda
come to these, hang around.
I mean, look around, there's not much.
Shit.
Thought it would be more exciting.
This is some shit you get drunk at,
for sure.
Yeah.
Do you guys wanna drink?
Fuck, yeah.
Always on some different shit, huh?
Love that dude.
You like Trey more than me?
Shut the fuck up with that shit.
You're such a hater, damn.
You're such a fucking hater.
-Who am I sitting with right now?
-That's not smooth.
-I've seen smoother shit.
-You have?
Yeah.
-Can you do smoother shit, though?
-Not right now.
Of course, not on the spot.
You're putting me on the spot right now.
Everyone's the same everywhere you go.
-Nah.
-Yeah.
Out here, I already know
shit is entirely different.
If I lived out here,
I would be lit all the time.
I wanna take a trip like you guys did.
I think that'll be fun.
Fuck a trip, man.
Are you guys not having fun here?
He has a crush on her,
I know that for a fact.
And Lady Bug
would not admit that, definitely.
In Lady Bug's eyes, though,
they're just friends, so, it's whatever.
You know, I don't have anything...
I love Trey.
He definitely knows
how I feel about her, though.
I got these B-E-E-R.
-Beer. Beer.
-B-E-E-R.
Let's go. We're leaving, bro.
I'm done with this. We fucking out.
-What's up?
-Bro, calm down.
Don't tell me to fucking calm down.
Yo, yo, yo, chill out, man.
-You smell like alcohol...
-I'm fucking leaving.
Are you just not having a good time?
-Like, what's up?
-Yeah.
I'm fucking done with this.
These people are fucking losers.
-Okay, just chill. Chill.
-I'm done with this shit.
-Calm down.
-Get in the fucking van.
-You coming with me?
-We don't got to take no van.
-Yo, chill, chill.
-Get calmed down.
What the fuck, Marcus?
-Yo, yo, Marcus, hey.
-Marcus, where are you going?
-Text Annie.
-Okay, I'll text Annie.
Calm down, man, what you doing?
-Yo, yo, yo.
-Marcus, I just want some.
-Take it away. Take it away.
-I just want some, Marcus.
Come on. Come on, bro. Get in the car.
Get in the car, man.
Right here. Go ahead. Get in there.
I hated that he got so jealous.
You know, like, the me and Trey thing
was always something
that really tick him off.
He's just insecure and very lost.
Hey, man, text Annie.
Make sure she know
that we gonna come back for her.
Trey, you gonna tell
Lady Bug you love her?
This is...
Marcus, you're drunk, just leave it alone.
Why you all always fucking
teaming up on me for no reason?
-What?
-The fuck?
-What are you talking about?
-What am I talking about?
You guys both know
what I'm fucking talking about.
-You're talking bullshit, man.
-I'm not fucking crazy.
-You talking out your ass, bro.
-I'm not fucking stupid.
I've seen the same shit
that y'all been fucking living.
-You're a fucking item.
-I don't wanna hear that, man.
We're not no fucking item, man.
Ain't nothing up here, Marcus, chill out.
-And you don't even know shit.
-I don't know shit?
You don't even know
why the fuck we're out here.
He's only out here
'cause he likes you, you know that?
Man, what the fuck. Fuck all y'all.
-Marcus...
-I'm out. Keep that shit.
Keep that shit, man.
Marcus, leave him alone.
You were acting tough.
Chill, what more you need?
Man, can you smell yourself, bro?
You're fucking drunk right now, man.
Just like your dad, man.
-You're turning exactly like your dad--
-Motherfucking--
Marcus, leave him alone. Marcus.
-Keep saying that shit.
-Keep that shit.
-Get the fuck out of here!
-You're acting like your father.
You don't fucking know me!
You don't know fucking shit about my dad.
Stop, yo, stop! Stop!
Hey, fuck you, man.
-Fuck me?
-Fuck you, bro.
You stay with your drunk boyfriend,
whatever the fuck y'all got going on, man,
keep that shit.
Keep that shit to yourself, all right?
-Trey, where are you going?
-I'm out of here, man.
Okay, but who got the GPS?
You got the end like that...
-You hold it like so.
-...and you eat it.
-Eat what? The joint?
-Yeah.
I think the best part of the trip...
was when we first got the van.
I feel like, in this life,
it's like a journey
to find yourself, you know?
You spend your whole life
figuring out yourself
and when you do figure out,
you know, like,
everything about yourself,
it keeps you at peace.
You know,
I love Lady Bug.
I feel like she's the type of person
I would wanna...
raise a family with, you know?
Everybody loves Lady Bug, though.
Literally everybody.
We all felt this similar happiness.
That was cool,
because it was like we were all as one.
Marcus.
Marcus, it's okay. It's okay.
He's so crazy.
But the best kind of crazy.
You gotta...
You gotta go.
It's easy to get lost
trying to figure things out.
No one really knows why we're here.
So, we all look to different places
to find purpose and meaning.
Maybe it's a new city,
maybe it's another person.
But the truth is,
purpose isn't something external.
It's something we create in our hearts,
our thoughts, our dreams.
It's okay not to have things figured out,
to not know who you are in this world.
Because the world
doesn't define who you are.
You do.
And once you've accepted that,
well, that's the day
you'll finally be free.
And if you could give yourself
a message for in 10 years,
if you look at this camera
and know you'll watch it in 10 years,
what would that message be?
My message in 10 years would be,
"Bitch, you did that shit."
Man, I don't know what you did, bro,
I hope that you... No.
Grind, baby, be on that grind.
Don't be idle,
know you were weak for that reason,
you gotta move on, you know?
I don't wanna ever see you being sad
for no reason, you know?
I love you. I fucking love you, baby.
And I see you and I recognise you.
That's love.
I would love to see that,
if it was me 10 years from now.
All right. This is crazy,
'cause this is very emotional for me.
Ten years from now, Khalid,
you're gonna have done
a lot of crazy shit,
lot of great shit.
You probably got too drunk on your 21st,
it's okay, your friends picked you up.
Hopefully, some of those friends
are still by your side in 10 years.
And hopefully, you mean it
when you say that you're happy.
Hopefully, you're still yourself
and hopefully, there's still
a little bit of me in you,
the day that you watch this,
10 years from now.
Love you.
Mutha... Joshua tree.
Okay, we good? Can we go?
-Yes.
-Let's fucking go!
I think we need the key.
I need a key.
There's no key in the car.
Guys, there's no key in the car.
"It's trying to get lit",
is old folks talk.
I got you. I got you.
-And that shit is booty.
-Thank you.
They got these.
I'm using this microscope
and they still look like...
I don't know why they give this
to people. Well, not people...
-The chickens.
-Well, animals are people too.
We're kind of cute, baby.
Yeah, we need to tell.
I was peeing looking at the stars
and the wolf started howling
the entire time I was peeing.
-What?
-How does that feel as a person?
Because it was the most beautiful
pee I've had in my life. I swear.
It was howling when I was peeing
and looking at the stars.
Bro, shut up.
I'm a wolf!