Under the current Islamic military regime,
women are not allowed to play soccer
in Sudan. And we also can't
make movies, but...
Marwa, I want to play in the women's cup
for the Sudanese national team!
Khartoum Offside
"What does love
has to do with me?
I called...
He never answered or called me back...
He was cruel and complained
He came, he distracted me
and then forgot me...
"What does love
has to do with me?
<I love you
with every bit of me
Your love is the world to me
<I love you
with every bit of me
Your love is the world to me
I think about him, then I forget.
My hopes rise again...
What does love
has to do with me?
They screwed you.
This is old.
One day,
I'm playing goalie...
And I didn't know
that my uncle was there.
The ball is coming
towards me...
I look up
and I see my uncle arriving.
I step away from the goal
and sit down next to him.
My teammates shout:
"Hinda! Get back in the goal!"
I pretend not to hear them,
"Hinda! The goal!"
I wanted my uncle to think
that I was just watching,
but they ruined
my plan.
My uncle shows up,
beats me and drags me home,
and the ball flies
into our goal.
Good boy,
you didn't go out with your mother...
Don't know your
of your mother?
129...
You didn't call her?
I tried
The cell phone
is not working.
May God forgive her...
Lord Almighty!
Her phone
is out of service.
Listen...
Tell her I stopped by
and to call me
I should receive the rent
by tonight.
I am very sleepy.
I was born an orphan.
I grew up in my grandmother's house.
It came from my grandfather. He had
four wives and many children.
He always heard stories about his inheritance
and the problems of the house...
Then I decided that one day
I would have my own home...
with my own money.
- What should I talk about? My life? My youth?
- Tell me about your youth.
<If only my lost youth
could come back again
One and again, my love
Until the moment, my love
I never forgot you
and you never forgot me
My grandfather Ernest Jubara
Atlabara...
He owned the well-known Baka mill,
in the south, in Atlabara.
This mill
was from the time of the English...
They called it the mill,
after the English left.
Originally, it was a bar.
A huge bar.
Where people drank,
enjoyed life.
And other things!
During the Second War
I think.
These are my mother's stories,
as if she were there...
In World War II, the customers
put up fights, I don't know how...
But there were deaths
in that bar.
My family even today
has nightmares about it
I would like to bring
that bar back...
- Does your family still have the bar?
- Yes.
I will open another one,
of my own.
Sasa Jabara!
I'm going to call
Sasa Jabara's Bar!
40 lashes.
You stand up,
dust off your ass...
Do some ice compresses
to reduce the swelling.
That's it.
But why drink in the streets,
be arrested and receive 40 lashes?
Drink where they can't arrest you,
at home, and go to sleep without the lash
-Why do you drink anyway?
-Do you want to paint the city red?
I'm not going to serve whiskey
or anything like that.
I will serve Kaji moror,
the local hooch and Abyad damira.
- What do you call the one with ginger?
-Atbaga.
Don't dry your clothes
indoors...
I was born in the south,
but I grew up in the north.
My people did not believe
that secession would actually happen...
Neither do I.
But it happened.
The South became
another country.
My parents became
from two different countries.
I did not vote for
for secession.
I didn't even vote.
Because I was not convinced.
My parents were not against
me playing soccer.
They thought,
where will sport take you?
We didn't see any progress,
and I could never represent Sudan.
Hi, Coach.
How are you?
Where have you been, Sara?
I was tired, Coach.
We want the activity to take off,
because you already have the money.
the money that comes from FIFA
for our Federation.
You need an office,
or come stay here with us in the federation.
In any case, Sara,
we're talking about years of work.
We don't want to waste energy,
and the girls are disappointed.
Because they don't have a chance
to play abroad.
As you have an activity,
I will log it and send it to FIFA.
We only have one field for women,
so people don't talk bad about us.
Salma stay with the group!
Don't move alone!
It is closed!
Go on, play!
Keep the ball!
Don't just stand there!
Speak up if you haven't paid yet
and pass it on.
I am behind on my rent,
but we have to pay.
Sunday then.
Saturday also
can we pay?
I just paid.
And the rest?
- Money is tight. How could it be?
- There were many of us, but several left.
We were counting on more people
to pay the rent.
They should say at the beginning,
whether or not they want to continue playing.
Now you don't have
enough money.
- Are you done yet?
- Not yet.
They asked for some tests
to renew my residence permit.
I had to take tests
for hepatitis and HIV.
They confiscated my passport
until the results came out.
If the results are not good,
they will not renew my residency.
What counts
as cleanliness and hygiene.
See that trash over there?
I'll clean it up.
I can work on Sunday.
You will open the store...
I'm going to take some sand
and throw it in that trash.
We will call you
around 11:00 or 12:00.
So you check
if we can rent the place.
There is another coffee shop nearby...
With a TV,
soccer channels...
They serve shisha and snacks...
In a better place.
The rent is a thousand a month.
Let's take a look.
This is a small place,
as the guy said.
And it comes with a partnership...
Then the profit
will be almost none.
There are no inspections here,
right?
Yes, you have to have good relations with the government.
with the government.
So they call
and let you know if there will be a raid...
But you have to pay,
of course you have to pay.
There is a fine of 2,000 pounds
for serving shisha.
Not for alcohol.
The fine for shisha
is one thousand...
Sara, let's get into
into the drug business...
I remember the game
of the old Barcelona team
Against Zidane.
Ronaldo, the Brazilian...
Roberto Carlos
and that Portuguese player...
Luis Figo!
It was the best team
of Real Madrid...
Here we go!
- A great save by the goalkeeper!
- It's the best
Barcelona has a problem, keeping
possession of the ball is no longer the best tactic.
Take a look
at Bayern Munich's team...
They scored five goals
against Arsenal!
In the same week
they beat Barcelona.
Is the court open?
I'm already full in front...
Sara has things
everywhere.
What's wrong with these things?
They are OK.
I don't have any.
They need to fill my things...
-But why mine?
-No, you're fine like this.
This ball is nice. I will take it
it to the children back home.
Not a dream!
Play with one touch.
That's it. Cool!
Good... very good!
Well done!
Asthma, your passes
are wrong, wow!
The man who trains you,
what is his name?
Coach Abduh.
- Coach.
Practice...
Coach.
He said it's only for adults
and that I'm too small.
I am ten years old!
I am quite tall.
So,
we are not the same height.
Right?
Sit down, sit down...
I can handle
anything...
I have a strong body.
Do you know how hard the ball
is hard?
I kicked with my toes
until I couldn't stand it, but I didn't cry.
Didn't you cry?
-No...
-Because you love soccer!
I love it!
More than anything!
I can't wear a veil in the field.
It gets in the way.
See that girl?
She's not wearing the veil...
Stupid girl. Your head
is backwards...
These are our customs
and traditions, girl.
Your customs and traditions?
Yes!
So someone who doesn't wear a veil
has a screw loose?
Yes!
So Marwa and I
are stupid?
Stupid! Stupid!
More than stupid!
I'm not going to get married.
But I will have children.
- But what?
- I'm going to have children.
How are you going to do it
without getting married?
Then,
shouldn't you have children?
The children don't show up
at the door of the house!
Then I'll put on makeup,
fix my hair...
and do these things
to impress men!
I was on my way to pay
some utility bills...
When I passed the soldiers
at the door.
My veil was on my shoulder
and I was in a ponytail.
A soldier says:
"Is it a girl or a boy?".
He would speak:
"Boy or girl? Boy or girl?"
I heard "A boy",
and it made me sad.
The other guy said:
"Hey girl!"
I pretended not to hear.
I kept walking
and he came after me...
And he said
"Hey, I'm talking to you!"
I said:
"I get it."
"Cover your head!"
I said, "You can't even tell
if I'm a girl or a boy!"
Make up your mind
and then we'll talk.
The first policeman says:
"What's going on?"
I said: "The soldiers kept
asking "girl or boy?
The whole problem
started with "boy or girl?"
Republic of Sudan:
*Basic Education Curriculum*
Turkish-Egyptian rule
over Sudan ended in 1885.
The Mahdist state began...
Omdurman became
the capital of Mahdia...
And they passed
Islamic Sharia law.
The causes of the colonization
of Sudan...
The internal affairs of the Mahdist state
have become vulnerable.
Colonialist activity in eastern Sudan and Africa
Sudan and Africa continue...
The British occupied Uganda
and the west-south Sudan.
Italy occupied Eritrea
and Kassala, Eastern Sudan.
Why is Sudan part
the Arab League?
Girl, we are an African country
and not Arab!
Addis Ababa and Uganda
are Africans.
How can Sudan
be Arab?
We are a Muslim state, maybe...
Ethiopia has Muslims too.
All this has changed so that they can
apply their policies...
But we are not Arabs.
If you go to Saudi Arabia
they will say you are
are not Arab...
In the past, I was attacked
secretly in the field...
Sukra and Faniya would come up
and hit me...
My leg would get swollen
after playing with them...
They would knock me down.
I looked around
and saw Sara in the distance...
In Japan, I took the European
for a trainer's license.
The exercise was about
the ice-sliding technique.
They were instructing the players
on how to slide.
- They should know, sliding is up to them...
- She was the last player...
The coach passed the ball,
the goalkeeper came out of the goal and I slid in.
I said:
"Hey, be careful, I'm from Africa."
My slip made
the dew to splash...
I remembered Captain Maged,
the dew splash was beautiful!
I lifted the ball
and kicked it into the goal!
The people applauded
like crazy!
The trainer said:
"Do you know how to do that?"
"Sure," I said.
"One of my favorite things!"
The back of her leg
turned black after the slide.
I heard this story
from one of the men's teams.
One of the national teams
national team...
They had a gynecologist
with them.
The federation asks us
to cover our legs...
They said, "Girls can't wear shorts.
can't wear shorts.
"What's the problem?
My girls are skinny!"
They were worried
that an officer would show up.
I said:
"You guys are really weird..."
This is a soccer uniform!
uniform!
But we agreed that,
if a religious official would come,
out of respect, because you are a
mentally disturbed person,
the girls would wear
long sweatpants.
But if a FIFA official
of FIFA comes,
why should we wear
workout clothes?
The game has rules!
They can't understand,
what can I do?
The veil slips,
while you are running...
You straighten it out
as the ball enters the goal!
This is absurd.
Am I here to keep my head covered
or to play?
How is a national
a national team?
You must take care
the teams you already have...
Start with them
and then bring in the other generation.
whether they win or lose,
it doesn't matter.
You have a
women's national team....
Sudan should have
a national team...
It should be us,
shouldn't we?
We are talking about our position
in the federation...
If something happens,
does the federation protect these girls?
They play,
but they are not organized,
and they have no support
or money...
You have to have money,
a committee and a headquarters...
You need to have 8 teams
to have competitions during the year...
Not just random departures...
There are also teams
in the provinces.
Yes, true,
Niala has a team...
And there is another one in Madani.
But to organize them,
you need a committee!
The activity takes place in groups of five,
since we don't play 11 against 11.
As I said, there will be a
development budget for you...
After the elections, comes a FIFA grant
for development...
You have wasted
many chances, girls.
I like women's soccer...
I stopped working with the guys
and now I train with them.
Even if Bakhita can't come to the training,
I will go alone.
None of them ever said
an unkind word to me.
Just pretty words?
That Sara!
If I could represent South Sudan,
I would put here two tennis balls...
Under a bra,
and she would be a pretty girl, ah yes!
When my son
turns two,
I will bring it to your court,
and I will say:
"Your father got a good start here!"
"The bum you see
started right here!"
The father saw Monot leaving the house
and asked
"Where are you going?" Monot said:
"I'm working with Sara."
Then my father sees me leaving...
Question: "Is Monot playing
with your team?".
I said:
"Yes, on the girls' team..."
"We have other guys
on the team, too.
He says, "Okay.
Do you guys play with them normally?"
I say, "Of course!"
The problem is this stupid Sudan,
where there is no progress.
Why can't you play abroad
like the Sudanese National Team?
So that they know their names.
They don't support...
I will draft some documents,
with official stamps...
We will create a team
with all the documents...
So we can receive invitations
from abroad directly...
An official team...
Because the Federation, God bless it,
is not to be trusted...
They refuse to guarantee
any of our rights...
They agree in words,
but do nothing.
They keep promising,
but nothing happens.
If we could travel abroad,
we wouldn't have any problems.
But how can we travel
and play as a team? How...?
We made many journeys
and departures together...
Not everyone in this team
are from the south...
We are from the mountains
of Nuba...
It is really beautiful there.
He asked
where we were originally from?
Many fled to Khartoum
because of the wars.
No one ever imagined
that Sudan would split in two...
Ultimately,
I am Sudanese.
The creation of a women's team has been presented
to the Organization of Islamic Jurisprudence....
That is the authority of the Islamic government
On Shariah Law. It decreed:
"The only sports allowed
for women are those that maintain health."
Football is for men
and inappropriate for women...
<We must warn against everything
that may cause
the abolition of the differences
between men and women...
The practice of this sport diverts women
from their feminine nature and incites violent instincts...
But the sport in question
involves creating a women's soccer team...
to play in the Sudan Cup.
Also, to play abroad,
in Europe, in the U.S. and Africa...
"Investigation: whose fault is it?
Women play soccer with men in the streets!"
So we decided against the creation
of a women's soccer league.
Holy be the Lord!
My father said that Friday's
on Friday was about us...
They said "sinful!"
"Shameful!"...the usual.
The newspapers talked
about our departure...
A stranger knocked
at my door...
I told my parents ,
"I feel you will have a summons."
I opened the door and a man asked,
"Are you Hala?"
"Yes," I said.
"You should go to the Department
of State Security." I asked why.
He said
"Because of soccer."
They asked, "Who invited you
to the game? Who are the others?"
At first, I denied everything,
of course!
He said, "It is a sin! It's not right to play
with boys in the street!"
I said,
"Yes, I play in the street."
"What about your father?"
he asked.
"You don't have any
problem with that."
They asked the same questions
to Asthma.
Asma said: "I play soccer
wherever possible".
They asked: "Where do you live?
"On the May block," she said.
"Where exactly?"
"In Hayy al-Arab..."
And so on,
one question after another...
When it was over,
the police cleared everything up.
The police had
received instructions
to learn the identity of the girls
who played that match...
find out where they live,
summon them...
and question them.
Okay, finishing up the work,
we'll meet there.
I should move
from Koubar, so...
Come on,
let me wash my face...
Are you going out
or are you staying home?
We will probably pass
past you...
Yesterday I went...
Renew my residence permit
residence permit...
They force you to take tests
for AIDS and Hepatitis C...
I went to get the results
and was told I had to do it again...
- Do what again?
- The blood tests.
- Again?
- Yes
-For how much?
250 pounds...
Only the two Southern
had to redo the tests.
All the others
have achieved renewal.
This sucks!
Why do they do this?
If it goes wrong,
what will you do?
I'll think about that later...
It's strange when you ask "why" and they answer "that's the way it is.
and they answer "that's the way it is".
What does this mean?
Give me a reason...
For starters:
why can't we play abroad?
We ask the people
of the federation.
We don't receive invitations to play
abroad? Not really!
The Arab Women's
of Women's Football was in Egypt...
They said we could go...
We pack our bags
and our hopes...
They canceled our trip
to Egypt, next door...
When you play abroad,
you realize your true level.
When you compete with people
better than you...
That is important.
Do you want me to read
her future?
-Her future or yours?
-Mine...
What is your plan?
I plan to travel...
Near or far?
Out of Sudan.
Okay, now put one
in each row.
He has some projects,
but nothing clear yet...
Here's a trip...
You will travel...
But not now...
Coming soon.
I have to tell you
the news...
Aisha was nominated for the elections
of the Federal Soccer Council.
I knew she would be...
She is a candidate!
Can you believe it?
Aisha and Hanan
from the Al Mawrada club
She is candidate number 2...
The third is Nahid.
Nahid,
she is a journalist.
Yes, I met her...
And Salma al-Majdi.
<Strong competition.
- Pretty strong indeed.
<And is Mervat in the running as well?
- Yes, it's number five.
If Mervat wins,
there will be no hope for us.
You are right!
If they reelect her,
it will be the same fight for another four years...
Because she doesn't know anything
about soccer.
God help us.
ask and you will find your way,
our home is near yours...
You are not led our way
We are led into your...
"The strongest board of directors
of the Soccer Federation".
We have 24 minutes...
- Are the girls here?
- Yes. They are all here.
Want to train or watch
the election results?
- Train!
- See the results!
Who wants to see the results,
raise your hand!
We hope that the concepts
change entirely.
We will find out who will occupy
the female vacancy...
Let's see the 8 candidates
for the women's vacancy...
- I think it must be Mervat...
- Mervat?!
In the experiment, I support Hanan.
She has worked very hard.
What about your
inflexibility?
Hanan is inflexible?!
- No, Hannan doesn't stand a chance...
- Why?
.....
Good God!
I am happy for you and your team.
I hope everyone accepts.
I hope so too.
I'm rooting for Hilal's men's team,
but I promise to cheer you on at the games.
You are very kind. Thank you!
Hey, Coach!
When do you announce the results
of the women's wave?
Not yet?
They are in the vice-presidency...
Are you still
in the vice presidency?
Hinda wants some ginger tea,
please.
- Right away, Hinda.
- Thank you, girls!
33 votes for Kamal Shaddad,
against Motassem...
34 for Kamal Hamed
Ibrahim Shaddad...
43 for Kamal Hamed
44 for Kamal Hamed
Ibrahim Shaddad...
Who's the boss? Kamal Shaddad!
Who is the boss? Kamal Shaddad!
They are counting the votes. We're waiting for
the results of the women's wave...
Now the result of the vote
for the women's seat in the Federation...
Nahed Bashir al-Baqir...
16 votes.
Mervat Hussen al-Sadeq...
20 votes.
Mervat won...
- Wow!
- Wow?
It stays in the same place.
You will continue
doing nothing...
No change
"The quiet soul"
Coach!
New Talents!
The tall girl is a tough one.
See how she kicks the ball?
They remind me of the old days.
Did you come on your own?
Come here!
The technician called them...
Hello, beautiful. What is your name?
Saja and Fidaa and Yusra
Want to see a picture
of our team?
Did you know that girls play soccer?
Or didn't you know?
I didn't know.
Fatouma, come here.
Look at this picture,
this is Coach Hinda.
Let's go,
take a closer look.
And this is me.
Want to see another picture?
Straight ahead.
A lot of drunk people here,
have you noticed?
Are there no sheep here?
In al-Hawa Street...
Why the bus
hasn't arrived yet...
What are you going to do?
We will buy our things
on a trip.
Can't we take
the sheep on our laps?
No, we can't.
The street is flooded.
Your friend is upset.
You brought us
the best you had.
Does it have sugar or not?
It doesn't...
Bring some for coffee
and morning tea.
Should I drink this or not?
A man flirted with me
in the store.
She is in a relationship.
I said
He fell in love with me
at first sight!
Dear Sir...
Can you imagine?
I said "no problem".
At first glance, Muhannad!
He asked me
where I lived...
I said Arkwit.
He asked, "Where are you from?"
"From here," I said.
He said,
"No, you are not."
I said, "I am a Southerner
mixed with Arab blood."
He said:
"Wow... I love you!"
He said,
"I'm going to visit him. Everything okay?"
I said, "No problem."
He asked if I was married
and I said no.
He said, "Well, I want you,
and asked me for the phone.
I gave him a wrong number.
Was he serious?
Of course I was serious.
The people of Darfur are straightforward!
People are already
are already celebrating...
Nancy, get rid of the bottles
of alcohol. The police are coming.
I studied and worked
at the same time.
I would get home at 1:00 in the morning
and get up at 6 a.m.
I worked cleaning toilets
and other simple jobs.
People talked...
But I was motivated
and with a goal to achieve.
If the Soccer Federation has sponsorship
for the men, it will have it for the women.
We have annual support from FIFA
since 1998.
They treat us
like an umbrella.
They ignore us and only turn to us
to us when they need us.
For how long
will they continue to treat us like this?
This is their right. If you don't demand it,
I can't do it all by myself.
It must not be like our politicians,
who talk but never act...
They only talk while our country
continues to go backwards.
They say, "We will do this and that
and we will support women's soccer".
And they have done nothing for us
since 1998.
The years have passed
and still no progress...
Our goal is to show people,
in Sudan and then in the rest of the world,
that there are girls who play soccer.
We have to pay out of our own pocket,
even if we have to beg.
I have a plan for women's soccer,
and you will see its impact.
Our goal is to disseminate
the culture of women's soccer.
But we have no sponsor
and the budget is pathetic.
Can you support us
with the transportation?
Give us the bus you have.
Are you still responsible for it?
Thank you very much, Coach.
I know you do what you can...
Who ordered the potatoes?
"Cultural and Athletic Challenge Club Support Fund
and Athletic Challenge".
Let me show you the research I did.
About what?
About women's sports
and that book I mentioned...
Women's sports
is one of your interests?
Never!
Impossible!
Are you interested
in sports, in general?
No!
Do you support women's soccer?
Never!
Is there a women's soccer team
team in Sudan?
No!
Do your family members support
your involvement in women's sports?
No!
Are you familiar with the International
FIFA?
God forbid!
Do you think there is a relationship
between politics and sports?
Scratch that question!
We know nothing about politics!
Do you think the biggest problem
that soccer faces is racism?
Objection... Objection, Sara!
This match is like a practice.
You know how to play.
The objective of this game is to show
people that we play soccer.
Are you okay?
Therefore,
there is no need to be afraid.
Play nice, girl!
Kick it again! Great!
Do you know how to dominate
the ball this way?
Oh smiling beauty
Your fragrance has captivated us
Our love for you is eternal
We ask for peace...
And an end to injustice
Life is like this...
But his days are numbered...
Sudan women's basketball team
team in 1976
Wesal Mousa Hasan,
Sudanese filmmaker in 1969
Pioneering Women of Sudan on the Front Lines
frontline of the 1964 protests
Al balabil, the group of three sisters,
Amal, Hadia and Hayah in 1970
The delegation representing Sudan
in Mexico in 1968