Human.
Here's the truth.
What is a human being?
It's not you, it's not me, it's not them. No.
The man is you.
me, them. the old man, Napoleon, Mohammed, in one.
Man this is huge!
It's all about beginnings and ends,
It's all in the man,
Everything for the man.
There is only the human being,
everything else is just a matter of his hands and his brain.
A man!
Chelovec.
That's great!
That sounds proud!
That sounds proud.
Recess.
So, can we have lunch?
You may.
Thank you.
Come on, maestro. Excuse me.
You're doing it again.
hiding the rehearsal.
Well, I can't get Satine!
I'm playing and I realize I'm in the wrong place.
(Footsteps on stage)
You need to believe in the sensitivity of the public.
You're a hard man to listen to.
The viewer, by your facial expressions and gestures,
what you're trying to tell them.
No, you keep playing that detail
And the tone.
Keep it upbeat, light, nervous.
I mean with a nerve.
Careless and nervous.
Light and carefree?
Imagine a dark, cold basement.
and for one coin.
you may be allowed to sleep under the bunks,
no pillow, no blanket.
And you only have one coin.
I'd like to see you feeling lighter,
after a night like this.
Barefoot who? People just like you and me.
They are, but they're not!
You and I are pampered by welfare,
makes a tragedy out of every problem.
Can't you see that Gorky's heroes,
for all their troubles
keep their spirits up,
a taste for life.
With all due respect, no.
I don't see it, because it doesn't happen in life.
And you and I have been creating
a theater to bring the truth of life to the people.
What is the truth of life?
You still don't know.
And the censors won't let us through
with that truth of yours.
Vladimir Ivanovich, and you
are familiar with
the master of sharp reportage?
Gilyarovsky, I think.
Familiar.
I hear he takes tours of Khitrovka.
What, you want to take a tour of these,
to the hot spots?
Introduce us.
They say he knows Khitrovka
and its inhabitants better than anyone.
Yes, Gorky also lived among the bums, but the fates
of his heroes were too punctilious.
Well, I don't have enough of that for Satin.
All right. (chuckles)
(harp playing)
(maitre d') I'm sorry, we're full.
And I have an appointment here
a meeting with Nemirovich-Danchenko.
Vladimir Ivanovich.
Vladimir Alexeyevich, dear!
Konstantin Sergeyevich!
Please love and pity.
Vladimir Alekseevich
Gilyarovsky, journalist, writer.
Famous researcher of Moscow slums.
I'm very glad.
Stanislavski.
Please.
(Gilyarovsky) Thank you.
(Maitre d') Menu.
I've heard a lot about you.
Talented actor, director.
Your theater is already a legend.
Thank you.
You're too kind.
Vladimir Ivanovich
said you'd taken on Gorky's new play. It's about bums.
That's a great idea.
That's why I really want to visit Khitrovka.
Can you take me there?
I can do that.
But I have to warn you right off the bat.
This is a very dangerous place.
Khitrovka, this is
not just beggar drunks.
Fugitive convicts, bandits and murderers hide there.
I'll go to Khitrovka myself
without brass knuckles
and I don't walk without a whip.
It's a scary place.
Vladimir Alexeyevich,
I've been reading your wonderful reports on Khitrovka,
and it seems to me,
that someone could write something like that
only a man who truly loves her.
Oh, come on. How can you love something like that?
No, no, no, no.
Konstantin Sergeyevich is right.
On Khitrovka, violence reigns, all the vices of the world.
all the vices of the world,
but I don't think you'll find a looser place.
It is always up to the individual here to choose how to act.
It's mesmerizing, you know!
Shall we go, then?
Did I scare you? Ha-ha.
I think I'll take my chances.
Gentlemen, are you ready to order?
Ah, consommé with nocelles,
game crepinettes, and a bottle of Lafite.
I'll have a boiled turbot,
with hollandaise sauce and a bottle of Rheinwein.
Here, by the way,
they serve a gorgeous salpicon on crunchies.
Highly recommended.
Yeah, that's great.
I'll have some sour soup.
And unfortunately, we don't serve soup.
I can offer you soup
licked with stuffed pickles.
Well! I think I'll pass!
Do you have any veal jelly with sour cream?
We'll find it.
And vodka!
(beggar's voice) Give me a hand for Christ's sake,
(singing a song to the harmonica)
Give it to me, for God's sake.
Now hold your pockets.
They'll be cleaned out in no time!
(They can also stab you with a knife.
Come and buy!
(dog yelling, barking)
This is the way through.
Baranki.
Aah!
Taste the pies, buy them!
Watch where you're going!
Let's buy! Spread out! Break it up!
Take it.
Just got here.
I made the deal first! It's my thing!
Check out the product, you won't regret it!
(harmonica and violin playing)
(Gilyarovsky) Over there.
Oh! Oh! Ho-ho!
Let's go, let's go.
Good wine. Let's buy it!
You won't regret it!
Don't be shy! Don't pass by!
Well, Konstantin Sergeyevich,
Come on, I'll show you the lodge.
Let's go.
(Gilyarovsky) Please.
It's called the Pig House after the name of the owner, Piggy.
Even the police don't poke their noses in there.
It's a busy place
Odor.
Here we go,
check it out.
(People Talking)
Let's go.
Come on.
Many years to Vladimir Alekseevich!
Thank you, brother! Thank you!
Many summers.....
(Gilyarovsky) Get outta here!
Vodka!
All of you!
(Gilyarovsky) After the fire
in the 12th year
General Khitrovo, built a remarkable square
front gardens, squares, then they added one market,
another.
The homeless, the vagrants, the unemployed appeared.
This is what we've got.
Why aren't they tearing it down?
Kulakov, the owner of the biggest lodging house,
he's a friend of the governor general.
And you know what that's like.
(horse neighing)
Well!
Welcome to the Convict Inn,
a den of outlaws,
thieves and fugitives!
Please!
(music playing)
Give me some vodka!
All right, clean this up!
half a bottle of vodka and some biscuits.
eggs, for an appetizer.
(Fighting, yelling)
(violin playing)
And what do you, you know them all?
Well, not all of them, of course, but I know some of them.
And he's over there, look.
Tell me, how old is this woman?
I'm afraid to guess.
She looks old.
And she's only 22 years old.
She's been a prostitute since she was eight years old.
Every new baby he has, he sells.
to beggars, and immediately spends the money on vodka.
Selling?
Yes! Here, on Khitrovka,
Children are the most traded commodity.
They are rented out to beggars from birth.
The last week of Lent,
a newborn baby to cry out, walks away ?
a quarter, a three-quarter, a hryvnia.
There were times when a child died in the morning, in the arms of beggars.
And she's still begging, till nightfall.
(song in French)
Who's that?
This is Ksenia Andreyevna.
Just princess.
Why princess?
Because they're real aristocrats.
How did she end up here?
Her father went bankrupt.
She ended up on Khitrovka as a girl.
To keep from starving, she learned to steal.
That's how it took root.
And now she is the Maruha of the most respected thief here, Baldoch.
I'm sorry, what did you say, Maruha?
Well, mistress or kept woman, whatever you like.
He's at the penitentiary, she's waiting for him,
Does she love him?
Who knows?
Vladimir Alexeyevich, introduce me.
I'm watching,
you can't resist her charms either.
Now.
Princess!
Come here!
Well, hello, Princess.
And good luck to you, too.
Have a seat.
How's it going?
Still going through your pockets?
Uncle Gilyai,
in front of strangers, don't embarrass me.
Well, when you were embarrassed about your truth.
I want you to meet him.
Konstantin Sergeyevich
Stanislavsky,...... our great director.
Have you heard of him?
No, I haven't.
Why,
wanted to tickle the nerves of vice?
Tickle your nerves.
You could say that,
Uncle Golay,
I'm sick of your
the curious.
They come to see us like a menagerie.
I'm not going to the menagerie, I need help.
We can help clean out your pockets.
No, really, I mean, I'm like,
I want to know,
what this man is like.
(Music playing)
Why?
It's not gonna work out,
what do you two have in common?
That's what this is all about.
In the play, I play a drunk.
And I, by all means,
I need to catch a glimpse of the real him.
Listen to this.
The man pays for everything himself.
To faith, to unbelief, to intelligence. To love.
That's why he's free.
Here, what is a human being?
A person is not you and me, not them..... No.
A person is you, me, them,
Napoleon, Mohammed in one.  It's huge!
A man is great! That sounds proud!
None of this is true.
What?
Well, as you have it, a man is a proud word.
Look at us.
Is this where a man can sound proud?
You say it with a sneer, with a chuckle,
I might have believed you,
( police yelling )
Bless you, Uncle Gilyai!
(Stanislavsky) What's going on?
(Gilyarovsky) Raid.
Now, everybody's gonna go up on the roof to wait it out.
But we shouldn't go there.
Let me introduce you to someone
I'd like you to meet a very interesting man.
Let's go.
A real Indian lives here.
Name's Raja.
But I think it's a nickname.
No one knows his real name.
An Indian?
(Gilyarovsky) Yes, he proudly calls himself a Seagh.
He has this amazing red turban
which he never takes off.
I think he sleeps in it.
How did he end up in Russia?
Who knows?
He doesn't tell us anything about himself.
An enigmatic personality.
The house from the inside looks like the cave of 40 bandits,
from the tale of 1,000 and One Nights.
He and I play chess sometimes.
Vladimir Alexeyevich, I think the door is open.
Is it open?
That's weird.
But since it's open, let's go in.
(footsteps on stairs)
(parrot squawking)
(disturbing music)
What's wrong with him?
Dead.
We should call the police.
(Laughter and street noise)
( horse neighing )
(Whistling)
Call Rudnikov!
That Raju has finally been whacked.
Bite your tongue and move your heels,
(Rudnikov) Well, show me where to go.
I've never been here.
(Gilyarovsky) Right here.
Maykov, wait for me here. Well, well,
And who are you, sir?
This is the alleged crime scene.
There should be no outsiders here.
It's with me. Konstantin Sergeyevich Stanislavsky,
the great director.
Another sightseer, then?
For God's sake, don't touch anything with your hands.
Let's go.
Ooh, so Raja passed away,
Kingdom of Heaven.
or whatever they're supposed to do.
Here Fedot look, here.
Vladimir Alexeyevich.
you're the one who pulled me out of pleasant company.
What's the rush?
Well, a dead body.
if I'd waited a couple or three
hours, I don't think he'd go anywhere.
(parrot squawking)
Aha!
(Gilyarovsky) I'm thinking, who could have killed him?
No, of course he's been doing
some shady dealings with the tricksters.
(Rudnikov) Ahh, the Khitrovites have it simple, finca,
cleaver, axe.
And there's the murder weapon,
some kind of toothpick. Yes?
(Rudnikov) Toothpick?
Vladimir Alexeyevich, what is it?
(Rudnikov) Don't touch it with your hands.
Well, what, what.
Some kind of decoration.
It's not like it's hanging on a nail.
It's stuck right into the wall.
(Rudnikov) What's the difference?
Raja here, the Oriental antiquities shop.
What wonders there are.
(Gilyarovsky) And yet,
who could have killed him?
I can't assume such a person has,
like Raja, had no enemies.
What do you want from me?
No forced entry, so no robbery.
There's no sign of a struggle, and what's missing is, or
it's not gone,
it's a hell of a mess.
Lots of goodness.
What if it's someone he knows?
Maybe he let him in.
I mean, who do you know who he knows?
And you, do you know many of his acquaintances?
Yeah, I guess no one.
Uh-huh.
So here I am, nobody but you.
You told me yourself, about your chess games.
Maybe you killed him.
Because of a lost chess game.
(Rudnikov) Well, confess, did you kill?
(Gilyarovsky) Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha. Funny!
(Rudnikoff) Yeah, it's funny.
Gentlemen, there's another dart here.
Just don't touch it with your hands.
Why here?
Why,
Why.
The killer missed.
Vladimir Alekseyevich, you should stay out of the investigators' business,
I'll do it without you.
Fedot Ivanovich, I'll take this and then we'll leave at once?
Kha, take it.
I don't need him.
(Rudnikov) Maykov!
All right, I want this place searched,
and then lock it down and don't let anyone in.
Take the bird, or it will die. Do it!
(Stanislavsky) Wait,
Check it out,
Who's that?
Like who. It's the Rajah himself.
Yes.... It's been over 10 years,
and he hasn't changed at all.
And he sailed on the steamship Petersburg?
Who knows.
Maybe I did.
His life is a mystery.
And now, it's going to go away altogether.
Let's go.
So what, they're gonna find the killer now?
I don't think so.
I don't think Raja has any relatives.
Soon, his assets will be dispersed into offices,
and he'll be safely forgotten.
But it's a fascinating case.
First of all, you have to figure it out,
what this mysterious toothpick is.
And can you die from such a small wound?
Uh, hold on.
Take a closer look.
The sharp end is a different color.
Maybe it's lubricated with something?
It's possible.
I know someone who can help us figure it out.
(Gilyarovsky) Professor! He's always being carried around somewhere.
Professor!
Where'd he go?
(Professor) Gelyai, are you?
Я!
You're so out of touch.
Come on in. I'll be right down.
Here's the professor, meet the professor.
Konstantin Sergeyevich
Stanislavsky, director and actor.
Yes, a great actor,
founder of the Moscow Art Theater.
And this is Agafon Spiridonovich Trassenmaer.
Doctor.
You can just call me Professor.
Look at him, he's beautiful!
Fresh.
It's only three hours,
Like a stabbing.
Professor, aren't you afraid they'll be looking for him?
WELL. by the time they realize
there'll be nothing left of him.
(Beggar) Professor, five kopecks are missing.
Come back in two days.
Not a dime now.
(beggar) Scrooge.
(Professor) Right! Nutis.
(Stanislavsky) What are you doing?
(professor) What does a director do?
Rehearsing.
And I'm a surgeon. I have to rehearse, too.
If there's anything that needs to be cut, feel free to ask.
(Gilyarovsky) Professor,
we've brought you something very interesting.
I bet you can't surprise me with anything right now.
(Gilyarovsky) Oh!
(Professor) Looks like I've lost.
(Gilyarovsky) Ah!
(Professor) Ask where you got it from, I guess there's no point.
Do you think you could kill a man with that?
Depends on what the stuff is impregnated with.
(Gilyarovsky) And?
I need time.
(Gilyarovsky) A day...
Two, three,
But no guarantees.
(Gilyarovsky) Okay, I'll come back in two days.
So long.
Let's go, Konstantin Sergeyevich!
(Nemirovich-Danchenko) The stoker is drunk again.
(Stanislavsky) So hire someone else.
(Nemirovich-Danchenko) The other will have to pay, twice as much.
Don't forget, if we're
we want to keep the lead actors this season,
they need to raise their salaries, and the prices
and everything's going up.
Only on firewood will we spend.....
3 000 ₽.
That being said, don't forget the royalties to the authors.
I've already paid the advance to Gorky.
Take my director's fee.
And for you in Three Sisters,
I want gooseberry jam on stage.
Not only is it
you can't find it anywhere else, it costs a fortune,
a fortune.
Vladimir Ivanovich, but you're a director.
And Chekhov said that gooseberries,
was Vershinin's favorite berry.
No one in the audience can see
what kind of jam Vershinin is eating on stage.
I can see that.
And, by the way, that watchman of yours is new,
what's his name?
Nemirovich-Danchenko) Kolotushkin.
He's a whisperer.
So what?
How and what?
How can a man like that even serve in the theater?
It's a theater!
Konstantin Sergeyevich,
our censors won't let "At the Bottom" through.
And you me about Kolotushkin!
(quiet music) Here, listen to what they say.
There is absolutely no plot in the play.
All that is present is a lot of random running around.
Or here's another thing, unchanged,
a play can't be not only produced,
but simply published.
It's unclear,
whether Gorky would even be allowed to return to Moscow.
I, of course, wrote police department, but--
(Stanislavsky) I beg your pardon,
(Nemirovich-Danchenko) Where are you going?
We're rehearsing.
Start without me.
All the mise-en-scène I've mapped out.
Konstantin Sergeyevich!
(man) Darling, do you have any white roses?
(florist) Unfortunately, no.
(wife) Darling, but who gives white roses on a birthday?
(man) I know what my sister likes.
(wife) Yeah, you know, but I always pick the gift.
Girls like brighter colors.
The princess speaks French.
Anna Shafran Manifesto of Mademoiselle.
(wife) At least take the red one!
(man) Red?
It is in the language of flowers, the color of passion.
Maybe,
white? The color of innocence and purity.
Ksenia Andreyevna!
Let me in, I don't know you,
Bring it back,
or I'll call a policeman.
(cabbie) Hey! Look out!
(man) Let's have the red ones.
You're welcome.
(wife) Here, I think it's a little fresher.
(man) Yes, darling, it's all for you.
(flower girl) You have good taste! Nice flowers!
The princess speaks French.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
(man) What? Where?
My God, my God, how can it be?
(wife) Andrei Ivanovich, you always lose everything!
Didn't you recognize me?
I'm Konstantin Stanislavsky, director.
Yesterday we were introduced by Gilyarovsky.
(Princess) By your grace, I'm left without a living today.
Alas, I could not do otherwise.
Let me take you out for coffee.
If I'm going to coffee,
definitely not with you.
Let me make it up to you.
How much do you need?
Are you just going to give the money to a thief
to a thief?
Not for nothing, .... for talking,
All right. Uh-huh.
But I'm still not having coffee with you.
(voice-over) Stop at Khitrovsky Lane!
You're weird.
Who could possibly be interested, a play about bums?
Aren't bums people?
The exes, the disgraced, the lost.
Is that what people are going to be called?
It's, uh, more out of fear.
After all, it is easier to shut out than to try to understand.
Understand what?
Why people, between a normal life
and the slums, they choose the slums.
You, you know how to dress nicely.
That's not my dress.
It doesn't matter.
You know how to behave socially,
You speak good French.
Why are you still on Khitrovka?
You have everything you need to live a private life.
I was brought up in Khitrovka.
My daddy, in a fit of white fever,
hit my mom in the head with a stool.
Then he died in Siberia, on a penal servitude.
And I was only four years old at the time.
Who needed me?
For the first couple years, I lived with an old beggar.
And stealing for her at the market,
to pay for a night's lodging.
And then this woman died.
I've been taken in by cats!
Cats?
Pimps,
according to you.
Because everything you just told me is not true.
Yeah, it's not true.
Don't take me any further.
Why?
Strangers are not welcome on Khitrovka!
And Uncle Gilyai is not with you now.
(cabbie) Look out!
Well, here you are!
And it's good to see you.
Your share.
There's a kha for you,
Rudnikov is waiting.
It's a great honor.
What does he want?
Why do I know?
But I wouldn't go.
Well, I have no sins.
(innkeeper murmurs)
(Voice) ...don't know anything.
Remembering Pharaoh following you....
(laughter)
Hello, Fedot Ivanovich!
Are you waiting for me?
You.
To what do I owe?
I was just wondering,
on Baldoch, not so much.
miss me?
Well, what's there to miss?
I'm a free bird.
Aah! We know how free-spirited you are.
Tell me,
and isn't that you,
he always had on his packages?
No catch, no thief.
But, uh. that's if you're not caught.
That's it, sweetheart!
Well, uh. your handkerchief?
Well, mine.
Well, you're keeping your mouth shut, that's good.
They found it at Raja's.
You don't remember when you dropped it?
I wasn't at Raja's.
You didn't?
It wasn't.
You'll be in a cell for a while.
You'll remember something.  Yes?
Here you go.
(Gilyarovsky) Rudnikov at his place?
(policeman) At himself.
(high-pitched noise)
I told you not to come to my place
to Khitrovka! Go!
О! Vladimir Alexeyevich!
What are you doing here?
Fedot Ivanovich?
I heard that you're the Princess
arrested for the murder of Raja.
(Rudnikov) Moscow is quickly filled with rumors.
Please.
Well, Vladimir Alexeyevich,
you're still in love with being a detective, aren't you?
What makes you think the murderer is the princess?
Here... That's what makes professionals different,
from amateurs. Perseverance and meticulousness.
Now you're gone, and my boys are along
and searched Raji's house and found it there,
this is her handkerchief.
What makes you think the handkerchief is hers?
The whole of Khitrovka
knows that Baldoch gave his princess
five dozen silk handkerchiefs, monogrammed.
And she dropped one of them at Raja's place.
(Stanislavsky) But that's not enough to prove guilt.
No, it's not enough.
But it's enough to get her
for her to plead guilty voluntarily.
Did she admit it?
No, not yet.
Stubborn girl.
It's okay, he'll confess.
Where's she gonna go?
Fedot Ivanovich, let me talk to her, huh?
It doesn't seem to fit.
Princess. Darts.
Why would she kill Raju?
Vladimir Alexeyevich,
here you are on Khitrovka, not the first year.
And you should know that there are crimes
for no reason at all, they do it all the time.
I'm not gonna let you talk.
You'll only embarrass her.
Still, I don't believe
that Ksenia Andreyevna could have killed.
She and I met casually the other day, had a chat.
She turned out to be a very deep person.
Konstantin Sergeyevich, you're an idealist!
I've seen it on Khitrovka.
And then the princess, she's a thief, a bandit's mistress.
Fedot Ivanovich is right, for a murder on Khitrovka,
you don't need a motive.
A cabbie!
I've seen how your Fedot Ivanovich works.
Well, our tour is over.
I did my best.
I think that's enough to work on the play.
Thank you.
With me?
No.
I think I'll take a walk.
Have a nice stay.
(Stanislavsky) If you're near the theater, drop by.
(Gilyarovsky) By all means.
Stoleshnikov.
(cabbie) Well!
(street noise)
(bells ringing)
(disturbing music)
Well, well, well.
The esteemed director breaks into the seat.
of committing a crime without police authorization.
That's a great headline for the papers!
It's just beautiful!
Ha-ha! What are you doing here?
Well, apparently the same as you.
I just came by to see
see if I could find anything interesting.
So how did you get in?
Just like you.
Through an open window.
It has to be,
the police forgot to lock up.
Do you hear that?
The door opened,
(Door creaks)
Someone's in here!
Maybe the police?
I don't think so.
And who?
What?
Quiet!
Who are you gentlemen?
Who the hell are you?
I am the nephew of the owner of this house.
How do you prove it?
I have a picture in my purse.
I'll let you go now, but no tricks.
What's your name?
Sanji.
What about you?
Stanislavsky, director.
Gilyarovsky.
Reporter.
Vladimir Alexeyevich?
Well.
(nephew) I've heard.
That's your uncle playing chess with you.
Well, where is he?
You probably don't know.
Your uncle was murdered.
We offer our sincere condolences.
Aah! Yeah! That's a serious blow to me.
My uncle brought me back as a boy from India.
Gave education.
How did he die?
In his neck, there was a dart sticking out.
Probably poisoned.
That's weird.
What do you think,
why would your uncle be killed?
I don't know.
No, of course he was doing
in some not-so-legal endeavors.
And Khitrovka is full of dangerous people.
And he's not that easy to kill.
He always had Chakra on him.
Chakra? What's that?
An ancient Indian throwing weapon.
Metal ring, with sharpened edges.
Is that her?
Yeah, that's her.
So there was a fight.
Someone comes to Raja's house at night.
He's letting him in.
The conversation turns into an argument. Raja
throws chakra,
but misses.
Do you know this house well?
Can you tell if there's anything missing?
Well, uh. it's gonna take me a while,
even though there's a stash.
My uncle showed it to me a few years ago.
He asked me to get something out of him,
if anything happens to him.
We can take a look.
She's gone.
What's not?
Caskets.
There must be something very valuable in it.
My uncle's a big fan of rarities,
started collecting them,
when....(dart whistle)
What's wrong with him?
Murdered!
Ooh! Get back, get back!
Well, well, well. Stop! Konstantin Sergeyevich, stay here.
I'll be right back.
No, I'm in.
(disturbing music)
(children screaming)
He's gone. Uh-huh!
Take a look.
А? That's weird.
The foot feels like it's bifurcating.
I've never seen anything like this before.
It's really weird. Everything
about this case,
it's all very strange.
Well, we should call Rudnikov.
He's gonna be so happy.
The princess is in a cell,
which means we have to look for the real killer. А!
(children's voices)
Let's go.
(Dart whistles)
What are you doing, Professor,
you want to kill the last person
who has bright feelings for you?
I didn't put poison on them.
The worst you could do was get your eye taken out.
Which is fine, of course.
Come on in, let's shoot.
I think they use this thing, like that.
I conducted a series of experiments
in which my favorite rat died.
But I still have the other one.
Would you like to see the effects of poison on a rat?
You don't have to.
We've seen that recently.
Yes? That's a shame.
Professor, what kind of poison is this?
You have no idea how many plants there are
that you can make
amazing poisons!
The choice depends on
how you want to kill your victim.
Instantly or make her suffer.
Professor, get to the point,
The poison was manufactured
from the seeds of the rare Abrus precatorius plant.
A rosary man.
In fact, to kill a person with this poison,
it doesn't even need to enter the bloodstream.
Just apply to the skin and it's done.
The Breadwinner
grows in hot countries with high levels of humidity.
humidity levels.
Southeast Asia, Burma, India.
But then I have no idea
how he could have gotten to Russia, I have no idea.
Raja from India,
this dart, it's a salute to his past.
Well, Professor, brilliant!
You're as good as ever!
(Professor) I haven't said anything new.
But thank you, it's nice.
Maybe we should
see how the poison works on the second rat.
Some other time.
We should probably get going. See you later.
Okay, have a good one.
(street noise)
(prostitutes laughing) Give me a cigarette!
Aren't you the barman?
I'm the barmaid. But I can see that,
you're not here to drink vodka.
Behind the dirty rags, you can't hide your origins.
Why are you here, gentlemen?
Satan needs to be talked to.
I don't know that one.
And you say Golay is here.
He knows.
All right. Uh-huh.
Escort your guests to the underworld.
(fighting noises)
(dogs barking)
(woman screaming)
A lot of knowledge,
many sorrows.
(disturbing music)
Golay, do I need to remind you what happens with
by those who come here uninvited?
Probably the same thing that's happening to those
who are in no hurry to pay back their debts.
Who's that?
Our great director, Stanislavski.
You ever heard of it?
No, I haven't.
That the director,
has brought you here, huh?
You have three minutes.
I wanted to know,
if it's surfaced on Khitrovka lately,
of some particularly valuable item.
But you know the rules.
I don't give up mine.
You know I don't give yours up either.
I'd like to have a word with the man
A very valuable thing, you say?
Yes, very much so.
Then not us.
We only work with the small stuff.
If anything, I'm serious, is this to Testov or Brown?
Brown's on the water right now.
And Testov?
And Testov doesn't deal with Khitrov's.
Only with Baldoch.
And only because he's a virtuoso.
Baltoch is on penal servitude.
I heard he escaped,
(Gilyarovsky) Did you hear or did you run away?
I heard.
All right! Time!
Well, we'll go.
It was a pleasure to meet you, have a nice day.
Did you have a good time?
Oh, that's great.
(click)
(screams fighting)
Ha!...That was convincing.
Vladimir Alekseyevich.
(Gilyarovsky) Okay.
We gotta get outta here.
Please. Hoo!
Ahaa!
(dogs barking)
Hoo!
What do you think,
Has Boltoch really escaped from hard labor?
Well, if Satan said he heard it,
then he escaped.
And where he could be hiding,
is here, on Khitrovka.
(Whistling)
Who's Testov?
Tests?
Nicanor Ivanovich, a well-known antiquarian in Moscow.
Which means he's not shy about buying stolen goods.
Then we must go to Nicanor Ivanovich.
(street noise)
Thank you
Vladimir Alexeyevich, see Bacchus,
of Michelangelo's work.
There must be a copy.
(Testov) Yes yes, of course, it's a copy.
Dear Konstantin Sergeyevich, 18th century.
I bought it in Florence from Count Strozzi.
Oh, I'm so glad!
I couldn't dream.
Saw "Three Sisters," your Vershinin,
this is something amazing!
So much restraint, so much nobility.
(Thank you.
So, Vladimir Alexeyevich, what brings you here?
You're not here to write a crime story, are you?
No, not a chronicle.
I just came by to ask if you've ever had
for days. some
an interesting offer? А?
Uh, Vladimir Alexeyevich!
Nikanor Ivanovich?
You've got the nose of a dog!
It was.
A ragamuffin came in,
brought a box of extraordinary beauty.
Where'd you get it?
Of course he did.
It's in the box,
It took my breath away.
The Spark of the East herself!
Spark of the East,
allow this......
The most unique necklace
An emerald of rare magnitude.
With a gold setting studded with diamonds.
And guess what, gentlemen,
I see this necklace in much the same way,
as you are now, in the hands of some ragamuffin!
And you bought it?
No. Real antique dealers
there's a rule,
we never buy stolen goods.
Must have turned the ragamuffin in to the police?
No, come on. I mean, they're clients.
Clients are sacred to us.
I just, I just walked him out.
And gentlemen, you know what.
just yesterday
an investigator came to see me,
with that accent.
English, I guess.
The most beautiful cane he had, the head of it.
skillfully carved in the shape of a winged beast,
with the body of a man and the head of a bird.
And what's the investigator?
And the investigator told me about the theft,
but he wouldn't tell me what was stolen.
But I knew right away
that this was about the Spark of the East.
So I told him the whole story.
Really, I think for an investigator,
his suit was too expensive.
And that cane!
What a curious story?
Exactly, exactly.
I think it would make.... a novella or a good play.
How fortunate we're here.
You know,
which, I'm sorry,
Konstantin Sergeyevich wanted to invite you to the theater.
Me?
Yes, yes, with my wife.
We have an opening night coming up.
We're doing a play by Gorky.
Well, I'm glad. We'll be there, of course, we will.
I'd love to.
All right. I guess we should get going.
Have a nice day.
Good to meet you, gentlemen,
(cane tapping)
Are you here yet?
I wasn't expecting you for another hour.
The back door was open.
How long have you been here?
Enough to hear everything you've said.
Who are these gentlemen?
Don't you know that?
These are our celebrities.
Directed by Stanislavsky, written by Nemirovsky.
You should definitely go see
to some Stanislavski production.
What he does on stage is something incredible.
Why did you tell on me?
Yeah, I'm just giving them a plot for a story.
or maybe a play.
Don't worry,
they won't take this story seriously.
Creative people.
And in our business,
connections are always important.
And then,
at this address at four o'clock
you'll be waiting for Boldoh at noon.
You definitely saw the necklace.
How are you now?
That's weird, that box has a secret.
And there are only two people who know this secret.
One of them is dead.
The second, yours truly.
The thing is, Baldoh
some kind of hacking genius.
There's nothing closed that he can't open.
Anything else?
Circumstances have changed.
I'll bring you the necklace tonight.
You'll pay me the full amount at once.
Oh-ho-ho-ho! Sweetest. No, no, no.
I'm afraid that's out of the question.
You have no reason to distrust me.
Then how about me, on your account.
Uh, well, uh,
let's just leave it at that. Today.
You bring me the goods,
and I'll send you the money tomorrow.
Otherwise, I wish you good luck finding a new buyer.
All right. Uh-huh.
The arrangements remain in place.
Think about it.
Where am I going to get away from you?
It's true!
Still, you shouldn't have said that much about me.
Shit! English!
(disturbing music)
(Dart whistles)
(quiet music)
Konstantin Sergeyevich,
Messrs. Chekhov and Nemirovich-Danchenko are waiting for you.
Please.
О! Ohh!
Anton Pavlovich, how nice to see you!
Mutual, mutual, please.
Thank you.
You're late, Konstantin Sergeyevich, we've already had lunch.
I'm not having lunch.
Suit yourself.
О! Ooh! Look at that!
Oh, my God.
that this is a greeting from the underworld.
It's a breakthrough in the restaurant business and a triumph of chemistry,
to make ice cream with liquid nitrogen.
How does it feel?
It's very curious.
Well, I really want to try this.
You guys have no peace of mind.
Anton Pavlovich,
we have Stanislavsky as a detective.
Oh, come on!
Yeah, he and Gilyarovsky have been going at it nonstop.
from the slums of Khitrov.
With Golay?
You can do it with Golay, it's okay with Golay.
By the way, I had him on vacation in Melikhovo last summer.
So he walked 80 miles in a day, killed a bear,
a fox and a lot of hares.
The thing is, we're involved in a very mysterious story.
a very mysterious story.
Konstantin Sergeyevich,
is a thrill-seeker.
Why me, too. About 10 years ago.
traveled from Siberia to Sakhalin,
and back by steamboat
through China, Burma and India.
It's been a wonderful journey.
Lots of, as you say, thrills.
Have you sailed past India?
That's right.
Then maybe you've heard of this strange weapon,
little darts soaked in poison?
They shoot them out of tubes like this.
You won't believe it, but I heard it.
Anton Pavlovich, don't keep me in suspense.
Sailing through the Indian Ocean,
We made a stop off the Andaman Islands
to pick up an Indian,
Sigha, who had just finished his service
in a British penal colony. It's a horrible place,
he said it was.
But that's not what this is about.
He asked me about Russia, I asked him about the islands.
And there's a tribe right there
Thank you.
dwarf savages,
who hunt with the aid
these little poisoned arrows.
Very similar to what you describe.
Did this tribe have any specialties,
maybe congenital deformities, or not all toes?
I don't know how I know!
But very much so,
maybe because they live extremely poor.
They say they even sell their children
to the British as servants.
Gentlemen! This is all very entertaining, of course.
Let's finally talk about the case.
Anton Pavlovich,
I apologize.
Anton Pavlovich, I believe your new play is a comedy?
Oh! It's not just comedy, it's farcical in places.
I really like the title I came up with
"The Cherry Orchard."
I'm sorry, could it be cherry?
No, no, no, that's the cherry one.
Cherry Orchard,
That sounds beautiful!
Yes.
Here we go,
by the way, how's the work going
on the Gorky play?
It's hard. With this censorship,
it's a disaster. It's rampant.
You.
Thank you.
Well, I've met Gavriil Kharitonovich,
hopefully he'll help us.
We'll be sure to put on your Cherry Orchard.
Ha ha ha! I'm telling you, it sounds!
Gentlemen, if you'll excuse me.
Urgent matters.
Anton Pavlovich was very happy to see you.
Gilyarovsky, hello!
I will.
Vladimir Ivanovich,
if you wouldn't mind grabbing the play.
What can I say, though?
Stanislavski.
Yes.
How interesting!
What's interesting?
An unusual dramaturgical twist.
Just like Shakespeare.
We're the only ones who left. И.
So?
Konstantin Sergeyevich
says it's a high-profile murder,
you can't blame someone else!
You really didn't find anything?
Nothing.
It's a hell of a thing.
What's this?
Come on.
Well, some kind of note.
To whom it is addressed is unclear.
I don't know how many of these are written in a day.
I beg your pardon, Fedot Ivanovich, there's an inconsolable widow.
Ooh! Excuse me, gentlemen,
I must leave you for a moment.
I beg you, don't touch anything here.
Yeah, yeah, sure,
Please don't touch anything!
Maykov with me!
(widow's lament)
I apologize.
This note is addressed to us.
The foreigner you're interested in,
is staying in a hotel, and there's no name.
Why do you think this note is addressed to us?
But I think the foreigner
is the Englishman who's supposedly the investigator.
Why go to all this trouble?
Why didn't Testov just tell us that?
So he couldn't.
This note was written
right after we talked to him.
We were discussing the necklace, the ragamuffin.
and the Englishman who was interested in the necklace.
Testov is killed right after he tells us
he tells us about the Englishman.
Could the murderer be an Englishman?
Why not a ragamuffin?
Testov was killed just like Raju and his nephew.
And darts are such a rare weapon
that I'm sure the killer is the same person.
Besides, you said it yourself,
Where are the Hitrovians and where are the darts.
And how did the Englishman know
that Testov was telling us about him?
He was probably eavesdropping on us.
There's a back door somewhere.
Yes,... nothing to hold on to.
Here, let me see,
Ha! Looks like Testov before he died,
wrote another note.
I never would have thought to perform
that kind of manipulation.
How come?
I told you.
when I was a kid, I dreamed of being a Pinkerton.
In one of his investigations,
he found the killer that way.
Gateway Quay near the abandoned docks.
Awesome! Awesome!
So you know where it is?
Let's find it.
I'm more than sure this is the meeting place,
an Englishman and a ragamuffin.
We have to hurry.
They were supposed to meet somewhere around here.
See also,
(Crows cawing)
(Gilyarovsky) Aha! There's our virtuoso.
Please make your acquaintance.
The legendary thief of Khitrov,
Mr. Baldoch. Rudnikov will be so happy.
He chased him around Khitrovka for a long time.
(Stanislavsky) What a horrible death.
(Gilyarovsky) Yeah!
Believe me, there's a lot of jiu-jitsu involved,
it's not without jiu-jitsu.
Look, same weird footprints,
that we saw at Raja's house.
So there were two perps.
Our Englishman and some unknown.
a creature with a two-toed foot.
It's all very similar to what Chekhov was talking about.
I think there's something to this
a dwarf savage from the Andaman Islands.
So you think an Englishman
brought to Russia from who knows where, this savage?
Why go to such pains?
Then the dwarf has a unique weapon,
darts that bring instant death!
Maybe, maybe.
All right, let's get out of here.
There's nothing more for us to do here,
so let Rudnikov handle it.
So you're saying
that the Englishman brought a dwarf.
Why is Baldoch killed
not with a dart? Because a fight broke out.
I think I understand Boldoch. He escaped from the penitentiary
and hid at Raja's house,
and the princess knew about it and visited him there.
She also dropped her handkerchief there, so she is silent,
He's afraid to give Baldoch up.
Baldoh happened to see the killers
Raji and scared them away.
While he was hiding out at Raji's,
must have gotten a glimpse of the stash.
and when Raju was killed,
seized the moment,
somehow managed to open the stash,
stole the necklace and wanted to sell it to Testov.
Testov decided not to get his hands dirty and sent an Englishman
the Englishman for the necklace.
Baldoch recognized the Englishman as the murderer and realized that he would not get out of here alive.
he would never get out of here alive.
That's why it's probably English,
and the necklace, already
somewhere very far away.
Nah, Baldock is an experienced thief.
He wouldn't take the necklace
to meet the unsub.
In that case, we need to understand,
what this Englishman will do now.
Will be looking for Baldoch's stash.
Well, or people who know where the stash is.
Like the princess.
She's on the police force, you can't get her that easily.
Yes. But we're not going to see her until tomorrow.
Do you have any plans for tonight?
There will always be plans.
Then we'll have to cancel them.
We're playing Chekhov tonight at 8:00.
You haven't seen his Three Sisters yet, have you?
No.
It's fine.
Tararabumbia, I'm sitting on a bollard.
And I weep bitterly.
He's just sitting there,
sits.
Why?
Nothing.
Did you love my mother?
Very much so.
When you take happiness in bits and pieces,
and then you lose it.
Like me.
You're getting rougher little by little,
you get mean.
That's where I'm simmering.
(disturbing music)
(dogs barking)
(Door creaks)
What can I get you?
My name is William Fox.
I'm a representative of a charity
"Angels of Peace.
We help people of noble birth,
in difficult situations.
There's a lady sitting here.
I'd like to talk to her.
Not allowed.
Bravo! Bravo!
Bravo!
(applause)
I'm William Fox,
from a British charity.
For a foreigner, you speak good Russian.
I've been traveling around Russia for two years now.
I like your country,
a lot of fun,
but that's not what this is about.
I have a business proposition for you.
I don't do business with strangers.
And we know each other.
Ksenia Andreyevna,
in absentia through Baldoch.
I don't know that one.
He has a thing, my thing, a very trifling thing.
It has value only to me,
because it belonged to my late mother.
Well, ask him.
Give her back to me.
I'll pay 5,000 rubles.
For nothing?
Meet Ponda, my servant.
A very unusual creature.
The last of Jarova's tribe of cannibals,
from the Andaman Islands.
Fires poisoned darts without missing a beat.
One scratch and the man is dead.
Go on, Pongo, go on.
You're scary.
Mademoiselle.
Pongo is basically an animal.
You never know what he'll do.
Okay, where were we?
Oh, yeah, that thing.
It was my mother's.
It's priceless to me.
I want to know where that thing is.
I don't know,
Ask Baldoch if you can find it.
I'm afraid he'll never tell anyone again.
Think about it.
That's it! Come on.
Well, Vladimir Alexeyevich,
I guess you can't avoid a great article
on the efficient work of the Moscow detective service.
Why, is there any good news?
Well, of course.
You're the one who brought them to me.
Found the killer,
a Baldoch, a thief and a convict on the run,
who has disposed of respectable gentlemen,
with particular cruelty.
And the reasons why, we unfortunately can't know,
because his own accomplices
killed him themselves. А!
(Stanislavsky) Well, you know it's not him.
That's it, case closed.
Besides, I'm going to make
a report to the chief of police.
Good! А! Fedot, may I have a word with the Princess?
Beautiful woman!
But, stupid is stupid.
All women are stupid!
How many times have I told her,
you have to build relationships with decent people.
And she got involved with this Baldoh.
They all come, the same way.
Teach them, teach them.
Fedot, huh?
So I put her down,
How'd they let you go?
There you go,
hold it back, wrong, let it go.
wrong, what am I supposed to do?
What have you done?
She is now in mortal danger.
(street noise)
(bazaar noise)
Hello, Mademoiselle!
Have you decided something?
I asked you to help me find my mother's item.
(disturbing music)
All right. Uh-huh,
I'll check the stash, but I'll go alone.
I don't feel right about giving away secret places.
If there's anything in there, I'll get it,
wherever you say,
in two hours.
Don't play games with me.
If there's something you're not happy about,
let your freak kill me right now,
In two hours,
There will be a carriage parked outside the inn.
Ponga will be on the goats,
you can't go wrong.
And don't let your freak follow me around.
Otherwise, you'll never see
the thing that belonged
to your mother.
It's a deal.
I hope you realize that deceiving me
there's no point.
Hey! Dude! Come here!
Listen, Princess, you're a beautiful woman.
Boldoh has been killed.
Come on, you'll be my mammy.
There's not enough money.
Well, we'll see about that.
All right, listen up.
Did Baldoch leave a big inheritance?
He did, he didn't,
what business is it of yours!
What's Baldoha's is mine.
You know the law.
No offense.
Give me what you got
What a jerk!
You bitch! Who you think you're fooling!
I'm gonna paint your face so bad,
that the very last
a beggar won't take you!
Draw as much as you want!
No, there's nothing else.
What are you watching?
Get out!
(Pantaloons! Let's get the knickers!
Handkerchiefs, handkerchiefs. Coming up! Let's buy!
(lock clicks)
Would you like to see it?
You're a very beautiful woman.
I would suggest that you come with me,
but I don't think you'd agree.
I disagree.
Aren't you forgetting something?
Thank you.
It's nice to do business with a real gentleman.
Did you?
I did.
Good for you!
Go to the rear!
I'll take command of the operation.
Fedot Ivanovich, good to see you!
Dear Avdotya Mikhailovna!
How is Platon Afanasyevich's health?
I hope all is well. Bow to him.
And here I am. catching a dangerous criminal.
Fedot, maybe it's time to start.
I'll ask you not to interfere.
I have everything under control.
Maykov, follow me!
Surround the carriage!
Well? Where's the perpetrator?
Goddamn English.
Where could they have gone?
Petrukhin! Go to the inn and search it. Move it!
Fedot Ivanovich, everything was sealed off, no mouse could get through.
What mouse?
Where are they then?
You've gone to heaven?
They are not saints. Search!
Vladimir Alekseyevich,
Yes
Konstantin Sergeyevich.
What's up? What you got there?
Oh, you're so sly! А!
That's where the Neglinnaya River flows below us.
and flows into the Bypass Canal.
This tunnel,
I know like the back of my hand, it's not going anywhere!
But you're not welcome with me,
or the suit.... you'll have to forget it.
Don't get your hopes up.
It's that easy,
you're not getting rid of me.
Suit yourself.
Fedot Ivanovich, you give us two policemen,
You take a boat and meet us there,
where the Neglinnaya
into the bypass canal. I got it!
I don't know what to do.
Look, the director's coming too.
All right, two over here!
Maykov, the rest of you, follow me!
Quickly to the Crimean bridge, take a boat.
And to the canal. We'll meet them there!
(water running)
Oh, my God, what is that?
There's a lot more to see here!
I don't think this canal's been cleaned since Catherine the Great.
the Great.
Gentlemen, we're going to have to split up here.
You go down this tunnel, we'll go down this tunnel.
They both go into the bypass channel.
That's where we'll take the Englishman down.
Konstantin Sergeyevich, take the flashlight.
Hands, I could still use them.
Let's go.
Thank you
Careful.
Uh, hold on.
Check it out,
(Gilyarovsky) What?
(Stanislavsky) No, it seemed to me.
And you're sure
that the Englishman isn't waiting for us here, anywhere?
I'm not sure.
But I know for a fact, we need to get here as soon as possible,
we need to find a way out.
Let's go.
Don't fall behind
Konstantin Sergeyevich,
Mr. Gilyarovsky?
I don't have the honor of knowing you.
You don't have to,
Don't follow me
and everybody walks out of here alive.
Haa!
(fighting noises)
Aah! Yes!
Aah!
And like this!
Aah! Well, what did you think.
Uh-huh!
Ah-ha-ha!
Oh, yeah!
Aah!
Well! Well! Eh!
I'll get you now!
Well, you were great!
Thank you.
Are you all right?
As you can see.
Give me your hand,
Maybe you shouldn't hold on.
А!
Oooh! Well!
Thank you.
We've got to keep that bastard from getting away.
I know my way around. We're gonna give him one!
See also,
it's them.
(boat noises)
Where's the boat from?
Where from? From where?
The bastard's prepared!
Hey, on the beach!
Look, it's Rudnikov.
Hey! Hey!
All right, we're gonna jump.
Slow down, Fedot Ivanovich! Slow down.
Let's go! Jump!
Are we gonna jump?
Yeah, we're gonna jump.
Come on, come on, come on.
Go! Move! Move!
You've been through a lot.
We missed the perp.
Ah, we did it on purpose, Fedot Ivanovich,
so that you wouldn't be out of work.
That's right.
Investigations should be handled by professionals.
Go! Go faster!
(boat noises)
Come on, come on, come on!
What's he got, dynamite?
Maykov, get the horn!
Hey there, on the boat!
Stop the rudeness!
No more dynamite!
Get to shore now!
Well, Fedot!
That's how he'll dock.
You foreign devil!
Fyodor Ivanovich, he'll sink us.
Konstantin Sergeyevich, can you swim?
No.
Magnificent!
Stand down!
We'll take them alive!
Kukushkin, boarding party!
Cuckoo, jump! Where to jump?
Fedot Ivanovich!
Come on, come on, come on.
Fedot, Kukushkin has flown away!
Won't he drown?
No!
(Rudnikov) Kukushkin is not sinking.
What, are you gonna shoot?
Don't get caught in the cauldron.
He's got a warehouse full of dynamite, it's gonna blow up,
we won't pick up any bones.
I'm the best shot in the entire imperial police force.
I beg you, Fedot!
Don't talk under your arm.
(explosion noise)
Stop car!
Yeah! There was an Englishman,
Well, he's not.
And no one will ever see the necklace again.
"Spark of the East."
Just like a good tragedy.
Here, a set by our artist Simov.
Victor Andreevich,
Here we'll be performing Maxim Gorky's play.
"At the Bottom."
That's great!
Like in life.
Yes, indeed,
it's like being in a Heathrow's lodging house.
By the way, Fedot Ivanovich, may I congratulate you?
The Order of Stanislaus is a worthy award!
With swords.
Although, to be fair,
I don't know what that was about.
Foreigners, some dwarves, poisoned arrows.
Where did all this come from in the capital city?
Noooo! That's a bloody weird one.
No stranger than human nature.
I think this story can be sufficiently
to accurately reconstruct,
based on human motives
and actions.
Well, give it a try.
This story started 10 -15 years ago in India.
In this most ancient
and a beautiful country
enslaved by the British,
during the suppression
of King Sekim's rebellion against the British, from his palace in
Tamlong, the unique "Spark of the East" necklace is missing.
I'm pretty sure it was stolen by our
Raja, who was then in the British army.
and a certain English officer, Benjamin Norris.
This story was very high-profile,
it was all over the British papers,
and I found out about her
from our painter Vereshchagin,
who was living in India at the time.
However,
Raja and Norris managed to get away with it.
Their guilt could not be proven.
Soon, however,
for some other serious offense,
Norris was exiled to penal servitude, in the Andaman Islands.
Raja
took advantage of the moment and ran away,
taking the necklace with her.
Thanks to Chekhov, we know that at the time, passing by.
Andaman Islands, the Russian steamship "Petersburg" sailed by.
That's how Raja traveled to Russia.
Subsequently, settling down
on Khitrovka.
However, Norris
managed to escape from hard labor,
and he immediately began searching for his companion.
Somehow, he met Testov,
who was already a famous collector at the time.
Of course, he knew of the existence of Spark East.
and most likely,
had already met Rajoy by then.
It was Testov
prompted Norris,
where to find Raju.
That's how Norris got to Khitrovka.
The night we found Raju dead.
Raju, in his own home.
Well, it's all very interesting, of course.
But there's no way we can verify your story.
Understand, in art, facts are not that important.
If you're
managed to convince the viewer,
then what you've created is the truth.
Allahu Akbar
(praying in Arabic)
Is that what a person is?
A person is not you,
not me, not them.
No, the person is you, I'm them,
the old man, Napoleon,
Mohammed, in one.
This is huge.
Do you understand?
In this one,
all the beginnings.
All ends.
It's all in the man,
everything for man,
only human beings exist.
Everything else is just
his handiwork
and his brain.
Chelovec.
That sounds
proudly.
Bravo! Bravo!
Konstantin Sergeyevich,
look who I brought you.
We just came by to congratulate you on your brilliant premiere.
Did you really like it?
Very much! Very much!
You said it so well this time,
A man is a proud word.
It made my heart skip a beat.
You're a great artist.
Thank you, Ksenia Andreyevna.
Not for nothing Vladimir Alexeyevich
he took me to all the hot spots.
No way!
It's made for you!
How did you do that?
You're a very beautiful woman.
I'd suggest you come away with me,
but I don't think you'd agree.
I disagree.
I wanted to offer you a place in the theater,
but you're a wealthy lady now,
and you can live in St. Petersburg or Paris.
It's so weird.
This necklace
could provide for me for three lifetimes to come.
I don't want to leave him.
Konstantin Sergeyevich, take it.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
I'm a lazy man.
And then I'll stop working altogether.
Have pity on Nemirovich-Danchenko!
Konstantin Sergeyevich,
Vladimir Alexeyevich, welcome.
Everyone's waiting for you.
Yeah, I'm coming, I'm coming,
Join us.
Thank you.
Would you like to join us?
We're going to the Hermitage to drink champagne in honor
the premiere.
No, thank you.
Uncle Gilyai, show me out,
Where are you going? Your place?
To Khitrovka.
Khitrovka?
Khitrovka, my house.
I grew up there,
and I'll stay there.
Somebody's got to sing in the pubs at night.
Goodbye, Konstantin Sergeyevich!
Я .....
Ksenia Andreyevna,
I've never met a woman like that.
You're extraordinary.
It's a declaration of love.
Your heart belongs to the theater, Konstantin Sergeyevich.
Let's go, Uncle Gilyai.
(sad music)
Whoa!
Princess, let me walk you home.
That kind of wealth will be cut off.
You're not afraid?
I'm not afraid.
You know me,
All right, then. Bless you.
Thank you for everything Uncle Gilyai!
Uncle Gilyai,
Vladimir Alexeyevich,
Take it.
Nah, I'm afraid I'll get drunk.
I'm not used to living in ideal conditions.
Keep it.
What am I supposed to do with him?
I can't sell it.
Why, you can split an emerald, melt down a chain.
You'll sell it to your own on Khitrovka, of course, not so expensive,
as a whole. But still.
No, I don't want to break it.
(water splashing)
Whoo! Ehhh!
Well, I'd better be going.
At least let me kiss you goodbye.
Well, goodbye!
Goodbye!
Princess!
I think I've lost my watch.
Have you seen them?
All fair and square.
Uncle Gelay.
That's my job.
All right! The truth is yours!
I'll give you a gift.