Rosanna!
I'm talking to you Rosanna
and I know you can hear me.
Please see to it that Karl doesn't
spend entire Summer at the computer.
And you too... don't read so much,
try to get outside also.
It's really beautiful over there.
You can ride the bikes anywhere.
You don't want to talk to me?
- No.
Rosanna, mom will need peace
after the surgery.
You're a big girl already,
you should understand.
What if I'll never see her again.
Don't be foolish.
The surgery could fail.
Don't you ever say that.
It can't fail.
Friar Johannes and Brother Martinus
got real close to making gold.
Did you kill them?
Recipe?!
Nobody must know about this.
Nobody shall ever know.
KID DETECTIVES AND
THE SCRET OF THE WHITE LADY
Markus! Are you deaf?
Markus!
I'm gonna be late for work,
you'll have to watch Emilia.
I'm already big.
Let me be the judge of that, okay.
You'll be home by 12.
I have to sell the books
of Mr. Krookus.
We're going to have guests,
have you already forgotten?
Mom, why do we have to have strangers
here for the whole Summer?
Loviis was my best friend at school.
She asked for my help,
I couldn't turn her down.
They will not ruin your summer.
Rosanna and Karl
are almost your age.
You'll have fun together.
Hey, help me close this.
Sometimes I wonder how many kids
do I really have.
Well, go on.
And don't forget.
We've got tickets for tonight.
Yeah-yeah.
Did you do everything correctly,
Henricus?
Yes, to create the homunculus,
I took one portion of bones,
after that
a little bit of semen
a bit skin and hair.
From every animal homunculus
has to look like.
Then I placed it all
in one container.
Covered everything
with horse manure
and left it for 40 days and 40 nights
untouched.
Now 40 days have passed
and the fetus of the homunculus
should be ready. Let's see it.
- Yes.
Instead of a little person
all I see
is horse manure.
Master, I did everything correctly.
It's already seventh attempt
that you have failed.
Throw this crap over the wall.
What are you staring at!
Haven't you seen crap before?
Go to work!
Buy a thriller "White Lady's
True Legend".
Written by our town's honorary
citizen Feliks Truu.
The bloodcurling tale
of the White Lady.
Witches, executioners
and burning of the witches.
Torture on the wheel.
This is stupid, nobody's
gonna buy it anyway.
Let's try for another 10 minutes.
Okay.
Only 7 euros and 9...
- Sorry.
What are you selling here?
- A book.
Feliks Truu's "True Story
of the White Lady".
So the White Lady was actually
an alchemist.
Very interesting theory.
Let's make a deal. If you promise
me, that it's a good read,
then I'll buy it.
I promise
- Promise?
- Yes.
Keep the change.
Go buy an icecream or something.
And who might you be?
I'm Emilia.
Can you tell me where is
the bishop's castle's museum?
Yes, it's right there,
around the corner.
By the way, my mom works there.
Excellent!
Maybe I'll meet your mom today.
During the entire morning
we've had only three guests.
If it continues like this,
we'll have to start firing people.
But White Lady's days are coming.
Then there's always more people.
- That's only temporary.
We need advertising.
More advertising...
- Sorry!
I couldn't help overhearing
your discussion.
When it comes to advertising,
I might be able to help you.
Who might you be?
Excuse me!
I am a photographer, Stig,
Stig Velson.
I am making a photo book of Haapsalu,
of the Bishop's Castle,
to be more exact.
Excuse us.
Berit, starting today,
you will be at this gentleman's
disposal 24/7.
This is exactly the advertising that we need.
Help!
Hello.
- Hello.
Hello, Markus. Hello, Emilia.
How did you do today?
Mr. Krookus, in three days we have
sold only two books.
One was bought by me and the other
one by a gentleman.
So sad that people don't care
about the true history of their town.
Split the money between you two.
Thanks.
- You've worked so hard.
Are you sure that everything happened
like it's written in this book?
Feliks Truu, this book's author
was internationally renowned
archaeologist.
He devoted his entire life
to exploring our Bishop's castle.
He stumbled upon the manuscript
of Bonifacius
and the White Lady's true story
is based on that.
And where is this manuscript now?
Unfortunately Feliks Truu died
so suddenly
that he couldn't tell anyone.
You have to be the last as always.
Hurry, Emilia, we had to be home
2 minutes ago.
Good bye.
- Good bye.
Rosanna, try to look more cheerful,
this is embarassing.
Remember, we'll be doing nothing
with these kids.
But why?
Our behaviour has to be so sucky
that they'll have to send us home.
Is this clear?
- Yes.
Come on in, don't be shy.
You'll be living here.
I'll take this bed.
- Take it if you want.
Thank you, you've really
put in an effort here.
Summer room, it needed to be
fixed up for some time already.
Kids were helping fully when they heard
they'll get playmates for summer.
I'll be going then, that way
I'll get back in time to visit Loviis.
Be good and listen to Berit.
- See you.
Don't worry, Rosanna takes a little
warming up but I can handle her.
Rosanna, do you want to
play badmington?
I don't want to play
any stupid ballgames.
Leave me alone!
Brother Franciscus is already
a third alchemist
that has died this month.
I think he stumbled
and fell off the wall.
But brother Martinus
who fell down the well?
And brother Johannes
who died unfortunately
after the supper?
Lord works in mysterious ways,
beyond reason for men.
They all worked on
manufacturing gold.
I'm afraid somebody wants to
hamper our efforts.
But who, Your Holiness?
I don't know yet but I swear,
I'll find out.
Hire yourself more
promising apprentices.
Gold has to be ready
by the end of this year.
And do not forget Homunculus.
Take it away.
I've lost my appetite.
Freeze! Hands on your head!
Face the wall!
What are you doing here?
I wanted to turn off the alarm
but something went wrong.
I opened a dance studio here.
- You may lower your hands.
May I see your documents?
Here you go.
Please, come on in!
I have to thank you somehow
for saving me from trouble.
Maybe a cup of coffee?
No, I have to go. Work matters.
Maybe you would be interested
in dance lessons?
For you I would give these for free.
Look, dancing and me,
these don't match.
Don't be so modest.
Take this at least.
Thank you!
See you later, Tonis Piir.
See you later, Karin Viisle.
Don't you ever regret it?
Regret what?
Marrying a man who can't dance,
sent to work to in the province?
Oh, come on!
Good boys!
Everyone within five seconds.
And you, you lazy bum,
what are you stalling?
One more.
I'm coming, coming.
Hello.
- Hello...
Yes. Piir here.
To Krookus' house?
Okay, I'll stop by the station.
Be right there.
What happened?
- Break in at Krookus'store.
I'll take you home.
No. I want to listen
to the music.
Would you care to dance?
I'd love to.
My dearest possessions, gone.
- Please remove your hand.
The robbers had to know
precisely what to take?
They didn't know anything.
There are clocks many times
more valuable
You said it yourself,
your dearest clocks.
I didn't mean it like this.
The thing is
Those clocks belonged
to our town's honorary citizen
Mister...
Don't touch!
- Sorry!
...Feliks Truu.
After his death I bought those
clocks from his daughter.
These have very high...
- Please.
...cultural value.
- I see.
One was up there.
And another one was here
Please, come and sit here.
Here were two really valuable clocks.
Here and here.
- Please, just sit.
Yes, thank you.
Let me take the photos, do my job.
Down here.
God, what a great misfortune!
Oh, hi.
- Hello-hello.
May I introduce my husband Tonis.
Stig Velson, photographer,
I told you about him.
Hello.
It was lovely, Berit, but
unfortunately I have to go now.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
That photographer seemed
like a pretty skilled dancer.
You noticed?
It was impossible not to.
Shall we go?
Kids, meal is ready!
Where are you going?
To eat.
You're not going anywhere.
We'll declare a hunger strike
until they send us home.
You can starve if you want
but I'm hungry.
Then you're a traitor. Nerd.
I'm not a traitor and I'm no nerd.
- Are too.
And a suck-up.
- Do you know...
We should be with mom right now.
Get it?
I think we should do
as mom and dad told us.
Good morning.
- Hi.
Where's Rosanna?
She didn't want to eat.
Rosanna!
I'm not going to pretend like
nothing bad hasn't happened.
Your mom is sick, about to have
a difficult surgery.
I'm sure there will come a time
when you have to support her.
Therefore there's no point
to starve yourself to death.
I'll never see mom again.
Mom promised you that
you'll meet again.
Promised, promised.
Only to get us away from there.
As much as I know Loviis,
She never breaks her promises
and we studied together for 12 years.
Rosanna.
Your mom would never lie to you
in such important matters.
Come, eat something.
Later you can go cycling.
Markus knows all sorts of cool places,
ruins and secret passageways.
Come!
And you shall see green flame
that comes from phosphorus.
What evil spirit has sent you
to this place?
I came because you called,
my name is Johan.
I heard you're looking
for an apprentice.
I could use a good apprentice,
but not one so eager
who would blow up my workshop.
What are you giggling about?
You finish the homunculus.
Where are you from?
- From the village.
I live with my mom.
My father was a doctor and an alchemist.
I learned these arts from him.
All right.
You can stay, for now.
Careful, I just got my hair done.
Tomorrow there's a jazz night at the
club. I rescheduled my shift.
I bought us two tickets.
Tonis, that is so sweet.
But tomorrow I can't.
What are you doing tomorrow?
I'm going to Noarootsi, to photograph
the sunset with Stig.
We have agreed with local fishermen.
Some other time.
- Don't be upset! That was really sweet.
Let's go!
Hello.
- Hello.
I'm on a break.
Thought I'd come by.
Check your security.
Great that you're concerned
for my security.
Come on in, let's see if
you're really that talentless.
I don't know.
I have no sense of rhythm.
Nobody is so unmusical
that they couldn't be
taught to dance.
You think so?
- Sure. Let's go.
Come in!
Hello.
- Hello.
Hi.
They are Rosanna and Karl.
They spend summer with us.
Hello, Karl.
- Hello.
Hello, Rosanna.
Mr. Krookus, I heard that
you were robbed last night.
Yes I was.
Number of costly clocks they took,
those scoundrels.
Could we look for those clock-robbers?
Your dad is already handling this.
He came by last night,
photographed everything.
Dad is so busy all the time.
We have much more time.
And besides, we would also
like to solve cases.
Yearning for a true case.
So be it, young detectives.
I'm hiring you.
And if you catch those robbers
then I guarantee you free icecream
for the whole summer.
Deal!
- Emilia and Karl,
you will check that corner.
Rosanna, you'll check
from over there.
I'm in charge of the whole operation.
- Maybe vice versa?
You'll check that corner over there.
And I'm in charge of the operation.
- OK, let's investigate together.
I found something.
- Wait, don't touch.
Mister Krookus, is this yours?
No, it's certainly not mine.
The bad guys probably dropped this.
Here are fingerprints.
Look what smart kids you are
I'll get the fingerprints.
Where did you learn this?
- Dad taught me.
We have two fingerprints.
How do you know whom
these belong to?
That we may find out through
police databank.
Only we have to get
to dad's office somehow.
Maybe you'll ask dad
to let you take a look?
Are you kidding?
He'll have a seizure if I step
near his work computer.
I've crashed it numerous times.
But let's do it like this!
Nobody's coming. Now!
Yes.
Stay there. I'll come right away.
Dammit!
There's one match.
Your dad is coming. Hurry!
Where on earth were you?
We were riding our bikes.
What happened?
- What happened?!
You should have looked
after the small ones.
Emilia and Karl wandered around
and Karl fell in the water.
If he catches a cold I have
no idea what to tell Loviis.
My legs are melting.
Hang on, dear. You'll get
hot tea in a minute.
With raspberries and honey.
Did you find the owner
of the fingerprints?
Yes, we did. Your self-sacrifice
was worth it.
These belong to Roobert Uurike,
address Sambla 41.
After it gets dark, me and Markus will go there
Get lost!
So...
What is it?
Honorable teacher.
I believe I have found a way
to hasten healing of the wounds.
Oh?
This is a true miracle.
I would like to get so far that my
elixir would cure all illnesses.
Pure hokum. There is no cure
for the plague.
There is no cure for
your aching head.
Bishop demands gold.
Therefore I cannot allow you
to continue with the cure.
Look for the Sorcerer's Stone.
That will help us turn metal into gold.
Brother Johan. Don't worry,
I'll help you.
We will work on your elixir
at nights.
Where do you think you're going?
We want to come with you.
I told you, you're too small.
If you don't take us with you,
I'll scream.
Okay, you can come,
but no whining.
That photographer has rented
an apartment here.
Me and Rosanna will go first,
then you'll follow.
Let me tell you, Aivar.
We have to get a new dog.
I hate it when I don't know if someone's
sneaking around my house or not.
First time to have a dog's wake.
Bottoms up.
Wait! That sounded so familiar.
Exactly like the clock Mr. Krookus had.
Exactly. It came from there.
They are the ones who robbed
the clock of Mr. Krookus.
You're a really smart kid.
Tonis!
- Yes?
- The kids are gone.
As long as they didn't go swimming
on their own.
We'll find them, don't worry.
There's an alarm all over the county.
Four kids on bikes cannot be
unseen for too long.
We'll look by the lighthouse as well.
- Okay.
Good day, officer Piir.
May I see your licence please.
You didn't see four kids on bicycles?
No sir, we didn't see
no kids anywhere, officer.
Please open the backdoor.
Sure, no problem.
We're transporting old furniture.
You can close this.
Drive safe.
- Thanks! All the best to you as well.
Out of the car!
Face down, on the ground,
hands on your back.
Face down, face down.
Hands on your back!
Did you wind the clocks?
Well, yeah.
The sound is so beautiful.
Idiot.
If only you knew what
I had to live through.
I have a handful of grey hair.
But Mom, nothing happened to us.
But could have happened.
Besided, you're dying your hair anyway.
Thanks!
The only good thing here is
that kids caught the clock robbers.
A year's worth of work,
brother Johan,
But now it seems that the elixir
might be finally ready.
I hope it will be useful for people.
Whom shall we try it on first?
I want to test this on myself.
I'm a little ill. If I get better
then the cure has power.
All right. But please be careful!
We don't know about the side effects.
I can't breathe!
Johan!
Are you going to turn me in?
Don't be afraid!
So, you two, together again.
Jacob!
No more coughing.
Mom, how are you doing?
Fine. Dad visits me every day.
I'm, getting preparatory treatment
and I feel quite good.
When is the surgery?
Next week.
When are you getting out?
It'll be couple of more weeks after the
surgery and then we'll see each other.
I have to go now.
Time for my procedures,
nurse came.
Hugs and kisses.
See you!
Teacher.
- Yes, what is it?
Here's a cure that can help
lots of people.
We prepared this with brother
Jacob at nights
I told you not to work
on the cure.
But ill people need to be cured,
there's a plague in town.
Teacher, we're asking
for your permission
To try this on the patients
of the hospital.
Because the cure may still have
dangerous side effects.
This is no cure.
That's poison, stirred by Devil's tail.
I cannot allow this.
We have to search for the
Sorcerer's Stone and make gold.
Bishop's patience is wearing thin.
Tests with the cure shall be postponed.
And remember this,
Alchemy is knowledge
about creation of the form
and its disappearance.
How is homunculus coming along?
Please.
Karl, 5 minutes is up,
it's my turn.
It's not yet 5 minutes.
Yes it is, give up the dog.
Take it!
That photographer again.
Why don't you like him?
I don't and that's it. Stuffing
his nose everywhere.
Siding up to Mom as well.
I think he's pretty cool.
Come!
- What place is this?
It used to be monastery's library.
Now it's been empty for years.
Look!
I've collecting these things here,
one by one
We'll start making your
healing elixir here.
My father used to deal with alchemy.
After he died from the plague
I promised myself
that I will make an elixir
that would cure all illnesses.
When I saw you for the first time,
then I felt as if
I'd never seen a face more beautiful.
Higher. From the pose.
Grab me from here. Don't
be afraid, I won't bite. Now I feel.
From here it's lifted.
Fingers round my hand, strong,
knees slightly bent.
Dad!?
What's he doing here?
If my eyes are correct
then he's learning to tango.
But he hates dancing.
You got caught!
Dad, you're taking dance lessons!
- No.
Yes. But don't mention this to mom.
Do you want to surprise her?
Surprise is the right word.
Do we have a deal?
Heureka!
You are really at it.
It's you, Brother. Yes.
I found the solution
how to get even purer gold,
wrote down the formulas.
Excellent.
Are you going somewhere?
Yes, work-related.
Now?
I forgot to tell you.
Can you imagine what idea Stig had?
He wants to go to the castle at night,
to shoot it in moonlight.
And you're the one
who has to go with him?
Yes. Director's orders, to be
at his disposal around the clock.
He has to finish the book.
What choice do I have?
I've become downright
irreplacable for him
Feels like this Stig can't even
go to the bathroom without you.
Okay then, there he is.
I hope officer Fear isn't jealous.
No.
No reason to be. I'll be back
in couple of hours.
Ciao, don't be so grumpy.
You're still talking about coincidence,
dear Bonifacius.
Holy Father, this is the handywork
of Devil himself
Brother Evaristus was too close
to creating gold.
Vade retro satana
So it's Devil's work?
Then we have to catch this Devil
and string him up.
Holy Father, there's no way
to catch the Devil.
Man doesn't possess
such power over him.
Don't you understand,
this is done by a man?
We have to come up
with a clever plan
to catch this murderer
and gold robber.
We have to find a way
how to drive that sucky Stig
out of town for good.
Before he takes away our mom.
I think we should scare
that Stig properly.
He doesn't look like a guy
who's afraid of anything.
If he met the real White Lady
at the castle tonight
then I bet he would be scared.
Where do we get the White Lady?
I saw that Stig has a camera
with Wifi.
He sends all the pictures
over internet to his hard drive.
So?
Same time that he's
photographing the castle,
me and Markus
will go to his room.
I'll hack his computer and leave
him some ghost photos.
Karl, dad told you,
no more hacking.
You've had enough trouble
because of this already.
But if it's for the sake of justice?
What if that sucky Stig really
woos my Mom
and takes her away for good?
All right, but this is
the very last time.
Teacher!
Teacher, I managed to create gold!
- Show me.
The purest gold that
I have ever seen.
Do you remember the whole process?
- Yes.
Write it all down so it remains
on the record forever.
Give me the gold recipe!
So you were the one
who killed all those monks?
That secret you shall take
to your grave.
You're the one who robbed formulas
and recipes for making gold.
Take him to the torture chamber,
he'll start talking.
Berit, what do you think if there's
any truth to this White Lady's tale?
I believe that every legend
is based on something.
White Lady or that young girl was really
buried somewhere within these walls?
I'm certain of it.
It was discovered that a girl dressed
as a boy had entered the castle
having an affair with
one of the monks
and these days it was punishable
by death.
Sad story.
I wouldn't be surprised if after this
a young girl's ghost would
haunt this place, appearing
on the window every year.
May I have a look?
- No.
Of course you can.
Over here.
Come!
Can you?
- Yes.
Look.
These are the files he is
photographing right now.
Photoshop some ghouls here.
ÂE
These he would not believe.
I'll add an old lady's picture
and make it transparent.
Okay. I'll look around.
What?
Stig has a gun.
- Show me
Put it back.
Look, if Stig sees this,
he'll be gone from this town
in a few hours.
Hang on.
Look. Here's a folder on Mr. Krookus.
Open it.
He has been following Mr. Krookus.
Karl, make a copy of this folder.
Yes.
We can go.
I don't want to be here.
Let me go.
Henricus
you have committed heinous murders.
Confess everything.
I have nothing to confess, Holy Father.
I don't know why I am here.
Tell us where did you hide the recipe
for making gold.
I know nothing, let me go.
Executioner, you're not doing
a proper job.
I confess.
I killed them all.
Me.
Why did you do it, brother?
Greed.
I... I wanted that...
only I would have instructions
for making gold.
That only I would know the
secret of the Sorcerer's Stone.
Tell us, where did you hide
the formula!
It's in my chamber.
There's a loose stone in the wall.
Behind it.
Mr. Krookus, we found
something really important.
Pictures of your clocks and you,
in a person's computer.
In addition to that,
He had a copy of a letter
by professor Feliks Truu.
The only thing familiar was
the name of Feliks Truu.
One time I bought some clocks
from his daughter.
Stamp albums, books
And his manuscript to the
White Lady's true story.
We printed out Feliks Truu's letter.
"My dear daughter,
if you're reading this, it means
You have discovered it inside
"Guide to photography's" back cover.
I hope you noticed our
secret marking on the back.
I want to tell you that inside
one of the clocks I hid
a very valuable treasure.
Find it and decide for yourself
what to do with it."
I believe we are really close
to creating the elixir.
Did you add enough garlic?
I believe so.
What is it?
It cannot start now.
Can it wait?
It's time, you have to help me.
I'll teach you.
I need clean clothes
and warm water.
Go on!
How is the gold-making
coming along?
What's the matter with Brother Johan?
Teacher, we have sinned.
What sin?
My real name is Johanna.
I hid that I'm a girl, or you wouldn't have
accepted me as an apprentice.
What are you looking at, you sinner!
Go bring a strong stick
and warm water.
And see that no-one finds out.
Feliks Truu wrote this letter
to his daughter
and hid it inside a book.
Wait, how did you get this?
We snuck into the house of Stig,
a photographer
and I hacked his computer
And Markus found a gun
belonging to that photographer.
Hello.
I have to show you something.
Can I come in?
- Hello.
Hello.
- Hi there.
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have barged
in early in the morning,
but it is really important.
I managed to catch White Lady
on a photo last night.
What are you talking about.
We never saw the White Lady.
But take a look at this photo.
I took this last night.
It is said that it is impossible
to see the ghosts in plain sight.
This must be the young girl
buried in the christening chapel.
That's the White Lady.
You're not taking this seriously?
These are just myths.
But this young woman's image
couldn't just, out of the blue
appear on the photograph.
That is strange. Maybe it's just
light effec t.
Doesn't look like it. Look, see.
I'm writing an article about this.
By God, White Lady finally
caught on a photograph.
No kids? Thought I'd show them
also the White Lady.
They went to see Mr. Krookus
about an hour ago.
There!
Working on some cases again?
No, just kids playing.
- They were very eager.
Well then, I'll go to write
that article.
No. Keep the photo.
Show it to kids as well.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Stig somehow got hold of
Feliks Truu's letters
and Stig hired robbers
to rob your clocks
to get the treasure.
That you have Feliks Truu's clocks,
he found out from the newspaper.
Truu's widow took many of his books
to the second-hand bookstore.
Stig probably bought
"Guide to Photography" from there.
Luckily your clocks are here.
- And treasure is inside one of them.
Mr. Krookus, we need to take
a look at your clocks.
Empty.
That was the last clock.
Maybe there's some somewhere else?
- I bought from Feliks Truu's daughter
five clocks. I remember that.
But I didn't buy all the clocks
from her.
Maybe she has some left.
- What is it?
Probably heard a cat.
This is what we'll do now.
How you're doing, Margit!
Oh, Herman, how nice to see you!
Likewise.
Come on in!
It's been ages since you came by.
Excuse us but we're in a hurry.
Is your husband home?
He's been living in Tallinn for years,
we divorced four years ago.
Oh, how sad.
Let me introduce you,
These are my young friends,
talented young detectives.
Detectives you say!?
Hello, detectives.
- Hello.
Actually, we came
because of a clock.
That's funny, you're already a
second person today asking this.
10 minutes ago there was one buyer.
Please tell me you didn't
sell this clock?
Yes I did. He offered
such a good price.
And it was a complete wreck.
I really needed the money
to fix this place.
What did this buyer look like?
He was a nice and kind man,
distinguished, about 40,
dark hair, a real gentleman.
Men like that come by very seldom.
It had to be Stig. But how
did he know to come here?
Maybe he listened to us? Remember,
Nassu started barking.
Let's find Stig and see if he found
anything from the clock.
Take your daughter,
you sinner.
Looks like a healthy child.
Johanna
we have a daughter.
But now you have to run
before Bishop finds out.
Bishop and his soldiers.
Save my child.
I cannot save you but maybe
your child.
I heard terrible things,
Brother Bonifacius.
Yes, everything is correct.
Here these sinners are,
I heard about it just now.
A face too flawless,
eyes too beautiful.
I had to be a fool not noticing
this snake.
Where is the child?
Which child?
- Don't be a fool.
Bonifacius, where is sinful fruit?
My eyes have seen no child.
I swear on Almighty, there was
a child in this room
Brother Gregorius
means Homunculus.
Look, Father, we managed to
complete the Homunculus.
Right now it's in early stages.
We'll deal with the Homunculus later.
Take the sinners
straight away to jail.
What am I going to do
with you, little one?
Now Stig gets the treasure and Feliks
Truu's daughter will lose everything.
So?
- There was no treasure inside the clock.
Where's the right clock then?
Maybe Mrs. Truu has sold clocks
to someone else as well?
Hello. It's us again.
How nice, come in.
- Sorry, but we're in a hurry.
Say, you didn't sell anyone else
any of your father's clocks?
Yes, a long time ago I sold another one.
- To whom?
One big round clock was bought
by Haapsalu's railway museum.
I know that clock.
It's in the station's main hall.
Thank you, Margit.
- What is it with these clocks?
Can't tell you now. Soon
you'll find out everything.
Don't ask me where did I get her.
Please raise her for a few months
until my work here is finished.
Go now.
How can we get it?
I don't know, let's ask the guard.
Nobody will allow us
to take down that clock.
But at night there's nobody here.
Let's hide under the benches
and when the doors close,
We'll take the clock down and see
if there's a treasure inside.
I don't know if it's the best idea?
But Feliks Truu's daughter is so poor
and her house needs fixing up.
Yes, that's true.
All right.
Let's do this.
Wait, wait.
Where are you going?
Herman promised to
teach us astronomy.
He'll show us Moon's craters
through his telescope.
Tonight is full moon.
- And it's supposed to be clear sky.
I'm afraid you'll wear
uncle Herman out.
Mom, uncle Herman is our friend.
And he's really happy
when we visit him
because he himself invited us.
Tonis, what do you think?
Let them go, kids'll have fun.
Okay, but take your phones.
I'll call Herman and check.
Why do you worry for them so much?
Bon appetit!
By what right?
Okay.
That was Stig, I know.
- You bet!
He probably found out from Margit
where another clock was.
Where did he get the key from?
Maybe stole from the guard?
- Or made a copy?
Let's call dad!
- No!
Then he'll know that we lied.
- Kids!
The situation is bad,
but not hopeless.
He locked us up.
We have to stay here
until morning.
Then we'll see.
Stig has gotten the treasure
from the clock anyway.
I'd like to know what treasure
it was in the clock.
Maybe diamonds.
I don't think that Feliks Truu
would have had diamonds.
They were so poor.
What would have been the point
to hide the treasure?
I'm listening.
- Hello, Herman.
I'm calling because of my father's clock.
I remembered that Dad
had one more clock.
What?
One more clock?
- Yes.
I'm right coming over,
with young detectives...
And Margit,
please don't tell anyone
about this clock.
Good morning, Margit!
- Hello Herman, hi kids!
Please, come on in.
Kids,
take your shoes off.
I kept it in the shed.
Dad wouldn't allow me
to throw it out.
Margit, now's the time to
tell you everything -Yes?
We're looking for a valuable treasure.
A treasure hidden in one of your clocks.
In my clock? Who hid it there?
With your permission we'd like
to open the clock now.
Of course.
- Boys!
Look!
- Treasure!
It's written by the hand
of monk Bonifacius.
Unbelievable!
It's worth much more
than gold or diamonds.
This is for you.
"My dear daughter,
story of the White Lady
I told you is all true...
During the archaeological dig
I managed to uncover
The diary of monk-alchemist
Bonifacius.
There he describes what happened
in the Bishop's castle of Haapsalu
between 1472 and 1474.
Based on this I wrote the
"True story of the White Lady".
Turns out my Dad's book
was based on reality.
Turns out.
"Alchemist Bonifacius
hid in the Bishop's castle
the instructions for making gold.
He created an intricate light effect
that shows once a year
with full moon the place
where it is hidden...
Unfortunately my healt
is too weak to look for it
and the season is not right.
If you can, please look
for those instructions.
Your loving dad."
Stig!
- Margit!
Don't tell him that we're here.
That is a very dangerous man.
He wants to get your father's treasure.
Hello!
Me again, because of those clocks.
Hello-hello.
Maybe that's the treasure map?
- No.
That's Bishop's castle's blueprint.
See. That's the christening chapel.
Right.
Tell me, did your father leave you
any more clocks?
All that I had I sold.
That's a pity.
Here is written in Latin:
"Look for it in August, at full moon."
White Lady will show you the way.
Oh, well, have a great day, Missis.
- Have a nice day.
We have to find that treasure.
- That's exactly what we'll do.
Let's meet a little before midnight
at the museum's front door.
How do we get in there?
My mom has the museum's keys
and I have a copy.
Sorry to interrupt, I'm so glad
that you want to help me,
but isn't this too dangerous?
- Margit, don't worry.
We're used to danger. Right, kids?
Of course.
I'm sure that Johanna and Jacob
managed to make gold
and that it is buried somewhere
in the chapel...
If only it was already midnight.
Maid Johanna.
You have violated
our sacred rules that state
that no woman shall ever
set foot inside the castle.
Therefore we are sentencing you
in the name of the divine power.
What is the punishment for the sinner?
Death.
The same goes for you, Jacob
You have sinned and
concealed this from us.
What shall be his punishment?
Death.
Hereby we sentence,
that Johanna
shall be walled up alive
into the wall of the christening chapel.
Monk Jacob shall be executed.
Sentence will be carried out immediately.
Hello. Your name must be?
- Yes, hello.
I need to talk to your mother.
Kids, go play.
Sorry, didn't mean to interrupt.
What are you talking about,
you're not interrupting.
Hello.
- Hello.
I see that you have read
my article.
Yes, I did and it was
simply amazing...
One agency wishes
That I would take White Lady's photo
tonight, at the same place.
I'm sure that tonight, with
full moon, she will reappear.
Tell me, Berit, could you come
to the castle with me tonight?
Of course, no problem. You made
our castle world famous.
I'm sure it'll be crowded tonight.
If you don't mind I'd like to join you.
I have an evening off.
Fabulous.
See you at midnight.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Yes, this is Piir.
Okay. I'll drive there straight away.
Don't tell me that you can't come
to see White Lady with us.
I've been called to Dirham.
- I just had to marry a policeman.
There's nothing you can do about it now.
I think you won't be bored with
those ghouls and ghostbusters, right?
I'll come to pick you up afterwards.
You're not even ready yet?
We don't want to see the White Lady.
- We've seen her every year.
You've always waited for this anxiously.
Rosanna and Karl?
We'll go to bed earlier today.
Yes. And we're very tired.
As you wish. I'm surprised.
No! No! No!
You won't get in trouble with your mom?
White Lady's treasure
is more important.
- Agreed.
Dear child, I brought you
something to eat and drink.
But I can't help you out as
there are guards everywhere.
How is Jacob?
He was executed.
But my child?
She's fine. She's at my sister's.
I can no longer come,
but I promise you this,
That I'll take care of your little girl
as if she was my own flesh and blood.
Here is the cure.
It will grant you sleep,
without any pain.
Johanna.
What should I do with your instructions
for making gold?
Minul seda enam vaja ei lahe.
Koige rohkem kahetsen ma seda,
et ma oma eliksiiri katsetada ei saanud.
I'll hide it in such a place,
your instructions,
where nobody will be able
to find it for some time.
And you shall show them
the way,
where this priceless treasure lies...
Goodbye.
Go with God, Johanna.
Berit, I have a huge request.
Would it be possible to take
a few shots inside the castle?
No. At nights we don't let
the visitors in.
But since you've done such
a great job promoting our castle,
Then I'll have to make an exception.
Come this way.
White Lady should appear
within 15 minutes.
Hide, quickly!
This is the christening chapel
And that's the window where
White Lady will appear on.
That's an optical trick.
I'm more interested in the basement
where she was walled in.
Do you have the key?
Of course. Come with me.
Lucky.
Let them go and look in the basement,
then they won't disturb us.
If Bonifacius is right,
then something is about to start.
See!
The White Lady
points at this stone here.
Help me to lift it.
Hold this.
That's Johanna's instruction
for making gold
and recipe for the curing elixir.
And gold.
And lots of it.
Margit Truu has now enough
money to fix her home.
I'm afraid not.
Children!
Nassu, where are you running, wait.
Wait, where are you going now?
Where do you want to go? Wait!
Faster. Go, go.
Those are my Mom's keys.
- Sharp eye, detective.
You know, Stig? Locking me
down here isn't funny.
- Silence!
Inside! Quickly!
Kids, what are you doing here?
That man's a robber, Mom.
- Harsh words, young man...
I don't understand anything anymore!
You'll have plenty of time
to catch up.
Mom, Stig is getting away with the
treasure, you have to do something!
Let him go, main thing is
that you're alive
You don't understand anything!
We found Johanna's instructions
for making gold
and a little gold and now
you're just letting him go.
We have to get out of here right now
And we have to catch
this no good robber.
Markus, where did you get these?
Later, Mom.
Okay, open this door very quietly.
What's this supposed to mean?
- Wait-wait.
It means that you're going
through that door.
If you're lucky, you'll meet
your family.
Me, monk-alchemist Bonifacius
Wrote this down in the year
of our Lord 1481.
Since I don't want the manuscript
to fall into wrong hands
I shall hide it into the floor
of the Bishop's castle.
I hope that some day it will
end up in good hands.
Praise the Lord!
Mom, we found Johanna's
instructions for making gold.
And a little bit of gold.
She did numerous curing elixirs,
you could get better with these.
Dear kids, I'm really grateful,
But it seems I'm already getting better.
Doctor told me this morning that
the tests have improved vastly.
Finally!
We thought with dad that his vacation
is about to start
And you could come home.
Next week already.
Rosanna, why am I not hearing cheering?
I thought that if we're not there
on the way,
then dad can take better care of you.
Yes. It would be much more peaceful
if there's just two of you.
Is it really about this?
Actually we started to like it here
and we'd like to stay in Haapsalu
until the end of the Summer.
Would you care to dance?
But you can't dance.
Go, mom, you have to go.
I had no idea you could dance. Amazing!
Dad, can we go fishing now?
Of course.
Are we gonna catch a big one today?
Very big.
- How do you know that?
Because we've earned this.