The future of Japan will be saved by robots.
Lately nuclear accidents are getting common.
In the field of health and safety, the current systems
in place already show their technological limits.
For the benefit of our workforce, we must get over this problem at all costs.
I want the government and the private sector to unite
Prime Minister Tabe: Developing Robots to Recover the Japanese Economy
Broadcasting from the National Diet
"ARK Project"
Started
and commit themselves to developing the world's most advanced robot.
For this reason we've created the "ARK Project".
Special Report
ARK Project - The depiction
of Japan's future
Our ultimate goal
ARK Project Chief Researcher
Dr. Nobuhiko Komyoji
is to create something able to complete physical problems that humans can not solve.
An Android.
The end result of our research, I hope
is peace for all mankind.
Motor skills are almost equal.
But there is an evident gap in judgement speed.
Could this be a weakness of the "Conscience Circuit"?
Strangely, it tries to infer emotion from facial expressions and the current situation.
Clearly, this capability isn't needed in battle.
What are you trying to do behind my back?
Professor Komyoji.
As you can see...
I am testing KJX-1's and BJX-2's fighting ability.
Jiro!
Okay, that's enough.
My Mari possess far better fighting skills than your Jiro,
And I felt the need to show it to Minister Tsubakitani.
I do not remember having developed Jiro as a combat android.
My ARK project is strictly for peaceful purposes.
For starters, this lab is different from America,
where the relative merits of an android is measured in combat ability alone.
That in itself is an anachronism.
However, we scientists sometimes have to follow where the "anachronism" goes.
Because fish that does not follow the tide just drown.
So from the very start the goal has always been military applications.
Well, I beg to reconsider.
He's so naive.
For someone known as one of Japan's top scientists.
What do you intend to do?
Of course, I will try to persuade Chief Komyoji.
Mari.
You are truly man's equal.
And on the other hand, Jiro.
Like your creator, you are missing an important thing.
You are an imperfect machine.
I am...
a machine.
Has it been a year?
That year must have been unbearable.
But it seems she has never told anyone what happened to Nobuhiko.
Don't you think that's insensitive of them?
Well, that just seems like how children their age would react.
I heard that things aren't going well in the Nobuhiko household.
It's been confirmed that she'll be studying abroad, and I wonder...
what will happen to the siblings because of it?
By gaining intelligence, the heart changes.
And while the heart changes to the knowledge,
The body is also affected.
And even before that…
Oh. Isn't that Mitsu?
Mitsu!
Hey! How are you?
What's up? Only two classes today?
Well, my lecture for this afternoon seems to be canceled.
Really? What a miracle!
Then come with me tonight.
Haruna is fishing herself a boyfriend...
-so I need company for a group date!
Pretty please?
But I don't really go to blind dates.
But it's a dinner, please!
I'm terribly sorry but it won't happen.
Mitchy!
What?
Oh, now I see.
So is he your type?
What, no, no, no!
He's just some journalist.
Journalist?
He's been asking me about my father recently.
What a waste, and he's good looking too.
If you don't act now, you'll never get anyting in life!
Quit telling me that.
I'm quite occupied with me and my brothers stuff already.
See ya.
Mitsu!
Mitchy... ouchies.
Good afternoon!
Thanks.
Dr. Komyoji...
The cause of your father's death.
It seems that you know what really happened, Mitchy.
Please stop calling me that.
As far as I know,
they are still continuing the project that your father started.
Dr. Komyoji, world renowned for his skill in robotic engineering,
was reportedly killed in an accident, and yet
there was no news coverage and the research program continued on.
Do you really think it was an accidental death?
I have no interest in the work of that guy.
Here you go with "that guy" again.
He was a single-father right?
Mr. Hattori!
The death of that guy...
You're really interested in reporting about that incident aren't you?
You men are always thinking about work.
It isn't like that at all, Mitchy.
I already told you to stop calling that.
I have to go prepare my brother's dinner.
If you have nothing more to ask, then I'll be going now.
"One day, a prince mounted atop a white horse will come for me."
Why do girls of today cling to this hope?
For instance,
Will that man take that girl to the world of her dreams?
I think not.
As one can plainly see of the men of real life,
they are content with the happiness found in the phone's screen held by their hands.
They cannot see that women are waiting in the real world.
And because of that, I'd rather dream of the princes of anime and manga.
Because I know that in this reality,
no prince will sweep me away and take me to another world.
I'm back.
Welcome home.
Would you like some curry tonight?
You like that don't you, Masaru.
Are you playing games again?
Are you done with your homework?
Do you think you can handle yourself once I start studying abroad?
Hey Mitchy, its me, Hattori.
Please, let me ask a few more questions.
I have nothing else to say.
Please stop coming to my home.
And stop calling me that too.
Masaru?
-What are you doing here?
Wh-wh-what's going on?
Mararu!
Sis, help me!
Masaru!
What!? What is all this!?
Sis, I'm scared!
Help me sis!
Masaru, Masaru!
Sis, help me!
Let me go!
Sis!
Masaru!
I'm scared!
Wait!
Let go!
That hurts, that hurts!
Masaru!
Who are you?
Run away, hurry.
I've got no choice, switch on.
A machine?!
Now I must do what a machine does.
I'm not going to continue to fight with you humans.
Sis.
Awesome!
Masaru.
What is this thing?
Awesome.
Stay back!
Hey, Mitchy!
Are you both ok?
Hey mister, did you see that?
It was so awe...
No, keep quiet.
Well I saw it more or less.
That guy who saved you, is he by chance a...
I don't know anything.
I don't understand anything.
You can keep asking, but I have no answers.
Oh come on.
Alright then.
Anyway, we'd better get out of here.
Let's go!
Over here!
Go, go, go!
Ow... got it!
It really is Jiro.
Jiro?
The one that disappeared sometime ago.
Don't you remember?
Is that the other prototype that Dr. Komyoji developed?
No. This is the one which he installed the "Conscience Circuit" in.
But you are correct in saying that there is another prototype.
More importantly, I want the son of Dr. Komyoji captured as soon as possible.
I just want the Komyoji File.
Wait a moment, Minister Tsubakitani.
Don't you see that the ARK Project does not need the Komyoji File anymore?
What are you talking about, Dr. Gilbert Kanzaki?
Komyoji is dead.
Is it not better to stop his research
and produce something greater than the Komyoji File?
I called you from America merely to assist him.
Can you do it alone?
I can.
My creation Mari far exceeds Komyoji's Jiro.
You were always and continue to be, only second to Komyoji's talent.
I just want to see the finished designs of Komyoji's research.
Whether you are indeed better than him or not is of no interest to me.
Why do not you trust him with the responsibility?
It's not that I don't trust his skill.
He is an excellent scientist.
He created you after all.
However,
He has no vision.
That is all.
Big accident last night in Shinagawa
Heavy machinery falls from high rise apartment
Here in Shinagawa, Tokyo, as you can see right behind me,
some heavy machinery fell from a 45 floor apartment building.
Fortunately no one was injured, however
police are still investigating construction workers for negligence
and other possible leads.
Ms. Kitajima.
Yes.
You mentioned heavy machinery, what kind was it?
Hey?
We all know that this is far from what we really saw right?
Look, this isn't the truth right?
This totally a cover-up.
In this case, wouldn't it be better to talk to the police?
No, even the police can't be trusted.
What would you even say to them?
If you say a bunch of mysterious armed men attacked,
they won't take you seriously!
But in the meantime, just stay put.
Mister, where are you going?
To work. To work.
I may not look like it,
but I'm a very hard worker.
Listen up, don't you leave this place.
Lock your doors and put away the keys.
You got that?
Morning!
Long time no see.
So you're still alive, you charlatan novelist.
I see you're as sharped tongued as always, old man.
By the way, being a cellphone novelist is just my part-time job.
Please refer to me as an "net journalist."
Youngsters these days are all "mobile" this
and "net" that and think it sounds good.
So what do you want?
Can you take look at this for a moment?
It has conspiracy written all over it, I'm sure.
If this turns out to be some kind of joke, I swear...
What conspiracy?
This time it's true!
This thing...
Where did you get this?
Hey, are we really going to be ok?
Mr. Journalist told us not to leave.
You can't trust that man. He's a weirdo.
I'll send a message to Professor Maeno.
Alright.
Professor Maeno was father's mentor right?
Although I don't want to rely on that guy's acquaintances,
in our current situation, he's the only person we can trust.
Sis.
No way!
Hurry!
Sis!
Masaru, are you alright?
Yup.
Just what are you?
Smartphone.
What?
They found your location when you used your smartphone.
I didn't ask about that.
Who or rather, what are you?
I am Jiro.
Jiro...
You're a machine aren't you?
Correct, I am a machine.
I knew it. Its true.
Being close to a machine like you gives me the creeps.
This is all my father's idea right?
If this is all the fault of that guy,
the less I want to go along with you!
Until my body ceases to function, I will protect both of you.
That is the mission Dr. Komyoji gave me.
I knew it…
In case you don't trust me,
anytime you need it, you can activate my forced shutdown system.
It's at my back.
Its location is...
Stop it!
Sis.
Just what is all this?
Hurry up and tell me.
All this…
appears to be linked to something very dangerous.
Your Excellency, the Minister of Defense has come to see you.
Come.
You called, your Excellency.
This time you've gone too far.
What do you mean?
Do not think that your partisan politics will continue unchecked.
Last night's accident in Shinagawa.
That was your doing am I right?
Impressive, your Excellency.
Only a small number of people are aware of this.
Why are you so eager to develop robots anyway?
I want you to convince me.
I'm listening.
Of course.
As Your Excellency already told the news,
It is for the safety of personnel and relief in disaster areas.
And also for work in hazardous areas.
Are those the only reasons?
Why do they need weapons then?
Do you not want me to know?
Oh forget it.
Now that territorial issues with our neighbors are getting serious,
it is safer for me not to know.
It is an honor to have your consideration.
However, Tsubakitani
right now the people do not want robotic research development.
You have to consider the public opinion.
Rebuilding the country and reviving the economy are our obligations. Am I wrong?
If the government always bends to the will of the people
this country will sink.
You're too extreme.
Those robots that you create with such passion
are just things after all.
And things are only things.
Human needs must come first.
Considering the public opinion will only confuse national policy!
Who's the one defending this country?
Who's the one willing to get involved in dangerous fighting?
He's someone who only knows how to make complaints
and does nothing by himself for the people of this country!
The best thing for all of us to do,
is to continue our work and research on androids.
Some things are things that are simply necessary.
Things are things you say?
Hurry up the development.
Starting today you are the head of the ARK Project.
Dr. Gilbert Kanzaki.
Congratulations, Professor Gill.
Professor... Gill.
We actually tagged along.
It's alright.
He's kinda interesting.
Masaru!
You're a machine aren't you? Like a robot?
Android.
Really?
Wow.
Cool! How do you do it?
Nanocrystals throughout my body display a 3D projection.
That hurt!
Masaru, stop that!
So, what do you think we should do next?
We should walk or use local transport.
Best to avoid main thoroughfares,
especially large stations and terminals.
If we don't waste time, then we can increase the gap between us and our pursuers.
And that will make it harder for them to find us.
Wow, you can think of everything!
That's amazing!
In addition, it is advisable that we sleep outdoors for today.
Wait a sec, it isn't up to you alone to decide these things!
What's wrong!?
Sounds like fun!
Start it up.
Look well, Komyoji.
So what do you think, Dr. Komyoji?
Clearly the attributes of Mari are above Jiro's.
It should be chosen as the prototype for the ARK Project.
Kanzaki, seeking efficiency in an android is a simple matter. However,
being able to properly have a heart is the most critical factor.
Heart?
Androids represent the future of humanity,
and they have the potential to be a force for good or a force for evil.
For this to be not forgotten,
I've represented blue as good and red as evil when I designed Jiro.
I've also entrusted the future through the Conscience Circuit of Jiro.
Androids are the future.
So I'm inferior to him huh?
Bullshit.
Soon I will rule the world that so adores him.
Jiro, this way! This way!
Hurry! Hurry!
Come over here!
Begin.
Jiro doesn't eat?
That's because he's a machine.
So what are your likes and dislikes?
Likes and dislikes? I have no such things.
That's because he's a machine.
So what about you two?
I like video games!
I don't have any.
What about manga?
Oh, that's nothing.
It's just to kill time.
What about studying abroad then?
I'm not particularly fond of it.
It's not like I'm going there because I like it.
I just thought that it would help me find something I really want to do.
Anyway, I think I've told enough about myself.
You must really like games don't you Jiro?
You're a machine after all.
I don't play games.
I do like music.
Really, which artist?
YMO
Who?
Dunno.
What about comedies?
The Drifters.
"Shimura, look back!"
You know any other jokes?
The Drifters.
Dahhunda!
Dahhunda! Dahhunda!...
Masaru.
Stop it already.
For you.
You look better when you smile.
Being angry all the time makes you look dumb.
You really shouldn't have.
I'm glad but,
It would be best not to harm living things.
They're not machines after all.
Is that an injury from the other day?
Are you alright?
I'm sorry about earlier.
About that "not machines" stuff.
Aren't you feeling cold?
Huh? No, I'm fine.
The fire is still there anyway.
Um... Thank you.
For looking after Masaru.
That kid is kinda hard to handle.
He's always very withdrawn.
I don't really know how to relate to him.
But since you arrived,
it's the first time I've ever seen him smile again.
He's changed a lot.
Became more cheerful.
How come?
How come? I really don't know.
Perhaps because you are a pers...
Or rather, an android that my father created.
Even indirectly,
perhaps he feels protected by his father.
Take for example "The Drifters" from yesterday.
That was what my father liked, right?
It's because of all the data uploaded to me by Dr. Komyoji.
Is that so?
For us, he was someone...
who only lived to work.
We have no memories of being cherished,
and we didn't even know if he loved us.
And now because of him,
we're involved in these strange things.
If my little brother's image of our father,
changes little by little,
then that might be more or less for the better.
And even for me,
perhaps…
It's nothing important.
Anyway, thank you for protecting us.
Until my body ceases to function,
I will protect both of you.
Huh?
Until my body ceases to function,
I will protect Mitsuko.
Is that true?
Hurry!
A Christmas present.
Cool huh?
As machine, I want to be perfect.
To be able to protect both of you.
It is the mission given to me.
Mission?
That's right.
You are a machine that that guy built, is it not?
Listen, Jiro.
It is the duty of an android to protect humans.
Do not forget that.
I'm counting on you.
Jiro has been located.
It is likely that he is with Masaru Komyoji.
Good. Capture Komyoji's son as soon as possible.
What about Jiro?
As long as I get the boy, I couldn't care less.
Do what you see fit.
Masaru?
Masaru!
Sis!
Masaru, are you alright?
Long time no see, Jiro.
Hesitating to attack the enemy.
You really are an imperfect android.
You're wrong.
It is best not to harm living things.
They're not machines after all.
A system capable of giving an android something similar to human emotion.
This is what the experimental Conscience Circuit embedded inside you is.
It's drawback is that you develop this meaningless obsession.
Obsession?
It has come to my conclusion that I should be the only android that must exist.
Is that so?
Switch On.
Incredible! He's definitely a machine.
Our objective,
is the data hidden in body of Masaru Komyoji.
If we can have that,
we guarantee you his life.
Be obedient and come with us.
Stop.
Stop it already!
After all you were just programmed to do all this, right?
Suffering for such a thing...
An android of your level,
deserves to be destroyed along with those foolish human emotions.
I... will fight!
Is that why you are imperfect?
Then die and become perfect.
Jiro!
Stop!
It's us you want, isn't it?
Just don't kill Jiro.
Sis.
Alright.
I do not want to waste strength even thinking about this piece of scrap metal.
Let's go.
Jiro, thank you.
Your mission is over now.
You're that android that Dr. Komyoji created, right?
And you are?
Kyujiro Maeno.
I received a message from Mitsuko and I was waiting for you all.
But when you guys didn't show up, I went searching.
Wait a moment.
I've spoken to that journalist that has long followed Dr. Komyoji.
Although he's a very annoying man,
I am afraid that he is in dire need of you.
Who knows, perhaps he might be of some help.
You know Dr. Komyoji?
Your Conscience Circuit is the brainchild of Dr. Komyoji and me.
Huh?
I'm a psychologist.
I'm bad in mechanical engineering.
My theory is that action is the source of all emotions.
He then made a perfect fusion this idea and mechanical engineering.
You are the culmination of me and Dr. Komyoji's research.
That's wrong.
I am an imperfect machine.
So let me ask you this, android:
What is perfection?
Maybe being perfect is imperfection.
and maybe being imperfect is perfection.
I do not understand.
Considering the damage to your head,
this may seem like too big of a burden to take in.
But even so...
There will come a time where in order to protect something,
you have to give up something else.
It is a very human thing.
I still... do not... understand.
We've found the Komyoji File!
And with this...
Professor Gill,
I trust you can complete the ARK Project using the Komyoji File.
No...
our true goal...
Defence Advanced Research By Komyoji Project
The curtain rises for the DARK Project.
My..
My research will not go to waste.
I'll do anything I can to get recognized.
Even destruction.
So, you're finally awake?
Or so I'd like say, but then you're a machine.
Perhaps "started up" is more appropriate, huh?
Good, good.
Where am I?
It is as you see.
The garbage dump of my life.
However, you should sleep for a while more.
How about that?
Impressive.
He really moved.
So what do you know?
Charlatan novelist?
I told you I'm a net journalist.
Anyway,
I think I know who built him, old man.
I believe that he's
an android made by Dr. Nobuhiko Komyoji
as part of the ARK Project.
ARK Project you say?
That robot production project that's made to deal with nuclear power accidents?
Well on the surface it is.
In actuality, unbeknownst to many,
the artificial human development project's products where to become fearsome weapons.
But during the project's development, Dr. Komyoji learned about the truth.
And so he left the ARK Project,
perceiving it to be a danger to his son and daughter.
And to protect the original data of the research project,
he hid it somewhere inside his son's body.
And then he ordered you to follow those two around for protection.
Am I right?
But the ARK Project;
Once you're in, you're not getting out.
Lastly, the guy pulling all the strings is
the nation's guardian.
Defense Minister Tsubakitani.
Bingo!
Right in the bull's eye.
Well done,
Charlatan report writer.
It's net journalist.
I have a request.
Could you keep him here for a while?
Those bastards are gotta be looking for him? So please?
Ok! I understand.
Those government personnel would never look in a dirty dump like this.
Moreover, with you and me around, who'd ever like to come here?
So true!
Where's Masaru and Mitsuko?
They're safe.
They were released.
And me?
What should I do?
We can say that your mission is over right?
Mission over.
I see.
Gradually these cloud networks formed the internet.
It is something created by professionals
to be much larger than other clouds and as an amalgamation of all forms of knowledge
Hey, isn't that great Mitsu?
You're really going to America!
But that means that she won't be back until four years.
Four years?
Terrible huh?
We'll miss you.
Really?
We'll definitely visit you,
then we'll hang out with your American friends!
That's so naughty!
Well, one way or another,
the two of you are fine so that's a relief.
Thank you for taking care of us.
Don't mention it.
Hey Mitchy.
Jiro is an android, but...
Yes?
How is he?
He's doing fine.
Want to see him?
No.
I think it's better not to.
Jiro has finished his mission as an android,
and we went back to a normal life.
I see.
That's true.
[Undergraduate and Graduate Studies in the US]
Hey, Mitsu?
You're leaving tomorrow and yet you're all gloomy.
Is that what they call "travel anxiety"?
Well?
You see! You see!
No, it's just that I've done a lot a stuff and I'm kinda tired.
Is that all?
I know!
You've met a nice guy and now having second thoughts?
Yes, that's it!
Absolutely!
Who? Where'd you find him? Where? Where?...
It's not that.
All I'm thinking about is going to the United States.
That's the only thing in my head right now.
I've chosen to forget all other things.
Well whatever you say then.
So there you are, Jiro.
And you are?
Hakaider.
The ultimate goal of DARK Project.
Hakaider?
Your mission is over.
He who is born from DARK,
Must return to DARK.
I refuse.
As machines, we have no other path.
Do you understand?
Either join forces me or just shutdown yourself right here.
What do you choose?
I choose another option.
I will defeat you right here.
In that case I'll have to eliminate you.
In order to prove the legitimacy of my existence.
It's no use.
I told you.
You are an imperfect machine.
You truly are an imperfect machine.
You're...
Come at me Jiro!
I'll show you how superior I am.
I cannot fight you.
You're not a machine.
You're human correct?
You're wrong.
I am the perfect machine!
When I turned into a machine I finally understood
how wonderful it is to be reborn into such a form!
Hurting a living being will only make Mitsuko sad.
It seems like the Conscience Circuit is sapping your will to fight.
I will eliminate you.
No one's going to protect you now.
I was protected?
It seems that has Mari arrived.
Sorry, Jiro.
I'll have to deal with you later.
Just you wait, I'll crush you for sure.
Have I offended the Minister?
I told you not to let him leave!
I was having a good time in Akihabara.
That should be good, right?
And you, Jironimo?
What do you intend to do next?
Why did she protect me?
Huh?
No, no.
Listen when peo..
Protecting humans is my mission.
But why,
did she protect me?
Ah.
Well, maybe...
it's because of her feelings at that moment.
Feelings?
In other words,
love, passion and stuff.
Love and passion?
Well you see, humans do many things that even they don't understand.
Especially when you like someone.
For our beloved, we would do anything without thinking about the pain.
Oh, what am I saying!
Well I am sorta a romantic.
You see, I really wanted to be content as a journalist.
but it wasn't enough to put food on the table.
So now I also make a living as a writer of teenage romantic pocketbooks.
Well said.
You learned all that first-hand,
am I right, charlatan novelist?
Oh shut up!
In summary,
every human being,
cannot live exactly how they want because they are imperfect.
Imperfect?
Dr. Gilbert Kanzaki.
Or rather,
Professor Gill.
I'm surprised that you turned yourself into a machine.
In addition, by acting on your own,
you ruined all the effort of hiding this project up to that point.
Minister, didn't you once mention
that things are just things?
I fully agree.
However, let me add something more.
People also are just things.
Professor Gill.
Do not get confused as to who your enemies are.
You are only just another thing.
Whatever.
If you cannot understand my will, then I will just have to make you obey me.
So until the end, you
never saw Dr. Komyoji's vision.
Then I'll just have to show you the kind of world I envision.
A world of destruction and chaos!
You take care of yourself while I'm away in boarding school.
Jiro…
We haven't seen him since that time, right?
Is he dead?
I've heard he's fine.
Mr. Hattori said so.
Huh?
If you already knew this, why don't we go see him?
At least say goodbye one last time!
But even if we meet...
And that person...
Jiro is just a machine right?
I'm sure he must have some new mission
protecting others.
Jiro must be sad.
Machines don't get sad.
I don't agree!
Hey, wait. Masaru.
The trump card for Japan's economic recovery
ARK Project research facility engulfed in massive fire.
Today in Tochigi Prefecture
The ARK Project's research facility
is being engulfed by a massive fire
which is continuing on even up to now.
Images taken from a remote camera show
the silhouette of a rampaging humanoid.
The armed forces are already in the site
and appear to be taking heavy casualties.
Old man.
Can you not increase my ability?
I can not increase it.
But I can tell you what limits you.
What do you mean?
This circuit here,
that's the one suppressing your strength.
By turning off this system
your power can be used to the fullest.
Turn off the Conscience Circuit?
Yes, but...
in all likelihood,
it is the one governing your thoughts and emotions.
In a sense it is your own self.
Do you understand?
If you turn off this system,
the person you one were will no longer exist.
So then please,
just stop this.
I understand.
But even so,
I am not human.
I am a machine!
But boss!
Just go watch the news right now!
Yes, yes, yes!
It's similar to that android!
The one I'm hiding right now.
Where's Jiro?
Umm.
Where did he go?
Hey Jironimo!
Jironimo!
That old...
Old man!
Where's Jironimo?
Well I tried to stop him, but he left anyway.
I knew it.
Why did you let him leave!?
Nobody can stop him.
He made his own decision to settle it machine to machine
and had the face of man full of determination.
Who am I to stop him?
What are you babbling about?
"Face of a man" you say?
But he's a machine!
He's not a machine!
He's just a "Drifter" fan.
What?
I thought you couldn't fight against a human?
You're wrong.
It is a fact that you and I are machines.
And it's up to another machine to stop a rampaging machine.
Because protecting humanity is a machine's duty.
In that case I have to eliminate you.
I shall continue to cause destruction until the world bends before me!
Like how I eliminated Dr. Komyoji,
I will eliminate you and Dr. Komyoji's entire family!
I won't let you.
You truly are an imperfect machine.
Thank you.
Mitchy!
Sis!
Hey, Mitchy!
Sis, there's trouble!
Jiro went off to settle the score that guy.
What?!
And to defeat him,
he's willing to die for it!
What do you mean he's willing to die!?
Mitchy.
The truth is,
Jiro is fighting with that rampaging android right now.
Something about settling it machine to machine.
But if this goes on, he'll certainly be killed!
No... utterly destroyed!
I don't understand why you're so conflicted, sis!
Masaru.
It's true that Jiro is a machine.
But he's more to me than that!
He may be machine or whatever...
But Jiro is Jiro!
I know that.
Mitchy!?
Passengers bound for Narita Airport, please board immediately.
I'm sorry Masaru.
Sis!
Mitchy!
This bus will soon bound for Narita Airport.
Wait!
I'll go with you!
I'll stop Jiro.
I don't want to let him die!
What will you do, Mitchy?
I'll stop them from fighting,
and then escape together with Jiro!
Mitchy.
Haven't I told you enough not to keep calling me that!
Here take it!
Go do it sis.
Come.
Don't you see Jiro?
I have done nothing wrong.
Machines do not exist for the humanity's benefit.
It is for power!
The search for power is what an android must strive for.
You're wrong.
It is to protect humans because they have hearts.
That will be your final mistake.
Mitchy hold on!
What!?
That's enough!
Please stop!
You may be just a machine,
however,
you have a heart.
So please don't sacrifice yourself for the sake of us humans.
anytime you need it, you can activate my forced shutdown system.
It's at my back.
It's true that I really want to protect you.
However, you aren't the only one I want to protect.
I...
I want to protect everyone's hearts.
Heart?
Your heart.
Masaru's heart.
Every human being's heart.
Thanks to you I realized,
what path a machine like me must take,
and what it truly means to protect someone.
And that is why,
I beg of you not to stop me.
Jiro?
What's wrong?
Protect the human heart?
This is the weakness of the Conscience Circuit.
With this strong electromagnetic pulse I'm creating, I can disrupt that circuit.
No...
I can make Komyoji's Conscience Circuit go crazy.
Jiro!
Jiro?
Hey, Jiro!
Jiro!
Hey!
Jiro?
Come on, Jiro.
Jiro.
I will fight to protect the hearts that must be protected!
It's not just my mission as a machine,
It is my will!
Until my body ceases to function,
I will protect both of you.
What?
You took out your Conscience Circuit?
Do you understand Jiro?
By getting rid your Conscience Circuit to defeat me,
You threw away your heart!
You threw away Dr. Komyoji as well!
You're wrong.
I removed my heart in order to protect other hearts.
Jiro.
Sorry.
I wasn't able to protect Professor Komyoji's heart.
That isn't important.
You've...
already helped us so much.
Jiro?
Are you ok?
It appears that even my body was imperfect.
Every human is.
We're all imperfect.
Jiro.
This would make for a great novel.
Now I know what I want be.
Someday I want to be like my father.
And I'll fix you up, Jiro.
I promise.
The professor's brain was retrieved right?
Yes.
As I've thought, this means that the work of Komyoji still survives.
This is the beginning of a new android project.
スイッチ　オン　ワン　ツー　スリー
Switch  On  1-2-3!
電流火花が身体を走る
Electrical sparks flows within his body
ジロー　チェンジ　キカイダー
Jiro  Change  Kikaider
ダークロボットむかえうて
Ambush the Dark Robots
人造人間キカイダー
Android Kikaider
チェンジ　チェンジ
Change  Change
ゴーゴゴーゴー　ゴゴゴー
Gogogogo  Gogogo
スイッチ　オン　ワン　ツー　スリー
Switch  On  1-2-3
サイドマシンでやってくる
He arrives in his Sidemachine
ジロー　チェンジ　キカイダー
Jiro  Change  Kikaider
ダークロボットおいかける
Pursue the Dark Robots
人造人間キカイダー
Android Kikaider
チェンジ　チェンジ
Change  Change
ゴーゴゴーゴー　ゴゴゴー
Gogogogo  Gogogo
スイッチ　オン　ワン　ツー　スリー
Switch  On  1-2-3
エアークラフト　大車輪
Aircraft, Great Swing
ジロー　チェンジ　キカイダー
Jiro  Change  Kikaider
ダークロボット投げ飛ばせ
Hurl the Dark Robots
人造人間キカイダー
Android Kikaider
チェンジ　チェンジ
Change  Change
ゴーゴゴーゴー　ゴゴゴー
Gogogogo  gogogo