My friends and I live happily
in a distant paradise.
Peace, quiet and tranquility
completely untouched by,
well, I don't even know
what it's untouched by,
we've never been touched...
I was just touched by
a touching romance novel.
I baked some cookies
with a touch of nutmeg.
I'm touching my
nose with my tongue.
- Will you guys get out of here!
- No need to get touchy.
Hey I said we were happy,
I didn't say we weren't
off our rockers.
Anyway, welcome to our home
KIKORIKI!
Safety, beauty...
friendship...we got it.
If you're looking for excitement,
purpose and chance to really shine
not our thing really.
Not that I'm complaining.
An old bird like me,
ah, who needs that stuff?
Okay, boys — cue the crescendo!
Wow, how romantic!
Could you imagine being here
with the love of your life someday?
Huh!? But well, I but ...
- Yes!
- No!
No!
- Krash! Please! Enough already.
- Krash!
- Here? Or here maybe?
Come on! Slow down!
Wait, I'm Serious.
Krash, I honestly I don't see
the point of this.
There!
The perfect spot!
We dig here.
Just think of it, Chiko.
Some future civilization
will dig up our box
in a hundred years, maybe a million.
Gimme that!
They'll learn about all our incredible
adventures and write amazing books about us.
Maybe we'll be like Robin
Hood or Ali Baba for them.
Today. Krash saved Kikoriki from
the terrible Viking invasion.
What are you even talking about?
What Vikings?
It's just us here,
and we're all friends.
This is crazy, Krash.
You don't get what I'm saying.
It's not whether it's real that matters
— it's whether it's fun to read!
Oh right,
just lie about ourselves, c'mon!
The books they write about
us will be nonsense!
It's not hooey if it
gets them excited.
What do you want to write?
Krash ate a carrot today?
We wanna thrill em, not kill em.
If someone finds this box
someday and opens it,
it’ll be like they discovered
some amazing world
and then they will
want to go out
and actually do stuff
not just sit around
and think about doing something.
Krash, hold on, something's
wrong about this...
Nothing wrong about it!
Nothing wrong at all.
It's our duty to the
next generation.
Don’t you see, Chiko?
And if I end up looking
amazing along the way,
then I'll just have
to live with that.
No, Krash, something's wrong with
the sand.... AAAAAAHHHHH!!!!!!
I'm thinking we can probably stop
digging now... AAAAAAHHHHHH!!!!
- Chiko? Are you alive?
- I must be or it wouldn’t hurt so much.
- Where are we?
- I-I-I don't know,
but anyplace else would
definitely would be better...
Come on now, Chiko.
It's like Ali Baba's cave.
- Shh! Hear that?
- Ha'?
I heard a noise.
THERE!
Come on, let's check it out.
It'll be cool.
Yeah, you mean like the time
we checked out the beehive?
Oh wow,
it's like some kind of magic box.
How cool is this thing, huh?
I got dibs on this!
Fine it’s all yours.
Let’s go before somebody
- Holy Carrot... is that a...
- dinosaur.
Chiko, this is crazy!
How could all this stuff get here?
No one'll believe this
is it even for real?
One thing's for real,
I'm really scared...
"Tired of the same old burger?
Try a different old burger!"
"Here are some meaningless
lines and shapes..."
“I'm losing my mind
film at eleven!”
“Tired of the same old cereal?
Try a different old cereal...”
Goal goal GOOOAAALLL!!
Please Lord make me taller-
We have to get out of here!
Okay - but we're takin'
this baby with us!
Don't drop it!
- Run this way!
- You mean like a scared idiot?
Don't let it go!
Rosa, I want to
say something here,
um, if, cuz...
Just lemme read this
Ahem, OK here goes...
I hope my words do not start to drift
As I stand here at the
edge of this cliff...
Ahem that's just a figure of speech,
not an actual...
Uh, I might be quiet like a sturgeon
But to open my heart
I sure don't need a surgeon.
I'm on the line, like a wet shirt
Preparing these words I am about to blurt
I shout these words
to the skies above
Rosa you are the one that I L—
Hold on, hey...
You'll never guess what we just did!
Maybe destroyed any
hope of ever being HAPPY
in this life!?!?
Point Dokko!
Come on?!
That birdie was out!
- This birdie says it was in.
- Hey everyone!
Look at what we found!
Here, here, careful,
down, down...
Perfect!
Maybe it's like,
an ice chest
Or a planter
A fish tank...or um...
Television.
Dokko! Hurry!
We're waiting here.
Sheesh, while we're young!
Whoops, too late.
Hold your horse feathers!
I need tools!
Let a master work!
- When I meet one, I'll be happy to.
So Carlin, you mean if this
television thing works,
we'll actually be able to see everything
that’s out there in the world?
Like everything
Castles and royal weddings
and faraway places?
That's what Dokko says!
I really hope so.
Because I mean, like,
I've read all of my
books so many times
and I'm sure this
television is going to
show me so many new things.
I just can't Walt to finally see
how the rest of the world lives.
This is really quite spectacular. Really
stellar. I read about television years ago,
but it was only a theory back then.
M-Hm...let's fix these loose hits...and...
Hey, stop pushing, let me
see, no fair pushing girls.
Quiet!
Oh, it's almost scary!
Please oh please oh please.
Voila!
A I forgot!
Back to the amazing adventures of Lucien!
When evil strikes our city again-
Lucien, Lucien!
When you're in trouble
you've got a friend--
Lucien, Lucien!
The bear in the blue mask - Lucien
Prepare for the blue mask - Lucien
Lucien! Lucien, Lucien!
Lucien, Lucien!
Lucien!
Haha, Lucien!
Wondering which shampoo gets my coat
so shiny —
You guessed it, Lucien!
On sale wherever shampoo
named after Lucien is sold!
When you're head in 10 the mall,
you don't expect no trouble,
But you folks know as well as
I do that Doctor
Caligari and his thugs
never rest...
I got this.
Gotcha, tiger!
Lucien Diapers 20% Discount
With Lucien brand diapers
UR-ine luck!
Just try to get em too wet!
- Wow, he did it! Our hero!
- You scared the organs out of me
That Lucien is some kind of hero.
You gotta be —
ya think the let
just any bum on TV?
Doesn't look like Caligari
was involved this time...
Though who knows...
arson is right up his alley...
Looking for a little
PICK ME UP, super-zero?
HA! Mwa ha! My little trap worked!
Obliterate him!
Ugh! So unfair!
Why would anyone want to Kill
a dreamboat like Lucien?
- TAKE THAT!
- I, too, fall to sympathize with them.
He doesn't deserve it.
You said it!
'Adventure of Lucien”'
So concludes another chapter
in "The Life of Lucien"!
Shot on location, all day, every day!
No one can help you now, Lucien!
Lucien brand potato chips
put punch in your crunch!
- Take that, Caligari!
- Oh Lucien, how can we ever thank you?
Now back to more Lucien.
Lucien, I feel life
slipping away from me--
I'm telling you, Maria, really.
it’s my fault!
I was simply too late.
- You were fine.
- Totally wasn't.
- No, you were fine.
- No, I wasn't.
Let's just agree to disagree.
Lucien, I'm fish food at this point,
but you have a world to save.
Watch out for Caligari and his gang...
They're everywhere... everywhere...
Maria? Maria!
MARIIIIIIA!
Agh, I can't take it anymore!
Not another second!
Who knows how but Caligari's creeps have
infested the earth,
destroying decency,
annihilating the innocent.
Lucien's working his karate-chopping
hands to the bone to stop them.
And we just let him.
What are we,
but a bunch of mooching,
no-account,
lousy loafing sponging
siphoning users,
freeloading on the flesh
of the last decent creature on earth.
Well maybe you folks
can just sit there
and let him do all our dirty work,
but this is one bird that can't.
Wuh? huh?
This is terrible.
The guy's a saint. a saint.
Working his karate-chopping
hands to the bone
While this nasty Caligari
wipes us all out,
one by one. Like... like... like...
Mariiiiiia... aaaaa!
Well then what are
we doing here, guys?
Let's get on the stick!
Lucien needs us more then ever
let's ride!
- We gotta find Lucien!
- What?
Dokko, where'd ya say the
signal is coming from?
Aa...iii... from across the sea!
Have you guys all
just lost your minds?
Okay let's get those gherkins stowed!
Chop chop, sailors!
Aye Aye, Mister Krash!
Gherkins, away!
Gherkins stowed!
- Swab the poop deck!
- Who named it the poop deck?
I believe it was that seagull flying over our heads.
Okay, this way with the TV!
Follow me!
There we go, this way! Come on, come on!
Now, just take it up the ladder.
Come on, what're ya waiting for!
Ah, Lucien Peanut Butter...
Great! So watch out, Caligari!
Dokko, stop goofing!
May contain nuts.
Just a bit more!
That's it, perfect.
It's a great honour for me
to be working with Lucian.
Lucian inspires us and teaches us
all to always be brave and honest.
I'm proud to know the only true
hero of this generation...
I for one respect your
decision to stay, Wally.
After all, there are those
of us who are called
to greatness. And there
are others of us
that are called to stay behind
and water the plants of those
that are called to greatness.
Do be a dear.
Rosa don't go!
You'll never make it out there!
Do you realize the ocean's almost
one hundred per cent water!
You'll drown! You'll get those
weird wrinkly fingertips!
Dear sweet Wally.
When you're fighting the good fight
the elements are on your side!
The wind! The sun!
We'll be fine!
Didn't you see three days ago how Lucien
crossed the ocean all by himself?
While wrestling robotic sharks!
You've all flipped your flapjacks!
And it's all this Lucien's fault!
I'll kill him, I'll kill him!
Die die diiiee!!!
Yeeuughh...!
Grab him, grab him! He's lost it!
It's just his nerves. Here —
Stay, boy.
Do your part proudly
there's a war to win, boy.
- And don't over water.
- Shove off, mates!
Bye Wal!
Bye, Rosa...
Lucien, don't leave!
- Why do you have to go?
- I'm sorry.
can’t. Justice calls.
- But when will we see you again?
- Maybe sometime down the line
in, say, ten — twenty years...
Oh gimme a break here...
twenty years...
Rosa!!!!!!!
- Keep it down, I'm trying to sleep.
Wally... Wally...
Wally!?1?
Rosa I gotta tell you
I (gasp) gotta tell ya (choke) I lov—
Wally...drink up. A spot of
warm tea will set you right.
OW! So I just sat there
on the beach forever.
OW!
I thought you definitely wouldn't
be gone for all that long.
OW! At the latest you'd come
to your senses by nighttime.
And when you didn't, I realized
you were right...
If something really matters
to you have to go after it,
even if it's totally crazy,
I mean totally crazy!
So I lit the lighthouse and here I am...
coming after...what matters most.
Welcome to Team Lucien!
That's the stuff, kid...
And THIS - makes it official!
I think blue's your color...
Holy carrot...!
"Hey you wild things! Let's
get this party started!"
Ahoy! Avast! Shalom!
We need help!
Hello!!! Yahoo, sailors! Hey! Hey come ONNNN! You've got room...!
Room, they got plenty —
hearing, not so much!
Who needs YOU?!
And you call that MUSIC?!
The forces of good are defeated once again!
Hal! Very soon...you will be destroyed
FOREVER!
Look sharp sailors!
Rough seas ahead!
Gee, thanks for filling me in.
I was about to start a pedicure.
Olga, if we don't make it, you should know
your lunch tastes just as
delicious in both directions!
Will you all stop with the jokes?!
It makes me nervous!
Oh, and these waves are
putting you to sleep?
So, where's this Lucien...?
What are we, chopped liver?!
- RO-SA! It's now or never!
- WHAT?
I just said "ROSA!
It's now or NEVERRR!"
"Push down on the lever"?
NO! That's not what I'm
trying to tell you!!
Rosa.... I...uh...
Mildew. Ecch.
Great Jolson's ghooooooooooooooost!!!
Wet wool! Wet wool!
- Batten down the hatches!
- Sadly [ failed hatch battening!
- Then man the rudder!
- We have a rudder?
Hey Krash?
Guys, at my funeral, just make sure
I don't claaaaaaaaaaaaaaaaash!
...watch it, Valentino, no means no...
Holy carrot!
We made it!
Vappabaduba!
And I didn't have to row!
Whaddaya know!
I can't believe we actually did it!
Three cheers for US!
We did it, we dd it, we did it!
Please hand over your papers - now!
We need your IDs and all the
paperwork for your boat!
No can do! We don't have any!
Your point of departure?
- Far away! Across the seal
- To help out-the good guys!
And team up with the biggest
hero of them all...
Lucien!
- Find anything yet?
- No, boss.
Try Immigration.
What a pain in my caboose.
Yes Boss!
Now listen! I DEMAND to know why
we're being locked up like criminals!
- like criminals...
- Oh, I don't know...
maybe it's because you have no...
No passports... no ID...
You've given us no CLUE as
to where you came from,
what you want and what
diseases you're carrying!
- Which ones would you like?
- You're killing me. Ugh.
Just to keep an eye
on you clowns,
we'll be throwing you in quarantine...
Quarantine my tushy feathers!
We know why you're really
covering your faces...
As if we can't tell by that sinister
glint in your beady little eyes!
Oh brother.
Those idiots think we're
too stupid to see that
they 're working for Caligari.
Imbeciles!
But I've got a trained actor's eye!
I spotted them...the very
second I first saw them!
Agreed! I've seen better acting
in a grade school pageant.
We're gonna need
Lucian to bust us out of here!
Which means one of us will
have to sneak out somehow
and let him know our whereabouts...
But how do we decide...who goes?
Quick, quick, quick!
Before they come back!
Oh, isn’t that great... JUST when
I was beginning to like it here!
Wait...whose is that one?
Uh, um, not mine. Who's left? etc...
Chiko...
Chiko?!
Far away, far from where you roam,
Far beyond the clouds,
there awaits your home.
Tied by a single thread
Stretching out from your door.
In your home, there a
light burns bright.
Burning through the night,
burning out of sight.
Tied by a single thread
Stretching out from your door.
Always know, anywhere you roam,
You are never lost.
There's a way back home.
Tied by a single thread
Stretching out from your door.
Excuse me, I can't find my friends.
Where’s the first place folks
go when they get here?
Blee blop um diddle, wait um, lemme think
about this, first place you go...oh yeah
the museum!
The museum?
Oh why dd I ever come on this trip?
Hey, you in ze fancy hat -
you gotta hit the road.
Dis ain't no disco. Ve're closed
for the night.
- Got nowhere to go...
- Den go home, porcupine
Hedgehog. My home is far away.
Don't know if I'll ever see it again.
You are cold, yah?
Maybe could use a strudel?
Zee name is "Pin."
It's all in zee takeoff, zee...
ze vind curves above his
vings, making ze vacuum,
Unt before you can say
bingity-bangity-bundt cake,
zee crazy dinosaur is flyink!
Ja, up in der sky even!
Barnstorming betveen
ze brontosauruses!
Sayonara stegosaurus!
Toodloo, T-Rex
zee you in zee funny papers!
I'm FLYING FLYING FLYINGGGG!!!
Und zen splat, ze big meteorite
smushes zem all flat.
- But zat von't be me!
- Really?
You want to fly? For real?
Zoon as I get outta zis place
you're gonna zee vot I can do.
But I read that penguins
were flightless birds.
Don't buy zee
baloney, porcupine.
Okay we got wings the size of pickles.
But it's all about zmartz! I've been
dreaming up vays to fly you neffer seen
backward forward,
to the past and to the future and ztill
be home for zoop undt veggie schnitzel.
Zis iss vere ze magic happens —
a.k.a. my home. Till I get a real one
that is. Checken ziss out — "ON!"
Woooooooowwww...
- Down, boy, down boy — heel!
- Wooow — YOU invented all of this?
I got a billion vhere zese came from
but no one is hiring mad
geniuses in ziss town.
So I verk here.
Now off to Zlumberland, my pointy pal.
But where are you gonna sleep?
Pah! Zleep is for weaklings
and zissypantses.
No offense, Porcupine.
- Hedgehog.
- Vatever.
Hope your big shot hero
friends find you tomorrow.
You're a good man,
Pin, just like Lucien.
Maybe I'll wake up and
this'll all be a dream...
And I'll be home with Krash, and
Olga and Rosa and Wally and...
Ever since Lucien began
fighting crime on his hit show,
a real life crime spree has plagued
our city and helped our ratings.
Today was no exception,
as another robbery took place during
the afternoon broadcast of LUCIEN.
Our field reporter exploits, I mean
explores their misery, shall we?
My mother gave me that jewelry.
Where were you, you dumb camel?
Watching the Lucien show,
like everyone else in town!
Next up, undercover weather
and tomorrow's cops.
Wait — reverse that.
hee hee sure baby, I'll
give 'em the royal welcome.
Get up there!
Ow, my neck!
They're coming — everyone act natural!
Oooookay kiddies — who's gonna
be big and brave for nursie?
Yesss! Woohoo!
That's the spirit!
Let's dance, feathers.
That's why I called,
What do you want first, the
good news or the bad news?
Or the pretty good news?
Okay, so bad news then good news
then some pretty good news?
Dead-end.
Oh, the good then
pretty good, then bad.
Okay. Here's the good news. What?
Okay, then here's the bad news.
Watch it, wool-bag!
Uhuhuh... Lucien... Lucien!!!
Lucien! Lucien!!!
The Lucien show!
Filmed live at Century Tower!
Century Tower...There!
All agents, we've got 624 in progress.
A lavender ram heading south on 3rd.
227 with a big 10-4 on the 624, Over.
Hey! Ram! Stop right there! Where
do you think you're going!
Hey, get a map, you crazy
foreigner doo-doo head!
Learn where you're going or beat it!
-Out of the way!
-You with them?
If I were mayor I tel you! Agh!
Attention: Ticket holders
for the LUCIEN SHOW recording
Tickets, please
please proceed to the studio.
Thanks.
Have a good day.
- Is Lucien in here?
- All day every day. You got a ticket?
You need a ticket! I said, STOP!
where do you think you're going?!
- Three lines? I'm calling my agent!
- Where do I throw out these new scripts?
Follow me, I'm throwing
out these new tapes.
Wardrobe, comin' through!
Excuse me, where's casting?
- Next couch, on the right.
- Lucien?
- Where's his contract?
- Here!
- What about his personal life?
- He grows potatoes.
Any debts?
He bought a big house downtown
and still hasn't paid it off.
He's ours!
This is my show and I ain't
lettin' some farmer who
won a contest off a box
of cereal call the shots,
I don't care if it's
in his deal or not.
He's gonna do what I
say, and that's final.
Lucien!
I can't believe it! Lucieeeeen!
Lucien, save us, we need your help!
Hang on, little feller —
there's trouble brewing.
I've got your back.
What is this, the three little pigs?
Where's the set for Doctor
Caligari's secret lair?
I made a few tweaks.
I'm sick of these senseless fights,
shoot-outs, and socks in the kisser.
Lucien's making the
show he want's to make.
A family show. Wholesome entertainment.
Enough jumping around and running about
like a lunatic, for a man of my age.
Ain't dignified.
Hal Jumping around and running?
The stunt men do all of that for you,
you useless old hack! This is our
world, hayseed. You just act in it.
Change the set back to Caligari's lair.
Anyone one does what this
loser says, they're fired!
Yeah, then good luck doing the
Lucien show without Lucien! I quit!
You quit when I say!
I created Lucien the day
I found you on the farm.
I only hired you
'cause you were cheap!
You shadow-creeper!
You sun-fearing weasel!
Let the winds gather the
threatening clouds,
and may the lightning
illuminate your errant ways!
Good luck with your silly little show, pal.
I'm going home.
Yeah? Going home?
I just have one question — WHAT home?
We're selling your house. You should
have read your contract more carefully.
You've got nothing without us.
No home, no car, no
savings, no pension!
Bupkis, bear! You owe so
much you'll be working
for us until the big
hibernation in the sky.
You're through!
You've got nothing,
nada...BUPKIS, bear!
You'll be paying it off for the
rest of your miserable life!
You'll never be free from
us, plow boy, never!
You messed with the wrong rhino, you
fur covered bag of fertilizer...
That's it! I win!
AND DON'T YOU FORGET IT!
Okay, let's go! Time
is money, folks!
We've got dead air to fill
Cue some music and get me a
replacement for this clown!
- Anybody!
- Move it, people, you heard him!
- How "bout this guy?
- We're not that desperate!
- Then how about this one?
- Good enough.
Get him onstage, disinfect him, and
get his lines up on the prompter.
Say hello, the sun is shining
Time to have some kooky fun.
Say goodbye to all
that whining, and sing
Stubi-dubi-dubi-dubum...
Say hello, the whole world loves you
you're one lucky son-of-a-gun.
Stubidoobidoo! Wondering which
shampoo gets my coat so shiny?
You guessed it... Julien!
Problems drop just like flies
When you just shut your eyes, and sing
Stubidu-dubidu
Stubi-dubi-dubi-dubum...
Why don't we try that kid
who was babbling on and
on about winds and storms
to read the weather
He didn't sound half bad!
Besides that... Bet
he works for peanuts!
Say hello, adventure's calling
A brand new life has just begun
Hold on, wait! Hero crossing!
Thank you very much...
But if-if-if you find it
all appalling, just sing
Say hello, the doors wide open
If you're ever havin' trouble copin', sing
Stubi-dubi-dubi-dubum...
- I have a little proposal for you.
- Talk to the hoof!
Lucien!
What the??
I don't care WHO he is,
you're in my parking spot!
- So out of the way— before I call a...
- What are we waiting for?
So sorry! You mean THAT Lucien.
I love this guy! There's no one
that that I love more than Lucien!
Let me help you...
...with your bag, sir...
you know I only eat YOUR tuna fish.
Wow... Lucien...
Autograph?
Make it to Shchafuhgahughlemaka.
They said they were part of your team.
Just sign here, and we'll
take care of the rest.
- Lucien! Holy carrot!
- Where have you been?
- We knew you'd come!
- We're so happy to see you! It's you!
Lucien!
Yall's are who?
Lucien's Team Invincible!
Hip, hooray!
Lucien? There's no more Lucien.
-What? What do you mean?
-What's he talking about?
I'm so confused...
What the heck should we call you then?
You shouldn't.
Stand clear of the closing doors.
Next stop: Igorville
Alright, I give up!
What do you nut jobs want from me?!
We came from far away to be
with you to defeat Caligari!
- And his minions!
The world is in peril!
Look! The fan club's closed, folks!
Ditch the masks and go home.
No autographs, no nothin'.
Am I making myself clear?
Now please leave me alone!
I've got a lot on my mind!
But sir, we came to fight!
wait a darn second
so you want us to fight EVIL together?
I see, you're not fans...
You're! A bunch of! Nutjobs!
I got NO energy for this.
- Go back to Kookoo-Ville, kids.
- Lucien! Wait!
Listen, get it together, team.
Just go with the flow. Don't
you get what's happening here?
You think he lets any bunch
of bananas fight with him?
He's really TESTING us, d'ya get it?
Caligari's spies are watching everything.
We gotta split up, fan out
It's time to go undercover.
And now, the moment you've
all been waiting for!
The terrifying leap into the abyss!
Featuring the once great star of the screen
- Lucien!
Go on, jump already
if you're gonna jump!
Psst, hey Lucien! Agent
Krash here, remember?
Agent Krash?
Oh, It's you.
Did you find your hedgehog
friend or whatever?
Haven't stopped looking -
that's what friends do.
I've searched the town
with a fine-toothed comb.
Maybe I needed a hairbrush.
Wonder if he's undercover,
like us...heard anything?
Nah.
Niiice!
That's a tough dive.
Let's hear it for Lucien!
He'll be signing autographs for
anyone with cash who still cares.
Stick around, next leap in 10 minutes!
And...done! There!
Museum
Eez it possible zat you missed zem?
No. Nobody came today either.
Ach, maybe tomorrow, Porcupine.
It's the television
event of the century!
Even huger than last week's
television event of the century.
Meet this generation's only
true hero - the amazing Julien!
Holy cannoli!
Look at these babies over here, Joey!
Can it, numb-nut! What kind
of mutton-head are you?
Krash! Carlin! Is that you?
You came for me?
- Oh, hello.
- H-hello...
Hey. How's it going?
Who are you?
Depends — uh, who are you?
Well, I'm nobody, really.
During the day I wait
around for my friends,
and at night, Pin lets
me sleep over here,
He's the guard. Oops!
Don't spread that around
he could get in trouble
for letting me stay.
No, heh heh your secret's
safe with us, little fella.
- Thanks. So you guys work nights eh?
- Uh...matter of fact, we do.
Ahhhh! You get everything polished
while the place is closed.
- Yeah, we're polishers.
- Why don't you take these ones?
What, you think we're idiots here?
Those cases are wired, dude.
Oh! No problem, guys.
Yeah, give us a hand
and we can clean out,
I mean clean up the whole joint.
Well, it was areal
pleasure meeting you.
Yeah, let us know if you end up
sleeping over, say, at the bank.
They got a safe there we really
been meaning to clean out, too.
See ya in the funny papers!
- Adios!
- Bye now! 'Night!
Go! Go! Go! MOVE IT!
Holy Schnitzel!
Charlie 1, to Charlie 2.
I have the two suspects in my sights!
Moving in!
Chiko? Vy dit you open zee door?
You're surrounded!
Resistance is futile!
Put your paws and flippers in the air,
or we open fire.
Do it!
Okay, er, let's give it a shot
Ahem, “for today's forecast we're um,
looking at lots of sunshine
“point to swirly stuff and big
line of triangles over shoulder”
moving West Northwest.”
That's fine you're fine, you're fine
everything's fine!
It's all good.
Where's that new kid! Three minutes to air!
I'm here! Over here! COMING!!
Hee hee hee!!! Can you
believe that little moron?
I thought you had bathwater
for brains but that guy!
Bathwater!
Hee hee! We're in the do-dee-o-do.
dooot doot da doo dah...
Hello?
Agent Rosa!
It's Agent Wally.
I need you to turn on the TV and check
out the weather report, right away!
Okay...
Good morning, Wally.
Today, were uh looking at lots of sunshine
with a bunch of clouds in the
approaching high pressure system.
The wind is windy, and the
ocean is exceedingly wet,
And even though there is a threat
of a storm coming in from the sea,
it will never stop me from telling you,
Rosa, what I've been wanting
to say to you for so long.
Rosa, I wanted to... Rosa,
I wanted to tell you that
for a really long time now,
I... I... you... I...
Wally! We found Chiko! Let’s go!
We found him!
- That's him!
- What is it? What's going on?
We found Chiko!
A major robbery was
stopped in progress—
Now the city can sleep
knowing— These criminal
masterminds, who have terrorized
the city are at last—
The getaway car has
not yet been found.
Would you care to comment
on these events?
Outrageous! They deserve life!
The verdict will be announced today.
You have been found guilty and
sentenced to life in prison!
Oh... oh please...
What do you freaks WANT!!!!
So what do you want me to do about it?
You want me to blow up
the cockamamie jail?
Oh, well, yes, thank you — Jolly good!
You're out of your coconuts.
Look, I've got enough
idiots trying to force
me do stuff without you
nut-bars joining in.
Now can you please leave
nicely, or do I have
to call the chuckle squad
to haul you away?!
But Lucien, we came all the way from across
the sea to help YOU in your mission.
Which got our friend put in jail!
Don't you care?
It's a Caligari plot, obviously!
When he heard we're all working together
he decided he had to break us up,
so he framed Chiko for a robbery.
Now don't you see that you've
got to help us all out?
Caligari is a made-up character!
Just the same as Lucien is
My real name is—
—Barry!
Fine, you're not nuts,
you're from far away.
You gambled everything to
come here and got ripped off.
WELL JOIN THE CLUB!
I wish I never left the farm!
I came to be a great actor...
and instead I'm selling shampoo!
So we both got robbed here.
Sometimes you aim for the sky
and get kicked in the can!
Tough! You clowns are NOT my problem!
Uh...Sounds like you're on the fence.
Take your time! We'll wait.
Seems he's coming around though!
Hey guys...? Just, please,
listen to me closely.
He's not gonna be “coming around”...
Okay? No really.
He's not...responsible for us...
He's just an actor...
and he's just playing a part...
It's not real-life...
It's like...theatre.
Like theater? It's just...pretend?
Make-believe and that's all?
- So, there's no Lucien? Nowhere?
- No one's swooping in to rescue us?
No one.
- Guys, come on. Let's go.
- See ya...
Thanks for getting
through to them for me.
Get away from me.
Here. Sorry we couldn't find any
gold-plated Egyptian dishes for you...
But we DID mange to find
you some ancient food!
Hey Chuck, do these new uniforms
make me look fat, or what?
- No, you look great!
- Yeah, but good-great, or great-great?
- Okay, team, Chiko's in there somewhere!
- Thanks for narrowing that down for us...
The first thing we do is get over this
high voltage electric fence... I think
Great! I'm right behind you!
And then what? Huh?
That, my friends, is the question.
Tell me. Have any of you folks
ever heard of the word...PLAN?
Of course we've got a plan!
Everyone knows you have to
have some kind of plan.
Colin, tell him the plan...
Tell him what the plan is, hm?
What? Me? PLAN?! What do I
look like, Planny McPlan?!
Maybe we can buy a plan...
There IS one shady character...who
just might be able to help!
I always did love this view.
How about... a heads-up before you
decide to drop in and scare me to death?
You know what a nervous
nellykins I am.
Look, Barry... I'll tell you
what I found on this “Chiko”.
Then I'm going back to bed.
He and that other guy are in cell
block 47 at the State Penitentiary.
There's a chance he'll be declared
incompetent for insanity—
You should hear the
dribble he's spewing:
Good, evil, peace, friends, Lucien,
Caligari, dinosaurs wearing slippers...
That screwball—one
of a kind, for sure.
There are six more right
outside your door. Humor me.
Caligari! It's a trap!
Ahh! Caligari!
Seriously, Barry!? This is your team?
I can't do it... — this is not some scripted
TV show -
it's a real prison break-out.
This is suicide!
C'mon, Eugene, you're the
master of ingenious plans.
I know, you're probably
thinkin' that when Old
Barry lost his job he
went off the deep end.
But it's not about that, Eugene.
These guys need us for real.
For once we could say we did
something
that actually mattered.
What do you say, old friend?
OK, here's the floor plan, the sewage
system, the security guards' schedule...
Quiet!
Anyone know electricity?
Uh, just basics...
You're on alarm systems.
Don't mess it up!
Listen up, geniuses.
There's not one part of this plan
that's unimportant, not a one!
You must commit every single
step of it to memory —
... 'til you know it in your sleep!
One misstep and you're all goners!
I've made a thousand cunning
plans in my career, and
every one of them, RUINED!
By a stupid mistake.
Uh uh...that and the fact
that you always stop to chit chat
before pushing the big red button!
Enough with the wisecracks!
Let's move on. ON to the weather!
What's up the for cast?
You with the horns.
I regret that it's looking
very stormy! Sir.
That's perfect. Most
important,
cool heads... Yeah.
Yagh! Woman, we're not
even being chased yet!
- Who gave you your license?
- What's a license?
Ugh - Pull up ahead at the station.
I'll wait for you there. Not to worry.
I bought you tickets for
the last train out.
The nine-fifteen.,
Hit the breaks, hit the breaks!
- Miss that train and you're on your own.
- Thanks, buddy.
What-what the devil are you wearing?!
I said black, nothing but black!!
But only bad guys wear black...
Wha - but - eugh!
Come on, it'll be fine!
Or not!
Lets do this...
Oh, buddy your life was looking
like you'd ride into the sunset.
Everything was easy as pie.
So quiet, so peaceful, so mellow.
And now your starring in
someone else's movie.
The wiring diagram used
completely different colors.
We're 20 seconds behind...
I'll cut this one, and the
red one too, just in case.
Chico...
Warden, I'm worried I
left my iron on at home!
Hey warden, warden, where you going?
- Chiko! Chikooo!
- Krash?
I can't believe it!
We've been looking all over for you!
I've been looking for you too!
I missed you so much!
Hello! Looks like fun!
Let’s have a pillow
fight, whaddayou say?!
Lucien...
It's you... I KNEW you'd
come and save us!
I knew it. ..
Ladies and Gentlemen: The train
scheduled to leave in five minutes
is actually leaving in five minutes.
We sincerely apologize
for any confusion.
- Look, Ma! It's Dr. Cali-gari!
- Right, and I'm Jab-ba the Hut...
- Yeah that's what dad calls you.
- I'll kill him,
Annnnd NOW! The moment
you've all been waiting for!
Presenting...the only
real hero of our times —
It's the Ju-lien SHOOOOW!
Hurry up!
- Uh...but... You forgot Pin!
- What's a Pin?
- He's in there...
- No you don't, kid!
We're sticking to the plan!
He's on his OWN!
I"m not going anywhere without Pin!
I am so in love with you...you—
Oh, forget it!
OPEN it!
But we don't have the keys
to these cells!
Oh all right, episode
three hundred sixty-five.
It's th Case of the Loose Tooth!
AC-TION!
Get that rope tied to the cell door!
Al right...Every—
body—out—of
my (ON/OFF) WAAAY!
Ring the alarm! Oh, I'm hit...
I think I'm hit...
Send backup!
That him?!
Hey, whoa! Vat in zee world
iss goink on here?!
Talk with your feet, flappy!
You'd better move it or lose it!
Just pretend you're having
a bad dream and relax...!
Agh, my sciatica...
Where—are—those—guys?!
- Go! Go! Go! Go!
- Move out, move out!
- We're done for.
Hey! Over here, you! Hurry up!
6-4-8-5-2-7-3-9!
Bingo!
Come on!
Come on, Chiko, come on!
Gimme your paws!
It’s a dream. It's just a DREAM!
I'm dreaming, that’s all...
Lullaby
and good night, go
to zleep leetle penguin,
Oh, good.
At least we have...power
It worked!
Hm, I don’t sink zat vas "off"!!
No...no...NOO!!
All right!
Were you taking a nap?!
It's all clear! C'mon!
Hey, wait! Where are the...
Crazy Al on the Crazy Eights with
some crrrrrazy weather news!
"Dude,
where's my blimp?"
Seems that storm has knocked our WJUL Eye
in the Sky blimp loose and it's outta here!
First caller to spot it wins a year's
supply of Julian Teeth Whitener!
Oh the insanity on the new Julian FM.
Now, back to our show!
Wondering which shampoo
gets my coat so shiny?
You guessed it... Julien!
Julien! Sign my face!
Sign my baby's face!
Sol After this
commercial...
go to scene 18.
Now back to our show...the
amazing adventures of...
Julien!
Sorry, you're fine, you're fine!
Everything's fine...It's all good.
Has anyone seen the new kid?
Tell him, three minutes to air!
I'm here, over here. Coming!
Can you believe
that little moron?
I thought you had
bathwater for brains,
- but that guy!
- Hah! Bathwater!
Hah! Bathwater!
What do you think you're
do-ing, coming here?!
How many times do I have to tell you
don't bring the loot to the studio!
Are you trying to get me
put away or something?!
But boss, you won't believe it!
Its like Christmas in July!
Yeah, there was some
four-eyes nerd there!
He handed it
right over to us!!
Will you look at all of this stuff!
You know, I never thought I’d say
this, but you idiots are geniuses!
Boss, you just keep everyone
staring at that idiot box,
and we'll keep stealing their stuff
from right under their noses!
- That's right, that’s right!
Boo. Boo. What a crock,
what a lowlife! Lock him up!
Throw away the key!
Test pattern! Bring up
the TEST PATTERNNN!!
Stu-bee-doobee-doobee...beedoh!
- There's only one harness left!
- We didn't count on the penguin!
Get outta here..
- But...
- C'mon, hurry up!
- Woah something's wrong!
- The rope is caught on a blimp!
WAS caught on a b—OOFF!
This'un's for real, boy.
Woaoaoaoaoaoaohhhh!!!
- Lucien!
- Barry! You can...
Agh! Come on!
- Faster, Olga! Don’t lose him!
- I'm trying! I'm trying!
Agh! Left! Turn left!
-Come on, turn left!
-Turn left!
Which is my left, my stirring
hand or my writing hand?
That's how I remember —
stirring or writing.
- When you're driving?
- No, when I'm cooking!
- We're not cooking!
- Right, we're dying!
Lemme out...
- Pull me in, PULL ME IN!!
- Gotcha!
Go! Everyone into the blimp, NOW!
Let's move it, folks! Pedal to the metal!
Chiko! You're almost home free,
buddy, so feel the burn!?
We got everyone?
Uh, not quite!
Hey weatherman.
You're not off the air yet.
Does anyone know how to
fly one of these things?
Don't look at me!
In theory, I can do it!
- And in practice?
- Let’s do it!
And this here goes- I'm
doing it, I'm flying!
I'm flying—look at this!
Chiko, look! A news camera!
It's recording everything!
I'm gonna record you,
so even after you die—
Which, let's face it,
pal, under the current
circumstances, is probably
only a matter of seconds
THEN, they'll find the
video, and know
that once upon a time
lived the great Chiko!
A real hedgehog for the ages.
You'll be famous! A legend! A STAR!
Oh good, more turbulence...
- Where are we?
- Somevhere over big vater.
Either we've been blown way out to sea, or
we're going in circles, I can't tell...
Hey, look! I see a light!
Those were my mother's last words...
- What light? Where?!
- It's a city!!
Come on, come on, press
something, come on!
Take us down before we
all get blown BACK!!
Krash! No!
H-h-holy carrot!
That’s our lighthouse!
No place like home! Bring
it nice and easy now...
Now we just need a nice landing.
Bam bam, cool!
Yes, Lucien was a TV hero.
Doesn't matter at all.
Whether it's a hero or not
we got more important then that.
And I like that.
Hold still.
Don't move!
Al right Chiko, here we go,
time for your big scene.
You've finally captured Caligari
and you've got him all tied up!
Yeeahh.
Okay, Caligari, ready to do this?
You're angry, you're scared.
You're ready to run. Feel
it but don't over feel it.
Action!
- So... are we there yet?
- Nah, not yet.
Almost there.
So, you know how they say that behind
every great man is a great woman?
Well, here I am behind you...
and you are the greatest...
You see, Rosa, after all we've been
through, there's nothing to be afraid of
anymore and I can finally just let the
words flow straight from my heart...
Rosa, you are the only one
that I have ever loved. There.
There! I said it!
You do know she's still lost
her hearing from the accident,
- right Wally?
- I know, I know,
but at least I can practice.
You are smokin', Action Star.
This and a Ferrari and I'm there.
Hurry it up, hot stuff!
You're already beautiful.
Coming, handsome!
Hold on!
Here! How's this?
Okey-doke, Peeplez!
Please! Come on...Can
I open my eyes now?
Almost there.
Scarf OFF!
Okay!
That is one FINE lookin'
house you got there!
It is lovely, isn't it?
Like they used to
make back in the day!
- And it comes with a real sturdy BENCH!
- Handy to have out in the yard!
- It's a beaut. Just perfect!
- Thanks, Berry!
And it's got a fireplace,
garden and pot - belly stove!
Uh, Rosa?
So, that means your hearing's back...
Say something?
So which one of you
does this belong to?
That, my dear friend... That
little number is yours! Go on!
- Step in!
- You crazy?
You want to... give this to me!
You guys are nuts!
I- I can't believe you folks!
I can’t just, come on! We're
talking about a house!
Sorry, dear chap! It looks like
you're stuck here...with us.
- Welcome Home!
Go ahead, Barry!
Ok guys, this is your last chance--
Going, going, going and a half—GONE!
Okay! I'm thinking, once a guy has a
house, it's time to have a house party!
I think it's time we get it started right now!
Come on, people, shake a leg!
My friends! Attention, my friends...?
A photo for posterity!
Okay, we're a bunch of fools.
We crashed a blimp and broke
every single bone in our bodies!
But we found two new guys that
we can CREAM in badminton!
Wait! We're-we're a cleaning service!
I could polish that gun for you...!
So, can you tell us Eugene,
how did you catch them?
Episode 112- The Case of the
Super-glued Steering Wheel
I'm so confused,
is this news, or is this the show?
I'm totally meshugenah.