Subtitles by explosiveskull
Hey, man.
This one here.
You hear that?
Oh shit.
Come on.
Oh shit, baby.
Whoa.
What the fuck?
What the hell do you want?
Don't stop now.
We were just enjoying the show.
You can join in if you want.
Wait, what the fuck is this?
Knock it off, Joan.
We're here for work.
Shut it, Miles.
Well, what's
going on here, huh?
Hey, hurry up.
I'm hungry.
Listen, listen, you guys
are wasting your time.
If this is some sort of
home invasion or something,
I don't have any valuables.
Frank doesn't like it when
people don't pay their debts.
Fuck me.
Listen, listen, okay.
I told him the other day, I
don't have that kind of cash.
I just need a few more days.
I'll get it to you tomorrow.
I swear to God.
You better or I'm coming back.
Okay, okay, I promise.
See?
Easy.
Fucking bitch.
What the fuck are you doing?
I was letting you
handle it your way.
I got a 200-pound
man coming at me
and you're just standing there
with your dick in your hand?
Okay, what do you
wanna do with the broad?
Forget about what
you've seen here.
This never happened.
Got it?
Yeah.
Good.
Let her go.
I like these.
Nice.
It's okay, it's okay.
What the fuck do you
think you're doing?
Having a little fun.
Come on.
You can go.
What's the matter with you?
We're here to do a
job and get outta here.
Uh-huh.
Or do you wanna wait around
for the cops to show up?
No.
Good.
Let's roll.
Fucking cunt.
What?
What did you just say?
I said I'm fucking hungry.
I heard what you said.
You ever have
a threesome, hmm?
Those are fun.
Yeah.
I had a threesome
one time, in prison.
Are you serious?
He is.
I never had one though.
First time for everything.
Yeah.
Hey, Anson.
We're gonna need a
clean-up crew here.
We got a body.
Yeah, make that two bodies.
All right, thanks.
What are you
standing there for?
Let's go.
See you later.
Maybe...
What's up, dog?
What you got?
Give me the usual,
a bottle of whiskey.
♪ ♪
Hey, can I get three
shot glasses, please?
Another job well done.
Oh, is that what it was?
What's that supposed to mean?
Oh, really?
Hey, where'd she go?
Aw shit.
What's wrong?
Joan's ex just showed up.
Yeah, so what?
So, she's
got a hard on for him.
This should be good.
Oh shit.
Just
give me one moment.
Long time, no see.
How you been?
Good, good, I've been good.
You?
Great.
I miss you, Anthony.
I should really get going.
It was nice seeing you.
Anthony.
Just like Saint Anthony,
finder of lost things.
I think I've lost something.
Can you help me find it?
Excuse me.
Is this slut bothering you?
Um.
We're having a moment here.
He's not interested.
Back off, bitch.
Oh, ooh, I'm scared.
Come on.
You should teach your new
girlfriend some manners.
What was that all about?
Whoa.
I'm tired.
Let's go back to my place.
I can't.
I'm with someone.
Bring him.
Hey.
Really Joan?
Come on, let's go.
Get the fuck out.
Hey hey hey,
right there's good.
Frank.
Sorry.
Please, come in.
Take care of them.
Put your clothes on.
Come on.
I'll be in the car.
Like anybody gives a shit.
I see you've been
entertaining again.
Got let off a little
steam now and again.
Well, I'm sure you let
off plenty last night.
You gotta be careful.
You don't know what kind
of people are out there.
I am those kind of people.
Remember?
Jesus, Joan.
You look like shit.
When's the last time you slept?
Couple of days maybe.
I could go for some eggs.
My bitch of a wife
has me on a diet
and I need eggs and
bacon and more bacon.
You know bacon's
bad for your heart.
Don't you
worry about my heart.
Too old to give a shit anyway.
I have some
leftover taco salad.
You're not old, by the way.
Seriously, if I
were a working stiff...
God forbid.
No, if I were a working stiff,
I'd be coming up on retirement.
People like
us, we don't retire.
Yeah, well you
keep pulling stunts
like the one you
pulled last night,
you'll be lucky
to see retirement.
Don't be silly.
I'm serious as a
heart attack, Joanie.
If you're not careful,
you're gonna wind up
with a bullet in the
back of your head.
Don't worry about me.
I'm faster and tougher
than any dickwad out there.
You're not
tougher than a bullet.
He was disrespecting me.
What was I supposed to do?
Well, let's just say
your managerial skill
leaves much to be desired.
Frank,
you know I would never do
anything to embarrass you.
I've outlived a lot of cocky
youngsters, just like you,
because I knew when
to keep my cool.
Well, you keep
eating like that,
I'm gonna outlive
you, no problem.
Very fucking funny.
Give me a napkin.
Listen,
my nephew, George, is
gonna be joining the crew.
I want you to look out for him.
And watch your temper.
If you don't change your ways,
you're gonna be looking
at an early retirement,
if you know what I mean.
Yeah, sorry, right.
All right, good.
Check in with Anson.
He's got an important
job for you.
Meanwhile, I gotta go
take care of the mess
you made last night.
Oh.
Can I help you?
No, I don't think you can.
Oh, just,
where do you think you're going?
Where do you think I'm going?
Up there.
Oh, okay.
I'm afraid we haven't
been properly introduced.
My name is George.
I run things around here.
That's funny.
Now get outta my face.
Whoa.
I don't think you understand.
My uncle owns this company.
And, by extension, me.
You work for him, you
work for me, sweetheart.
You got that?
You don't run shit.
You might be Frank's nephew,
but you're just
another dumbass kid.
So, get your head out of your
ass and get outta my face.
Joan.
What?
You gonna let her
talk to me like this?
Anson wants to see you.
Be sure to wash and wax it.
I see you met Joan.
Yeah yeah yeah, she's feisty.
I really like that.
I'd stay out of her face.
She bites.
Yeah, me too.
Hey do me a favor.
Take this to the dry
cleaners, get the blood out,
have 'em back to
me tomorrow, okay?
Appreciate that.
What the fuck is
going on around here?
Who is this guy?
You gotta put up with him.
He's the boss-man's nephew.
Hey, George.
It was just a joke, buddy.
Hey, George, come back here.
Yo.
Doesn't match now.
This doesn't make any sense.
Hey, Joan.
How's it going?
Can't complain.
Never-ending
paperwork.
It's not easy being a
woman in a man's world.
Ain't that the truth?
Will you give us
some privacy, Donna?
Yes, sir.
And get
your feet off my desk.
And what can
I do for you today,
oh great Mr. Anson, sir?
Cut the crap.
I got a dead employee.
That's what's up.
So?
Can't you just do
the usual casserole?
The usual casserole?
What's that supposed to mean?
What am I gonna tell
this kid's family, huh?
You can tell them
that their star athlete
tried to kill me
with a baseball bat.
It was self-defense.
Self-defense or not, don't
you ever do that again.
You hear me?
Look, man, you got a problem?
Talk to Frank.
You watch yourself.
Frank can only do so much.
Now, got something
for you to do.
Frank has asked you to
personally take care of this.
Some asshole with a conscience
is causing trouble
for us downtown.
I get it.
A few punches, a
little bit of blood,
and everyone gets the message.
Anthony?
Social worker at the
Downtown Youth Shelter.
He got the bright idea to
step out of the shelter
and onto the streets,
trying to help these kids
clean their lives up.
Well, it means a drop
in demand for us.
You need to go and
send a message.
Are you deaf?
No.
No, I got this.
I sent the boys out
on a different job.
You'll handle this one yourself.
Got it?
Donna, get back in here.
Shit.
Hey, babe.
Did you miss me?
Sorry about last night.
That's not why I'm here.
You've been making some problems
for some very important people.
What are you talking about?
You know what this is about.
I'm sorry.
I don't.
These are our best customers.
You get in the way
of our business,
we'll get in the way of yours.
Is this about
the youth shelter?
You don't look so good.
Why don't you calm down.
Let's go get some fresh air.
Why are you always trying
to shove me down, huh?
I'm not a little girl anymore.
Fuck.
I can't do this.
What's gotten into you?
Are you on something?
Get the hell outta here.
Now.
Go.
Hey, guys.
What's up?
I don't wanna go out to...
Shut your fucking mouth.
What the
fuck was that for?
I said
shut your mouth.
Oh, that's a good one.
A little fight, huh?
Back up.
Don't make me shoot you.
Oh, oh.
Whoo!
See what happens to
your fucking gun, huh?
This is
what happens, huh?
You know, Joan, I used to
think you were a hot chick.
Yeah.
That was until
I got to know you,
you know?
You know, maybe if you
were like a team player,
which you're not.
Yeah.
We got your back
and your always running
your fucking mouth.
Where you going,
where you going?
Where you going?
Oh.
Yes!
I fucking got her.
Where you going?
No one's home, honey.
Where you going, huh?
Hey, don't kill her yet.
Don't kill her yet.
Let's have some fun, right?
If she tries to
run, you shoot her.
Okay, relax.
- Don't fucking run.
- Come on, let's go, let's go.
Oh!
That lady got balls.
Whoo!
Ah, fuck.
What the fuck?
Hey, where's your
fucking knife now?
Yeah.
You better not run, though.
Let's just kill
her man, come on.
Stop!
Wait, what's Frank gonna think
once Frank's heard about this?
We're gonna tell him
that you got killed
by a rival gang.
It happens all the time.
- Fuck you.
- Oh.
Fuck all of you.
I won't forget this.
What are you gonna do?
You gonna scratch
out our eyes, huh,
with your empty promises,
your empty threats, huh?
Why couldn't you
just shut your mouth
and take your cut?
You know what?
Shut your fucking mouth, okay?
Because you would order
us around with your jokes
and your empty threats, but
you know how to do your job?
Me, not you, all right?
Now, I do the job
and I get the glory.
Yeah.
Wait, stop stop, please.
Please, I got money.
I got about $30,000
in a box under my bed.
If you let me go,
it's all yours.
We all got money.
Yeah, we all got money.
Just walk away.
You know what?
Let me shoot her, come on.
I don't think I will,
but thanks for that tip.
Miles,
please don't do this.
Oh!
Fucking bitch.
You gonna help me with this?
Goddamn, yes.
Fucking bitch.
All right, Miles,
Miles, enough, man.
Come on, let's get
the fuck outta here.
Yeah, she thought
she was better than us.
Fucking bitch is.
Whoo!
I gotta start doing more cardio.
Fucking feel alive.
Whoo!
Let's go, bitch tits.
- Come on.
- Let's go.
I haven't
shot up for weeks.
What about your dad?
Did you speak to him?
Fuck that asshole.
Always going on and on
about the old country
and how he used to be and
he wasn't even born there.
Well, but he is your father.
No, not
according to him.
Ah, you shouldn't
take personally
things that are said in the
heat of the moment, right?
Anthony, can I talk
to you for a moment?
Um, sure.
Guys, would you excuse
me for a moment?
Cheryl, what's wrong?
Do you remember that girl
you used to date, Joan?
I just saw her yesterday.
Why?
You wanna tell me
what's really going on?
What do you mean?
She came here the other day,
was looking for you.
It's fine.
Don't worry about it.
It's really nothing for
you to get upset about.
I don't want her
hanging around here.
I don't like her.
I know all about the
people she hangs out with,
all about the things she does.
I don't want her
around this house.
This is a safe zone.
So, next time you see
her, tell her to stay away
or I will.
Yes, ma'am.
Good.
Now get back to work.
Who's there?
What, what's wrong?
Well, I
thought I saw something.
Aw, you're dreaming.
Go back to sleep, honey.
I saw something.
Hey, get out of here.
Sorry.
What are you doing?
What was that?
There was a
strange woman in the corner.
Come on.
Joan, what are you doing here?
Leave the light off, please.
Can't keep doing this.
You have to let it go.
Now you're breaking
into my place.
You know those guys I
used to hang out with?
Of course.
They're the bane
of my existence.
I'm gonna get them and
I need you to help me.
What am I gonna do?
You're the only
one that I can trust.
I need to make them pay
for what they've done.
What have they done?
They jumped me
outside of my apartment.
Oh my god.
Are you okay?
Let me take you to a hospital,
let the cops take care of this.
The cops?
What are they gonna do?
I'll take you to a hospital,
but I'm not gonna help you
with some ridiculous vendetta.
Very well.
You won't join me, then
I'll do it on my own.
You're going to see what a
woman's wrath looks like.
Joan, you need to stop this.
I have to
congratulate you, Miles.
Revenues been up since
you took over the crew.
Up by 12.5%.
That's what happens when
you put a man in charge.
Yeah, makin'
a real killin' now.
What's that supposed to mean?
Cool your jets, asshole.
You got something
you wanna fuckin' say?
Relax, dude.
It's a joke, okay?
It's nothing.
Hey, we all know
whose dick is bigger.
Let's get our work done.
That's right, bitch tits.
Get out there and do
your fucking jobs.
Listen man, keep your
fucking mouth shut.
Anthony.
Anthony, it's me.
You're following me now?
Hey, did I come
over last night?
Do you remember me coming by?
What?
Look, something
strange is happening.
Listen, you need to stay
away from me, all right?
Don't talk to me.
I can't deal with this.
Just go away.
Oh, and one more thing.
I need to talk to you.
I can't.
I don't wanna get involved.
You're the only
person I can turn to.
Really?
Don't you have anyone else,
your friends?
My friends took a
crowbar to my skull.
I'm sorry, I can't.
Let me go.
I'm not doing anything.
Hey, you wanna work my
streets, you gotta pay the rent.
Stop wriggling
around, you bitch.
Let me go.
Now shut your fucking mouth.
You talk when I
tell you to talk.
Rose?
Hey, this ain't none
of your concern, retard.
Who the fuck are you?
I'm not talking to you.
You wanna make
this your business?
It's my job.
Oh, are you a cop?
He's my youth counselor.
Oh shit.
You're a counselor.
Well, mister counselor, one
of your little charges here
has been working my
streets without a permit.
Very big no no.
Bad little girl.
Bad girl.
Let her go.
She's just a teenager.
Oh, she feels more
like a woman to me.
We got a teenager.
You get the fuck back.
You got knocked the fuck out.
That what happens, you fuck.
Now, listen here, buddy.
I got no beef with you,
but you keep messin' with us,
you're gonna end
up six feet under.
Kick his fucking ass, Miles.
Stop it.
You understand okay?
Get your hands off him.
What the fuck?
Where did you come from?
Get her outta here.
What the fuck
are you doing here?
It doesn't matter.
You know what?
I'm in charge now. We don't
pussyfoot around anymore.
You always were
easily distracted.
Motherfucker!
You're gonna have to
try harder than that.
We don't fuck
around here anymore.
Time to bring this bitch down.
Miles, let's get
outta here, man.
This shit ain't right.
What was that?
We need to get outta here.
Take her back to the shelter.
I'll be all right.
I'm not leaving you here.
I know a place
where it's safe.
I used to come here when
my parents would fight.
Back before I
was at the shelter.
God.
You all right?
I don't think so.
How did you, um, do that
thing with the shadows?
Just seems like
it was a part of me.
It was pretty fucking cool.
Did they hurt
you or violate you?
Did they?
No.
Those guys wouldn't know
their dicks from a rubber hose.
You sure got a mouth on you.
Ain't that the truth.
Well, I need to get going.
Got prior engagements?
I gotta clean up.
What?
Just go.
Are you sure you're okay?
You want me to take you
back to the shelter?
No, I'd rather stay here.
You sure you're safe with her?
I'm not gonna hurt her.
Well, don't let anyone
else get in here, all right?
What do you see in him?
He's cute in a
dorky kind of way.
Besides, girls like me
can't afford to be picky.
What happened to you?
I heard that you got attacked.
I don't like to
think about it.
Oh, but
what was it like?
I don't know.
I don't remember everything.
There was a sharp
pain in my head
and suddenly my
whole body went numb
and next thing I know,
I woke up in some alley.
It was like you came
back from the dead.
God.
I wonder what it's
like to be dead.
You know, it must
be kind of peaceful.
Peaceful?
It's not peaceful.
It's painful.
There's something that happened,
something I can't explain.
Just,
just blackness.
Besides, what are you doing,
disrespecting your
body like that
just to make a
little bit of money?
You should be getting
ready for prom,
not sleeping in some
filthy warehouse.
It's a long story.
You don't wanna hear it.
I got all the
time in the world.
I guess I could tell you.
I don't know.
I guess it all started
back in middle school.
There was one year at camp,
all the girls used to sneak
into the boy's cabins at night.
The usual teenager horny shit.
Anyway, one night we were
hanging out and chatting
and some people
started making out.
And this big kid, Mario,
he was probably a
football player,
he comes over and
starts kissing me.
And at first I
went along with it,
'cause I liked the attention.
Then he started to
get a little rough
and I told him to
stop and he wouldn't.
And his friends just
kept cheering him on.
I just laid there and
let him do his thing.
I laid there numb.
My mind went elsewhere.
But after that I could feel it,
all of them laughing at
me and calling me a slut
and a whore.
Wow.
Tell me about it.
Now I'm telling you all this.
How did you wind up
sleeping with men for money?
I tried to get a
job, really I did,
but who's gonna hire a
16-year-old homeless kid?
Sorry.
I know what it feels like.
It gets better.
It does.
I left home when I was 17
years old and I made it.
Look at me.
You?
And have my friends
leave me for dead.
No thanks.
Well, there's gotta
be a better way.
I don't know.
I'm just tired.
Thank you
for helping me out.
And I do hope that you
get this all figured out.
You're welcome.
Goodnight.
Night.
Hey.
Hi.
Well, I made it home safely,
as you can see.
I'm scared.
What's going on?
I don't know.
I wish I did.
Is this it for me,
hanging out in alleyways
and warehouses with
the scum of humanity?
They're good kids.
Rose seems okay.
What if you had a chance
to make things better?
What if this is what
you were meant to do?
That's depressing.
Maybe you were
meant to protect them.
From what?
I can't even protect myself.
Wouldn't you have wanted
someone to help you out?
It doesn't work like that.
Well, maybe it does.
I like your optimism.
Think about it.
What if you could make
a difference here?
Oh.
Thank you, dear.
Of course, Frank.
Miles, tell him
what you told me.
It was her, I swear to God.
Who?
It was that fucking
barracuda, Joan.
I am not happy.
You were supposed
to finish her off.
I could've sworn that we did.
Don't worry, Frank.
We'll take care of
this little problem.
I hope that you do.
You wouldn't want to
disappoint me again, would you?
No, Frank, I wouldn't.
Good, get out.
Dirk, stay behind.
We need to talk.
I'm sorry we let you down.
Do we trust these
guys to do the job.
Oh, absolutely.
They're my best men.
I'm sorry I failed you.
All these years, you
never have until now.
Wait.
Look, you, come on.
It's not gonna happen again.
I'm never gonna fail you again.
I know that you won't.
What the...
Miles, you're in charge now.
Take care of the situation.
All right.
Leave it.
Donna.
You work for me now.
You understand?
Good.
Now, get a clean-up
crew in here.
I'm afraid that Dirk
has made a mess.
All right, bitches,
things are gonna change.
I'm in charge now.
Hey, you notice anything
strange going on around here?
No, we all knew this
day was coming, guys.
What the hell?
No no no, I'm talking about
Frank is acting differently.
Eh, Frank just
needs to get laid.
What the fuck are we gonna
do about this feisty bitch?
I don't know.
Hey, working?
Fuck off.
What the fuck?
Nice ride.
Where you taking it?
Uh, what?
No no no, slow down.
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Goddamn it.
You.
You too.
God, you motherfuckers.
This is what we're
gonna do, okay?
You get back there now.
No, I don't give
a fuck, all right?
Are you telling me what?
I'm gonna knock your fucking
teeth in when I see you.
Shut the fuck up.
Your job is very
fucking simple.
You get in there you get...
What the fuck you talking about?
It's a girl!
It's a fucking girl, okay?
She's got high-heels on.
I don't fucking know, all right?
She still has such a nice ass.
What the fuck, though?
She got, like, shadows and shit.
How did she do that?
Maybe she's a fucking ninja.
I know how we're
gonna get this bitch.
Light it up, boys.
Light it
up, man, we're ready.
Like moths to a flame.
Cheryl, why are you
calling me so late?
There's a
fire at the shelter
and we can't find Dimitri.
I'll be right there.
Dimitri!
Dimitri.
Dimitri, wake up.
Wake up.
God.
You know, I am trying
to stay positive.
I'm trying to be here for them.
You, you just wanna
go after them.
You just wanna kill them.
You just wanna be like them.
You just wanna do all that.
It is not an answer.
Violence only begets violence.
This ends tonight.
A kid is dead.
You understand that?
You don't, do you?
Fine.
Go.
Go, do what you wanna do.
I'm done.
Yeah.
Mmm, ma ma ma ma.
What the fuck?
I paid my fucking bill.
Fucking bullshit.
Hello?
What the fuck?
Ah, you fucking bitch.
What the fuck are
you doing here?
You want money, huh?
Fucking take it.
It's under the fucking...
Ah, fuck.
Fuck.
Don't, don't.
You thought I was
dead, didn't you?
Good riddance.
Ah.
Yeah?
Whoa, slow down, what?
What?
No, you stay right there.
Fuck!
Neal, get in here.
Ah.
Yeah?
I need you to get Henry.
You guys are gonna go do something
for me right now, okay?
Normally I don't say anything.
And I know you're
thinking you're doing
what you gotta do, right?
But...
you gotta be careful.
None of this is worth going out
and getting yourself
killed over.
That's very insightful of you.
You know, I'm truly touched
that you're concerned
about me like that,
but I tell you what,
if you like, you can come by my
house later, tuck me into bed,
maybe give me a little
inner-thigh massage,
but you worry 'bout you.
You don't tell me what to do
and you don't ever, ever
warn me like that, okay?
I understand.
You do you.
Right
over here, honey, please.
Did you need a ride or...
Uh-uh.
I think I'd rather walk.
Okay, we'll be
back at the place
for dinner tonight, all right?
Call me if you see
or hear anything.
I will.
Okay.
Joan, are you there?
Stay away.
I figured I'd let you know
that we're all okay.
They found us a new shelter.
It's not okay.
It won't be until
they're all dead.
You look terrible.
Go.
Go far away and
never come back here.
Act like you've
never met me before.
Sometimes bad things
happen to good people.
It's not your fault.
Just let me rest in peace.
Miles, you're next.
Where you going, huh?
Where you going?
You got her?
Got her, man.
You can't
run back to the safety
of your little shelter anymore.
It's gone.
What happened to it?
Why are you doing this?
Killing me isn't
going to do anything.
No, see?
That's where you're wrong.
It's gonna make me feel a lot better.
God, you're cute.
Don't worry.
I'm not gonna shoot you.
I'm just gonna
collect a little debt.
I have nothing
to do with this.
You're wrong.
You have everything
to do with this.
It's just business.
You mess with my customers,
I'll mess with you.
Time to take care of
this little annoyance.
Let's do it, baby.
Let's do it.
Ah, come on, Joan.
You wanna dance, Joan, huh?
Here to save the day again?
Joan, watch out.
Enough of your talk, lady.
I don't know what
the problem is.
Every time I turn the lights on,
bitches just be
disappearing on me.
Ooh.
Oh shit.
Come on, Joan.
You wanna play?
Let's fucking play, Joan.
Fuck this.
How 'bout you do
something about Miles,
'cause he's already out of hand.
He's gonna get everybody killed.
It's fine.
Just keep me updated.
Jesus, Frank, what
happened to easy money?
Arson, murder, too
high and level.
I trust him.
He knows what he's doing.
Will you give us a minute?
Will you
get me a sandwich?
I think you've wasted
enough of our time already.
Oh, Jesu...
You've been a good
friend and a good partner.
There's no reason
that has to change.
You just need to
have a little faith.
Everything's gonna be fine.
Okay.
Frank, you're not
gonna like this.
You here to lecture me?
I wanna
say I'm sorry.
I heard about what
happened with Cheryl.
It's not about her.
Then what is this about?
Revenge?
What do you think?
Getting
all settled in?
It's nothing.
Just a few things I
picked up off the street.
I wish you would listen to me.
You can't keep doing this.
You're not gonna stop me.
It's all I have left.
You've got me, the
kids, the shelter.
You mean the shelter
that they burned down?
We'll get a new one.
We'll rebuild and move
on, just like you do.
What makes you so different?
What makes you stay with me
when everyone else
has abandoned me?
Hm?
I guess I'm just stubborn.
I'm not gonna give up on you.
I like that about you.
Maybe you're right.
Maybe we should just
forget about the past
and move away,
get out of here.
It's for the best.
Are we gonna get a house
with a white picket fence
and be a happy couple, hmm?
Joan, it's not the time.
Now's the perfect time.
It's cold.
Do you want your
shirt back on?
No, leave it off.
Wait, this isn't right.
What's wrong?
This isn't right.
Relax.
Stay with me.
I'm not going anywhere.
Get me something, anything
that connects to her.
I got nothing.
There's gotta be
a way to get to her.
You boys, always
thinking with your head
and not your hearts.
You gotta follow her heart.
That's how you get to her.
Remember her ex-boyfriend,
that social worker?
Seems he's been
spending a lot of time
at this warehouse lately.
The 63rd Street warehouse.
It's been boarded up forever.
It's just a tax write-off.
What's so special
about that place?
I don't know.
Well, let's head down there
first thing tomorrow morning,
find out.
Ho ho, my man.
Thanks.
How's the head.
Ah, just a mild concussion.
Doc said I'll be good
in a couple weeks,
but in the meantime...
gave me some of the good stuff.
Maybe you oughta go
home and just rest up.
Yeah, I wish I could, man,
but Frank has got
guys working overtime.
It's like he's on some sort
of crusade or something.
Well, I'd rather
not talk about that.
Yeah?
Why not?
All right,
between you and me,
just don't feel right.
Look, I've been with
Frank a lot of years
and we have done
some crazy shit,
but nothing like
this, killing kids,
burning down a homeless shelter.
Whatever it takes.
I mean, it's just
business, right?
Business,
don't make me laugh.
There's gotta be
a line somewhere.
How far are you willing to go?
How much are we
willing to sacrifice?
I don't know, man.
Shit, I just work here.
I gotta get home.
My old lady's on me
about all the time I'm
putting in around here.
Hey, I wish I had
an old lady on me.
We have a big
day tomorrow, dog.
You should rest up.
Ah.
We've got her.
It's too bad your
girlfriend's not here.
She's not around much
during the day, is she?
Look, we're done
with all this.
We're leaving.
You won.
I have a message for Joan.
It's very important
that she get it.
Yeah, what's the message?
That's the message.
Who's there?
You've got a lot
of nerve coming here.
Haven't you caused
enough damage?
I'm sorry about what happened.
Look, I know you
probably hate me,
but you're the only
person who can help.
I've been looking
everywhere for Anthony.
I can't find him.
You
don't know, do you?
I don't have time for this.
Just tell me where he is.
He's not anywhere.
He's dead.
Dead?
What do you mean dead?
I mean he's gone
and it's all your fault.
If you hadn't gotten him
mixed up in all this,
he'd still be here.
Don't you dare judge me.
You have no idea what
I've been through.
You sit up here in your
big comfortable house,
away from the world.
You don't know what it's like
for people like us out there.
I've been doing
this a long time.
I see the damage you people do.
Why do you think I do this?
It's to protect the world
from criminals like you.
I did everything I could
do to survive on the streets,
but don't you blame me.
I would've never done
anything to hurt him
or cause him any kind of pain.
I loved him.
Hey.
I know you.
You don't
wanna know me.
Yeah, I do.
Seems like we always get stuck.
Wheel goin' 'round.
No matter how far we go,
we're always right
back where we started.
No matter how much pain and
sorrow they've caused us,
we keep going back to
that source of pain.
Pretty wise
words coming from a
prince of the streets,
like yourself.
I try.
Here, have some.
Genuine rotgut.
Nice.
No no no.
I know it.
I know it's tough.
What can you do, but to sit back
and look up at the
stars, revel at them.
Revel at the glory.
Isn't it amazing, universe?
I don't give a fuck
about the universe.
Anthony's dead.
If it weren't for me,
he'd still be alive.
I'm sure this
Anthony was special.
I wish I could bring
him back, but I can't.
Thanks.
God, won't they ever shut up?
Who are
you talking about?
You can't hear them?
They're all around us.
Joan.
Frank, you son of a bitch.
Now you've done it.
Blood will fill the
streets tonight.
Yes, but I will
do the bloodletting.
You have the mark upon you.
Leave now before it spreads.
Joan, at last.
Well, I see all the
stories are true.
Very impressive.
But you've also become
a real pain in the ass,
sticking your fingers into
other people's business.
Why'd you kill Anthony?
He never did anything to you.
I didn't kill him.
You did.
We both
know that's not true.
What was I supposed to do?
You turned your back on us.
You betrayed my trust.
You didn't deserve my trust.
You never did.
I just finally realized that.
Poor little precocious Joan,
thinks she's the
top of the class,
but she doesn't realize
without me protecting her,
she'd have been dead
a long time ago.
I'm here to collect a debt
and you're not gonna stop me.
I don't think that you will.
Why's that?
Let's take a walk
down memory lane, hm?
When I was a kid, I didn't have
much going for me, aimless.
But there was a perfectly
good war going on
on the other side of the
world, called Desert Storm,
sounded romantic.
So, I signed up to
fight terrorists
and they shipped me off
to the middle of nowhere,
but we were
completely unprepared.
They had no idea what
we were up against.
It was sheer hell.
Snakes, scorpions, heat,
IEDS, and roadside bombers.
And I was a specialist.
So, I spent months at a
stretch alone in the desert,
nothing but sand and desolation.
I should've died there,
but there are also dark
forces in the desert,
very powerful,
very primal forces.
And so I...
survived.
And I came back
and I brought some of
that darkness with me.
That's a real nice story,
but what's it got to do with me?
We all have our own demons.
There's a darkness
on your soul, Joan.
I saw it when we first met.
I knew were we meant
to be together.
Don't fight it.
We're all one big happy family.
Join us, Joan.
I can never join you,
not after everything
you've done.
What I've done is
help you to become
who you truly are, by
stripping away your weakness,
the last remnant
of your humanity.
I have freed you.
And now it's time
for you to come home
where you belong.
I think I'll
decline, thank you.
I'm very disappointed...
but...
it's been fun.
What are you gonna do?
You think you're the
only one with tricks?
Watch this.
How'd you do that?
Been around long enough
to learn a few things.
Very disappointed.
Such a waste of potential.
I won't stop until I kill you.
Hello?
Anthony, is that you?
I can hear you.
Anthony?
It's me, Joan.
Stay away from me!
Let me help you.
What do you want?
I'm here to save you.
She thinks
she can save me,
but she's mistaken.
I'm beyond redemption.
I don't understand.
She doesn't understand.
Perhaps she never will.
Anthony is dead, gone forever.
There's only I.
And who are you?
I am your past
come to haunt you.
Stop this now.
You are Anthony and I am Joan.
Joan.
I knew a Joan.
She was tough, but fair.
Unfortunately, she died.
No.
I'm right here.
I'm right here in front of you.
You're confusing me.
Pull yourself together.
Forget about the past.
We're here now and
I need your help.
We're gonna find the men
who did this to you, to us.
But I need you to be strong.
Can you do that for me?
I will be strong.
Good.
Now let's go find this asshole
and teach him not
to mess with us.
Okay.
Look around.
There's gotta be
some sort of clue
as to where he's hiding.
He has
left the building.
He's gone, never to return.
Leave it.
I can smell him.
He's gotta be here somewhere.
Come on, Frank, where are you?
No.
It's no use.
He's hiding somewhere and
he doesn't wanna be found.
I bet I know someone who knows.
Hello, Neal.
Hey, Joan.
Here to collect a debt.
Yeah, I know.
What we did to you was terrible.
I didn't have anything
to do with it.
I'm not here for you.
Where's Frank?
I know where he is.
I need you to let me go.
Just show us where he is
and you won't get hurt.
Come on, this way.
A little feature that wasn't
on the real estate listing.
Joint's got a safe room.
Ah, you finally found
my little sanctuary.
Well done.
And I see you brought a friend.
Behold, I see an
angel before me.
But even Lucifer
was an angel once.
You and I both know
that's not why I'm here.
Yes, and I'm very
disappointed, Joan.
After all this,
after everything
I've done for you,
you turn your back on
your father like this.
Very cute.
You're not my father.
My father was an abusive asshole
and an alcoholic.
You're birth-father, yes,
but I like to think that
you have come to think of me
as a father too.
Don't you flatter yourself.
When I first met you,
you were a street punk,
a kid, but I took you in
and I molded you, turned
you into the killer
that you are today.
Who told you how to hold a gun?
I did.
Who taught you how to fight?
Who taught you how
to love, how to fuck?
Well, that was a long time ago
and that time has passed.
Now it's time for the student
to become the teacher.
Very well.
This isn't good.
Leave her alone.
Now, it's just
you and me now,
just like it's always been.
What a shame.
We make such a good pair,
but that's all over now, Joan.
No.
Joan, what are you doing?
Stop, stop.
Is this some kind of trick?
No, it's me.
It's Frank.
Kid, I didn't have a choice.
I had to survive.
I had a wife, kids,
waiting for me at home.
I did what I had to do.
I'm sorry, kid.
I'm sorry too, Frank.
Anthony.
Anthony, don't do this to
me again, Anthony, please.
Please.
You.
I thought I killed you already.
You can't kill
me, little girl.
I'm already a part of you.
There's no point in fighting.
I've already won.
You haven't won shit.
Haven't I?
What are you feeling right now?
Hatred, anger, a
lust for vengeance?
That's me.
I'm already inside your head.
The more you hate, the
more we become entwined.
Delicious.
There's no place that you
can go that I won't find you.
We are bound to each other.
I'm sorry,
Anthony, I'm sorry.
You're alive, you're alive.
I remember who I was.
I refuse to
play by your rules.
You said I had a decision.
You said I had a choice.
I've made my decision
and this is what I choose.
Well, this, this
is more powerful.
I'm sorry, Frank,
but it's time for
you to go home.
So, have you seen
her since that night?
I like to think that
she's still out there.
I don't know, I think I saw
her a couple nights ago.
I was walking home late at night
and I could feel someone
watching me from the shadows.
I bet it was her
watching over me.
I think you're seeing things.
I'm gonna be late.
Gotta go.
All right, be safe.
Oh, don't worry.
I'm sure Joan will keep me safe.
Hey, where you running?
What are you doing out
here so late by yourself?
Leave me alone.
I ain't got no money.
What do you mean
you ain't go no money?
Hey, where you're going,
you don't need any money.
Leave him alone.
What are you
gonna do about it?
No, dude dude
dude, that's Joan.
Yeah, you should
do what she says.
You don't wanna get
on her bad side.
Let's get outta here.
You should
watch yourself.
It's dangerous
out here at night.
Thanks.
Subtitles by explosiveskull