The little spider # #
# Upgrade 'on the gutter #
It was the # rain #
- No!
# And the spider fell down '... #
I tried to scream.
- No!
- She needs to be saved  her.
You hurt someone?
Holy shit. Feast!
Hey, behave in such a way as
do not you leave the highway.
That sucks.
Honey,
have you seen my blue tie?
I'll have 'need
for the feast of Jenkins.
which,by the way,
I am not sure really I wanna go to.
- What do you think?
- think fast.
A lot of people sitting
around the piano to sing.
You can go for us?
Spring break!
Hey, Taylor, come on, get on!
Oh yes, 'Yeah, right.
- Taylor!
- Hey, Maddy.
whatever.
- See you at the party tonight!
- Feast!
There were 20 guys in that car.
Can I come with you?
Yeah ,
I. .. I can not believe that
your parents would let you do.
It 's been a year.
Do not touch my guitar. Ok?
I put it myself.
Mmm, you've got  such a pretty daughter.
And if ... we did a video?
Look at you.
Are you having fun?
Next, I have to look.
Look at me!
It '...
I love it.
Smile.
React!
Look at me.
Tell them!
Hey, Maddy,
Help me convince Cammi
to come with us.
Oh, you ... you have to come!
It must come, true Taylor?
I do not know.
Derrick, remove from me the thing
off your face!
It ', Derrick! Either you stick it
in that place, you pervert.
You ', you expect,
that we take off our shirts
or something?
It ', enough. The kids are sleeping outside
in tents tonight.
Help me to stake out
the tent, Taylor?
Help me with the pole
tent, Taylor!
- All the centimeter? That class.
- That's disgusting.
We want you to come with us!
In addition, we need
another girl.
I do not know. I have a lot of things to do
for school and I can not come.
- Next.
- When we got home a day earlier.
Oh my God, 'so' sexy!
Oh hey ...
How is my partner
laboratory?
Hey, Dylan.
- Hey, what's going on?
- How are you, Dylan?
- Hey, Dylan.
- Oh, how you doing, man?
I think I could come.
It gives you 'bother this?
This?
Here you are.
You will take away 'this tape.
But if you say something,
a word, I'll 'kill you.
Let's take a picture!
Line up.
- What?
- Line up for the photo!
I'll give 'a chance' to go away,
counting to 10.
Are you ready?
Ok, ok, 1 ...
1 ...
2 ...
3.
3!
My conditional and 'over.
I'm ready to celebrate!
It ', you managed to stay a year
whole without getting arrested again.
Adam!
Hey, those are your parents?
Here's to a great tour!
Embarrassing ...
That's cool.
We'll see.
I love you too.
Do not come out to say hello?
They are pain in the ass.
It took hours
for giving me permission to come.
You have really nice parents!
It starts!
- In a lads holiday!
- It ', put music!
- The Poolside, cool!
- Come on, Trevor, come on!
On the street!
SRT project and I 'proud to present
A Vacation to Die.
I Translation: Eriante, Demo
Yevgeny, letsmakenumbers
I Revision: Spawn
[SRT project]
Are you okay?
- I'm cold.
- Are you cold?
There are 38 degrees in here and you're cold?
I just shudder.
It happens to me sometimes.
It '.
Here you are.
It was my mother.
- E 'here for a century.
- Thank you.
- Fuck!
- Oh.
Here, take it.
It 's beautiful.
Cammi ...
Do not disappoint me now.
Wow, a year ago,
you were a shy little girl and now
here's to spring break.
It ', and a year ago
were in juvie.
Not a bad
I have changed my life, huh?
- They have a huge bow.
- Really? I'm so 'cute.
- I want the shoes so '.
- Fuse!
- Puffy, Oko, come back here right away.
- Fuse! Where are you going?
- Puffy, what are you doing?
- Oko, Fuse!
- Fuse!
- What are they doing now?
I Next gas station is 155 miles.
I Wild Jack says:
"Beware of the giant boa"
- Hey, careful, Derrick.
- Tricky!
Hey you, rock star.
Send me a message?
Yeah, 'cause' I do
always, Adam.
- Let's start first.
- Pre-match?
- We will sell 'beer?
- Let's do it!
Come on!
- Let me see.
- Get out!
Ouch! Maddy!
Fuck! My foot!
I'm sorry.
It's not 'fun!
Taylor, I do not
laughing at you.
What 'happened?
Are you okay?
I think so. '
He's fine. It 's just ...
His parents do not have paid
much attention since he 'came back.
- There is going all out.
- I do not know.
I knew a year ago
and it was exactly the same.
Dear, Adam.
Hey!
Hell, out here, everyone.
I'm Wild Jack.
Next, everyone here,
around here right away.
I must ask you one thing.
How would you like
see a boa constrictor
large enough
to eat a man.
Hello!
When you come from Wild Jack
you have to see the boa constrictor.
7 and a half meters.
E 'of the' in that shed.
You know, once and 'release
and ate ... an eraser.
My partner Carl and I,
we take care of him.
We give them to eat,
we clean the poop and stuff like that.
In these parts,
1.66
00:14:42,570 -> 00:14:43,970
everyone knows him
and if they are away,
fear him.
The great Pete.
Pete the boa constrictor.
A snake eater.
It 'a reptile scary.
- So, who wants to see it?
- I want to see it!
It '? Want to see it? $ 2.
It costs $ 2.
- A head?
- $ 2, $ 2 each.
Next time, let's go.
- He does not give '2 bucks.
- Come on, give it to me.
Dropped. Paying.
- Let me get $ 2.
- These are 2 ...
These are 2.
Come on, come on.
Hey!
Will never have him, you know?
Who?
Next.
Cammi, we realized all
look like Dylan.
I. ..
I do not want to be mean, but ...
you're not her type.
I'll I'm just saying ... as a friend.
I do not want to see you hurt.
Friends?
It 's the right time
'cause my partner Carl,
is doing the nap.
It was his turn.
So 'a good time.
The snake has just eaten.
We enter through this door.
Ouch. Revenue.
- I can not wait to see it.
- Right here.
Tuck here. Make space.
There 'room for everyone. Plenty of space.
Revenue. Next, you, put your '.
It's okay.
Shh, stand still.
The snake should not be awakened.
Observed.
The reptilian brain has much
in common with the DNA
of humans.
It's about the human ...
But maybe you and 'evolved
much more 'than humans
in terms of animal intelligence ...
- Oh, please.
- And ability 'to survive
and perhaps even
conquer the man!
Who 'really the animal more'
smart on planet earth?
Ask yourself this question!
And here's to you Pete,
the giant snake.
Oh God!
Pete, what did you eat?
Have you eaten Carl!
Oh my God, look,
Pete and 'alive!
Look, and 'alive!
Carl! And 'real!
Live!
Oh, his tail is moving.
It was worth it
for $ 2, come on.
It 's alive, look!
It 's just a trick.
It 'really a bad snake!
Hey, now go back.
It 'a joke, come on.
Will remember for a lifetime.
Hey guys, what are you doing?
Open the door.
Guys,
let's go.
Open the door.
Guys?
Guys, open the door!
Guys, there is' something in here!
Guys, come on! Open the door!
It's not 'fun!
Guys, open the door!
Open the door!
I open it for you.
Ouch.
Adam?
Oh, you were the 'inside?
Now you're screwed.
Come on, brother, you were
just messing with you.
Are you okay?
Friend! Hey!
Come on, man.
This damn door
I redid the manicure.
- Paint on the fingers, splinters ...
- Damn!
- Come on, you've never made a joke?
- I am a bit 'jealous.
Sometimes you're idiots
guys, I swear.
Look, I'm the 5 and 'the first ...
What '...?
What the hell '?
A grain of corn,
I think it's a grain of corn.
- Come on, brother.
- It's about time!
Jack, I told you
not to eat that stuff.
Hey Taylor, I have to drive, moved.
Get out of there '.
Hey, guys!
Hey ...
what ... what '?
Well ', I was' behind
to listen to my C.B.
and it seems that someone
was killed on the highway.
And now all traffic
flows up to Corn County.
- Accident?
- No, someone did that to pieces.
E 'was slain really well.
And if I were you,
I would change the road.
Unless you
commitments for a month or two.
Hey, guys,
someone 'was killed.
What?
Well ', he killed?
Maybe we should leave.
Well, 'according to that nut them'
Corn County and the road to 'clogged.
Can I let you all fooled.
We take the back roads.
- I want these in central, okay?
- I got it.
Bodrogi.
- What?
- Bodrogi.
Oh shit.
Jesus'.
From side to side.
You say?
Where 'the girl?
E 'on vacation with his friends.
At the lake or to the spa?
To the lake. We have a guardian
the park on hold.
God
Keep me posted.
I want news' ...
in real time.
Ok, sir.
I feel bad
for the girl.
I You are already 'dead.
- Guys, listen, silence!
- I # # The little spider
Upgrade 'on the gutter #
# I and the spider fell down '...
- Fuck! Just messing with the radio!
- Oh, that shit!
Shit, now
does not take right here!
- Oh shit.
- What the hell was that?
I need to check the tires.
Strange.
The tires are in place!
What the hell 'was?
Guys, I think
that we have broken.
You think it was electric?
There 'a bit here.
Give me.
Listen, this is not
we are no properties' private.
Ok?
Forget the cable. Let's go.
Look, Madison.
- You think it's open?
- It ', maybe 30-40 years ago.
Let's go see this place?
In many other places we will go
before arriving at the lake?
- Where '?
- Between 4.2 miles.
- We can read.
- Come on.
- Freeze!
- Adam, are you afraid?
Come on, Adam, you'll keep '
hand during the ride.
Stop.
Wait, I said.
Do not come near.
Ok.
I want you to take this thing,
turn,
and go out of here.
Listen, we do not want to bother.
We just wanted
through here, please.
What's wrong with you, boy? You do not have
understood what I just said?
Turn around and go to hell!
- What's going on here?
- Get back inside.
Do not make me use.
Now move
and go to hell!
Ok, let's go, let's go!
Come on!
Well ', we're going in the direction
wrong, that 'of course.
Trevor, fuck.
Come back!
Guys, let's go back.
We should go home.
No, we should go back to the old
and be more 'friendly.
- Portiamogli of food or something else.
- Food?
Madison, had a gun. If
wanted food, we would have taken it.
It has no right to stop us.
It's not 'her the way.
Guys,
the cable and 'broken, right?
Let us fast from the '
and will not be 'never know.
Derrick is right.
You know what?
- I need a drink.
- Hey, give me one.
Place lost!
Oh yes'!
Well ...
welcome back!
- Hello. Hello. Hello!
- This can not 'be good.
Be '...
welcome back
I'm Henry Lee.
What's up, guys?
You have decided to
accept my offer?
I want you to take this thing,
I turn, and go out of here.
Have you decided all
to accept my offer?
- Maybe?
- Well ',
You have to go down this road
and then turn right.
In about half a mile, past
for a small campsite amazing.
Right in front of
to the amusement park.
Focolare, but nothing but water '.
- You guys, you have enough water?
- I thought we was getting into.
I was just playing with you.
No, you got it wrong
what I said.
I Go to hell! Move!
But you're welcome to stay.
I can give you water if you want.
- Be ', and' nice of you!
- Derrick!
Do you live here?
It ', ma'am. I take care
the amusement park.
I keep it clean.
And what they 'remained, however.
I had a flock here, but ...
I had 5000 sheep
simultaneously.
You know, the sheep
animals are more 'stupid
that you can ever meet.
Well, you guys.
Be careful.
It 's just a stretch of road,
about half a mile!
Okay, back
if you need water!
And you can caress
my sheep, if you want.
It ', stop it. Seriously.
God
It 'seriously, man.
Stop it.
Cammi.
I'm sorry.
- Bumper Cars? How do we get?
- It 'creepy.
Taylor, you were not
sull'autoscontro born?
How do we get?
Navigate. Up.
Scoot, moved.
O my God!
- O my God!
- Okay, Taylor.
- Ok.
- Hey! And 'closed for some reason!
- This place is' crazy!
- Taylor!
It '...
Abandoned for a while '.
I think that's where we'll be here.
Do you wear contact lenses, eh?
Hey guys, we have to see it!
Come on!
Want to join?
Sure.
- Do not think so!
- Do not you come in?
We're going to see
on this side.
I wonder if
someone still works.
It 's all wet.
Dude, seriously?
How many cobwebs, man!
What 'that smell?
Madison, we are entering
in the maze of trees bottle.
It 's so horrible.
- From the
- I will not go '.
- Maddy, come on.
- No, and 'dirty.
- No.
Taylor!
It 's just a ride.
And 'wet.
The tin man walking!
It 's been ...
it was left for
when it was in operation.
Muerto?
Ok, there are a lot of bottles.
Taylor?
Taylor!
Guys!
Guys, look!
Boys. Guys!
Guys!
Guys, look!
Guys, guys!
Ok. Look.
No, guys!
Wait, wait!
Another time.
I Pay attention to the swords
of Muertos.
Shit.
It ', it worked.
Keep arms and legs
in a safe position.
Come on, guys.
Let's go to the castle of death.
- Yeah ', the castle of death!
- I guess we will go there '!
- Come on!
- Hey, push again ...
Castle of death is!
I Welcome to the castle of death.
I is coming forward
of your death
What 'up here?
I Take care
the swords of the Muertos.
I Please keep your arms ...
I Taylor
I Be careful where you step.
I could lose not only the way.
I might lose my head
Hey.
Is everything okay?
It '.
- It's cold in here?
- Cold?
No.
No. Not really.
Hey, come on.
Dylan.
Dylan?
Dylan!
What?
Dylan?
I Welcome
My home entertainment.
I Now it 's too late
to go back.
I 'Cause I fixed?
Not 'so' bad to lose his head.
I least I can look
around corners, do not like you.
I Welcome
My home entertainment.
I - It 's too late to turn back.
- It 's too weird!
Yes, yes, 'Let's go.
Come on.
I least I can look
around corners, do not like you.
I Welcome
My home entertainment.
Where were you?!
Can not a girl '
get lost in here.
Fantastic!
Guys, guys!
This place 'gorgeous!
Instead of 'sleep outside tonight,
'cause we stay here?
Or not.
- Okay, I I go out.
- Come on.
- Let's get out of here.
- Sorry, move!
I'm going out of here!
Here, here!
Cammi, let me help you.
What's up '?
- Nothing, I was just ...
- What's up '?!
Your hair ...
Nothing, come on.
Hey, Maddy, what's up '?
It 'just mad' cause you and '
lost in the labyrinth of the bottles.
I have not lost.
Taylor, you were hiding from me.
God, get it over with.
You're so 'good with that, Cody.
Just wait until we get to the lake.
God, Taylor,
you put more alcohol apart?
You're just a featherweight!
Hey, where you going?
Where do you think?
Hey.
Nothing beats that house entertainment.
Yeah, this whole place
me 'the willies!
Hey, it was fun the 'inside!
Guys, you have not seen what a strange
bedroom had that type.
However, before we leave
this place tomorrow morning,
and better '.
Ah ok,
very funny.
- Who took it?
- What?
Adam, you took my guitar?
- Give me the guitar.
- Did you put behind you.
- I know where I put it.
- Come on, who took it?
- We do not own, Cody.
Taylor, give it back.
- We do not own, Cody!
- I put it here!
It's not 'fun, guys! Ve
you are going between you? Come on!
Hello?
- Where are you going?
- To get a light, relaxed!
Calm down, man.
Relax!
Ouch.
Who has it?
Huh?
Bitches.
It's not 'fun.
So what?
Keep.
Listen, give it to me!
Give it to me, man!
- I do not see here, man.
- It '?
- Okay, where 'my guitar?
- What?
Just play.
When you went to pee,
did you hide it. Where 'the guitar?
- Do not joke Adam! Give it to me.
- I do not have.
- Calm .
- Give me the guitar!
Stupid guitar!
- Cammi , give me the torch.
- Where did you put it?
I did not take myself.
- You're an idiot .
- Fuck you.
Come on!
Is he serious ?
And ' so' cute
when is the fool .
Oh my god you think
someone like Cody ?
Wait .
Wait!
- Oh my God , you! Not you.
- No! No, we ...
- You .
- Taylor , no! We ...
we made out
only a couple of times.
A couple of times .
Hey get back .
Stop it !
- I mean ' ... did you see him ?
- I do not think we had with us !
Hey, guys ,
Come and see .
- Here is Adam .
- I never went to them ' .
- It ' ? So who ' ?
- Okay, who else , and ' get up?
We all got up
before or after .
No, I think it was the last
song that he sang .
Ok, I 'm going to try .
Not alone !
I'm coming with you.
I have a bad feeling about this .
If I translate you are passionate about
and fun , come with us to translate .
I [ SRT project]
www.phoenix.forumgalaxy.com
I appreciate that you came
with me and everything, but
when we find him, I
talk , okay? You can go back .
Just know that I have not
the guitar.
It's okay .
- Hey there ' .
- Run!
- Wait!
- Go, go .
How much time do we give him ?
Well, probably
they are ' together.
Cody and Adam ?
I do not think .
Let's give him another 10 minutes .
20 .
We use cell phones
to light.
Let 's see .
Okay, here we go.
Oh my God!
I think we are in the back
the house of horrors.
There will be an endless '
places to hide .
I think we can get ...
Madison?
Madison !
Madison.
Madison?
I'll stay .
Okay, there ' another torch ?
I have a lighter !
I'll take one .
Hey , what the fuck !
Oh my God!
Hello !
How are you?
Welcome , dear customers !
Spider Holiday.
Nice to meet you .
My real name ' Melvin
but no one calls me ' .
I'm Melvin Holiday.
If you do, I'll kill you .
- Say it.
- No.
Come on, say it.
Come on, call me Melvin .
I'm just kidding.
It does not matter .
- Whoo !
- No!
Hello .
You're a little ' more' small of your
friend . What's it called ? Cody ?
No!
Where ' Cody ?
- Oh my God!
- What did you do?
- Let go of me ! What are you doing ?
Get off me!
- What the fuck ?
- Do not tell me.
- It ' ...
- Get off me! Get off me!
Get off me!
- It 's your boy?
- Where ' ?
Where ' ?
But shut up .
Do not fear,
and ' in the Funhouse .
Hey , what the fuck ! bastard
sick! Let me go !
Shut your mouth , okay?
- I'm not sick .
- What do you want ?
If you want us to leave !
Enough, enough !
And ' the last thing I want.
Stop moving.
Too much fun .
Are you having fun ?
Eh Eh !
Always keep your arms locked .
I have to see if it works !
You'll love ' .
- What do you do ?
- Di ' "Cheese " !
Adam !
No!
Now do not peek .
Uh , okay.
Get something to drink.
Adam .
- Hey , Adam.
- Adam , Adam.
Adam ! Adam !
- Adam .
- Cammi ! Cammi !
What ... What the fuck?
- It's so ' hot.
- Uh ...
It ' .
So ...
When you think back?
- Want something to drink?
- Of course .
Like the color I wear ?
Do you think I should ...
remove it , you say?
God , Derrick ,
I'm not hitting on you .
I'm just fuckin 'around
asking questions.
No, I ...
Fuck no , I'm ...
I ... I ...
I think it's cute.
Dylan , Adam and ' dead.
What do we do ?
I have not seen Cody and Maddy .
Hey, listen .
Hear that?
Maddy !
Cody !
Madison.
Hey .
He took Cody.
- Where ' Cody ?
- In the dark room.
- We have to go back.
- No! He killed Adam !
- You killed him .
- Who?
Spider.
Trevor , Dylan , go .
Go ! I'll stay .
- We have to go !
- I 'll kill ' !
- There 's going to kill ' everyone!
- We Tornar in Madison.
No, I can not! Let me ...
Do not leave me . Please stay .
Stay here , stay here .
Safe.
Die ' !
Come on, Derrick ,
Put on a song rhythm .
They should not
be already ' back?
Who knows?
Look what I found .
You never know .
# I can break your heart #
# You , you, you #
# You, you , you ... #
Oh God
I'm going to lie down.
Do not get any ideas .
Oh fuck .
Oh, thank God you're here .
Boys .
You know the old off-road ?
- It ' ?
- It ' badly injured .
- Come with me ?
- Uh ... sorry, I ...
I'm Mel Holiday.
Call Melvin .
Say it.
Hello , Melvin .
Let's go. Let's get him to the hospital.
Thank you very much .
- Ok .
- Come on .
Do not have a car?
Run .
Taylor !
You know
the girl them ' inside?
It ' pretty.
I want you to take this thing
I torniate back and you leave right away.
I Via immediately .
What a mess.
- Cody ?
- Hey , slow down !
- Fuck!
- Here there 'no !
Cody ?
Cody !
Fuck!
We looked everywhere .
He said he was here .
She did not say
I saw him .
When we entered,
after what we have lost
the cell signal ?
They will be 4 or 5 kilometers.
The old man had a cell phone.
- A fixed .
- You want to go there ' ?
- If you kill us ?
- What do we do ?
Let Cody, that's what.
We are looking for Cody.
- I take the phone .
- Where are you going ?
- Looking for the phone.
- Come on, come on, we have to ... Dylan !
Get ...
Fuck.
Cody ?
Hey, I take off
the tape , okay?
Be still , okay?
Stand still !
Let me take off
the tape !
Oh, the TV !
It ' something! it is
approaching! It ' something!
Wait, wait !
Oh No!
It ' something!
It ' a trap!
It ' a trick!
Oh my God!
Cammi !
The ' above !
Cody !
- What?
- Get the TV ! The ' .
The tv ...
looking for something !
You ' , it ' , please!
- I'm fine .
- Are you okay?
- Are you okay .
- I'm fine . Are you okay ?
What do you mean you're okay?
You scared me to death!
- I'm fine .
- Cammi , Cammi .
You can enter.
- I tried to warn you , right?
- Where ' the phone?
But you little idiots
you're back .
It does not work .
He cut the wire.
We have to get out.
We have to get out! Help me !
It 's too late!
You did this?
Do you know who ' ?
You ' , I know who ' .
But I do not know
if you really know him .
You may know someone
lifetime
and I do not really know .
You can also raise it
lifetime
and do not know him at all.
What do you and ' success my son?
Oh , you know what
I ' success , you bastard .
Oh, come on , Spider.
It worked.
They're back.
No thanks to you .
I torniate back and you leave right away.
I knew you would come back .
You wanted to make them run away .
I've seen it . Why ' ? !
I saw you try
to make them go away ! I've seen !
Hold this.
- Hold it !
- Do not make me do it !
Get up!
When will end ' ?
How many more ?
Stop it .
I grew up.
Do not do it .
That family.
That little girl .
Is ' Shut the fuck up !
And you no longer have ' stopped .
I was trying to save her!
Come here , come here.
- Thank you, Cammi .
- I'm going to take Maddy .
Force.
Come on, man , come on.
Madison.
Madison?
Madison !
What ?
Cody , Cody , Cody !
Do not get up !
What's going on ?
Hello .
Breathe, breathe .
Breathe, here .
So ' ... breathes.
Here we are .
Breathe .
'Cause you do this ?
I do not understand the logic
of your question .
The time and ' money
and I will not waste yours.
He had to ...
just happen.
Saro ' fast .
Are you ready?
Come on, man ! Let's go.
We have to get out of here !
We need to ...
Oh, fuck ... come on!
Come on, boy .
I'm sorry , man.
I'm sorry !
Madison?
Madison !
Hello .
I'm Melvin Holiday.
Trevor !
Hello , Cammi .
Are you ... Cammi ,
right?
See , I'm very confused now .
No, no, no .
I'm not gonna ' hurt .
Listen , I need to talk to you.
It 's been a long time.
Listen, I got so much shit
I have so much shit in me .
And I need to talk to you.
So you can not go
wherever you want , okay?
Do not go .
It ' been strong, Cammi .
- Fuck.
- Where are you going ?
I see you .
I wonder where she went .
I wonder where he will go ' now .
Do not take a step , fuck.
Get up! On your feet!
Do not move.
I said do not move.
It should be ' down' .
I could sgozzarti .
You could cut my throat .
Oh, yes ' .
- Say it.
- You could cut my throat .
You are mine .
You're mine , say it!
- I'm yours .
- Say it!
I'm yours !
Are you finished?
I'm sick of this .
Are you ...
so ' sexy.
Where have you been , Spider ?
This thing takes a long time .
It 'was someone ?
There ' catered ' in a pit.
I kept it just for you.
- Want to be the last ?
- I do not think it's been a year.
- I still care
- I've never taken off.
I Land of the Prison Muertos .
Oh , my God!
Oh, my God, you're alive!
Get off of me !
What's up ' ?
You're so ' stupid .
Hello !
I love you too.
Stupid as the others.
Bitch !
What?
Spider , kill !
Spider , kill her now !
Kill her!
Do it!
I 've cut my arm!
Oh ... cock, and ' a casino.
- What did you do ?
- It's not ' my fault.
You're so ' stupid.
Shut up .
Oh , my God!
I'm sorry .
He ruined everything!
- It ' ... I'm sorry .
- Why ' ?
Spider ,
Spider , you're so ' stupid.
- I'm not stupid .
- What did you do ?
- I'm not stupid . Shut up .
- Stupid . No!
Is ' shut up!
- No!
- She ' Shut up!
Do not move!
Now we can talk .
I have cut off his head.
Taylor.
He would not shut up , you know?
And ' as if I had done for you .
For me ?
It was not much of a friend, eh ?
He lied to everyone.
We 've brought them all here.
You should be careful ...
also with the family,
you know what I mean?
Do you have a family?
I still have a mother somewhere.
I killed my father.
No!
You killed yourself ?
I did it with my stepfather.
But I killed my real father ,
a long time ago .
Once I had a sister.
A half-sister .
What about you?
Of your family?
I had an older brother ' old ...
A half-brother .
E ' dead!
My sister ...
dirono she was dead.
They said he was dead.
And I know that if I
still have a chance ' to see her,
put things in order .
I found you.
Please tell me
why ' of your nickname.
She used to sing a little song .
The little spider # #
# Upgrade ' on the gutter #
It was the # rain #
# And the spider fell down ' ... #
Oh , my God!
You're the one that kept me on track.
You.
Cammi .
You took away .
You took away from me.
Now I can not stop it.
You have to figure it out.
They ...
tried to stop me.
But do not stop.
Enough, enough , enough!
What are you doing ?
Cammi !
I can not hear ...
Cammi ... I need you .
I need ...
I did it for you.
Spider.
You ' , it ' .
You ' , it's me .
No!
Oh , no!
Dylan.
No.
Oh , you're alive !
Come on , come on.
What ... what happens?
I had to stop .
You are a danger to driving.
I can not stop looking at you.
I feel ...
so ' ...
Oh, and ' in place. Alright
It's all right .
You are safe ,
you're home now .
Are you at home.
You're safe.
Cara.
The hospital called .
Dylan and ' out of intensive care
She'll be fine ' , honey.
Mom ...
Mom, I need you.
I need to find
my real mother .
They took her away and told me
that my brother was dead,
but it was not , right?
No.
It 's true .
Spider was not dead.
I have to find my mother.
- I have to find my mother.
- Okay .