Previously on Kings
When i read the signs in my life,
they say that I was
sent here to help you.
Then do that.
They only use people like us.
Look what they do.
Make me wait all day to get
paid because my son died.
We will in six months' time
Give over port prosperity
in exchange for lasting peace.
Why are you cutting him out?
Because he is taking up
too much attention.
- He's a good person.
- He's not that virtuous.
No one is.
I've been keeping pictures of our
family Out of the free press for years.
Being king is a young man's game
And silas is growing old.
We need to know we have
a replacement at the ready.
What do you call it
when i go to the countryside?
We say you're in serenity.
Then serenity ends.
Silas.
Lucky for the rain.
Silks came in.
20 days or so we'll be ready to harvest.
What do you mean we, city boy?
You gonna give up your parades
and princesses And get your hands dirty?
King only gave me a 48-Hour furlough.
Figures.
Ethan.
Why did you send back my check?
I don't want silas' money.
You don't have to step up for eli alone.
He was my brother too.
Boys!
Come on in!
So anybody been in the tabloids lately?
shut it.
Daniel. Table.
I just want to check the score.
...Gilboa and gath.
- A future in which our people--
- Why is the king on every channel?
...Instead of bullets and bombs.
Port prosperity,
a city once conquered From gath
now pledged by me for return,
Carrying their pledge for peace.
No lean sacrifice, but fair.
In order to safeguard that pledge,
I know make public our intention To
return to gath not just port prosperity,
But all territory taken
in the battle of prosperity
- Including lands north of the river.
- That's us.
- ???
- He just gave away our home.
Redraw our own map,
make our face ugly.
You have to talk him out of this.
- Me?
- You're his hero.
He doesn't listen to people like me.
If he won't, others will.
You could speak out.
You need to try, david.
...As the city builds up
its infrastructure to house...
This is not a policy.
This is a decree.
This may well be our king's right,
But it is not just.
He calls for peace,
But denies me the cost.
Good day to be a critic.
This criticism will
embolden your enemies.
How should we proceed?
- Sir.
- Captain shepherd.
You were with your family
when i made my announcement.
How did they react to my decree?
They feel betrayed, sir.
My father and brother
died to defend our home
And you just gave it
to the ones who killed them.
There must be something else
we can trade with gath
To preserve the border towns.
- You could postpone--
- You were not brought here
to debate the merit Of my decisions.
Only to determine the
position of your loyalty.
With your family. With your king.
- I see both sides.
- Oh, both sides amounts to neither.
David,
do you believe that there are
forces Beyond our understanding
That have given me this role?
I believe you were chosen
king for a reason.
And when i ask you
to trust me, will you?
Port prosperity has called a forum.
You will go and publicly
endorse the king's position.
No one cares what i think.
My family will disown me.
Which is why the people
will care what you think.
To see you of all sacrifice
to your king will sway others.
And if it doesn't?
Then you will identify anyone attempting
To undermine the king's decision
And bring them to my attention.
We will have peace.
And those who obstruct it are
wolves Carving out my flock for food.
David, your family may not like it,
But your king needs your help.
www.1000fr.com presents
kings s01ep05
Capture:FRM@大宝
Sync:FRS@赏彩虹沐风雨 追风雨看彩虹
You worry where you shouldn't.
Don't rush lines on your face, hmm?
The handover of port prosperity
will proceed as planned.
Unless the people won't allow it.
People will cool off
just like this omelet.
Now come on, sit down.
We're going to eat.
They're already starting to protest.
You don't care what
your people say about you?
A handful grumbling at the press.
No cause for alarm.
A healthy exercising of the freedoms
I'm pretty sure i gave them.
You should put down your apron
And go to their rally at prosperity.
Show them their king still cares.
I prefer it when you harp on healthcare.
Yeah, well i know how it
feels to not be heard.
The people cannot have
what they want at every turn.
Neither can you.
That's the definition
of governing and parenting.
My presence there would only inflame.
Besides, i got the
situation under control.
I sent my best man.
Who?
Silas didn't listen, did he?
He's not gonna budge.
We'll set him straight.
I'm glad you're with us.
I skipped breakfast.
Even when i'm pissed at
him I take the omelet.
Thanks for the support.
Trying to change his mind?
You'd have an easier time
asking the rain to stop.
Uniform, please.
I've run out of ways to please him.
He's used to everyone loving him.
He doesn't see as well as he used to.
Or maybe he just doesn't care.
He would if he understood.
This is different.
They're already calling it "port calamity."
People are gathering
right now to protest this.
- Really? Who is?
- Plenty.
That's just awful.
Well, if you really want to help him,
Maybe some criticism
is exactly what he needs.
You have the air of a man
who's made a decision.
Not yet, uncle.
I made you an offer, jack.
You've left me waiting for an answer.
How about a token then?
Something to help me make up my mind.
You're buying unity news network.
Huh. You read the paper?
Why is everyone surprised
when i pay attention?
It's the largest news station
in the country And it's yours.
I want a hand in it.
"Buy me a toy, uncle."
But news doesn't seem your speed.
Or yours.
Maybe we're both just sad About
the state of free press in shiloh.
- It's a crime.
- Shameful.
My father needs the media today.
If i were the one controlling
his public image...
He'd have to give you more
than scraps from the table.
He'd have to kiss my ass.
Is this what it'll take?
The price of your support
against your father?
We need our man
at the turn of history, jack.
We need our new king and soon.
Let's just say this
will help me make my decision.
I can't believe he did this!
From a damned coffee pot!
You stood where the poor man was serving.
Well, he should've anticipated.
Have him hung.
Hanged.
Laundry is hung.
Valets are hanged.
And so are queens...
who correct their husbands.
- What?
- Sir, your meeting.
Oh, haven't i got enough
on my head today?
Didn't i ask that rescheduled?
- It was.
- Well, do it again.
I have.
Shall i put miss ghent off a third time?
Katrina ghent?
Well.
Now i see why she donated
so generously At first night.
- What does she want?
- Well, i can live with the mystery.
Send her away.
Centerfold, december, '95.
- April, '96.
- December. Snow boots.
Definitely furry snow boots.
I've seen better.
- Who?
- Miss ghent,
the king has to reschedule.
Then i got dressed today for no reason.
- Our sincerest apologies.
- Save the apology.
Name the price.
I need an audience with the king
And you're the dragon at every gate.
- Even dragons eat.
- Ma'am.
Oh, come, woman. I have too
much money not to give you some.
Think that as a donation
towards your sister's care.
That institution can't be cheap.
- You're underestimated.
- And right tired of it.
Last chance.
No?
you're a very good dragon.
- Where are we supposed to go?
- Premiere, what about our jobs?
They're talking about a
resettlement package For everyone.
New homes, new jobs.
The port at pella's being expanded
To route all shipping and dock work.
He can't do that to us.
My brother works for the king
and even he's here with us.
Captain shepherd. Captain.
We all saw how you took out that tank
And we're all proud
that you come from around here.
My family lives north of the river.
We'll be asked to move just like you.
So do you think the king is right?
I hate the idea of losing our home.
I lost my father.
My brother.
I know a lot of you here
lost people too.
And it's natural to say
they died for this land
And we're never giving it up.
That's right.
But i'd happily trade our
farm to bring dad or eli back.
Lives are more important than livelihood.
I think of all the other
fathers and brothers
Who are gonna go on living
because silas ended the war
And it makes me love our king even more.
What will your king do if we refuse?
Will he forcefully evict
us out of our homes?
As i understand it,
If you choose to stay
you'll be living in gath.
God gave us this land!
And not even silas can take it away!
???Yeah!
Who will stand with me
Against the king?
- ethan, Ethan, stop.
- Our blood! Our land!
- Don't do this!
- our blood! Our land!
- Stop!
our blood! Our land!
Our blood! Our land!
Polls indicating
overwhelming public support
For king silas' decision
to return port prosperity--
This is where it happens.
Where the news gets crafted,
Then run by your father every day.
It looks so...honest.
Maybe you can make it more so.
I've benefitted more than any.
But this country needs
an information source
That won't kneel to
the king's approval.
The first town crier to cry freely.
Your father will be so proud.
Port prosperity.
...Directly affected by
the handover of port prosperity.
Let's bring in some criticism.
Give voice to the opposition.
Those who think he's being unkind
To our gentle heartlanders.
Yes. You listen to him.
We'll make the king look foolish.
Hmm. And later in the day
When he looks foolish still And he
tells all the other cameras to leave,
You tell ours to stay.
...Peaceful protest at
the docks of port prosperity.
I'm going to port prosperity.
I'm not sure that's advisable.
Just do it.
- Thank you.
- Mm-Hmm.
- Oh, well thank you all.
- Thank you.
- We're so proud.
Next time, lorem, to the championships.
I'm from the south, and in case
you'd forgotten We hate lorem.
Now you're king.
You don't have a favorite team.
I used to break things
when they'd win.
Sir, the protest at port prosperity.
My daughter's already
bent my ear on this.
Still it--It might be prudent
To call an emergency meeting.
We did something that was
unpopular but necessary.
There are those that
will pitch their fits.
I've dispatched captain shepherd.
I trust him to do
all the situation requires.
Perhaps i'm not making
the situation clear, sir.
The protestors are threatening
to shut down the port.
- This is--
- This is a tantrum.
I will not be drawn in.
Keep your mood where it is.
Your staff will dust off the guillotine.
Hmm?
Take a bath. Read a book. Fire someone.
But this new habit of barking
at every shadow Is unsustainable.
What about the countryside?
Hmm?
You always come back so refreshed
And likeable when you go there.
Time for a trip, hmm?
- Trip?
- um.
Not a bad idea.
Thomasina.
Let's go get some air.
Reverend, a word?
William cross come to my congregation.
Now i really have seen everything.
Don't get your hopes up, ephram.
It's you i've come to see. Not him.
I will always hope for you.
Change is in the air.
Like winter.
Can you smell the wood burning?
I have.
Silas will fall.
That may be his fate.
- Someday.
- Someday soon maybe.
And i want to know
when that time comes
If you can set aside our differences
And do what is best for the people.
Like we did once when we were young
And saw a king in silas.
You and did not make silas king.
Ha.
Funny. I don't remember
him writing any checks.
Minds are gathering.
Resources.
More every day.
A group will be meeting
to consider the season.
We'd like you to join us.
Time to be young again.
God...
Will choose the next king of this realm.
Not you.
Then ask you boss who he's chosen.
Line thrown out. Trout brought in.
Necessity turned to pastime.
Mediated by luck.
Attributed to skill.
It's all in the wrist, you know.
Sir, we have reports.
The press is aware you're here.
Oh, you two!
All nervous, huh?
Hanson, you're like a cat at the
edge of the tub. Let a man relax.
Sir.
A bad time?
Seems you have your audience.
I don't blame you for avoiding me,
The notorious katrina ghent,
tabloid staple.
Who clearly doesn't deserve a word of it.
So i married for money.
He was a syphilitic walrus.
Explain the intrusion
before i sit you on my fish.
I sold my reputation
for a lot of money.
I want to buy it back.
Make me a minister in your boardroom.
A minister?
Do you have any special
qualifications I should know about?
- An area of expertise?
- Oh, you pick.
I don't care about power.
Assign whoever you want to run
the thing And tell me my mind.
I just want a seat at the table.
You're offering to buy a ministry.
And overpay.
Unlucky for you, There's no positions
in my government For sale today.
But i admire forthrightness.
So i'm going to pardon you For
trying to bribe a sovereign while wet.
Good day, mrs. Ghent.
The situation could explode
at any minute And he's fishing.
With her.
He's not himself.
Law enforcement has been on
the scene As a precautionary measure.
But it appears the situation
is escalating In port prosperity.
Our land! God's land!
- Our land! God's land!
- Don't put this on god.
You don't really believe that.
- I believe in our family.
- So do i!
Come on. You sold us out
for the palace life.
Our land! God's land! Our land!
You lost yourself. You're a traitor.
- God's land!
- We're not going anywhere!
Ethan!
Come on!
- Block the door!
What were you thinking?
You slew your goliath.
Maybe silas is mine.
This isn't a competition,
ethan.
Fighting over the good spot
on the couch. This is real.
What are you doing?
What we have to.
They shot first
into an unarmed crowd.
We have the right
to defend ourselves.
This was never a rally,
was it?
You planned an insurrection.
Silas didn't give us a choice.
We're gonna shut
down the whole port.
Stop everything from moving.
Now we have the whole world watching.
We'll be here every day humiliating him,
until he does right by us,
By our country.
Or he could just kill you,
ethan.
Killing us will turn
the whole country against him.
We've tied his hands.
You go out there
and you tell 'em
We won't stand for it.
We want our god-Given land back.
And we want the freedom
to live on it.
We have an update
from port prosperity.
They barricaded themselves And sent
captain shepherd out with a statement.
"We've fought for the king
and spilled our blood,
But if he tries to take our land
We will fight against him."
Local police have requested
military assistance.
They don't need it.
At last count, one is dead,
31 injured.
- Shepherd reports a compliment of guns.
- They can play at soldiers all they want.
We will not get involved.
Sir.
I have concern.
For your heart.
Doctor gave it
a clean bill just winter.
Not the function.
The temperature.
I fear it's gone cold.
Since serenity, sir.
Since you stopped going.
I know of no such place.
So it seems.
You have a point?
Without it...
Without her,
You have not been yourself as..
as i know you.
What you spite sharply
escapes notice.
And what gave
you pause doesn't.
And without the countervalence
of warmth,
You've grown mean, sir.
And i don't know how
to serve this cold silas.
And my duty is
to protect the family.
Then do it from the car.
How heavily armed
are the rebels?
They're not rebels.
They're people like you and me just
trying to make a point for the cameras.
The mayor just ordered us
to go in and shut them down.
No, you can't move in on the building.
We need to wait the protestors out.
I'm taking my orders
from the mayor now.
You take your orders
from the king.
I'm going in to speak
on his behalf.
What are you doing?
I'm gonna give them a chance
to save themselves
And show them someone still cares.
I care.
My brother ethan is in there.
I can't let you do this.
This--This isn't your place.
Michelle.
Keep him here.
I'm going in.
You're gonna let
the princess walk in there?
Don't let her go in there!
Three port prosperity
police officers
Who are listed in stable condition.
Wait.
Is that michelle benjamin?
Yes, we are seeing
princess michelle
Making her way to the front
of the stronghold.
Until just a few moments ago,
It seemed like the police were
gearing up for some sort of--
You're not gonna
believe this.
Ethan shepherd.
Does this mean silas
is cancelling the handover?
No.
He's not gonna change his mind.
Then what are you doing here?
I came to apologize.
The king shouldn't have given up
your land without consulting you.
That's what you're offering?
An apology?
And a deal.
Lay down your guns and
i go out to the press
And announce that the king
has granted you all amnesty.
You can go back to your lives.
Your families.
This uprising forgiven in full.
So he doesn't even
know you're here.
??If i speak for him,
for you,
He has no choice but
to honor it.
You think we're gonna quit
when we've come this far?
It's that or prison.
Either way what you're doing here
is gonna 'cause your families
more suffering than a handover
of land every could.
I think we could do
a lot better than that.
- What are you doing?
-  Forcing the king's hand.
- This isn't the plan.
- We can settle everything today.
Let's see silas ignore us now.
Bring in the king's own!
Storm 'em!
Kill everyone inside!
- She gets out safe.
- She will.
Media blackout. No impediments.
- Already done.
Only unn refuses to comply.
We got baker at the helm.
Call him, tell him to pull 'em out.
It's not baker anymore, sir.
Jack?
Call katrina ghent.
???Out.
Secure the perimeter.
??? We're the only network To
defy the king's blackout order.
- We're getting pressure.
- Dear god.
Not pressure.
My father sent his own daughter
in harm's way to be his mascot.
If he's ordering a media blackout
Then she already failed
And he doesn't want
anyone knowing it.
I say we broadcast
some embarrassment.
I say we don't.
Kill the live feed.
Go to black or find the weather.
We're off the port.
Excuse me. Why is anyone
listening to her?
Because they just got
the message i own the place.
Crossgen owns the network.
It did. I just bought up
the whole mess of shares.
My lawyers told me it's called an
"angry takeover," Something like that.
What do i know?
You must've really
pissed off your dad.
He had katrina ghent buy it out from
under us. He's that scared of transparency.
Or of you having
any real power.
He'd rather appoint that whore
than let you assert yourself.
You wanted my answer.
You have it.
No doubts.
I'm in.
Deep as you need me.
A pawn lost.
But we have our king.
He's no good to us
without samuels.
Without his blessing, The public will
never support a coup against silas.
Samuels will come.
A truly unprecedented and historic
move by the royal family at prosperity
With michelle benjamin stunning local
officials by meeting with protestors,
Now called rebels by some.
We now have word and can confirm
that the situation is resolved.
A peaceful resolution.
Who's in command here?
I am.
Sir, you should know not all the protestors
inside meant to risk her life.
His brother's one of the rebels.
He means to defend him.
One shepherd leaves
my flock.
The other leads them astray.
Yes, he took radical action to force
your hand, but he would never hurt her.
Others would.
She's there.
When she was chipped, i prayed
never to have to use it.
She's surrounded by
my best marksmen.
When i give the order,
just like flipping the switch,
Evveryone in there
save michell goes dark.
They don't deserve this.
My daughter's in
there at gunpoint.
I don't care if the whole world dies
as long as she comes out safe.
My family has given up
so much for you.
Please don't take ethan from us.
Let me go in there.
I can talk to them.
I can try to get them
to give themselves up.
This is the safest
and best plan,
The only way to secure her safety.
Give me a chance.
Why should i trust
my daughter's life to chance?
When everything inside me
screamed I was
betraying my family,
I still trusted you.
You have two minutes,
but know this.
Once in there, we cannot
distinguish you from other.
And in two minutes' time
if you're still in there
And standing you die
with the others.
You coddle him.
This is no time for it.
We should proceed
with the original plan.
Enough.
It's over.
The press is gone.
Everyone is...
Except men with guns.
Put down yours.
While you still have a chance.
But our cause is right.
We can't surrender.
Martyring yourselves
won't change anything.
No one will even know.
God will.
God will know.
GET OUT. NOW.
Excuse me.
What about mom, huh?
What about our family?
I'm doing this for them.
You're not doing this for them.
Or god.
You're doing this for you.
What do you know?
You left us!
You couldn't stand that
i actually did something
- While you did nothing.
- I took care of mom!
Mom won't survive if
she loses another son!
You think this honors eli?
You're nothing like him.
Thank god he's dead.
Because if he could see you
He'd be ashamed.
Now.
You can stop worrying.
I'm fine.
Oh, good.
Now i can have you killed.
I should kill your serviceman too.
He answers to me, not you.
Not ever. That was the deal.
Do anything that stupid again
and all deals are off,
Save the one i made
with your jailor.
- You had me chipped?
- When you were five.
Your words today at the river.
Sir.
More than i ever heard you
string together in a month.
Now you've been in my employ
in this capacity for how long?
- I don't keep count.
- How long?
Ten years, eight months,
some days.
Maybe it's time
for a promotion.
Klotz, where can
i find shepherd?
Already sent for him
waiting on the king, ma'am.
Oh, my god. You love
thomasina. Since when?
First night. Hair up.
Something happened.
- You are so screwed.
- Oh, i'm so screwed.
Let me explain.
You picked the wrong time
to stretch your wings.
I didn't know michelle was at risk
When i told the cameras to stay.
- I didn't know.
- And if you did?
I might've done the same.
You should be careful
accepting gifts from your uncle.
They're never actually gifts.
You push me to prove myself
Then cut me down when i aspire.
It doesn't exactly encourage.
No, i haven't been
fair to you, have i?
Some ministry positions
have recently opened
And i'm thinking of offering
one To someone in name only.
Maybe you should
have the job of it.
- You're giving me a ministry?
- The teeth behind the title.
Teach you to exercise
power without credit.
That's if you're still
interested in the position.
I am.
I think you two will
enjoy working together.
I don't know
where they took him.
There's no record of ethan
at any of the jails.
It's like they made him disappear.
I didn't know we did that.
I'm so sorry.
What you did...
Trying to save a princess
who doesn't know her place...
You don't have a place.
He's lucky to have
someone as loyal as you.
Captain.
The king awaits.
Show him, abner.
He's earned the right.
You were watching ethan
before the rally?
Your brother and his accomplices
Have been conspiring for weeks.
You knew what
they were gonna do.
That there was gonna be an uprising
And you let this happen?
A lone messenger sent out
to face an angry mob.
An inadequate response
to make me look deaf and dumb
And all the while fishing
as the crisis played on.
- To see who took the bait.
- Draw out the enemies.
You never wanted me to succeed.
The people have the right
To mock, scorn, criticize,
and burn Unflattering photographs
in effigy until morning.
But i will not have my country Drawn
back into war by opportunists or fanatics.
- What's gonna happen to my brother?
- He committed treason.
He saved michelle.
Which is why he's
alive to stand trial.
I cannot brook insurrection.
But on your pledge that he
will return to face trial...
I'll release him
into your custody.
Sir.
I don't know why you think
he deserves special treatment.
Only concern yourself
with that i do.
The reverend samuels and william
Absent from our catch?
I'd have thought them first
in the bucket.
We have no evidence against them.
Should some be manufactured?
Their day will come.
Why did you warn me it was a trap?
Because silas has grown soft.
And is no longer the man
i swore to follow.
Ethan.
Don't talk to me anymore, david.
Don't talk to any of us.
www.opensubtitles.org