- This morning, in judge
Miriam Howard's court house,
very bizarre civil right case will unfold.
A very successful and
educated financial investors,
otherwise seemingly normal man,
wants to challenge county's
rules, on marrying his pet dog.
As you can see the protests,
this civil right case
has become a controversial stoop.
Whatever happens, we will see one thing
we would never thought
we would be able to see.
Both straight and gay
marriage activists have United
against
- Randy please marry me
instead of Koko, please.
- A young women is even
out here proposing.
We will see what judge Howard thinks
about this strange case.
-  All rise.
Court is now in session.
The honorable Miriam Howard presiding.
- Thank you officer Rice.
Good morning everyone.
-  Good morning.
- Today we will hear
arguments in a civil rights
violation case filed by
plaintiff Randy Bobbs,
against the County regarding its arcane
and narrowly minded restrictions
on the definition of marriage.
Mr. Bobbs wants to marry his dog.
Now this one is gonna
take some explaining.
Are you the counsel for Mr. Bobbs,
attorney Michael Curtison?
- Yes, your honor.
Good morning
- Mr. Curtison, I'm surely hoping that,
this isn't some kind of publicity stunt.
Have you seen the mob out there?
Don't make a mockery of my courtroom.
- No, not at all your honor.
This is my client's life at stake here.
I'll explain how my
client, Mr. Randy Bobbs
has lost so much in his
life, and should be allowed
to marry his true love Koko.
In fact your honor,
before filing this case,
Randy tried to get married at
a church, but he was denied.
- Marriage is the ultimate commitment
between two living souls.
Do you know what it means to get married?
Do you know what it means
to get married in a church?
It's so much more than two
people falling in love.
It's a decision made
before God and the church.
The two are brought together
for God's Providence
and for God's purpose.
Randy, so good to see you.
- You too.
- I'm glad you came in.
And you brought your dog,
what a beautiful animal.
Oh my God, I love animals.
How long have you had her?
- We've been together for
a little over six months
but I knew she was the
one, the moment I met her.
- I'm a little confused.
Weren't we supposed to meet your fiance?
- She's here, I want to marry Koko.
- Excuse me.
- It's like what you said on the sermon.
The love I have with
her, I wanna celebrate
the highest honor by marriage.
She's loyal to me and she's
faithful to me as I am to her.
That's why I want to marry Koko.
- You didn't hear a word of my sermon.
You didn't understand a word of my sermon.
- No, sir, I did, I completely did.
And I wanna honor the
relationship I have with Koko
through marriage.
- You don't marry a dog, it's an animal.
Human beings don't marry animals.
Where are you getting this?
- She's more than just an animal though.
She's she's my soulmate.
- No soulmate, that's an animal.
You gotta get outta
here, you have to leave.
You're wasting my time.
I don't have time for this.
- But sir...
- Look, please, please.
- Come on, Koko.
- And Mr. Curtison, just,
how did you come about
representing Mr. Bobbs
in this nobel course?
- Mr. Bobbs and I were college roommates,
during our undergrad years,
we've remained close ever since.
Seen each other through
life's ups and downs.
Randy Bobbs is a normal guy,
but it's important to know
what he has gone through.
I met Randy on the first day of college.
He was moving his boxes,
my parents were moving my boxes,
we were roommates.
- Oh, hi.
- I'm your new roommate.
Oh, hi, I'm Randy Bobbs.
- Michael Dwayne Curtison,
but I go by Mike.
- I was just gonna take this downstairs,
do you need it for yourself or?
- Oh, no thanks.
I wanted to do it myself but,
my dad insist on hiring movers.
- Okay, well.
What side did you want?
Cause I I'm good with either.
- Wait.
We can flip a coin.
Heads I win, tails you lose.
Cool?
- Wait, what?
-  Just testing to see
if you're paying attention.
- Okay. I'll call it in then.
Tails.
- Your choice.
- So do you always use a
coin to make decisions or?
- It's my lucky coin.
- Okay. And I'll take this side.
- Done.
Wanna go grab a pizza?
- Yeah, yeah, let's go for some food.
Oh Mike, this is Ralph.
This is my roommate, Mike.
- Hi Mr. Ralph, I gotta use the restroom.
So I'll meet you down in 15?
- Sure, see you there.
All right.
- If your parents were here
to see you off to college.
Wow, they would be so proud
of the man you've become.
- I'm here because of you, Ralph.
And now is probably the
time to say, thank you.
- Well, that's everything,
have a good semester.
Don't forget, you have a very
busy week in front of you.
- Yeah, I'm excited about
starting work on campus,
you know, between the
job and the scholarship,
I won't have to use any of
the funds my parents left me.
- Sounds like you've became
a bonafide financial advisor.
Okay. Don't let me keep you.
Touch base anytime, anything, you know.
- Thank you.
- Been a pleasure, have fun tonight.
- I will.
♪ I have started to regret ♪
♪ Every dollar that I have spent ♪
- I like this place, it looks nice.
- The lighting.
- I think this is our waitress.
- Hey there, Mike, Randy.
I'm Shauna.
- Wow, you daunt moment there.
- You know that actually happens a lot.
What can I get you guys to drink?
- Two light beers, please?
- What?
You're ordering beer?
- Just testing you.
Two coke Shauna.
- Coke it is.
The student's special today is a large
two tropical pizza for 5.99.
- How about pepperoni and mushroom?
- Wait, that was gonna be my suggestion.
Maybe they pair us up
based on common interests.
I don't remember pizza question though.
- I will be back with
your coke guys, okay?
- So Mike, let's start with the basics.
What's your major?
- I was a math nerd in high school
but I did kick ass on the debate team.
My father is a lawyer and
his father was a lawyer
and so forth.
I'm free law, it's in my genetics,
then it's off to law school.
I might go on with my dad's firm but,
he does a lot of business
law and corporate stuff.
Not like the stuff you see on TV.
I wanna get out there and
fight for the little guy.
You know what I mean?
So what's your story?
- I'm a business finance major.
- You don't talk much, do you Bobbs?
- I say what I need.
I'm sorry, it's just been
really hard for me to open up,
ever since my parents passed away.
- Wow, when did that happen?
- I was eight years old.
My whole family, my
parents, my sister, my dog,
they all died in a
pretty bad car accident.
- I'm sorry if I brought stuff
up that you don't wanna talk
about, we can switch gears if you want to.
- It was a long time ago.
- Hey, you guys okay?
- Life. Life is hard Shauna.
- Yeah. Tropical pizza is coming up.
- Like, I'm not trying to be nosy but,
I thought Ralph was your dad.
Like, who raised you?
Did you grow up in foster homes?
- I had to, until Ralph got full custody.
He's a friend of my dad's from the army
and from high school.
- The custody is being
placed to this guardian,
Mr. Ralph Williamson, unto
this minor until his legal age.
- Thank you, your honor.
I'm prepared to raise Randy
and provide from a nurturing
and caring environment
for him to grow up in.
His father and I were in the army.
He has no living relatives he can go to.
- Yes Randy, you do want to say something.
- Thank you for letting
me stay with Mr. Ralph.
I don't wanna go back
to foster home anymore.
I'll be good, I promise.
- Oh yes, Randy I know you're a good boy.
- Mr. Ralph, are you my dad now?
- No, but I will be the next best thing.
- He's the next best thing I have,
to still having my real dad.
- That's awesome.
My dad's so busy being a lawyer that,
I just grew up on my own.
- It's cool.
- All right, bon appétit, boys.
There you go.
- That's good Shauna.
I caught you looking at Shauna's boobs.
- And then she says, "bon appétit."
- And then we both thought
about, bonny Shauna.
Hey, that brings me to my next question.
- What?
- Gay or straight?
- I didn't really date in high school,
but I know I'm not attracted to guys.
I just never been with the girl alone.
- Wait, so you're saying...
- Yeah, yeah, I'm a virgin.
I just didn't see having
sex as a priority.
I had to do well in school
so I can get into a good
university and do my family proud.
There was never time for dates
or to ask girls out or...
Sorry man, I didn't mean
to spill so much on you.
- Well, you don't talk much,
you sure had a lot to say.
I guess he was,
- You are too funny.
- Just testing you man.
To us Bobbs and a hell
of the next four years.
Your honor, Randy was never
good at meeting girls,
but he fell in love with Jessica.
- Hey Jessica, come here.
You two don't bite,
So the usual pizza today, huh?
- The name in bold, don't fix it.
Actually, something different sounds nice.
- You can try Hawaiian
style, that's my favorite.
- Oh yeah, that sounds good.
- All right Randy, shaking it off.
So a Hawaiian with pineapple and ham
and two coke, coming right up.
- Wait a minute, classy stare, flush face.
- You're turned on by the
new chick, aren't you?
- Come on, not funny.
- Do you know her?
Well, does she know you exist,
or is this some distinct
stalker type thing?
- She knows.
- So go talk to her.
- Come on, because, I just
don't wanna break my hopes.
- Here you go, you're welcome.
- Hey, where is that new shadow?
- Oh, her training is over,
she's in the back somewhere.
I'll be back with pizza, okay?
- I got to go take a leak.
If she comes over here, pull
some balls, talk to her.
Jessica Evans, meet Randy Bobbs.
Randy Bobbs, Jessica.
There you go, hardest part is done.
You two continue, I got to go study
- Here, sit down.
- So last I was here
it was Randy and Mike.
Now we have Randy and Jessica.
Man, the world is moving
too fast
- Yeah, it's spinning pretty fast.
Jessica, did you want a coke?
- Yeah sure, that'd be great.
- Yeah here, just take mine.
- Aww, sweet.
- Randy, tell me a little bit about you.
- No, I thought you would go first.
I always wondered what
it would be like to hear
the sound of your voice.
- Do you like what you're hearing so far?
- Yes actually, very much.
Your face suit your voice.
I don't really know what I mean by that.
See, this is why I want you
to go first and me to listen.
- Okay, okay.
Well, I'm originally from Kansas.
I lived there till I was 13,
and then my dad moved to Indiana.
♪ I go for you ♪
♪ My heart is new ♪
♪ Easy as a sea ♪
♪ You go for me ♪
♪ Sometimes we are tired ♪
♪ Then we're inspired ♪
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday dear Randy ♪
- Hey Andy, thanks for coming.
- I'm so excited to be here,
and thanks for choosing a
dog friendly restaurant.
You know I don't go
anywhere without my dog.
- You're crazy.
- Oh, you know I love my dog.
- Randy, let's cut the cake.
- First I just wanna say,
how great this birthday is everyone.
And thank you for sharing with me.
These last three years, I can't imagine
what it would be like, without you all.
- Okay, okay, let's dig in.
-  Yeah.
- Great birthday, bro.
We had a great time.
- We got to bounce man.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Thanks still young Bobbs
- And you need to get rest.
It was great seeing you.
- You too.
Thanks for come down here.
- No problem.
- So your birthday's not over yet.
- Thanks mike.
- Let's go.
- Bye guys.
- I really hope you enjoyed your birthday
and this is the card I got for you.
And we can do whatever
you're comfortable with.
Order room service or...
- I'll see y'all later, right?
- So Bobbs, do you feel like a man now?
- If you're somehow
asking about what happened
after the party, you
can wonder all you want.
I know, you know what
Jessica wrote in that card.
And besides a real gentleman,
doesn't kiss and tell.
- Wow. Kill joy.
- I'm gonna ask Jessica to marry me.
- Don't get carried away here, man.
- What are you trying to say, man?
- I just don't want you to
make a long-term decision
experience in the first act of love.
- I didn't just do it.
In my heart I felt a closeness, a trust.
- That's just the blood rushing
from one head to the next.
- Look man, we're friends and all,
but I don't think I like
what you're trying to say
about Jessica.
- Hold on dude, I'm not saying anything
you shouldn't be thinking yourself.
I know she's your first and all,
she might not be your one and only.
Just make it a long engagement.
- okay. So can you tell
me what we're doing here?
I probably know what you're gonna say.
- You will see.
-  Enjoy.
- Thank you.
Cheers.
- Randy, are you about to
do anything big and dumb?
- Just wait, it's about to start.
Jessica Evans, will you do me
the honor of becoming my wife
for the rest of my life?
- Yes, yes Randy.
♪ You know we love each other very much ♪
♪ Sometimes love just gets in the way ♪
- Okay, we have part of the story.
You two graduated together.
Randy got engaged with Jessica.
When are you gonna get more specific
and get to the point, at any
time soon now Mr. Curtison,
speed this up.
- Yes, your honor.
If you allow me.
So after graduating, Randy
moved up the corporate ladder.
He and Jessica moved into a nice home
in a nice neighborhood.
They were doing very well together.
- I'm so proud of you, Randy.
We could have gone out
to celebrate, you know.
- It's perfect, my lady.
Celebrating another promotion
and another raise is best
here, just the two of us.
- Randy, we've been saving
and now you're making more,
does this mean we can finally get married?
- Jessa, I thought we decided to wait
until we can afford the
huge wedding you want.
And after you finish college.
- I know, but I can finish
college after we get married
and we can do that now.
It doesn't even have to be a big wedding.
And with this raise we can
go honeymoon in Europe.
- Europe?
- Randy yes, please.
Let's set a date this summer.
You know we can afford it now.
- Well, for you honey, anything.
- Hey Randy, do you know why the boss
is holding a big meeting?
- Not exactly.
- Because I'm very scared
and, am I going to get fired?
- No, no, don't worry.
Let's just see what he says.
- Okay. Oh good, because I
really do not want to get fired.
Are you coming with me?
- You go ahead, I'll be right there.
- Hello executives.
You all know about recent losses.
Well, I'm here to share with
you that it's gotten worse.
We have to take drastic cuts now.
- Bobbs, you have that
file I asked you about?
Please.
Thank you, Bobs.
And let me say on behalf of
the executives assembled today
that you have been an amazing
asset of this company.
We have to cut some positions,
and I trust that you and
everyone else in this room
will be here with us till the end.
This plan you've worked
on Bobbs it's a good one.
We'll have to liquidate
assets, employee assets,
and severely cut benefit
packages and salary packages.
Even our own.
I'm sorry, it's the only way.
This company, has weathered worst storms
than this over the years.
I thank you for your
dedication to the company
and your continued dedication.
Thank you all.
That'll be it for now.
- Bye Bobbs, I'm leaving now.
- See you Christina.
- Bobbs, did you get your email?
They're cutting my pay
in half, Margaret's too.
- Yes, this sucks.
- They have to, Kelly.
We all have to tighten
our belts around here
otherwise the company will go bankrupt.
- I'm not doing it.
- Like the big guy said,
we can weather this storm.
- Or not.
What about you Bobbs?
Are you gonna stick around?
I already have a pretty good
standing offer, I can accept.
- I'm going to do redo my resume,
I'm going to look for
better opportunities.
- Hey, hey, this company
has been great to us.
And loyalty works both ways, right?
It may mean some mean
months but the numbers say,
the boss is right.
We all stand to come back
stronger than before.
- Jeez Bobbs, I wish I
shared your optimism.
- Don't worry if we just have faith
and let the market do its thing, maybe--
- Yeah. Are you gonna explain
it that way to Jessica?
- Let's go.
-  This is ridiculous.
- So it's about work, it's bad.
The company took a huge hit
in the market this week.
All of our money is gone.
- Whose money?
- The firms, our investors, ours.
- My God.
How much?
- How much have we personally lost?
Honey, everything.
And I have to handle a 30% pay cut.
- You mean we have to
handle a 30% pay cut.
- Yes, we have to.
- Can you try to find a new job?
- No, the company will bounce
back better than ever Jess.
I'm sure of it.
We just have to have confidence.
- How long?
A year, more?
- Well realistically, it
could take three to five years
for us to rebuild.
- Randy, I had it all planned out.
We're gonna get married,
honeymoon in Europe.
I was finally gonna be
able to go back to college
and get my degree.
I could finally start my online business.
And now you're telling me
three to five more years.
- Look, I can talk to my boss
tomorrow and I'll get a better
idea of what we're really
dealing with time-wise.
But until then, we just
have to have confidence
and then we can have the
wedding of your dreams,
of our dreams.
And you can go back to school.
- Hey Bobbs.
- Hey Kelly, what's going on?
- A few of us are going out
to have a drink after work,
you wanna come?
- Thanks, but I have to pass.
- Jessica didn't he take
the new so well, huh?
- We've had better nights.
- I'll talk to you later.
- All right.
Hey Mike, I'm glad you called.
I can use a friendly voice today.
- I figured.
I read this morning's news and your firm
is teetering on the brink,
but how are you in a potential Mrs coping?
- Well, I could see right now, short term,
things are gonna be tight.
We're gonna have to downsize
to a smaller apartment,
Return one of the lease cars,
no honeymoon in Europe.
She really wanted that.
I'm not even sure when we can afford
any type of wedding now.
- Wow.
Hey Bobbs, I'm sorry about
how, the way things turned out.
- Thanks, Mike.
I'm really looking forward
to seeing you tonight.
All be there in about six, 6:30.
- Sure, I usually get home around six,
and Jessica usually has dinner ready,
So I'll have her emotionally
preps for you, hopefully.
And again Mike, no joking
about money or my job.
She grew up without much.
It nearly broke her parents
to get her as far in college
as they could until you
know, their money ran out.
- Okay, okay Bobbs listen,
take a chill pill and relax.
Okay. And how about you just
buy Jessica some flowers.
- That's actually a really good idea.
- Randy, Jessica.
You guys, your know
your door's open, right?
Where is Jessica.
- She's gone.
- When is she coming back?
- Never Mike, she left me.
She wrote a letter.
"I'm afraid to restart from scratch,
ruined wedding and honeymoon plans.
Afraid of being poor,
lost confidence," in me?
You wanna know what I think, Mike,
She didn't love me,
she loved my money.
Just money.
Why didn't I see that?
I'm so stupid.
- Christ, Randy.
I don't know what to say.
Don't blame yourself.
There isn't a guy alive who
hasn't been blinded by sex,
even I have.
And you cope well, how is that?
-  cause I'm an
excellent bullshiter.
Dude, I'm scared shitless
of getting hurt or rejected.
That's why I play the fence.
I keep my shields up, but you
Bobbs, you're the cool one.
With all the hurt and
pain you've been through,
you were not afraid.
You have no clue how much
respek I have for you bro.
- I guess I will have to
put my shields up too.
Thanks man.
You're a good friend.
Actually, you're my best friend, ever.
- I can't take credit, one's
best friend is oneself.
Shit, that's cool, why is my phone?
Let me record that before I forget.
One's best friend is oneself.
No, one's best friend is oneself.
One's best friend--
- Okay, okay, if all done waxing Socratic,
I would really like to get out of here.
I can still feel her, everywhere.
Let's just go anywhere but here.
-  Hi honey, I'm
calling to say I love you.
Hi honey, I'm calling to say I love you.
- Randy Bobbs.
-  Hey Randy, it's me.
- Oh, hi Ralph.
What a nice surprise.
I was gonna call you a little later.
- Tony called me last
night, I'm beyond words.
I have an idea of what you're feeling now,
because my wife left me,
but we both know from experience that,
you have to just allow time to pass.
- It's funny Ralph,
how Jessica leaving me
when I lost all my money,
it's kind of like when
you got divorced, right?
When your wife left you
after you got injured.
- Well, it's the same in that
neither of us did anything
to mistreat or abuse
or even were unfaithful
to the women we loved.
What we have to do is
let it go through this,
you've lost a relationships today
and you should be angry about
it, sad and finally accept it.
- I will need to move
to a smaller apartment,
probably some crappy hole with a wall.
Jessica cleaned out the
bank account when she left.
So between that and pay cut,
I'll have to live off hotdogs.
- Those are just details Randy,
you've got be better off
when you went through this.
You know I'm here for you.
So if you wanna come home for the weekend,
maybe it's a good idea
to get away for a while.
- I think I'd like that, Ralph.
Thanks.
I feel dead here.
I'll call when I'm on my way and Ralph,
-  Yes Randy.
have a big pan of lasagna
ready when I get there.
You bet Randy, safe journey.
Hey and Randy, when you
get here be ready to eat.
- Take care Ralph.
Hey Mike, what's up?
- Well actually, a couple of things.
I'm headed to the airport
right now, I'm flying your way.
Be there by 11, can you pick me up?
- Yeah, sure.
But, why not rental on waiting?
- Well, because this is a quick spur
of the moment kind of thing.
And I wanted to talk to you in person.
- Ooh, such intrigue, it
has to be about a girl.
It has to be.
Dude, I'm gonna be a dad.
- Oh, Oh wow, Mike.
Wow.
Just testing you man.
All right, I'll send you over
all my flight information.
- Sure, I'll--
- All right, bye.
You wanna sit here?
-  Sure.
- Hey guys. Welcome.
My name is Terry, I'm
gonna be your waitress.
These are your menus, do
you want something to drink?
- A couple of soft drinks.
- Yes, I'll be back.
- So What's the big news?
- Well, I met someone another
lawyer at a conference.
We're into the same music,
politics, food, movies.
- Here you go, boys.
Just to let you know, we're known
for the Chilly cheeseburger.
It comes with fries and coleslaw.
-  It sounds good to me, Terry.
- Yes?
-  What about you Mike?
-  I'll take one.
- That was easy then,
I'll get us started, okay?
- Cheers.
To us ever evolving men
and to your new gal.
Y'all live happily ever after.
- You're here.
- Hey, if you like her so much,
why don't you go talk to her?
- What?
- You're obviously
drooling over the brunette.
Hey Terry.
- Yes.
- You see that group of ladies over there?
-  Yes.
How about you put their
tab on Randy's tab.
I will be glad to.
Which one caught your eye?
The Burnett on the right?
- You're sharp, Terry.
- I'll be back, okay?
Hi ladies, I just wanna let you know
that those guys over there,
they paid for your dinner.
- So are you gonna go talk to them?
- Okay, okay.
I know how this works.
I say no but, my best friend
makes it happen anyways.
- Come on, show me how it's done.
- Oh my God, he is coming, he is coming.
Shush, don't speak.
- Hi ladies.
-  Hi.
- My name is Randy.
-  Hi Randy
-  Hi Randy.
- We're all veterinarian
techs at the animal shelter.
Tonight we are celebrating.
- That's right.
My incredible staff here and myself,
got all of our dogs back to good health.
No more kennel cough.
That really is something.
I can't imagine what it is
like to see sick animals.
- The worst are the mistreated ones.
- It's sad, isn't it?
How someone can take the
devotion of the sweet nature
creature and just intentionally
hurt it, I can't imagine.
- Randy, why don't you come
visit us at the animal shelter?
You can see me in the other
angels of mercy in action.
Unless you're busy or you know.
- Well, if you're not busy.
- Well, she wouldn't be, I will see to it.
Come by tomorrow around noon, right Randy?
- Yeah, yeah.
Here is my card, just text me the address.
- Yeah, I'll text you.
- Great.
It was nice to meet you ladies.
-  Nice to meet you Randy.
And thank you for dinner.
- Anytime.
- Thank you so much.
-  Bye, have a goodnight.
- So mission accomplished?
- Yes, sir.
I have lunch with her tomorrow.
Her supervisor set it up.
They all work at the animal shelter.
- Hi Randy.
That's a very nicely wrapped gift.
I'll go let Trish know that you're here.
- Trish?
- Oh, I mean Patricia, she
likes to be called Trish.
I'll let her know that her
steamy man is here for his tour.
- Thank you Manila.
-  Anytime.
- Hi Randy, sorry I'm running late.
- It's okay, I got you this.
- Oh, that was so nice,
but you didn't have to do that.
- I figured someone around
here could use a special treat.
- That was unexpected of you, Randy.
- I'm sure you have a few
clients that could use a treat.
- Why don't you come on back
and I'll give you the grand tour.
- Okay Trish, let's go.
- Sorry, it's so loud in there.
- It's okay, they're just
talking to each other.
- Come on.
This is the office.
- It's nice.
- So Peggy said once the tour is over,
if you want, we can go to lunch.
- That sounds nice, I would like that.
I mean, if you want to.
I guess I didn't properly ask you, did I?
-  Allan, this is Randy.
We're just about to go out to lunch.
What's wrong?
- I have tried everything,
nothing seems to make her happy
and she's not eating neither.
-  Is it okay to pet him?
- Yeah, of course.
She clearly likes you.
I mean, I couldn't get that
much of a reaction from her.
Peggy, come look at her now.
- Wow, that's amazing, Allan.
- What's her name?
- The tag says Koko.
- We just found her sitting
on the back porch steps
a few weeks ago when we opened.
- She's a sweet angel and mystery
- Really unresponsive when she came but,
we ran all sorts of
tests, nothing was wrong.
We couldn't figure it out.
- Nothing is wrong, you're all right Koko.
- She's a special one.
I think she is here with a purpose.
- She's here for me.
I mean, I'm here for her.
I mean, I don't know what I mean.
What's the process for me to adopt her?
- Well you know, the two
week waiting period is over.
So technically you can adopt her.
You can come back this afternoon.
- Come on Koko.
- It's okay, Koko.
You be a good girl, okay?
I'll be right back, I'll be
here to get you, all right.
I promise.
- So shall we?
- Oh yeah, lunch, right?
Yeah. Let's let's make it quick
so I can get back here to Koko.
- Okay. There's a quick soup and sandwich
shop around the corner.
- Sounds great, let's go.
♪ Going nowhere fast ♪
♪ I was running in place ♪
♪ Cornered by the past ♪
♪ Then I saw your face ♪
♪ Now I'm in love ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ You don't even see ♪
♪ What you did for me ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ I was almost gone ♪
♪ Heaven to come ♪
♪ You came along ♪
♪ And you filled me up ♪
♪ Now I'm in love ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
-  Hey, Koko.
Hey Bob, how are you liking new office
with the big wide open window?
- It's great, thank you.
Though I never really,
never really had time
to look out the window.
- We all owe all this to you.
- It's not just me,
everyone here has worked
so hard to pull us back
from destruction.
- Destruction?
We're doing better than
we've ever done before.
Now we're gonna work on
you, enjoying your life.
You got to get a nicer looking car.
You'd have to get a nicer apartment.
You have to find a girlfriend.
- Well actually, I have met someone.
- Congratulations. Excellent.
And this is for you for your promotion.
- Wow. Thank you.
Brand new laptop Koko.
And this is my third promotion.
Are you proud of me?
I know you like your new fancy house.
I love you Koko.
I can't explain it, but it
doesn't feel like you're a dog.
I sense you, you feel me,
the real me, inside and out.
You love me unconditionally.
Ever since I've met you
everything has better.
Losing my parents, losing Jessica,
I can finally put all that behind me.
You understand, don't you girl?
How can I ever show you
how much you mean to me?
Some day, if I don't
get up to take you out
I may not have gotten up at all.
I want to pay you the
highest honor possible,
but how?
I don't know yet.
I will, and when I do
you just watch me girl,
it will be a form of tribute
no one will ever forget.
- Hi Randy.
Can I come in?
I see you got companion.
And this place is amazing.
- Jessica, what did
you want to talk about?
- I've just been trying to figure out
a way to apologize for just leaving.
I was terrified of being poor.
Not finishing college was hard enough
to cope with as it was.
And then when things went South
for you money wise at work,
I just freaked out.
I went home for awhile, but,
I couldn't stop thinking about you,
about us.
I saw you in the park today,
And it just made me realize
how much I missed you.
- I'm stunned, Jessica.
I don't even know what to say.
There's someone else in my life now.
Someone who loves me and only me,
Who's loyal and wants to be with me,
for richer or for poorer, whatever.
I can never trust you again.
I'm sorry.
- Well, I had to try.
Are you sure you found the real thing?
- I'm sure.
When I'm with her, I feel complete.
I don't know, I just can't explain it.
- You don't have to try, I get it.
- You know, I would
rather be having a donut
than this orange.
My husband never lets
me have a donut at home.
- That's because he wants you
to keep your gorgeous figure.
- Seriously?
- Yeah. And if I had your figure,
I'd be dating every night.
- Really?
Okay girls, time to get back to work
and back to washing the doggies.
- No, I'm so tired.
- I know. I know.
Okay Trish, spell it.
You and Randy have been dating
for over six months now.
So where are things at?
You never even talk about it?
- I don't know.
It's a bit weird sometimes.
- Weird, why?
- He's obsessed with Koko.
It's like everything we
do we have to make sure
it's okay for Koko to come too.
I finally got him to
agree to let my sister
watch Koko for the night,
but only so that we could go to dinner
with his college roommate.
- It'll be fine.
I think Randy is just having
a little case of puppy love.
Just give him some time and space.
He'll come around, I know.
- He's the perfect guy, otherwise.
-  He is.
- At least tonight he'll be
focused on me and not Koko.
- Amen.
- When my friend came back,
Bobbs looks at him and he says,
you're wasting your parent's money.
That guy was so mad.
- Well, he had about eight beer
bongs and can barely stand.
Truth hurts.
Where is he today?
- His parent's basement.
Excuse me, I'm gonna
call and make sure Koko
is okay with your sister.
- Bobbs I don't get to see you much,
besides you've got a perfectly
good date sitting here.
Relax.
- You're right, I'm sorry guys.
It's just, this is the
first time we've been apart
since we met and I'm nervous.
- Bobbs, I understand.
I see all over your social media posts.
I know what Koko looks
like more than Trish here.
If you love her so much,
why don't you marry Koko?
- Mike please don't give him any ideas.
- I'll be right back.
- Does he really take that
dog everywhere, even to work?
- Yeah, it's that far.
- I don't know if I
should tell you this but,
he lost his entire family
as a kid, even the dog.
- He didn't mention a dog when he told me.
-  He has a lot of trust issues.
- We've been dating for six months now.
I kind of think he's the one.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Everything is okay with Koko.
- And everything's fine here.
Well, we'll have to do this again sometime
when I get back in town.
And hopefully you two
will have news for me.
- Maybe I will.
- Okay Mr. Curtison, now we have some idea
of his mindset and background.
But what was it that
solidified your client's desire
to marry his pet dog?
I was just about to finish.
I know you've been very
patient with me thus far.
- Let's hear it.
- That all people should
be treated equally
regardless of who they
are or who they love.
It's a victory for the allies
and friends and supporters
who spent years even
decades working and praying
for change to come.
This morning the Supreme Court recognized
that the constitution
guarantees marriage equality
and slowly made an entire country realize
that love is love.
- Many couples taking
advantage of the rights
they've been granted to
choose their own partner
are foregoing the
traditional church ceremony
opting instead for a simple civil service.
As many faiths have enough--
- Did you hear that girl?
With these new laws, we
can marry who we want.
- If you love us so much,
why don't you marry Koko?
- Marriage is an ultimate commitment
between two living souls.
- I didn't even think about it.
I didn't even think about a legal wedding.
In order to honor you
in the highest regard,
Koko, Will you marry me?
Will you marry me?
And it's settled.
We'll head down to the courthouse tomorrow
and get our license.
Oh man, I got to call Mike.
I got to call Patricia.
They can meet us down there.
Hey Mike, I need you to try to break away
from your conference tomorrow.
I'm gonna be at the courthouse tomorrow
and I need your help.
I have something really
important I need to take care of,
and I need you there.
Meet me at ten.
- Hey Randy, what's up?
- First, I wanna say I had a
great time the other night.
You're great company.
Sorry I was so distracted.
- Oh no, it's okay.
I mean, if I can't understand
puppy love who can, right?
You at work?
- No actually, I took some time off to,
to think about some things.
- Like what?
- I'm going down to
the courthouse tomorrow
and I really want you to be there.
I have something really special planned
and I need you to be there.
Can you come?
Yeah sure, if it's that important.
I can get off work, what time?
- At 10.
- You wanna give me a hint
about what's happening
at the courthouse.
- No, I'd rather it be a surprise.
You'll understand when you get there,
and Mike should be there too.
- Okay, I'll be there.
- Okay, great.
You're the best.
- Okay, bye.
Oh my God,
Oh my God, he's gonna propose.
Oh, I need to do my nails.
I need to get a new dress.
Oh my God, he is gonna propose.
Do you think it's too fast?
I mean, I know Randy and
I just started dating
six months ago, but I'm really excited.
- You're fine.
- There he is.
- Hey Randy, you can't bring your--
- Yes, can I help you?
Excuse me, sir, I'm sorry,
but unless that's a
registered service animal
there are no pets
allowed in this building.
Your dog needs to wait outside.
- We're here today because,
we're applying for a marriage license.
And I'm applying with the love of my life.
- Well, that's a very sweet way to propose
but your dog still needs to wait outside.
I don't think you understand.
I'm here for our license.
- Sir, in order to obtain a dog license
you don't need to bring
your dog into the building.
- No, we're not here for a dog license,
I'm here for a wedding license,
for myself and my bride to be, Koko.
I don't know what kind of sick joke
you're trying to pull here, but--
- It's not a joke.
She's the soul I feel most
connected to in this world.
- Security, I need your help here.
- Okay, what's going on?
- This nut over here is trying
to obtain a marriage license
for him and his four legged bride.
Would you handle this please?
- Yes. Sir, I'm gonna have
to ask you to leave now.
Now.
- Excuse me.
I'm so sorry.
Randy.
Randy,
have you lost your beloved mind?
You can't marry a dog, man.
Have you flipped out on me?
- Where did Trish go?
- Probably to a bar to get a drink
because of that public humiliation.
- Public humiliation?
I was the one they were laughing at.
- Jeez man, are you that
blinded by that dog?
Trish thought you were here
to get a license to marry her,
not Koko.
You said it be a special day for her.
- Because she was the one
who brought us together.
I thought she of all
people would understand
why I was doing what I was
doing and be happy for us.
I'm sure when I explain it
to her, she'll understand.
- She'll know more than me.
I feel this connection with Koko,
stronger than anything
else alive in this world.
And I want to honor that bond
in the highest regard possible
and take her as my bride.
- Randy, I understand everything
you went through as a kid
and everything which you've
lost, including Jessica.
- Jessica opened up my eyes and my heart.
Without her, I would never
have found my way to Koko.
And besides, aren't you
the civil rights champ?
Don't I have a right to marry who I want?
- It's kinda been a debate
about who you came marry,
but a dog, I don't know.
I have to do some research.
- Help, help me Mike.
Please, help me.
Help me get married to Koko.
A marriage license may
just be a piece of paper
but it would mean everything to me,
if I could show that
we're bonded together.
- You know I'm fresh out
of law school, right?
You really think I can work miracles?
- Yes, I always thought that of you.
- Okay Randy, call it.
- You still have that lucky coin?
Heads.
- Heads it is.
It's like she understands.
- She knows Mike, somehow she knows.
- Okay Randy, I'll follow the case.
- Mr. Randy Bobbs?
- Yes.
- Mr. Bobbs, we are from
Animal Protection Services
I'm Sam Advow and she's...
- Zia, Zia Fret animal control officer.
- How can I help you guys?
- Listen, we're here
because we got a report
of potential abuse on a dog named Koko.
- Abuse, what kind of abuse?
Who would make such a claim?
I take care of Koko with the
utmost respect she deserves.
I would never harm or endanger her.
This is insane.
Mr. Bobbs, I have court orders
to get custody of your dog
until it has been determined
whether she has been
abused or not in any way.
Here.
- Oh God, you think I...
- Well, you did try to marry her.
Are you two doing anything?
- You're sick.
- Mr. Bobbs, whether she
has been abused or not,
it has to be determined.
According to this court order,
please surrender your dog to Ms. Zia.
- Where did she go?
- Let me get her, she's probably scared.
Koko,
Look, I don't know what this is about but,
I think I have a good
idea of who's behind it.
So just go with these people
and they'll take good care of you.
- Hey, come with me.
- You guys will take care of her, right?
- Yeah, we will take good care of her.
- Hey, I know what happened to Koko.
- I bet you do.
How could you file a report against me?
I know you're upset about
the courthouse fiasco
but why don't you tell them
I would do something to Koko.
Don't you know how much I love her?
- Randy, I'm not the
one that turned you in.
We got a court order that says an official
filed report of potential abuse, not me.
- The court, so it's part of my lawsuit.
Oh my God, Tricia, I didn't wanna believe
you would do something so cold.
- I was really hurt at the courthouse.
I thought you were gonna propose.
And I probably would have said no,
because we haven't known
each other that long but,
I thought about it.
Randy you're sweet and caring
and a little naive at times.
But this is something you
really want, I understand.
I get it.
- They're not telling me anything, Trish.
I don't even know where she is.
She could be hurting somewhere.
- That's why I messaged
you, she's with us.
- Oh, thank God.
At your animal shelter?
- Yeah.
Between you and me, the
vet checks did not find
any signs of abuse.
We're just holding her until your hearing.
- So Koko is okay?
- No, she's not eating, she's not active.
She's really sad without you.
But I'm doing my best to keep her company.
- Okay, good.
It's Mike.
Hi, hi Mike.
Thank you for getting back to me.
Yeah.
Yeah, they just took her.
They had a court order, so
I had to let them, right?
But thankfully, Trish
is looking after her.
Mike, can you file a
motion to get Koko back?
Something, I need to hang over
here, I'm literally dying.
Okay, okay.
All right, bye bye.
Mike, thank you.
Patricia, I'm sorry.
- Mike is gonna do something.
They can't get away with this.
- Thank you Tricia, you're a great friend.
- Yeah, friends.
- Okay Mr. Curtison, you did
a fine job telling a story,
but I'd need some solid precedent,
some other cases where this has happened
to at least consider your case.
- Your honor, I will present evidence,
showing people all over the world,
being allowed to marry animal.
- Okay everyone, if we can't
act like grownups about this,
everyone's out of here.
That's your first warning.
Okay Mr. Curtison, it's on you.
- So judge Howard, are you married?
- That's your second time, three
strikes and everyone's out.
Do you get it people?
And you Mr. Curtison,
you can't ask me a question like that.
The tone in which you asked it,
didn't get lost on the
gallery, nor myself.
Another little crowd-pleaser like that,
I'll hold you for contempt.
- I beg your pardon for
the bit of grand standing,
your honor.
But I just wanted you to be open-minded.
- I'm not an unsympathetic
person, Mr. Curtison,
I will listen and weigh
out all the evidence
for your case that you bring before me.
And for the record, I've been married
to the man of my dreams for over 36 years.
You may continue.
- Thank you, your honor.
My point was only to illustrate that Koko
bonded immediately with Mr. Bobbs
the first time they were introduced.
Just like all pure and natural love does.
- Oh please, isn't that enough?
- Mr. Stills, you are way out of line.
- These two are clearly
just attention seekers
for who knows what reason.
They can't actually
expect you to entertain
these senseless ideas.
- Thank you.
Thank you for looking
out for me Mr, Stills,
but I'm a big girl and I'll decide
what I can entertain and what I can't.
Are we clear?
- Yes, your honor. Yes.
- You'll get your turn soon enough.
You were saying Mr. Curtison?
- Thank you, your honor.
I was saying, none of
us can clearly define
what it means to love or be in love.
We feel something, a
physiological reaction
to another that we just can't explain.
It's not perverse or a natural,
on the contrary, it's totally organic.
We will show you there
is no reason why Mr. Bobs
shouldn't be granted a marriage license.
And we will cite real instances.
Thank you, your honor.
- You know, we'll see
about these other cases.
Okay. All right.
Now the question to the
County is, Mr. Stills is,
should we go against our
established procedures?
Like my grandpa used to say,
if it ain't broke, don't fix it.
Okay Mr. Stills.
- Thank you, your honor.
If it ain't broke, don't fix it.
This statute has been on
the books for over 100 years
and it needs to remain in
effect without exception.
Think of the chaos this would cause
when processing standpoint alone.
Forms would have to be changed
from male, female and other,
to species specific.
And why stop at animals?
This could lead the
request to marry everything
from pickup trucks to robots.
Today's circus simply can't be allowed.
Thank you, your honor.
- Ball is in your court.
You may present your evidence.
- Your honor, I have
copies for your review.
May I approach?
- Well thank you for saving
me the research Mr. Curtison.
I would also like to ask your kindness.
I have a few witnesses, they
will testify to strengthen bond
between Randy and Koko.
- Okay, you have my permission
to present your witnesses,
provided I don't have any
objection from the County.
-  Fine, your honor.
- Good.
We're gonna take a 15 minute recess
and officer Rice, make sure
that the animal control officer
and the psychiatrist are here.
-  Yes your
honor, I will bring them in.
- Court is adjourned.
- Dr. Kingston, a man
by the name Randy Bobbs
wants to marry his dog.
Does that mean he is
suffering from schizophrenia?
- Listen, as Mr. Bobbs
psychiatrist, I'm here to testify
not give any views.
- Hi Randy, hi Mike.
- Trish, did you bring Koko?
- She's outside with animal control.
- She's here, can I see her?
- No, you still got a hearing to finish.
- Court is now back in session.
- I wish you guys all the best.
- Officer rice, I want the
County witnesses first.
- Good morning, your honor.
Mr. Bobbs is not crazy.
He's a highly intelligent,
highly successful young man.
He just wants to marry
who he wants to marry.
- There was a complain
came from, county clerk.
But all we found, a guy who
loves and cares his dog.
We don't see any abuse.
So Animal Control is willing
to release Koko to Randy.
I've seen my friend Randy,
deal with a lot of heartache in his life,
but now he's happy.
He's never been as happy
as he is with Koko.
- It's not just about Randy,
Koko needs him too, she's
not doing good without him.
She barely eats.
You know, I have never
seen such love between
two individuals.
- Since Randy has found Koko,
he has been more motivated than ever.
Since Koko was taken away, Bobbs
has been miserable at work.
He misses her terribly.
- I raised Randy,
but he taught me a very
important lesson in life.
I was injured during the Gulf War
and I can't have sex anymore.
I used to believe that,
I couldn't have a relationship without sex
but when I saw the love
between Randy and Koko,
it gave me a realization
there's so much more
to a relationship than sex.
I started dating and I think
I found the right woman.
It would be very fitting
for Randy to be allowed
to be with the woman he wants.
Thank you, your honor.
-  Randy Bobbs to the stand.
You may be seated.
- This is your chance to
tell your side in your words.
- First, thank you your honor,
for hearing my case today.
I'll do my best to explain why
I want to take this action.
- I must say Mr. Bobbs,
you have demonstrated
amazing resiliency in your life.
You have suffered great losses
and it truly saddens me.
- Thank you, your honor.
It was those losses that kept me in fear
of of love and relationships.
I've always found it hard
to open up with people.
I tried with my first fiance
but she left me and I
was devastated again.
But then I met Koko and
my whole life has changed.
I'm a better person because of Koko.
I've never felt this bond
with anyone else before.
She's there for me, and I'm there for her.
That's what it means to be in love.
The more time we spend together,
the more whole I feel as a person.
I want to have a lawful
official way to pay tribute
to the soul I feel most connected to.
That's why I decided to marry Koko.
But when the County took
her away, I'm sorry.
I apologize, your honor.
I just want the world
to acknowledge how pure,
how right the bond between us is.
So what if she's a different species?
The bond we have, the love is real.
Marriage is the only way to to acknowledge
and celebrate that love.
I'm not asking for much, am I your honor?
- You're asking for an
awful lot, Mr. Bobbs.
It's gonna be tough for me to say yes,
because even if your attorney has provided
and presented anecdotal evidence
of cases all over the world
I have to follow the law
of this jurisdiction.
And I'm sorry, but I
don't believe that the law
is going to allow that.
- Your honor, if I may interject.
Yes Mr. Curtison, this is your witness.
- Your honor, we're all
here today because my client
is forbidden by law to
marry his dog, correct?
- You are interrupting
me to state the obvious?
I hope this is in some kind
of attempt to skirt the law.
- Funny you should say that,
we're not here to skirt
the law, nor is the County.
If your honor will allow me,
I like to read the law out loud.
- Perhaps you better, Mr. Curtison.
- Your honor, the statute clearly states,
the marriage is between two people.
- Technically Mr. Stills
is incorrect, and I quote,
"A marriage license shall be
issued to two consenting adults
who can appear before the clerk."
The law only requires
two consenting adults.
- Okay fine, I'll grant that
Koko is an adult in dog years
but she can't consent, she's a dog.
- Your honor, let's just ask Koko.
- What?
Here now, in my courtroom?
- Your honor, I have
proof of scientific study
showing that everything that
we say a dog can understand.
May I approach?
- Okay, Mr. Bobbs is done.
I'll allow this but, Mr. Curtison,
is this it for your case?
What?
Really, is this it?
- Yes, your honor.
- All right Mr. Bobbs, you're dismissed.
- Your honor, this is Koko.
- She's gorgeous.
Officer Rice, please have
the witness take the stand.
- Your honor, a dog in the witness stand?
- We need to hear from Koko, Mr. Stills.
Let's see if that study is correct.
Koko, do you want to get married to Randy?
- Your honor, you can't be serious.
What, it is just tone of voice not words.
Koko, do you wanna get buried?
- Well, that's certainly a
different reaction, Mr. Stills.
I don't think she likes you.
- Well, I still can't
believe that this hound
can really understand
what's going on here today.
- No, I think Koko has proven her point.
Thank you Koko, you are dismissed.
And thank you officer.
Well, I think we've all
learned something here today.
There are all forms of love in this world
and no one person can define it,
except to know when you're in it.
And we've learned that
a statute on the books
needs forever updating
since we are the judicial
and not the legislative branch
of this fine local government
we can't alter or bend the
rules specially when stated
as clearly as they are.
it's up to the lawmakers now,
to put their finger in
this dyke before it leaks
any more on the floor of
someone else's courtroom.
I may live to regret this,
but that's my ruling.
This court orders that Mr.
Bobbs to obtain the license,
the marriage license that
he is seeking be allowed.
Court is adjourned.
- So there we have it,
the actual news exclusive.
Judge Howard just ruled,
Randy Bobbs and his dog Koko
can get married.
- Koko, Koko, girl
- Congratulations you two.
She is all yours.
- Let's go, let's go.
- Good job, kid.
- Thank you.
- You will be famous.
♪ Going nowhere fast ♪
♪ I was running in place ♪
♪ Cornered by the past ♪
♪ Then I saw your face ♪
♪ Now I'm in love ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ You don't even see ♪
♪ What you did for me ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ I was almost gone ♪
♪ Heaven to come ♪
♪ You came along ♪
♪ And you filled me up ♪
♪ Now I'm I love ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ Hoping that you know ♪
♪ How I love you so ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ Now I'm I love ♪
♪ Now I'm in love ♪
♪ I'm in love ♪
♪ You know we are allies ♪
♪ That you save my life ♪
♪ I'm in love. ♪