Well done. Prolong it.
Very well. And now we'll moo likea cow.
Great. And once again.
Only stronger as if you were abig,
hoarse cow.
Excellent.
Now say it in a simple manner,
mind breathing and rhythm.
Hi, it's me.
Say it very cheerfully: Hi, it's me.
And what if more cheerfully.
Hi, it's me.
OK, and now be angry,
you can even frown.
Hi, it's me.
That was great. But make it angrier.
You'rea wicked old man.
Hi, it's me.
That was brilliant.
And now say it sadly: Hi, it's me.
Hi, it's me.
Good boy.
You're doing very well.
Did you practice at home?
Of course, you didn't.
Anyway, you weregreat.
As always, you deserve aprize -
these are speech-improving waffles.
Now I'll turn on the tape recorder
and you're gonna tell me
what you did at school today.
Hey, what's up?
We'vealready recorded your voice once.
Don't you want to do it again?
It's not scary at all.
Mind breathing - breath in and breath out.
Well, tell me what did you do there.
Alone?
What happened?
What's this rush for?
You never call for no reason.
You date a woman or what?
Are you coming in?
Cool. I forgot you had this film.
Who's that - me or Lina?
It's you.
Do you remember
when we used to play cards?
You'd always say:
If you win, you can do whatever you want,
but if you lose, I'm the boss.
And then you'd always laugh
and say the cards were written all over my face.
I have some brandy,
wine is on the table.
Wanna drink?
No.
You need some refurbishment.
You live here like atramp.
It's good for me as it is.
When the flat is yours,
do whatever you want.
OK, what's up?
Gambled away again?
Need money? How much?
I just wanted to see my daughter.
Happens rarely.
It's you who never call.
Living like this, dad, you will...
Stop being grumpy.
I have cancer.
How much do you need?
Thetest results are on thetable.
I've decided not to wait till the end.
Pills, hospitals,
they're not for me, you know.
What do mean
you're not waiting till the end?
I wanna see if the fortune
is still by my side.
Let's play?
Come on, let's do it.
Dad, what are you talking about?
Let's play.
Dad, how can you say this?
Don't give up. You have to fight.
With these odds
I wouldn't even start a game.
But it's possible to curethe cancer.
Don't even dare to think about that.
Coward. You wimped out.
OK, then go, go away.
Don't talk to melikethat.
I know the professor.
He'll do everything I ask. I'll pay him.
You've always been gutless.
Go away.
Don't forget to say goodbye to Lina.
OK, you won. Let's play.
The Collectress
Are you fucking blind?
I'm very sorry.
Fuck you sorry.
Where did you buy your driving license?
Are you going to work?
To work what?
Stop asking all this bullshit.
It's eight to nine now.
Tell your price and go away.
So wake up ifit's eight to nine.
You crashed my bumper.
They are fucking expensive.
So are we calling cops or what?
Hundred is enough?
Two fifty.
No.
Fuck you. Wait till I see you again.
Hi. How do you like my new wheels?
They suit you.
Hello to you too, yes,
I'm fine, thejourney was great.
No time for that.
I'm in a rush, the patients arewaiting.
Raminta told me there were
three complaints against you from parents.
We can't afford that, what's up?
My father died.
Jesus, I'm sorry.
Take a holiday or something.
The clinic is small,
if rumours start going, we'll be ruined.
I understand, I'm OK.
Who let the dog in? No animals here.
It's me. It's OK.
We'll arrange the photo session,
make some posters. Hi.
By the way, I got the video editor's number.
Should I make an appointment or?
Give it to me, I'll do it myself.
What's this for?
You asked me to make
a short film for conference.
So my sister and me shot a bit.
Have you written the text?
I should practice a bit beforethepresentation.
I've decided to make
my presentations myself.
This one's going to be the first.
Are you serious?
You were always stage frighten.
Good evening.
Two champagnes.
Did you see? Damn sexy.
What are you going to do
with the money?
Don't know yet.
Half of the flat is not so big money.
You're right.
I'll buy some clothes at least.
And you know,
I got Tom into a corner.
Already? You're fast.
Yes, there's nothing to wait for.
And then there is the dowry for the start.
You know the girls
are planning a hen-party.
They doubted if it wasn't not too soon,
you know... dad.
But I told them not to besilly.
So therewill bea party.
Remember to bring the camera on Saturday?
What?
I've told you more than once.
We bore your drunk face at our wedding.
But this is just too much.
What is it exactly you don't like?
I did my job.
Those pooing horses look disgusting.
But they do it in reality.
It's pure documentary.
While the oath is being made,
you show people yawning.
And then eating like fucking pigs.
Theseare your words not mine.
I filmed everything as it was.
You aregonna redo this video again.
Look, the danceis on slow motion.
We wanted it to be nice, romantic.
Look, that's romantic - out of focus.
You took shitload of money from us.
It's not a wedding, it's somekind ofparody.
As I've told you already,
I filmed everything as it was.
I see.
You're going to give my money back.
I'll get you, you drunkard.
It's not your fucking business.
If you are here for wedding video,
I suggest you going somewhere else.
Get the fuck out ofhere, you doggone ass.
Bounder.
It's seven already? Well, come in.
I'll finish up hereand then I'm all yours.
Got overloaded with weddings.
Come on, mouse,
do your fucking job.
Don't just stand it there,
it drives me fuckin' mad.
You could clean up abit
before suggesting a seat.
Listen, lady,
stop telling me how to live.
There was one already.
So what did you bring - school celebration,
Easter party? Or maybe funeral?
I told you I'm a speech therapist.
Oh right, speech therapist.
But why no funeral.
I'd make a great stuff out of it,
just imaginethewinged body out of the coffin.
Let's change the subject.
Ah, you'll never please the bitches.
There is always something wrong -
either bad editing or living in mess.
This bitch is going to pay you.
So better finish up your coffee
and let's get down to business.
OK. So what do you want?
Here's therecord of
five stammering children.
I apply different therapy methods with them.
It's teaching material for theseminar.
Nothing much to do,
just make it 10-12 minutes length.
Deadline?
Tomorrow half eight
the office girl will come to takeit.
Does the office girl
know what is beautiful?
It doesn't have to be beautiful.
Just the length and so that it has a sequence.
Great.
The door is open.
Goodbye.
And now wemove on to another presentation
"The old and the new ways to curethestammering"
by Gaile Grigalaviciute,
thespeech therapist of the private clinic.
We have film here.
Hello, dear colleagues.
I have some footage on the practical examples
how to apply thenew methods.
Whilewatching I'll make some comments.
Then your questions.
Turn off the light, please.
Hi, it's me.
This is how they learn to intonate,
which later could be applied in everyday life.
Here's another exercise.
Stop faking off, read the text. Slower.
Read slower, listen to the rhythm. Slower.
But I am slow.
OK, that's enough. Now listen.
How do you like it?
Lt' OK.
It's not OK, you stutter.
No, my speaking is OK.
So you want to keep it like that.
You don't want to learn talk fluently.
But I do talk fluently.
OK, read once again.
Do it for me, please.
Gaile, don't you dare to leave.
I'm not prepared.
I'll keep you company.
Why so sad?
Why, why?
I'm OK.
You're silent all evening.
Come on, let's drink.
Let's go inside, it's starting.
Hey, you retard,
you could've told you lost your mind.
Gaile, listen to me.
Stop, you asshole,
and behave like a man.
You are quick to rook, yeah, you prick!
Damned macho fucker!
Quick to rook, yeah. Fucker.
OK, let's play the last one on the nod.
Some day.
Piss off, enough drinking for free.
Fuck it, don't leave me likethat, I'm broke.
So bugger off.
What a surprise.
Beer, schnapps or what?
I brought new footage.
You aresick or what, Missy?
Do you know what's the time?
I need you to edit me something.
You are great.
Yeah, right, just snap
your fingers and I'm on it.
Olichka, one more.
First, pay for what you've already drunk.
Put it on my account.
You don't have any.
Come on, Olichka.
Just mess around
with me and you're out of here.
Fucking hole.
"Una testis, nulatestis".
Do you know what it means?
Thank you, good job.
Enjoy.
Sorry for themethods
and for staying here.
Your cluckings are queer,
nothing like I'veseen before.
Coffee?
Yes, thank you.
Sorry for asking,
but what's the point with your filming?
Coming down on peopleat nighttime,
wasting your money.
Can't find something filthy on the net?
It's everything but that,
I need something different.
So I shouldn't worry
that you are some kind of pervert?
Can you hear?
Boys or girls?
The laughter.
Sorry, what does it
have to do with balls?
No, no.
I need laughter now.
Listen, I'll pay you.
OK, there's Shtirlitz going down thestreet...
I need you to film me.
No way, I won't mess
around with the camera.
Be quiet.
Clients?
Let's go.
It looks cheap.
Are you sure it's gonna to be funny?
Believe me,
it will be when you watch it.
Well, are you ready?
Wait a minute, I'll go first.
It's going to be kind of
rehearsal before sister's wedding.
Hi.
I brought it. Sorry, should've done it earlier.
Editing is done, if you want.
Of course, I want.
And how do you like it, honestly?
Why ask? You'll seeit.
When you think it over now,
it all turned out wacky.
I shouldn't have yelled at you
in front of everybody.
But you arenot angry
with me, are you?
Peace?
OK, peace.
That guy had it coming -
he got an accident at work.
So, let's go shopping.
I need to buy some
stuff before the wedding.
I can't park here.
I'll get it clamped.
Leave it in a car park.
I don't have much time.
Do you know at least
when my wedding is?
If I were you, I'd think it over.
I'm sorry, Saulius' mother has called;
they'rebeing late, but on their way now.
Today's session is canceled.
But they're on their way.
I'm telling you -
today's session is canceled.
The same with others.
OK, but if the boss asks?
I don't feel good.
Would you likea cup of tea?
No, thanks.
Hey, doggy, come here.
Leavethe dog for a minute.
How did you like it?
Curious way to win
over the employee.
I didn't expect you
to be so insightful.
Your car is awesome.
I hope it's not the end of our evening.
So huge, damn kicky fast.
I'd like to have a ride.
Nobody drives it but me.
Sure?
Yes.
Really?
So?
Cool.
Where are you going?
What are you doing?
Are going to take this snot?
Thereareno cars here,
wehave to take him.
Thanks a lot.
You can drop me off somewhere in the city.
Are you going from the pub?
The same as you, judging from the smell.
How's the car? Pimped up?
Believe me, it's gonna be enough for you.
Gaile, slow down.
Don't you like it?
Take it easy.
Look out.
What the fuck are you doing?
Gaile, stop the car.
I always wanted to run a red light.
Gaile, don't you dare.
Damnly expensive car.
Gaile, for fuck's sake,
stop the damn car, you bitch!
Get out of the car! Piss off, you two!
Get out you fucking avant-garde!
You are gonna make
your shitty films, ah?
You've filmed yourself enough,
just bugger off my car.
We'll talk about this tomorrow.
If you would've continued,
I'd have freaked out as well.
When you come to think about it,
I would've never done anything like that before.
Is it ringing in your bag?
The boss?
What happens when you
forget your sister's wedding?
Are wetaking this one?
Yes.
Only don't put it on theback seat.
Come to me.
Take the camera,
we have to film the dog.
Later, OK?
Let's finish it up herefirst.
No, do it now.
He'll run away.
Well, doggy, can you run fast?
I'm afraid you'll cry,
not laugh, watching this record.
Laughter is not enough.
You need different stuff.
Interesting.
I'm sorry,
may I borrow the dog for a minute?
Thereis a troublesome child,
he could play with it.
Wait... outside.
Come to me, come.
It was an accident.
We'll buy another one.
Nothing, not even a hand shook.
I haveto come close,
to kiss and just leave?
Are you sure you'll do it?
I don't believe it.
I thought you were gonna freak out.
Freak out? Why?
Fuck it. Damn hard snout.
How many times did I tell you,
you haveto be...
Oh, hi. You'd better come tomorrow.
The pipe got burst.
What about hardware? Computer?
Not much ofit here.
You know, just call in tomorrow.
I'll tidy up a bit.
Let me in.
So you say pipes.
Well. It's not abig deal,
we'll buy a new monitor, computer as well.
Listen, lady,
don't tell me what to do.
Mind your own business.
Get me some napkins.
Who did this to you?
Don't tell me it's your clients.
What's the difference?
Mind your own business.
What they're gonna do? Come back?
They do that anyway. I give a shit.
Nobody kills for that money.
If you get beaten, you can't work.
You say, nobody is going to kill?
I can pay your debts.
Then they leave you in peace.
In return you'll have to film me.
You and your stupid videos.
Did you gambleaway or went into business?
Never mind, it's just poker.
How much?
How much, how much... Twenty grants.
Litas?
Litas, litas.
So would you like to
work for me for twenty?
I won't give you the money.
I don't trust gamblers.
You'll take meto the creditor.
This is not gonna to happen, that's for sure.
We'll pick the camera.
It's going to be your first task.
Are you insane or what?
They won't let us mess around with the camera.
We'll hide it.
Where? In your bag?
Do you have the money?
She has.
Wait there.
So now you are carrying women's bags?
Pussy licker.
So we are going.
Wait aminute.
Do you think I'm an idiot, cannot count?
What do you mean?
You forgot the interest.
What interest?
I wanna play.
Stop joking. Giveus a week,
I'll give everything back.
What week?
Have you any idea what you're talking about?
With pleasure. Follow me.
I can only gamblewith money
we brought. That's all I have.
OK, let it be.
Thank you.
Can you play at least?
Three thousand.
Raise.
Check.
All in.
Gaile.
Take it easy.
Ifl win we're clear of debts.
Gaile.
Shut up.
Where did you learn to gamble?
It's one of the two things
I inherited from my father.
What's thesecond?
Nobody ever did anything like that to me.
Cool, they were fucked.
Did you see her face?
The debt is bullshit,
but thegamewas awesome.
Did you like it?
Of course, why ask.
You liked theway I played?
Come on, to bluff likethat.
You're genius.
How do you likeme as a woman?
Well, you sure are straightforward.
Do you really want to know?
Let's go.
Hello.
Double for a night.
Room number
Sign here, please.
Good night.
Come here.
You hide here.
When I'm back you start filming.
Hey, whereare you going?
Wait here.
You see, I already know
where to look for you.
Right. Here comes the porn star.
If you don't want me to be followed,
get a mobile.
I haven't edited yet.
Come back later.
It's disgusting.
One more.
Disgusting, you say?
Who is disgusting? Him or me?
Piss off. One more.
We made a deal.
Sorry, I just can't stand your face.
I hope you'll help me.
With what?
Filming your orgies?
I really need that.
Yes, you need help.
And if it wasn't for your money,
I'd be gone already.
OK, weare settled.
You're free to go.
Come on.
And now what?
Nothing.
The stone reaches the water
and drowns to the depths.
Silent and lonely.
And the river takes it all to the sea, or maybe...
So this is how you seduce women?
Stay here.
So?
Don't talk, just look.
Are you going to film me or what?
Gaile, give me your hand and go down.
Don't come closer, step back.
Film. And don't even think of rescuing me.
Gaile, stop it.
Film.
Haven't you ever thought about that yourself?
You chickened out?
How would you like-
to float farther or gravitate to the bottom?
Film them.
Hey, you fucking jerk,
takeaway your camera.
Keep filming.
Wereare you faggots going?
What the fuck did you say, bitch?
Shut the fuck up or
I'll throw you myself from this fuckin' bridge.
Stop or I'll jump.
You're sick. Idiot. Jump!
She'll do it for sure.
Look who is there.
I was wondering if this was the right place.
Do you have it?
I do.
Gaile, let me in.
Let me in.
You enjoy crying, you really do.
So you are gonna watch now and cry.
Let me in.
If I were killed
would you come to my funeral?
Makea video, huh?
Would you come, would you?
Gaile, please let me in.
Don't do this to me.
Gaile, give me your hand.
Step back. Film.
Hey you faggots,
where are you going?
Hey, guys, guys.
Guys what? Fuck it.
Who's the ass now,
who's the fucking ass?
People coming.
Let's get the fuck out of here, come on.
Hi.
I should've called you a while ago.
No, no, I guess it's tiredness.
I'm also very sorry.
Are you angry on me?
No, it's not because of that.
I had troubles. Yes.
What? That's great.
When?
OK. But let's meet in my place.
Bring Tom.
I havea surprise for you.
No, you'll see when you come.
OK, see you, bye.
I'm so glad we met.
We'll have a chat, therehas been a while.
Nice eyes shadows.
Who's there? The surprise? Finally.
Good evening.
Hi. I'm Lina.
Nice to meet you.
This is my husband, Tom.
My pleasure.
Sorry.
Help him baby, OK?
Can you imagine, this namby-pamby
would keep running away from me with guys.
I was small and so curious, you know.
So oncel caught her with a neighbour.
How old were you then?
Fourteen, I reckon.
Probably.
Maybe cigarette?
I just quit.
Did Gaile show you the pictures?
And dad's film?
I did.
You didn't, you liar.
Come on, put it on.
Tom, come here.
Gaile is showing thefilm.
OK, I'll show you the film.
What's that?
Bitch.
You can leave now.
Give me the cable.
Then what?
C'mon, give me the cable.
Who do you think you are?
Sit there, I'll get it myself.
What are you doing?
You werenot allowed.
What? You didn't expect that?
Don't you like it?
It's you who startle constantly.
Sit down.
I forbid you.
Sit down. I told you to sit.
Stop it.
Don't you need me anymore?
Stand back.
You think you are
the only one who count?
I hate you.
Don't makea clown of yourself.
Do you know what's the second thing
I inherited from my father?
Myself.
Follow me.