Give me work!
Of war and loss you were aware,
Earth tremors from the bloodshed.
Why did you not prepare?
Children died without a home
a piece of bread was bought with gold.
Why did you not prepare?
The time of grace is over now
for Jesus came and you were left behind.
Two are sleeping in their bed,
when one awakens the other one is dead.
Why did you not prepare?
Two are walking side by side,
one taken up, one left behind.
Why did you not prepare?
The time of grace is over now,
for Jesus came and you were left behind.
Of war and loss you were aware,
Earth tremors from the bloodshed.
Why did you not prepare?
How many candles should I put?
- I don’t know, just light'em.
Are you sure that’s a good idea?
Of course, it was one of those last minute
offers. Trips like this usually cost a fortune.
Where do you keep the painkillers?
But did the children agree to staying?
They weren’t against it per se.
And in any case this is
about something else.
I'm talking about
a real childhood.
A childhood like the
one you and I had.
You have no idea how hard it is to keep
them away from their phones in the city.
It’s like they’re under a spell!
“Happy Birthday to You,
Happy Birthday to You,
Happy Birthday, Dear Mom/Helju
Happy Birthday to You!”
and congratulations to Mihkel
for finally quitting his job!
Make a wish!
Country folk are so nice,
I feel good about the kids staying.
There's nothing else we can do.
It's time to man up! Or woman up!
“From flower to flower he flies,
Towards the beehive he strives,
While thundering clouds arise,
Towards the beehive he flies..."
No further than here!
Have you all lost your mind?
This here is an ancestral grove,
a sacred place.
It’s like church, but in the forest.
You wouldn’t go take down
a church, would you?
So fuck off, this is my land!
And second, there’s no point for you
to do this now -
unless you want to break the blades.
We put nails in the tree trunks!
You damned green terrorists!
You're taking away
an honest man’s livelihood.
Old classmate,
if you want an honest living,
join us at the fire department!
Do you think my bank loan
will take a break, too?
It won’t!
I lose 200 euros every minute!
Do you understand?
200 euros!
Jesus Christ!
Let’s do that header photo now?
Victory!
You don’t know what it’s like
when somebody just takes your phone away.
And if I don’t upload new content
I might as well be dead!
You don’t have to stare
at your phones all the time.
There are so many things to do
in the world.
I doubt there’s anything to do
in the countryside.
The berries need to be picked.
The apples need to be raked.
The firewood needs to be chopped.
These are Grandpa Helmut’s things,
they should be sorted out.
The grass needs to be cut
with this scythe.
I want to cut the grass!
- Go ahead.
What else needs to be done?
- All the grass needs to be cut!
Maybe Mia should do it?
Can we feed the chickens?
Well alright, let’s feed the chickens.
This, my dear children,
is the world’s best fertilizer.
And when you have
the world’s best fertilizer,
then everything else
is the best as well.
You have the world’s best potatoes,
the world’s best carrots,
the best turnips, the best cabbages,
the best crops, the best vegetables,
everything is the best!
What's with the smell?
This fertilizer is chicken shit.
Eww!
Do you want a clothes’ peg
on your nose?
Sorry I don’t like shit!
I've had enough for one day.
Well of course,
we’ve done so much, haven’t we?
A whole ten minutes worth.
Oh you city kids...
What's with all this work anyway?
Why can’t we just be?
Because people can’t survive
if they don’t eat
and in order to eat,
one must work.
Such are the rules of this world
whether you like it or not.
You're retired,
why don’t you just
get your food from the store
like the old people
who live in the city?
Dear child, I can’t afford that,
because I need to save up.
Why do you need money?
You have chicken shit
and the world’s best of everything.
Roast!
I'm saving up for my funeral.
"A Modern Day Mutiny:
The War on Facebook"
All i need is your signature!
My kids will die of hunger...
But those devils are singing and crying
as if the trees were alive!
The trees are alive.
What?
What do you want?
I'm actually on vacation right now.
A signature
for the cutting permit.
Which cutting permit?
I don’t want my children
to die of hunger.
My harvester...
Thank you!
Wait!
Give this to your kids.
You are a good person,
mister governor.
You get my vote
every single time.
Knock-knock, may we enter?
He is a wonderful person.
Our parish is very lucky
to have him.
I see you are still beloved.
Not by everyone.
All of these years in power,
one difficult decision after the other.
But has anyone ever
zoomed in on the details?
Has anyone ever noticed all of the
good that I've done for this parish?
Now there’s this stupid Facebook
where every moron can have an opinion.
And I have to report
to these people?
Where has this come to?
Heaven help me!
Calm them down!
You know how to do it
all too well.
I will not go on Facebook
nor start sharing cat videos!
I have better things to do,
like rest on my vacation.
And that toilet paper
needs to be shut down
or we need to
replace the editor.
Hold your horses!
We have an alliance,
you're in the coalition,
I'm in the opposition,
I pull, you push.
So just handle the situation.
- How?
Just look at this dump!
The ceiling will crumble on
the land management department.
So, all of these boxes
are going to the library.
You do not enter the governor's office
without knocking!
The rest of the offices
have already been cleared.
Go have some coffee!
Out-out-out!
What are you doing?
Where the fuck are you sitting?
This is the governor's chair!
Why can't we just tell them to fuck off like
we did with the council of village elders?
It’s just a lack of Kinderstube.
They’re snowflakes
with no respect for authority.
But authority needs
to be respected!
Why don’t you figure out
what these people want.
Maybe it’s as simple as a playground
for kids or a bicycle road.
Get to the bottom of it!
So pull yourself together!
Authority...
"Donor Day! Give Blood!
Concert to save the sacred forest"
Bologna, a soup bone and chaff bread.
There you go.
- Thank you!
No need for a receipt.
- I.46.
Oh, I brought exact change.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Good bye!
- Let's go.
She did the dab?
He did the tailwhip?
Go on, say hello!
Don’t stay out too long.
Dinner time is soon.
So basically one of my classmates
has more subscribers than I do,
but my videos
have way more likes than hers.
It’s a real bummer that our parents
took off with our phones.
I bet my subscribers
are panicking.
But why do you smell like shit?
Oh... we do, don’t we...
It’s because we helped Grandma
clean the chicken coup.
She has so many chores!
To sum it up,
our summer is ruined.
That sucks. We can’t use our phones either,
Dad just confiscated them.
He said we have to spend
the rest of the summer outside,
even though he himself
is on his phone all the time.
Is there anything to do here
that doesn’t require the internet?
Well...
This is the crossroad!
We turn right, you go straight.
OK.
- We had to go to dinner!
Oh yeah! Bye!
Hey, I remembered something!
There’s internet in the library
and they have two computers.
One is a bit old and run down,
but we can use it for YouTube.
You know these guys?
- Me? No.
Why are they waving?
- I don’t know. I thought they knew you.
No way.
How long is this going to take?
- I don’t know.
We could have been in
Turkey by now.
Greetings!
- Hello!
How long will all this last?
This is going to last forever,
But the phones are going to be
in the box for a few days.
Why?
In the interest of everything.
Let’s switch them off as well.
Oh fuck, I took
the kids’ phones with me!
But August was born
ten minutes later
and by then
it was August already.
Do you get it? They’re twins,
but they’re born in different months!
So cool!
Help!
What now?
You don’t want it either?
I do want it, I'm starving.
We thank you,
Dear Heavenly Father,
for all you have given us.
Amen!
Does God really exist?
He does, if you believe in Him.
Dig in!
Grandma!
Where do you grow your avocados?
I'm vegetarian!
What's this?
- Sauerkraut.
Are you sure this is vegetarian?
It's sauerkraut! Full of vitamins!
The best vegetarian food there is.
Smells like
the world’s best fertilizer.
What goes around, comes around.
Roast!
- Roast!
Shall we go and make the beds?
- Let's do it.
You'll regret this!
Kiddies, maybe you can
fit in one bed?
I don’t want to sleep
next to that fartbag!
This bed is too narrow and in
any case the farting is not my fault!
It's because of the sauerkraut
like Grandma said.
So enjoy!
You remind me of myself
at your age.
I can’t inflate this,
if you keep farting!
And you're just like your father,
when he was little.
I wonder if you inherited
his tickle spot?
Chukupakniki!
Well that’s nice,
they didn’t leave us any money either!
Go to sleep now,
tomorrow’s another day.
Grandma, tell us something.
A fairytale?
Tell us about
when you were little.
When I was little?
I'll tell you a story of when I was little
and had no money.
I decided to build myself a Kratt.
To do that I needed to sneak out during
a full moon and go to the manor house
Sorry, what's a Kratt?
Kratt is a creature that you build yourself
and who does all your work for you
and brings you mounds of gold.
I was about your age,
when my grandmother told me a story
that she had heard
from her grandmother.
So that was your
great-great-great-grandmother.
What was the story about?
It was about the Count’s missing journal,
which had the instructions for making a Kratt.
You see the Count was very interested
in witchcraft and mysticism...
Did you find the notebook, or not?
No, I didn’t find it.
Thanks, cool story!
I found something much better
that night at the manor house.
What did you find?
- Your grandfather!
Mounds of gold...
Hello!
Mia, Kevin — for you!
Hello, aunt Helju! Can Mia and
Kevin go to the library with us?
To the library?
Our Estonian language teacher said
that we need to read.
It’s raining
and there isn’t much to do, so...
Of course you can go to the library!
So nice!
Would you like some pancakes?
Are they gluten-free?
Gluten-free?
That's how you plan on going?
It's pouring out there.
Damn...
Grandma, do you have trash bags?
Trash bags?
There should be some
under the sink.
"When among the good and the close,
nobody is alone.”
"SAVE THE SACRED FOREST!"
“Nobody is alone!”
“Nobody is alone,
nobody is alone..."”
Hello!
What do you want from here?
Did you come to crush
our civic initiative?
No-no...
Just try us!
I came for the blood drive.
I don’t want to crush anyone,
on the contrary,
I as governor care a lot. I want to help,
because who are we alone? Nobody!
Our strength as people lies in unity.
Let’s wrap it up
and go set up by the store.
Lembit!
I remember when you were a little kid and used
to play computer games at the manor house.
What happened?
Why are young people so negative?
Show me your petition!
Saving the sacred forest?
That's beautiful!
What a nice idea!
I want to support you.
Has anyone got a pen?
Do you realize
this document will end up on your desk
so that the parish government
would deny the cutting application?
On my desk?
Of course!
Whose desk would it be if not mine?
I sign every document, I sign...
That's why I'm here -
to tell you there’s no need
for protests!
The parish government
is always willing to cooperate,
especially with young people.
The youth is our future!
No!
I don’t want any more boxes!
Do you understand?
Oh my God!
They’ve moved the whole manor house here!
We'd like to use the Internet,
but can’t find the computers in this mess.
Where the devil
are the computers?
How about reading books?
This is a library, afterall.
Thanks, but no thanks!
That looks like a star!
So it must be from the Soviet times.
It's in German?
Oh my God!
These boxes are from the manor!
This is the Count’s journal!
What about it?
Can we take books home?
What kind of a book is that?
It’s a children’s book
about how to make stuff.
Take it, then.
But make sure you bring it back!
Yes!
Do you mean to say that
the parish government
will not grant a cutting permit
for the sacred forest?
No, of course not!
If you don’t want me to?
No!
The sacred forest is saved!
Long live the governor!
Let’s parade around Muusalu!
Let's make a stop by the store
and later on by the parish government!
Stop!
Although our hearts sing with joy
we can't just kidnap someone
and mess up their plans.
What plans?
“Nobody is alone,
nobody is alone...”
Yes, Kalvik?
When you're finished in the manor park,
bring the harvester back.
The hippies lied —
There are no nails!
Let’s cut this
fucking forest down!
What wonderful news! Well done!
Honesty will prevail!
Do you have all your things?
Yep!
- OK!
The kids of today...
Ill have them back in the morning.
Sounds good.
Oh, you darling...
Oh, you darlings...
These are the kids of today!
OK!
Tuuli has a fear of matches
and Taavi’s pet peeve is a drug raid.
No need to be so scared!
The mast is made of solid oak wood.
"No need to be so scared!
The mast is made of solid oak wood..."
This is so annoying and it will take
all night or all summer.
Schiissel means bowl.
With Google Translate
we’d already have our Kratt.
But why do we need this Kratt?
And could just focus on being old
and anyway I already told you this.
But maybe Grandma doesn’t want
to just focus on being old?
I'm older, I'm the teenager,
I decide!
We need Internet!
We don’t hang out online because we're bored
or because we have nothing better to do.
And make us feel good.
That's not why we do it.
Even though the happiness hormones
make us giddy, we are not addicted.
On the contrary,
thanks to technology
we are once again connected
as we were in times of yore
and as nature still is connected
through the mycelium.
Friends!
Nature itself is our guide,
keeping us on the right path.
Long live nature!
Long live Facebook!
Long live cooperation!
The sacred forest has been spared!
The smiley with the sunglasses
and then some flowers.
What do you think?
Good job, Lembit!
Should I post it?
Yeah!
But why can’t we go online?
Roast!
Because of my gut feeling,
dear son.
You're still little,
but the Internet is big.
It’s full of threats
that I can’t protect you from.
But we need the Internet!
How come kids today just can’t seem to cope
without the Internet?
Why do you need it so badly?
We have a book
and it’s in German
and we would really like to read it,
but don’t know how.
So we thought we might
use Google Translate,
but we don’t have Internet.
It's past your bedtime.
August!
Calm down!
I majored in German,
in case any of you didn’t know.
For building a Kratt you can use
whatever is handy.
For example...
an oven prong for a spine,
a wheel hub for a belly,
a spindle for the body,
two halves of a wooden bowl
can make up the posterior...
I guess they mean butt.
That's all the stuff
you're gonna take?
Well, this is a surprise!
I really didn’t see it coming.
It belongs to my wife.
She’s in Brussels at the moment.
See you later, kids!
Bye!
So what are we gonna do now?
Now we're gonna build the Kratt.
A pipe!
Perfect!
Let’s meet here at exactly II o’clock at
night and not a word of this to any parents!
You, Arno...
You are a good boy.
I can tell you one thing.
No rascal in this world
wants to be fold the truth.
But lie to them...
Lie!
Yes.
Then you're the man.
But why do we need the blood?
Because it said so in the book
and anyway it’s just three drops,
stop being such a baby!
Even the doctor
usually takes more than that.
I'm not a baby!
Wait!
I have a better idea.
Yep!
It’s not the first time
we come here at night.
If we can’t get
online at home...
You punks!
There is someone
behind the window.
Who?
- I don’t know.
But he doesn't look human.
He's all red, eyes blinking.
Churchwarden, who else!
No, it's a...
A ghost!
Help!
You damn rascal,
what the hell are you tooting!
Don't go!
Again with the batteries...
Oh, sweet Jesus,
now he'll get killed!
A-four, a-three a-two, a-one,
an old man leaped over a bomb.
The bomb it went off
with a bang,
the old man’s pants
in shreds now hang.
A frog peeped out
to breathe some air.
The old man asked:
Who's over there?
Children!
How much more?
Exactly at midnight.
Midnight is at twelve, right?
Yes, but then what?
Well, then we have to whistle
and then Satan should show up
and then we’re gonna
buy a soul from him.
I don’t want to meet Satan!
Come on, it's like shopping.
Just business!
When you buy stuff on eBay, you have
no idea who's really sending it to you.
You might as well
buy it from the Devil.
Children!
Oh dear Lord!
Oh kiddies, what have you done!
Damn it!
Where’s the fuel?
What are you trying to do?
Whistle.
What the fuck do you want?
Fizzy drinks?
“Your Show”
A tear on my cheek,
lips ajar and through them
only your name to be heard.
I think only of you, my angel.
Dreaming only of you,
living only for you.
There is only love on my mind.
I kiss your picture, lying
in front of me, on the table,
and press it against my heart...
You're pretty big already,
maybe you want jobs?
If you have a stable income,
you can get a loan,
buy your own place
and stop living
with your stupid parents.
My boss could get you a really good gig
somewhere far from here.
When we grow up,
we will have self-driving cars
and universal basic income,
so we’re not gonna have to
work at all.
Yep!
In that case,
may I interest you
in some fentanyl?
We'd like to buy a soul.
Gimme!
No-no, scammer!
You're not getting anything
until you give us a soul!
You brat!
You have no idea
how things work!
How can I be sure that the bag
isn’t full of redcurrant juice or ketchup?
Give it to me!
OK, you can smell it.
This is great!
Rhesus negative.
My favourite!
What about the soul?
It’s already there...
What did I tell you -
just like eBay!
So, now our Kratt
should have come to life,
which means we have to keep on
giving it work.
But what if
we can’t keep doing that?
Well, I didn’t really get that part.
Her translation was all over the place.
I told you
we needed to do a proper job.
Someone has used a saw on it!
What are those?
Grandma!
Maybe me and August
should go home now?
You're not going anywhere!
Where do I call?
II2!
Yes, hello, ambulance?
We had an accident with our Granny!
She fell!
Let's start exercising!
Elboes back, hands to the side!
She has a scythe
stuck in her head!
Elboes back, hands to the side!
Touch your toes!
Does anyone know the address?
Touch your toes one more time!
Have you had enough
of traditional recreation?
Grab a phone and call Muusalu Recreation
Center! Sign up to aju-huasca training!
Ouch, don’t do that!
Muusalu Recreation Center!
Give me work!
Raise your right arm!
Raise your left arm!
Do the dab!
The ambulance will be here soon!
The ambulance!
Oh no!
Hurry!
We have to get rid of the scythe!
No, we shouldn't pull it out, because
that would create internal bleeding.
They taught that at Boy Scouts.
The saw!
Pie?
Salty!
Give me work!
Now we're going to let
the paramedics eat in peace
and then we will send them off,
because you are alright!
Give me work!
Come with me!
First give yourself a round of applause.
Then let’s go into the garden,
because the apples need raking...
I think we should go home now.
The berries need to be picked,
the firewood needs to be chopped...
Kratt is a bad idea!
Sure, in the beginning it might make things easier,
but at one point there just isn’t any work left
and then Kratt will break your neck.
Translate!
I don’t know if we should
translate everything.
You don’t want to lie to him, do you? Lies always
find their way back to bite you in the ass.
Wait, can’t you just trick a Kratt?
There’s no trick. Some have tried
giving him a task he couldn’t complete,
like making a ladder out of bread
or something, but it doesn’t work.
Bread ladder.
(In German) Bread ladder? What is bread ladder?
- Brot Leiter - bread ladder.
Bread ladder? Kivimae Pets, rest his soul,
had his Kratt make a bread ladder
and his kids used it to climb the barn.
Bread ladder will not stop Kratt.
Maybe we should tell them?
No, stupid, that way
Estonia will never be free.
Let the landlord write down what he is told
and he’ll soon figure it all out for himself.
Yes! That's it! Yes!
"Peace on Facebook"
“I’m done. Went to my Mother's!"
Puss-puss!
Where did the pool go?
I need to rest.
The pool can go fuck itself.
I have to, you have to rest.
I could...
I could go to the beach!
What's that?
- Sorbet!
But where’s Grandma?
Up there painting the house purple.
Where did you get it?
- Grandma brought it.
How exactly?
Give me work!
Let the chickens
out of the coup,
so they can live happily
like us!
What if you don’t give her work?
Then we just have to tell her
to make a ladder out of bread.
She is going to start, but will never finish, because
it’s not possible to make a ladder out of bread.
So it’s a mission impossible and she’ll
keep at it until the processor fries.
I want to call Mommy and Daddy!
Kevin, wait!
I know it’s all a big mess,
but we are going to sort it out.
I promise!
Just eat your ice cream, take it easy
and don’t worry all the time!
Evil is real, goodness is real,
The bad are bad and the good are good.
Wrath is real, meanness is real.
Maybe the bad are the ones who are good?
Without good there’d be no evil.
Without evil — no good.
Evil plots would just fall through,
if everyone was only good.
Evil is a part of this world.
The same can be said of good.
The law of life is plain and simple -
without evil there’d be no good.
Evil is real, goodness is real,
The bad are bad and the good are good.
Wrath is real, meanness is real.
Maybe the bad are the ones who are good?
Hello, Raivo here.
Yeah, I'm on vacation.
A couple of days ago
I signed a cutting permit.
Can you check
which area was it for?
Gotcha.
That's what I thought.
The windows are from when
the school was renovated.
The red bricks are from
the boiler room chimney.
The stairs came from
the social housing project
And the timber I got
from the harbour.
We have no shortage of sand here
and there’s always
enough cement to go around.
Look at how many
big projects we’ve done in this parish!
You've made them happen!
This here is a monument to you!
Stop worrying
about that sacred forest.
We all knew it was
going to be taken down.
I even won ten euros!
Ten euros...
What ten euros?
I got the boot loose, see?
You can get on your way now.
I'm in a bit of a hurry,
I need to clean up for the big party.
What party?
Where?
In the pizza parlour.
I can’t eat another bite!
What a great day!
We have to go home now.
How about taking some to go?
They’re gluten-free!
Thanks, but no thanks!
OK.
Now can we call Daddy?
No!
The day’s not over yet.
But we don’t know
how to get Granny back.
Let's just sleep on it.
The best ideas usually come
when you're dreaming.
Mia!
- Kevin?
If we don’t come up with anything
by morning, then I'm gonna call Daddy.
Fine.
Don’t make any more pancakes!
Give me work!
Go lie down in bed.
Now pull the blanket up.
Give me work!
And now sleep until tomorrow.
We'll figure out what to do then.
Stop moving, you piece of crap!
Pull over!
Fuck off!
I'm not going in there.
Oh, so I am going?
Gonna put the house in order?
Or should I not go?
Shut up!
Easy come, easy... fuck!
Where is everybody?
They’re on the roof.
The fireworks will start soon.
I'd better wait here.
Two whiskeys, double.
Give me work!
Wrong blood.
That was outstanding!
Much cooler than
the school renovation!
And a lot cheaper!
And that last blast!
Now let’s start drinking!
Is it you?
You're gonna be the new parish governor?
You fucking assholes!
Who wants to get punched first?
I admit the bet was mean.
The sacred forest
was going to have to go anyway
to make room
for the gravel quarry.
So I'm just left out of the game?
Such are the rules of the world.
We can’t let anyone else
govern this parish.
People have to believe that there is
a new ruler to replace the old one.
Otherwise
they are going see right through it.
And people like us
will be finished.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about you.
About us!
About holding on to power!
You need to make it simple.
Look here,
Siim
is young.
Young people trust
other young people.
Right when everyone
loses all faith in you
he will swoop in
from the opposition
like a prince on a white horse
to dethrone the lying son of a bitch
who destroyed the sacred forest.
Transfer of power!
Everyone is happy again
and we can keep
building our summer house.
What will I do?
Go back to being a vet.
Or whatever it is that you were doing.
Or retire!
Don’t even think about retiring!
You're going to be
in the opposition.
You sit on your ass
on different boards and councils
and take out benefits!
Fuck, I'm gonna strangle you!
Help me!
Your fucking time
is fucking over!
Don’t get Siim riled up,
he holds a black belt!
What the fuck have you done?
What are you doing here?
Give me work!
Helju, I don’t even have
a job myself.
Give me work!
Helju?
Punch Siim in the face!
And make the rest into pizzas!
Which one is Siim?
She’s nowhere to be found.
How do you know this is the right number?
- I got it from the notebook.
Maybe they’re gonna call back.
So what do we do now?
What do we do? What do we do?
Why do I always have to
have all the answers?
Let's tell everything to
August and Juuli’s Dad!
Let me get this straight -
you bought a soul from the booth?
From the Devil.
I'm sorry, from the Devil.
You bought a soul from the Devil
and it went inside Grandma Helju?
Yes.
And now a scythe fell on her head
and she’s missing?
The scythe has been stuck
in her head for days.
The Kratt we built fell on her.
August, did you build
something that fell on Helju?
I made it strong,
I used pillars!
Where are you going?
We want to come with!
You're not going anywhere!
You will stay put
until I return.
Go online or something.
What do we do now?
Let’s ask Vivil
Got something!
Last one...
Why aren’t you working?
Mother, open the door!
I got something!
Are you deaf? I found
something with a fucking reward!
No cursing! God is watching!
If your father were alive,
he’d beat the crap out of you.
Do you think I enjoy cooking fentanyl?
Quiet! Calm down!
Settle down now, it’s alright.
We could be completely fucked.
For having a job at all!
Show me what you got!
I'm sure.
No clapping in church!
Helju!
Children, you don’t joke
about these things!
We’re not joking,
we’re dead serious!
We didn’t have
anyone else to turn to.
We could go back to the crossroad, but the
next full moon Thursday is I don’t know when.
No, coming here
was the right thing to do.
During my career I've had many brushes with
situations that require a professional approach.
I have used holy water
to cleanse buildings from bad energy,
I've consecrated factories
and correctional facilities.
But exorcism
has never been on my plate
until now.
What's inside the box?
DJI Fantom 4.
We have to go
and find the old lady.
Taavi, you and your team
go check the swamp,
Madis and Juks
you'll go towards Hansuristi,
Elis and Andro
you take a look in the quarry,
and after that ancestral grove.
If you find something, then...
Let's get going!
We're losing light.
“Let the little children come to me.”
The view from above
is very beautiful!
Flying over Estonia
like an angel!
I couldn’t resist the temptation
and bought one
for the congregation.
They don’t cost much
anything nowadays.
But what are you
going to do with it?
Most of our parishioners
are elderly
and they have
a tendency to get lost.
Some go berrypicking
and can’t find their way back,
others forget where they live.
So I fly my drone
and see where they went.
I have to say
it works really well.
The batteries need charging.
Where did you say
your Grandma disappeared?
I think that’s where
we should start.
Give me work!
Give me a cold beer.
I have a splitting headache.
There you go!
Give me work!
Just do whatever it is that you were doing
before you came here, you old witch.
This book doesn’t have
anything useful for anyone!
This hocus-pocus
is a waste of time!
You don’t believe us!
Once I too was young and foolish.
What about Grandma?
If she hasn’t returned by morning,
call the police.
We should get going.
Why?
Because, first of all,
Dad told us to stay home
and second,
I feel like if we spend too much time
hanging out with you guys, then...
we might end up with
an irreversible childhood trauma.
Yep!
Will we try to call Daddy now?
Have you considered that
he might not want to pick up?
Grandma!
I forgot the drone batteries...
Back down, Satan!
Now we need the Bible,
water
and lots of candles!
You motherfucker!
That damned governor!
Broke my spectacles.
Those are just frames.
They used to have lenses,
but then I got that laser surgery.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy Name,
thy kingdom come, thy will be done,
on earth as it is in heaven.
For ever and ever.
Amen!
Hot? Very good!
Hell is hot as well!
Pour it already!
Give me work, give me work...
God, grant me the serenity to
accept the things I cannot change,
and wisdom to
know the difference.
Pour it!
“Nobody is alone!”
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost!
Crop failures, famine,
difficult childhood,
school shootings,
wars, depression,
drug addiction,
rock’n’roll, contemporary art,
gay propaganda,
promiscuity!
Sin!
It is time to end it all!
Praise the Lord!
Wait!
It's not my fault!
Isn’t it a bit of a cliché
to blame Satan for everything?
I only do what I am asked.
Your dualistic world view
is inadequate!
So perhaps some tolerance
is in order, dear shepherd?
So you came to film
the burning manor house?
Go on, film the whole damn thing!
Here’s some helicopter dick for you!
Suck it!
Are you getting this?
Nevermind him, let’s just take a new header
photo. It's getting cold, I want to go home.
What header photo?
Why do you need those header photos
and memes and Facebook Lives and all that?
What are you trying to do?
Organize a coup through Facebook?
Power is slavery!
You damn bastards!
Do you really think you
can change something?
Make it better?
I've been doing it my whole life
and what's the point?
Sorry, I don’t know what to do either, but
another sacred forest has just been cut down.
We can’t just sit on our asses
and watch the world turn to shit.
There’s always gonna be someone
who doesn’t like something.
Where are you going?
I'm just gonna light myself on fire.
I'm gonna go burn at a stake.
A horrible end is better
than endless horror.
This is not the end,
everything will go on.
If you don’t solve your mess in this life,
you'll just come back to do another round.
Stop dicking around,
jump and we will catch you.
I don’t want to come
back for another round.
You're not going anywhere!
Your time has come!
May Lord have mercy on you!
Have you heard the story of the Count
who got himself killed by Kratt?
No, I haven't.
I heard the story from my Mom.
She had heard it from her Grandmother
who had heard it from her Grandmother
who is my great-great-great-great...
What was the story?
It's the story of the Count
who sold his soul
to give life to Little Count
who was basically a doll.
Now I understand the story
completely differently.
That's why I needed to quit my job.
Because if you work,
you're the Kratt
and if you don’t work,
you're the Count.
And if you're the Count
Then the Kratt will come
and wring your neck.
I like stories that have a happy end.
The end...
The end is indeed happy.
What do you think you're doing?
Bring her back to life already!
Back to life?
That I can’t do.
What do you mean?
Read from your instructions!
There are no instructions for this,
not even in the Bible.
Man has no power of this.
Only God has the power
to bring someone back to life.
Only He knows the time for us
to enter this world
and the time
we must take our leave.
Well, ask Him about it!
He will not reply.
He will, if you believe!
I do recall a time in my childhood,
A gentle voice I heard as if in dreams.
It was more tender than lark’s warble
and even softer than a spring breeze.
For a long time it tried to win me over
and fill my life with happiness and bliss.
My foolish heart resisted
and was stone cold,
I did not see the joy that I had missed.
Then finally the day dawned when I
received the call much clearer than before.
And Jesus walked into my heart as freely,
As tears of joy came flowing out of me.
This voice is now my guardian and leader
I follow on wherever it may go.
The brilliant sky above me opens wide,
I run to Jesus and stay on his side.
Wow...
Mommy! Daddy!
How have you been?
You know what?
We have been doing great!
You have no idea what happened!
It’s absolutely crazy!
Like on the first day Kevin wakes up,
he doesn’t even know where he is.
And then he sees Grandma killing a chicken
and he freaks out and then...
Phones!
Here, Kevin!
I have to make an Insta story.
We missed you so much!
Welcome back!
Mama!
The place looks so beautiful!
If we would have known it’s so pretty here,
we wouldn’t have left Estonia.
Well of course!
I had some time to think...
Me too.
You too!
I wanted to...
It’s all alright.
Alright!
I'm so glad we were able to talk.
I feel so much better!
We brought you a little something.
It's nothing special,
but there was nothing to buy there.
Well, thank you!
“Don’t worry, be happy!”
Let's have some coffee!
- Yes, let's!
Is it alive now?
What?
Yeah-yeah!
Thank you!
Give me work!