KU - FU
FROM SICILY WITH FURY ( Italian Title)
Bravo!
Show me the power of your strength.
Brake it with just one strike.
- But that's a tree.
- Do not argue my orders. Strike it!
Remember the technique I tought you.
Power. Concentration.
Strike it. STRIKE IT!
What a pity!
For the fourtieth time
I witness this scene.
For an old man like me,
to fracture an arm, would be a disgrace.
For you, it is a real disappointment.
Chinese proverb, chapter 4,
section 11.
Master... you always speak about China.
- Why didn't you stay there?
- I wish!
They kicked me out
because I was smuggling rice.
- From Beijing to Palermo?
- No, from Palermo to Beijing.
- This way, you could earn more.
- Is that so?
Now, let's eat.
Master,
why do I eat always vegetables?
Because you're young,
to keep in shape to fight.
I am old, and to train you
I need to eat well.
- Enjoy.
The fork picks up the spaghetti well.
- Can I taste the sauce?
- Just a little.
Master, can I have a glass of wine.
- No, wine is bad for you. Water!
- Water?
- Water. Fresh springwater.
- From the pit.
- I won't come up here anymore.
- And how do I do without a car?
- You're right.
- Sit down.
- Important news.
- Important?
- You must go to Rome.
- To Rome?
Yes.
- The capital of China.
- Up to a point.
What I'm going to do to Rome?
I've learned that the Board of Rome
has a vacancy for traffic warden...
and they are organizing a tournament
of karate and kung fu.
And the winner will fill the vacancy.
You know who will be
the winner?
- Will be you.
- Me?
- Yes
- Me, is impossible.
I'll send a letter of recommendation
to my friend, Kon Ki Lay.
- I do not know, Don Vitto.
- Kon Ki Lay.
- I do not know, word of honor.
- Kon Ki Lay is my friend.
He's the best instructor
of all the nipponian schools.
I will ask him to help you
improve your technique.
You will help me?
Give me this honor?
- Exactly.
- Make me a champion?
The biggest champion.
This way, you fill the vacancy,
marry my daughter and take care of me.
Sorry Master,
I agree with what you say...
but I live alone for so many years...
and never had the pleasure
to meet this girl.
Are you interested?
- Certainly.
- Are you 18?
- A bit more.
- Here is the picture.
It is an erotic photography,
but innocent indeed.
But this is Leonarda!
She is 18 years.
The photo is a bit old, but...
I'm proud.
I'll be back a winner.
This will be my wife.
I'll defend her from all dangers.
Dragons, dinosaurs.
I'll fight against all.
No one will touch her.
Leave her alone!
KON KI LAY
SCHOOL OF MARTIAL ARTS
Moron, look where you're going.
You smashed my brand new little car.
I'll kill you. I'll flay you, damn.
Asshole.
See what you did? Do you understand?
I'll make you just a hole, asshole.
You smashed my new little car.
Thank God. I will not forget.
Sorry, I did not see you.
Big jackass!
Pardon me, gentlemen.
Gentlemen,
beware of the wall!
I've seen you practicing.
You know the winner of the tournament
will fill the traffic vacancy in Rome.
If you continue like this,
none of you will win.
Do you want to win it or not?
- YES.
How so?
- No.
- NO!!
- Bravo Maramaldo, that's the way.
Your adversaries...
will use all the
tricks available...
I mean...
to win...
- is that what you want?
- YES!!
How so?
- NO!
- Who are you?
- "SHA KI."
"SHA KI"
"NAGAGE SHA KI"
Stand up my son.
- "SHA KE NAGAGE."
- Yes.
- Who are you?
- I'm sent by Don Vitto.
- Who is he?
- The big shot of Sicily.
What does he want?
A letter for you.
Maramaldo read it.
- You're a tough one.
- Modesty aside.
- Are you strong?
- Yes.
What then are you here for?
Maramaldo,
teach him a lesson.
Very well.
You're in the place you're looking for.
For the police vacancy,
you'll have to prove you're worth.
Ma'am... have you asked already?
What is your specialty?
Everything that is Chinese.
Earthworms, mashed ants, beetle sauce.
Roasted dog.
Cockroach white soup.
- It makes my stomach sick.
- Is there something lighter?
Want something lighter?
- Yes, two doses.
- Yes undercooked.
- Want undercooked?
They have everything hidden inside.
Two doses of locusts
to table 4.
Here, stir this.
Tastes better this way.
Here is the champion.
I was a great champion.
in the art of Kung Fu...
and also Fu Manchu,
and everything else.
Abebe,the local striker,
bang, bang...
- You're a buffoon.
- No, he's not a buffoon.
He was a rising promise.
Used to show such powerful strikes...
up to the day he got mad
and wanted to destroy the Pisa Tower.
- The Pisa Tower? -
Yes. He kept striking it, bang, bang...
with all that fat
jumping up and down.
There he goes, the strongest of all,
watch out Europe...
Sit there and wait. I'll talk
to the owner to get you a place to sleep.
What a cozy Chinese restaurant.
- Sir, are you eating?
- Yes, what is the specialty?
- Earthworms, mashed ants,
- No, no.
- Beetle sauce.
- No. Thank you.
- Roasted dog.
- No.
- Cockroach white soup.
- No, no. Absolutely not.
- Chinese specialty
- Yes, that yes.
Sir, enjoy it.
Waiter.
- How can I help you, Sir? Like it?
- Immense.
- Get me another.
- Want another specialty?
- Italian, please.
- Yes sir.
Alright.
Bring me Italian pasta.
- Forgive me... want to eat in peace?
- What, looking for war?
- Why are you touching the girl?
- Because she is good.
I did not like the shirt.
- Here is your plate.
- Bring me a drink. - Yes sir.
Now, I'll sing a song
from Northern China.
It is the drama of a woman
abandoned by her husband.
And her enormous pain.
Bravo
This time since you've liked it,
I'll sing another song.
"Pendriosa."
An allusion to spring.
To the nature that surrounds us
and we sometimes mistreat.
And now, to the gentle request...
I'll sing a melancholy song...
- Get ready.
- Yes.
which portrays the drama of a seller,
watching the cutting of her husband's leg
Now, another song.
If it keeps this way
we'll get enough for tomorrow.
- Yeah, but it is best to walk.
- Walk, nothing. Okay, let's go.
Enough.
Bring that poor to drink something.
Come on,
the boss wants to talk to you.
Stop!
- Do you know who I am?
- No.
- Attila.
- The scourge of God.
- Everyone fears me wherever I go.
- Not everyone!
- It is racy, the fool.
- So it seems.
- You know who I am?
- No.
I'm Franco.
Known as "The Prickly Pear."
- And what do you do?
- I'll show you...
if you touch me in the wound.
I belong to the school of
Master Kon Ki Lay.
I arrived this morning on the ferry.
- We have a champion here, guys.
- Modesty aside.
He is from Master Ki Kon Lay's school.
Now you have a worthy opponent.
We put a bit of salt.
A bit of lettuce,
comes in handy.
Then add pepper.
A bit of olive oil.
It is my hand!
Goddamn you!
Boys, put him to fly.
Misfortunes never come alone.
My children,
this place is very special...
that we can not change it.
My daughter loves the bar so much...
that I tolerate a lot.
- But when someone causes disorders,
I want to know. - And why?
So I can beat them up!
Bravo!
Superb!
Allow me to congratulate you.
Bravo! Spectacular.
What a headbutt.
I know hard heads,
but yours,
is an authentic weapon, powerful,
worthy of you.
- My congratulations.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Where did you get in from?
- Through there.
- Through there?
- Yes
- Of course.
What do you do?
Do you like where you sleep.
It is close to mine.
Yes, I do.
I'm just not happy with your father.
Kekkorr Captive.
No. Kekkorr Nocaptive.
He makes no distinctions.
Captive worker, fair, unfair...
and then sends everyone away.
I find a strange name.
"Kekkorr."
No, Ke Colonel.
It's the surname.
- The other is the name.
- Oh, Ke Cuckold?
But I like his name.
Ke Cuckold.
Look, another school.
Who will it belong to?
This is the school of Lho Kon Te.
It is attended by the evil ones
that ruined my show.
It should be big-shots.
Look at the letters, what do they mean?
I means: we are the best.
Attention!
You're a bunch of cowards.
What a great show you put out.
- We have to win at any cost.
- We will.
This is a speech,
not a two way conversation.
Listen carefully.
That police vacancy
must be ours.
It is a position
of great importance.
Whoever holds it
will be the master of Rome.
Thus,
we have to win the tournament.
But we have to be careful.
We have to study the opponent.
Find a weak spot.
And find out everything
that goes on Kon Ki Lay's school.
Do you know anyone there,
that can be our spy.
Yes, a certain Aldo Marama.
- Maramaldo
- Yes, a treacherous, jealous guy.
Very well.
Bribe him! Hire him!
And to get everything in order...
I will have sent from Milan,
three killers, friends of mine.
Ki Kaka Mai,
Tutti Li Tui
Va A Fan,
- But these are professional killers.
- That's right.
This way we can eliminate
all the men of Ki Kon Lay.
- My God, Mary! Who are they, moroccans?
- I wish, we'll see what they want.
1500 lire.
Help.
Bandits on the loose.
Great idea
to pretend to be...
turists.
Today I will show you...
how to fight Kung-Fu.
The deadly struggle.
- The unforgiving. Give me your hand.
- Ooooh!
Quiet!
- Ear
- Ooooh!
Quiet!
The eyes.
- Ooooh!
- Quiet!
I see nothing.
What the eyes can't seen,
the heart can't feel.
The samurai.
What do you want here?
Who are you?
- Ki Kaka Mai,
- The Deaf.
- Tutti Li Tui.
- The Mute.
- The Fan Van.
- The Blind-dust.
Out of my school.
Oh my God!
Help me!
Get ready to fight!
Attack!
Go Maramaldo
Poor Maramaldo.
Go!
- I do not I fight.
- Use the Kung-Fu.
Do not insist.
- Aren't you brave?
- Yes, I am.
- Then, go.
- No! I'm against violence.
Get out of here!
Coward.
See what they did to Maramaldo.
- Get out, traitor!
- Have mercy.
You do not have guts
for martial arts.
Moron! You again.
Don't you see where you're going.
You smashed into
my new little car again.
Fortunately I have insurance.
If I grab you, I smash your head.
You're lucky I'm calm.
You jerk.
Be calm, be calm.
Go slow!
- What do you want?
- Beer.
Beer.
Three beers.
- How much beer do you have?
A lot.
One box.
Two boxes.
Three boxes.
My poor luck.
- You again.
- I didn't mean to...
- Are you happy?
- Yes.
That's what I thought.
Very clever, bravo, bravo.
It's amazing what a few beers
can do, isn't it?
Just that sometimes we do things
we shouldn't. Come a bit closer.
No! Not me.
I have a headache.
I beg you, I beg you.
Headache.
- Where, where?
- Here, at the side of the head.
- At the side of the head.
-Let me see.
The secret of karate...
lies in the close relationship...
with the philosophy of life and
their continuous improvement.
SemPo Kojo.
Ju Jutsu.
Kung Fu.
What will it be, a Chinese fungus?
What the hell is this chapter about?
May I come in?
What is it?
What the hell of a manner to get in?
Sorry master, got distracted and the fist
took more power than I predicted.
I didn't like what you did.
Go away! Go away!
And I had so much faith in you.
And you what do you do?
- You contribute to that disaster.
- Master, I want to redeem myself.
- Why? - I won't let
an old man to be humiliated..
as well as his fellow pupils.
- Who is the old man?
- It is the master.
I?
I'm not even a centenarian.
- Forgive me.
- I'm near, 97, 96, 95.
- You have a great appearance.
- Yes, yes.
- You know why?
- A special diet?
No.
A specific treatment.
What could it be?
Because I follow the strict rules...
of a guide book.
- A last "bieta"
- And as such...
- I'm going to reveal you a secret.
- Thank you Master.
That'll be very helpful.
Kiss my hand,
not yours.
Do you know what is Kung Fu?
Sure.
We eat it all the time in Sicily.
- What?
- "Che stato."
- How "Che stato?"
- Ku fu is "Che stato."
- What is ku fu?
- It's the same thing.
Kung Fu!
- In Chinese dialect.
- You got it spot on.
- It is a defensive and offensive
millenial art. - Millenial?
Keep it in mind.
I'll teach it to you.
- Thank you.
- And more...
Kiss mine.
And another thing
I want to tell you.
- Yes
- Take a look around...
- to see if anyone is listening to us.
- Leave it to me.
Tiki, tiki, tiki, te,
unstoppable in karate.
Tiki,tiki,tiki, two,
unstoppable in Kung Fu.
- Nobody around.
- Listen.
- I'll tell you something nobody knows.
- Nobody?
I'll make you
an invincible man.
A very strong man.
- An unbeatable man.
- Unbeatable?
- A superman.
- Like Flash Gordon?
Stronger.
- Like Batman?
- Stronger.
I got it.
Like the member kitt.
- Much stronger. This one is nothing.
- Nothing?
You'll possess the power of the
" Hand of Travertine."
- The " Hand of Travertine?"
- But you can only use it...
for sports, not for personal use.
- Remember that.
- I swear.
Come in.
Are they for me?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
You know,
I won't send you away anymore.
I have always been alone.
Getting hit by tomatoes, potatoes,
eggs, waiting for him to come...
- to give love.
- Yes, I understand.
A young woman can not live like this.
- I'll help you.
- Thank you.
-Are you happy?
- Yes.
Letter from the fiancée?
No, poor thing,
she can't read nor write.
She is illiterate.
Well, to a certain extent.
You are right.
Let me show you something.
Here it is.
I have her always with me.
- Is it your daughter?
- No, it's my fiancée.
- She's a little baby.
- She was a little baby.
But it's been so many years.
It's like anything, a land that
if not taken care of...
only grows grass, you know?
Do you like her?
Do you want me
to tell you something?
I don't care.
I'm happy for you.
- And you, why are you happy?
- I'm happy because I have a secret.
- A secret?
- Yes, but I can not tell anyone.
So, you think I'm a nobody.
Well, I did not want to offend you.
You are, soul, body, mind, fire.
You're everything to me.
But it's a secret.
- So, tell me!
- If I tell you,
- you won't tell anyone?
- No. - Do you swear?
- What is it?
- It is a Chinese oath.
- And this, what is it?
- It's a Sicilian oath.
In fact, it is a Neapolitan oath,
a song from a certain Franco Rizzo.
- Tell me.
- It's like this.
- My master Kon Ki Lay...
- Your master Kon Ki Lay...
- revealed to me...
- revealed to you...
- the secret...
- of the "Hand of Travertine."
- And who is he?
- He is...
Master Lho Kon Te?
Where is
I have something important to tell
Master Lho Kon Te.
What is this?
- What is going on here?
- Master...
I have something important
to tell you.
Master Kon Ki Lay is teaching
Franco, a secret from Ancient China.
The "Hand of Travertine."
- From Ancient China?
The "Hand of Travertine?"  - Yes.
- Who is this Franco?
-It's the new pupil of Master Kon Ki Lay.
- Can this Franco, win the tournament?
- Yes.
- And why do you betray your master?
- Because I was the favorite...
The bravest of all. I Beat them all,
but with the arrival of this Franco...
Now, everybody beat me,
everybody...
Bravo. You have a
great sense of honor.
This vengeful heart of yours
will...
kill you.
May my hand be with you.
Thank you master.
- You're new around here?
- Yes, I'm passing by.
- I'm mr. Strozzi, the store owner.
- Nice to meet you.
- Do you practice Karate or Kung Fu?
- Karate.
We have everything for karate.
We have everything for the sport
and the best.
See, Karate Gi's.
Anything you want.
Is at your disposal.
- You're right but...
- Everything you need.
We are here to serve you.
See, this here.
An ancient mask.
See, what a beauty.
- Very well.
- And this, so beautiful.
- I mean ...
- See this.
- A hand bag.
- I can not buy anything because...
- I have no money.
- No problem.
We sell on credit.
Let us note in the book.
Monthly, okay?
Let's start with the date.
Rome, May 29,
and the rest, we'll write later.
Thank you. Come again.
Goodbye.
- What a beautiful place. Magnificent.
- I brought you here...
- for you to practice in secret.
- Thank you, master.
No one must know.
Today we start with the exercise
of our mentor.
- Yes, of course.
- My father.
- From your father.
- From now on...
have a deep breath,
breathe.
What is it?
- I'm choking.
-You have to get used to this air.
- This air.
-Look around. Here we don't see a soul.
Today we start practicing.
Come, come.
Lower.
- Master, it is heavy.
- What heavy. It is your impression.
- My impression?
- Come, come.
- Until that house.
- That's  3 kilometers.
- This is to strengthen the muscles.
- They are hard as rocks.
Rocks what?
Keep going.
- Be strong?
- Come on,  come on.
- Come on.
- We are arriving
You showed your strength.
Put it here. Here.
Slowly. Inside
are my best clothes.
- Slowly, slowly.
- I can't anymore!
Bravo, my son!
What are you doing?
What the hell are you doing? Get up!
- Get up!
- I have no strength.
Bravo. It's enough.
You did a great job today.
- Following the tradition of our father...
- Master kon Ki Lay.
- Do you want me to bring the furniture?
- No, no.
- I don't need. I'll do everything. Go.
- He's a miser, let's go.
- We spoke of...
- Of your father.
- Of course. My father.
- Yes.
- The master had many parents?
- Yes, many.
- And mothers?
- Ah, mothers, only one.
This will be the first training
to strengthen the hand.
- These ones!
- We start like this.
Pay attention.
Put your hands in there like this.
I have to put my hands
inside this hot cauldron?
- But, master, I'm afraid.
- What the hell of Chinese are you?
- It's burning hot!
- See as I do!
I have long sleeves.
You try.
- You want me to try with my hands?
- Yes, with your hands.
- With all the strength?
- Yes.
- More than once.
Sant Rosaly, I promise...
Very well. Bravo!
Come on! Come on!
Today, we'll start the hardest part
of your training
It is the "Hand of Travertine."
- Master, can't we skip
the "Travertine" training? - No, no!
- I failed the Kung-Fu lessons.
- That's not true.
I am the instructor here.
And I think you'll do very well.
- You think? - Sure.
You'll see, everything will be alright.
- If you think?
- Listen to me.
You should hit the wall
with the bottom of the hand...
to strengthen it,
in this way.
- A quick swipe.
- Exactly.
On the wall.
First lightly, then harder
and finally with full force.
- If I got ir right, with bottom of hand.
- Yes.
- But I fracture the arm.
- No.
It is to strengthen it.
I'll show you. See!
But why should I do it?
It's you who should show courage.
- You're the one who must do it.
- Me? - Ready? Go for it!
Guys, the house was fully
destroyed.
Wait a minute
I'll check it out.
Hey, don't you go with Mr. Rodrigo?
What a disgrace!
Guys, someone was
down there.
Let's get out of here.
Quickly.
I told you to check before.
Fantastic.
How did you do it?
That's amazing.
You've got invincible power.
I'm proud of you, you know?
- It was Maramaldo. - Yes
- He has no hands!
What does he wants his hands for?
My hands?
Stop! Do not move,
or else you're dead.
If it's a kidnapping, you got the
wrong person because I haven't a nickel.
It's not a kidnapping. You're coming
with us. It is an invitation.
An invitation with two knives
pointed to Franco.
- Okay, where do you take me?
- You don't need to know.
- Who invites me?
- You don't need.
Get in, get in.
Okay, without shouting.
I told it was a kidnapping.
Thank you.
Remember, you will only use
the "Hand of Travertine"...
for sport activities and not
for personal matters.
Come closer.
Sit down please.
- Do you know where you are?
- Of course I do.
In the school of a big shot.
- And do you know who I am?
- Of course I do. Master Lho Kon Te.
And you are not afraid?
- No. Why should I?
- Do you know why I brought you here?
- No.
- To make you a proposal.
- A proposal?
- Yes
- What kind?
Simple. In the next tournament
you'll fight for my school.
- Do you accept?
- No.
- Why not? Because I won't betray
master Kon Ki Lay.
- Besides...
- Oh, I forgot.
the 'Hand of Travertine?"
You know what we'll do with his hand?
The headstone of your grave.
After this demonstration,
do you accept my proposal?
Franco, what are you doing?
You're reaking the promise.
Kiss it.
That's it.
Remember the "Hand of Travertine."
That's better.
Be patient.
Show your power.
Show who you are.
Open the windows.
Unlock the doors.
Besides the "Hand of Travertine",
he also has a loose ass.
Damn you, again!
- I don't know him.
- Who doesn'tt know this bastard?
It lands on my little car, everyday.
I'm pissed off . I'll send
this moron, to the madhouse.
- I was dressing myself...
-Open the door. Let me see the damage.
Look, the pervert!
What are you doing?
What are you doing? Landing
is not enough? Also, want my wife?
Get out of my car,
I'll kick your ass.
It's not only the car,
now, is also my wife.
- Don't be jealous...
- Get out of my sight!
My clothes. My clothes.
Don't throw them to the ground.
The situation is serious.
We must do something.
Master, you don't trust me?
You don't think I can win?
That's right.
Master, we have always
the option of the killers.
- They just need your command.
- No. I have a better idea.
Which?
- Mr. Strozzi, please.
- Speaking.
I wanted to ask you a favor.
Just a minute, please.
- May I come in?
- Please.
- How are you?
- Very well, thank you.
What a beautiful home.
Worthy of you.
- I'm glad you're doing well.
- I owe you a lot.
- Do not thank me, but you remember me?
- Of course, I do.
- Remember we have a score to settle.
- Yes, I remember.
- Remember this?
- This, not so much.
- That I owed you this.
- These are some little arrears.
- Some little arrears that you owe me.
- Forgive me.
- Which you're going to pay, right?
- I can't because I have no money...
But if you could take a little off,
you know,...no?
I'm going to work for the City Hall.
- Forgive me.
- Please.
- With which hand did you sign this bill?
- With this one.
- Allow me?
- Be my guest. - Thank you.
I am wretched, you know?
That cannibal would eat my whole hand.
How will I do the tournament now?
Take it easy. Kung Fu is not everything
in life. You're overreacting.
Don't you see, one hand washes the other
and without them I don't know what to do.
Now with one hand, what do I do?
The other says, stop, stop!
Okay,
I'm going to make a special treatment.
At this point everyone
will be looking for me.
Especially... my master,
if I don't show up, he'll be worried.
Pity, after all that effort.
After all that tiredness.
To him, my misfortune,
will be a big disappointment.
- Murderer, what are you doing?
- Nothing.
This is acupuncture.
To relieve pain
and the fever.
Ormai, the vacancy
for the traffic warden is yours.
Basically,
you have no opponents.
- Guaranteed you'll win.
- How do you know?
It is true that I have no opponents.
I am Attila.
And wherever I go,
everyone fears me.
- Lately, have you been to my house?
- Yes, I have.
- Without my order. - I stop there to...
- Do not do it anymore.
What do I pay the gardener for?
Excuse me, master?
Mr. Strozzi wants to talk to you.
Come in Mr. Strozzi.
- What is the pleasure of your visit?
- Thank you.
- I am honored with your visit.
- The honor is mine.
Mr. Strozzi was the one who got rid of
the "Hand of Travertine."
No gentlemen,
I used an Italian method...
that can destroy a man
or a nation.
The protest!
- A que devo a honra da sua visita?
- Ai, sim.
Glad to see you, but there is the issue
of the debt in protest.
Who will pay it now, since Franco
has been out of circulation?
Do not worry.
Everything will be paid...
and with interest.
Take him!
No.
See what that cannibal did.
Beautiful.
It is always a hand.
Yes, but I can't fight anymore.
I feel the hand all sore.
That old scrouge ruined me.
See.
If you really want to fight,
why don't you marry me?
But that is another kind of combat,
you know?
I prepared to win.
- You're going to win.
- Of course I will.
- I'll help you.
- You, how?
Master, where is your champion?
- When will he get in the ring?
- He is coming.
Master, I can't wait anymore. I am
obliged to give the victory to Attila.
Be patient.
- Then, I will continue.
- Yes, yes.
Boys take this guy away,
we will continue.
Attention please!
Attila the Scourge.
The terror of the city
and countryside.
will now face,
the opponent Renato,
Chinese by birth
and Italian by adoption.
There he is.
Applause. Applause.
Here is your opportunity
to compete in the tournament.
We won the tournament!
Master, when will he arrive?
If there are no more opponents,
I'll give the victory to Attila.
Why do I have to go
through this situation?
Finally, he arrived.
Now they are going to see
what he will do.
Go after him, go after him.
Go after him.
You stay there.
And you there. Do we agree?
The rules are to be followed.
No, to dirty tricks.
Get back to him.
Franco, what do you do.
Use your head like Daddy.
Coward. You're worth nothing.
Go.
Go Franco, hit him hard.
With the head like Daddy.
Go Franco.
Bravo!
Thank you Mr. kekkor.
With this wig,
you gave me the possibility...
to defeat the terrible Attila.
You should have seen it.
How exciting.
- Especially over Attila.
- That's why it is my treasure...
my secret weapon.
When I don't have it I feel naked.
Truth is, without it I would not be able
to defend my interests.
Mr. Kekkor.
- I'll show you my secret.
- Okay.
This...
is what made the difference.
Well thought, well thought.
Let's toast to the victory.
This is my wig.
Give it to me.
Papa, cann't you walk.
Let me help you.
Without the wig,
I'm nobody.
At least give me moral support.
Beat them.
- Daddy.
- Calm down.
- Wait, wait.
Some bread.
The eels do not want to sleep...
the crabs...
There they are...
ready to get fun.
And now some flour...
for a good baking.
Flour from the best quality.
How beautiful you are in white.
You look like three ghosts.
Genlemen...
may I have your attention.
Now we're going do get
a real headbutt.
Yes....seriously.
Let's do the following.
I'll count  one, two, three,
and then you give a headbutt.
Okay?
I'll be in the middle.
One.
Two.
Three.
Come, come celebrate the victory.
- Mr. Kekkor.
- What is it?
I want to ask your daughter's hand.
As you wish,
you're too famous to be refused.
- Do you allow?
- Yes.
Daddy.
Francoso.
Franco. Francoso, come here.
Give me a hug.
- Ohhh, the briefcase.
- Dom Vito.
- Who is this?
- Franco.
- I'm aware of your victory. Bravo!
Bang, bang!
- You deserve a prize. A surprise.
- A surprise?
Come in my darling.
Look, what a beauty, look.
Francoso, this is the Imaculate flower
I promised you.
My daughter.
Francoso, you deserve her.
It's your wife.
- Your wife?
- Who is this?
- Your husband.
- Husband, what husband?
- I like this one. Go away.
Come here, my treasure.
- I like skinnies, but we'll manage it.
- Oh, my scatterbrained.
Franco...
the time has come.
- Here is the owner of Rome.
- What owner?
No, the Presidente of Rome.
- The Mayor of Rome.
- What a nonsense. What do you say?
We got it.
My son.
- Kiss the gentleman.
- Why?
This gentleman is here
to confirm that you...
are the winner
for the traffic warden's vacancy.
- Kiss him, kiss him.
- May I? - He's a bit shy.
- You kissed the Mayor of Rome.
- I'm happy.
- From now on, I'm your father.
- Why?
By a chinese tradition,
a man who is a mentor of anoter man...
who does everything for him
to become a man... - That's true.
Therefore, becomes is father.
Thus, from now on you'll work for you
and take care of me, as well.
- I agree, but I'm going to marry her.
- What? Alright.
- Yes, but you'll take care of me because
I'm your father. - The father is I!
- What? I am the father.
- No, I am. - No, no, I am.
- I am the father.  - The father is I.
- Excuse me, I am, not any of you.
- A stick for you, another for me
and we'll see who... - No, no.
What you're doing
is against the law.
And you too.
- We're stoppped here and the officer
do nothing.  - Isn't that enough?
No, no.
Don't recognise me, right?
Disturbing the public order?
A thief of high caliber.
Once wanted to kill me.
- Don't like it, right?
- No, no! I beg you!
I'll give you
the strike of mercy.
The END
Translation and subtitles: Soumar