Your Highness!
I have set you free.
Now, please teach me black magic.
Ambar!
Have you found her yet?
Not yet, where on earth is she?
Mom must be worried sick at home.
Try to reach her again
through her walkie-talkie.
Ambar, do you read me?
No answer.
Try to reach Panji and Kresna.
Kresna, do you read me?
I'll look for her over there.
-Panji, do you read me?
-Come on, you almost got it!
Aim for that one!
Watch for the wind!
Hurry up already! It's our turn now!
Be quiet! He's concentrating.
You guys will take the heat
if he misses the target.
Take a deep breath with a calm mind.
Relax your body,
and you can start this exercise.
Now, imagine...
...your pain as a white orb
that emits healing light.
What? Okay, I take this off!
Hey.
What's wrong?
Edwin.
You know that my mom told me
to watch the kids, don't you?
Are you sure you're my boyfriend?
You're not helping at all.
Okay, look.
We shouldn't panic
in a situation like this.
We have to be calm.
Otherwise, we'll make a wrong move.
We should just close our eyes now...
...and take a deep breath.
Hold it for a second...
...and exhale slowly.
Done. Do you feel more relaxed now?
Ambar, do you read me? Copy.
I worry about you.
Ambar!
Kresna!
Grab the prize from him!
Don't you dare.
No!
Help me!
Let go! This is for my sister!
The doll's head is cut off!
You guys are jerks!
Panji! Kresna!
-Come on, run!
-Run!
Hey, don't go! You little...
That's enough!
Ambar!
Ambar?
Ambar, do you read me?
Ambar!
Ambar, do you read me? Copy.
Ambar, do you read me?
I'm on the Ferris wheel, Miko.
How did she get up there?
-Ambar?
-Ambar!
Dinda!
Ambar!
Oh, my God, Ambar!
How did you get up there?
A beautiful woman took me up there.
Where is she now?
I don't know.
She's gone.
Don't tell me...
...that she was a Kuntilanak.
-Miko!
The Kuntilanak is already gone.
Dinda has defeated her.
Kuntilanak?
Wow.
You guys have quite an imagination.
Does Kuntilanak really exist?
-Yes, she does!
-Have you guys seen her?
-Yes, we have.
Yes, I have!
Okay.
If you don't believe her existence,
she will come and haunt you.
Isn't that scary?
You should be careful, Edwin.
Stop it!
Stop talking nonsense!
Let's go home now.
Let's go.
See?
I told you to always stick together!
You should not be preoccupied
with yourselves and ignore the others!
Thank God you found Ambar!
If she had been missing,
who would be responsible?
It was my fault, Mom.
I failed to look after her.
If one of you failed,
it means all of you failed!
You are all grounded
for the next three days!
Oh, no!
You too, Young Lady.
Now, you should all take a bath
and go to bed.
Okay?
Come on, Ambar.
Mom.
Next time, I promise to be more careful.
Sure, Dear.
Listen.
I just want them to be able
to take care of each other.
That's all.
Having brothers and sisters like them
is a wonderful feeling, isn't it?
I can't imagine if one day
I have to go back to Los Angeles,
I will surely miss them so much.
Be careful, Julia.
They are very good
at making people miss them.
I'm coming!
Good afternoon, Mrs Dona.
Let me introduce myself.
I am Karmila, Dinda's biological mother.
I'm sorry for coming here
without any notice, Mrs Dona.
Actually, I've been tracking Dinda
for a very long time now.
And I just found out that Dinda is here.
I'm sorry.
But do you have anything,
or maybe a document...
...which can prove that you really are
Dinda's biological mother?
I've visited Mrs Tantri,
the head of the orphanage.
I was the one who put Dinda there.
And I still remember the shape
of the baby basket,
her blanket,
and even if I have to describe
the situation that night,
I still remember.
Why did you leave her there?
I'm sorry, Ma'am.
I can't tell you that.
It's for her own sake.
I would like to express
my gratitude for you...
...for taking care of Dinda
all this time.
Sure.
-But...
-Ma'am.
I'm not planning
to take Dinda right away.
I know how you feel.
Thank you.
Whenever you are ready,
please bring Dinda to my place.
I will be waiting for her.
Mom.
Dinda.
Is it true that the woman who came by
is my biological mother?
Well, that's what she told me.
However, I still need to reconfirm it.
You don't believe her?
I don't.
Since all of this comes so sudden,
I have to be careful.
Besides, I found her attitude
rather strange.
-Strange?
-Yes.
I have to check with Mrs Tantri first.
I've been calling her all day,
but she's unreachable.
Even if you think she's strange,
I still want to see my mother.
Yes, I understand.
But please give me a little more time
to be completely sure, okay?
-You're doing this on purpose, right?
-No, I'm not.
You don't want me to go.
It's not like that, Dinda.
Don't you want to see me happy?
Of course. But I just want to...
Dinda!
A heart?
Dinda?
Whatever issues you have or we have,
leaving this house is not the solution.
I strongly believe...
...if you ask mom's permission first,
you'd have a better chance
to solve your problem.
And if she grants her permission,
I will go with you.
We will come too, Dinda.
Me too.
We will all go with you.
If you are absolutely sure about that,
I won't stand in your way.
Julia.
You must accompany her.
I will, Mom.
But...
...the others also wants to come.
It's because they said that they are...
Family.
That's right.
Is Edwin coming along too?
Yes, he is, Mom.
Take good care of them.
Don't worry about it, Mom.
Let's go, let's go, up to the forest
It's a very long journey
Look left, look right
There's nothing but trees
It's really boring
Edwin, they say
that this is a forbidden forest.
Which forest?
Aokigahara forest in Japan is known
as a place to commit suicide.
As for this forest,
people often come here
to find black magic.
You guys are crazy. You're too young
to believe in scary stories.
But this is a fact.
I think we've found the address.
Yeah.
Julia...
What's wrong, Ambar?
I need to poop.
-Please pull over, Edwin.
-Okay, hold on a second.
Don't stop here.
This is a haunted forest!
Cut it out, Miko!
She has an upset stomach!
What if she poops here?
This is a spooky forest, Fatty!
So you want to do this again, Skinny?
-What, Fatty?
-Come on, knock it off!
That's enough, Miko!
-Stop it, Panji, Miko!
-Enough...
Watch the road!
Are you guys okay?
Are you okay, Panji?
The car won't start.
What was that?
What kind of fur is this?
It looks like human hair.
It's not animal fur?
There's no trace of anything either.
Edwin!
-I think we've arrived.
-Really?
Look!
Yeah.
-Let's just push the car, then.
-Alright.
We're almost there!
Keep pushing.
Just a little bit more.
Stop it here. Okay!
-Is this the place?
-Yeah.
This is definitely the place.
Excuse me, Ma'am.
I am Julia, Mrs Dona's youngest daughter.
And these are my little brothers
and sisters.
This is...
I am Edwin, her boyfriend.
We come here to find...
Who's the little one back there?
Hello, Ma'am. My name is Kresna.
-This is Miko.
-Hi.
This one is Panji,
and that little girl is Ambar.
-And that one is...
-Dinda.
That's right, Ma'am.
I'm so glad to have you in my arms.
Ambar, are you okay?
Excuse me, Ma'am.
May we use the toilet?
Sure.
It's right over there.
Thank you.
Let's go to the toilet.
Julia, here.
-I need to fix the car.
-Okay.
Let's go.
Come on in.
It's okay, Ma'am.
We will wait outside.
But I'm so tired.
Did you say you wanted to enjoy
the scenery?
When did I say that?
I said this forest is...
We're so happy to be here, Ma'am.
Is that right?
Thank you.
Let's go inside, Dinda.
We should give Dinda and her mother
time to get to know each other.
Let's just stay outside for a moment.
Get in, Ambar.
When did you take that picture, Mom?
It was taken a long time ago.
Kresna, what is that?
Let's go over there.
-Kresna.
-What is it?
Why do I have a bad feeling?
What do you mean?
Let's just go inside the house.
Come on.
Are you done, Ambar?
Not yet.
Calm down.
-It's me.
-You startled me!
Are you okay?
-Wow!
I'm sure you are all very tired.
I have prepared your rooms.
The boys can go to the room
at the first door to the right.
Julia and Ambar can stay
in Dinda's former room.
-Let's go.
-Okay.
Let's go.
Thank you, Ma'am.
-I am first!
-No! Move it!
Move it!
Move!
-This is my bed.
-No, it's mine!
-This is mine!
-Let's do rock, paper, scissors.
-Okay.
Come, I want to show you something.
By the way, Edwin,
don't you feel that there
is something creepy about this place?
After all, this house
is in the middle of a haunted forest.
Why don't you do yoga
to calm your nerves? Come on.
Kresna, Panji, let's do some yoga.
This will make us calm.
Over here, Miko.
You will feel and sleep better.
Okay?
Come on.
Where is Miko?
There you are.
Okay, take a deep breath.
Exhale slowly.
Are you feeling better now?
Miko, where are the others?
Kresna!
-What is it?
-Come and take a look at this!
Come here!
Wow!
These are some great collections!
Marvelous!
Take a look.
All the Pandava knights are here!
There is Bima, Arjuna,
Yudistira,
Nakula, and Sadewa.
Kresna, what is this white screen for?
This is called geber,
a screen to play shadow puppets.
How do we play shadow puppets?
Let me show you.
Move, please.
What are you doing?
Seriously?
Oh, my God! Why are they lights out?
Kresna!
Hey, Panji.
I have bad news for you.
Beware, Kuwera,
the leader of evil spirits will come.
The ruler of Alanka...
...and the leader of darkness
will be summoned!
I have prepared everything
that you've asked for.
Every child that has been left here,
always has their picture taken.
I...
...also found this letter
in Dinda's baby basket.
Dear.
Do you like it?
All of these...
Did you make them?
Yes, I made them myself.
I'd be happy if you want to try
to make one.
What do you say?
This clay pot too.
You are a very special child.
Come on.
Try to finish this one, okay?
Go on.
Do you want to try to make this one?
I will help you.
Ambar.
Where have you been?
Hey.
What's wrong?
Dinda is so mean.
What do you mean by that?
I'm afraid she will ask me to go home.
Hail, all forces of darkness,
evil spirits,
masters of the Alanka region,
Kuwera has summoned you to come!
Beware, the wrathful evil spirits
will come as they are sent by...
Kresna!
Why are you watching from here?
I just saw...
Saw what?
I saw...
Are you okay?
Of course I am. What's the matter?
Empty your mind.
Free all the irrational thoughts.
Miko? Did you fall a sleep?
No, I didn't.
Okay.
Don't snore again, okay?
Listen to me.
Take a deep breath.
Miko?
No!
Edwin!
Just go home!
This place is dangerous.
Edwin!
You will be...
...taken by...
...Kuntilanak!
Kresna!
Panji!
Miko?
What's the matter? Edwin?
Edwin?
Edwin is acting strange, Julia.
-Edwin?
-Edwin!
Edwin?
-Edwin?
-Edwin!
Edwin!
-Edwin?
Edwin?
I'm sure he did something
that was inappropriate...
...on the way through the forest.
That's why...
...the spirits here
felt disturbed by him.
You see?
What did I tell you?
This forest is haunted!
I must give this letter...
...when someone comes by
and claims...
...that she is Mrs Karmila.
Please read this letter very carefully.
It all began when our dream came true.
Having our own remote small cottage.
This is all for you.
We didn't know the people
at the village called the place...
...as the lair of Kuntilanak.
Many people had been reported missing.
But we didn't believe them,
even though many strange
incidents occurred.
It was until she came for the first time.
I saw her appear in front of my eyes.
We finally realized that night...
...that as one of the cult followers
of Mangkujiwo...
...which has been passed down
for generations to our family.
This is inevitable, Karmila!
We can't deny what has been
ingrained upon us.
This black magic. This curse!
That creature thinks...
...she can take every firstborn
of Mangkujiwo bloodlines,
but not our daughter, Honey.
Never.
But this is what that creature desires!
-This is our fate, Karmila.
-No!
We must sacrifice our firstborn daughter.
We don't have a choice.
I have a solution.
For the sake of our daughter!
A couple of days later, I heard a news...
...that Mrs Karmila and her husband...
...disappeared mysteriously
in that cottage.
That's why I was confused
when you told me...
...that there was a woman
who came over...
...and claimed to be Dinda's mother.
Before we enjoy our meals,
Dinda would like to show you something.
We made this all by ourselves.
Dinda is indeed very talented.
I just taught her a little bit,
and she continued like a pro.
I don't like it!
I'm sorry, Ma'am.
Let me talk to her. Excuse me.
Well, then. Let's eat.
Enjoy your meal.
Because you will really need it.
Ambar?
Why are these pictures kept here?
Mrs Karmila?
Are you on a diet, Panji?
Why don't you eat more?
I'm not on a diet.
I'm just full, that's all.
What's the matter?
Do you not like my cooking?
It tastes good, Ma'am. Really good.
-I need to go to the toilet.
-Aren't you scared?
No, I'm not.
There's something odd about Mrs Karmila.
I'm sure there's something weird.
I'm sorry if it's a little noisy.
It's okay, Ma'am.
It's been a long time since we heard
the sound of Panji's friend.
Let me help you, Mom.
I'll help you too.
No, it's okay. Just leave it there.
Panji, Kresna and Edwin,
you should all rest in your room, okay?
-Alright, then. Let's go.
-Dinda, come here.
-Come on.
-Let's go.
You are so diligent, Dinda.
Your hair is all messed up and tangled.
Wait a minute, okay?
Julia?
Ambar.
Why did you run off like that?
Why aren't you eating?
We've all eaten our dinner, you know?
I don't feel like eating.
You'll get sick, you know?
Where's Julia?
Ambar, stop fooling around.
-I asked where's Julia.
-I don't know.
Alright, you should go to your room.
Let me look for her, okay?
-Let's go, Ambar.
-Let's go.
Are you done with the dishes?
It's done, Mom.
Thank you, Dear.
Let's go to bed now.
Have a seat, Dear.
Julia?
What's wrong with me?
Why don't I remember anything?
Edwin? Where's Julia?
Kresna! Panji!
I just saw Mrs Karmila.
Her feet didn't touch the ground.
She was floating.
-Floating?
-That's nonsense, Miko!
There's no way her feet
weren't on the ground.
Kresna.
Do you remember when you were playing
with those shadow puppets?
What about it?
When you were playing
with those shadow puppets,
I saw you were being strangled
by some kind of shadow.
What kind of shadow?
The shadow of...
...a Kuntilanak.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because...
-Now I remember!
-Edwin?
Hold on a second.
Wasn't there a little girl by the window?
And you said...
What kind of shadow did you saw?
The shadow of a Kuntilanak.
What did you say
about Mrs Karmila just now?
-Her feet weren't on the ground.
-Okay.
Where is she now?
Inside her room.
Okay, let's go outside. Come on.
-Let's go outside.
-Alright.
-Hurry up!
-Come on, Ambar!
-Let's go!
-Go, go, go!
I'm really happy to see you, Mom.
Tak lelo
Lelo, lelo ledung
My child with a lovely face
If you cry
-Hurry up.
-Let's go.
Come on, hurry.
It's all in this book.
Let me see that.
This is it!
These are the ones that I saw.
"Ponta and Ponti."
"The twin siblings who are known
to accompany demons and ghosts."
"They like dirty places and blood."
"Their appearances
are often associated..."
"...with a Kuntilanak."
Holy shit! I knew
there's something wrong with this house!
Alright, you guys wait here.
Let me look for Julia and Dinda, okay?
Don't go anywhere!
But if you guys see anything,
just run straight to the car.
Got it?
See? What did I tell you?
There's something wrong about this place!
I want to go home and be with Mommy.
Alright, you guys have to listen
to what I say, okay? Now...
Edwin!
-Edwin!
Julia?
Okay.
Julia!
Hey, Julia!
Edwin?
Dinda?
Let's get out of here.
-Where are you going?
-My body can't move!
Didn't Dinda asked all of you
to live here?
No, Ma'am. We want to go home.
You can't go home.
Once you step inside this house,
you will live here forever.
No!
Do you want me to show you something?
It's falling off!
What is that?
Do you really think...
...you can leave this place?
Where are you?
Don't you want to play?
Where do you think you're going?
Miko!
The Kuntilanak is gone.
Come on.
This is our chance to get Dinda.
Kresna.
Kresna!
What? The Kuntilanak is already gone.
Let's go already.
-Kresna!
-Hurry, get up!
-Where are you going?
-Let's go! Hurry!
Come on!
Julia, wake up!
Come on, wake up. Julia!
Julia, calm down.
Who is that?
I have no idea.
There were two little girls over there!
With white hairs?
Yes.
Right, I saw them too.
Is it possible that Mrs Karmila is a...
Kuntilanak?
Yes.
Damn!
Okay, there's something wrong
with this house.
-We should go home, okay?
-No, wait! Ambar!
We must look for her.
Ambar is already outside, okay?
But I have no idea where Dinda is.
We must look for her now! Come on!
Come on, come to hell!
Let go of him! Come on!
Let go!
Go, go!
Edwin!
Let's just hide over here.
Ambar, you should...
Where's Ambar?
I don't know.
-And what about Miko?
-I don't know!
Miko?
Oh, my God!
Miko!
Oh, my God! Where the hell are we?
Kresna.
Hold on a second. What is that?
There are some kind of lights over there.
I think there's a crowd there.
-Let's check it out.
-Okay.
Wow! What is this place, Panji?
Kresna...
Come on, Panji.
Kresna, what are we doing here?
This place is really spooky.
Hurry up and ask them.
We shouldn't stay here any longer.
Alright, be patient.
Excuse me, may I ask you something?
Come with me to hell.
Let's go! Hurry!
Hurry up, Panji!
Panji, back away!
What? Why are we...
Kresna, what the hell is that?
Dinda!
Dinda, wake up!
Come on, wake up.
Julia, Edwin? What's wrong?
It's Mrs Karmila... She's...
She's not what you think she is.
Edwin, tell her!
Mrs Karmila and this entire house...
Oh, so my lovely daughter
is already awake?
Come with me, Dinda.
Ma'am.
Dinda is leaving with us right now.
And you are going to let us leave.
What do you mean by that?
We already know what you really are!
What a temper.
Dinda.
It's been a long time
since you're with me.
Don't you miss me?
I really love you, Dear.
No, Dinda. Don't fall for her tricks.
Come here.
Dinda?
You dare to oppose me?
Edwin!
Dinda, run!
Come on, Dinda!
Edwin!
Dinda, hurry!
Come on, Edwin!
Julia, get out of here!
No! Come on, hurry!
Get out, Julia!
Get out!
Let's go, Dinda.
Ambar, Kresna, Panji, Miko!
Julia, where are the others?
Just calm down, okay?
-Julia, Dinda!
-Mom!
-Are you okay?
-Yes.
Where are the others?
-They're gone, Mom.
-Gone? Where?
-Where are they?
-Hold on, Mom.
Inside that house there's a chamber
under the basement.
I think that's her lair.
If they were taken by the Kuntilanak,
perhaps she took them there.
Dinda, listen to me very carefully.
You came from the Mangkujiwo bloodline
who worships Kuntilanak.
According to the pact, as a first born
you will be given to the Kuntilanak.
Your late parents tried to sever
that pact.
They tried to lock her up
and sealed her lair.
But the Mangkujiwo family
weren't going to let that pass.
They sent someone to free the Kuntilanak.
And now that creature
is coming after you.
And she considers you
as her own daughter.
That creature can transform
to look like your mother.
This is from your mother.
This is...
Isn't that Mrs Karmila's hairpin?
Hairpin? Are you sure?
It looks like a branch of a tree.
Tree?
This hairpin is related to a tree
where the lair of Kuntilanak is.
My mother wanted me to go there.
Mom, Edwin is still inside.
I have to help him.
Julia!
You are not allowed to go there.
Let me help them instead, okay?
Edwin!
There's no point.
I'm sure the Kuntilanak
will come after me.
And maybe my brothers and sister
are in her hands right now.
-I should be the one to face her.
-No, you shouldn't.
No! Let me do that!
You must hide. Go on, hide. Hurry!
Edwin!
Mom, it's Edwin...
He's still inside.
I can't go in there!
Julia, please calm down.
Once that creature comes out,
we will burn her.
Afterwards, we look for your brothers
and sisters.
We must leave this place at once.
But...
Edwin!
Edwin?
Come with us to hell.
Mrs Dona.
You're here.
Where is Dinda?
She's mine!
How dare you oppose me...
...in my own house?
Oppose me in the forest of Ujung Sedo?
You have tasted life,
haven't you?
Listen, Dinda is hiding right now.
Find her and protect her.
-I will face this creature.
-But, Mom...
Just do as I say! Go!
Dinda?
Dinda, where are you?
Dona.
I know what's on your mind.
I know what you wish for.
There are too many disappointments
in your heart...
...because you are unable to fulfill
all your wishes.
Dinda?
I can make all your dreams come true.
You know that, don't you?
Tak lelo
Lelo, lelo ledung
Where are my children?
Edwin, come to your senses!
Do you think...
...you are going to leave this place?
Edwin, come to your senses!
No, Julia!
Edwin!
Dinda...
Dinda.
We are at Ujung Sedo.
The forest of Kuntilanak.
Dinda, be careful!
My Child, there you are.
-Watch out!
-Look out, Dinda!
My child.
Watch out, Dinda!
Come here, My Dear.
Dinda!
The strongest one is the master!
You little...
Dinda!
-Be careful, Dinda!
-Watch out!
-Come here!
-Dinda!
Come here!
Hold on, Dinda!
Dinda!
You belong to me, Dinda!
A heart.
A tree.
Dinda!
-Dinda!
Edwin?
-Mom!
-Edwin?
-Edwin, are you okay?
Come on, Miko. Be careful.
Mom!
Oh, my lovely children!
-Are you guys alright?
-Mom!
-Edwin?
-Edwin.
-Julia.
Edwin, are you okay?
Sometimes, what we are looking for
is right in front of us all along.
All this time, I've been searching
for my biological mother.
And yet, there's someone else
who loves me more than her.
It's Mrs Dona.
I am grateful
that she never gave up on me,
and I will love her forever.
Tak lelo
Lelo, lelo ledung