Good morning. I will be right there.
-Manju?
-Sir?
-Is Mr. Krishnadas here?
-Yes, sir. He is in the office.
Sir.
Yes.
-Sir, shall I pack these as well?
-Sure.
Sir, there is information from the IB
that a criminal might enter via our coast.
The fax will arrive shortly.
Sir, we need to strengthen
the coastal region.
So, it would be great
if you could issue an order.
I've been doing this
for more than 30 years.
Now it's up to guys
like you to give orders.
Sir?
I think you forgot about it.
I retired yesterday.
Everything is ready, sir.
-Tell them I'm coming.
-Okay, sir.
-What happened?
-Sorry, sir.
As far as each one of us is concerned,
this is a day that we can't avoid.
The day when we leave behind
our official life for our retired life.
Today, our respected Mr. Krishnadas
will bid farewell to us.
He is the perfect example for how
an investigating officer should be.
In the course of his official life,
he has witnessed many developments
and investigated many cases.
But when we look back on his career
the first thing that comes to
our mind is the Charlie case…
and fugitive Kurup.
It would have been
dismissed as an accident case.
But with his analytical skills,
he was able to solve
the mystery behind it.
KURUP
FROM CHERIYANAAD TO MADRAS
Don't break it again.
When did you come, Brother-in-law?
I couldn't stay back when
-I heard about Gopikrishnan.
-Sharada, give it to everyone?
That's why I came here.
I knew that my son
-will pass with flying colors.
-Shut up!
Don't you feel ashamed to brag about it?
What are you saying?
After all, Gopi got a seat in PUC.
Why do you feel ashamed, brother-in-law?
Where is the first class seat holder?
He went to college to
enroll for degree course.
So, he went to college
to enroll for degree!
My dear, your eldest son,
Mr. Gopikrishna Kurup
flunked the PUC exams.
-What?
How can he join army at such a young age?
It's not army.
It's the Indian Air force.
Also, one doesn't join the air force.
They decide who joins them.
You were an army man.
Tell her how it works.
What if he gets into
trouble and ends up in jail?
We will be humiliated.
He doesn't need to join the
air force to end up in jail.
Don't worry about it.
Just imagine our Gopi
in an air force uniform!
He will look so smart.
That's all you need to think right now.
-Isn't Gopi home yet?
-I don't know.
Maybe he will show up
with a degree certificate.
He can't pull off his
tricks there, Gomathi.
It's the air force, after all.
The Indian Air force.
RECOLLECTIONS BY PETER
Stop talking and go in there now.
I wonder what terror awaits me here.
Here you go.
Hey!
-Hello!
-Where are you going?
Where are you off to?
Don't you see the queue?
Bloody Indians!
Who say that?
And now he is showing off!
I say who say that!
You!
Shoe not polished.
This is how you stand in air force camp!
Do you know the meaning of decorum?
Sorry, sir.
Everybody… fall-in in threes.
In three lines!
Come!
Attention!
Stand at ease.
"Abranjan!"
Don't know "abranjan"?
Useless fellows!
Hands out.
Sitting position.
Good!
-Sir, coffee.
-Stand at ease.
-Murthy?
-Sir?
-"Abranjan!"
-Who is that bloody idiot?
Stand at ease!
"Abranjan."
-Good!
-Sir is calling you.
Attention!
-Yes.
-You, take position! Do drill.
-Sir.
Attention.
Stand at ease.
"Abranjan!"
Sir?
-Who are you?
-Sir, myself Gopikrishnan.
-Coming from--
-I don't think you belong here.
No, sir. I mean, yes, sir.
I finished the written test, sir.
Third attempt.
-Now medical test, sir.
-Why are you here?
-Sir, medical test.
-No.
I asked, why Indian Air force?
To fly, sir.
Stand at ease!
You can do it right here.
-Anand?
-Sir?
-Teach him how to fly.
-Yes, sir.
Until I say. Get out!
Attention! "Abranjan."
Stand at ease!
Here.
Attention!
-Sir?
-Fly.
-Fly, sir?
-Stand at ease!
Fly.
Attention.
Stand at ease.
-Is this okay, sir?
-Attention!
Stand at ease.
Let your bloody legs also fly high!
Legs.
Okay, sir.
Back to line.
The prestigious Indian Air force.
There are some of us here.
My father has no taste in art.
I just obeyed his command
and gave up what I loved the
most, that is the guitar and the stage.
That's how folland gnat
and cockpit invaded my life.
RIP, Rockstar Peter!
RIP!
Then we have Surjit Singh
who wants to keep up the legacy
of two generations of patriotism.
A true Indian by heart!
And then we have him.
Forget the air force!
His folks don't have a
clue about anything as well.
He doesn't know
where he is flying to.
Meet the Great "Gopikrishnan."
Hello!
"Abranjan."
-Hey, Peter! Wake up.
-What is it?
Switch off the lights and
go back to sleep!
Hey, try knocking again.
Come on, boys! Come on!
Hey, Peter!
You bloody idiot!
Take your position.
Get up!
How dare you sleep during the parade!
-Come on, get up!
-Don't hit me.
-Who the hell will fetch the shoe?
-No!
-Take it!
-I'll take it, sir!
Come on! Get going!
Do you come here to sleep?
-No, sir, I…
-I will be screwed!
You have become airmen.
An airman always should be
physically fit and mentally agile.
-And here-- GK!
-Sir! Yes, sir.
-Sleeping in the classroom?
-Yes, sir.
Get out of my classroom!
And 20 rounds in the airfield!
Hey! Where is it?
-Hey, what are you doing?
-Hey!
-Did you see my bedsheet?
-I can't even find my own.
-What?
-It's missing.
General salute!
-Hey!
-Sir?
-Why are you late?
-Sorry, sir.
-Bathroom, sir.
-See, Mr. Gopikrishnan Pillai…
this is an airman training school.
-Don't make it an animal training school.
-Sir.
-Sorry, sir.
-Twenty rounds around the airfield.
-And right time for the class.
-One!
Peter, look straight.
Lift the rifle higher.
Proper.
-Where are you off to?
-Dinner, sir.
-What time is your dinner?
-Seven o'clock, sir.
What is the time right now?
-7:03 p.m. sir.
-Why are you late?
Evening punishment, sir.
50 rounds.
For the bloody three minutes,
three hours in the ground!
Get into the rooster position.
Sir, I already completed one punishment.
Sorry, sir.
Welcome to animal training school.
Take your position for next three hours.
-Anand.
-Sir.
Take the position.
Take proper rooster position.
Lift your buttocks.
-Stay right there.
-Yes, sir.
Sir!
He is also late, sir.
To heck with you, Gopi!
-Look at them.
-Hey, dude!
What are you staring at?
Go to your dormantry.
Peter darling, hope the winds
are favorable to your aircraft.
We Mustangs are coming to the
MCC to rock the brains out on the 20th.
Indie Rock Festival it is!
The void you made after
your take-off is yet to be filled
and will always remain vacant.
Since you are near, we hope we can
perform together towards awesomeness.
Waiting for your landing there.
Fly and come buddy! With love, M.
Hey, come on up!
Hey, this is my bedsheet.
Come quickly!
You are…
GK?
-It's you!
-Yes, Peter Pan.
What are you up to this time?
Don't you want to go to your big event?
Come on.
-Where are you taking me?
-Be quiet.
Someone will hear us.
So this is your bed bug in the air force!
GK, where are we going?
-Hi!
-All good?
-Absolutely.
-Hi, Chandan.
-Hello.
-Who are these guys?
-Old friends.
Jimmy.
-I need your help.
-Tell me.
-Okay.
-Thank you, bro.
-Love birds, please give way.
-GK!
-Keep going!
-One second.
-We are here.
-GK!
Hi, everybody! There is a surprise.
Our beloved friend, Mr. Peter.
He is here. We really miss your string.
Come on to the stage.
Right now.
Peter George!
Thank you!
Thank you so much for the warm welcome.
I'm here just because
of my new friend, GK!
Where is GK?
He will screw up. I'll be right back.
-Go, man!
-GK!
-Excuse me.
-One minute.
May I borrow this?
-Hey, what is this?
-What are you doing?
GK, what are you doing?
See where the world is going
My Susie darling
One, two…
One, two, three. Go!
There is a girl next door called Rosie
Looks like she's on the disco floor
In her bell-bottoms and high heels
The girl trots like a horse on wheels
When I went to England one time
I fell in love with a madam for a time
Then I returned home
I passed that love to Rosie nearby
While madam butters her bread
For breakfast everyday
Rosie has stewed cassava
With sardine curry to begin the day
Hey, stop the music!
Hi, boys.
-Hi, sir.
-Jai Hind, sir!
-Sir.
Hey, Dominique.
Sir is here.
Thank you.
Jai Hind, sir.
Cheers!
Sir?
-Peter?
-Sir.
Peter George.
-I see a vibrant future in you.
-Thank you, sir.
But what surprises me is…
why hasn't your friend here quit yet?
Sir… I came here so I
can succeed in life.
Sooner or later, I will.
Really?
Listen carefully.
I have a surprise for you in Bombay.
Get ready for that, chap.
Sir, with your guidance, always ready.
Let us see. Cheers!
Cheers!
-Oh, come on!
-What?
Music!
Kumarasamy!
A new sky, a new earth and a new world.
Where the scents of dream, loss,
love and vengeance waft by at once.
The exquisite city of dreams and desire.
As someone once said "Amchi Mumbai".
Each of you will go to the
billet assigned to your trade.
Report to the base
station at 7:00 a.m. tomorrow.
The information of the billets is on
the notice board in the corridor.
Come on.
Let's go. Alpha is this way.
Billet three for accounts is over there.
GK was right.
It's easy to give up when you lose.
The difficult part is to
prove that you can win.
The Indo-Pakistani War of 1971
groomed the airman in me.
Just like the music
that captivated me once,
this air force life gave me a
lot of joy and responsibilities.
But Gopikrishnan seemed
like a changed man.
Was it drudgery or senior
officers' conduct towards him?
Something seemed to bother him.
GK?
-What happened?
-Peter George.
These people will make me work to death.
It will be alright.
Why didn't you attend Sharada's call?
I'll call back.
Please take off that bedsheet.
Please fold it as well.
For the next fusion party.
-Nonsense!
-Won't you come with me?
Of course. Do you want to do it now?
No.
I'm going home tomorrow.
I got sick leave for a month.
-Shall we do it when I'm back?
-Certainly.
But make sure you come back!
I'll come back.
Sure.
Sorry.
That day, when he said goodbye
I thought it was a farewell
before another vacation.
But it wasn't.
It was his final goodbye…
from the air force and my life.
-I realized it later.
-Thank you.
-You played well.
-Hi, Peter.
-Hi.
-Good game.
-Thank you.
-It's been a while, right?
-Yeah, it's been some time.
The Bonus Act revision is on.
I was busy with that.
Okay.
Hey, I'm really sorry.
I heard about it when
the dispatch arrived today.
-What happened?
-It's about your friend Gopikrishnan.
What about him?
The police inquiry
report came this morning.
Don't you know about it?
Tell me what the matter is.
He committed suicide.
-Who?
-Gopikrishnan.
-Are you sure?
-Yes!
I was there when the report
was handed over to Mr. Sathya.
-It was very unfortunate.
-Oh, God!
The circular might be issued
to all departments tomorrow.
When the circular is issued,
the entire department
and unit will know about it.
But there is someone
who ought to hear it first.
Sharada.
It wasn't easy for me to
inform her of that death.
What brings you here?
We received a message in the office.
The report says it was a suicide.
But GK?
Why would GK do such a thing?
What could be the reason?
Do you know why?
HIM AND HER
What did the telegram say?
It just said, "Come home."
Could this be about your marriage?
That's a good guess.
You'll have to find a new teacher
if I stop working after my wedding
to learn Hindi and Marathi. Okay?
Why should I learn Hindi
and Gujarati if I have to go to Persia?
-I'd rather learn Arabic.
-So, that's your plan!
-I'm putting your tea on my tab.
-Attagirl!
You bought me tea as your wedding treat.
Shall we go?
You can go ahead.
I need to make a local call.
-Gopikrishnan, there's a call for you.
-Okay.
-Peter, I'll be right back. Salim.
Come on.
Hello.
Is this young lord?
Well, I'm all grown-up now.
And speaking about the label…
I gave it up long ago.
Is this someone from Cheriyanaad?
It's me, Sharada.
Remember?
I'm in Bombay studying nursing.
Ms. Malini is funding my studies.
She wants you to come home
if you're free this Sunday.
I'll think about it.
You can hang up.
Shall I give you the address?
I don't need the address.
Don't worry about it.
People from the air force
can come flying anywhere.
Have your first peg when
the mustard seeds pop.
-Awesome!
-So, shall we start?
-Water?
-No, I don't need water.
You don't?
Give it to me.
Hey.
Add a little water, young man.
Don't have it neat!
Do you see that grey hair on you?
I want to keep mine as it is.
-That's why it's better to have neat.
-That's how I started as well.
Go and get the clothes from upstairs.
-Okay.
-Hide the glass.
-Isn't it ready yet?
-Give me ten minutes.
Don't try to hide. I know what it is.
You have lived only
one-third of your life.
Really?
Oh, you meant him.
-Aunt, where's Sharada?
-She went upstairs to get the clothes.
-Don't leave me alone.
-I'll be back soon.
-Do you want to cut your life short?
-Just one more.
Do whatever you like!
Why did you come up?
Do they need me downstairs?
Yes, someone needs you.
But…
it's not them.
Somebody else needs you now.
Beautiful eyes make a girl…
look even more beautiful.
You are a beautiful girl.
Come closer.
A man doesn't look good…
when he forces himself on woman…
but only when he is guarding her dignity.
Do you still want to do this, young lord?
Is this a confession…
or admission of guilt?
-What if it's neither?
-Then?
Can you marry me?
Are you still hungover?
I don't drink cheap arrack.
Defence personnel have a liquor quota.
And it has a certain standard.
I saw your standards yesterday.
I asked only because I truly like you.
Don't think it will be strange just
because you were our servant's daughter.
I'm a man…
and you are a beautiful girl.
That's all.
I'll be with you until my death.
A troublemaker like you
could end up in jail.
There are chances of you going to jail…
but I won't.
I promise you. Alright?
Don't pay. I've an account here.
If your answer is a "yes…"
then I'll pay from now on.
Sir, here's the money for two cups of tea.
This moment of mine
Has blossomed again
Let's wander in this beautiful night
There won't be anyone over there
May it be a beautiful time
Let me mesmerize you
And you can mesmerize me
In this beautiful night…
Oh, beauty that wanders
Let's embrace
We are meant for each other
Come to me, my love
Let's be happy
Are you alone?
Yes. What happened, Aunt?
Don't try to act too smart.
Where is Gopikrishnan
who dropped you off here?
I took pity on a servant's girl.
That's why I brought you here with me.
But don't take it as an
opportunity to flirt with our boy.
What's the matter, Aunt?
I heard you shouting.
Gopikrishnan, don't try to fool me.
I don't care what you think
but she can't stay here anymore.
So, we are sending her back home.
Her staying here is a
problem for you, right?
What do you mean, Gopi?
We don't get it.
If I don't keep my promise to her…
people will blame it on your upbringing.
Pack your bags.
Do you want me to book
the trunk call to our town?
Or will you do it yourself?
Go and pack your things.
If the heart is the ocean
Then the heartbeats are its waves
You are my life
Without you I'm incomplete
This birth is nothing without you
Don't be shy
Touch me right away
I have trust on you
Your wish is mine
You are my breath
You are my heartbeat
You are my life
This moment of life
Has blossomed again
Let's wander in this beautiful night
Let's wander in this night
Oh beauty that wanders
Let's embrace
We are meant for each other
Come to me, my love
Let's be happy
What will you have, sir?
-What do I order?
-Just order something.
-Get us two cups of tea.
-Okay.
Shall I go?
Just when my dreams
were about to take wings
the sun in my life was set forever.
Where do I go now?
I don't know.
I'LL BE AT THE SUBWAY
Why?
You can ask me anything except for that.
Sharada!
Listen to me!
That's all I want to know.
Why?
It's a secret.
A secret that's not
meant for Bombay city.
I'll tell you everything…
but not here. Somewhere far away.
I'll tell you in Persia.
Show me your palm.
I won't charge a lot of money.
-I don't like to get my palm read.
-Okay.
You can hide the lines on your palm.
But your destiny…
You can't hide it even if you wanted to.
What's your name?
Kurup.
Sudhakara Kurup.
Sharada, sorry.
I got a bit late.
-Hey, come on. Catch me.
-Stop.
Thank you. Hey, greet them.
How are you?
Boss!
Assalamu alaikum, sir.
Come, please.
What's wrong with you?
I've been noticing it for a while.
What is it?
What happened?
Nothing.
We are going back to India.
That's all.
What do you mean?
What will we do there?
Our house is still under construction.
We have to raise two children.
Expenses will only go up.
What do you plan to do for money?
I haven't done anything that
has put our family in distress.
I won't do that in the future either.
So, I'll take the decisions here.
WHEN THE VILLAINS COME TOGETHER
-Can I woo her?
-Don't waste your time.
-She looks pretty, right?
-That will be an understatement.
Then, tell me.
Where do you think she is from?
Her nose looks like…
I think she is from Punjab.
Or maybe she is from Gujarat.
You have to decide on one.
Yes, got it.
-She is from Bihar.
-How can you be so sure?
-Just look at how she walks.
-Really?
What are you doing?
You can ask her whatever you wanted to.
-What are you guys discussing?
-Leave me!
Please help me!
Let go of me.
-Here you go!
-You!
I will… I will not spare you.
Brother?
-Help!
-Bhaskar.
-Let her go.
-Let's decide on something.
Either I will spend
my time with this girl…
-or someone will die.
-Hey!
What are you doing?
Let her go!
-Bro!
-Hey! Keep quiet!
I'm Roni.
I am Minister Rajesh Pancholi's
brother-in-law.
I want to use the phone.
Step aside.
-Roni.
-Bro!
-How did you get him out?
-I called my brother-in-law for it.
Bro!
Why did you hire a taxi?
Where's our car?
You're right.
It does look like a taxi.
Why did you hire a taxi, bro?
Let's get going now.
I'll tell you in detail when we are home.
-No, tell me now.
-No.
Why will you not tell now?
We're not leaving until you tell me.
Come on, say it.
Only then we'll get the signal.
I mean, to leave.
Bro.
-Where are the bottles?
-There is one in each suitcase.
Really?
Say it quickly. You come with me.
We had to pledge the car
because of an emergency.
I can return it in a week.
-Roni.
-Yeah.
Listen carefully.
Until I get my car back
you won't come with me.
You may leave.
I'll take care of it.
I want this car.
Single price.
Ready cash.
Do you agree for it?
-What?
-What is this?
Give it to me.
Scotch Whiskey.
Go and call him.
He will send a state car to get you home.
-Bro!
-Yeah.
Bring the luggage over there.
Here's a beautiful journey
With a beautiful weather
I hope I don't get lost
Here's a beautiful journey
With a beautiful weather
I hope the dawn doesn't come soon
What's happening?
The movie Kati Patang
-used to be a stage play.
-Okay.
Don't you watch plays anymore?
I said, don't you watch plays anymore?
I don't have the time, bro.
That's true! How can he make time?
He is always in the arrack shop.
That's true!
Brother…
why don't you take him
to Persia once again?
At least he can make
some money over there.
I haven't recovered
from my first visit yet.
Neither have I.
Hear me out, Pankaj.
You don't have to go to
Persia to make money.
Then?
You can make money from here as well.
It's easy for you, brother.
But it's damn difficult
for people like us.
You can do it as well.
But you need to stick with sir.
Suppose you had a lot of money.
What will you do with it?
But now that you have asked…
I feel greedy.
An old secondhand Ambassador car.
I can drive it around and make a living.
-Pankaj.
-Yeah?
Don't settle for one.
You can buy ten new Ambassador cars.
I'll give you the money.
What do you think?
How is my mansion, Shyamu?
It looks like our sheikh's palace, sir.
Don't you want a house like this?
Yes, I do.
-But not such a big house.
-What's the deal, bro?
Relax.
We are about to do some mischief.
So it's good to begin
with a glass of drink.
Drink? Why not?
Bhaskar.
I have a life insurance policy in Persia.
-Why don't we claim it?
-We can.
Is it worth thousands?
It will be about eight lakh rupees.
Eight lakh rupees?
Why didn't you bring it with you?
That's okay.
Tell Sharada to
bring it tomorrow itself.
What the hell are you saying?
It can be claimed only after my death.
Brother, what's the plan?
I'll tell you.
-Bhaskar.
-Yes?
Who am I?
-Don't you know who you are?
-I didn't mean that!
What's my name?
Gopikrishnan.
What?
Gopikrishnan?
Shyamu, tell me.
What's my name?
Kurup… Sudhakara Kurup.
So if Gopikrishnan could
become Sudhakara Kurup…
then in a matter of no time…
Sudhakar can
be reborn as somebody else.
Am I right, Bhaskar?
Good idea!
It's very interesting.
But how can that happen?
It won't happen on its own.
It has to be done by us.
But if it goes as per our plan…
we can share
the eight lakh rupees among us.
Eight lakh rupees?
I'm ready to do anything
for eight lakh rupees.
You can't have
eight lakh rupees to yourself.
It's for all of us.
-At least I'll get a part of it.
-Now listen.
I want a body double.
A corpse of the same height and build.
We will get a body double.
We have to go to Kottayam.
Then we have to go to the medical college.
Pick up the thing.
-And come back here.
-What thing?
-Corpse.
-Corpse?
-Madhu.
-Who is Madhu?
Just explain it, Bhaskar.
We can do it with Madhu's help.
But it's going to cost you some money.
Go for it.
Don't worry about the expenses.
I'll take care of it.
People will say I'm showing off
because I'm a Gulf expat.
They won't say that.
Then they should say that.
Here.
Keep this inside, Mom.
-Note down the date.
-Okay.
We just got back from Kottayam.
Madhu said there was a corpse
in the medical college there.
Tell me what happened.
We reached late because of this fellow.
There's nothing left to say.
By the time we got there
they had already burnt the corpse.
But now I have a different plan in mind.
-We will--
-I'm not interested in your story.
Neither am I obliged to
split the money with you.
So if you can't do it, then get lost!
Stop playing around and
give those things to me.
Quiet!
It must be here.
Oh, no! Bhaskar, careful!
We are finished.
What have I done?
It's rotten.
-Bhaskar.
-Yes.
Shouldn't we cover the grave?
Go and cover it.
And have tea before you return.
-Bhaskar.
-Yes?
It's a woman.
Pankaj.
Stop the car.
I think a body has washed up.
-Let's check.
-Come along with me.
-Come on.
-Let's go.
-Slow down. You're getting old!
-Nonsense!
Pankaj, how can we
move the corpse from here?
-Excuse me, brother.
-Move.
When did it wash up?
Just now.
I was tempted by the
offer of eight lakh rupees.
But now I feel stuck
between the devil and the sea.
Do you think it's possible, Bhaskar?
Yes, it's possible.
It has happened before.
So let's not talk about that.
All of us have equal stakes in the money.
You can decide if you want it or not.
Kurup will go ahead with the plan.
I'll be right back.
-Sir, shall I take it?
-Wait a minute.
Here you go.
Would you like to have anything else, sir?
-No.
-Okay, sir.
I need to go home early.
Come on!
Hey, Kanhaiya!
I am here!
Hey!
-Do you have a matchbox?
-Yes.
Here it is, sir.
-Do you smoke?
-Yes, occasionally.
-Just cigarettes, right?
-Not that much.
Here.
I had a cigarette in my pocket.
-Here you go.
-No thanks, sir.
Hey, it's from Persia.
-Do you drink?
-Yes, at times.
Come on then, join me.
No, sir. I'm on duty right now.
What do you mean?
See! That's our car.
-We'll go, have a drink
-Sir.
-and come back. Done!
-Sir, I can't drink on duty.
-I swear nobody will come to know.
-No, thank you, sir.
-Come on, man!
-No, sir.
Have a few drinks with me.
It will lighten up your mood.
No, sir. It's okay.
-Sir, leave me alone. Sir, I'm working.
-Let's have a drink.
-You can go after having a drink.
-Brother, take your hands off me.
-Why can't you drink with me?
-Hey, take your hands off me.
I said let me go.
-Just have a drink with me!
-Take your hands off me!
You idiot! How could you do this to me!
-Let him go!
-You…
I will not spare you.
I will force you to have it.
-How could you not listen to me?
-Sorry.
You idiot!
Shut up or I'll pay back for all
that you have done since Persia.
Got it?
Will it hurt if you get a fresh corpse?
Help him get better and drop him home!
I'll be at Kumar's bar.
-Bro!
-Get lost!
Hey.
-What?
-What is eight divided by four?
That will be two.
Why?
So, what is eight divided by three?
Three?
Bhaskar, watch out!
-Pankaj.
-Yeah.
When we have someone with us
who is as tall and big as Kurup…
why should we hunt for another corpse?
You got scared?
Just think about it.
Eight lakh!
We three will get it.
Two-and-a-half lakh goes for one!
Two-and-a-half lakh goes for twice!
And the final call for
two-and-a-half lakh!
I'll take the balance 50,000 rupees
as a prize for my wicked mind.
IN PURSUIT OF HIM
Sir.
Sir, careful.
Step back.
-Johnny?
-Sir.
Collect the soil from here
and also the matchbox.
Sir.
It's difficult, sir.
The face is fully charred
but we know that it's a man.
So, are you doing a postmortem
on the spot?
Yes.
-Johnny?
-Sir.
Any other information? Evidence?
The car belongs to Sudhakar Kurup.
He came home three weeks ago.
Two of our men have gone to his place.
-In civil dress?
-Yes, sir.
-Check the area once again.
-Sure, sir.
He is going to be taken to the court.
Sir is here.
-Sir.
-What's happening here?
-Kurup used to stay here.
This is his relative's house, sir.
Sir, they seem convinced
that Kurup is dead.
But… when I passed by their
kitchen I could smell chicken curry.
Chicken curry!
Oh, no!
Why did you throw it?
Was the chicken curry too salty?
It is…
Sir, it had gone bad.
-Are you going to a wedding?
-No, sir.
I always dress up like this.
You go inside. The baby is crying.
He is with dad.
Is the man who died in
the fields, your relative?
Yes, sir.
Come here.
How did you find it out?
-It's Kurup's car, right?
-Yeah.
Kurup doesn't trust
anyone else with his car.
Oh, is that so?
If you think it's Sudhakara Kurup,
then, why didn't you come there?
-Is there any issue between both of you?
-Not at all.
Kurup is like a younger brother to me.
I can't bear to see him like that, sir.
So, what next?
We have to make
arrangements for the funeral.
Everyone has to be informed.
What about his relatives?
His father died a long time ago.
His mother is at a hospital in Pandalam.
His wife, Sharada, is in Persia.
She hasn't been informed yet.
Is that a washroom?
Yes, it's a washroom.
We don't use it anymore.
Nobody comes here anymore, sir.
What is it, sir?
Didn't I tell you that we
don't use it anymore?
Step aside.
Don't you go to a barbershop, Bhaskar?
Or do you like to set your hair on fire?
To heck with you!
It's right here.
Fold your sleeves.
No, sir.
It looks better this way.
There's a lot of powder on your face.
So you can't look any better.
Fold it.
Come on!
Fold it up.
Come on, do it.
What happened?
It happened while I was warming
myself up by the fire this morning.
This happened at the
same time as well, right?
-Johnny?
-Sir.
Something was burnt in here.
Find out what it is.
Send the burnt hair and
matchsticks to the forensic lab.
Yes, sir.
And this fellow…
Let's take him with us.
Come on, Bhaskar.
Give me something to eat, sir.
I have been here for a while now.
-Johnny?
-Sir?
Bhaskar loves chicken, right?
-Buy a chicken biryani for him.
-Okay, sir.
Go.
Sir, pass the water.
Water!
-Johnny?
-Sir?
Don't give him water for two days.
Okay, sir.
But…
Sir.
Go ahead.
Sudhakara Kurup was murdered.
I killed him.
Kurup took me to Persia a few years ago.
It was of no use.
I ran several errands
for him for two years.
Then he sent me back
without paying a penny.
We have been at odds ever since.
Whenever I asked for my money…
he would give excuses.
Then he would buy me a
drink and send me home.
I had been waiting for my chance.
So, when I got hold of him…
Sir, I was drunk at that time.
Give me some water.
I didn't mean to kill him.
But I don't regret it either.
DEPUTY SUPERINTENDENT OF POLICE
CHENGANNUR
Sir, here is the detailed
report on Sudhakara Kurup.
-Johnny?
-Sir.
What do you think?
Did Bhaskar kill Sudhakara Kurup?
Sir, Bhaskar is a compulsive liar.
Did he have a strong motive for murder?
I don't know, sir.
But why should he take
the blame for murder, sir?
This is my hunch.
There's something fishy about this case.
-You do one thing.
-Sir.
Check the latest missing cases.
-Okay, sir.
-Let's see.
-What's his name?
-Sir, his name is Charlie.
He is a representative.
He has been missing for three days.
-So, has it been three days?
-Yes, sir.
-Any news about him?
-We are investigating.
He told us that he would
return the same night.
He wanted to take her to
the Church feast.
This is his wife.
We went to the police when
he didn't return for two days.
Can Charlie drive?
No, sir. Why?
It's nothing.
There was an incident in Cheriyanaad.
A car accident.
We recovered a body from the car.
The man hasn't been identified yet.
We came to check if the two
cases are somehow related.
-Johnny?
-Sir.
This is his photo.
This isn't him, sir.
I can understand what you are feeling.
This is just a part of our investigation.
We found this on that body.
Does it belong to Charlie?
I don't know, sir.
Nancy. My child!
-May I?
-Sir, it's not possible. He can't drive.
I think she is confused.
It can't be Charlie.
I apologize for bothering you.
In some cases people are misidentified.
That's why I wanted to check.
Does this belong to Charlie?
This belongs to my husband, sir.
This belonged to my husband.
My child and I have
no one in this world, sir.
My child has been orphaned.
Stop hitting me, sir.
Please stop it.
Sir, I'll tell you everything.
That's enough.
I'll take the balance 50,000 rupees…
as a prize for my wicked mind.
Bhaskar.
My boss…
How can we do that to him?
You are a very smart guy!
You seem to be a good man.
-Pankaj!
-Yeah.
Open the boot of the car.
Somebody needs a ride.
Pull the car over there.
-Are you headed for Alappuzha?
-Yeah.
Can I get a ride?
Three buses passed without stopping.
Shyamu, open the door for this fellow.
-Come on.
-Goodbye, bro.
Okay.
Thank you, brother.
Pankaj, is that you?
Charlie?
-What are you doing here?
-I'm back in town now.
Nancy is pregnant.
Oh.
Today is our wedding anniversary.
I promised to take her to
the Church fest.
That's why I started at night itself.
Bhaskar?
I know this young man.
That makes everything so easy.
-You should have a drink with us.
-Oh, no, bro.
I told you I have to take
my wife to the church.
Pankaj!
Pankaj.
-Alappuzha is straight ahead, right?
-Yes.
We have to go to Pallana
to pick someone up.
-Then we will go to Alappuzha.
-Alright.
Whether it's a feast or a festival,
this is a must to have a good time.
Take it easy.
-Have a drink.
-No, brother.
-My wife is pregnant. It makes her sick.
-Hey.
It's the only joy in life.
Come on.
No. Let it be.
Pankaj!
Stop the car.
I don't feel comfortable
sitting here anymore.
No drinks on a feast day!
What kind of a man are you?
-Have a drink. Come on!
-No!
Hey, have one.
Have it.
It tastes foul.
Alcohols do taste foul.
Just drink it!
No, brother.
Come on, have it.
No. Let it be.
Have it!
Drink!
Hold him down!
-How dare you turn down a drink?
-Bro.
Pankaj!
How dare you spit in the car!
Hold him tight!
Have it.
Move him here.
Stop right here.
KUTTANANDAN BAR
I told you to take him home.
We got what you asked for.
-Where did you find it?
-We just killed him.
About an hour ago, right?
Get the car.
We can't go to my house.
Let's go to your place.
Hurry up!
Take it to the washroom at the back.
Shyamu, help them.
Are you doing it in here?
We will burn the face now.
The body can be burned somewhere else.
That's okay.
Let me set you on fire.
Come on, fire up!
Bhaskar!
Careful.
Hurry up!
So, you will do anything for money.
-Right?
-No, sir.
We couldn't turn down the
offer of eight lakh rupees.
-Eight lakh?
-Yeah.
Can we ever make so
much money in our lifetime?
It's true, sir.
He told me to dream of ten
Ambassador cars parked on my porch.
That's how Kurup lured us.
What was your share?
Sir…
we were promised two lakh rupees each.
Two lakh!
That means two lakh
rupees for Sudhakara Kurup.
Do you know how much Kurup
and his wife earn in Gulf?
80,000 rupees a month!
The same guy committed a murder…
for two lakh rupees.
Forget about that.
-Will he do it for eight lakh, Johnny?
-No, sir.
So, money was not the only
motive behind the murder.
When did you last see Kurup, Bhaskar?
In the paddy field that night.
And you?
Ernakulam, sir.
Then he asked me to
board a bus to Chavakkad.
Who else was with you?
That day…
Kurup and…
Pankaj were there with me.
I know you are working hard.
But how can I convince our superiors?
Now that we have issued a
lookout circular for Kurup across India,
they have warned of
cutting my salary to pay it off.
In fact, I can put up with that.
What really annoys me are the
reporters and their relentless questions.
So, what's the status
of the investigation?
Can we nab Sudhakara Kurup
before the end of this century?
Sir, cigarette.
I need a blade.
I'll get it for you, sir.
Can I ask you something?
It's the same question.
If you were in Kurup's place,
what will you do after the murder?
I'll leave the country
if I think I'll be caught.
-But Kurup hasn't left the country yet.
-Yes.
He can't travel using his passport.
Then, how can he flee the country?
He can use a fake passport.
It's easy for him to get one.
As per Bhaskar's statement,
Kurup revealed his plan
to Ponnachan, Sabu and Bhaskar
on the same day he arrived.
Which means the story
about Sudhakara Kurup's death
was conceived not
in Kerala but in Persia.
Kurup came home in a hurry without
bothering to make a fake passport.
So, the story of his death was
created not only for the people here
but also for his friends
outside the country.
-What do you mean?
-Sir…
somebody in Persia should
believe that Kurup is dead.
Or should feel compelled to believe in it.
Sir.
Sudhakara Kurup has
been seen in Alankrita Lodge.
-Who gave the tip-off?
-Sir, one of the hotel staff called.
Das?
Sir?
Deal with him before
he is taken to the court.
Sir, here is the blade.
Kurup is in there, sir.
-Room number 122.
-Okay.
-Hey, break it down.
-Sir.
Move.
Sir, he is not here.
-Check downstairs. Quick!
-Yes, sir.
He has left by the backyard.
Let's go and check there.
Sir, over there.
Perazhi Transport Service.
18th point.
Mannar.
Sir.
We couldn't find him, sir.
He got away.
Kurup has an acquaintance in Mannar.
It could be a relative or a friend.
-Find out who it is.
-Yes, sir.
-Make it quick! Right now.
-Okay, sir!
Tell me something.
Radhakrishnan brought
Sudhakara Kurup to your home.
Where did he go from here?
I don't like to repeat myself.
Maybe it's because of my age.
Anyway, I don't like it at all.
But I'll still tell you…
for the last time.
I don't know.
So, won't you speak the truth?
Smart fellow!
You figured it out yourself.
Gopal Kurup will not speak about it.
Nobody can make him do that.
Good!
I like your confidence.
Listen.
I'll be 75 in a month's time.
Do you want to use third degree
methods on an old man?
You have more to lose than I do.
Don't you want to be promoted as SP?
If you bully me and
something happens to me
then you will be in big trouble.
Do you want that?
SP!
Sounds good!
When I joined the police force…
I wanted to bag the SI post.
And I got it!
I got more than what I wished for.
So I'm not afraid of anybody.
If you are afraid of third-degree methods,
then we can find another way.
-Doesn't one come before three, Johnny?
-Yes, sir.
Then let's start from one.
Don't compel him. You know how it is.
-You can start.
-Okay.
Kurup?
Can you hear me?
When did you last see Sudhakara Kurup?
Where will you go now?
I'll go to Uncle Vijay's house in Bhopal.
And then…
But I'm sure about one thing.
From now on, I decide who will see me.
I don't care if it's police…
or politician.
I have only two questions for you.
Where did he go? And when?
It has been four days now.
He left for Malini's house in Bombay.
Don't you know it's a crime
to give shelter to a criminal?
Yes, we know that, sir.
In fact, we had decided that
we will turn him out if he came.
But after all… he is our boy.
I want to see the bedroom that he used.
-Is either of you diabetic?
-No, sir.
This is a prescription for insulin.
That must be Gopi's.
-You wait here.
-Okay.
-Hello. Police.
-Sir.
-Where is this from?
-Just a minute, bro.
Sir, this is prescribed from ward C.
Go straight and take left.
Are you sure it was him?
Yes, sir.
It's the same guy.
Do you remember how tall he was?
He wasn't as tall as you, sir.
This man is more than six feet tall.
You are mistaken.
Oh! Here it is.
Thank you.
WANTED
KURUP
Sir.
These are letters from all the people
who claim to have
seen Sudhakara Kurup.
You can throw out the anonymous letters.
I've done that, sir.
These are the remaining ones.
Frankly speaking…
I don't know what to believe
and what not to believe.
I can't tell the difference.
P. KRISHNADAS
If there is truth in any of these,
it will find us eventually.
What is it, sir?
This letter not only mentions Kurup.
It also refers to someone he met.
Issac.
He's up there.
Alright, thank you.
Bye.
Good evening, Mr. Issac.
How are you?
I'm Krishnadas from down south.
Kerala Police.
I was checking some
files from a few years ago.
I found something that
I could use to take you with me.
I'm ready to forget that
but on one condition.
You have to forget Kurup.
Now you will talk.
And I will listen.
I know where Kurup is.
His whereabouts are in here.
Sharma?
Take him!
Come on, let's go.
Come on, take him with you.
-Let's go.
-What are you saying?
We leave a trail on every path we take.
No crime can conceal it.
Not everyone who arrives
at a crime scene can detect it.
But the one who searches for it,
will certainly find that trail.
-Are these your regular visitors?
-Yes, sir.
Johnny?
-What happened, sir?
-Royal Viking Line.
He plans to leave the country on a ship.
This is our last chance.
We should get him before he gets away.
-Should we inform the local police?
-Yes, we should.
Stop!
-Wait.
-Sir.
Do you see this man?
He is Kurup.
He is a dangerous criminal
with several cases against him.
Look at it carefully.
Search for him in every nook and corner.
He could be here in disguise.
Alright? You can go now.
-Johnny!
-Go and catch him!
Go!
-Don't let him run!
-Catch him! Move!
-Go! Catch him!
-Come on! Catch him!
Police! We need to search
the ship for a suspect.
Alright.
Go and check over there.
-Check properly.
-You rascal!
-Get him!
-Sir, we got him.
Sir, I'm not Kurup.
Believe me. I am not Kurup.
Who the hell are you?
I'm Hari Kumar from Goa.
This is how I make a living.
-Sir, then what about Kurup?
-I have a sermon in South Africa.
-Take him away.
-Sir.
Come on, you dog.
-Come.
-Take him away.
-Thank you, sir.
-Alright.
-Thank you.
Sir?
-Their driver is missing.
-Sir.
Sir, I'm a saint, a Godman.
Please let me go, sir.
-Really?
-Let me go.
-Am I a fool?
-Let me go, sir.
Keep quiet!
We stood there and watched as
the Royal Viking Line sailed away.
A lot more had happened which
neither did I saw nor others knew about.
More pieces had to come
together to know the full story.
Moreover, it is he who needs
to tell us about.
Can I get two cups of tea?
Brother?
Can I get a biscuit?
-How much do you want?
-Give me a packet of it.
I want one as well.
-Give me a cup of tea.
-Give me a cup of coffee.
-I don't want to go.
-I don't want to hear your excuses.
You ought to listen to me.
I don't want to join air force.
Will you just walk in there?
Will you do well at least this time?
I promise I'll make it big, Uncle.
What happened, GK?
This place suffocates me.
I'm getting out. You go back to sleep.
Don't be stupid, man.
They will catch you
no matter where you go.
-That's why I'm still here.
-Damn it!
If I were in my village, I would
have had Mangal's toddy,
then smoked a cigarette and relaxed.
But I am stuck here.
Are you allowed to go out at night?
What?
I sneak out.
One cigarette, bro.
Hey, let's name it
Indie Rock Fusion Festival.
-How is it?
-It's awesome!
Brother?
Where can I get a bottle of rum?
You can't get it at this time.
Can we get one?
-It's difficult to get one now.
-No, you won't get it.
-Is there any place I could get one now?
-Now…
Yes, you can get it from that building.
-From the air force camp?
-Yeah.
That's where I'm coming from.
Smart guy!
So, you jumped out of
the sea to catch a fish?
There is nothing that you
can't find on your campus.
We pay threefold the price
to buy booze from there.
-Threefold?
-Yeah.
Threefold!
Who's that?
Brother, can I get some rum?
-Rum?
-Yeah.
-How much?
-I would need…
-two bottles of it.
-Really?
Yes.
-You?
-Mr. Murthy!
-Mr. Murthy.
-What?
-I need three bottles today.
-Okay.
GK, what happened?
There are bugs in the air force.
-Bedbugs!
-Oh!
Hey, GK.
Here it is.
This isn't enough to
satisfy MCC's thirst.
-Take it.
-Tell me when you need more.
Okay.
But I will need a small profit out of it.
-You can resell your share.
-Okay.
Here you go.
My dear Gopikrishnan, you
will turn me into a full-time crook.
-You are a crook already!
-Get lost!
I have lost my peace of mind.
It used to take four months
for me to sell so much booze.
But you sold it in just three weeks.
Gopikrishna, if you carry on
selling the booze
then I might have to start brewing
arrack for the officers here.
If you plan to brew arrack
then you can count me in.
But I need a commission fee.
Speaking of a commission fee…
-What is this?
-It's a superb pair of boots!
Why should only the
air force guys wear it?
Size eight.
It will fit everyone and not
just the air force guys.
Here's the money.
-Alright.
-That's great.
That's not the only thing.
-I have found other things too.
-Really?
Like what?
I'll tell you later.
Sir.
I came here so that I can succeed in life.
Sooner or later, I will.
I have a surprise for you in Bombay.
I had just started living my dream
when that posting struck me
like a bolt of lightning.
Madras gave me new hopes
to go to Bombay,
the city of the Marathas.
So… you are Gopikrishnan from Madras!
Yes, sir.
It's a little hot in here.
Shall we go out and talk?
Here, take this. Come.
-I hope everything is in order.
-Yes, sir.
-Gopikrishnan?
-Sir.
What are you staring at?
Just do your job.
Yes, sir.
-Mr. Gopikrishnan?
-Sir.
If you thought that a store assistant
can sit back and relax in the store,
then, you got it wrong.
It doesn't work like that.
There…
That's the inventory register. Take it!
Open it up.
That's your goods received note.
You must record every
entry in the register.
Including rack numbers.
It's four o'clock now.
And I want it by seven.
If you get even one entry wrong…
I don't have to tell you anything, right?
And before you start,
I want your haircut done.
-Mr. Gopikrishnan?
-Sir.
Welcome to the real world of pain!
Didn't Dominique mention about a surprise?
I'm the surprise.
Dismissed!
I prayed to God
that not even my enemies
should be given a surprise like this.
But no God listens to the
prayers of an atheist like me!
As soon as I opened that
door, I proved myself wrong.
Mastan…
Muthaliyar and Karim Lala ruled
over Bombay city.
Now it's our Bombay as well.
That's me and my new-found friend.
Issac!
The further limit is you
It has been found
-And spun my dreams there
-Keep this over there.
No matter what
Difficulty may come
I will look into it
We will win
Tomorrow will
Bring a change in our lives
The war is over.
Congratulations, GK.
There is a new bounty.
A Singapore consignment.
Shall I go ahead with it?
What happened, GK?
We have been taking
commissions until now.
Let's play a new game.
You will get your commission from me.
But not as the tenth man
in a match of 11 players.
You will be the first
man of your match.
Do you see this?
This is our trump card.
What is so special about it?
What is the connection between
winning a war and a commission?
Our country has bought weapons
worth crores for the sake of war.
Now that the war is over,
they will be stashed away.
Their sorting and accounting is…
more or less my responsibility.
If you try hard, I'm
sure we can find buyers.
Right?
I was used to preying on small fish.
Issac gave me the boat and
nets to hunt for giant sharks.
My first catch turned out to be this man.
An underworld arms dealer
called Leo Ragnor.
Thanks a million, Issac!
Keep them over here.
Make it quick.
Only eight more boxes, after that done.
-What are you doing here?
-Sir, these are the rejected goods.
-So I'm sending them back.
-Do you have the documents?
-Yes, sir, it's in the jeep.
-Show them to me.
Alright.
-Carry on.
-Thank you, sir.
Goodnight, sir.
That was well played!
Let me know if you
are interested to join us.
Yeah, let me get my termination letter.
-Hope that's not too far.
-Hey, Leo, we will lose all our business.
Guys, hurry up.
Where is the stock in here?
How many times have I
told you to verify them?
-Did you do it?
-Sir, all stock--
Stop giving stories!
Full inventory with details.
I want it in a week. Is that clear?
Sir, one week is very less time.
Shut up!
This is the Indian Air force.
This uniform demands honesty and respect.
And it comes with
integrity and discipline.
This is not a place for losers and liars.
Do you get me?
-Yes, sir.
-Get out!
-What do I order?
-Just order something.
I'm going home tomorrow.
I got sick leave… for a month.
Place it properly.
-We are here for an investigation.
-Tell me.
-Are you related to Gopikrishnan Kurup?
-I'm his father.
Gopikrishnan?
He is no more, sir.
He was very ill when he came here.
I'll go and check with the neighbors.
-You stay right here, okay?
-Yes.
Excuse me.
Did you hear about your
neighbor Gopikrishnan's death?
We were in Bhopal.
We came as soon as we got the news.
That's a lie, sir.
I met him at the field yesterday.
He was cutting the leaves.
Keep your voice down or he will hear you.
By the way, how did
you persuade your father?
Doesn't every God have a weak
spot that he is afraid of?
What exactly do you gain
from your death certificate?
I'm done with the air force.
Once they get this certificate,
they won't come looking for me.
-Shall we go?
-Yeah.
-Alright, goodbye.
-See you.
I WILL BE AT THE SUBWAY
ARYA SAMAJ TEMPLE, BOMBAY
Leo!
That's the guy I told you about.
Hold this.
-Hello, my friend.
-How are you?
Welcome to the city of black gold!
Thank you.
-My wife, Sharada.
-Hi!
The people of my village envied me.
But I don't blame them for it.
-It's because I held the title of
-Good morning.
Progress Assistant in
an oil company in Persia.
-Greetings.
-And I earned a five-digit salary.
-Good morning, Daisy.
-But the price that I had set
for myself was much greater than that.
Here, take him. I'll be right back.
-Hi, Leo.
-Hey.
What's new?
-Remember the prince I told you about?
-Yeah.
That's the guy.
-How is she?
-Very nice.
This is Walid.
He was one of the
richest princes of Persia.
It took me two-and-a-half
years to reach out to him.
Come on! Do it!
-No brakes!
-What?
No brakes!
-Try again.
-No brakes!
-Drive off-road! Here!
-No!
The car may overturn.
There is only one way now.
You should jump at the count of three.
One…
two… three!
Three! Jump!
Jump!
Obedient!
The king wants me
to stay out of business.
I know I'm young.
But I'm not so naive
when it comes to business.
Everyone is trying their luck.
Why should I stay away?
The thing is that Walid liked me a lot.
Being the prince's sidekick means…
being as powerful as our chief minister.
This is the best translation
I can give while I catch my breath.
Thank you.
Greet him, dear.
Boss!
-Assalamu alaikum, sir.
-Good to see you.
-I am fine. Please sit inside.
-Thank you.
Come.
Will you please manage?
Dad will be right back, son.
Shyamu, serve these to the
ones sitting outside.
I will call you if I need something.
Walid entrusted me with a job that day.
The job of a true Satan.
I'm not that great…
to turn down that offer.
Yes, boss.
-Shyamu.
-Sir?
Give me a number.
Number?
Eight.
Noushad, I need two
tickets to Kerala next month.
-Date of travel, sir?
-On the fourth.
-Alright.
-It's for Shyamu and me.
Okay, sir.
-What about your return?
-Return…
-Only Shyamu needs a return ticket.
-Okay, sir.
I'll inform the date later.
-First class, okay?
-Sure, sir.
Alright.
What's this?
Haven't you read it?
That's why I want to know.
Don't raise your voice.
I took a life insurance. Any problem?
Why do you need life insurance now?
All of us have to die someday, right?
Don't think too much about it.
I have a life insurance policy in Persia.
Why don't we claim it?
Why not?
I want a body double.
A corpse of the same height and build.
So if Gopikrishnan could
become Sudhakara Kurup…
then in no time…
Sudhakara Kurup will be
reborn as somebody else.
Are you doing it in here?
We will burn the face now.
The body can be burned somewhere else.
Your return ticket is booked
for the tenth of next month.
-Let me see if I can prepone it.
-Okay, sir.
Sir?
Don't leave your house
until the matter clears up.
Okay, sir.
Sir, here is the blade.
Kurup is in there, sir.
-Room number 122.
-Okay.
Brother?
-Hey, break it down.
-Sir.
-Move.
Sir, he is not here.
-Check downstairs. Quick!
-Yes, sir.
-Kurup has an acquaintance in Mannar.
-Sir.
It could be a relative or a friend.
-Find out who it is.
-Yes, sir.
-Make it quick! Right now.
-Sure, sir!
POLICE
Let's go.
Sir, you are still here.
You must have to spend a lot
of money to call the police.
Keep this with you.
-Hello
-Hello, is this Krishnadas sir's office?
-Yes.
-Is sir there?
Who is calling?
This is from the Postal Department.
Is sir there?
No.
-When can I talk to him?
-I don't know.
It's an urgent matter.
Can you tell me when he will be back?
I told you I don't know.
Sir is in Bhopal now.
Really? What's he doing there, sir?
He went to nab Sudhakara Kurup.
Okay, sir.
I'll hang up.
Hello?
I'll inform sir when he is back.
What's your name?
Tell him Kurup called from Bhopal.
-Who?
-Kurup.
Sudhakara Kurup.
To hell with Sudhakara Kurup!
Hang down, you idiot!
Bhopal!
-Hey.
-Yeah.
Gopikrishnan's news
has reached Bhopal as well.
You should ask him to leave.
Gopi!
-He is not in here.
-He has already left with his things.
Please keep this.
-Look at the rates of the--
-Greetings.
Aunt.
Why did you come here?
The police are looking for you.
Do you want to drag us into it?
You were always reckless and brash.
Now look where you ended up.
Do you have the guts
to kill someone, Gopi?
Do you think I will do such a thing?
Listen to me.
-Aunt.
-Yes.
You have to stop reading
the newspaper to know the truth.
It's true that I told them to
get a corpse from the mortuary.
But I didn't tell them to kill anybody.
Neither did I kill anyone.
But now…
everybody thinks that I'm
the mastermind behind it.
What about Sharada?
She is back home.
Why don't you call Vijay in Bhopal?
-Do you have his number?
-No, thanks.
-That's where I'm coming from.
-What happened?
I left before they kicked me out.
What will you do now?
I won't bother you.
I haven't eaten anything for days.
Can I stay at your place for one day?
Just one day!
Come.
Have some more rice.
Come and embrace me
Don't delay now
Let's make this cold night
Into a steamy one
The twinkling stars…
He must have gone to Malini's house
in Bombay.
To distant lands unknown
Bye, Aunt.
These times never end
But besiege like darkness
I am not in my limits
Curbing myself
Is a difficult thing to do
Oh, my beloved
What kind of love is this?
It's full of peace and pain
It's full of different aspects
I am full of restlessness
Tell me what I should do now
It's full of peace and pain
It's full of different aspects
I am full of restlessness
Tell me what I should do now
Yes.
Kurup called me yesterday.
He is in Bombay now.
He wants me to help him meet Sharada.
What is it, sir?
Is Kurup foolish enough to trust you?
Where will Kurup meet Sharada?
In jail?
Come and embrace me
Don't delay anymore
Let's make this cold night
Into a steamy one
Until the twinkling stars appear
To distant lands unknown
The difficult times
Hey 210, is that Kurup?
No, it's that guy who helps the old lady.
The storm doesn't end but
We still have some hope
The times will change
For me as well
What kind of love is this?
It's full of peace and pain
It's full of different aspects
I am full of restlessness
Tell me what I should do now
It's full of peace and pain
It's full of different aspects
I am full of restlessness
Tell me what I should do now
I'll inform you as soon as Leo calls me.
What are you staring at? Get out!
Leo chose a country for me to get away.
And he gave the tickets to Issac.
But before I could reach there,
-the police arrived on my trail.
-Hey, leave me.
Brother, give me a cup of tea.
Here you go.
-What happened, brother?
-Hey, Shakil.
He is our aide.
There isn't a problem.
Okay, brother.
I don't know where I should go from here.
It's because Krishnadas
knows where to find me.
So from now, the police won't chase Kurup.
Instead Kurup will chase the police.
Let's go.
-Brother, follow that vehicle.
-Okay.
Beneath the blue sea
Traversing the deep shore
Ahead of the time
You will go ahead
He is like a submarine
A submarine
In the deep sea where the waves sway
This journey seems unending
The shore looks a long way away
Stop the car! Get out of the car.
All clear.
-Stop!
-Explain it to them.
Attention, everyone.
This is Kurup.
Look at the sketch carefully.
You can leave now.
POLICE
Check over there.
-I will check here.
-Yes, sir.
Over there.
Ahead of time
You need to pass it
He is like a submarine
A submarine!
-Go and check there.
-Okay, sir.
-Oh, no!
-Stop right there!
Catch him!
Sir.
The driver is missing.
When that car went up in flames
everybody thought it was a fool's
plan to swipe eight lakh rupees.
But…
was that the truth?
I didn't ask for coffee.
What's my new name?
Alexander.
The fourth son of the sultan's
third wife had realized that
his status was no better
than that of a corpse.
So, Walid set out to become
as strong as the sultan himself.
The black gold aka crude oil!
That was Walid's investment.
My job was to smuggle it
without the sultan's knowledge.
That means my life itself…
was my investment.
And I decided to risk
my life for the same.
Walid kept receiving
double the market price.
But what about me?
I got the mere bones that he threw at me.
Thank you.
But boss, my next deal…
is very big.
Three million US dollar.
But… risk is…
also very big.
When was the last time you saw
one of the royals in jail?
-So, the risk is only yours.
-He was right.
Not a single person of the royal
bloodline had ever gone to jail.
Risk!
It was entirely mine.
So, I decided to take
a risk for the last time.
I swiped three million US dollars
from the sultan.
However… I didn't take the
money to Walid this time.
Shyamu.
We shouldn't insist on getting
only frozen bodies from the morgue.
If they look hard…
they can find it otherwise.
That can be done, sir.
But we need the right men for the job.
That's our guy.
He will do anything for his friends.
But if he loses it, he
will not spare you as well.
He'll be of use to us.
So, how do we persuade
him to kill someone?
I think I know that.
We can't go to my place.
Let's go to your place.
Hurry up!
The insurance of eight lakh
rupees was just a precursor
to make Walid believe of my death.
-Give me a number.
-Number?
Eight.
The distance between the
three million US dollars and me is
is as much as the sea and this ship.
Kurup's character can now come to an end.
The future belongs to Alexander.
Charlie had to sacrifice his life for it.
But in my world…
if someone matters to me…
then that's myself.
Alexander!
Sudhakara Kurup should remain a fugitive.
The punishment that
he is worthy of…
isn't yet written down
in our legal system.
He deserves a sentence…
that is greater than all the judgments.
-Hello, captain speaking.
-Can I speak to Walid?
It's very sad that you
haven't had him yet.
I guess we are looking
for the same person.
I will now make sure he
suffers every inch to death.
-Yeah.
-Walid.
The rat you are looking
for is on your ship.
-He will need help.
-Okay, thank you.
I'll take good care of him.
Alexander!
Sudhakara Kurup will remain a fugitive.
If some day…
Charlie's son wants to
avenge his father's death
tell him that
a police officer did
that a long time ago.
Sir, you forgot this.
WHERE IS KURUP?
DOPPELGANGER IN HARIDWAR
Police leave for Las Vegas
to look for Kurup.
It is related to a murder that
happened in 1948.
Gabriel, we have spotted Alexander.
He is coming out on the
streets with two bodyguards.
Do you see him?
Can you see him, Gabriel? Over.
I got him, over.
Take as many pictures as possible.
Take close-ups as well. Over!
Yeah.
Gabriel, can you hear me?
Gabriel, can you please respond?