A gangster, that's what you are!
A gangster!
You think my fear of scandal
will keep you safe?
You think I'll swallow my pride?
Wrong!
You'll return the money you stole
so ignobly!
You can stare!
Do I look like a victim?
I won't be intimidated!
If you don't return my money
in five minutes, I'll call the police!
Gangsters like you must be kept
from doing harm!
You don't frighten me!
No you don't!
What's on your mind?
A pity!
Jérôme ...
Tidy up.
- Straight left?
- Right uppercut.
- Counter?
- Check!
Mademoiselle is improving.
Put him in a taxi
and send him home.
His umbrella.
Right.
Come on!
Hello? ...
Catherine here.
Any news?
The bachelor flat, yes.
Address?
4 rue Lauriston?
Third floor right.
Wait, let me write it down.
Yes, yes ...
I'm listening.
The man? ...
Yes.
And the woman.
Very good.
Are there servants in the flat?
How many?
Two?
Can they be bought?
Together or separately?
How much for the pair?
Oh, that's nothing ...
Naturally.
Thank you.
All done?
Yes, Mademoiselle.
But, if Mademoiselle permits me,
the next time a creature like that
shows up, I'll take care of him.
But why?
I won't have Mademoiselle
risk her life unnecessarily.
No drama!
First, I'm not risking my life.
Second, I'm old enough to take care
of myself, aren't I?
I won't have you run
unnecessary risks!
It pains me!
You may act the grown lady,
but to me you're still a little girl!
There, there, nursie dear!
Don't go soft on me!
Risks are fun!
It's fun to be scared!
Speaking of which, tonight --
- Where's the invitation?
- I have it.
What's the old dear's name?
Mme d'Ambroisie
requests the pleasure ...
I've gotten hired as a waiter.
The staff has been informed.
Don't lose sight of me, waiter.
- Yes, Mademoiselle.
- And be extremely prudent.
As usual, Mademoiselle.
Does Mademoiselle think that tonight
we'll have a chance to ...
I think so!
The young woman
with the emeralds.
Yes, I saw.
- Where is she?
- By the table.
- Well?
- Very interesting.
- And the man with her?
- I have his details.
Thanks, Jérôme.
- Take care of the rest.
- Of course.
Isn't it too risky?
No. And it's worth it!
A kiss -- a caress --
a rare opportunity!
- Are you sure?
- Trust me.
This is the real thing.
Can you hesitate?
- No.
- Well, then!
Come!
The lady with the emeralds
is worth a followup.
- Get her address.
- I have it.
17 rue Tristan.
And the man's?
78 rue Bois-le-Vent.
Got it, thanks.
- May I see you Thursday, my place?
- I'm married, Jacques!
Thursday is a no-husband day!
You idiot!
But we must -- hello! --
we must love each other, Gisèle.
Love is written in your hand.
Just read between the lines.
- And it's in my cards. So ...
- You rush me, Jacques!
Must we wait until you're a widow
and I married to love each other?
You don't love me, Jacques.
I love you and I desire you.
Let's enjoy the coincidence!
Jacques, you're not serious!
Lucky for us.
May heaven hear you!
- Are you looking for someone?
- My dear, it's too dreadful!
- All my jewels! Gone!
- It can't be!
At least you're wearing
some of them.
These are false!
I was afraid to wear the real ones.
My husband was right --
I invite such people!
- Oh, my dear Alice --
- No, Catherine ...
Do you suspect anyone?
Too many!
I don't know which to choose!
What are you going to do?
I'm a woman of action.
I've already done it!
Look.
Police!
Hands up!
Nobody leave!
- What did he say?
- He said, "Hands up!"
"Nobody leave!"
- So, my place, Thursday?
- No.
- 3:00?
- 6 rue de l'Evêché?
- No.
- 4th floor?
- First door left?
- No.
Brrrng!
There you are.
In thought.
I saw it in your eyes.
Right now,
you're at my place.
Your heart and soul
are at my place.
Not your body --
but that's a detail.
- Hands up!
- Sorry.
Thursday, 3:00, 6 rue de l'Evêché,
5th floor, first door left?
Forward!
You said 4th floor.
You!
Hands up!
What a lovely party.
- Hello, Gisèle.
- Hello, Jacques.
It's 4:00.
You're an hour late.
- What do you mean?
- But you're here!
It's 3:00!
To arrive on time to a lovers' meeting
is to arrive late.
This isn't a lovers' meeting.
It's a friends' meeting.
Then let's make ...
friendship.
What a curious place you have.
Flowers ... ivy ...
cacti ...
- A real hothouse!
- You are its rarest, frailest flower!
- You live in a garden.
- And you wear one.
Remove that flowerbed
you're using as a hat.
I only came to prove I wasn't
afraid of you.
Why do you push me away
if you're not afraid?
I shouldn't have come. ...
What if my husband turned up?
I'd say, "No need to knock --
I detest violence!"
I think he followed me.
Let me look --
He has no right to follow you!
The wife must follow her husband.
Are you brave? Courageous?
Then don't fear a kiss,
a kiss is not a catastrophe!
The one thing I fear is love.
Poor little thing!
I will protect you from love.
Shelter in my arms.
There, you're safe.
If love tries anything,
it'll have me to answer to.
- Did you hear that?
- Yes, it's 3:30.
- The doorbell!
- Your hearing!
- Listen!
- You're right, it's the doorbell.
- It's my husband, I know his ring.
- But it's my doorbell.
- Where are the back stairs?
- I won't let you sneak out like that!
You'll leave as you came,
by the front door!
The back stairs, or I'll jump
out the window!
There are no back stairs,
it's a studio in an old house.
- What can we do?
- Wait.
He'll get tired of ringing
and go away.
Is he playing scales?
- What are you doing?
- Letting Pierre in.
- Then I'll hit him.
- Kill my husband?!
I'll just knock him out.
While he's KO,
you escape.
- Do you know your strength?
- Of course I do!
Draw the curtains
so he doesn't see me.
- Just a second!
- You'll hit my husband!
- I'm a dreadful woman!
- I adore you!
Now, here we go!
Oh, heavens ...
- What?
- It's a woman.
- Who?
- I don't know.
I hope I've not killed her.
No, she's breathing.
- And she's pretty.
- What?
Not as pretty as all that.
Rather ordinary.
The way you open doors ...
- Who did you think I was?
- A friend.
Quite a business,
being your friend.
He was just playing a joke.
Oh, that was a joke!
Well, aren't you witty!
- Oh, well ...
- Almost killingly funny!
Don't worry --
your face isn't marked.
- Lucky you.
- Really? Why?
If you'd put my jaw out --
you'd be sorry.
You might ask the lady
what she's doing here.
That's so.
What are you doing here?
You should thank me.
I am Providence.
I bring you a tranquil tomorrow.
But Madame --
You live in dissipation,
lust, deceit.
Love takes too much time,
desire is quicker.
Your days have only 2 hours,
cinq à sept.
You don't make love,
you kill time.
But what business is that
of yours?
Yes, I'd like to know!
Poor little thing!
What are you in this man's life?
Just this moment. Your affair will last
no longer than a rainbow.
Just look at him!
His sly, drooping eyes,
his cynical mouth --
his hands that distribute caresses
like leaflets to every passerby.
He's the very picture of debauchery
and can expect to end in misery --
for who would have pity on him?
That is why I bring him a means
to safeguard his future.
Thanks to this combination clock
and savings bank,
he can advance in perfect security
towards his declining years
by simply inserting a coin or two
in this slot each morning.
This useful and artistic object,
precision engineered,
weighing no more than 750 grams --
I'm not selling it, I'm giving it to him!
For it's a gift to exchange this clock
against -- no!
No, not ten thousand francs, not nine,
not eight -- I'll tell you the sum now,
brace yourselves --
against -- 3,000 francs!
I'm sorry, I don't need a clock.
- You do.
- I don't.
I'll bet you 1,000 francs
you'll buy it for 3,000.
You lose.
Do I?
Then let's talk seriously.
I am in the apartment of
Jacques Tavère?
- Yes.
- Good!
Then give me my 3,000 francs
and we'll say no more.
We've just said
we don't want it.
You are Mme Pierre Morland?
- Yes.
- Of 48 avenue de Saxe?
- The wife of Mr Pierre Morland?
- But --
- If you want
I could also demonstrate my clock to
Mr Pierre Morland, 48 av. de Saxe.
- Blackmail.
- No.
No, no, no,
Targeted marketing.
Oh, yes.
- Madame is a blackmailer.
- A pretty trade!
If you were a man, I'd gladly
break your neck.
You've already tried it.
Well?
My 3,000 francs?
Business must be booming,
at prices like that.
I can't complain.
I have an established clientele.
I even have return customers,
to whom I've sold 20-25 clocks.
Of course, establishing contact
is always ... delicate.
But they catch on quickly.
Some even go so far as to ...
pass on their friends' addresses.
- That's a little bonus.
- Pay her and make her go!
There!
At last a reasonable word!
Here's the order form,
all filled out for you -- just sign!
Add a cheque for 3,000 francs,
and everything will be in order.
You think I'm in cahoots with the lady
and splitting the take with her.
Well, you're wrong!
- Isn't he wrong, Gisèle?
- Are you mad?
I never for a second thought
you could know this adventuress.
Thank you, Monsieur.
Better luck in the future.
- Would you open the door for me?
- With pleasure!
- Right, Gisèle?
- Oh, yes!
This time it is my husband!
I'd be delighted to meet him.
- Why must it always be your husband?
- Were you expecting someone else?
- Open, or I'll break down the door!
- Charming!
- Hide, for God's sake!
- Where am I supposed to hide?
You're so disorganized!
- Hello, Pierre!
- Gisèle!
- How are you?
- Gisèle is here!
- You're joking.
- I saw her go in.
That wasn't her!
Then why didn't you open the door
sooner?
I didn't hear you ring.
You didn't -- ?
You're a liar!
- Now, Pierre --
- Gisèle!
I tell you, I know she's here!
- Pierre, please ...
- Leave me alone! Gisèle!
Good God, Pierre,
calm yourself!
Gisèle is here!
Gisèle!
- Tell me where she is!
- In the name of our friendship --
Don't make a scandal!
She's not on the balcony!
Nor back there!
- Listen, Pierre --
- Let me through!
Wouldn't you rather
have a drink?
Pierre, calm down!
I've never seen you like this.
That's the bathroom!
What's going on?
Who is this creature?
Call the police!
Don't, Madame,
I beg of you!
Please forgive me.
I'm a fool.
Better a fool
than a cuckold, no?
I don't understand.
I actually believed
that my wife ...
And you were wrong!
And you admit you were wrong,
and off you go.
Put yourself in my place --
appearances were against Gisèle!
For shame!
You deceiver!
Who is this Gisèle?
- My wife.
- As I suspected, alas!
Jacques is deceiving me
with your wife!
Not at all!
You're easily convinced!
- I have proof of Gisèle's innocence!
- What proof?
Well ... she's not here!
Oh really?
How do you know?
She's here, my poor fellow!
She's here,
she's everywhere in here!
This mirror is Gisèle!
This dreadful clock is Gisèle!
That casually tossed bouquet,
also Gisèle!
Oh, woe is me!
Madame, don't make my mistake
of judging too quickly!
Again, I beg your pardon.
I've been such a fool ...
But ... she's delightful!
Well ...
And high time too!
- I thought he'd never leave.
- Poor fellow.
I don't know how to thank you.
You were wonderful.
Don't thank me.
It wasn't for you.
If I lied, it was to spare him
unnecessary pain.
Well, you're amazing.
So I've heard.
I've heard it all, in fact.
I hope this experience will be
a lesson to you.
No moralizing, please!
- Feeling more sure of yourself now?
- Was I unsure?
- You were pale as a lily!
- Not at all!
- I was afraid for Gisèle.
- For Gisèle.
Then you'd better reassure her.
My God, I almost forgot! ...
Gisèle!
Where are you?
Is he gone? ...
Quick, my hat!
- Hurry, get my hat!
- No need to hurry now!
Don't start!
I won't forget today anytime soon!
What have you got
to complain about?
- This is all your fault.
- My fault? I'm here by pure chance.
No, you wanted a little adventure.
But not the kind you found.
- What do you mean?
- I'm not here to quibble.
Stick to your grift
and spare me your lecture.
- You accept only my assistance?
- Now, now ...
- Do you defend her?
- No, but she did save us both.
- And you paid her for it!
- He paid for the clock.
But not for the little drama
I improvised.
It wasn't worth much --
what are lies to you?
Gisèle, don't scold her
for saving us!
- It's humiliating.
- Oh, is she proud now?
It's humiliating to have
such a credulous husband.
Believing the first idiot
he hears!
Little girl,
you're asking for it!
Don't speak to me in that tone.
- Your husband may not be fooled.
- How so?
You insisted too much
on his going.
That would have alerted me --
and I think it did him.
- Don't listen to her.
- Your fate is still in my hands.
Well, I'm going.
Enough of this creature's caprices!
- You shan't leave!
- She shall!
- Am I in the way?
- No, she was stopping you!
- She'll leave when I say so.
- Do you hear that?
Only I can save you --
if I care to!
Of course --
you can do anything!
- Time will tell.
- You're a fortuneteller too!
Sometimes, yes.
And right now I foresee
great, great trouble for you.
For one of you,
in particular ...
... who's strolling down there.
Careful!
- He's down there!
- Who?
He! ... Yes, he!
- What's he waiting for?
- You to come out.
Apparently my little drama
didn't quite convince him.
What a boor!
I can't bear mistrustful people!
He's not going to deny
the obvious!
I'm going to be sick!
Don't make matters worse!
Of course,
you don't have an idea now!
Yes I do.
I have a second clock.
- Are you asking 3,000 francs?
- Not at all.
You'll give me them
without my asking.
We're drowning, and you want to haggle
before saving us!
I'm not a philanthropist!
The time I've wasted with you
could have been spent
with another client!
3,000 francs,
that's that.
It's too much!
I won't pay!
As you like!
Farewell!
Give her the 3,000 francs
to get us out of this!
- 3,000 francs?
- My honor is worth that!
- Well, really ...
- Don't haggle!
Very well, 3,000 francs.
What's your idea?
Trust me.
Let's see ... give me a hat.
A hat, a hat ...
here you are!
No, no, one of your hats!
My cheque!
Are you crazy?
- She's crazy!
- Let me alone!
You paid me,
you're getting your money's worth.
- I'm an honest worker.
- And a pieceworker!
Don't you understand?
I'm making a jealous scene.
Yes, and so?
And so, you ask your friend
to bring these items up.
Madame will hide behind the door,
and, as soon as your friend enters,
- Madame will slip away.
- Brilliant! Go, go now.
- And I won't charge you extra.
- For throwing out my hat?
Passing as your mistress --
it's compromising!
But you do owe me 3,000 francs
for my story -- agreed?
- Yes or no?
- Oh, all right, yes.
No, no!
That's Papa!
- Right -- sorry.
- No, that's Maman!
Very likely.
Ah, Marguerite ...
Pierre! Pierre!
Bring my things up!
Hurry!
I'll explain!
Now, no mistakes!
Here's the situation:
I'm your jealous mistress,
in a rage.
Making a horrible scene,
storm, cyclone --
That's it!
Now let's get set.
Easy, easy!
A cyclone,
but an apartment cyclone!
Passion
on the installment plan!
Bourgeois!
Bougeois? Me?
My clock!
- Oh, lovely.
- You could do the same.
No, no!
A bit more realism!
- And slap yourself.
- With pleasure!
- I said slap yourself!
- Sorry.
I'll teach you manners,
my girl!
- You'll pay for this!
- What?
- That was your foot, not your hand!
- Oh, right.
Pull yourself together!
Quickly!
- What happened to you?
- Come in, old boy.
- Look at this mess.
- What was that?
A draft.
What a scene we just had!
- You don't hold back, do you?
- Where is she?
- Where are you?
- Madame, where are you?
- The window!
- I hardly think so.
Up there! What's she doing?
Come on!
- Madame ...
- Now, darling ...
Don't touch me!
- My love ...
- She said don't touch!
- Ouch!
- Poor little thing ...
Poor little thing?
Talk to her!
Please get up, Madame.
Help me ...
not you!
Calm yourself, Madame ...
listen ...
Don't be upset ...
what are you looking for?
A hankie ...
- Do you have a handkerchief?
- Thank you ...
Please calm yourself ...
I swear Jacques is innocent.
He loves you!
He always has!
He's never stopped loving you!
He told me so just yesterday!
- Really?
- Yes!
- He told you so?
- Yes, yes!
- Word of honor?
- Yes, Madame!
- Do you swear it?
- On Jacques's head!
What did he say, just yesterday?
What did he tell you?
He was saying how much he loved you,
that you were his life ...
He's talked of you since ...
well, a very, very long time ago!
What does he call me,
when he talks about me?
Uh ... he would never tell me
your name!
No, never!
I said,
"Her name is my dearest secret."
"If I yielded to your curiosity,
I would lose something."
- You see?
- Exactly.
Ah, no!
No, no, no!
You're being chivalrous!
Yes, chivalrous!
But how can I believe you?
Ah, no! It's over,
it's all over!
I can but die!
Catherine, Catherine ...
Image of Catherine, farewell!
One must always make a rough draft
of one's suicide.
So like her.
Farewell, me!
Gather up my remains,
gentlemen.
My mirror!
His mirror!
There's his love!
- You brute!
- You see, I can but die!
Don't be rash, Madame!
My revolver!
Farewell, Jacques!
May we meet in heaven!
Hello?
Hello? Hello.
Hello, Jacques?
Yes? Yes, it is.
- Is he still there?
- Yes.
Is he still suspicious?
No, not at all.
- No, it's fine.
- What's that?
The line is clear.
Good day, Monsieur.
What's this?
- Why did you hang up so fast?
- What are you imagining now?
- That was a woman!
- It was the phone company.
The phone company!
From now on, I won't trust
anything he says!
Oh no, Madame, you must!
He's an oaf, but ...
he loves you deeply!
If you leave him, his life
will be ruined!
Alcohol, wicked women --
that's what you'd condemn him to!
You're a good, honest man.
Oh yes, you are!
But he!
Defend yourself, man!
Think of our past, my love!
Think of our first meeting!
It was in autumn,
in Versailles.
Twilight ...
Twilight ... was falling.
You wandered alone ... listless ...
through an alley
of russet oaks ...
And our trip to Spain,
remember?
Coming back through Basque Country,
Landes, Touraine ...
And our nights ...
Our nights ... that lasted
until 3:00 in the afternoon.
Ah ... you trusted me then.
How well you lie!
My love ...
What more can I say?
- Say you believe me.
- Yes.
Yes, perhaps ...
I want so much to believe you ...
Even if I don't believe you,
I can pretend to.
And by pretending ...
I'll come truly to believe you.
Jacques ...
my little Jacques ...
Ah ... magnificent ...
Ah ... marvelous ...
But ... but ...
where'd he go?
Let go of me! He's gone!
So soon?
- You think so?
- I do indeed.
You behaved disgracefully.
- You took advantage of the situation.
- You didn't seem to mind.
I was acting.
Yes, but you were carried away
by your own performance.
No! Your pasteboard kisses would have
brought me back to reality.
You don't think you're irresistible,
do you?
No more than yourself.
I, at least, kept my head.
I couldn't love a woman
I had paid, Madame.
To me, you're an employee.
A day laborer.
Now your work is over
and you're dismissed.
I'll have no further need of you.
For your sake,
I hope not!
Your second clock will be delivered
tomorrow before noon.
I didn't ask the time!
Gisèle, answer me ...
I insist we invite the lady
to dinner!
Nonsense!
It's not!
I was a fool, the least I can do
is invite her to dinner!
Completely unnecessary.
And don't think of dining
with that adventuress.
But she's a perfect lady!
I don't want her to think me
a boor.
Be a dear and phone Jacques.
I feel a bit better
knowing that when I left
they were reconciling ...
very tenderly, if you know what I mean!
What!
I left on tiptoe,
so as not to disturb them!
Spare me the details!
Oh, but darling --
they love each other!
I think it's sweet.
Don't you?
Of course!
- And it's taken a load off my mind!
- Oh, yes.
- when I think I could have imagined --
- Imagined what?
How stupid jealousy is!
- So, will you call Jacques?
- No!
How stubborn you can be!
Hello? Yes?
Oh yes ...
She's fine ...
Dinner?
Dinner with her?
My poor old chap,
we've broken up ...
Yes, it's final.
- Suppose I sent her flowers?
- Flowers?
- No, no flowers -- she has hay fever.
- Scentless flowers?
Scentless flowers? Scentless flowers?
Err ...
- Give me her address, for God's sake!
- Your tone ...
Roussel ...
yes, like the song ...
50 rue de l'Abbaye.
And I tell you
I will never see her again!
Pierre Morland invites Catherine Roussel
to dine with him at the Pavillon Rose.
Get me dossier 412.
- The Tavère-Morland case?
- Yes.
Case report --
take this down --
Outcome excellent --
two clocks.
And complete the forms.
Jacques Tavère --
Standard lover.
100% oaf.
Distinguishing features:
has no taste.
Pierre Morland.
Jealous husband.
Conformist.
Tailor-made clothes.
Ready-made opinions.
Gisèle Morland.
Pretty. Flirtatious.
Unsettled.
Fidelity: short-term,
but could be consolidated.
Conclusion:
to be followed up.
No, case closed!
I hope never to see them again.
I have an excellent lead
for Mademoiselle --
Baron Verdier and Madame --
- No, no, drop it.
- Why?
- That liaison has lasted 10 years.
- So?
It's too late to intervene.
- I thought tonight --
- No!
You don't understand how I work.
Do you think I sell my clocks
at gunpoint?
- I never said that!
- But you thought it! Jérôme?
- Mademoiselle?
- How long have you known me?
I've known Mademoiselle
since the day she was born.
Am I a gentleman?
- A perfect gentleman.
- But I never --
When I sold my clocks normally,
what happened?
Mademoiselle was shown out,
sometimes rudely, by normal customers.
- And since I sell to selected couples?
- Mademoiselle is no longer shown out.
- How many clocks have I sold?
- 404.
How many straying wives
have I brought back to the fold?
More than 200 --
10 of them dubious.
Thank you, Jérôme.
Is that clear?
- Yes, Mademoiselle.
- You may go.
Yes, Mademoiselle.
Excuse me.
Bravo! You were magnificent,
as always -- dignity, style ...
- Anything new?
- Not much -- oh, yes!
Last night, at Mme d'Ambroisie's,
I was on the trail -- false --
of the thieves they arrested
in the salon.
Not for us.
Now, the girl with the emeralds
and the tall blond man --
Quite far along.
But nothing decisive.
- What are they waiting for?
- To be free.
His wife leaves tomorrow.
He'll dine with the girl.
- Where?
- The Pavillon Rose.
The Pavillon Rose?
Tomorrow?
- My guests aren't here yet?
- Not yet, M. Morland.
All alone?
Where's Gisèle?
Oh ... migraine.
So it'll just be us boys
tonight?
The table's set for three.
And the third place setting?
- Sterling!
- Man? Woman?
Woman.
- Do I know her?
- By heart.
No! Who is it?
Guess.
I'm no good at riddles.
Who is it?
- Catherine.
- Catherine?
Yes, Catherine!
- I don't know her.
- Come, come, old boy!
- What do you mean?
- Don't be a sorehead!
I'm not, I just don't know her.
"I don't know her!"
"I won't know her!"
I've been through the same thing
with Gisèle.
There she is!
No scenes, now!
Sweetness and light ...
Charm!
You invited that ... person?
I invited Catherine!
You must be mad!
Your relationship short-circuited
because of me --
I'm just resetting it!
- Good evening, Pierre!
- Dear lady ...
Good evening, you!
Oh, you look dreadful.
Why so cold and formal!
- What?
- Kiss each other!
I have no desire to kiss him.
Unbelievable. So my kiss would be
extremely disagreeable to you?
- Extremely.
- In that case --
Good evening, doll!
Good evening,
ignoble individual!
- I hated that.
- So did I.
Do sit down.
You're sulking at your own hearts.
I chose the menu --
I'm sure you'll like it.
- Let the festivities begin!
- Very well, sir.
Don't brood, old boy!
He may seem callous,
but he has a tender heart!
Jacques may be charming
to his friends ...
but to a woman --
that's a different story!
Be indulgent --
he loves you!
He can be unbearable --
you've no idea!
- I have my ways.
- Complexes!
Complexes?
He goes to bed with his shoes on
in case there's a fire!
- No!
- Rubbish!
- Do you dare say I'm lying?
- Yes!
- You don't sleep in your shoes?
- No!
I had to put a doormat
beside the bed!
Revolting.
Delightful!
And then the clocks!
What about clocks?
He collects clocks!
Not just any clocks --
savings bank clocks!
I've seen them,
they're dreadful!
Didn't I see them
at your place?
He forces them on me!
He refuses to come over
unless I have them!
I'm a martyr to his whims!
False from beginning to end!
She's completely ...
Now that's ... that's ...
unchivalrous.
I hate clocks!
You hate them, do you?
He bought two, just the day
before yesterday!
Two clocks I'll throw out the window
this very night!
You say that because
Pierre is here!
But you know you'll relapse!
You'll buy others --
you know you can't
resist temptation!
You'll fall in love with another --
but they're all the same!
- Not pretty?
- No!
Very pretty,
in my opinion.
- Especially the last one!
- From two days ago? Yes.
That one you won't have!
No, you won't!
I'll see to that --
or it'll cost you!
- If I want it, I'll have it!
- Oh no you won't!
He's obsessed!
I have to keep an eye on him.
On yourself!
Do you know the game
Madame plays?
Cheque-hunting, old boy!
She comes home at night
loaded with cheques!
Cheques all over the floor!
Watch yourself!
We're here tonight to toast
your reconciliation!
Oh, headwaiter!
Wine list, please.
- Let's have another bottle.
- That doesn't seem wise.
Good idea.
I'm devilish thirsty.
What's up?
- All set.
- What?
The couple with the emeralds.
Another bottle of the same.
- It's tonight.
- Where?
Her place.
17 rue Tristan.
So I've brought the necessary.
- It's in the cloakroom.
- Thanks.
- Aren't these peaches delicious?
- Yes.
Did you see?
He was scared!
- I scared him!
- You scare everyone.
Jacques ...
Jacques Tavère ...
- C'est moi.
- Get up for me and go over there.
- For you?
- Yes.
Go soak your head in cold water,
it'll do me good.
Catherine ...
Jacques ...
No! Pierre ...
That's right!
Catherine ...
You appeal to me so ...
But I won't speak of it to you,
because Jacques is my best friend.
As he is my best friend,
I will respect you, Catherine.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
But when he comes back,
I'm going to slap him.
Then he won't be my best friend
and I can tell you ...
"Catherine, you're beautiful."
All gone!
It's infallible.
- I'll bring your change, Madame.
- Keep it.
There he is!
- I'm going to do it!
- Hard!
Listen, Jacques ...
and don't move ...
- Again!
- Oh, no ...
Oh, how can I slap
my best friend?
- But he likes it!
- Don't ask the impossible!
- You refuse?
- I refuse.
- I scorn you.
- I don't care.
None for me?
I give you 30 seconds
to finish this glass.
Dear old Pierre ...
Off she goes!
- Well, she's cross!
- Why?
She didn't get her slap!
That's right,
I owe her a slap ...
- But gently ...
- Gently or not!
What address, Madame?
17 rue Tristan.
My cloakroom check!
Quick, I'm in a hurry!
- Where is the lady going?
- 17 rue Tristan.
- My car!
- This way, Monsieur.
Did you see this one?
Worth a fortune!
- And how it gleams!
- I saw.
Together with what I
picked up ...
Look --
all we need.
And now let's beat it.
I'll be glad
when we're 24 hours older.
- So you noticed too?
- No, what?
- The woman watching us.
- What woman?
- She watched us constantly.
- Maybe she liked your looks.
I don't think so.
Something else was on her mind.
We've run into her before.
- We have?
- Think back.
- Well?
- Mme d'Ambroisie's.
Where Sambo kissed his way
to a big haul.
- You're right!
- You never notice anything.
- Think she's police?
- Or in the same game as us.
Oh, my fur!
I forgot it and he brought it back.
Thank you!
You're a good, honest fellow.
I'll give you a discount
on the next clock I sell you!
- Goodbye!
- Not goodbye, I'm coming with you!
- Where?
- There, where you're going!
Can't you see
I'm going to work?
I hate women who work.
- What's that?
- I'll see.
Good evening!
Madame! Madame!
What do you want?
- You weren't expecting me, were you?
- No!
Oh, what a lovely, lovely place
you have!
Family portraits, too!
I ask you,
what are you doing here?
Offering you a bargain!
What bargain?
I am Providence --
I offer you a peaceful future!
Monsieur, you lead a dreadful life!
Full of dissipation, debauchery,
and lies!
And where is it leading you?
That is why Providence
brings you this ...
this exquisite little clock!
And thanks to this exquisite
little clock
You can advance with confidence
towards your declining years.
All you need --
Pay no attention to that lady!
Come in, Monsieur.
Providence ...
c'est moi!
Why didn't you stay
where I left you?
It takes a better woman than you
to shake me off!
I have something to say too!
No, not you!
Not me?
We'll see about that!
Live! Live in dissipation
and debauchery!
Life is short!
Never mind the clock!
Let go!
Gisèle ...
Ouch.
Catherine ...
- Where am I?
- On the road.
The road to where?
The land of heart's desire.
Hey, hey, hey ...
Who are you, Monsieur?
This is my car, Monsieur!
Give me back my car at once,
Monsieur!
Easy on the accelerator!
- He'll wreck it!
- Be quiet!
This is my car.
Get out!
- Shut it, would you?
- Shut what?
Your traps!
Well, I'm going to sleep.
Wake me at the end of the line.
- Where's the bag?
- I don't know!
- Fine mess we're in.
- And those two?
They're out cold.
- Open the door.
- It's stuck!
- Push.
- I'm pushing!
- My necklace!
- Why didn't you guard those two?
If you hadn't jerked the wheell!
Only because that broad
threw her bag!
- There's the bag!
- Come on!
Where's the diamond? ...
There it is!
Let's beat it!
What are you doing in my shop?
What?
No one there?
What time is it?
- Hey, where are you going?
- I was looking for you!
- We heard a crash.
- You'll see -- it's a disaster!
You were going too fast!
Don't you know the rule?
- 30 km/hour in town!
- I'm not the driver, I own the shop!
How was I supposed to know?
- No driver?
- He took off!
- Who'll pay my damages?
- I'll investigate.
A revolver.
Loaded?
Catherine? Catherine!
- Are you hurt?
- Something's pressing on me ...
Anything broken?
Why is he asking?
If nothing's broken,
get out!
He could address me in another tone,
don't you think?
These must be the jewel thieves
we're looking out for.
Come to the station and explain
why you have a loaded gun
and all these jewels in your car.
Hurry up!
Come here.
Whose car is it?
- Yours?
- His.
I didn't ask you. ...
Speak only when questioned.
I said it was his car, because
two witnesses are better --
You're not a witness,
you're the accused!
Accused?
Of what?
- You'll know later.
- At what o'clock?
- Are you through interrogating me?
- Is that a question?
- Why?
- You said "Speak only when questioned."
So I wanted to know if
you were questioning me
so as not to irritate you,
because you seem dreadfully --
- irritable.
- Silence!
I'll continue.
Whose car is it?
- Mine.
- His.
And who was driving it?
A man and a woman.
- They were both driving?
- No, they were in the front seat.
But who was driving?
- The man.
- What man?
- I don't know.
- You don't know?
- No.
- What?
You were in your own car and you didn't
know the man at the wheel?
I didn't.
Then why was he in your car?
I don't know. I found myself in my car
and he was already in it.
- That's very strange.
- It is.
Where had you met him?
At their place.
- At what time?
- Midnight, one in the morning ...
They'd invited you?
No, they weren't expecting me.
I was there to sell them a clock.
- What?
- Clocks are my business.
You sell clocks
at 1:00 a.m.?
- But they aren't ordinary clocks!
- I should say not!
This gentleman accompanied you?
No, he followed me against my will --
right, Jacques?
- Do you two know each other, at least?
- I know him very well.
Yes, she knows me very well.
I hardly know her at all.
Don't get subtle with me.
If you're going to be wiseacres,
I'll lock you up.
- Good idea!
- No it's not!
Send them in.
Come on!
Hurry up!
It's Monsieur Tavère!
What are you doing here?
That's what I'd like to know!
You must be mad --
don't you know Monsieur Tavère?
Tavère? No.
- You don't know our châtelain?
- No, sir.
I don't know the area.
I've just been assigned here.
If I'd known,
I would have treated him differently.
That reminds me of a song ...
- I am overwhelmed with confusion --
- Now, now ...
- A night in lockup!
- An interesting experience.
And we slept very well.
Didn't we, dear lady?
Indeed.
You snored wonderfully.
I snored?
It was like being in an airplane.
Then I didn't snore.
At most, I ... vroomed.
- Much more romantic.
- You must be exhausted, dear lady.
What does that matter,
if Monsieur slept well?
- Monsieur, could you release us?
- With pleasure!
- Then I'll go.
- My apologies!
You're too kind.
My thanks
for your gracious hospitality.
Catherine! Catherine!
Goodbye!
Vroom without me!
- Goodbye, then.
- M. Tavère, I can't apologize enough.
- I hope you won't hold this against me.
- Not at all! Goodbye.
But I should have been there!
But one can't be everywhere.
- Especially at night!
- How right you are. Goodbye now!
Mademoiselle!
Allow me to introduce myself --
Jacques Tavère.
Tavère, Jacques --
mean anything to you?
- Go to the devil!
- I'm there already.
- Nice weather we're having.
- Leave me alone!
Our little misadventure
hasn't cooled your temper.
- It was all your fault.
- Yours too, a little.
- You tried to stop my clocks.
- Keep out of other people's business!
Just what I was about
to tell you.
What a pity you didn't end up
under the car.
- Thank you -- oaf.
- Not at all -- wench.
Cretin.
- Vermin. - Boor.
- Shrew. - Buffoon. ...
To think you took thieves
for for lovers!
I suppose you never
make mistakes!
Yes -- I thought you
were clever.
If only you hadn't made me drink.
I usually drink water, Monsieur.
And I'm a vegetarian.
That's why you have
such a vile temper.
- Watch yourself!
- You jostled me!
Charming!
I wish you could see yourself!
- It would put a smile on your face.
- No!
It would!
The way you look ...
Oh, I can't go on!
I'm tired!
I need sleep. I'm thirsty.
I'm hungry.
Hot coffee.
Milk. Cream.
Butter, honey, jam.
And lovely crusty toast.
All for you at my place
if you behave.
- Is your place far?
- Seven kilometers.
- Seven ... I can't!
- Come on!
- I'll carry you!
- No, don't!
It's incompatible with my dignity.
Think of something else.
But what?
- Where are we?
- To the devil!
You said to go to the devil --
here we are!
Driver!
Driver, to Paris, please!
- An idée fixe, clearly.
- I must go home!
How about a nice hot bath first?
- Boiling hot?
- Xavier, boiling hot for Madame!
Boiling hot for Madame.
Then you'll drive me
to the station?
Then you'll have that breakfast
we were talking about.
- No, I'm not hungry any more.
- Driver, you're dismissed.
Your place is charming.
Oh, it's lovely.
Much nicer
than being in prison!
I can just see you vrooming
beneath the trees.
Xavier, Mlle Catherine
is sleeping.
- You'll be sure not to wake her.
- Of course, Monsieur.
She needs rest.
Complete rest.
- Certainly, Monsieur.
- So keep things quiet.
If she should wake
and ask for anything,
give her whatever she wants,
immediately.
- Behave exactly as though ...
- Indeed.
- Monsieur can count on me.
- Thank you. To business!
If she should wake while I'm out,
don't let her leave, of course.
Of course.
Poor young lady.
She hasn't had a bad time of it,
but ...
She mustn't be crossed.
She's ...
Is it that serious?
Jacques?
Jacques-Jacques-Jacques-
Jacques-Jacques ...
Jacques ...
Oh, are you there?
- Is the car ready?
- The car?
To take me to the station.
There is no car,
Mademoiselle.
- What time is the train?
- There is no train.
- Where is the station?
- There is no station.
- What is there, then?
- Nothing.
How does one get back to Paris?
Does one telephone?
That's it. ... One goes ...
by telephone.
By telephone?
What are you talking about?
- You. - Me? - Yes. Are you mad?
- Mad? - Yes!
If Mademoiselle says so.
If I say so?
What is wrong with you?
- Who? - You. - Me? - Yes.
- Nothing.
Go get Mr Jacques,
I need to talk with him.
- Yes, yes ...
- I said go get him!
If Mademoiselle will wait here ...
Yes, but what are you waiting for?
Go get the master of the house,
I say!
Mademoiselle must not
get excited.
You are beginning
to get on my nerves!
And you'll make me miss
my train!
You clumsy,
you almost --
Oh, the brutes!
The brutes!
They would have sprayed me.
Certainly, Mademoiselle.
What?
Can one go through here?
Well, don't mind me.
Excuse me.
It's all right, Mademoiselle!
Don't worry!
What is all this?
Is it a joke?
If that's how Mademoiselle takes it,
so much the better.
I'm going to speak to the master.
I'll find him myself.
Enough of this nonsense,
I'm going home.
- Careful!
- What?
In her state, Mademoiselle should
try to keep calm.
In my state?
What state?
If Mademoiselle would only rest,
she'd be better balanced.
You think I'm crazy!
He thinks I'm crazy!
Jacques!
Jacques, I command you to tell him
I'm not crazy!
We know. Mademoiselle just needs
a little rest.
Just listen to him!
- Just stay here, nice and quiet --
- Nice and quiet!
- I could strangle someone!
- The crisis is upon her!
No, but it will be!
Jacques --
Did you see that?
Listen to me.
I must get back to Paris.
Aren't you comfortable here?
You don't mean to keep me here
by force?
Think of it as a holiday.
- I will go.
- Tomorrow.
Immediately!
We must call everyone.
Monsieur!
We'll get reinforcements.
I am ready --
Oh, really?
You clearly need rest.
I will go home!
That's final!
Don't shout like that --
I'll think Xavier was right.
Will you give me a car to go home,
yes or no?
No. You're in such a state
that I must order you to rest.
- You order me!
- Careful, Monsieur!
The mad require caution!
So I'm mad!
I'm mad, am I?
I'll show you mad!
I'm mad, mad, mad!
I never doubted it.
Sir, the garden hose!
I will strangle him!
Help! She's strangling me!
Monsieur!
Now, now!
Playtime is over!
Let me go,
you brute!
Let me go, you oaf!
Bumpkin! Clodhopper!
What's wrong with you?
Is this how country air affects you?
Perhaps!
I'm not crazy!
I must get back to Paris!
I have clocks to sell!
How unfortunate.
I am determined to prevent
your exercising that talent.
- Impossible.
- I will not let you cause further harm.
Lovers will be able to love
in peace.
You're a public danger, Madame.
You're not going to lock me up
in here?
A few days of reflection
will do you good.
You idiot.
- You can't be serious.
- Back, back!
You've made my life a misery
since I met you.
How many others did you afflict
before me? But that's all over!
I'll avenge them here and now!
Go ahead --
I don't care.
Scream away.
This is an upper floor
and I sleep on the other side
of the house.
Goodbye
and happy meditation.
Good afternoon.
I'd like to speak to Mr Tavère.
Mr Tavère is at his stables.
Hearthside Alarm Clocks, sir --
awake to music!
Please give him my card.
I'm a specialist.
- And experienced.
- Clearly.
Monsieur!
Come up! Come up!
I'm on the upper floor!
Come to the upper floor, I say!
The door at the end
of the corridor!
It's locked, but the key
is in the lock!
Poor fellow.
Not his lucky day.
- Pardon me, sir.
- What is it?
A person to see Monsieur.
Hearthside Alarm Clocks
He's selling ...
would you believe it!
Was that he?
Pity. I missed the chance
to throw him out.
Let's see if calm is restored.
That's the way to tame them!
No, monsieur, the office
is closed at this hour.
It's you!
In that outfit!
It is I, in this outfit.
If you only knew how I got it!
I was going mad with anxiety!
I thought you were dead!
I was looking everywhere!
I called Pierre Morland --
if not for him, I'd have
called the police and told all!
- Why not the dog pound?
- Very funny.
Morland reassured me.
We'd have talked longer,
but he was meeting
that miserable Tavère.
Why?
He's having a dinner party
at his country place.
- He thought he'd see you there.
- Never!
A dinner party, you say ...
- at the home of Jacques.
- of Mr Tavère.
From now on,
I won't leave your side!
Good evening, Xavier.
Are we dining outside?
What an extraordinary idea!
- I hope you won't catch cold.
- What?
I hope you won't catch cold!
- Mr Tavère seems very nervous.
- Doesn't he, Doctor?
He received us in the strangest manner.
- Usually so cool and calm, he bolted!
- He seems worn out.
- Overwork.
- Women.
- Monsieur is bleeding!
- I forgot to shave!
You might have reminded me.
- Such an eventful day ...
- What are we eating?
- The menu!
- It will be simple, naturally.
Go on, then, serve!
- Upstairs?
- Not a peep.
- She's sleeping?
- Apparently.
Absolute silence in that part
of the house!
- You're back!
- Indeed.
Where did you get to?
- You've made up with Catherine?
- Absolutely.
Then why isn't she here?
She didn't want to come.
But if you're reconciled --
She couldn't be here,
if you prefer.
- You're hiding something.
- Catherine and I adore each other!
- But this isn't the moment --
- What are you talking about?
He was telling me that
he adores Catherine.
But -- shhh!
Was that you singing?
What was it?
- Idiot.
- Who's that?
- What's the matter?
- Just pain.
Oh, yes.
Because of Catherine.
Such dramatic sighs!
When depression persists
and the first symptoms appear --
- What must be done, Doctor?
- Treatment! Otherwise ...
- Otherwise?
- Ah!
Pierre, I'm counting on you to make
this dinner a success.
- And you too!
- Of course!
It's a duty dinner.
The Président is brusque,
but an excellent fellow.
And he could be very helpful
to me.
The doctor was telling me
stories of madmen.
- They can be very amusing.
- Or tragic!
Why didn't you insist
that Catherine be here?
- Oh, no!
- But yes!
She's pretty, sparkling,
intelligent ...
- Pierre, don't insist!
- Don't.
That's right, you've never met her!
She's divine.
She's unique!
That's the woman you should marry!
She'd be your true love!
If I were to marry all my true loves,
I'd have a harem.
- What on earth?
- Shooting pains in my arm.
And there.
And my head ...
One shouldn't give dinners
in a state like that!
My dear Président,
let's seat ourselves for dinner.
Why are we being seated
when nothing's ready?
Strange way to treat guests!
My apologies ...
it's just that Xavier ...
- What's wrong with Jacques?
- I wonder!
Something strange is going on
in this house.
A year ago, after a period of fatigue,
the wife of one of my friends --
I beg your pardon?
- The wife of one of his friends --
- Perhaps.
The wife of one of his friends!
No.
- Catherine!
- But how did you know her name?
Catherine!
I was sure of it!
My dear,
how happy Jacques will be!
- I'm so relieved you're here with me!
- Why?
- What's going on?
- It's dreadful --
- What?
You mean you don't know?
No.
Hello!
But -- upstairs!
You see?
Jacques ...
is mad!
I told you so!
Who are you?
Hearthside Alarm Clocks.
You'll help me, won't you?
The slightest upset
might unhinge him!
What an evening!
- How could it happen so suddenly?
- He was always a bit --
But he's gotten so much worse
over the past few hours!
Poor Jacques!
We're all on your side!
Right, Gisèle?
I forgot you haven't met --
Gisèle, this is Jacques' true love!
Pardon me.
Poor Jacques!
Isn't it dreadful?
Enough of this playacting.
- I've saved your reputation again.
- You won't take Jacques from me.
- Careful, your husband.
- You don't frighten me.
Oh, it's dreadful!
- What's going on now?
- If you only knew what Gi-
Hush, now --
Jacques will recover.
I'll calm down.
She's a bit shaken,
but that's understandable.
Here's our dear Jacques!
Let's be seated, dear friends!
My brooch! My brooch!
I've lost my brooch!
Where?
That wretched woman!
Please, not a word!
She was about to tell Pierre
everything.
Ah, here it is!
Dinner is served!
- I hope it wasn't serious.
- I don't think it was.
Who's that?
Who are you, my good fellow?
- Jérôme, sir.
- Jérôme?
- Yes, Jérôme.
- Oh, of course! Good old Jérôme!
He's been in Jacques' service
since childhood.
Serve yourselves!
Jacques composed the menu.
He'd hate your neglecting
his dishes, eh Jacques?
- He has very distinctive tastes!
- As do you, my love!
- What do you say to this dish, sweet?
- You tell me, precious!
But it's your recipe, dearest!
Oh, well.
Be that as it may.
It might be good, at that!
Shoestrings.
The music doesn't bother you,
does it?
- What music?
- I don't hear anything.
The orchestra!
Do you hear music?
- Yes ... yes, yes, yes!
- Very well, then.
You're sure it doesn't bother you,
Pierre?
No, no, it doesn't bother me.
- Right, Gisèle?
- On the contrary!
It's a fine orchestra.
But it tends to play
too loudly.
Jérôme! ...
Ask them to play more softly.
Mademoiselle will remember
they don't speak French.
I forgot! Motion them to stop,
I fear they're upsetting Mr Jacques.
No, it's delightful!
Don't you love that --
Ah, that music!
It gives me a wild desire to dance.
Come, my dear.
It's a waltz.
- How long will this nonsense go on?
- You know I'm mad!
I swear --
To prevent me from doing
further harm?
That I'm a public danger?
That lovers will be able to love
in peace?
You should be dancing
with Gisèle.
Sir! Sir!
What are you doing?
Not that way!
Stop, stop!
My dear friend!
Who is that?
Those clothes!
How glad I am to see you!
To the left, this time,
and on the lawn, please!
Don't worry!
What a charming outfit! And unusual!
Isn't he charming, Jacques?
What a good idea to invite him!
- Invited?
- This way, please!
Do sit down --
in the place of honor!
Not he!
Anything, but not that!
Get out!
Jacques!
Your foster brother!
What!
- What's going on?
- She's mad.
She's mad, too!
I'll come back another time.
- Get out! Disappear!
- But Jacques!
Do you think we're in danger?
- I can't stand it!
- Dear lady ...
I can't bear this mad existence!
I give up, Jacques.
- I refuse to marry you.
- What?
- I'm so sorry to hurt you!
I know you meant to announce
our engagement tonight.
How marvelous!
This woman will drive me mad!
No irony, Jacques -- not after
two years trying to cure you!
Two years?
Yes, it's true -- two years ago
we decided to marry!
Could be.
Not a word is true!
Not a word ...?
Jacques!
Don't you remember Versailles?
Don't you remember the great alley
of russet oaks
on which twilight was ...
was falling?
Don't you remember?
- I remember!
- See, Pierre remembers!
- I don't blame you for your amnesia.
- That's rather sweet.
Nothing that happened to us
was really your fault.
That consoles me.
But you do love me, Jacques!
You do love me,
I know it!
But you forget me,
you lose me ...
And to find me again,
you look for me
in every other woman.
Just ask the women here!
What does she dare insinuate?
Oh Jacques, you'll never know
how much I've suffered!
And my suffering?
Does that mean nothing?
- Your suffering?
- Yes, every time you leave me!
You're always leaving me!
Even today,
when I begged you not to!
After all, I can't lock you up
in your bedroom!
Then why do you forget everything?
Why, why?
When we had to sleep on straw?
When we groped our way
along obscure paths?
Our journey in that horrid wagon?
The auto accident we had
together?
We could have died
that night ...
never knowing how our love
would end.
Because it's over, Jacques!
I'm leaving you!
Too bad for me!
Too bad for you --
for one day you'll regret
giving up a love like mine!
As I may regret not taking a chance
and risking everything!
Fascinating!
You know, neither one is crazy.
They're both crazy.
My love, if you won't take a chance --
- What's this?
- My love!
The farce is over,
the crowd has gone.
No, they followed me!
They're all here,
and we're madder than ever!
My love, if you won't take a chance,
I am resolute!
I won't let you leave my heart,
my life!
My estate, my house ...
My arms ...
Help me ...
Help me return to sanity.
They're mad about each other,
plain as rain!
- Eh?
- Plain as rain!
Perhaps.
Well, let's eat, anyhow!
It's true ...
they're all there!
See them peeking out!
- Catherine ...
- Jacques ...
So ... I'm no longer
a public danger?
Oh ... you're my love.
My angel ...
a devil of an angel!
Swear to me,
in our life going forward:
no more clocks!
- Not a one!
- You swear?
I swear.
Time means nothing to us now.
True.
Let's forget it.
- For ever.