What's happening?
Stop it, would you?
I do not want fights
at the market,
here we buy and sell honestly.
- Am I clear?
- Yes, all right.
Come on, give him your hand
Now the deal is over.
For you, don Francè
Be good.
Here, this is your cut.
Take care of it, Nicolì.
- Don Francè?.
- What's up?
Three, four, five...
- An important news.
- What's up?
- Don Pasquale Ronciglio is back.
- Oh yes?
- He's going crazy.
- What does he want?
He says he is
in charge here.
Does he say so?
Where is he now?
In the cows' pen
together with Tore the Scarred.
Let's go meet him
He must be with some friends.
Let's offer him a drink.
We must not think
that he came to provoke us.
You think so?
Maybe he wants to buy some
cows, who knows.
And if it's not
for that, then...
Well, then, it's his problem, don Francè.
He's over there, see?
Listen to me carefully
when Pasquale Ronciglio speaks
it is Law.
And nobody dares
to question his words.
And from today, here
everyone
must come to me.
and only to me,
got it?
Don Pasquà
Look who's here.
Don Francesco Aliprandi.
How come you're here?
That's what I ask you
I thought I explained
myself well
last time
didn't I?
You did indeed, as a God.
But you did not convince me.
No.
The market is big
too big for one man
so I thought to
leave the horned beasts to you
and the pigs for myself.
You are in charge of
the market for cows and oxen
and I the market for pigs.
It seems fair to me.
Or...
...do you want to be the
king of the horned beasts
and the pigs?
Do you know what I say?
It is a real pity
that we have not
organized
the shit market
otherwise...
... the king of the
assholes would be you!
Don Ciccio
the mouth that dares
to offend Pasquale Ronciglio
will not speak again
if not to apologize.
If you are a man of honor
I'll wait for you at 11:00pm
at the Arzano warehouse.
Agreed.
And to show you my
good intentions,
now,
I'll give you an advance.
Let's go.
Hello!
Daddy! Daddy!
My little prince
were you a good boy at school?
Yes, dad.
- Uh how cute!
- How cute it is!
- It's so tiny!
So champ, how are you?
Are you happy that your daddy
came pick you up, eh?
- Why do not you come all the times?
- Dad is busy
- Nicolino is here as well.
- No, he's short.
For you I am always short?
Next time I'll call a soldier!
I also want my friends to see you,
you are an important father.
All fathers are important.
Come on let's go buy the bike.
The bike?
Dad, you promised it
for my party.
Today it's a big party for me.
Wait dad
Let's go it's late.
What are you doing
leave that dog alone, let's go.
Robè, hurry up, would you?
Let's go
But it's so small,
it can't even walk.
Why do not we take it?
Do it for me, dad!
Sure, let's go around
collecting dogs on the street
let's do that
and it'll be perfect.
Dad, please
Let's take it!
Look
instead of the
bicycle, we take him.
Did not you want
the racing bike?
I do not care anymore,
this is better than a bike
But it does not run though.
It does not matter.
Alright then
whatever you want, my little prince.
Are you happy now?
Thanks Dad.
Go.
Be careful Nicolì,
dogs are messy, now you
will have to take care of them.
Jesus, Jesus, let's hope
he does not have fleas!
Right...
Be careful, you never know!
Even the dog now!
Nicolì, it is called Napoleon.
The Emperor!
Good evening...
To everyone, good evening!
My good evening
I give it
to Madam Rosa!
My good evening
I give it
to everyone!
Everyone in the
neighborhood must
gets my good evening!
I told everyone
good evening
Napoleon!
Wait wait!
No!
Stop, stop!
Don Franceso
Don Francesco!
What happened, Rosa?
What's all this
noise in the street?
A terrible thing, don Francè,
terrible!
A terrible thing?
What are you talking about?
Where is Roberto?
He wanted to catch the dog
that was running away
and a car ran over him!
Roberto! Roberto!
- My son, what have they done to you?
- Dad...
Dad, how's Napoleon?
Napoleon is fine
do not worry about it, think of you!
- Daddy do not cry, please!
- Don't move!
- Stay with me!
- No, I do not cry, yes,
I'll stay with you!
Do not leave me daddy,
help me, help me!
I will not leave you, Dad
helps you, Dad helps you!
Dad, do not leave me!
Your dad won't leave
you, he won't leave you.
Slowly.
Where are they taking me?
Come with me, dad!
Yes, yes I am coming with
you, do not worry.
Slow down, do not hurt him!
I'm so scared!
No, do not be afraid,
do not be afraid, my son!
Don Francè, I'll come along!
I'll go with you too!
All right Rosa, come with us.
Guys,
when you see him
you know what you have to do.
Dad, do not worry
it's nothing
you will see, it is nothing!
Jesus, Jesus
I can not think about it
I was there, two steps away
I tried to stop him
but it was not possible!
Jesus.
I thought I was going crazy!
Two hours have passed here,
how come
we still don't know anything?
Yes, tell me
Yes, yes.
Yes.
All right, I understand.
Yes, professor.
Sister, sorry
I'm Francesco Alibrandi,
the father of the child
that was brought here a
little while ago.
How is him?
Tell me, is it bad?
He's still in surgery
Rest assured,
they are doing
everything possible.
Did you get any news?
Are there any hopes for my son?
Sister, please, talk!
Only a miracle can save him.
But have faith,
God is so merciful,
even if sometimes
He wants to test us.
- Yes.
You are right!
Yes.
It's 11 and three quarters.
You are witnesses
I waited for him,
and he did not come
Francesco Aliprandi
is the last of the skunks.
Quite right!
Don Pasquà,
blood and wine
are the same color.
Now we are going to
have a nice soup,
a glass of Gragnano
at the tavern of Peppino The Russian.
It's a good idea
and call also a good guitar player
tonight around me I want
singing and good music.
Let's go guys.
Oxygen, oxygen.
Mother Mary...
"God is merciful
even if sometimes
he tests us".
Blood pressure?
It's collapsing, professor.
Increase oxygen.
If God is truly merciful
so you must be as well,
as you are a mother!
Roberto must not die.
It is not right for
a child like him
to pay without a blame.
Do not abandon him,
be close to him.
If someone has to suffer,
then choose me
and save Roberto.
He's all I have left.
Save my son, Mother Mary.
I give you my word of honor
that I will apologize
to Don Pasquale Ronciglio.
I swear I will do it
but you must save him!
You must save him...
We have done everything possible
but...
... I do not think
he will manage.
And speaking of wine
let's drink to the Neapolitan song!
The most beautiful song in the world!
And then let's have a toast
to the health of Don
Pasquale Ronciglio,
the sugar of all Naples!
Hurray Pasquale!
Great Pasquale!
Don Francesco Aliprandi
do you like to do
April's fool off season ?
Or maybe your watch doesn't work
Don Pasqua'
before all these friends
I humbly apologize to you
for what happened at the market.
I was crazy, sorry.
You heard, eh?
Don Francesco has converted
and he has became St. Francis!
Don Pasqua',
I did my duty.
I apologized
do not push it.
The scale can tilt over.
Alright then.
But since I appreciate
and I respect you
I want to give you back
a little improved
that deposit
that you have given me.
You gave me water
and I give you wine.
So we're even, eh?
Don Francè?
Don Francè,
did everything go well?
Did it go well or not?
Nicolì,
I'm like that eel.
Look,
it is broken, yet it still moves
it wants to pretend it is alive.
But it's not true.
It's dead.
It's dead, like me.
- Documents - Hurry,
I'm in a hurry.
Right away, Sir
Brigadier, I am here
at your orders!
I'm not a brigadier.
Jesus, so to speak.
No offense.
What happened?
It happened
that you have done
a right turn
without signaling it
and therefore you must
get a ticket.
Uh, Jesus!
A right turn?
It is not possible!
Why is not it possible?
It's not possible because...
... my steering wheel is blocked.
It doesn't
turn right!
I understand, all right,
circulation license.
What license?
The license for public transport.
Is this a taxi?
What taxi, brigadier?
Where is the taxi?
This! Is it yours?
- Which one?
- The taxi!
This is a taxi, isn't it?
Yes, it's also written so,
Brigadier, that's my name
Nicolino Tassi,
at your command!
You even
painted it yellow?!
Why? You don't like yellow?
It's a beautiful color!
Wait a moment.
Sir, yes sir, brigadier!
Go on!
I'll miss the plane
but what the heck!
- Right away
the plane will wait
do not worry!
What..are you crazy?
He's calling you
- No...
What do you want?
Are you in a hurry or not?
In the North, these things
don't happen...
So, are you done?
All right, Francè.
So go have lunch, come on.
Thank you.
Go eat!
Okay then
at three o'clock
you'll be here.
Okay engineer, see you!
Francè I'm going to eat,
see you later.
Don Francesco.
Don Francesco, here you are!
I told you many times
get rid of that "don".
I do not want to
repeat it anymore,
do you understand?
I humbly beg your pardon,
Don Francesco.
Again?
See, it's stronger than me
what can I do?
- All right, forget it.
- What do you want?
I want to tell you that
the results are out.
- The results?
- Eh!
The school report card
of your son!
And how did he go?
How did he go?
Like a supersonic plane,
Don Francesco!
All right, forget it
it does not matter
tell me!
He passed with great scores!
He's now an accountant!
Accountant!
Eh, what a big deal, he's not an emperor!
Oh my God.
Don Francè
are not you happy?
- Yes, I'm happy.
At least this crappy job,
has given me this
joy, eh!
Tomorrow we will
celebrate, Nicolì!
Of course!
Did you bring me
something to eat?
Of course I did!
An excellent omelette
with side dish of dessert
that's eggs and cheese
do you try to make them
more appealing now?
Eh, Nicolì?
you know how it is
to sugarcoat
makes life more bearable.
Did you eat?
No, I have a child's stomach
that just...
- I get it
when you talk like
this, you're starving
eat, come on.
- Just to taste it
just to taste it!
Would you like some?
Who are those people?
What do you care,
think about eating
I was just saying...
What do you want?
Don Pasquale sent us.
They told us,
that you know why.
One moment,
there must be a mistake.
I do not know anything about this.
- That's enough!
- Leave me!
- Get in there.
We'll show you...
Salvatore, look at him,
doesn't he look like
Francesco Aliprandi?
Who, that beggar over there?
Yes, the big one that's eating.
Yeah, it's him
let's see what he says
that piece of shit.
Let's go check it out.
I know it's a frittata
but omelette is nicer.
Let me look at him.
Let me look at him good
this stinky one.
- It's him!
I do not think so.
This one seems
an honest person.
He is a man who works.
Do you question my words?
We can find out immediately.
If he shits in his pants
You're right.
Go away.
Francesco Aliprandi,
stand up.
Do you understand? Get up!
It's him!
Francesco Aliprandi
is a piece of shit!
All Naples knows it!
And the whole world
must know it!
Roberto...
... is an accountant, eh?
Did I bother you?
You're an ass!
I won't sing then...
I raise the glass
to the health of the
new accountant!
- Best wishes!
- Good boy!
- Best wishes to Robertino!
Dad,
we'll keep this.
Best wishes, best wishes and best wishes!
- Best wishes!
- To health, to yours, best wishes!
- Thank you.
- The cake!
- No, I do not
want the cake, eh!
I baked it, it came out really well.
Accountant?
He has the face
of Ministry of Finance!
Nicolì, what are you
doing, you are making fun of Roberto?
Why?
No, I said
the Swiss Ministry of Finance!
Hey Mariù,
do not you wish Roberto well?
Come on, give him
a kiss, come on.
No.
Why not, what's
wrong with you?
He saw you when you were born
and now you are shy?
Come here Mariù
I'll give you a kiss.
Give him the kiss, come on!
- Ugh!
Behave!
Mariù!
Why are you acting like that?
Mariù where are you going?
Come here right away, come on!
Mariù!
Come on, come back to the table, Mariù
They are wild at that age
don't mind it.
Hey, what are we doing?
Don't we dance?
The dance of honor is up to me, eh!
Who raised
this amazing boy?
Are you hitting on me, Rosa?
I raised you like a mother,
you are like my son.
So, let's start the dances!
I would dance with the lady!
Hey Nicolì
Nicolì, do not push it!
Absolutely not!
Mrs..
Humbly...
... I was a Charleston champion!
Thanks Francè.
Giovà, I wanted to talk to you.
Why, what have we been doing so far?
No, please, do not joke around
I speak seriously.
All right.
Oh boy,
I'm not as young as you are.
What do you think, I'm old now
old unfortunately!
What are you saying, Donna Rosa?
You are still a babba'!
Sure...
You're a candy, Donna Rosa!
What I have done so far
I did it only for Roberto
to give him an honest life.
I suffered everything,
insults, humiliations
they spared me nothing,
nothing, dear Giovanni.
If you are up and go down
nobody helps you.
This is life, my dear.
Yes, but I want to
change this life.
I am fed up
to always be among people
that remind me of
what I used to be.
Well you know it.
I'm a theatre entrepreneur,
and if you'll come to the
theater tomorrow
I'm sure together
we will find a deal, okay?
- Thank you.
I knew I could count on you.
Do not even mention it.
My lady!
You are very tall!
Stop now Robertino please
my head is spinning,
I'm collapsing
What are you saying, Rosa?
you never collapse,
you are eternal!
Are you kidding?
Oh my God, oh my God, my God
my head is spinning!
Sorry, sorry.
Donna Rosa has given up!
Would you like to dance?
Hey, what's wrong?
- You don't like me at all?
- No, no
I do not dislike you.
So, Princess Cinderella,
Would you like to dance with me?
Madam, I was born to dance!
How beautiful they are!
Let's cheer to our
accountant, Francè!
To our health!
So, let's start from
the point that says:
"You have a mustache
and take these slaps "
All right?
Francesco Aliprandi is looking for you.
Come come!
Are you ready?
Of course I'm ready.
You should focus on your
character's face!
- Hi
- Sit down.
So you are giving me your advice!
Who should I give it to, my grandma?
Mother Mary, Oh my God!
- After so many years of glorious career.
- They are starting.
- Start, it is late.
- Come on!
Right from there you
had to start, yes?
From the slaps!
I have to remember
the beginning!
You have a mustache
and now take these slaps!
Holy God!
Oh my God!
The theater will burst!
No, no, no!
The theatre won't burst
But my name will
fall from the poster!
What the hell did
the author write?
You'll see that this asshole
will make a mess!
Calm down Giovà
What do you want,
this is what the author wrote
do you want to stop it or not?
I say
a positive man like me
of such an importance!
Yes, of such an importance,
let's say...
Let's say it, a man of honor!
An honorable!
He treats me like shit
in front of everyone
and I do not say anything?
Look at him, Jesus
in his normal life
people treat him like shit continuously
and he never does anything,
but today he can't take it!
So you know what we do?
You will say the line
and he gets the slap, alright?
Are you okay with that or not?
Good, I like it, good!
All right!
Yes, so the theater tonight
will be covered
with whistles and boos!
All right
it's right.
- Are you all right with that?
- Yes, it's OK with me.
Should not I spit in your face?
Let's calm down everyone
Listen, say what you want
but I won't do the
act like this!
Ah, no?
I'd make an ass of myself
in front of the audience!
- Aren't you used to it?
- What?
You're making me
lose my patience!
I can't believe it!
You have been signed up
to be a villain, or not?
Good!
Very well, finally
you said it!
The villain!
Not the moron!
Jesus, but...
...but you know it
you have been taking slaps
all your life
now you are suddenly ashamed
of it
and you do not want any more
so, you are doing it on purpose!
At least let me die by murder!
If it were a pivotal scene
I'd say yes!
I'd make such a fallen Madonna
that will make the theatre burst!
Who are you? Trinita'?!
Shut up,
what are you talking about!
I should shut up?
He's got so many aches and pains
he can't even walk
All right
Yes!
Next time
I will put it in the contract
slap, spit in the face
and kick in the ass
never!
No...!
You must tell me when
I will sign you up again!
I do not understand
are we professionals
or amateurs!?
Holy words!
You know what?
you broke my balls
like two salami of Afragola!
A professional actor..
- Me, me!
- No!
Professional?
You are the head
of the artistic incompetence!
You are the dramatic result
of compulsory schooling
That's enough!
Work
or you will not be paid
No, no, what do you
say Don Giovà...
I expressed my opinion
but if you do not agree
there are no problems!
- He regretted.
Listen up, listen up!
Here I am the first
actor, or not?
Yes sir, you play the first actor
I don't play it, I am it!
So, if I'm the first actor
I'll be able to slap tons!
Come on, slap him and go on!
- Here!
- No, no, no!
I won't do it, I won't
do it and I won't do it!
He won't do it, he won't
do it, he won't do it!
- Author!
What an hassle
I can never be calm.
- Author!
Author I say it!
Author says he!
Author!
Call the author!
A moment, what's up?
Let's see if it's possible
to take slaps off the script!
I say yes!
I can't take anything off.
It's the song!
We must respect the rhymes.
You remember the lines
Yes or no?
Sure!
"You have a mustache
and take these slaps "
Is it clear?
You see?
It also rhymes.
You are the one
with the mustache,
and so you are the one that
gets the slaps!
Oh yes?
So I'll take off my mustache!
At least, I say
give me the satisfaction
to have a scuffle!
Yes, maybe
we'll put a ring on the stage...
But there is no guappo
that would allow to be mortified
in front of the people!
You do not say anything!
I'll tell you!
I won't do it like that.
He won't do it.
Which guappo
would be mortified
in front of people like that?
- This is not a guappo.
- And what then? What?
It is filth!
Ah, it's just filth...
You said a great truth,
great truth.
It is the ideal
character for you
Ideal for me?
And now you know
what I tell you?
That you'll play
your character!
Or else, you will never work again!
Is it clear?
- All right?
Okay I say so!
All right, he says so!
Yes, of course I say it!
You have a mustache too.
So take these slaps!
Madonna, he killed me!
Is it possible that one
must get angry
early in the morning?
I tried to give some sense
to my role,
because a guappo
that does not react
is not a guappo!
But if it's okay with you...
At least try to pay
me a little more
as an incentive.
- I protest!
- Forget it...
Giovà I don't think today is
a good day to speak about work.
Let's talk later, okay?
All right.
Nicolì call Roberto, let's go.
Right away.
My gentlemen
You know what?
It is useless to go
around obstacles.
Let us postpone the matter
of the slaps this evening.
Let's get back to rehearsing, come on.
Yes Yes Yes.
we'll do everything you want
but I stick with my mind.
Yeah Ok...
- Are you stuck?
- One moment...
Come on, your father
is waiting for you!
- And I would like to hear the scream
- Yes, I scream too
Come on!
- You have a mustache face...
- Robè...
Go easy, we're rehearsing.
And do not move!
You have a mustache face
and get these slaps!
Good!
Good! Bis! Again
Robè, you too now?
- Go, Dad is waiting for you
- Come on Robè...
Come on, from the beginning.
Let's take it back from the slap
without giving him the slap.
Hello!
Do not you remember me?
Were you in the
theater at the rehearsal?
In front row...
And if I'm not mistaken
you also looked at my legs.
How could I not look at them
they were so beautiful.
What are you doing here?
I was waiting.
Waiting for whom?
You.
You me?
And why?
Because...
...well...
... I wanted to see you again!
Look,
do we want to quit
with being so formal,
what do you think?
And do we want to quit
saying nonsense?
I do not like being stopped
in the street, all right?
And...
... how did you know
that I was there at Sannazzaro?
Uncle Giovanni told me.
I wanted to see you again
after that audition at the theatre
- I mean, wait
- And no, eh...
Or both, or nothing
We become informal
and you leave me alone okay?
But why
I'm not a thief.
If it were enough
not to be a thief
do you know how many people I
would have chasing me?
Well considering our times
very few.
Maybe you're right.
You know, I think it's
hard to get rid of you.
In your opinion,
what should I do?
Scream with joy
to see you again
and throw my arms
around your neck?
No, but we could get to know
each other better
go out together sometimes.
Should I consider it an
official invitation?
Yes, an official invitation!
You're rich then.
I'm not complaining.
Would you like to go
to the cinema?
I can not stand it.
Look, there's a better idea.
I know a place
where it is possible
to have a snack and dance.
- Agreed?
- Agreed!
So, see you tonight.
See you tonight!
It's the mirror's fault.
you don't see yourself?
You are handsome!
Sorry dad.
No thanks, I'm not
hungry anymore.
No no thank you.
No thanks Rosa, I'm
not hungry anymore.
Now you repeat what I say?
Sorry dad
I'm not really hungry tonight.
That's no true, you've devoured the soup!
Soup?
Yes, of course, the soup
That's why I'm not
hungry anymore.
Listen you...
Leave him alone, Rosa.
He is in a hurry to go out.
Did not you notice?
He deserves it.
He studied all year long.
- Go ahead
- Thanks dad!
Look dad...
Here is the request, eh!
I get it, I get it.
Ten thousand liras.
I'm sorry I can
not give you more.
Daddy, it will be enough!
Do not worry, thanks, bye!
- Bye Rosa!
- Be careful, my son!
Pretty boy!
Roberto!
What's up?
Where are you going?
Out.
Out where?
What do you care?
So?
Go on.
Then at some point
he stops the Rolls
and he tells me:
"Do you want to get out, honey?"
And I, confused:
"Why? I do not live here."
And he: "Yes I know
but I want to show you
a little thing. "
Same brand?
Of course, same brand.
Do not you drink?
You look upset...
Are you feeling bad?
No, I'm fine
Do not worry.
As you want
so what was I saying?
Ah yes, here
I do not trust the guy
very much
but I get out the car anyway.
He takes me to a
big jewelry store.
He takes a necklace of emeralds
and puts it around my neck.
He says to me: "It's yours!
And if you do not like
it we'll change it,
and take everything you want!
And then?
After?
There is not a later...
... I always wake up
at the same point!
Do you believe in dreams?
Do you believe that
if you dream
always the same thing
at some point, it'll come true?
I do not know
I never dreamed.
But it is not possible!
Everyone dreams.
Maybe you do not remember it.
No, it's impossible.
I have a strong memory.
I remember even
the color of the panties
that you brought when
I saw you the first time.
Shame on you
you shouldn't say certain things.
Listen, what do you do in life?
So what's your job?
I do nothing.
Are you that rich?
No, I mean
that I am unemployed.
I finished school
a month ago.
You're one of those
daddy's brats
graduates, lawyers,
what are you?
I am an accountant,
only accountant.
Accountant?
Are there accountants
that are millionaires?
That made a lot of money?
I do not think so.
I like this song,
let's go!
This way.
Who's that girl?
I do not know her
it's the first time
she comes here.
And is she alone?
No, she's with that guy.
Please, Mr. Ronciglio.
What can we bring you tonight?
The usual.
Good.
Not bad at all the girl, eh?
I like dancing.
I would do it all night.
What is this?
The bill.
Damn, what a rip-off!
Why, how much is it?
Fifty thousand.
Something wrong, sir?
No, it's that...
I'm afraid I don't have
enough money with me.
What are you talking about?
You do not have the money
to pay the bill?
What's happening?
The gentleman can not
pay the bill.
- Take them to the office.
- Please gentlemen.
One moment.
They are my guests.
And bring them a bottle
of what I drink.
- Right away.
Have a seat.
You are very kind.
Really...
... I do not know
how to thank you.
Mr.?
Ronciglio.
There is nothing to thank about.
It's nothing.
I like
to be with young people
Especially when
they look so nice.
Thank you.
You are very kind, Mr. Ronciglio.
What's your name?
Ninfarosa.
A graceful name.
And what do you do?
I am an actor in a small theatre.
Nothing important yet.
You're young, you have
time to succeed.
It depends on your effort
and on the right friendships.
And what do you do?
Nothing at the moment,
I'm unemployed.
Roberto is an accountant,
he graduated recently.
And, you know
nowadays
he has yet to find a
permanent job.
He also
needs
the right friendship.
But he does not have it...
Come on, Ninfarosa
this is not the moment.
Let her talk, what's wrong
You care about it, do not you?
I would be very grateful
to whom would give him a hand.
Let me look into it.
Tomorrow
come here in my name
and something could be done.
All will work out fine.
- Thank you!
- No worries.
To your luck, guys.
Now let's have fun, eh?
Shall we dance?
With pleasure.
Dolphin calls Shark.
If you are listening, answer.
Over.
Shark listening.
I am in the established area.
Over.
Over..
Damn, where are you
I can't see you
you're making me lose my sight.
Make me a daisy.
How are you?
all ok?
Good, good enough.
You'll see that next time
it will be even better.
Here they are!
All right, shut off.
I saw them.
It's positive!
Come on, we are almost done
Boy, ready?
Yes done!
All right!
Roberto!
You finally arrived!
My love!
Here it is.
Say what you want
but for me the best coffee
is always the
old-fashioned one.
Those modern traps
are good for nothing.
I agree!
Hurry up Rosa
or I'll be late.
Here it is.
How is this work going?
I'd like you to
tell me something
about what you do and
who these people are.
Come on Robè,
talk to your dad.
Dad, now it's just
a training period.
For superstition,
I prefer not to say anything.
And you know
it's about administrative checks.
A company... of canned food.
You know
accounting books,
tax reports,
then if they are happy,
in two months they will hire me.
That's all?
That's all.
Now I have to go, bye dad.
Dear Rosa,
this boy
is not telling the truth.
I'm loaded, go!
So, are you happy?
- I'm really happy.
- You like it, eh?
Yes!
You are indeed earning a lot
of money
with this job!
Can't complain!
Is it dangerous?
No, it's not dangerous
it's a piece of cake for me!
- Wait up!
Look, that's so pretty
Will you buy it for me?
Which one?
The one over there.
All right, come in.
- Will it be very expensive?
- No, come, come!
I'll buy you
whatever you want!
This one, Mariù?
I do not like it.
Then your mother will come see it.
Come on, move
or your mum will get angry!
And what are you doing here?
Why do not you go
back home?
Are you angry with me?
And with whom then?
With Roberto.
Roberto?
What did Roberto do to you?
Come on, tell me everything.
Come on.
So?
I met him this morning.
He was with a girl
and he kissed her
in front of everybody!
Where?
In the middle of the road.
In the middle of the road!
Here, now talk slowly
and tell me everything
Ok Mariù?
Go, go, boy, go!
Yes, get close.
So you are the accountant, eh?
Good,
full inventory
boat and warehouse
and be careful,
Don Pasquale is very picky.
All right.
- Have you got the load invoice?
- I have nothing.
Have you got the warehouse load invoice?
Yes, here is everything
you just have to check it
and sign the receipt.
All right.
Robè?
Yes, dad?
Come here.
Actually I'm tired
I would like to go to bed.
Instead, you will
talk to me first.
It has been a long time
that we haven't seen each other,
you and me.
Come here.
Well you know...
... there is a lot of
work at the office
and then...
And then there are women
What did you say?
Who's that girl,
who kissed you on the street
without being ashamed?
Who told you?
This does not matter.
Answer.
She is a girl.
This I already knew.
- And then?
- And then nothing.
We get along well
and we go out from time to time.
Once, we were
used to introduce
the girlfriend to our parents.
Dad, she's not a girlfriend.
Nowadays,
these things are not serious.
Maybe to you.
- Not me.
- Sorry dad come on.
One doesn't have to marry
all the women who...
who...?
Go on...
I mean
we get along well
and that's it.
Who is she?
You know her,
she works in Uncle Giovanni's theatre.
She is a young actress.
- Ah, that little hottie?
- Do not call her that!
I call her what she deserves.
She has already
caused a lot of trouble.
Careful Robè
Those are women
that first lift you up
and then sink you.
Ninfarosa will not do it
- She's like the others too
- No, they're all lies!
And I do not allow you
to say that!
What did you say?
You do not allow me?
Your father?
Sorry dad.
It's that now I'm
not a kid anymore.
I'm a man.
And I have the right
to my own opinion.
The rights are won
by merits.
Not by chatter!
Your mother, before she died
I promised
to defend you any cost
- And I'll do it Robè!
- All right, defend me.
Defend me from
whatever you want!
But do not push yourself
into my life!
Because it's mine and mine
alone, do you understand?
Roberto!
What will you
show me now?
Now I'll show you
all the land on which
we have put our hands
before the Regulatory Plan.
But...
- Are these lands close to town?
- Yup.
That is, outside town
but near the houses
all in the building area
with building permits.
What about the mayor?
All right, the Plan is precise.
Excuse me.
- Don't worry.
- Come, come.
Sorry Don Pasquale
I would like to show you
the last operation
in Mergellina.
Here it is
This
is the withdrawal made
for the gasoline for
the deliveries
and this one instead
here, this one
is the fuel withdrawal
for the motorboats.
- Very good, Roberto
- And this...
... this is the amount
given to men
employed in the operation.
Please sign over here.
Good job.
- I see you're accurate.
- Thank you.
- He's a good boy, I'm happy.
- Yup.
So Don Pasqua',
here are the areas
that interest us.
Don Francesco still
owns the Mercedes.
Good for him.
The only thing left from
when he was a Boss.
Where's the stuff,
did you steal it?
You have to pay for it,
do you understand?
Leave this boy immediately!
Piece of shit!
Who are you?
Come here.
What did those two want?
- Money.
- Money?
Why?
Because...
... they gave me some stuff
and now...
... now they wanted to be paid.
Why?
For this.
Drugs?
You are crazy!
At your age?
Do you want to ruin yourself?
Stop!
You go away
and you too.
As for you.
I advise you not to meddle
if you do not want
Don Pasquale Ronciglio
to get pissed off
Ronciglio!
Even the children...
Listen to me,
listen to me well.
You came out of the games
covering yourself with shit
and covered with shit.
You have to hide
You are out from guapperia
And if you want to
live without trouble
think about your own business
don't get involved.
Is it clear?
You're out.
This is not guapperia
it's just disgusting.
Anyway, I've warned you.
You're out!
How disgusting...
Ninfarosa!
Ninfarò where are you?
Hello.
I didn't hear you get in.
What's wrong?
What was Pasquale
Ronciglio doing here?
My business.
Are you jealous now?
I do not want that man
to step foot in this house
He must not look at you.
Is it clear?!
Wait a moment
I do not take orders from anyone
and from you the least!
I see who I like
and when I like.
If it suits you, it's
like that and we are friends
or else...
- Whore!
I do not allow you to
talk to me like that
and I will not allow
that filthy man
to do as he wishes!
- Where are you going?
- Guess.
No...
Roberto, wait a moment.
Roberto!
Since when you don't
knock the door?
I have to talk to you.
It's not a good reason
get out and knock
Don Pasquale, I have to talk
to you about serious things.
You?
You are kidding me
before talking about
serious things
you must be a man.
And to become a man,
it will take some time.
I want you to leave Ninfarosa alone.
I want?
- Did you say exactly "I want"?
- Yup.
I said it.
You are crazy.
Today your head isn't working.
Go away or I'll kick you
in the ass.
Let's settle this thing, first.
You'd better.
Listen up, boy,
why should I do it?
If I leave
being kicked by you
from this office.
I'll be back
soon
with the police!
Police?
What does the police
have to do with it?
I've understood something too
Don Pasquale Ronciglio
and in certain situations
everyone uses the weapons he can
and you do not just import rags
And what do you know
about it?
I know.
The police still doesn't
but I do.
I know everything
that happens here.
and dealing drugs isn't a game.
You know it well
is it not true?
Sure.
I know it very well,
you are definitely right
but there is no reason
to make it a big deal.
Work is one thing,
private matters another.
No, for me there
is no difference.
We just need to talk through
these things!
Among people of honor
there must not be any
misunderstandings,
and a woman
has never been so important,
for Pasquale Ronciglio,
to push him to
compromise work
and friendships.
Yup...
I like Ninfarosa.
I do not deny it.
But not to the point
to risk my position.
You can keep her.
She's yours.
Then you assure me
that you will not see her again?
Sure.
On your honor?
I assure you
that girl
will no longer be a
reason for disagreement
between us two.
Word of Pasquale Ronciglio.
Thank you.
Greetings, boy.
Come.
Come, come.
Listen to me very well.
I have a job for you.
A job that will
have to be perfect.
You will have to get
rid of that young man...
... that young man
forever.
Sorry
Does the Aliprandi
family live here?
- Yes, on the third floor.
- Thank you.
What do you want, my
son is not here.
You...
... are you Roberto's father?
And you are Ninfarosa!
For God's sake
forget it, it's serious!
- What is serious?
- Roberto!
They want to kill him!
Kill?
Who wants
to kill my son?
Speak for God's sake!
Pasquale Ronciglio!
Ronciglio?
and what does my son
have to do with him?
with Ronciglio, speak!
- He has worked for him for more than two months.
- For him?
They must have had
a fight for me.
Where is Roberto now?
I heard that Tore
is supposed to take him
at sea
for a load of cigarettes.
In Santa Lucia, then
Ronciglio keeps his motorboats
there.
I'll come with you!
Get away from me!
- Don Salvatore...
- Hello!
- My regards.
Are not you ready yet?
All right, don Salvatò,
all right.
What's all this about?
There were no scheduled
trips today.
Programs are dangerous
they always end up
at the ears of the wrong person.
There is a special
load over there
and it's up to us to pick it up.
Something wrong?
No nothing, I was just saying.
Jump down, move!
So, what are you waiting for?
Let's go!
Go.
Don Francè, I'll go with you.
No, go to the small pier.
Stop.
You are not allowed!
Stop!
What do you want?
Get away!
Hurry up, turn
the engine on
or I will shoot
you in the mouth!
Come on, hurry up,
do as I say
or I will kill you!
Come on, run, run!
What are you doing?
Do not waste time, hurry up!
Come on!
Faster!
You know where they are!
Go on, go, go!
Faster. faster!
When will we get there?
In a quarter of an hour.
Are you in a hurry?!
We have all the time
we need.
Come on!
What's happened?
I do not know.
Maybe a problem
with the engine,
go, take a look
You are good with these things, no?
Hurry!
There is my son there!
Fast, hurry up!
Hurry up!
Do not worry
Roberto is also my friend.
Good,
it's done!
Pull over,
that's him.
Fast, hurry up.
Let's help him, let's help him!
Pull over, pull over!
Hurry up!
Robè...
Roberto,
my son,
tell me, what did
they do to you?
What did they do to you, eh?
Do not cry, dad.
Yes, I cry.
I cry, my son, I cry, I cry!
Yes..
No, no!
No, my dear son
I only have you,
do not leave me!
Do not leave me, please,
my dear son!
No, no!
My dear son...
Quick, run, run fast!
They have to save my son!
And now
I would like to propose a toast
to the health of Don
Pasquale Ronciglio
and to his fortune!
Congratulations don Pasquale!
- Best wishes!
- Thanks, cheers to you!
You cooked him.
Now eat him!
I do not carry weapons
don Francesco Aliprandi.
You can not shoot
a defenseless man.
You can not do it.
You are a man of honor!
I have no weapons.
You can not do it.
I am a finished man.
Find a gun and defend yourself.
Because I want to kill you!
You can not, Don Francesco
This is a good place
You can not do it
here, you can not!
Don Francè, look behind!
Out, out!
Pasquale Ronciglio.
Piece of shit.
My dear son...
Here, that's the ship!
You know, I know the captain
he is a friend, a Greek.
Yes, a Greek,
a man of honor,
one of those like us.
Thank you...
I'll deal with it.
I'll go and get back right away
Right away!
Yes.
I must return.
I promised you that I
have to come back.
My son...
You're an important dad...
All fathers
are important...
I raise the glass, to the
health of the new accountant...
I see you...
My son...
A terrible accident
a car hit him.
No Roberto!
- Were you good at school?
- Yes, dad!
Roberto.
Don Francè, all right!
Don Francè!
Don Francè, all
right, all right!
Don Francè...
You do not have to
worry, Nicolì.
You said it
It's all right.
You will see, I will come back.
What are you doing, are you crying?
Do not cry,
do not cry Nicolì!
Every man has his destiny.
It was written like this.
Nicolì...
Goodbye, my Naples.
How many sorrows you gave me...
But you will always
be in my heart.
Goodbye, my Naples.
Goodbye.