(organ music)
(whip cracking)
(groaning)
(shouting)
(screaming)
(clanking)
(indistinct chatter)
(shouting)
(groaning)
No!
(gulping)
You’re a monster.
The devil has possessed you.
(grunting)
No!
(shouting)
(groaning)
My sweet, my darling,
I love you.
Let my love unite our souls.
(groaning)
Don’t resist.
Open your heart to me.
(groaning)
(groaning continues)
(shouting)
(groaning)
(laughing, applause)
(indistinct chatter)
(soft music)
(music stopping)
Okay, Charlie, hold everything
for the front page, will you?
Got that? Good.
-How’s my favorite boss?
-Fine, Anna.
-Here’s the mail.
-Ah, thank you.
How did you like
the performance last night?
I am a great actress.
-You’re a what?
-I’ve got talent.
Talent? What matters to me
is the box office tape.
Oh, in that case,
you should be very happy
because we had
a hell of a crowd.
-Excuse me.
-Okay, come on in.
-Good morning, Raymond.
-Hello, Vogel.
-Good morning, young lady.
-Morning, sir.
Here’s the story you wanted
for the next issue
-of your magazine.
-That’s fine.
Very interesting,
the torture chambers
of the Inquisition.
Huh, it’s got punch.
The storyline is not so hot,
but all of the details
are absolutely authentic
and some of them
are quite extraordinary.
My dear Vogel, your humility
as a writer is very touching,
but you know as well as I do
that our readers eat up
those sadomasochistic stories
of yours.
Oh, I don’t invent anything.
It’s all based on
real-life experience,
not my personal experience.
Really?
You’re a man of science,
Mr. Vogel.
We must know evil
to be able to fight it.
They tell me you used to be
a priest once.
Some people will say anything.
Tell me, Vogel, my friend,
are you an unfrocked priest
or not?
What difference does it make?
Well, it’s an interesting angle.
We could publish a serial:
Memoirs of an Unfrocked Priest.
We could try it.
I’ll let you know.
Anyway, I’ll drop in soon.
-All right.
-Goodbye.
A pleasure. Goodbye, Mr. Vogel.
Goodbye, Miss Anna.
Hmm...
(laughing)
He really is a weirdy.
He scares the pants off me.
Don’t be silly,
he’s perfectly harmless.
It’s nothing
but a literary pose.
How about a nice little kiss?
(moaning)
I’m going to scare you, yeah.
We’ll organize
a real Black Mass.
-Really?
-Really.
-We’ll conjure up the devil.
-My god.
(moaning)
That’s right, we’re going
to be needing a girl
for the sacrificial victim.
How exciting.
Mrs. Cartier will be
the celebrant.
And I’ll go and find a victim
at the Beelzebub Club.
-Not coming to my place?
-Not now.
Bad boy, you’re so cruel.
(moaning)
(organ music)
-Oh, please.
-No, not here.
Yeah, come to my place.
Oh, come on.
Oh, come on, please.
Huh?
(giggling)
(owl hooting)
(clicking)
(indistinct chatter)
Ah, Rose! Hello.
Hello.
-You’re late.
-Oh, I’ve got news for you.
-What is it?
-We’ve got to find
a sacrifice victim
for Saturday.
Why do we need somebody else?
It’s for a real Black Mass.
-How about the crypt?
-Oh, the crypt is a good idea.
Marina will be there,
maybe we can talk her into it.
Okay.
Speed up and come on.
Be right with you.
(funky music)
-Hi!
This Black Mass...
-How are you?
-Hi, Ray.
What the hell
is a Black Mass anyway?
-Hi, honey. Hi!
-Oh, well, it’s a lot of fun
and all that, you know.
You go through the motions
of a Black Mass.
There’s lots of millionaires,
it ends in a gangbang.
-Rich girls too?
-Plenty.
There’s something
for every taste,
and they are all rich.
You can count on
making a bundle.
Oh, and what exactly
am I supposed to do?
Oh! Nothing special.
Just make it.
Only make it with who? Anybody?
-You could always try Raymond.
-Aw!
If you prefer,
you can get yourself a girl.
There’s no shortage
of naked women.
(laughing)
-Coming?
-Uh...
I wouldn’t miss it
for anything.
Okay, then it’s settled.
To us. Cheers!
(music stopping)
(birds chirping)
(organ and guitar music)
(barking)
"Apartments for rent."
(music stopping)
-Uh, how do you do?
-Yes, sir?
Do you have an apartment
available?
Yes, sir, I do.
An apartment
overlooking the street?
Yes, I think so, sir.
Thank you. In that case,
I’ll take it.
Very well, sir.
-Your name, please?
-Mathis Daniel.
Mathis Daniel.
(soft music)
(sighing)
Ooh, I’m worn out.
Typical.
You’re always tired.
Too lazy even to hang up
your things.
It’s resting
that keeps me young.
How can you live
in a mess like this?
Anyhow, that way
I can find everything.
Very funny.
(guitar music)
Can I give you a hand?
(chuckles)
Here, catch.
Oopla.
Now what?
(giggling)
-Let’s make love.
-Why not?
(laughing)
-Let’s rehearse for Saturday.
-The Black Mass, yes.
Our own show.
So, how will we do it?
Ooh, tell me, Anna.
You’ll be the young lover.
I’ll be the shy virgin.
You’ll wear a long, black cloak.
I’ll be carrying
a concealed dagger
to protect my virtue,
so watch out.
You’re going to need more
than a dagger.
Prove it.
I surrender.
And I’ll take my dagger
and caress you very gently.
Stroke you with it gently,
just enough not to break
the skin.
And when you are trembling
with excitement,
I’ll kill you!
(laughing)
(music stopping)
I could use a drink.
I’ll join you.
Oh, hell, another customer.
Good evening. I hope
I’m not too late to be served.
That’s all right, sir.
What’ll you have?
-Scotch.
-Right away.
Any particular brand?
Uh, no.
Buy me a drink?
If you like.
Take what you want.
Marina, another Scotch.
What are you doing out so late?
I can’t stand crowded places.
It’s sad to be alone.
Everything is sad.
This place,
was it a church once?
Who cares what it was?
Yes, who cares?
Here’s to churches.
Look, would you mind
coming with me?
-Where to?
-My place.
Gonna be nice to me?
Yes, very nice to you.
Do you live nearby?
Nearby.
Let’s go, there’s no time
to lose.
I’ll just slip into my clothes.
(howling)
(organ music)
Quite a place you’ve got here.
It serves my purpose.
-Come on.
-Hey, what’s the big hurry?
Ah, yes.
Make yourself at home.
(sighing)
(music stopping)
(speaking Latin)
(soft moaning)
(clears throat)
Where did you go?
-Where were you?
-I was praying.
I pray before anything I do.
I have a private chapel.
Chapel?
Yes, I have a chapel
in my house.
What’s strange about that?
Oh?
Nothing, I guess.
Only you don’t usually find them
in places I go.
I’m not surprised,
you’re a whore.
Hey, go easy.
I bet you don’t find
many honest, God-fearing men
among the customers
you associate with.
That’s not true.
One of my customers
once took me to a mass.
So piety is not dead yet?
It’s not what you think.
It was a Black Mass.
A Black Mass?
Yes, it was
an exciting evening.
How many times have you been?
Not often, a couple of times.
It’s a pretty weird experience.
Where was it?
In Paris,
in some cave or other.
-Give me the address.
-I don’t remember.
Now come on.
Don’t keep a lady waiting.
So you’re in a hurry.
No, but if you want me to stay,
we ought to talk
a little business.
Ouch.
I’ll pay.
If you like, I’ll stay with you
until tomorrow.
I do like.
Yes, you’ve got to stay here.
What are you doing?
Take off your clothes.
Take off your clothes!
You hear?
Take off your clothes.
Who took you to the Black Mass?
-Tell me.
-Just friends, that’s all.
Yes, friends, friends.
-What friends?
-Some of my friends
who come to the discotheque.
The discotheque. Which?
You know it,
it’s the one in a cave.
Yes, their names, their names.
-There’s Raymond.
-Raymond. Who else?
-Anna.
-Anna. Who else?
-And Paulie.
-Who else?
I want all the names.
Stop it, you’re hurting me!
You’ve got to tell me
the names!
I want to know all the names!
Tell me!
Tell me.
I’ve got to know.
(guitar music)
(music stopping)
You must kiss this cross.
Kiss this cross.
Kiss it if you want
to save your soul.
Repeat after me:
I am possessed by the devil.
You are possessed by the devil!
I know you are.
-I’m going to exorcise you.
-You’re crazy.
All right, it’s true,
I’m possessed by the devil.
Confess that the devil
is ruling you
in heart, mind, and body.
In heart, mind, and body,
confess, child,
confess to Heaven.
-Confess.
-I confess
that the devil rules me
in heart, mind, and body.
Swear it!
Yes.
That’s good.
Now repeat: Humbly,
I accept the punishment
for my greatest offense
and my wicked transgressions.
-Repeat it.
-Please!
Go on!
Repent.
Repent!
(gasping)
(speaking Latin)
Amen.
Your excoriation
will now begin.
(gasping)
(moaning)
Ah.
(whimpering)
(singing in Latin)
(clanking)
(clanking continues)
(gasping)
I will save you.
(singing in Latin)
You are possessed by the devil.
You are an instrument
of hellfire, of damnation,
and the wages of sin is death.
I am all too familiar with sin.
I used to be a priest formerly.
I was expelled
from the priesthood.
Those idiots thought
I was too severe.
They were wrong!
My heart was pure and just,
and--and intransigent
in dealing with sin.
I fought with sin,
I fought with vice.
That’s why I will exorcise you
and tear the devil
out of your heart.
You’re going to die,
but your soul will mount
to the joys of paradise.
Out, Satan.
(gasping)
(music starting)
(speaking Latin)
(squawking)
(pattering)
(music stopping)
Good evening.
Good evening, Your Lordship.
Your guests are awaiting you.
Thank you.
(moody music)
-Good evening.
-Happy to see you.
Please step in the salon.
Oh, my friends,
I’m so glad you could come.
-How nice of you to ask us.
-This is a pleasure.
-Good evening, Count.
-Good evening.
Good evening.
Oh, I was wondering
if you would make it.
We wouldn’t have missed this
for anything.
Hello!
Oh, you look wonderful.
Hello, how are you?
Oh, this will be
a great evening.
-Yes.
-Yeah.
Come, Satan.
(drum music)
(heavy breathing)
The Black Mass has begun.
Come, mighty, all-powerful
king of darkness.
Pray, accept the sacrifice
we humbly offer.
Your chosen one
is awaiting you.
Your faithful offer her to you
as a sign of their devotion.
(owl hooting)
(organ music)
Admit the devil
into your hearts,
your minds, your bodies.
Come, Abaddon.
Come, oh, father of lies.
(speaking Latin)
(shouting)
(whip cracking, shouting)
Spirit of Hell, enter into us.
Oh, Satan,
fill us with your evil power.
You will bring
the sweetness to sin.
You, our master,
help us to tread
the path of luxury and vice.
Oh, Prince of Hades,
come, our beloved lord.
We pay you homage.
We are your slaves.
We worship you
more than the moon
and more than the fires
of the sun.
Satan!
Accept the sacrifice
that we offer you,
and may her blood flow free
into the ritual vessel.
(speaking Latin)
Priestess of the devil,
I raise up this dagger
that is now the instrument
of your design.
Come to me, Prince of Hell,
and give me the strength
to accomplish your sacrifice.
Accept your chosen one.
Accept your bride
whose blood shall flow
in honor of your might.
Satan, we worship you.
No.
(screaming)
(music stopping)
My dear friends, I’m delighted
to present Marina,
our victim, who played her part
to perfection.
(applause)
And this is the dagger.
Mm-hm.
And, now...
...for the second stage.
(moody music)
(moaning, laughing)
Oh, baby, you really know
how to do it.
(groaning)
Ah!
(indistinct chatter)
(laughing)
(groaning)
(grunting)
Hey, Louise, she’s very nice.
(groaning)
Enjoy yourself.
Let the pleasure reign.
Come on.
Let’s see some action.
Mmm.
Oh, babe.
(groaning)
(indistinct chatter)
(laughing)
Hey. Hey!
Ooh.
(groaning)
(music stopping)
(engine puttering)
(humming)
So, how did you enjoy yourself?
Just a nice party,
nothing special.
Nothing special?
You were making it with
just about anything in sight.
Aw. Oof.
Well, it’s the only way
to have fun or it’s a bore.
Don’t be angry, darling.
You’re the man
I’m in love with.
Yes, I know that,
only I find it hard
to understand.
Oh well, I guess it’s just
our difference in age.
Oh, but that’s no reason
to be jealous.
I don’t like feeling ridiculous.
Aww.
You sometimes get
the funniest ideas.
You’re a fine-looking man.
Your jealousy is flattering,
as a matter of fact.
It’s not jealousy.
It’s simply that I don’t like
those people.
That’s the last time we go
to one of those parties.
Aww.
(door opening quietly)
(grunting and struggling)
(gasping)
-David, help!
-I’ll save your soul.
Who are you?
You are an instrument
of the Devil.
You’re in danger of Hell.
I will save you.
-I’ll exorcise you.
-No!
-Let me go!
-You must pay for your sins.
-You must be crazy!
-But you aren’t going to
die in a state of grace.
I shall purify your soul.
Repent, my child!
Repent, and you will be saved.
(gasping)
(breathing shakily)
(grunting)
Out,
Satan!
There.
In nomine Patris!
Et Filii!
(breathing heavily)
(knife clicking)
(dreadful music)
(indistinct whispering)
-Good morning.
-Good morning, inspector.
I’m all through here.
-What a mess!
-You’ve done your work,
but my work’s just beginning,
-I’m afraid.
-Who is that young man with you?
He’s my new assistant,
only, if you ask me--
Oh.
Find anything
interesting, doctor?
Doesn’t have the appearance
of the usual sex crime.
So, we are not dealing
with a sex maniac.
-How ’bout the weapon?
-A thin-bladed knife,
blade about seven inches long.
Disemboweled the woman,
stabbed the husband.
-A real massacre!
-A sadist.
It could be,
but maybe a vendetta.
Or a nut!
Well, in my opinion, it was
neither one nor the other.
Something here strikes me
as very interesting.
The form of the wounds
and the depth of the incisions,
everything seems to point
to the exorcism ritual
of the early Inquisition.
So you believe that our assassin
is Torquemada?
Could be a Torquemada
of the present day.
According to the theories
of Flange and Obermeier,
our technological age leads to
a return to superstition.
Oh, now, please, Malou,
cut out the flights
of imagination
and concentrate on conducting
this investigation properly.
Well, inspector,
one of our men spotted somebody,
a suspicious character
hangin’ around.
My friend, your grand inquisitor
is probably nothing
but a cheap sneak thief
who got in a panic.
Is this the guy?
Yes, inspector.
Your name?
They call me Meathead.
Take off your cap.
-No, I won’t.
-I said take it off!
You pay the hospital
if I get pneumonia.
Okay, so what’s your name?
Meathead.
I want your real name.
(indistinct foreign name)
But for convenience,
they call me Meathead.
-So what’s your story?
-Nothing.
You were hanging around
that hotel there, what for?
Who, me?
-I was fermenting.
-What?
Don’t you talk English?
I was sleeping off a hangover!
Look, we didn’t get you
in here because of that,
but because you were
carrying a knife.
Oh!
A tiny little knife
for peeling bananas.
Look, we know
you’ve got a record.
They seem to like pulling me in,
but I never harm
nobody in my life.
I’m an angel with
a deadly face, that’s all.
Just the finger of fate.
(sighing)
Well, Meathead,
fate’s really got you this time.
All right, then, angel,
you’re gonna be
our guest once more.
You’re going to try and explain
just how you didn’t
murder the Cartiers,
you get me?
-Take him away.
-Let’s go.
It’s monotonous.
Pardon me, inspector,
but do you really believe that
that man’s the criminal?
Now, listen,
you college theorists would
think I’m making a mistake
in holding Mr. Meathead,
but I’ve got to hold somebody,
innocent or guilty,
so that I’ll be left in peace
to find the real criminal.
(easygoing music)
(moaning)
(groaning)
(gasping)
Oh.
(deranged music)
Anybody home?
Doesn’t look like it.
(deranged music)
You there, Rose?
We’re in the bathtub.
Let’s get comfortable.
(giggling)
(deranged music)
(laughing)
Hi, fellas.
Hi there, Rose.
-Hello.
-Hi!
Don’t mind us.
-Make yourselves at home.
-Oh!
(deranged music)
(giggling)
What brings you here?
We came to get Raymond.
He’s not here.
He’s with the police.
It’s not important,
anyway, I’m busy now.
(deranged music)
(moaning)
(moaning and giggling)
No.
(deranged music)
Why don’t you
take off your robe?
(indistinct speaking)
Your name?
Raymond Franval.
Occupation?
I am the Director
of Venus Publications
and of the Dagger
and Garter Weekly.
Ah, a purveyor of culture.
Are you one of
my readers, perhaps?
No.
I hardly have
the time to even read
the sport page in the Figaro.
Ah, yes, well,
I see what you mean.
My magazine wouldn’t exactly
be up your street.
Mr. Franval,
I called you in here
in the hope you could
give me some details
or some sidelights
on the Cartiers.
The Cartiers,
I see them around occasionally.
They’re nice people,
plenty of money.
You’ll never see them again.
They’ve been murdered.
(gasping)
Your magazine’s grapevine
doesn’t seem to be
working as it should.
That’s enough, Malou.
We found one of
your visiting cards
in the pocket of Mr. Cartier.
As a journalist,
do you have any idea
about a possible culprit?
Enemies?
Acquaintances?
Or something interesting
from your angle of
Dagger and Garter?
Nothing at all.
They were merely nice folks.
Incidentally, they were rich,
only they didn’t have
money to burn,
-far from it.
-Yes, yes, I understand.
Mr. Franval, I take it
you have no objections, then,
-to, uh, identifying the bodies?
-Huh!
Well, I find it unpleasant,
but if you insist, I will.
Call Durand.
Durand.
Take this gentleman
along to the morgue.
-Follow me, please.
-Right.
May I ask exactly how
the Cartier’s were killed?
They were murdered
with a dagger,
just like in
the stories you publish.
That’s interesting,
maybe I can use it.
We like authenticity,
good-bye.
I’m ready.
Well, Malou,
what do you think of him
for our culprit?
No comment.
(muffled screaming)
Mm, Maria Teresa.
Hm.
My darling,
why are you angry with me?
(Maria sighing)
-Why? Why?
-Do you really want to know?
I love you!
Maria.
Because you’re
a vicious old sadist,
-a homosexual.
-Yes, it’s true.
-A degenerate.
-Oh, yes!
-A dirty pig!
-It’s true.
-A shit eater, a swine!
-Yes, oh, yes.
-I disgust you.
-No! Let me go.
Come here.
On your knees.
(moaning)
Undress me.
Oh, mm.
(moaning)
Take off your clothes.
(groaning)
(moaning)
Maria.
Get undressed.
(moaning
and breathing heavily)
Oh, look at that.
Oh, yeah.
(breathing heavily)
You’re a filthy old lecher.
You are as disgusting
as a leper’s sores.
(moaning)
I hate you!
I abhor you!
Oh, Maria.
You make me vomit! Ah!
(moaning)
All right, stand up.
-Get on the bed...
-Maria.
...you old imp.
Oh, Maria.
-Oh, darling.
-You filth!
(breathing heavily)
(moaning)
(rooster crowing)
(suspicious music)
(moaning)
Yes, oh, Maria!
Oh, Maria, that’s--
Yes, yes, Maria.
(moaning and grunting)
-You dirty lecher!
-Maria!
-You old pervert!
-Yes, more, oh.
Travesty! Rapist!
(indistinct speaking)
(moaning and grunting)
(somber music)
(gasping)
Don’t be scared.
Don’t be afraid, countess.
I’ve come to save your soul.
You are a sinner!
I’m going to help you
expiate your sins.
Stand up!
Who are you?
What do you want?
Put your head down.
Put it down!
(screaming)
(grunting)
Ego te absolvo de peccatis
tuis in nomine Patris
et Filii
et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
(door closing)
(upbeat music)
So, you have a hunch
the police suspect you?
-That’s about it.
-Ha.
They must be out of their minds!
Even a cop could tell
you’re not a murderer.
You can say that again.
Anyway, I suspect
the murderer is
probably one of our crowd.
You could be right,
and I don’t wanna be
the next victim.
-That’s all we needed, huh.
-Our murderer doesn’t only
-kill women.
-Say he wants
equal numbers of men and women.
I heard that sex
maniacs like that
often have method
in their madness.
No, I think you’re wrong.
He’s a woman hater.
So they think
I did those killings
to provide authentic
material for my magazine.
After all, if I really had
committed those murders,
it wouldn’t be for
that sort of reason.
Well, I mean, I’d rather
rape Raquel Welch
or pull a hold-up, for example.
No, no, I can’t believe
that the police
really think that I did it,
only they’re
absolutely convinced
that I played a part in it
somewhere or other.
They think I lead a bad life.
-They’re not far off.
-Maybe!
(laughing)
Anyhow, what do you expect?
A cop could never understand
-our way of life.
-I guess not, Rose.
Yet, I think they’re
getting near the truth.
The motive behind these murders
has got something to do
with our quest for excitement
in the domain of black magic.
(laidback music)
Excuse me,
I thought Raymond was here.
Well, come in anyway.
Thank you.
I came to bring him
my new manuscript.
It’s supposed to go
in next week’s number.
I’d be very glad
if you would read it.
-Fine, I’d like to.
-It’s a true story.
Yes, I’ll read it!
I shall be honored
to have your opinion
as to its merits.
It’s a story of unhappiness.
You promise you’ll read it?
I already said so.
Thank you.
What for?
The darkness
of Mary Anna’s room
was pierced by
only a faint light.
On the other side of the street,
somebody moved a curtain.
The man’s tormented,
haggard face looked out.
His eyes expressed
his hopeless longing for her,
but his heart denied him
the courage to speak.
But his vigil was not in vain.
Mary Anna came into her room.
She was not alone this time.
Her partner in fleshly
lusts was with her.
The two girls
clasped each other,
and began to undress.
Their gleaming
bodies were exposed.
Hands clasped, mouths met
in forbidden kisses.
The man decided
to free Mary Anna
of the demon
that possessed her...
(thumping)
...to save her soul
at any cost.
He had the power to save her.
(knocking)
He opened the door
of his apartment
and directed his feet
toward her dwelling.
Ah!
Mr. Vogel!
-Good evening.
-But why are,
-why are you here?
-I have to speak to you.
Oh, all right.
(screaming)
(lively music)
(whimpering)
Anna.
-Mm-hm.
-Anna!
(shakily breathing)
(grunting)
(moaning)
-Anna. Anna.
-No.
No! Let me go!
-Anna!
-Let me go!
Oh!
Don’t be afraid.
I don’t want to kill you.
I don’t want to kill you!
(Vogel sobbing)
You’re possessed by the Devil.
Possessed by the Devil.
-No! No!
-You are possessed by the Devil.
You’re possessed by the Devil!
-No!
-I will exorcise you.
I will free you.
You must repent!
Anna, I’ll save you.
(screaming and grunting)
Anna! Anna!
(screaming)
I love you.
You’re possessed
by the Devil,
but I love you.
I love you, Anna.
Love you.
No, stay down!
(crying)
Ego te absolvo
de peccatis
tuis...
...in nomine Patris
et Filii et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
(energetic music)
That’s funny.
What is?
Anna’s not back yet.
Maybe she’s out with Fred.
(doorbell ringing)
-There she is.
-Open it.
(energetic music)
Hello!
-Hello, Rose!
-Marina, Fred.
-Hi, there!
-What’s this in aid of?
We’ve come to pick up Anna.
But Anna’s not here.
We thought she was out with you!
That’s very strange.
We had a date to go
to the movies together.
-Yes, that’s strange.
-That’s just what I said to Ray.
Well, I suppose
she wants to be alone.
That doesn’t sound like her.
No, it doesn’t really.
I hope nothing’s
happened to her.
(energetic music)
(muffled music)
(moaning)
(breathing heavily)
(muffled music)
(phone ringing)
Oh, for God’s sake!
Hello?
Anna!
Where are you?
Where are you, honey?
You what?
You’re with a friend,
well, what friend?
Answer me!
She hung up.
So, what?
Well, she always has had
rather peculiar ways.
Only recently,
she’s gotten worse.
(typewriter clacking)
Inspector, the technical
services Interpol
sent our data into the computer,
and it came up with a few names.
Among them, I selected
Vogel, Paul, a Czechoslovak.
His real name is Paul Rosik.
He’s an unfrocked priest
escaped from an asylum.
He’s a writer,
and the German police
want him for
offenses against minors.
He could be our man.
My dear Malou,
you are the limit.
Perhaps this
poor Vogel is crazy,
but that doesn’t prove
that he’s the man we’re after.
Even though he happens
to live in the apartment
right across the street
from those girls
who are friends of Franval,
-the magazine publisher?
-So Vogel lives opposite,
so what?
Well, if that’s not enough,
go ahead and call me an idiot,
but I’d like a little talk
with Franval and his friends.
-They’re all yours.
-You’re in for a shock.
-I’d better see what he’s up to.
-Okay, I’ll hold the fort.
Malou?
(typewriter clacking)
(yawning)
Mm.
Oh.
Hmph!
Hm.
Raymond!
-Raymond, wake up.
-What do you want?
Anna isn’t back yet.
I’m beginning to get worried.
Well, she did phone after all.
She’s old enough
to know what she’s doing.
I know.
Maybe I’m being stupid,
but it’s just not like her.
This is the first time
she’s stayed away
for an entire night!
Well, what of it?
I’m scared, that’s all.
I’ve got a nasty feeling
something’s happened to her.
You think so?
(doorbell ringing)
Police.
-Good morning.
-The police?
-Good morning, inspector.
-Sorry for disturbing you.
What can we do
for you gentlemen?
This is Inspector Tanner
and his assistant.
Ah.
Did you know that
a certain Paul Vogel
has rented an apartment
just opposite yours?
No, why should we?
Did you also know
that for the last two days,
nobody seems to have
seen him around anywhere?
He has done a vanishing act.
That’s a coincidence.
Uh, Anna,
a friend who lives here with me,
has vanished as well.
If I can give you
a word of advice,
I’d cut out all of this nonsense
of yours with black masses.
Already four of
your group have died.
You might even be the next.
Mm.
Nomine Patris, et Filii,
et Spiritus Sancti.
Amen.
Oremus.
(singing prayer in Latin)
(Anna groaning)
My darling, Anna,
I absolve you of your sins.
I absolve you!
(tense music)
Anna!
(screaming)
(tense music)
(grunting and slapping)
(spitting)
(tense music)
(screaming)
(inaudible)
(tense music)
Rose, come here!
What is it?
This is one of
Paul Vogel’s manuscripts.
-Where did you find it?
-Right here.
He talks about torture,
flagellation,
crucifying a girl,
exorcising the Devil,
read it!
He talks of disemboweling,
washing away sins with blood,
and purification with a knife.
-Well, what is it?
-I want to talk to you.
What about?
That last story of yours.
Did it impress you?
Yes, very much.
Extremely sadomasochistic.
But nevertheless,
it had the ring
of authentic experience.
What are you implying?
That you know a lot too much
about these murders
for a man who is innocent!
You mean that I--
You don’t understand.
She’s very upset about
the disappearance of Anna.
You mean Anna’s disappeared?
You know she’s disappeared!
If you suspect me,
then go to the police.
My conscience is clear.
What about yours?
Are your consciences
as clear as they should be?
Our black masses, perhaps.
Black masses?
What do you mean?
That’s right,
if you’re interested,
we’re holding one later tonight
in the cloister of the Templars.
It would give us
great pleasure if you attend,
Mr. Vogel.
I’ll come.
Yes.
I’ll come!
(clattering)
(rattling)
Ah!
(groaning)
(grunting)
(eerie music)
(easygoing jazz music)
(whipping)
(music stops)
Ah.
Inspector! Inspector!
You took a terrible chance,
you might have been murdered.
You college boys never make
mistakes like ordinary cops.
Oh, but this
mistake really hurts.
I’ve been looking for you
because they’re holding
another black mass.
(easygoing jazz music)
(manic distorted music)
There goes the murderer.
-He just killed Rose!
-Get in.
(urgent music)
(car speeding away)
(sirens wailing)
(car speeding)
(siren wailing)
(urgent music)
We’ve got to hurry.
Come, Anna!
(urgent music)
(screaming)
(car approaching)
-Hold it, Vogel!
-Anna! Anna!
No!
Let me go!
Or I’ll kill her.
I delivered them from evil.
I freed them from
the power of the Devil.
I don’t want to hurt this girl!
I love her!
I’ll save her soul
by my prayers.
I’ll purify her of her sins!
Don’t you understand?
I am the sword of the Lord.
I am the sword of the Lord!
You must let me go.
Let us go!
-Give yourself up.
-Go away, or I’ll kill her.
Don’t make me.
You mustn’t!
(gun firing)
(screaming)
Anna!
You’ve got to admit, inspector,
that we police college graduates
get the right idea sometimes.
Mm-hm, well, uh,
these egg-head cops,
I’m not convinced.
Maybe you are an exception.
Good work, Malou.
(car starting)
(upbeat music)