"Even if God didn't exist, Religion
would still be Saintly and Divine."
Now you, in leaving this school...
... will find yourselves facing,
just as you may have studied...
... two conceptions of reality:
... that of the Catholic,
and that of the Marxist.
It's useless to think otherwise...
... the reality in Europe is just that,
divided into two parts.
I don't want to tell you:
"You must choose", because you...
... being of the bourgeois,
have already chosen.
I will however add something
that I'd like you to keep private.
Whatever your position
in life may be...
... first and foremost it should
be one of moral responsibility.
What does that mean?
It means...
... that the story of men,
that which has brought man...
... to this point,
has always been founded...
... on moral choice,
on the heart's impulse.
Therefore, the real reason...
... the cold rationalism,
algebra, mathematics...
... isn't the story.
Because the story of mankind...
... is an aspiration
conscious of what is good.
An act of love that embraces humanity.
This is the true education.
This is civilization.
This is the blowing of
the high winds of culture.
This...
... is liberty.
CORRUPTION
Oh, young master...
Come, come!
After so many years...
You were so little when you came here.
Allow me...
Are you in a bad mood, Stefano?
We're going back to life!
To women!
Enough of this "Alma Mater", we're free!
Don't speak Latin, I'm sick of it!
Congratulations, Stefano! Bye!
We made it!
Bye, Claudio!
Keep in touch!
- Hi. So, you're leaving?
- Soon.
- I came to say goodbye.
- Yes, good...
- Where will you go?
- To my father's house, for now.
- So, you've made your mind up?
- I think so.
I've been meaning to give
you this book for a while.
The editor is one of
your father's competitors.
- Something to remember him by.
- I want you to read it.
You think this book will do
what you never managed to?
That isn't what I meant.
See, I have absolutely nothing
against your improbable career choice.
Why? Don't you believe in it?
It's not that I don't believe in it.
It's that... look, let's
speak frankly for a moment.
You're leaving, and we'll probably
never see each other again.
To me it seems as though your chosen
vocation is founded on a...
... true religiousness, Catholic.
Yet yours is a vague aspiration...
... full of good faith, of purity...
... but vague, imprecise.
To be a priest...
Being a priest is, above all,
a discipline.
I know that.
But I can't do anything else.
And then, if it's something that
moves me, that gives me strength...
... if, well, if the thought of a pure
and religious life makes me happy...
... why should I have to renounce it?
And what about your father?
Have you told your father?
No, but I'll tell him.
It won't be easy.
Goodbye, Stefano.
I hope that your decision
turns out to be just and true...
... and that I, all things
considered, was wrong.
- You would prefer to be wrong?
- Yes...
But, unfortunately I'm
almost always right.
Goodbye, Stefano.
- Goodbye, and thank you!
- Good luck!
Come, I'll show you your room.
Through here.
Here you are.
Come.
If this is what you decide,
we'll be waiting for you.
Stefano!
"Alitalia, second call..."
"... departure flight number 14222."
- Father!
- Hey there! Hi.
Hello, Judy!
- Did you have a good trip?
- Yes, Father.
- Where are we going now?
- To the office.
I have things to attend to.
But after that we have
the entire day together.
I wanted to go and find Mother.
Do you know how she is?
No, I don't know. And you know very
well that I've never been fond of...
... your mother's imaginary illnesses.
Perhaps they're not so imaginary. Otherwise
they wouldn't have taken her at the clinic...
Sick people like your mother are
a gift from heaven for those clinics.
50,000 lire a day...
But anyway, if you like,
we can go and see her.
Will you come as well?
I'll wait for you downstairs.
Stefano!
Mother!
How are you?
I just woke up, but you know...
... I could have sleep for longer.
How long will the treatment last?
I don't know.
Ten, eleven days.
Fifteen days, Mrs. Mattioli.
Just think, Stefano,
another fifteen days.
I'll sleep fifteen days
without even realizing.
- When did you get back?
- I've finished at school.
Did you pass?
Yes, I wrote...
Didn't you receive my letter?
Um... I don't know... maybe.
But, you know, this treatment is
a must. I've spent my days...
Didn't your father tell you?
I want to know...
... what he told you. He finds my
exhaustion funny, doesn't he?
No, that's not true.
He was worried about you.
Here you are, today I've made you
a heavier meal than usual.
If I could only eat this way outside...
... without the bother of chewing,
of swallowing, of...
You would soon tire of it, Ma'am.
No, my dear, you're mistaken!
The diet...
... cleanses the skin.
- Isn't that right?
- Yes, that's right!
Hand me the mirror.
Go and open the window.
See, it's the second time that I've...
... this sleep treatment...
... stretches....
No!
Close it!
I was saying that...
... it's the second time I've
done this sleep treatment...
... it stretches me out,
rejuvenates me.
Isn't that right?
And you know, you don't dream anything,
good dreams or bad dreams.
Come here, sit down.
The doctor will be here soon
and you haven't told me anything.
That's true, Mother, we never
see each other anymore.
I know, but you grow up too fast...
... and I get old too fast!
I have no way to defend myself!
- From what?
- From insomnia!
You're young, you don't understand!
See...
... insomnia at my age
is a terrible thing!
Alone! Alone at night with all
my thoughts, here, here, here!
Don't think about that.
When you leave here everything
will be fine, you'll see.
Oh! You'll see, you'll see! What do you
think I see, after the life I've had?!
The others, talk, talk... yes!
But I....
Do you know what I think, Stefano?
For me death will be the first
good night's sleep I've had in my life.
Ready for a nice nap?
Yes, Doctor, I'm ready.
- So, when will I wake up?
- In two days.
Did you hear that? Two days.
Will you come and see me?
- Good morning, Sir!
- Good morning, Gianna!
- Ooh, if it isn't Stefano! Welcome back!
- Thank you.
Mr. Leo, Pennisi is waiting for you,
he's in your study.
- Ah, yes, send him in.
- Yes, right way.
- Wait for me through there with Gianna.
- Yes, Father.
Come on.
Giuseppe, go on through!
So, you've finished at boarding school?
You've lost weight, though.
What, they don't feed you there?
Not too much.
So, Gianna, how's business?
Good, good! As usual.
Who's that?
She's here because of your father.
- Gianna, send me Stefano.
- Yes, right away.
Pass it on to administration.
Sir, the storekeeper is
waiting for you outside.
- What should I tell him?
- Send him in.
- Don't tell me you're tired?
- No, no, of course not!
Good, because this evening I'm
taking you to a cocktail bar...
... where all the intellectuals
in Milan like to hang out.
All good people, you know,
my competition, they're always...
... trying to put me out of business,
but never quite manage it!
Yes, come in!
Come on, in you come.
Please, come forward.
Don't be afraid.
- Are you the storekeeper?
- Yes.
I've never seen you before.
How long have you been here?
18 months.
Listen, would you like to explain
to me why the accounts are showing...
... a deficit of 870,000
lire in revenue stamps?
I don't know.
I swear on my mother's life.
I check them all.
I check them every day.
Here, look.
The accounts department is clear,
there's a deficit. Where did it end up?
They must be mistaken.
What, machines make mistakes now?
I don't know.
Someone must have stole them!
There's no doubt that
someone stole them...
... but they stole them
from you, not from me.
If the sum isn't returned
within three days...
... you will be interrogated by
someone much more qualified than me.
Is that clear?
But what can I do, Sir?
I earn 60,000 lire a month,
I can't possibly...
I couldn't possibly...
How can I, if you don't help me?
You may go.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
He seemed sincere.
They always seem sincere.
I know, I know, there are
unpleasant situations...
... there are difficult
decisions to make.
But unfortunately, that's how it is...
... you can't avoid them,
it's part of such responsibility.
If I always allowed my sentiments
to dictate things...
... at this point I'd be
selling books on a market stall.
Instead, I have 500 employees.
And if there's a rotten branch...
... you must cut it off right away,
if you wish the tree to remain healthy.
Remember them, these words.
Perhaps today they seem absurd...
... but when you come to work
for my company...
... and hold a position of
some responsibility...
... well, when you're the
one running this place...
... you will realise that
there exist two sets of morals:
... one for he who commands,
and one for he who obeys.
Yes, my son, unfortunately...
... that's the way it is.
One day you will be have
to make unpleasant decisions...
... that go against your
own sentiments; I'm sure of it!
But there will always be
one important compensation...
... that you are giving work
to 500 families...
... meaning 500 fathers
that will have secured...
... a future for themselves
and their children.
Do you see?
This is what counts...
... because the rest is all lies!
Thank goodness you're here!
No even Vittoria is coming! She's at
the "Olive Branch" with her mother...
... the one who won a good will award...
... it's always the same people
and always the same food...
See? What am I supposed
to do with all these starters?
No one comes here anymore!
Who knows what they'll do, then...
Do you want something to drink?
Whisky?
- Hey, Morandi!
- Ah, hi, Boss!
- How are you?
- Good, good.
Here, this is here my son.
He's a big fan of yours, you know!
Stefano, here's your chance!
I'll leave you two to it.
I think I must have read everything
you've written up to this point.
My dear boy, you surprise me.
I know of your opinions already,
your father has told me a lot about you.
I wouldn't think that a
young catholic, these days...
... would be interested in my books.
I wouldn't be a good catholic
if I didn't try to understand.
When the war was on and
you were just a little boy...
... when he really started to read,
to become interested...
It's an old industry, you know. Not the
most fitting business for your father.
Italy isn't a country of ideas,
but of electric appliances.
I'm surprised that you've read my work.
Isn't it the ideas that make a story?
No, it's the objects...
... or rather, a certain number
of objects that can be sold.
But your ideas are not made of objects.
That's why they don't sell,
and why people don't read them.
Tell me, have you thought of
going into politics? - No.
- So you'll be working with your father.
- I don't think so, for now.
- That's a shame. I hope to see you
at the publishing house. - Of course.
I go there three times a week.
Why don't you come?
- Okay!
- Good!
Listen, Morandi: don't bother
putting my photo on the cover.
- Just do your own nice presentation
and that will be enough. - Okay, okay...
- Why, have you written a book?
- Of course? Didn't you know?
And you're presenting
my father's book?
Of course, Stefano.
Aren't you happy?
Who's for some Parmesan?
Hey! Hi, Adriana!
I came by the office this morning.
- Ah, yes. What did you want?
- Nothing, I was just passing.
- Ah... do you know my son?
- No.
Very well, here he is!
He knows everyone, your father.
He's like the devil.
All at once his heir appears.
Good for you!
So, what did Morandi tell you?
He's alright, isn't he? - Yes.
He was a smart man. Did 5 years in
Ponza in confinement, under fascism.
- Did you know that?
- Yes, I knew.
- Now he's working with you?
- Yes. He's always been a prestigious name.
A moralist who writes in the left-wing
and pseudo left-wing newspapers...
Anyway, he's useful.
It's that I'm paying him to do nothing
in particular, that bothers me a little.
His books are important.
Well! I wouldn't call them important,
but fortunately for us they still work.
He's a Saint of the Resistance, you know.
Ha! A true idealist!
Even more than you.
You don't much care for idealism,
do you father?
Of course not! It's old news, and a
miracle that people still believe in it.
Then what are you?
Do you believe in ideas or not?
My son, I don't go to school anymore.
These days I'm an industrialist,
meaning someone who believes in facts...
... not in ideas.
And tomorrow you'll be an
industrialist yourself...
... now that you're done with
your needless education.
I don't think so.
You don't think what?
I've made a decision, Father,
regarding my life.
And what would that be?
I've decided to join a convent.
Come, come!
Let's at least hear why.
- Would you like something to drink?
- No, thank you.
I hope...
... actually, I'm sure
you don't disapprove, do you?
I didn't say anything,
just asked a question:
... I asked you why.
What can I tell you?
All I can say is that above all
this decision is a necessity for me.
Oh, really? Well this necessity of
yours must stem from something...
... you know, an opinion on the world,
a long time spent reflecting... or no?
- Perhaps I'm mistaken.
- No, you're not mistaken.
It's a result of these past two years,
a combination of opinion and reflection.
Just as you say.
Help me understand.
Opinions, reflections... and they are?
Meaning, that I feel the need
to believe in something...
... immaterial, something idealogical.
Careful!
"Idealogical" is a dangerous word.
If a Jesuit heard you talk like that,
he would doubt your career choice.
It's true, but it's so tiring
for me to speak with you.
- What? Why?
- Because you...
... don't believe in anything.
Who says so?
That's what you're saying.
No, I actually quite firmly
believe in many things.
You know which?
I believe in power.
And I also believe in money.
Why not?
Things that disgust you, I'm sure.
Isn't that right?
- Yes, that's true. - I know, I liked
to judge people at your age as well.
But becoming a priest isn't necessary.
And because, I'm sure that after
just a month you'll be back home.
No. I've decided.
And anyway, you'll see.
We'll see.
Anyhow, we can talk about it more
tomorrow, can't we?
- Go on, go to bed now. Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Sorry to wake you.
Listen, I have an idea.
Tomorrow I'll attend to some business,
and then on Saturday we'll take the yacht...
... and we'll go out to sea, you and I...
... for a nice trip.
That way we can talk and get to
know each other better, can't we?
What do you say?
Does it sound like a good idea?
Yes, it sounds great!
Excellent!
Okay, then.
- Night.
- Goodnight, Father.
Hello!
What, you don't say hello?
- How are you?
- So, which one is "Noah's Ark"?
- What?
- Your father's boat, no?
- Why? Are you coming with us?
- Of course! Do you mind?
Come on, get in!
Well, it's about time!
I was about to leave without you.
It's not like I can fly!
I left as soon as you called me.
Wait! Take your shoes off
before coming aboard.
Oh, really? Are those the rules?
Gian! Take the lady's cases
upstairs, go on!
Remember that you're on a yacht,
here, we're not on the street.
You didn't tell me she was coming.
- Oh, I didn't?
- No. - Oh, dear.
Hey there, Captain!
Are we ready to cast off?
We're ready, Mr. Leo!
Higher!
Go on, more!
You looked good up there.
Aren't you afraid of heights?
Hey, where are you going?
- To take a shower.
- With all this water around us?
I want to get changed.
You're not a very good host, you know!
- It wasn't me who invited you.
- Tell me how you really feel!
What do you want me to do,
dive in and swim back to land?
Stefano!
Say, what do you have against me?
- Nothing.
- Then why do you look at me like that?
Come on, let's have a chat.
Come on.
- How old are you?
- 23.
And... have you been with many men?
Are you really interested? It sounds like
you're collecting data for a census!
- How do you earn a living?
- Oh, on whatever I find.
- In the city there are enough opportunities.
- Like what, for example?
Have you seen those photographs
sailors keep in their cabins?
Well, I've done that as well.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Yes, why not? Of course.
Have you ever been with a woman?
- Well...
- So, you have?
- No.
- Why? Don't you like women?
What does that matter?
If you liked them,
you would have done it already, no?
Is that all you think exists
between a man and a woman?
What else could there be?
There could be... love.
One could fall in love.
That's what I'm saying!
That's what I mean!
No, you're saying that love
is to sleep with someone.
Of course! What else could it be?
You know, you sound so foolish.
- So, you would go with anyone?
- No, with the men I like.
If someone is good...
What does "good" mean to you?
"Good" can mean many different things.
If he buys you things, if he's kind...
But above all if he really wants you...
... if he wants only you,
and he wants you at all costs.
Then he really loves you.
It's quite rare!
So by "good" you mean...
... good in general?
Good with others, you mean,
good with everyone.
No, that's an asshole!
I mean good with me, not with others.
If he's good with others,
what would that make me? Just anyone?
- And that's it? Nothing else?
- What do you want there to be?
So, for you a man is just
something that you find useful?
If a woman doesn't look for
protection and affection in a man...
... what does she look for?
Anyway, a woman knows right away
what a man is really like.
- And what's that?
- I already told you!
It has to be someone who
wants you at all costs.
So then you're sure,
you don't have to worry...
... you feel supported.
- Yes, even better if he's rich!
You're such an idiot!
So, Cosimo!
Are you going to put the ladder down?
Right away, Sir!
Come on, I want to test the water!
- Stefano, you can watch me from the boat!
- Yes, Father!
- Ready, Mr. Leo!
- Here I am!
Beautiful sea, isn't it?
Look at that!
Venus in the flesh!
- Beautiful, isn't she? Hi!
- Hello there! What is there to eat?
- Are you hungry?
- Mmm, very!
Go on, Federico!
Go and get the food ready!
Right away, Sir.
- So have you been with many men?
- Does it interest you that much?
Your face and eyes are so childlike...
... and yet you're so different.
You're like...
... like something without a soul,
without anything!
You're a difficult one, aren't you?
You think a little too much.
That's why you've never
been with a woman.
- Why, shouldn't one think?
- Yes, yes, but you see...
What?
Not if one thinks like you, you know.
Go on, I know it's just a
phase you're going through.
- So, am I "good" enough for you?
- I'd say so.
- And why is that?
- Because you have nice eyes...
... you're well built,
and you also have strong hands.
- So what I think doesn't interest you?
- Of course not! Why should it?
- And anyway, I already know you.
- What do you mean by that?
Go on, you know what I mean!
- Why did you say that you already know me?
- I know you a little.
- Look out, Adriana!
- How disgusting!
In olden times they fed little
girls like you to the eels.
I'd kill someone before they
could do that to me.
That's gratitude for you.
You tire yourself out catching dinner...
... and all you get back is death threats.
But you see: there has always been...
... a war between the snake and the woman...
... ever since the famous apple,
the original sin.
It'll never be over between them, you know.
And everyone screams:
"Where there's woman, there's sin."
So, get rid of the woman...
... get rid of sex.
We must be chaste, pure, impotent...
And of course, that's the problem...
... sex maniacs, sick in the head...
... and the women, frigid and immaculate.
You would think that it
would be something so simple...
... so right, no?
Far from good and bad!
That's the only relationship.
Remember that, my boy...
... the natural relationship
between the male and the female.
So tell me,
do you have something against women?
No. I find them very beautiful.
Hey, look at that, those five stars.
That's Orion's constellation,
also called "The Hunter".
And over there, those three in a triangle,
that's the Greater Dog.
Well! I'll never understand how
you can see a dog in the stars!
Well, it's very simple.
And because our ancestors probably
had a better imagination than us.
So what's changed?
Nothing has changed,
it's just that we know more now.
And science will inevitably kill poetry.
For example: when someone living in the
olden times saw lightning, they thought of God.
These days we know it's electrical discharge.
This is why we're less religious.
And what would you do if you saw
a gigantic hand in the sky, right now...
... pointing a finger down at you?
Well, nothing!
What do you think I'd do?
I'd repent my sins.
Stefano, find my constellation for me.
I'm a Sagittarius.
Well, you see those five stars?
That's the bow and that's the arrow.
And you, Leo, what star sign are you?
- I'm a Sagittarius as well.
- No good!
A Sagittarius never gets
on with another Sagittarius.
What about you, Stefano?
What sign are you, Virgo?
- Gemini.
- Sagittarius and Gemini: assured happiness.
- Say, are you going to bed?
- Yes, and you?
We'll stay out here a little longer.
No one is to wake me before
9 O'clock, understood?
Then we'll let you sleep.
Goodnight.
- Stefano...
- Yes?
Tell me the truth, now.
You were just joking when you mentioned...
... closing yourself in a convent
with your prayer beads.
It's not a joke.
It's crazy talk. I mean...
... how on earth did you come
up with such an idea?
It's a decision I've spent a
lot of time thinking over.
- Really? Since when?
- This last year at school.
I see, but you know that at your age
many people make rash decisions.
- Let's at least talk about it.
- Yes, of course.
So you would believe in God...
... in the Son, the Holy Ghost,
in Immaculate Conception? - Exactly.
Don't you realise how that sounds?
Men are about to set foot on the Moon...
... and you still believe in such lies?
And you're an intelligent kid!
How can you believe in such things?
Why?
It's all clear to you, is it?
Everything simple,
everything explained...
Mysteries just don't exist, do they?
Don't you realise that,
to reason in the way that you reason...
... is merely to simplify things...
... to see only the superficial,
and not the substance in things?
Unfortunately, the substance in things
is the thing itself, all else is lies!
No.
No, no, I'll never see that.
Otherwise I might as well be dead.
There exists higher values, believe me,
than things, than money, than power.
And what power, anyway?
And for how long?
- It doesn't matter how long it lasts,
just that it lasts. - There, you see...
... I like to think that we have
the right to live better lives...
... without staining ourselves, without
marking our conscience. - Oh, really!
Just to be clear:
in a world that isn't religious...
... I wish to live religiously.
And what about me?
You don't think about me, do you?
You want to love everyone, except me.
You don't realise that it's
because I have just one son...
... that I've worked for my
whole life, up to this point?
You don't do it for me,
you do it for yourself.
Because that's how you are,
because it's your calling.
Mine is different, actually,
the opposite.
And I've decided to follow
it with all my heart.
Anyway, I'll never allow it!
Now, that's enough talking.
Alright?
Then I'll be forced speak with you again.
When we go home I'm leaving
you and moving to the convent.
- Which convent, anyway? - I've already
spoken to them, they're waiting for me.
- You're still just a minor.
- Yes.
- I'm asking you for permission.
- Ah, no!
I won't give you anything,
not until you're 21 years old!
That's not right, Father. What,
are you forcing me to disobey you?
If I stop you doing this foolishness,
one day you'll thank me.
It's useless, Father!
I'm sorry, but this is my path.
This is very upsetting for me, you know?
I'm sorry Father, but you've
caused me a lot of pain.
Ah, I have?
What about the pain that
you've caused me?
Do you think that I'm indifferent
to the fact that I might lose a son...
... now, at the exact moment
that I've found him once again?
But you won't lose me!
You'll always be my father, it's
just that you'll have a priest for a son.
I already told you that having a priest
for a son is something I will not tolerate!
It's an idea that mortifies me,
that disgusts me!
I want a son who follows in my footsteps...
... who continues what I've started...
But Father...
... don't you understand that
I can never work with you? Never!
Do you think that I could live like you,
ordering people around, people who..
... only obey me because they're afraid?
- No! You're the one who's afraid!
People talk how you're talking
when they're afraid and weak.
This is life!
He who commands, and he who obeys!
It's always been the same, my dear boy!
Yes, but you're not interested in living,
you just want to hide behind a robe...
... just like your mother hides
herself away in those clinics.
This isn't a career, it's cowardice,
that's what it is...
... and I don't want a coward for a son.
But I'll make you change your mind,
my dear priest.
We'll see if you're strong enough.
Come on, don't be afraid,
defend yourself!
You have the strength of your vocation, no?
Then fight!
Let's see how you do, with
all your saints and holy mothers!
I pity you.
Stefano!
Hey...
What have you done?
Come on, in here.
- Captain, we're just off Cala Brigantina!
- Very Good, Mr. Leo!
Half an hour early...
My estimates are always exact.
- Hey! Hi! Did you sleep well?
- Yes, thank you.
Where are we going?
Where's Stefano?
Still sleeping?
- How should I know?
- You should know, shouldn't you?
Hey! Wake up, sleepy head!
Come on, it's a wonderful day!
- Where are we?
- In the shallows of Palmarola.
Come on, let's go fishing!
Come on, get up.
I want to leave.
What?
If you drop me ashore at Ponza,
I'll take the ferry.
What are you upset about now?
Are you still thinking about that
stupid discussion from last night?
Our holiday has only just started.
- We won't speak about it again, okay?
- Father!
- Let me leave, please.
- Where? - I want to leave, Father.
Come here a moment, come closer.
What's all this about you wanting
to leave? Has something happened?
- No.
- Then what's this tantrum all about?
You should stay here. You'll see...
... it's a beautiful island,
I'm sure that you'll really like it.
Young master! What are you doing?!
Hey, you!
Stop!
Help, Father!
Father!
Father, help me!
Help me!
Help...
Go!
I'm sorry!
Help!
Pull alongside him.
Leave me alone.
Yes, of course, right away.
I just brought you some cognac,
that's if you want it.
No, thank you.
You know, Stefano, I'm really
not interested if you drink or not.
The thing that worries me is your
inclination to always say "no".
If you always say "no", people will
stop offering you things.
I said "thank you".
Yes, I know, you have good manners.
This is a nice watch!
Is it yours? Did you buy it?
Yes.
Where?
- In Losanna.
- Ah! In Losanna!
- Father...
- Yes?
For the first time in my life...
... I've sinned.
I've betrayed both you and myself.
Last night...
What?
- I slept with Adriana.
- I had imagined as much.
Besides, I saw it coming,
considering how you act together.
Why won't you let me off?
Order them to dock somewhere.
I'll go away.
Go where, Stefano?
I don't know.
- Help me, Father!
- How can I, if you won't let me?
Father, please, I didn't know...
I swear, I didn't mean to...
What do you mean?
Adriana...
What do I care about Adriana?
No, it's you I'm thinking about.
It's you I'm worried about.
Don't you see that you even you
really don't know what you want?
You can't make that decision.
If your chosen career was one of
sincerity, authenticity, honesty...
... I would have probably given in.
But how long has it lasted,
that which we spoke about?
So then, how can you still
think of it as your true calling?
No. I know.
It's not that I'm always right about
everything, quite the opposite...
... but I take my reasoning from facts.
You cannot be chaste.
No one was born for chastity, no one.
Get that into your head.
I know.
Now it's all over.
All these years of renunciation,
of exaltation...
... only to arrive at this...
... at this betrayal!
What betrayal?
Actually, I find it right,
the thing you did...
... it's so human, natural.
Evidently...
... strength of will isn't enough.
And just like that...
... it's over!
- What's over?
- Everything, Father! Everything!
Nothing is over, my son,
quite the opposite...
Now you will start again,
start your life alongside me.
I need you, Stefano.
My strength isn't what it was.
I'm an old man, my son.
It's not easy always being so hard, intolerant.
And only you can help me.
What can I do?
You know how to do everything...
... all you need is you.
But you can do... you can do so much.
Come to Milan with me.
We can run the publishing house together.
- Wouldn't you like that, Stefano?
- Yes, I would.
Good! It's yours, you know!
You can choose which books you want
and you'll have fun, you'll see.
Books aren't just money, you know,
they're ideas, important things...
For a young man like you...
... it will be a duty just
as noble as religion.
Well, get some rest, now.
- Father...
- Yes?
When did you and Mother
start hating each other?
When we got married.
Sleep.
- He saw you, Father!
- So?
He took your license plate number!
Well, I hope it brings him luck!
It ends in 13, you know!
- Welcome back, Sir!
- Thank you!
- Thank you, Gianna! Any news?
Lots of letters and two calls from
Brockhaus, about the dictionary.
Good morning, Sir!
I....
Stefano!
What are you doing, Stefano?
Here I am, Father!
Come on!
- What were you doing back there?
- Nothing.
- And does he have a say in the commission?
- Of course, he has the decisive vote!
- Then send him a cheque.
- A cheque?!
Of course, a cheque!
We'll see if he sends it back.
It's not an offence, you know.
Want something to drink, Stefano?
- A whisky?
- Okay.
Eight volumes in a single month...
I'll have to increase production.
I ask myself how you sell so many.
- It's not like people read that much.
- Oh, but they sure do sell!
In Italy the book has become
a consumer good these days.
- Yes. But do they read them?
- How should I know?
Anyway, they buy them,
and that's what counts.
They buy them as they would
buy a tie or a pair of shoes.
What happened?
- What happened?!
- The storekeeper, out the window!
Ribechi, call the police!
Out of here, you! Go on!
- Where are you going? - Father, let go of me!
- Stay right where you are!
Give me a cover, something...
Here!
Away! Get away from him!
Get away, go on! Get back inside!
Very well, Sir. Yes...
No, no responsibility!
Hey, what can you do...
Okay, the one....
Sort it out for me. A couple of million
or even more, it doesn't matter.
These things happen...
Very well. Let me know...
I don't want the newspapers to breath
as much as a breath a word of this!
Everyone looks to make a
scandal out of a story like this!
Don't worry, I told you.
No one will talk about it.
I still have some authority left.
It's nothing to do with you, is it?
- Do you want something to eat?
- Why not?
- Vincenzo! Prepare a plate of cold
meats for the professor. - Right away!
Are you eating with us, Stefano?
- Good evening!
- Good evening, Ribechi. Well?
- The father of the boy is here with me.
- Ah, good!
I convinced him. Though perhaps now it's best
if you talk to him. You know...
... how these things are...
- Yes, of course. Where is he?
I left him downstairs in the car.
I already hinted at the amount you
mentioned earlier...
... and he's in agreement, he doesn't
wish to make a fuss. - Okay, okay. Come on.
And just like that, you...
... the moralist...
... the one who dishes out morals to
Italians in the newspapers every week...
... is hired to cover up a murder.
With your pure man facade...
... you've bought the public...
... the newspapers, everyone, and you've
placed a rock on top of a murder.
What murder?
That guy was just crazy!
Go on, Stefano, I'm surprised at you.
Surprised?
Surprised how sick you make me?
You, my father, everyone.
Do you know that he was just an
unfortunate kid, that he wasn't to blame?
A harmless being, a desperate boy.
I saw him, he came to me...
... and for a measly million lire
they pushed him to suicide!
I beg you, can you not go
to the newspapers tomorrow...
... tonight, right away, and
tell them everything that happened?
Tell them about a mad man who
threw himself out of a window?
I beg you, do something!
I beg you, do it...
... now, right away, no matter
how much money my father gives you!
What should I do, in your opinion?
Make a scandal!
I'll be with you, against my father,
I swear it!
Alright, Stefano, that will do!
Such a fuss!
Yes, such a fuss for
someone who just died...
And for who none of you give
a damn about, you most of all.
So, you're corrupt too.
You're up to your neck
in the world of the sly, too.
All done! What did I tell you?
Everything can be sorted out
with a little goodwill.
Now he's speaking with the
lawyer and then he'll be gone.
- Did you leave him downstairs alone?
- Well, he asked me to.
And we have to be careful about these things,
we don't want him to lose his head.
Vincenzo, call the gentleman
downstairs in the car...
... and offer him something to eat.
- Right away, Sir! - Let's go.
- Stefano, sit down!
- Stefano is quite agitated.
I know, he's always agitated.
He'll end up in one of those beds
next to his mother at a clinic.
Perhaps you should listen to him,
that might be better.
Oh, of course! Come no!
Let him speak...
... he can tell us what the Bible
says we should do at this point.
How boring your irony is, Father.
It sounds bad, vulgar.
And you know why it's vulgar?
Because it's useless, Father.
You're not funny.
You're not a good person!
Did you hear that, Morandi?
If I'm not mistaken, you were the
one who wanted him to talk...
... and you only ended up
angering our little altar boy here.
But since all of this talk was started...
... because of some crazy guy who
threw himself out of a window...
... even if I wanted to,
I can't resurrect the dead.
I can, however, pay them,
and that's exactly what I'm doing.
You may as well spit on them,
too, if you're going to pay them.
Don't talk like your mother.
You spit on everything.
You did the right thing to call me.
I wasn't sure I'd hear from you again!
Well? How do I look?
Good!
Actually, tonight I look terrible.
I ruined all my skin on that damn boat.
I shouldn't have come, I know.
But the trip was quite nice.
- Did you know that I've not
seen your father since then? - No?
Of course, I couldn't after
what happened between us.
To tell you the truth,
I'd have carried on all the same...
... it was clear that he
only invited me for you...
... so it can't have offended him.
You don't think so?
I think that's exactly why he invited me.
Anyway, I don't regret it.
Do you know what I told him?
"Alright, Leo, I won't make a fuss."
"I'll pack my case and leave."
As if I didn't know why he asked me to come.
And anyway, it's true, because if
I'd known, I wouldn't have done it.
No! Well, for you I'd have done it.
What's wrong? Are you sad?
What can you do? I'm a little sad,
you know, because I ended up...
... really liking Leo.
He's quite charming, don't you find?
Never mind!
Anyway, it's not like I'm being left alone.
Ah, my darling, I could never
carry on without someone in my life.
And anyway, with the money he gave me...
I bought two apartments:
one to rent, and the other to live in.
But I have to finish paying for
them before the year's out.
You're not happy to own your own place?
Of course! But you need money, and lots of it.
Money is something your father understands.
What can you do? The world is what it is!
Your father is right about that, too.
- Don't you find?
- No.
He's not right.
A world in which my father is
right can never be good.
Take it from me, Stefano, live your life!
Live, and don't think! It's better that way!
But how?
How am I supposed to live?
Come inside with me for a minute...
... you could use a distraction.
- What are you going to do?
- My brother is in there.
I need to help him with something,
then we can leave.
He gets into a mess every day,
imagine if I didn't keep an eye on him!
So, are you coming?
Come on, I'll take you home afterwards.
- What are we really doing, anyway?
- Right.
- Why, what do you want to do?
- Exactly, where are we going?
You're right, the world is what
it is and can't be changed.
That's more like it!
I'm rich, and I'll defend my money...
... just like my father does.
Finally, you understand!
Lucky you!
And anyway, money does grows on trees!