No! What are you doing? No!
No Margaret! No!
Margaret!
THE CURSE OF THE VAMPIRE
People's idols are silver and gold which are
the work of men's hands.
They have mouths and speak not.
They have eyes and see not.
They have ears but hear not.
Lord...
May thy infinite light
enlightens his way to eternity.
Dr. Mersch was a great man.
Thank you Mr Baron for using your influence to send us
a doctor as soon as possible.
As mayor
I must confess my concern at the strange circumstances of these deaths.
We need to wipe the silly
superstitions of these people.
Do not worry. You can count
on my help if you need it.
Thank you.
Afternoon. This is
the town hall, isn't it?
Yes, Miss. It is here.
Good afternoon. You are the new doctor, aren't you? Come in.
The mayor awaits you.
Mr Rohan, Dr. Materlick and his nurse.
Sit down, please.
- Thank you.
Here is my nomination.
Yes I know. You asked for
an energetic Doctor
to fight against superstition in this region.
This is precisely why I asked for this place.
Miss Erika is my assistant.
Fine.
You will live in the house of Dr. Mersch.
Incidentally, in his report sent to
the Ministry of Health,
the Dr. mentioned a disease
that seems to have spread
throughout the region for a long time.
Could you tell me more about it?
I do not know but you should read
Dr Mersch's diary. He noted everything.
Here it is.
I had it in case you asked for it.
-Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
-It's nothing.
My name is Christopher Rohan.
-I guess that you want to relax now.
-Yes.
I will accompany you.
Do you need anything else?
What can you tell me about this
mysterious disease that kills young people?
Oh, don't ask me about this.
They are vampires.
Dr. Mersch laughed at me when we
talked about it. He said it was a joke.
Vampires don't exist.
But they do.
-Well, Ladies. Good night.
-Good night.
I can not find scientific explanations for these
cases often repeated on regular periods.
People of the country
attribute this terrible
disease to the bite of vampires,
blood suckers that are resurrecting on the full moon.
It is an absurd idea
but legends tell that
vampires are cadavers
that can feed on human blood.
They rise in the night.
It is also says that vampires can be
killed with a stake through the heart.
They can be recognized by the fact that
they are not reflected in a mirror.
A cross can stop them.
I repeat that these superstitions are unacceptable for
a man of science like me.
And yet I must admit
that something strange...
Open the door.
Dr. Materlick?
Yes. It's me.
I am the servant of Baron Von Rysselbert.
The Baron is very sick.
Another heart attack.
His son sent me to seek you.
I ask you to accompany me.
My car is waiting for you.
Baron Von Rysselbert? Erika prepares
the briefcase. Wait a minute.
Let's go.
She is the housekeeper. She will
lead you to the Baron's room.
Please follow me.
Come in.
Good evening Dr. Materlick.
I'm Carl Von Rysselbert, the Baron's son.
Tell me, what is wrong with your father?
An attack. It happens often.
He suffers from a bad heart.
Coramine.
-So Doctor?
-The danger has passed.
Veil him carefully.
Please come with me.
How is he?
He had a heart failure but he will
recover soon. Do not worry.
Here we are far from civilization.
I'm afraid that another attack
could happen again.
Can you stay in the castle?
But we left everything we needed at home.
Do not worry about it.
Otto will take the nurse to the village
and she will get what's necessary.
I'm asking you, please.
I'm afraid. Afraid to be without
anyone's help in this castle.
My father because of his little fads
removed the telephone
and anything that represented progress.
It's okay. We will stay.
Thank you very much.
Want something to drink?
No thanks.
The tranquility of having a doctor nearby.
You drink a lot?
No, only when I'm nervous.
Here.
It will do you good.
This is curious.
These tracks remind me of something
that Dr. Mersch wrote about.
These marks?
People say that these are traces of vampires.
But you can see...
I'm still alive.
I love, you see,
I love which is impossible.
Which is beyond life.
I love the mystery which is prohibited.
If I was Adam
I would not have expected
the temptation of Eve.
What is forbidden delights me
because it's an adventure.
The real life.
Because it enlightens the
terrible night we live in.
This is why...
by the full moon...
I feel reborn.
I'm like the others.
But do not pay attention.
In this family we're all a little crazy.
Doesn't it seem wonderful to you?
The castle was built 600 years
ago by the Templars.
Here they celebrated their secret rites.
Here they conspired, buried their
treasures and tortured their enemies.
Some nights I hear their terrible wailing.
I believe in reincarnation.
I understand that this may seem absurd.
But I feel as if my ancestor is living in me.
I hear the call of the beyond
which makes me reborn.
Doctor, your nurse has arrived.
If you don't mind I will
accompany you to your rooms.
Thank you. Good night.
Rest well, Doctor.
I'll be on guard, Doctor.
Need something?
- No thanks.
Good night.
- See you tomorrow.
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon. What do you want?
- I'd like to send a telegram.
You're the new Doctor, aren't you?
-Too bad.
-Too bad?
Yes because you're too young and too
pretty to lock yourself in a hole like that.
I find this hole very enjoyable.
Here blows an unhealthy wind.
Believe me. In your place
I'd have left a long time ago.
I wouldn't wait till tomorrow.
Why?
For health reasons.
How much do I owe you?
- 30 francs.
-Good bye.
-Good bye Miss.
The doctor said you should take this medicine.
I have not seen her this morning.
You know where she is?
She went to the village.
She wants to call a specialist
for him to do an analysis.
I feel very well.
When I have a crisis like last night
I recover in a few hours.
Know how to play?
-No Mr Baron but I can try.
-We'll see about that.
It is very easy.
Hold this.
You must hit there. You see?
With the cane on the white ball.
Not like that. To the right.
Cane straight to touch the red ball. Ouch!
It was almost that.
Hello Miss.
I'll take you so you can visit the area around the castle.
Fantastic! If you allow it Mr Baron.
Yes my girl.
Do not go near the marshes, Carl.
You remind me of a woman
who meant a lot to me.
She is no longer?
Her name's Margaret. She's my cousin.
She went to Switzerland and I haven't heard from her since.
-She was married to another.
-No.
Well, I think not.
Sometimes I see her at night.
It's her ghost.
She's watching me.
-Come. We'll see the marsh
-But your father said ...
Ah, old man's habit!
I do not know why but this marsh attracts me.
I come here often just
to contemplate water.
As if a strange influence forced me to.
Look.
Isn't it wonderful?
Impressive.
Water is the principle and end of life.
Mistress of death.
Here I kissed Margaret for the first time.
It is a magical place.
Let's go. Let's flee from here.
I'm afraid.
Afraid?
Yes.
Afraid to know that
I'm not like the others.
I don't understand.
At the center of the swamp
there is quicksand.
When I was a child I saw my horse drown.
Drown slowly.
Slowly.
After that I was sick for a long time.
I can't...
I can't forget it.
Margaret.
You were there!
You've seen her too?
Don't leave me.
She's there.
Don't you see her?
No.
Margaret!
Wait for me!
Margaret.
Come on, let's go to the ruins.
What happened?
Can I enter?
I just got here.
Serve yourself a drink.
I'm a little ahead.
I'm pooped. I did not know you had
to run so much to get married.
Want some?
I gotta go.
You must understand Max.
I do it for her.
She has always been very
interested in vampirism.
This passion made her seek the
place of doctor in the village.
And I think she is in danger.
There's few days before the wedding.
But of course, you received
a telegram and you go.
And to the fiancé you say
"understand Max"
and he understands.
Come on darling, you know how much I
love you but I can't leave her alone.
I do not understand.
It's not an excuse for postponing the wedding?
-You know it's not.
-So what is the reason?
When we were students my parents had
the accident that took their lives.
I was broke and couldn't pay for my studies.
Then Greta and her family supplied all my needs.
Thanks to her I am now Doctor.
If she sends a telegram that says
"come, I need you", I gotta go.
You understand now, Max?
She did not put her address.
I'll get it from the town hall.
I won't be long.
In the end I have to thank you. I will
have more time to bury my boy's life.
Idiot!
I'll take your car. Mine is down.
-Take care of yourself.
-Now go on.
I have to change.
With my health problems
I'm not allowed to drink.
But tonight,
if you permit it Doctor,
I'll make an exception.
I want you to taste the
brandy that I keep in my cellar.
It is over a 100 years.
It is very strong and dangerous
and I am not accustomed to drink.
Don't you think you have to
become a devil first
before trying to become a saint?
A great sinner will be able to become a
saint more easily than
the man who's never experienced the pleasures of life.
To find true love you must
have loved many times before.
Do you understand?
I think to know what love is
you only need to love once.
Nice answer
and I do not want to remove
your illusions about romanticism.
And you Doctor?
Do you share the opinion
of your lovely assistant?
Yes.
But I have not loved enough.
I am very interested in my profession.
And that's all.
What do you think of the Brandy?
The first impact is amazing and doesn't leave enough time to enjoy it.
It's true.
Well. One of you dare to get another glass?
I do.
Otto, serve me another drink.
With your permission we will retire.
- Mr Baron must rest and so do we.
Good night.
We'll have to obey the Doctor.
Doctor.
Enter.
The Baron has had another attack.
I beg you to accompany me.
One moment.
Calm down, Baron. Calm down.
I'm here Doctor.
Give me the briefcase.
Come on. Calm down.
Coramine.
-How many drops?
-20.
You will feel better.
Margaret.
It is not easy for your Doctor friend
to face a village full
of superstitious people.
Greta is very brave.
Do not worry.
-She knows what she's doing.
-I hope.
She's all alone in this town and
she is counting on your
cooperation as an analyst.
We worked together a long time.
Are you married?
Why do you ask?
For nothing.
I do not want to hide that the
attacks of your father worry me.
That night, despite the painkillers,
he was unable to sleep soundly.
He is obsessed with a name
that he repeats endlessly.
Margaret.
You know who this is?
Yes. My cousin.
She disappeared.
It's been said that she left for Switzerland but we never learned anything.
My father loved her above all else.
Perhaps more than me.
This coat of arms, what does it mean?
These are the arms of the family.
This grid is no longer used?
Of course not.
Nice castle.
According to the legend it was
built over 600 years ago.
Hello Otto.
-Good afternoon.
-We come to see the Doctor.
Go please.
Good afternoon.
-Hello, Carl.
-How are you?
-Doctor.
-Good afternoon.
Carl, this is my friend.
Doctor Nell.
Son of the Baron.
Enchanted and welcome.
Do you want to have something?
Thank you. We had lunch on the way.
Let us have at least the honor of
accepting our hospitality at the castle.
Thank you, I accept with pleasure.
This way I can chat with Dr. Materlick.
Incidentally, Mr Mayor, can
I speak with you a moment?
Whenever you want.
-Doctor. Please.
-Thank you.
I have good news.
The material you requested is finally here.
I am grateful to you, Mr Rohan.
So now I can open the clinic.
The arrival of Dr. Nell is providential.
I am ready to fight with
all my strength against
this strange anemia Dr.
Mersch speaks of in his diary.
Tonight is the full moon
and it seems
that it is at that moment
that the disease wakes up.
This is something weird and
bordering on superstition that I
would like to see definitely destroyed.
Despite the passing of time, people continue to believe in vampires.
And you Mr Rohan?
Do you believe they exist?
A grown man can not believe in them
but despite that
I put a lock on my door at night.
The lover knocked at the door of his beloved.
She asked: Who is it?
He answered: It's me.
She did not open the door
and despairing he knocked again and
to the question "Who is this?"
he replied: I am you.
Then the door opened.
I wouldn't have opened the door.
Because if it was really
the lover who knocked
he would only say: you.
Forgetting himself.
You're too subtle Erica.
Upon your arrival at the castle,
as soon as I saw you, I knew
no one and nothing could separate us.
And yet we are still separated.
Why?
I feel the anguish of not
being free, my hands are chained.
Erica, I want you to
understand me, I'm sick.
For all my love that goes beyond life
I beg you to leave the castle.
Do not wait. Not even until the night.
Erica you're crazy, crazier than me.
Run away from me.
I can cause you a lot of trouble.
Forgive me.
The Baron had an accident and since
then nobody has seen his cousin.
He said she studies in Switzerland.
It is all fascinating.
Here is Dr Mersch's diary.
Read it. It confirms my suspicions.
Mr Baron asks you to forgivee him,
he will not come to dinner.
-And Mr. Carl?
-He had to leave.
Ask Mr Baron if I can go
to see him after dinner.
-I have to do an analysis.
-Very well Miss.
How interesting. Dr. Mersch
insinuates the existence of vampires.
Almost, almost...
He had to be a very imaginative man.
Come in.
Excuse me Mr Baron.
I just neeed to get a blood test.
Good.
It will not be long.
I will do you no harm.
Your arm.
Bend it.
Clench the fist please.
That's it.
You will feel just a little bite.
-So? It hurt you?
-No.
What's going on?
Greta I'm very scared.
I heard a terrible cry.
So did I. Everything that happens
in this castle is very strange.
Let's see what it is.
The housekeeper is trying to hide something.
I assure you it was not
the Baron who screamed like that.
I'm going to my room and locking myself in.
When the analysis is finished I will
leave and try to forget this castle forever.
Speak lower.
Erica...
Something wrong Miss?
No.
I thought I heard women laughing.
I was looking for my nurse who is not in her room.
She has probably gone
for a walk with Mr Carl.
The night is beautiful.
Margaret...
Erica...
Come in.
Hello Mr Rohan.
Hello Brenda.
I allowed myself to call
you to ask a favor.
I know you and Marisa grew up together.
You were very friendly.
After what happened Marisa is in shock.
She should not be left alone.
As she has no parents, I thought you ...
Do not worry Mr Rohan. I will keep her company.
I know what she must feel.
She was married for a short time.
Thank you.
I'm happy to help her. Tell me Mr Rohan.
Is it true her neck had vampire bites?
Nonsense! People's superstitions!
Vampires do not exist.
It is true her neck had bites, but
her body lay all night in the countryside. It could've been any animal.
But people say ...
Yet these are superstitions!
Don't tell me that you also believe in vampires.
You know Mr Mayor, Dr. Mersch said the same. And the truth is that ...
Alright, alright, forget it ...
If you no longer need me ...
No thank you.
Rest easy. I'm going straight to her house.
-Good.
-Good day Mr Mayor.
You should go to sleep.
I will help you to do everything I can.
Why's he taking so long?
He always goes outside to walk
and leaves me alone.
I sing, I sing because I'm scared.
You have nothing to fear.
I'm with you.
As at the internship.
Do you remember?
We shared the same room together.
We shared everything everywhere.
After that you got married
and we no longer saw each other. Now it will be as before.
I'll take care of you.
Soon you will forget everything.
Well, go to sleep now.
I'll see you again soon.
Do not cry my child.
Your mother will never fail you.
He's there.
He must not leave the castles domain.
He's gone. He'll return
only if the moon's hiding.
This is horrible. The poor people
who will fall under his hand.
He must be here.
Carl!
There! He's there!
Miss Erica is not in her room.
And Mr. Carl? Where is he?
He sleeps. He went outside last
night and returned very late.
Erica probably went down to the village.
Without telling me?
Believe me. I'm very worried.
We must search for her.
She wouldn't leave without saying anything.
Brenda?
He's coming.
What's wrong with you Brenda?
Please tell me.
He's coming.
I feel it.
He approaches.
Brenda?
He's coming. I feel it.
He approaches.
He's coming. He's coming.
Wait a moment please.
I'll talk with the mayor.
Sorry Mr Mayor.
Dr. Materlick wants to talk to you.
Tell her to enter.
Good morning.
Sorry to bother you
but I am very concerned.
My assistant Miss Rosenberg has
disappeared from the castle.
Nobody's seen her since last night.
In addition, Brenda, our nurse
is having a nervous breakdown.
And most disturbing is that she has
traces of a bite that looks...
Like a vampire?
Please Doctor.
You are really nervous.
Tonight I will go to the castle.
Your nurse will certainly be back.
The only danger is if she
approaches the swamp.
There's quicksand there and she would not be the first victim. But I don't think so.
I do not know what happened to Erica.
I looked all over the house.
You think it's possible
she changed into a vampire?
We must find her quickly.
What worries me is that the butler told me
that they went out together last night.
I'm afraid for her.
I think Carl knows where she is.
-You didn't tell me they were together?
-But it is precisely for that reason.
Carl is a psychopath.
You're making me afraid Greta.
We will form groups.
This girl could get lost in the
ruins of the monastery or in the marsh.
Carl, you know very well
the ruins, go ahead.
-I'll go with Carl.
-I'll go to the marshes.
I'm going with you.
Good luck.
Otto, do not lose sight of Carl.
I heard that you didn't spend the night in the castle.
Without being indiscreet, can
you tell me where you were?
Yesterday? Yes, I was in town.
Erica, my nurse, went out
with you some nights.
-You didn't see her last night?
-No, that's why we're trying to find her.
I do not understand why you're asking me this question.
I love Erica and I am
concerned about her fate.
This morning I was in the village.
Brenda was unconscious and spoke in dreamy hallucinated words.
Besides
she had on her neck the same mark as you.
Tonight is the full moon.
You're not afraid to be alone with me?
Your skin may tempt a vampire.
Dear Carl, I do not believe in vampires.
I believe in psychopaths and killers.
You accuse me?
Look. There are the ruins.
We'd better split up.
Yes Carl. As you wish.
You're going to stay
here and do nothing?
No.
I am nervous about this.
I believe that this is the end.
We tried to hide Margaret
for several years.
She was bitten. She turned into a monster
and she also destroyed your son Carl.
This night of full moon
nothing can hold them back.
On our conscience weighs the victims
who fall between their claws.
Dr. Mersch foresaw it all. That's
why you have caused the accident
that cost him his life.
And now Dr. Materlick risks the same fate.
I can not stay like this.
I will confess everything to the mayor.
Shut up! Shut up!
You will not tell anyone. You cannot
reveal what happens in this castle.
This is our secret.
Your son Carl?
What're you going to do with him?
Lock him up and never let him out.
Never.
You're mad!
You hurt?
-No. It's nothing.
-You sure?
Let's go.
Erica!
Erica back!
Erica don't go! At the bottom
of the marsh there's quicksand.
The poor woman!
The emotion was too strong.
Nobody can now say that the suspicions of Dr. Mersch were proven. She went crazy.
Hurry up please.
timings : meatisgood
translation : aloysius70 + Senor Zitos