THE DEATH OF THE SCORPION
Come in, boy.
I'll fix you a drink.
Calm down,
don't be like that.
You pay me now.
Right away.
I have no money, I swear.
I have no money.
I swear!
Shut up, you dirty bitch.
Cut. It's a good one.
Now give me a
close up of the wound.
How'd it go?
Perfect.
- What do you think about it?
- It's awful.
- It's your script.
- So what?
- Which one should we use?
- The fake one, of course.
I never liked this type of roles.
- Don't move.
It's only that I'm fit for them
and I know how to play them.
I'd like to play the role
of a counsel, a doctor...
...a businessman...
Because the role of a homosexual...
- I don't see myself in it.
- Please don't move...
40 seconds.
And the second one?
Ten seconds less.
- Ready?
- Yeah, let's roll.
Will the blood be visible enough?
I think it's okay.
- Look.
- Let me see.
Problems.
Problems all the time.
People would go to the
movies to have a good time.
- I don't make films for friends.
- I don't want to write them either.
But you can make new
things with a minimal risk.
Let's see this
through to the end.
- I'll talk to him.
- Hey.
- Hey, Álvaro.
- Come here.
- What?
Nobody's eaten in 12 hours.
- I know, patience...
- I'm saying it for the boys...
- You can't cut the shooting now.
- Always the same old song...
- More and more...
- Only 15 more minutes...
You can't teach me anything
of the business world.
And much less of cinema.
The audience is always king.
What are the alternatives?
Don't play the intellectual.
This detective series is going well.
Think of another story.
Add some suspense, bed
scenes and a bit of action.
And cheap.
You've done real good
things for me in the past.
- What have you done?
- What is it now?
Stop moving!
That's all I have.
I told you to bring
a big pot of it!
I'm sorry.
You're a good pro and I
want you to work with me.
But if you go on like that,
I'll know what to do.
I was just sayin'.
You'll have that
script, don't worry.
He's just clumsy. He dropped
it and he has no more of it.
And I still need to
encourage this sloppy lot.
Is it true what I heard?
I dropped it accidentally.
Well, then paint it or something!
I've had enough!
Everyone back to work!
We can't waste more time!
That's no way to shoot...
He's right, everyone
back to work...
Good.
- Add your sugar yourself.
- Okay.
Careful with your cup.
That's it.
Caress him.
I like it sweet.
- Good.
- Very sweet.
- How many would you like?
- Two, please.
Kiss him.
Perfect.
Awesome.
What's your production
plan for next year?
Cinema is a very
effective teaching tool.
I mean the producer's role
is very important
and this is my great concern.
Now on the couch.
My concern and many
other producers' too.
The public needs a product
they can enjoy and feel entertained with.
And which may also
contribute to raise...
- Their cultural level?
- Exactly.
Cultural, artistic...
We need to combine these interests
with the industry's own interests.
Carmen, you left film acting early to
devote yourself to your husband,
your son and the home
life to become Mrs. Riera.
Do you regret it?
No. I'm completely happy.
Being a housewife is one of
the best parts a woman can play.
Nostalgic?
Not really.
I feel totally fulfilled.
So the actress has
gone away for good.
Well, you never can tell.
But I'm a very happy woman now.
So much so, that sometimes
I think I'm dreaming.
That's all. We'll
publish it in 15 days.
- Ready?
- Yes.
Why in 15 days, mum?
Why does he say so?
- Pleased to meet you.
- Bye, thank you.
- I'll walk you out.
- Thank you.
- Oh...
- We need to help each other.
- Just call me if you need anything.
- Okay.
Goodbye.
Pleased to meet you.
Ouch!
You're always complaining.
Be still and don't be a pain.
Come on.
Give dad a kiss.
Happy?
You can't complain. You've
got to admit I'm a good actress.
I'm sorry, what did you say?
Nothing...
What do we do about it?
Say something.
Come over here.
The font is a bit sophisticated.
But the text...
If you don't want your husband
to know that you have a lover...
That's ridiculous.
Leave half a million...
Not bad.
Does anybody know
you come around here?
Dunno... a girlfriend...
What girlfriend?
Leave me alone.
Pawn something.
Are you out of your mind?
You know he controls everything.
Don't exaggerate.
We must find a solution.
What?
We have to pay.
I don't know how.
But we'll have to pay.
The problem is your son.
Carlos is mine.
Nobody can take
him away from me.
First, we must know...
What will Andrés
do if he finds out?
Maybe he won't mind.
Since we have a meeting at
your house tomorrow evening...
I'll just ask him.
It's late.
Come, I want you on top.
The plot begins with
the usual triangle.
And an exorbitant
blackmail that they can't pay.
Sounds good to me.
Why wouldn't she get a divorce?
Because of her husband's money?
Nobody will believe that.
- It has to be something more private.
- Their children.
Most married couples
will go on for their children.
No.
What for, then?
Love?
Yes, even if you
may think otherwise.
I'm sick of this gadget!
In how many movies
have you used it already?
This is its fifth one.
I hope we'll ditch it
for our next movie.
Let's be serious now.
Women are afraid
of living alone.
They get married because
they know no better.
You must speak from experience.
They bind themselves
for their children.
It's my turn now.
Any woman will lose them
if she dares to separate.
They always stay with the father.
Isabel...
You don't have a clue
about how men think.
If you and I should be married,
and you'd want to separate,
you can take the children.
You obviously don't
have any children.
What would you do?
Just suppose you find out
Carmen is cheating on you.
Bullshit!
That's the attitude the
husband must have in the movie.
That's the story's
initial dramatic spine.
I'm tired.
Okay.
We need some action.
Drugs, trafficking in women...
Okay, let's leave it as it is.
All men are the same.
They think of nothing else.
Sex, always sex.
Please calm down, madam.
Of course...
At his age...
His secretary is
always flirting.
I suspected it.
When you get old,
they just dump you.
Do you want to file
for a separation?
No...
With the report we've got, we'd
be able to claim maintenance.
No...
So what do you want me to do?
I don't know.
. No need to worry, madam.
- Okay, thank you very much.
- Have a nice day.
- Bye.
- Hi, Carmen.
- Hi.
I came to visit a friend.
She lives upstairs. On the 4th floor.
It's two floors up.
Do you want to come
in and chat for a while?
No, I can't. I'm in a
hurry. Some other day.
That's too bad.
The girlfriend
trick is too old.
You have problems, haven't you?
What is it?
Nothing, nothing.
- You have a lover.
- What?
Someone knows and
is blackmailing you.
Come on, I'm a counsel.
Try to trust me a little.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
It was clear that
you'd be in trouble.
You'd better admit it.
You got married to escalate.
You didn't give it much thought
and found yourself pregnant.
How do you know?
I follow you.
I get bored,
and I'd read the rags.
I like to read gossip
about famous people.
Do you think I still have
hard feelings about it?
It was ten years ago.
I'm not that mean.
I can be of help.
Will you take the elevator?
Or you'd rather
walk down the stairs?
We've got two hours.
You're a bit late, aren't you?
This is all I could get.
I'd never wear it.
Do you think
Andrés will find out?
If you pay, it becomes a loop.
- What will you do next month?
- It won't happen again.
Why?
He's asking too much.
He can't be a pro.
Who told you that?
Luis.
I see.
What are you doing?
Someone needs to
pick up a package.
Not very original, but
I can't think of anything else.
Please, don't.
Why would you come here anyway?
I dunno.
Someone will pick
up this package.
Does Luis know you're here?
No.
Are you in love?
You don't ask these
things this way.
You are.
Let's go.
Come...
Can I already give you...?
Of course.
Go get it.
For my mum.
For Mother's Day.
What is it?
A man is kicking the ball.
The grass.
People who are watching.
- And the sky.
- Very well.
Hey, Carlitos...
Go get the box.
What is this?
Help her out.
How nice!
Thank you.
- One moment.
- I love it. It's so beautiful.
It's for you, madam.
The seamstress.
Excuse me.
Quite a coat, eh?
Come...
Hello?
And now you'll tell me
everything you have drawn.
Hi.
That was foul play, my dear.
- Who is it?
- You'll receive another postcard.
And these are the stars.
No tricks this time.
And no counsellors either.
Okay. I'll drop
by this afternoon.
Come on now.
Straight to the clouds!
Go get it.
Run!
Where's Carmen?
In her room.
- She's not feeling well lately.
- What's wrong?
I don't know.
It must be the weather.
It affects her a lot.
There you go!
You'd better take a break.
- Want some? - No
- Oh, just for today.
Drinking doesn't agree with me.
Have you thought
about the actors?
Not yet.
I've got her only.
Your wife could do it.
No, the main character
must be a stunning woman.
A second-rate Italian.
Co-productions want it that way.
She'd love to make a comeback.
That's impossible.
So, what was the plot?
She hires a private eye.
- No, no... That's too clichéd.
Private eyes are very
colourless roles anyway.
She'd better hire...
a counsellor instead.
An old friend.
She trusts him.
What's the difference?
It's the same thing.
She goes to see him on her own.
She doesn't tell
her guy about it.
He gets pissed off and
breaks up with her. But why?
She has money, or at
least she can get it for sure.
She'd better pay if
she wants to have fun.
It's crystal clear.
- How are you feeling?
- I'm better, thank you.
You have a call from Rome.
- Hi, Luis.
- Hi.
Are you still angry?
Be careful.
I don't care.
Please try to understand.
Fernando takes
care of these things.
- I thought he could help us.
- Yeah, I saw that.
- I'm sorry.
- Listen...
I don't want more
troubles, understand?
I need you.
Go find that friend of
yours if you feel alone.
- He's more experienced.
- Luis, won't you play with me?
- There's the ball.
- We'll use this one instead.
Come on, hit it.
You've had such a
straight face all evening.
I needed to make
a good impression.
You amused them
for both of us anyway.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, but I'm tired.
You'd better sit down.
That soprano and the
orchestra were great.
But Wagner bores me.
He makes me thirsty.
Wait... have a drink.
- The last one.
- No.
Open up!
What do you want?
I'm really exhausted.
I have a headache.
Just open up!
Goodnight.
Luis!
What is it?
Feeling nervous?
Listen...
But I feel very happy.
So much so, that sometimes...
I feel like I'm dreaming.
- Mummy?
- What are you doing here?
- Where's daddy?
- He's out on a trip.
Don't look at me that way.
He won't bring you anything.
Yes, he will.
Can I sleep with you?
You're too old for that.
Come on, stay still.
Come on kid, stay still.
Let's go to bed.
- No time for comics.
- Please. - No.
- It's time to sleep.
- Please...
- I want to read it.
- Give me a kiss.
Carmen.
What are you doing?
You're freezing.
Come.
- I'd like to spend the night here.
- That won't be possible.
Just imagine when the maid
gets into your room with your breakfast...
Where is she?
Miss!
Miss?
Do you like me?
- I've got some wrinkles...
- Get out...
What's this about?
Who's there?
Stay here.
Who was that?
Nothing.
Just a joke.
- Who was that?
- Nothing...
It's normal in this
neighbourhood.
We can't see each other again...
...here.
We must be more cautious.
Don't you ever leave me!
- Hi.
First off, none of them
has any previous record.
This is the cottage's service.
The cooker is a widow.
She'd only leave on Sundays to go
to mass and visit her married cousin.
She spends the
whole afternoon there.
She gets back by
nine with the bus.
The most interesting thing about her
must be the line she travels with.
Oh well...
The maid and the gardener
are irrelevant to the case.
This must have come out
of the production company.
Carmen has been displaced
ever since she got married.
She's lost all of her friends.
All the people she knows
now come from Andrés's side.
Álvaro Sánchez.
He works as a production
chief and is Andrés's henchman.
He'd only go from home to work.
He's married, with five children.
The concierge says
he's in financial trouble.
He can't pay the instalments
of a fridge he bought.
He owes three months' rent
but he keeps on buying things.
Juan Dalmau.
He's also married.
No children.
He's always hanging around.
He boasts about being a film director.
And he'd always use
credit cards to pay.
Luis Serra.
Single.
He lives on his own.
He lives an orderly life,
writing scripts at home.
He'd barely go out.
No known debts.
Everything Carmen told you about is true.
He's an orphan.
He's been working with Andrés since
he was 15. He started out as a gofer.
I wish I'd make the good
money he makes now.
Let me see.
Isabel Borras.
She lives with her parents.
She'd go out to party often,
and she'd stay the night at her friends'
houses sometimes, but nothing else.
She likes to have fun.
She works on a whim.
She's some sort of secretary. Both for
the production company and on shootings.
She comes from a wealthy family.
She spends the night
with Luis once a week.
Regularly.
That's all.
I see.
When do you have to pay?
In a few days.
Does Carmen know
another postcard arrived?
No, she doesn't.
You're in for a world of hurt.
Why would you?
Don't worry.
I can handle it.
I'm sorry, I thought you
had left. I'll come back later.
Hey, you!
Keep the wheel aside.
What are they doing?
They're cleaning up the beach.
Can't it be done automatically?
Labour is cheaper.
You know...
The blackmailer may be one of
the models who go out with Juan.
Or Isabel.
Or Álvaro.
Or Álvaro's wife.
- It could be anyone.
- You're only taking half of it...
Even Luis.
Come on...
Are you jealous?
Andrés would just
push people around.
- Who can put up with it?
- You can.
Wait no more.
Get ahead of yourself.
Strike first.
Sue him for divorce.
- It's not so easy.
- Why?
You don't know him.
He'd try to kill me.
I'm serious.
Okay...
What about the kid in the park?
Nothing.
He fetched the package
for a box of candy.
Sugar?
Yes.
Two, please.
It can't be a single person.
I'm looking for a girl with
an old woman's voice...
...who may act in collusion with
someone from the production company.
We've got some
contradictory information here.
What are you thinking of?
Are you aware that Luis
may also be implied?
Don't be silly.
He has no reason to.
He just left me.
I found out...
...that your guy
sleeps with Isabel.
I was thinking that tonight I'll
make things clear, no matter what.
Or almost.
No!
You can't be serious!
What about the kid?
He needs a family, he needs his father!
Please don't yell at me.
You'll see us anytime you want.
The three of us.
There are countless
ways to settle this.
I know I'm hurting you,
and I'm sorry for that.
- Because I love you.
- Duh!
Yes, I do.
But we're so different
from each other.
I feel oppressed in this house.
You've got to understand.
I'm so disappointed, Carmen.
There must be something else to it.
Something I don't
even want to consider!
Don't waste your time on that.
I simply don't feel
happy anymore.
I'm depressed.
You have anything you want.
If you're depressed,
you can see a psychiatrist.
I'm not sick!
I simply want to be myself.
I want to be something!
Can't you even see that?
I don't know what
else to tell you.
Please think it over.
We must think it over.
At least for a while.
Leave me alone.
As you like it.
I work too much.
Carmen is always at home.
Carlos is not a toddler anymore.
Its only logical.
When women get bored,
they start thinking too much.
We could call her
to a casting session.
- Carmen?
- Yes, but an easy one.
Sounds great.
I think she needs a distraction.
She's the true main character,
and can do a great job.
She goes from one lover to another,
always threatened by blackmailers.
Won't it be too monotonous?
No.
She tries to divorce her
husband before he finds out.
And what does her husband do?
I'm not quite sure yet.
He's suspicious.
He may react violently.
But he has no
evidence against her.
And he needs to believe that
his wife has told him the truth.
And they don't get
a divorce in the end.
That's impossible.
The audience
would feel ripped off.
People love
melodramatic endings.
Well...
...that's what you always say.
Okay, then start writing that script and
we'll call her for the casting session.
Alright.
See you later.
- Hi.
Scotch, please.
Who's that guy who just came in.
Do you know him?
- He's looking at you.
- I never saw him before.
But I don't like him at all.
- Where is she?
- In the toilet.
- It was the same dress.
- Yes, but the skirt was longer.
- I heard of a new place.
- Let's go see it.
No.
It's not her.
I'm sorry.
- Hi there. Do you come here often?
- Have you finished?
Are you having fun?
Come in.
Hi.
You look lovely.
You're tailor-made
for the character.
Nervous?
- Yes.
- It's just a test.
Yeah, but after so long...
This is what you do best.
I know very well.
Here.
- All of it?
- Up to the sign.
How are you doing?
- I feel very alone.
- Stop it.
- What about Isabel?
- Oh...
Does your counsellor know
what my tobacco brand is too?
So I'm a suspect too.
- So you keep receiving postcards.
- No, I don't.
Hi, Luis.
- Are you ready?
- Just a second.
Friends?
Friends.
Do I push the travelling forward?
- Yes.
Okay.
- Let's go.
Come on, leave
your nerves behind.
It's no big deal.
It'll be very easy for you.
We can start.
- There
Just stand there.
- Hi.
- Do I look good?
- Prettier than ever.
- Do you like my dress?
- You could back-comb your hair a bit...
Mind the spotlight.
What do you want?
Will I see you tonight?
I've got a lot of work to do.
I think I'll stay home.
Are you in some kind of trouble?
Why?
No...
We'll have dinner
together tomorrow.
- Tonight I need to write.
- We're ready too.
Well, what is it?
I'm not sure.
A strange guy was asking around.
He told me he was a
friend of yours and he's not.
He wouldn't tell me his name.
How was he?
In his forties,
quite handsome.
Some Grey hair.
An interesting man.
What did he want?
He wanted to know who was
hiring the voices for the dubbings.
I didn't understand. He asked
about everybody. Juan, Álvaro, you...
Why are you worried about it?
I think it's just an
old-fashioned flirting method.
I don't think so.
- Ready when you are.
- I'll be right there.
If he's a friend, he'll say
something eventually.
- See you tomorrow?
- You bet.
- Hey you.
- Hi.
Tell her what you want from her.
I don't know why
she's so nervous.
I'm off.
Have you learnt it?
Couldn't we just put something
here like a table or a chair...?
Something I can lean on.
No, no... A good actress
wouldn't need any of this.
Just imagine the stage.
It'll be easier when we shoot.
Imagine you're in a room.
In a house or in a hotel.
It doesn't matter.
You're a self-confident woman,
who's in a
relationship with a bore.
A really big bore.
You're with him but deep
inside you despise him.
Someone like that sinister one.
- Who?
- Who else?
Don't stop even if you
make a mistake, okay?
Okay.
Camera.
We're rolling.
Go ahead, Carmen.
Where have you been?
We can't go on like this.
I don't want to keep seeing you every
afternoon from 5 to 7 in this lousy room.
I'm a rich woman, my dear.
And I can still be much richer.
It's very simple.
My husband has to vanish.
You've got to be joking.
You could be a
good father to my son.
Are you afraid?
Would you rather be dragging
around like this for life?
You're a loser.
This is all you
have to offer me.
This is all.
I was playing a role.
I was lying.
Please forgive me.
What's this all about?
I was in a casting
for a film today.
Which film?
I wanted to surprise you.
It's a very nice role.
- Andrés...
- Andrés?
I see.
You just told him you want a
divorce and now you accept.
You don't see.
Why?
Why does he believe in you now?
You're a frustrated person.
They offer you a shit film and
you accept it with pleasure.
- Don't be vulgar.
- I am vulgar, so what?
Fernando...
- Leave me alone.
- Come here.
- What for?
- Come.
Come...
- I love you.
- I love you too, very much.
- Very much.
- Fernando...
Very much.
- Please don't.
- I'll handle this.
Hello?
- Hello?
- It's the second time you fail to pay.
- Your husband will
know all about it today.
Your honeymoon is over.
Goodbye forever.
Her again?
Enough.
- It's over.
- What?
The voice is fake.
It's a recording.
I'm positive.
Why didn't you tell me?
What could you do about it?
Nothing.
She had us both under her
fingers, and she has been quicker.
Your husband knows everything.
I can't believe it.
You'll have to
make decisions now.
I'm out of here.
See how useful my job is.
Come with me, with Carlos.
Yes.
I say we both run away.
We fly to Mexico tonight.
My brother lives there.
He works in the insurance
business. He'll help us.
It's not a very brilliant
proposal, I know.
But that's all I've got.
Take a chance.
You'll never be happy here.
Are you coming?
Too over the top.
What do you think?
- Let's hear it all, with music.
- Okay.
Come over.
I'll fix you a drink.
Come closer.
Calm down, boy.
You pay me now.
Right away!
I have no money here, I swear!
What are you trying to do?
No! No!
This is for you,
you dirty bitch!
Lights on.
It's no good.
Why?
It's a good one.
Next one.
It's okay.
Get it finished by 12h.
- That's impossible.
- Not a minute longer.
What do we do now?
Go ahead.
Where is he?
- In the editing room.
- Wait for me outside.
I need to talk to you.
Andrés.
Trust me.
You must do something about it.
Wake up!
Carmen loves you.
- I'm a fool.
- Don't let her go.
You need to protect her.
What can I do?
Listen...
Carmen and you have been having
problems for some time now, right?
Use your head.
She can't be in
love with that guy.
Sure...
As in your damned script.
- You knew!
- Let go of me!
What a foolish thing to say.
She'll forget all about it as soon
as she starts shooting the film.
I'm sure about it.
She doesn't deserve a thing!
Do you want her
to stay with you?
You must go home now.
She may still be there.
Let her be in her room tonight.
You need to.
You're her husband, aren't you?
I'll take care of him.
Here's his address.
I'll go to see him.
And tonight he'll
take that flight.
But on his own.
Carmen will understand.
- How could she...?
- Don't dwell on that.
If not for her,
do it for your son.
- She'll pay me back for this!
- Calm down!
Leave it in my hands.
You're capable of anything.
If he refuses to beat it,
then we'll have to scare him.
You need to write a cheque now.
A blank one.
You'll get it clean and cheap.
I'll drop by your house
when everything is settled.
Affairs just end when
they reach a certain limit.
And fast.
Open the door, please.
Mr. Vidal, so glad to find you.
My husband is gone!
He hasn't arrived home yet. I've call
every hospital in town and his friends.
Where can he be?
Maybe he ran away with his secretary.
I'm very busy now, I'm sorry.
Please help me!
I'm sorry I can't help you.
You feel alone, empty
inside, depressed...
And I swallowed
it all like a fool!
This is what he's
after, nothing else!
Stop it!
What do you know?
You think everybody's
as brute as you?
If you can't think straight,
someone will have to do it for you.
I'm sick of hearing
you tell me what to do!
Not this time, you hear me?
- What's this?
- It'll help you sleep.
Oh no!
I'm leaving!
You can have it all. You can
have Carlos if you want him.
I won't stand one more
single night in this house!
- Andrés!
- Nobody cheats on me!
Take this.
Good girl.
He's beating her down.
Get the hell out of here!
Go to sleep!
Andrés!
Open up!
Okay, have a good trip.
Radio Miramar. It's three minutes to
one. In a short while we'll be joined by...
Don't say a word
or I'll cut your throat.
We're going on a trip together.
So?
He took the flight.
It was easy.
He understood and went away.
Just like that?
Two hundred and the tickets.
I got some ideas for
the script in return.
- Are you sleepy?
- No.
- I'd like to discuss them.
- You can stay.
- Downstairs?
- Sure.
- Where's Carmen?
- She's sleeping. - Perfect.
No, I beat her.
Women are complicated.
Tomorrow she'll respect you.
Treat her kind.
Thank you, Luis.
Care for a drink?
- Is that an invitation?
- Of course.
Right on time.
I convinced him at one o'clock.
At two o'clock...
...he was climbing
the steps of the plane.
At three o'clock...
everything's over.
It seems we have a happy ending.
Lover vanishes and
marriage is still on.
Do you like it?
- That's a lot of coincidences.
- Please...
Luckily films are just films.
Let me carry on.
Everything's over.
We need some
imagination at play.
- Do you have your handgun here?
- Yes, as usual.
Get it.
From the war.
But it works.
Imagine it was Fernando
who rung the bell instead of me.
You have a quarrel, you fight...
He gets the knife
and you have the gun.
A stab wound, a shot...
...and the story ends with the
death of both husband and lover.
Shoot.
And the husband dies
for being too cautious.
It's empty.
The bullets are here.
That's a very vulgar ending.
Nobody will believe that.
As vulgar as the reconciled
couple, don't you think?
Another possibility.
The fourth character,
the blackmailer.
I'd rather it be a young,
attractive woman.
Fernando is about to uncover her and
she knows. What does she do about it?
She sends me these.
- Fernando goes away.
- But he can return.
Not for Carmen, but
to keep on searching.
- Too risky for her.
- A very dangerous thing to do.
She could end up in jail.
I don't understand any of this.
Suppose I'm the
fourth character.
Suppose...
The tickets, the cheque...
It was all a lie.
Fernando is tied
up in the garden.
Nobody knows you've come here.
Nobody would hear the shot.
You kill us both and
can still get away with it.
Then, the next day
they find the dead bodies of
the husband and his wife's lover.
A crime of passion.
And that's the end.
But Carmen can press
charges against you.
She knows nothing.
Both of them were
looking for a girl.
Okay, it works.
But I guess...
you'll have to build
your own scenery.
Wiping down prints,
dropping things around...
Do you like it like this?
What are you doing?
I'm pointing a gun at you.
What's going on?
- What is it?
- I'm sorry.
Excuse me.
I was thirsty.
I'm sorry.
- Should I change the sheet?
- No.
It's okay.
I'm very sleepy.
Sure.
You were tired.
I can change it, really.
No.
What time is it?
Two o'clock.
That's great.
We still have plenty
of time to sleep.
Madam!
Madam, they're dead!
Open up!
What is it?
The master...
he's in the office!
Don't touch anything, madam.
We must call the police.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
I'm very sorry.
See you, Carmen.
Take care.
Where's the boy?
I sent him to the
country with his uncles.
He likes it there.
I don't want him mixed up in this.
What's wrong?
Come with me, please.
That's his mother.
I don't want to see her.
You didn't love either of them.
I thought I knew him well.
I can hardly believe it.
You never can tell with people.
That's the way it is.
Luis, I'm scared.
Why?
I have to testify again and...
...I'm a bad liar.
Do you want everyone to
know that we were lovers?
She's the only one who knows,
and they won't catch her.
First and foremost,
you're an actress.
Or aren't you?
It all fits together.
You can be sure about it.
Don't be ghoulish.
It's not funny.
You look like a beetle.
Put this on.
How do I look?
You're hot.
- What are we drinking to?
- You.
Because you are finally free.
Do you really like your hairdo?
No...
- You should let it grow longer...
- I've always had it like this.
Andrés liked it this way.
You're going to change now.
It makes me
younger and I like it.
Come...
I've got something for you.
It's a surprise.
Pull the blinds and wait.
You can come in now.
What are you doing?
Put this wig on.
Now!
Let go of me!
You're hurting me.
She must be like you.
A long-haired woman.
Tall.
Wearing boots.
And a skirt.
You were the blackmailer, Carmen.
This I'm sure.
You think you're so smart.
What are you talking about?
- Enough! I'm out of here.
- You stay here!
Okay, that's enough!
No!
You make a loser
fall in love with you.
He'll run away with you,
but you set him up perfectly.
Fernando comes to pick
you up but he meets Andrés,
who's furious as he
just received the photos.
The result:
Free as a bird.
Álvaro.
Take this.
Anything that is not signed
will be on hold indefinitely.
- You can't do that.
- I have powers granted on me.
I need some fresh air.
We've got enough funds.
We'll make another kind of movies.
Okay.
What kind?
We'll see.
For the present we'll just finish
what's already started.
This is not a bank, Luis.
We can't stop.
What about the script
you were writing?
It won't be made either.
It would too morbid to make
such a film after what happened.
- Isabel!
- Yes, bye.
Answer when I call you.
Print this.
Send it to distribution
and production companies.
If you have any questions,
check the archive.
- Production manager.
- Can't you read or what?
It's the second
time you fail to pay.
Your husband will
know all about it today.
Your honeymoon is over.
Goodbye, forever.
Hello?
- Is Luis there?
- One moment.
The widow's on the phone,
Mr. Production Manager.
- Carmen?
- Hi.
- What's wrong?
- Are you busy?
Yes, of course.
What is it?
You may think I'm silly,
but I need some air.
Can you take a walk with me?
You mean now?
Yes, I'll pick you up.
Okay, yes.
See you, love.
I'm going to change
the ending of the film.
What are you talking about?
I'm not the blackmailer.
I don't want to be.
Give me that!
Don't be naive.
I sent all the evidence to a notary
in case something happens to me.
Why did you do it?
For money?
Take it easy...
I did it for you, Carmen.
You've never done
anything for me, Luis.
What did you have before
and what do you have now?
Can't you see the difference?
Carmen...
I love you.
You don't love anybody.
Anybody.
This attraction stops for one
minute so you can see the view.
It's all the time that's left
for this lurid story to end.
Do you want me to jump off?
It's up to you.
They're waiting
for you down there.
It's your life or mine.
If I jump off,
you'll come with me.
You can do it.
But it would be
useless and you know it.
Okay.
Sometimes you win,
sometimes you lose.
That's right.
Luis...
Sometimes you win,
sometimes you lose.
How long do I have?
Seconds.
And you...
What will you do without me?
What will I do?
I don't know.
But the story ends with you.
=== Fansubs by Sifasol ===