FREE LOVE
Miss Fifine!
Fifine!
Fifine?
Fifine.
Fifine disappeared.
Maybe he's killing himself
for a fling.
It all started a month ago,
when my grandmother died.
and Miguel, the notary, said
that we would only open the will...
in the presence of his
two other grandchildren...
my cousins
Jean-Paul and Séraphine...
disappeared since the great
family feud of 1942.
Miguel looked for them.
29 days passed.
Hello?
Hello, Cesar?
Good morning, Mr. Miguel.
Yes.
I think Miss Miléna
is in her room.
Yes. I'm going to play there.
What's that?
Mr. Cesar, the new chambermaid.
I'll take care of you.
Yes?
Go ahead.
- Hello, Miguel?
- Miléna?
I found it.
They were traveling.
I have all the information.
Just a moment.
That's it.
"Jean-Paul Brett-Juval,
was born in Washington...
on March 15, 1930,
lives in Paris, etc.
Current address
Rue de Berry, 144.
Fashion photographer,
manager of the Omnia Mode agency.
Séraphine Brett-Juval,
Jean-Paul's younger sister.
She was born in Washington in 1939,
where she lived until her mother's death...
in 1956.
He lived in Paris with his brother...
lives at 46 Rue Jacob,
with Mr. Robert Godard...
fashion photographer,
an associate of the aforementioned."
What a relief, Miguel.
I thought I'd never find them.
Your cousin is in Biarritz...
at the Hotel Du Palais,
where I spoke to him.
He might come on Friday.
Are you arriving on Friday?
Do you know what time?
It's all right.
Call again.
Thanks and see you later, Miguel.
You can call me Mr. Cesar.
Yes, Mr. Cesar.
But I'll say "you".
If you're going to start,
I'll throw you out now.
- So I'm calm.
- Why is that?
By the way you look at me.
If you are...
very kind...
we'll manage.
I'm a young woman.
- Are you laughing at me?
- No, Mr. Cesar.
I say I'm young.
Good.
Rosa will show you
her room...
and when she's settled in,
you will see Miss Miléna.
What will you do with the money?
when you have it?
- I'm going to buy a "ganadería".
- A what?
Bull breeding.
- I forgot you were an aficionado.
- Aficionado.
Robert, let's be serious.
We're going to have to delay our
to Cadequés by three days.
You mean?
You're taking me to Perpignan...
- And, or wait for me for three days...
- Lovely.
...or go straight to Cadequés
and I'll come to you.
I'm sure you'll find a girl
to wait for me.
And Jean-Paul?
He'll be arriving from Biarritz.
I'll make an appointment
with him in Perpignan...
and he'll take me to the castle.
Are you ashamed
to come with me to the castle?
I don't want to show up
as a boyfriend.
You know, cousin Miléna
must be the type...
provincial spinster,
all stuck up and stuff.
As you wish. But I warn you
that if you find a girl...
I recommended it myself.
I know our agreement.
Everyone has their freedom.
Good morning, miss.
I'll take care of the luggage.
Thank you.
Séraphine?
- Nice to meet you.
- Me too, Miléna.
- Kiss?
- Yes.
You speak
French very well.
I've been in France
for three years now.
Prudence will show you to your room.
Didn't your brother come along?
No. I came from Paris...
with a friend.
We slept in Perpignan.
My brother was supposed to meet me
at the hotel, but he didn't show up.
- No?
- But it won't be long.
What do you want?
- Ms. Brett-Juval, please?
- From whom?
I... say it's from
her brother's.
- Yes. It's Mr. Jean-Paul.
- Don't!
Jean-Paul?
Yes.
Miléna.
I didn't recognize you, Jean-Paul.
Not either, Miléna.
The last time we saw each other,
I was one year old.
Of course.
Your sister has arrived.
She didn't see you in Perpignan.
Yes. I was late.
I'd like to see you.
I think he's in his room,
taking a shower.
Prudence will show you her room.
It's next to hers.
Good morning.
Who is she?
She's the cook's granddaughter.
She's on vacation here.
When dinner is ready,
I'll send for you.
Cesar. Do you want to look after
Mr. Jean-Paul?
It was your father's
of your father.
There's no shortage of places.
It was always called
the room of the Borgia.
- That's right.
- You know, Mr. Jean-Paul...
it was a family joke.
Someone must have said it, and it stuck.
And what is it called?
Cesar.
- Cesar?
- Cesar. Excuse me.
Well done, Cesar.
- The suitcases...
- No, that's fine.
No.
- The bathroom is at the back, on the right.
- Perfect.
- You don't need me anymore?
- No, you don't.
Tell me. Where is
my sister's room?
- It's the fourth Chinese.
- Chinese?
That's it. You'll understand,
when you see it.
Third door on the right.
Do you know it?
- You're welcome.
Dinner is at eight.
- If Mr. Miguel isn't late.
- I'll be ready.
Thank you very much. Thank you very much.
Yes. Come in.
Robert? You here?
Yes, as you can see.
What happened?
I forbade you to come.
You don't forbid me anything.
And when you left,
your brother called.
- So what?
- He won't be here until Monday.
The whole team went to Spain.
That's great.
I've come to tell you
what to say to your cousin.
The truth, of course.
- Difficult.
- What do you mean, difficult?
- I'll tell you.
- Have you been up to something?
Yeah, it sounds like a joke.
When I arrived, the chambermaid
took me for Jean-Paul.
- Jean-Paul?
- Yes.
And the worst thing is that his cousin
took me for him too.
- It's not true.
- It's the pure truth.
And you didn't explain?
I haven't explained anything.
She thinks I'm Jean-Paul.
You're completely crazy.
Why did you do that?
I don't know.
I thought it was funny.
- Is it the cousin you like?
- The cousin?
Don't play the fool.
I know you.
It's not the first time
you've done that to me.
What about our agreement?
Listen. They're calling us to dinner
in five minutes.
Perfect. I'm hungry.
- Do you make fun of me?
- Not at all.
It's not a tragedy
me having dinner here.
Very well. When we're
at the table, I'll explain to Miléna.
- Give me one night.
- Not at all, Robert.
I'll explain everything. And now.
Don't do that.
You'll see.
I tried to call
to say I was going to be late...
- but your line is faulty.
- Good.
Cesar didn't say anything.
It's a thread. This is Mr. Miguel Barran.
My cousin Séraphine.
- Good evening, miss.
- Good night, ma'am.
Jean-Paul, Miguel Barran.
- Good evening, sir.
- Good night, sir.
- That'll do, Cesar.
- Yes, miss.
Jean-Paul, on my right.
Séraphine, Miguel.
Robert?
Robert.
- My name is Jean-Paul.
- Please, I don't want to laugh.
So. What happens then?
- I'm afraid.
- Of what?
- The Chinese room scares me.
- You're not five anymore.
Yes, but that's not all.
- I'm worried.
- Worried?
Yes, with the lies.
That's going to end badly.
No. When Jean-Paul arrives,
we'll just laugh it off.
Not me.
- Why didn't you say anything then?
- I don't know.
- Did you like the notary?
- Are you crazy?
And that
is also in our agreement.
I'll help you if you help me,
but right now, I'm sleepy.
- I want to be with you.
- No way.
- If you don't want to, I'll tell you everything.
- Nice.
- Be kind.
- Don't.
And he says he loves me.
Did I say that?
Well done. Since that's the case,
I won't go to Cadequés.
Good.
A girl.
Yes?
- Good morning, Mr. Jean-Paul.
- Good morning, Cesar.
- Did you sleep well?
- Very well.
The weather looks good.
It's always good weather here,
sir.
You don't seem to like it here.
I can say that, in general...
and with all due respect...
I'm deeply bored.
- Have you been here long?
- Ten years.
You must miss
distractions.
Only one thing interests me.
Women.
I don't see anything wrong with that, Cesar.
On the contrary.
Recruitment here
can't be easy.
- I have a trick.
- A trick?
That's it.
Lady Henriette gave me freedom
in personnel matters.
For example, I'm
who employs the chambermaids.
- Do you understand?
- Very well.
I choose a local one,
one I like, of course...
e...
- And if she resists...
- I'll put it out the door.
Really?
- What if I want to get married?
- I won't allow it, Mr. Jean-Paul.
They end up marrying
someone local.
Having served here is a benchmark.
No. What I like is change.
If any of them get attached to me,
I'll throw them out.
Congratulations, Cesar.
You're a Casanova.
By the way,
your latest hire.
- Not bad.
- What's not bad?
But it won't be easy.
No?
She's only been here for three days
and I haven't had much time for her...
but I have the impression
it won't be easy at all.
Come on, Cesar, you don't have to
lose your self-confidence.
Of course.
Of course. But I'll try
anyway. That's for sure.
- Good luck, Cesar.
- Thank you, Mr. Jean-Paul.
May I remind
to Mr. Jean-Paul...
he has a meeting
in the library at 10am.
THE KING OF MODELS
Come on.
Prudence, I see you
out of commission.
I was waiting for your orders.
Get the trays,
to get busy.
Yes, Mr. Cesar.
Come in.
ROBERT GODARD
PHOTOGRAPHER
What's wrong?
Nothing. I've come for the tray.
On the table, Cesar.
Thank you, Cesar.
First, I'd like to thank
Miguel's presence.
You may not know it, but you read
a will in the notary's office.
It's nothing, Miléna.
I gathered them here, as notary public
of Lady Henriette...
who died on June 16th
1959, in this castle.
She appointed me
her executor.
I will read the
she has made.
"This is my will.
I, the undersigned...
Henriette Amélie Jeanne Juval,
widow of Sir John Brett...
- killed on June 18, 1917..."
- What?
The pencils.
I've never forgotten.
At the Council meetings
chaired by Lady Henriette...
- It's okay, Cesar.
- I'd put the pencils in.
So I don't see why
I wouldn't continue...
putting...
the pencils. There it is.
Nothing missing?
It's all right.
Leave us, Cesar, please.
"I make the following
as follows:
I appoint universal legatees,
jointly for the whole...
or separately, for a third,
my three grandchildren, namely...
Jean-Paul Eric Pierre
Brett-Juval...
Séraphine Alexandra
Miléna Françoise
Brett-Juval...
who are in charge of
distributing the following...
Mr. Cesar?
- What do you want?
- It's ugly to listen like that.
Mind your own business.
I want to know what's going on.
I never do that
and I know everything.
"Made, written and dated
by my hands...
healthy in body and spirit
in my castle of Aubarède...
in 1957, November 2nd.
Signed:
Henriette Brett-Juval."
From reading...
except for the legacies
Casaneuve, Lerbier and Loinod...
and taking into account the other
legacies mentioned...
the total amount of which is
six million francs...
and taking into account
of Lady Henriette...
to leave the Cardonna couple
the use of the Cedars Pavilion...
in Sainte Marguerite
and two hectares around it...
results, I said, from reading...
that Lady Henriette leaves all
her estate in equal shares...
to the three grandchildren present:
Séraphine, Jean-Paul and Miléna.
There you go. It's hard to say what
these assets represent.
However, it is my duty...
let them know that the
of these assets...
- is minimal.
- But business is good.
- Quite well.
- Yes, but the profits...
have been reinvested
for six years...
to finance equipment
and a reserve fund.
I mean, it's no good.
In the long term,
its parts are realizable.
And then there's the castle.
The castle?
Yes, the castle
now belongs to you...
and his brother and cousin.
Your only two problems,
at the moment...
are the problem
of inheritance rights...
and what to do with the castle,
between the three of you.
- Is he sellable?
- Hardly. Certainly below his value.
I think Miléna
should decide.
Does she want to continue
to live here?
You know, it's only been a month...
It's hard for me to leave,
sentimentally.
Of course. There's no hurry.
That's all there is to it.
In fact, nothing will be decided
before Monday.
You have to look at the banks
and each of the accounts.
It's only Saturday.
And there's a selection tomorrow.
- There's what?
- Rugby, my dear.
He's the coach of a team.
The winter round is coming
and Miguel would never miss it.
Don't be unfair, Miléna. I can be
at your disposal tomorrow, if you like...
but I don't see the point.
Are there any races in the region?
- Races?
- Yes. Fifine loves bullfighting.
Actually, there's one tomorrow.
If you like, I can accompany you.
What about your rugby, Miguel?
I also like bulls.
They stayed at the table
14 minutes longer than yesterday.
- Do you time your meals now?
- Always.
This proves that they are
getting to know each other better.
You're clever, Cesar, you know that?
Smart.
Mr. Cesar. Can you do that now?
I like you. Very much so.
Is Mr. Cesar crazy?
- Call me Cesar.
- Aren't you ashamed, Mr. Cesar?
- Do we swim in it?
- Yes.
The water is not very clean.
The system is old.
Each time is different.
Tell me, Miléna.
Who is this Miguel?
Miguel?
Yes. Who is it?
He's a curious man.
Curious? Miguel?
- Does that make the clock work?
- Yes, it does.
And this is for climbing
on the roof?
No. It's to go to the tower.
Do you want to go up to the roof?
- I'd like to.
- This way. Come along.
- And when did he show up?
- Miguel?
When he returned from Indochina. His father
bought him a notary's office in Perpignan...
and a grandmother chose him as her favorite.
And Fifine and me,
she never talked about?
Never.
Since the fight in 1942,
he has given up on his family.
His real children
were Michael and me.
And she never thought...
Yes.
- So what?
- Then nothing.
And it's none of your business.
Why? Between cousins...
There is no interest.
One day, Miguel and I stopped
understand each other. That's all.
- Just like that? One day, abruptly?
- Yes.
Like this.
One day.
Suddenly.
What's the matter, Miléna?
Don't you feel well?
It's nothing.
Let's go back, Jean-Paul.
I still have to answer
to letters of condolence.
Can I help you?
You can make the envelopes,
if you like.
- Why do they call her Fifine?
- It was Robert's idea.
- He thinks Séraphine is too angelic.
- Robert?
Robert Godard.
My brother's partner.
- Yes, who I spoke to on the phone.
- That's it.
You still haven't told me
what you think of Miléna.
I hardly know her.
After five years?
She's a lovely friend,
but very closed.
I think she's very beautiful.
Strange that I never thought of her
in any other way.
- Otherwise?
- Yes. If I were a man...
What are you doing there?
- Fifine. What are you doing?
- Admiring the landscape.
I mean, I don't like her?
- No. Why?
- Why not?
It's like this.
What if I send her away?
- But why?
- Because he doesn't want to sleep with me.
- What a mentality.
- I don't like pretentious people.
I'm not pretentious...
but I'm a virgin, Mr. Cesar.
I told you the other day.
Are you mocking me?
Jure.
- What's that?
- That she's a virgin.
Swear.
Are you mocking me?
No, but...
- I have the right not to want to.
- You have no right at all.
He's not my type.
You mean?
- I don't want to say it.
- Say it anyway.
- You'll get angry again.
- I swear I won't.
Well...
I think you're a pig.
And Johnny was going so fast
on his bike...
that when he crossed
the village, no one saw.
So, as there was
anything in the village...
people said:
"It's Johnny coming through".
How silly.
- Do you think they're suspicious?
- Not Miléna, anyway.
We'd better not be together
too long. You may notice.
I have the impression that you
started looking after the little cousin.
Yes. I have my plan.
I'll take care of her and you'll take care of him.
We're in agreement, aren't we?
What if I fall in love with him?
He's handsome.
Much better.
Beautiful and seductive.
Almost as beautiful
as Luis Miguel Dominguin.
- Who?
- Please, Robert. It's not funny.
What's that?
That's it. It's started again.
Curious, this mania.
- Do you think that's normal?
- It's someone playing the organ.
At midnight?
Go and see, Robert.
This kind of thing terrifies me.
Excuse my curiosity.
I thought it was a ghost.
No. It's me.
I like playing at night.
It's like an addiction.
Nice addiction.
- Was it "Jesus, Joy of Men"?
- Yes.
There's something about this song...
of suffering,
which has always fascinated me.
Of threatened joy.
Good.
So, good night.
Good evening.
Prudence?
Open.
I won't do anything.
- I came to talk.
- No, I didn't.
Prudence.
I'm going to break down the door.
Prudence? Prudence?
Are you listening, Prudence?
Mr. Cesar?
Take my tray
and give me yours.
Take Miss Fifine's,
I'll take Mr. Jean-Paul's.
Why do you want to
take his?
Don't you want to see Miss Fifine
in bed in the morning?
- Yes, she is.
- She's pretty, isn't she?
What about you?
All right, then. Let's switch.
Let's go.
Come on, come on.
Come in.
- Good morning, Mr. Robert.
- What's this?
Nothing, Mr. Godard.
I said good morning.
- Who said that?
- My little finger.
Come here, you.
Put the tray down.
You're good, Prudence.
You won't say anything.
- But I can.
- It's a joke.
It's only two days.
- That's it.
- What do you mean, that's it?
Listen.
- I can buy your silence.
- Very nice.
It's you who are beautiful.
Very.
What would please her?
I don't know.
Don't be afraid.
I'll give you whatever you want.
I'm not afraid.
Hello?
Miguel.
A game of pool?
I only played it in Indochina.
But it's fine, yes.
I'm going to finish getting dressed.
See you soon.
You'll be nice
and wait for me to come and talk to you.
- When?
In his room, at midnight.
I'll keep it under warranty.
All right today?
I'll see.
A real vacation.
I never thought,
when I arrived.
- Confess that you didn't like the idea.
- I didn't know her.
Are you disappointed
with the inheritance?
No. Not at all.
I mean, a little bit.
- Not that I want to be rich...
- But I will be. It's only a matter of time.
It doesn't matter to me.
I really enjoyed meeting her.
I've never had any friends.
I like you too.
- Have we dropped the formality?
- Absolutely.
- Do you want to?
- Yes. If you want to.
Your sister is wonderful.
- My sister?
- Yes. Fifine.
- Isn't she your sister?
- Yes, she is.
- Unfortunately.
- Unfortunately?
Yes, she's a
very funny girl.
She has a clownish side, but deep down,
she's very sensitive and disarming.
That's funny. I imagined you
old maid and provincial.
- With glasses and a bun?
- Yes. Almost.
It's just that I'm provincial,
compared to you.
- You've read everything, seen everything...
- Come on, don't exaggerate.
He knows everything.
Except the bulls.
I find her very frank and direct.
- Unable to conceal.
- Every woman conceals something.
Look at Miléna,
which seems so mysterious.
Certainly, deep down,
it's as transparent as glass.
Don't kid yourself, Jean-Paul.
- Miléna has its problems.
- Which problems?
I don't know. There's something about her...
suspended, tied up.
Miléna is a woman in waiting.
Maybe I'll wait for you.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
It's an impression.
There's nothing
between Miléna and me.
That's all.
Shall we find them?
Okay.
Look, Miléna,
how sinister they look.
Sinister, no.
- Very nice.
- You're right.
- Are you calling each other "you"?
- Aren't we all?
- Miguel, what's up?
- Yes. Fifine. If you like.
- I would never have dared.
- Now, don't be formal.
- Cousin, you're beautiful.
- Cousin, you're fun.
And Miguel and Miléna don't say "you"?
It's been five years,
let's not start today.
May I serve you, miss?
In five minutes, Prudence.
We're not having lunch like this.
- But Mr. Cesar said...
- Well, Cesar can wait.
I'm going to the shower.
- Did you call the factory, Miguel?
- No. I forgot.
- I'll call you while you change.
- All right, then.
And I can call him
"you"?
Prudence.
I remind you that your race
is at 4pm.
Check the lady.
LETTERS TO MILENA
"Miléna is a
rich and dense.
However, at first,
I didn't like it very much...
although it is,
by color and shape...
a woman we take
in our arms...
that we ripped from the world
or fire, I don't know...
and who girds himself
in your arms...
docile, confident."
I don't want to be
from the world.
No fire?
Can I take the coffee?
Cesar? Something wrong?
It's the little one.
She made my mouth water.
And when that's the case,
I must drink.
- And she doesn't want to.
- Despite my advice?
- What is this mystery?
- Cesar sighs for Prudence.
Sigh?
I know that. Please,
don't bother that girl.
Cesar, change your technique.
Pour on the steam.
- The steam?
- Tell her you love her.
Put one knee on the ground...
- A knee on the ground?
- Yes. And ask for his hand.
And I ask for his hand.
- What if she gives it to me?
- Just pull. The rest follows.
Jean-Paul,
you're disgusting.
So any medium counts?
It didn't always work out.
Jean-Paul is wrong.
Love is not to be trifled with.
- Beautiful commonplace
- What should I do then?
- Declare yourself now, attack at night.
- He's right.
Night is the oblivion
of the day.
That's wrong.
The night divides those who love.
Tonight,
I want to dance in the moonlight.
Beautiful.
Check and kill.
Prudence, I love you.
- Don't start again.
- No, Prudence, it really is love.
- But how?
- Platonically.
- Are you ill, Mr. Cesar?
- Give me your hand, Prudence.
- No way.
- Please, Prudence.
I want to get married.
- It's the heat.
- I want to marry her.
- Are you serious?
- Do you like children?
- No.
- Me neither.
What's it like?
What's all this?
Miss, Mr. Cesar
wants to marry me.
Don't listen to that satyr.
- Have you arranged the whisky for today?
- Of course. I'll check.
- I'm counting on you.
- Yes.
And stop making a fool of yourself.
Remember, it's your day off.
And yours too, Prudence.
- If you want to go to the race...
- Thank you, miss.
- Say it. Are you a satyr?
- Me? No, no.
Watch out, Cesar.
I've got my eye on you.
You can woo me if you want,
but properly.
Thank you.
But why whisky?
They're having a party,
a month after Grandma's death?
The night...
is the forgetfulness of the day.
Music, please.
Don't shout like that.
Let's have some music.
"Slow, please.
- Dance?
- Yes.
"Although it is,
by color and shape...
a woman we take
in our arms..."
What are we holding in our arms?
- "That we pluck from the world."
- "Or fire."
- "I don't know."
- "Who's wrapped in your arms...
docile, confident."
Are you rejecting me?
Hello.
I mean you no harm.
I know.
Are you leaving me?
Hello.
- Are your loves going well?
- You're my only love.
- Did you drink?
- Yes, quite a lot.
I prefer it that way.
Do you like him?
A lot.
- It's even dangerous.
- What's dangerous?
- Playing with love.
- That's all.
- Time is suspended.
- To what?
If we only knew...
- How are you?
- Not too well.
I think she's afraid.
- Afraid?
- Yes.
And so am I.
- You?
- Yes. Me.
Give him a drink.
It's an idea.
Miléna, you're my
cousin.
- You must have others.
- No.
No more.
See you tomorrow morning.
Until whenever you want.
Are you leaving me again?
Hello.
She's the kind of woman
who slips through your fingers.
It appeared! I knew you
were hiding!
Be kind, Mr. Cesar.
Leave me alone.
Be yourself. If you're kind,
I won't hurt you!
No?
No! No!
Stop right there!
Bitch!
Stop!
You'll see!
- Leave me alone! Go to bed!
- With you!
- No!
- Yes!
Did you say you loved me?
That you wanted to get married?
- Right away!
- No! No!
You dirty man!
- Are you crazy or what?
- I'm going to love you! I'm going to love you!
Come here!
Come here! Come here!
- Come here! Stop! Stop!
- Stop!
Help! Help! He's out of his mind!
Don't come any closer. We're not
do this here, only in bed.
- Not today! Tomorrow! Get out!
- Right now!
- Help me!
- Prudence!
Now I've got you.
- You can let me go!
- No! Listen. Stay still.
My pretty.
My little cutie.
Come on, let's go.
Damn.
Cesar.
I think this is yours.
To complete your collection.
My collection?
Come on, Cesar.
You did what you could.
He surrendered to the setbacks
of the war.
Reversals of the war.
Do you know what
William of Orange?
"You don't have to wait
to undertake...
nor overcome in order to persevere."
- William of Orange.
- William of Orange...
"the Taciturn".
The Taciturn?
So, that being the case...
Do you know what
William of Orange?
No.
But he must have been right.
Miléna, my love.
Jean-Paul.
You're charming.
Do you love me?
You said "without feelings".
Just so you know.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
Do you love me?
I love her.
Come in.
ROBERT GODARD
PHOTOGRAPHER
Did you sleep well?
- I haven't slept a wink.
- But he's waking up.
- I was pretending.
- I was lying. I was sleeping like a child.
I dreamt that I couldn't sleep.
You're a baby.
But it was you who seduced me.
Do you think I'm a flirt?
Yes, I think so.
Don't laugh, Miguel.
- I'm sad.
- Sad? What are you sad about?
I don't know.
- As if I were going to die.
- Are you crazy?
Crazy and robust.
- Are you leaving?
- Yes.
It's Monday. I'm going to work.
For you.
I still have phone calls to make
for your will.
I'll be back later.
- Have you thought about it?
- About what?
If you love me.
I'll tell you tonight.
- No. Now.
- Later.
Later,
when I get back.
- Miguel?
- Good morning, Miléna.
Did you sleep well?
I want to show you something,
Miguel.
Are you hiding, Miléna?
Yes.
Like in melodramas,
I'm not who you think I am.
Who are you, Jean-Paul?
- I'm not Jean-Paul.
- I know.
Robert Godard.
Who are you, Robert Godard?
Nothing complicated.
I'm Jean-Paul's partner.
We've been working together
for five years.
We founded a
fashion photo agency.
Fifine told me about you.
About her Robert.
- After all, he's Fifine's lover.
- Was.
- Don't play with words.
- I don't. I was Fifine's lover.
Now I'm yours and
and I love you.
What about her? Didn't you love her?
I liked her. She's different.
Whatever.
What's with the comedy?
Because of you.
Mine?
Passion at first sight.
When I arrived on Saturday...
you said, "Jean-Paul?"
and I said yes, because
I wanted to be with you.
Easy to say now.
I don't believe it, Jean-Paul.
- You're talking nonsense.
- It's not nonsense. It's true.
You're a buffoon.
You wanted an adventure, that's all.
What amazes me is
Fifine being part of the arrangement.
It wasn't agreed.
- Yes. So she knew?
- It was give and take.
You mean?
If I revealed that I was her lover,
she wouldn't have Miguel...
and if he'd known about me,
he wouldn't have dared.
It would have been better.
What nonsense.
You should have known
that I would find out.
- It didn't take long.
- How did you know?
Prudence.
I know, I know.
Dear Prudence.
And the first thing he did
was to tell Miguel.
Of course. Do you realize that?
He opened a will
in front of a false brother.
- So what? He went to get the police?
- You're out of your mind.
- And where is Jean-Paul?
- He should be here soon.
Saturday, on the phone,
he said he was coming Monday.
- So everything falls into place?
- No.
You stay with me.
Not at all.
And Fifine?
- He's young. He'll console himself.
- How do you know?
Fifine and I were friends
who slept together, and that was it.
- She will console herself with Miguel.
- Miguel is a womanizer.
He always had a lot of women.
If he gets what he wants,
she will be unhappy.
I'm convinced
that you love him.
Fifine!
- Come on, that's what's needed.
- Come quickly.
Fifine!
- Fifine!
- Cesar, have you seen Miss Fifine?
- Miss Fifine?
- And you, Prudence?
- No, miss.
- What happened?
- Fifine has disappeared.
- I'll explain. She could kill herself.
- Kill herself?
- Search before the brother arrives.
- What's wrong?
- Does she have another brother?
- Yes, come on.
Another brother?
- It's my fault.
- No. It's mine.
- I should say I loved her.
- Is this the time to argue?
- It's my fault.
- No. It's Jean-Paul's.
Robert, in fact.
Here's how his story turned out.
- Miléna...
- That's it.
If anything happens to him,
I won't forgive you.
Let's look in the garden.
Don't you love me anymore?
I don't have time
to think about it.
Fifine?
Miss Fifine!
Fifine!
Fifine?
Fifine disappeared.
Maybe he's killing himself
for a fling.
The four of us played the
of thoughtless love.
We take ourselves for libertines.
A car is coming.
Good morning.
- Are you Mr. Jean-Paul?
- Yes.
Mr. Jean-Paul!
- Miguel Barran.
- Jean-Paul Brett-Juval. What's going on?
Fifine disappeared.
- My sister?
- What a time to arrive.
- What are you doing there?
- Fifine has disappeared.
- He's already said it. Explain.
- Do you remember that you wanted to kill yourself?
- What about it?
- I'm afraid it'll start again.
- Why?
- I'll explain later.
- Are you Jean-Paul?
- Yes.
I'm Miléna.
I'm sorry to see you like this.
- The welcome is strange.
- Your sister has disappeared.
- Did you look?
- Yes.
- You too, Cesar?
- All that's missing is the basement.
- The swimming pool.
- That's right. I'll check it out.
- What can I do?
- Nothing.
- I'll go back to the greenhouse and have a look.
- I'll come along.
- You don't have to.
- I'm going anyway.
- What's her name?
- Florence.
- Do you know where Fifine is?
- Yes.
Go and get it.
Let's go. Go and get her.
Tell her brother wants to see her.
Let's go!
Fifine?
Come along. Your brother is there.
Jean-Paul.
Come on, Fifine.
Were you playing
hide and seek?
Don't make fun of me, Jean-Paul.
I'm very unhappy.
You know...
when you play a game,
there is always a loser.
I've lost everything.
Not at all.
It was a joke.
- So don't cry.
- Please prepare the lilac room...
for Mr. Jean-Paul.
- What tone is that?
- Run it.
You don't lose
by waiting, you know?
Leave them.
They don't need us anymore.
Miléna.
Do you have one for me?
The first cigarette
after the scare...
is the best.
No. The best is after love.
Yes.
And with you.
With you.