You must always pay attention
and behave yourself.
If you behave, you'll not have
to come back here.
And if you have bad thoughts,
get rid of them.
Take a walk, shake you head,
whatever.
I prefer that you'll
never come back.
Got it?
I'd rather never see you again.
Anyway, we had a good time here.
Yes, not bad.
Give your mother
what you made for her.
-Thank you!
-For the cigarettes.
We made it at the workshop
of Occupational Therapy.
Muchas gracias.
You can put the packet inside
and the brand won't show.
Can I have one?
THE GARDEN
Madam,
you have a phone call.
Hold me, look how I am.
Hello. How I are you?
Good. Yes, we got here fine.
Yes, Liso is alright.
He even has put on some weight.
He'll visit you soon.
Then you can take a walk together,
I told him.
I have to go, I'm busy.
Kisses, bye.
Bye.
Push the "off" button.
Sonia is glad that you're home,
right, Sonia?
Yes, madam.
I am exhausted.
Animals are quite something.
Open the window
to air the room.
And take this to the kitchen,
your father doesn't like...
...that I smoke in here.
Your mother gave you a nice present.
If you want, I can take you
for a ride.
No, I´m afraid.
-Are you afraid?
-Yes...
It´s nice.
If you promise me to go slow, OK.
I'll ride slowly.
No, I prefer to ride slower
25? Is that possible?
I have to practice a little bit more.
THE BIKE
What are you doing?
Nothing, I was looking at you.
At whom?
I was looking at you.
What is this?
A bike.
I can see that, but where it came from?
A present.
Did you go out?
I did.
Here I am.
But I am not here anymore.
I'm better, you know.
I'm on medication.
I'm not doing very well
since the last time.
Can I give you a kiss?
What?
The last one and then I'll go...
and you'll never see me again.
You don't realize what you
have done to me, do you?
Yes or no?
Yes.
It's hard for me
to get my life back.
Sure.
-That you are lacking something?
-Yes.
That you have to think
about something...
Yes.
I can't get used to some things.
But if you eat well
and take the medicines...
-Are you taking them?
-Yes, I do.
That's very important.
You think that the medicines
won't do any good...
But medicines and exercises
are very good.
You should never stay...
...quiet.
Did you ever think about
meeting somebody else?
No, no.
You never felt the need
for another love?
No.
I'm fine, I like men.
I like to be nice to them
so they won't think that I...
Not long ago, a guy wanted
to buy me an ice cream.
He was very nice...
but no, better not.
Sonia!
Did you touch at my charcoals
when you did the cleaning?
Forget it, Sonia.
FLOWERS
Load the gun.
Get in position.
This side forward.
Take aim.
Loosen your elbows a bit.
Your pulse is not steady.
Take aim... shoot.
Take the magazine out.
That's it.
Excuse me.
Are you spying on me?
I could spend my whole life looking
at you in your sleep.
I am jealous of the women
who watch you in your sleep.
When you were a baby...
I spend hours looking at you
in your sleep.
I looked at you
and I couldn't believe it.
All the time I wanted
to wake up your father...
Wake him up and ask him:
"How did this child appear?
Where came something
so beautiful from?"
What a bore...
If you don't want to work anymore...
if you don't want to study
or do anything, tell me.
Everything will be alright,
what you do and
what you don't do.
If you don't want to live anymore,
you should tell me.
Don't keep it to yourself.
You should live
like the boys of your age.
Go out and things like that.
You can't be locked in here
all your life.
You want to smoke?
You used to have friends,
a girlfriend...
Yes, I used to have...
Are you sleeping well?
Yes, I feel better.
-You feel better?
-Yes
Take this, go out and have fun.
Please, take it.
Find yourself a girl and everything.
Here's some more,
in case the girl's expensive.
I like your house.
It is not my house.
It's nice.
No smoking.
There are candies there,
take some if you want.
It's OK, thanks.
What is your name?
Sofía.
Is it your only name?
No kisses, I told you.
You are sad.
You are very cute...
You should find yourself
a girlfriend.
You have no need to pay.
Are you studying or working?
-You are not studying or working?
-No
-But you must be doing something.
-No, nothing.
Everybody does something.
I do this because I study,
for instance.
I go to Law School.
Is there nothing
you would like to do?
You should think about it.
What is this?
Eyes.
How strange.
I had another tattoo
beneath this one.
It was the face of Maradona.
It was badly done.
Show me the one on your back.
What is it?
My grandfather's face.
Why your grandfather?
He never asked me anything.
Good luck.
TIME
I brought you a glass of milk.
Thanks.
Are you still not sleeping?
Now I'm sleeping a little bit.
Are you taking your pills?
Yes, I do.
I like this.
The needles.
The little box.
Yes, it's nice.
And this?
To thread the needle.
If you can't thread it,
you use this.
You pass it through the needle.
and that's it.
Very easy.
For those
who don't have good eyesight.
I think I have good eyesight.
Can you thread one?
-You let me try?
-Yes.
They say you should never thread
the needle with your hand.
-Bad luck?
-Yes.
If you do, you'll split
with your best friend.
Because needle and thread
are good friends.
-Can you?
-No.
-You don't have good eyesight.
-More or less...
-My hand is shaking.
-Why?
Because you smoke too much,
that's why.
You're nervous.
-Nervous.
-Yes.
This one shakes more
than this one.
Can you do this?
I'm making this outfit
for my daughter.
She is devoted
to the Virgin of Copacabana.
She dances.
Let's see.
My hands are a bit clumsy.
Forward.
They are rude.
Hands are never rude or clumsy.
There...
No... stop.
You got lost.
-Do you know Bolivia?
-No.
It is very nice.
Are you homesick?
Yes, I miss my country.
But...
I hope that some day
I will go back there.
I live with my memories.
Do you have memories?
Yes.
I have seven brothers.
-That's a lot.
-Yes.
You could lend me one.
A brother?
They are grown up now.
-I'm the youngest.
-Yes?
Yes.
The Virgin of Copacabana
is in La Paz.
If you want, some day
we'll go with your family
and I'll show you Bolivia.
What?
Are you thinking of Bolivia?
No, I'm calm.
My mind went blank.
I never understood
what happened between us.
Why it didn't work.
I don't know, sometimes I wonder.
Not very often.
But when I'm alone...
I think of you.
You can see the sky from here,
I like that.
In my house you don't see it
like this.
I don't want you to sleep here.
Why?
Because tomorrow arrives Julian
and I don't want to.
There's a couch in the living room.
You can stay there until daybreak.
It's not right to come
without letting me know.
Wake up!
It's raining fire!
Fire and blood!
-What are you saying?
-Everything is red.
We have to get out of here.
-This is the end.
-No! Enough!
-Enough!
-We have to get out of here.
You are not well,
you must leave.
Come on.
THE CHILDREN
What do you want, Ivonne?
-Tutuca?
-Tutuca
The colored one.
That's you.
You must have been
three or four years old.
If you look carefully,
you'll see that you're smiling.
That's it!
Very good.
Liso!
Sonia!
I woke up a while ago
and you weren't here.
Neither you or Liso.
But madam, today is my day off.
-Why are you sad, madam?
-I'm worried about my son.
He will change.
I hope so.
We'll give him time.
Madam.
What?
I want to tell you
that I'm going back to Bolivia.
What? Back to Bolivia?
Why?
Because I am homesick.
What do you miss?
Everything, madam.
CEREMONIES
It's time you start to work,
don't you think?
You could come a couple
of days a week to help me.
Sure, if you want...
I could come.
And what do you want?
Do you prefer to be in the hospital?
No.
What do you want?
You must want something.
Nothing, I don't want anything.
Nothing.
Does nothing interest you?
You can't live
if nothing interests you.
I would like to have a child.
What are you saying?
You can't have a child
in your condition.
Besides, you don't have somebody.
Sure.
You screwed everything.
You play the madman,
you have no willpower.
Sometimes I get tired too,
you know?
I do...
but I have no way out.
Go up every morning and move on,
if I want it or not.
I have to go on.
Sure.
THE RIVER
Do you want to say goodbye to granny
one more time?
No, it's OK.
Did you see that Marina is here?
You liked her so much
when you were little.
She has two children, you know?
She'd like to say hello.
I heard about the hospital.
It was hard, wasn't it?
It's over now.
You look good.
What are you doing?
I came to say goodbye.
I'm going to Bolivia.
I'm going with you.
What are you saying?
What are you going to do
in Bolivia?
These are clothes
I don't wear any more.
I don't know what weather
you have there...
but I'm sure you can use them.
Thank you so much, madam,
God bless you.
Are you out of your mind?
Shoot!
Go ahead, shoot me!
LA PAZ
-Four multiplied by eight?
-¡32!
-36... 40, 44...!
-What?
An eagle!
Four by eight?
-32!
-36!
36 is wrong.
-Four multiplied by nine?
-40!
36!
-Four multiplied by nine?
-36!
-Is eight plus one = seven?
-Nine!
-You.
Very good.
Four multiplied by three?
12.
Four by three = 12.
Your father says hello.
He is sad because of what happened.
OK. Forget it.
I thought you quit smoking.
You can't quit everything.
Do you feel good here?
Yes, very good.
I'm fine.
You could have done the same thing
without going so far.
You think there are
no poor people in Argentina?
Stop it, Mom.