THE TRAP
Based on Anthony Gilbert's
"Mystery in the Woodshed"
Directed by
Carlos Hugo Christensen
It's 3 P.M. in Buenos Aires.
The huge concrete jungle quivers...
with the intensity of
some amazing beehive.
Paulina Figueroa was the victim
of a selfish and dominant father.
Her teenage dreams
fled before her brooding eyes...
like some beautiful scenery
flashing from a train window.
An unrelenting inferiority complex...
finally withered what
was left of her youth.
When she turned 25, Paulina Figueroa
felt that her heart had become old...
and she had given up all
hope of ever finding love.
When her father died,
she left her provincial property.
She arrived at the big city
and became one of those silent beings...
that gloomily gaze at
other people's happiness.
A happiness so overwhelming
to those that feel lonely.
Four cardinal points
determined her life direction:
Her yearly income, her apartment,
cinema - which awoke
unknown feelings in her -
and lastly, the most exciting adventure
of her thwarted youth.
FEMALE MORAL SOCIETY
Dear members, let us strengthen
women's social emancipation...
but let us also mercilessly fight
against the false moral emancipation...
that has corrupted
the purest of virtues.
Thank you so much,
my dearest fellow members.
In our next meeting we shall form a
committee, presided by a secretary,
who will develop
a strategy for our campaign,
the initial object of which shall be...
to do battle against
the shameless exhibition...
of women's intimate
garments in window shops.
What about male garments?
We'll discuss that
when the time comes.
Miss Figueroa, please don't leave
the premises. I need to talk to you.
The meeting is over.
I have a hunch she wants
to name you Secretary.
No. I'm too insignificant
for such an important task.
Have you decided on a film?
How about the Opera theater?
They're showing "Arch of Triumph".
From what I've heard it's fantastic.
Ingrid Bergman marries Boyer,
whom she meets in the train.
And after a passionate romance,
she winds up in pieces by the chimney.
Isn't that awesome?
How very American.
That doesn't happen in real life.
Do you think not?
Sometimes fantasy
doesn't dare become as strange...
...as reality.
See you later then.
Five o'clock at the Richmond tea house?
See you later.
READING ROOM
Thus began Paulina Figueroa's
peculiar adventure.
She'd bide her time, chastely surrounded
by her romantic novel collection,
when she randomly opened
an evening newspaper.
GENTLEMAN OF A CERTAIN AGE, single,
would like to meet a formal lady,
with the intent of marriage. Preferably
a lady who enjoys the quiet life...
in the country. Own fortune. No
relatives a must. P.O. Box # 75, Tigre.
A strange emotion
shook Paulina Figueroa.
What did that ad mean? Was it a joke?
Impossible. She'd be the last
to make fun out of someone's loneliness.
But what kind of woman
answers such a peculiar ad?
Would a straightforward
man place an ad looking for a wife?
What would he be like? Old, perhaps?
Or simply a vulgar man.
And why not a man full of vices?
A sick man?
Excuse me, ma'am.
A rare feeling of hope enveloped her.
Yes, there was no doubt
there were good men about.
Lonely and shy like her.
They get far away calls from life,
and even get bled little by little.
Dear sir, I've read your ad
and since I'm also a lonely person,
I can readily understand that someone
can be obliged by circumstances...
to choose a partner
in such an... unusual way.
And thus I'm writing
to request more details.
My name is Paulina Figueroa.
I'm single and well off.
I'm experienced with domestic chores.
I love the quiet life and have spent
most of my youth in the country.
As you'll notice,
our tastes are similar.
Naturally, if you were to be interested
we'd both need more information.
But if I've made a mistake
and your ad is only in jest,
please forget about this letter.
Paulina thought that her letter was
more like a housekeeper seeking a job.
But finally decided that
this wasn't so important.
...I'm worth 450,000 pesos...
I'm still interested,
and circumstances haven't changed.
Can I request an answer by telegram?
Madam, my island is a lonely place.
But it is lovely.
And with a speed boat there's
no reason to feel isolated.
Could this be the paradise
you yearn for in your best dreams?
Yours sincerely, Hugo Morán
ARRIVING TUESDAY ON SPECIFIED TRAIN
AFFECTIONALLY PAULINA FIGUEROA
Paulina Figueroa? I'm Hugo Morán.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
I was afraid you'd changed you mind.
It's not easy coming to meet a stranger.
Good afternoon, Mr. Morán!
So your wife is finally here!
How are you, Mrs. Morán?
You took so long we had started
to believe you were a ghost.
Speaking of ghosts, I suppose you'll
like the house your husband chose.
To each his own.
Don't go scaring her.
Paulina, Miss Martin
is the neighbor I mentioned.
- Pleased to meet you.
- I trust we'll be good friends.
Not much fun around here. And having
a writer as a husband must be boring.
What do you think of this
creature? It came by train.
My sister and I have
a soft spot for animals.
They're more intelligent
than most of the men.
Of course, novelists
are the exception.
I'll be seeing you. Don't vanish!
Don't be discouraged.
Like all spinsters, Miss Martin
is an incorrigible chatterbox.
But she's helped us break the ice.
Why did you make her
think I was your wife?
Oh!
Once she came to see me.
Or rather she invaded my house.
I got scared and lied
about being married.
She seemed determined
to organize my life.
Judging by your ad, you'd think that
that's what you were looking for.
Yes, but my search was more demanding.
A companion for life.
What an infinite promise
in such a brief phrase.
Paulina Figueroa can now hear
life's warm callings.
The time has come to leave
her in company of her destiny.
She was terribly selfish.
She'd humiliate me with her money.
And she could never
understand my urge to write.
Finally, after many bitter years...
we were divorced
and I returned from France.
I felt old and weary.
And I sought shelter in solitude.
And this healed my wound.
But it also finally awoke in my heart...
the need for a new and real home.
Then I realized... that it was too late
to get involved in other people's lives.
The ad was my only hope.
I perceived part of what you're
saying from your letter.
Perhaps that's why I decided to reply.
Do you know why
I chose yours among the other letters?
Because yours was so sincere.
It revealed the
sweetness of your character.
And the strength of your personality.
Maybe I'm different
from what you imagine.
My father would turn on his
grave if he could see me now.
He would always mock my lack of spirit.
How little your father knew you.
But I believe in fate.
I shudder to think that I might not
have read the newspaper that day.
None of this would have happened.
I... believe, Mr. Morán,
that you've hypnotized me.
I've never talked this way.
Truth be told...
I've never had anyone
to talk to this way.
I hope you have me
for the rest of your life.
Nothing would be better.
THE CHIMERA
The first time I saw the house,
I also thought it looked gloomy.
Who convinced you to rent this house?
Nobody.
On the contrary,
some people tried to dissuade me.
Miss Martin even mentioned a ghost.
Just wait for spring to bloom.
The island will be covered
in flowers and birds.
- Are there ghosts?
- I've never seen any.
But if there were. Wouldn't you
want to help me chase them away?
I hope you like my tea.
An old friend sends it to me from India.
That's why I like
to prepare it myself.
Do you want to pour it?
Unless you're superstitious.
- Penny for your thoughts.
- You'd laugh if I told you.
- Try me.
- It's...
I haven't spoken much to
men since my father's death.
Now it's your turn.
- My turn?
- I've told you nearly all my life.
But I hardly know anything about yours.
Are you really so alone in the world?
So much that... if I were to have an
accident, no one would ask about me.
How pessimistic.
What about relatives?
They're a necessary evil.
I may have some
very distant ones.
But they've never
shown any interest in me.
I've been pretty much alone.
On or two friends... and my lawyer.
Your lawyer?
Mr. Sause. But I hardly see him.
Practically only when
I go for my yearly check.
That means that he
handles all your business.
But do you at least know where
your money is invested?
No. I don't know any details.
I pay him to look after my interests.
And what if he
didn't do his job properly?
Impossible. He was my
father's lawyer for twenty years.
I suspect you have
an exceedingly trusting nature.
For example: You hardly know me.
I could very well be
a penniless adventurer...
on the lookout for a woman like you.
No, Mr. Morán. If that were so
you wouldn't have chosen me.
There are many wealthy
women who would be glad to...
...marry an obscure writer?
A man whose spirit is broken?
Who prefers to live in the shadows?
How little you know
about women, Paulina.
Some of them prefer the simple life.
And now, tell me about your books.
What for? There's so little to tell...
I'd rather show
you the rest of the house.
Your presence has already begun
to dispel the sadness in this house.
The kitchen.
It's not very modern, but
Mrs. Salcedo manages quite well.
This way.
That's the woodshed.
That's where I write the novels
that might drive you away from me.
I also use it as a carpentry shed.
Yes, that's another one
of my hobbies. Come, Paulina.
THE BOAR
We still have time...
Will the Portuguese guy come through?
Do you think he'll dare?
- Hello, Mr. Morán.
- Mr. Mayer.
- This is my wife.
- Glad to meet you, madam. Finally here.
- Will you be having lunch?
- Yes.
Put some champagne on ice.
- An anniversary?
- You guessed it, Mr. Mayer.
Fifth wedding anniversary.
On my way!
It looks like Miss Martin spread my lie!
Of course it's Paul Deval.
A bit older.
But it's him all right.
- What could he be doing around here?
- The usual...
- I'm going to find out.
- Waiter!
Mr. Marchand?
Isn't that Mr. Deval
with the young woman?
No. It's Mr. Morán, from
"The Chimera" island, and his wife.
I must have confused him with
someone else. Some beer, please.
Perhaps it's not him.
I don't know... But it would be natural
for him to have changed his name.
He was found innocent, but all of
Paris believes Deval killed his wife.
To Mrs. Paulina Morán.
To the stingiest man alive.
- Just a moment.
- Where are you going?
It's a secret.
You leave... you leave and
every minute feels like an hour.
My wedding gift.
Have a look.
LIFE INSURANCE POLICY
I leave everything I own to my
dear wife Paulina Figueroa de Morán.
My estate in all concepts
will be transferred to her.
Thank you, darling.
It just occurred to me that
I should have done the same.
But I suppose you'd be
the one that inherits my money.
Isn't that so?
It's more likely that your
distant relatives would fight over it.
That would be very unfair.
One of these days I have to go to
Buenos Aires to transfer my apartment.
I'll go and see Mr. Sause.
Leaving me so soon?
I won't allow it.
Besides, any attorney in Tigre
can authenticate your will.
But what would Mr. Sause think?
That you made me do it?
Especially if he
thinks you're a "snob".
Why are we even talking
about these silly things?
- Is there any rush?
- None.
I love you.
And I have no plans to die so soon.
It would jeopardize you, wouldn't it?
Me?
You should read some crime novels.
The ingénue marries a stranger.
She writes her will
and soon dies in a solitary place.
Like the woodshed, for example.
You see, my love? Now you
have a plot for your next novel.
Good morning.
Are you Mrs. Salcedo?
- Can I start the cleaning?
- As you wish.
- Is the master in?
- He went to the woodshed.
I see you're an early bird.
Good. That means I can finish earlier.
My husband mentioned that...
you wouldn't stay overnight.
Where do you expect to find
a decent woman at night?
In her own bed, madam!
Besides, I wouldn't live in this
house for all the money in the world.
Why not?
Didn't your husband
mention the lost soul?
- The ghost!
- It's not a joke, madam.
You'll see it. It's the ghost
of a woman who lived right here.
One night her husband threw her out,
and she drowned herself in the creek.
They say she cursed this house...
so that nobody would be happy in it.
You can't really believe that story.
It's not a story, ma'am.
Some neighbors have seen her
at night; dressed in white and crying.
I'd die if I saw her.
If you need a woman all day,
you'll have to look for someone else.
No, no. That's not what I meant.
What time should I serve lunch?
At... I'd better ask my husband.
- Hugo...
- What's the matter?
Nothing, darling. You won't
ever leave me here alone, will you?
You're trembling!
But... I bet that stupid
hag has been telling you stories.
Paulina...
- Has that nonsense scared you?
- No.
But the house is so gloomy...
Perhaps it would look more
cheerful if we painted it.
Why waste our money?
The contract will expire by Christmas.
And... perhaps
we won't be here by then.
Why not?
No... don't tell me. Let me guess.
I know! Your book?
- Perhaps.
- You're right.
It will be a success and we'll be rich.
Was that what you
wanted to tell me, darling?
What else could it have been?
From now on
you'll have to work harder.
I'll be less selfish and
only steal your nights.
Won't you get bored during the day?
I'll let you write. And if have time...
I'll plant a garden there so you
can see the flowers while you work.
Here's the list, madam.
Don't forget the ant poison.
Hurry up, Paulina!
I'll get the speedboat out.
Mrs. Morán!
Mrs. Morán! At last we meet again.
We thought you were dead.
This is my sister Josefina.
- Pleased to meet you.
- You've let us down, ma'am.
When you arrived we thought we'd
gained a neighbor. Instead we lost two.
Hugo and I are very
attached to our house.
Don't be so clannish.
Us spinsters enjoy meeting a man
we can look at every now and then.
Why don't you come to dinner some time?
You'll meet Cecilia
and see our greenhouse.
Of course. We'll go
one of these nights.
- How about next Monday?
- Fine.
- Nine o'clock. Don't forget.
- Don't worry.
And say hello
to your hermit husband for us.
Goodbye.
Hi!
- Get your shopping done?
- All of it. What about you?
Uhuh. I went to the post office.
They gave me this letter.
It's from Agatha!
Listen to this.
"When will I see your alluring house
and meet your seductive husband?"
"We'll end up thinking he's an enfeebled
old man if you keep on hiding him."
The gossip that must be
going around at the Female Society.
We'll have to invite her.
I don't want them
to think you married a cripple.
Why don't you go get her?
You wanted to see your
apartment and I believe... your lawyer.
Good idea. Thanks for
reminding me of my will.
I'll ring Mr. Sause and
tell him I'm going tomorrow.
- Excuse me.
- Don't leave, miss. I'm through here.
- Thank you, sir. And pardon me.
- Not at all.
This cabin seems to be
full of pleasant surprises.
Something to drink, Mr. Casares?
I'll have some whisky in honor
of your telephone cabin.
Did you buy it from
a wizard, Mr. Mayer?
What a pity. Sause is away.
But... What about his partner?
Didn't you say he had a partner?
He's an unbearable individual.
I'm more comfortable
with Mr. Sause. Anyway...
I'll write to Agatha and invite her.
Today.
She must know right away
that I'm not a monster.
- What will it be, Mrs. Morán?
- Tea with toasts.
Guess what? You'll have to
wear a black tie on Monday.
Miss Martin has invited us to dinner.
In honor of the world's happiest couple.
- Come in!
- Hello, Miss Martin.
I can't believe it.
The first visit in two months!
- You can be sure it won't be the last.
- I hope not.
- Where's your sister?
- Taking care of Cecilia.
She'll be right down.
Well! Mario!
My nephew, Mario Casares.
An officer in the National Police.
Excuse me, I'll go check on Cecilia.
Come on, Mrs. Morán. Be frank.
Explain your husband's mystery.
Mystery? There's none.
Then how can you live
in that horrible house?
People suspect you're
involved in black magic.
Very flattering. But I must confess
that the truth isn't so enthralling.
My aunt is something else.
Ever since I gave her
a set of crime novels...
she keeps trying to solve
mysteries everywhere.
How's Cecilia doing?
Not so good.
Don't worry and drink your coffee.
So when will you publish
your famous book, Mr. Morán?
I can't wait to read it.
I'm afraid it won't be
as exciting as your crime novels.
It's a novel without any mysteries.
Please excuse me.
- More coffee, Mr. Morán?
- No, thanks.
I've always envied writers.
It must be marvelous to be able
to invent beautiful adventures.
There's something better than
inventing them which is to live them.
As is surely the case with Mr. Casares.
Not quite, ma'am.
Going after a murderer
is not as exciting as in the movies.
But you do need a lot of courage.
This is also no merit.
At my age,
I'm too young to think of fear.
Quick, quick! Cecilia's
just had quintuplets!
Quintuplets!
Don't be alarmed, ma'am.
Come let's go see Cecilia.
What did you think of the reception?
Unforgettable...
when I think it'll be the last one.
Was it that boring?
I must confess I had a lot of fun.
It felt like a Female Society dinner.
Cecilia was the star of the night.
But the young man was nice, wasn't he?
The national policeman?
Cops were never my thing.
Good thing we won't see him again.
MR. PAUL DEVAL
CHIMERA ISLAND
RM CHOEL CREEK
TIGRE
It's the wrong address.
No... it's for me.
Strange, I thought I had mentioned it.
It was my pen name in France.
So many secrets you must hide from me.
You already know the only important one.
That I adore you.
You will find the motive
for this letter very interesting.
We'll be waiting for you next Thursday
at 4 PM at the Lander lumberyard.
Good afternoon, Lander.
The gentlemen you
summoned are waiting for you.
Yes, they're interested in
this business. I'll explain later.
Where are they?
Well? Here I am.
Mr. Deval... Excuse me...
Doubtlessly you prefer
we address you as Mr. Morán?
Makes no difference.
Are you sure?
They don't know Morán In Paris.
But everyone remembers Paul Deval.
Flatterer...
There's a certain kind of popularity
that nobody wants, Mr. Deval.
Yours, for example,
might alarm your wife.
How much to avoid the annoyance?
40,000 pesos.
I'll need a few days to get the sum.
A deal like the one in Paris?
Perhaps.
A week?
Two weeks from today.
Your place?
At the Boar Inn.
You have to admire the bastard.
I almost gave him a discount.
We'll pay our respects
when he becomes a widower.
How about a beer in advance?
Let's go.
Forgive me, darling.
Lander kept me longer than expected.
Mrs. Salcedo, this is for the
living room windows. Leave it there.
Why are you looking
at me like that, Agatha?
Do you think I've changed?
I'm amazed.
You look ten years younger.
Truth be told,
I looked ten years older before.
Where did you meet him?
I mean your husband.
I could hold it against you that
you never talked much about him.
I was afraid you'd mock me.
Or that my marriage to
a stranger would seem crazy to you.
But how did you meet him?
Nowadays it's almost impossible to find
a man who is... at least presentable.
You found one who is more interesting
than what any one of us aspired.
I met him at a station.
By chance?
I believe in fate, Agatha.
Sooner or later, I had to meet him.
Is he a widower?
- Divorced?
- No.
Can I come in?
Yes, darling.
We'll have tea in a little while.
I wish we had a better
room to offer you, Miss Valle.
But this one is very comfortable.
It'll look much better
after I've cleaned it.
Why don't you show her
the island while I finish?
- Glad to!
- Please don't bother on my account.
On the contrary, it shall be
a pleasure to show you our paradise.
Let's enjoy that I'm married
to such a wonderful woman.
She's not afraid of
leaving me alone with you.
Come.
So, what did you think of Paulina?
Splendid.
Much better than
when she was single.
Is that so?
You can't imagine how that flatters me.
By feeling... somewhat
responsible for that transformation.
She... she told me she
had met you at a station.
That's right.
I had gone to meet
a woman I didn't know.
I had to pick her out
among all the others.
Then I saw Paulina.
Will you laugh if I tell you
it was love at first sight?
Very romantic.
She wasn't offended when I spoke.
That was reassuring to me.
I admire women who can tackle life.
That's incredible.
Paulina was always very shy.
When a woman finds love,
she loses those little hang-ups.
Come. I'll show you
the best part of our island.
This is the famous creek
where the ghost drowned.
What ghost?
Didn't Paulina mention
it in her letters?
- No.
- How odd!
She thinks of nothing else.
Just imagine. She's living
in a house with a ghost...
and the ghost won't show up.
Paulina feels let down.
Sometimes I feel like dressing up in a
bed sheet and hiding in the woods.
Just to please her.
She'd be frightened to death.
I doubt it, Miss Valle.
Any woman who marries
a stranger must be very brave.
But Paulina gets frightened by a mouse!
That is a privilege
that is almost exclusively female.
All intelligent women
are afraid of mice!
To me, that's one of Paulina's...
most charming characteristics.
- Tea is ready, sir.
- Thank you, Mrs. Salcedo.
You can leave now. Tomorrow, on
the other hand, we'll need you all day.
If that's all right with you.
No problem, sir.
I'll take it.
- See you tomorrow.
- Until tomorrow.
Mrs. Salcedo asked to leave early.
I think she's going
to the dentist or something.
But she'll be here all day tomorrow.
Was I wrong to let her go?
Everything you do is right.
Tea?
Not for me.
I've got a splitting headache.
I'll go get you some aspirin.
Thanks, I already had one.
Why don't you lie down a while?
My train doesn't leave until seven.
You're right. I won't be long.
Hugo, don't let Agatha get bored.
Now that were alone,
I'll confess something.
This week I was afraid your presence
would remind her of her old amusements.
The Female Society is not much fun.
Yes, but she had friends
who took her out for some fun.
Where?
Did Paulina tell you that?
She keeps no secrets from me.
I see.
Will you tell my wife
if I leave you for a while?
I have to go to the lumberyard to get
some wood for the roof in the woodshed.
Go on. I'll pick
some flowers in the meantime.
Perfect!
You'll take with you
the best memento from this house:
Paulina's roses.
See you later.
Agatha?
Agatha!
Hugo!
Paulina!
Come, help me!
Paulina had an accident.
Are you sure?
- Maybe it was a shock.
- A shock?
Look!
Perhaps it was a shock, nevertheless.
Perhaps she saw the ghost after all!
Why are you staring at me like that?
Didn't you say she wanted to see it?
- What do you know about the ghost?
- Hypocrite!
Isn't it what you wanted to happen?
Look at your formidable wife!
Turned into a rag!
The brave Paulina was
almost scared to death!
She was terrified! Isn't that so?
Answer me!
You mean it was you?
- What's this, Miss Valle?
- You know it as well as I do.
Why do you ask me?
You've got eyes just like everyone else!
- Do you realize what you've done?
- Let me go!
It's useless to blame me! You're solely
responsible and I'll tell anyone I want!
I'm not an idiot like your wife!
Shut up!
You're poisoned with envy!
You fraud!
Shut up I said!
You won't stay
a minute longer in this house!
Go!
I got so annoyed with her envy,
that I started to
exaggerate my wife's virtues.
Perhaps I overdid it, doctor.
And that idiot of a woman,
overcome by jealousy,
tried to make a fool of Paulina
by dressing up as a ghost.
- Is she still here?
- No, doctor.
I left her in Tigre
when I went to get you.
Better so.
Don't worry, the sedative
will help her rest all night.
She'll be much better tomorrow.
Should I tell her the truth, doctor?
Yes, but not tonight.
It will be a hard blow for Paulina.
She was her best friend.
It's better to lose a friend than
to live under the spell of a ghost.
Hugo!
Paulina, it's me.
I came to see how you were doing.
Turn on the lamp, I beg you!
Darling, you're soaking wet.
You need to change your clothes.
No, don't leave.
I know it will be back when I'm alone.
Listen to me!
I need to tell you the truth.
Dr. Vargas advised me
to wait until tomorrow,
but it's better
for you to know right now.
Paulina... there was no ghost!
Your friend dressed up to scare you.
Agatha?
I saw her when she was
coming back from the woods,
hiding the wedding veil.
She was laughing like a madwoman.
Screaming that you were a coward!
It's that... Agatha, my best friend...
She was jealous, I know
because she couldn't hide it...
But to exact such a cruel vengeance...
I don't want to see her again!
You'll never see her again, darling.
I lost control...
and I treated her violently.
I don't think she'll want to
set foot in this house again.
- Do you feel better now?
- Yes, darling, but...
- What?
- Promise me we'll find another house.
I promise you.
And now, get some rest.
I'll sleep in the other
room so I won't disturb you.
No.
Don't ever leave me alone at night.
What's wrong, Paulina?
I woke up and didn't
see you. I got scared.
I went out for some fresh air.
It was too hot to sleep.
Forgive me.
You have to get a hold of yourself.
Remember what the doctor said.
- Don't get angry, darling.
- I'm not angry!
But I'm worried
that you're still obsessed.
You're right. I know.
But I can't help it.
When I'm alone, I feel like
something awful is threatening me.
I'll get over it.
When we leave this house I'll
forget about the whole thing, darling.
THE LILACS
This is my dream house.
Isn't it ideal for us?
Yes...
But 200,000 pesos
is a lot of money, Paulina.
We can ask Gutiérrez
to get us a discount.
He's forewarned us
that the owner wouldn't accept.
Besides, you know I don't
have that kind of money.
I'm sorry if this a disappointment. But
we need to find something more modest.
I'm not giving up.
Do my relatives mean anything to you?
Of course not.
Then, my love...
"The Lilacs" is ours.
We'll write to Mr. Sause today
asking him for the money.
But can't you see that
this will reduce your income?
Why should I care?
Doesn't my husband support me?
Paulina!
Where were you going?
I thought you were writing.
You promised not go there until I'm
finished with the piece of furniture.
I want my present to be a real surprise.
I bring my own surprise, darling. Look.
250,000 pesos?
That's more than necessary.
Of course. We'll have to buy furniture,
curtains, thousands of things!
You're becoming a spendthrift.
No. I want you to
deposit it in your account.
But it's your money.
Our money. To buy our house.
Write to the agent today.
- No, Paulina.
- Please.
It's my wedding gift.
- No, darling. No!
- I'm begging you. Take it.
You've given me so much.
All right.
Wait. I haven't said I accepted yet.
- If I miss, you'll take care
of everything. - That's not fair.
You'll miss on purpose.
I never cheat at games.
We hope to avoid visiting your home...
As agreed, we'll wait for
you at the "Boar" in 3 DAYS.
Shall we meet at the inn as usual?
Yes, but don't worry if I'm late.
Lander heard about us moving out of
Tigre and wants to buy the boat.
I'm on my way to the lumberyard.
Three days...
three days... three days...
- Good afternoon.
- Sir?
I've come to pick up
a ticket for Paul Deval.
- Where to?
- Rome.
Fine. Just a moment.
Here it is, Mr. Deval.
It's 3,160 pesos.
Tomorrow at 10 PM at the
office or at 12 at the airport.
Please pay at the cashier.
Thank you.
Mrs. Morán. It's been a long time.
We don't go out much, Mr. Casares.
How are your aunts?
With Cecilia and her puppies.
Can I give you a lift?
- Don't bother, I'm close.
- Going to the inn?
Get in, please.
My aunts said you were
thinking of moving.
- Is that so?
- Yes.
We found a beautiful house in Martínez.
But I'm worried because the
agent hasn't answered yet.
I'd hate to miss out on that house.
Do you dislike Tigre that much?
Our island is too gloomy.
It's hard to believe
joy is absent if you're around.
If you knew The Chimera, Mr. Casares...
I've been there. We went to inspect
it due to the absurd ghost legend.
And yet when you arrived,
I knew superstition would rise again.
Eventually there will be talk of
someone who was briefly on the island.
Like an enchanting apparition.
Thanks for the flattery,
but the fantasy is over.
That's "The Boar".
If I may, I'll keep you company
until your husband arrives.
I'd like to greet him.
It might be the last time I see you two.
Of course. I'll just be
a moment on the phone.
Should I order some gin?
Just tea and toasts at this time of day.
The usual whisky, Mr. Casares?
No. I prefer tea
nowadays, my dear Mayer.
Mr. Gutiérrez? This is Mrs. Morán.
How are you ma'am?
But your husband wrote that you
were no longer interested in the house.
- You must be mistaken, Mr. Gutiérrez.
- Just a moment. I'll get the letter.
- Yes?
- It's here. Listen.
"I'm letting you know
that after some consideration,
"we've decided
not to purchase the house."
"My wife finds it too large, and,
considering the high prices,
"we think it better
to stay where we are."
"At least, until the contract expires."
Was that clear, ma'am?
Hello. Hello!
Own fortune.
No relatives a must.
I could very well be
a penniless adventurer...
on the lookout for a woman like you.
Besides, any attorney in Tigre
can authenticate your will.
Strange, I thought I had mentioned it.
It was my pen name in France.
Paul Deval.
I never cheat at games.
How are you, darling?
Better.
- It must have been the heat.
- Yes.
Drink this cognac, madam.
It'll do you good.
Thank you.
We better get home straight away.
No.
I don't think I have the strength...
to walk to the boat.
Why don't you stay in Tigre tonight?
It's not necessary.
I can take you to the pier in my Jeep.
- But...
- We'll appreciate it, Mr. Casares.
Lean on me, darling.
The air will do you good.
Yes.
- I went by the post office.
- Did Gutiérrez write?
No.
Don't you think he's taking a long time?
Real estate agents for you.
They start off in a rush...
But... Did you explain in your
letter that it was urgent?
I'll tell you the whole truth.
I didn't tell you before so you
wouldn't think I was hot-headed.
When I wrote for the second time, I sent
him a check for the price of the house.
To settle the purchase.
I've got his receipt on my desk.
Don't be alarmed.
I was careful about it.
The check won't be
honored until I agree.
Sit down, darling.
Madam had a bit of a sunstroke.
Should I make some tea?
I'll make it.
For the cupboard, Mrs. Salcedo.
And here's the ant poison.
I'll go get the tea.
- Mrs. Salcedo, could you do me a favor?
- What is it?
Could you... stay until tomorrow.
I feel really sick...
And we're so isolated.
I'm sorry, madam. I wouldn't be able
to sleep a wink in this house.
Just for tonight?
Impossible. Excuse me, madam.
Here, Mrs. Salcedo.
- What is it?
- The list of things I didn't get today.
Very well, madam. Dinner is in
the cupboard. See you tomorrow.
Come, darling.
You still don't look well.
I'll go get the sugar bowl.
Two?
The heat is unbearable.
- Aren't you having your tea?
- Yes.
Please, run and tell Miss Martin
to come and see me urgently.
Darn it! I forgot to buy cigarettes.
Can you handle being
alone for a little while?
Are you going to Tigre?
No, darling. Just to the lumberyard.
I'll borrow a pack from old Lander.
Lie down meanwhile. Tonight you'll
have dinner in bed. Like kids do.
Why did you come here, Paulina?
I wasn't going to kill you.
I just wanted your money.
I would have left without harming you.
She was nosy too.
She saw me that day
I scared you in the woods.
And I couldn't let her... spoil my plan!
She had understood everything!
Later on...
I couldn't get her out of here.
Because you didn't
want to be alone at night!
I have no choice, Paulina.
It's useless to scream.
She screamed in vain too.
I'm not scared.
I don't care if you kill me!
Today I found out I was married
to a scoundrel! But I wasn't scared.
Was I scared when
I put poison in your cup?
Now you can kill me if you want!
You coward!
I thought you'd die faster. But you
won't resist much after I'm dead.
The poison will
destroy you little by little.
When you desperately cling to life,
you'll remember Agatha. And me!
And all the poor women you deceived!
He's there in the woodshed!
I don't know how I managed to fool him.
Mrs. Salcedo,
can you handle the speedboat?
Yes, Mr. Casares.
Take the lady and call my station.
What about you?
Don't worry. Everything will be fine.
Let's go ma'am.
No.
Paul Deval.
This passport should clear up
many things. Did you get the ticket?
Yes.
The body shows no signs of poisoning.
If the young woman's
statement is true...
lies are once again
the best female weapon.
It'll be easy to prove her innocence.
Your testimony as regards Morán
strangling Miss Valle is precious.
Poor woman.
When he said he had taken her
to the station, she was already dead.
Should we take Mrs. Morán to Tigre?
Yes. I'll handle it.
Believe me, Torres. The weak
sex is the mightiest on the planet.
Paulina Figueroa is on her way,
perchance, to true happiness.
But her sad story
will not be an exception...
as long as the lonely human beings...
that await their fate...
lost in the cement jungle
of the big cities, exist.
52 year old WIDOWER, with own fortune,
wishes to meet a WIDOW under...
similar circumstances for marriage.
No children, no relatives.
Write PO Box 877,
Buenos Aires.
Subtitles: scalisto for KG