- What does this letter mean?
- I hoped you would come earlier.
I couldn’t risk missing my flight.
I'm going now.
- Bye.
- No, wait.
There's no rush.
And you can take a later flight.
Not now. It's late,
and I wrote everything.
Everything? I don't know a thing.
You said you'd go live by yourself
when you returned from Africa.
It means we have grown up.
- You married me to grow up?
- No. I hoped you'd grow up.
The taxi is here. Will you help me?
Come on, please. Get the suitcases.
I don't want you to leave me.
I wouldn't want to either,
but it's useless to talk about it.
Let's go. It's late.
Your father being sick
was an excuse to get rid of me.
- You know it's not true.
- Oh, sure.
You're going to Africa to meet
a father you've never seen.
- An old colonial.
- Don't be silly. He's dying.
Now have an emblematic death
in the family.
Colonialism is dying.
Yes, just go on.
No, Fiorenza. Wait!
I didn't mean to!
Please!
- Espresso.
- Right away.
- Mrs. Fiorenza?
- Yes.
- Your father sends me.
- How is he feeling?
What do they say? Is there hope?
They hope... that he dies.
They just want Italians
to leave, in any way...
Put yourself in the Africans' place.
If a guest, after three days, stinks.
Imagine us, after 80 years!
- Where are we going?
- Massawa, where your father lives.
- Is it far from Asmara?
- 2,500 meters... downwards.
If you go on the plateau
and look at the sea,
black girl, a slave among slaves,
you'll see that as in a dream...
- Are they curing him, at least?
- Yes. They don't give a darn.
In Western Africa they gave
a medal to the malaria mosquito
for the great contribution to
the extermination of the white man.
Not out of resentment.
It seems to be
an initiative in defense of Nature.
- Cool, huh?
- I bet you come from Rome.
Granddad. We've been here since 1887.
Granddad was a "chicken" soldier.
It's what the Abyssinians called the
"bersaglieri" because of the feathers.
He was with Colonel De Cristoforis,
the "Cinquecento".
Do you know Piazza dei Cinquecento,
near the station?
That one.
They were taking supplies to the
outposts, and he met the Abyssinians,
so Granddad stayed.
Do you see that hill up there?
It's Dogali.
Balilla!
Balilla! Is your name Balilla?
I have to get up.
I don't want my daughter to find me
in bed like an invalid.
- Balilla!
- You can't get up.
The doctor says it will hurt you.
Where's Balilla? I never
find him when I need him.
He's always going with sluts!
He will end up in a bad way.
- Here's Balilla.
- Where have you been?
- I went to call the doctor.
- I need my pants. Come.
Help me.
- No, wait.
- What do you want?
- You can't get up.
- Who will stop me? You?
If I hadn't sent you to school,
you would be naked in a hut
being a witch doctor,
not a real one!
- I'm getting up.
- I said no.
- You hate me.
- You are very sick and you know it.
Nice gratitude!
Who brought you water?
Who brought vegetation
to this desert of rocks?
They called it "the rocks' conquest".
It was true! We should have
massacred all of you.
As the Americans did
with the Indians.
See? You hate me, Captain.
When you were little,
you used to jump on my lap
and I held you in my arms
as if you were my son.
You had a daughter you'd never seen.
You are a bad father for everybody.
Hear that? You gave your son
a great education.
Young people are too severe.
Young people know nothing
about life.
You're laughing? Go away! Away!
All of you, go to hell!
Balilla.
Not you. You stay here.
Oh, sad and impassioned gypsy,
who make your violin cry
among your fingers,
continue playing
like a sweet serenade,
while I am pale
and silently listen to this tango.
On this perfumed night,
I will enchain my heart
to another heart.
Play only for me,
oh, gypsy violin.
Maybe you too are thinking
of a love down there
under a faraway sky.
If some secret sorrow
makes your hand tremble,
this tango of love
makes my heart tremble.
Oh, gypsy violin.
Dad.
I wanted to get up, but they
forbid it. They're the bosses now.
Don't move.
- How are you?
- And you?
- Can't you see? I'm dying.
- And you laugh?
No. It's that I look at you,
and for a moment I thought
I'd seen your mother again.
- We don't have a lot to say.
- We'll have time.
I didn't want to abandon a woman
with a baby in her arms,
but Africa was still inside of me.
Now they say it was all wrong.
But we were 20 years old.
I understand.
After the war, I tried to
get used to living in Italy.
- Just for a short while.
- The time it took for your birth.
Right. The worst was over.
- Why don't you come back to Italy?
- Me? Among Communists?
You should stay here.
- And do what?
- What do you do in Rome?
I don't know... I go out
in the evening, I see people.
Your mother went out at night too,
but not in Africa.
She never wanted to come here.
She was afraid of snakes.
I've lived in this country
for 37 years
and I never saw a snake.
Maybe she didn't love you enough.
Does she still live happily
with the engineer?
She still lives with the engineer,
but I don't know if she's happy.
- And you?
- Me, what?
Are you happy with your husband?
You surely married some roughneck.
We are not very lucky
with marriages in the family.
- Do you have children?
- No.
Why not? Children are important.
We thought that in the beginning
it was better to have fun.
But maybe only your husband
has fun.
Why do you say this?
Those scoundrels! After 20 years
of running the salt mines,
now they want to substitute me
with a Japanese.
These Japanese people
are everywhere.
My dear, you can't even imagine
what Massawa was like in 1936.
Each evening there was a party
on some boat.
They received you
with lined up soldiers.
All in white starched uniforms!
You can't recognize them anymore.
Sailors are hobos,
all black, wearing blue jeans.
But they say it's better,
we are all the same. As who?
But I told them,
"If you send those Japanese,"
"I'll go behind a salt barricade
and receive them with rifle shots."
Captain!
He never leaves me.
He's always chasing me.
- What do you want?
- Why did you go out?
Go home. The doctor said
that you must stay in bed.
We did the war together
in the 28h Eritrean regiment.
We lived together 40 years.
We were prisoners in Kenya
together,
and together we'll end up
under the red Eritrean soil.
- Dad!
- Captain!
- It's nothing.
- Let's have him sit down.
Leave me alone.
- I'll do it myself.
- Easy!
- Dad, do you feel sick?
- Don't be scared.
You're too stubborn.
You are not young anymore.
Time has gone by.
Don't listen to him.
He's old.
He's worse than a mother-in-law.
You shouldn't have.
You made a mistake.
The Lord is my shepherd.
I shall not want.
He has me rest
on grassy pastures.
He leads me to calm waters.
He reassures me.
He guides me to the right path
for the love of his name.
If I should walk
into an obscure valley,
I wouldn't fear any evil
because you are with me.
Your stick and your rod
give me security.
In front of me, you prepare a meal
under my enemies' eyes.
You sprinkle my head with oil.
My chalice overflows.
What do you care?
Happiness and grace will be me
companions every day of my life
and I'll live in the House of the Lord
for many long years.
Eternal rest grant to him,
Oh Lord.
And may eternal light shine on him.
Rest in peace. Amen.
- Hello?
- Love, do you hear me?
- It's me, Orazio.
- Massawa is on line.
Darn! I can't hear a word.
Miss, what kind of phones are these!
- Speak, sir.
- I can't speak alone like a lunatic.
Fiorenza, can you hear me?
You must come back home now.
You know I'm scared at night.
I must turn on all the lights,
and I can't sleep.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- I'm not talking to you.
Fiorenza, I found out
that everything creaks in this house.
There are many strange noises,
footsteps.
And you can hear music...
No, not music.
Fiorenza, I think we had
a misunderstanding.
We must try
starting over again.
Come back soon, please.
Will you come back?
Miss, nobody is answering!
Are you sure
she wants to talk to you?
Yes!
No.
As usual, my wife
didn't hear a word.
She might be under the effect
of tranquillizers.
If she doesn't get drunk
with sleeping pills, she can't sleep.
You must understand that,
she's having a nervous breakdown.
I'm sorry, sir. Have you finished?
No. Can you tell me what time
it is now down there?
It's dawn, sir.
It must be a wonderful country
if it's daytime at night.
Madam!
The car is here
to go to the airport.
- What monkey is that?
- A baboon.
- Where are they going?
- Down there, in the Savannah.
Madam, it's late.
You'll miss your flight.
Where does this lead to?
The Savannah.
I'm leaving.
I have a schedule to respect.
- Are you Pan American?
- Don't make fun. I'm leaving.
That poor woman lost her father.
Maybe she was crying. Wait.
- No.
- Then fuck off.
Wait. Here she is!
Here's the plateau.
We'll be in Asmara in a while.
If I lose my flight for Italy,
don't worry.
- Where do those roads go?
- They just go!
Otherwise what roads would they be?
You don't want
to go back to Italy, do you?
I spent my whole childhood
having paper boats float
on the bidet water.
I used to say,
"This is Dad navigating
towards Africa".
- And my mother would hit me.
- A horrible childhood!
Many times I travelled clandestinely
on those small boats.
But I didn't think about my father.
I thought about monkeys, lions,
the Three Wise Men.
- The Three Wise Men?
Caspar was Abyssinian,
a Negus maybe.
So many times, after Christmas, I went
back to Africa with him on his camel!
We always left before
they dismantled the Nativity scenes.
From the Nativity to Africa
across imaginary lands.
OK. You want me to detour you.
- Yes, please!
- Go on the plateau
and turn 180 degrees.
It's like hijacking.
- This will costs you more.
- I know you.
How beautiful! Are they castles?
Yes.
No. They are rocks.
They are castles
of an imaginary kingdom.
Walls of cities that never existed.
See? Does this look like an airport?
Where is the asphalt?
When you come here you don't land.
You touch the ground
like a migrating bird.
Let's go get the suitcases.
- We'll make out a single bill.
- It's not very big, anyway!
- Tell them "Salam".
- Salam!
Don't look at them like that,
or they'll notice it.
- Notice what?
- That their tits are uncovered.
- They don't know?
- They do, but they don't care.
If you make it obvious,
you'll make a bad impression.
- I don't understand.
- You just arrived
and you expect to understand?
This is Africa.
- What is it?
- I don't know.
- Suddenly I felt...
- Me too, but don't worry about it.
It's the sunset.
It's always like this in Africa.
If someone doesn't shoot himself at
this hour, he may live another day.
It's anguish.
It's nothing. Animals feel it too,
because predators come out.
It's an insidious time.
And if you felt it, it means
you're somewhat of an animal too.
It's a compliment,
but it's just a moment.
I already feel better.
How are you?
- Just as before.
- Let's go, then.
This is my shop. I sell t-shirts,
towels, socks, undershirts,
stuff like that.
I'm the pride and joy
of the local market.
- But I never open. I don't care.
- Is your name Getulio?
What else to who sells underwear
to Nomads, Lawrence of Arabia?
Must this child be washed
all the time?
She'll get some illness.
They wash her too much.
- I live here. Do you want to eat?
- No, thanks.
Don't be shy!
A soup, a plate of spaghetti...
Thank you, but I'm very tired.
Nothing, then.
- Is it alright?
- Yes. It's cute.
But a woman's touch is missing.
A woman's touch
was enough once.
Just one touch and my heart,
brain and wallet phased out.
- It happens.
- Nobody touches anything.
Let's leave everything the way it is.
Come. I'll prepare the room
in a minute.
Sorry about the mess, but...
We won't touch anything.
We'll leave everything as it is.
- No. We should take a look.
- Where?
What are you looking for?
There are no bedbugs,
but there can be a scorpion.
Keep this away from the wall.
- Why?
- The "scolopendra"!
It won't hurt you,
but it can scare you.
If some snake comes out, don't be
afraid. They aren't poisonous.
Thanks for telling me.
They're just disgusting
if they slip under the covers.
- What is it?
- It's a hyena.
Don't worry, it's a sort of dog.
- It cries like this?
That's a jackal.
It's a sort of hyena.
But it's strange.
Strange!
What is strange?
Maybe you didn't hear it,
but we also heard a cheetah.
Is it a sort of cat?
Yes, but when it arrives,
the hyena and the jackal run away.
Dogs run away from cats here?
Yes. It's a matter of proportions.
The dogs you talk about
are like this. While cats...
What is this?
- I don't know.
- But you must know!
In Africa, at night,
there are mysterious voices
that maybe are nothing.
But imagination exaggerates,
magnifies.
- But what is it?
- What is it?
Nothing! Or everything.
Or vice versa.
One thing that it's totally nothing,
nor is it everything...
I don't know if I explained that,
but outside of here...
There's Africa.
You had better keep
the door closed.
- Lions could come in.
- No. They don't bother you.
They are almost domestic.
They attack only if you bother them.
- You mind your own business...
- I'll bear that in mind.
Mosquitos come in.
Those will really devour you.
Good night.
- And thanks.
- For what?
Stay low. Don't make noise.
Fortunately Gualtiero didn't
hear you. He's a heavy sleeper.
Who is Gualtiero?
I knew you were awake.
You can't fool me.
I'll catch you.
What will you catch?
Don't get nervous.
What are you doing?
Are you scared of the lady?
I'll send her away. Wait.
Where are you going?
Wait.
Wait!
It's me!
He noticed. He sometimes does.
- Noticed what?
- That I'm human.
The perspiration betrays me.
I perspire a lot, but reptiles don't.
- Why? Otherwise...
- He would never have noticed.
Who is it?
Don't worry. He looks like a bandit,
but he's the gamekeeper.
Don't bother the crocodile,
or he'll eat you.
He can't eat me. Gualtiero and I are
related. We are blood relatives.
What are you doing?
Before he eats you, I'll kill you.
You can't.
It's against the rules.
If you kill me,
it's like killing an animal.
I'm tired of hearing you say
this nonsense.
Nonsense? Is it nonsense
that every man has an ancestor
that can be an animal,
a plant, a mineral...
It was just an example.
You think that this is just a rock,
that it's not related to anyone,
it's not a blood relative.
- What?
- Yes...
You laugh!
How do you explain
that in Rome I have a cousin,
but I feel more similar
to Gualtiero than to him?
Not because he's in Rome
and I am in the bush.
- Why, then?
- Because he's an imbecile.
I seem imbecile, but the truth is,
Gualtiero and I have
a magic bond, of fables
that in Africa become true.
It's not the reality you know,
but it's never-the-less real.
Even better!
Do you understand that?
I don't know.
You don't either, huh?
The fact is that we, down here.
Men, animals, trees, rivers...
Rocks!
- We are all people of the Earth.
- I'm not.
- I am.
- But it's not true.
I know.
But it's beautiful.
Who is it?
I had a head
full of curls and fables.
I was born here, on the river.
As soon as Mom saw me,
she ran away with an English colonel.
Dad was always away
and I grew up with crocodiles.
Maybe you, as a woman,
are frightened,
but I spent days with them.
Remember when you were little
during the summer afternoons
when time never went by?
Who stays awake in the world?
Kids and lizards.
Who doesn't know these creatures
has an arbitrary idea
of human relationships.
Go that way.
Go around.
Don't make noise.
Tell your dad I'll catch him.
Where does he think he's going?
Sorry if I told you these things,
but I never talk to anyone.
You'll say, "You don't have
someone, a friend?"
Where can you find one?
Man is son of the moon.
He's all dark inside.
His brain is frozen.
I don't think I completely
understand you.
Sure...
Look at that imbecile!
It's flying over me because I'm
a fellow countryman. Italians abroad!
I don't care about being Italian.
I'd like to be a crocodile.
It wasn't even predicted today.
Maybe people are coming.
- Are you waiting for someone?
- I'm not.
But I have a bad premonition.
It's ready!
I knew it!
Who is it?
He's a handsome man.
- Good morning.
- You could pave that street.
It's not a street.
It's a river bed.
Then put water in it.
It's not the right season.
Come. The sun is deceiving here.
- Why did you come?
- I ask myself that too.
- The sun.
- I was in Venice at Mom's.
My flight was cancelled
because it was foggy.
I took a train to Rome.
A 7 hour trip.
There was a strike at the station.
I couldn't smoke on the taxi.
- A useless trip.
- Useless?
- I must talk to you. Alone.
- No. Stay.
I have nothing to say.
Where does he come from?
The pilot told me.
Even if he flew over the house
at a low altitude to warn you
so you wouldn't get caught.
- He does it because he's a jackass.
- I'm talking to my wife.
- Is he staying long?
- No, he's leaving.
- I'll stay until we clear things up.
Where would he go? There are
no hotels or restaurants here.
The only choice is to stay. Please.
I'd like to sit down a bit, in fact.
One thing at a time.
You'll clear things up after you eat.
- He'll leave after having eaten.
- I accept because I'm tired.
- Let us eat in peace.
- Without washing our hands.
Eat. I made it.
He knows how to make soup.
A real pioneer!
See? This is what he's like.
We all make mistakes in life!
I took an impossible trip
convinced I'd find you in tears.
- I'm sorry about your father.
- Don't worry.
Why are you getting into this?
I'm grieved even if I didn't know him.
I'm the only one who knew him.
Believe me, you can forget it.
I wanted to say that...
- What?
- There's a mosquito in the soup.
You think of everything
to be a victim.
There.
- It's gone.
- You worry about mosquitos in Africa?
- You don't?
- No.
It's good to know.
I was saying I never expected
to find my wife with a man without
a shirt among huts and mosquitos,
even if I you don't bother with them.
I don't know why.
They bother me.
And the soup is disgusting.
Not only because of the mosquitos,
but because he made it. Disgusting!
How exaggerated!
You don't need to cry.
After having eaten,
my eyes always water.
Like crocodiles.
Considering the welcoming,
I'll take the first flight leaving.
Excellent idea.
The first flight
leaves tomorrow morning.
Tonight you'll sleep
at the end of the hut.
What? I'll sleep with him?
If there are no hotels,
I won't sleep in the street.
I'm busy tonight.
My bed is vacant.
If that doesn't disgust you too.
I don't want to be alone with him.
- Don't you sleep alone with me?
- It's different with you.
Is it an offense or a compliment?
Let him sleep here.
I'll come with you tonight.
- Where?
- I don't know. Where are you going?
Is it true that reptiles like music?
No. Gualtiero likes this song.
I tried with others, but he comes out
only with this song.
- Why doesn't he come out?
- There's no logic in relationships.
I keep saying, "I'll catch him".
- But what do I catch?
- Listen.
Will you do me a favor?
Forget it.
- Forget it?
- At least for tonight.
- What's with tonight?
- I don't know.
It's the most serene night
of my life.
Tonight? What sort of life
did you lead?
You can't imagine.
Your familiar tone...
Must that lamp stay lit?
Yes.
As soon as Gualtiero comes out,
he'll be dazed by the light.
It's like a paralysis.
He's at my mercy.
I could hit him over the head.
It doesn't seem like it,
but crocodiles are stupid.
Crocodiles?
I don't understand.
- They're singing at the village
- No. Those are poachers.
They say they killed
a crocodile very long...
Oh, God! Gualtiero. Hurry!
Where are we going?
- It's not him.
- How do you know?
His eye. He has a lunatic's eye.
And he's bigger.
He'll eat you in one bite.
You really care about Gualtiero, huh?
Jump. The gamekeeper
only comes when he feels like it.
Don't get so excited.
You just killed a lizard.
What are you doing up there?
Stop with these idiot things.
Let's go home.
- He's still here.
- I thought he'd left.
Come down immediately.
You are exaggerating
with this Africa.
I'm tired of your whims.
You've been having them
for a lifetime.
I haven't eaten in two days.
This climate is bad for me.
I hate the sun, the dust
and the prehistory.
You know how it will end up.
I must always shout with you.
See how easy it is?
- Where do you think you're going?
- Orazio.
- You go. I'm staying.
- Here?
- Yes.
- Are you crazy? What's here?
See?
You didn't even look around.
You're doing it on purpose.
You know very well
that there's nothing here.
If there's no connection, I'll yell.
Yes. We're far away
from Via Condotti.
- Look.
- I should see it?
I didn't sleep last night
in that hut.
Cries, screeches, inhuman voices.
The blacks. They spoke
continuously until dawn.
Then suddenly... silence.
An ambush type silence
like in a mystery book.
It was like that for you every night.
It's not true.
I even finished my cigarettes.
I looked everywhere,
but naturally he doesn't smoke.
Maybe I didn't sleep because
I waited for you to come back.
- It happened to me every night.
- Sorry, but I'm going.
Why him?
What sense is a man like him?
- Don't involve me.
- You must tell me who you are
and what you do in life, besides
spending nights along a river and...
And the mosquitos!
Like the night we'd finished
the Flit.
Be quiet.
You don't remember anymore?
Come on. Let's go home.
You won.
The lady's suitcases.
It's just your impression.
Here in Africa...
- You can find the connection.
- Congratulations.
Please, let's go.
- Are you getting in or not?
- I don't know. I'm undecided.
I have a schedule to respect.
- I have my dignity.
- Is the plane embarrassing?
What? That's not it.
- Will you wait half an hour?
- You think I'm a taxi?
- I don't know what to do.
- Fuck off.
What manners! This dust!
Listen. Excuse me.
I changed my mind.
Stop!
Excuse me. Wait a minute.
I didn't want to offend you. Stop.
Don't leave me here, please.
The truth is, my husband is crazy.
He's crazy without a reason,
as everybody up there.
- Do you hear me?
- Yes.
Orazio would wake me up
in the middle of the night saying,
"I'm bored. Let's go out!
I get nervous at home."
In the beginning I went out.
I fell asleep in the car,
standing up, against the walls.
Do you hear me?
One night I said,
"You go out, I'm staying in bed."
Do you understand?
It was the beginning of the end.
Lately he came home
just to change and shave.
He's say,
"What are you doing tonight?"
"Shall we go drink something
somewhere?"
Where is this somewhere?
Listen.
- What do you do here during the day?
- Wait for darkness.
- And when it's dark?
- You wait for it to be day.
Want some advice? Find a goal in life.
It's necessary in Africa too.
A hotel.
Incredible. It really exists.
He's right.
It's as if it didn't exist.
Young man, wake up.
I can see that she doesn't sleep
at night and talk too much.
Excuse me. I normally am
very nervous. Imagine today!
You all seem crazy here.
Including the pilots.
I don't know if it's the effect of the
place, or the people who come here
have brains that... Not me.
I don't like Africa at all.
My wife likes all this stuff,
and she even likes a man
I don't approve of.
If I did, it would be a liberation.
I'm perfectly well off by myself.
Sir, your raincoat!
Excuse me, miss.
Do you speak Italian?
We could have a drink together.
Let's sit at the cafe.
Do you come out of a fairy-tale book?
Are you the daughter of the king
of the river or the Savannah?
Dear and beautiful African girl,
Italy remains in Africa
and you remain in my heart.
What am I saying?
Am I crazy?
You could appear on coffee bags
with a cup in your hand
in the ad of a coffee shop.
This is horrible too.
Oh, God!
Maybe I know who you are.
You are the fertile half-moon.
You are Antinea, queen of Atlantis,
the lost continent. Stop.
I can't take it anymore.
What are you doing?
No, please. Don't go away.
Just tell me who you are.
Are you the mysterious flame
of queen Loana?
The eternal woman?
Where are you going?
Don't take her away.
Tell me who she is.
She disappeared in the Sahara nights,
slowly,
in the garden of oblivion.
- See? He's provoking me.
- Don't look at him. Be nonchalant.
I stop, and he stops.
It's useless that you look at me
like that. I'll catch you!
- Answer when I speak!
- Are you crazy?
- What are you saying?
- Nothing.
Wait.
Wait. I'll show you.
Are you going under water?
- It's easy for you amphibians.
- Leave him alone.
- What are you doing?
- I had to tell him something.
The last.
This way.
- Is he still here?
- No. He left.
What are you doing tonight?
I'll wait for it to be day.
- How are you, madam?
- Fine, and you?
- Will you eat with us, madam?
- No, thanks. They're waiting for me.
First you eat and then you go.
- What is he doing?
- He comes here every night to eat.
When at dawn the baboons
return to the Savannah, he stays.
He's scared of the forest.
He doesn't like being with monkeys.
He likes being with men.
He looks at men work, talk.
Maybe he wants to learn.
Who knows! Or maybe he's crazy.
He thinks he's a man
and doesn't know he's a monkey.
They are passionate kisses, love...
She liked me immediately.
- He's with the long haired woman?
- Madam is here.
The husband is always better.
- What is it?
- Sorry. I was looking for Fiorenza.
You look for women
in other people's beds?
- I always found mine.
- I feel sorry for you.
Weren't you supposed to...
- Yes, but I met an angel.
- This woman.
No. I met this one at the cafe.
The angel flew away with a camel.
Sure!
Excuse me for disturbing you.
No, wait.
I wouldn't want you to think... It's
just company. Don't misunderstand
I'm happy for you.
I was looking for Fiorenza.
You're telling me? I came from Italy
for her. Let's talk about it.
About what?
No. Excuse me.
One can't be alone with his problems
that they rummage in your bed.
Are we crazy? I know these men
who try to be moralists.
He was looking for Fiorenza.
It's what I came to do.
Sorry. I must talk to that man.
Wait for me, I'll be back.
Listen. Don't make me run.
I wanted to tell you not to worry.
She'll come back.
Don't worry.
They always come back unfortunately.
What did you understand?
I just want to be hospitable.
She'll get lost. You must know
how to get around in Africa.
Where will she go?
When it's dark here...
It's very dark.
- What?
- I didn't speak.
The muezzin!
You want to get into
other people's business?
- He says God is great.
- Brilliant intuition!
He says life passes.
Everything turns to dust.
You're trying to intimidate me?
- I'm saying...
- Stop! I hate these topics.
Tell me something.
What do these blacks think?
- Are we engaged?
- No. I must hang on to someone.
- It's an illness.
- Must you hang on to me?
If you'd stayed in bed,
you'd have recovered. I know her.
You're the type of man
I always hated.
You don't have to do anything
for women to like you.
You can go around dirty,
without washing.
Stinking.
Women will find
evocative odors on you,
reminding them of a lost childhood.
If it wasn't so, I would like you.
But no.
Women! They always divide us
and put us one against the other.
If Fiorenza is missing,
we'll have to call the police.
She might have found out you stayed
and she disappeared.
- I think it's the only reason.
- Believe me.
If I were you, I wouldn't worry.
Women are strange.
Women again!
I liked being on my own.
I had to meet these lunatics!
Her and the father,
little paper boats, Three Wise Men.
- He has to hang on to someone.
- Me?
Is it a punishment?
Will you just leave me alone?
I have things to do.
- I know what you have to do.
- Meaning?
I got information.
You chase a crocodile.
How disgusting!
Gualtiero is not disgusting.
- Who is Gualtiero?
- He's not disgusting.
Keep your hands off of me.
Understand?
Not in the face, jerk!
No, don't tickle me.
I'll go crazy. Please.
- Look at what a man!
- Crocodile man!
- I'll kill you.
- Don't think I'm having fun.
- It's a nervous twitch.
- Yeah, sure...
- What should I say?
- Always this dust.
What do they want?
This is crazy!
Stop. Are you crazy?
Don't touch me.
How did you get here?
You scared me.
You went too far away.
It's not safe.
I lost myself following a baboon.
It was night, so I slept there.
- I've never slept so well in my life.
- Of course.
- We come from here.
- We, who?
We used to live in the forest,
on trees
with our cousins,
chimpanzees, gibbons.
Then we went out of the forest
and we came to the Savannah.
- Why did we get off trees?
- I don't know.
The forest was peaceful, safe.
The Savannah was the unknown,
it was danger.
Maybe that is what attracted men.
The danger.
We weren't men yet
when we left the forest.
Here, we learned to use our hands
and to walk erect.
- In the Savannah?
- Yes.
We became men here.
This was man's first home.
That is why I felt at home.
- Like returning to a familiar place.
- Maybe.
Getulio is right.
We are all people of the Earth.
No. There was just one animal
in the Savannah like us, the baboon.
Then man became man
and the baboon remained an animal.
Since then, man is alone.
Look. Baboons.
- Where?
- Down there. Near the forest.
During the day they stay in the
Savannah. Then they leave at night.
Why do they go back to the forest?
Maybe because they know that if
they stay here, they'll become men.
This is why every night at sunset
they go back on trees.
To be able to remain monkeys.
When I think about it,
I feel a great pity.
For us or for the monkeys?
Are you going out tonight too?
I wonder why I only meet men
who always go out at night.
- He didn't leave.
- I know. I saw him.
He goes around the town
like a madman, but I...
I found something out today.
It's not to get away from him or to
see my father that I ended up here.
Nor for spirit of adventure
or distraction.
You know what brought me to Africa?
Nostalgia.
Didn't we have a date last night?
- I'm not busy anymore at night.
- Sure.
I knew someone else who
never had commitments... with me.
I don't care about you,
about Africa and Gualtiero!
- Not even Gualtiero.
- Not Gualtiero!
She comes and explains everything!
I've had an offer for years
from some Germans.
They want him for a zoo.
You know what I'm doing tonight?
I'll get him, sell him,
go to Paris and go with sluts.
Are you laughing?
You don't think I'll do it?
What am I doing here,
alone like a hyena?
Who am I out here
in the middle of Africa?
They sent Granddad,
Dad remained,
and I chase Gualtiero?
- Yes.
I just saw trees in life,
rivers and animals.
- People of the Earth.
- I never met anyone.
Who am I, Captain Nemo?
When it's dark here,
it's really dark.
While in Paris...
Can you imagine?
Paris is all lit up.
The traffic lights, ads on buildings,
windows, movie theaters,
cafes,
everybody drinking and smoking.
Nightclubs full of excited
and horny women.
I'll close myself in the Moulin Rouge
and die there.
It's not fair.
You're not looking at me? Are you
upset? I could've come earlier.
I know!
I don't give a darn about her.
I'm an animal.
I'll catch you.
You won't get away.
You're not running off?
Does the light bother you?
Gualtiero, it's me.
I told him not to bother
the crocodile. He ate him.
He wanted to go to Paris.
I should've killed him.
It was awesome.
Fortunately I didn't see anything.
All these people were running.
Good thing I waited.
Let's go back together.
What it is? Fiorenza.
Wait. Talk to me.
The sandals?
What are you doing?
You want to leave again?
You know I'm afraid the water.
Come back.
- Where is she going?
- Down there. In the Savannah.
I can't fly over the Savannah forever.
The autonomy is finishing.
My wife's lover died.
Don't you realize it?
And you talk to me
about autonomy? It's absurd.
We can't fly after sunset.
Want to end up against a mountain?
It could be an idea.
Dying here.
- Yes, but not with me.
- You just worry about piloting.