Right, Maria… Toni, over there, okay.
- Over there.
- And… keep still.
Frame.
We'll wait five seconds in black.
Action.
THE ARRIVAL
Hey there! Hi, how are you?
- Fine.
- How's it going?
- Fine, and you?
- Great.
Hi!
- Hi, darling. It's good to see you, honey!
- Hey, Alejandro, you're looking good.
I haven't seen you in ages. How's things?
Every time I come, it's like…
- It's the tops.
- Long time no see.
- Well, a couple of months.
- Where shall I leave this?
- I'll take it into the other room.
- Two months, since the last dinner party?
- The dinner we had…
- Hey, that Gallardo bag!
- I'll keep hold of it.
- The one we had here.
- I don't trust your husband.
- Has it really been two months?
- Yeah, it's been two months.
- Here, take this.
- Hey, fantastic, thanks.
- Thanks.
- Do you fancy a drink? Wine?
- The nancy boy...
- Here take this.
- The nancy boy brought a bottle of marc.
What have you brought?
- You jackass.
- What have you brought?
- Me?
- You've brought something, right?
- Don't play around, you know.
- Hang on, come here.
- Come here.
- Right.
- So, how are you?
- Fine.
- Fine?
- What about you? It's been ages.
He's… Tell them.
- What's happened?
- He's pulled.
- What?
- He has a rod this big.
- No.
- What?
- A huge dick this big.
- Not yet.
- It's not true. Not yet. I wish I had…
- Where did you meet him?
- He's turned romantic now, you know?
- Well…
Through an app.
- What's it called?
- Well, one...
- Grindr.
- No, I mean…
- the guy with the big dick.
- Alberto. What difference does it make?
- What nonsense. You're so silly.
- Why?
- What's the big deal?
- Leave him alone.
- Alright, it's cool.
- Watch it.
Lorena's coming with her new boyfriend.
- Did you know about him or not?
- Yes.
And...
- Don't be a bitch, babe.
- Why, what's up?
No, it's fine.
He's an older guy, a meteorologist.
What a picture!
- Seriously?
- How old is he?
- No idea.
- Really old?
- I think he's in his fifties.
- How old though?
Dude, the usual, Lorena's type,
Lorena likes older guys.
- You're such a nag.
- She's always with older guys.
The last guy she was with…
I think he was retired.
- Retired? This guy?
- No, the guy she was with before.
- Seriously?
- Lorena always goes for older guys.
Where's my mobile?
- I can't make Lorena out.
- Really?
No, I just can't… Well…
I can't make her out.
Is that my mobile?
You must come to my new restaurant.
Let's do a selfie.
- Where is it?
- In Chueca.
- What's it called?
- El Intruso, it's fabulous.
- Tell me about the menu.
- No, no way,
- come and try it.
- Honey.
No, hang on, I'm blurred.
- Another.
- Your husband is an asshole.
- Hey, why?
- He's an asshole.
Shut up.
- No, I'm joking.
- Look at the camera, it's for Instagram.
I'll go, Maria.
- I've no idea.
- Hi!
What's up, dudes?
- Look at you!
- You're looking good.
How you doing?
- How you doing, bro?
- I'm good.
Hi!
- Hey, dude!
- Hi, gorgeous.
- How are you?
- Good, and you?
- Hi.
- What's up?
- How you doing?
- Great.
I didn't bring anything in the end.
- Hi there.
- Nothing at all?
You're looking good.
- Here, give me your coat.
- Yeah, sure.
Didn't you bring your guitar, Carlos?
No, but Toni's got one.
- We've got one.
- Cool.
- How's things?
- Good.
- Can you get me a drink?
- Sure, what do you fancy?
You got beer?
- Beer? Sure.
- Yes, please.
How you doing?
- Fine.
- Are you doing gigs and stuff?
We're putting a new record together
and things are going a bit slow.
We've both got different jobs
because we can't live off music.
We must go to a Jevi gig.
- We really must go to a Jevi gig.
- No way.
- With a J.
- You're great.
We're not heavies, you know.
I know, it's just the name "Jevi's,"
but it's really cool.
It's a great group.
- What's up?
- Nothing, it just makes me laugh.
- The thing about Jevi with a J.
- And with an I.
It's like Levi's, but Jevi's.
No, I mean, I've heard some of your stuff
and it sounds a bit like…
a bit like country, right?
I mean, a bit more
and you'll be playing folk music!
Well, you have to add
a bit of humor to music.
It's about having fun.
If we don't have much time to do it
and we don't make any money from it,
- at least we have some fun.
- I love the lyrics.
- They're funny.
- They're great.
- I don't smoke anymore.
- Good on you.
- I need to give it up.
- What's that?
It's vaping.
Since when?
Do you fancy it now with a glass of wine?
Do you fancy a beer or something? Carlos?
Sorry? I've got one.
- Can you get me another, hon?
- Sure.
Have you got a glass?
- Whose is this wine? Yours, Maria?
- I've got a glass.
It's mine. Drink it.
I swear, I can't cope with Carlos.
Why not? You get on well with him.
Maria, you know we hooked up, right?
What? You never told me.
I can't believe it.
You didn't know we hooked up?
Well, you told me
you stayed up late and so on,
but you never mentioned hooking up.
I mean, you shagged?
- Yes, Maria, we've shagged several times.
- I don't believe it.
- Several times.
- You what?
I get really…
What are you on about?
- What have I touched?
- I don't think Toni knows.
Don't say a word to Toni.
- Not one word.
- Okay.
- No, honestly.
- He shags around, honey.
- No, but… I shag around too.
- Sure.
I know your husband, he's a big mouth.
Gym was my favorite subject, you know.
Is it politically incorrect to say "gym"
in the field of sports science?
Or do you have to say
"physical education"?
Yes, it's politically incorrect.
I mean, you should say
"physical education."
I mean, the name is
"physical education," not "gym."
But you can say "gym," you know.
My pupils say, "Let's go to gym."
- Maria, I've been out and about all day.
- I was dying to see you.
- It's so good to see you.
- I'm sorry.
- Hell, it's been such a long time.
- I've got something for you.
- Sorry?
- I've got something you might like.
- What is it?
- I'll show it to you in a minute.
Someone's here.
Who's coming?
Lore?
- Hey, Maria!
- Hey!
- How are you, honey?
- Good.
- I couldn't wait to see you.
- Me too, darling.
- How are you?
- Good. Come in.
- Hi.
- Hi, sweetie.
- How are you?
- Fine, and you?
- I'm good, and you?
- Good.
It's lovely and warm in here.
- I guess it's cold out.
- A bit. I've brought some wine.
- Hey, how nice!
- A bottle of wine and a loaf of bread.
A loaf of bread? Great.
- Toni.
- Carles.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
- How you doing?
- Good.
- Lore says it's cold outside.
- I can't remember…
- Toni.
- Right, Toni.
Carles, sorry, I haven't introduced you.
- Hello, I'm Carlos. Easy to remember.
- Carles.
Right, this is Toni, Alex and Marta.
- How you doing?
- Good.
Give me your coat.
- Sure.
- I'll hang it up.
- I'm fine, and you?
- Fine.
You're all looking good.
- How's things?
- Your coat.
Yeah, sure.
I'll keep my bag with me,
it's got my ciggies…
- You must take a look, I've got...
- Well…
- Seriously, it hurts.
- Carles, have a seat.
- What about your bag?
- I'll leave it over here, for my ciggies.
- You're Alex, right?
- Yes. Alex.
Well then…
- My word!
- I know.
Well, don't think about it now, relax.
Does it hurt?
- Yeah, it's really sore.
- Don't worry.
Leave it for now,
but you must come and see me.
Give me a call, get an appointment
and I'll see to you.
Sure, I want you to give me
a full checkup and cleaning.
I'll do the whole lot.
- Don't worry.
- Are you a dentist?
No, I'm a patient.
A patient! Right.
How's it going with this guy?
He's unbelievable.
You saw the bag he brought, right?
- So what? It's only natural.
- I was a bit embarrassed.
- Whatever for?
- Well, I saw him,
he turned up with a plastic bag,
with a loaf of bread.
He brought a loaf of bread, I swear.
- It looks delicious, babe.
- It's really nice.
The plastic bag though, hon.
I was a bit embarrassed, Maria.
- I didn't know where to hide.
- What? Nonsense. Don't be silly.
- It's a super loaf though.
- Good heavens!
- He's so cute.
- Delightful. Ideal.
He's really cute.
Carles, thanks for the loaf.
It's a Galician-style loaf of bread,
from the local baker's.
They make good ones and I thought,
well, it might seem a bit…
I love it.
- …tacky, but still…
- Not at all.
- Are you from Valencia?
- Yes.
So am I.
- Both from Valencia.
- Whereabouts?
- I'm from Moncada.
- Moncada?
- A town near Valencia. You heard of it?
- Moncada, sure.
- Where are you from?
- Gandia.
- Gandia? Cool.
- Yes.
But then I went to Alcira
and then I moved to Valencia.
- Right.
- There's a lot of vice in Moncada, right?
- Vice?
- Miami… Moncada. Moncada Vice.
Sorry.
- No, carry on.
- I'm sorry.
- Carry on.
- Sorry, it was a joke.
- The thing is...
- No, it sounded like…
No, with the People's Party,
there's a lot of corruption, so they say.
- You're right.
- That's what you meant.
- Right, Carles?
- Loads.
Hang on,
do we have to talk about this now?
About what?
- About what?
- Have you read the news today?
- What the…
- Well…
- It makes me laugh.
- I'll tell you about it.
I'll tell you about it.
Can we smoke? Shall we smoke?
Yeah? Are we allowed?
Right then…
There's no problem because I'm innocent.
- Innocent?
- Innocent of what?
Look, news came out today
stating accusations against me.
- What?
- Accusations have been brought against me.
I face an accusation of embezzlement,
corrupt practice,
several invoices have come to light
which are under my name,
but it's…
Look, it's an architect who wants my job.
- Okay?
- An architect...
- He's after my job.
- Toni works...
I work as an architect
at city hall in Parla.
Anyway, it was in the press today
that I face accusations
of embezzlement and corrupt practice.
But I'm innocent. Everything's alright.
The invoices are fake.
It's just a matter of…
It's a hate campaign against me.
- Have others been accused, or just you?
- It's an individual.
It's an architect who's after my job.
- But you...
- It's not related to any…
It's none of my business.
Some building work we did on the roof
for a bullring. Don't laugh, Marta.
Don't laugh, it's the roof for a bullring.
Hang on a minute,
how come you knew about it?
- I read about it.
- Where? Where has it been...
It was in El País today.
But I'm not worried, honestly.
It's all untrue. Everything's fine.
Nothing will come of it.
What could happen to you?
- What could happen?
- Toni, explain it properly.
You know what it's all about.
Well, the thing is,
we did some construction work,
the roofing on the bullring in Parla.
It was three years ago.
Anyway, there were extra costs,
and they have used
those extra costs to say
that I had issued invoices to the company
that had been awarded the building work.
Well, it's the typical thing,
it's a really common case. I mean…
- Yeah, really common.
- You bet.
Especially in Valencia.
I think the water you drink in Valencia
must have some chemical component
that makes you all fucking corrupt.
Marta, honey,
your jokes are getting on my nerves, okay?
It's an accusation, I mean…
- there's no problem.
- I'm not so sure.
For something like that
to be in the press…
- Maria.
- No, honestly, I'm not worried.
- Forgive me.
- It's okay, honey.
- You know what I'm like.
- I just want us all to support him today.
It's alright, honestly, I'm not worried
and that's what really matters.
Don't worry, everything's fine.
- If you're fine about it…
- I'm fine, I'm cool.
- Did you read it this morning?
- Is that why you're smoking?
- I guess so. Among other things.
- Can someone open this bottle? I can't.
- I don't know where the corkscrews are.
- I'll do it.
- I can do it.
- It's okay, he'll do it.
Toni, nothing like this
has ever happened to you.
No, never. It's all a bit crazy.
I mean, the invoices,
it's all a bit bizarre.
The post will be up for grabs next year
and it's a much sought-after post.
Of course.
- But…
- Toni has his studio downstairs.
I know what projects he's working on
and he's never mentioned
any kitchen whatsoever,
Toni doesn't do kitchens.
- I did this one.
- And it's beautiful.
We're talking about prison sentences.
Go to hell, you know?
I'm as left-wing as you can get.
You're left-wing,
but your parents aren't much.
- So what, honey?
- Toni's parents aren't left-wing either.
What does that have to do with it?
- It's me, Toni.
- Sorry, Carles,
this is the first time you've met us.
- All this gets me kind of…
- Tell us about yourself.
Yeah, come on,
tell us about yourself, Carles.
- What do you do?
- Now he'll say he's a politician.
- "An architect at city hall in Parla."
- I'm…
I'm going to get your job.
- No, seriously.
- What do you do, Carles?
Well,
- I'm...
- Apart from looking after our friend.
- You okay, Carles?
- Yes.
- Don't hassle him.
- Meteorologist.
Meteorologist?
- Sorry.
- Marta finds everything funny.
- I find everything funny.
- Yeah, I realized that.
Well, at least you know…
- Everything's going well, I think.
- Everything is fine. How are you?
- Well, I was a bit worried...
- No, I'm fine. Maria, everything's fine.
- I know, but… who knows?
- I wanted this to come about like this.
To specialize,
you have to study atmospheric science,
- which is an extra year.
- Which university?
- Madrid.
- Sorry?
In Madrid.
You can only study in Madrid or Barcelona.
That branch.
But anyway,
it's a degree course like any other,
- but it depends on physics, that's all.
- No, I'm sure.
- I've never met a meteorologist.
- Everyone thinks it's those people on TV.
- The weatherman.
- Weren't you…
No, I worked in television
for a year and I quit.
- Were you on the news?
- Yes.
Regional TV.
- Canal Nou.
- For a year.
But I got fed up and left.
Before they closed down.
A bit of music? No, Maria isn't keen.
- There won't be a raid here tonight, huh?
- I hope not.
If you have anything to hide, hide it now.
I'd love it if there was a raid. You bet.
- Me too.
- Why? For a bit of action?
- Of course! They suddenly barge in...
- Hey, listen,
I'm falling for your guy, he's great.
- He wants a raid.
- Me too. I love raids. I love the cops.
- They can sit down for dinner, no worries.
- Great, sure.
Sure, and they can search.
Well, they won't find much here.
They'll find Birro.
- What?
- I was looking forward to having a drink.
Birro!
You okay? Birro, come here. Birro.
I've brought some weed. From our club.
- I haven't smoked in ages.
- Come on, a bit today.
I need it, after the day I've had today,
it's been a really tough day.
- How many followers have you got?
- About 130,000. Don't you follow me?
- I can't remember how many you've got.
- Behind Carlos. Here.
Instagrammer?
- Yes.
- She's at it all the time,
- taking videos and photos all the time.
- I catch you looking gorgeous, dammit.
You do, sweetie, but sometimes it's like,
"Maria, leave it out…"
She does it well.
- She doesn't do it tacky…
- No, not at all, I love it.
It might be a good idea
not to post too many things tonight.
The day he gets an accusation
brought against him, he's seen partying,
tell me about it.
Yeah, exactly.
I've known this would happen
for two weeks now.
The news came out today,
but I knew about this two weeks ago.
The news about Greta came as a shock.
Today is a fucking day for mourning.
Haven't you read about it?
- I have.
- No, read the news.
Lorena, Greta Thunberg has been murdered.
- She was murdered...
- Search it.
- Has no one read it?
- I haven't read the news today,
I haven't heard a damn thing.
I know nothing at all.
I came through the door and found out
that Toni has accusations against him.
I haven't read anything,
with the shit day I've had.
What are you on about?
- Did you know about Greta Thunberg?
- Of course.
I don't believe it.
- I swear.
- On Twitter, worldwide.
No way, it's unbelievable, honestly.
- It's her parents' fault.
- Exactly, I'd kill her parents.
- What are you on about?
- I'd kill her fucking parents.
Not her parents, it's a social problem,
if she's been killed.
What do you mean, her parents?
Her parents?
- Do you consider her incompetent?
- If I had a child,
which I don't and I never will,
- thanks to the universe...
- Hey, listen,
- this girl...
- She's 16, you know.
- She isn't a kid.
- She started out really young.
- She started when she was 14, Marta.
- She didn't do the same things.
If my kid tells me she's going to fight
for the universe on Fridays,
- I'd thrash her and tell her to study.
- Marta, babe,
what are you on about?
A girl that has stood up every Friday
and dared to say things
that grown-ups haven't dared to say.
- Can I say it here with my friends or not?
- She's right.
- Of course you can.
- Come on, man.
THE DINNER
- It's really hot now.
- It's giving off a lot of heat.
- Can someone tell me how it works?
- I can't, it's new.
- Marta, you.
- How it works? Sure.
Please, tell us.
You put the cheese in these things, okay?
In these things.
The cheese melts, like a sauce.
You can put the accompaniments, the eggs,
potatoes, et cetera, on your plate.
And everything that can be cooked,
the leeks, tomatoes and so on,
goes on there.
- The quail eggs are so cute!
- The eggs on here?
It's really strong, don't mix it much,
put it over this side.
Otherwise it gets too strong.
- I'll make it up.
- Pass me the oil.
- I think we can add a splash here, right?
- Yeah.
The potato is great, it forms a coating.
I'd eat a lot of potato if I were you.
- Delicious.
- Aren't you having any?
Carles, aren't you going to eat?
- This is wonderful.
- I'm not really hungry.
Let me try.
Do you mind taking your mobile and this
off the table? It's just that…
- you know, I don't like it.
- No, please. A photo before we start!
- Maria, don't post anything.
- Why not?
I'd rather you didn't post anything today.
- That won't be the police, will it?
- No, man.
- I hope not.
- Why would it be the police?
- Maria.
- Amparo.
- What's up, honey?
- Let me come in.
- Sure.
- Sorry, I know you've got guests.
No worries.
- I need to tell you something.
- What's up?
I've brought you a cake.
- Please forgive me, I'm sorry.
- Hi, Amparo.
- Hello.
- How are you?
Hello, Antonio.
She calls me Antonio.
- Are you alright?
- I'm not too good.
- Really?
- This is a tiramisu I've made.
Delicious! Why though?
- It's for you.
- There was no need, but thank you, dear.
- Come out onto the terrace with me.
- Listen, this is Amparo.
I've brought a dessert,
I'm on a diet and I can't eat it.
- What dessert is it?
- Tiramisu.
- Did you know we had guests to dinner?
- We met at the supermarket this morning,
but I make this dessert
every year on the same day.
I have to,
but I can't eat it, I'm on a diet.
Thank you very much.
- Can we have a chat on the terrace?
- Sure.
- Carry on.
- Don't chat on the terrace.
Chat over there,
you'll freeze to death, it's cold out.
I'll tell you later.
I don't want to interrupt.
What's up?
- I can't go home, I have no electricity.
- It's gone off?
Shall I go over to your house
and check it out?
No, it's best to leave it
as it is right now.
That's why I wanted you to go outside
to see something, but never mind, later.
Amparo, stay a while.
Well, I could do
with something to drink actually.
- A drink?
- Man, you bet.
- Are you staying for dinner then, Amparo?
- No, good heavens, how embarrassing.
We're embarrassing?
It's the electricity.
I have no electricity right now.
But if you pour me some wine,
I'll have a drink.
How sweet.
This is like the accused,
his wife, the neighbor…
The accused, the neighbor,
his wife and other things, right?
- It was a film.
- An X-rated one.
- No.
- It sounds like an X-rated one.
- It's one of those films...
- Amparo.
- The accused…
- Sit here if you like.
- Toni, open this bottle, I'm hopeless.
- Sure.
Are you alright there?
- Do you live in a cottage too?
- I came as I was.
- You look lovely.
- I was about to say the same thing.
It's a bit of a special day for me.
Well, you look fabulous
considering you've come as you were.
Absolutely.
- White wine, Amparo?
- Yes, please.
Get another plate for Amparo, please.
- No, I'm not going to eat.
- Just a bit.
No, I'm on a diet.
- I'll get you a small plate.
- Are you on a diet, Amparo?
The quails eggs, for fuck's sake. Dammit.
Well, have you got any stain remover?
Toni.
- It's alright.
- What's the matter, Lorena, honey?
- It's alright!
- Don't hassle her.
- You're overacting a bit.
- Okay, it's alright.
- It's no problem, I've stained my dress.
- Okay, alright.
- Lorena has things to sort out.
- You're stressed out.
- Amparo…
- I saw you the minute I walked in.
- No way.
- You noticed it, right?
Yes, get it off your chest.
Seriously, Amparo's right,
I agree, get it off your chest.
- No.
- This is freaking me out.
- You have a special energy too.
- Energy, right?
Yes.
- I'll tell you what I've got at home.
- What have you got?
- I'm really intrigued.
- I've got people.
- Your husband?
- No, other people, from other worlds.
- Hey, I think we should drink a toast…
- And close the shutters.
- …to Amparo, because she's here.
- Thank you.
- To Lorena.
- Yeah, to Lorena, come on.
- To Carles.
- Cheer up, Lorena.
- To Alex, 'cause he's shagged.
No, not yet.
- Have you shagged?
- Yes.
No!
How romantic.
- No, I don't like you hassling me.
- Alex, cool it.
That's enough.
- Okay, cool it.
- Things are getting a bit intense tonight,
- let's all calm down a bit.
- Shall we go do some lines?
- Please...
- That's enough.
Sorry, it was a joke.
Well, Amparo, it wasn't a joke.
It wasn't, Marta.
We get together for dinner once a month.
Everything's fine.
Don't worry about me, Antonio, I...
- Amparo always calls me Antonio.
- Well, if you like, I can...
No, I love it.
My mum used to call me Antonio.
I sometimes hear people talking about you
and they call you Antonio.
Yeah.
Do you know what kids do these days
when something like this happens?
They go, "Boom!"
Kids these days go, "Boom!"
Yes, seriously.
- Like they're dropping a bomb.
- Well.
I'll tell you a joke.
One woman says to her friend,
"Honey..." Maria, for example.
"Maria, after 25 years of marriage,
would you marry your husband again?"
And she replies…
"Yes. Screw him."
That's a good one!
- Yeah.
- I like it.
- Screw him.
- Yeah, screw him. Sure.
- Sure.
- Screw him.
- It's for heterosexuals with husbands.
Sorry, you're a widow.
- But I love that joke.
- Excuse me, I'm a widow…
- Exactly.
- …but I'm about to be reborn.
- Really?
- Yes.
- What do you mean, "about to be reborn"?
- Well, I'm on Tinder.
- Don't laugh.
- And he's on Grindr.
- My daughter got me on it.
- You're on Tinder?
- Boom!
Amparo is on Tinder.
What's wrong with being on Tinder?
There's nothing wrong with that.
Did you meet your boyfriend on Tinder?
- No, but…
- Tell us about it, Amparo.
Well, I'm getting the hang of it.
- I don't need Tinder.
- Have you had a date yet?
- I've had a few dates.
- How did it go?
I didn't go.
- I don't dare, but I'm working on it.
- You must go, you've nothing to lose.
It's a message
from my husband via another…
- another person.
- Really?
He says I must live again.
Before I die, I must live another life.
You need to have sex, Amparo.
- You need to have lots of sex.
- Yes, sorry, that's what Tinder is for.
- Yes, I know.
- Well, and to meet people, right?
- Marta, are you on Tinder?
- No, I'm not, I don't need it, my love.
- She has restaurants.
- It's the figure, you know?
After what happened to that girl
from Valencia who was butchered…
- I'll have one last one.
- Who?
That girl from Valencia
who was butchered after dating some guy.
What was that?
The girl from Valencia, in Carcaixent or...
Does everything happen in Valencia
these days, or what? I mean…
It would be good for Carles to talk.
- Carles, could you say something?
- Marta, you're being a bit nasty.
- Me?
- You're being a bit nasty.
- I think maybe…
- No, not at all.
- Yes, she suddenly…
- I don't know, I mean…
We're here chatting...
- No, honestly...
- You needn't have a go at everyone.
- I'm not having a go at everyone.
- You are.
- She's like that sometimes.
- Exactly, you know what I'm like.
That's the way I am, I speak my mind,
- I've no filter. Okay.
- Yeah, we know you, but…
- Is this switched off, Toni?
- Good grief.
Are you going to the bathroom?
- Yes.
- Let her go, it might do her good.
- It will do her good.
- I need a pee.
- Can I go with you?
- No.
- Amparo, are you a lesbian?
- I've a finger in every pie.
- Alex is Marta's friend.
- Alright.
- Everyone's friend, right?
- Of course.
Everyone's friend, of course.
Your gaze pierces my eyes like a sword
It pierces my eyes like a sword
Love is so sweet.
Cheers, to love.
- Here's to love.
- Have you been married long?
- Married?
- Aren't you married?
- No.
Sorry.
How old-fashioned, right?
- No, it's all the rage now.
- We're married.
- Right.
- They are, we aren't.
- We're…
- How long have you been together?
A couple of fillings.
A couple of fillings, absolutely.
How did you meet?
At the dentist's surgery?
How did it come about?
At the dentist's surgery,
the goddamn surgery.
The goddamn surgery.
You don't know what happened to me today.
- What happened?
- I mean, well…
I've had a shit day, it started out shit.
A shit day. I woke up,
I saw five calls from Leonor.
- I had to start at eight...
- Leonor is your…
She's my fucking boss.
I mean, I had loads of missed calls.
I woke up and I couldn't find my fucking
knickers, I couldn't find anything.
I got there, I go to the office…
You know, the taxi cost me 20 euros,
fucking 20 euros.
I get to the surgery and I give
some fucking guy root canal treatment.
And the son of a bitch says…
that I've stolen
one of his gold tooth crowns.
- You what?
- I swear.
I stole a fucking gold crown
from his fucking tooth. I mean...
- There and then?
- Why would I want a fucking gold crown?
- Seriously, why would I want one?
- Hey, Lorena, the thing is,
has Leonor said anything to you about it?
Of course she has.
The guy literally ran out,
shouting like a madman, telling Leonor…
He may have been Jewish with a trauma.
- While you were doing his treatment?
- Exactly, because suddenly
he goes kind of groggy.
I'm doing the root canal treatment,
and when I finish, he says he had
a gold crown on one of his teeth
and I'd taken it off.
I didn't see any gold crown.
- Toni.
- I felt like
sticking that ultrasonic scaler
up his ass.
She could've killed him. Just like Greta.
- What do you mean?
- Would you have killed Greta too?
- Greta?
- Greta Thunberg.
A girl called Greta
came to my house today.
No, Greta Thunberg.
It may have been her spirit.
- No, I mean...
- In person?
I don't know, I was thinking about Greta…
- Did she knock on the door?
- No.
What the hell…
You have struggled a lot
and you have climbed mountains
with walking sticks.
I see you have climbed with sticks, but
one day you'll come down without sticks.
Hang on a minute, please.
No, she's right.
Life is different for you, it's easier.
- You're right.
- She's my neighbor.
You're all a bit preppy.
- Preppy?
- You've had it all given to you.
What about you?
How many restaurants have you got?
- Hey, sorry.
- She's worked hard for them.
Yeah, great.
- Hang on a minute.
- What is preppy?
- You've got restaurants?
- I've got five restaurants.
Yes, my family had
two restaurants in Valencia
and when I took over the company,
I opened five restaurants in Madrid.
- Good heavens, a businesswoman!
- When were you poor?
Well, poor… My family had
a restaurant their whole life.
- Restaurants make a lot of money.
- You've never been poor in your life.
- What?
- You've never been fucking poor.
Even though you worked in a bar.
I've been a hard worker and my family
have been workers all their life.
My family have a restaurant,
and my mother got up at five o'clock
every fucking morning
to go to the market to buy food,
to buy the supplies,
to then cook. And I studied a degree
and I took over the family restaurant...
- That doesn't mean you're poor.
- What are you so wound up about?
- Exactly, what are you so wound up about?
- Take out what you've got and share it.
Take out what you've got and share it.
I'll share it out if I feel like it.
What do I have to share?
A bit of wine?
I don't think
it's such a strange question.
Alex, everything's alright.
- No, but she said my…
- Are you a homosexual?
Well, I'll get up and get it.
If you tell me where it is, I'll get it.
Carles, I don't know, but it wouldn't be
a bad idea to look for it.
- No.
- Give me a kiss.
I suddenly imagined
a group of meteorologists
where they all greeted one another
slapping hands.
- It makes me laugh.
- It makes you laugh because I do it.
I'm no kid.
If you did it, it wouldn't make you laugh.
Everything about meteorologists
makes me laugh.
Sorry, I got kind of nervous.
The thing is…
Sorry.
Lorena, you're not well, honey.
Lorena, do you want a line?
- I do. I want a line.
- Don't you want a line?
- Sorry.
- What has just happened, please?
- Hang on a minute.
- No, never mind.
- Have you brought your Satisfyer?
- I could do with one.
Maria.
Amparo, you were the one who was shocked
when she said it.
Friends, I have never got stoned.
- Hang on.
- Alright, that's a lie.
I got stoned a long time ago...
- What did you do?
- Lots of things.
- Lots of things?
- But I haven't got stoned in years,
and what I feel like right now…
I want to get stoned, drink a lot...
- No.
- Honestly, I do. I feel like it.
You're crying, laughing,
you're unstable right now.
- Carlos, honestly.
- I feel fucking great.
- I feel like doing a line.
- I don't recommend drugs to friends
- who are suddenly...
- Leave me alone, man.
- For God's sake.
- I'll let you, you're old enough.
Of course she is.
- What would you know?
- That's not what I'm saying.
- Lorena!
- It's not a good time to take drugs.
- Hey!
- Good heavens, what's that?
- An eight ball.
- For feeling good.
- This is XTC.
- What do you mean?
- It's XTC.
- We said cocaine, not XTC.
- See, it isn't a preppy house.
- Maria, not XTC.
There wouldn't be XTC in a preppy house.
- Come with me, honey.
- Have you never tried XTC?
- Are you alright, Carles?
- Goddamn drugs.
Tonight, I want…
- All we need now…
- I want
- to enjoy it.
- …ls for the cops to come, after you.
I want to enjoy it!
Come on, honey, come with me.
Come on, come with me.
- Hey!
- Water, or what?
Water. Great!
- Come with me, honey.
- Has she had some of this before?
- She's not well.
- Are you alright?
- I'm fabulous.
- You're a bit pissed.
- No, I'm great.
- You'll be great in a minute.
She's my friend
and she's acting a bit strange.
She's your friend?
You must look after her then.
- She's your friend, right?
- Yes. It's precaution.
Asshole, shut it, man.
Looking after your friend.
Carles, cool it, yeah? Cool it.
- A bit of water for Lorena.
- Hell, the guest.
Excuse me, if I don't look after her…
If I don't look after her,
leave her alone.
He's groped all the women in this room.
Maybe you've had a bit too much to drink.
It's no big deal.
- Well, let's drink a toast.
- Sure.
- Let's drink a toast, everything's fine.
- To Carles' bread.
To Lorena. She's a great woman
with a great personality.
- I'll drink to that.
- She's fucking wonderful.
- Please.
- And that's that.
- Listen…
- She earns her money, she works hard.
She can do whatever she wants,
with whoever she wants,
however she wants.
What do you do?
Well, I don't cry and laugh non-stop
in the space of ten minutes.
You earn your money and do your stuff
and pay your taxes so we can all...
I don't understand this paternalism.
You're having a go at her
and I don't know what you do yet.
I'm having a go at her?
- She says you're a musician.
- That's enough, Carles.
I mean, are you self-sufficient?
Yes, I think you're mistaking advice
for concern for a friend.
And in a way you feel attacked
and I don't know why,
you're the new guy here.
- That's enough.
- You're the new guy.
I've known this woman
for much longer than you.
And?
Although I don't screw her,
I take an interest in her.
- I like her and I love her.
- So do I.
Well…
- Sorry.
- Lorena.
Love her the way she is.
- The way she is.
- Okay. Your hand, please.
- I love her the way she is.
- Your hand.
Alright? And if she wants to…
- get stoned or hallucinate, she can.
- Yeah, sure.
What does it matter?
- Let's drink another toast.
- Yes.
- Everything's fine, okay?
- Go on then.
Peace, please.
- I didn't know which side to cover.
- It's alright.
- Go for it!
- You bet!
Go to the bathroom.
- Go to the bathroom.
- Honey, I'm a bit nervous.
What's wrong?
Your guy is a bit…
He's had a bit of a clash with Carlos.
- Really?
- Everything's fine, but…
Toni!
Alex, what's wrong?
- I have to do a story for 1,000 bucks.
- What?
Yeah, I need to get stuff,
the brief is basically, "impossible look."
- What do you have to do, get dressed up?
- Yes!
- Now?
- What the hell shall I put on?
- The brief is "impossible look"?
- Impossible look!
Impossible look.
- I get paid 1,000 bucks.
- You what?
- Seriously?
- Wear this, Maria.
- Look at this.
- Toni!
- Maria is crazy, like this all day.
- Maria, honey. Wear...
If I don't do it at 11 on the dot,
I don't get paid.
Maria, this one.
- This one, definitely.
- This one.
- Gosh.
- Wait.
Not over the top, dammit.
- Who cares?
- Put it on over the top.
- No, Lorena, it's an impossible look.
- Alright, impossible look.
- The other way round.
- Fuck Toni, I'm doing it for you.
- Whose is this?
- Impossible look.
Who the hell sent me this?
- I'm not a size two!
- No, leave it.
- It's an impossible look.
- She's getting worked up.
- Where's Toni?
- The skirt.
- What's up?
- It's 11 p.m.
- I told you to remind me at 11 p.m.
- What for?
For the goddamn stories,
I get paid 1,000 bucks.
Right, we're almost ready.
- Don't tag me in that story.
- Get out of the way, please.
No, don't wear that.
- I need a bit of meditation.
- Let's undo this.
- We'll leave it undone...
- Take a deep breath.
This is impossible.
No, it isn't impossible.
It's possible, trust me.
Do you remember
the last dinner we had together?
I'll go get the eyeshadows.
Amparo, lend me your kimono.
Well, on my way home…
Wait, Maria, honey.
- …I ran over a dog.
- You ran over a dog?
- I ran over a dog.
- You what?
- You ran over a dog?
On my way home from here.
When I left here.
I ran over it by accident.
It suddenly appeared…
Don't worry about it.
It's alright. Did it die?
I killed it. Yes, and I left.
- But a dog…
- I can't handle it.
- It was an accident.
- I'd been drinking.
- But a dog…
- A fucking dog!
- A shit dog.
- What about the car?
And you drove off?
Do you prefer video or photo?
- I don't run away.
- Action!
I don't do those things.
Hello, friends from Mexico,
I'm having dinner with my friends…
- Alex, it's just a dog.
- I know.
It's a shit dog. It's a fucking dog, Alex.
…with this brand of vegan make-up.
It hasn't been tested on animals,
which is why I recommend it.
Did you know about the dog, Marta?
Alright…
Is this an impossible look?
This make-up is definitely impossible.
Food products.
Trust it.
- That was awful.
- No, you look fabulous.
You look fabulous, you look great.
You know, in no time people will start
wearing sequin suits
and checkered scarves.
I swear, I sometimes think
I'm playing a role and it's like, what?
Where did this come from?
Maria.
Maria, don't tag me, dammit, I told you.
You won't be on it.
I don't want to be on it,
today isn't a good day for this, okay?
Today isn't a good day
to do this in front of me.
I get paid 1,000 bucks, Toni.
He needs help.
I feel like dancing right now.
Do you remember Woman Against Woman?
What's up, babe?
I made that tiramisu because my husband
and I… It's our anniversary today.
It would've been our 30th anniversary.
I'm just saying, if you want to do
a story, don't do it in front of me.
- Stay away and...
- I swear, you're an asshole.
- Why don't we play some music?
- Do you need anything, sweetie?
He's got bipolar disorder.
I don't mean to stick my nose in,
but I can sense these things.
- Carlos, honestly.
- I can sense them.
Hell, that's the way it is.
I mean, I don't know…
We had an argument
and Toni had to intervene.
Don't start to think I'm making this up.
Everyone saw it.
There was a very awkward silence.
Hi.
- Hey, this feels really good.
- Yeah?
Things aren't as important as they seem.
Shall we go to your place?
You can tell me what you've got there.
Go outside
and sort out what you need to sort out.
Is it turned off?
- Not bad. Quite good.
- Thanks for doing something tonight.
How you doing?
Everything alright, Carlos?
Are you alright?
Thanks, you're so kind.
You're great helpers.
- In the end I stayed, Maria, thank you.
- Great, Amparo.
- If it's what you fancied, that's great.
- To be honest…
I sometimes see you from my house.
Except for when they pull
my shutters down.
But I sometimes see you and I envy you.
- Why?
- Because you love one another.
- We love each other? Do you think so?
- I think so, right?
You have a great future ahead,
you make a good couple.
Thanks, Amparo.
I see when the light comes on
and when it goes off at night.
And it reminds me of things.
Not like me. Every time I turn on
the light, they pull the shutters down.
Where's the garbage?
The garbage, Maria?
The garbage is over there, Toni.
Like it wasn't your fucking house.
- It often happens.
- Sorry?
- It's normal, it often happens.
- Normal…
- What do you mean?
- No, what happened in there…
Hey, let's go inside,
we have to help out, come on.
- Come inside, please.
- We're going to eat Amparo's dessert.
- Just a minute ago.
- Do you know what a déjà vu is?
Absolutely, guys,
I've just had an amazing déjà vu.
I had a déjà vu outside.
- Everything alright?
- Yes, why?
- You both seemed a bit strange earlier.
- Why?
- Strange? Who?
- You and Toni.
- Nah.
- Do you think I'm stupid?
- I don't know.
Time for tiramisu.
When are the cops coming?
- The cops aren't coming.
- Christ!
- The cops aren't going to come today.
- Why not?
No, there's no need.
- So, did you make this, Amparo?
- Yes, I made it.
- Delicious.
- I make it, but I don't eat it.
- Why not?
- I've made it every year for 30 years.
- Why don't you eat it?
Because I don't want to.
You either have a cake or you eat it.
I'd rather have it than eat it.
You can't have both.
- But I want you to eat it.
- Why should we trust you
- if you don't eat it?
- I'm going to eat it right now.
I'm a bit apprehensive
about eating this cake.
- Everything is sorted.
- Okay.
- Sit and eat.
- Let's serve.
I'll cut it. Okay, perfect.
It's salty. It's disgusting.
- Amparo, can you do me a favor?
- Yes.
It tastes awful, honestly, Amparo.
- It tastes like shit. It's salty.
- Marta.
If the tiramisu doesn't taste nice,
it wasn't me.
Yeah, sure, someone went to your house
and made the tiramisu.
Do you want to come to my house?
- Do you want to come to my house?
- Give it a rest, Amparo.
Maybe you're the one
who shouldn't have come here tonight.
Look out of the window.
Have you seen what's out there?
- Go and have a look.
- The house with wood?
- The house with the shutters down.
- And the wood up top?
The shutters are always down.
I can't open them.
I've lots of people at home who don't
want me to open them, just pull them down.
- Sorry.
- Lots of real people?
Lots of people who walk along the ceiling.
- Greta has been to her house.
- Excuse me, I'm leaving.
- Amparo.
- No.
- Amparo, no, what are you on about?
- No, Amparo, you're fun.
If it's salty…
- It's just salty, that's all.
- You think I'm mad...
- Amparo.
- It's alright, it doesn't matter.
It's the thought that counts,
you made us the cake.
Sure.
But maybe you should open the shutters,
to let some light in.
- You're spilling all the wine.
- No, I'm pouring you some.
No, she's leaving now. Amparo's leaving.
- She isn't leaving.
- She'll go when she wants.
- You keep directing people's behavior.
- I've stirred up a bit of trouble.
- You're all the same.
- Stop a minute. Can we cool it?
Can we talk about something else?
Why don't you just let people
do what they want?
- Can you stop a minute, please?
- Are you the justice of the peace?
I don't give a damn.
It doesn't look as though
you don't give a damn.
I don't give a damn,
but you're forever giving orders
on how people should behave.
- No, excuse me, you said before...
- Can we play a game?
- Yes, a game.
- You said to let people do what they want.
Well, she wanted to go home.
I'm just respecting her wishes.
A game!
Amparo. Develop this.
Develop this.
What was that game?
Each person has to…
say…
I don't know, I can't think of it.
What the person on their right is lacking.
What do you think
the person on your right is lacking.
- Seriously?
- I like this game.
- I like it too.
- We all do.
- It's clear to me. What else?
- Yes, Amparo, you start.
- Yes.
- Compassion.
- I'll accept that.
- You lack compassion?
- Yes.
- Where's the wine?
I lack compassion.
Carles.
- Carles about me?
- Yes.
Toni lacks a little bit of…
arrogance.
- I lack arrogance?
- He lacks?
Yes, to accept...
- He lacks honesty.
- To accept, without any problem,
that he's corrupt.
It's no big deal.
- Carles.
- Arrogance isn't a bad thing.
- Pass me the white wine.
- Well, it doesn't matter.
Maria. Maria lacks…
- She's your host too.
- Maria lacks…
- hope.
- Hope? Me?
- You lack hope.
- Right, hope.
- It's a game, right?
- It's a game.
- Yeah.
It's a game, but…
It's a bit intense.
Marta lacks humility.
Alright.
- Marta, your turn.
- Maria…
- Maria lacks…
- Lorena.
- You have to say what Lorena lacks.
- On your right.
- You can't take revenge.
- What does Maria lack?
- She has to say what I lack.
- She wants revenge.
Lorena lacks… balls.
Balls? I lack balls?
I'll never have balls.
- Because I've got ovaries.
- Okay, alright, ovaries.
- Ovaries.
- Lorena lacks ovaries.
- Exactly. I agree with that.
- Alex.
- What does Alex lack?
- Alex lacks…
Alex lacks affection on all sides.
- I think the same.
- You're right.
It isn't your turn.
- I think the same.
- It isn't your turn though.
It's hot in here.
Carlos lacks a big dick.
- Maybe.
- I think so.
- I think so too.
- Carles.
Right?
Maybe. It's quite possible.
I never say no to anything.
Right, you need to cry
what you keep hidden away deep down.
Thank you.
It's alright, it's what I see,
but I could be wrong.
Come on, Amparo, let's eat your cake
because you've made it with your pussy.
Come on,
let's drink a toast to the tiramisu.
Even though it's awful,
we'll drink a toast.
- To this tirami...
- It's fucking disgusting this tiramisu.
- It's awful, but it doesn't matter.
- Fucking shit.
Why do you think I'm not eating it?
It's fucking shit.
Who made this cake with you?
A little boy.
Get away.
- No, seriously.
- Let's not talk about it.
No, I want to know who made it.
I mean, you came here,
you suddenly turned up.
- We don't know why…
- Got a light?
- …but you turned up.
- Lorena,
- because she's our neighbor.
- No, she turned up.
She came here, she knew you had guests
for dinner and she turned up
because she damn well wanted to come…
- No, her electricity went off.
- No, that's what she says.
We've got fucking electricity,
but she hasn't, fine. She turned up...
I often have power cuts
because strange things happen in my house.
I came, and you're right,
I came because I envied you all,
because I'm on my own and I feel like
being with people. That's the truth.
What was that song
by Silvio Rodríguez, remember?
It goes, "I saw light in the windows."
- "I saw light in the windows... "
- It's alright.
- Everything's alright.
- You sure?
- Shall we patch things up?
- What era are you guys from?
Forget it, let's kiss and make up.
Everything's alright, okay.
I was suddenly dreaming
This is disgusting. Have you tried it?
Have you tried this shit?
- It doesn't taste that bad.
- Seriously, it doesn't taste bad?
- Maria, it tastes awful.
- What matters
is what you feel
when you taste that awful tiramisu.
- A load of shit.
- It's inedible.
- It's bitter.
- So do you eat it or not?
- No, I don't.
- You've learnt something then.
When something is bitter and tastes awful,
don't eat it, you bastard.
- Sorry, it's just...
- Your neighbor is full of surprises.
No, sing it.
- Please don't trouble yourself…
- There's a cute Instagrammer,
an architect from Andalusia,
I can't remember his name.
- Instagrammer.
- Instagram.
- He's getting a bit friendly with Amparo.
- I know.
That's enough, we all want to sing a bit.
We could all sing for a while, right?
- Yeah, sure.
- Right then.
- Do it so we can all sing.
- Lorena, if you want to sing,
- go into the lounge.
- Let's all sing.
- This song.
- Let's go to the lounge.
Carles, I'm sorry.
- Wait, I'll grab my beer.
- You don't know what you're missing.
I can imagine. A lot, I'm sure.
Come on, come and sing with us.
- Let's sing together.
- I'm leaving
I didn't come to upset you
Let alone offend you
- I saw light in the windows
- What is it?
I saw voices singing
And involuntarily I was touching
THE PARTY
Lore, what do you want, hon?
I want a shot,
but I want to drink a toast.
- Let's drink a toast, please.
- Yes, a toast.
- Okay, then I'll fetch some glasses.
- We should always raise a glass.
- To what?
- To life.
Drink up or you won't fuck.
So, bottoms up, down the hatch, cheers.
- I'm not one for drinking shots.
- What do you usually drink?
- To Greta, they've finally got rid of her.
- Fuck.
I've got her at my house.
To Greta, to all the girls in the world,
they're worth their weight in gold.
How does the saying go?
Dead dogs don't bite.
I know…
It's a bit… Carles.
I mean,
I don't wish to renew hostilities,
but what you just did was in bad taste.
It doesn't matter, Carlos.
It's just a simple comment.
- No, it's a comment in bad taste.
- It doesn't matter.
We're happy in front of the fire,
drinking toasts.
We've had a fucking good dinner
that our friends have done for us.
- I'm not arguing about that.
- Okay?
Life!
- Life is full of surprises.
- Carles, it's alright.
I just don't want you
to make those comments.
They annoy me, that's all.
So I'm asking you not to, please.
- Lots of things annoy you.
- That's enough.
Yes, but I say things politely, don't I?
Maria, can I have some water?
- Water, right away.
- My mouth is really dry.
Water, rum, gin,
- whisky…
- That too. Everything is good tonight.
Honestly, I swear, the son of a bitch,
saying I stole his fucking gold crown!
- To hell with him.
- The son of a bitch, you know.
- Maybe I did.
- Toni!
- Maybe I did steal it.
- You nicked it?
Amparo,
go fetch some lemons, I've none left.
On the lemon tree outside.
Take out the little wisdom I've got,
take it out.
The little wisdom we've got, take it out.
Carlos, it's 12,000 euros.
That's all it is, it's alright.
It's nothing serious.
It isn't really serious.
I mean, it's serious, but not too serious.
- It's alright.
- Toni, look...
I needed that cash.
I needed it.
- Look, Carles, look how cute.
- No, keep it away.
- What's the matter?
- Stop it.
It's so cute.
It's all public money, everything.
Money is an invention.
Why did you say all that stuff
when we got here?
- About…
- Well…
Because I have to defend myself
and defend my image.
What's the matter?
What's the matter, darling?
What's up?
Carles, what's the matter? It's a dog.
It's gorgeous. Birrito is really cute.
Carles, what's the matter?
- Yes.
- Pay it back then.
- If it's only 12,000 euros.
- It isn't that easy, mate.
I wish it was.
It's not just a case of paying it back.
It's not the money.
I mean, I've been caught out.
The problem now is defending myself,
so no one will believe
I took 12,000 euros.
You stole it.
- I'm so glad you're here.
- I'll tell you something…
Your husband is a good man.
I know.
I'll be right there.
Darling, please. Seriously.
Maria!
I'll get a gin and tonic for Carlos.
- How are you feeling?
- Fine.
- You're okay?
- I'm really happy.
- Happy?
- I had a some XTC.
- Everything is going well.
- Really well.
Be quiet!
Please, don't say no, man.
Birrito, sweetie, Birrito.
Maria, Toni, call Birrito.
Maria, can you take
the dog outside, please?
I think you should take it
for a walk for a while.
- What?
- What's up with his balls?
Nothing, it's just… nothing.
What are they saying, Birrito?
Guys.
What's going on?
Come here, come up onto the podium.
- You'll see Paris.
- Get up and you'll see Paris.
- Paris!
- Look, Carles.
If you like, come to my house tonight.
- Sure.
- Yeah.
- Fine by me.
- What for?
- To help me.
- There are lots of people there.
There might be a big party.
Carles.
- Please, don't embarrass me like this.
- Look at this.
- What?
- Go on, say it.
- It doesn't matter.
- No,
but maybe I…
Look, I just let myself go a little bit.
I improvise…
- I'm serious, Carlos.
- We've…
- Are you joking?
- No.
Are you on Tinder?
Tinder.
Well,
aren't you going to put any music on?
Come over here, Carles.
Let's tell him about it.
- He's had a bit of trouble with a dog.
- A dog?
Yeah.
When a dog comes near me,
my balls start to get swollen, literally.
- To hell with dogs.
- It's no joke, his balls get swollen.
Your balls get swollen?
- You bet.
- Why have a dog?
I've tried
all kinds of medication for allergies.
Where's Birro?
- Leave Birro.
- Birro!
- Stop it.
Leave Birro,
my boyfriend gets itchy balls.
- What?
- Carles gets itchy balls.
What does he say?
Have you seen a doctor for advice?
I've taken all the medication
for all the fucking allergies that exist
and none of them do anything.
They said they'll give me
a psychological test
to see if it's a psychological problem.
I can't understand how the hell
you screw an 80-year-old meteorologist.
Some parents
don't even give it to their children.
What do you like, Amparo?
Play a song on the guitar.
Play something.
Carlos, please.
Gosh, Maria, this has got me really high.
- I swear.
- It's the XTC.
I've no idea. I don't know what it is.
Bravo!
I've never tried other things.
And I don't know if I'm willing or not
to let something happen,
but if one day it were to happen,
if I were to have something with someone,
it could well be with you. Possibly.
If it happens now?
It can't happen now. Not now.
It can't happen now.
It won't happen now.
Not now, it can't happen now.
With people, yes.
I have a kind of…
No, I said leave Lorena alone.
Somewhere else.
Most of all somewhere else.
Christ.
I shouldn't have got stoned today.
- Why not?
- I shouldn't.
Are you crying again?
- What do you mean, you like Carlos?
- I like Carlos?
- Kind of…
- I really like him.
Like, really?
He's cute.
- I'd screw him.
- You and all the girls.
- Goddamn Carlos.
- I'm with a fucking man
with itchy balls.
- It's terrible.
- Get that shit out of your head, Lorena.
What are you worried about?
- Carles...
- You can play the ukulele.
Play the ukulele.
Yeah.
- Did you take XTC?
- Just a bit.
Hey, we need some rum, gin,
- gin and tonics...
- What's this?
Pass me that gin and tonic
and I'll be on my way.
No, that's water.
- The ukulele.
- If that's what you can do, do it.
Alright.
- Carlos.
- What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm sorry.
There's nothing wrong, honey.
There's nothing wrong.
- Have you got a light?
- Yes.
Listen…
I mean,
is it this guy? To rule things out.
Is it because of this guy?
No. I don't know.
- Lorena, who is this guy?
- I don't know.
- He's got itchy balls.
- A client?
- It's the dog.
- He talks to me this close.
He touches me. He touches everyone.
- You're in it too, Amparo.
- I'm not needed.
Your girlfriend was crying.
Amparo, take a look at this lad,
he looks pretty bad.
- What's wrong?
- What's up?
- Are you alright, honey?
- Thanks for the lad.
You're all… Have you taken drugs?
That's enough. My wife's over there.
My wife.
My wife is over there, Alex.
Are you alright? Do you want to puke?
Are you alright, Carles?
Hey, the meteorologist is on a low.
The son of a bitch
that accused me of stealing a crown...
- Lore, honey, Carles isn't well.
- Are his balls itchy?
His balls are itchy
'cause he's allergic to the dog.
- Tell him to fuck off.
- What's he allergic to?
He's fainting, hon,
something's wrong with him.
- Carlos, help me, please.
- He brought the bread
and the wine in a plastic bag.
Shall we call an ambulance?
- I don't know, he doesn't feel well.
- Are your balls itchy, Carles?
- You've got itchy balls.
- Wait a minute,
- stand up.
- Poor thing.
The guy has got itchy balls.
No, he's in a bad way,
wait a minute, please.
Hold on!
- Hey!
- Please!
Take it easy.
Please, this man is...
- Calm down, okay.
- Okay, take it easy.
- Open the door.
- Yes, open the door, get some fresh air.
- Please.
- Alejandro!
Maria,
get the dog out of here this minute!
- Get the dog out of the house, now.
- Birro.
Hello, Carles.
Scratch his balls.
Alex! Shut the fuck up!
- Are you off your head?
- Where are you?
- Carles, honey.
- Carles!
- Don't hassle him.
- He's an asshole.
- Lorena, has this happened before?
I don't know, it's the first time.
All I know is that the dog was causing
some kind of a reaction.
- Has he fainted because of the dog?
- I don't know.
I don't know him that well.
I've only been seeing him two months.
This guy is a fucking shit guy,
he's been touching our butts all night.
I'm telling you.
Seriously, he's fainted, he can't hear me.
This is no time for this.
Now you know,
he's been touching our butts.
He's been touching our goddamn butts.
This is no time for this nonsense,
goddammit.
- Marta, not now.
- Carlos...
- Not now.
- Don't push me aside like that.
- What an asshole.
- Marta, I'm sorry, okay? Look at him.
His eyes are closing.
Call the emergency services.
Shall I call? Okay, I'll call.
Carles, come on. Wake up!
Son of a bitch. Come on!
Wake up, you son of a bitch.
- Did he touch your ass?
- Everything.
- Carles.
- Get a cloth.
- Carles, darling.
- Okay, he's coming round.
Carles, darling,
don't you remember anything?
- You're in a bit of a...
- Alex!
Alex, that's enough!
Christ!
Carles, you're at a friends' dinner party.
Friends who…
- are with you and everything's fine.
- But they're not really your friends.
- You kind of came…
- Wrongfully.
- Lift him up.
- Let's see how you are.
Carlos, how come you can't cope?
You love this.
Talk to me and tell me
you don't need an ambulance.
They're two of a kind.
Looking at them both now…
- Carles.
- Let's sit him up.
- You need to rest, right?
- He can't.
- Come on, Carles.
Be careful.
- There we go.
- It's alright.
Right.
- That's enough, Carlos.
- Carles, honey.
- What's his name?
- Carles.
- What else?
- The guitar!
It was a gift from me
and it cost a fortune, dammit!
Just a second. That's it.
- You'll come with me to my house, okay?
- Do you want a line, Carles?
Do you want to come with Greta,
to my house?
With Greta?
People die
- because they don't have all this.
- Of course.
- Youth, love, affection...
- This is being alive, right?
This experiment was filmed live
amongst friends
and with no budget on 7 December 2019.
The cast had a short description
of their character.
All the acting was improvised.
Without a script.
Three months later, a global pandemic
forced all Spanish citizens
to remain confined to their homes
under a state of alarm.
- It was all a lie.
- A lie?
It was a lie. This is water.
The son of a bitch gave me a fright.
I thought he was really dying.
Look at Amparo.
You're all fucking great!
You're fucking great!