Deck the halls
with boughs of holly
Fa la la la la, la la la la
'Tis the season to be jolly
This
Christmas, give the gift of love
from Lynn D. Jewelers.
Lynn D. Jewelers,
providing fine jewelry...
It's not even Halloween yet.
That's Lacy.
She needs to find
her Christmas spirit.
It's been gone
for a long, long time.
She was always on the nice list
and she truly loved Christmas,
but like so many,
things happen in life
that cause you
to follow another path.
Unfortunately, for this poor
girl, hers happened at Christmas.
She needs a good dose
of Christmas magic
and maybe a few do-overs
to get things right.
What time are you
gonna be there?
I need to get in
before Nora arrives.
She has something important
she wants to speak
with me about.
Which, between you and me,
I think she's going to finally
promote me to partner.
I'm there in five minutes, Lacy.
I'll have everything set up
for you and your big day.
I can get you that new peppermint
Christmas latte instead of your regular.
You know I don't want any
of that sweet holiday garbage.
I just want my
regular daily fix,
and I'm definitely gonna need it
to get through today.
I hate one-on-ones,
I hate surprises,
and most importantly, you know
I hate them at the holidays.
I'm just teasing you, Lacy.
Just get in here
and focus on becoming partner.
I already have your iced half-caff
ristretto, Venti, four-pump sugar-free
cinnamon dulce, soy,
skinny latte ready for you.
See you shortly.
Or as I like to call it,
the Ice Queen's Happy Juice.
Mm, funny, funny, Raymond.
You'll definitely
get a job as a comedian
if this whole interior design
career doesn't take off for you.
Enjoy your drink while you can,
because Nora's already
in the conference room
waiting for you.
Surprise.
One, two...
Why didn't you tell me
that to begin with?
You know I hate surprises!
Did she get here before you?
Lacy, please,
no one gets here before me.
Look, for five years
we've worked together.
You are a talented,
brilliant woman.
You've worked your butt off
to get here,
and it's your time now.
So finish
your breathing exercises,
take your drink,
and go get what you deserve.
- Good morning, Lacy.
- Good morning.
- Oh, I so love the holidays.
- Oh.
This time of year
is just magical.
- Hmm.
- Definitely the best time to be in our line of work.
Oh, yes, it's such
a jolly good time.
If you're into
that sort of thing.
Get over yourself, my dear.
You will find yourself
appreciating
"that sort of thing" some day.
If anything,
you should appreciate
how high your sales
have been this season.
You are the star of our company.
And, Lacy, you have a remarkable
following with our clients.
We just landed
two very large accounts.
Oh, this holiday
is going to be spectacular.
What is that knocking?
Ah, moving on.
This office
is going to be so busy
that we all need to keep
a positive holiday energy.
Heading into
this holiday season, Lacy,
we can't afford
any more of your negativity,
and especially outbursts.
So because of all of this,
I want you to have a change about
your Christmas attitude. Hm?
Maybe try to have a smidge
of fun this holiday?
So that is why I am
bringing in someone to help.
What?
No, Nora, that is...
There is no need for that.
I have been doing this
for so long by myself,
I couldn't possibly
work with anyone else.
This has nothing
to do with the holidays.
Where is this coming from?
I've been working on this.
I'm not difficult.
I mean, I've been going to a therapist.
I'm more mindful.
I just have some issues
with the holidays.
Lacy, my niece just graduated
from the New York
School of Interior Design,
and I want you to mentor her.
Lacy, I once mentored you
and look what became of you.
I hope you do
the same for my niece.
I'm not asking you, Lacy.
And where am I supposed to find
this lovely and talented,
perfect Christmas gift?
Oh, she's right behind you.
Lacy, meet my niece, Jenna.
Nice to meet you, Lacy.
I'm such a huge fan
of all your designs.
I grew up
admiring all your work.
My Aunt Nora always tells me
I remind her of you.
I used so many
of your past designs
as inspiration
while I was at school.
I like to think my designs reflect
yours, just a little freshened up.
I'm sure you'll teach me
so many things.
Okay!
She seems nice.
What the hell
just happened in there?
I-I was ambushed.
"Freshened up."
Did she really
just say that to me?
What a condescending
little snot.
I thought I was going in there
for a promotion
that I have been
working so hard for.
And now I'm stuck babysitting
some spoiled little rich kid?
And who is Nora to tell me
that I'm stressed out?
And I have a temper, really?
I do not have a temper.
- Tell me I don't have a temper!
- What temper?
I've only ducked a couple
staplers these past few years.
Keep doing your breathing.
I don't hear you counting.
One, two, three,
uh-huh, yeah, breathe.
Now, seriously,
an extra set of hands
with all this work
could be good for us.
Why don't you take some time for yourself?
Balance the work.
Even try to enjoy the holiday.
You know, sing a carol,
indulge in some eggnog...
maybe even a
little holiday romance.
Maybe not.
But, look,
let's just give Jenna a chance.
I'm just saying,
how bad could she be?
Yay!
Where you going?
Are these your designs
for the new Underhill account?
Wow!
You have outdone yourself again.
I know you couldn't do it without me.
- Okay.
- Just sayin'.
Look, these guys are brand new,
and they came to us
so highly recommended.
I did a little extra work
and the deadline
isn't till tomorrow.
No stress, no outbursts.
We are ahead on all accounts,
and this is
the first deadline tomorrow.
Nora will be beyond impressed.
And you, you have been
very good with Jenna,
who surprisingly has been pretty
helpful, wouldn't you say?
She's entirely too bubbly
for my liking,
but yes, she has been
more helpful than not.
And speak of the devil.
I hope I'm not interrupting.
I wanted to let you guys know
that there are
candy cane cupcakes
that I made in the breakroom.
Better get in there quick,
though, 'cause they're going fast.
I think I saw Darryl eat three.
Darryl, all he does
is crunches numbers and eats.
You know,
Lacy loves candy canes.
Yeah, I'll go get us some.
Peppermint's her favorite.
Be nice.
I want to thank you
for being so nice to me, Lacy.
I'm watching you, absorbing everything
you say and do, like I'm a big sponge.
Oh, I'm such a dork
for saying that.
Are those the new designs
for the Underhill account?
- Mm-hmm.
- May I?
Lacy, these are fabulous.
I've never seen
anything like this.
You have to let me take you out
so I can pick your brain.
I know the perfect place that has a
Christmas martini with a peppermint twist.
It's perfect because you
love peppermint so much.
I wanna know
everything about you,
where you studied,
what your inspirations are.
I wanna know
who the real Lacy is.
That's great, Jenna.
I have to go find Raymond.
He can set it up,
but just for now, stay focused,
as the Underhills
are not our only account.
Too bad the Underhills
are the only account
that matters.
This firm's legacy is mine...
not yours, Lacy.
Merry Christmas, everybody.
I want to thank you
for working so hard.
We are getting close
to the holiday break,
and we are breaking records
this year.
I want to congratulate my niece
and newest member of our office
for outstanding performance
in just the first two weeks.
I received a call this morning
from Mr. James Underhill himself.
He was so blown away by the
designs my niece Jenna did
that he wants her and only her
to handle their account.
Breathe.
Oh, shoot.
Those designs are mine,
you-you elf witch!
I knew I couldn't trust you!
You have no idea
how to do those designs!
You've never even
spoken to the Underhills!
You can hardly handle
speaking on the phone
with your bubbly attitude
and your stupid holiday spirit!
You are more concerned with
passing out candy canes
than coming up with
any real ideas!
Well, you can take
those candy canes
- and shove them...
- Lacy, what are you doing?
Lacy, that is enough!
Jenna?
She's absolutely insane.
Of course those are my ideas.
You've told me how unhinged she can
become, this whole office knows.
Not only did I come up
with those ideas,
but I tried to do it
while providing this office
with some much-needed
holiday spirit.
It's like, not being
an old scrooge for the holidays.
Old scrooge? Oh, I'm gonna rip those
elf ears off your smug little head!
Now, enough everyone!
Lacy, that is it!
You need to
get a hold of yourself,
and try to learn to embrace
the Christmas spirit.
I don't want to see you back in
this office until the new year.
- That's final.
- Nora...
And if anyone else has anything
to say, they can leave, too.
But you won't have the luxury
of coming back in the new year.
Happy holidays.
Excuse me.
Lacy, why are you
packing all this up?
You'll be back
before you know it.
I highly doubt it, Raymond.
Don't you see
the bigger picture here?
Jenna has been
out for my job all along.
You've been my best friend
for more than five years now.
I care about you
more than an associate should.
This is about you.
No one else.
Think about it. Who gets
angry during the holidays?
You need to take this week
and figure out how to fix you.
You are a beautiful,
intelligent woman
who has no one in her life
but her dashing assistant.
It's time for you
to learn to relax, love,
and embrace the holidays.
On that note, I've scheduled you
an appointment tonight
with Dr. Noelles.
Who the heck is that?
Dr. Baker is on vacation
and his office suggested him.
And no buts, just go.
It's time for you
to work on you.
Merry Christmas.
No grumbling.
Mm-hmm. Mm-mmm.
Thank you, girl.
I want to thank you
for seeing me, Dr. Noelles.
I-I didn't realize Dr. Baker was
out of town for the holidays,
and I really needed to
speak with somebody.
I can't believe what happened.
Everything was going so great
until that little demon arrived.
And Nora just allowed her
to sabotage me,
and everyone at the office
adores her.
Why do bad things always happen
to me during the holidays?
Well, Lacy, I do
see that you have anger issues
that come from
an unresolved occurrence
that happened
during the holiday season.
It doesn't have anything to do
with any unresolved occurrence.
It's this little Elf on the Shelf,
just showed up and sabotaged me,
and I'm supposed to sit back
and let it happen? No way.
It doesn't have anything
to do with my past.
Lacy, you've
come to me for a reason.
You've become sarcastic
and angry during the holidays
for many years now,
but your temper
has nothing to do
with the holiday season.
Lacy, you only have
one life to live.
I believe that you need to
get out of this city
which has made you so hard.
You need to look at the big
picture in your life, Lacy,
and find what is truly missing.
- Where would I go?
- Funny you should ask.
It's a quaint little B&B
run by the Maguires
in the town of Oregon, Illinois.
I have a room
reserved for you for a week.
Go, spend Christmas there.
It's an enchanting place.
I promise you will find the
answers to all you are looking for.
Maybe even a little surprise.
Doctor?
I can't believe this.
I'm lost in the middle
of nowhere in a whiteout.
Where is this place?
Where did that storm go?
Oh, thank you very much.
Where were you
when the storm was happening?
Lacy, you need to be
around people now.
Welcome, welcome.
You must be Lacy.
Dear, you look so cold.
Can I get you some eggnog
to warm you up?
- A little toot never hurts anyone.
- Hi, hello.
No, that's not necessary. I'm actually
exhausted from the long drive.
That's a good idea, Marce.
Get us all a drink,
and then we can come and bring
our guest down here to sit
and we'll get to know
our visitor.
After all,
we promised Dr. Noelles
we'd take good care of you.
We are so lucky
Dr. Noelles sent you here.
You're our only guest
for the week.
We usually are
a packed house at Christmas.
Oh, I appreciate your hospitality.
If I could just see my room.
Oh, I hope you
like the holidays.
After all, Oregon's known
for its Christmas spectacular.
We have so many things scheduled
every day until Christmas,
and, hey, Marcy here,
she's a wonderful cook.
Especially her fruitcake.
Do you like fruitcake, Lacy?
Oh, Hank, stop teasing
the poor girl.
She looks tired from the drive.
Why don't we show her the room
so she can get some shut-eye?
You can take
your drink with you.
That's a good idea, Mar.
We do get up early
in these parts.
Early?
Yes, the room is a good idea.
Thank you both
for being so welcoming.
Now, uh, bathroom's private,
but it's at the end of the hall.
Kitchen's downstairs
in case you want anything,
however, we do all the cooking.
Oh, and, uh, breakfast,
it's when the rooster crows.
We're gonna let you be.
Come on, Hank, let's go.
We're gonna turn in ourselves.
We got a big day tomorrow.
Have a good night.
Jingle, jingle!
Deck the halls
with boughs of holly
Fa, la, la, la
Very Christmassy.
Are you smiling at me?
Creepy little elf.
Great.
I'm talking to myself again.
Wonder what's in this drink.
You've got to be kidding me.
Could
someone shut that darn bird up?!
Where's my phone?
I need to call Raymond.
I just had it,
where could it be?
Oh, please, please,
please, please.
Please don't be broken.
Call Raymond.
Call Raymond!
I could've sworn
I turned you around last night.
Creepy little elf.
I need a hot shower, my latte,
and a working cell tower.
There's gotta be one
somewhere in this hick town.
Oh, good morning, Lacy.
How did you sleep?
I hope the room
was to your liking.
Marcy, the room was fine,
if not for the crowing
that woke me up,
but the shower had no hot water.
I froze my bottom off.
Hank, are we
having hot water problems?
No, the water's
working just fine.
Ice storm knocked out
the cell towers, though,
and the landlines are down, too.
Well, the chief will be by
in a little while.
He'll let us know what's what.
He always comes by for a slice
of Marcy's fruitcake.
Hey, you should take that plate and fill
it up with some of this fine spread.
I think I'm just gonna
grab a latte in town
and try and find
some phone reception.
I'm sure my office
is trying to get a hold of me.
Oh, I'm sure they are, dear.
Listen, this'll be here
every morning for you,
so why don't you try
and relax and enjoy it?
Thanks, but I don't think
I'll be staying long.
This may have been
a mistake for me.
I-I do appreciate you both,
but I think all of this
is just a bit
too festive for me.
Being festive
is what Oregon's all about.
You shouldn't miss
the Christmas festival.
Oh, the festival
is where I found my true love.
Jingle, jingle, Lacy!
It's time to get in your
car and get your job back, Lacy.
No phone, no hot water,
this place stinks.
Come on!
What the...?
Everything all right here,
young lady?
I need to get out of here
and my car won't start.
Now why would you wanna get out of
this fine establishment so quickly?
The Maguires are some of
the finest people I know, Lacy.
I'm sorry, do I know you?
News travels fast in this here town.
I'm the chief of police.
I make it a point to know
who's coming into my town.
Kind of like
the welcome wagon, so...
welcome.
Great, uh, Chief...?
Melville,
but you can call me Brody.
Great, Brody. Um, any way you
could use your CB thinga-majigy
or walkie-talkie
to call me a mechanic?
You're in luck.
In a town this small,
I'm not only chief of police,
I'm the mechanic, too.
Please, pop your hood.
Well, Lacy, you want
the good news or the bad news?
The way my life's been going,
just hit me
with the bad news first.
Your alternator's kaput.
I can fix it, but we need to
order the part first.
How long is that gonna take?
Being it's so close
to Christmas,
if we order it now, probably
not more than a few days.
I'll call Deputy Donner
to bring the tow truck.
- Thanks, Sheriff. Thanks, Chief.
- Mm. Mm.
Why don't you give me
the good news?
Well, now...
you get to join me inside
for a slice of Marcy Maguire's
famous fruitcake.
Well, you didn't get
very far, Lacy.
Oh, Brody, how 'bout a cup
of coffee and some fruitcake?
What happened?
- My car died.
- We'll get it fixed.
She just needs a new part.
I'll order it
after I have my fruitcake.
Lacy, what can we do
to cheer you up?
I just need to get to town.
I need to check in
with my office, my friends.
That'd be Raymond, but I need to
let them know I got here safely.
Even if you get into town, I don't think
you'll have any luck with the phones.
Maybe I can get an email out? I mean,
how are you gonna order the part?
I'll order it after the phones are
back in service, obviously.
Lacy, if you need to get to town,
I'm sure Jakey can take you.
Of course,
that's a great idea, Marcy.
He'll be back any minute.
Great.
Is he the town's mayor
who just also happens to be
the town's taxi?
Hey, there.
Welcome to the Pinehill B&B.
I see you met Mom and Dad, but
they didn't tell me about you.
Lacy, this is our son Jakey.
He's headed to town to pick up
some Christmas lights.
He runs our Christmas tree farm.
Jakey, maybe you could
take her to town with you?
I'd really appreciate
a ride to town, Jakey.
It's not a problem, provided you
love the smell of Christmas trees
because the truck
is covered in pine needles.
Oh, I love the smell
of pine needles.
I just really
need to get to town.
Alrighty. Giddy up.
Oh, don't forget to pick up
the Christmas wreaths.
Hey, you gonna bring back
our special package with you?
Sure thing, Pop.
Oh, good.
That was quick.
Thanks.
So, you in a goth band?
I dress chic, unlike you,
the poster boy for Carhartt.
Okay. Well, what brings you
to town, Elvira?
I was told that to get into the
Christmas spirit, I should come here.
I wanted to leave, but my car broke
down, and no phone reception, so...
Well, I've already been there.
No cell service,
but I can definitely try to get
you into the Christmas spirit.
I'd like that, Jakey.
Is that what I should call you?
Or do you prefer Jake?
I prefer Jake.
Sounds more chic, right?
Anyway, we're here.
Stop it!
Oh, hi there, Jakey.
Where you been hiding yourself?
At the Christmas tree farm,
Rosie.
Where I always am
this time of year.
And who do we have here?
I've not seen you before.
And I know everyone.
I'm Lacy. I'm looking for
a phone or internet connection.
You're not gonna find
that anywhere, hon.
Not after that ice storm.
Listen, hon,
why don't I make you
some of my nice,
delicious Christmas glug
and a slice
of homemade pumpkin pie?
Oh, I shouldn't.
And I don't know what glug is.
Oh, it's a bit of a warm
Christmas cocktail.
You should try some,
but I'll warn you,
too much will
knock your socks off.
- It's too early for a drink.
- It's five o'clock somewhere.
Hm-hm.
Lacy, what have you got to do?
Come on, I'll get you one.
Let's get to know each other
a little better.
Come here.
I'll be back
to pick you up in a few.
You two ladies, be nice.
Especially you, Dot.
Hm?
He's right. You'll see.
You see, Lacy,
glug is like truth serum.
One sip and you'll be
crowin' like a rooster.
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
- All right.
- Cheers.
So how did you land the most
eligible bachelor in town?
Stop, I had no idea
he was eligible or a bachelor.
I just hitched a ride with him
to get to town.
I have to get back to
my life in Chicago.
There are people there
depending on me.
Raymond is depending on me.
I'm sure he's trying
to get a hold of me.
Well, I don't know
who this Raymond is,
but Jakey is a fine catch.
And we both saw the way you two
were lookin' at each other.
All the girls
in this little town
- would love to be in your place.
- Mm-hm.
Especially me.
I wasn't looking at him
in any way.
I just met him.
We definitely
have nothing in common.
Oh, I second that,
based on the way you dress.
- Okay!
- What is with my clothes?
This is very city chic.
Well, in case
you hadn't noticed,
out here we dress
Christmas chic.
Christmas chic!
Now, Lacy, Christmas
is full of surprises,
and Jake can be
your Christmas surprise.
I wish he was
my Christmas surprise.
Wrapped up in a big red bow.
It's happenin' for you.
- You are so bad, I'm tellin' you!
- No! No!
She... If you hang around
her too long...
No, it didn't happen like that.
- Yes, it did.
- Well, I see you all enjoyed the glug,
especially you, Dot.
Shh!
All right,
I hate to break this soiree up,
but I gotta get some stuff
back to the inn.
Well, tell your mom I hope she
enjoyed the pumpkin pie I sent over
- and tell her to join us next time!
- All right, you got it.
Oh!
And, Lacy,
enjoy your Christmas surprise!
Ooh! Oh, my goodness.
Miss?
Hold your horses!
Can't you see
we're busy over here?
Careful.
You must be Lacy.
Do you like fish?
What-what do you mean,
do I like fish?
I've been ice fishing all day.
This is the biggest one
I caught.
Jake, this is
the cutest little boy.
He just told me
he's been fishing all day.
Little boy?
Little boy?!
How rude are you?
I'm a ten-year-old girl!
You just probably haven't ever
seen a girl with a fish like this.
Well, maybe where I'm from,
little girls don't fish.
Out here,
little girls do fish, Lacy.
Meet my daughter, Faith.
Daughter?
Merry Christmas, Lacy.
This is what you get
for calling me a boy.
- Jingle, jingle!
- Ooh!
- Come here, you!
- Oh, how you doin'?
- Good, good.
- Did you have a fun time today?
- I did.
- Oh, catch a lot of fish?
Just like your grandpa.
Lacy...
a little bird told me
you had some glug today.
How did you like it?
Ooh, some of my eggnog
would be perfect for happy hour.
I could really use that
right about now.
Deck the halls
with boughs of holly
Fa la la la la, la la la la
'Tis the season to be jolly
You've got to be kidding me.
That bird again?
Could someone
shut that darn bird up?
Where's my phone?
I need to call Raymond.
I just had it,
where could it be?
Oh, please, not again.
Okay, little man.
Let's let Mrs. Maguire
turn you around this time.
At least my fuzzies are dry.
Please, God,
let there be hot water.
Marcy's workin' overtime.
Oh, good morning, Lacy.
How did you sleep? I hope
the room was to your liking.
Marcy, the shower
had no hot water again.
Hank, are we
having hot water problems?
No, the water's working fine.
Ice storm knocked down
the cell tower, though,
and the landlines are down, too.
Well, the chief will be by
in a little while.
He'll let us know what's what.
He always comes by for a slice of
Marcy's fruitcake in the morning.
Hey, you should take that plate
and fill it up
with some of this fine spread.
I need to go to my car.
I'm sure my office is trying to
get a hold of me by now.
I'm sure they are, dear.
Listen, this spread'll
be here every morning,
so why don't you try
to relax and enjoy it?
Hey, have a great day.
Yeah, Hank,
you told me that yesterday.
It's back. My car's back.
Everything okay here,
young lady?
Are you kidding?
You were supposed to fix my car.
Now why would you wanna get out of
this fine establishment so quickly?
The Maguires are some of
the finest people I know, Lacy.
Chief, I met you yesterday.
News travels fast
in this here town.
Now, I'm the chief of police.
I make it a point to know
who's coming into my town.
I'm kind of like
the welcome wagon, so...
welcome.
What is going on?
Chief Melville,
but you can call me Brody.
Okay, now this is
really too bizarre.
What is happening?
You're in luck.
In a town this small,
I'm not only chief of police,
I'm the mechanic, too.
Please, pop your hood.
Well, Lacy, you want
the good news or the bad news?
Forget it, let's just go inside
and get your fruitcake.
Your alternator's kaput.
Okay, the good news.
Well, now...
you get to join me inside
for a slice of Marcy Maguire's
famous fruitcake.
Well, you didn't
get very far, Lacy.
Brody, how about a cup of coffee
and some fruitcake?
- What happened?
- I'm going insane.
We'll get it fixed.
She just needs a new part.
I'll order it
after I have my fruitcake.
Lacy, what can we do
to cheer you up?
I need to get to town. I need
to get in touch with my office.
Even if you get into town, I don't think
you'll have any luck with the phones.
You already told me that, Brody.
How are we gonna order
the new part?
Well, I'll order it
after the phones
are back in service, obviously.
Lacy, if you need to
get to town,
I'm sure Jakey can take you.
Of course,
that's a great idea, Marcy.
He'll be back any minute.
When does he get here?
Hi there.
Welcome to the Pinehill B&B.
I see you met Mom and Dad, but
they didn't tell me about you.
Lacy, this is our son Jakey.
He's headed to town to pick up
some Christmas lights.
He runs our Christmas tree farm.
Jakey, maybe you could
take her to town with you?
I really need a ride
in your truck, Jakey.
It's not a problem, provided you
love the smell of Christmas trees
because the truck
is covered in pine needles.
- Oh, definitely. Let's just go.
- Giddy up.
Oh, don't forget to pick up
the Christmas wreaths.
Hey, you gonna bring back
our special package with you?
Sure thing, Pop.
So, you in a goth band?
No. Are you the town comedian?
Ouch. I'm just having fun
with you, Morticia.
So where are we
going today, Jakey?
First of all, I prefer Jake.
Secondly, I'm headed to
my Christmas tree farm.
If you're trying to get in the
Christmas spirit, it's a magical place.
I've never seen
anything magical, Jakey,
and I'm really not one
for the holidays.
All right, well,
I'll bet you
one of my mom's fruitcakes
that you'll agree with me.
I don't eat fruitcake,
but I'll take that bet.
Alrighty. Giddy up.
So this is where
you sell the trees from?
This place is pretty big
to just be supplying for Oregon.
Oh, we're actually the major supplier
for the entire Northwest region.
Every Christmas, we send the
trees out about a month before.
Ones that are for next year
are over there.
Those are the leftovers
from this year.
And about a mile that way...
you'll find the ones
for ten years from now.
You know, we've gotta
protect our ecosystem.
I never get tired of this view.
Especially at this time of year.
Yeah, this is...
this is pretty impressive.
Well, if we head this way,
I can show you the barn.
I bet you say that
to all the girls, Jakey.
No, no girls, Lacy,
not for a while now.
Don, I need your help.
I got stuck.
Faith, that is a two-person saw.
How'd you get it
that far in there?
She's short, but she's strong.
Oh, howdy, Jake.
You gonna introduce us
to your friend there?
Don, this is Lacy.
Otherwise known as
Cruella de Vil.
She makes Cruella look nice.
Okay. Enough with the clothes
jokes, cowboy. Let's call a truce.
Well, it's a pleasure
to meet you, Lacy.
And don't listen to them.
I think you look fine.
Might even be
the prettiest girl in town now.
Hey, miss, have you ever
used a two-person saw before?
I bet you haven't.
I bet you haven't cut anything
other than using scissors.
Faith, Lacy's probably never
done anything like this.
She probably doesn't wanna
get dirty, either.
Yeah, she definitely doesn't wanna
get those spiffy clothes dirty.
I'm not afraid of getting dirty.
Of course I've sawed before.
Gimme the saw.
Faith, what were you thinking?
You could have
seriously hurt someone.
It's okay. I'm-I'm fine.
Really, it's-it's all good.
I'm okay.
Kids...
you can't live with 'em
and you can't sell 'em.
She's a feisty one, isn't she?
You have any kids, Don?
Who, me? Kids? No!
I'm the town's MEB,
most eligible bachelor.
But, uh, no one's got me yet.
Let's talk about
what's really on your mind.
You mean Jake?
Okay. What's his story?
Oh, Jake's the best guy in town.
He treats everybody
like they're family.
But that poor guy...
Life has put him
through the ringer.
He had Faith and got married
right after high school.
He moved from Oregon to Chicago.
They had a nice little house
in the suburbs,
and they were very happy.
Until...
one snowy night,
his wife, Amanda...
she was killed
by a drunk driver.
His whole world was shattered.
So he brought his baby
back home to Oregon,
and it's been him and Faith
and the whole town ever since.
He's a good dad and a good man.
And we all treat his daughter
as if she's our own,
and, you know,
naturally that might be why
Faith has a little bit
of an issue with you.
She's feisty, but she's just
trying to protect her dad.
But the one thing that
little girl needs most is a mom.
Wow, I had no idea.
That's terrible.
Hey, um...
I don't know if you're up for
it, but let's take a walk.
Faith's gonna stay in there for a little
while just to collect her thoughts,
and she'll be out
to apologize soon enough.
She does not
need to apologize to me.
That was some good competition.
I needed that.
I haven't done
a double saw in forever.
Ah, you looked like a pro
out there, Lacy.
Yeah, I'll be sure
to tell my bruises that.
I want to thank you
for being so nice to me.
This time of the year
isn't usually so festive.
Yeah, well, I wanna apologize
to you about Faith.
She can get like this
with new ladies around.
Are there new ladies
around often?
No, not really.
In this town,
it's usually tourists,
and that's not anything
I'm looking for anyway.
So she can have her fun with them.
It's, uh... it's especially hard
for her around the holidays.
Yeah, Don told me what happened
to you guys. I'm so sorry.
Must be really hard
for you, too.
Look, uh, when I said that there
were no new girls, I meant it.
I was very lucky to have an
extremely special relationship
that brought me
the joy of my life.
Now I just focus on being
a good dad and a better person.
Maybe that's it for me.
I know it sounds cheesy, but...
it works for us.
Don says that you're
the best guy in town,
so I think
you're doin' pretty good.
Yeah. Thanks.
But I'm sure you noticed that Faith
is a little rough around the edges.
I'm sure she picks that up from her
number one role model being her daddy.
So what about you?
What brings a city gal
like yourself
out to Oregon, lllinois?
Well, I was told I was overworked
and unpleasant to be around,
so I was actually sent here,
as Oregon is the place to get
into the Christmas spirit.
You know, I really didn't think
I was gonna enjoy it over here,
but I have to admit,
I'm having a really nice time.
I can see why
you like it so much.
The trees are beautiful.
Each one's like a work of art.
That's my designer eye speaking.
Well, don't go
wearing flannel on me now.
Ah, I would not be
caught dead in one.
Okay, okay.
I think you could pull it off.
We'll get you a blinking light
sweater, some reindeer ears,
and a cute little elf costume.
Here, have a peppermint cupcake!
Well, now,
see how happy you look?
I told you
these trees are magical.
Especially this one.
This is the pride and joy
of Pinehill Farms.
Magic, huh?
Maybe you can find some way
to try and convince me.
I think I might
know how to do that.
Oh, Dad...
You're showing
your magic Christmas tree.
Sorry to interrupt.
I just had to apologize.
Oh, you don't have to
apologize to me, Faith.
We were just having
a friendly competition, right?
You're right.
But I still wanna say
I'm sorry, Lacy.
You look like you need to be
more in the Christmas spirit.
So I figured an early
Christmas gift would be nice.
Good work, Girdy.
I hate that rooster!
Take that, you stupid bird!
I hate the wind, too.
All right, where is my phone?
I need to call Raymond.
I just had it,
where could it be?
Hey, rooster!
Hope you're hungry!
Oh, good morning, Lacy.
How did you sleep?
I hope the room
was to your liking.
Marcy, ask Hank
about the hot water.
Hank, are we having
hot water problems?
No, the water's working fine.
Ice storm knocked down
the cell towers...
I know about the ice storm, Hank.
I need to go to my car.
Ha!
I'm going insane.
This is not possible.
How can it be the same day?
Everything okay here,
young lady?
Okay, Brody.
Why is my car still sitting here
when I need to
get out of this place?
Now why would you wanna
get out of a fine establishment
like this so quickly?
The Maguires are some of
the finest people I know, Lacy.
You're the chief, the mechanic, the
town's welcome wagon, yada, yada, yada.
Just go inside
and get your fruitcake.
News travels fast in this here town.
I'm the chief of police.
I make it a point to note
who's coming into my town.
I'm kind of like
the welcome wagon, so...
welcome!
Great, Chief. Don't worry,
I'll call you Brody.
Hi there.
Welcome to the Pinehill B&B.
Jakey, I need to
get out of here,
so just take me
wherever you're going today.
Okay, I'm game.
But you just gotta
answer me one question.
Oh, don't say it.
Goth? Beatnik? Oh, no, you're a Cure fan.
No, no, no, no.
You were headed to a poetry slam
festival, took a wrong turn,
and ended up in Christmas town.
Don't you ever listen to
a different song?
Well, I'm not picky
and besides, it's the holidays
so any Christmas song
is fine with me.
Okay, explain that!
That's a pretty good
coincidence,
considering the fact the town
has one radio station
and all the buttons
are programmed to it.
Where are you going today,
Jakey?
I'm just headed to
the town square.
Gotta pick up
my special little package.
- You mean Faith.
- Yeah, that is who I'm going to pick up.
We've got a whole day planned.
You're welcome to join us.
Oh, I will definitely join you.
That little package is just
full of surprises, isn't she?
It's about time Faith
gets a surprise.
Great. You're gonna love Faith.
La-la-la-la, la-la-la-la
La-la-la-la
Hey, it's Jake!
Oh, hey.
Sorry, I was aiming for my dad.
Let's call a truce
and get these boys!
All right, Lacy.
- Yeah!
- Get 'em, Faith!
No!
All right, all right,
cease fire, cease fire.
Ooh! All right, come on.
Let's get some hot chocolate,
on me. Come on.
- Alrighty.
- All right, I need...
- Just keep pouring 'em.
- Alrighty.
Here's one.
I want the marshmallows in it.
Marshmallows, all right.
I can't believe you're actually
having fun with me.
It looks like you
kinda like my dad.
Um, well, he seems like
a really nice guy.
You know, your dad has a quality
I've never seen
in someone before.
Does that bother you, Faith?
Because I know how much
you love your dad,
and I would never wanna
take that away from you.
You see, Lacy, it's always
just been me and my dad.
The problem is
I've seen ladies
look at my dad...
but he never looked at them
the way he looks at you.
And you don't like that,
do you, Faith?
Faith, I know you lost your mom
when you were little.
No one is ever
going to replace her.
I'm sure your mom
was an amazing lady
who loved both you
and your daddy very much.
And I'm sure she'd want you
both to be happy.
Don't you think?
Yeah, I guess so.
I just don't want
anything to change.
I like things the way they are.
Funny thing about change,
as scary as it can be sometimes,
change can be a nice surprise.
Have you ever been married,
Lacy?
Nope. Not yet.
Almost, but it didn't work out.
Were you sad
when it didn't work out?
I guess.
Is that why you wear all black?
What is it with you people
and my black clothes?
I just think it looks chic.
Well, maybe a good change
would be putting some color
into your wardrobe.
Okay, come on, you crazy girl.
Let's go rescue your dad.
We can see who can
put the most whipped cream
in their hot cocoa.
Ooh, I love whipped cream!
You're on.
I'm going over with my friends.
Hey, Lacy, if you want to know
where there's mistletoe,
it's over by
the big Christmas wreath!
Wow. You're amazing.
She hasn't taken to
anyone like that ever.
Well, I was a snowball champion
when I was little.
- Really?
- No.
I don't think I've ever
been in a snowball fight
in my entire life.
I was just trying to
survive those kids.
Well, you certainly
held your own.
They can be pretty rough.
You guys really hit it off.
She was actually smiling at you.
She actually made fun
of my clothes, too.
Yeah, yeah.
The apple doesn't fall
too far from the tree.
Clearly.
She's a good girl, though.
She's adorable.
And I don't say that about...
any kids.
So, uh...
what's your story, Lacy?
Never married, no kids,
always workin'.
How'd a beautiful girl
like yourself not get tied down?
Tied down as in married,
kids, or both?
You tell me.
Okay, here we go.
Um, I was in a relationship
for quite some time.
Blake was his name.
Both of us were always working.
You know, we were successful
and enjoying life,
and making money
and traveling together.
It was just...
It was so much fun,
but I didn't realize
how fast the time was going by.
And I started to notice
that Blake wanted more
and that he was ready
to take the next step.
I was young and brash
and completely
immersed in my career.
I told him that
marriage and kids
may not be what I wanted
in the future.
I'll never forget the look on his
face when he walked out of the room.
I never thought he would
just up and leave, but he did.
I came home from work
Christmas Eve and he was gone.
All he left
was a note that said,
"Lacy, I wanted to give you
a fresh start Christmas Day."
Well, that, uh,
certainly makes things
a little clearer for me.
A broken heart
on Christmas would...
certainly taint
the holidays for anyone.
But I personally think
that Blake is the one
who made the mistake
leaving you.
I mean,
you seem pretty happy now.
And look how you
connected with Faith.
Maybe it's time we mend
that old Grinchy heart of yours.
And how do you
expect to do that, Jakey?
Well, I've got one or two old
Christmas surprises up my sleeve.
That's funny, the reason I was told to
come here was for a Christmas surprise.
Well, what a surprise.
We're sitting under mistletoe.
Yeah, I've been told the most unforgettable
kisses happen under mistletoe.
- La, la
- La-la, la
Out jumps good old Santa Claus
Down through the chimney
with lots of toys
All for the little one's
Christmas joys
Ho, ho, ho Who wouldn't go?
We should go find Faith.
So, this is where the
Christmas festival takes place.
Yeah.
I mean, they work all year
just to set it up,
and people come from
far and wide just to see it.
You basically can't come through
the town without experiencing it.
Well, I mean,
that all sounds good,
but I don't think
I have anyone to go with.
Well, uh...
I think I can help with that.
As long as you don't mind
sharing me with another lady.
Hey, you two,
can we get something to eat?
- Yes.
- All right, come on.
So, as I was saying,
usually Faith and I
make a day of it every year.
But based on what I saw today,
I don't think Faith would mind
if you joined us tomorrow.
So what do you say, Faith?
I would be honored
to join you and Faith tomorrow.
I really want to spend the day
with you tomorrow.
The festival is so much fun.
Now let's get some food.
- Food.
- Yes!
She's so beautiful
when she's sleeping.
This is the only time
that she's quiet.
I bet.
But you really are doing
an amazing job with her.
She's quite the smart
young lady.
So, uh, you looking forward
to tomorrow?
Yes, I really am.
I think I might stick out
like a sore thumb.
Maybe I can borrow one of Faith's
light-up Christmas necklaces?
I'm sure she's got
plenty to spare.
If not, we'll just throw a big
red bow on you and call it a day.
Thank you for such
a wonderful day today, Jake.
It's been a long time
since I felt anything good
around the holidays.
I opened up to you about...
Look, you don't
need to explain, Lacy.
You know, I...
I know we've all got a past,
but it's what makes us
who we are today.
Believe me, life will
throw you some curveballs,
but it's what you
make of 'em that counts.
I'm not the same person
I was ten years ago,
and I doubt
that you are, either.
Does it seem weird
that I'm only just now
figuring out who I am and what
I want my life to look like?
I feel like I've been running
away from change for so long
that I've missed out
on something
that could have been
extraordinary.
Yeah, but change is scary.
But, you know,
if you don't embrace it,
you'll never know what extraordinary
journey you're missing out on.
I've always believed that
people come into
and out of your life
at different times
and different reasons.
As I've always said,
you've just got to have
a little faith.
Faith.
That's a good one.
I do appreciate your point,
though.
And, honestly, I've never
connected with a kid
as much as I did with her today.
Well, looks like
we got you home.
Well, you, my dear,
I will see tomorrow.
Mm-hmm.
I'll be the one
with the big red bow.
I'm sure we can
find you something
a little less noticeable.
Eh.
Ah, I've gotta get you
to try some of Rosie's glug.
Hope you're ready
to have fun tomorrow.
I'm going insane.
Now I know I'm going insane.
Lacy, you've got to
snap out of this.
This can't be real.
Christmastime is a time
of love and forgiveness.
Get over yourself, my dear.
You will
find yourself appreciating
"that sort of thing" someday.
It's time for you
to work on you.
The festival is where
I found my true love.
Lacy, enjoy
your Christmas surprise.
One thing that little girl
needs most is a mom.
You need to look at
the big picture in your life, Lacy.
That old bird is right on time.
Ooh! lt's cold.
Hmm, where is my phone?
Nice catch.
December 24th.
Twenty-three missed calls.
Lacy, it's Raymond.
Call me back
when you get this message.
Just want to make sure
you got there all right.
Hey, there,
bet you're not calling me back
because you've met someone and
finally enjoying the holidays.
Who am I kiddin'?
Just call me back.
Lacy, it's Raymond, call me back.
I really need to talk to you.
Crazy stuff going on
here at the office.
Lacy, where are you?
Call me back, it's urgent.
Nora's asking for you.
She is not happy.
Okay, Nora told me I need to be
keeping better tabs on you.
I must not be doing my job.
Well, I told her if she
hadn't told you to beat it,
she wouldn't be
in this situation.
Okay, I didn't actually say
that, but she's looking for you.
Hello, Lacy, it's Nora.
If you can call me back
as soon as possible,
I'd like to discuss
a few things with you.
I'm at the office
and I'll be about...
Time to wake up.
Cold shower, here I come.
Marcy is really
working overtime.
Hot water. Yes!
There is actually hot water!
Well, hey, creepy little friend.
Maybe you're a little cute.
No, not quite.
Oh, good morning, Lacy.
How did you sleep? I hope
the room was to your liking.
Thanks, Marcy. Yeah, I got
a good night's rest last night.
The shower finally had hot water,
it felt amazing this morning.
Oh, Lacy, a fella by the name
of Raymond called for you.
Left a couple of messages,
sounded quite urgent.
Oh, he also said you would really
enjoy this drink in the morning.
We've never heard of an iced
half-caff, four-pump, sugar-free,
cinnamon skinny
something or other.
Sounds pretty fancy to me.
Hank had to drive two towns over
just to find a place
that would make one for you.
You gotta keep
the guests happy, right, Marcy?
It's Christmastime.
Wow, thank you, Hank.
I can't believe
you would do that for me.
Mmm...
Oh, this hits the spot.
I guess my office
was worried about me
since they haven't been able
to get a hold of me
- the past couple of days.
- I'm sure they are, dear.
Listen, this spread'll
be here every morning,
so why don't you just try
and relax and enjoy it?
It all looks delicious.
To be honest,
I woke up famished this morning.
Must be all
the fresh country air.
Are you headed to
the festival today, Lacy?
I was planning on it
since I heard it was
the event of the year
in this town.
Maybe I'll get a few ideas
for future projects.
Only trouble is I don't think
I have the right outfit for it.
Well, maybe we can
help you with that.
Marcy's got so many of those
Christmas sweaters around this house,
I'm sure we can find something
that'll suit you just fine.
I know just the one,
it'll fit you perfectly.
Go, go, go.
- Well, hello, folks.
- Oh, Brody, come in.
Just stopping in for my jet fuel
and that delicious fruitcake.
Who's ready
for the big day today?
Well, we were
just talking about that.
Uh, Marcy's helping Lacy here.
She's gonna get out of
those city clothes, finally.
Well, good for you.
We can't have you going into
our festival wearing all black.
Not that there's anything wrong
with that, but you'll see.
Here we dress what you city folk
might call "Christmas chic."
I've heard that
from someone before.
I brought your sporty
little car back, Lacy.
Ooh, she's fast.
It's as good as new, though.
Oh, um, great.
Well, I thought
you'd be thrilled.
I mean, I worked overtime on it.
You said you had to
get back to the city.
No, I-I do. You're right.
Thank you, Brody.
Lacy,
your festival outfit awaits!
Go, go, go!
- Shall we?
- Let's.
Drumroll, please!
I'm proud to present
the honorary queen
of the Oregon Festival!
Well! Look at you.
You're pretty enough
to be on a Christmas card.
Everything fit her perfectly.
I still got it.
Well, that sweater looks like
it was made just for you.
It really does fit perfectly.
I hope it looks okay.
Well, well, well.
Look what we have here.
Somebody's ready to hit the
festival, wouldn't you say, Faith?
You look pretty, Lacy.
I want you to wear this.
We can be matchers.
Thanks, Faith.
I don't think I've ever owned
anything like this before.
Do you think I'll fit in?
I think you look perfect.
I think red's your new black.
You're still a big city gal
to me, Lacy.
Well, I think we are all ready
for the festival.
Let's go have some fun.
Giddy up, Faith.
Remember, bein' festive
is what Oregon's all about.
Lacy, you forgot your drink.
Yuck, this is gross!
What is this?
It's an acquired taste, Faith.
Bye, Grandma.
Jingle, jingle!
- Merry Christmas, Jake.
- Merry Christmas.
Hey, Lacy.
I'm going over with my friends,
but I want you to know,
I'll be thinking about you.
Well, if you need to find me,
just look for
the blinking lights.
- I am one lucky dad.
- You are the best dad.
You don't sound
so committed to that.
I love her, she's my daughter.
Lacy!
We told you'd land the most
eligible bachelor in town!
Too bad, Jakey. I could've
been all yours!
- Okay, girl!
- Whoo!
It's true.
So, is this too Christmassy
for your all-black
designer world?
Stop! No, I think
it's absolutely beautiful.
I can completely see why this
takes a full year to set up.
Well, don't go
stealin' our ideas now.
We've got patents
on all these designs.
And if I do steal them,
what you gonna do about it?
Well, I might just have to lock you
up for a long time and keep you here.
Does that sound so bad?
Oh, I don't know.
I guess I could
make the best out of it.
Just so I don't have to dress like
Santa's little helper every day.
Hmm...
How are you two kids
enjoying this magnificent day?
Can't say it could've
turned out any better.
Don, you always have
such perfect timing.
Well, you know I like to
make my presence known.
- And you look ravishing, my dear.
- Oh, why, thank you. So do you.
That's the only way this old
fool can kiss a girl anymore.
Mistletoe doesn't even
work for him.
He's gotta blind 'em
with his tie.
Stop it.
All right, well,
let's go get some
of Rosie's famous glug.
All right,
you better be careful.
One glug is one too many.
Oh, believe me, I know.
What are you two
squawkin' about?
Dot is saying that her Yule log
is better than
your mom's fruitcake.
My Yule log is so much better,
I don't have to put "famous"
in front of it.
Well, my fruitcake is "famous"
because it's won awards
in three separate counties.
I'd take the fruitcake
over the Yule log.
That's convenient,
you're her husband.
- Well, you're her best friend.
- Yeah.
You two, weigh in.
I plead the fifth.
Oh, um, well, unfortunately,
I haven't had Yule log
or fruitcake before.
We didn't have
Christmas treats in my house.
This is perfect.
Lacy has never had
either of these, ever.
She will judge the winner!
Oh, I...
Why does she get both?
Well, Faith, Lacy has never had
Yule log or fruitcake,
so she's gonna try
Grandma's fruitcake
and Dot's Yule log
and decide which is best.
Faith, please help me eat these.
No way. With these crazy
ladies, you're on your own.
Thanks, Faith.
Okay, everyone,
I will do my best,
but please don't
hold it against me.
Oh, it's so good.
So creamy and smooth.
Oh, this texture's
just like tiramisu.
You need to clean your palate
before you taste mine, Lacy.
It's chewy.
There's some fruit,
there's a cherry.
And... there's a nut.
Oh, can I have
some more glug, please?
Lacy, it's an acquired taste.
I think we know
who the winner is.
Now, now,
I've got my Christmas treats.
Who wants some of my homemade
caramel and candy apples?
I love candy apples!
I'll have one.
Caramel apples are way better.
Okay, how about my favorite?
Christmas fudge,
nuts or no nuts?
- Nuts. Mm-hmm, yeah.
- Nuts. Nuts.
Looks like you're gonna be
needed a bit more.
I think my favorite
Christmas treat is you.
Who's that?
Nora? Raymond?
What-what are you doing here?
Lacy, we've been trying
to get a hold of you for days.
Oh, ice storm
took down the lines.
They've been down a few days.
Just went back up today.
I'm, uh, Jake Maguire.
My parents, Marcy and Hank.
They own the B&B that Lacy's
staying at here in town.
Everyone, this is my boss, Nora,
and my associate, Raymond.
We work together back in Chicago
at the design firm.
Would you like to try
some of my famous fruitcake?
How about a plate of the Yule
log that just won the taste test,
- according to Lacy?
- She did not pick yours.
I have candy
and caramel apples for you.
Oh, do you like fudge
with nuts or without?
I'll bring you two mugs of glug.
No, thank you.
No, thank you, sir, thank you.
I don't do fruitcake.
There's drinks
here or something?
Lacy, I made a mistake.
Jenna has made a mess
of our two largest accounts.
Well, she admitted to me
that she stole your designs.
She couldn't
come up with anything.
And now those two clients
say that they will walk away
unless you come back
and head their accounts again.
I made a mistake, but my mistake
was not listening to Jenna,
it was not promoting you
to partner.
Now, don't let
my little mishap with Jenna
deter you from what
is rightfully yours.
Lacy, just say yes!
This is what
you've always wanted.
I am so honored and flattered
that you came
all this way to say this to me.
I know you, you wouldn't
do this for just anyone.
Lacy, are you gonna leave us?
Please, don't go.
If you had asked me this
two weeks ago,
I would've
jumped at the opportunity.
I was so ready for it.
I was anticipating it,
and I was so furious
when it didn't happen.
I lost part of myself
and what I needed in life.
I met someone wonderful
who told me that certain people
come in and out of your life
for different reasons.
And I need to believe that.
I wanna start living my life
and being happy.
So...
as much as I would love
to accept your amazing offer,
I have to decline.
But, Lacy, you're willing to
just give up on your dream?
I wouldn't say that.
I think that people's dreams
can change,
and I think I want
to start sharing mine.
This stuff is fabulous!
Such a distinct taste,
I could drink it all day.
Nora, I do have one
recommendation for the company.
My replacement
should be Raymond.
- Raymond?
- Me?
Yes, Raymond, you.
Nora, I've never worked with
anyone so talented.
Our clients know Raymond
and they love him.
I can't imagine anyone else better
suited to take lead than Raymond.
Well, Raymond,
we don't have much time.
We need to
get back to the office
and hammer out the kinks
that were created by
you know who.
I just wish it could have
turned out slightly different.
Thank you so much for everything
you've done for me.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, Lacy.
Lacy, are you sure
this is what you want?
Raymond, the craziest thing has
been happening since I got here.
I feel like I've been living the
same day over and over again,
but it made me realize that I
have a second chance at true love.
A Christmas surprise.
How many times
have I been telling you that?
Wait a minute,
you don't like surprises.
Who is he, okay?
Not that Deputy Don character.
No.
Okay! Stud alert!
Good for you, Lacy.
Merry Christmas, you guys.
Be nice to my friend.
Little word of advice,
she hates surprises.
Hey, everyone, I'd like to get
some glug to go if possible.
It was so good!
Nice to meet you all.
Truly a pleasure to meet you.
- Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas!
Does this mean
you're staying, Lacy?
Well, I don't know if you heard
what just happened here,
but I don't actually have a job
to go back to anymore.
So I was hoping you'd be willing
to let me spend Christmas with you.
Now, Faith,
no more tricks, right?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Merry Christmas, Lacy.
Well, I don't suppose
you heard all that.
Yeah, you could say that.
Well, it's out there now,
and it's pretty awkward,
but the truth is they're right.
I haven't been much fun to be around
at Christmas for a long time now,
but you, Faith,
and this crazy, crazy town
have helped me find myself again
and really believe in Christmas.
I can't tell you what's been
happening since I got here,
but yesterday we just had
the most amazing day together
and I didn't want it to end.
I was so worried I'd wake up and
you and Faith wouldn't be here.
And then there was
this reindeer,
and you and Faith
covered in gold.
And then I woke up again,
and I-I know I'm not making
a lot of sense right now,
but the point is,
I finally figured out
what my Christmas surprise is
and it's all
that matters to me now.
You and Faith are my
Christmas surprise, Jake.
Well... I'm glad that
you figured that out
because you're our
Christmas surprise, too, Lacy.
You know, Jake, I'm gonna need one
more Christmas surprise from you.
What's that?
I'm gonna need you to kiss me
under that mistletoe again.
Yep, that's me.
Merry Christmas, Lacy.
Merry Christmas, Jake.
Merry Christmas to all,
and to all a good night!
Well, Lacy finally
got her Christmas surprise.
She may have repeated
a few days to find it,
but the Christmas spirit
will always find you.
And in Lacy's case, she found
love through Christmas do-overs,
eventually figuring out that life
is always filled with surprises.
Embracing them enabled her
to find what she was missing.
Lacy found her true love and she
was gifted the love of a child.
That's the ultimate
Christmas surprise.
Deck the halls
with boughs of holly
Fa la la la la, la la la la
'Tis the season to be jolly
Don we now our gay apparel
Fa la la la la, la la la la
Troll the ancient Yuletide carol
Deck the halls
with boughs of holly
Fa la la la la, la la la la
'Tis the season to be jolly
Don we now our gay apparel
Fa la la la la, la la la la
Troll the ancient Yuletide carol
I love everything
about Christmas.
Fast away the old year passes
Fa la la la la, la la la la
Hail the new year
lads and lasses
Fa la la la la, la la la la
Sing we joyous all together
Heedless of the wind and weather
Fa la la la la, la la la la