Stop
Sir, would you like a room?
I need a couple of deluxe rooms,
could you show me?
Yes, please
Are you alright?
Yes
Nanny, help the Mistress in to have
some rest
Yes
You go to your room first
Put it upstairs
Yes
Brother, don't mind me saying this
you knew the journey would be difficult
and bringing along family is inconvenient
I have no choice
Since I married your sister-in-law
she hasn't returned home
Her home happens to be enroute
as we escort the goods
Ying Qi too might as well have
a reunion with grandpa
However we haven't used this road
for a long time
and we're escorting
a million taels of silver this time
It's best to be cautious
Sincere apologies
if I've lacked in my services
So it's chief Han
No... I retired long ago
just running a small business here
Please bear with the humble service
Waiter
Yes
Bring us food and wine
I want to drink to my heart's content
with security chief Fang... its my treat
Thanks, that's not necessary
I can still afford to be the host
If you refuse
I'll assume that you give me no face
It'd be my pleasure then
That's more like it
Chief Fang
what goods are you escorting this time?
Money for refugees along the Yellow River
With your fame as the Iron Arm
who'd dare to do anything?
You needn't take the trouble yourself
You're too kind
Overflowing of the river has made
many refugees suffer
I am just doing my part
I respect you, it's good fortune that
we meet today
Let me raise you a toast
Chief Han, brother Fang has said that
the refugees
are still suffering & await our money;
It isn't likely that he'd be
in a mood to drink
Instead, let's drink on our return
You don't appreciate our respect
I fear you will have no way out
What do you want?
Leave the money, or else
don't even think of it
How much more?
Almost done
Ying Qi...
Dad, I'm scared
Let's go
Ying Qi...
Come
Girl, your kung fu's accomplished,
come down
Teacher, I've brought food
to go along with your wine
Ying Qi, come here
You want to go downhill, right?
Teacher, you said Han Shi Xiong
is still alive?
This fellow
has not shown his face for years
Even if he's dead I still want to
desecrate his corpse
I support your departure
but the time is not yet ripe for revenge
The Jins are invading our country
The officials
are cowards and think only of
their welfare
We martial artists
should not just stand by and
let this happen
I want to serve my country
even if it means death
Good
But this matter
is not one that could be tackled alone
You take this letter
to the Flying Dragon Fortress
in Da Kun Mountain
and find Lord Xia
He is gathering heroes
to re-establish our country
Give him the letter and he'll know
what to do
The letter is important
so keep it well
Never lose it to the hands of villains
Don't worry
"Yi On Inn"
Excuse... sir, inside please
Welcome
Upstairs please
Is this room acceptable?
It will do
Please leave your name
Thanks
Excuse me, how far is it to the
Da Kun Mountain?
It's about 20 miles ahead
Master Wu has asked you to give this pill
to Chief Ba Shan
There's a secret message inside
listing the names of generals
guarding the frontier
and the strength of their troops
We are waiting for his further
instructions
I will give it to him the soonest I can
It's top secret, be careful
Don't worry... it's not the first time
This is a reward from Master Wu
We'll divide it equally
Good...
Boss, there are many beggars outside
Would the beggars' gang be
causing trouble again?
Could our plan to help Master Wu
to contact with Jins have been exposed?
I'll leave first
Inform me of chief Ba Shan's reply
the moment you've it
Master Yan, wait
it's better to take the back door
Alright
Hey, are you people all dead? Come on out
What's up... stay calm
Pal, you want to eat?
Have a seat, my treat
Good
In that case
we'll come everyday
Good
Let's just pretend it's my birthday
Really? My heartiest congratulations then
But I am not eating today, I need a room
Treating you to a meal is not a problem
but as regards a room...
What, am I not eligible
if I'm dressed up like this?
Look what this is
Enough for a night?
Yes... it's rather too much... waiter
Yes
Lead this guest to a room
Yes, this way please
Sir, this room please
I want this one
Sorry, it's been taken
No way, I must have it
Can't you ask him to move out?
How can I? He was here first
I don't care, just ask him to leave
No
I could move
but someone wouldn't agree to that
Who?
My sword
Want to fight? That's easy, come on
Search his room
Oh, so it's a beautiful lady;
but what a pity for her to be with him
Mr. Wei, take a look
Look what this is?
"Han Shi Xiong"
How did Han Shi Xiong's dagger
end up with her?
It's likely that his enemies caught up
with him
Then let's kill her first
"Fang Ying Qi"
Fang Ying Qi
Are you using the Ice Steel Sword?
You admit defeat, right?
Who are you?
None of your business
Lady, you look so desperate
Alright. Here, I'll return the letter
to you
This is the flying dagger you used
20 years ago
I'm wondering why would the girl have it?
What is that girl's name?
Fang Ying Qi
I suspect she's Fang Ning's descendant
We slaughtered everyone of the
Fang family that year
how could there be any descendant?
Maybe one of them got away
According to the waiter at Yi On Inn
she's headed for Da Kun Mountain
Tong Ming, get rid of her
Actually, I was thinking of the same thing
Let's do it quickly
I'll leave first
Changing my name to Cai Yi
I am now a spy at Da Kun Mountain
Last night Xia Zi Long urgently
asked me over
to discuss something important
You rest assured and just leave
I'll take care of that girl. Farewell
Go
Miss, why are you being so unreasonable?
You stole my dagger,
why should I reason with you?
Whoa, whoa... I stole your flying dagger?
You know what you did
Nonsense, it's you who injured my brothers
I have yet to get even with you
I simply can't accept the fact that
you bully people
You don't know good from bad
What are you talking about?
Go back to your room and
take a look, you'll know
Miss, don't sleep tonight
Beware, someone might ambush you
Shoot
I'll deal with them
May I have your name?
I am head of the Beggars' Clan,
Qin Shang Yi
My respects. I am Fang Ying Qi
on teacher's orders to go to
Da Kun Mountain
I know
You do?
I read your letter yesterday
and know you're a righteous heroine
So I protected you secretly on the way
I am in your debt
Since we are on the same side
you needn't stand on ceremony
You really never took my flying dagger?
No, I fear it has been
retained by Wei Tong Ming
What is he like?
He is a traitor
I parleyed with him yesterday
in order to get evidence of his treason
I almost mistook him for a good guy...
so stupid of me!
Miss Fang, appearances deceive
You ought to be careful all the time
That's really a good advice
I'll always remember it
Where's our big brother?
Over there...
Miss Fang, there's still 20 miles
to Da Kun Mountain
You'd better set off earlier
Alright
Let me see you off
No need. Brother Qin, see you later
Be careful then
"Flying Dragon Fortress"
I've got reports
that Wu Chang Sheng
bribed corrupted officials
to obtain confidential news and
play traitor with Jins
That's why I invite you all here
for a discussion
Wu Chang Sheng is rich and powerful
Seeing the Jin army's prowess
and fearing for his assets
he ingratiates the Jins
and chief Ba Shan
He is bent on selling the country
for his own advantage
Our Flying Dragon clan
is committed to ridding our country
of traitors
Now that we've confirmed
Wu Chang Sheng is a traitor
we should get rid of him
Right
Chief Cai is right
But Wu Chang Sheng's Black Wind Fort
has lots of good fighters, and he has also
solicited the aid of many
villainous mercenaries
It wouldn't be easy to get rid of him
You needn't let his
power diminish your confidence
You...
Please, stop quarrelling
this is not the time to argue
We mustn't land ourselves in a
disadvantageous position
& should devise a plan to get rid of
Wu Chang Sheng
That's what we need to do today;
to find a way to go against Wu Chang Sheng
My lord, someone requests to see you
Priest Xuan Zhen, please invite him
at once
Yes
He's here
That's great, he could give us a hand
We are now stronger than ever
Look who's here
It's a girl
This is Lord Xia
My respects, I am Fang Ying Qi
You are?
I am priest Xuan Zhen's student
this is a letter for you from him
What about priest Xuan Zhen?
Being old and feeble
he has sent me instead
to receive your orders
Great...
Since you are his best student
I guess you must have learnt a lot
from him
Please demonstrate some of your skills
What do you all think?
Great, it's a wonderful idea
I will comply with your wish
Please give me your valued guidance
Great...
Very good...
Thank you...
Indeed a great master trains
great students
You're too kind
You must be tired
please go and rest
Thank you
Escort Miss Fang to take a rest
Yes
Please
I'll take my leave
Lord Xia, Miss Fang's skills are marvelous
and is indeed a top student of the priest
Right...
I want to send her to assassinate
Wu Chang Sheng
I think she'll surely succeed
What do you think?
Attack
Chase
Use more power and come up
Go ahead, I'll cover your back
Mount your horse, quick
Let's rest here
Thanks for your help, what's your name?
Oh, Brother Qin, it's you
Wu Chang Sheng harms the country
and people
I have been wanting to kill him
I have been impersonating a time keeper
and been waiting for the right opportunity
but I haven't been able to sneak in
Today I saw them lay many traps
and planted ambush everywhere
Something is bound to happen tonight
I didn't expect it would be you
Did you throw the tiles
in the alley to warn me just now?
However, you didn't take heed
and almost got killed
You have once again risked your life
to save me
I really don't know how to thank you
Please don't misunderstand me
I didn't do it for this reason
To know a friend like you
is my good fortune
You flatter me
I hope that one day amity would
prevail in this country
so we can establish a restful home
and enjoy a peaceful life
I am a beggar
and sort of used to a tough life
and hunger
A good life is alien to me
Why are you going to Black Wind Fort?
This was an order from Da Kun Mountain
That's strange, could there be a spy?
How so?
They know Black Wind Fort
is heavily guarded
why would they send you there all alone?
Besides, Wu Chang Sheng
seemed to know in advance
you were going there
Right
Whose idea was it?
I hear it was Cai Yi's
Cai Yi?
I see
Lord Xia, you still haven't rested
Ying Qi has not returned
how could I be at rest
Same as I
If anything happens to her
how could I face priest Xuan Zhen?
It's almost dawn,
I think she may have failed
Mr. Cai, please give the orders
Gather all men before dawn
and attack Black Wind Fort
We must save Ying Qi
No need
Ying Qi
Master Cai, I am back
You had me worried sick
It seemed Wu Chang Sheng was prepared
and fighters were hidden everywhere
I had no chance to go in
Are you hurt?
I was surrounded
and broke through with much effort
Though I did not accomplish my mission
I managed to snatch their flag
to cheer up our spirits
Am I right? Master Cai
Yes... you are great
Ying Qi, take a rest first
I'll take my leave then
You should rest too
Yes
What? Fang Ying Qi survived?
That's unexpected
Maybe it's not yet time for her to die
Her kung fu is really good
Even Qin Shang Yi was no match for her
He fought with her?
They came to know each other through
a fight
Just pure chance
but now they are the best of friends
Right, we'll use their relationship
to kill her
Someone's coming
Take a look quickly
Don't move, what are you doing here?
Why are you behaving suspiciously?
I am looking for Miss Fang Ying Qi
He must be a spy, bring him to Lord Xia
I am no spy
What do you want with miss Fang?
Our Chief Qin has asked me
to deliver a letter to her
Where's the letter?
I must give it to her in person
Nonsense, hand it out
Miss Fang is here
Miss Fang, this person is looking for you
For me?
Our Chief Qin has asked me
to deliver a letter to you
These food supplies will be delivered
to the Jins
They will be delivered to
the frontier in 4 carriages
via Ba Xian Mountain straight to Ku Peak
Unfortunately I don't have the
manpower to rob it
How dare Wu Chang Sheng
deliver groceries to the Jins!
Damn it
Wu Chang Sheng would bring sorrow
to the people
That means
we must get hold of his rations
and not let it fall into the hands of Jins
That's right...
Miss Fang, is the news reliable?
Definitely, you need not worry about it
Tomorrow is the eighth day of the month
We'll bring some men to lay ambush
and crush them head on
Alright, tomorrow we'll go
separate ways in 5 teams
The first team will be led by Lord Fei
and intercept them at the south
of Ba Xian Mountain
The second team will be led by
Lord Gong Sun
and intercept them at the west
of Ba Xian Mountain
Attack
We have suffered great losses this time
because we were not discreet enough
The enemies knew of our plan beforehand
and took precautions
Does it mean we have a traitor amongst us?
I knew from the very start
that the news was fake
Miss Fang, I don't understand
why did you do that,
what's your intention?
What do you mean?
Lord Fei, you suspect
there's a traitor among us
I think the traitor is right
in front of us here
Chief Cai, what proof do you have?
Proof?
Lord Xia, will you please go
and search her room
Maybe you'll find something out
Alright, let's go
Wait, you want to search my room...
with pleasure
Chief Cai
But what if you can't find anything?
Then it'll be my stupidity
and I'm willing to be punished
Really?
Yes, and no regrets. Go
Search
Yes
A traitor should be
sentenced to death, take her
Ying Qi, speak whatever you have to say
Lord Cai, what's your intention
in doing this?
Take her away
Go
Wait, I don't deal underhandedly
The truth will be out one day
Hurry and chase
Brother Wai, you are here
Is your manager here?
He... he's inside...
Sir, have a seat inside
Sir, this way please
What would you like to eat?
A catty of wine, a dish of spicy meat
How come he's not here yet?
There're too many people here
Let's talk inside
Coming, it's yours
Yan Ji Jiang is not here yet?
No, what happened?
Chief Ba Shan's letter came
a few days late
Wu Chang Sheng is very anxious
Could something have happened
to Yan Ji Jiang enroute?
I don't think so
Yan Ji Jiang isn't a careless person
I must attend to some business
at Shan Yang Province
and will be back in 10 to 14 days
If Yan Ji Jiang comes,
give the confidential letter to Master Wu
I will, don't worry
I'll be off then
"Green Station"
Master Yan, you are here again
Yes, is business good?
Not bad... have a seat please...
Alright
Have some tea and rest. Waiter,
bring some tea
Yes, coming
Master Yan, have some tea
Alright
Master Yan is such a busy man
and has to be here two or three times
a month
Well, one has to make a living... no choice
He's Yan Ji Jiang
Thank you
Butterflies & bees visit
flowers blossoming in spring
they are like lovers who cling to
each other
Strolling along a flowery path
soothed by gentle breeze
The declining days of spring
cannot be retained
what is in your heart that cannot be said?
Great
Not bad
Thank you
Good, good
"From Yan Ji Jiang"
Yan Ji Jiang? How come he's here?
Where's he?
He's waiting at the courtyard
Greetings to Lord Wu
Brother Ji Jiang, we've never met
but have already developed
a spiritual nexus with you
Why have you come personally this time?
I...
These are my trusted men
Do speak whatever's on your mind
I am under orders from chief Ba Shan
to deliver a letter to lord Wu
And the letter?
Why didn't you send it to me
through Wei Tong Ming?
The roads weren't safe and
so I was delayed for 2 days
Only after getting here I realised
Brother Tong Ming has gone to
the Shan Yang Province
Being an important task, I came myself
Wei Tong Ming has gone to
the Shan Yang Province?
Yes, his family is there
He said he'll return in about half a month
Make yourself at home,
I'll take my leave now
Please
How long would you stay this time?
Chief Ba Shan has ordered
if there's anything lord Wu
would like me to do
I'll try my best effort
You're too kind...
I have a letter that you could give
to Chief Ba Shan
Please stay here for a few days
Sorry to bother you
Come, men
Yes
Escort master Yan
to the east chamber to rest
Yes
Please
Thank you
Come, men
Yes
Please invite lord Cai here
for a discussion
Yes
What can I do for you, Master Wu?
I have received an order
from Chief Ba Shan
and he has decided to launch attack
next month
and we've been given
till the end of this month
to exterminate the gang
at Da Kun Mountain
How should we go about it?
Da Kun Mountain has a lot of
kung fu experts
I don't think
we could do it this easily
That's why I need your advice
I've an idea; it's my birthday day
after tomorrow
Under the pretext of celebrating this,
Xia Zi Long must come as a guest
At that time we could then
corner them and kill them all
Good idea
I will hide with Bas brothers
near Cai's Residence and await
your orders to ambush them
Right, when Xia Zi Long and his men arrive
we'll fire signal, what do you think?
Great plan, let's do it
I'll send out the invitations today
You have thought of a good plan
As long as the Jins can succeed
in their attack
you and I will enjoy endless riches
Han Shi Xiong, you are so sly
Let's do our parts, I'll leave now
Farewell
Lord Wu
Brother Ji Jiang, your visit is timely
Stay at my place for a few more days
I guarantee I'll have good news
for chief Ba Shan
Lord Wu, wasn't that Han Shi Xiong?
Yes, you know him?
Of course
Not only is he an old friend
of the family's
my late parents were indebted to him
What a good fortune we meet again
It must be fate
so I could repay him
To show such gratitude
you are indeed a gentleman
But perhaps there's something that
you don't know
20 years ago Han Shi Xiong
was a well-known bandit
He teamed up with Wei Tong Ming
and made his fame everywhere by
using a flying dagger
He has became our informant
in these 2 years
I have heard you are shrewd and capable
and I respect you a lot
You're too kind
I ought to make a move
Tong Ming, you're back?
Didn't you say you'd be back
10 days later?
I hung around the Shan Yang Province
for 2 days
and as soon as I finished my affairs,
I returned
Lord Wu, who was that?
I seem to have seen him somewhere before
I just can't place him
You're dumb, he is Yan Ji Jiang
What? He is Yan Ji Jiang?
Yes, you must be sick
not to recognise your old friend
Of course I know Yan Ji Jiang
But I'm sure he isn't
Who is he? An impostor?
Lord Wu, keep it low
so as not to alert him
Let's play along with him
and see what his plans are
Spare some change, sir
I want to see your Chief Qin Shang Yi
do you know where he is?
Go
Waiter...
Coming... what would you like?
A chicken, meat, fish in vinegar
a bowl of spicy soup and 50 dumplings
Can you finish them?
3 catties of wine too
A chicken, meat, fish in vinegar
a bowl of spicy soup and 50 dumplings
You didn't pay yet
I don't have money
Madam, something like that
just isn't done!
What's the matter...
She ate but refuses to pay
What?
She didn't pay for the meal
Don't you know who I am
How dare you, you must be tired of living
Please have pity on me
It won't happen again
Not that easy, hey, beat her up
Get up...
Again
Stop, have mercy on her
Stop beating
You all are beating up an old woman
it's not a hero's deed
If she can't pay, I'll pay for her
Is that enough?
Yes...
Take it
Thank you... let her go...
It's alright
Are you hurt?
This old woman is so pitiful
We'll take her to Big Brother
I didn't expect it was you
Otherwise how could
I find you
Miss Fang, how clever you are
It's no big deal
but too bad we had to drag
the boss into this
and cause him to lose some money
You must have some urgent matters
I've found out Wu Chang Sheng
conspired with Cai Yi
On the pretext of celebrating birthday
they'll lure Lord Xia to the feast
Then they'll ambush him
and kill all his men
Why don't you go to Da Kun Mountain
and warn Lord Xia?
Cai Yi accused me of being a traitor
How can I go to the Da Kun Mountain?
Brother Qin, the reason
I looked for you today is
to request you to convey the message
to Lord Xia
Alright, you go back first,
I'll go tonight
I'll contact you tomorrow night, see you
Come back
You have your tricks, but I have mine
Miss Fang, you have nowhere to run
Catch her
Wait
Attack
Thank you for coming, have a seat...
Brother Chai, come...
Congratulations...
Have a seat...
Chief Cai, my greetings to you
Have a seat please
Many happy returns
Lord Wai, please
Lord Wai
Any instructions from Master Wu?
Go as planned
I've also brought you good news
Fang Ying Qi and Qin Shang Yi
have all been captured
Tonight, you can carry out your plan
at ease
Good
Master, let me go, I'm innocent
Stop shouting...
Let go of me, damn
Damn you
Why isn't he here yet?
Could there be any plan change?
Master
Master, Lord Xia Zi Long arrives
Invite him in
Yes
Lord Xia
Congratulations...
It's your 50th birthday,
what a jolly celebration
Thank you all for coming, please
Master
Tell them to launch the fireworks
Yes
Attack
"Longevity"
Oh, it's you
Wei Tong Ming, twenty years ago
you and Han Shi Xiong
killed my whole family, didn't you?
No...
It was Han Shi Xiong who did it
You traitor
Even if I spared you
other people won't
I'll cut you up into pieces
Watch me
It's beautiful
Bravo...
Lord, excuse me for a second
Please
Have a seat please
Master, Lord Wu Chang Sheng has
sent you a present
Bastard, I don't know Wu Chang Sheng
how come he has sent me a present?
Get lost
The present is here
I don't want to look at it, throw it away
Yes
Wait
Let me see
A human head!
What's going on?
Lord Xia, he's the traitor
Bull shit, who are you?
How dare you accuse me
Come, grab her
Yes
Anyone who comes close will die
Ying Qi, it's you
Cai Yi is just his alias
He's the renowned and wicked robber
Han Shi Xiong
Conspiring with Wu Chang Sheng,
he used festivities
to lure you to come
and capture you all
to obtain favour from Chief Ba Shan
Lord Xia, you've almost fallen
into his trap
Bull shit
What proof do you have for saying so?
Wu Chang Sheng has brought his men
to offer help
We've destroyed them all
This head is the proof
Han Shi Xiong, you are
such a monster
Traitors deserve to be killed, attack
Master, catch the sword
Han Shi Xiong,
today is your 50th birthday;
and it's going to be the day you die
Kill