1776.
The British colonies of America
revolted against the crown.
Under a very young American
flag, which still has 13 stars,
those who are called rebels,
fiercely fighting for
their independence.
But a powerful and
organized British army
American General Washington
can oppose only the militia -
poorly equipped and poorly trained.
Catastrophically there is not
enough weapons, food, clothes.
Despite the courage and enthusiasm,
the insurgents pursue
defeats and setbacks,
and many of them have
already been exterminated.
- Ephraim Patnam!
- Missing!
- James Thomas Hight!
- Fight Halston!
- It's gone!
- Jonathan Mitchell!
- Killed for freedom!
But the desire to win
has not gone anywhere.
The young nation, led by its leader Washington,
was giving birth to its first heroes.
Nathan Hale,
convicted of treason...
and sentenced
to death by hanging.
Nathan Hale, do you want to
say something before the execution?
Yes!
I'm sorry that I have only one
life to give it for my Motherland.
Bring the sentence to execution!
However, in the evenings
after some battles,
Washington felt like
overwhelming responsibility.
Heavy pressure on his strong
shoulders the former farmer.
Lord, give me strength,
to withstand all these
troubles and cruelties.
Lord, support the faith
in me of my compatriots
and help us achieve peace.
Forgive me, sir, your presence
in the General Staff is required.
General Washington.
My name is Saylis Dean, sir.
Hello, sir.
Do you want to sit down?
Thank you sir.
General Washington,
Congress is sending me to France.
Mr. Benjamin Franklin, of course -
their official representative.
My work is the purchase of weapons, ammunition
and the recruitment of officers for the army.
So, as you can see, my task -
more in the shadows... inconspicuous.
May God help you
in your endeavors, sir!
If there is a country that can help us, -
this is France.
They said that our business
there is very supportive.
But...
Did Congress send you
to me with this good news?
No.
No, I came to you of my own free will.
I would be very surprised.
These gentlemen do not
know the rules of courtesy.
It's much better to have a people
on your side, not its representatives.
And the people are on your side, sir.
Mr. Dean,
Tell me, in France, that the
situation here can not be worse.
But also tell them...
without a fleet,
officers, without weapons,
provisions...
We will fight to the end!
God willing!
LAFAYETT.
"LA FAYETT"
In Paris, in the famous
tavern "Wooden Sword",
gathered a brilliant noisy youth,
carried away with new ideas.
Now it's your turn,
my dear marquis!
Thank you. You have discouraged
me from drinking, dear Count.
Gentlemen!
Taking advantage of the freedom
of opinion that is so dear to us,
I declare that the Marquis de La
Fayette, who is so bold on the tongue,
not so strong in two other things:
In wine and in women!
No more than one glass,
no more than one woman!
His wife is charming, but
she is still a child!
Challenge accepted!
He drinks! He drinks!
Bottoms Up! Bottoms Up!
He drank it!
This must be washed!
Gentlemen, good evening!
I brought you a gift from our
friend, Benjamin Franklin.
Portrait of the army commander of the rebels,
General George Washington in his youth!
Bravo!
Long live America!
Uh, no! No! It's impossible!
I have already allowed you and your friends
to hang here Rousseau, Diderot and Voltaire!
Writers do not care about the police. But
not the general! I will have problems!
Silence, friend!
The golden words of our innkeeper!
Thank God, the idiot police
is not afraid of writers.
But do not be writers -
there would be no generals!
The pen offers - the sword does!
The place of General Washington - between
Jean-Jacques Rousseau and Mr. Voltaire.
Let there and remains. Freedom!
Mr. Marquis, you know that every evening spies
come here, disguised as petty bourgeoises.
Because of you they will
throw me into the Bastille!
I'll go with you and ask for
the same camera as you.
"Er, no, listen..."
- Equality!
Friends! Raise the glasses
for the heroic rebels
and for General Washington!
If he is so rich, why
is he a revolutionary?
So it is necessary! Otherwise, what
will we do to make a revolution?
Mr. Marquis, there is a bastard!
Come here, mister gendarme!
Despite your clothes of a petty bourgeois,
we, as you can see, have found out! Come on!
Go, swing with us for the
victory of the rebels!
Brotherhood!
And then report to Mr. Morp.
You are mistaken, monsieur!
My name is Sayles Dean.
I am a citizen of America.
I report only to
General Washington.
Welcome! Welcome!
Well, tell me, Mr. Dean!
I came to Paris to
recruit volunteers.
I was correctly informed
by sending here.
Yes, monsieur, we are all volunteers here.
When are we going?
That's it, monsieur!
You are in a hurry even more than me!
I must draft contracts for
the service of Mr. Franklin,
find a ship, weapons...
How are you doing?
General Washington asked me to
convey that everything is very bad,
but we will fight to the last.
Mr. Dean, my friends and I are officers
of His Majesty the King of France.
For us here, too, everything will be bad.
We will be prevented from
leaving, but we will leave!
Where, Mr. Marquis?
To America, Mr. Gendarme!
Your honesty facilitates my task, Mr.
Marquis.
Your task is to spy and report!
So go, report!
Here you are in a public place.
While there is order, you
have no right to interfere.
Washington! "He's an English general...
he's an Englishman."
"Are you taking me for a fool?"
"How can you do that!"
Dispose of!
Tell me thank you, mister gendarme.
You almost committed a crime.
It's you, monsieur, now you are doing it!
Wearing one of the most notable names of the
kingdom and serving as a sword to the king,
you have no right
to dispose of it!
Lift it up, monsieur.
Want to teach me a lesson?
I will teach you another.
I can not fight with
His Majesty's officer.
But I can arrest him!
Patrol, to me!
Your sword, monsieur!
And it's at the same time!
Well, it's started again!
I knew it! I warned!
For help! Help!
And all because of the picture!
Oh, it's well defended,
your Washington!
Leroy, leave it to me!
Leave him to me!
The killers! The executioners!
Death to the derzhimordam!
Gentlemen patrol,
raise your commander!
Who loves me - for me!
See you soon, Mr. Dean!
As you can see, the
beginning has been made!
I hope Segur wins!
Hooray!
"This is Count d'Artois!"
- I lost 100 crowns.
- And I'm 200!
And I'm 300. I'm even
a flatterer than you!
The king is so pleased that
we put on his losing brother.
I put 1000 ECU on it!
Father, I lost.
I, too, it seems.
All of us are good flatterers.
I confess, I did not think about that.
I'm going to pay for the wager.
Do not join Adrienne?
Certainly, my son-in-law.
The hat of Madame de Simian prevented
me from seeing the finish.
Me too, my father.
It's strange! This foreigner
just arrived at the races.
How could Gilbert
make a bet with him?
What ship?
Arrived yesterday in Le Havre.
This is Sussex.
With rifles?
With pugachami. But yes, with guns...
And what about the police?
Vergencin closes his eyes.
"Vernen!" "Sire?"
Who is this talking to the
Marquis de La Fayette?
I do not see from here, sire.
I have very poor eyesight.
This is Sileas Dean, an agent
of the Americans, sir.
You, Morpas, on the contrary,
have excellent eyesight!
Thank God, despite the years,
I'm still pretty far away.
Which is very useful for the minister.
On board the baron Kalb will rise.
And I?
Your contract, Mr. Marquis,
Franklin, too, signed.
Thank him.
Tell the baron of Kalbu
that I am sailing with him.
And what about your wife?
I'll talk to her.
Look at Gilbert's glowing look.
Do you like losing
so much, dear?
One nuance -
I like hopeless things.
In that case, you have
a chance, my dear!
Excuse me.
Gilbert!
Because of your fault, Aglaya and
I are treated like two horses!
- What does it mean?
- We are betting on, imagine!
Which will arrive...
Will arrive where?
Do not pretend, monster!
Excuse me. I have already arrived.
Father, I'm kidnapping my wife from you.
I need to talk to her.
About love! I know.
But first - the king.
Now that we've all lost to him,
let's see if we like him.
Do you like racing, gentlemen?
"I find them fascinating, sire."
Then why did not you participate
in them as a rider?
I have the honor of being a
royal musketeer, Your Majesty.
I'm a good rider with
only a sword in my hand.
Worthy answer musketeer, sir.
And what do you say, Morpah?
It will be a pity if your Majesty
will lose such officers.
Why should I lose them?
As far as I know, we are not at war.
No one can know whether Sire,
we are fighting or not.
By the way, I imposed an embargo today
on a ship loaded with
weapons for Americans.
I inform your Majesty.
You have chosen the wrong moment
to tell me about it, Morpah.
"Not so bad."
"Forgive me, Your Majesty,
in which case I must
inform Your Majesty,
that for my part I
gave permission!
Oh, gentlemen! We're here at the races!
They play, but do not decide.
Why do we need 2 ministers if they
need to be separated all the time?
Oh, Your Majesty will
be very cheerful now!
It is necessary to choose between
Washington and Cornwallis.
Again!
"Explain yourself, countess!"
In the next race Count Segur appears
under the name of Washington, and...
I presume, Morpa, do
you bet on England?
The Minister of Finance is obliged to
make reliable investments, monsieur.
Then... 500 on Washington.
Good! 500 on Cornwallis.
I do not know what Washington looks
like, Sire, but Segur is so charming!
I put 1000 ECU on it.
And I, Madame,
should put on both.
This is very sensible, sir!
"And you, M. De La Fayette?"
"You must excuse me, Your Majesty,
I do not trust great ideas to horses.
Be they even English.
King, who dreams only to sleep,
the queen - just have fun,
The English, whom we
hate, but imitate,
and the war in America, which
turned into horse races!
Sire, I was just thinking...
This is a great opportunity
for you to make a decision!
What solution?
"About that ship!"
If Noahle wins, you will
stand on the side of Morp;
If Segur - on the side Verzhenna.
Really, madam, you always
give excellent advice.
Washington.
Sire, you must follow
Vergenna's advice!
Gilbert!
"A hot young man!"
"Forgive me, sire."
I told your Majesty:
Horse racing is my passion.
Races and rebels.
All 20-year-old young people,
Sire, in fact - rebels.
The king was joking, monsieur.
Not at all! What is said, it is said.
The ship can swim.
"The Romans had races in chariots."
"And they bet, too?"
Oh no. It's an English idea.
Do you think there is a future
for such entertainment?
This is what Mr. de Conflans maintains.
Sire! The English General Howe
led the 33,000-strong army,
defeated the insurgents.
Oh shit...
What an obliging person!
He saved me trouble.
It is better to bet on the
army than on one horse.
I stand on the side of Morp,
whose vision is definitely
better than yours.
I looked through my fingers
at secret help to the rebels.
From now on, I forbid it.
Gilbert!
On the outskirts of Passy -
a small secluded house,
the house of Benjamin Franklin, the
main man of the American Revolution.
Virginia and New York.
Forgive me for being late, gentlemen.
Police? "Oh, no, it's worse."
My father-in-law!
The news of the defeat of the Americans -
is it true or not?
True!
"I'm sorry, Baron, I did not notice you."
This is my role. Kalba no one notices.
All the bad news is true: Howe defeated
Washington, Morpa - Verzhenna.
And farewell, ship!
We will not have the opportunity to make
this journey together, Mr. Marquis.
"Quickly, you lose hope, Baron!"
Fast?
I waited 30 years for the
general's epaulettes,
no difference - German,
English or French!
Color is not important,
it's important to rank!
But even American
people are eluding me!
And for me, not rank is important,
but struggle, Mr. Kalb!
Better a soldier in the rebel army than
a general in the army of the king!
It's because of your age.
You will still find yourself other battles.
And this... is over!
Finished!
I do not share the opinion
of Baron Kalba here?
Not all, Gilbert.
Not you, Dean!
The defeat can be a
victory, only...
Only...?
"Franklin is not here."
I noticed. Where is he?
In the next room with an
ambassador who came from America.
Only I'm afraid, M. De La Fayette,
that in that message -
"Everything is over!"
It's over!
Gentlemen!
Congress of Boston
proclaimed the independence
of the American colonies!
Long live the Congress!
Mr. Franklin,
independence does not
proclaim, it is conquered!
It's true, Mr. Kalb.
But they do not lose it either.
In one single battle!
Lose! If she's the last!
The last battle will be the one
where the British will be defeated!
"You, Mr. Marquis?"
Me! And you, General Kalb!
All of you who will go with me!
- On the air balloon?
- On the ship! On my!
"Can you get the ship?"
"Ships are bought."
"They cost more than conscience," monsieur.
You are rich, but is the price
of the ship known to you?
Load with weapons? A?
Freedom of price does not matter, monsieur!
But now it is freedom
you run the risk if the king finds
out that you want to buy a ship!
When he finds out, I'll be
on the high seas already.
One moment!
Are you serious,
Monsieur de La Fayette?
Can you find 100-120
thousand livres?
And even 2 times more!
I do not want to offend anyone,
but we all sail with a contract in your
pocket and epaulettes on your shoulders.
But you - you do not ask for anything,
but offer a ship and weapons?
"But on one condition."
Ah, all the same! What?
That this ship was
called "Victory".
Bravo, Gilbert! Bravo!
"And in the evening he goes to her."
"Are you sure about that?"
Is he a secretive person?
No, that's it!
He himself confessed: "I rush
to ideas, flags, women"...
So what? 2 chances out
of 3 that you are wrong.
But I love him.
And if only he loved you?
If he did not like ideas, flags,
if women did not love him?
Would you love him?
I think yes.
For me, love is so simple...
For him, too! And even too much!
He needs fame.
And this woman can make you
suffer more than others.
You are not asleep?
Do not touch me, Gilbert!
Adrienne...
How could I embrace you if I had
been in the arms of another before?
Answer!
I'm sure that Countess
de Simian likes you!
Yes, I like it. I do not deny.
I also like Aglaya.
Only they both have what
plays against them.
What?
You!
My soul!
But then where do you go in the
evenings under the cover of secrecy?
To one old gentleman -
To Benjamin Franklin.
Why are you hiding this from me?
"Because you're a little girl."
I'm a spouse and mother!
Yes, and it is also!
A little girl, wife, mother.
Is this not enough?
Is it worth it to load these
charming little hangers?
If I was sure of your love, you
could do whatever you want!
Even leave?
To leave?
Not sure if I'll be back?
To the rebels!
So?
Yes, my soul, so.
And that is not all.
You do not need to stop me:
You heard the king.
They are following us openly.
Especially for me.
And you are close to the most
severe of my supervisors.
- Who is it?
- Your father.
Shikua! "Yes, Mr. Duke?"
Where did Mr. de La Fayette come from?
You can choose.
To be with him against
me, to keep me.
Or with me against
him, to lose me.
See what I'm asking my girl?
Just like the heroine Corneille.
What, including this bill, is
the sum of 112 thousand livres.
And 29 days of waiting.
Körgret, Mr. Marquis, was one
of your most beautiful estates.
I was not going to sacrifice them.
It was necessary to play in competition.
I would prefer to sell 2
estates, but wait 2 times less.
Mr. Marquis, you did not deem it necessary
to entrust the old notary and family friend,
what are you going to
do with this money.
Yes, it's a fortune, but
the one who gets it,
can and wait.
There are cases, monsieur, when
to force to wait is a crime.
"Well, dear master?"
"He raised the sum."
But I still do not know what
he's going to do with her.
- Only a mysterious phrase.
- What?
What to force to wait.
Sometimes it's a crime.
I will not be until
the evening, my soul.
This melody will accompany me.
Together with the one who plays it.
"Have you collected the full amount?"
Yes.
Until evening, Mother.
"Is it gold there?"
"Forget it, forget it."
Here I am stupid!
When the husband leaves his wife with pockets
full of gold, then he goes for gifts.
That's right, mother,
I'm going to get gifts.
"Sit down, Gilbert."
"I have a meeting, Father."
I know. I'll take you there.
I ask you to.
My dear Mr. Dean, I am
only a peasant son,
like your mischief from Missouri.
But I knew many noblemen.
A glass on the chest - and they are
ready to go broke for a noble purpose.
Sober they too are ruined,
but for the sake of women.
"But not La Fayette, Mr. Kalb."
"That's what I thought."
But look - he pulls a week,
and this is the limit.
If today I do not leave for Bordeaux,
I will not make it there by Monday.
And on Monday everything will be over -
there will be no more ship.
He said - at 4 o'clock.
The latest.
And now - without 15 four.
112 thousand livres that you have here...
You are well informed.
Then you probably know who
this gold is intended for?
Yes. "Countess de Simian?"
No. The rebels.
Only one woman could
inform you so well.
You have your secrets, I have mine.
"But if it's Adrienne..."
"What is Adrienne?"
She is my wife!
"She's my daughter!"
This is your state, you want.
Give it to the rebels,
but give it away secretly
and do nothing else.
Your sword belongs to the king.
"One day, he may be happy."
"But while he is careful."
Do you think you are leaving Noahle for America's sake?
But, it may be that for the sake of the Bastille!
"She does not frighten me."
And me yes.
For my daughter's husband, I wish
for a better fate than a prison.
So, before we go to your meeting,
we will first go to another one.
Let's try to put the king's
suspicions to sleep.
Are you taking me to the king?
"No, to his brother."
- To whom?
To the eldest.
Let in Mr. de La Fayette.
Give me this.
And then your clothes are deformed.
I do not confiscate it,
but I am depositing it.
Thank you.
Welcome, Monsieur de La Fayette
under this roof, which
will become yours!
Mine?
My First Junk Camera
lives in my house.
But, it seems, for you it is news?
Yes, forgive me, monsignor.
Mr. D'Aién probably
wanted to surprise me.
As I see, he succeeded.
But he should consult me!
Yes, this title is a high honor, monsignor,
and I feel that it is not worthy.
Your name, your uniform,
your condition -
make you just very even worthy!
Thank you, monsieur.
But in addition to these
merits, which you listed,
I have weaknesses that
I cherish even more:
My ideas!
Oh, yes... I forgot.
To have ideas today is
considered a good form.
What's an idea!
As if the origin of
this does not save!
Youth, name, fortune and wife -
this is not enough for you?
Leave ideas to those
who need them to live!
They also need me to live.
And my ideas prevent
me from serving you.
I would like, monsieur, to
judge this you left to me.
"They're built on one word, monsieur."
Which?
- Freedom!
- Oh yeah! Only a word!
"But it raises the world!"
"Only a part, the most modest."
The youngest!
Monsieur de La Fayette!
Your honesty is another
virtue to be in my court.
Your father-in-law did not hide from me
your sympathy for the colonists of America,
but treat these
filibusters as...
how women treat their hair!
Do not build your life in fashion,
because in France everything
comes out of fashion.
And nothing changes.
Everything will change, I hope!
Otherwise, France should be sorry if...
And the king? How is the king, monsieur?
And the people, monsignor?
What about the people?
The people will be only
happy if several hot goals
will stop grinding tongue!
These people do not speak language!
They're fighting!
Against dishonesty of ministers,
against corruption of judges,
for reducing the slavery
of this "happy" people!
This is a program of
revolution, monsieur!?
And you will understand, monsieur, that a
revolutionary can not be the First Junker Chamber...
I'm not a king, but
someday I can become one!
Yes!
And from now on I believe that a revolutionary is
dangerous not only for France, but also for my home!
I warned you, monsieur!
Monsignor awaits the Duke of Aiens.
Well, what did you tell him?
You will learn from his own lips.
Oh, your clothes are
completely deformed.
Oh, I'm sorry!
I had just been appointed First Cavalry
Officer of the King's brother.
I need you for an urgent
and secret mission!
In Bordeaux! Everything is over!
And here he is!
Between two gendarmes?
Thank you, gentlemen!
I do not need you anymore!
You are cool, Monsieur de La Fayette!
Bye!
And soon come back!
The first mission of your son-in-law
is successfully completed.
Sorry?
The King's brother entrusted him the delivery of a large
sum of gold, and I had the honor of escorting him.
Honor?! This honor can
lead you to the Bastille!
I already despaired...
Well?
It was the Countess
de Simian, Herr Duke.
Again...
A scene from Marivo, dear.
"Is it my fault?"
My father-in-law began to worry if I throw rebels
for the sake of your beautiful eyes, the countess.
God grant. At least my beautiful eyes
will not bring you to the Bastille.
Gilbert, we're going to the queen.
In honor of what is it?
Your comedy can not
deceive anyone.
With all the inconveniences
of your mistress's situation,
I also have privileges.
One merciful soul, in secret
from Morp, warned me.
About what?
M. De La Fayette.
We first see you at a concert
of chamber music, monsieur?
It is so, Your Majesty.
Or maybe you just want to meet
here with dear Mr. Lozan?
Or with the sweet Maurois?
Or with this glorious Segur,
whom I also rarely see?
No, M. De La Fayette came
to see your Majesty,
on my advice.
You turn my salon into
a place of conspiracy!
But it's so entertaining.
And people who amuse me are
worthy of my condescension.
I am embarrassed...
But your Majesty knows
my sincerity...
And I know your
problems, monsieur.
And I'm betting that you came to
listen to my music to talk about them.
Yes, Your Majesty!
God, what a funny man he is!
Nothing will escape
from Your Majesty!
Oh, no... Alas!
Gentlemen! King!
Sire, let me...
What you need?
Your signature, sir.
I'm going to the queen.
Your signature will wait until tomorrow!
You persevere!
Sire, persistence -
the main duty of the Minister.
But not before 9 am!
Speak. But fast.
I adore this arietta.
I'm afraid it's too late, Your Majesty.
Morpas chases me even
from you, madam.
You are my last refuge
from this annoying person.
Last thing.
Sign? I decided
that at such a time
I want to make only
one decision: Sleep!
So use this immoderate
love to sleep!
What are you doing?
"Quiet, please do not be afraid!"
I'm afraid, sir, that these
signatures are urgent.
Listen, my friend!
So I take refuge or study?
You are right, madam.
Start the music.
Get it over with, monsieur.
You look puzzled, Louis.
Is from what.
These are warrants for arrest.
You look at the surname!
How, monsieur! Arrest the nobles
who came to me as friends?
They just came to your Majesty,
because they must be arrested.
I take you as a witness, sir:
Your Minister accuses me of conspiracy!
Watch the words, Morp!
Take your files.
Queen is right, this is not the right time.
Your Majesty will not reproach me, if I
soon bring you a new decree for signature?
"What Decree?"
- About war.
About war...
"England is losing patience."
And the departure to America of Mr.
La Fayette and his friends
will be the last straw...
England...
You should let me
listen to the music.
I'm sorry, madam, but the friendship of England
demands that we choose our friends well.
Wait, Sire!
Interested persons are all here!
Unless of elementary politeness
should not they be informed?
I'm in your quarters,
madam, I obey.
Gentlemen!
The Queen disgusts that we decide
your fate behind your back.
I note that you yourself decide
the fate of France for mine.
So, to make it pleasant,
I will inform you,
that I sign the arrest
of all four of you.
And now - music.
Sire, I was just thinking...
Is there no more... elegant
way to appease England,
than to imprison Mr. de La Fayette?
What kind?
Yes, send it to them!
A delightful idea!
Monsieur de La Fayette is not an
ambassador, but in London his uncle Noail.
Relatives call each other to visit,
especially if the king advises.
Oh, madam, why do I need two ministers,
if you are alone, stand ten?
You will go to London, monsieur.
Moreover, it's time
for me to go to bed.
"Your Majesty..."
"That's enough, Morpah!"
You saw, it's already 10 pm!
This is madness!
If they will not let me
sleep, where France will go!
How can I thank Your Majesty?
Having turned heads to English women.
"Be patient, though..."
I do not like to endure.
Good luck in London!
My dear Noail, at the risk of
shocking our glorious Germein,
I repeat to you: We should not
have taken Canada away from you.
You forget, Your Grace, that
England lives by trade.
And what does this trade live?
His colonies.
But if you take away from
friends their colonies,
one fine morning you can wake up
without trade, without colonies...
and without friends!
What a pity for France, that on
the throne you were not seated,
but your brother.
I like everything in France:
Her ideas, her spirit
and her wine!
What shall we drink, gentlemen?
But...
for France, of course!
"For England!"
- For both!
Ah, you are very timely,
my dear d'Aijen!
Your Highness.
France - the subject of our gossip.
But did not you promise to bring Mr.
De La Fayette?
He's here, Your Grace.
Oh, excuse me, monsieur.
I've heard a lot about you, but I
did not expect you to be so young!
I also!
Your youth makes
you even prettier.
And less dangerous.
Will you raise this glass with us?
For the alliance?
"What alliance?"
"Our two countries!"
With pleasure, Your Grace, but when
there will not be a third between us.
Which one?
America.
America, monsieur, is not a country.
This is an English colony.
Lord Germaine, the Minister of Colonies.
Monsieur.
I've heard a lot about you, Mr.
De La Fayette.
Did you want to cross the Atlantic?
And crossed only the English Channel.
I thought you understood
who the winner is?
The ministries are always in a hurry
to declare victory, Your Excellency.
The rebels did not
surrender, as far as I know?
Gold, which is distributed by Mr.
Sales Dean and Franklin in Paris,
not for a long time delay this fact.
Not gold calls for the action of
friends of freedom, Your Excellency.
What can not you say about the German
mercenaries fighting for you...
It's better than the bandits from the
big road, who are recruited in France!
If the French volunteers -
just a rabble,
How could they stop
the British army?
You forget who you are visiting!
No, no, leave it.
I also like French fervor.
Major General Cornwallis.
- And here is our guest of honor!
- Yes.
Mr. de La Fayette, you will
receive the latest news
about your rebel friends.
Gentlemen, I have the honor and
pleasure to present to you.
Major-General Cornwallis, who
has just returned from America.
Sir! Sir!
Are you French, monsieur?
Forgive me, but my English ears
have not heard your name well.
The Marquis de La Fayette.
Do you like hunting?
So much so that I keep
souvenirs about her.
I spent all my childhood in Auvergne.
They hunt a lot.
A! As in the west of England,
in the Duchy of Cornwall.
I hope to return there
when the war is over.
Is it not said in London
that it is coming to an end?
In London? Maybe.
Do you think the
insurgents will last long?
While they have a leader
like Washington, yes.
And his army, monsieur?
Does it deserve the
honor of Lord Zhermeyn?
You are young, monsieur, but
you are a military man.
Gang partisan with bare feet,
armed with hunting rifles
and without officers,
deterrent to the onslaught
of the British army
does not deserve anything
other than contempt?
Oh yeah.
Victory!
Monsieur de La Fayette,
I heard that the rebels have
many friends in France.
Are you one of them?
You are a military man, monsieur.
I'm sure you do not
need to explain.
For a young man and a spiritual, is there a
better reason for fighting than freedom?!
If I understood you correctly,
but I think I understood...
next time we will meet
with a weapon in hand...
just like now.
Perhaps on different sides
of the battlefield.
I'm afraid you're right.
Certainly!
Attention!
"Your bird, sir!"
"No, it's yours!"
Sorry, you just messed her up.
In any case, I will
remember your frankness.
With pleasure.
And I - your courtesy.
I'm from Kalba.
Mister Bancroft!
At your service, monsieur.
"Are you staying in London?"
Till.
Can I trust you with one errand?
You see that yes.
I will give you a letter for my
father-in-law of the Duke of Aiens.
But you will give it
to him only in a week.
"Mr. Bancroft?"
- Right.
They say you have a letter
from my son-in-law for me?
Right.
Why did not he give it to him?
When we write to someone, it means
we do not want to meet with him.
I suppose you know everything?
Not true. Nothing.
But you serve as a messenger
of my son-in-law?
I like to provide services.
This is a farewell letter.
This is what you knew?
Right.
But it's not my business.
There is one thing that you
may be able to explain to me.
Maybe.
My brother-in-law writes to me:
"When you receive this letter, it
will take a week from my departure."
Yes.
But my son-in-law left
London only yesterday!
Yes.
He did not ask you
to wait this week?
Right. "Why did not you do it?"
I already told you -
I like to provide services.
You are such a curious character, Mr.
Bancroft!
Right.
I know how interested you are in Mr.
La Fayette.
Why make you wait a whole week,
to find out all the
details of his journey?
What details?
"Did not he tell you?"
Usually travelers in farewell
letters give some details?
For example?
"Oh... I know so little."
I only know that your son-in-law must
meet in Paris with a certain Baron Kalb,
with whom he will rise in Bordeaux
aboard the ship "Victory",
immediately sailing to America,
where Mr. La Fayette will fight
in the ranks of the rebels
in the rank of general
of the American army.
As you can see, I do not know
much, let's just say - nothing!
It was necessary to give
me this letter right away!
Well no!
A week later.
"It's either too early or too late."
No, if you urgently send a person,
he will make it to Paris in time.
Believe me, I figured it all out.
You are playing a strange game, monsieur!
Right.
I lead even 2 games. As you can see.
- Counting on a double win!
- That's not true.
To win for sure.
And how much do I owe you?
Wait for the win, Mr. Duke.
Soon!
- Stop!
- Miss it!
Courier from London for
royal intelligence!
Is this a good time
to bother people?
Give here an envelope.
Let the messenger be
sent to me immediately.
Adrienne...
Now listen to me.
I did not return.
I'd like to check out.
Yes, my soul.
"When?"
- Now.
No choice.
I would cease to respect myself.
You too.
I'll be waiting for you!
"My little girl..."
You will be mocked.
You will also have your own war.
Against the father, against
the king, against all...
It is much harder to fight against
friends than against enemies.
You, too, must know one thing...
- Yes?
- Dad...
It was not I who told him.
You suspected me, I know.
But I did not say anything to him.
Always call me your girl.
But when you are there...
remember that you
have a real wife!
Run!
Faster!
I'll detain them.
What's wrong, monsieur?
Madame, by order of the King, we must make sure
of the identity of the Marquis de La Fayette.
But the Marquis in London!
Upstairs it should know.
The order of the king
is categorical, madam.
Let us verify that Mr. de La
Fayette is not here for sure.
Show me this order.
Perform your duties, monsieur.
Well, did you find him?
You should be better,
madam, if I could find it!
Ugh, barely escaped!
To me the bloodhounds of Morp!
We immediately leave!
You do not know, Gilbert, but Morpas woke
the king in the middle of the night!
Heck! What did he say to him?
I warn you, everything will be
done to prevent your departure.
Dear Dean, I never thought that
it would be a pleasure trip.
And what do you say when your king
will consider you a deserter?
The deserters are the losers.
And I'm going to win!
Monsieur de La Fayette,
listen to me.
You must understand what I should
give you this advice, but...
stay!
Mr. Franklin, I'm sorry,
but I can not follow.
What should I say to
General Washington?
What do you think of all of France.
We go! I already did not believe it.
"You will be a general, Baron!"
"A funny team, Mr. Marquis."
What?
These horses, we are with you...
I'm German, you're French.
But I cultivate prudence, and you...
how can I say...
fanatic!
A fake baron, a real marquis.
A former poor man who will become a rich man
and a rich man by birth who may become poor.
But under the American flag!
You will see, we have a common.
What?
We are free!
Your mascot?
Yes, my talisman.
And this is yours?
Yes, it's mine.
Dragoons are catching up! Faster!
Faster Faster! We will be caught up!
Take the horses off the route!
Quickly!
Where are they?
I advise you to tell everything!
Where are the ones you drove?
I do not understand anything!
We are heading towards the Antilles.
I said "aside"...
Why are they laughing?
We are not sailing to the Antilles?
Captain Loco Barsolino.
Hello Captain!
You see, the Antilles -
it was for Commander Bordeaux.
And you will go to America.
In America? As to America?!
With a stop in the Antilles?
No, without any stops.
"And my cargo?" "What load?"
A little cloth, a bit of
junk to sell on the islands.
It was not stipulated in
our contract, Captain!
America was not there too!
Captain, you can sell
your goods in America.
If it is seen by the British, they
will not buy, but will be taken away.
He's right.
Then I'll buy it.
"The whole?"
- That's all.
What will you do with all this cloth?
You know how many of them!
But not enough to dress
the entire rebel army.
Come on, captain, get off
the anchor immediately.
"Immediately?
And your luggage, Mr. Marquis?"
My luggage?
We will not wait for him.
Yes, but I have to wait for something.
- What?
- The tide!
2 hours more.
2 hours?
But in 2 hours there will be dragoons!
What can you do? The tide can not
be here before, mister marquis!
Impossible!
Pray, Marquis.
And I believe only in the devil!
And I'm in Madonna.
The Madonna heard you, Mr. Marquis.
The calm begins.
Stop!
It's late, Captain.
Damn it!
Do not be afraid, Baron.
If I am found on board,
Victory is confiscated
together with all weapons and provisions.
"Yes, like Sussex."
- No!
"Victory" must swim!
Captain! Comes calm,
and you sail away!
Without me.
- But this is impossible...
- No, without you we will not sail!
Swim! This is my first order!
And last.
Change me there as best you can.
Your talisman turned
out better, Baron.
It was necessary for you
to run, mister marquis!
But, finally, I caught up with you.
I had a message for you.
Message from the King.
That's how then do not
believe in the devil?
I will make your route
myself up to Marseilles.
Do not be offended by the precautions
that we are forced to take against you.
Remember, on the contrary, we will not do
anything about the team and the cargo.
As you can see, you are not
under arrest, Mr. Marquis.
Your carriage is waiting for you.
He was not arrested.
No. But he is put in a carriage.
Wait! By the order of the king!
Tell me, please, who are you,
monsieur, and where are you going?
Marquis de La Fayette, I go to
Marseilles by the order of the King.
Is that what you wanted to know?
All right, monsieur.
Sorry for the precautions...
Let's hit the road!
Cut off the road! Stop it!
Maurois!
You did not leave? Without
you I will not go!
But nothing hindered you!
You were free.
I did not come to accompany you, Gilbert.
I came for you.
To return to the "Victory."
Swim?
Listen, without us, our
departure does not make sense.
So I offered to drop anchor
in Spain, in Los Pasajes.
Everyone agreed, I jumped
into the first boat and...
And you want me to hug you tight
and follow you to Pacheases?
On, read it.
The king orders me
to go to Marseilles,
and I'm going.
But I order you
to go to America!
Fight 2 times more and win!
Leave, Maurois! Leave!
"Farewell, Gilbert!"
- Goodbye!
Maurois!
It is he!
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I am sure! It is he!
Boat! Faster!
Prepare to sail!
Sailors starboard - ready!
Give up the moorings!
Lift the jib and the mizzen!
Congratulations, Morpah!
Just in vain, day and night
watching for Mr. La Fayette.
If Your Majesty
listened to me...
Why are you laughing, madam?
Agree that he beautifully
guided you around your finger!
I do not know if it will be
considered beautiful England!
What is the temperature in the
English Embassy, Vergeon?
Frosty, sir.
This proves, Sir, that
England does not consider
the help of La Fayette to the
rebels is so insignificant.
Do not you think, madam, that a
young man who does not have 20,
will change the course
of history in America?
How to know!
Monsieur de La Fayette disobeyed
me, and you are having fun, madam!
No! But if he, on the
high seas, heard you...
he would surely be cheerful!
Looking for English frigates, Mr.
Marquis?
Your assistant thinks that
we can meet them here.
We can not even meet a miracle.
But I do not really believe in a miracle.
Have you ever been inspected at sea?
No never.
The frigate raises a red
flag, and you are white.
Never!
On the 1 st demand,
you quickly raise it.
Never!
On the 2nd requirement,
if "No way!" - "Fire!"
Do you know how many cannons
are in small English frigates?
- 12!
- And we have 2.
So no sea fights!
Well, that's nice.
You are sensible, Mr. Marquis.
You will go to the
frigate full sails.
Abortage and attack on swords!
We in the sea trade
often transport swords.
But we do not touch them.
I'll give you lessons.
I sold you my ship, Mr. Marquis,
but not your own skin!
On swords... Aha!
At the same English frigate on the horizon,
untie the boat from the port side!
We calmly go to the sea!
Count to 20 and then - bang!
For the ship has already been paid.
"Being a defender of
freedom, which I worship,"
being himself free
more than anyone else,
in a friendly manner, offering its
services to this so interesting republic,
I offer her only my
sincerity and my good will.
No special interest,
no ambition.
Working for my glory, I
work for their happiness.
Adrienne, my soul,
and one more day has ended.
"The night does not allow me to continue, for I have
forbidden any light on my ship for several days."
Sometimes I ask myself,
but does it exist?
Who!
America!
We, probably, passed it.
La Ruyri was lucky.
He is fond of birds.
Only after all they are all the same.
And here not!
These things are different.
Yes? And what?
They are American.
Yes, these are no longer seabirds.
The earth is near!
Thank God!
Let's drink to this!
Oh, obvious progress
in English, Marquis!
But I never drink for success
"before", it's a bad omen.
The ship is straight
ahead on the port side!
You see!
What makes you think that he is English?
"I'll bet on my epaulet."
Agreed, Baron!
This is the English forte.
I won.
Believe me, Mr. Marquis,
raise the white flag.
Just touch it,
and I will make you forget
the taste of tobacco!
Here I command!
Raise the alarm!
The rest - stand around me.
The Baron!
My contract with the rebels does
not provide for sea fights.
Them - too!
Look at them!
If you go with me,
then they too!
Oh, I do not give you orders, Baron.
But you're an American officer!
And I'll die like a banal sailor?
I,
which the sea can not stand!
Okay. Take the weapon!
Come on!
Let's!
Foreman!
Get ready for boarding!
In the hold!
Prepare for battle!
Unfasten the guns, prepare the
cores and pots with fire!
To fight on both sides!
The Gunners are ready!
Straighten Mars!
Turn them a little bit so
they can see our flag!
The ship is American!
Hooray! American!
"Hey, American ship!"
- ABOUT!
4...
5, 6,
7, 8,
9...
Madonna... this is a miracle!
I lost!
This is for you. I already have mine.
Oh thanks. Hooray!
Ahead of the earth on the starboard side!
My friends, this is America!
America!
We freely arrived here, so that the
young country could live freely!
We swear to either
win or perish!
We swear!
PHILADELPHIA
THE AMERICAN CONGRESS.
We will not let emotions dazzle ourselves!
A large number
of so-called volunteers
of the French who are
sent to us by Mr. Dean,
joined us exclusively
for the sake of money.
Their little interest in
our goal, they go here for work,
for the sake of salaries and titles, which
they would not receive in their own country.
In my opinion, and I declare
this to you without obstructions,
such people here are undesirable!
We do not need them!
"Undesirable"...
I'm asking for the floor!
Who are you, sir?
One of them is "undesirable"!
Mr. Chairman...
I have not finished my speech yet!
When I'm done, I'll give the word to you.
I'm sorry, sir.
But I'm the Marquis de La Fayette.
I arrived here with my friends,
so... it's hard for me, sir.
We crossed the sea on a ship
that I bought with my own money,
to help you in your war.
My friends, my ship, my money -
YOUR war!
That's what we are "undesirable", Mr.
Chairman.
Sorry.
May Lord Marquis
forgive my frankness,
but we need more
skilled artillerymen,
rather than in young aristocrats,
Hardly speaking our language!
Therefore, we can not approve your
contracts signed with Mr. Dean in Paris.
Mr. Chairman...
...you do not understand
what your words mean for us!
For those who have overcome
so much to join you!
We left everything!
Threw it all!
Our houses, our wives,
our children - everything!
To help you make
your country free!
Forget about the contracts of Mr. Dean.
Forget our contracts.
Forget my ship, forget my name.
The only service, about
which we ask this assembly,
be soldiers!
Without contracts, without pay!
Without payment... but in your army!
Let us fight alongside you!
The attractiveness of democracy
is that one can always explain.
And not only to someone
one, but to all!
Everyone has the right to speak.
The Assembly passed a decision.
You can come back, gentlemen.
Speaks English.
"In view of the fact that
the Marquis de La Fayette"
with such zeal perceived freedom,
for which the United States is fighting,
that he left his family and relatives
and at his own expense came here,
to offer their services to the US,
not requiring any content,
nor a special status,
ready to risk his
life for our cause,
The Congress decided...
...accept his services...
"Given his zeal,"
as well as the nobility of
his kind and his allies,
he will be promoted to the rank of
Major-General of the US Army...
Thank you.
Stop!
We came to General Washington.
Washington, what kind of person is he?
"A man rather than a general."
I can not stand babbling and flattery.
The man is very simple,
almost ascetic.
But his handshake
will break your hand!
Even when he was a child,
he threw a coin in 1 dollar...
...to the other side of the Potomac.
- Braggart, then!
Oh, no, not at all!
Once he confessed that
he tore up the cherry.
To which the father,
having forgiven him, said:
"Better than 1,000 cherries torn
from the roots, than just one lie."
And he remembered that.
Never lie -
this should make life very difficult.
With their people - no.
With politicians - yes.
They say he is very religious?
Yes very...
On the shoulder!
Free!
Welcome, Monsieur de La Fayette!
No, General. La Fayette is he.
"Are you La Fayette?"
Yes, monsieur.
But you are so young!
You are my son's fit!
"Like many of your soldiers."
This is yes...
But they are also the sons of America.
And you are a Frenchman.
With a great fortune, from a noble family.
What can not be said
about most of my "sons".
Greatness does not come by birth, monsieur,
but in the struggle for great goals.
Yes. And you already have a
good fight against Congress.
But the British -
even more uncompromising.
And you saw my troops.
I ask you to judge them
only after the battle.
I came here not to
judge, but to study.
Good.
Well, first you can study this.
Cornwallis received reinforcements of
5 thousand Brandenburg mercenaries.
General Howe - 120 new guns.
And General Clinton is a new
regiment of mountaineers.
And you, monsieur, a 20-year-old marquise,
Prussian baron, their field
assistants - that's all!
Exactly.
And at the same time, I do not know why,
but I would not change.
Thank you, monsieur.
I think that the main thing in the war is to
have a commander for whom you are ready to die.
- Ha, they say he's a general!
- They are recruited right in the cradle.
Smir-no!
- Hold it. 6 cartridges per person.
- Oh no!
- This is the order.
- "Do they want us to hunt squirrels?"
Between 6 squirrels and
6 recruits, I put on recruits.
Exactly! 6-That's what I said.
We do not go into battle, but we go back.
General Sullivan needs
all available ammunition,
to cover our retreat from the enemy.
Here and so.
- "What command do you entrust to me?"
- "Not yet.
But I have the rank of Major-General!
Yes, Major-General, who
did not smell gunpowder.
But he imagined so many times!
Command requires more
than imagination.
"I can join Sullivan's army."
No.
I've taken care of you...
...my militiamen.
Look at them.
Barefoot, hungry,
6 cartridges per person.
They have nothing.
There is nothing to be proud of.
But if I give them commanders of
the famous Marquis de La Fayette,
who came for three seas
to lead them into battle,
I think this will raise their fighting
spirit more than shoes and ammunition.
Yes. But when?
Patience, my boy.
In war everything happens
faster than we think.
Except, probably, a victory.
Brandywine is not far, sir.
I heard that Washington received
reinforcements from France.
- Troops?
- "No, no, officers."
Soon we will fight
with some generals.
There they are, sir!
Wade is not guarded, sir!
- All right. Forward!
- Come on!
Neither of our intentions. If
he remains in his positions...
We will go to the back of Sullivan and
attack with the arrival of darkness.
What's the matter, soldiers?
We're the intelligence
of Sullivan's army, sir!
We could not go back,
the Scots cut us off.
- Which side of the river?
- "On this one, sir."
Cornwallis crossed the river.
- Are they coming at us?
- No, sir, they're attacking Sullivan's army.
It looks like our intelligence
service was pierced.
- What are we going to do for Sullivan?
- We will come to his aid!
Our young friend answered
your question, Baron.
- "Are we not leaving?"
-  Let's try.
Do you want to help Sullivan
with 6 cartridges per person?!
The necessary is
never impossible.
You have to do everything to save Sullivan's
artillery, because I do not have the other.
General, do I command the militia?
Yes. Now you can take command.
Youth - how wonderful it is!
I know you only have 6 rounds.
But I myself - only this!
Behind me!
You were told, 2,000
people, monsieur?
There are 10 thousand of them, if not more.
Kalb, with your dragoons you are
defending the rearguard artillery.
But still you must protect the bridge,
for perhaps Cornwallis will want to
cut us off from the path to retreat.
Good luck, Baron!
Thank you, monsieur.
Hurry, you sons of bitches!
At this rate, you
will not be overtaken!
- "This is the avant-garde of Cornwallis."
- At last!
Gentlemen, good luck!
They attack us on the right flank.
And they go into the bayonet!
So they do not have enough ammunition.
Put all the infantry into battle.
And let the artillery be at full force.
Punch cold.
The first line, forward!
Fire!
Get in line!
This is the gentleman who
deserves to be considered closer!
Do not run! To be built!
Do not give up!
Group!
I thought so! This is La Fayette!
- Marquis?
- Yes.
- How do you know?
- "I met him in England." On the hunt.
On a different kind of hunt.
Terrific! And I knew his father.
In the Battle of Mirindene.
Not for long - just to kill him.
It seems that the
same fate awaits his son.
Fire!
Gilbert! Are you hurt?
Sorry!
- Give up!
- Never!
Doctor...
You said French, sir?
Yes.
There are several of them.
You said he's a major?
Major General, Sergeant.
But he's almost a boy!
There are no ranks here...
Yes, they do not matter here.
It's not as bad as it seems, sir.
But he lost a lot of blood.
This is one of the French.
Very stubborn.
Refuses to go to the hospital.
Let him be transported to Mount Vernon.
Immediately!
- To your house, sir?
- Yes.
- I doubt that he will agree.
- "And you do not say where he's being taken."
Calb! Is he...
Yes! Yes.
He managed to cross.
Where are you taking me?
Where? Where are we going?
Casper! Casper!
Quickly!
Welcome to Mount Vernon!
Thank you very much, madam.
Your husband played a joke with me.
I should not be here.
I'm ashamed!
Shameful? Why are you ashamed, monsieur?
Get in bed!
Do not be so upset!
This risk threatens only the brave!
Oh! Adrianna? Is this your wife?
Do I correctly pronounce her name?
Yes... fine.
Stay here, I'll be right back.
My husband said that you are allowed
only one lesson - writing to Adrianne.
Is that all he said?
No. He said that I should
treat you like his own son.
Madame...
Tell him I'm grateful.
"Because you are the wife
of an American officer,"
I must give you my instructions.
You will be told:
"They were again defeated at Philadelphia."
You'll answer:
"It's true, but on the plain, with
two armies of the same strength,
experienced soldiers always have
an advantage over newcomers. "
Nothing will undermine his spirit!
And he says that nothing will also
undermine the spirit of the rebels.
"Seeing the courage of these people, I
tell myself that if the king saw them..."
King, madame!
I asked His Majesty to come.
Do not hide the letter, madam.
I, for my part, also have news from M.
De La Fayette,
but the letter sent to
you, I'm also interested.
He is in America against
your will, but he is there!
Can you have a better observer
than an American major general?
What does he say about Philadelphia?
"You will be objected:" This is a disaster!
It's the capital of America! "
This is a boulevard of freedom..."
No one for his tongue pulls.
You will politely answer:
Well?
"You're stupid!"
Speeches without blunt!
Why?
"Philadelphia is a sad city,
its port is already closed.
Only Congress made it famous. But
it has no strategic significance. "
And Washington?
About half the letter, sir.
He says that this is "the greatest military
and wisest statesman in the world."
He admires and loves
him as his father.
Your husband, in addition
to the American uniform,
there is a heart.
-"Oh, no, Sire."
He always repeats to me
that he fights for France.
And how is his health?
He does not write to me, sir.
Good.
He was wounded.
He hides it.
Do not say anything, sir!
Do not be afraid. He disobeyed me, but I
respect the courage of him and his wife.
And I'm not jealous of him for Washington.
Oh, my dear! How's your boy?
Oh, he's more obedient now.
Proof: I could have escaped, but
I'm sitting, waiting for you.
So I'm doubly glad to see you.
You do not have to wait
any longer, my boy.
No, La Fayette, it's
too early to walk!
No, no, it's okay.
I received a letter.
I want you to read it.
- From France?
- No. Hence.
From a member of Congress, Conway.
Conway? "Read it, please."
He proposes to you, to summarize,
to open a second front.
Yes. Personally lead the
expedition to Canada.
What, if successful, could
bring Canada back to France.
Exactly. What do you think of it?
Oh, this offer is very beneficial
for you personally and for France.
Yes, maybe... But I made
inquiries about this Conway.
A! My wife alarmed you for no reason.
Do not believe in women.
Yours, I believe.
Conway started intrigues against you.
"Intrigue" is a big word.
Maybe.
But this is the right word.
He made me this offer
to tear off from you.
Yes, but you can find pros here.
Politics does not
end with the war.
And, first of all, you are a Frenchman!
Monsieur, if the United States has already begun
to disengage, what is the point of fighting?
And I do not fight so that the
British give Canada Canada,
and to give America to the Americans!
I've been thinking a lot, monsieur.
We still can not
beat the English.
They should be harassed,
pulled, until the day,
When we can call them to battle and
in a place that we choose ourselves!
I'm sorry if I said stupid.
No, it's not stupid.
I myself have been thinking for some time about
a campaign of attacks, skirmishes with them.
And, frankly, I even thought
of entrusting it to you.
"Then I'm coming with you!"
"Only when you can walk."
But look! I go! I can walk!
La Fayette, I was also young.
I like this self-confidence,
this passion.
But I can advise you one thing that has
been very useful to me since my youth:
Patience!
Patience...
La Fayette was capable of
everything except patience.
And the same evening...
Thank you!
Your grateful son, Gilbert.
Do not shoot! Do not shoot!
Friends!
But the Iroquois were for the English?
- They were. La Fayette lured them.
- Clear.
Yes, there are victories
worth talking about.
Listen to me carefully, Kirov.
Here's the plan I'm offering you.
Tonight you and your warriors...
Do not shoot, these
are friendly Indians!
Friendly?
And what then are the enemy?
Ambush!
Forgive me, gentlemen,
I have finished cognac,
but I'm waiting for the
delivery of the magnificent port.
Ah, there he is!
We have been waiting impatiently
for you, Phillips, for you and port.
- I'm sorry, sir, but he's not.
- What?
Are you all drunk?
All the provisions have been taken from us.
My dear Phillips, but it's a disaster!
Give the entire port to the enemy
headquarters - this is a tactical error!
And who is responsible for this blow?
- Monsieur de La Fayette.
- Oh no! Again he!
I can not wait until it's over, and I
can tell this boy what I think about him!
- This is a small war and a small officer.
- "Neither, Phillips."
Refusing a pre-losing battle -
this is sanity.
But La Fayette pulls us to
the left, then to the right...
and never - face to face.
He learned to leave us with
an unquenchable thirst for battle...
and booze!
"What a long wait, beloved..."
And you are so far away,
surrounded by such dangers,
that every moment I tremble
for your precious life.
I am supported only by the
actions that I take to help you
before the king and queen.
She is a woman, she
understands my fears.
"But its location does not quench
my thirst for your embrace..."
You are summoned to General Washington,
Gilbert. It is very important.
Pass this order.
Ah, mister marquis! I've
been waiting for you.
So, gentlemen.
The threat from the north fades.
Burgoyne walked away. And I
order General Gates to start moving.
It's time to attack.
We will attack Burgoyne here!
In Saratoga!
Here, where we lured them...
there we will break them!
The rebels won a crushing
victory over the British,
capturing the city of Saratoga!
- Long live what?
- Saratoga, sir.
The city taken by the rebels, after the
complete defeat of the British army.
"City"! Rather, the settlement.
As for the British army, it can not
be defeated in one single battle.
And why are they shouting under our
windows? This is not a French victory.
The people, Sire, want to show
you who his sympathies are with.
If you follow the sympathies of the
people, where will it lead us?
And if we follow the antipathies of the
minister, where does this lead us?
Washington! "Now Washington..."
This is a fact: The people are
fascinated by this war. First.
This is their war, sir.
No, this is not a war. This is an uprising.
And even more, monsieur:
This is a struggle for independence.
- In which France is completely neutral.
- No, not perfect.
Mr. de La Fayette is a Frenchman.
Now you will say that we must follow Mr.
De La Fayette?
"It's not me talking, it's the people!"
"But the people..."
You are not here to argue,
gentlemen, but to give me advice.
I'm listening to you.
The victory at Saratoga
fills our hearts with joy.
But we will not make the same
mistake as our opponents.
Do not underestimate their army.
We need other victories.
And for this we need
the help of France.
I express my gratitude
to Madame de La Fayette,
which struggles to get this
support from the queen.
What is equivalent to the
support of the king.
A letter from the King, Mr. Ambassador.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Hold it.
Read it, madam.
This victory is bigger
than under Saratoga!
Without you and your husband,
we would not have won it.
"Draft allied treaty between
France and the United States!"
From the ship "Alliance"
La Fayette again saw the coast of France.
But it was not a return.
The young Major-General of the American
Army went on this trip with a special task.
Stand on the roadside, this
is the royal carriage.
My soul!
Let me look at you.
Gilbert...
To Versailles!
The first thing is the king!
Hey, now slow.
We have plenty of time.
Mr. Marquis de La Fayette, the
envoy of General Washington,
and Madame de La Fayette!
My dear, I always believed
that my son-in-law
real hero.
Mr. De La Fayette, the envoy
of General Washington.
Let him come in.
I will be grateful to you, monsieur, if you
do not come to me in a foreign uniform.
"I remained loyal to you subjects."
"Devotees"?
When you like it.
Your case is very serious, monsieur.
And delicate.
As your Majesty
decides, it will.
That's it!
Decide in such a difficult matter!
I should arrest you.
As you tell me, sir.
As you tell me, as you say...
And how will Mr. Washington order?
But we have an
alliance with him now.
That's right, sir.
And what say you, madam?
It is quite clear that M. De La
Fayette deserved punishment.
If that's what the queen says...
If I were you, my friend, I would put Mr.
De La Fayette under arrest...
Is not it!
"In the estate of de Noeille."
Tet-a-tet with his charming wife,
which he so unworthily abandoned.
I would notice to Your Majesty...
No! Do not look at me!
The queen has a tremendous
political flair.
If Mr. de La Fayette remains
locked in the Noail estate,
he can not be a triumphant
in the salons of Paris,
and this is the main thing.
So, monsieur, you are placed
under strict arrest. At home.
And I forbid you to
leave your wife.
I will personally track it.
You are too kind, sire.
And now, Mr. Major General,
tell me a little about
these Americans...
La Fayette told the king
about the Americans,
and even a lot and a long time.
For many months -
King, Queen, Morp...
England also has a
sire, a powerful ally:
"Hunger."
- Hey!
Hey, the stagecoach, guys!
With the arrival of each stagecoach,
they hope that he is carrying food and money.
Stagecoach from Baltimore.
I hope that delegates from
Congress are coming with him.
But first of all I hope for
a letter from M. De La Fayette.
- But it's been 7 months since he left.
- So what?
You've received many emails from him.
But that's all.
They are more useful to me
than all the help from the Congress.
Bad General
Washington feeds his horses!
And your people too.
- "From La Fayette?"
- No.
Welcome, gentlemen.
Thank you sir.
My name is William Livingstone,
the elected congressman from New Jersey.
Congratulations!
And once again united in a new struggle:
Washington against the Congress,
La Fayette v. Versailles.
Poverty, sir...
The captain can not even buy a
pair of boots for his salary!
And loans for which
Congress votes?
They do not cost French gold.
French gold should serve
primarily France!
May your Majesty forgive me, but the
gold spent on one Versailles castle,
it would be enough to dress
the entire American army.
For my part, I will give all my fortune, until
the last lyroid, until the last centime!
Washington will be able to win
only if it has ships, more ships,
a soldier, a soldier,
money, more money!
Money, money, money...
I would like to remind you, sir,
But you must understand Congress!
Give us victory, we
will give you money!
Give me money, and
I will give you victory!
After Saratoga, much time passed.
And we're all waiting.
Are you waiting?
Waiting for what?
- When you start the attack!
- "Attack?" Where?
- I do not know where, but the attack!
- Attack to what?
- I do not know what. Attack!
- "Do not attack on an empty stomach, sir!"
Until cardinal changes occur,
my army will shrink
because of three things:
Hunger,
decomposition and flight.
And there's nothing to be done about it.
I think it's time to
inspect the troops, General!
American troops are not just Americans.
There is enough of everything.
For lack of reinforcements, Washington
has to take everyone in a row.
Adventurers for a long time can not
withstand deprivation and discipline.
This is disgusting!
How can you so neglect people?!
You said three battalions?
Where is the third?
- Where is the third battalion?
- "Here, sir."
Ah... where are the others?
They all deserted, sir!
My duty, sir, to report to Congress
sentences.
What exactly do you mean, sir?
I will propose to
change the higher command.
Do you have any wishes
that I could give to Congress?
Yes, there is.
Tell your beautiful congressmen that I'm not
fighting for them, but for the American people!
And that I will continue to do
this, whether they agree with me or not.
And I beg you to read this letter
from Mr. Benjamin Franklin to Congress.
Read them all, especially
the place where he says:
"Monsieur de La Fayette fights with all
zeal with the whole royal court for America."
Hmm, fighting against the
Versailles court should be very pleasant.
Pleasantness, sir, will be when La Fayette
will receive for us 60 million livres
and so we need reinforcements.
I'll give your letter
to Congress, General.
Despite my strong doubts about Mr.
Marquis...
and his well-known
wishes, issued for reality.
Have a nice day, sir!
You are also a good lawyer, monsieur.
We will send to Mr. Washington 4 thousand
people and 60 ships, as you asked.
Americans are also a
generous people, monsieur.
They will never forget the help of
France if France needs their help.
The help of America?
In any case, not in victory in the war.
In the war, monsieur.
Soldiers of freedom are the best of all.
Maybe.
But ours, being only
soldiers of the king...
must be under an experienced command.
This is the Count de Roshambo. He will
command the ground forces in America.
You understand, monsieur, that the king can not entrust
such responsibility to the 20-year-old lieutenant.
Let the general of the American army.
I can only command with
your help, monsieur.
Full and sincere.
But, maybe I broke
your ambitions?
I have no other ambitions
than to serve!
General, here I am!
And... not alone!
French fleet?
So does France have a fleet?
Do England want to take away not
only the colonies, but also the sea?
Under the command of Admiral Grass.
They say more about the
reinforcement of 4 thousand Frenchmen.
- For La Fayette?
- "Oh, no, sir."
Commander General de Roshambo.
The devil's a boy.
I prepared a surprise for him.
Does he like to run?
He will have to run very fast.
And this time he will not leave me.
Captain Spears, returned from Yorktown.
- What's the news, Spears?
- "The squadron has entered the Shakespeare Bay."
The frigate dropped anchor.
- French?
- "No, sir, English."
- You must have been mistaken!
- "I do not think so, sir."
General La Fayette himself saw the ships.
A lot of them.
English!
The situation is critical.
The ship's guns will get it.
He's waiting for your instructions.
Return to General La Fayette.
Tell them that Roshambo's army will step out
from the north, and mine from the west.
Without waiting for us,
General La Fayette is ordered
remove redoubt,
covering Yorktown.
But General La Fayette risks falling into
a vice between the English fleet and Cornwallis!
But like La Fayette himself, I'm
counting on the arrival of the French fleet.
Or Cornwallis will be blocked here,
or we will be broken...
Follow me!
We'll go along the
forest, behind the redoubt.
Let's go through my style.
It seems. They're going
to attack Phillips's position!
Strange idea!
What does Washington want to do?
The fleet anchored
in Shakespeare Bay.
If they capture our fleet, the
ship's guns will not be able to help us.
Perhaps this is a maneuver
to smoke you out of Yorktown, sir?
Look, they only
used a handful of people.
I agree. I will not move.
Washington and
Roshambo can not beat me.
I'll wait for their frontal attack.
Well, what?
This is General La Fayette, sir.
La Fayette?!
Damn boy!
Already here we are attacked?
What a smart one!
Maybe too smart!
Hoping to drive us,
like a chicken from a perch.
A will find a trap here.
Fire!
The situation of expensive
Phillips is complicated.
I hope he cope.
Behind me! To battle!
General La Fayette in a mousetrap!
Go!
On right! A company of grenadiers!
To battle!
This madman will break
his neck about my grenadiers.
Phillips killed his father La Fayette.
It's a shame if she kills her son.
Washington!
Sorry, sir, but
Yorktown is 3 miles away!
- Order to speed up the step.
- "Speed up the pace!"
Accelerate the step!
Turn the gun!
Gentlemen of the English,
accept my compliments!
Damn boy!
From our guns!
Let's go to the shelter.
I have no desire to be killed.
Especially English cannons!
Fire!
Look!
French or English?
Their minimum is 30.
This is an English squadron.
Sir!
The French fleet!
Gentlemen, this is the
greatest day of the war!
Yes it's de Grasse!
The French fleet!
Are they crazy?
This is the French squadron, sir.
French? And how many
ships do they have? Two? Three?
About 30, sir.
30?!
Sir! General
Roshambo's army surrounds us.
Behind me, Rangers!
I will not see the sea.
Be of good cheer, Kalb!
The carriages will soon arrive.
The orderlies!
There will never be a general Kalb.
Will be! Without us, we
would all be captured!
Got it?
You, who are so fond of freedom...
Marquis, I'll die
for this bitch too!
Yes, Kalb.
"You know that, do not you?"
Do not look at me anymore, Marquis.
Looks like this mousetrap...
was set for me.
On the shoulder!
Mission accomplished, Monsieur!
Weapons on the ground!
My sword, sir.
Until now, she
only knew victories.
I know that, sir.
We and our allies
are very proud of this.
Military fortune is capricious.
You broke the English general,
and I congratulate you on that.
But the English army does not give up.
The English army has always
shown us an example of fortitude.
But you have to admit that
we in America follow your example.
As for me, I hope,
this victory will put an end
to this brutal and unjust war.
Can I ask you a favor, sir?
Of course. About what?
General La Fayette?
Something I do not see it.
He kept slipping
away from me all the time.
Can I finally meet with him?
I think that this time...
he will wait for you.
I paid dearly for the
right to meet with you.
Can I ask you to
speak privately?
With pleasure, monsieur.
I always kept the hope of
receiving you in my tent.
I am always at my meetings, Mr.
La Fayette.
- Me too, sir.
- "Even on the unpleasant."
They made me run.
They undoubtedly
remembered how I love hunting.
Unfortunately,
as before, you killed.
You are to be congratulated.
Thank you sir.
But by the way, your success to a
large extent depended on my high command.
Lord Clinton will not let me win the battle
until he himself does not win at least one.
Then, probably, I
should congratulate you
with the fact that you lost this one?
Not so long the general
to understand such things.
Our army has always been
the strongest, as you know.
Only ours - more deserved.
No one will argue
with you, I'm sure.
But you were alone
against General Washington,
Count Roshambo, Count
de Grasse, Baron Vomenil...
And you!
Do not put yourself in the last place.
You were the most dangerous for us.
Is there anything
I can do for you?
Yes.
Please make sure that my soldiers, and
your prisoners, are treated like human beings.
You do not have to worry, sir.
Americans have been captured
for too long to abuse others badly.
Let me have one more word, sir.
Your army was not the strongest.
The strength of the army is not in
numbers, but in the case that it defends.
The war was not over yet, but the battle
at Yorktown turned out to be decisive.
The path to victory was opened.
And La Fayette could keep the way
to France with an easy heart.
Now, Mr. Marquis,
we are parting.
Victory brings and parting.
Nothing can separate the
front-line comrades.
Your wife, your children, your friends...
and glory... A lot of you are waiting.
And most importantly - France.
The uniform will change, but not the case.
The Lord made it so that
you were born a Marquis.
But each of us will
remember that freedom
was born Frenchwoman.
But she was taught to walk by America.
Without you, I would remain
an officer - a troublemaker,
a talker from a tavern.
Congress made me a general,
you are a soldier.
I hope you will come
back to us someday.
Yes. And perhaps the
ambassador of the new France.
Maybe.
But when? And will I still be here?
Farewell, son.
Good-bye, monsieur.
God bless you!
Thank you sir.
Thank you!
Damn the boy!
"I'm waiting for you.
You will return, I know.
But only when America's
independence is securely secured. "
It is done, beloved.
Independence is assured.
Mankind has won this process.
Freedom now has a
refuge on Earth.