WEB-DL / WEBRip / WEB
Duration: 1:39:01
FPS: 24
- Hey!
- What's going on?
What happened?
Are you okay?
Come on, I'll help you.
I'm fine.
Let's go to the hospital.
No, I'm fine. Just...
help me inside.
Who did this to you?
Those motherfuckers...
Gil was attacked.
What?
They beat him up.
- Gil, are you okay?
- Yes, I just need to sit down.
- Who was it?
- I don't know.
- Need help?
- No, I can manage.
Come to the kitchen.
Hawla, come to the kitchen.
Hawla, stop what you're doing
and come to the kitchen.
- Go see how Gil's doing.
- In a minute.
There's lots to do in the kitchen.
Go help out.
Okay, sit down here.
Shit...
- You're sure you don't want a doctor?
- Yes.
How awful.
They could've killed you.
Forget it...
It was all planned.
So you would help me.
Come here.
Are you cold?
Not anymore.
Asher,
don't bother,
we're not putting that one up.
What?
I told you, no soldiers on this wall.
Only the Resistance.
Put this up instead.
Don't move.
Finally!
So, how do you like it?
It's weird.
Can you explain to my friend Andre
what's the subject of this exhibition?
It's political art.
We believe it's very important
to raise awareness
on political issues through art.
Especially in those days, yes...
Nowadays...
Okay, take care.
What's going on?
- A little problem came up.
- Why isn't it ready?
He'll be here soon and we'll finish.
Honey, if you want to work in America
you have to be professional.
This is not professional.
You're right, it'll be ready soon.
- And where is the artist?
- He'll be here soon.
He's on his way, he'll be here.
- He can't wait to meet you.
- Likewise.
Okay, go finish up.
Make it fast.
Laila is the PR of the gallery
and tonight is the opening night.
It's great.
This way.
This is the best place in Haifa
to party.
It's super cool.
- Looks like Ali Baba's cave.
- It is.
Do we have to talk about it now?
I can't judge till I've heard all sides.
It's a matter of principle.
Speaking of principles...
how do you justify your lovers?
As if I've had that many...
Why are you asking?
Asking what?
Are you messing with me?
No question has only one answer.
What does that mean?
It's always the same.
People cling to a question
and don't let go.
It sucks.
When you act this way,
it's as if I don't exist.
Is this what your husband does, too?
Leave him out of it.
I'm also surprised
by how often my mood changes.
That's the only reason I asked.
You're impossible.
- Hey.
- Hi.
I was looking for you.
Naama, my sister.
Stepsister.
You don't really have a sister.
Figures you'd show up with a girl.
Laila, wait.
I have stuff to do.
Don't forget,
you have an exhibition tonight.
What's wrong?
Tomer and I no longer have sex.
I can't even remember
the last time.
I'm home with the kids all day.
He barely notices me,
he's always busy.
I'm a slave.
I can't stand what he writes,
and he can't forgive me for this.
Have you talked about it?
No.
I know all couples reach a point
where all that's left is family life,
but...
I don't care if he writes
and this drives him nuts.
A century ago, he would've learned
his father's trade
and become a carpenter,
but now he has to be a writer.
If he doesn't know
what he loves about me...
how can we build anything together?
I need a drink.
- Good evening.
- Hello.
- What do you want?
- A quick frisk before going in.
Nonsense! Do you know who I am?
- Of course.
- Really?
I have to frisk you
even if you own half of Haifa.
Just let me frisk you,
then you can go.
Arms up.
Go ahead.
This way, sir.
- Welcome.
- Hello.
Meeting someone?
- My wife.
- Go ahead.
Have you seen my wife?
What?
Who's your wife?
A lady helped me hang the pictures.
- Laila, the gallery owner.
- Laila's your wife?
Yes.
I see. She was here,
but I don't know where she went.
Maybe upstairs.
I don't think she's here.
Laila?
Last night I dreamt
I was climbing Mount Carmel.
I got dizzy and felt really sick.
So I told the person I was with:
"Let's not overdo it,
there's room for everyone in the valley".
Maybe you were there with me?
If you were king for a day,
what would you do?
Erase reality.
And how?
Dunno.
I haven't thought about that.
It's not you,
it's me,
I don't think it will work between us.
But I love you.
But I think we overrate the present.
The fact that we're together now,
for example...
we give it too much importance.
Is that all you have to say?
You wasted your energy on the exhibit.
Where were you?
- I looked everywhere.
- Some last minute issues.
You shouldn't have left me here,
..waiting like a fool.
- Relax.
Did you see the photos?
Go look at them in the gallery.
Some are really nice,
I think you'll like them.
Do you hate Israelis?
I don't speak Hebrew.
Sometimes I wouldn't mind
seeing them all croak,
sometimes not.
I have other things to think about.
They say love and hate are alike.
And wouldn't you?
Wouldn't you hate Israelis
if they kept you in prison,
if they locked you up
and humiliated you?
If they forced you
to see your mother, father,
sister, the man you love,
your children, die?
Or go crazy day after day,
year after year,
generation after generation?
I don't think I have the right
to say you're wrong.
Of course not, you're Israeli.
Maybe we have more reasons
to complain than you.
It's no "maybe", of course you do.
Then have some compassion.
You want too much, too much.
Look, the difference between...
what happens inside us
and what happens outside,
is so big
and the space in between...
we pay a tremendous price for it.
The life we live
is so full of nuances
and it's marked by an endless struggle
between good intentions,
good wishes,
and evil thoughts, evil deeds.
Imagine if you did
what you said you'd do,
and then you realize...
you regret it,
it's not what you meant to do.
You'd be super sorry for that.
Maybe it would change you,
maybe...
it would make you be a different person.
You said that.
Okay...
Have a good night.
You, too.
Do you really think
this gallery makes sense?
Of course.
The fact that it exists proves
how much this initiative is needed.
What today is worth devoting
all one's energy to?
The time of the great epochs...
has passed.
Religion?
Why not?
And other than religion,
the nation, the State...
science, culture? No, no.
That leaves the arts.
But nowadays, it feels like everything
has been done already.
Don't look always to the past.
I agree.
We give too much importance
to too many things.
Bye-bye, my friend.
I have a proposal for you.
I'm going to open a gallery in L.A.
I would like to show your work.
Doesn't sound like
you have much to gain.
It's not a question of money.
The money it'll cost
is nothing compared to
what I wish to gain.
To gain from me?
I don't hear that often.
Your personality is what interests me.
My personality?
- I have a question for you.
- Go ahead.
What's in it for Laila?
Money?
I heard you want to use her connections
to buy land in Ramallah.
No offense,
but if you and I intend to work together,
we should be honest from the beginning.
Do you always believe rumors?
In this country, we have the means
to know everything about everyone.
I know.
Indeed, I've spoken some business
to some people.
Listen, Laila doesn't know
about your plan.
She thinks
that she's your only interest.
My only interest is to promote
Palestinian art and culture,
and your exhibition
could be very interesting
to the American audience
and sponsors.
Bullshit.
Your only interest
is to promote yourself.
Not a clever thing to say.
I'll think about your proposal.
I say, if you're thinking of something
then just do it.
You're weird.
Sometimes,
it feels like my thoughts come out
then return,
as if I was in the bedroom
with the door shut.
There are days
when everything around me is clear,
when it's easy to go out of myself
and go somewhere else.
But there are days
when I feel closed in
and everything
becomes sad, suffocating.
What kind of day is today?
Dunno.
I'm not sure.
You should do what you have to do.
Not just talk about it.
You say just let it happen,
but it's more dangerous to let it happen
than to make it happen.
Fathi...
I once had a friend...
he was so messed up
and I felt like he...
just wanted someone to touch him.
Not in a sexual way,
though that could've happened too,
but it seemed like he needed a hug.
And that night, I'll never forget...
He needed someone.
I lay down next to him
and looked at his back,
but didn't touch him.
I couldn't sleep a wink.
Then he decided to die.
I'm tormented by the thought
that I could've done something,
if I had only hugged him.
I was afraid he would misinterpret
the situation, I don't know...
I couldn't save him.
Bon!
It's a full house.
What's wrong?
What are you staring at?
Want a sip?
Too bad.
It's all gone.
Now I want it even more.
Funny, the things we want most
are the hardest to obtain.
You know what, Hawla?
I don't know...
I don't know what you mean,
but I do know one thing:
you shouldn't make things
so complicated.
Enjoy life a little.
Nature, kids...
Kids give us stability.
I disagree.
- Yusef.
- Yes, bro?
Keep an eye on the pan.
- Hey!
- How's it going, boss?
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
- Good.
Hawla, look at me.
What do I look like?
A lawyer?
An artist?
A politician?
You're overdoing it, aren't you?
Well?
Maybe a photographer?
Why, what does a photographer
look like?
Nobody looks like what they are,
except religious people.
Nothing is stable, everything changes.
There are no more answers,
no more feelings.
Just opinions and half-truths.
Know what I mean?
I like it that way.
Really?
Everything is stuck,
not just you.
No big deal.
It just means people don't know
what to think or do.
I think that's a good thing.
I want to go look for hafafish.
- What is hafafish?
- Bats.
Bats? Now?
You never know...
Gimme a kiss.
A little one.
Hey, hey, Fathi, Fathi.
Fathi, what's wrong?
We have to stop seeing each other.
What?
Why?
Because I can't be seen with you.
You know I don't give a damn
about what people think.
You know that.
- Don't you get it?
- What?
They can't touch you,
they'll take it out on me.
I'd never let anyone hurt you.
- You know that.
- Stop it.
They'll come get you first,
then me.
Stop it, enough.
Don't think about it.
Stop worrying
about what might happen and live.
Want to live in this moment?
Want to kiss me?
Well?
Relax.
Look at her... Josephine.
You might not know,
but Josephine thinks she's a saint.
But believe me...
she's dying from her sins.
Do you think I'm like Josephine?
Meaning the way a sculpture
is like a piece of wood?
Wow.
Nice.
You know, at times when I'm invited
to social events,
I feel like a person who walks out
before the last scene, you know?
Into a dark space,
leaving behind a hat, a cane,
and a play.
Fathi, you'll be leaving me
in a few days.
How will I deal with my issues?
We can be together.
Just... give me your hand.
Let's go.
Explain to me
why you sent an Israeli photographer...
I'm talking to you.
An Israeli photographer to America
on behalf of the gallery?
What were you thinking?
Use your head.
It could help the gallery.
I told you not to meddle in politics
without talking to me first.
I will, but you're overreacting.
There's a big difference
between promoting the Palestinian cause
and promoting an Israeli photographer.
Know how many messages I've gotten
from interested clients?
Gil is famous
and Roberta is respected worldwide.
Roberta? Her?
You're so shallow.
Hani.
Hani?
- Whisky, please.
- Right away.
- Hello, Gil.
- Hello.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Cheers.
Gil...
can you tell me
what my wife sees in Roberta?
Maybe...
she can help her with her career.
I don't know...
Other ideas?
Maybe she has an artistic side.
A women like that has an artistic side?
Ever notice how many people
talk to themselves on the street?
There's something wrong with them.
Whatever they can't swallow,
they spit out.
With some people, the need to create
works the same way.
I think there is something wrong with her.
When you're as rich as her,
why not be an artist?
You didn't want to be an artist,
did you?
Not really.
Never.
I just documented
the lives of others.
To you.
To life.
I wanted to tell you something.
At one point in life,
everything you do is for someone else.
The sun shines only for him,
he's everywhere and you're nowhere.
But yet, you don't do it
because you expect that person
to feel exactly the same way.
Until, in end, those two people...
almost cease to exist.
They exist, but only for each other
and all that remains
is a world for the two of them,
where there's nothing
but mutual encouragement,
devotion,
friendship,
and total self-sacrifice.
Fill it up.
More?
Enough.
- Listen to this song...
- Go ahead.
Kiss me, Hani, Hani, kiss me...
You and your nonsense!
- I found a bottle...
- Hush.
- Full of water.
- Enough.
- Hi.
- Hello.
- Can I get a mixed Martini?
- Sure.
Mixed with what?
Dunno, that's what it's called.
What's it mixed with, Hani?
Lemon, bro.
Lemon.
Not working tomorrow?
No, tomorrow is Saturday.
Right.
Silly me.
No, thanks.
You don't smoke?
Sometimes when I drink.
You drink often?
No, I don't like drinking alone.
- Majd.
- Naama.
- Nice to meet you.
- Likewise.
Thanks.
- Cheers.
- Look me in the eye!
- I did.
Why are you here alone?
I came to see the exhibition.
It's my brother's work.
First time here?
I was born here.
Here?
Not right here, but in Haifa.
- In a hospital.
- I figured.
I think you're really sweet.
You're really sweet, too.
Laila, where did you go tonight?
And the night tells me:
"Give my regards to Laila"
Love is not sweet
Unless Laila sings tonight...
- You don't understand, do you?
- No.
- But it's nice.
- Thanks.
Were you warned about the Arabs
you'd meet in Haifa?
I've never been afraid of Arabs.
They're no different from other men.
You know what bothers me?
The way my husband looks at me.
Because he loves you.
He can't wait
for everything I've done to flop.
He's worried about you.
He's not a fan of Roberta.
She only looks out for herself.
Roberta thinks her reputation
can help us both.
Of course.
She says that because she's rich.
All she cares about is fame.
Why?
Because she can.
What do you have against her?
Nothing.
You seem bitter.
You're never happy with anything.
Roberta told me
you turned down her offer.
She's a liar.
I didn't say yes or no.
All you do is criticize.
She could get us both
out of this shithole.
Where were you?
I went for a walk.
Listen, Gil...
I don't want to step on my wife's toes,
but between you and me...
do you think this is a good idea?
When politics falls into the hands
of amateurs
it's very dangerous.
That Roberta is odd, isn't she?
Who does she think she is?
If you loved your homeland...
- Then?
- What?
Then what?
If I loved my homeland then what?
I'd find a way.
A covert way out
that my wife wouldn't notice.
- Nobody takes me seriously here.
- That's not true.
Everyone here thinks
you're an excellent photographer.
You know what keeps the Middle East going?
- More or less.
- People like me.
You see what's happening,
do you call that balanced?
I'm leaving.
What do you want?
Kamal Khadr.
Mr. Leech?
Do I look like a leech to you?
You don't look like Mr. Leech.
Range Rover.
You look like someone
who has it all.
Thanks to my hard work.
Can't a man enjoy
what he's worked hard for?
Some work, and some shed blood.
Must be a fancy car.
What did it cost?
Don't push your luck,
give me back my keys.
How much did it cost?
Kid...
Watch out.
How much?
Enough!
Sometimes, I regret my life.
That's the only thing you can't do.
Unlike you, I haven't done much yet
so I have nothing to regret.
You have no idea how that feels.
It's an unpleasant situation.
Nobody has the right
to deny the burden of life,
to deny the fact
that we're all doomed.
If life were short
and mostly empty...
You never listen when I try
to tell you something important.
Know how many times I've felt fear...
growing inside of me,
when I wasn't paying attention?
Suddenly, I've realized
how different we are.
If something is bothering you
it's not my fault.
What really bothers you are my opinions
about the morals of this generation.
You'd probably disappoint me
if I asked you to be more ethical.
Let me tell you something...
if you asked me
for an open relationship,
I would disappoint you.
A decision like this
requires some preparation.
That's how I see it.
You still haven't told me
how much this car costs.
Get out.
One million?
50,000?
100,000 at most.
What do you want, money?
100? 200? 300?
That's all I have on me.
Listen, honey,
we're like an insurance agency.
The only difference is,
we set fire to the property
of those who aren't smart enough
to buy our insurance.
What do you want?
How much is this car worth?
- What?
- How much is it worth?
It's used.
Sure.
It's nothing special.
I beg to differ.
And...
it loses half its value
with every passing year.
How long have you had it?
Three and a half years.
That's 60,000.
What?
The carburetor's ruined,
the tires are worn down. Maybe 20,000.
Give me a break.
It's a gem.
40,000.
What?
- Fine, who's it for?
- The Palestinian Resistance.
That's too much!
We use the money
to buy weapons,
to pay the fighters,
and if they die,
to help their families,
their wives and children.
Fine, I'll write you a check.
Want a receipt, too?
I really don't have any cash on me.
Okay, I believe you.
Who do I make it out to?
To the nightclub.
And watch what you do.
Get out now.
How dare you threaten me?
Get out!
Now!
You got off easy this time.
We need to talk.
Did Hisham send you?
He's desperate.
He wants a baby but...
I don't.
Then no it is.
But it'll kill him.
Or me.
You'll be fine.
Even when we're old and wrinkly,
Hisham's face will be young and fresh.
Even if his hair goes white.
He thinks he has to protect me.
That's why he thinks
I need to get pregnant.
He'll say that good mothers
take care of their children,
but he'll raise them with his principles.
He wants me to belong only to him.
He wants to turn us into
a ridiculous bourgeois couple.
I'm his whole world.
But I'd rather have your baby.
I can't betray a friend.
Am I moving too fast?
You're not attracted to me?
You like me, I know it.
I can tell by how you look at me
when you come over.
You try to keep your cool
and tell yourself
you don't betray friends.
But hundreds of times you've thought:
"I'd love to fuck Hawla".
You should've...
You should've used your lying mouth
for more than just talk.
Hawla, you don't want to do this.
You shouldn't do it.
I don't understand you.
It's simple.
Fine,
I won't keep you.
Don't tell Hisham, okay?
It'll be our secret.
Hisham!
What's up?
Come here, shithead.
What are you doing?
Hawla.
What's gotten into you?
Hawla, what are you doing?
What's wrong?
- Calm down, calm down.
- Leave me alone.
You'll regret that.
I'm sorry.
Come here...
Stay away!
Hawla, calm down.
Sorry, sorry...
I didn't mean to.
Calm down, come here.
Come here.
It's all right, honey.
I'm sorry.
Trust me,
the political system today
is like a bad play,
same old characters, same old stories,
same old plots.
But if you change the backdrop,
the crowds always clap.
Absurd.
Disagreeing with him again?
You contradict everything he says.
I didn't mean to.
You want to have a baby,
but in a world like this,
do you have the right to have a child
or is it just the animal instinct talking?
- Is something wrong?
- No.
Everything and nothing can be said
without saying anything.
Just like what you do.
When I was 15,
my uncle and Salma...
- Who is Salma?
- Salma is my friend.
She and my uncle
were crazy about each other.
They always met up secretly.
She was proud of her actions
but ashamed around me.
Know what I mean?
More or less.
- How far did she go?
- She never told me.
But my uncle was 15 years older.
I doubt she went very far.
Maybe not, but...
in any case, when my father found out,
he sent her to Europe.
You should've seen my uncle.
He...
wandered day and night,
doing nothing.
He got old, lost his youth.
One day, I was in my bed
when the door opened.
I knew it was him.
He stood by the door
and said my name.
He had a sweet voice.
He made a strange sound...
like a crying baby.
Ever hear a sound like that?
No.
He was crying without tears.
Then he suddenly leapt onto my bed.
He put his head next to mine,
I felt his hand...
moving across my body.
I...
just stayed there and didn't move.
I felt helpless.
He touched my face with one hand and...
my breasts with the other.
He tried to kiss me but I pulled away.
He was a much older man,
I was just a kid,
I was strong enough to stop him but...
I did nothing.
And I hated myself for this.
He stroked my hair
and left without saying a word.
Your opinions have taken root in us...
and have imprisoned us for life.
You're all liars.
You want to see us broken
and play with us like puppets.
If we don't wake up now,
it will just be another case...
of murder.
And the next victim could be me.
Leave us alone for once.
If you weren't showing off your body,
nothing would've happened.
I bet you provoked him.
What are you doing out so late?
Where are your brothers?
I don't know what'll become of me.
They threaten me, nobody believes me.
I'm ashamed to tell them about me.
I have nowhere to go.
I was kicked out of my home.
I feel like
they're watching my every move.
I feel like I'm suffocating.
I'm afraid no one can help me.
Last night...
I dreamt Hawla was climbing
up a ladder.
Suddenly...
Suddenly, I lost my balance.
The ladder slipped from my hands,
I tried to grab it.
She fell.
She fell on her back
like Christ on the cross.
You should take her to a doctor.
She's changed lately.
I'm worried.
I don't want her to die.
Hisham,
she needs someone to take care of her
and listen to her.
Amir?
- No.
- Sorry.
Excuse me... Amir?
- No.
- No?
- Gila?
- Yes.
- Amir?
Thanks.
- How are you?
- Good evening.
- I'm nervous.
I thought you'd be... younger.
- Younger?
- Yes.
I thought you'd be more Jewish.
Sorry.
- A drink?
- What?
Sorry, my Hebrew sucks,
can I speak in English?
Okay.
What do you do in life?
I'm a widow.
I buried my husband, thank God.
No, I mean, I was very sad.
He died a year ago and...
- I'm sorry.
- Why? You didn't kill him!
It's not your fault.
- A toast!
- Cheers.
- Sakha sahkten, as you say.
- Sahkten.
What do you do?
I'm a rapper.
- Rap? In Arabic?
- Yeah.
Let me hear something.
You're a senior, unlike me
I've always loved rap,
for you it's just a dream...
Wow, that's kind of scary!
Do you improvise, too?
No.
- You know, on the spot.
- I understand.
Amir, Amir, Amir
Where are you, Amir?
I came looking for you, Amir
And couldn't find you, Amir
And you surprised me, Amir
And I surprised you, Amir
- Cheers to us...
- Cheers.
To a fun night
Where are you, Amir?
Where?
- Where?
- Right here.
Where?
See?
Where are you, Amir?
I can sing, too.
- Sure.
- Yes.
I leave nearby if you want to come.
- Nearby?
- Yes.
Yes?
Okay and...
Okay, but first
I need to use the bathroom. Okay?
Sure.
I need to powder my nose.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Okay, I'm here.
- I'm here.
Bye-bye.
This film is dedicated
to the memory of Gideon Gitai
Subtitles:
Laser S. Film s.r.l. - Rome