CHAPTER ONE: ABBRACCIO
THE MEANING OF THE WORD "HUG" -
WRAP YOUR ARMS AROUND SOMEONE
EXAMPLE: NEED A HUG
OR: UNION WITH THEM,
WHO WILL LEAD YOU TO RUIN
EXAMPLE: DEATH GRIP
TWO MONTHS EARLIER
Thank you!
- Well, how many?
- About 30.
- Next time, 15.
- But it was almost 300!
Oh, shit!
Love Seacret magazine prints out
in two days, and I need the answers tomorrow.
Why did I say yes?
Actually, since you've been on it,
"You can't tell your heart to do what you want."
the most fashionable column ever!
Everyone needs Gabriel Garcia Marquez's advice.
You should read his books
and look for answers in them,
not a magazine article.
Come on.
Why do you want printouts
and not an e-mail?
There's only three of us
who know I'm doing this column.
But it won't be for long, hopefully.
- All right, I'll see you tomorrow.
- See you tomorrow.
ROMAN BREAKUPS
- Good evening!
- Good evening.
Franco!
I'll leave my bike here?
- Yeah, leave it, I'll put it away later.
- Uh, okay.
What a nice young man!
Do you live here?
Signora, I'm Tommaso.
Tommaso Rosso, entrance B, apartment 8.
B, apartment 8...
What a coincidence! Look who's here!
Former tenant from apartment 8-B,
Spanish!
- Good evening, ma'am!
- Good evening, my dear.
Nice to meet you, Tommaso.
Zoé.
Did you know that you both lived
in the same apartment?
What sign are you?
- Taurus.
That's a great sign!
- Both of you.
- Mom, leave people alone!
Uh, excuse me.
- Okay, Franco, it's nothing.
- Bye.
- You speak Italian?
- A little.
- You speak Spanish?
You're back from vacation?
I was on a business trip.
Three weeks in Tokyo.
Tokyo?
I love Tokyo.
I have a collection of... What are they called?
Comic books, Japanese manga.
Really? I love them.
Do you want to see them?
Just like that, huh?
Can you show me the way?
Thank you.
It's a beautiful house!
It's marvelous!
Thank you.
So it's really a comic book story?
You thought it was an excuse?
I don't know.
Sorry, it's a little messy.
It's okay.
Would you like something to drink?
I don't mind.
Who is this woman?
That's my wife.
Is that a problem?
Not at all.
- No?
- No.
No?
Welcome back!
Shall we celebrate?
What are we celebrating, Tom?
My flight?
I'm a wreck.
Let's celebrate your return for now,
and I found some great apartments,
that you should check out,
so you can stop spending a lot of money,
to rent your "marvelous" house.
What did you decide about the novel?
If they want to print it,
the ending will be what it is.
The only reason I'm not giving up
because the last book didn't work out.
I know you don't agree.
If that's what you decide,
I guess you're sure.
I guess so.
White or red?
It's up to you.
Uh, no, I don't care.
White.
I'm saying how is it possible
to end an epic couple story
with such romantic nonsense?
This fic idea, what with the happy ending.
books sell better...
I think it's funny.
No?
Giuseppe, I won't change the ending,
you don't have to insist, no,
I'm not gonna change the ending.
I get it, I know "Blue Carpet" didn't work,
I've heard that one,
it's not because he's sad.
Okay? So, uh.
Look, there's no point in insisting
the finale stays as it is.
You know the terms,
and if you hear anything, you call me.
Bye.
Maybe you should give up.
Good morning.
Listen, while you were in Tokyo,
I saw that there are some great apartments for sale
some great apartments for us.
- They're smaller, but, uh.
- I'm sorry.
Mr. Takeshi?
- Zoya!
- "Yes." I'm gone.
- Good morning, Nina.
- Welcome back, Zoya.
- How are you?
- Fine, thanks, and you?
All right. Uh-huh.
A report on the demo of Global Hunters.
Thank you.
Compared to last week,
only six percent of the players
were able to complete the level.
That's good news, isn't it?
Is that good news?
Last week it was ten percent.
Come with me, Nina.
Hey, everybody! How's it going?
Hello.
Does anyone know why, in 1978.
100 yen coins disappeared in Japan?
And the government had to
to mint four times as many?
No?
No one?
"Space Invaders."
The 100 yen coin was needed
for the "Space Invaders" game,
the most massive game in history.
Everyone played it:
children,
adults, the whole family.
Losing our heads to get there
until the last, fastest.
and invincible alien.
And everyone wanted a 100 yen coin,
to beat him,
all of them.
But only three percent were able to do so.
Three, Nina, not six.
It's 100 yen, my souvenir from Tokyo.
May he help you, good job.
15 more.
I haven't even looked at the others.
Well, you read it.
"Sunbeam 48: Hey, Marquez.
I have known orgasm, but not with my husband."
No.
"I hate her.
I don't just want to leave her,
I want her to suffer,
hooked on psychotropic drugs.
Or worse:
let her have cellulite."
- Advice?
- No, no, none.
No.
"I'm 38, have a young son.
I want a divorce.
I don't care about the theories
that love changes shape.
- I want to fuck."
- Here.
- "And not just at Christmas."
- Of course it is.
I can't watch this.
"Andre88:
"Hey, my girlfriend's always
shoving socks in my mouth..."
Fuck it!
There are boundaries.
"We've been married for almost 40 years,
and 14 of them are trying to get a divorce.
But at the end of the day, we're still together."
How do you see it?
How do I see it?
You should see a psychoanalyst for treatment,
instead of writing in a journal.
Give it to me.
"Hey Marquez, life tyrannizes and hurts..."
Oh, my God!
"Hi Marquez, my girlfriend..."
This, in general, could be ....
"Hey Marquez, I don't..."
CHAPTER TWO: FINE
THE MEANING OF THE WORD "END" IS
FINAL PART OF SOMETHING
EXAMPLE: WORK IN PROGRESS
OR: COMPLETION OF SOMETHING
EXAMPLE: THE END HAS COME
Hey, Marquez,
I'm not Italian.
I'm 35 years old, I have a great
job and an Italian man.
We met in Rome.
My sister came here
on a student exchange
and ended up living here.
And when I could, I decided to come to her.
I didn't think I'd stay long,
but I've been living with him for almost ten years.
But as of late, I've been having a crisis.
And after 40 days,
we've been at home together,
I'm not sure how I feel anymore.
and I don't know what to do.
I don't know if I love him anymore,
and I can't figure out if it's
affection, friendship, or something else?
I've always dumped all my loved ones on my own
and I've seen them suffer.
And I don't want him to suffer either.
I'm confused.
How do I know how I feel about him?
On the 27th, we'll be ten years together,
and I need to decide that sooner.
- Zoya.
- Hey, Tom.
I'm gonna be late at the office.
I won't be able to stop by the house.
I'll see you right at Nello's, okay?
All right. Uh-huh.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, yeah...
Oh, that's great.
- I'll see you later.
- Okay, bye.
Omar?
- Is that wine again?
- Okay, it's for her.
For God's sake!
A little bit, please!
Are we having a vacation here?
Gianni and Simone are in the lead this time,
they have 224 points.
- Well done, my love!
- Sweetie.
You're unbearable!
Only you will awaken in me
homophobic instinct!
Daddy!
He's right.
In my country, you wouldn't even be allowed
you wouldn't even be allowed in a restaurant like this.
You don't have restaurants like that in your country, nigger.
You can't say "nigger."
No, he's allowed,
because he's a half-nigger himself.
Well, half a negro...
I'm beige, to be sure!
Even though they haven't won anything
in the last five years,
Tommaso and Zoya when she gets here,
came in a respectable second place.
I'm sorry...
- Ah, there she is!
- It's finally here!
- How did you get here?
- It's about time!
And in third place.
is me and my princess,
but with an excellent prospect
of going up, right, honey?
I'm not a princess.
Me and my... chef.
Then, I'm not yours, I'm mine.
Bravo, Viola!
Rebel!
How do you say "explotación infantil"?
- "Exploitation of minors."
- Exactly.
It's not exploitation, it's tax avoidance.
He's paying, but in black cash.
And then there's everyone else on the list,
like Omar and Valerie,
they used to walk side by side,
but this year has been disappointing.
The Senegalese trebuchet was horrible.....
- Agreed.
- The inexorable decline of straight people.
Well, at least you've got rhythm in your blood.
Hey, man, it's not just that.
Affirmative.
You're rude.
They still make jokes about pussy,
like little kids.
Let's wait to see what they come up with
Héléna and Humberto will come up with,
and in the meantime, pass me the wine.
Now that's a really good one!
Okay, repeat the presentation.
We're having asparagus pate as an appetizer.
with oranges.
Orange peel, peel.
Orange peel
and sea bass burgers.
- No, that's sea bass.
- It's sea bass.
I said it's sea bass,
I went to the market, not you.
- It's the same thing, Umberto.
- It's not the same...
Okay, I'll get back to you later.
- Are you done eating that thing?
- Here they are, easy, easy.....
So, are you ready?
For an appetizer today.
would like to offer you
asparagus pâté
orange peeled
and fish bisque.
However!
From the perch, to be exact.
And the second one is simple, but with a new twist,
because, as Nello teaches us,
if you make it new,
you could sell it for twice as much.
And it's the beef that's...
We have to go.
I'm sorry, unfortunately,
it's an emergency, I need to get back to city hall.
It's really important, I'm sorry.
Daughter, mommy has an emergency,
and she has to go to work.
I'll see you tomorrow, right?
- Bye. Bye.
- Bye, daughter.
- Bye, guys.
- Bye. Bye.
Don't tell her "tomorrow" if it's not tomorrow.
Sorry again!
- Have fun!
- Bye!
Well...
Here's our dish, I'll get the rest.
Did you vote the right way?
He cheated off you?
Let's do the math, shall we?
You didn't even say hello to me.
- Yeah.
- Hey, you two!
There are children here!
Sorry, there's a couple gay guys here,
illegal immigrant, fat guy,
and your problem is,
is that I said hello to my wife?
- Viola...
- With his wife.
We've been together ten years,
can you say "wife"?
What else should I call you?
Roommate, partner?
Zoé?
Okay, Zoya.
No, Zoe.
Spain - Italy: 2 - 1.
And now for the final tally.
Come on, princess, summarize.
It's that princess again!
39.
О, 39!
Humberto, basically,
except for the bickering,
the result tastes great!
An altercation?
Well, for a couple, bickering
it's normal, isn't it?
- Yeah, it's revitalizing.
- It sure does!
- If there's a relationship.
- Well, you need distance, too.
Are we done with the rhetorical phrases?
Look at them!
They are always together and never fight.
Or maybe in a video game...
something unexpected happens?
It's an artificial intelligence dream come true.
The problem is, what exactly
that drives the human mind
to push the boundaries?
Curiosity.
Ah...the best game is a precise calculation.
So your video game can't anticipate
anticipate any more than you do?
Thankfully, no.
I'm sleeping, okay?
I'm very tired.
Good night.
CHAPTER THREE: PIANO
MEANING OF THE WORD: SLOW
EXAMPLE: GO SLOW
OR: "PLAN" IS A STRATEGY
RESULT ACHIEVEMENT
EXAMPLE: HE HAD A PLAN
Dear Zoya, I read your letter,
but I decided not to respond publicly.
In order to do that, I'm gonna need
a little more of your story.
Marquez.
I didn't wait for an answer.
I've never written in a magazine
and I don't know what it's like.
So why did you text me?
"Living with someone for over seven years
can be an act of great
heroism... or great cowardice.
It's up to you to decide what it is."
My bad, those are my words.
That sentence struck me,
and I wrote to you,
just like that, without thinking.
Did you meet another man?
- Zoya!
- I'm sorry it's so late.
Tom, you left
a bunch of hair in the sink again.
It's for the hundredth time, even on a toothbrush!
- Going to work already?
- Yes, the Japanese.
They're long awake. Put it away!
How much work do these Japanese people do...
- I'll clean it up later.
- You'll clean it up later, yeah.
Then...
No, no one else.
It's just me.
Don't look, there's two paparazzi outside.
Even here, I'm being watched.
Why are you here?
Did you see what Nello had?
I can't take it anymore!
I did, but it was an emergency.
Always an emergency, every day!
She's the mayor, Umberto,
and we're a pretty complicated town.
You should put yourself in my shoes.....
- Excuse me, can I take a selfie?
- Uh, yeah, sure.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I'm taking selfies.
Do you understand? In selfies!
I can't take another two years of this.
What if she goes to the polls again?
Ten years of this kind of life is not for me!
I think it's really time to break up.
- I don't understand.
- What?
I don't understand how anyone could ever think
to break up with someone
so suddenly.
What are you talking about, Tommaso,
don't you understand how I live now?
- No.
- I don't want that anymore.
What do you want?
I'd like to talk to Helena,
not her press office.
Understand, I'm certainly proud that she's the mayor of Rome.....
And I can even understand
that this is a difficult time for the city,
and I don't want to get in her way, but I can't do it anymore!
Have you thought about how Matilda will suffer?
Of course, yes, I'm always thinking about her.
- But I'm going to teach her an important lesson.
- What's that?
"Put yourself first,
and if you're unhappy somewhere,
you can take your life in your hands and walk away,
even from an unhappy marriage."
Is your marriage unhappy?
Not unhappy, it's no longer a marriage.
Lucky you, you're having a good time with Zoey.
- Coffee?
- Yeah.
Before I give you any advice,
tell me about your boyfriend.
What's he like?
Personality, irony, sex?
"Personality on a C.
Irony is a C-plus.
Sex is a three with two minuses..."
What's three with two minuses?
She gave me a report card!
А?
Uh, no, no, nothing.
Avocado and tuna or salmon and kelp?
- Me...
- "I don't care."
Listen, you've been weird lately.
But...is there a problem?
You never ask me questions like that.
Because you're not usually weird.
I have problems at work, that's all.
You talk to me about work
you only tell me about the problems.
There's a little more now, Tom.
You faked an orgasm with me?
I'm sorry?
Just asking.
Am I having an orgasm with you?
I don't think so.
So, no.
Have the gentlemen chosen yet?
- Yeah, salmon and kelp.
- Me, too.
How did you come up with the idea
to write to the magazine?
You don't even dare admit it to me.
Zoya,
your letter came to me.
Tom!
Do you want to try
two-player mode with me?
There's something wrong with the demo.
Yes...
Yes?
- You ready?
- Moment.
- I'm ready.
- Let's go.
Seriously?
What are you doing?
If you kill me, it's over, hello!
Help from you.
I'm sorry.
And Frangipane's antics today?
Shall we discuss it, or what?
I'm speechless, speechless!
What did I say?
No, Giulio, I'm sorry,
only emotional education
can defeat gender-based violence today,
not the police, I'm sorry.
Oh, yeah!
We need to change course, Giulio!
Of course!
To this day, schools still have a soccer field.
The boys play,
and the girls sit and watch!
At most, they walk on a tire
or playing classics!
That's right, yes!
That's what I'm saying, let's take action.
Let's get the principals involved, the parents ...
And talk about equal opportunity.
Of course!
We need witnesses, okay.
Let's take a poll, yes.
Let's hurry up,
because if this keeps up,
I don't know how long I can hold out.
Yeah, okay.
See you tomorrow, thanks, bye.
"My family is a family in reverse.
Daddy cooks, does my homework with me,
drying my hair
and reads me bedtime books.
I love my daddy very much,
and my mom, too, even though she's often not home.
She often works on television.
She's very famous,
and my dad is very kind.
It's the other way around in the family
of my friend Vittoria,
because her dad is
is a very famous actor,
and my mom is a very kind woman."
You see?
Men are changing at last, aren't they?
What's this girl's mom doing?
- I want to write to her, she's very--
- She's the mayor of Rome.
А...
- Matilda's essay?
- Yes.
See, she's a smart and modern girl,
because writing these things is no small thing....
Helena, that's not the point
of our daughter's essay.
But that's exactly the point, sorry.....
No, try going beyond the words,
listen to what's in there.
Umberto, the point is exactly the point,
that our daughter will not spend
wait her whole life for Prince Charming,
who's gonna bring her this.
I've been wearing them since this morning and my legs are tired.
What's that got to do with it?
I'm telling you, Matilda
is trying to tell you something else.
I'm sorry...
Vanya, did you read Bernabei's interview?
Why does he keep
challenging the pedestrian zone?
It's already decided!
Of course!
Cook rice for the signora?
- Thanks, Gladys, I'll do it.
- ...pedestrian zone.
Bernabei always does
what he wants, sorry, Vanya!
All right, that's enough.
Watching you put
your book in front of others,
incredibly sad!
Everyone does it, even famous writers.
And what's that?
What have you decided with Helena?
Break up with her.
Humberto, you've been together 20 years,
How can you let a marriage go to waste like that?
I don't know what's gotten into everybody.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, I am.
We just have to find a way
that doesn't hurt Helena's public image.
And I... I don't know how to say this.
You already asked me that,
I don't know what to tell you
to tell you or advise you.
Well, you spend every week
advising strangers
always something true, precise, subtle,
and you can't say
a few words to your best friend?
It's not like that when it comes to you.
I respond to strangers.
And I still don't understand
why you would do something so stupid.
- Well, I'll give you the reasons why.
- Go ahead.
First of all, I'm in the public eye now,
including physically.
Second, she's talking crap
about male emotional emancipation.
Third, I do everything
that a mom should do.
I have seven more of these items, shall I continue?
No, what's the problem,
embarrassed to be a "pama"?
No, don't say that word,
"pama" is a sexist expression.
I said that once
and I fought with Helena for three days.
I'm a father.
And it's not about what I do,
it's about what I don't do anymore,
starting with sex, that's four,
and, from a prostate perspective,
that can't be underestimated either.
Fifth, I'm not a husband anymore.
Sixth, I'm no longer a teacher,
which has serious consequences.
Seven, that the students don't know
who Italo Calvino is.
Now do you understand my situation?
Here you go.
Listen, Humberto.
If you could anonymously
ask Helena about your relationship,
what would you ask?
I don't get it, what do you mean?
If you could
get her to confess something,
not knowing that she's admitting it to you.
Like, if she's cheating on you
or if she still loves you, I don't know.
What would you ask?
Tommaso, I don't understand shit.
Well, I'd ask Ellena....
I'd ask her if she was happy.
Or unhappy, as I am now.
The problem with the fourth mission.
And on top of all the glitches,
the fact that you can so easily
to kill your playmate is, uh.
Yes, that's right, in connection with this.....
No, there should at least be
the controller vibrating.
But what we wanted to do, Zoya.
We have to make it more unstable, okay?
We're a few days away from the 27th,
and I want to meet you.
You want to play a game?
I work with games.
So it all depends on the game.
Write me something
that you hate about him.
It's a beautiful song, isn't it?
- Esther!
- Hey!
- How are you, sister?
- Hello, daughter-in-law!
- Hello, son-in-law.
- Flavio!
- So, how are you?
- How's your stomach?
- It's good.
- Brother-in-law?
- Yes!
Here I am.
Tell the truth,
did it make you happy that I asked you
to help us move today?
It's like waking up on your day off and saying:
"What would be wacky this morning?
A good move."
Relax, I've got it all done.
- All that's left is the light stuff.
- Yeah, I can see that.
- Hey, what about Abel?
- Hands up!
- Who is it?
- Now you're gonna help me pack!
Okay, your uncle will help you pack,
but first I have to
help my dad carry the boxes.
All right?
Bye, sweetie!
How's the apartment search going?
All right. (chuckles)
I'm looking, and Zoya says no.
Are you talking to me?
Esther drove me crazy looking for a house.
Yes...
He doesn't drive.
He hates driving,
so I have to drive myself.
Dump a man if he doesn't drive?
Drives what?
No, that's okay. I'm gonna go get other things.
Two: hair, everywhere.
You should have seen the bathroom after he shaved.
Three, he's 43 years old,
and he still dresses like a 20-year-old.
Fourth, he only listens
only to depressing music.
Five: "I don't care."
He always says that.
He never offers anything.
Restaurants, trips, movies--
it's always me.
But you like to organize things.
Six: he still hasn't learned
how to say my name.
Seven: he's stupid.
His new novel is out of print
because he won't change the ending.
"Commercial" is a terrible word for him.
I asked for one thing...
Tom?
Are you done?
No, we just started...
Thank you.
- Abel, your skateboard.
- Yeah, Dad.
It's just scary to see a house like this.
You bet...
Then...
Everything's gone to hell with this move.
- These are your things.
- My stuff?
There's an essay.
Mom's letter?
Mom's letter, yeah.
Oh my god...
Need to write again, my goodness....
Actually, I don't think
it's irreparable.
Eighth, I'm no longer happy
with him around.
Nine: Maybe
I just forgot how to be happy.
Tenth: I don't know.
- You okay?
- Yeah, just... a little tired.
Look, uh.
I'll drive.
No, no, I'll drive.
No, I'll drive, you park.
It's fine.
I haven't told her yet.
I'm waiting for the right time.
- Help me!
- Again?
Umberto, think carefully.
You know, breaking up
after all these years is crazy!
- It's gonna be hard, it's gonna be sad.
- Well, I already know that.
You'll have to box up the books,
fighting over CDs: "That's mine!
- No, it's yours..."
Sharing photos... How?
Official photos,
I'm always in the back, out of focus, okay.
Why don't you think about
about the good things between you two?
Well, why don't you just focus on work?
At work? Look!
- We're alone, no one's here.
- Of course, everyone's in class.
Of course you are,
the kids are in class and I'm in the hallway!
I've been sent to the reserve,
I was marginalized.
- You know, me!
- They made you deputy director!
Exactly, also a mockery,
because it's the eighth:
not only am I unable to teach
because of administrative duties,
but, uh, the ninth:
According to the department head,
a man in my position
can't just be a teacher, okay?
Me, who's used to being on the front lines!
I've been killed!
How much did I weigh three years ago?
Only 120 kilos! Do you understand?
- What?
- There's no tenth item.
Tenth...
Yes? Ah, here, come here, Laruffa.
How's the new teacher?
Have we passed Calvino yet?
Who, teacher?
Number ten. Go on, go.
And this is one of the best.
Hi.
What's the music?
It lifts your spirits.
What are you doing?
Working on a new ending for the novel.
- You did?
- Yeah.
As usual, the fridge is empty.
- I'm gonna order some food, okay?
- I ordered a Syrian restaurant.
For 9:00 p.m.
All right. Uh-huh.
- You like it?
- I do.
Good evening, may I leave a menu?
Of course, thank you.
No, no, wait.
This way...
- Mustabal...
- Yes.
Taratura Aleppo,
full Damascus and Fattoush for two.
- That's great.
- Uh, thank you.
Well, I already looked it up online.
No, wait.
I'll give it a shot.
No.
You take one of them,
then you put this in there.
Try it!
I've been thinking.
It's been a long time since we've been away for a weekend.
We were recently in Tuscany.
I mean alone,
without the whole horde of friends.
I don't know if I can.
We have a project to deliver and we're behind.
I don't have time
to find a hotel, buy tickets.
Maybe I can.
- Where do you want to go?
- Prague.
Paris...
Places where couples go
barely start dating.
Or where couples who are in crisis go.
Beautiful cutlets!
The more distant I get, the cuter he gets.
This is awkward.
It's easier to start a war than to end it.
You've been through this?
How do you know all this?
Because I'm Gabriel Garcia Marquez.
Need I remind you that you're corresponding
with a famous dead writer.
Ironic, too.
I hope you're at least not ugly.
Maybe.
What kind of guy are you?
I'll tell you myself.
You seem rough, but you're fragile.
And when you're fragile, you get rude.
You pick the wine, you pay the bill.
and you know how to cheat.
Maybe.
You think I'm weird?
I think you...
original.
I'm sorry!
Whoever it is,
he has to stop shaving in the bathroom.
First of all, it's not your house,
and when there's hair everywhere, I can't stand it.
Okay?
Thank you.
- I like it, what do you think?
- "My girlfriend..."
- That's the guy with the sock in his mouth!
- I must have made a mistake, it was from below.
Why are you here?
There was no business.
Do you want to go for a walk?
A walk?
We live in Rome and we never walk.
Where do you want to go?
It's been a rough day.
We'll take a walk while standing still.
Stop joking around.
I'm not kidding, Zoya.
Kidding.
Zo-e.
Zoé.
I can't say it.
I get "F" for "Foe."
- It's difficult.
- Tongue between teeth...
If it's between the teeth, it's "Dzoe."
Thank you.
CHAPTER FOUR: SOGNO
THE MEANING OF THE WORD "DREAM" -
A VISION OF THE FUTURE THAT YOU BELIEVE IN
EXAMPLE: I HAVE A DREAM
OR: UNFOUNDED HOPE
EXAMPLE: IT'S JUST A DREAM
Now I have to ride a bike,
and I hate bikes!
Umberto, you can't
always complain about everything!
Tommaso, I have hemorrhoids,
so I have the right to complain!
Helena made me do it,
she started a campaign for bike lanes
and he says, "You can't be photographed
in the car again."
But there's no way in hell I'm ditching the car!
Compromise is normal for a couple.
You can change a little for her, can't you?
A little? Tommaso, I'm a different person,
You've known me for 25 years,
was I like this in college?
Yeah, in college.
we used to call you poor thing.
Para-param, para-param, para-param,
Para-para-para-pam-pam-pam, I screwed up!
I remember, but that's exactly why
she fell in love:
for my witty remarks
that got me in trouble.
She laughed, sometimes to the point of tears.
And now he's terrorizing me.
Now before I talk,
I have to count to five thousand!
Then it's easy.
Don't count anymore.
Don't give up your witty
your witty remarks, be like you were in your 20s.
Maybe then she'll stop
to tolerate you.
How did it occur to you
to show up like that?
Convenient.
No one asked you
to dress uncomfortable but clean!
Ah, just a coffee stain....
During the anthem, I'll put my hand over my heart....
Is this a matter of etiquette?
No, it's a rag question.
Not etiquette, hygiene.
You're a formalist, Héléna.
I'm not Helena here, I'm the mayor, and you're my...
I'm not, I'm always Umberto.
This way, this way, please!
- The picture's from here!
- Mayor!
One more shot!
- Thank you!
- Look here, please!
- Please take a look at this!
- Thank you.
Please stand during the national anthem!
- Please.
- Yes, I am.
- Good luck, guys.
- Thank you.
It was just a joke, Héléna.
Don't you realize
that we're gonna be all over the papers tomorrow?
I will be destroyed.
How can you say that?
We're already in a crisis!
- Are we in crisis?
- Of course we're in crisis.
The coalition has disintegrated, all the polls are against....
We're hanging by a thread.
Is that funny?
What's so funny?
You laughed at my jokes once!
Once! Not twice or thrice!
In fact, for what it's worth,
you were once proud of me for being in politics.
- Listen, uh.
- Can someone help me with my homework?
- Yeah, baby. Now.
- Yes, baby. Daddy's gonna help.
Yesterday was a good day.
Things have gotten better,
and I'm thinking about leaving him.
It's all so weird.
Do you feel guilty?
He gave no reason to hurt him,
but sometimes I feel like I'm betraying him.
Did you cheat on him?
Yes.
You really cheated?
A long time ago, but it has nothing to do
with this crisis.
- Zoya!
- What?
I'm gonna go take out the trash.
All right. Uh-huh.
Anyway, he was cheating on me, too,
but I didn't tell him I knew it.
Why didn't you tell him?
There was no problem between us.
It happens.
- Why'd you do it?
- It happens.
I was suddenly terrified
at the thought of losing him.
Are you coming to bed?
I'll write for a while and then I'll come back.
All right. Uh-huh.
- Nina, coffee, please.
- Right away.
Speaking of the production bonus:
give my bonus to the guys.
I'm sure they'll be able
to achieve three percent development.
Suit yourself.
London called,
want to expedite your arrival.
We'll announce it in five days.
I thought I had a few more weeks.
Why?
You want to change your mind?
No, no, no, no.
But...I have some things I need to take care of.
Handle it.
Tom?
Where are we going so elegant?
Surprise!
Listen, do you know how to tie this thing?
Which one?
Is that the surprise?
Why?
Bad?
No, but I've never
seen you dressed like that.
All right. Uh-huh.
There's always a first time.
Can you come here for a minute?
- I have something important to tell you.
- Zoya, we're late.
I'll take the car and wait downstairs,
hurry up, get dressed.
Are you gonna tell me where we're going?
You go on in, I'll park.
Good evening, everyone,
and welcome to the presentation,
after years of waiting,
Tommaso Rosso's third, new novel.
I'd like to first read to you
a quote from the beginning of my book.
"In that moment, there was nothing
"but quiet happiness.
But he would have preferred mature unhappiness
that smooth glide,
no bumps, no waves,
without storms,
"like a giant ship
stuck in a pool."
Are you saying you don't believe
in your romantic ending?
I know in novels, the author determines the ending,
as opposed to what happens in life.
There's another surprise.
Another one?
- We're going to see a house.
- Now?
Now.
- Okay.
- This house is for sale.
It's smaller, but I think it's, uh,
it's perfect for us.
So...
Wait...
Momentum...
Can you see anything?
- Yeah. (chuckles)
- Uh-huh?
Okay...
Here we go.
This is the living room.
Look at the terrace!
You can see all of Rome from here.
There's the kitchen-dining room.
And here at the end,
there's an extra room, just in case.
Look, open-beam ceiling.
Isn't that a miracle?
And here...
It's a bedroom
with a panoramic window.
Look at the light!
Wonderful...
We made love.
I'm pretty sure I don't love him anymore.
How am I supposed to tell him now?
CHAPTER FIVE: ACCETTA
OF THE MEANING OF THE WORD "ACCEPT" -
ACCEPT THAT THIS IS THE WAY IT SHOULD BE
EXAMPLE: ACCEPT REALITY
OR: "HATCHET" - A SMALL AXE
EXAMPLE: HATCHET
Ellena realized something was wrong.
The party realized she was in crisis,
and they called me and asked me to support her,
because they're afraid that her anxiety
will affect the council's position.
They're afraid she'll drop everything.
Are you listening?
Yeah, yeah.
You thought it was as easy
as closing a company?
It's about people, Umberto.
But when something is over, it's over.
It's like... putting a Band-Aid on a wound.
I had just decided
to tell her everything tonight, even, uh.
I wrote another non-harmful speech....
May I?
Let's hear it.
"Beloved,
everything I've felt for you
all these years, I can't describe.
I asked the poets for help.
"I must have climbed a million stairs
I descended by giving you my hand..."
Wait, Umberto.
First of all, Héléna is not dead.
So you want to break up with her,
starting with a declaration of love,
quoting Montale?
Why.
Why don't you tell the truth,
why don't you tell the goddamn truth?
You don't love her anymore?
Tommaso, I love Helena,
but not the Helena that's with me now.
There's only one Héléna,
the one you're with right now.
And it's no use being nice and sweet, believe me.
You want my advice?
Here's what Marquez would say.
That's the old ending to my book.
Yeah, but, uh.
I can't tell her all this like this.
You told me all of this yourself.
How you've felt all these years.
Or have you forgotten?
Nina, would you be willing
to come to London with me?
I don't know.
But I think that's
that's up to the brass, not me.
What if it were up to you?
I recently started living together
and I need to talk to my boyfriend.
- Did I say something wrong?
- No, you didn't.
How did you two meet?
In one chat room, the site's support chat room.
We wrote to each other,
then we met,
love at first sight.
I hope you weren't chatting during work hours.
No.
A couple of chairs...
On this side...
I've never done anything
irrational in my entire life,
but I'd like to meet you.
One second, this is an important message,
and I have to-- I have to take this.
Why do you want to see me?
I don't even know what you look like.
But I have a feeling that in a few days.
you've gotten to know me better than Tommaso.
And you can also help me
to find the right words
to break up with him.
I could be one of those two.
Or none of them.
It doesn't matter.
I'm willing to take the risk.
What about you?
6:00 p.m., Del Fico's Bar.
How do you recognize me?
You're as beautiful as a painting,
with a nervous look on her face
and black nail polish.
- Hey. (chuckles)
Why are you dressed like that?
Ah, nonsense, an aperitif with the bosses.
I'll go straight to the restaurant from there, okay?
Uh, okay. Zoya?
Yes?
Will you give me a hug?
What do you mean?
I mean, a hug.
Okay, but you don't ask that kind of thing.
It happens spontaneously.
But not you.
Not true.
I'm gonna go, it's getting late.
I'll have a gin and tonic!
Tom?
What are you doing here?
I invited Umberto over for a beer, but, uh.
But I didn't think you'd come here.
Wait a minute. I've got a sticking point.
Who are you writing to?
To the bosses.
Asked why they were late.
It's Umberto.
He's got an override, he's not coming.
- Well, I'll be off.
- Bye.
Zoya,
what's wrong with you?
You can't say "nothing"
or "problems at work."
Right, please, as always before.
I've been offered a move to London.
- It's a promotion, Tom.
- И?
- Can I get you anything?
- No, nothing, thank you.
Why didn't you say so before?
You've never taken much
interested in my work.
And you're mine,
you don't even know who I'm writing for.
But right now, it's about both of us.
Why didn't you tell me?
Because it's a decision
that I want to make.
alone.
And...have you decided?
Not yet.
Well, I'm gonna go.
Here comes the brass.
Tell him I said hi.
I'll see you right at Nello's, okay?
All right. Uh-huh.
You didn't come.
I saw you with a man and I left.
It's you, I'm sure of it.
I was with Tommaso.
Now I've seen you, it's all clear to me.
Don't delay.
You don't need my words anymore.
Drop it.
Héléna, listen to me.
Come on, come on, I'm listening.
I should tell you something,
but I thought I'd write.
"During those years, I felt
"abandoned, humiliated,
set aside like a trinket,
like an old glass ball
with snow inside.
I thought the snow wasn't there anymore.
But one day I turned the ball over,
and the snow started spinning like it used to.
That was the hundredth time
I've seen something without you.
I can't stand your late-night meetings anymore,
constant emergencies,
the way you get angry
when they change the road network.
But most of all, I can't
not be who I want to be anymore:
by a teacher,
husband,
a man."
Whose writing is this?
You didn't even listen to me
when I came to ask for a divorce.
I heard every word.
It doesn't look like it.
When have I ever humiliated you?
Who stopped you from teaching? Being a man?
"Snowballing" again?
Well, have I been listening well?
Not even the last sentence?
I'm a woman, Umberto,
I can do many things at once.
When we started living together,
you knew what I wanted to do.
Politics is my mission, Umberto.
It's one thing to go to a meeting,
to see "We loved each other so much."
to eat pork,
to discuss the society
that we leave to our children.
It's another thing
is to live a life of constant inactivity,
where's my moment of fame--
magazine cover photo,
where I fall off my bike!
With all of our city's problems.
do you care how you came out in the picture?
No, what I care about
that I go to the store with security,
who's judging me
that I bought a discount ham!
What worries me is that during your self-imposed isolation.
you were hardly ever home!
We're the only ones
who didn't stay home together during quarantine!
First of all, don't raise your voice at me.
- I didn't raise my voice.
- You're raising your voice!
And now you're stepping it up!
And, two, you have no idea,
that I've had to deal with
in that time.
What, am I, the mayor of Rome, going to sit at home?
- Do you realize what you're saying?
- Yes, I do.
I realize there's always a problem.
Years of formal dinners
where I ate poorly and ate little,
terrified of which fork to get,
scolded for pouring water
in the wrong cup.
Can't you see we've changed?
Everything has changed.
Don't be a child, Umberto.
So tell me, what exactly has changed?
- What's changed?
- Everything, Héléna, everything has changed, everything!
Now, we used to organize demonstrations
against the exploitation of the workers,
and now we have two Filipinos!
Formalized,
and we pay taxes, vacation pay,
13th paycheck, what's the big deal?
In that I want to give back to my students,
my car and my marriage!
You want your 20s back.
And that I can even understand.
I know I'm very busy,
but you can't
ask me to do that right now.
Wait a few months, we'll figure it out.
There are things like this,
that affect everyone.
And if you're betting our marriage
above the best interests of our city,
you're ungrateful and irresponsible.
A crisis of the party?
The interests of the city, Héléna?
You've completely lost your sense of proportion.
You don't love me anymore?
I'm no longer in love
a cold, formal lady,
that's standing in front of me.
Now sign my restraining order to keep you.
By the way, it's been an hour.
I should have borrowed Esther's
a Spanish frying pan.
A frying pan is like a frying pan.
No, "paella" is a special skillet,
not just the recipe.
The frying pan matters, Tom.
Okay, hand me two sheets of newspaper.
If you want, you can wait there.
That's not what we were going to do.
We decided it together.
Not all decisions are made together, it seems.
- Working in London, Tom, it's, uh.
- No, no, no.
Uh, hold on.
What do I have to look forward to?
Just to let the rice dry, okay?
All right. Uh-huh.
We'll wait.
How much did it come out to, baby?
You can't even be called baby?
Okay, let's go.
24 points.
24!
Guys, I'm sorry, but I'm afraid,
Spain won't get a prize tonight.
- The rice was a little overcooked.
- Yeah.
- The squid was a little tough.
- And the dessert was gross.
You don't say "disgusting."
they say "didn't like it."
Yeah, I didn't like him,
because he was mean.
We had a disagreement on the menu.
My fault, I was a little nervous.
Then, the frying pan is no good.
Attention!
Now it's the frying pan's fault!
Did the agitator fit?
Like when you lose at tennis.
It's always the racket's fault.
This is typical of Italians.
It's always someone else's fault.
Always!
Why so gloomy?
It's a game, right?
A high-pressure zone from northern Europe...
Tommaso, we need to talk.
- Check the readiness...
- We'll talk.
- Now that the cake--
- Turn it off, please.
You can sprinkle powdered sugar on top.....
You're welcome.
It's really hard for me to find the right words.
Don't pick it up.
It's all right.
It's very clear, Zoya.
It's been a long time coming.
I don't want to sit here and listen
your pity speech about how
that it's over between us.
I'm sorry.
Okay...
I don't know what's happening to me.
I assure you that I will always
I'll always be here for you, you know.
"I'll always be there for you, you know."
My God, you are so...corny.
Trite, Tom, why?
Tom! Tom! That's the navigator's name!
Tell me.
Is this about London?
Because of a lot of things...
I'm not sure about a lot of things anymore, Tom.
And I don't want to be held down by a relationship.
Who's holding you?
Я?
Id.
And I'm sorry I kept you for ten years
in this shitty town.
It's called ambition, Tom.
You don't know what it is.
Too bad, I thought you'd understand,
But I guess not.
You're leaving me, what's there to understand?
That I feel bad, too.
If you want, I'll caress you, huh?
Do you want a caress?
Don't be a child.
You don't get it.
I never understand anything.
You always understand everything,
and the rest of the world doesn't.
You know, my friends can't stand you,
and you haven't even noticed?
Get off your heels once in a while
and ask what people really think of you.
I don't get it.
You know... fine.
- Tommaso...
- Zoya.
Go to hell.
- Hey.
- How's it going? Everything okay?
Yes.
I'll stay with you for a few days.
Uh, sure.
Got any wine?
At 1:30 in the morning?
What are we drinking to?
To my promotion.
Assigned?
They'll announce it tomorrow.
Is it possible to celebrate earlier?
No, no, I'm not superstitious.
I left Tommaso.
TOMMASO ROSSO
"MEANS NEVER"
"TOUCHING FINALE"
No tears.
It happens.
It's in the nature of things.
You change and you make choices.
And when you break up, the one who leaves,
and has to give explanations.
I know,
but that's the kind of rhetoric that means.
I won't.
On the contrary, I'll smile.
Let's do it the other way around.
You tell me.
I want to know
what you think of me, the truth.
Without any pathos.
Don't worry, I can't fire you.
Nina?
No, nothing comes to mind.
Virginia?
Marco?
Okay, I don't insist.
Ah, Nina, it came to me in the general newsletter:
"There's a corporate party tonight."
What's going to happen tonight?
Well, it's a party at the same establishment.....
It came to you by mistake.
If you come over, we can have a drink together.
- A drink?
- Why don't you--
Well done, Tommaso.
Bad news always comes in pairs.
Okay, this is for her.
Give it to her when she comes to get her stuff.
- Anyway, Tommaso, I've read it.
- Yes.
Shall I tell you the truth?
It's kind of boring,
except for the finale, which is just good!
Since you're here, will you have lunch with us?
Friday, Maria is making onion soup.
Yeah, thanks, but it's, uh.
not exactly my favorite dish.
And it's not mine.
What's more, it disgusts me.
But she's been brewing it since
since we got engaged.
And I haven't dared to tell her that since 1969,
and now I have to pay that tax for 50 years.
I escaped, the guards didn't see me.
Suddenly I wanted to see you like I used to,
alone with you.
And I missed that car.
It's without an accelerant, if we get caught,
you'll lose six or seven percent of the vote.
Do you remember when...
When we drove it to Turin
to the De André concert?
September 18, 1991.
I got sick on the first song.
I've always loved you,
I never loved you...
Love comes.
Love is gone.
Okay, Héléna, don't cry.
It's a complicated situation as it is.
I tried, I really did.
But lately.
I've been missing the situation, completely.
I'm a terrible wife, my mom and the mayor too.
- Terrible.
- That's not true.
That's not true, you're a great mayor.
Umberto, please come to your senses.
Come back.
But you're the one who has to go back.
To be Helena again,
not just our mayor.
Not to register marriages,
but taking care of your own.
If that's the way you think it is,
it's old-fashioned male chauvinism,
which doesn't do you any honor. It's not you, no.
Helena, don't campaign,
I'll vote for you anyway.
If you're worried about how it's gonna be perceived,
no one will ever know.
If I miss a couple of formal dinners,
you'll be better off.
Héléna, Héléna...
- Sweetheart.
- Listen to me.
No more pictures,
enough security,
enough of City Hall.
It's blackmail.
You don't understand...
You're the one who doesn't understand.
Here you go.
Thank you, Mrs. Maria.
- I left my keys in the office.
- Why?
Tommaso left them for me on purpose.
So you're going to London?
Yes.
Are you happy?
You'll see the queen.
Yes, I'm very happy.
Wouldn't miss the pope.....
Well, you're gonna miss your daddy.
Look, you come to us
for the golden wedding tomorrow?
I don't think I can.
I have meetings at work.
Come on, we keep it simple,
out here in the yard.
By the way, we have to hurry.
Time to make onion soup.
I love onion soup.
Fifty years Franco's been asking me for it!
Ever since we met,
and I don't know how to tell him
that this soup disgusts me.
You should see how much he loves him!
Fifty years of onion soup?
I took it with food.
Gotta go, bye!
Bye.
I broke up with him.
I wish I could tell you
what it was like.
Why don't you fuck--
I feel good about it.
Do you want to do it tonight?
We have an adjourned meeting.
Don't write to me ever again.
Sorry, I'm really busy.
Okay, have a good night.
AND TO YOU, MY LOVE.
AND YOU.
- Esther?
- What is it?
- Do you want to go out tonight?
- Abel has a fever.
I guess it's no big deal.
- Flavio's not home.
- Can't you get a babysitter?
I could, but I don't want to.
When Abel has a fever,
I want to be there for him.
That's right.
Mom, I think I'm gonna throw up.
Exactly.
Then mom's probably
have to hold your head.
Come on, come on.
Call Nina, the assistant.
I'm sorry I didn't get a chance to tell you
that the car's a little--
No problem.
It's fun.
Yeah, especially if we get pulled over.
Wait, wait, wait!
Let's go.
We're in for an unforgettable evening.
- Are you sure?
- Dad, it's a one-unit difference.
Guys, that's a record: 57 points.
Wow...
Thank you.
Always a great team effort
with this giant.
Honey!
We deserve an aperitif, don't we?
You know the way.
I'm jealous. It's a genius idea--
barley coffee tiramisu.
The idea was pretty stupid,
but it was good, right?
Well, guys, I gotta go, Matilda's tired.
When he says that,
it means he's tired.
Listen, what about Héléna?
Who, the mayor?
We're meeting at home,
"good morning," "good evening."
- Uh, Zoya? Have you guys been in touch?
- Uh, no.
Maybe I should tell her I'm Marquez.
No, no, don't.
What was, was.
Did Dostoyevsky's idiot
become a hero at the end?
No.
Did you do something stupid, act like a coward?
Well, and be a coward to the end.
Matilda, come on.
Jacket, bye-bye, let's go!
- Bye, baby.
- Bye!
- Bye.
Hey, this couples contest idea is awesome!
For years now, we've been like this...
I'm a good cook,
next time we'll be on the team.
- Aperitif?
- Two.
Guys, the next time
you want to introduce me to someone,
please give me a heads-up.
Ever since you came
to the barbershop for a shave,
she's always asking about you.
Honey, have fun!
She says she gives massages with lard.
Where'd you get her?
Come on, Tom, relax.....
Don't call me "Tom," please.
You, too.
All right, guys,
the cafeteria's closed, go in peace.
I have an order for 30 people for tomorrow,
and I have to clean up.
You don't deserve it, but we'll help you out, okay....
- Come on!
- Yeah, come on.
Do you need a ride home?
Yes.
Come on, sweetie, we'll help....
- Come on!
- One more!
- Excuse me, ma'am!
- Cheers, guys!
- Let's go!
- Bottoms up!
Come on, come on!
I want to dance!
Nina!
Why didn't you want to answer me?
I know how to listen to criticism....
- What are you celebrating?
- Your departure.
What?
Just because you're leaving!
Going to work every day
with fear is not a gift!
Does anyone else have anything else to say?
I don't know how to tell you,
but you're a bitch.
Sure, you're the boss,
but a smile once in a while?
What the fuck...
Yeah, but at least we
learned how to say "100 yen."
All right?
"Nina.
do you know why, in 1978.
didn't have 100 yen coins?"
"Space Invaders!"
Are you Zoya, Nina's boss?
Did she tell you I'm a bitch?
No.
- She said you're going to London.
- It's true, I'm going to London.
London is the best of the best.
London is better, really. It's beautiful.
No, no, no, it's not better.
No, it's better. Right?
If I give up everything,
it's got to be better, right?
I don't know.
We're leaving.
Can I take you home?
I can take you.
Thank you.
Madonna, what a nice house! It's huge!
- Congratulations.
- It's not mine.
I'm taking it off.
And I have to move out,
because my ex-wife, uh.
My former... partner terminated her contract.
Yes, Gianni told me something
that she left because she was going to London.
Well, it's a little more complicated than that....
She...
became a senior manager
for a major European company.
"Senior Manager"?
What kind of job? I've never heard of it.
So, the supervisor...
You know that game where you have
your own avatar?
No, I like other games.
And so, dear friends of the night,
we are back on the air...
Hey!
Where do I go?
Piazza Campitelli, 20.
- Okay?
- All right.
- Stop, no.
- Boom, boom, that one's over, too.
- That's enough.
- Another bottle.
I don't.
- Yeah, yeah.
- Stop, no, stop.
- That was fast!
- Whoa!
Zoya...
- Am I in the wrong house?
- What are you doing here?
You brought her to our house?
This isn't our home anymore.
That's the head of the company?
Who's the boy? Little brother?
Where'd you get that whore?
Hey, señorita, fuck you!
Hey, hey, calm down.
Everyone...everyone calm down, all of us.
I'm sorry, did you come here to fuck
with this young man in our house?
This isn't our home anymore.
And I'm not a youngster, I'm 22 years old.
What about you?
What were you doing with that...award?
I don't have to answer
to you about what I'm doing.
Okay, but I thought
you had better taste, let's say.
And I thought you had a taste
"a little more mature, shall we say.
Again! I'm an adult.
Hello, Mom?
No, I was giving a ride home to a lady
who wasn't feeling well.
And now I'm now...
Look at me... "lady"!
- Why?
- I apologize.
- You're drunk.
- You're an idiot and a moron.
- You're very drunk.
- You're very stupid.
I don't understand you.
Let's go, come on!
Or I'll have to scratch someone here!
Congratulations!
It's good to talk about this nerd all evening!
You know what? You deserve her.
And you're coming with me.
Bye!
- Bye.
- Goodbye.
Zoya, no.
Stop drinking.
Hey, no, no, no, no, no.
That's enough.
Tom...
I'm not feeling well.
I feel bad, too.
No...
I'm not feeling well,
because I've been drinking...a lot.
I thought that...
Template Template Template.
Fucking exes.
Plus the fact that it was awesome!
And now?
What's gonna happen?
Look...
"Hi, my name is Zoé,
I'm ten years old,
and I like video games.
Today my dad explained to me
that nothing is created,
nothing is destroyed, everything is transformed.
He said that mom...
looks like a cloud.
When it's cold,
the vapor in the clouds turns to snow,
and when it's hot,
it turns to water and it rains.
And then the sun comes out again,
everything warms up, even the puddles.
The water turns to vapor and flies into the sky,
becomes a cloud again, as it was before."
Dad wanted to tell me,
that mom would somehow be back soon.
And here we go,
favorite,
a breakup after many years
should be something like this, no?
Don't collapse,
but to change.
But I didn't want to change.
You did it all.
It happens, Tommaso.
It happens, that's all.
It's nobody's fault.
It's raining,
you get wet and dry,
and it's raining again.
The only thing that can be done is.
open the umbrella.
Bye.
- We'll talk.
- Uh, okay.
- Uh, okay?
- I'll, uh, I'll call you.
Uh, sure.
I can't believe it!
You're here, thank you!
Thank you, I wasn't expecting it, and I'm so glad I did!
Maria will be even more pleased.
- Come in, have some...
- No, Franco.
- Five minutes!
- Thank you.
Five minutes, and then you're on your way. Come on in!
Maria!
Maria, look,
who came to congratulate us!
Oh, how nice! You guys are so cute!
So you came together? That's good news!
No, no, no, we just, uh.
came by to congratulate you, and, uh.
And we'll go right away.
- Come on, let's go cut the cake.
- Yeah.
How elegant you are!
What's your name?
Zoé, Mrs. Rachele.
Welcome, Zoe.
Unless you have a date for tonight,
I can introduce you to this young man.
Nice to meet you, Tommaso.
- Zoe.
- What sign are you?
- Both Taurus.
Signora Rachele, we...
- Mom, leave them alone.
- What a beautiful couple you are!
All right, I better go.
Yeah, go on, the kid'll be out of school soon.
At least he doesn't have to pay.
You're such a bitch!
You started it.
How's it going with the book?
Well...
It's for sale, they'll make a new contract with me.
- You didn't tell me that.
- What?
"Bitch."
In ten years.
No.
Obviously, for ten years I didn't think so.
You know what I've realized these days?
That we never really fought.
Not once in ten years.
We never threw plates.
Everything was...
so peacefully.
We avoided arguments, didn't tell the whole truth.
The truth is a little dangerous, Zoe.
Sometimes you need it,
even though it hurts.
You cheated on me?
- What about you?
- Yeah.
What can I say? It happened.
Amen.
"It happened, amen."
I'll get you a drink.
All right. Uh-huh.
Daughter, let's get
clothes for tomorrow so we won't be late.
It's ready, my mom already made it this afternoon.
So, tell me, what do you want for breakfast?
Mom had already put it in her briefcase.
Daddy, Mommy... says,
that when I grow up,
I need a husband like you.
Mom always gives the best advice.
Well, Dad, it's okay,
Mom wants to be chairman of the board.
Hey, two minutes, then turn off the light and go to sleep.
- Good night.
I thought.
You're right.
You come first.
I'm resigning.
Good night.
CHAPTER SIX: LASCIARE
THE MEANING OF THE WORD "LEAVE" IS
WALK AWAY FROM SOMEONE OR SOMETHING
EXAMPLE: I HAVE TO LEAVE YOU
OR: LEAVE SELECTION.
TAKE-IT-OR-LEAVE-IT
- Here.
- Thank you.
- Are you done?
- I am.
- Go brush your teeth with your dad.
- (sighs) Okay.
Maybe I left him for nothing.
Do you miss him?
Maybe you miss living with him
these ten years?
Shared friends, habits...
That's normal.
Breaking up after all these years
is also a way out of--
from the community.
Think of London, Zoe.
It's what you've always wanted.
I started chatting with a stranger.
He confused me even more.
Absurd,
but it's like he knows how I feel.
It's a long explanation.
The thing is.
I didn't tell Tom about it.
He was honest with me.
I don't.
So, uh.
You're not married, you have no children,
and most importantly, you don't share a mortgage.
You can choose,
but you should have clarity.
And if there's something
to confess something to Tommaso, it better be now,
before it's too late.
Thank you, thank you very much...
- Thank you very much.
- Bye, thank you.
- Hey, what's your name?
- Desiree.
- I'll read it right away.
- Thank you.
- And I'll need a signature.
- Bye.
- Hey, what's your name?
- Stefano.
Stefano...
- Here you go.
- Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
- Who do you want me to sign it for?
- For Zoé.
I really enjoyed the book,
although it does feel like the ending is unfair.
This ending isn't mine, it's the readers' ending.
What would your finale be?
EVERYONE HAS THE ENDING
THAT THEY DESERVE
TOMMASO
- Is everything okay?
- Uh, yeah, yeah.
I need to see you.
You're the only person
I can trust.
- Thank you.
Hi.
I'm sorry, I can't right now.
- Thank you.
- Who do you want me to sign it for?
- Alessandro.
"THERE WAS NOTHING IN THE WORLD MORE COMPLICATED THAN LOVE"
GABRIEL GARCIA MARQUEZ
Write to me,
what you hate about him.
You faked an orgasm with me?
You cheated on him?
Explain it to me.
What are you talking about, Zoya?
Are you serious?
I can't believe you actually did it.
Zoya, please, not now.
"Not now"? "Not now"?
You've been mocking me this whole time!
You're so short!
- Am I short?
- Uh, yeah.
And when you asked a magazine for advice
on how to dump me, isn't that low?
I've been hanging out with that guy,
so I wouldn't hurt you!
I can't believe it. Are you crazy?
Why didn't you say what you were writing there?
- Why?
- "Why?"
- Yes.
Didn't you realize?
It was the right thing to do!
I've learned more about us in a month
than I have in ten years.
You don't understand, Tommaso, you stole from me!
Now you're telling me "Tommaso"?
- Tell me, Zoe.
- Zoe.
- Zoe!
- Zoe, asshole!
You can't say my name!
You were aroused by texting with a John Doe,
who understands you.
Too bad, the one who's not like me,
the one you were flirting with,
kissing you in the morning
and throwing your hair all over the bathroom.
- You're a walrus dick!
- Oh, finally a reaction!
Let's have a real fight,
since you haven't had enough!
Look, 200 people are looking at us, come on!
Don't overestimate yourself, Tommaso!
There are 40 of them.
That's a lot
for such literary crap!
Why didn't you tell those 40 poor people,
that while you were trying to leave me,
you wanted to cheat on me with who knows who?
That's not true, and let's not talk about cheating,
Tommaso, please!
- No, let's do it!
- You did it first!
Why didn't you say anything when you found out?
- It didn't matter.
- It didn't matter to you!
The only thing you cared about
was that our relationship go smoothly,
not interfere with your life, your career!
Zoya, Zoya, Zoya! There's only you!
And that was important, Zoya!
And fucking a guy in Tokyo is important, too,
and you didn't have the guts to admit it,
even when I asked you!
- You know what's important?
- What?
That you were blind when our relationship
didn't work out for years,
that we were like friends
who occasionally fucked,
since it's protocol!
We could have talked about it!
For two months we were cooped up in the house,
you've been writing these fucking emails for two months!
Why'd you do it, why'd you do it?
- Why?
- Yes.
Look at me, Zoya.
Look how I'm dressed.
Look at me.
Even...
shitty ending to this book...
Who do you think he's for?
You should have had the courage to ask me,
not sneaking around.
- I was trying to ask you when you were!
- Of course I was!
And when you weren't talking,
how perfect
"Space Invaders!
And what was so important
did you ask me, Tommaso?
Did you ask me if I wanted to get married?
Do I really want to buy a house with you,
do I want to have a baby?
Did you ask me?
Are you kidding me? You always said
that marriage is conditional,
that you don't want kids!
- Did you ever ask me?
- Of course I asked you!
But the only way
to show you something
to shove it up your virtual shit!
The only way I can show you
to show you something is to walk away from you!
I wonder what we've been doing all these years?
Nothing...
We...
had dinner at the restaurant.
- Tommaso, I need help.
- Umberto, please, not today.
Today Héléna is resigning for me.
- That's what you wanted, right?
- You're the one who said I wanted it.
Don't you dare say that.
I was just giving advice, you did it yourself.
"When you build a wall,
remember what you leave on the outside."
- God, what is that, a horoscope?
- "Baron in the tree," you ignoramus.
Hey, Humberto, I got business today,
you're not the only one in the world, okay?
I built a wall and left Ellena outside,
and now I don't know how to stop her.
Now you're gonna come with me
and tell me you wrote it!
Slow down, today's not the day.
- But you have to help me!
- I'm sick of you!
What a blow!
Come with me.
Where to?
To the hospital in case I broke your nose?
Let's go.
A press conference has been urgently called,
to be held at City Hall.
She recognized Marquez as me.
We threw all the plates and glasses
all the plates and glasses,
unbroken in ten years.
...Lately, our mayor hasn't....
Damn, it's hard to break up!
It's really hard.
...they never miss an opportunity
to criticize her work,
as we can hear in this interview.
How can a woman
who can't bring her family together,
to rally the entire city of Rome?
I don't know, you tell me!
It was a statement by the secretary of the Party
of the New Italian Renaissance,
made a few minutes
before the conference began...
Umberto, where the hell are we?
But...
There he is, she's here...
Hello, welcome, everyone.
Thank you for being here.
Without getting too personal,
I absolutely must
to take responsibility for the city,
who deserves 100% of my energy,
of my time and my devotion.
But the people I care about deserve the same.
So, uh,
Having discussed it with my party and....
and after...
a long discussion with my family....
Wait!
I never believed that someone like you
could fall in love with someone like me.
Remember what you were like when you were 25?
As beautiful as she is now.
And I was fat, too,
almost as fat as he is now.
So I thought:
"Okay, she's gonna leave me someday."
The more you grew, the fatter I got.
I thought I was
an example of nonconformity for you,
to show that you're different.
But you married me, and I thought:
"Now she's gonna leave me."
Then Matilda was born,
and I thought, "He's going to quit now."
Then there's the secretary, the counselor,
and now head of the city of Rome.
And every time I thought, "She's going to leave me."
But since you didn't leave me,
I've decided to leave you on my own.
I exaggerated your shortcomings,
to justify your fear.
But instead of retreating,
I had to step forward:
to be with you.
I mean, millions of women in history
have done so, for centuries.
And they had to do that,
they had no choice.
Can I, a man,
to live like this for 20 years
or a couple terms in office?
I think so.
So, Héléna,
come home with this ribbon.
Usually after such a passionate speech.
the crowd stands up and, uh.
and applauds, but, uh.
Get out of here now, please,
this is an official press conference,
not an American movie.
I'm sorry...
Uh, excuse me.
- What's going on?
- I don't understand.
Umberto!
Take off your glasses.
You were being disgusting, as usual.
But I recognize you now.
- I'll see you at dinner.
- What dinner?
It's gonna be a long time,
I'm gonna be asked a million questions.
Okay, we'll have breakfast together tomorrow.
No, I'll leave early tomorrow,
should be at the construction site of the third subway line.
The work got up there, they found two amphorae.
That's a shame. Well, I'll see you when you get back.
And on Wednesday morning.
I'm driving to Brussels at dawn
on the Committee of European Capitals of Culture.
- I must--
- Save Rome, I know.
I'll give it a try.
I'll be waiting.
But!
Dinner will get cold,
and Matilda and I will make a scene for you
a scene for being late,
and you're not gonna say anything,
because there's more of us.
And at home, we're in charge.
Id.
I'll be in stiff opposition,
but responsibly!
- Smile.
- Why?
There are photographers here.
Nina, can you call, uh.
Tommaso?
Here's a new report.
Three percent, not six percent.
Excuse us for just then.
And thanks from everyone for the bonus.
It's a gift from us,
for good luck.
100 yen...
Thank you.
Come on.
Here's to the new senior manager
of the London branch.
Momentum.
First, I want to hug each and every one of you,
bitches.
Now you know the whole story.
Mother of God, you were flirting
with Gabriel Garcia Marquez!
He took me...
He knew what to say, asshole!
You betcha!
So, basically.
you fell in love with Tommaso?
- He didn't choose the wine.
- What do you mean?
The first time we went out together,
we were at a wine bar.
Tommaso says to me:
"Take your pick, I don't care."
Never happened,
so a man doesn't pick out my wine.
Oddly enough, this one...
his relaxed nature
in any situation, I liked it.
Always in jeans, always in a sweatshirt,
even at your wedding, remember?
How will I forget? He ruined all the pictures.
And the way he said my name:
"N-Zoya, N-Zoya..."
It was horrible...
But it made me happy.
Zoé, you know, that's exactly what it is,
that you hated about him.
Hey, Marquez.
I wanted to ask you
one last favor.
I'd like to see Tommaso.
Where we met, on the Sisto Bridge.
It's our anniversary.
Am I right?
It's not about whether you're right or wrong.
I don't know if he'll agree.
Did you pack a suitcase?
The essentials.
I don't like to bring a lot of stuff with me.
I know.
What happened to your nose?
Well, let's say it's all Marquez.
- Are you okay?
- I'm not.
No, it's not.
But you have to answer:
"I'm fine, thank you. And you?"
I feel weird.
I don't know what I want.
Do you want to...
who drives a car with a tie on.
and listening to happy music,
writes novels with happy endings
without throwing her hair in the sink.
Tell me why, if I left you,
it makes me feel bad for some reason,
and you're like light and carefree?
I think it's because I'm desperate, Zoe.
So much for "joking" as usual.
Why would you want to see me?
Because it's not true
that we only had dinner at the restaurant.
We traveled,
we laughed a lot, Tom.
You're the person
who made me laugh the most
in my life.
We saved a lot of money
on broken plates.
And we made love less often than everyone else,
but a lot better than everyone else.
And three with two minuses?
Well, it's a weighted average.
As opposed to the arithmetic mean,
every number counts as more than just a number,
but it also carries a certain weight,
its importance, which affects the calculation.
You got it?
I realized that...
you always have
a genius way of looking at things, Zoe.
You see?
I've learned when I don't have to anymore.
Come with me.
We want to...
too different, Zoya.
Let's give it a try.
I've tried all these months,
but it didn't work out.
And so I'm not me anymore.
I'm... embarrassed.
I still don't like to drive,
I like sad music.
and sad endings.
And it's nobody's fault.
It happens.
If that's the case, why am I not happy?
Why?
Because the thought
of leaving without you makes me sad.
Incredibly sad.
I could come with you.
But what if I asked you to stay?
All right. Uh-huh.
Okay, I'll stay with you.
- Uh-huh?
- Yeah.
And when are you going to give me a hard time about it?
How soon we have each other...
hate?
And I don't want to hate you, Zoya.
I realized I wanted to be with you.
You don't want to be with me.
You're afraid of being without me.
Will you do me a favor?
Can you say that corny phrase?
It's a good place to be right now.
I'll always be there for you, you know.
ROMAN BREAKUPS
Good evening.
Are you two together?
- Uh, no.