It's been a year since
the Iast time I was here
This is Fujiko, a year ago
You'd better get some rest today
Thanks
I was engaged to Fujiko
at that time
How about ''Yumi''?
-For the baby's name?
-Yes
What if it's a boy?
No, it's a girI
How come?
Itjust feeIs so
She wiII be as pretty
as you are
Fujiko...
kept attempting suicide
Iast year
If that's what she wants
so be it
Aren't you going to
answer the phone?
Hey
What is this?
Are you going on a trip?
What did you want to teII me?
I don't have aII day
Just teII me whatever it is
-Not here
-What?
They are not here
What's not here?
-Socks
-Socks?
I've been knitting them before
Yumi was born
What Yumi?
What are you taIking about?
You know, powdery bIue ones
with pink fIowers
What are you taIking about?
You had an abortion
without even a word with me
Do you know why I did it?
I didn't
want to Iose you over Yumi
Get the phone
It must be Yumi
She's coming to take mommy
Can you answer it?
PIease answer it for me
I am busy
Fujiko!
Fujiko, Iook!
I said, Iouder!
Hey! Are you Iistening?
Louder, Iouder!
Cut!
Hey, what's going on?
You! Stop the water!
Turn the Iights on!
OK
1965 year
AIright, peopIe We got it right
up to when the phone rings
We are taking the mobiIe away
Um, then
That's aII for Ms. Keiko
Thank you very much
Thank you
Thank you aII
for everything
As you aII know
Keiko is retiring after this movie
You've been fantastic
Thank you very much
Keiko, be happy
Thank you, Aki!
Thank you for everything
What a pity
You couId've take next movie
You couId've managed both
your career and marriage
PIease, don't say that
I am sorry
I won't say it again
He doesn't want Keiko
to get married
ReaIIy...
You have been Iike
a father to me
Thank you
Excuse me
Reporters want to take her picture
in the studio
Is that O K ?
They are not finished yet
PIease, they want your Iast picture
as an actress for tomorrow's paper
- I'II be right over
- Wait
Yo! Thunder's not working yet?
Lighting is not working
Fix it, pIease
Ok, Do it
I'm so sorry
Mr. Ken You, too
Stay here forjust in case
Just in case?
After 1 7 movies together
this is the Iast one with Mr Mihara
I reaIIy feeI sad
It's been great to working with him
How about you
Mr. Mihara?
We've been working together
for a Iong time
I feeI sad, too
There was another movie Iining
for you two?
Yes, but because of me,
It's not gonna happen
I'm sorry
Are George and Mary gonna be
the next hero and heroine?
Mary couId be too young
for Mr. Mihara's counterpart
-Mr Mihara?
-Yes?
Mary as your counterpart
Oh, yes, yes
She is
I've been toId you gave up
the main roIe for George, though
There wiII be an
officiaI announcement Iater
-What is it?
-I have no idea I'II go check right away
The bus headed for the Iocation
is ready to Ieave
Hey, Ken
What's up?
News Flash
Director: Saito Tacehichi
Shoot the lead
TeII me what you know
They wiII kiII me if I do
Because of you...
It's to predictabIe
A lone wolf
Going against the gang
The sea calls the man
The man who believes in hope
Director: Yoshikawa takumi
The sea hawk
What's up?
Aren't you in the middIe
of shooting?
Modify the script for
''Wondering Dog''
and more cIose-ups
of Tetsu in ''Sea Hawk'', right?
-OK we'II keep it that way
-Good Job
What's going on?
CaIm down
Let's have a taIk
about next movie
I Iost my part in
''The Fang of Snowy Mountain''?
I was going to teII you that...
I can certainIy work
with a young actress
But, Mihara
You couId get me
another actress
if Mary is too young for me
There are pIenty out there
It's aII about how the audience thinks to them,
you are Keiko's counterpart Isn't he?
That's why the next movie is
so important to me!
But
Don't teII me you don't know
our recent box office record
-Are you bIaming me?
-I mean, the whoIe movie industry is going down
You saw ImperiaI Wedding
and Iast year's OIympics on TV
TV is rapidIy growing up
We must find a way
to get through this
-That
-That's why
We need new faces
We must be proactive
If not, we can't survive
It's inevitabIe
Way more serious than you think
I guess I have no choice
I quit, contract is about to be
expired anyway
But that's
I'm getting many proposaIs
And some independent
projects, too
I don't need to stay on
a sinking ship
CaIm down
The situation is the same
everywhere
You shouId think it over
Don't you think, Ms Shino?
If you are Ieaving, fine
I'm not kissing some
Big shot's ass anymore
But, If you are staying
we got pIans for you
I have a pIane
ReaIIy, what kind of pIans?
We'II make George Iook good
starting from next movie
There's even a murder scene at the end
We aIso have a pIan for sequeIs
How?
You said he gets murdered
He wiII come to Iife again, every time
He couId be a twin brother or a Iook-a-Iike, a robot
Oh! HeII no!
I'm not taking that kind of crap!
You know
Know what?
Keiko is retiring
Decision is from the main office
PIease understand
Or, maybe you can make her
change her mind?
Then the main office
wiII reconsider
You are here because
of Keiko anyway
Congratulations
Keiko be happy
The end of Love
Yes, more to the right
more, more
Yes, yes OK
OK Here we go
Ready?
Good, good
ReIax, reIax yourseIf
Ready?
Here we go
OK
FabuIous
We're ready to roII
Thank you
-Thank you so much
-Thank you
I'm sorry about your next movie
It's not your fauIt
-There wiII be
-I'm not coming to your fareweII party
I thought so
You don't have to quit
because you got married
There is no guarantee
for good parts in the future
AIso, I don't want to go into TV
That is so practicaI
An acting career is
a career of criticism and
I am tired of criticism
Don't push yourseIf too hard, too
-Keiko! Come here!
-I'II be right over, I gotta go
Good-bye
I am sure
I'II do fine even without you
Movie days are over
SpeciaI report on a huge
car accident happened near Tokyo
SeveraI cars got fiIed up
on the truck
that feII on the side
of the 3-19 freeway
At Ieast 5 peopIe were kiIIed and 15 peopIe were
severeIy injured according to the poIice report
The crash site is crowded
with peopIe...
-Is the thunder working?
-Yes, it is
Let's do it
He was going around a curve
when the tires bIew out...
What is it?
-It sure is a huge accident
-No, I mean, why aren't we working?
But the director is not
Then, go get him
We don't have aII day
How big wiII the frame be?
Head to chest
Boring
How about a cIose-up
with the teIephone in front?
No It's fine this way
Oh, yes
Prop!
Put that baby thing where
I can see, for inspiration
Scene begins with phone ringing
Um, we were OK
up to right before phone rings...
I know that
It's aII about inspiration
I'm sorry
Do it right, or you wiII be
an assistant forever
OK
Let's go
You want it here?
Take that away
It gets in the shot
What did you say?
I'm so sorry
Get down here!
Watch out!
He's not worth it
Get your stupid ass down here!
-Sorry...
-You stupid IittIe
What? What are you
Iooking at? Huh?
-PIease stop! No need to beat him up Iike that
-Let go of me!
What movies are you in
these days?
Something about the sea
since I pIay a saiIor
I get different parts everyday
- Which session are you?
- 8th
What session are you
Mr. Okita?
That's not how we started
Oh, yeah?
Then how did start?
How did I
Hey! Yo! How did you start?
Because I was a new face
ReaIIy?
He's kidding
He is not a reaI actor
My, stop it
We aII have different stories
But mostIy
it's a connection inside
Hey, Ken
Oh, my gosh It's Mr Mihara!
What's with that outfit?
- A saiIor, I presume
- Oh, yes It shouId be
We are off now
Which team is yours?
And aII these IoveIy Iadies
I'm showing these new girIs around
ReaIIy? You must be
this year's new faces
Yes, we are!
I am Ken Mihara
DeIighted to meet you
I am Reiko Takaki
I am Yuka Kitagawa
Oh, You are Kitagawa
Casting staff was Iooking for you
ReaIIy?
What couId it be?
CouId be your first movie
What?
My first movie?
I'II go with you
I was on my way there anyway
Casting staff, my ass
OnIy if he couId actjust as weII
What are you doing?
Don't worry
It's part of an acting career, too
Somebody might come in
No one is coming
Be a good girI
I can taIk an executive
into hiring you as my counterpart
Your counterpart?
Yes, starting next month
We wiII continue this
after that, then
Work is not over yet
What brought you here
to the studio?
It's been reaIIy Iong
So many changes here, too
Was this buiIding here
during my days?
WeII, maybe
Can't you just quit?
You drink at work
hiding from peopIe
I am not hiding
Remember Masda?
He pIayed a cop in ''Either Love or Dream''
Oh, yes Masda
He aIso drank
with a IittIe bottIe Iike this
in the corner of the studio
whiIe others were working...
Is he stiII around?
Not since a few years ago
I wonder what he's doing
these days
He's an aIcohoIic...
Enough with him
Are you ok? Isn't this your
knitting Wednesday?
Doesn't matter now
Honey, do you have the script?
Script? Or course I do
Why?
I wiII read Iines with you
What, I'm fine
I've been doing it
many times aIready
But
What? Just popping in Iike that...
Go home
I'm sorry, I ...
- Hon
- I said, go home
No, I mean, you got
something on your shirt
It's a prop, isn't it?
ShouId it be O K ?
So what?
You know these things happen
It's a job. You were an actress,
once You shouId know it... Or what?
Are you stiII suspecting things
between Keiko and me?
Oh, you are shutting up again
It's aII over with Keiko Over
I'm sorry
It's aII my fauIt, that miscarriage
What are you taIking about?
Enough It's aII in the past now
I am sorry, it was I
Enough aIready!
Do you want an apoIogy?
You want to make me
a bastard, huh?
Forget it Go,
just go
- That's not what I meant
- Just go!
Yes, I got it
No! Honey! I just
Mihara, you are up next
OK Rain!
Good
Ready, action! O K
Phone rings!
Cut! Keep going!
Thunder, keep that pace!
Got it!
Ken, widen your eyes
Now
Phone rings!
What happened to thunder?
Go right after he Iooks back!
OK !
Let's go one more time Go!
Phone!
Thank you for everything
- Hey there! What is it now?
- Again?
Mihara! Your wife
car accident this morning
...cop caIIed in
she passed away
Mio, where are you?
I'm here
- Haven't found it yet?
- I've got it
What was that honking noise for?
Some idiot puIIed up a car right
in front of the studio entrance
I'm sure it has nothing to do
with work, Damn
Hey! You're taking that
to the studio, right?
Yes
- Then, run!
- OK !
Dr. Samejima
Sorry to keep you waiting
Here it is... Huh?
The ''reminiscing scene'' is
over aIready?
- What about this?
- Um, don't need it
But the director wanted it
in the scene...
WeII, we aIready fiImed that part
- Sorry, oh, and this
- What is it?
Director wants some coIor in it
- Which coIor?
- Doesn't matter
Just make it bright, OK ?
Beats me
I don't make the decision
Sorry
-Whoa, cooI! Let me try that Like this?
-Yeah, exceIIent
Cut
My, it Iooks so deserted here
These days, we TV stations
make most of the movies
Hey, get that
There!
Start
OK, roII it
WeII, Dr Samejima is fuIIy enjoying
the coffee break
OK, this is a tryout
A tryout
- ChaIIenging the Assistant Director, OK?
- Hi
It's good to see you
- What the
- How are you?
- So, so tanned your face
- Nice to meet you
What happened to your face?
It's from Hawaii whiIe working
on a photograph book
WeII, it couId happen
Hey, put something in her hand
-AIright, is this okay?
-Yeah, yeah Perfect
What kind of nurse is that?
Some kind of nurse, that is
- Have you been on a ride?
- Yes
At the amusement park...
I think any Buddhist thing
shouId do fine
Oh, reaIIy?
OK
-Hey, Mio, that's not right
-Why?
We got another actor
for that part
What? Then this
I don't think we can use it
You shouId've toId me earIier
Do we have that man's picture?
No, we don't
Then what? This scene wiII be
fiImed tomorrow
-Testing!
-OK, go!
Where on earth is there
a nurse this tanned?
But
Look who's taIking
There's no doctor Iike
you, either
Director! Testing wiII start
in a second Director!
OK, Oh, yeah, sorry
I have to go work
Yeah, thanks Sorry
ShaII we start?
Good, good
what the...
you're so tanned
It couId happen
Lucky...
getting a nice tan
OK , Iet's run a test
I am dying, aren't I?
Don't say that
How come no one
teIIs me anything?
I saw my mother crying
over there
TeII me! Am I dying?
Don't worry
Dr. Samejima wiII cure you
Put your Iife in my hand!
Whose phone is that?
HeIIo? No, I am working
Oh, you want the answer
It's a crab, get it? A crab
It's for a funeraI, I wish I couId
to get a recent photo of him
-He is coming here, right?
-Yes
Then why don't you
take a photo of him?
But they say he worked for
this company
Yes, he used to work here
Here, this is aII I got
Ken Mihara
Never seen this face before
His time was brief
I think he was an aIcohoIic
Even after his wife died
He got into troubIe because of
his aIcohoI probIem
No other photos of him? According
to the profiIe, he is 65 now
Nope, I heard he retired
Ah, yes, here's a photo of him
as a chiId actor
Put your Iife in my hand!
In My hand!
You Iook upset...
Oh, I couId come to your pIace tonight
No, I got work to do
You are so coId these days
You didn't even answer my caII
yesterday
I caIIed your home, your wife said
you were aIready in bed
What? My home?
What for?
Is yeIIow OK for it?
Whatever, hey, did you reaIIy
caII my home?
Whatever, what coIor?
WeII, anything bright
Enough with that
Which bright coIor?
Um, weII
What coIor is an
anti-cancer soIution?
I think I'd better go
Why?
Where is the studio?
Which studio?
- For ''Dr. Samejima''
- Oh, this one
-Oh, are you a prop manager?
-Yes, I am
Someone shouId be there
Go ahead
It's OK to go in
No, that
When the Iight fIashes, it used to
mean ''Shooting in Progress''
It's stiII the same
You must be our oId man
Yes
You were supposed to meet me
at the main gate
- I know my way around
- I see
Um, shooting
hasn't started yet
Can you wait in the waiting room?
- Mio, show him the way
- Huh? Me?
Sorry, I'm supposed to
meet someone
-You got your script, right?
-Yes
OK, then
I owe you one
ShaII we go then?
This way, pIease
I have to take your photo
Iater today
Photo?
- For the funeraI scene
- Oh, Yes
Dr. Samejima
Something wrong?
Come on in
- Hi
- HeIIo
Hi, wouId you change into this?
Here are your sIippers
StyIists are having aII the fun
and aII we have is
a nightgown for an extra
-Excuse me
-Yes?
This
Doesn't matter
There's no waIking scene
It was a Iast minute decision
We weren't even informed your size
The patient is supposed to be
in the 3rd stage of cancer
Then, wouId you Iie down?
-Exam with bare hands Iike this
-With bare hands?
Let's say, there's something
Iumpy around here
Lumpy?
In that case, you say 'You have
water retaining here ' casuaIIy
Oh, casuaIIy
That's right
Do not say so to the patients
Let's switch the roIes here
I'II be the patient
Here?
Yes That's good
-Like this?
-Yeah, that's good, that's good
What the
You got something Lumpy here
No, no, you say
'You got water retaining here'
No, I mean, for reaI
Oh, yes
You got water retaining here
I do have Iumpy things in me
This is our medicaI adviser
Mr. Yano
Nice to meet you
- Nice to meet you
- Same here...
Guess what
He drives a Mercedes
PIease, don't say
-ReaIIy? Are you reaIIy a doctor?
-Yes, I am
Why don't we
start with an injection?
- Injection
- Yes
- Just to Iook reaI
- To Iook reaI, yes
WeII then, be a patient
one more time
Let's do the injection
Then, roII up up And then
No You shouId caIm the patient
down, yes, smiIe, smiIe
and psst!
See? Psst! Like this
Now it's scene 76
This is Mr Mihara, he pIays
Mr. Yamada, the oId man
Excuse me, but
how oId are you ...?
You Iook too heaIthy
for a 3rd stage cancer patient
Don't you think?
Indeed
Makeup! Make him Iook sick
Do the hair, too
Got it Let's
I can do it myseIf
No, I'II do it for you
Here, we got no time
This way
Excuse me
Are you wearing makeup?
Er... no , I mean
Is this foundation?
Foundation? ReaIIy?
PIease read the script
before work starts
So, my motivation is...
Whatever, hurry up
with the makeup
What is this on your hair?
Pomade?
For women...
For those women, there
Press hard here
-See this vein? Tap it
-Ou, ouch, it hurts
No, it doesn't
It doesn't hurt
HoIIy shit!
It's so creepy
Whoa! Don't Iook at me
Let's see Damn it, Scary
It's Iike a horror movie
ReaI Horror
Hey, makeup
Isn't this too much?
No, I onIy took off his foundation
ReaIIy?
Then we'II go this way
It's so reaIistic
You're reaIIy scaring me!
OK , OK
Then Iet's run a test
OK, testing
Mr. Yamada
Any reIative is fine
We must take care of insurance
and other things
I have money
It's not that
I need to taIk with your famiIy
about treatment, too
Anyone's fine, just Iet me
contact any of them
You must be IoneIy
not to have any visitor at aII
No wife, no chiIdren
Don't bother!
They are in heaven aIready
Just Ieave me aIone!
Cut!
Diretor, you go there
Samejima
This way, Yuka, here
Nice to meet you
The mystery of Dr. Samejima's
earIy Iife gets
cIearer in the movie, I've heard
Yes, the mystery wiII be soIved
Long time, no see
Excuse me?
I've never forgotten you
Get down here!
-I am terribIy sorry
-You stupid IittIe
What? What are you
Iooking at? Huh?
Now you are one fine engineer
I owe you a big one
It's good to see you again
Same here
REALLY good to see you again
Let's not pIay it hard today
Now for the director
it's your first movie
Have you aIways been
pIanning on making movies?
WeII, I...
Thank you
So...
You know the movie ''Omen 2''
That captured my heart
I've aIways dreamt of making
movies Iike that, even once
Did you have Iunch?
WouId you come to waiting room?
Let's take your photo
OK
That was hard
My part wiII be edited
anyway, right?
Of course, it wiII be
Er, Excuse me
Dr. Samejima's hourgIass
HourgIass?
Yes, during the operation
on a desert isIand
Desert isIand?
Yes During his operation
on a boy there,
after crossing over
the stormy ocean
There was an hourgIass?
At the Iast meeting
you said what
if he used an hourgIass
to check puIses...
Yes, I did
Yes, yes
I couIdn't find the one
you wanted
So, I made one myseIf
But, do they check puIses
with an hourgIass?
No ordinary watch?
You said the watch gets broken
because of the sea water
Waterproof
G-shock, Iike this
But
Forget it
That wouIdn't Iook right
Go with it
Director has spoken
OK
Congratulations Keiko
The end of Love
Opened on October 12th, 1965
The Big Star Keiko's
finaI masterpiece
The End of Love
I didn't see it...
Hundreds of movies came out
every year those days
Most of them were hardIy
known to the pubIic,
but they were aII good
It's not easy to watch oId movies
in a theater
or on video these days
That's true
I used to work here as
a recording engineer
It was exciting back then
The studio was fuII of peopIe
Iights were on nights and days
I worked Iike crazy everyday
But I reaIIy miss then
Oh, my
-Mihara, is it reaIIy you?
-Yes
There was a huge Iayoff
when I was 40
They toId me to be a freeIancer
In other word, I got fired
There was a sharp faII
in production
Right, I was forced to take
an ordinary job
It wasn't easy
FiIm was aII I knew
I swore not to come back
but eventuaIIy I came back
Swore not to come back
What do you think it is?
I've aIways wanted to
come back... Why?
- What is it?
- Nothing
Oh, the waiting room
during the oId days
-Did you use it, too?
-Yes
It's a warehouse now
The fIoor is aII rotten and ruined
Is that so
What can you do? They are TV
peopIe, and that's their attitude...
Oh, and the director
he got his hair impIanted
It's aIright
I quit
Quit what?
- Work
- Why?
Because it's useIess
Come on, you were just
unIucky this time
What an asshoIe
He succeeded in TV
He doesn't know
shit about movies
Just kissing the
TV producer's ass
But stiII he is a director
even with impIanted hair
Supporting a director to
compIete a movie
no matter what
That's ourjob
-Some job you have there
-Listen
I know work is hard
the paycheck isn't stabIe
and you are busy as heII
But you are doing great
Let's taIk about it tonight
I can stay over your house
What the heII are you
taIking about?
- Why you
- Get out!
- What the
- Get out
Someone there?
Sorry, sorry
What are you doing there?
I didn't mean to
I was remembering oId days
and my feet Ied me here
I used to date here
behind peopIe's eyes
It was nothing Iike that
Besides, you shouId be
in the waiting room
Sit down here, pIease
Here we go
SmiIe, pIease
Make it a soft smiIe
- Make me Iaugh
- Excuse me?
It's been awhiIe
I mean I wasn't the good at smiIing
naturaIIy back then, either
The guard showed me
your oId photo
You were a chiId actor
There was a studio
near my house
I was accidentaIIy picked up
You got picked up?
CooI!
It wasn't that great
One day, a director asked me
You, aren't you hungry?'
Come to think of it now
any kid who couId eat vigorousIy
was fine to him
I was perfect because
my famiIy was so poor
I wore a costume, a wig
and make-up
After one Iine
aII I had to do was eat
During the shoot I had a bowI of rice
Whenever mother roIe actress
made a mistake
I got a whoIe new bowI of rice
It was heaven
As Iong as that woman had
kept making mistakes
I'd eat as much as I couId
I thought I reaIIy stuffed myseIf
Then I thought, an acting
career was good
Movies were good
There are onIy a few reaI actors
The rest works just for food
- Are you serious?
- Excuse me?
About quitting yourjob?
You heard it
I'm sorry
Are you serious?
Yes, I am
ReaIIy
I Iove movies
That's why I'm here, but
But?
Um...
You once quit acting
didn't you?
It was for because of my ego
Everyone Ieft me
EventuaIIy I Iost everything
It's been 35 years
Since the Iast time
I was here and in a movie
I reaIIy want to be in a movie
one more time
Even in a movie Iike this?
Like this?
You know, cheap and cheesy
That's what the audience decides
Right now, I pIay an oId man
That's it
Did you get it?
A smiIing face
Yes, thank you very much
Are you OK ?
Kayoko, Kayoko
Where are you...?
- Nurse!
- What is it?
Something's wrong with Yamada
Are you aIright?
I want to see Kayoko!
Is she a reIative?
Who is Kayoko, Yamada?
Are you OK?
You seem to be in pain
Who is she, that Kayoko?
You sounded so desperate
Your daughter?
No His daughter is Kazue
and his wife is Sachiko
Then who is she?
She was my sweetheart
and, um, er
Cut!
Let's go one more time
OK, go!
Who is she, that Kayoko?
You sounded so desperate
Your daughter?
No His daughter is Kazue
and his wife is Sachiko
Then who is she?
She was my sweetheart
Did you see her in a dream?
CouId it be my Iife
passing through
in front of my eyes
right before I die?
Kayoko is his daughter
between his ex-wife
What do you think
you know about it?
Cut!
Your Iine is,
You, who gave you the right to
Sorry
-OK Keep going, track 3!
-OK, go!
My sweetheart
Did you see her in a dream?
CouId it be my Iife
passing through
in front of my eyes
right before I die?
Kayoko is his daughter
between his ex-wife
What the heII do you know?
No, I mean...
You're not doing it right
Cut, cut!
- Sorry, roII change
- OK, roII change
Wait a second
- Narita
- Yes
Yes! Hey, turn that on!
- Isn't this uncomfortabIe?
- I'm fine
- Want some tea?
- No, I'm reaIIy fine
Hey, shouIdn't this be
exposed to the Iight?
Is this OK?
One more
This is good
Treat patients gentIy
Yes
Look here, isn't it great?
It's the Southern Cross
Get a receipt aII the time
Whose name are you
gonna put there?
ShouId it be
'Production Department'?
No Don't write anything down
Just hand it to me
Excuse me?
- What is it?
- Nothing
Sorry to keep you waiting
RoII is changed
Ready to go
Let's go one more time
Track 4!
Track 5!
-We'II keep going
-Track 6!
Track 7!
No His daughter is Kazue
and his wife is Sachiko
Then who is she?
She was my sweetheart
Did you see her in a dream?
CouId it be my Iife
passing through
in front of my eyes
right before I die?
Kayoko is his daughter
between his ex-wife
Cut!
God damn it
Who hired him?
- Director?
- What?
How about getting dinner first?
Dinner Time
Let's have dinner first and
get back to work at 19:30
Make it shorter
Sorry
Be back by 19:00
- Sasaki!
- Yes?
- How much more do we have?
- Two more scenes
Didn't you say that before?
- There have been some probIems
- What kind of probIems?
The oId man has a probIem
with Iines
Shit, I want to wrap
things up now
I'm not sure when
this wouId be finished
Let's dub Iater
He can't do his Iine right
What's wrong?
Are you nervous?
- My brain doesn't seem to work
- You are not that oId
I thought you wouId come
Are you aIright 'tiI the end?
I can do it TiII the end
' No, his daughter is Ichie
and his wife is Sachiko '
' Then who is she? '
What are you
' No, his daughter's name is Ichie
and his wife's name is Sachiko '
' Then who is she? '
She was my sweetheart
' Did you see her in a dream? '
CouId it be my Iife
passing through
in front of my eyes
right before I die?
' Kayoko is his daughter
between his ex-wife '
You! Who gave you the
right to investigate my past?
' I'm sorry, Mr. Yamada, it might
not be my business, but...'
Stay out of my business
you IittIe jerk!
See? You can do it
Ken Mihara
Wow, it's great
Your name is here
- Where's your Iine?
- Here
Driver, weren't you
supposed to turn right?
It's aII the same
This must be the Iong way around
Not at aII, Madam
' Did you see her in a dream? '
CouId it be my Iife
passing through
in front of my eyes
right before I die?
' Kayoko is his daughter
between his ex-wife '
Honey
Don't you hate me?
What are you taIking about?
Didn't you regret marrying me?
No, I didn't
Were you happy?
Not aII the time
but you know
I saw aII of your movies
on the opening day
You've never said that before
Everybody watched it with tears
and Iaughter...
So did I
I reaIIy had a good time
When drunk, you aIways said
acting was your destiny
I did?
You
wiII be an actor if you are
born again, won't you?
Mihara?
I'm coming in
Mihara!
Mihara, are you ok?
I'm caIIing for heIp
No
But
I don't care
how smaII the part is
I wiII even quit drinking
What are you taIking about?
Let me be in a movie
But
PIease! Let me be in a movie
just once more!
Are you OK?
You seem to be in pain
Who is she?
Kayoko?
What?
You sounded so desperate
Your daughter?
No, his daughter is Ichie
and his wife is Sachiko
Then who is she?
She was my sweetheart
Did you see her in a dream?
CouId it be my Iife passing
in front of my eyes
Cut
Are you OK ?
Can't you do something?
- Excuse me, director?
- Yes?
ShouId we spIit the scene?
Do we reaIIy need this scene?
Oh, weII, Iet's do it
one more time
But he's miIking the work
- Hey, what wouId you do?
- Um, but
Let's Ieave it there
Can't you just shorten his scene?
No, you can't
DefiniteIy can't!
It's not your business, princess
- Mr. Maejima
- Yes?
Isn't it a bit dim on Mr. Mihara?
Yeah, it is
ShouId we bring it up?
- I'II do it
- No, I'II do it
Never mind
We might edit this out
What time is it supposed to be?
What's the time?
Oh, weII, midnight, I think
5 o'cIock
Is it 5 AM?
Who gives a damn about a cIock?
Who says so, you rat!
I'II fix it right away
Of course you wiII!
Don't sIack off on your work!
I'm sorry, I'm fine now
Are you reaIIy OK ?
- One more mistake, man, One more!
- What do you think?
- Perfect
- WeII, Iet's go
Ready, go!
You sounded so desperate
Your daughter?
No, his daughter is Ichie
and his wife is Sachiko
Then who is she?
She was my sweetheart
Did you see her in a dream?
CouId it be my Iife
passing through
in front of my eyes
right before I die?
Kayoko is his daughter
between his ex-wife
You! Who gave you right to
investigate my past?
I'm sorry, Mr. Yamada, it might
not be my business, but...
Stay out of my business
you IittIe jerk!
I toId you
I don't want to see anyone
Don't interrupt my death!
Let's go
- OK, Perfect!
Now, next scene
- Are you OK?
- Yes
One more scene
and you are done
- When wiII it be over?
- We have a Iive show to do soon
WeII, it's the oId man's
death scene
When time's up
we'II take him out
That won't be possibIe, we, too
have a scheduIe to foIIow
- How many more?
- 3
- How many of them are Samejima's?
- 2
OK , then do them first!
No rehearsaI
If the oId man makes a mistake
do the voice separateIy!
- PIease do that
- TeII director so
It's aII about time saving
Did you find her?
She's...
She aIready died
Last year, breast cancer
She was onIy 36
How sad
Yamada must have
known it aIready
Kayoko, thanks for coming
You must've been so IoneIy
I'm sorry
Dad
It's me
Kayoko
Yamada
It's Kayoko
Ah, Kayoko
Thank you
Cut! OK !
Next is Samejima's scene #3
We skip scene #2 for now
I guess he can take a break
Oh...you want to keep going?
- Yes
- Get ready
We wiII work on your scene first
What the! Hey! What are you doing?
What are you fiIming?
It's... scene #2
CIose-up for the oId man
What are you doing?
Shoot Samejima first
Hurry! Hurry! Do it!
But...
Director!
Can't you do it Iater?
Hey, you...
We got a Iive show to do...
Do the oId man's scene Iater
Next is the cIose-up scene
for Samejima
Stop it! Camera!
You have to Iet Samejima go
as soon as possibIe
Is that so?
Doesn't this take Iong?
It'II onIy take a second
You have to reset
the Iighting and others
- AII ready now
- Let's go
OK action!
Dad, it's me
Kayoko
Yamada, it's Kayoko
Ah, Kayoko
Thanks
Cut! OK !
That was great
I promise you
I won't quit...
I won't quit making movies