Viviana I have to run away.
When Franco arrives I'll call you.
- But a kick in the ass!
- Ernesto it's enough!
I have to do something important,
can I leave Sharon
here for an hour?
No, Cosimo.
Take her to the taxi stand.
All right, thank you.
It's about Anna, Franco's daughter.
Answer.
Ernesto!
You're a pain in the ass with that gun!
Come here, my love.
Go to the window and see if Franco comes.
Go.
- Hello, Anna.
- Anna, darling.
Hi Vivi, has the
present for dad arrived?
Yes, here it is, look.
Perfect!
Tell him it's from mom too.
Sure, he'll be happy.
I can't wait
to see him in this suit.
How are you, are
you in love with someone?
I don't have time,
I have to study like crazy.
But she's
daddy's girl, if she finds
a boyfriend, he'll
have a heart attack.
He's been rehearsing
his parting speech for a month now.
"Once upon a time
there was a good policeman, who in
35 years of service he never..."
How is it that he says he?
“… shot a
Christian in his lifetime.”
Even Anna knows it.
My dad is really Franco
Amore, in name and in fact.
Here he is, he's coming.
Gabriele, turn off the lamp back there.
We all have to hide.
You get under the table.
Don't mess everything up.
Doctor Loria, be careful with your glass.
Fulvio take it here.
- Ernesto?
- Where will I hide?
You...
Come here, sit on the armchair...
and you hide with your jacket.
Watch out for the bottle.
Ok. Very good.
Wonderful, I will hang it here.
You have to stick to
the wall like wallpaper.
Perfect.
My love.
Surprise!
What do you look like?
- I had a stroke.
- Poor pensioner.
- Hello.
What a surprise.
I went for a jog.
He how are you?
Well.
Starting tomorrow
you can plan the marathon.
Look over there, how are you?
- Hello.
- Look who's there.
Here I am! I'm here too!
What are you doing here?
Don't you have to study for exams?
I wouldn't have missed
your party for the world.
I'm sorry I'm not there.
Look at your daughter and your
ex what a sweetie they sent you.
- How beautiful!
- For tonight and for tomorrow's photos.
Yes, for the speech.
I'm told you're preparing a
beautiful retirement speech.
You need to pinch them.
No, the speech is beautiful.
Try on the jacket, I want
to see how it fits on you.
Let's try it. Sarah, can you hold this?
One and two.
Here you go, what do you say?
From behind it is perfect!
- Really.
- Yes, it's perfect!
Love.
- He's getting emotional!
- Drink!
- Sorry...
- A toast!
Excuse me.
Surely it's Sarno, he's
already called a couple of times.
In fact it's him, he'll want to wish you a happy birthday.
Doctor, good evening.
Yes.
All right.
- I have to go, excuse me.
- Now?
Tonight too?
You retire tomorrow,
can't someone else go?
I'm sorry my love.
It was Sarno, the usual trouble.
- At this time?
- I'll call you if I need to.
You stay.
Of course, you come and go.
- We'll wait for you here.
- Yes.
- Excuse me.
- We keep the party warm.
Take the sparkling wine, come on!
Hi, I'm a colleague.
Let him through.
Thank you.
What was Dino doing here?
Do you know something?
I don't know shit, Doc.'
Three bullets to the chest.
One severed the aorta.
It was...
a quick death.
Stop!
[TEN DAYS EARLIER]
"The first time I wore a 'uniform".
I was 20.
And today, after 35 years,
I can guarantee that I am even more proud...
even more proud...
more and more.
Always...
prouder of my choice..."
"...of my choice made."
Move on!
"More and more proud...
of my choice...
done."
And voilà, paradise.
What you are holding is not
a watch, you are holding time.
Let's be clear.
When you train at Milan, maybe
Ibra doesn't even look at you.
But if he's in the locker room he
sees what you have on her wrist,
then see how he works
hard to make you score!
And then it costs shit!
Bro, do you want to take a selfie with Abdu?
- No thank you.  I support Inter.
- Shit, Inter.
Everyone has his cross.
Cosimo, sell ​​a 50,000 euro watch
and drive around in a shit car?
It's a service car.
And a real cop.
He acts as my chauffeur when I
need him and I give him 50 euros.
Be a good boy.
Lady.
Franco.
Have a couple of hours of extra time?
Abdu, at the next goal you tap your
wrist and do Cosimo's C for the camera.
- Promised.
- Be good, understand?
Fuck Abdu!
These fucking Chinese,
someone has to explain it to me.
It would take Piero Angela.
What's it about having no hair?
"The new generations...
The younger generations..."
Well, it's the same.
"...they should look at the photos
of our heroes at the police station,
and be inspired by those heroic looks".
"Be inspired by the looks..."
Heroic!
"...to heroic looks..."
Yes?
What the fuck happened?
Help me or we are ruined!
The Chinese boss is dying.
- Did you call the ambulance?
- You called it!
Go down and make the call.
Get the driver, because if he
dies I want a Chinese witness.
Go!
Stronger. These are caresses.
Where the fuck am I going dressed like this?
Hey!
What do you want?
Leave it alone, it doesn't suit you.
These people hurt you.
Thank you.  I'll do it.
Get dressed in the elevator.
Come on, Franco.
I'm in.
Can you give me a hand?
Can you press 29?
The last one?
If you don't look down, nothing happens.
Don't worry.
"Don't look down."
I look down.
Finally I can look
at Milan from above.
So it's a whim.
How am I, Franco?
You are an angel.
You always answer me like this.
Can't you see that I'm all sweaty because of you?
You made me run.
My feet already hurt.
I like it when you sweat because of me.
Franco!
I'm serious.
How am I?
In my opinion?
No, according to the parish priest of San Demente.
I don't know what he thinks, but to
me you are an angel come down to earth.
All right.
Even the parish priest, if he saw you, would say:
"A miracle!
Angels exist."
- You're a lunatic.
- No!
- Watch out!  You make my jacket dirty.
- Excuse me.
- What's up?
- You are pretty.
Yes?
Much.
All right.
May we?
Bro, what the fuck.
Do not say anything.
We parked away.
No parking suited him.
Why do I have to take the fines?
It annoys me.
It annoys you to have them removed.
We have to remove this.
Never been arrested for
bribing a public official.
What did you bring?
- Parmigiana.
- You are a genius.
Excuse me.
In my opinion, he doesn't like the provolone.
- What do you mean?
- What did he say?
"You don't like it."
He talks like a chef.
Hello, could he tell Zhang
Zhu that we are here?
Yes, my dad is waiting for you.
- May I?
- No thank you.  I prefer to keep it.
Okay.  I'll tell him you arrived.
I've been frying all morning.
- Cosimo, do you speak Chinese?
- Huh?
- No, I don't know.
- Excuse me.
Zhang Zhu, is a form of respect.
They like it.
Zhang Zhu.
It's ready.  Welcome.
Please.
- Mr. Zhu.
- Allow me.
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
Za Zu Zhang.
Pleasure.
I'm Viviana, Franco's wife.
- Pleasure.
- I made you a parmigiana
to give you some energy in
this complicated juncture of life.
Very kind of you, thanks.
Keep it upright as the oil could leak.
Thank you.
It's pretty spicy.
It's good for the heart.
- I like it spicy.
- In Calabria we do it like this.
I figured you liked it too.
It's good for the heart.
' Viviana? - Yes.
The wife of the hero
who saved my life.
- Yes.
- I have a nice present too.
You didn't have to.
This is carp fish.
- Beautiful.
- He lives in the Yellow River.
According to legend, every year thousands
of carp fish swim upriver to spawn.
But there is a waterfall,
the Dragon Waterfall,
which is very high,
so they can't climb it.
But there is always a better one who
manages to climb and becomes a dragon.
So, in China, for us,
carp fish is the
symbol of good luck.
Like your husband.
For me it is a carp fish.
- He?
- Yes.
I too always say that he is a fish,
because he always bites everything.
It's good.
Anyway, all kidding aside,
Franco is a solid man, Zhu Za Zhang.
Such a cool guy.
Indeed.
I fell in love with him
from the first moment.
This big fish!
I understand you.
I was 20 years old, I was very young.
I had just arrived in Milan.
It was love at first sight.
Zhang Zhu wants me
to introduce the family.
Follow me?
- Go.
- I'll be right there.
Are you with Olivia?
Anything, ask me.
- Thanks again.
- Please.
- Allow me.
I finish here and come.
Thank you for coming.
Thank you for the invite.
How are you, Mr. Zhang?
I take all these
medicines, I need to rest
and reflect a bit
about what has been and what will be.
Right.
I heard that
you will retire soon, right?
I too have to reflect on what
has been and what will be.
- Well, well.
- Yes.
When the day comes,
I would like you to come and work for me.
It would be a great honor.
Please.
Mr. Zhang would
like to give you the
opportunity to set up
a security service for us.
Very similar to the one he offers
to Cosimo, but on a larger scale.
You are always so modest.
Franco, that's great.
Very big.
Your generosity knows no bounds, Mr. Zhang.
My son-in-law will be running the
business while I'm still recovering.
- Pleasure, and bon appétit.
- Thank you.
I hope you enjoy the
parmigiana I brought you.
Look, it's your suit.
It's fine with you.
I have been in service for 35 years.
There are some rules that I would like to apply.
The same rules I use with Cosimo.
Tell me.
I do not transport
people with a criminal record, armed people,
and I don't do security with
stolen goods and narcotics.
That's all.
Our company has been operating
legally for 20 years in this country.
- Did you take us for criminals?
- No, no
Excuse me, I didn't mean to offend you.
It was to be clear.
In all honesty...
We Chinese are very
good at generating cash,
a bad financial guard makes
life very difficult for us.
For this, we decided to
explore the world of Cosimo.
Because so much cash
can become a small stone.
So, it's me asking you
not to do anything illegal,
- that could get us in trouble.
- We agree.
Very good.
The first shipment will arrive next week.
Mr. Amore will need reliable help.
Franco can bring a colleague, right?
Next week?
Wednesday or Thursday.
I thought Mr. Zhang needed
my services after retirement.
Mr. Zhang also said
that I now run the business.
So the first shipment
arrives next week.
Two batches for 5,000 euros
in cash could be fine, right?
Yes, they could.
It's just that...
I want to think about it for a moment.
Here, at the slightest bullshit
they take away your pension.
I'm getting there, I'm almost there.
The only shit he could
do before retirement
would be to say no to this contract,
not to take an hour's drive.
Good day, gentlemen.
Enjoy the party.
Five thousand euros for one day.
You earn them in three months.
And be sophisticated too, Franco.
What the fuck!
How many years have I
seen you return home dissatisfied?
Whiny, long-snouted like Calimero?
Huh?
Franco, we've waited forever.
You've always remained assistant chief.
Here is your revenge against
all those who wished you badly.
Franco, are you listening to me?
Yes.
Sorry, love, but when
do you find an employer
who calls you like Zhang called you?
"My hero."
"My fish brings good luck."  Come on!
There is no better champagne than this.
Let's make a toast that
now Tito is coming too.
- Is Tito there? Where is he?
- He's here. He's coming.
Can we make a toast with Tito?
What should we toast to?
To the Chinese, Franco.
We hit the super jackpot.
What the fuck!
Leave him alone.
He's stubborn.
Is the job he offered him dangerous?
- Dangerous?  For Franco?
- I'm asking.
He is more pacifist than Gandhi.
He saved Zhang's life.
And he told me:
"How can I thank Franco?"
He was thinking of 600 euros.
I told him, "No, with that's he
will feel  offended. He's a solid man.
Since you have this
gemstone business
from Africa, hire
Franco for security.
After 35 years of service,
he sees things we don't...
Understood?
And I told him you're retiring.
I won't be retired yet next week.
- Í know.!'
I know.
And that's the problem?
Cosimo, if I walk around with
you and they stop me, I can
tell you're my wife's cousin
and I'm giving you a lift.
If they stop me with the Chinese,
what do I tell them?
You are right.
Sorry bro'.
In your 35-year honorable career,
in which you've never shot anyone,
when was the last time they stopped you?
When?
Do they have to stop you
now doing this thing for Zhang?
Come on.
Franco, I'm sorry, but he's right.
This is a negative thought.
So what?
Hey.
- Beautiful cousin, how are you?
- Good.
- You look good.
- Stop it!
Before the little one came,
Giorgina cooked as if it were
always the feast of San Rocco.
Now that we're married,
she became vegan.
Tito, she keeps you in shape.
How are you and the baby?
They are fine.
Come and visit us every now and then.
So you also see Cataldo, who
is becoming a handsome boy.
Yes, I would like that too.
Good. Let's make a toast.
Commissioner.
Milan would be safer with
a commissioner like you.
So?
What are we toasting to, Bruce Lee?
'The fucking Chinese bought everything.
What should we call you, Genghis Cazz?
I'll go get some air.  Excuse me.
- Please.
But why are you always teasing him?
I only compliment him.
- No.
- I respect that.
He's the one who never greets me.
Vivian...
It's a bit psycho-rigid.
No offense.
He is a lovable man, but psycho-rigid.
It's character.
No. Franco only respects the rules.
All right?
I had to beg him to come here.
So, don't start with this puppet.
Why?  We are good people.
So!
If a judge enters here,
he closes the doors
and puts you and  your comrades on trial
One, two and three.
This is a partnership.
- We have to spread out.
- Scatter you two!
Why don't you give it to Ernesto?
Truly?
Don't you want to bring it?
The helmet came off, it needs to be glued.
- He'll be delighted. He loves guns.
- Amore?
I'm ruining you this morning.
For me cappuccino and brioche.
- Stay on a diet!
- He made me run tonight.
I deserved it.
The first 50 meters
it looked like Bolt,
then the bellows
came and he collapsed.
I'll put it here, then I'll take it.
If I don't catch
you, go to the ground.
Stop it.
So I can't get the handcuffs off you.
But look at this!
- China is close.
- Do not move.
Hey!
- All ready for the final greeting?
- Yes, sir.
You wrote a speech of four
hours and 40 minutes.
We need to shorten it, but
not the part where you praise me.
- That's important.
- Certainly.
- He has a face like ass.
- A career animal.
Tell us about this bad night.
Filipinos against Chinese in Gothic.
Two Filipinos on the
ground, stab wounds.
We arrived right away.
Then, a third Filipino approaches,
points me to a dark alley and says:
"They hide there. They are armed."
I thought, "The fuck I'm
going down a dark alley."
I was going to tell him, "Take
a gun, shoot whoever you want."
Then, I see this asshole rocketing off.
What was I supposed to do?  I followed him.
Anyway, two small fish.
They'd stashed doses of
shaboo nearby for retrieval.
We caught one, who's right there.
He is 17 years old.
Chinese? Yes, Paolo Sarpi.
With the fuck talking.
What happened to yours?
Mine, as he ran, said
he would give himself up.
I gave him your name.  He comes
to break you at the end of the shift.
Congratulations!
Good morning, Katia.
Give them what they want, today I pay.
- Hello, Katia.
- Hello.
- For me the usual.
- Me too.
At that time?
The history of Gothic...
it made me think of yours.
Before, you didn't see or
hear these Chinese gangs.
You saw that.
Have you heard?  He is 17 years old.
Gucci T-shirt, 50,000 euro
Rolex, Dolce and Gabbana shoes.
Bao Zhang is the old guard.
The son-in-law, he is younger,
but he seems to me a correct person.
He is reliable.
Will he not be in drugs?
They have to try.
Eight hundred euros.
- Eight hundred shit!
- One hour of work.
Two-thousand.
- 1500.
- 2500.
- Two-thousand.
- You shitty stingy.
- We are late?
- Three minutes early.
I want to hear what Cosimo says.
- Good morning.
- Hi.
Everything OK?
Me too.
Please.
One minute and I'll be there.
- Franco?
- Huh?
What are they doing here?
they are expanding with the Chinese.
- They're renovating.
- I understand.
- It's great!
- Huh?
It's a big stone.
Do not look.
- Mind your own business.
- Shh!
I told him to mind his own business.
Cosimo, we need to get the
cutters and machinery
from Tel Aviv.
The machinery?
I spent a lot of money on this.
The world is full of skamerz.
- What he said?
- Skamerz.
Huh?
Skamerz.
I don't know what it is.  You know it?
I know scamorza.
How stupid!
Come.
Bro, Bao Zhang is waiting for you.
- Goodbye.
- See you later.
Please come in.
Come here.
But that big stone, what is it?
Like what is it?
Cugi, that's the future.
You are crazy!
I'm happy.
Goodbye.
At that time?
Where can I take you to dinner?
- What are you saying?
- Why?
Don't start being a spendthrift.
If you really have to, one simple thing.
Oysters and champagne.
- Hey!
- See, you make me emotional.
The oysters!
Take this.
The rest, when things are done.
- Even the phone?
- Yes.
Leave yours at home.
Do I need to worry?
No, I do that too.
As a precaution.
They also give us the car.
At eight he lands, at nine we're done.
What do I do while you drive?
Try not to be discouraged,
and keep an eye out.
It's not easy to do it together.
In fact, I can't make any
promises about the first one.
Then do as you like.
He doesn't listen, he's stubborn.  Now
I have to argue with the whole building.
Stubborn as a mule,
he is just like his mother.
Does she still ask you about Antonella?
Every now and then,
when his friends tell him
something that puts him in trouble.
Anyway, you're a great dad.
He's coming along fine.
- Did you understand?
- What do you have?
- The melon!
- Yes, the melon.
- You said: "A great dad."
- Yes, and I repeat.
You play the stingy.
You know what I do with these?
I take him to Puglia to
meet the rest of the family.
- Do you understand that father?
- Well done!
Ernest!
Break everything.
But leave it be.
- He's not doing anything.
- Destroys the house.
These are tough, listen.
- What are you saying?
- Yes.
She told me she would give them to me ripe.
Who told you that?
The one below, I got them there.
Franco, I can't travel all
over Milan to do the shopping.
Would you like to taste it?
I'm listening.
- No!  Don't eat Franco.
- It's tough, huh?
Tomorrow I'll quarrel about that too.
You are a baron!
Done!
Go!
I wanted to tell you...
What will you tell us?
Wait a moment.
I want to explain
why I retire early.
I am a policeman who has
always given his best for 35 years.
I'm not talking about a career, it doesn't make sense.
Viviana's parents are what they are.
But they used this thing
as an excuse not to
make a career out of it.
I don't tell her anything.
Why would I make her feel bad?
She would suffer unnecessarily.
But even she can't get over it,
she doesn't understand it.  Rightly!
If you really want to know, I love...
I have given up.
What a dickhead you are.
Come on!  fuck you!
I'm talking to you.
I am joking.
Seriously speaking,
it's interesting when you say that it was
your choice that you took it in the ass.
Who, when the fuck did I say that?
"By choice of Love"...
What the fuck does that have to do with it!
- You really are an idiot!
- You like it, huh!
Show if you like it.
- It's them?
- I think so.
Why are there two of them?
Hi, I'm Fei Fei.
You?
- Good evening, I'm Franco.
- Dino.
Franco, Dino.
Good evening, Franco.
Is this the car?
- They gave us this.
- Okay.
I need a moment alone in the car.
Let's go later, okay?
Mr. Zhang mentioned
one passenger with a briefcase.
- Who is he?
- My boyfriend.
Chun Ba.
I'm sorry,
but it's better for him to take a
taxi and go to the hotel.
I'm not going without my boyfriend.
Shall I take the taxi too?
Then we search him.
We went through
airport security.
- Still we need to check.
- All right.
Let yourself be searched.
Open your arms.
He's clean.
Boss, let's go!
I'm exhausted.
When it's all over, I
want to go on vacation.
But where?
Las Vegas,
New York, Hong Kong or Hawaii?
Something is wrong.
I don't like it.
What's the problem?
I think you are the problem.
You are too nervous.
Take it easy.
Do you know it all?
Do you want me to change the song?
Whistle for me that of the white Alfa Romeo.
I try to remember it.
Chief, what's going on?
- What happened?
- We have a flat tire.
Rear left, holy shit.
We had a puncture, we have
to stop and change the wheel.
Don't stop.
These guys don't understand shit.
What does this say?
- Go!
- Fuck you scream!
What's wrong?
What the fuck is going on?
They are coming for us.
- Have you seen that bike?
- No.
How many magazines do you have?
One.
And a fart in the barrel.
Ready to fire.
There's a gas station
next time, shall I go out?
Yes.
There will also be cameras.
Let this moron pass!
Let me in, wait.  Don't you see it?
Go, what the fuck are you flashing, go!
Maybe it's just a coincidence.
What? It's not a coincidence!
Miss, I no longer handle the car.
We stop, we change the wheel, I'll take you.
- You explain it to him in English.
- What can I explain to you?
No, if we stop, we're dead.
Did you understand or not?
Fei Fei, don't scream,
you give me a headache!
Let us do our job.
- No, holy shit!
- What's up?
Shut up, let me talk.
Don't talk.
Holy shit.
- Hello.
- Greetings.
She's riding on the rim, you know?
Yes, I'm a colleague, I
stopped to change the tire.
- Greetings!
- Hi.
- Are you on duty?
- Yes.
We bring these two Chinese
tourists to file a complaint.
As soon as they arrived they were robbed.
Can I see the badges?
Thanks, alright.
Do you turn it, please?
Show the photo.
Thanks, alright.
Which police station are you from?
Do you want to know it? Look I'm married.
Does it make me witty?
Answer me, colleague, please?
We are on mobile.
Thank you.
Wait here, don't go away.
I will check.
- You think she believed you?
- Let's go.
We're going now!
Alright, now let's fix it.
Be calm.
Fuck...
You don't tell me right.
She didn't believe it.
I need to see the
occupants' documents, please.
I thought you'd help me change the tire.
Now what are you doing, a check?
Yes exactly, a check.
It's a regular check, mate.
But is it always like this?  We are on duty...
This car is not in service.
- Roll down all the windows.
- They just gave it to us.
We showed you the
badges, let's end it here.
No!
Roll down the windows and
give me the passenger IDs.
- Roll down the window.
- Listen for a second.
Stay in your place.
Hands out, thank you.
But are you serious?
We are on duty.
We are armed, do you want to make war?
I said hands on the
dashboard, both of you, in sight!
Put your hands on the dashboard.
You are stupid.
You're so stupid you
can't see they aren't cops.
Shut up, Fei Fei. Let us work.
Ask which barracks they are from.
There is a
problem and nobody believes me.
Nureyev is the sister-in-law
of the Moskva lieutenant.
Appointed, which barracks are you from?
What's in the briefcase?
You didn't introduce yourself
and you didn't answer me, it's not polite.
We need to check the briefcase.
You have to do something, now!
Can I see the card?
I don't have to show you
anything, I'm in uniform and I'm working.
Let's say I check the briefcase and
then go fuck yourself wherever you want.
Okay?
I told you not to stop the car!
Why don't you do anything?
You are all together!
Help!
He is armed!
I`ll kill you!
Take me home.
Help!
Stay with me!
Hey!
They said you wouldn't shoot.
Who told you?
As it unlocks, I'll call for help.
Twenty-seven, 10, 13.
The birthday of my son.
Colleagues are coming now.
Go away!
No!
Who is it now?
- Hi!
- Hi.
Hello?
Can you talk?
A moment.
Wait a moment.
Guys, uncork, if you want to relax.
I'm coming
Yes, tell me.
On the road to Malpensa there is a motorway
service station with a large truck park,
come here please.
What happened?
I tell you when I see you.
Go now, please.
- Go now.
- How, now?
Yes now.
It's important, do you understand?
But people are coming for the
surprise party, did you know.
Find an excuse.
Bring bottles of water, soap,
a suit and sneakers.
Wait a moment.
Tell me again what I have to bring you.
Bottles of water, soap,
a tracksuit and sneakers.
- All right?
- Yes, don't worry. I'm coming.
What's going on, Franco?
Come here, it's open.
I can't touch anything, you come.
Did you bring soap and water?
- Yes.
- Bring them to me. Come here.
What happened, Franco?
Open the bottle.
I can't touch anything.
Give me the soap.
- Put the soap on.
- What did you do?
I didn't do anything.
Put it here.
Where's Dino?
Can you tell me where Dino is?
Franco?
Love, Dino is not...
Not what?
They were many.
Get ready.
I should turn myself in and confess everything.
I knew you would say this bullshit.
You would go to jail!
Do you understand that, Franco?
We lose everything.
Think, please.
Me and you. All!
Have you thought about your daughter?
What will Anna do in Brighton
without your pension?
You have to come back here.
She has to leave her
studies, go to work...
We are on the edge of a precipice.
And when one stands on the edge
of a precipice, what does one do?
Does he jump?
No...
What I thought was...
Now who gets the diamonds?
Are you serious, Vivia?
Yes, Franco.  Who gets them?
Vivian, no.
Get this out of your head, please.
We are close to the police station, leave me here.
Here come Bonnie and Clyde...
Pull over the car.
Pull over.
Come on.
Will you wait for me, please?
We take them and run away.
Let's go far, Franco.
On a warm island where
no one can find us anymore.
You have to think positive.
You have to visualize this
future on the deserted island...
Viviana, fuck!
You're drilling my brain.
You don't know shit
about how the... works
- What?
- Shit.
Indeed.
You watch too much crap on TV.
What does that have to do with anything?
The road has other rules, my love.
In real life, someone who
escapes to a desert island doesn't
have time to lie down on
the towel, they shoot at him.
If I want to do things
right, I have to go to
Bao Zhang, I have to kneel
down and apologize to him.
I have to go to Sarno and
explain what happened.
Then maybe they keep me alive.
A bad trial is better than a
good funeral, remember that.
Who has arrived, Inspector Callaghan?
Am I watching too much bullshit on TV?
But fuck you, Viviana.
No! You go fuck yourself.
Here I am, sorry.
I forgot to buy the vodka.
Hang on for a moment, it's Sarno.
Ready, Commissioner.
Franco left the phone at home.
He went for a jog.
We're all here for the
surprise party we threw for him.
Say hello to Franco's boss.
Hello!
Doctor, do you want to join us too?
Sure, when he gets back I'll call.
- Cousins!
- Cosimo!
Meet Sharon.
She is American, but she speaks Italian well.
Nice to meet you.
- Pleasure and welcome.
- Thank you.
Have you heard from your husband?
No, he went for a run. So who knows?
- Do you want to have a heart attack?
- What heart attack?
Exams are okay.
- Excuse me.
- Guys!
Sara, Rita, Lorenzo, can you give me a hand?
I have a lot of things to do.
- Did you cook everything yourself?
- Yes.
You were already with the glass in your hand.
And who else, Sharon?
I usually order take out at parties.
I choose the restaurant, one click,
and no headache to go shopping.
- Do you have a dishwasher?
- Sorry, I have to run.
Yes?
Yes. As soon as Franco arrives,
let me call. It's important.
- Everything is fine?
- Yes, everything is fine.
- I'll kick him in...
- Ernesto, enough with that gun.
He's Dino's son, leave him there.
I'm going to do an important service.
Sharon stays here, I'll
pick her up in an hour.
No, Cosimo, don't leave me here for long.
I know you, you show up in four hours.
This evening is not the night.
Do you know what you do?
She takes her to the taxi stand.
There's one near here.
- You are always kind, thank you.
- My pleasure.
- Fuck you.
- Fuck you too.
And tonight there are two!
This must be Anna, Franco's daughter.
Answer.
Ernesto, you piss me off with that gun.
Franco!
We were waiting for you, what happened?
- Her name is Sharon, she is American.
- Pleasure.
But she understands Italian well.
How was this race with your mates?
They told me there was a mishap.
What happened?
The race went badly, Cosimo.
There was a big trouble.
We were in Rho, near Cerchiate...
and there were five serious injuries.
- Were they hurt?
- A lot, yes.
Three on one side, two on the other.
Also Dino, my colleague.
I know a physiotherapist in the Brera area...
I'm sorry, love.
In Italy, when two
people talk, you don't interrupt.
It's not polite, okay?
Bro, the package you had,
Where?
But do you understand what happened?
The package was taken by
those who injured you, right?
Come down for a moment,
so we can talk better. Please.
Get off.
Come down, Cosimo.
What the fuck am I getting off?
Damn you!  But do you
understand what a fucking mess...
Hurray!
Sorry. It must be Sarno.
He's called a couple times already.
He will want to wish you well.
You answer?
Go.
Good evening doctor.
Yes, yes.
Give him a shoe cover and let him pass.
Are you all right, colleague?
Thank you.
Who was the first to arrive here?
I don't know, you should ask the station.
Yes?
What happened?
Who the fuck was that you put in my car?
Where's the goods?
No. I want to talk to your father-in-law.
No, you talk to me.
Where are the goods?
What the fuck do I know! I don't know.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, please.
Sorry, excuse me.
Doctor?
Can I talk to you for a moment?
Did you understand what happened?
I don't understand shit.
The gun in Dino's hand...
It's strange that he didn't
have that of ordinance.
We await the forensics.
And we understand.
I, doc...
Doctor, I've worked with Ruggeri
for 20 years, he has a son to raise.
Bullshit like that he would never do.
Franco, you know...
that money,
is the brother of the devil.
This you have to say?
Don't you dare talk to me like that.
Stay where you fucking are.
The prosecutor is coming.
I wish you were here when he arrives.
All right?
All right.
Do you want to tell me
something before talking to them?
I have nothing to say.
Allow me, sorry.
- Franco!
- Viviana.
- A mess here...
- I know, we're all upset.
Fulvio and Nureyev are coming to you.
They put the gun he fired into Dino's hand.
Do you understand what I'm telling you?
Yes or no?
I understand.
Franco...
If Dino was still alive, do you
know what he would tell you?
Huh?
"Wake up, Franco, don't think about me,
he thinks about saving your ass.
Finish this last night without
letting anything distract you."
Is it true or not, that he would tell you so?
The thing we talked
about earlier in the car…
If you think about it, it's our only way out.
I have all eyes on me.
Do you want me to come and help you?
What the fuck are you saying?
Let me do it!
There are some things I need to understand.
- I have to figure out some things.
- What do you still need to understand?
I am coming.
Vivian?
- Fuck you!
- Guys!
Come on, come with me.
We too. After you.
Listen to me.
Too many badges shot and died...
in this story.
We'll be the mobile...
Did you know he did this job?
We are collecting the reports
for the numerous eyewitnesses...
Do you have relatives in Moscova?
Yes.
Franci's brother is marshal.
Do you know who was
the first to arrive on site?
...the other victim is
an off-duty police officer.
And the last two victims are
the Carabinieri in uniform...
Dino Ruggeri is the most
honest cop I've ever met.
He was honest!
And Daria what was it? Was she corrupt?
Do you know Daria? Do you know her?
You don't know her!
- She was my sister!
- Discipline, fuck!
Let's get to work, come on.
Who has to go to the office, go.
Out of the way.
Let it pass.
Can you ask if there is a
white Alfa Romeo in service?
Yes, we let you know.
Ready?
Where's Dad?
Dad's at work, honey.
Get in.
Viviana!
- Cosimo!
- Beautiful cousin, come here.
- Tito, what are you doing here?
- Cousin!
- Are you looking for Franco?
- No.
We wanted to know how you were.
Do you need help?
No, what help?
This mess happened...
everything at once.
I can't think about it yet.
What a fucking mess, Viviana.
Now we have to get out of this mess,
because we are accountable to the Chinese.
- To the Chinese?
- Huh.
The goods are theirs,
and they rightly want it.
What are you talking about? What goods?
I have the boy in the car.
By any chance, did Franco
tell you anything about it?
About what, sorry?
Viviana, let's be clear,
if you want to get
rid of this burden
and this whole mess,
don't worry, we'll
deliver the goods to them.
- Still?
- Vivian...
We solve this problem in the
family, without all these worries.
Tito, I thank you, but I don't
know anything about these things.
You have to ask Franco.
- I have the child in the car.
- Wait. Come here.
I have the child in the car, I
have to take it to my aunt's.
Why all this hurry?
Then I'll call you.  Bye thank you.
Inspector Sarno wants to
speak to you with the prosecutor.
Love, can you do a favor for Viviana?
All right.
Can you see if there's a car following us?
With the gentlemen I spoke to earlier.
The big one you used to
shoot at home with the gun.
Do you remember?
- Yes.
- Here, that one.
See if that gentleman is inside a car.
You have lost a friend, I have lost two.
Enough bullshit, right?
Colleague, be careful what you say.
I'll take you down with me.
We both drown.
I'm the chief prosecutor Roberta Botta.
Pleasure.
He is the public prosecutor Fresi.
- Pleasure.
- Amore, my pleasure.
We'd just like to ask you a
few questions, if you don't mind.
I'm here, please...
Milan, 3 June 2022.
It's 2:07.
We are on the Carugate
motorway junction of the A51.
I am the chief prosecutor Roberta
Botta with the public prosecutor Fresi.
We are hearing from Assistant
Chief Franco Amore about what
took place on the Segrate exit of the motorway
where died:
the agent Dino Ruggeri, the marshal
Daria Criscito, officer Armando Guerra
and two Asian nationals, one identified,
the other still being identified.
So when was the last time
you spoke to your colleague Dino Ruggeri?
This morning.
I was on duty with him.
Did you know about Dino's double job?
He never told me about it.
Did he tell you what
you were going to do tonight?
He didn't say anything.
We were waiting for him at my
house for a small family party.
Did he ever talk about...
Financial problems?
With 1800 euros a month...
he had a complicated life.
He had holes in his hands.
he gave everything to his son.
However, I want to be clear
never, ever would Dino Ruggeri
have done something illegal.
He was the most honest police officer that…
We are not accusing him of anything.
We just want to try to clarify.
What did you do tonight,
between 7 and 9.30 pm?
Are you just trying to clarify?
You are pathetic.
Answer, Franco, please.
I was running.
I got home to find my wife had
thrown me a surprise retirement party.
There I learned of what had happened, from the Doctor.
What time did you arrive at the party?
Doctor, if you want the
details, call me tomorrow at the
police station, or wherever
you want, and question me.
Now, if you don't mind, I'm going to
say hello to my brother who's down there.
He doesn't fuck with me.
Yes?
I came here to say
that I still trust the fishman's word.
I'm going home now,
and I wait for the delivery.
I'm so sorry for your friend.
Thank you.
Ma'am, you can't pass.
The road is blocked.
I'm sorry, officer.
Excuse me, I'm just...
I'm a relative of agent Dino Ruggeri.
The boy behind here is his son.
I learned that he was
injured in an accident.
We came right away.
Commissioner Sarno called me, told
me I was authorized to come here.
However, I didn't understand much.
- Let me go and see.
- Wait.
I'm very worried.
They are slippers.
There is a relative of agent Ruggeri, she seems
to have been called by Commissioner Sarno.
Do I let her pass?
Thank you, officer. Very nice.
Ma'am, you can't pass.
Hey.
Did you wake up, baby?
I want to go home, I want my bed.
But how?
Did you know that sleeping
in the car is a crazy adventure?
Like real superheroes.
There are no superheroes who sleep in cars.
So what do you think Batman
never fell asleep in the Batmobile?
Ernesto, let's do something.
You stay here, I'll be there
and back in a flash, like Wonder Woman.
All right?
Love?
Is that Dino's body?
Turn around, I'm here.
- What the fuck are you doing here?
- I'm afraid, Franco!
We...
we must do something,
or end up like Dino too.
Honey, you have to leave it to me.
They lock us into this sooner or later.
Did you understand?
Look at me.  What are you doing?
Nobody catches you.
But how can I do without you?
You know it's the only way, tell me where I am.
C'mon honey.
Do you see at the end of the tunnel?
There is a bridge.
Yes, I see.
Before all?
I told you.
What do you want to do?
What do I have to do?
Soon they find them.
It doesn't mean we have
to let everything go like this.
No.
Please.
Can you give me some hope, my love?
What a scene!
In my opinion, a crazy photo comes from this bridge.
No?
If they catch you, they'll kick your ass.
Look, I'll try.
If the cops come by, will you give me a shout?
All right. Hurry up.
Here?
The first to call was a police station from Porta Ticinese,
and at the Moscova they have
a service Alfa, a white Giulietta.
Among the people, there is one in civilian clothes.
I know him, yes. He's burnt.
There was one man, they moved him.
Investigated before the Expo, for
laundering loot withone of our people.
They killed ours, not even a scratch on him.
- What is his name?
- Attili.
Lieutenant.
Excuse me.
- You need to turn off the fucking flashlight.
- What?
Turn off the fucking flashlight.
How do I find it without light?
Franco, there is water.
Will I come back with mask and tube?
Come back, we're screwing up.
No. Franco, listen to me.
Where did you throw them?
- In the middle.
- In the middle?
In the middle of...
In the middle.
Was it here?
I see you, do you see me?
Get down!
Is it here? - No, further.
How much further?
- A few steps.
- More specific.
How many meters?
Four, five, what do I know?
Four or five?
One two three four...
and five.
- Was he here?
- Get down!
They should be there.
- Run away, my love.
- What is it?
- They're coming for them.
- Who?
The Chinese. Go away.
Viviana, go away.
No. Franco, I'm almost there.
I beg you, go away.
Wait!
There they are.
They're behind you, hurry up!
There is something here.  I found them, love!
He stays with me.
No!  No!
- I'm sorry, Franco.
- Let it be. He gets into the car.
- There are still those waiting for me.
- Don't go home.
Drive on the ring road and don't stop.
I'll call you.
Beautiful love...
Will you tell me what you're thinking?
That man had dad's shoes.
Did he fall asleep?
Yes. He cried a lot and
then collapsed like a stone.
Darling, you'd better leave now.
Take him to his grandparents.
- Do you hear? I'm in Puglia.
- Yes where?
In Spongano, small village in Puglia.
Dino told me that his
grandmother was a seamstress.
Everyone knows her.
These here...
we must forget them.
As if they weren't there.
- Did you understand?
- Yes.
Relax.
What's up?
Nothing.
One told me I had to finish the
shift as if nothing had happened.
One watches bullshit on TV.
You're an idiot!
I recovered everything.
I am coming.
They said you wouldn't shoot.
In 35 years as a policeman,
he has never shot anyone.
You don't have to tell anyone.
Vivian?
Especially to your family.
We don't tell him anything.
Roll down the window.
He wakes up your partner.
Franco, please!
Get the guns and put them on the dashboard.
Show me your hands!
Throw the phones behind you.
Darnit...
Come up, Cosimo.
We have a quiet chat.
Bro, park.
We have a drink inside.
I want to get some fresh air.
These cars are full of options.
We got into a mess, Franco.
However,
you must be calm, please.
Let me talk.
Because, in my opinion,
you're going a little too crazy.
Me...
I am sorry.
But what happened, happened.
Believe me, I swear.
I am really very sorry
about what happened to your colleague.
But I swear I have nothing to do with it.
Franco...
Franco, for God's sake...
They kill us both.
Let's go.
It starts.
Franco knew nothing.
On the contrary...
we chose him because we
were sure he wouldn't react.
Everyone considers him a weakling.
One who doesn't shoot.
There, I said it.
The carabinieri, my cousin,
Tito Russo, went there.
With whom he maintains relations.
And I informed him of the shipment.
Finish.
The idea came from his son-in-law.
Bullshit! I'll fucking kill you!
What's on your mind?
You don't know what you are doing.
Take him away!
But did you hear what he said?
Bullshit! This idiot talks bullshit.
His son-in-law told us that he was
dying and that he would take control of Milan.
And then, I checked with my cousin.
I only acted as an intermediary, I swear.
Zhang Zhu...
Please forgive me.
Please.
Franco, tell him something
to calm things down.  Please.
Here are the names and
numbers of the other two accomplices.
A corrupt carabiniere
from the Moscova barracks
and Tito Russo, his cousin, a 'ndragheta.
If you hurry, you can find them
in front of his jewelry store.
I'll let you sort out your family problems.
My diamonds?
I have the diamonds, Mr. Zhang.
And I keep them.
I told you I didn't want
people with guns in the car.
The shooting was your fucking guard's fault.
I'm keeping them, Mr. Zhang.
Anyway, sooner or later
I get caught for this story.
They take away my pension,
they put me in San Vittore.
My wife and daughter need to stay calm.
They also take away my best friend's pension,
who died tonight.
I need the diamonds, I
have to take care of his son.
I have to raise him, he's still small.
But above all, for once,
I want the satisfaction of being like Robin Hood.
I steal from a rich man to
give to a poor bastard who
has had the ambition to be
an honest person all his life.
Now, if you don't mind,
I still have an hour of work left.
Take care, Cosimo.
Franco!
Franco, don't leave me here.
They will kill me!
How dare you look my cousin in the face?
32, from the Puma 103.
I see you, Puma 103.
All patrols listening from Puma 103.
I'm the assistant chief Franco Amore.
I wanted to say hello to all colleagues,
thank them sincerely,
and tell you that this...
it is my last radio message,
my last communication.
In fact, I finish today
thirty-five years of honorable
service in the state police.
I even wrote a speech, but I'm saving it.
It will be for another time.
Today is a very special day for
me because, as you all know...
we have lost our colleague Dino Ruggeri.
A worthy colleague, an honest man...
a family man, a friend,
a civil servant, one of us.
I wish everyone good luck
and a bright future.
From Puma 103, last step and out.
Thank you all.
This is Vanessa, Gino and
Carla from the operations center.
We all wish you the best.
Dino will always remain in our hearts.
Romans wheel!
Franco, you have been an
older brother, a guide to all of us.
Colleagues, let's all turn on the sirens,
for our Dino.
A big hug, Franco.
39, at Puma 103.
What do you think, that we will miss you?
I better shut up.
We say hello from San Siro.
We are at Ticinese with
the Garibaldi unit.
An affectionate hug, Franco.