LEE Soon-jae
YOON So-Jung
SONG Jae-ho
KIM Su-mi
You there.
Did you fall because of me?
No, right?
Are you hurt?
No.
I'm talking to you!
I asked you
if you were hurt!
Don't make me repeat myself!
- I'm fine
- Don't mumble!
Is he deaf?
Speak up!
I'm not hurt!
You can go!
You're really okay?
Don't blame me later on.
- You got it?
- Okay.
You got it?
Yes!
Goddamn motorcycle.
Piece of junk.
I shouldn't have stopped.
Damn it.
Now I have to drag it up.
Excuse me.
Excuse me!
What are you calling me for?
I'd like to buy some milk.
Is a dollar enough?
Look here.
Are you trying to
repay me or something?
I don't need your money.
Forget about it.
You don't have to yell at me.
I've seen you around
in the mornings.
Take it.
It's leftover anyway.
Why are you out
in this weather?
Those scraps aren't even
worth much.
You don't have a family
to support you?
No.
What?
- I said I don't.
- Sheesh.
What are you doing?
You want to break your hip?
The snow will freeze up soon.
Why is thing so heavy?
Grab the back!
Oh my!
Damn back.
Are you all right?
No, I'm not.
I almost threw out my back.
Take care.
Drive safe.
Just worry about yourself.
Oh my!
It's nothing.
I'm fine, so go on!
Sheesh.
Shucks,
that was embarrassing.
LATE BLOSSOM
Get rid of that
piece of junk, Gramps.
Did you just call me
a piece of junk?
Put your hearing aid on!
This old hearing aid is
dying out on me.
Deok-bae.
Is there someone
who takes these?
Of course.
This is worth money too.
Do you have to
give it to them?
What do you need it for?
Can you give it to
someone else or not?
Of course not.
It's a matter of loyalty.
Deok-bae.
Don't take your time
and just say it.
There's a new parlor
across the street.
What about it?
Wonder where you got the money
to spend there every night.
Gramps!
- Deok-bae.
- Yes? Yes, Father!
- Why are you so jumpy?
- I'm not jumpy.
Watch the store.
Going somewhere?
Have a nice day.
I'll watch the store!
Good morning.
- Is Dal-suis running late?
- Seems so.
I see.
It's getting bright now.
Should've been here by now.
It's cold.
Why don't you wait inside?
I'm late.
It's morning now.
Why am I worrying about it?
Shucks.
Give me one carton, Gramps.
But what if she breaks a hip?
- Gramps, I want to buy milk!
- Is that why she's not here?
- What is he mumbling about?
- No, that's absurd.
Grandpa!
Milk, please! Milk!
Crazy bastard.
Excuse me?
I've got no milk for you!
No milk!
Annoying little punk!
Who does he think he is?
Just looking at you
makes me sick.
Why was he yelling at me?
Sheesh.
Be careful.
Have a nice day.
Hello.
Hello, sir!
Oh!
You're late today.
- Yes, it ended up that way.
- You don't have to shout!
- You have your hearing aid!
- Don't shout now.
I don't wear it when I'm riding,
since it's so loud.
I see.
And who might you be?
He's the manager of
the parking lot.
Mr. JANG Kun-bong.
Nice to meet you.
Well, I have deliveries to make.
What a racket.
It is.
Thanks to that motorcycle,
I'm never late.
- You wanted an alarm clock, right?
- You have one?
I put some rice cakes
in there for your wife.
See you tomorrow.
Dal-su!
- Thanks again.
- It's just a piece of junk.
Honey.
Remember to use
the bedpan next time.
Okay?
Say "ah".
Good.
Chew it well.
What did you do today?
Tell me.
I made stew with noodles
for lunch today.
Ordering in is easier,
but I had nothing better to do.
Dal-su from the junkyard
gave me an alarm clock...
I'll get three hours of sleep.
That's strange.
Why isn't the parking lot open yet?
I'm not sure.
He's never been late before.
My goodness!
I'm late!
He didn't look.
It's cold.
So cold.
Grandpa.
Let's get some sleep
on a Sunday.
It's just habit.
I can't help waking up.
Then go for a walk or something.
You want to go?
Sheesh.
I apologize.
Have a nice day.
I apologize again.
Could I ask you a favor?
Please go to my house
and lock the front gate.
Take your shoes off
inside the house!
My, my...
She's gone senile.
Don't eat that dirt!
She's completely lost her mind.
Sheesh.
Isn't there a guardian here?
Anyone looking for
a senile old woman?
- Huh?
- Huh!
- It's freezing!
- Freezing!
Jesus, it's freezing.
- What's your home number?
- Jesus. Freezing.
Darn it.
Doesn't know her name
or her address.
Darn it.
I'm going to freeze to death.
What are you doing,
old hag?
Your hair is all white.
Of course it is, at this age.
Don't grow old, dear.
You can't get old.
Don't grow old, darling.
Goddamn it.
What did you do today?
Tell me.
Tell me what you did.
Stop pulling!
Tell me!
She's driving me crazy.
- Hurry up. Tell me.
- All right.
Well...
This morning...
I couldn't sleep,
so I was watching TV.
Then Yuna comes and...
- Yuna is my granddaughter.
- I know.
Excuse me?
Is anyone home?
Hello?
What?
The front gate was open?
Honey!
- Again.
- What do you mean, again?
I came out to the park
and now I'm stuck with you.
- Start again from park.
- Sheesh.
I went for a walk in Siberia
and got stuck with a senile granny.
She took my clothes and shoes
and I'm freezing now.
The end.
This old fart has lost his mind.
How could you go to Siberia?
Are you thinking clearly now?
- You know what Siberia is?
- Of course I do.
It's two stops away
on the 105 bus.
- Gosh darn it.
You really don't know
where you live?
- Where did you come from?
- Goodness gracious!
Over there.
Can you find it if we go there?
What am I even asking you for?
That tickles!
- Shush.
- Shush!
The kids are inside,
so wait out here.
- You got it?
- Okay.
Why do I bother?
- Stay here.
- Okay.
So cold.
Yay!
That looks fun!
- Follow me!
- Should I push?
Hurry up!
This is fun!
Wasn't that Gramps?
Hi!
You'll get sick
running around like that.
We should call the police first.
I'll call the police.
Go check the streets.
Right.
Hey!
- I parked here just yesterday!
- Yes, I know...
But no one's here right now.
- Come back later.
- You've got to be kidding.
Hey.
Do you even know who I am?
Shit, that's hot!
You little punk.
Who are you?
That's none of your business.
Why does everyone here
look like shit?
You've got shit on your face.
That's no way to talk
to a stranger.
We' re not strangers now.
Bam!
You flinched, asshole.
What?
You want a piece of this?
Can you see it?
Try to see my fist, asshole!
Goddamn...
Use words, sir.
- Get your car out, punk.
- Yes, sir.
You said it was around here.
Over by that telephone pole.
We've been there
dozens of times.
What the hell are you
laughing for?
I'm working my butt off here.
What?
Don't glare at me.
All you do is swear,
fucking old fart.
What did you just say to me?
What did you say?
Get off.
Go take a cab.
- Cabs are expensive.
- Then take the bus! Get off!
No!
What?
That's how you want to do this?
Fine.
- Get off.
- No.
Get off!
Wait. Honey...
I'm not your honey.
Boo...
Boo what?
Poo...
Poop?
- I'm pooping.
- Jesus Christ!
- What am I supposed to do?
- It's coming out.
No, don't!
Hold it in for a minute.
My goodness.
One already came out.
Just hold it in.
Okay?
Pee-pee!
She has Alzheimer's,
so she couldn't have gone far.
Please find her.
Thank you so much...
What's taking so long?
Are you done yet?
We'll both freeze to death!
Granny!
You better not be eating it
like you ate that dirt!
Why aren't you answering me?
Granny.
See the toilet paper?
Wipe with that!
Don't get poop on your clothes!
- Excuse me.
- Excuse what?
Just hurry up and poop.
What are you doing?
I'm just...
Hey!
Give me back my umbrella,
you thief!
Damn it.
Sheesh.
Honey!
Can you hear me?
Where are you?
Honey!
Where were you?
Where did you go?
Are you all right?
Aren't you cold?
Are you okay?
- Where were you?
- I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
- I'm cold.
- Let's get you home.
- What took you so long?
- Were you scared?
- I want to go home. It's cold.
- Let's go home.
We'll get you warmed up.
- I'm hungry.
- Okay.
- Thank you so much!
- Shucks.
You don't need to thank me.
Hurry and get her home.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
That's how I wanted to grow old.
I'm KIM Man-seok.
What's your name?
- I'm SONG.
- What's your first name?
I don't have one.
You don't have a name?
My father was drafted
into the military.
Mother waited for him
to come back and name me.
People began calling me
by my last name,
and I was called SONG
ever since.
I came from a small town
in the countryside.
Deep in the mountains
in Kangwon Province.
We'll be set
once we get to Seoul.
Just trust me.
Mom...
I'll come back with lots of money.
We thought we would
make it in Seoul.
But there were many people
and not enough jobs.
He slowly changed,
but I stood by him.
I'm good at sticking it through.
We eventually had a daughter,
and he left to go and
make some money.
That was the last time
I saw him.
My child's body began to burn up.
Doctor!
I carried her in my arms
and ran all around town...
Save my baby!
But...
Since then,
I don't think I've ever been happy.
I'm being punished.
For breaking my mother's heart.
You want me to read this for you?
I don't know how to read.
I see.
Have a seat.
"To SONG"...
To SONG.
They say that fate works in
mysterious ways.
You and I walk the same road
every single morning.
Some would even call that fate.
But we still don't know each...
- Going somewhere?
- Just out.
- What about dinner?
- No thanks.
- But it's you r favorite stew.
- Skipping one meal won't kill me.
Out of the way!
- It's time for dinner.
- I don't want any.
- I made mushroom stew.
- To hell with the mushrooms.
- You' re not eating?
- No!
I'm goddamn sick of
mushroom stew.
I'll be waiting at the hill
where we always cross.
"Around six o'clock"...
Goodness.
- It's already past eight.
- I should leave.
Wait...
You forgot your letter!
Am I being stood up?
Even if she doesn't like me...
That granny...
She could at least come and
tell me in person.
I would've had dinner
if I had known.
Mushroom stew...
Oh!
Why, if it isn't SONG!
I'm sorry.
- Did you wait long?
- Not at all.
I thought maybe
something came up,
so I just had dinner with a friend.
- Did you just get here?
- Yes.
The truth is...
I don't know how to read.
You can't read?
No.
I told you,
I just ate dinner.
Your nose is running.
Gosh darn it.
I waited for three hours.
You happy now?
Let's go.
As long as I saw you.
Button up.
It's cold.
You know how to tell time, right?
I'll see you then.
You look pretty.
There's a seat.
It looks expensive.
Let's go somewhere else.
How expensive could it possibly be?
Why is it so expensive here?
I didn't bring you out
to eat this crap.
Just try it.
This crap is surprisingly good.
Watch the road.
This is the real deal.
You don't drink milk, right?
No, I'm going to drink it.
Weren't you lactose intolerant?
I'll be fine
if I drink a little at a time.
Milk is good for the bones.
- It's all right.
- Sure it is.
Just follow me.
Come on.
What brings you here, Grandpa?
Old people living alone
get money, right?
- The government grants?
- How much is it?
It depends on the situation.
If there are children or not,
and any income...
A rough guess!
- A hundred dollars?
- What?
A hundred and fifty?
That wouldn't even pay
the damn gas bill!
They'll give me all that money?
Yes.
It'd take more than a month
to save up that much.
- Thank you.
- Sure...
- Thank you so much.
- It's from the government, not me.
Thank them, too.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Hurry and register her.
- Did you print out the list of benefits?
- Right.
Here it is.
It's so little!
I'd get her more if I could...
Me too.
Could I have your ID?
I don't have one.
You don't have any ID?
No...
She can just make one now, right?
You shouldn't impose.
They've got more important
government things to do.
Government things?
- Expedite her things, Yuna.
- Okay.
We'll make you an ID first.
Can I have your name?
SONG.
Your first name?
Well...
Only.
Only what?
You're not understanding me.
It's Only SONG.
Write it down.
Don't try to spell it out.
As in "you're my only one"...
That ONLY!
That's good.
Okay, gorgeous.
Pretend to look away,
and then one, two, three!
Fantastic!
- You have beautiful eyes.
- Smile some more.
You want to be smiling
in your funeral picture.
- What did you just say?
- What?
Why, I oughta...
This is for her ID!
Of course. An ID picture.
Of course.
- Get a good shot!
- I will, sir.
All right, gorgeous.
Bring up all that energy
from your toes,
all the way up,
and two, three!
Bravo!
Put 'er there!
How dare he mess up my hair?
Grumpy old fart.
Bring me the salt!
My goodness!
- You're back, sir.
- One more picture!
- Print one more, idiot.
- Okay.
This way.
Oh my...
You're playing innocent now?
- It's just that our regulations...
- Screw your regulations.
Don't you know who I am?
I'll tell your boss
and fire your ass.
I apologize.
I'll be back once I get this checked
at the auto shop.
I'm sorry, sir.
Have a nice day.
Dad.
Young-ok.
What are you doing here?
Just...
Let's go inside.
Damn it.
I should move out of
this rough neighborhood.
What the hell?
They covered it up!
This is destruction of evidence!
Goddamn it!
Anyone home?
Granny?
What brings you here?
Come on in.
Please excuse the mess.
Your ID came out.
Here.
Only SONG.
You should receive the grant
starting from next month.
How could I ever thank you?
- It's nothing, really.
- How kind of you.
Wait one minute.
- No, I should get going...
- I'll be right back.
Granny.
Yes?
Everyone is scared of Grandpa.
Aren't you scared of him?
He has a foul mouth,
but he's soft inside.
When he said your name
back at the town hall...
"Only SONG"...
I thought he was really saying,
"There's only SONG for me. "
Are you all right?
My hand slipped...
I think Grandpa really likes you.
Don't you think so?
I shouldn't have brought out
such a humble meal.
No, it's great.
Is this what I think it is?
It's one of my favorite vegetables.
How did you know?
What was your name?
It's KIM Yuna.
Just like the pretty girl
who ice skates.
People say I look like her too.
And you're really cute too, Granny.
- Digestive medicine, please.
- Sure.
I'm sorry for asking you again.
I can help you
with the security deposit.
I know I should see Mom, too...
But the diner is busy.
I'm sorry.
Go on.
FIXED DEPOSIT ACCOUNT
I'm going to live with
Mom and Dad forever.
Don't worry about retirement.
You've got two reliable sons.
I'll become rich and support you.
- Make a lot, please.
- Don't worry.
We've got nothing
to worry about.
Since the commute is so long...
We're going to move out
once we get married.
I'm sorry we won't be
living with you.
Help yourself.
That's how our eldest son left.
- You should get going.
- Right.
We'll visit often.
There's no need for that.
I'm sorry we rushed it
when Mom's health is so bad.
But we'll visit often.
We became people they
talked of visiting often.
Now we 're a couple again.
We used to be a family.
Sheesh.
Hey, punk.
Did you see SONG?
Why are you looking for her?
Don't question me.
Just answer my question.
She's been in the manager's office
a lot these days.
What?
Ocean.
O- C-E-A-N...
You write well now.
Why is he flashing smiles at her?
And why is she smiling back?
You're getting much better.
Jesus!
- Go away!
- What are you doing?
Go!
That's good.
Have a nice day.
What are you doing here?
I should get going.
Are you looking for SONG?
Don't call her SONG.
Her name is Only SONG now.
- Ms. SONG went to my house.
- What?
You dragged her
into your house now?
You're always swearing so much.
And you're that popular
because you don't?
Let's go inside.
Let's have some tea.
" Let's have some tea. "
He doesn't get
how serious this is.
Here.
It's a pinwheel!
It's spinning!
- You're good at it.
- Thank you.
I don't drink coffee!
You can't take her away
with this lousy coffee.
Don't you see this?
I'm tougher than I look!
I'll speak casually since
we're about the same age.
See if I care.
I'm teaching her how to read.
How to read?
Do you know
what she learned to spell first?
Your name.
KIM Man-seok.
Drink up before it gets cold.
It tastes pretty good.
How sweet.
You're pretty jumpy these days.
You're home early.
I gave Granny SONG her ID today.
You did?
Grandpa.
You like her, don't you?
What?
You like Granny SONG.
Me?
Yes.
- That's what you sensed?
- Yes.
You think she'd sense it too?
Of course.
Aw, shucks.
Go tell her.
It's enough if she senses it.
- You have to tell her yourself.
- Why?
Because Granny SONG is a woman too.
Telling her yourself makes
all the difference.
What do I say?
" I love you, dear. "
You're crazy!
You have to tell her.
Go and tell her,
"I love you, dear. "
Yuna.
For people our age,
"dear" is meant for our spouses.
What that means is...
"Dear" is only for
your late grandmother.
It's the least respect
that I can pay her.
I looked at her ID
and her birthday is tomorrow.
Good night.
Wait for me, dear.
Slow down, please.
What are you dawdling for?
Hurry up.
- Help me move the table.
- Lazy old woman.
You can carry it one at a time.
Pick up some digestive medicine.
At least pretend to listen to me!
How could you not know
when it's gotten so severe?
If the cancer spread so much,
shouldn't she be in pain?
She probably was,
in a great amount of pain.
Dear, buy me some milk.
Why milk, all of a sudden?
- You're going yourself?
- Who else is there to go?
Why not?
She can't have
any dairy products.
- Just let her have one.
- Give it to me, sir.
I mean it.
- But she wants some milk.
- No, she can't.
She won't have any more.
They're saying that milk
isn't good for you.
This is nice, though.
Having my blunt husband
taking care of me for once.
Just get well.
I'll buy you milk every day.
Would you be all right?
Would it be okay if I do?
Where are all the small rocks?
It's rather big...
Can I come in for a minute?
You're not curious about
why I didn't work today?
I'm sure you had some reason.
You wouldn't for no reason.
So, you didn't wait for me?
I waited.
The kitchen's through here?
Stay right there.
It's your birthday today.
Should we get the lights?
Yes.
No, I meant those lights.
Wait.
Why are you in such a hurry?
Happy birthday to you.
You could clap along.
Happy birthday
my Only SONG.
Happy birthday to you.
Dam n lyrics.
I wanted to get you
a cheap ring or something,
but the stores were closed.
Here.
My arm is hurting.
You're not opening it?
My dear...
I love you.
You can blow them out now.
THANK YOU, KIM MAN-SEOK.
FROM ONLY SONG
What did you do today?
Tell me.
Well...
I don't know what I'm doing,
to be honest.
My mind is elsewhere all day.
Like I'm dreaming
with my eyes open.
Eyes open?
How long has it been like this?
I don't know.
My tummy hurts a lot.
She's okay, right?
What did they say?
Should we all go on a picnic?
This is the taxi I used to drive.
No one would take it and
I couldn't throw it away, either.
A lot like us, eh?
I don't know if I could...
go on without her.
The test results aren't even back yet.
Honey!
Look here, Kun-bong.
I don't have any friends.
Because of my bad temper, I guess.
Is that okay, though?
Seems I've made a new friend
at this old age.
You came to us too late.
The best we can do is to
relieve her with painkillers.
You should prepare yourself...
Mommy...
Don't cry.
If you cry, then I cry too.
Why is it so cold this spring?
Why are you here?
I have to work, Grandpa.
Work.
Don't mind me.
How does this work?
It's not for you, Grandpa.
- Did you buy gloves?
- Oh, no.
- Did they catch your eye, though?
- What?
I didn't buy them.
They were a gift.
Nice and soft
because it's real leather.
How did you notice
when I didn't say anything?
Because it's high quality leather, eh?
Have a nice day everyone!
Come straight home after work.
Good day, gentlemen.
What brings you here, Gramps?
- That looks like a bad move.
- You even have gloves on.
Well, aren't you sharp!
- How'd you know that it's leather?
- I never said anything about leather...
It's different from
that fake synthetic stuff.
No air slips in
between the fingers.
Take a look.
Sounds nice, doesn't it?
Have a nice day, then.
You too, Gramps.
Is he sick or something?
Real leather does sound nice, though.
Huh?
Academy lessons?
Missing one day won't kill him.
Bring him with you.
NOW HIRING? MANAGER
We'll be waiting for you then.
All right. Bye.
- What's that sign for?
- You're here.
Is it because of your wife?
I was thinking about
taking her on a trip.
- Is that from SONG?
- Yeah, isn't it nice?
It's real cow leather.
Nice and soft.
Hello?
It's you.
As long as you're coming.
Don't be late.
And bring the kids.
We'll be waiting.
All right.
Are they thinking of
moving in with us?
- You know we have two kids, right?
- Come on.
We have kids too.
My kids are in high school.
Should we look into
a cheap nursing home?
They have Young-ok.
She's their favorite, anyway.
- You two come inside too.
- Yes, sir!
We're all here, Dad.
Honey.
These kids...
You brought them into the world.
So many of them, eh?
You did good, honey.
Is there something wrong, Dad?
- You can all go now.
- What?
- Go on.
- Dad.
Get up.
Come on.
- I'm sorry, Dad.
- No need for that.
I'll pay you back as soon as I can.
Get on home.
Go.
Go on.
- Go.
- Thank you. Come again.
Goodbye all of you.
You can sleep in now.
- Is this everything?
- Yes.
Wait, I'll take that!
Woah!
Are you all right?
- Are you hurt?
- How typical of me.
What are you taking these for?
It's such a waste.
You wear them everywhere,
don't you?
These are special gloves, buddy.
Be good to SONG, Man-seok.
We could all go any day now,
at this old age.
Stop trying to sound so wise.
We've had such a long life together.
I'd still pick you in my next life.
What about you?
You always gave to me
and I only took from you.
I couldn't do that to you again
You know what?
You're so beautiful.
- More beautiful with age.
- Liar.
I'm serious.
Don't cry.
It's bitter.
I'm so sorry.
Goodbye.
I'm a timid old man.
I couldn't go on without you.
So hold on tight to my hand.
Let's find each other again.
Gramps.
Someone named JANG Kun-bong
left this for you yesterday.
- Kun-bong was here?
- Someone like that.
Dear Man-seok...
I was quite lonely,
but I enjoyed my time
with you and SONG.
Thanks to you two,
we now have
good memories to cherish.
For so many years,
my wife and I have
depended on each other.
I was afraid of being left behind.
So I've decided to go with my wife.
Since we've always been
at each other's side.
Man-seok.
I have a favor to ask.
I don't want the world
to know how we left.
Don't want to cause trouble
for our children.
Thank you, my friend.
JANG'S HOUSE
Damn fool worried for his kids
even as he died.
You did the right thing.
Kun-bong would be very grateful.
How did they pass away?
They slept through a gas leak.
heard they were a loving couple.
- How old were they?
- Seventy-seven, I heard.
- It was quite timely.
- Su re.
They would've just lived
to burden their children.
- It was timely.
- Better than troubling their kids.
That's what everyone is saying.
What's so timely about it,
you punks!
What's so timely about it?
- We didn't mean it like that, sir.
- How can any death be good?
Should all us old folks just die?
Crazy bastards!
Timely, my ass!
Kun-bong!
They're saying that
you died at a good time!
That it's good you died,
you damn fool.
Only...
What's on your mind?
Man-seok...
Why are you stalling?
You're going back
to your hometown?
Because you don't want
to lose me?
That's right.
Because I don't want
to lose you.
Death will tear us apart
soon enough,
and I don't think
I could stand it.
How could I let you go?
The first happiness of my life...
I want to go back home,
and grow old cherishing it.
Listen to me.
You think
we can meet again?
We'll never see each other again!
Go, then.
Just leave me!
Let's never see each other again!
Don't even come
if you hear that I died!
I'll take you.
To your home.
WELCOME TO SURARI HILL
600M ABOVE SEA LEVEL
Only...
I just felt like saying your name.
Man-seok...
I just wanted to say it too.
Could I hold you once?
Could we see each other again?
Could we see each other
before we die?
- Grandpa.
- Yeah.
- You're here again?
- Coming from work?
Why did you let her go, then?
Don't worry.
This will pass.
I'll get used to it.
Life is about
getting used to things.
This is our house.
So you moved in here.
Yes, with my mom.
That's sweet of you.
The granny who lived here
asked me to.
She said it's dangerous
for motorcycles in the dark.
Directed by CHOO Chang-Min
Translated by
Stefanie Y. Hong