Who is that? Who?
Who are you? Who are you?
Who are you?
Ghost! Ghost!
Ghost! Ghost! Ghost! Ghost! Ghost!
Tell me buddy, how was my performance?
You were awesome buddy!
The watchman got so
scared he fled the scene.
For the next two or three
months no man will work..
..here as the watchman!
Cheers!
Don't be tensed. Cool!
Take, your tension will disappear!
Shivani, your father's people
can't find out our whereabouts.
Let's go!
Don't get scared.
Such a house in this big forest!
Moreover, the bed is arranged?
You stay here!
Thrishul!
Thrishul! Thrishul! Thrishul!
Open the door thrishul!
Thrishul!
Please open the door.
Please open the door, please!
Thrishul! Please. Thrishul! Thrishul!
How is our first night surprise?
Cool, Cool! First night has to
be thrilling, at least a bit Shivani!
Future lovers should
talk about our love chasing..
..marriage, this first-night
set-up as if it were a horror story.
You think it's funny! I almost died..
Don't ever say that again.
Thrishul, which one is
greater love or admiration?
That love which is full
of admiration is greatest!
So, do you love me or admire me?
I admire you lovingly!
It's my great fortune that
I found you, who love and admire me.
I'm very lucky!
I'm very happy! I love you so much!
I'll take birth again
and again to be with you.
But for now, enough of you!
Oh, he killed her!
So, you are upset because of that?
This is a movie, baby!
You shouldn't take
is seriously and get upset!
Take it easy dear.
Isn't it sin to cheat people
about love and kill them?
My dear, we do know that
when you get connected to..
..something you are easily affected.
But please change
your facial expressions..
..so that we all can go out, okay?
What happened dear?
He has put his leg on the way!
We don't want trouble,
let's go by the other side!
See this yaar!
These kind of people
don't understand words.
Is she going to use pepper spray?
These days that's the trend.
Its better we..
There's no signal in my phone, dear!
What, no signals there? Use my phone!
Why should we waste
a call for you guys!
Is there message balance?
Hundred messages are free.
I don't need so many.
One message is enough!
If you see girls alone,
you start teasing them?
I'm going to break every ones..
Break what?
What? What are you going to break?
What are you seeing?
What are you going to do? Get lost!
Come!
Hey, you! We are here to frighten
people and make our livelihood!
If you guys get frightened and
run away, how are we going to live?
It's against our culture.
If this continues,
our species will go extinct!
- How does he look?
- He looks exactly like a hero, brother!
I don't know where he lives, but
I do have his number with me, brother.
His phone number is with you?
Anyway, we'll discuss this later.
First, call him!
It's ringing brother.
Hey, you!
You beat-up my boys, I believe.
Do you think you are a hero?
What nonsense are
you talking you loser?
I have a daughter,
whose age is like a heroines' age.
Do I look like a hero to you?
To find out my age you have to
make a video call you foolish fellow.
Not a voice all! Cut the call!
What happened, brother?
Brother!
Who was that guy, child?
Which guy father?
That guy who came like
a hero and fought with goons..
..to save you, that guy!
I don't know him father.
So, you say that even though
there's no relation between..
..you both he has risked
his life to save you?
You should not try
to fool your father!
By the way,
who was that amazing stud who risked..
..everything to save me?
He's my brother!
I had sent him a message
asking him to come.
- Your brother?
- Yeah!
Then, to whom did you send
a message from that rowdy's phone?
She doesn't have a brother, for sure.
I don't think she
even has a boyfriend.
After everything was over,
uncle arrived, right?
She must have sent him the message.
I was very stressed at that time,
so I sent the message to my father.
Your brother came
on time and saved us!
Or else I don't know
what would've happened to us!
He's completed his training
and waiting for his joining..
..orders, a future police man he is!
Usually police come
at the climax, right?
How come your brother
came at the beginning?
He's like Shiva Mani!
If you send a single message
saying that you have a problem
..he'll be there to handle everything!
Is that so?
You guys keep making fun of me because
I don't have a boyfriend, right?
Now once your brother comes
here I'll make him fall for me!
It's not that easy to make
my brother fall for you dear.
He is another Shiva Mani!
He'll not fall for any girls?
Gabbar Singh, power star Pavan kalyan
Garu said a dialogue about women!
Now, I'm going to tell
a dialogue about men.
A man should fall
in love with a girl..
..and it's for sure he's
going to fall, it's inevitable!
He'll fall in love with a girl,
even if it takes a week..
..or a month or even a year!
See now, what is going to happen now!
Our seniors are ragging
us and troubling us.
Please save me!
Do you know how it is
when Yamini sends a message?
Brother, we are here in
the Balaji theatre and some..
..scoundrels are troubling
me and my friends!
Come soon and save us bro!
Do you know how the message
that came just now is?
Please brother, save me!
In my college some of
our seniors are ragging me.
Please come!
When the message is so polite,
it's definitely not from my sister.
That's why I knew there is
some twist in this and sent my friend!
You are real police, brother!
By the way, my name is Vikram!
Radha!
"Why is this so?
Why is this so? Why is this so?"
"This guy I met is like a thunder!"
"He is showering in my heart!"
"Something has started
which I've never seen!"
"It's happening inside me."
"Suddenly something magical happened,
and my heart leaped in joy for it!"
"My heart is running after
you and it says she wants you!"
"This magic,
is it all because of you?"
"Are you the one who is tickling me?"
"Why is this so?
Why is this so? Why is this so?"
"Why is this so?"
"I've started liking myself so much!"
"Thoughts of you
are making me feel shy!"
"I can feel you inside my heart!"
"Now a days, I'm a changed person,
this seems so magical!"
"All this is because of you!"
"This guy I met is like a thunder!"
"Why is this so?
Why is this so? Why is this so?"
"It's very difficult to
explain what is happening to me!"
"You looked at me and
made something happen!"
"A flood has engulfed me
and do you know what its name is?"
"You have stolen me from myself
and now I feel I'm part of you!"
"This guy I met is like a thunder!"
"Why is this so?
Why is this so? Why is this so?"
"Why is this so? "
Two thousand rupees for two coffees?
Is the pocket money mom and
dad are giving is not enough for you?
Are you doing a part time job?
When you have a brother like me,
if you do these kind of..
..jobs it's going
to be humiliating for me!
Stop your over acting, will you?
Are you showing off in front of her?
Why do you speak like that?
When I called you some
time ago why did you cut my call?
You see..
That..
You cut Yamini's call?
Hello, enough of you.
You too disconnected my call!
When father gave me some
pocket money I brought my..
..friends to this coffee
shop to treat them.
I can't find my money.
Hey, server!
Bring two plates idli,
and two plates pesarattu upma!
Okay sir.
You have a bill in your hand..
..and I don't have money
in my hand to clear that bill!
First thing in the morning,
I got this case!
- Hey, Simhachalam! Simhachalam,
come here. - Yes sir.
Take this sir inside
and make him grind the dal!
- Sir!
What?
Same situation, Sir!
What all did you eat?
- Pizza!
- Burger!
- Ice-cream!
- We even drank cool drinks, sir!
Bearer! Take their bags and phones
and make them clean the kitchen!
Okay.
Sir, we've cleaned the
kitchen completely. See you, sir!
When you work, we let you go.
That's the olden system.
Punishment cum cash is the new trend!
Call some of your
people and get the cash..
..or else I'll make you work
like the waiter for a months' time!
Oh, is that so? Yesterday
Seenu had asked me for some money.
So I took the money from
your purse and gave him!
I thought of telling you but I forgot!
I thought it must me you!
Yamini, I have to pay my bill.
Go and grind the dal!
All the money was in the purse!
What do we do now?
I'll handle it!
I don't know what she's going
to tell mother, I'll see you later!
Okay.
What baby, did you both fought again?
Mummy, she's telling all lies.
Radha is just a friend to me!
She didn't tell anything yet.
By the way, why will she tell lies?
We caught you! Who is that Radha?
No mummy,
Radha is just a friend to me!
When we are hesitating to
talk about a person that means..
..we have a relation with that one.
Bring that Radha home once!
Mosa garu! Mosa garu! Mosa garu!
To hell with these people!
The can't let me do even
puja in peace! Hey you Kasi, Kasi.
- Where the hell are you?
- I'm right in front of you!
The day I took my oath as
the president of this apartment..
..that I'll never let the people in this
apartment suffer any kind of trouble.
What are they going through?
Mosa keeps his word and
never changes his attitude!
First stop your nonsense so that
we can go there and see what happened!
Let's go! Follow me!
Hey, this apartment comes
under our area. Who are you?
Who do you think am I?
Mo stands for modern and Sa stands
for Sampradayam which means culture.
I took mo and sa
and made my name Mosa..
..and became the president
of this apartment!
Don't try to challenge me.
You'll burn to ashes!
It's not you who should say that.
Others should say that!
I heard it, I heard your minds voice!
First send them out.
Why should we have trouble with them?
If we give them ten
rupees they'll go away!
Of course!
It's not your money we give, but mine!
- Thanks sir!
- Okay, leave!
Not just hearing mind voice!
You need to have a mind!
Mr. President!
Today these beggars
have come near our house.
Tomorrow they may
come inside the house.
You'll have to stop all
this as you are the president!
What should I do, you tell me?
Okay, I'll do this!
I'll bring Ivanka from America!
Then all the security
people will be here!
Why do you talk about
what's impossible?
Do what is possible!
You tell what you want. He'll do it!
Ayya, president garu.
A patient without treatment
and an apartment without watchman..
..both are not safe!
First, appoint a watchman here, sir!
Of course, of course!
I've been calling those
security agency people!
They are getting scared to
send a watchman for our apartment!
Sir, Mr. Murali, you are
using our apartment watchman as..
..if he is your own personal servant!
How much did I use Sir?
In the morning to get
breakfast from restaurant..
..in the afternoon to get lunch..
..and once in a while I send
him to the market or maybe liquor.
- That is all, isn't it?
- Sir!
Now I understand why those
watchmen used to ruN away like that!
Yes, of course. I understand it!
What happened driver?
I don't know madam! I'll check.
Auto can't start madam.
Some problem in the engine I guess!
If any auto comes this side
I'll arrange it for you madam.
Okay!
Driver!
Madam?
I live nearby. I can walk home.
Okay madam.
So, last night a shadow followed you,
that too like a ghost?
If the shadow is a ghost either
it'll attack you or frighten you!
But this way of following is new,
isn't it?
Maybe that shadow loves Radha.
Do ghosts also love?
If someone is beautiful like Radha!
What atmas,
even pretatmas also will fall in love!
Do you know how scared
I was last night?
You all find it funny, do you?
Radha! Just joking,
don't take it seriously!
I would like to share other
people's sadness, instead of..
..making fun of them like this!
I don't know why, but I feel this
is the guy who followed me last night.
You said last night it was a shadow?
I feel he was that shadow!
I feel you got scared
of that shadow a lot.
That's why you feel so.
You stop thinking about
that shadow for a while and..
And?
If you think about me..
Here, if anyone sees both
of us like this it won't be good.
You go! Bye.
Is that all?
What else do you want?
- I mean..
- Okay, bye!
Radha.
What?
It's very difficult to tell girls about
what you have in your heart, isn't it?
I don't know about boys, but girls
can't express themselves to guys!
It's very difficult.
If we get into chatting here,
it's even more difficult. You leave!
- Bye, you take care.
- Okay, bye!
Hey, you! What's your problem man?
Why are you looking at me?
Who are you, man?
Radha, what happened?
From a couple of days
this guy is following me.
If we see his face
we'll get nightmares.
- I'm going to hit him..
- Radha, wait a second.
Hey, you! I've seen you
in front of Radhas apartment.
Why are you following her?
He won't budge like this.
If we complain to police and when
they hit him, he'll learn his lesson.
See, this is your last warning.
If I see you again following
this girl, that's all. Go!
Get lost!
Radha, cool!
A surprise for you!
Radha, my mother.
Mummy, radha!
Namaste aunty!
Come inside dear!
Why didn't you tell me you
are bringing me to your house?
I did tell you it's a surprise,
didn't I? Come!
Yamini, see who's here!
- Hey!
- Hi!
Dear, she is our son's friend Radha.
Namaste uncle!
- How are you, dear?
- I'm fine uncle.
How are your parents?
My mother died in my childhood,
my father is everything to me.
He is a bank manager.
You don't be worried dear.
From today on we have two daughters!
Vikram told us that he likes you.
"Do you know the language
in which the heart communicates?
"Have you heard the music of my heart
which is trying to tell you something?"
"Do you know the language
in which the heart communicates?
"Have you heard the music of my heart
which is trying to tell you something?"
"Have you spoken something?
Have I heard something?"
"Let's lock and tie
a knot to unite us.."
"..which can put an end to
all the wars waging in our hearts."
"I think I'll say no!"
"Do you know the language
in which the heart communicates?
"Have you heard the music of my heart
which is trying to tell you something?"
"Can't you understand how impatient your
soul is to shower me with affection?"
"Ask your breath and eyes
which are inviting me to fill.."
"..you with signs of endearment."
"The steps I take are leading
me to shower you with kisses."
"This is very true!
Is it the time yet?"
"Should we wait even more?"
"Do you know the language
in which the heart communicates?
"Have you heard the music of my heart
which is trying to tell you something?"
"The sky showers the earth
with kisses of rain drops."
"The waves of the sea have
been waiting to meet their.."
"..destination all this while."
"The flowers have a display
of affection with the air.."
"..surrounding them."
"I want you to accept
the offering of my affection."
"Isn't this love eternal?"
"Do you know the language
in which the heart communicates?
"Have you heard the music of my heart
which is trying to tell you something?"
"Do you know the language
in which the heart communicates?
"Have you heard the music of my heart
which is trying to tell you something?"
What darling, these days
you don't come over to my place?
A new chick has come,
and her touch is electrifying, is it?
Yes, darling!
I wish to come over.
But these days my superior
is stressing me so much that I..
..can't perform well anymore!
Whatever it is, please don't remind me
all this during my night duties, baby.
Just a minute, I'll call you back!
Start the vehicle.
Are you the watchman
for this apartment?
Excuse me!
That fellow is my assistant.
An assistant to the watchman?
How much is your salary?
Sir, you are mistaken.
I'm the president of this apartment.
Is that so?
Aren't there any CC TV
cameras in this apartment?
No watchman either!
Watchman has gone to ooty, and
CC cameras I've ordered from America.
They are on the way!
CC cameras from USA, is it?
And watchman comes from ooty?
Your way of working
is as ridiculous as you are.
Modern above and traditional below.
I don't know what you'll do,
but I give you just two days.
Arrange CC TV cameras to this
apartment and appoint a watchman here.
Sure sir.
Just now four bikes came
into this apartment, who are they?
They are our boys.
They live in this apartment.
- Take care!
- Sure sir.
Hey, you!
Have your ears stopped working?
Can't you hear your phone ringing?
Phone is ringing so loudly,
have your ears stopped working?
You are glaring at me,
but can't attend the call?
Hello, who is it?
It's from the security agency.
One minute, Sir!
The call is from the security agency.
Give it to me.
Go! Go, and do your work!
That's what I do!
Hello!
Sir, Mr. Mosa, it's me sir!
We can talk later bro,
first tell me about the watchman!
I've given your apartment address
to a new watchman called Rudra..
..he must be there by now!
You are saying a new watchman,
does he know the situation here or no?
You are there to tell all that sir,
aren't you?
Okay, okay!
I'll explain him everything.
But send him soon dear. These
people here are stressing me a lot.
He should be there by now, just check!
There is a chair near the gate,
you go and sit there.
I'll come and explain
everything to you later!
I have a lot of work now.
Please close the door!
What happened?
Watchman!
We need to get some vegetables!
It's okay, I'll go to get them.
Why are you here?
Who appointed you here?
It's too late already,
go to your flat!
Please close the door!
I can't understand whether he
is mad or stupid and I might go mad!
What an auspicious day today is,
it's as if the Goddess..
..Lakshmi Devi herself
has come to our house today.
Why will someone like you
want to meet the president like me?
If you do something so stupid,
anyone will think of you!
What is that stupid thing that I did?
Why did you appoint such a watchman?
He looks like a thief,
remove him from here immediately!
Good my dear!
When there was no watchman,
you all people stressed me about it.
When I prayed to so many
deities we've found him finally.
And now you say he looks like a thief,
send him away and start stressing me?
Have you seen his face properly?
He looks like someone who steals hens
and chicken from the neighbourhood.
Can't you see that?
My dear, he is a watchman
who stays near the gate.
He's not the son-in-law of
the family to select a handsome hunk.
I don't care about all that, sir.
Will you send that fellow away or not?
There's no way I can send him away!
Even if the sky tears
down or whatever! It's mosa!
Mosa keeps his word and
never changes his attitude!
You go and change your decision!
Radha, radha!
What happened to you?
Why are you so absent minded?
That sweeper has come back!
Where did you see him?
He has come as a watchman
for our apartment!
Come!
I think he's not here. You leave!
If anyone sees both of us
together here it won't be good!
Take care!
Please close the door!
Leave me!
Am I exaggerating about the watchman?
Plumber has come,
he said to stop the tap!
Watchman, what is your name?
Watchman!
Hello!
Hi uncle, hi aunty!
Hi!
Come dear, coma and sit!
Brother,
Radha and Vikram love each other.
We all like Radha a lot!
All that is fine! If you
all like my daughter, is it enough?
Should I not like your son?
What does my son lack!
He stood first in SI training.
In a couple of days he'll
get the posting for sure!
Father!
Uncle, tell me what I
should do to make you like me!
I'm willing to do anything for Radha.
Brother-in-law, when I see your affection
and your children's' good conduct..
..I feel my daughter is going to be
happier in your house than she was here.
She is a motherless child, if
she commits any mistake unknowingly..
..please forgive her with a big heart.
Daddy!
Brother-in-law, if you wish so, you can
make your son-in-law stay in your house!
We don't need such a fortune,
brother-in-law.
You people can take your
daughter-in-law to your house!
Brother, find an auspicious
day and set the muhurtham!
Sure, today itself I'll
ask the pundit and get a good..
..muhurtham and inform you people.
See you later, Brother-in-law!
Sure, Brother-in-law!
See you my dear!
Bye.
Bye!
Watchman.
Lift the boy!
Watchman, put the boy down!
Wait!
See Vinay, from now on you have to
take support of this leg pad and walk.
If you think you can't do it,
you can't do anything.
On the other hand, if you
decide that you can accomplish it..
..you can handle anything.
Motivate your brain,
which thinks I can't walk!
Activate your body!
Even if your step falters
or you trip and fall down..
..you have to bring yourself up!
If you listen to your heart,
you can never walk in your life again!
Awaken your mind and soul.
Vivekananda said, strength
is life and weakness is death!
If you decide you can
definitely walk again.
Even if you fall down a few times
you'll get up and walk again for sure.
If you want to win,
you have to step forward tirelessly..
..how many ever difficulties
might come your way.
Brother, find an auspicious
day and set the muhurtham!
Okay!
Watchman, have you gone mad?
Why are you doing like this? Give way!
Hey, you have killed our trust!
From many years we live here together.
We may not trust each other,
but we all trust the watchman!
If we are going out we
handover the house keys to you!
If the womenfolk in our houses are alone,
we inform you and go out.
You have betrayed that trust today.
Disloyal fellow!
Why do you talk to him, Sir?
It's like chanting vedas
in from of demons! You give way!
You wait uncle,
we'll give him coating in our style!
No. no! we'll send him away!
If you send away someone
who did a mistake, it's not right!
Today he held your
daughters' hand, later..
..he may do the same
thing to some other girl!
Oh, no no! you be quite sir.
Why do we need all this nuisance?
If we call police,
they'll come and take this fellow away!
You wait uncle! We'll handle him!
You held Radha sister's hand?
Stop it!
First, send him out.
Did you see our Radha sister's good heart?
Though you caught
her hand she forgave you.
Why do you still talk, take him away.
Oh, no no! don't do anything to him, boys!
You frightened us, right?
You people have humiliated
me publicly and beat me until..
..I bleed and threw me out!
You'll die!
All of you people will die.
There will be a dead body
every day in this apartment.
My words are ultimate!
You'll die, all of you will die!
All of you will die!
That watchman frightened us, man!
I can't take it!
It was his bad luck that he came here!
Hey man, until that Mosa garu
finds another watchman, we are free birds!
Why do we need his nonsense now?
Let's enjoy the party!
Cheers!
Hey, it looks like that watchman has come!
He'll not leave us alone so easily,
okay! Run boys!
Mosa garu, pavan babu has died sir.
Call the police, sir!
Pavan, pavan!
Pavan.
He did what he said!
He killed my child, sir!
What does that mean?
I'll tell you all that!
There will be a dead body
every day in this apartment.
We thought, because those boys
hit him he said all that in anger.
We didn't think he'll really kill!
Sir.
Because we hit him he
killed one of us with revenge.
We are very scared whom
he is going to kill tomorrow!
Don't worry!
You don't have to be scared at all!
I'll handle everything.
I'm going to catch him for sure!
Especially you be careful.
At any situation,
you shouldn't go out alone.
If at all anything urgent,
you take somebody with you!
Be careful!
On the first day that he came,
Radhamma had told me to..
..send that fellow away as he is not good!
I didn't listen to her on that day.
If I had heeded on that day,
today this wouldn't have happened sir!
Which agency had sent him?
Falcon security agency, sir!
They've come recently!
Greetings Sir. Please be seated!
You have sent Rudra to Madhuram
apartments, we need his details.
Why sir?
What?
If we don't tell what happened,
will you not give?
I just wanted to know what happened.
He brutally murdered a resident
of that apartment and escaped!
My God! One minute Sir!
Name alone is there sir.
Is name alone enough?
Will you not take address details!
Even that name Rudra,
he himself must have taken!
He's planned everything.
How can you appoint
a watchman in that way?
From how long do you know him?
He came to our office,
searching for a job three months ago.
He kept asking us every day for work.
One day, the Madhuram
apartment president..
..Mr. Mosa called me and warned
me that they need a watchman immediately.
We have ten years agreement with
that apartment to provide it security.
That fellow came exactly at that time.
Sir, he is new!
When I came to know that
he didn't work anywhere as the..
..security guard, I decided
that he'll be the right guy for that..
..Madhuram apartments and sent him there.
Why did you think he is the
right person for that apartment?
Actually sir,
no one liked to work in that apartment.
Why did no one like?
There were rumors that there
is a ghost in that apartment..
..parking area,
and that'll never let anyone stay there.
Ghost?
Yes sir! That's why
no one liked to work there!
Rudra is new here, he doesn't
know anything about that apartment.
That's why I sent him there sir.
That's all!
How can he not know anything
about that apartment?
He used to sweep the
roads around that area!
Really?
I think that's why he was so
elated when I said about that apartment.
I thought he's happy because he got a job!
Will you call the guy who
left the apartment last time..
..because he said there is a ghost?
He is not here sir.
Last time when he saw the ghost
he lost his mind and became mad.
He is getting treated in
the Erragadda mental hospital!
This is not a normal case.
There's lot of matter behind it.
To find out the mysterious
connection between Rudra..
..that murder and the ghost,
I have to pull the right cords..
..and shake everything up.
Ajay, get some water!
Sit down.
Tell me now!
What is the relation between you and that
watchman who murderer in that apartment?
That fellow used to..
..work along with us as a contract worker.
That's how I know him.
Because of that friendliness I used
to go to that apartment, now and then!
That's all sir.
That night,
I saw you bury something there.
What was that?
Lemon, sir!
True sir, they were just lemon.
My husband doesn't work.
He is an alcoholic.
He spends all my earnings for his liquor.
I have a grownup daughter, sir.
I want to arrange money
for my girls wedding..
..so I save my money without
my husband's knowledge..
..and bury it in that
apartment in few places, sir.
I dig a hole and bury some money
and cover it with dirt and lemons there..
..and cover again with dirt,
so that no one will check it.
Even if they do, they'll only
see lemon and then they'll get scared..
..and will not dig deeper,
that's what I thought sir.
When I came to know that apartment
people hit Rudra and chased him away
..that same night I went and..
..took all my money and came back sir.
True, sir.
I swear on my daughter!
Okay.
You go!
Who killed that boy?
Was it Rudra or the
ghost in that apartment?
If we catch Rudra,
we'll come to know the truth sir!
No, that's for later!
First we have to take care
of the ghost in that apartment.
SI sir, why did you
ask us all to come here?
When we were enquiring
about the watchman who is..
..supposed to have committed
a murder in this apartment..
..we came to know about
some unbelievable truths, I..
..mean matters.
What are they sir?
Do you all know why
all the previous watchmen..
..used to run away from this apartment?
Why is that, son?
In your apartment parking..
..there is a ghost
Ghost?
Has anyone of you ever..
I know it's funny, seen a ghost?
We've never seen a ghost sir!
It's the first time we have
heard that word here, from your mouth.
If there is really a ghost here,
it should frighten us or kill us!
But frightening the watchman,
how does that make sense, sir?
Isn't it? Logic, right?
I came here to find that out.
Who among you have frightened
the watchmen and chased them away.
I need to know now!
If you tell on your own its better.
Because if I ask in my style..
..you guys can't bear it.
What's all this man?
Sir..
..we used to do that.
At night, we used to wear ghost
masks and frighten the watchmen!
Sir, did you hear that?
What's the benefit for
you in frightening them?
Sir, once police booked
us in a drunk and drive case.
They called our parents
and counseled them.
That's how our parents
came to know that we drink.
They warned us that they'll
stop giving us our pocket money.
We made a plan that we should
not get caught even if we drink.
We planned a scheme,
and made a deal with watchman Shivayya.
If we give him a quarter every day..
..he'll allow us to party
in the parking during the night.
From then on, we used to booze
in the parking lot every night.
Shivayya wanted to cash our
weakness and he started to blackmail us.
He used to demand us for money or liquor,
whenever he wanted.
Since we couldn't cope
with that we started to..
..think about a way
to send him away from here.
That's when we got an idea.
How about wearing ghosts mask..
..and frighten the watchman
so that he runs away on his own?
We all liked that idea!
We did just that and the plan succeeded.
Then we started chasing away all
the watchmen that came to this apartment.
Then, why didn't you frighten Rudra?
We tried sir, but it didn't work out!
Instead that Rudra frigtened us.
Sai.
My son.
Sai!
Take the pictures!
My son!
Who saw it?
I've seen it sir. I came up
here to put my clothes for drying.
He was lying there dead.
My son. Sai!
Sai!
Sir, see this sir!
That fellow did what he said, Sir?
Vikram.
Did you see this? He did what he said.
Do something and catch that fellow, son!
The people in this apartment
are shivering with fear..
..thinking about what
is going to happen next.
Please catch him, Sir!
Sir, he'll not spare us, sir.
Please sir, save us sir.
Sir, next it's my turn
or this fellows' sir.
We are scared he might
kill both of us together, sir!
We'll run away and hide somewhere sir.
It's safer for you to be here.
If you go out,
he'll find you people easily.
Moreover, outside we can't
give you the kind of security..
..that we are able to provide you here.
Don't go out of your
flats until he is caught!
We'll surely catch him. Be careful.
I know this. I can't hurt anyone.
That Rudra used to come with
me in the lift every day night..
..until my house, but I couldn't
question his asking why he is stalking me.
I never thought he'll take this as
an excuse and start misbehaving with me.
It's such a sad thing that those
boys got caught in all this because of me.
I'm the reason for all these murders!
Radha, you don't be sad.
It's my responsibility
to keep everyone safe.
I'll catch that Rudra at any cost.
Dead or alive!
Radha, I'll never let tears
roll from your eyes, I promise.
"O my dearest, o my dearest!"
"You have add the colour
of your dreams to my eyes and.."
"..made my world beautiful! "
"I'll become the sound of
your heart and stay within you as.."
"..if I'm the breath in your life.
"O my dearest, o my dearest!
O my dearest, o my dearest!"
"These three knots have
become hundred years journey."
You are in me and I'm in you!"
"My steps have learned
dance because of you.."
"..my breath has learned
to sing because of you!"
"Our destination is same and
let's continue this friendship.."
"..at every step and every second,
O my dearest!"
"Let's stay together for all the yugas,
"O my dearest!"
"This ours is the oldest new love story."
"You are the greatest
companion for my heart. "
"You are the heart of my
heart and I feel I'm the luckiest.."
"..o my dearest!"
"The happiness showered
me and drenched me, o my dearest!
"O my dearest! O my dearest!"
Police is searching for
this murderer who killed two..
..people in Madhuram
apartments and escaped.
If anyone finds a whereabouts of this man,
City police..
..department personnel has
requested the public to call..
..on the below given numbers
to give any information.
Sir, it's me who called you sir!
Call two constables!
What is this, this guy murdered two people
and here he is sleeping so peacefully?
He drank the juice from the fridge,
he'll not wake up now.
Hey, what is this juice from the fridge?
Yes sir! After my father's death
my mother became mad due to tension.
For her to sleep well in the
night she has to take sleeping pills.
But she hates taking tablets
and she never used to take them.
So we started mixing them in the
juice and give her a glass full of juice..
..mixed with the tablets every night,
which we keep in the fridge all the time.
That's why this fellow
doesn't know about all that..
..he thought it's just juice and have it.
That's why he is sleeping like this.
He slept a lot, wake him up!
Why am I here?
Why are you hitting me?
If we investigate you
in the police station..
..there will be many
rules and regulations.
While here, no rules!
If you don't tell the truth, I can even
encounter you and no one can question me.
Ajay.
Do we look like fools to you?
Why did you kill those two so brutally?
Tell me! Tell!
I guessed it!
I had guessed something
like this is going to happen!
I was like a watch dog for
those people in that apartment..
..and the beat me up and sent me away.
That's why, that is the reason why
they have brought this upon themselves.
What nonsense are you talking?
Tell me the truth.
I'm telling you the truth!
It's not going to stop
with these two deaths.
Some more will die.
Daily there are going to be deaths.
This is the truth!
See, come to the point straight.
Are you killing them or
have you paid people to kill them?
If you talk nonsense I'll shoot you.
You'll shoot me, okay!
How will you kill her
who murdered those two people?
Who is she?
In that same apartment,
the lady who lives in the flat no. 307.
That Pramila?
If you say one more word about Pramila,
I myself will kill you!
Pramila died two years ago.
No, it's been 2 years,
3 months and 15 days until today!
Pramila has turned into a
ghost and she is full of revenge!
Sir, he has committed those
murders and want to shift the blame..
..on a ghost who is not there
and want to escape with this story.
You, don't tell me cock and bull stories!
Moreover, in these days
you talk about ghosts and demons?
Do you plan to side
track the case and escape?
Hail to Lord Shankar!
We are sadhus without any selfishness.
We don't know to kill
people but we only save them.
If we have to,
we give our lives to save you people!
Our only goal is this worlds happiness.
Do you know what really happened?
What mother, you are thinking deeply?
Rudhra, yesterdad I had
been to an apartment on the..
..request of those residents
of that apartment to conduct Rudra yagam!
[Sanskrit chants]
I'll kill, I'll kill!
I'll kill everyone.
When you were alive you
were a handicapped person..
..who couldn't take
care of her own chores.
How will you kill now?
I'll kill!
I'll kill everyone.
You have turned into an soul and stayed
back here, what do you want to accomplish?
You can't move an inch from
the chair in which you are sitting.
You keep chanting "I'll kill.
I'll kill" and there by gather power.
How much ever power you gather,
you can't do anything!
Do you know why?
Because you are handicapped!
How much ever you keep trying,
it's all waste.
Death is the final
destination for the life!
All those are of no use,
stop chasing them.
Ghost spirit schemes are
dangerous and disastrous.
Leave this earth and go to other world.
As long as you are here,
your soul will not find peace.
An soul without peace has
neither a meaning nor a goal!
Go, go away!
I'll not go, I'll not go anywhere!
Until I take my revenge
I'll not go away from here.
Only after I take the revenge,
my soul will find peace!
Tell me about your revenge, I'll help you!
I'll not tell you! You go away, leave!
Pramila has acquired lot of powers now.
With vengefulness, she wants to kill
all the people she had planned to kill.
What are we going to do now, matha ji?
I told her that she is handicapped..
..and she can't accomplish
anything and made her believe this.
You told us that,
if an soul wants to kill somebody..
..it keeps telling
itself that it'll kill..
..and there by acquire the
power needed to do what it wants to do!
How much ever power
the soul has acquired..
..if it wants to kill somebody..
..it does need another body,
doesn't it matha ji?
That's why,
it has selected the body of Radha..
..who too lives in the same apartment.
If I had not gone to that apartment
for the Rudra yagam yesterday..
..many disasters would have happened!
If we have to pacify that pramila
who is full of vengeance now..
..the powers that I
have now will not be enough.
I'm going to kedarnath!
There I'll do 11 days abishekam
to Shivalingam and bring back..
..the vibudhi (ash) and ganga jalam.
Until then, you have to make
sure that soul doesn't enter Radha's body.
This is most sacred vibudhi (ash),
use only in the most urgent situation.
This raksha will keep
you safe from that soul.
In that way,
because of the matha ji's command..
..I have been keeping
Radha safe all the time.
You have been keeping Radha safe, is it?
Then why did you misbehave with Radha?
That too has a reason!
No, if she hears anyone
saying encouraging words..
..that prompt her to action
saying you can do it and you..
..can accomplish it,
it's very difficult to stop her!
Harahara mahaadeva!
Vibudhi (ash) is finished!
I should not allow the
soul to enter Radha's house.
What should I do?
What am I supposed to do?
Your matha ji worked on my mind
and had confined me to my wheel chair.
But today I have come to know my power.
Now no one can stop me
from entering into Radha's body.
You and your matha ji together,
both of you can't stop me in any way!
If you go out of this apartment,
no one can stop you.
That's why I have confined
you within this apartment!
Hey, I'll make sure you
don't touch Radha's body.
Hail to Lord Shankar!
You have put obstacles in my way!
Now see how I will throw
you out of this apartment!
In that way, I managed to stop pramilas
soul from going out of the apartment.
Then I thought of keeping Radha out..
..of the apartment and
I kept waiting for her arrival.
That's why I had to
take hold of Radha's hand.
I didn't have any bad intentions
as you all have assumed.
When those people were beating me..
..the rakshana cord that was tied on
my hand came off and fell somewhere there.
To find that,
I went to that apartment that same night.
Who are you?
Pramila, you .... Here ... again?
I want to kill those people
who killed me and my father.
For that purpose I'm here!
What?
Uncle didn't die due to heart attack?
Somebody killed you and uncle, is it?
Who are they?
Parvathi, the accident that took place
on that day has taken you away from us.
I never thought our baby,
who should be running..
..and leaping around like a deer,
will be confined to a wheel chair.
Now I have to live for her,
Parvathi, I'll live for our baby!
How is our new flat, my dear?
In the old house everywhere
there are your memories.
Our memories should give
us courage and fortify our lives!
They shouldn't give us pain.
That's why I sold that
old flat and bought this new one!
Why do you cry and feel bad baby?
When I fell in love with
your mother and married her..
..I got disconnected
from all my relatives.
That's why, though we have so
many of our people, we have become loners.
Newness brings along new changes,
here everyone is new to you.
New acquaintances, you'll like them all!
Hi uncle!
Hi dear!
Hi!
Pramila met with an accident, dear!
You have shifted into the flat, newly?
Yes dear, it's us!
We live in the adjacent 305 flat,
me and my father!
Where are you both going?
Not anywhere!
I thought I'll just
take her out for a while.
Uncle, leave that to me!
I'll take Pramila out.
I'll introduce her to everyone!
I'm very happy Pramila.
Since we both are girls without a mother,
we understood..
..each other very well and became
good friends in such short while.
If you face any kind of problem here..
..I'm there to help you out!
I'm going to Hyderabad to collect
funds for Rajesh uncle's orphanage.
I'll be back in about 4 days?
Okay?
Hey, what the hell are you fellows doing?
It's a place for
respectable people to live..
..it's not a bar or pub
for you to get drunk and play!
Oh, really? We don't know that!
Hey, old man!
Hold your tongue or else it'll get cut!
Hey, why should we fight with him?
Let's make him our friend.
Because, this uncle
has a beautiful daughter!
At least for her sake we can let him go!
Hey, she is handicapped!
So what bro? She is very beautiful.
She'll not resist us, whatever we do!
That's what we need, right?
Shut up!
It's not your fault that you talk rubbish.
It's your upbringing that is not right!
I'll not talk with you now.
I'll speak with your parents
in the morning tomorrow.
He slapped me;
I'm going to teach him a lesson bro!
He said he's going to
complain to our parents..
If our parents come to know about this,
it's going to be a big issue!
They'll stop giving us our pocket money.
He said he'll show us his power tomorrow..
..we'll show him our power today itself!
- Let's go.
Tomorrow, from England the
military doctor is going to come here.
The doctors from here have
sent all your reports to him.
He checked all of them and said that
we should get ready for the operation.
That's why I brought this money, my dear!
I can spend any amount of money..
..so that my little girl can run and leap
around like a deer in front of my eyes!
Who is it, at this hour?
Who is it, I'm coming!
Why have you come here?
You all just get out,
or else I'll shout and call everyone.
Are you going to call everyone?
Bro, the girl!
See the money!
If we take so much money,
he'll give police complaint.
What should we do bro?
Let's kill!
If we kill,
will the police leave us alone?
They'll arrest us and throw us into jail!
I can't live without liquor!
We'll make people believe
that the old man got a heart attack!
Look at the old man; does he
look like someone who gets a heart attack?
We'll make him get a heart attack!
See this golden biscuit,
sitting in the wheel chair.
If we touch her romantically..
..his heart will stop beating.
Yes, hit yourself!
That's what we too want!
If we get result without killing,
that's good for us!
Hit until you lose your life!
Yes, hit yourself!
He's dead!
Hey, if we kill her too, its better!
No bro, if they both die,
it's going to be a police case!
That'll be dangerous for us.
Leave her alone!
She'll die of hunger and thirst,
in few days.
We shouldn't spare such idiots!
I'll put a police case
and make sure they go to jail.
Such murderers should get punished.
There's nothing we can do now!
Are we going to let go
of those people who were reason..
..for your death and uncles' death?
I'll not spare them.
Until I kill them with my own hands,
my revenge will not subside!
And I'll not leave this place.
For my purpose to get fulfilled,
I need your help Radha.
Death is the correct punishment
for those scoundrels.
Tell me what I should do, Pramila?
Now I'm just an soul with
vengeful heart because I've died.
If I have to kill those
fellows I'll need your body Radha!
Hey, it looks like that watchman has come!
He'll not leave us alone so easily, okay!
Run boys!
Hey, who are you?
You forgot me so soon.
You had killed me and my father,
haven't you?
How much ever you scream,
the noise will not come out.
In that way, with the help of Radha..
..pramila killed those
two boys and took her revenge.
This is the real truth.
Radha is helping Pramilas soul?
Sir, all the while he had
been talking about your daughter.
She'll help soul's and ghost spirit too!
Sir, do something and help those boys sir!
Oh no.
She has killed two people already!
And plans to kill two more.
We have to go to the apartment.
Let's go.
Sir, you too come along sir!
The cord that matha
ji tied to my hand is gone.
It's not easy to stop the soul's,
as you imagine.
I'll go to the ashram and
get that rakshana cord again.
But one point SI sir,
you have to be very careful.
If you act in haste,
your life gets into danger.
Rudra garu,
now what is the condition of my daughter?
Everything that Parameshwara
will take care of.
Hail to Lord Shankar!
What is this life!
We used to be like race horses..
..because of that watchman
we have become central jail prisoners.
Fear of death is the
most stressful matter in life.
Either to frighten fear or to remove
all sadness, alcohol is the best solution!
Hey, bro! Come, let's go out.
I'll handle whatever happens.
Hey.. wake up.
What, shekar!
You people also commit murders, right?
Then why are you so
scared when you see death?
Sister, Radha sister,
we didn't kill anyone willingly sister!
We did it when we were
under the influence of alcohol.
And we got our punishment for that sister.
I've started to understand that God will
not forgive us if we cheat good people.
The 25 lakhs that we took from
uncle on that day were lost in betting.
Because of that sin,
my three friends have died.
Please sister; I've done what is wrong.
I'll never do anything
like this again, sister.
Forgive me sister, please sister.
Sister.
I made mistake.
Forgive me sister.
I'll never do anything like this again.
Sister
Pramila has died very long ago, right?
Why is she there?
Sister.
When I was handicapped,
I was scared of you!
And you made fun of me.
Now, when I'm asking
you to come closer to me..
..why are you getting
scared and running away?
Are you arrogant because
your limbs are working?
He killed my father.
No one can stop me from killing him now.
You go away from here!
He may have been the reason
for your death and your father's death.
But there is law to
give him his punishment.
I'll make sure he gets punished.
You leave Radha's body and go away.
I'll not leave Radha's
body until I finish killing him.
You move aside, go away! Go.
I know very well how to
bring you out of Radha's body.
Your strength is..
..only while you are inside this building.
You can't go out from here..
..how much ever you may try.
Hey, shekar wait!
Vikram.
What happened to me?
Radha, do you realize what you are doing?
This fellow ruined
pramilas beautiful life.
He has no right to be alive.
As long as you are there,
you'll be stopping me.
I'll kill you!
Did that God send you here
to save the people who have sinned?
It's the great God who punishes
sinners and saves righteous people.
Who are we to say anything!
Anyhow, what do you know
about that Omni present God?
He always likes to forgive
but doesn't punish anyone.
I'm not the God you all believe in,
to forgive a sinner.
I'm a vengeful demon.
Mine is not a story,
but a revengeful agony.
Don't try to stop me, leave me alone.
Pramila!
[Sanskrit chants]
A person who thinks soul
can kill others or a person..
..who thinks soul can get killed
by others, both these are foolish.
Because, in Geeta, Govinda has
said that soul will not kill anyone..
..nor get killed by anyone.
You need to know, that our
births and deaths are due to our deeds.
There is no record in any history that..
..an soul has attained
peace by killing its enemy.
You go away!
Leave Radha's body and go away.
Put aside your anger which
is a doorway to hell and find peace.
If my vengeance is not fulfilled,
my soul will not find peace matha ji.
My revenge will not be
satisfied with your words.
I'll not leave Radha's
body without killing that fellow.
Pramila, soul should seek
peace and go away to upper worlds.
It shouldn't become a
reason for distress like this.
I meditated all these
days and acquired power to..
..kill that fellow,
but not to get scared of you.
Hail to Lord Shankar!
Radha!
I need that body!
This Radha, who helped you up until now,
will forget about your past from now on.
Once she gains consciousness, she
would have forgotten everything about you!
Pramila, give up your futile efforts.
You can't do anything
to anyone from now on.
Seek peace.
People who have died
will have to be born..
..and people who are born have to die.
That's for sure!
Your soul has to go back to higher worlds.
You have one more janmaa.
Don't distress your
soul with vengeful thoughts.
That God will give them the
correct punishment for their sins.
Go back peacefully!
We can't escape the result
of our deeds, Pramila.
We all are the pawns in that
world drama that Shiva is playing out.
We have to fulfil our dharma,
but shouldn't betray ourselves..
..with thoughts of revenge. Cry!
Make your anger come
out of you through tears.
Now your Radha is safe.
You both get married happily
and have kids and lead a peaceful life!
Radha..
..have it!
I kept my word that I
had promised to your father.
What was that?
I mean.
I told him that I'll
take good care of you.
I was thinking about it.
He is still alive!
Where have you gone away, Pramila?
You've left without taking your revenge!
How is it going to be satisfied?