The Hinterland
Algeria isn't just a picturesque region
used by caravans with no camels...
… but also a land of prodigious
industrial and commercial activity
… and of great agricultural richness.
Algiers
That day the mail boat from Marseille
brought to Algiers a young man
who had spent a large inheritance.
… and a young girl on her way to collect
an inheritance from an uncle in Algiers.
Pierre Hoffer, the big spender,
liked a lot Claudin Duvernet,
who was about to inherit.
Manuel Duvernet and his sister Diane,
Claudie's cousins, were firmly
counting on the inheritance.
Sometimes one is happy to meet
old friends from the regiment ;
Pierre was thrilled to meet Zoubir.
No way you're staying at a hotel !
You're staying with me.
The Duvernet family's lawyer...
"… and I appoint as sole legatee
my niece Claudie."
Your old uncle didn't forget you.
He has paid your debts.
Miss, you're inheriting
a villa at Sidi Ferruch.
… and in the south, a large esate.
Since the car now belongs to you,
you can do the driving.
… I wish the voyage would have
lasted another hour ; I was in love.
To think that I will never see her again!
Pierre Hoffer had agreed to
temporarily stay with his friend Zoubir.
I'm starting to think that one
doesn't necessarily have to be
a sucker to get married.
As for money matters... I'm counting
on my uncle Christian Hoffer.
He's the reason why I'm coming to Algeria.
Christian Hoffer is rich,
but he's of an odd sort.
You may end up being disappointed.
I was two years old when he saw me last.
He's kept an fond memory of me.
At Sidi Ferruch, the villa
that Claudie Duvernet had inherited.
Christian Hoffer, Pierre's uncle, had come
to Algeria as a poor man.
Now he had become one of
the richest farmers of the region.
The Hoffer farm is here, right ?
Tell me, my good man,
do you know Christian Hoffer ?
Slightly. That's me !
You're my nephew ?
Dinner time at the Hoffer farm.
Hold your appetite !
We're waiting for my nephew
who just arrived from Paris.
Why on earth are you dressed as a waiter ?
Meanwhile, in Claudie Duvernet's villa.
Why are you drinking like that ?
Do you have those
72.000 francs that I owe ?
There is a way to get that money...
But you don't have any vigor !
Oh, if I was only a man...
Madam is served.
Pardon miss, but that is the place
of the mistress of the house.
The next morning, Christian Hoffer
had decided he would have
his nephew see his farmland.
So lazybones, you still
think you are in Paris ?
We're going to watch the ploughing,
so don't put on a tox.
Let's go.
Today he's dressed like a fool.
It seemed a simple thing to ask
Christian Hoffer for money from afar.
In person, it seemed different...
How much ?
A hundred thousand.
I will pay you back... naturally.
Do you have any idea how much
work it takes us to raise
a hundred thousand francs ?
A hundred years ago,
our predecessors found nothing
but swampland here.
Before it was transformed into
fertile soil; thousands of settlers
died during the effort.
While they were here, our
grandfathers needed better roads.
That's why we were waiting
for you to turn up, son.
It was here, at Sidi Ferruch, that
the French troops disembarked in 1830.
You will have your hundred
thousand francs, but on one condition...
That you spend six months
working here, in order to learn
the value of hard labor.
Agreed !
A week went by...
Hey ! You over there !
What can you do? There's a shortage
on labor in Algeria, they say.
What a lovely day !
Claudie, I have to speak with
my uncle... I must talk
to him right away !
What fair weather !
Uncle, I have decided to marry.
And with whom ?
With Claudie Duvernet.
And you claimed that you loved
the earth. A woman passes by
and you are ready to go.
Because you will follow her
to Paris as soon as she
has sold the property, right ?
And I thought that I had
found a son in you...
What will become of me?
Claudie Duvernet had decided
to go visit the farmland
that she owned in the South.
Pierre had apparently
abandoned his projects.
I come to say goodbye, I'm
leaving for the South tomorrow.
Claudie Duvernet left yesterday.
We'll need to make up a plot
so that I can accompany you.
You are buying sheep ; Zoubir
is selling just that on his farm.
He's leaving tonight.
Alright, then ! We'll go see the flock.
In the meantime, Claudie arrived at
the estate inherited from her uncle.
ESTATE FOR SALE
This farm is giving no profit. We put it
on sale at our uncle's death. We thought
that we were doing the right thing.
Claudie Duvernet is the one that
you need to ask for instructions.
The estate belongs to her.
Claudie was taken with her new domain.
She discovered unknown distractions
thanks to the falconer Ahmed.
To think that the domain would be
ours if it wasn't for that girl.
Still we can do nothing to her...
At Zoubir's place...
You were talking about a gazelle hunt.
Can't you invite my uncle and Claudie ?
I want them to get acquainted.
Very good! I'll join you.
I would gladly spend my whole life here.
I hope that your cousins
will do me the honor of
joining the hunt as well.
I would be glad to,
but my brother can't.
He's busy that day.
Why don't you want me
to take part in the hunt ?
You probably have better things to do.
That girl robbed us ! We should
have gotten the inheritance.
We will get it in the end !
What if I married Claudie ?
Leaving for the hunt.
This time there's no going back.
You're not chickening out ?
You think you're clever because
you forced me into meeting
that girl that I didn't want to see.
But that's your driver.
You brought him to the hunt ?
He's an excellent beater.
I even advice you to take him
with you during the hunt.
Claudie Duvernet's horse had taken
the bit between its teeth ...
What a disgraceful thing we have done.
This form of hunting is barbarous...
If you are tired, I can
take you to the citadel, miss.
I'm dying...
I want to clear my conscience...
I have done a misdeed.
I am in a hopeless situation, Claudie...
Only you can save me.
You must marry me.
You are in my power, and
I am prepared to do anything.
I will kill you if I have to.
By the palm grove...
You could still catch him...
This kidnapping story is
just another set-up. You'll have
to choose between the girl and me.
For the last time, will you marry
me or do you prefer to die ?
The chamel wadi went to
block the road for the fugitives.
Sell me your dromedary. This young girl
is wounded, her life is in danger...
The horses are exhausted.
They can't go on in the sand.
Make your falcon attack the dromedary!
Where did the engaged couple go ?
Look at that !
Today he's dressed as a farmer.
Subtitles by knappen@KG