THE FIRST CRY
I just tell Gaby that today's baby was born Cristina with a dolphin. It was so exciting!
My name is Adriana. For over 30 years I am a midwife in Mexico.
And my passion is the interplay between babies and dolphins.
Gaby  already know that the dolphin emits ultrasounds with its sonar. Now discovered that these vibrations soothe and stimulate the baby.
Dolphin reacts well Condo presence of Gaby.
Does the baby will be born today Gaby?
I do not know. But she is prepared.
Today is a special day. There will be a total eclipse of the Sun.
I believe that the planets influence the birth, think of all the women the world they're at the end of pregnancy.
Imagine them on track Shadow of the Moon, ready to give birth Condo.
And think of all babies, they'll cry for the first time. As with all of us.
Gaby wants to have the child in the sea. I take her to discover this Caribbean beach.
The ideal place for a natural childbirth. Discreet and intimate.
Are delighted decides that your baby will be born here.
We live here with 4 other couples a large house close to this magnificent lake, in the northern United States.
I think we do a nice pair. I, Vanessa Quebec.
And he, the American Michael ... my love.
I bet this will be our last ride boat, the two. Yes, today we will be three.
We call it  Lilicoy, "Fruit of passion" (passion fruit) in Hawaiian. Will be born in our house with our friends without medical help or a midwife.
It is called this a "free birth".
A baby's eclipse, I like the idea.
I have pains, and I know my baby is coming. I asked to my mother me to paint the body. Bonita R I want to be your arrival.
Kencro stand beside me, with our first two children.
My name is  Majtonr'e. I am indigenous Kayapo the Amazon jungle.
We must remove everything is negative. I want to Gaby release your fears.
So with his head under water she discovers the excitement of
fetus in amniotic fluid.
... and faces the anguish birth, to live and to eliminate them.
Javier's father, is with us.
A village midwife has experience. Touch my baby and says it's time.
Fortunately  already got some plants to alleviate pain. A massage with them will do me good.
Given the proximity  delivery ... well ... I see that Michael is worried.
And if things go wrong... He talk much with others.
In general, the reaction is obvious:
The real danger is not the nature, but the hospital and all the technological interventions.
Women have always  Condo light. They got that strength.
And I know that you can give birth following the hearing of my body.
Kencro already sees the Pokecro our son as a hunter.
My name is Mane. I grew up with my people the Sahara.
I know the desert well. I'm a nomad. It is impossible to get lost here, if you're a Tuareg.
Nearly two years I married Mohammed. He pitched camp near a well.
And we'll wait here the arrival of our first child.
Baby Gaby is underway. Labor begins in the pool, but even before birth, going to the beach which is 5 minutes away.
Gaby is calm. I merely guide it with some exercises.
I admit that drag the rest community for my adventure.
I am pleased that Michael can talk to women who made the same choice I made.
Together, we fight for a fairer world ... and here, with the Parliament of Maine.
Today, take control of birth my son is following in that direction. It is the Claims a free woman.
Jose Luis is our doctor. He has made hundreds deliveries under water. There's only intervention if necessary.
It is our privilege to let Gaby will fully enjoy the process of motherhood. We're only here to admire the miracle of life.
Michael asks himself it should feel nervous, but know that I trust in my decision ...  let him calmer.
Jose Luis is on the beach to prepare all the material. Soon we will have with him.
Baby is born. We have no time to go to the beach.
It is a girl.
If welcome, Natalie.
Santiago is the eldest brother, now. Also need to take care of it. So I ask you that name or give Condo sister.
My name is Hung. I am a gynecologist at the hospital Ho Chi Minh City for 10 years. Already helped many babies being born.
It is simple: we are the largest motherhood in the world.
45,000 deliveries per year. What gives 120 babies a day.
Here in Vietnam  that women prefer
Condo Give birth at the hospital. And I think that's good.
Fact, statistics prove that things go better now than when they went home. Here saved many lives.
It is usually easier to hear it ... Putting it down.
- You heard him earlier?
- Now I have a small contraction.
Okay, you have contractions. My intuition was right. I was told it would be today. This proves that the baby and I we understand.
I joined Michael, Lauren, Keith and others the last time. Again I tell you that I am confident and know what to do.
True, there is a risk. Death is part the birth process.
If by chance there is a serious complication ... accept all consequences.
Such is life.
I want you to know ... that's life. You should not feel responsible. It is how I see things.
I'm not from Varanasi. I left the field because quer'iamoos a better life, but still so poor as before.
We live in a vacant lot with my parents, on the banks of the Ganges. Gather the cow dung. What is sacred fuel.
My husband has a Pedicabs.
We already have a big girl Puja,
a boy Arjul,
and Artie is the youngest. We hope the is the last quarter.
My name is Sunita.
Hello?
- Hello?! Already begun to be born?
- Yes!
It's very exciting!
The pool is warm?
Ethan is to fill it. We light the fireplace and has begun! Resumed contractions, I'll stop talking for a while.
- Can keep us informed overnight?
- Of course, we call when born.
- They can speak in any language.
- Whether in English, French, Portuguese, we call.
Wait ... The Father is there with you?
- Dad...
- Is it time?
- There.
- You're already in labor? You'll call a midwife or will you have him alone?
Now we are late to talk about it, Daddy. I told you before.
- Never know what you can do.
- Do not worry.
- Well, yes, my God! I'll try.
- Okay. Oh, Daddy.
- A kiss. Good luck
- Thanks.
There.
I can not go to a hospital, would be a catastrophe. Physicians are always a cesarean ... to bring more money.
And we almost did not what to eat ... So come see the midwife of the neighborhood here. She does not take much.
I feel better. She says it's not a girl. We already have two, and gifts for girls cost much in India.
Advised me to eat sugar before delivery with butter and hot milk to help the baby come down.
Tells me not to worry. Will give me a shot and it will be okay. If something happens, will be here with me.
She also says women, who come to her house crying, out laughing.
It is normal to have so much pain? Nobody tells me anything...
Gotta find the strength to get up and go to the shelter.
women should not give birth in tents because that is where we sleep with men.
It's tradition. I'll have my baby in the desert sands.
My baby is coming. Midwife gives me rice to have luck. It is a custom.
It  night... and I'm afraid. My mom and camellias 're here to help me.
Sandhi, another girl. I'll do the operation for not having more children. Four arrive already.
Help me, Mom! It hurts me so much ...
I'm exhausted.
I hear them talking to Mohammed.
If it were to seek because there is a problem. However, respected the ritual.
My God, take this goat as an offering and protect our lives.
I see the images of the eclipse on TV. And I think we should have an influence on births.
It seems that all women from the region decided to give birth tonight. It is amazing.
Faneck, the name Michael invented for a boy.
We're so alone, in desert.
God decided to take my son. I have to accept.
- It is wonderful! How is he?
- Okay.
- It takes time to make a Man
- Well, born RS 4 hours.
- Born RS 4?
- Yes, but ...
I can hear it
- But I left the placenta.
- I drove out to? You not have asked for a midwife to come and collect?
Well... Perhaps we will.
- How is the baby? Has long hair?
- Very much, as Michael.
- How Michael?
- Yes, exactly like him.
- I'll see if expelled this placenta ...
- Okay.
Faneck was born 3 hours ago and the placenta still not left. Everyone is worried because they know I am in danger of hemorrhaging.
Michael decides Condo  call his mother. She had five children, should know.
Tell us what we can not wait, we should go to hospital immediately.
Thirty minutes is the maximum waiting time before leaving the placenta manually.
- Correct.
Thanks, Mom. I love you too, thanks.
Dr. Yoshimura helped me to be born.
Me, Yukiko, and is it going to help my child to be born.
He says that a birth is like the sunrise: we can not stop him even accelerate it. And I believe him.
It's clear to us that modernity upset everything. What we need turn the old way of life in Japan.
The protocol of hospitals dehumanizes birth, treat him like a disease.
But the woman is not a machine and the baby is not a product.
- Do you feel it?
- Slowly.
Here she comes. Very good.
Ahh, yes ... Well done!
Hello!
There.
My name is  Kokoya. I Oleseitoi's fifth wife. There are 10 women.
Nasieku midwife will help me to give birth our seventh child.
We  Masads.
Today I came to the temple ask that all goes well.
I almost died the last Since I gave birth Condo. Wonder if the gods are more favorable this time.
wizard reads the stones. He tells me he will go well and one boy announces today. It is the day that the Moon will hide the sun.
Everyone thinks that Sandy is my stage name. It's not. It is my real name in real life and onstage.
I love dancing when I'm pregnant. My body is completely different. It's great to feel so.
We lost many cows because of drought. So Oleseitoi want it to be a girl.
Masads Among the men of the other villages provide cattle to the father to win the girl, and marry her later.
Inspire.
When it is  balarina,
nothing else matters.
Until the day I met Fred. With him, I felt like having a child.
There is a natural reflex to expel the baby. Which leads us to force quickly and efficiently.
But like most women take the epidural, we must teach them to push ...
In a way, is to force an artificial manner. Women do not do this way, when it is natural.
Most are children standing squatting or sitting. The position lying is mainly in European countries.
- I will not ever get!
- Brace yourself, close your eyes and imagine the baby to slide out. Go ... continues ...
It's amazing I have to learn to give birth. Elsewhere, there are women they do not even think about it.
- So, how is it?
- It's hard.
- Do not move ...
- Yes, it is beginning to stir a little.
- Look, there he is ... so cute! Are you turning?
- Yes it is.
- Go, go!
- Let him turn around, look at your nose ...
It's so beautiful ...
- Has eyes like yours. Look. It seems ...
- No.
- It's beautiful.
- Yes, it's beautiful. As the father.
The Moon is closer. You mean my baby will be born.
The sky is changing.
My name is Elizabeth.
'm Siberian.
Outside 're 50 degrees Celsius, but that does not scare me. I live near the North Pole.
They took me by helicopter to the hospital Katanga.
I was with many contractions.
We do not have the right to give birth how our grandparents.
That's why I'm here alone ... and my husband got the dogs and reindeer on the ice.
We  Dolgans. The last nomads the north.
The doctor decided I do a cesarean.
My baby is too great ... I'm very worried.
A clinic of Dr. Yoshimura ... a traditional house was built. We live here as if lived 200 years ago.
Strive  body as before ... we have a healthy diet ... and give birth without medical intervention, like our ancestors.
They tell me I have a little girl, Ana. I wanted to have her beside me.
Everything is prepared for feel good ... serene ...
With the other mothers, live in harmony. We talked a lot.
I tell them I was born here as my brother and my daughter Utano.
In fact, I think, somehow, Dr. Yoshimura as a grandfather.
In my family we say in jest we are supporters of "salmon Part R": We always come back to the same place terms for our children.
Oleseitoi has a hundred children. Each birth respected tradition: Spitting on the baby ...
Say it is ugly ... for luck ... poke a bull and take you a little blood and give me to drink; for me to regain strength.
Oleseitoi is very happy for being a girl. We called it Nemal'i, which brings prosperity.
- You had your child at home?
- Yes, on the couch.
- It must have been painful ...
Can you imagine?
Pilar wants to have her first child the dolphins. Trusts. You know you can have him alone.
I tell him that the great strength of women is knowing that our body ready for this.
The hypothesis of a cesarean you do not seem plausible, since her grandmother had 15 children without complications, and all born at home.
Tonight we will train. It not be forgotten that the birth can occur overnight.
Fernando  the attendant, chose two dolphins calm who love contact with people.
One is a female, Mouna, are waiting for a baby.
The dolphin uses its sonar. Ultrasound affect humans and the intrauterine life,
enhance our immune defenses and balancing the functioning the two hemispheres cererbrais.
That's why tonight, immediately after working with the dolphins the moms are gonna have wonderful dreams and they'll sleep a lot.
In my last show during pregnancy dance on a boat ...
To accustom the baby dolphin,
trained birth with a doll.
Utano will witness the birth the brother. Although has only three years, I think they'll remember for a lifetime.
It's funny ... You ask me if it's an egg it will come out of my belly. Father tells him no.
Utano is proud to have hosted the Yuit brother, and have cut the cord.
It seems that our son, Nino, decided to be born today. There are a total eclipse. It is very rare. He will at least have it on the day of his birth.
Let me go see my cat.
- Both traffic today!
- Good day ... No, no, I'm now into motherhood.
- Go off the phone.
Fred is a little nervous.
- It is the second red raisins ...
- Would he be born in the car?
- Over an hour of traffic jam. Aguentas or not?
- Sure ... I have pains, but I'm fine. Do not unnerve me, Fred.
Maternity
- It's here, huh?
- We arrive.
- Come down here. I'll park the car.
- Okay, we'll be parents. Are you afraid?
- I'm fine.
It is a ritual  ours: each rose petal is a wish Sofia.
But for all babies who were born on this day only in which the Moon met with the Sun.
According to a Talmudic legend, when a baby is born, he still bears the ultimate knowledge of their ancestors.
That's when an angel tells him to keep this knowledge secret.
Put down a finger on his lips and at that moment the baby forgets everything to enter into life.
A touch of the angel left a trace: the small groove between our upper lip and nose.
Only this moment is that the baby may launch its first cry.
Sin'ead O'Connor "A New Born Child"
-----
Just as two breaths become one breath,
As two whispers become a cry,
Miracle before us lies,
The glory of a new-born child.
These half-closed eyes already see,
Looking without looking within.
A testament of truth before, before our eyes.
The glory of a new-born child.
This place, where life's long path begins,
If they be princes, queens, or kings,
Laid helpless here at mother's side,
The glory of a new-born child.