RSG Release Team
Wait...
Later!
Careful, it'll get crumpled.
Just hold your arm straight.
And now...
Here are the candidates in the
talent portion of the competition.
And our first candidate for today is...
Arlina Delos Santos!
Excuse me...
Have a drink.
Don't be nervous.
Remember, just keep on going.
We're here to have fun.
Remember, it's what's inside
you that counts, okay?
Not your looks.
Alright.
Go for it!
Yes, Mommy.
Ma'am, my child is ready!
She'll join and sing now.
Just stay over there.
I'll call you when it's her turn.
Stop touching that! For crying out loud!
That gown cost me 2,000 pesos!
So, you better win.
Beat all those other kids!
And the next one to present her talent,
is candidate number 7.
She belongs to section Pussycat
under Miss Maglinao's kinder class.
She's 7 years old.
And her favorite subject is...
Wow! Math!
Here she is...
Maria Nathalia Bustamante Gascon.
Mommy's tummy was big and round!
What's that?! My brother Ojie pondered.
A ball? A basketball?
No, it's something else.
Maybe a little toy?
No, it's a bundle of joy.
What's inside, Mommy?
A surprise I offer.
The surprise turned out to be me!
How could the ball become a baby?
Mother breaks into joyous laughter.
When you grow a little older...
You will surely discover.
You taught her all that?
My goodness, that will never win!
Hurry up, they're lining up
for the graduation march.
What's wrong?
She wants to join the other kids now.
Finally! Then, hurry up.
Let's go, they're about to march.
How about you guys?
Hurry now!
You should have recited another piece.
Because you'll never win with that.
It's not a big deal if you don't make it.
This isn't about looks anyway.
Then why the heck join a beauty contest
if you're not being judged for your beauty?
Brother!
Give me that cap so I can finally graduate.
Here are the judges' decision
for our Miss Kindergarten contest...
Let's start with our special awards.
The judges have chosen the
Best in Costume and Miss Talent.
And the special award
for Best in Costume goes to...
Stop complaining.
From Section Elephant under Ms. Zenaida Mendoza...
Candidate number 1, Arlina Delos Santos.
And the Ms. Talent awardee comes from
Section Giraffe under Ms. Louie Cruz...
- Candidate number 4...
- That must be your lousy poem.
Erika Guevara!
And now ladies and gentlemen...
The winner of the much awaited Ms. Kinder award...
She comes from Section Pussycat.
I'm sure you already know who she is!
Candidate number 7.
Maria Nathalia Bustamante Gascon!
Okay! You did great!
Yes! Yes!
Give me that.
Believe it or not, Maya won by unanimous decision.
She really stood out among the other candidates.
- Ding, get the sauce for that.
- Sure, there's some over there.
I'll get the hotdogs.
Excuse me.
Mom, my friends.
Give them something to eat. Feel at home, okay?
Find a spot outside, okay?
Can you bring this outside for the kids?
Give me that.
- I'll take care of this.
- Okay.
As I was saying...
My mother and my brother's father got married.
Then they split up.
My gosh Maya, that's bad!
My mother says when God joins two people together,
no one can break them apart.
How did God get in the picture?
Because it's God who marries people.
That isn't true!
My mother and her husband
were married by a town mayor.
The mayor of Abucay. You can even ask my father.
Dad!
Mom and Ojie's father were married
by the mayor of Abucay right?
Maya!
I want to sponsor Maya in the
Johnson & Johnson's search for the
Prince and Princess of Manila 1998!
- This is a huge deal!
- There's no more ice cream, Mom!
- You'll get a lot of money!
- I already called the store.
- There's a cash prize!
- But that takes time!
- The ice cream will come!
- There's an educational plan!
So young and you're already spreading gossip.
But, I'm just telling the truth!
Still, there are things that
you can't tell other peope!
You must be ashamed!
Mommy said you shouldn't be ashamed of the truth.
What if you stole something,
won't you be ashamed of it?
Mommy said, you should never do what is shameful!
Ding!
Your mother's on the phone. She's raving mad.
Maya, be careful!
Let me continue...
For crying out loud, stop it!
So to continue my story...
- My mother and my brother's father split up.
- Hello, Ma?
After that...
my mother and my father...
became like this.
Married?
That can't be! She's already married.
Not married!
They're just real tight.
As my father's mother would say...
Married only in bed!
Maya!
Mother wants me to come home.
She's going out of town
to look for maids for her agency.
No one will be at the house.
Don't get mad.
Every single time my mother needs me,
you get mad.
I'm not angry! See?
That wasn't an angry face!
I'm actually really happy.
You get mad everytime she calls me.
That's not the point.
Your mother calling you doesn't make me angry.
I get angry because she's doing this to prove
that you're at her beck and call.
And I can't do anything about it
because we aren't married.
So...
What can you say?
I gotta go.
See you when I see you!
Well...
See yours when I see yours!
All the kids I know only have
one father even if they have 10 siblings!
Shouldn't it be that way, Mom?
Not always.
Sometimes, couples break up.
Especially if they fight all the time.
Did you and dad fight all the time?
The truth is...
Your father and I?
No!
Then why?
Because your father was offered a job in Surigao.
He was the senior technician
in a mining company.
I didn't go because I had a job here.
Was your job more important than my father?
I wanted to make something of myself, too.
I have my own dreams.
I don't get it.
It's easy, listen...
I'm your mother.
You love me very much.
But you wouldn't like it if I said to you:
"Ojie, you can only love me."
Or "Stop going to school."
Or "Ojie, you can't be with
your friends because I'd be alone."
Would you like that?
Of course not!
What about me?
Precisely! What about you?
It's the same with married people.
As much as they love each other...
they have to think of themselves, too.
Don't you love him anymore?
Fool!
Of course I do!
I love Raffy, your father.
I love Ding as well.
It's not easy to understand...
Because sometimes...
Sometimes, when...
It's just the way it is.
It's just how it is?
Do you understand now?
No, I still can't.
I was so shocked.
I froze in fear. I couldn't even move.
I could smell gasoline all over my body.
Then, he lit the match.
His eyes turned wild, like the devil himself.
He said to me,
"You thought, I couldn't do this?"
And that lit match...
He threw it at me!
My whole body went up in flames.
Until now, I still can't believe he did this to me.
I can't go with you.
There's no one with the children.
I asked my neighbor to keep an eye on them.
The woman called again.
The one who just keeps crying?
Yes, she's driving me crazy!
Are you alone?
No one lobbies in the Senate alone.
Everybody will be there.
What about Soledad Gatdula's case?
The migrant is now handling it.
They'll get the body repatriated.
Alright, I have to go.
See you when I see you!
Well...
What time did he arrive?
So, that means I can stay here a bit longer?
Your brother, is he home?
No, nevermind.
If I talk to your father,
he'd think I have a crush on him.
Alright darling, okay.
Hi.
Do you still remember me?
I'm back here in Manila.
How are you?
My brother told me you'd be here.
How's Ojie?
He's all grown up!
In fact, he's already circumcised.
I can't tell if he's a grown up or still my baby.
He's already courting girls
but sometimes he acts like a child.
You must have spoiled him.
A bit.
I let him have his way.
Can I see Ojie?
Why not?
When do you want to?
Tomorrow?
It's up to you. Where?
It's up to you.
What time?
Why don't...
you find yourself...
a spouse as well, Raffy?
It's been a long time since we were together.
I have.
It's been a year.
She's pregnant now.
I'll become a father again.
You must be happy, huh?
Mom, are you sure he's Ojie's father?
Why, of course!
Ding...
It's not like we're checking in a motel!
We aren't doing anything wrong.
Is that so?
Mom...
Will you still recognize Ojie's father?
Of course. Your mother's still in love with him!
Of course I do. He's my friend!
Just your friend? Mom, he's my father!
He's your husband!
Fool!
Mom's real husband is my father!
No way, silly! My father is mom's real husband!
Fine, they're both my husbands!
Two husbands?
Elizabeth Taylor had seven!
Hey!
You're not Elizabeth Taylor!
Oh, this isn't going anywhere.
Ojie, eat your dinner. You have to be up early.
I'll also have dinner now. I'm going with you.
Right! Go with them!
To be the chaperone!
Mom! Ojie's nervous.
He doesn't know what his father's like.
Hey! You're the one who's nervous.
You've nothing to worry about.
He's only Ojie's father!
Maya's afraid, my father won't
like her tagging along.
Mom, does he know you have another child?
Yes of course!
You told him?
Why not?
See? She told him!
Maya said my father might not like her
because she's not his daughter.
Ojie's asking if his father loves him,
how come he hasn't visited him before?
Poor Raffy, you both think ill of him!
You haven't even met him yet
and you're already judging the man.
Why don't you get to know him first?
Approve?
Approve!
Hi.
This is Ojie.
And this is Maya.
Ojie...
He's your father.
Hi.
How are you, really?
Are you happy?
Sometimes.
Sometimes? Why not always?
It's fine to be sad once in a while.
We should also feel sad sometimes.
So when you're happy, it's more meaningful.
In that sense, you are truly happy.
Did you come back
because you got tired of Surigao?
It's hard for Elinor.
What about your work?
When the baby comes, we'll go to America.
Really?
Yeah. New York.
You've always said you hated living in the city.
That you prefer living in a quiet town.
What will you do in New York?
No! Wait.
What I said was,
I wanted to experience different places.
Oh...
I'm sorry...
That things turned out this way for us.
Don't talk like that!
There's nothing wrong with our lives.
There's nothing to apologize for.
She shivered in fright.
The police were after us.
The women ran with their children.
My child couldn't move.
She shivered in fright.
Then -
- My father doesn't shout!
- He does too!
It's my father who doesn't shout!
What's going on!
How can you say your father doesn't shout?
You don't even know him.
I hate you! You're not my brother!
You love your father more than mine.
Of course, he's my father!
There's nothing you can do about it.
He's my father!
What's happening here?
Tell your children to shut up!
What's the problem?
He said you love his father more than mine.
Of course, he's her husband!
You're so pesky!
Wait, wait!
Hold on a minute!
I love them both, okay?
You can't love them both!
But, I do and I can't change that!
Besides, with love...
You don't divide love, you multiply it.
Maya, please, stop it!
Don't shout at the children!
Don't shout at my mom!
That's why she loves his dad more.
You should have seen them embrace.
They even kissed!
See? I told you!
That's right!
They were really sweet like newlyweds.
You're such a turncoat!
Do you even know what newlyweds look like?
Don't change the topic.
Did you kiss him?
You should know Maya...
Friends kiss each other, especially if they
haven't seen each other for a long time.
You just saw each other yesterday!
She's right!
We were still uncomfortable with each other then!
It's only today that we got to...
Do what?
Confess your love for each other?
Oh, please!
Not in front of the kids...
So what?
I thought there's nothing wrong with the truth?
We didn't do anything wrong. So stop accusing me!
You mean to say my daughter's a liar?
I never said that!
All I said was that's not the truth!
Ojie, are they fighting now?
We're okay now right?
Put something on.
You'll catch a cold again.
Hello?
Hi. Raffy!
Thank you.
Why didn't you bring your daughter?
That won't be a good idea.
She might ask to stay here.
I wonder what's taking Raffy so long.
I could have done the grocery myself.
Let him do it!
He's used to doing it anyway.
Really now?
He claims he just started learning.
My goodness, Raffy.
It always takes him forever
but all he ever buys are canned goods.
When we were together,
all we had were canned goods.
I didn't like to cook.
Really?
Didn't he tell you about it?
It's just, we never really got to talk about you.
I'll wait for Dad outside, Mom.
Sure.
I'll go out now.
This is hard for my son.
It'll be the first time he'll be away from home.
But this is his father's house.
That's what I mean.
It's his father's house...
but it's not his home.
The truth is...
Even his own father isn't quite his father.
My son's afraid you might not like him.
He might do something you won't like.
And if that were so,
he might...
He might lose the chance
to become close to his father.
Is that why you chose to bring him over,
instead of meeting Raffy somewhere else?
To see me personally?
To see whether I'm the type who beats children?
I'm his mother.
Mom, Dad's here!
- Hi!
- Sorry. It was so crowded at the supermarket.
Here, I bought a lot of stuff.
Where's Maya?
She's with her dad.
You should have brought her along.
Come on, let's eat.
No, don't bother!
I'm afraid I can't stay longer. I have to go to the office.
Bye!
Call me anytime you want.
Yes, Mom.
Elinor?
Don't worry about Ojie. He'll be fine here.
I'll see you to the door.
Take care, Mom.
Another one of our migrant workers
was raped and killed abroad.
What is the government doing about it?
Do they even know what's going on?
Mr. Ramos!
You may not be aware of it
but in Singapore
migrant domestic workers
are subjected to mandatory pregnancy tests.
There's also a process for abused women.
So they they can also be helped...
Do you realize Johnny...
Some men treat their penis like a gun?
No, really!
Because when they are mad at women...
they use their penis to threaten and intimidate.
Aren't I right?
Have you seen...
Did you watch the film, Full Metal Jacket?
There's a scene there where
there are soldiers marching.
And their chant goes like this:
This is my weapon.
This is my gun.
This is for business.
This is for fun!
You mean, they hold their thing...
Like this?
You know what?
I know this guy.
It's not a gun he likens his penis to.
Gold!
Who?
My ex-husband.
Back then...
Everytime he was mad at me,
he'd refuse to have sex with me.
He thinks his penis is a priceless commodity!
You're being emotional.
To think you've been separated for years now.
You must still be in love with him.
Of course not!
Then why are you still thinking about him?
That gold was precious.
Lea.
Sister, this is my daughter.
This is Maya? She's so pretty!
- How are you?
- Fine, sister.
And smart, too!
That woman who kept
calling us and crying is here.
Goodness! She's the wife of Sigmund Olivares.
Does his name ring a bell?
Sportsman?
Correct!
Sportsman, promoter, banker
and I don't know what else.
If you saw her, your heart will break.
She's severely battered and almost hysterical.
Now all she wants is never
to see the husband again.
I don't ever wanna see your face again.
You understand?
I'm leaving you for good Sigmund!
I'm here at the Women Crisis
and Survival Center now.
What is the address of this center?
I'm telling this bastard that
I don't want to ever go back to him.
Well not unless of course you still
wanna make a go of this marriage.
Stop it! You're going to fall.
Stop being so stubborn!
Stop it!
Maya, here it is! Give me just a minute!
I don't want to!
She's exhausted from tagging
along with you all day.
I don't understand why you
had to leave Ojie there!
You don't even care to know
what's happening to him!
Maya, stop it already.
You're giving me a headache!
I don't want to!
Do you know what time it is? It's 9PM!
The kid hasn't had dinner!
She should've eaten at 7!
Will you never stop?
I'm losing my patience here!
- Stop it!
- I don't want to!
Here! I'll make dinner.
You should have told me you'll be late!
I could have prepared something!
Then, she wouldn't be starving now!
Really, Maya you don't plan to stop?!
I'm really going to cover your mouth now!
I'll cook some eggs. How do you want them done?
You make so much noise! You can be a siren!
Did you hear me, Lea?!
What do I do with the eggs?!
Well damn it! Make them hatch!
How are you, Ojie?
What?
How are you?
Does your Uncle Ding treat you well?
Yeah.
Like you're his own son?
Yeah... sure.
You sound unconvinced...
No!
I mean... yes!
But...
But sometimes it's hard.
What do you mean?
Knowing that I'm not really his son.
Why?
You mean, there's a gap between you two?
You can't talk to him?
When it's just us.
When we're with other people,
I keep my distance.
Especially before.
Why?
Well...
Maybe because...
People might think that I'm his son.
What's wrong with that?
Once...
but this was a long time ago...
Someone asked him how I was related to Mom.
And he said, I was her nephew.
But I'm not angry, Dad.
Ding is nice to me.
He doesn't even scold me.
And I love Maya very much.
Even if she's only my half sister,
I won't exchange her for anything.
The smoke is making my eyes sting.
What is it?
Is there anything wrong?
Can we talk?
About my son?
What did you say?
You heard me, Lei.
I'm asking you if you'd consider
giving me the custody of Ojie.
We'll take him with us to America.
We won't be leaving until the baby comes though.
So you have an entire year to think about it.
Really now. It's nothing!
Of course I'm not angry!
He's your son as much as he is mine!
Don't worry about it.
I don't mind at all.
Besides, it's his decision anyway.
Do you want to tell him yourself?
Or do you want me to do it?
Ok...
No problem.
I'll do it for you.
Okay, see you around!
Bye!
It's nice to have your mother by your side.
She'll always be there
for you when things go wrong.
She'll be there to kiss your pains away.
On the other hand...
There are some things
that are better to ask a father.
Things that a father better understands.
You know what...
You'll go through feelings and experiences
that only a father can help you go through.
Ugly!
We're not asking you to choose between us, Ojie.
We're giving you the right
to make your own decision.
So, think about your answer well.
What's happening?
I don't understand you!
You've been crying for a month!
What's wrong!?
The teacher is right, Mrs. Gascon.
Your children should have the same family name
if you want to pay the PTA fee once.
What if they have different fathers?
Why?
Is your first husband dead?
No.
To whom are you married?
To no one.
Well how do I call you now?
Call me Lea.
That's what my children's fathers call me.
Mrs. De Lara...
Will you make up your mind?
What do you really want to call me?
Well I suggest that you transfer one
of your children to another school.
Why Ms. Bustamante?
So we can avoid a scandal!
That would be good for you and for your children.
Don't you go telling me
what's good for my children!
- Look Ms.-
- There's nothing wrong with my children!
Maybe there's something wrong with you!
- Listen to me-
- No you listen to me!
You want to expel one of my children?
Go ahead! Do it!
But know that DECS
and the courts will hear about it!
I will not allow you to discriminate
my children, Mrs. Zalamea.
And you'd better believe that.
Bye, Mom!
Dad!
What took you so long?
This is hard for me as well.
Everytime Raffy takes Ojie...
I feel sorry for my daughter.
She misses her brother.
Why not tell Raffy not to take Ojie so often?
How can I deny my son
the chance to be with his father?
It scares me sometimes, though.
Everytime Raffy takes Ojie...
I feel like I'm slowly losing my son.
Wow, we're talking serious, man!
I bet the next thing that'll come out
of your mouth will be pure rubbish!
Hello!
Johnny, you awake?
No, no... It's not an emergency.
It's about my son's school project...
A radio?
You called me up in the dead
of the night to ask about a radio?
You could have just bought one!
Why do you have to make one?
I said I'm sorry!
It's for my son's project!
What can I do if the project requires -
I'm back...
This time it's for real.
It gets more and more violent!
All because of these evaluations!
He's got all these creditors running after him.
I don't want to go back to him, ever!
I don't want to go back.
I don't ever want to go back
Ever!
Sister...
It's possible my mother may change her mind.
But not me.
I want out of this family!
For you...
Call Ojie.
Tell him I'm home.
He's not here.
What?
Mom...
I think I have to tell you this...
Ojie has been going out every night.
He has been skipping school
and he's always playing billiards.
What time it is? I'm running
out of luck and I'm hungry!
Who's turn is it?
Is it my turn? Alright! I'll finish this!
Do you know what gambling does to people's lives?
Once you get hooked, there's no turning back!
It'll ruin your life!
You'll destroy your life!
You don't have to shout at him!
I'm not talking to you!
But you always do what you want.
Why can't we?
I'm not doing anything wrong!
That's what you think!
But, you're wrong! You're wrong!
Ojie...
Ojie! Ojie!
Ojie!
Ojie...
Ojie! Ojie!
Ojie!
I'm sorry to bother you, Uncle Johnny.
It's okay.
I can't call my father because
Grandma will take it against Mom.
Because you see,
Ojie wasn't able to attend this Boy Scout thing...
because he had to bring a father along.
He tried to call his dad...
but he was away and didn't return his call.
He didn't want to ask my Dad
because he's not his father anyway.
So, he told his teacher that
he didn't want to join the Boy Scouts...
but that's not true because it's his dream.
You should have told me
about this Boy Scout ceremony.
Even if you're father isn't here...
I am.
I could have tied the Boy Scout
kerchief around your neck...
I can be a father too.
But please...
don't blame me for your father's shortcomings.
Don't take out on me things
I can't do anything about.
Mom...
Mom, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry too, son.
Hey! Close your eyes.
Don't peep!
I don't like cheating.
Hold on...
Okay...
Open your eyes!
Wow!
Is this ours, Mom?
It's all yours.
Just be careful. Be very very careful.
We'll try it out now!
Go ahead. Be careful though!
Let's play, Ojie!
I said be careful! Stay close!
So now, you say 'be careful'!
But you buy them a bike, knowing it's dangerous.
That's nothing but trouble!
Hey!
Not too fast!
Wow, you both got good grades.
Wow, Ojie! It's just the
1st quarter but look! An 80 and 85!
- Good!
- Mom, you must be mistaken.
Those must be my grades.
Yikes!
I became a De Lara!
Mom, mine's Gascon!
Yikes!
The different surnames of my children
must be quite confusing for you.
Well at this point...
I have already accepted your situation.
There.
One for each teacher.
Thank you.
You have to pay for those cards.
No not to me, to the cashier.
Ms. Bustamante,
you're going to meet
the teachers of your children.
Since you seem to have extra money,
you might want to make
a contribution for the dead.
There's nothing funny about a gruesome death, Ms. Bustamante.
He's the father of your daughter's classmate.
Their house was set on fire.
You didn't know that a fire
broke out near here last Saturday ?
Fire?
Yes, fire!
As in 'fire'.
The squatters' area was burned down.
Of course, no one will claim responsibility for it.
But if you know your history,
this has been going on for quite some time.
Especially when the government
wants to drive them away.
Soliman, the one who died, thought
one of his children was left inside.
He braved the fire and went back in.
But the fire already spread.
He couldn't get out anymore.
Now, Ms. Bustamante, tell me if that's funny.
I'm sorry.
You should be.
I wonder, why wasn't it featured in the papers?
Why?
Since when were poor people
like Soliman given importance?
Can you help me get some details like...
the number of families affected,
where have they been relocated,
and whether the government is doing anything.
What for?
To call the attention of the authorities...
The NGOs...
The proper government agencies.
Why?
Do you have any connections?
I work for a non-government agency.
Women in Crisis Center to be exact.
I never realized...
I know you don't.
I always thought that...
That, well...
That you were, you know...
A hospitality girl.
I can believe that.
When you say Women in Crisis Center,
do you mean victims of rape and domestic violence?
In particular, yes.
Everything that concerns women,
but in general anything that concerns human rights.
Well everything that concerns
human rights concerns women.
Of course.
Do you believe that violations on
human rights are still rampant in our country?
Of course, don't you?
I do! If I didn't,
I would not be concerned
for the welfare of the squatters.
In fact...
I have always been
a staunch supporter of militant groups.
Really?
Of course,
I don't join rallies since I'm a principal.
I have to keep a low profile.
But when my teachers went on strike...
I think I was the only principal
who refused to submit their names.
I see.
They weren't fired because
DECS never got their names.
And I am so proud of what I did.
You should be.
Well, it was nice meeting you Ms. Bustamante.
Call me Lea.
Whatever.
A rose, by any other name...
How does that saying go again?
Well Mr. Olivares, your wife may be willing
to go back to you, but not your daughter.
She already signed a statement with us saying that
she left your house over her own free will.
And we also use that to get a court order,
barring you from getting anywhere near her.
It's all my fault...
Yes!
She's now in our custody.
If you want to get her back,
you would have to fight us in court.
Thank you very much, Attorney.
Mrs. Cruz, thank you so much.
Thank you!
- I'll see them to their car.
- Alright, Johnny.
- Thank you again, Attorney.
- Okay!
Sister...
We have a fax from Baguio about the conference.
Oh, I almost forgot! Lea!
Lea, wait!
Do you think you can go?
Where?
A conference in Baguio. It'll only be for a day.
You and Johnny.
You'll like this. It's a natural color.
Okay. After that, give me a facial
and remove all my white heads.
Everytime you come here, you get the whole deal!
If I know, you have a date!
Is he your boyfriend yet?
Still a prospect. Ouch!
Maya...
Call your Grandma again.
Ask if your father's there.
Then tell your father to come home.
Right away, okay?
I have a date.
- How do I look?
- Great!
Medy, use the Greek Red okay?
Mom...
You want me to try grandma's house again?
You know Maya, by now, she's already on to you.
I bet she suspects that
you're calling your Dad for Mom.
The more she won't give him the phone.
What now, Mom?
Do you have a plan B?
You're okay right?
Behave yourselves. Don't fight, okay?
Maya, watch your mouth, don't talk a lot okay?
Sleep early tonight, I'll fetch you tomorrow.
But where are you taking us?
Leave it to me.
Mister, turn right over there.
Please, Elinor? It's an emergency.
If I don't make it,
my job is at stake. I'll get fired.
Okay... It's fine.
Ojie, Maya, get down. Hurry!
Your bags!
Hurry!
Go, kiss your Auntie Elinor.
- Hi, Auntie!
- Ojie, kiss your auntie!
Ojie...
Your father will be back shortly, Ojie.
Lea, come in!
Sorry, the cab's waiting.
I'm so sorry about this.
I'll pick them up tomorrow.
It's alright.
Thank you! And give Raffy my thanks.
Sure.
Bye now.
Behave yourselves, okay?
- Yes, Mom.
- Bye!
Mom?
Approve!
Sorry, I'm late! Let's go!
I'm not going.
I told...
Sister Ann to go instead.
I'll stay here in the office.
Oh! Lea you're here! Let's go!
Let's go! Let's go! They're waiting for us.
One more please. Have a sandwich, Lea.
No thanks. I lost my appetite.
My goodness!
Lea here has been grumpy
ever since we left Manila!
Right! Maybe she's in love!
I thought I would be able to,
you know, but turns out I won't!
Sister, can we talk?
What is it?
I have a question.
I'm curious. Don't you ever think about love?
What?
Love!
As in 'love'!
I'm not talking about love for God
or for your neighbors.
I'm talking about romantic love...
The love of a man for a woman
or a woman for a man.
The one that comes with sex and lust.
Jesus, Mary, and Joseph!
You see, even if you're a nun,
you're still a human being.
Priests are also human beings.
Look at Father Ignacio.
Doesn't he have a mistress?
Really now, Lea!
You're being crazy!
You're cursing, Sister!
You're even making me sin!
Why make things that are
natural to humans immoral?
It's only natural to be sad.
It's natural to want a man.
When I'm sad, I become more
conscious of the men around me.
The only man I don't even
bother considering is my father.
Jesus, Mary, Joseph! What's with you?
Watch some porn and you'll see what I mean.
Just don't let feminism get in the way.
My goodness! It's like heaven on earth, Sister!
Stop it! What's your problem?
I don't have a problem! I'm merely stating facts.
I'm just saying that if you watch porn,
even Father Peter will look attractive to you.
Who's Father Peter?
I don't know a Father Peter.
You do!
Father Peter Meter!
Do we all fit in the picture?
I set it already, just take the picture.
Take your places!
One more! One more!
One more!
Thank you!
What do we do next?
Let's shop!
We're going to buy a broom.
Let's visit the Grotto first.
The Grotto again?
After the Grotto, then we buy your broom...
Mister, my broom...
Thank you!
Ding!
Damn it!
What took you so long?
Where have you been?
- But you-
- What were you thinking?
You even dragged my child into this?!
Your husband has been calling!
His wife already gave birth!
Hi!
Is it a boy or a girl?
Let's go outside.
Who gave you the right to leave
your children with my wife?
You knew she was pregnant right?
You knew that right?!
Damn it!
Look at me!
I've been worrying about a pregnant wife
and I still had to tend to two children!
You didn't even care to think
that she could give birth anytime!
You should quit your job
so you can look after your children!
Do you understand what you're saying?
I'll support my son!
Then do it!
It's your responsibility anyway!
But even then, you have no right
to tell me what to do!
I didn't leave my job for you then,
what makes you think I'll do it now?
That's why I'm talking to you now!
I'm through with this conversation!
I don't want to talk about this anymore!
We're done talking.
Mom, was it cold in Baguio?
When are you taking us there?
We'll plan it.
Look, I brought you these...
- That's mine!
- Wait! This is better!
Wait, don't fight! Here's a doll for you.
Wow, a doll!
We have peanut brittle!
- I want some!
- Just eat it tomorrow!
There are strawberries as well.
This food is delicious as well!
Mom, you should have brought
something for Ojie's baby brother, too.
I didn't think she would give birth already.
Mom...
Ojie's dad said the baby looks like Ojie.
But, the baby looks weird!
It looks like an old baby full of wrinkles.
Silly, all babies look that way.
Right. But in a week or two,
he'll become a handsome baby.
Mom, is he also my brother?
Of course not!
But he can be if you want.
Auntie Elinor said I could make him my brother.
You know, Mommy, I slept beside Auntie Elinor.
She let me feel the baby in her stomach.
We told each other lots and
lots of stories the whole day.
Mom, please bring me there again.
I don't really like staying in your office.
Auntie Elinor said I'm welcome
to go there, even every Saturday.
The information should be complete
before you submit it to me, okay?
Sister?
What is it this time?
Can I take a day off tomorrow?
It's Saturday, anyway.
Press this.
It's working!
Really?
Yes!
Hi!
Wow!
Thank you, Maya!
Isn't he handsome?
Thank you...
I'm should be more thankful.
Thank you, too.
Chubby little baby!
Chubby boy!
You're hungry aren't you?
Time for milk!
Yes, it's time for milk now!
Okay, time for milk!
Be careful, you might drop him!
Don't worry. I'm used to taking care of babies.
I used to volunteer at an orphanage.
Really?
It's part of our school curriculum.
Lea!
Lea...
Lea, your neighbor called.
Your children had an accident!
Ojie...
Maya...
Are they cousins?
No, they are siblings.
Ding...
This is Raffy.
Raffy, this is Ding.
They're the fathers.
Damn it!
Okay nurse, thank you.
What really happened?
Now you're asking.
After giving priority
to your job over your children.
I'll just be outside.
You know, you're just perfect.
Even in front of other people!
You, where were you?
With your mother!
Who bought the bike, was it me?
I'm talking to you!
Lea, wait!
Lea! Don't turn away when I'm talking to you.
Can't we talk decently?
The kids already met an accident!
They shouldn't be left by themselves.
I can always take Maya to my mother.
But you won't allow it!
Don't gang up on my mother!
Why did you stand up? Come here.
Do you have anything more to say?
Don't give me that attitude.
You've been on my case since a few nights ago.
I haven't forgotten.
You were all 'No, Lea this' and "No, Lea that'.
You're so kind to your wife!
But when I was your wife, you didn't even
bring me to the hospital when I gave birth to your son!
What are you talking about?!
Who didn't bring you to the hospital?
Don't accuse me of something I didn't do!
Lea, you're really stupid!
It was me! I didn't bring you to the hospital.
Right, I am stupid!
I'm stupid! I'm stupid!
That's why I have you as husbands!
- Hey, Lea we're in a hospital, stop shouting!
- Hey! Don't you walk out on me!
Wait! Lea!
Since you're such good fathers...
go ahead and take care of your own children!
If you go, I'll take Maya to my mother's!
I'll bring Ojie home!
Go ahead!
To hell with you both! You can each have yours!
One...
Two!
Go to hell!
Lea are you okay?
It really bugs me.
When two women with the same
man come face to face ...
They claw at each other.
If they don't, it doesn't feel right.
When my two perfect husbands met ...
instead of clubbing each other,
sthey ganged up on me?
I just don't get it.
Be quiet!
I'm not kidding.
I mean, they hit off like brothers.
It's true I promise! I really don't get it!
Because men are decent.
Civilized, my ass! That wasn't decent!
Hey, shut up!
Let's get out of here.
I don't know who is afraid of who.
Okay, okay!
This is dragging on for too long...
One thing I don't get...
Doesn't it bother Ding that I
used to have sex with Raffy then?
Or does it bother Raffy that it's
Ding I have sex with now?
Damn it, Lea...
You know what? I bet you...
They must have been lovers in their past lives!
Well then let them be!
Let them have sex!
My goodness, Lea there are other people around
and we're talking about sex!
I want to do it.
You really are crazy!
This is still half-full.
If a woman admits that she wants to have sex
does it make her a whore?
Of course not!
But then again...
A whore doesn't really find real pleasure in it.
How could she, when most men...
are all about hands or all about penises?
When I watch pornos on the VHS...
I can't get that thought out of my mind.
I find myself wishing...
I wish that when two people connect with their bodies,
they also connect with each other's soul.
I wish that when a man thrusts into a woman,
he reaches the real core of her being.
That men may touch the
secret recesses of women's minds...
That he hears the words we don't utter.
Sometimes...
I cannot help but think...
In the thousand times that
I made love to Raffy or Ding...
They failed to touch my soul.
In my nakedness...
I wish they realized...
That from head to toe...
I am a mother!
Damn it, Johnny!
Damn them!
I'm not a bad person.
I'm not a bad mother!
Happy New Year!
This is all cheese, okay?
The table is ready.
Ojie, Maya, it's time to eat! Wash your hands.
Dad said he would be back by Christmas.
It's only January.
You'll have to wait for December!
But where is your husband by the way?
The last time Mom saw him was All Saints' Day.
I think I'll be seeing him on Valentine's day.
Come on, let's eat!
What do you want darling? Sister?
Here, Jinky.
That's my classmate.
How do you know?
She called earlier. I told her to just call me again.
I didn't want to cry then.
It's not a good way to start the New Year.
Why?
Mom, remember my classmate?
The one whose father died in the fire?
The one with eight children?
What about them?
Elizabeth, our classmate, said that
the mother of our classmate just died.
She killed herself.
Hello?
Oh, Elizabeth! What is it?
By the way...
Here's a gift for you.
From me and the children.
Just put it there.
Where's Maya?
Asleep. Do you want me to wake her up?
No, I won't be staying long.
I just wanted to talk to you.
Let's sit down, okay?
I know I've been away for a long time.
It's okay.
There'll be other Christmases.
I want to explain...
I don't want a fight.
It all depends on you.
I want to work on our relationship.
I even made a list of New Year's resolutions.
It's over between us.
There's someone else.
It's been going on for quite some time now.
I just couldn't tell you.
And it has reached the point
where I have to marry her.
When will the wedding be?
It's done.
Last Christmas.
Did you hear what I just said?
Lea...
I won't be sleeping here anymore.
Of course.
You can't possibly...
Have sex here...
- and have sex there...
- Curse your foul mouth!
Damn you too! What do you call it then?
Fucking, screwing, sex...
It's all the same!
You're just ashamed to say it.
You're so ashamed...
That your wife,
had been another man's wife.
- That's not true!
- Yes, it is!
Go upstairs!
You don't like to hear the truth
because you can't defend it.
That I'm a mistress.
And you're the other man.
Damn it!
What we had was not just a fling!
But to you,
This was just that.
Two people screwing around.
If not...
Then why didn't you protect what we had?
How about me?
For even just a little bit...
Why didn't you ever defend me?
At the very least,
You could have given me another chance...
Even just the smallest chance...
to defend myself.
He's my father!
No one is taking your father away from you.
No one can take anybody away from anyone
because people don't own other people.
That's why everyone is given his own mind
so he can make his own decisions.
What will you do now?
Nothing.
I'll just have to accept it.
That's life.
Hard...
But you can do something about it.
Her father wants to get Maya.
Are you going to give her up?
Her father wants to get her.
Your father wants to get you.
You make your own decision!
Why don't you make the decision?
You're the mother!
Because it's your life!
You should help us!
This is not like homework where
I can help you with the answers.
You can do it!
I've been through it too.
Tell her to help us think.
Mom, please help us out!
What if we go with them and then
later on we want to go home to you?
I'll always be here, Maya.
Even if you go with your fathers,
I'll always be your mother.
Lea, put him in the car.
Hold her. I'll go find the other kids.
The problems of this family never seem to end.
Two girls were brought to their relatives.
I heard that they're being molested by their uncle.
I told you that yesterday. They're over there.
Let's go children!
We're going to bring the children now?
Yes, no one is going to feed them here.
My children!
Get in the car!
Lea, I just got a call from the center.
Go straight to the hospital after this.
The child who was raped by her father
had a nervous breakdown.
Take care of it, okay?
I told you, even if they have no father,
as long as you're there to be their mother.
You shouldn't have left them!
Children can do without their father
but not without their mother.
There! That is our stage.
See! It's not overwhelming at all.
What I want to know is how I
can best introduce you.
Lea Bustamante will do.
I hope you don't mind.
You could have given the children your surname.
You're single, you can do that.
The truth is, I'm married to Ojie's father.
In Maya's case,
I wanted her to have a name.
Although a woman never has a name of her own.
She assumes the name of her father or her husband.
But if you will give Maya your name,
at least this time, her name will come from you.
And then,
she can tell the world that
her name is that of her mother's.
And you as well!
You can tell the world that
your daughter has your name.
Although no matter whose name a woman carries...
It is she alone who creates her own identity.
Because only she will make her
own mark in the world.
Well?
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Happy Women's Day my friend.
Happy Women's Day.
Your Aunt Aileen is nice.
She'll be like your own mother.
Your grandma also misses you a lot.
She hasn't seen you in a long time.
Tell her she can visit me anytime.
It's no problem.
That's why I want you to stay with us.
I miss you already!
But I can't leave my mother.
I have only one mother.
You have only one father, too! Me!
Dad, I can't leave Mom
for all the grandmas in the world.
And come to think of it,
I don't even like grandma.
What if you won't see me anymore?
No problem.
I have a lot of your pictures anyway!
You're so hard to talk to.
You can get mad at me if you want to.
I still won't leave my mom.
She's my mother!
No, Dad. It's not because
no one will take care of her.
Mom has lots of friends.
And besides, that's not the reason.
It's just that I don't want
to lose my mom nor my sister.
Are you angry?
No, I'm not.
You understand, right?
I really like Auntie Elinor.
But she's not my mother.
The problem is solved, Mom.
We already told both our fathers.
We won't go with them.
We won't exchange you for anything in this world.
Happy Women's Day, Mom.
We love you very much.
Do you regret anything about your life?
Me? About you and Ding?
Without you, I won't have my children.
Do you still love Ding?
You also want to ask whether
I still love you, right?
My answer is yes. I love you and I love him...
It's not that easy to understand
but it's the way it is.
If you love me, why did we end up like this?
Why didn't you come with me when I had to leave?
Why did you leave when I couldn't go with you?
Because we are two independent people...
Who wanted to do different things.
I lost you.
But if I clung on to you...
I would have lost myself.
How can you live with someone
who has lost her identity?
She'll never make a good wife.
Why did you ask me out?
No reason.
To say goodbye. Elinor and I are leaving.
Take care of the children, Lei.
And yourself too.
Are you happy, Raf?
Sometimes.
Do you understand, Raf?
That I won't ever be sorry
for anything in my life?
Not to you and not to anyone.
There's nothing to be sorry for.
Can you lend me just one more day of your life?
Let's give each other just one more day.
What will we do?
Anything!
Let's go to the places where we used to go...
Eat the food we used to share...
Drink from a single glass...
Swap stories, laugh together...
Dream and make memories.
Please, Raf?
Let's be crazy even just for a day!
Thank you.
I can't think of anything to say.
I can only think that not too long ago,
when Ojie was younger...
He was asking me how babies are made.
He stopped asking me that question.
Perhaps he has learned the answer.
Now you know the answer, Ojie!
But then, that question can easily be answered.
What's harder to answer...
Is how can children grow up
to become decent human beings.
For if every child were molded in such a way,
then we would have a just
and decent society by now.
One that we can proudly pass on to you.
But we are still trying hard to achieve this.
Anything that can be done
to prepare a better future for you.
Many of us try to make a better world for you.
For all of us!
To all of you, parents and children alike...
May you have a wonderful journey
of reaching for the stars!