Invitation.
What's this?
It's not an invitation.
It's an arrest
warrant for your boss.
Excuse me.
Wrong invitation.
Before you do
anything stupid...
Like this?
Yeah.
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
What's going on here?
You come here and
interrupt my son's wedding.
I've killed for less.
I know.
You're a hard man
to find, Rasto.
It's Mr. Boranovic.
We just missed each other
three years ago in Berlin.
You looked right at me in
Caracas in '09, remember that?
Doesn't matter now.
You're the Interpol man.
MI6, actually, but yes.
You have no authority
to arrest me here.
You're right, I don't.
But they do.
In my country, I'm a hero.
They will not extradite me.
They already have.
20 minutes from now,
you'll be on a plane
heading to The Hague.
You really want a bloodbath
at your son's wedding,
Mr. Boranovic?
Get him out of here.
I'll be home in a week.
- One week!
- We'll see.
Hey, man.
Jesus, Jake,
- what are you doin'?
- Dad, I, I'm sorry.
I forgot, okay, I was out...
Jake, you were
supposed to take
your medicine four
hours ago, man.
I know, I'm sorry.
I just forgot.
Stop apologizing to me, okay?
It's not about me.
It never has been.
We've been through this.
Okay, just, just listen
to me for a second.
Understand this,
you can do whatever
you want in this life, okay?
Whatever it is you want, but
the one thing that you can
never, ever do is forget
to take your medicine.
You with me?
Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
- Yeah.
I'm sorry, man, I just...
I, I'm sorry.
I just forgot, Dad.
It's okay.
You hungry?
You want something
to eat, maybe?
Uh, I was actually
gonna go shoot
the bow for a little bit.
If you want, come out
and shoot it with me?
Sounds good.
I'll join you out there
in a little bit, okay?
Hey.
Hey!
How many times I tell
you not to sit in my chair?
You know, the bathroom
floor needs cleanin'.
Damn kid.
Hey, baby, it's me.
Oh, my God,
I've been so worried.
How did it go?
Everything went fine.
You know how they are.
They like to kick
and scream more than
they actually like to fight.
Nolan, this guy's
not your normal suspect.
You said, what?
He's already killed
three witnesses?
You don't need to
worry about that.
Of course I'm
gonna worry about it.
Well, we got a great case
and good news is we finally
have him in custody.
He's landed four hours ago.
Oh, great, we
can't wait to see you.
Nolan?
- Nolan?
- Look, honey I'm so sorry.
There's nothing I
can do about this,
but I have to fly to the
States before I come home.
You've been gone a
month trying to find this guy.
I know.
One more piece of evidence.
Gotta get it tied up
before Boranovic sees
the judge Monday
morning, that's all.
You told Shelly
you'd be home already.
And I thought I would be.
Look, I'll call her
after school, okay?
Baby, 20 years.
You've done your part.
Someone else can
take it from here.
Emma, we've already
spoken about this.
Nolan.
It's just the things
I've seen this man do.
I know, I know.
No, you don't, baby.
No, you don't, you haven't
seen the things I've seen.
And I'm not about to let our
daughter grow up in world
where men like this walk free.
Certainly not while I can
do something about it.
Do what you gotta do.
We miss you is all.
I miss you, too.
I'll be home in
a couple of days.
Yeah.
Now, please try
not to worry, okay?
Dangerous part's over now.
I love you.
You too.
I go to court in one
week, and as we speak,
there's an agent en route
collecting evidence.
Hello?
Yes, get it done in a week,
and I'll pay you double.
And if you don't,
you'll get nothing.
Yes, completely dissolved.
No body, no blood, no trace.
Like they never existed.
Okay, so
what do you say?
40, 50?
Like, all right, 50.
- Yeah.
- Copy.
- Yeah, I like that.
- Okay, it's a lock.
- Hey, Jake.
- Hey.
Uh, check this out.
New arrowheads.
Just became regulation.
Where'd you get these?
Wait a minute, is
this the charge
that went on my credit card?
I, I, I didn't
think you'd mind.
Oh, come on, Jake.
What're you thinkin', man?
Dad, they increased
lethality, okay?
So you don't have to go chasing
a blood trail through the woods.
Does it change the flight?
Website says no.
Well, it doesn't matter, okay?
You still should
have come to me.
It's a little irresponsible,
don't you think?
He asked me first.
Oh, did he?
I told him it was okay.
My credit card's
maxed out this month.
Okay, fine, but you still
should have come to me.
- I mean...
- Dad.
Hey, it's a little excessive,
don't you think, guys?
- Come on.
- He knows what he's doing.
I, I just wanted it to be a
surprise for our trip, okay?
Oh, it's a surprise all right.
Hey, let him do something
nice for his father.
He can work off the
money later, right?
Yes, I'll work it off.
Frank, just relax.
- We're on vacation.
- Okay.
This is the summer house.
You live for the
summer house, right?
- Yes.
- Just relax.
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Okay, it's fine.
We'll use it.
It's no problem, we'll use it.
But just talk to me next time.
Just talk to me.
I'm gonna get my guard.
Okay.
Mm, because that's
so easy, right?
Listen.
He loves you.
- You know that.
- I know.
He's just been on high
alert since you arrived.
It's all he knows how to do.
He can't help it.
Thanks for covering for me.
You really should
have asked first.
I know.
Let me see that.
It's pretty cool.
Yeah, it's
pretty badass, right?
Hey, Daddy, watch me.
It's okay, it's not bad.
Try again.
Compensate for the wind.
Reference the trees,
it helps a lot.
Listen, I'm thinking
your kill shot's
still around 40 yards, but I
wanna know how you're gonna
do with a still shot, okay?
How can you do holding
and waiting for the prey
to show its perfect face, okay?
- Okay.
- Try it, let's see it.
I want you to hold.
Okay, hold.
Release.
Not bad at all.
Not bad at all, Jake.
Give me a look at that?
Still got a long way
to catch the old man.
Keep at it, you're looking good.
- Yeah.
- Okay, keep at it.
Fuck!
Excuse me, you know
where I can find...
No, no, just the bags.
What do you mean?
This year we're
goin' full survival.
Gonna eat what we catch.
We're gonna cook it on a spit,
gonna hang the meat up overnight
so the bears don't eat it.
We're gonna boil
the water we find.
We're goin' old school, pal.
Except sleep in a bag.
That's right, Jake.
It does get a little cold
out there, doesn't it?
Drop that.
Cool.
Yeah, cool.
Okay.
Get rid of that, lock
this up, we gotta pick up
the ATVs on the way.
Okay.
- Hey.
- Hey, almost ready?
Yeah, we're good.
Have so much fun.
Be safe.
Bring me something awesome.
Take care of my baby.
- I love you.
- So long.
- Okay.
- See you.
- Okay, bye.
You, have fun.
- I will.
- Be safe.
Okay.
Take care of each other.
I'll take care of myself.
Be good.
All right.
Don't have too much fun
here without us, though.
All right.
Do you like it, Daddy?
He didn't even finish
dumpin' the trash.
He didn't lock up.
He didn't call, nothin'.
It was like he vanished.
Think Boranovic
tracked him down?
Look, I think we
have a problem here.
First kid has disappeared.
That tracks.
Interpol got a call from
the adoption agency.
They've uncovered a hack.
When?
A few days ago.
Forensics tracked the activity.
They only took one file.
The John Doe on
the Boranovic boys.
Well, how did they
even know where to look?
No idea.
But they're not
new to cybercrime.
If it was them, Rasto knows
everything now including
the names and location
of both offspring.
Got it.
Look, we're done here.
We have an open
case, I mean shouldn't we...
Look, Rasto is
extremely selective.
He's used the same
worker for years.
He's a ghost.
If this isn't him,
locals can handle it.
But if it is, then
the boy's long gone.
Nothing more we can do here.
We need to go find Jake Kimber.
Can I help?
Oh, oh, I'm good.
Really?
Um, no, I'm good.
Thank you.
I don't mind.
I got it.
I'm tryin' to find my way
back to the, uh, the highway.
Just go back the
way that you came.
What kind of logger
gets lost in the woods?
Guess I just
got turned around.
Look at me.
I don't have to hurt you.
Down.
Damn it.
At the cabin this
week for the annual
hunting trip with my dad.
I'm gonna link the map
down in the description
so you guys can check it out.
And I got a new bow, which
I'm hoping to christen with
a beautiful 12 point.
And it's not rifle season,
so me and my dad are gonna be
the only ones out there.
It's gonna be pretty amazing.
Seems like we should've
brought horses instead.
Well, I didn't
wanna overwhelm you.
Wouldn't bother me.
I'd hunt horseback,
Indian style.
Yeah, well, before
the Spanish came,
the Natives did hunt on foot.
So, we already are, then?
One of us is.
They didn't have little
wheels on their bows.
Okay, okay.
Okay, man, listen up.
I don't think this path takes us
all the way down to
the valley floor.
So, we'll take this one till
it ends, dump the quads,
and continue on foot.
- Sound good to you?
- Yep.
- We locked?
- Yeah.
You have the key?
- Yep.
- Cool.
Sweet.
Here comes the cops.
June, we are 10-eight
at the Kimber property.
And be advised, our federal
friends are already on scene.
Don't let 'em
push you around, Sheriff.
But be nice.
I'm always nice.
That woman.
Gentlemen.
They're weekenders.
A couple o' weeks during
the summers, mostly.
They're fine enough
people, yeah.
Truck's gone.
But Frank and his son
plan a big hunting trip
every year about this time, so.
And what about the car?
That belong to the wife?
Yeah.
Maybe she's out with
friends, who knows?
Well, maybe you
can help us find her?
We thank you for
your assistance.
Yeah, well, when the FBI
tells you to do somethin',
I guess you do it, huh?
Hell, even if they are foreign.
You think you might be able
to help us get inside, Sheriff?
Why, hell, I
don't know how y'all
do it in Her Majesty's domain.
Over here, on this
side of the pond,
ownership's 9/10ths of the law.
We cannot barge into
the house without
a duly executed warrant
and you know that.
When lives are in danger...
I believe that's
reasonable grounds.
No matter where you are.
- Yeah.
- Sir.
Yeah, yeah.
Now tell me, what reason
might that be, son?
That's
on a need-to-know.
It's my county.
Jesus Christ.
Gray, you hear
what I just said?
- I did.
- Oh, hell.
Doctrine of
Plainview, Sheriff.
We are within our rights.
Aw, hell.
Hey, asshole, when my
father's talkin', you listen!
Take it easy, boy.
Oh, Christ almighty.
Don't say a word.
Oh, yeah.
No, yeah.
No, boy.
What the hell you doin', huh?
- I told you to stay with me.
- Gray.
You'll screw
up this crime scene.
By the time they're done
here, that kid'll be long dead.
Bureau forensics will
be here in an hour.
For 20 years.
I'll be damned if my office
is gonna mess this up.
Okay, good.
Look, keep an eye on
these guys, will you?
I'm gonna take a look around.
Jake Kimber had a
Facebook page deleted today
after he and his father
left to go hunting.
Hey and one more thing.
The kid's a hemophiliac.
Well, that
doesn't make this any easier.
No, Sheriff?
Mr. Gray.
I am going to apologize to you.
I didn't take your word.
No harm done, Sheriff.
We're on the same team, anyway.
Besides, I think this guy,
he's been one step ahead
of all of us, anyway.
Yeah, well, I decided
to call the pro shop.
Frank, he took out
an archery permit.
He didn't list
where he was goin'.
You think they're still alive?
Truthfully, I don't know.
But I hope so.
I've been
waitin' a long time
to come back up here, Jake.
I mean, this is,
this is awesome.
Yeah.
Wow, I mean.
Hey, that looks like a good
spot for base camp, yeah?
Yeah.
- You bedding there?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Looks soft.
I'll park it here,
we got our fire.
Good.
I mean, this thing's
gonna come in so handy.
Glad you picked
that thing up, right?
I remember how excited you
were when we bought that.
Get the rocks and don't tell Ma.
Okay.
No one really seems
to listen, though.
Oh, God, gorgeous, isn't it?
Come on,
what're you doin'?
You think you're
in college already?
Let's move.
Your snoring
kept me up all night.
That was the plan.
So, today we're gonna
lighten up the load,
just take one backpack.
You good?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, last one.
We better bag a buck,
or we'll be eatin'
dandelions all day.
- Do me a favor?
- Mm hm?
Put the ammo in yours?
Good.
Oh, no, no.
Allow me.
I'd feel bad if I didn't
shoulder the burden.
And I'd feel
bad if you didn't.
Hey, you hear that?
What?
It sounds like another engine.
Well, it's not rifle season,
and a little too far out for
someone to be takin' a joyride.
Let's orange up just in case.
All right.
And it's not rifle season,
so me and my dad are gonna be
the only ones out there.
It's gonna be pretty amazing.
So, Sheriff, I'm
assuming a helicopter won't
be a problem for you.
Search and rescue
get us up there?
Oh, Christ.
My only chopper's on loan,
fightin' them damn fires in Utah.
What are my options?
I camped up there before.
We're gonna need ATVs, four
by fours and whatever...
Yeah, how long
to get up there?
Two hours.
Fuck.
Well, I'm sorry to
rain on your parade,
but I just think we
- can't just go up there...
- This isn't about rain on
a fucking parade, kid.
This is about saving
lives, you hear me?
Frank and Jake Kimber.
We don't find them by nightfall,
I can guarantee you
they'll be dead and buried.
Who's this fella who's
huntin' 'em, anyway?
He's a monster.
Son, you wanna
give us a minute?
He can get you to the trailhead.
Look, I know he's
green behind the ears.
Yeah, and that's exactly
why he's not coming.
He knows this valley
as good as anyone.
He can put you right
down on top of 'em.
Look, he is my son, and
I think he needs this.
He stands in my
way for one second,
I'll leave him where he stands.
I can respect that.
All right, I'm gonna stay here.
I'm gonna try and rustle
up some eyes in the sky,
get some resources together.
I'm gonna see you in the valley.
Thank you.
Gray?
You take care of my boy, huh?
That's Frank Kimber's truck.
You know who
this one belongs to?
I don't know that one.
You wanna run a
plate check on it?
Yeah, it
won't take a minute.
Gray, take a look at this.
Hey, look.
Tracks.
They had three sets.
Run a search for a stolen ATV?
That we could do.
It's just gonna tell us
who he killed to get it.
There's nothin'
on the truck itself.
But the registered
owner's wife filed
a missing person two days ago.
And apparently
ain't found him yet.
They're not going to.
Deputy, you know this
area pretty well, huh?
Yeah.
There's a steep
climb into the valley
and that's the only trail in.
But we could hike around
the ridge and flank 'em.
It's a good idea.
So, what's the visual on
the valley from up there?
Well, I brought my drone.
I'm kind of a hobbyist, but, uh,
I think I could probably go pro.
Looks like he
trashed their ATVs.
Good news, it means
he's still here.
Mean's he hasn't killed 'em yet.
Why would they leave the quads
so far from the valley floor?
There's no trails down there,
and it's just too rugged.
Plus, the engines
scare off the prey.
So, what's the flight
time of this thing?
About 20 minutes?
Maybe?
Well, I guess we'll find out.
So, which way
you wanna hunt, Jake?
I think I'm gonna go that way.
Okay, good.
What do you mean, good?
Obviously, you didn't
see the deer tracks
headin' off in that direction.
But, hey, if you wanna
go down that way,
be my guest, but you
might starve to death.
I'm gonna go this way.
Gunshot, gunshot.
What was that?
Jesus, Jake, somebody's
shootin' at us.
Jesus Christ.
Hey!
Stop shooting!
There are people down here!
Ah, god damn you!
- Shit!
- Hunters down here
for Christ's sake!
If somebody makes a
mistake like that,
they're supposed to
identify themselves
and come down to make sure
that nobody's injured.
Doesn't make any sense.
Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Have you been hit?
- No, no, no.
- Are you sure?
Yeah, just, it scared me.
Okay.
Jesus!
What the.
Something's wrong.
Oh, God.
Okay, someone is
definitely shooting at us.
So, ditch those,
but hold onto 'em.
We might need them
later on, okay?
Okay, okay.
Seems to me this guy's
at least 600 yards away.
- The gun, the gun.
- Jake, come back here!
Jesus Christ,
what are you doing?
I'm fine, I'm fine,
we need the gun.
Just take the gun.
Here, here.
- Dad.
- Yeah?
Oh, Jesus.
Oh, God.
Damn it.
Okay, that means we better
be back to base camp
- within 24 hours, am I right?
- Yeah, 24 hours.
Okay.
Right now, we gotta
make it to the water.
- Okay.
- It'll lead us back to camp.
Stay low, hug the rocks.
Let's move.
Watch your step here.
Let's take five.
You okay?
Look, he could be chasing us.
We should, we should either
go through the water,
or find a place
somewhere down here
to hide and wait for him.
I don't know, Jake,
neither one sounds
like a good idea to me.
We're too exposed in the water.
We'd have to draw him real
close to be of any effect.
Jesus, what is that?
You hear that?
Yeah.
Yeah, it sounds
like, it's a drone!
Jesus,
you think it's his?
I mean, it seems like we
would have heard it before.
Could it be someone else?
Is it a search party?
Why would anyone
be searching for us?
Well, it's either him
or it's someone else,
but if it's someone
else, we're gonna miss
our chance at being seen.
Okay, let's just stay
behind the rocks for now.
There you go.
Come on, you see that?
Can you see that?
There, right
there, you see him?
Come on.
Jesus, he just shot it down.
Well, that proves
it's not his.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck, you hit?
No, I don't, I don't think so.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck, we gotta go.
Move, stay low, stay low.
Down, down, move, move!
Move!
There's somebody
flying that thing, right?
Where's the closest
ridgeline, Jake?
Uh, closest
ridgeline's that way.
Can you make it?
- Yeah.
- You good?
- Be careful, let's go.
Come on, come on.
Oh, shit.
Oh, fuck.
Okay, we still have the
radio in the truck, right?
Okay, get back there.
Tell your father we
need backup right now.
If I can't make it
back to the truck,
you're out here alone.
You know what we're
up against, right?
Okay.
We better get to the Kimbers.
Stay with me.
Frank Kimber!
We're not here to hurt you.
Then step out
and show me your hands!
We're not the ones
shooting at you.
But he's not far behind us.
Who the hell are you?
We're stepping out.
Don't shoot.
Keep your hands up, Deputy.
Stay.
Easy, easy.
It's okay.
Okay, who are you
and what's goin' on?
Now, you know the
deputy here, huh?
Yeah.
My name's Nolan Gray
from British Intelligence.
I'm here to protect you both.
We've already lost
one of our team,
Agent Butler from the FBI.
There's information, sir,
you don't know
about your son here.
You are both in grave danger,
more than you could
possibly imagine.
I need to know
what's goin' on.
And I'm happy to tell you.
On the move.
We need to leave right now.
Son.
Do we have a choice?
Please.
Okay, okay.
Deputy, lead the way.
- It's a climb.
- Stay close.
But this is the only way out.
Come on, double time.
During the civil
wars of Yugoslavia,
there were war lords who operated
their own private armies.
One of these men operated on
a particularly brutal scale.
He was called The Tiger.
Many of that war's
worst massacres
were carried out by his men.
He would cleanse entire
villages of anyone
he would consider inferior;
Croats, Bosniaks,
Jews, Kosovars.
Kill the men and use their
women as his personal toys.
Slaves to abuse as he pleased.
There's no telling how many
women and girls he assaulted.
He kept them until he
was bored with them
or until they became pregnant.
Paperwork said
Jake's mother and father
were killed in the war.
That's because some agencies
decided to not let truth
get in the way of
protecting a child.
Especially when
they're a war criminal.
Wait, wait, wait
are you saying,
are you saying that I
was conceived in a rape?
Jesus.
Your biological father, Jake,
is a man named Rasto Boranovic.
He was indicted for war crimes
including what he
did to your mother.
We've been hunting
him for 20 years,
and last week we got him.
He's in custody awaiting
trial in The Hague.
And that's why
we're being shot at?
Boranovic disappeared
along with his private army.
He's become a very powerful
figure in organized crime,
exporting drugs
into Eastern Europe.
Always buys from a
cartel in Mexico.
Now, they lose their Boranovic,
they lose a huge
foothold in the market.
The man hunting you, he's
a professional killer.
He'll kill every one
of us to get to you.
But how does killing
these two protect Boranovic?
Because Jake here is the
evidence that will put him away.
Jake, your biological
mother's still alive.
She's going to testify.
Now, with your
DNA and her story,
we put Boranovic, your
father, away for...
Don't call him my father!
He's not my father.
Who caught this guy?
I did.
What about my mother?
My biological mother?
When I found her,
she was in Sarajevo.
She's taking a great
risk testifying.
She's a brave woman, Jake.
Okay, look, this
doesn't make any sense.
There's gotta be more
evidence than just Jake.
Oh, we have a lot
of evidence, Frank.
Most of it's circumstantial.
We did find another offspring,
a half-brother to you.
But four days ago,
he disappeared.
And we haven't found
a trace of him.
How did this guy find
us all the way out here?
Did he go to my house?
Is my wife okay?
No.
Oh, God, no.
We haven't found a body yet.
- Deputy!
- Wait, wait, wait, wait,
wait so, she could
still be alive?
- Please, Jake.
- No, no, she could!
She could, yes.
But the way the man does things,
we don't find bodies, Jake.
He makes people disappear.
That's what he does.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Frank.
They killed my
mom because of me?
Did they kill my
No, Jesus, no.
Based upon the shot
that killed my partner,
he's a mile, maybe
less, behind us.
I'm sorry, Frank, we
have to keep moving.
I'm sorry.
Oh, Jesus, no.
Dad.
Dad, I'm so sorry.
Frank.
Frank, we've gotta keep moving.
We have to leave.
Lead us
out of here, Deputy.
Come on.
June?
They should've been back by now.
Any word?
Not since this morning.
All right.
Just keep me posted, huh?
So, you work for the
International Criminal Court?
No.
Right now, I'm kind of on loan
from British Intelligence.
I was airborne 10 years.
It was a boring time
for an American warrior.
No Afghanistan, no Iraq.
Best we got was
Panama and Grenada.
Well, you know how that works.
Luck of the draw, right?
But you came home.
- I'm a lucky guy.
- Yeah.
Look, I really appreciate
you tryin' to save my boy.
But I'm curious, why do it?
Why risk your life
for another country?
I mean, I thank God
every day for Jake,
but I'm curious, what you do?
You think it'll really
make a difference?
I hope so.
What I do know, Frank, is
apathy changes nothing,
and the way I see things,
a parent losing a child,
it's the same pain no
matter where you're from.
I'm tired of borders deciding
who we help and who we don't.
But there'll always
be plenty who get away,
and there will always be
those to replace them.
You're right.
Human nature.
Maybe the threat of life
in prison stops one man.
Then we're saving lives.
Come on.
You okay there, Frank?
I, I
may need a minute.
Okay, yeah.
Let's catch our breath.
Are you sure it's just
one guy tracking us?
No.
But I think if there was more,
they'd be triangulating
us by now.
Well, if it's just one guy,
why don't we triangulate him?
Jake, I don't
think you understand
the situation you're in.
This man's been killing people
since he was a teenager.
If we want any chance of
staying alive in this thing,
we stay one step ahead of him.
Now, we didn't
check in which means
search and rescue is behind us.
We get that blood sample,
we get the DNA here
officially on record.
Killing Jake serves no
purpose for them, then.
Look, we stay out of his
way, and we wait for backup.
But it could take
at least another day
to get more men out here.
We don't have another day.
Jake needs to take his medicine.
Look, I'm fine as
long as I don't bleed.
And what if you do bleed?
What if you get shot?
What if you fall and bruise?
Safest bet, we go back
through base camp.
Frank, listen, I saw it.
Your ATVs are trashed
and everything you had.
We head that way, we're
heading straight for him.
There's a little
town called Titus.
It's about 12 miles from here.
It's really just a
bar and a gas station,
but it's the closest
place to find people.
Good, let's do that.
No, no, no, no way!
Keep your fucking voice down.
I am trying to keep you alive.
Do you hear me?
I know this man.
He's a very dangerous
human being.
We keep moving.
I agree with Gray.
You're a fucking coward.
Jake, that is enough.
Hey, get moving.
Get up, get up, get up.
Get a handle on your boy.
Hey.
Stay calm, we'll get
through this, okay?
- Okay.
- Come on.
Is there any way we can get
that chopper back here by dawn?
Aw, hell no, son.
Christ, look, I got three
men unaccounted for.
I need to be in the
air at first light.
June, can you come in here?
Yeah, Sheriff?
I need you to
call Bill Miller.
- Bill Miller?
- Yes, Bill Miller.
I know he's an ass,
but his brother
and he's got that
crop duster, yeah?
- Yeah?
- All right.
Ask him to have that thing here
first thing in the morning.
All right, I'll call him.
You doin' okay?
I'm sorry for the
way I acted earlier.
Jake, you have
nothing to be sorry for.
A lot of things have
changed for you today.
You've been braver than most.
I, uh, I just
feel like my whole life's a lie.
I can't believe my mom's dead.
I'm sorry.
You shouldn't have
to go through this.
You know, I see how
much your dad loves you.
He wants you to be strong.
You have to be strong
for each other.
You know that?
I'm gonna keep an eye
open tonight, Jake.
Try and get some
rest if you can.
Hang in there.
I heard motorcycles.
That could be the search party.
Not a chance.
They'll be coming in
by air or by foot.
He's right, son.
Look, I found
the perfect spot.
High ground over here.
Perfect for cover.
No matter what, they
don't know where you are.
Do not compromise your position.
He's right, stay
put, stay low.
What if you don't come back?
We keep moving.
- You got this?
- Yeah.
Let's move out, come on.
They're headed your way.
Spread out and wait.
Let's play.
Get down.
He's
coming back, right?
He knows what he's doing.
Ah, I should have
killed you in Budapest
when I had the chance.
I don't remember
you having a chance.
This didn't need to happen.
Now, you start listening to me.
We need to move.
Come on, we gotta go, come on.
Let's go.
Stay with me.
Hey, you see anyone?
No, we're clear.
Hey, hey, hey.
How bad is it?
It's bad.
I don't know, maybe it's a disc.
I just, I need rest.
I'm just gonna
slow you guys down.
Then we stay here
and finish this,
and wait for search and rescue.
They gotta be close.
Are you sure?
You can't make it?
Jake, we can't make assumptions.
We don't know how many
people are out there.
I gotta get you to Titus.
No, no, no!
Fuck that!
Son, you're already
on borrowed time.
Come on, we've
been through this.
All it takes is a
bruise, a gunshot.
No way, Dad.
I cannot lose you, too.
Listen to me, okay?
Just listen to me.
I can make it out here.
I can survive, come
on, you know me!
There's plenty of food.
I'll be, I'll be fine.
I'll be fine, okay?
I'll be fine.
Your only hope is for
you guys to get out
and come back with help.
There's no other choice.
I'm coming back for you.
Oh, I know you will.
Jake.
Come on, get outta here.
I'll get him!
Got you.
Come on, Frank.
Come on.
Jesus.
Where's the boy?
I have no clue.
What do you want me to say?
He took a left at the evergreen?
Even if I did know, I
wouldn't tell you, so come on.
Go ahead.
Did you kill my wife?
Did you?
Oh, is Sarah here?
She's, um, she's
incapacitated.
Oh, nothin' serious, I hope.
No, no.
Um, she's, uh, she's
just not available.
I'm the gardener.
Oh, well, uh, could, could
you see that she gets these?
We just wanted to
welcome 'em back.
They're really nice people.
- Very nice.
- Real neighborly.
Okay, I'll, um, I'll
let her know you came by.
If, if, if you wanna
sneak a couple of those,
I won't tell anybody.
And now my son?
Your son?
He's not your son.
He's not your blood.
Why do you care?
Why do I.
I spent 18 years of
my life raising him.
Watching him grow.
Teaching him right from wrong.
It's obvious to
me that you never
had a father do the
same thing for you.
Gray.
Yeah, I know.
Look, Jake, going back
there right now goes
against everything
we should be doing.
Fuck it.
Let's go get him.
Come on.
It's an ambush.
He doesn't know we're here.
Oh, Jesus.
Okay, you're gonna have
to go ahead without me.
No, no, I can help you.
No, I made a
promise to your dad.
You go this way.
A mile, maybe two.
Find a place to hide.
You wait for me.
You don't see me in one hour,
get to that town by dark.
Okay?
- Okay.
- Go on, Jake, go.
Oh, shit.
No, no, no.
No, no, no, no, no.
Shit.
Gray!
Can you hear me?
I'm unarmed.
Turn around.
It's just me.
You know, I always
wondered how things
would end up between us.
You?
Seems you have the advantage.
Stay where you are.
I have enough
reasons to kill you.
Gray, always by the book.
And now you're gonna arrest me?
Yeah.
Probably should.
Might go look for that, uh,
little daughter of yours,
that pretty wife, if you don't.
Tryin' to push my buttons, Z?
We could settle it here.
Just the two of us.
- If you want.
- I don't.
I'm gonna walk you in.
You're going to stand trial, Z.
In that case.
Hand me the tele,
the telephone.
The telephone.
She's, she's just learning.
Mine, too.
Hope, hope she knows
how, how proud I am of her.
She will.
Is it done?
It's done.
Dad!
Is that you, Jake?
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
- I'm okay.
Are you okay?
- Are you shot?
- It was just a graze.
I'm okay.
The rest helped, but I'm
still in a little pain.
Jesus, Jake, you're cut.
No, I'm fine, I'm fine.
I'm okay, I have time.
Can you walk?
Where's Gray?
- Let's go.
- Okay.
Come on.
Okay.
Oh, oh, got you.
- Mom, Dad!
- Help me.
I got you, okay, okay.
We've got you.
Are you good?
I got you.
Jake, relax.
You look good.
Do my shoes match my belt?
That's a thing, right?
- Shoes and belts?
- Jake.
Listen, it's your mother.
Your biological mother.
She brought you into this world.
And I promise you,
she's going to love you.
Okay.
Okay?
You know, I wanted to mention,
if you want to
meet the man that...
My biological father?
Uh, no, no.
There's no need.
I, I don't owe him anything.
Your family's what
you make it, right?
- Is that her?
- It is.
It's that time, Jake.
You gonna go see her?
Thank you.
Go on, get outta here.
Change of plans.
I'm coming home.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull