Western Front
1914-1918
In 5 reels.
This film is dedicated to the
mothers, to those whose sons
have fallen on the sad plains
of Flanders, there where the countless
wooden crosses are planted...
the crosses of the Yser.
Produced by Gaston Schoukens
and Paul Flon.
Photography Bell and Nicolas
Assistant Ed. Breville
Roles: the old mother - the women
the old father - the eldest son
the youngest son - the girl
In a small town in
the north of France.
"So, mama, will all
be ready in time?"
"Don't worry, all will be ready."
"I'm not worried,
I just want to know."
"Is there anything
else to do, Mrs.?"
"Almost nothing, Brigitte, only
the flowers need to be placed."
"Now that everything is ready,
I will call them."
"Suzette!"
"Come all in, the table is ready."
"Papa!" "Mama!"
"Uncle John!"
"My dear children. It's for mama
and me a great happiness, today,
to find our children
back around us."
"My dear Peter, my dear Lucy,
it's five years ago today
that you were united."
"I hope it'll be granted to
me to attend this anniversary
many more times...
We harbour the best wishes
for your joint happiness...
And no less for our
dear little Suzette."
"It's the alarm bell!"
"Mobilisation!"
Army and Navy - Order
for general mobilisation.
"Finally we will be able to
show them, that we are French."
The whole of France prepared
to defend itself with truly
admirable enthusiasm and unity.
A waving flag, a vibrating
Marseillaise and our love
then knows only the fatherland.
"Poor little ones, for them war
is but a flag swashing in the wind,
and the blaring of the clarions...
...but for me, who'se seen
1870, war is the disruption
of the entire life,
the destruction of cities,
children with hunger
and mothers who cry."
On all the roads of France
the soldiers go to the border.
"Come on, old man, a glass of wine.
To sing well you must drink well."
"I thank you, I'm not
thirsty right now.
"How, you're not thirsty?
But you've just yelled
to burst the throat."
And during that time, to replace
the men duty had called...
the franciscan sisters gather the
grain harvest to ensure the bread
that the land will need tomorrow.
Their delicate hands, unsuited
to that kind of work, with a
soic endurance wield
the heavy scythe of the mowers.
Under the grape fire.
After two months of excessive
fatigue, two months of nights
without rest and fights without end...
the soldiers, missing everything,
hold on to the Yser in despair.
In the basement of a ruined house,
a few men have been placed, on outpost.
"Did you notice that "William"
is sending them to us
like pidgeons, this morning?
"Let's use that moment of
calming to relieve the
comrades down by the water."
"No, thanks, I'm too tired."
"Talk of bombardment! Eleven
dead, some sixty wounded
and that without an attack."
"I've seen near the white farm a shell
explode close to one of our men...
...Sadly I couldn't come to his
aid and I don't know who it is.
"My dear brother, I assure
you that I made it okay."
"That big Firmin, who was only a few
steps away from me, has had his belly cut
open this morning by a piece of shell"
"That brave Lambert too, was
killed close to the white farm."
"Dear god! How terrible is the war!"
"Rest a bit, my good man,
I... I'm going to write."
Hotel In bed they sleep.
"Outpost number five here."
"Understood! In half an hour."
"Bouchard!"
"You're the only one who hasn't
been on guard; so it's up to
you to take the mission."
"That's how I think about it
too, besides look at the boys,
they're all exhausted."
"On the other bank stands
the house of the ferryman."
"it's about exploding it."
"In the basement near an old suitcase
is a mine that we laid there when we
were still on the other side of the water."
"In half an hour it'll be dark
enough and old Achilles will
be there with his little boat..."
"...with the help of which
you can cross the Yser."
"Understood! In half an hour the
house of the ferryman will blow!"
"You see down there that cart,
you must pass it on the left."
"Corporal, I have still 15 minutes;
I'm going to finish the letter
I was writing to my wife."
"My poor John, why did
you go in my place?"
"That our little Suzette
would not lose her father."
"We must return down there
immediately. An effort, Jean,
I'll help you... Courage..."
On the plains of Flanders, under
the rattle of the machine guns,
and the booming of the canons...
The marine artillery of admiral
Ronarc'h have come to reinforce
the handful of Belgians...
...who cling desperately
to their native ground.
"Bayonets on the rifles!"
"Mother."
In a hospital at St. Georges.
"I'd like to write."
"Don't think about it! You forget,
that the major has perscribed
the biggest possible rest."
"You're unwise, you
will worsen the fever."
"I beg you, a few words."
"So be it, but no more
than two minutes."
"Poor chap... It would be a
miracle if he pulled through."
"Down there."
"Madam, here are two letters,
that were just delivered."
"Lucy, this one is for you."
...so that Jean and I are
since five days in an outpost
at the banks of the Yser.
Even though now and then we have
to face terrible bombardments,
it's going as well as it can.
At the moment that I write you, Jean
is here with me and charges me to
tell you that he embraces you all.
My dear parents, I write
to you from St. Georges where
I was brought two days ago
because of an injury.
Do not worry yourself:
The nurse assures me
this morning that I'll be recovered
in a fortnight. Hope to see you soon
and embrace little Suzette for me.
Your affectionate son Jean.
"My poor little one."
"Why worry yourself mama, if he
writes, that it isn't serious."
"I've got a premonition that he
isn't telling the whole truth."
"Papa, he suffers! Our little
one calls for his mother perhaps."
"I beg you, papa, I want to see
him; I want to see my Jean again."
"Say, papa, Saint Georges is
not so far, let us go there!"
For hours and hours the poor mother,
exhausted from fatigue, found
in the love for her son...
...the power to continue
the bitter Calvary road.
"I am very tired papa, but that
is nothing, I am so happy, for
soon I will be near to him."
"Courage, mama, we
will soon be there!"
"Could you allow us on your cart,
we're going to Saint Georges."
"That is not possible, madamette,
and besides, it's forbidden!"
"I'm an old mother who goes to
see her son in the hospital...
Don't you have a mother as well?"
"I don't go until Saint Georges,
but climb on anyway, that will
save you a few kilometers anyway."
"How glad he will be,
our little one, to see us."
Having arrived near Saint Georges...
"Follow this road, it's straight ahead."
"Poor mother who won't
see her son again!"
A dreadful premonition
oppressed both poor seniors...
...and they continued their way
without daring to communicate
each other their thoughts.
"I would lile to see my son, sir."
"But there are a lot of sons here,
madam. What is your name?"
"Bouchard."
"Here is a mother who would like
to see her son, soldier Bouchard."
"Will you follow me,
I will bring you to him."
"So... he lives, doesn't he?"
"Why yes, madam, he lives...
although his injury is serious."
"Pierre!"
"So it's you, my Pierre?"
"But... then... your brother
Jean... where is he?
"Jean died of his injuries two
days ago and is being buried now,
mother, but he was a hero.
"How cruel is the war.
Thus thousands of victims from
families have fallen and for what."