- Can I look in your cases?
- I've been through the scanner.
Are you challenging me?
Come on!
Have we met in Saint-Germain?
They're all thieves there.
OK?
And you're a good girl.
I'l doit.
Go into the airport.
I spotted a girl inside.
- Inside?
- In Customs.
She's wearing a uniform.
Ask for her number.
Have you put on weight?
People say I have,
but I can't see it.
I can!
That's enough!
- Have you found it?
- It?
The rare bird.
No, I haven't found it.
You've put on weight
because you haven't looked.
I have looked, José,
but I don't have your eye.
No, you don't.
- Maybe there are none left.
- Maybe...
You've nabbed them.
What about girls?
Stop it, José!
An old elephant like you
can find water.
I can find water, with my trunk!
Enjoy your stay.
You're in room 1104,
11th floor.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Mr Stockman...
This is my son, Drissa.
What do you want?
I want you to take my son.
- To Europe, to play football.
- No. I'm tired.
He's a great footballer.
Everyone says so.
Take him to Europe.
I understand, but I'm tired.
Goodbye!
I told you I arrived yesterday.
I said I'd call you.
Gigi, I promised I'd call you.
I was going to call you.
You know me...
I'm speaking quietly
because I'm in a meeting.
I'm working.
I have to go. Yes.
I'l call you back.
- Mr Stockman?
- Just a moment.
Someone to see you.
You again?
I forgot to give you this.
My son is in the paper.
You came back to give me this?
I slept outside the hotel.
- You slept outside?
- Yes.
You're
Cr:
az
yl
I don't listen to other people.
Sorry.
- What's his name?
- Drissa.
- Where is he?
- Down there.
Underneath my balcony?
Go on! Play for the white man!
Fine...
Off you go...
You should try the circus.
He's like a sea lion.
A piece of wood that floats
will never be a caiman.
Do you understand?
Leaving already?
I'm going right now.
Wait a minute.
I might have something else
to declare.
I'l give you some money
for a taxi.
We've been trying to get
a meeting for a year.
That's the Stockman effect.
We need to play this subtly.
Subtlety is my middle name.
Put your case on your head.
Your case.
Put your briefcase on your head.
You're a good pilot!
Boubacar at Anderlecht,
was that you?
Indeed.
And Matute at Newcastle?
Yes.
Eboué, at Arsenal?
You're very good, Mr Stockman.
What's your secret?
May I?
I have a big nose!
I have a nose for it.
What do you think of Mr Costa,
our coach?
Honestly? Can I be honest?
He's an idiot.
The match against Cameroon.
He takes Boka off after 10 minutes
for a poor dribble.
He should never
have taken him off.
He should have let him
carry on playing.
If he wants to be Teutonic,
he should go to Germany!
They'll play in Lederhosen!
- Sorry, it's my sense of humour.
- I agree.
You're a visionary.
I'l hire you.
To do what?
This is a talented generation.
We need the right coach
to find them.
Come closer.
Ivory Coast will win the World Cup.
They've been saying that
for 30 years.
"Africa is the future for football."
Africa will never win the World Cup.
Why not?
Look at the 2002 World Cup.
Senegal won the opening match
against the world champions,
France.
It was a great match.
But did they go back
to the hotel to rest? No.
They went back to the hotel,
with some girls.
They got drunk and spent 3 days...
Did they get to the final?
No.
The players could hardly
open their eyes on the bus.
"I regret it now!"
- Could you go a month without...?
- Get out.
Minister,
I have the agreement...
I said: "Get out!"
What did I say?
Wake up!
Look at him, look at him...
He's apologizing for being alive!
H
[
s
asleep!
The last time,
what did I ask for?
- A killer.
- "A killer." And is he?
No.
I wanted a son of a bitch.
A guy with zero IQ.
If he stops to think, it's no good.
That's what he does.
OK?
Do you need a rest?
He's scared of the ball!
What's his name?
- Dramon.
- Dramon! You call him!
Dramon, come here!
Kick the ball
only if there's an opening.
The ball isn't on fire.
Don't be scared of it.
Go on! Go for the ball!
You told them playing football
would make them rich.
It's not true.
Only Salif has become rich.
And the other kids
who do nothing...
They're struggling.
Salif supports a whole village.
Not like other kids.
Hold on! Salif,
1 kid out of 1,000 in the village
who succeeds.
One kid: Salif!
One kid.
Better than nothing.
- And the others?
- That's the law, Bibo.
That was hardly football.
Hardly football.
You weren't playing.
You were trotting.
Have you concrete feet?
- My feet hurt.
- Your feet hurt?
What do you want?
Should I stop spending
a week each month
watching you play?
Shall I stop wasting my money?
Stop believing in you?
I believe in you.
You don't believe in yourselves.
I'd rather go back.
Mr José...
Calm down.
I understand.
I know them.
They'll rally.
They'll work.
They'll do better.
Children...
I'd like you to feel guilty
of underachieving.
Back on the pitch.
Coach!
Let me play?
- Who is this?
- I don't know him.
He's not local.
You want to play?
In those shoes?
I know him.
Get lost.
We don't want gangs here.
Come here and say that.
Don't bother.
Back to the game.
Goon!
Go away.
Is this it?
I think so.
He plays here every night.
That's him.
In the Brazil shirt.
He's got something.
Go and get him.
You're not bad.
- What's your name?
- Koné Yaya.
- How old are you?
-19.
19 and the rest!
You can't kid me.
Anyway...
Even if you're 25,
I guarantee I can get you playing
in the Champions League.
Here.
10am at the Bibo ground.
Know where it is?
Think about it.
When you're old...
They'll say: "That guy
crossing the road. It's Yayal
"He was in the final
against Barcelona."
When I'm old,
they'll ask how I managed
to buy such a nice house.
Yes.
That too.
I suggest
you send over
one of your scouts, OK?
So he can see for himself.
Just watch him play.
I'l pay the costs.
You'll see, he's a rocket.
He just needs a launch pad.
OK. I'll call you tomorrow.
Thanks.
- Hello, precious.
- Hello, darling.
- You get more beautiful.
- Thank you.
- Oh my, oh my...
- It's for you.
Have you decided?
Yes. I'll have steak tartare
without capers.
And some pinot noir.
I haven't.
- When was the fish caught?
- Today.
- It's fresh?
- Of course.
I'm undecided.
This might help.
That was the wine list.
- Grilled chicken.
- OK.
Why didn't you tell me?
You'd seen.
- All part of your charm.
- Crap, José!
Everyone can read in Belgium.
She thinks she's clever.
Working 12 hours a day
for 1,200 F...
She looks like a penguin.
That's why she doesn't like you.
If she knew...
- What?
- She thinks you're paying me.
You don't need me.
I know that look.
"Why don't you give me money?"
You think I'm made of money.
You think we're all rich in Europe.
No.
I think I'm pregnant.
- Who's the father?
- You.
Me? I doubt that.
Remember Grand-Bassam?
The condom broke.
You think it's mine?
I'm not the only visitor!
Did the sperm have a moustache?
- Hi, José!
- Is that it?
- José, is that it?
- Calm down.
- Precious...
- You annoy me.
Gigi! Gigi!
Forgive me.
He's a war machine.
The best scout in Belgium.
That's why they're sending him.
That's him.
They'll take everything.
Come on.
Where is this black pearl?
In a safe place.
- No-one knows about him?
- No.
He plays in a rough neighbourhood,
at night.
- At night?
- Most play at night.
They have to work.
They work in the day
and play at night.
That's their strength...
They sense their opponents.
They have a sixth sense.
It's incredible.
They're like lizards.
They're nyctalopic.
- "Nyctalopic"?
- Nyctalopic.
They can see in the dark.
- That's their strength.
- Really?
Lizards are nyctalopic.
Lizards can see in the dark
and dodge.
They dodge.
They sense the ball in the dark.
It's a strength.
Birds aren't nyctalopic.
- Birds?
- They go to sleep.
Or they'd bump into things.
No!
Well done! Sit down, children.
Sit down.
That was such a pleasure.
The lovely song rising...
That was too slow.
We're from this association:
A pair of shoes for my African buddy.
Come on.
Children!
Excuse me.
- Do you really want these shoes?
- Yes!
Why?
Who do you want to be like?
- Aruna Dindane.
- Who?
- He's a great player.
A really great player.
And do you know why?
Up until the age of 16,
Aruna played without shoes.
He played barefoot.
Being barefoot is your strength.
You feel the ball better.
It makes you special.
Fine!
That's your opinion.
Let's carry on.
Come along...
Think about it, children.
You have to love football.
Go away, you idiot!
The shoes are for you.
Take them.
Adama! I'm watching!
- Pina colada.
- Baileys.
Pina colada.
Are you married?
Married?
Do you have a wife?
No. I'm not married.
When are you going back
to Belgium?
I'm here for a week.
- Just a week?
- Yes.
- It's a pity.
- Pity.
I'l have to make the most of you.
Pardon?
- I'll have to make the most of you.
- Yes!
I've chosen sea bass.
Profiteroles and fish are light.
That's not why you called.
Hubert and I thought...
So you won't have to meet
my parents,
come to the church.
You'll have drinks and all that.
They can come to the meal.
Hold on.
I can't come to my son's wedding?
You want to spend
the evening with my parents?
No. That's what I thought.
And you need to pay 2,000 euros.
- I sent the money.
- When?
I did, but I'm in Africa!
- You didn't.
- Can't hear you.
Don't listen to her.
You're a man.
José, you're a killer.
Yes, I'm a killer. You're right.
You're right.
You have rhythm, Koen.
When you dance,
you look like David Bowie.
Like in Let's Dance.
It's not those legs he's using.
It's the third leg!
Did you see those soldiers?
It's for security.
No. It was too much.
It's for your protection.
I want three driers.
- For drying hair.
- OK.
There are the driers.
That's the big couch.
- How do containers work?
- What containers?
She wants to order special sinks
for washing hair.
"Special sinks"?
Yes. Professional stuff
for her salon.
With integral shower heads.
Can we forget about sinks
and containers
and concentrate?
We've a match in an hour.
Go without me.
I trust you.
Girls, take a walk.
But...
Are you OK?
You can't talk to them like that.
Koen...
You've flipped.
You're buying a hair salon
for some prostitute?
Hold on, José.
She isn't a prostitute.
Don't talk about Fleur like that.
I love her.
And she loves me.
Koen...
10.
Up! Get up!
I came to see you.
Get up!
Here.
You should eat before a match.
Eat.
If I only send rascals to Europe,
the source will dry up.
José told me they have problems
with Bouba and the others.
They won't want more Africans.
Look at this.
They don't like that.
Get rid of that.
- Abdou, scrub!
- It's not going.
It can't look like a tattoo.
It's not going.
Scrub like a man!
Are you a girl?
[t wasn't hard enough.
Abdou!
You're the one who should go.
I don't want to play.
Honour what God has given you.
- Who will take care of Abdou?
- Me.
I'll treat him like a son.
Hello?
You're at the hotel?
They won't give you the keys?
Put him on.
Yes, sir. It's me.
She's my girlfriend.
Give them to her.
Yes, love. I'm coming.
You enjoy your bath.
Come on!
They're damaging him.
Mohamed...
Why did you do that?
That was slaughter!
You think that
will get you to Europe?
He's going to Europe.
Come on.
It's not right to play like that.
- It's understandable, José.
- What is?
That kid has been training
for 4 years.
He turns up and takes his place.
You can understand it.
You don't succeed
because another fails.
Get me a cigarette.
- You don't like him?
- No.
- Why not?
- You're not taking me to Europe.
We should open a sandwich shop.
Good idea.
With my knowledge.
We can do sandwiches
with chicken curry, salad.
We'll call it crab,
but use surimi.
That will be an increase...
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'm busy.
No...
It's not what you think.
It's my little sister.
We're clothes shopping.
I can't really talk.
That's not true!
You've forgotten me.
I was on time.
Ciao-ciao.
Will we make our own bread?
José?
What is wrong, José?
Sir, please...
My mobile has gone in the water.
- I'm sick of your mobile.
- Why did you do that?
- I was sick of it.
- I can't work now.
Good, you're here with me.
With me.
Have some decency.
Some morals.
Your morality is for Whites!
When the plate is full.
If you didn't have money,
I wouldn't sleep with you.
You're pathetic.
You're a pathetic man.
Just a dog!
Filthy White!
Who pays for everything?
Mr Stockman.
We found him at the buffet.
- Is he with you?
- Yes.
Really?
Are you ready?
Off we go.
- Hello!
- All right?
- What do you think?
- It's nice.
- Great, isn't it?
- Yeah...
You can't get on the plane
dressed like that.
Good. I'm staying.
Staying?
Yes. 3 more weeks.
The container arrives in 10 days
and we open the salon in 2 weeks.
I'm staying here.
Open the salon?
Everything is sorted out for Yaya.
They're expecting you.
No problem!
And your wife?
I called her.
She knows.
Stay.
I know how you feel.
You want to protect them.
Be a hero.
You think they need you.
The girls here,
it's like building a motorway.
You'll never see the end of it.
Think about it.
Come with me.
I'm staying.
It's your life.
He's not coming.
Nothing worse
than a White who thinks he's Black.
Let's go.
Like your new outfit?
They're your club colours.
Welcome to Charleroi Sporting Club.
It's a good club, you'll see.
What's all this?
OK, let me get out.
Leave it to me.
There's too many of them.
Wait...
There's no more.
Hello.
Please follow me.
- Follow me.
- What is it?
- I've a plane to catch.
Do you know him?
- Where are you from?
- Bako.
Ring any bells?
- You look like a Dioula.
- I am a Dioula.
- And you don't know Bako?
- I came to Abidjan aged 5.
Can we move on?
Our plane's waiting.
He's been here for 2 days.
- What for?
- He says he's his father.
His name's Alassane Koné.
- What's yours?
- Yaya.
- Yaya what?
- Koné Yaya.
He's your father?
- Oh, Yaya, is that your father?
- No!
I left the village at 5.
There are lots of Konés.
Yaya...
Hamedine left Abidjan on Friday.
He said you were going
to play in the Whites' country.
In a big club.
Inch Allah! We're proud of you.
I can't give you anything now.
Only later.
I have to do a test.
If I pass, I'll have a contract.
Then I'll have money.
Money?
You want money
now he's a heavyweight?
You gonna find him
a bunch of fathers?
Right now, I'm his father.
How much?
CHARLEROI STADIUM
You OK?
- Sort of.
- You don't look good.
It's malaria.
Shit...
The day of the test?
Unbelievable!
I don't believe it!
Get me some medicine.
Don't worry, I will.
Oh, no, not him! Shit...
Be right back.
Dr Livingstone, I presume!
Hey, the Mourinho of Africa!
Did you get your end away?
How are you?
- You're saving the season.
- I'm saving your club.
Got your golden boy?
Where is he?
There.
- Him?
- Yeah.
Why's he in the car?
He's suffering from jet lag.
Jet lag?
Abidjan to Brussels, that's...
An hour. An hour and a bit.
It's longer for them.
He's no good.
I can't use him.
Give me 30 minutes!
Just 30 minutes, OK?
He's a rocket!
Hi, Son.
- What do you want?
- I was passing...
Hello, madam.
Classy!
Nice place!
All this equipment...
- Good quality.
- What do you want?
Give the kid a shot.
He's got malaria.
He's from Cote d'Ivoire.
He's got a chance to play here.
His test is in half an hour.
Without a shot...
- This is a veterinary practice.
- I know.
All I'm asking for is a shot.
It's nothing...
You're ashamed
of your slave-trading father.
- Where do you get off...
- Ask him.
Yaya, come here.
Tell him where you lived.
You'll see.
Tell him where you slept.
Under bridges.
With taxis, tyres and iron sheets.
Now he's got the chance to play.
Just give him a shot!
Coach, let's go.
Wait over there while I finish this.
Thanks.
He'll sort you out, you'll see.
Is he your child?
Yes, he's my son.
What?
- You don't believe me?
- Yes, I do.
But when he looks you in the eye,
you bow your head.
That's why I asked.
I bow my head? Rubbish!
You're still doing it.
Get on it!
What use is that?
Get warmed up.
Goon!
Talk to each other!
He's on his own!
Yaya...
Mark number 3.
His legs have gone.
Mark him and wait for the ball.
OK?
Let him go!
Nice, eh?
Each time he went round,
he said:
"I should have listened
to my mother!"
The trainer said:
"What did she say?"
"I don't know,
I didn't listen to her!"
"I didn't listen to her!"
This is less funny.
Koen's report on Yaya.
I know.
I've read it. He's Flemish.
He didn't write much.
In Abidjan, he gave it his all!
His all!
What do you want me to do?
Let him play once.
Just once.
After yesterday and this,
no-one wants him to play.
I've got good instincts.
You did.
José, you had good instincts.
One of the best.
You brought us lots of people.
But in the last 2 years?
- Are you kidding? I don't know...
- Who?
Who have you brought to Belgium?
Boubacar.
He plays for Anderlecht 1 match in 4.
They want to sell him.
- Who else?
- Kouassi.
He plays in Division 3, José.
You've brought us no-one.
- You're tired.
- No.
It's not your fault.
It's Africa.
But I've good news for you.
I need a scout for the youngsters.
You look around, find them,
bring them back here.
What do you mean?
You're burying me?
Are you?
No, on the contrary.
You'l like it.
You work Sundays.
You can go to bars,
tell stories to the parents...
I'll think about it.
Hurry up, they've started!
Faster.
What's up?
He told me to pay 2 euros
for training.
You didn't tell me that.
It's because you have to...
It's a club...
I don't want to pay to play.
Yaya, they rent the pitch!
The trainer's a volunteer.
Here.
Don't worry.
Show them what you've got.
I'l find a club that deserves you.
Goon!
What's your name?
Koné Yaya.
"Koné Yaya."
I like the way you play.
- How old are you?
-19.
- Where you from?
- Cote d'Ivoire.
Get dressed, I'll wait for you.
- Who gave you this address?
- The old man.
- What old man?
- Stockman.
Why aren't you working?
You can walk if you want.
With me, you'll run.
It's me. What's up?
What?
You're kidding!
What after-sales service?
I sell football players,
not washing machines!
What?
You're kidding.
Hold on.
Wait. I've no idea!
I don't spend my time
with my hand in my player's pants.
OK. Calm down.
I'll take care of it, OK?
I'll take care of it.
I'l call you back.
Change of plan.
Hello.
I've come for my player.
The Ivorian. Boubacar.
I'm his agent.
Sit down.
He's got a game in 3 hours
in Bruges.
He's missed the bus,
so if you could...
Ah, great! Thanks a lot.
There's a hill to settle.
6 Camparis, 650 euros?
It's a rip-off.
He made a hole in the baize
with his cigarette.
That's the Congolese for you!
Don't lie to people.
He's drunk.
He doesn't remember.
- Where's the hole?
- Pardon?
You ask us to pay,
we have to see the hole.
He's not wrong.
If there really is a hole,
show it to me for the insurance.
Go find it.
Find it!
Goon.
Here it is.
Il go.
Coach, it wasn't made today.
Come and look.
It wasn't made today.
Can't you see it's a hole?
Hello, baby.
I've bought you Chanel No 5.
Chanel No 5, a large bottle.
There wasn't any Chanel No 19.
It doesn't exist anymore.
I asked. Chanel No 5 is better,
more expensive.
I'l give it to my friend here.
He'll give it to you.
At least you're sure to get it.
Yeah.
Yes, love you.
Hey, you...
Take some things to my girl
in Abidjan.
I'm not going.
I'm here for a reason.
Who are you?
What's your name?
- Koné Yaya.
- I never heard of you.
I know all the footballers.
I never heard of Yaya Koné.
I know where they poach
the best players.
But God doesn't help everyone.
Fool!
The bus is already at Ghent.
Here. You smell of alcohol.
Stop the bus!
I've got something for you.
Here. It's Deep Heat.
Where'd you get this?
- Thanks.
- I got it from the club.
Yaya, come here.
Someone to see you.
Ready for training, guys?
You think you can turn up
and Koen will take you in?
Where will you sleep?
- She'll stay with me.
- No. That's impossible.
- We'll be fine.
- Don't even think about it.
Football's what matters.
Concentrate.
- It'll be fine, coach.
- No!
Stop playing Mother Teresa.
She can't stay with you.
- We can't leave her outside.
- No. But let me handle it.
Can you go get a milkshake?
They're very good.
The best favour you can do her
is to send her back to Abidjan.
Understand?
Next year,
she'll be on the game.
It's her life.
Answer me honestly.
Are you happy here?
I've imported 23 players.
23.
They all said they were very happy.
But they didn't mean it.
Touch, or else you can't go.
I can't give you exact figures.
What can I guarantee you?
The best. I'll get it.
A club, a salary.
An apartment, better than this one.
A real place.
I can't decide just like that.
Before we go any further,
look at this.
Thanks.
Listen.
You must sign this document.
With this, I'll look for a contract
straightaway.
I'll find one within a week.
In a month, you'll be playing
for a big club.
Not reserves. First team.
Where is this club?
Look.
I got a fax from Vardar Skopje.
- It's better.
- Is it a good club?
It's a Macedonian club.
You know Macedonia?
Yugoslavia.
- That's in Europe?
- Yes, itis.
It's 2,200km from here.
Here. Sign there.
Hello. José Stockman.
Here to see Koen. Is he in?
Come in.
Darling?
- Hi, Koen!
- Hi, José.
All right?
- My wife, Rita.
- We've met.
It was unbearable.
- Really?
- Yes.
You can't believe the fuss she made.
At home,
with the neighbours, my family...
And at the club.
She even went to see the chairman.
"Chairman, he's left me
for an African whore!"
You should've seen my face!
- What did I look like?
- With your bubu!
My bubu...
And you?
- I'm not so good.
- Really?
I've got problems.
Because of you.
Because of me?
In Abidjan, you were thinking
with your cock.
Keep your voice down!
Did you see what you wrote?
Let's talk about this over a drink.
No, no, no.
Give me another report.
A more positive one.
Didn't I make it clear?
Africa is over for me.
Can you imagine stirring it up again?
- It'll be a nightmare.
- Really?
Want to see a nightmare?
Look.
See her?
Recognise her?
- What is this?
- "This"?
Her name's Fleur.
The bumble bee planted his seed.
With your creative willy.
Zwijn! You got her pregnant.
But I'll take care of it.
I'l do you a favour.
Know what you're gonna do?
Write me a positive report on Yaya
and we'll forget all about it.
No! That's no good!
You need to be more lyrical.
More praise.
I'm sorry, I'm stressed.
I can't doit.
I'l dictate, you type.
- Sure they won't get out?
- Don't worry.
"Young Koné...
"combines..."
No. "This magnificent player
combines...
"endurance and strength.
"Furthermore, he is able
"to score with both feet.
"The left and the right."
Are you here for a while?
Want a drink?
Ah, darling,
I invited your friend's friends in.
This is my husband, Koen.
Hello.
I was saying that this weekend,
we could take them
to the Christmas fair.
Oh, yes, yes...
You should go.
It's very nice. Yes.
There's a stall
with a shop
where they make puddings.
Very good ones.
There's one
with brown-sugar biscuit.
Brown sugar...
Do you know it?
Do you have that in Cote d'Ivoire?
It's very good.
Here, a present for you.
To celebrate you joining the Zebras.
You like them?
Try them on.
Break them in.
30,000 spectators.
- This is Yaya's ultrasound.
- Ultrasound?
He has a ventricular hypertrophy.
So what?
There's a risk of heart attack
when under duress.
It may happen tomorrow, or never.
- Give me percentages!
- 10, 12%.
Have you seen
how many millions we owe?
He's our golden fleece!
And you say:
"He may have a heart attack."
Please!
We're running the same risk.
The bills give me a heart attack.
It's a life we're talking about.
My granddad had the same thing.
He's still alive.
If he was my son...
We need to make money!
Doctor, he's not your son.
- Anyway...
- What? He's Black?
- I didn't say that.
- You thought it.
That's it. I've decided. It's over.
You want to kill him?
Stop him playing.
If he doesn't play,
he'll shoot himself.
He ate every other day at home.
Now he eats every day
and feeds 40 people in Africa.
Now make your decision.
Tell him he can't play
because of his heart.
Ethically speaking...
Ethics don't feed anyone!
Forget it!
Tell him why he's not playing.
Because of this?
He'll laugh in your face!
José, calm down.
Can he decide for himself?
He must be sure.
His life is in danger.
I'l explain it to him.
OK, Coach?
Is there a problem?
- He's OK.
- This is just the start.
You'd make a silk purse
out of a sow's ear.
Get on the bonnet with the chairman.
With my player.
Look this way!
Show us the car keys.
Thank you, chairman.
This way! Yayal
We have a problem.
Someone says
he's signed Yaya.
- He'd have to go through me.
- OK, then.
Tomorrow, fax me your contract.
I don't have one.
I work on trust.
On trust?
You're crazy.
Well?
I told him...
Is there a problem?
Excuse me.
Coach, I'm sorry.
Why? I wanted a bastard.
You are one.
When were you gonna tell me?
When?
Hello?
Abdou, it's Yaya.
All right?
Yes, not too bad.
Not too bad.
- And you?
- Fine.
I'm at the market buying oranges.
Yes, it's good.
I've seen show.
Yes, it's pretty.
Very pretty.
Send me some snow.
You want a Playstation or snow?
- Both.
- You want everything?
Abdou, they gave me a car.
But the pedals are wrong.
There's only two.
Check it out. There are three.
There's only two, I tell you!
And the gears are just letters.
What letters?
P,R,NandD.
- R must mean run.
- And P is pray?
If Ris run, P is pray.
dio!
What?
Give them to someone.
They're new.
- Is it him?
- What's left of him.
Not much.
That's why
you shouldn't play with it.
I'l take his ashes
to his home village.
Koné is a Muslim name.
The imam will cut off your balls!
- Hello, boss.
- Hello.
- You're selling?
- Yeah.
- How much?
- 150.
1507? And this one?
It's already sold.
That one too.
I've got 100.
- No. 120.
- I've only got 100.
- 110.
- Come down to 100.
- Close it and put it in the car.
- What about the body?
You can't wash shirts.
What, and you can?
Yes. You can't wash anything.
Abdou!
Would you like to be my assistant?
It's not difficult.
You go to Yopougon.
Watch the match, like before.
Spot the best players.
Take their parents' number
and I'm there.
It'd be good.
You'd be my scout.
It's a good job.
You're made for the role.
You've got good instincts.
- Don't you want to?
- No.
It's white man's work.
- Can you call her?
- And say what?
She knows my number.
If you call her, it's different.
She's busy.
She'll call you later.
Be patient.
Gigi's different with you.
She talks about you fondly.
Not like the others.
We've been together 3 years.
Why doesn't she tell me?
It's hard for ex-streetwalkers
to feel love.
Do you love Gigi?
Yeah.
Really?
Then teach her to love you.
Really teach her.
Push it into position.
There, like that.
Other side. That's it.
Thank you.
Hey, Mum!
Who's that in the box?
Our eldest son.
We're taking him back to the village.
What about the little one inside?
It's a boy.
Whitey's the dad.
Congratulations!
I said you discovered Aruna Dindane.
The stiff's shitting rice!
Mr Koné, José Stockman.
We met at the airport, remember?
Yaya is dead.
I'm sorry.
What did he say?
Does he want to kill me?
No. He said to kill a goat.
Welcome!
He was well liked.
This is a big paper.
The new jewel of Charleroi
God bless you!
For the good life
you gave to Yaya.
He thanks you for everything
you did for his son.
- No!
- Leave it! Look.
- We can't leave him...
- He's fine there.
To Serge and Bibo