(Commotion)
Gilbert, I don't have it.
-It's not true ?
-In 25 years,
I have never forgotten a corkscrew.
-Promise, I won't say it.
-Thank you.
-Christian? The crane.
-Yes I know.
(Cadenced music)
-51 meters high.
This crane can lift
up to 100 tonnes!
One hundred tonnes of containers
to unload ships.
-BRAVO !
-This crane
is three million euros!
-Four.
-I'm told four.
-AH YES.
-Financed
40%
from the Languedoc-Roussillon region.
-Occitanie.
- Sorry, no, no. Occitanie!
-AH ANYWAY !
-40% by the general council
of the eastern Pyrenees!
40% by the ...
-No, because here we are at 120%.
-Ah, well yes.
And at 20% by the
Perpignan Chamber of Commerce , in charge
port management.
I now declare open
the crane's inauguration
ceremony!
(Applause)
-Thank you.
(Whispers)
-And There you go !
(Clamor)
-Thank you.
-My dear friends, this crane,
unique, is able to lift everything.
All ! Except our glasses.
(Laughs)
I now appeal
to the essentials, let's raise our glasses!
And for that,
I invite you to join
the buffet with confidence.
(Brouhaha)
-You saw the mayor
for the inauguration?
"Yes, the pride of Port-Vendres,
"a 51 meter high crane!
"Huh, Milene, Milene ..."
-Wait, I'm doing Milene.
"I'm coming, Mr. Mayor, I'm coming!"
-Milene!
-Wait, I have something to say.
-AH.
-I have something to tell you.
So what's going on?
-Oh, Christian!
-What?
-It's homemade,
I just finished.
-You don't have any other
boxes in your freezer
homemade?
(Laughs)
There's Jean-Mi,
and that's why we're here,
celebrating the end
of his nervous breakdown!
-YES!
-Thank you.
-go, JEAN-MI!
JEAN-MI! JEAN-MI!
-But Jean-Mi, you too!
Looked !
-I walked in.
-Shit, that brings good luck.
(Laughs)
-It's true that it's better.
I feel it !
I used to cry for nothing.
All this is over.
I feel depression ...
is behind me.
-Jean-Mi is healed!
-YES!
JEAN-MI! JEAN-MI! JEAN-MI!
-She has a face.
- For the moment,
no boat to unload.
Those who come
already have their crane!
-But it's a region
that has projects.
As an elected official, it is useless to carry out
projects, it is enough to have them.
(Laughs)
By the way, Mr. Mayor.
-Yes ?
-What's up ?
-For ?
-You were not committed
to reduce the staff of the town hall?
-Is that so ? Menard?
-It becomes clearer. We are going to ...
We're going to strangle them.
- Can't we wait for
the elections?
We elected, we are still there
to be re-elected.
(Laughs)
-But, Mayor, I
promise, I promise.
-Ah yes.
-let's go to the crane!
-TO THE CRANE.
-What is that ?
-It's weird.
It's the same, but it's not the same.
-I dunno.
-Something is missing.
-Thierry ?
-Yes, my Michel?
(He moans.)
What is it?
(he whispers)
- What is it?
-What?
-What's this ?
Speak !
-I do not understand.
-Wait, I did taekwondo.
I'm a good one!
-It's okay.
-Thierry, you can mess around
on women and rugby,
on your homemade frozen dishes,
but never on Ricard!
You will not kiss us on the Ricard!
-Speak !
Before it's too late.
He can be stupid, and so can I!
If we start with 2,
you will believe that we are 3.
-I know.
It's not pastis 51.
It's pastis 45!
-It's not true ?
- You never do it again!
You never do that to us!
Six degrees?
In the yellow,
it's like at NASA,
within 6 degrees,
you miss the goal!
-Six degrees lower,
you're targeting Cahors, you're farting Limoges.
-We have no room for error.
-NO.
-You know
what the town hall is preparing for us?
Lay off people.
We won't let it happen.
The revolt rumbles.
The fight is getting ready!
(He sings)
It's the fight
Finale
Let's get together and tomorrow
The International
Will be the human race
-I didn't introduce
Frédéric Lambert from BIC.
-The what?
-The Catalan Industrial Bank.
- Sir.
-My regards.
I introduce you
my wife, Céline.
- My tributes, madam.
You're charming.
-Thank you.
-She often comes to rest
on our sailboat.
-It's so relaxing,
so peaceful ...
Sometimes a little long,
especially in the evening.
-Ah yes, that is loneliness.
I will come to see you.
Finally, see your boat,
because I love sailing.
-You cross out?
-All the time.
Finally, as soon as possible.
I love tillers,
straight bars, very solid.
Finally, the bars, what.
-Me too.
-Here, there.
I suggest you taste
these famous mini-pizzas
of Thierry, on the quay.
-Thank you.
-It's homemade.
Please, Mr. Mayor.
With me...
-I'm not hungry anymore.
-We do the prawn dance?
-YES!
- I'm going to get my guitar.
-NON !
-But, you,
I'm doing taekwondo.
-Get out of here !
-XO, XO, HI, HI.
(They chuckle.)
-Let's go !
(Clamor)
-THREE FOUR.
- THIS IS THE DANCE OF THE GAMBAS
IN SKEWERS
LIKE SHEEP
PALAM PAM PAM
IT'S THE DANCE OF THE GAMBAS
MOUTH FULL, FULL HAND
It's disgusting
PALAM PAM PAM
-WE ARE ...
-GAMBAS!
- WE ARE ... -
KINDS!
-Are we fish
?
-NO NO NO !
-Are we
lobsters?
-WE HAVE NO DART
-Are we old
crabs?
-WE WANT RAB
- NO TENTACLE OCTOPUS
HOW DO YOU WANT ...
- THAT I GO BACK
PALAM PAM PAM
IT'S THE DANCE OF THE GAMBAS
MOUTH FULL, FULL HAND
It's disgusting
PALAM PAM PAM
WE ARE...
-It's homemade!
(Hubbub)
-WE ARE ...
-GAMBAS!
-Very beautiful house.
-Ah yes, really, very beautiful.
-Thank you.
So, I don't know
if you saw the terrace,
but the stainless steel posts
were welded by hand,
old.
-By the municipal, I hope?
-You are never better served
than by yourself.
-During working hours?
-Of course.
-Of course. There are some leaders,
but they have a good background.
Ah, Madame Lambert!
Have you seen my posts?
-Stainless steel posts!
Welded by hand, I love it.
- By hand, I love it.
(Laughs)
Huh, Mayor?
-Are you doing well, Ménard?
-Please have
a moment of attention.
-Wait, there is Gilbert
who wants to speak. Listen to Gilbert!
-Thank you, Christian.
-I will help you. Oh, silence,
there is Gilbert who wants to speak.
-So ...
-I have something to say before.
Good news, that's it,
the union office,
he connected us.
La "wify" marche.
-AH !
-We will vote
for the trip with the union.
We have 2 options.
Or a 3-day stay in Paris,
with a visit to the Louvre,
Eiffel Tower,
Sacré-Coeur, finally ...
With Paris,
with the air of Paris, gray weather,
pollution ... Paris, what!
Either 3 days in Perthus,
with its snow-capped mountains,
its clean air, its zero-rated Ricard,
and his daughters who are waiting
to get the purses.
We go to the vote,
who is for Perthus?
-YES!
-For the 6th consecutive year,
Perthus was adopted
unanimously.
-YES!
-Yes!
-We can't do anything about it,
it's democracy.
-My mother said to me:
"If you like this Vero that much,
"you have to marry her.
"Because at Lavergne,
we are clean.
"We get married, and then we go to bed."
The problem is that...
she's from Port-Vendres
, I'm from Collioure ...
I tell myself that love
can erase this difference,
but there are several kilometers.
At least three.
-If you think she's the woman
of your life, marry her.
-There is no other anyway.
You just have to know
if we're going well together.
-Are you kidding or what, Gilbert?
Already, I will tell you,
physically, you are on top.
After that, what remains?
Intellectually?
Intellectually, you are ...
How to tell you, you are ...
You are the same, that's it.
No, I mean,
you will get no better
than this Vero, I think.
* - We sheath, we draw.
We sheath, we draw.
Yes, that's good, Vero, like that.
Very hard on the buttocks. It's coming.
We draw, we sheath.
-In any case,
I put more than 36.
-A 36 maybe,
but who is suffering, Vero, huh?
* -Go girls, let's go down.
Always lower.
She sneers.
-Oh there, it's not a thong,
it is a wire for cutting butter.
It's a fat cutting wire!
(Laughs)
* -And we believe in it.
We spread our thighs well, Vero.
Yes that's it !
-But that's what we dream of.
(To laugh)
- It makes me think that Sunday,
I'm going to make a blank.
Are you okay, Solange?
The reflections?
When I see you, I tell myself
that I'm going to do a stew.
Or veal.
In sauce.
And why are you here?
It is
the town hall dance class .
And you are a baker!
-I have an exemption.
My brother-in-law,
who was a municipal employee,
died on duty.
-Is it working, cirrhosis,
in a work accident?
( Vero laughter .) * -Hush, hush, ladies.
We left. We sheath again.
On sheath. On sheath again.
It is English.
(They chuckle.)
I'm fine, Miss Perec,
are you comfortable?
This outfit
is more for the death of the swan.
-There is the capture of the duck.
(Laughs)
* -Go, we finish
as usual, on 5 pumps.
Let's go.
(Techno music)
And one...
-But my breasts are cupping.
*-And two...
-The couple is a team,
an osmosis, a complementarity.
It's a harmony, that's it.
The couple is a harmony.
Oh shit, it closed!
Damn, damn, bitch.
What did I tell you?
-You were in harmony.
-Here, the couple
is a harmony.
Sweetheart !
-Yes, it's closed.
-She is angry
because she doesn't know
how to tell me I love you.
-Here !
- Apparently, she figured out
how to say I love you.
Well see you tomorrow.
-Yes, hi, Gilbert!
I'm going,
because the evening is going to be ...
It is normal,
it is necessary, sometimes.
Sweetheart ?
It's me, it's Christian.
-Skates.
-How do you know
I don't have skates?
Your back is turned.
-based on the Noise.
We respect the soil.
It's the tiling
to Mom.
-It is true that he is pretty,
tiling for mom.
-Do not overdo it.
What do you think this is?
-Bah, that,
it's suitcases.
-Bravo, you're in good shape.
And what do you deduce from this?
-I dunno.
-I leave.
And after ?
-After "I'm leaving"? Well, you're leaving,
he leaves,
we leave, you leave ...
-I'm leaving you.
-I leave you, you leave me,
he leaves us ...
Are you leaving me?
Ghislaine, you?
But wait,
think, look at yourself.
I mean,
that's more what it was.
In my opinion, you will find nobody.
Or else, you
must have cash in common.
I don't want to be pessimistic ...
-Salaud, go!
-Here.
Women, you want the truth,
and afterwards you moan.
(Sigh)
-Ah!
-My crib!
My crib!
-You inflate us, with your crib!
A communist who makes a manger.
It's ridiculous.
With a train!
In Palestine, moreover!
-The train
is a tribute to the SNCF.
-You mouth,
is this a tribute to bullshit?
-Sweetheart ?
-Do not touch me !
I'm stuck from the back.
-Damn !
Ah, Mayor!
(Veroic laughter.)
Yes, I will tell them.
Please excuse me,
I just got the mayor
on the phone,
he is on his way.
(Clamours of relief)
-Another one who was taken
for his skills.
-She does 95 F in skills.
-And 36 in general culture.
(Laughs)
-Menard, faster,
I have to celebrate a marriage.
(Laughs)
-Mr. the Mayor, the pourou!
The pourou!
-Oh no !
-LE POUROU.
-LE POUROU, LE POUROU.
-So, the pourou,
if you don't know,
you drop it
directly into your mouth.
But as I am
very strong ...
-Oh yes, you're strong.
-It falls on the head,
runs down the nose
and then it ends up in the mouth.
Attention,
we often have our faces full.
-It reminds me of something!
-Is that so ?
-Ah yes, full face! Go ahead !
(Hoarse laughs)
Looked.
-Shit !
-Well then?
-I stained it!
-So ?
-So what ?
-Do we know more?
-Sure ?
-The noise that runs.
-Wait, it's confirmed.
We are talking about a cart
of 30 early retirements.
More moral harassment, the total.
But here we are.
-You are too strong.
-I know.
(Tire screeching)
-He's there !
That's it, there it is.
(Sighs relieved)
(Horns)
Youhou!
We are here !
-Another girl from Port-Vendres
who leaves for Collioure.
They seek to depopulate us.
Collioure has stretched out his nets.
-So,
they don't just fish anchovies,
in Collioure.
-They also catch tunas.
(Laughs)
-With red eyes!
-It's bluefin tuna.
-Stop,
she could hear us.
-But I hear everything.
Bitch!
Someone knocked.
-Ah, Milene!
-Mr. the mayor.
-Ah, but they are there!
There is a lot of people. Okay okay !
-What is this shirt?
-It's good, it's nothing.
Good evening.
Ah !
Bah, sit down, huh.
So,
we're not going to be pissed off
at the start.
So, under the powers
conferred on me, I ...
It is with great joy
and a certain honor
that I'm going to ask you
the fateful question.
M. Gilbert Lavergne,
do you accept to take for wife
Miss Véronique Lafarge,
here present?
-I think.
-Ah no.
No, we don't say: "I think".
-I believe ?
-No more.
No no.
We say yes!
-Yes.
-Here ! To you.
Miss Véronique Lafarge,
do you agree to take as a spouse
Mr. Gilbert Lavergne, here present?
-I think I believe it.
-Ah not!
-I think I think so.
-Non !
Okay, come on, uh, yes.
Huh? Here.
-Yes.
-So, under powers,
I declare you husband and wife.
So traditionally,
the town hall of Port-Vendres
has joy ... What?
Huh? Ah shit!
-Normally, the city offers you
a liter of olive oil,
but we don't have any more.
You will take it next year ...
for divorce.
(Laughs)
- Okay, come on.
Uh ... sorry.
I'm exhausted, I'm going to ...
Come on.
-And this shirt?
-It's fashionable. It's nothing.
Good evening,
rest well, see you later.
(The door slams.)
-My brothers, my friends, my children,
you are always welcome
in the house of Christ.
Let’s sit down, my brothers.
We will now be
able to sing. Solange?
(He gives the note.)
Three, four.
-GOD IS LOVE
GOD IS MY JOY
I MUST IN HER WORSHIP
SPLIT MY JOY
IMMACULATE OF LOVE
IMMACULATE OF FAITH
-I have in his worship to
burst my joy
-Thank you, Solange.
Let us stand up, my brothers.
(Laughter)
All together.
Three four.
-GOD IS LOVE
GOD IS MY JOY
I HAVE IN HIS
CULT TO EXPLORE MY JOY
IMMACULATE OF LOVE
IMMACULATE OF FAITH
I MUST IN HER WORSHIP
SPLIT MY JOY
-God is love...
-Let’s sit down, my brothers.
I am going now
to be able to bless this union.
Pablo ?
(He quibbles in Latin.)
Maurice ?
You, Gilbert,
do you want to take Véronique
for wife?
-Yes.
-And you, Véronique,
do you want to take Gilbert
as a husband?
(Growling)
-Yes.
-I declare you united
by the bonds of marriage.
For eternity.
Kiss you.
Go in peace.
All go
in the peace of Christ.
Maurice ?
Music.
("E Viva Espana"
Georgette Plana)
(Bells are ringing.)
-LIVE THE BRIDGES!
(Acclamations)
-It's stupid
to swing grass, right?
-And your friends
who rock chlorine?
-It's beautiful, all these municipal people.
-We're taking care of it, Mr. Mayor.
The supervisory ministry is formal and
will have to start skimming.
Skim, Mr. Mayor.
We're going to degrease the mammoth.
It starts tomorrow.
-Tomorrow?
Ménard, can't we wait for
the Municipal ones?
-Impossible,
modernity is on the march!
- On the march ... On the march towards what?
-Welcome to you all,
for the wedding
from my son, Gilbert.
-Ah, his Titounet.
-Thanks thanks.
Have a good evening and have fun!
-And everything is homemade!
(Laughs)
-Yes of course ! We all saw
the packaging on the way out.
Ah, how I put her!
Ah, but are you reading, Michel?
-It's Philo magazine.
-Philo magazine?
-Yes, I am subscribed.
(He whistles.)
It's because of the Internet.
I wanted to subscribe
at Fishing Trolling magazine,
but my finger snapped
and I checked Philo.
So, I read it.
-And then, what does that say?
-This week is:
"The ego is a fiction".
-But lego,
lego, the game? Because I love it.
-Here is a song
from my composition, in English,
because yes, I write in English.
I write a little
in all languages.
Italy inspired me
with beautiful melodies,
Africa, wild rhythms.
Cette chanson s'appelle :
"Oh wast to win".
-Wast to win.
-Oh wast to win
Oh win wast
And come to be
To be away
-He ensures, in English, Rémy.
-The Rock it's English.
It's like the pool.
It is English.
"On, off".
The pool broom. "On, off".
And "Full" when the basket is full.
"Full" means full.
-I won't be long to be full.
(Laughs)
-Hop hop, no stories.
I want you in working order.
My body is a youth center
with many workshops.
And...
they are all open.
(Growl)
(Laughter)
-Gilbert!
-And come to be
To be away
(Applause)
Thanks thanks.
And now a slow.
I will ask the newlyweds
to open the ball.
- Come on.
(Cheers)
(Soft music)
I want you.
I want to ... from your body.
-We're going to eat first, huh?
-We will eat, my chick.
We will eat. We will eat!
We'll eat everything, huh?
Huh, chick?
(He moans.)
Excuse me, with the warmth,
I have the deformation that turns.
-Ah no, I ...
It smells good, the deodorant that turns.
- Don't force yourself, come on.
With the heat, I know,
I have sweat that smells of urine.
You see, sometimes I tell myself
that I pissed myself on it,
and in fact not!
I just have sweaty hands.
- Wait for me, Vero!
(Disgusted sigh)
Come on, Vero.
I will make you dream.
-Bah, Gilbert ?
What is it, Gilbert?
It doesn't seem to be going.
-She scares me.
-What?
-I don't feel it.
-You make me laugh,
we had to deal with it before.
You said yes.
-At church I was going to say no.
-But why did you say yes?
-I saw,
they had prepared couscous ...
Hats, all that,
costs money.
-Don't worry, it'll work out.
The couple is the habit.
The couple is an osmosis.
-Are you with Gisou?
-Gisou, right now, she is ...
(He is snarling.)
a bit like that.
"Paquito"
(Acclamations)
-Ole!
-Olé!
-Hey, ho!
(Brouhaha)
-Calm, calm!
Gently, oh!
-It's my little one!
-Hey, hey, hey!
-Ole!
-Are we going, Gilbert?
-I will take couscous.
-We're going, I'm telling you.
It will be royal, couscous.
Well served, with meat.
(Growl)
-Oh sorry.
(Acclamations)
- I suspected
that you were a little drunk.
And as we suspected,
that you would be drunk,
it's me, who brings everyone back.
-Go, Michel!
-Go!
-So ?
(Buzz)
-Ah not,
it's Kevin who will bring us back.
(Acclamations)
-KEVIN! KEVIN!
KEVIN! KEVIN! KEVIN!
-Go, on the way!
-KEVIN! KEVIN!
(Bips)
-It's good, my little rabbit.
(To laugh)
(Acclamations)
-HE IS REALLY...
HE IS REALLY...
IT IS REALLY PHENOMENAL
LA LA LA LA LA
LA LA LA LA LA LA
GO KEVIN!
GO!
GO KEVIN! GO!
-You don't carry me?
-what ?
-Like in the movies.
-What movies?
-De Valte.
-Valte?
-Valte Disney.
Princess
in the sleeping wood,
with the diadarème.
-Ah yes.
-Mmh?
-I weigh the pros and cons and ...
there is against, finally ...
Come on!
(He moans.)
Fucking whore whore!
-Well, it's nice!
(Alarm)
* -The code is 43-43.
(Buzz)
(He sighs.)
(Groans of effort)
-More...
Are you there, Maurice?
-Well, yes, this
is my parents' hotel.
There, I keep it,
since they are at ... a wedding!
It's ... what's their name?
It's Gilbert and Véro
who get married.
-Are you stupid or what?
We were there !
-Is that so ?
There, the newlyweds will not delay,
I'm waiting for them.
The bedroom is over there.
You have ... How to say?
At 12.43 m, there is a staircase.
And 8.43 m after, the bedroom.
Number 12 and a half.
-He is boring with his measurements.
Why 12 and a half?
-Because in hotels,
room 13, it brings bad luck.
So my parents, they said to themselves,
so as not to lose a room,
they will do the 12 and a half
Because my father at first
said to my mother ...
-Go ahead, Guingamp!
Damn, there's the whole team.
12 and a half?
-12 and a half, 12 and a half.
(Someone knocked.)
-Gilbert ?
-Why are you there?
-To see if it's okay.
-Yes, for the moment, it's okay,
she's calm.
-She is beautiful !
-She scares me !
-But she's bleeding!
Did you hit it?
-I didn't feel anything.
It looks like a dead trout.
-Yes because...
she has red eyes.
Okay, Gilbert, you gotta go.
-Did you see how
she protrudes from the bed?
(Grunts)
Oh fuck ! She scares me.
-Gilbert, you said yes.
-I said yes...
-You said yes.
-No, I think.
-Gilbert !
- Come on, I'm going.
-Do not go !
-Hey ! You make her dream, huh?
You make him fart point G.
I'm going. Do not be afraid.
-Don't go far, stay behind.
-I stay here.
If there is a problem, you call me.
If it's okay, you sing.
Do you know any songs?
-"Capri is over" ?
-But to say "It starts".
-So, "Capri is starting"?
-Okay. I'm behind.
- Don't close!
-Yes.
-Leave a light
in the corridor. I am scared.
(Vero sighs.)
-Oh, Gilbert.
Oh, my little Gilbert!
My Chick !
Ours !
-Do you prefer that
we discuss before?
-My ass, yes!
Three years of fallow
and you want to chat?
Come over here,
you're gonna get the tractor out
and plow the plot.
-You must plow, Gilbert!
-Yes, I'm going to stuff it!
-I will eat your body.
(He moans.)
-Gilbert, I turn off the light.
-No !
-Yes, thoroughly!
Come on, put the package.
-Capri, it starts!
-And Long live Spain
Oh, Ghislaine?
But don't you sleep?
-Skates.
-Oh, the skates, the skates ...
(She sighs.)
It's okay ?
-I'm getting the rooster.
It calms the pain.
So, I love it.
-Go ahead, polish!
After, it will be my turn!
(He's laughing.)
-Very funny.
-I'm coming back from the hotel, that's it.
Gilbert and Véro,
he is looking for his G-spot.
-It will take time.
-Why do you say that ?
-Because
you never found mine.
-How did you ever find that?
Didn't you enjoy?
-Titounet?
It's mom, my Titounet.
Open up!
-Darling, it struck.
-It's mom.
(She knocks.)
Titounet?
-You go back to bed!
And you shut up,
that's how we like you.
Yes ?
All is well, mother-in-law!
-Everything is fine ?
(Relieved sigh)
Does it give you pleasure?
-Yes, and vice versa.
Especially for the moment,
but hey ...
-You find it
good ?
-Yes.
- Size level,
he is normal ?
-Yes.
-It works ?
-The drawbridge, are you okay?
Say it now.
When you have damaged it,
it will be too late.
Sorry, but I'm going to finish Titounet.
-Is that so ?
(She shouts.)
Go ahead, Gilbert!
Give him his race, big thing!
Gilbert screams.
-Ghislaine,
if you love me,
give me a sign.
-And, well!
I'm giving you a sign!
-So you kick me out of my house?
-We bought with
my parents' money , it's my home.
-But still !
-That's enough !
-the washing machine,
mom paid for it.
-She does pilling.
-And the garage?
Who paid for the wood, the cement,
the glue?
-It's the town hall!
-Well, there you go !
If I didn't work at the town hall,
we would have paid for it.
And the wrought iron gate,
I did it!
It's my garage.
-Thank you. Since that's it,
go live there, in your garage!
-I can take
part of Lourdes?
-Yes, and don't forget
the crib that goes with it!
Good night, go to the garage!
-Oh, damn, Christian!
Christian, you're here!
Oh, Christian, Christian,
Christian, you rae here !
-But what is it?
-He disappeared !
-Who has disappeared ?
-My chick, Titounet!
-Titounet disappeared?
-But I tell you!
We were screaming in the dark ...
you see ?
-Yes.
-Especially me.
I was trying to enjoy.
-Yes !
-And suddenly,
I dozed off, and nothing!
When I woke up, he had run away!
-What do you mean ?
But before, you had ...
-But no !
-I do not believe !
A guy who hit the church
and the paella, he stays to fuck.
After the worst,
he waits for the best.
Have there been any signs before?
-But no.
Oh yes !
(Broken glasses)
Yes, you know, he was shaking.
And he squeaked too.
Like a wet dog
afraid of the fox.
(Little squeaks)
-You do well the wet dog
who is afraid.
-And he sang.
Capri is over !
-It's normal,
I told her to sing,
it's a code.
Speaking of "It's over",
this is a finished step.
Are you okay, Michel?
-You have red eyes,
Vero.
Stops chlorine.
-It's not chlorine!
-It's not chlorine.
-What's this ?
-Titounet has disappeared.
He left, he fled.
-Titounet is gone?
-Yes.
-Véro!
Don't be afraid,
we will find you!
We will find Titounet!
-The news is not good.
Ménard and his gang,
they've finished their audit,
they want to degrease the mammoth.
-Degrease the mammoth?
Do n't worry, do you know what we're going to do?
I called Paris,
we're going to organize a movement.
And we will win!
-And we will win.
- THIS IS THE FINAL FIGHT
Let's get together and tomorrow
THE INTERNATIONAL
- WILL BE THE HUMAN GENDER -
Will be the human gender
It's read ...
-Michel?
You said "human son-in-law",
that's not it.
He said "human son-in-law"!
The human race !
-No, it's "son-in-law"!
I know the song !
-But no, it's "like".
-It's "gender"!
-You haven't finished!
-It's the final fight
Let's get together and tomorrow
L'Internationale
-Vas-y, vas-y.
-Will be human-in-law!
I tell you, it's "son-in-law"
You're annoying!
I know the song, anyway!
-Do not hesitate,
Mr. Mayor.
One clean, precise shot. Paris...
Paris supports us.
We are cutting down on the public service.
Did you see what they did?
SNCF, France Telecom ... pfft!
We fire!
I got a call from the prefecture.
Fire!
Paris...
we observe with a magnifying glass.
-Never.
-Moreover, it is said
that your name is circulating in Paris.
Finally, would circulate ...
for a national mission.
-Is that so ?
-See a national function.
Missiste.
-Menisse?
-Minèstre.
- Minister?
-Minister.
-Minister?
But we're going to fuck them outside, yes!
How ? Uh, 40?
-Thirty. If we start with that,
we are precursors.
And Paris will thank you.
Firing people is modern,
You have to put pressure on the employee, make
him want to leave.
Large companies have done this
successfully.
They rotted the atmosphere,
result:
lots of voluntary departures.
You have to break them down,
make them psychological rags
of sub-men,
firmness, Minister.
-Thank you, Mr. Chef de Cabinet!
Yes, Milene?
-It's coffee.
-Thank you.
-Mr. The Minister.
She did Sciences Po.
-Yes, 5 years old.
Five times in the 1st year.
(Laughs)
- "Your coffee, Mr. Mayor."
-You forget the lips.
-Attends.
-It's for my file.
-The neckline,
when she leans.
- Must see well.
-Up to the hairs.
(Laughs)
- Go ahead, call
me a whore, too.
-Of ?
-The stink.
-Why do you say that ?
-You will laugh less
once on the list.
-The list, but which list?
-And my file?
-He is waiting his turn!
-I am alone.
-THAT'S ENOUGH !
-The list of voluntary departures.
-But from where?
-Of town hall ?
-Of town hall.
- Stop, we're inviting.
-They talk about 20 or 30 departures.
They want to sicken people.
-Wait, Milene, talk,
we're colleagues!
And we are even friends.
-Is that so ? As I have breasts
that plic-plic
and the buttocks that plop-ploc,
I did not quite hear.
(Suspenseful music)
-Do you think he's there?
-Yes, he loves this corner.
You'll see, he's going to go out.
(He imitates an animal cry.)
(He imitates a crying baby.)
-How, love? Gilbert?
Gilbert, get out of there,
everyone is worried.
- Get out of there, Gilbert!
I brought couscous.
It's Blackfoot,
they can't resist it.
-Mmh! Gilbert!
-Come on, Michel.
-It's good, couscous to mom!
Come, Gilbert!
Gilbert, get out of there!
-Did you eat his couscous?
-Non.
-Didn't you eat it?
-No why ?
-I dunno. Come on!
Come,
he's going out.
Look at him. Look at him !
Look at him, I told you!
Look at him.
-It's beautiful.
It looks like an isard at the stream.
Go ahead, my little doe, drink.
-Did you eat couscous?
-Stop, you're painful.
-Look at him.
-She scares me.
-Go, eat your couscous.
Swallow the seed, swallow.
- Swallow, Titounet.
It's good.
He's a Titounet.
A Titounet to his dad.
-Usually, mom,
she puts dumplings
in the couscous.
-Well, there, she did not wear one.
-Gilbert, relax.
It's never that a problem
sexual, it gets better,
it's temporary.
-I don't think so.
A starting couple
to kiss more,
it fucks more at all.
-No, at one point, it starts again.
-She scares me.
With her big voice, she said,
"I'm going to eat your body."
We do not say so.
-No.
-No, it does not say, my Titounet.
A part of the body, yes,
but not the body.
-A part, yes. Ah yes, a part!
-Eat, my Titounet.
-Apart, yes?
-Yes.
Calm down, Titounet.
But no, there is nothing.
Come on, let's go home, Gilbert.
Come on, let's go back, huh?
-Okay.
(Soft music)
-People are bastards!
They throw fridges
anywhere!
-Wait, I'll help you, Michel.
-Go!
And Titounet?
He would not come to help us?
-You saw the night it had,
Titounet?
-Yes, Titounet is tired!
Huh? Titounet
is Catherine Deneuve!
-Go, one, two, three ...
-SUN.
-I like it
when the job is done.
Thank you, Catherine.
This time again,
we have preserved the planet well.
- Fortunately,
there are guys like us.
You see, Gilbert,
the garbage truck has broken down, well
, we have ideas.
-Jean-Mi ?
Jean-Mi ?
Crissements
Jean-Mi !
-What is happening ?
-He doesn't look good.
-The tramontana has risen,
all the leaves are gone.
-It's the relapse,
he comes to us.
-You say what, Michel?
(Klaxons)
Un burn-out ! Coming out,
is when a homo reveals himself
to all those who already knew it.
That's it !
-Ah yes.
-A burnout, he farted a cable.
You're not going out
6 months of sick leave like that.
Not at work.
You need
psychological assistance.
-It would require the shrink of the town hall.
She speaks in his office
and he snorts.
-How many times
I said to Ménard:
"Send us
the town hall psychologist!"
-Wind. It's the wind.
(Horns)
-Yes, Jean-Mi.
-In the beginning,
it advanced 2.43 m,
then fell 1.43 m.
-You inflate us with your figures.
It is painful.
-He came from the front.
(Horns and protests)
The headwind, and there ...
-Are you moving there?
(Police sirens)
-Yes, yes, excuse me!
(Horns)
-Oh, that's fine!
-Jean-Mi relapses.
-We have an emergency too.
-We are going to Weldom,
they have planchas at - 28%.
-Why - 28%?
-Because we're on the 28th.
- It's stupid that we're not the 35th!
Because there would have been
more reduction.
And the 35th of the month, it does not exist.
If we don't understand the valves ...
It is not serious.
Let's go !
-Go!
-Hop!
It goes!
Sirens
Hop, hop, hop, hop, hop!
(Horns)
You shine at the bottom, at the bottom!
It's good, it goes!
It's good, come on!
-Mr. the mayor ?
-I said to myself :
"This poor woman,
all alone, who is bored.
"The mayor can't tolerate this."
Look, I have two.
-I love to eat it.
Come in.
-In all honor.
-Of course.
-So, Mrs. Véro, what is
this noise that runs?
Are there voluntary departures?
-We're talking about it, yes.
But we are going to fight,
the union is there.
-I hope he's there.
Since the time he trained,
the union!
- Their local paid by the town hall,
it became a tapas bar.
And we pay charges.
-We say that,
we are in the private sector.
I only make a living
if I work, it's different.
When I say win,
the term is strong,
this year, we made - 30%.
-The same.
Minus 30%.
-For 10 years
you have been doing - 30% every year.
Do you continue to work
for - 300%?
You like your work, well done!
-Hello !
-It's Halloween all year round.
Do lessons end at 11 am?
-It's not lessons,
it's sports.
-We wonder
what the teachers are doing.
-They are on vacation
or they are preparing their vacation.
(Laughs)
-For you, the private sector,
are you working?
Are the officials lazy?
-I have one.
This is a teacher who is very sick,
the doctor said to him: "You only have
two months to live".
And the teacher answers:
"Can I have July and August?"
-Well I'm leaving.
-And in fact,
What do I use you for?
-What are you serving me?
You’re useless,
Solange !
-Marades, the hour is serious.
Yolande, hurry up,
we have a job.
I brought down Georges-Paul
from the national section of the union.
in order to define together
a strategy
to fight against the oppression
of the employers who oppress us.
-I introduce myself, Georges-Paul.
My parents, already,
were activists.
They called me that
in tribute to Georges Marchais.
And Paul, for Paul Éluard.
-Me, they called me Jean-Mi
in tribute to Jean-Michel Jarre.
-And me, Jean-Louis.
In tribute to Jean-Louis David,
the hairdresser.
-I'm Gilbert,
in tribute to Gilbert Bécaud.
-Me, Michel,
in tribute to Jacques Brel.
-It does not work.
-If his parents wanted
to call him Michel,
but Michel Brel,
it ended the same.
-It's true that it doesn't work
when it ends the same.
Céline Dion is not called Marion,
because Marion Dion,
it's been boiled,
we don't understand well.
-I think the news
from Paris is disturbing.
-Very.
The government has plans
for dark cuts.
Especially in the public service.
To break the official.
Did you see what they did
to the SNCF?
-We are going to organize a fight
that we hope is historic.
A struggle that will go down
in history.
-It's the fight
-Not now.
A struggle
which will amaze everyone.
We must be envied.
The others must say:
"The municipal authorities of Port-Vendres
are the strongest."
Make
the Aude winegrowers dream .
SNCF will say: "We weren't even hoping
it could happen."
At Air France,
who are the best,
they say to themselves:
"We
wouldn't have even imagined it!
But we are going to do it!
Everyone will admire us,
even our women!
Our women will start to
admire us!
To say:
"They are the best!"
They will have surges of desire
for us.
Our women will love to
make love again!
And we won't have time!
We will say: "We can't!"
And then we will go,
away, with the fight,
and we'll come back.
And there we will make love to them.
Yes, we will make love to them,
we will give them pleasure!
Gislaine,
you're going to have fun, Gislaine!
She will be able to do more!
Her body will be bloodless ...
She will be able to do more,
Ghislaine!
Hm, excuse me.
This is an example, it could be
Françoise, Martine, anyway.
-Finally...
we'll see, we don't have
to sleep, either?
Finally, we will see, what ...
-Good,
I want a historic fight,
there will be a before
and after Port-Vendres.
-After Port-Vendres, it's Banyuls.
-shush!
-Wait,
everyone knows that.
-It's true, after Port-Vendres,
it's Banyuls.
-Are you ready
for a historic fight?
-YES.
-Of course.
-Someone have something
to add? It is time.
-NO.
-Well.
I did 12 hours by train ...
- Shit, strikes,
by force.
(To laugh)
Ah but I said that to mess around!
It was for...
-It's for our records. Profile.
-But it was for fun.
(Clicks)
-Me too, it's for fun.
-Know that there are several
trends in our section.
-And what about Hamoniste?
-No, nobody plays it.
-Gilbert !
Michel, trendy?
-I represent
the left wing, social trend,
Marxist-Lenin-Melanchonist.
-No problem.
-I'm all for it
a classic class struggle,
partisan Stalino-Krazuckist.
In fact, we are syndico-progresso
Marie-Georges-Buffétistes.
-Very good. And you are ?
-New.
-No, no water,
thank you.
(Admiring
whistles ) -BRAVO.
-Is not national level?
-But yes,
but I know, Mr. Morales!
You've been here eight times.
Okay, look, look.
How did you initial?
-In blue.
-And you signed?
-Quickly.
-In black, Mr. Morales.
You signed in black.
For the initials
and the signature,
you need the same color.
-I'm going over?
-Yes, but not here.
You are not going to block my
customers all morning.
We already have a colleague who is stopped.
That's enough !
-There is nobody.
-No but it's not possible, that!
Who is who runs this office?
Who is it
Who is it, who knows, here?
She's the chef.
As she is stopped,
the chief is me.
Where are they, permanently?
-They are at Ricard.
-They didn't say anything?
-Yes.
Christian wants to fuck his wife.
-Oh fuck !
I see that the strike.
-A hard strike.
- Very hard.
And very long.
-Ghislaine would say to you: "That's enough."
-Women who do not kiss
are rascals.
- They always say:
"Enough is enough!"
-"That's enough !"
-And my file?
-THAT'S ENOUGH !
-That's what I propose to you,
the zealous strike.
I demand a democratic vote
unanimously.
-Now that this measure
has been adopted,
can we know what it is?
-Work all the time.
Work day, night ...
-HEIN?
-Engorent work
by work.
(Whispers)
-Georges-Paul, you will understand
that this measure deserves reflection.
Can you leave us?
-OK, I'm going back to Paris.
I have a Perpignan-Paris
which goes through Strasbourg-Brest,
I don't want to miss it.
I await your position.
-Michel,
can you bring him back to the station?
-I planned, I drank only 5.
-Impeccable.
Uh, what was I going to say?
All the others,
meet tonight
for a conference,
at the Le France bar.
-Why at the bar?
-If we don't do it at the bar,
journalists won't come.
-Ah yes.
-Think, anyway.
-No more fears
And humiliations
No more comments
and disappointments
Tomorrow will be another day
All together
Come on, all together!
No more fears
and humiliations
No more
Tomorrow will be another day
All together
If someone wants to buy the record,
we have it.
-Are you there, France 3?
-Yes.
-We do the reporting?
-No, we don't have the equipment.
-What do you mean ?
- Strike of the guards.
-Shit ! And you, right?
-No, we will go on strike
on Mondays and Thursdays.
Every two weeks.
Plus one Tuesday a month.
-It's complicated to remember.
-We don't want to hinder the SNCF strike.
-The railwaymen are holding on?
-Yes, with the air
traffic controllers , they make a mess out of it.
-It's work,
to fuck a constant mess.
-Yes, it's work.
-I like debates, like that,
when it runs.
-Me too, I fuse.
I'll eat your body.
Titounet.
(He squeaks.)
(Laughs)
-Come back soon.
-Let's not abuse.
-We can't abuse
de bonnes choses. Miss Mme?
Your earring.
(We knock.)
Come in!
Yes, Chouquette?
-Who is it?
-Who is that ?
-The syndicate !
-YES!
-From Paris...
-BOUH!
-Wants to impose us
a new movement,
the strike of zeal!
What is
the zeal strike? Michel!
Explain to us what it is.
-The strike of zeal,
is to work day and night,
to clog everything.
-I can speak ?
-Go ahead.
-I speak or I go in taekwondo.
Do people realize
what we're getting at?
We, in our team of 3,
we have always been 5,
which is normal.
-YEAH.
Since September, there are only 4 of us.
What is the purpose of the government
and the mayor?
That we are 3
for a team of 3?
-And why not a tandem of 2?
(Clamor)
-If we go on strike with zeal,
we will prove that we could be 3.
And they will put us at 3.
Is that what we want?
-NO !
-No way !
-If we work at night,
they will understand
that we can do it.
-Thank you ! I propose a vote.
Who is for this zealous strike
imposed by Paris?
This tunnel which will lead nowhere
and will set a bad example.
Raise the glass if you are in favor.
Nobody ?
Anyone else
to add?
(Cuckoo clock)
Fuck you!
(Glass breakage)
-I will do it to you,
the zeal strike.
Tirelessly.
I'm going to disrupt
the biorhythm.
-We said we wouldn't do it.
We voted against.
-I will eat your body.
-Damned, Véro!
Have you eaten a dog?
-I will eat you !
-Attends !
Buddies say
we can't
eat the body.
A bit, yes, but not everything.
(Grunts)
(He squeaks.)
-You arrive right
at the aperitif time! Are you settled?
-And I don't have a watch.
-That's the beasts.
Rhinos always drink
at the same time, as we do.
It's okay ? Is your wife rolling?
-By the way, thanks for the doctor.
-It's a friend, I asked him.
-I have a certificate:
"Penile irritation".
Eight days of rest.
I feel
like I left for a month.
-When you don't fuck,
it always seems longer.
Is she still asking?
-What she likes that!
-She likes it, we can't help it!
But take it
not too many, ...
-No, he told me 5 a day.
-Yes, but 5 granules.
-If in doubt, I put 5 tubes.
You never know.
What kills me the most
is his imagination, you know?
She constantly invented
new positions.
-It's not true ? Tell me!
- One evening, I was watching TV,
she arrives, she puts on me ...
but not in a good way.
Head to ass.
-Head to ass?
No kidding ?
-I heard about it,
but doing it is different.
You're used to seeing the same head,
and suddenly, you're facing Chabal ...
-Me, if there is Chabal in the fray,
I do not put the head there!
-We're stupid.
-I know well !
But we are stupid because we drink
or we drink because we are stupid?
Can I use one?
- I don't mind.
-But Chabal with long hair
or when he had cut his beard?
- Are you farting your bottle?
- "Fart." Yes,
if there is one left.
Ah! He was there,
one remains.
-Saved!
Cheers.
- Yours, Gilbert.
(Recoil beeps)
Ah!
This is Michel!
-Are you, with your wife,
sexually okay?
-As soon as she asks,
I'm there.
-And she asks?
-Never.
More
I am present.
-It's essential.
- Must be present.
- Must be diligent.
-Go, Michel, how are you?
-Hello, Michel.
Houla !
There was an emergency.
-Oh fuck !
I was on the reserve.
I'm not getting used to it.
They’re going to kick the world,
30 voluntary departures,
and we do nothing.
-Finally, we do nothing,
we think, already.
-You Gilbert, you don't know,
you're too young,
but the social movement of 2007!
They wanted to delete
the coffee machine. Huh?
-We fought. We
went on a general strike. Hunger-strike.
-No thirst?
-We were not far.
-Yeah.
-And there,
for 30 people, we do nothing.
I can't even say.
I was on the grave
from Françoise,
I didn't even dare talk to her about it.
-Here.
-Well I'm leaving.
It's the last one, above 5,
I see lights.
I drive,
I'm not dangerous,
but ...
-No.
I see lights.
Come on!
And smoke.
-She is dead, his wife?
-No, she left.
-Is that so ?
-Parisians always carry
a souvenir.
They bring wine, olives ...
and there is one, he brought his wife back.
He was unhappy, Michel,
he cried and he had this idea
of inventing that she was dead.
Because a woman who left,
you know why you're crying,
but a woman who died,
you know where you cry.
-Don't you give one?
-And.
You know that we can say
that we supported viticulture.
-Will you have some olives?
-I don't want to, it just ...
-Yes, it does.
- Wine does nothing to me,
but the olive makes me sick.
We have already seen
Rekindle the fire
of an ancient volcano
We thought we were too old
-Is it over?
-Do not leave me
Don't leave
me Don't leave me
- I'm not leaving you,
I'm going!
-I would offer you
Pearls of rain
from a country where it does not rain
-As much to offer me a Twingo!
Rain pearls,
it's not practical!
You do not say anything anymore ?
-Capri
It's finish !
And to say that it was the city
Of my first love
-Minable.
-Shit, shit, shit!
Do you know what I'm going to do?
I'm going to blow up your Lake Geneva!
- Don't touch Lake Geneva!
It's a thousand hours of work.
Without the pike.
-It's a dolphin!
-My pike, a dolphin?
-Of course, it's Skippy,
everyone recognized it!
-Skippy is a kangaroo.
-You're always right, that's
the problem.
-Skippy is a kangaroo!
-But I do not touch it,
your lake Geneva shit!
Damn, it's not true!
Gilbert,
from Christian, will you receive me?
( Crackling ) * - Yes, I receive you,
but not 5 of 5, I put you 4,
because of the crackling.
-Shut up !
-It's good, there are more.
-All, we will give the top
for the start of the sweeper
ecological electric.
Attention...
* Top, electric sweeper.
-Go!
-Top electricity, it works.
Let's go !
* -And let's go for the
ecological electric sweeper .
Suspenseful music
Whore !
(Smash)
The purpose of this anonymous meeting
is ...
stop the action of the town hall,
which seeks to fire 30 people.
-IT'S DISGUSTING.
-So, you noticed,
we have hoods.
Why do we have hoods?
To stay at ...
-Why?
-To stay at ...
-West ?
-Fashionable ?
-Inside ?
-To the left ?
-To remain anonymous!
(Disappointed sighs)
-I knew it, I didn't dare say it.
-Good, I'm making the call. Gilbert?
-Present.
-Michel?
-Yes.
-Yolande?
-Jean Louis ?
-Yes !
-Bruno?
-Yes.
-Jean-Patrice?
-Hey!
- Sorry, Vero, I forgot you.
-It would require holes
for the mouth.
-On I thought.
There are straws.
Gilbert, pass on,
you only take one
per person, we pay them!
What is the mayor's weak point?
Everyone knows it,
it's sex.
-Of course, it's clear.
-YES.
(Someone knocked.)
(Steps approach.)
-Uh, Mr. Mayor?
Mayor?
- One second,
I'm on a file.
"Train Man" in eight letters
and it starts with an S.
-Centurion.
-With an S?
-Oh no. Yes, uh ... -
It's a senator!
Here ! A train of senators.
-Justly, I come to speak
to you about the audit of the Court of Auditors.
-Yes, good, so what?
-It would concern the management
of your personal property
and the use
that you would
certain benefits,
which you would exaggerate.
-It's a joke ?
I left my office as a notary
to be exemplary!
Because it's true,
I recognize it,
when I was a notary,
I screwed, of the world.
(Laughs)
I stuffed myself!
But beware, legally.
-Of course.
-Hey ! I was a scoundrel ...
What a bandit!
No limit ! But the,
since I became mayor,
I never abused my position.
-I know, but having said that,
they send an inspector.
She comes to check
your use of the town hall
for your personal home.
-Good, well, that's fine, I risk nothing.
Huh, Ménard?
-Ah, "Precarious situation"
starting with a G,
8 letters: "Garde à vue (custody)"!
- Are you having fun?
-Yes ! No.
Is ...
-Ah, well, yes, that's it.
Yes.
(Someone knocked.)
-We are waiting for someone?
Go see, Vero!
-Véro, it's a song!
-Ah there is a song.
-A beautiful piece!
-Oh, eh !
-It's Milene!
She has revelations for us.
- Let her come in.
We're listening to you, Milene.
-Good morning, Christian.
-Hello.
-The mayor is a junk.
-OH THAT !
-It's not new!
-We know it.
-And here is my revelation.
The mayor has concerns.
It comes from Paris.
-When it comes from Paris,
there is trouble.
-It's good.
It comes from a review to you?
-No, it's from me!
(Admiring whistles)
- congrats!
-You-go, Milène.
-It is suspected
of having diverted personnel
and materials from the town hall
for the construction of his house.
-So what ? We all do it.
-Yes, but we are salaried,
it's like a bonus.
-Ah !
(He chokes.)
-Thank you, Michel.
-You are in a
reintegration internship in the suburbs.
You are the new municipal officials,
we are counting on you.
Finis, flights,
no more robberies,
a new life begins.
For that, we have tools.
So there, for example, do you have one?
-A brush ?
-Very good !
And that what is it ?
-A rake ?
-Well done !
And right behind there, do we have one?
More difficult, that.
Have you never seen one?
Okay, it's a wheelbarrow.
You can't
know everything on the 1st day.
So let's get started,
I'll come back to see you later,
We are motivated, we believe in it!
Okay ?
Go to work, I'll be back.
Be wise. Come on, kids.
-Go, go ahead, Jean-Mi, go ahead!
-Excuse me please.
I'm the town hall psychologist,
so let me do it.
-In any case, the 1st time,
it was 6.43 m.
-Jean-Michel, you are very strong,
there is no headwind,
you control the machine,
you are stronger than it.
-Wait,
from the tree over there, there are 2.43 m.
-Why does he always say 43?
-It's his size.
And it measures with the feet.
He took a balloon in the head
2 years ago, since,
it counts and it ends up with 43!
-I will pass you
in handicap committee.
He too
can have the competition.
-Ah, he will get
to start the snowblower.
-Look at them !
-Go ahead, Jean-Mi, you can do it!
Yes, Jean-Mi,
Yes Jean-Mi, it's coming! It's coming !
It's coming, I'm coming!
No, sorry, excuse me, it's ...
it's coming, it's coming ...
It's coming.
-We are at 142,000 euros
in materials, Mr. Mayor.
-How ?
-142,000 euros.
-You can avoid
to speak while chewing?
-Of course.
-Sure, we have no right?
-The town hall,
it's not you.
-It's still great,
as a concept.
We would be mayor,
we would break our ass
for these rednecks
and we would have no advantage?
-Not these.
-What remains,
as an advantage, then?
Kiss gourds?
-Wine.
-Ah, Milene!
Were you there?
-No, I just arrived.
-Ah! Well, we were talking about you.
-Yes, we said good!
-Is that so ?
Mr. Mayor, the controller,
you will receive it ...
-By side, my little one,
in the small office.
And must rot me,
that it is sad, overloaded,
that it is pitiful.
-OK,
I'm going to go and have a drink.
-Okay. Thank you, Milène.
I'll put a hit too.
-A little bit, Mayor?
-The commissars, there.
-Pardon.
(We strike.)
-Mr. THE MAYOR ?
-Yes ?
-Miss Leblanc.
-Not Leblanc, Legrand!
Come on, get out of here.
Hello, man!
We are going to play.
We're going to have a little game.
(Laughter)
I'm showing it to you.
(She sighs.)
So wait, ...
There is a mess in this bag!
Ah yes, these are the photos
of the mayor's house.
Lots of fees. Superb house
on the heights of Port-Vendres.
He smashed a mountain.
Luxury materials:
marble, stainless steel ...
Look. Magnificent.
Huge works!
Everything was blocked in Port-Vendres.
It can inspire you,
if you do
Works.
Ah! And these are friends of his,
charming girls.
You will watch this too.
Here it is ! The !
Ah, very important!
The pencil ! So the pencil ...
(She sneers.)
A control without a pencil
is not a control.
-Ah.
-You saw, Miss Perec,
I did not tremble.
-I saw, Jean-Mi. I saw.
You turned on the snowblower.
-Here.
I approached the sheet,
I blew it,
I did not shake.
-Jean-Mi,
you have overcome the trauma.
It's a great moment,
even for me.
We're not used to it,
we psychologists,
to have results.
I am touched.
-But what the hell is she doing?
But come!
Look at this.
So ?
-We said 10 a.m. and it was minus 4,
so I was waiting.
-You don't pretend
to be stupid.
-I don't like to pretend.
-Do you have the equipment?
-Yes.
-Menard, what are you doing?
It's my office.
-I'm training, sir,
for the future.
-Ah yes. Okay, book me
a table at La Treille.
With a low-end formula,
like we are poor and we know it.
-Good.
-And find me
an old car.
The rotten Clio.
-It's mine.
-Perfect, as
long as she smells like a dog.
-The inspector?
-No, Ménard, the car!
-Of course !
-It's expensive.
We will take two menus at 11 euros.
You know, at the town hall,
we have modest means.
-It's good !
Good reflex! Miss,
what do you have in champagne?
-More ?
-There is only one.
People don't drink it.
Except when the town hall pays.
So there, when it's the mayor ...
-So 2 cuts of the best.
Mr. Baldéli ...
insiders.
(Evil laugh)
But I'm kidding!
-It's weird, these sandwiches
with bones in it.
-It's the principle
from the chop sandwich.
-Hey ! The trap is set,
there is more to wait.
The mayor will fall, I believe.
Are you better off with Véro?
-I believe.
She begins
to think of something else.
It passes him, to think that in the ass.
There, for example,
we leave for Cap d'Agde
for themed evenings.
It will be painful.
-It depends on the themes.
-As long as it's not ass.
-Yes, at the level of the ass,
the Cap d'Agde, it is cunning.
There, there.
(Mocking laughter)
-What?
-The file is heavy,
very heavy.
Having said that ...
-That said?
-I understand.
I understand these women
who in an atmosphere ...
(She sighs.)
who breathes love ...
this moist heat,
this warmth!
These smells ... This smell
which emanates from a body ...
Your body!
You are a sleeping tiger.
You know, we don't enjoy every day
at the Court of Auditors.
-Is that so ?
- Are you looking at me, Tigger?
Like prey?
But I am your prey!
(He roars.)
-You see what, as an animal?
-An owl ?
-No, a gazelle!
-Ah, I had not seen the horns.
-A light gazelle,
which is beautiful, which grazes ...
a gazelle frolicking!
A gazelle who sees
a sleeping tiger.
(He roars.)
Him, he dreams of enjoyment!
His eyes are closed.
He opens them!
-Ah !
-He takes it in the face,
love, wild beast!
But the gazelle
feels the danger.
(Moans)
Her little heart beats a hundred an hour.
(Clicks)
(Groans of effort)
(He sighs.)
(Shout)
-More...
what are you doing there?
-We are there anonymously.
-Yes, I can see.
-Gilbert, blow up the slideshow.
-Let's go !
(Mocking laughter)
-Good, OK, it's good!
What do you want ?
-Either you stop
measuring 30 redundancies
and you integrate
the suburban trainees,
either we swing you.
-Offenders?
But it is useless!
-Well then, what do we do, Baldéli?
Oh, Ghislaine? But are you walking?
-Yes.
-It's moving to see you in
front of the Lourdes setting.
-I'm not leaving anymore.
Here is our room. Well done.
I was told everything.
You're my winner.
You trapped them, you got the mayor.
And you know what ?
My body is thirsty for a winner.
Come on, come now.
-In front of the ducks?
Aren't they too young?
-But there are lots of old people!
(Shouts of pleasure)
(Ghislaine screams.)
(Disco music)
-Ah!
-Disco evening! Titounet.
-A SPEECH ! A SPEECH !
A SPEECH !
-Wait!
In high place,
we decided to downsize
the public service.
(Hoots)
And I was against it!
-Yeah ...
-Yes Yes !
Yes, I told them:
"No, but you take
our municipal officials for pawns?
-We're not pawns.
- "I take you, I throw you!
I reject you!
(Brouhaha)
-It's human beings!
- "No, no!
"They are people.
"Quite simply people
from Port-Vendres!
-YES!
- "They stay or I leave!
-You leave !
(Laughs)
- "It's them or me!"
-YES !
-I say "We",
because I am one of yours.
We won !
Everyone stays!
(Cheers)
I even managed to integrate
our three young people
at the service of the staff!
-YES!
-It's amazing.
-Three young people from neighborhoods
who are said to be in difficulty,
but that I call:
"In evolutionary movement".
-YES!
-What, guys?
(Impressed sighs)
(Acclamations)
-He Ho ! On the other hand...
gently the movement there.
-I scared me!
-You're a good one.
-Bah ... Bah, Maurice,
What's the matter ?
Do you measure more, Maurice?
-It's me talking, huh?
I'm the one speaking.
(Admiring sighs)
-MAURITIUS! MAURITIUS!
MAURITIUS! MAURITIUS!
MAURITIUS! MAURITIUS! MAURITIUS!
-I've been
stupid for 2 years measuring everything.
Hair like that,
43 here, 43 there ...
Now that I have visited
thanks to the shrink,
I have 40% disability.
(Cheers)
-So, then, then ...
So I'm not measuring, huh?
I have my disabled card.
(Admiring sighs)
I
park where I want and fuck everyone!
(Acclamations)
I can not tell you.
-MAURITIUS! MAURITIUS!
-Well done !
-MAURITIUS!
-Are you okay, Christian?
- It's okay, Gilbert, it's okay.
I am in emotion.
-Is that so ?
-And I have admiration
for what Maurice did.
Two years of work,
in silence, of self-denial!
The objective, to
obtain the Disability card.
He works, he says nothing, he gets it.
Hat.
-Especially that to be stupid
all the time,
never let go.
-No !
A permanent idiot
cannot relax.
The idiot, he's tired.
You know,
idiots sleep a lot.
-Is that so ?
-Yes, they rest,
it tires you to be stupid.
We trained him,
he arrives at the disability card.
Hat!
It's our team from France.
You want the title,
you work and you get it.
-Somewhere,
we are educators.
Oh it's...
It moves me.
And with your wife, how are you?
- It's okay,
she understood who was the boss.
-Be careful, do
n't give him too much taste for all this,
because you give them that,
they take that from you.
-Are you yours?
-She scares me.
(He groans.)
-In less than 2 minutes,
I go around the port!
-Yeah, that's it !
(Mocking laughter)
Attention !
- GO!
(Klaxon)
(Cheers)
-Bravo, Michel!
(Brouhaha)
(Klaxons)
(Tire screeching)
(Shocks)
(Fall in water)
-Hey, you see?
I knew
it would one day serve the crane.
-Bravo, Mr. Mayor.
-What are you thinking about, Michel?
-We are few to think too much,
and too little to think little.
-But it's beautiful,
that, Michel! Who wrote this?
-Françoise Sagan.
-French?
-Sportswoman?
-Yes I think.
-She could have made books.
-She should have made
books, Françoise Sagan.
I would still help
viticulture myself.
-What we were united!
-We have always supported
viticulture.
We are united!
-Of course !
Go, go! Go for it.
Go for it !
-Who are you talking to ?
-For spectators.
We're done, it's good!
-Ah yes, but ...
They are on zealous strike,
they will not budge.
-Cheers.
Do you know what they want?
We are destabilizing.
- By not moving?
-Exact, and so are we well in place.
- Well in place.
-We've said enough bullshit.
-Enough is enough.
-But too much is too much!
-It's also beautiful, Michel,
it could make a headline.
-What do you mean ?
-A movie title.
-Here !
-A movie about what?
-On us.
-The municipal.
-The municipal!
-WHAT ?
-You caught the big head.
-Not the big head, the close-up.
-She takes up the whole screen.
-I will stay.
Go ahead, we'll see you more.
Everyone sees me.
Look, show, you're there too.
Huh, is he there?
- GO!
-Go, go, now.
Be reasonable.
-It's crazy,
we're going to be late for the aperitif.
-And the aperitif is sacred!
It's not unpleasant!
It is true that close-ups,
I too, get a taste for it!
We would be stupid to leave,
we are good with you.
It's true that we spent ...
-But no!
-If you have a big head.
-No, we don't have that much,
the big head.
-Good, come on!
Be reasonable, get out of the way.
-Tell him to cut!
-It cuts !
-Go.
-We're leaving.
-We get attached, finally.
We shouldn't, but hey.
-We get attached to you, hold on.
-Me too, I'm attached!
-I don't know where I put my bus.
-But no, it is in the water.
-Your bus,
it fell in the harbor yesterday.
(Michel laughs)
Damn, haven't you read the script?
-It makes you amnesic, you ...
-Alcohol.
-But get out!
-Warning !
-Go away !
It is true they insist.
-After a while it is painful.
Standing, the convicts of hunger
(Laughs)
Excuse me, it shook me.
- Come on, let's do it again.
- Go ahead, do it again.
-It's relapse,
he is depressed.
It's relapse,
there, it makes us depression.
-Sorry.
-It's relapse.
(Laughs)
Calm down, calm down!
-I tell myself ...
-Because I finish the word.
-Because I start to look:
"But what is it?"
-I think I believe it.
-More ! No, finally!
Yes ! Huh? Well yes ?
So yes ?
-Yes.
-Well ! So ... Oh?
In...
By virtue ...
(Laughs)
-You cut before me!
-I have a Perpignan-Paris
that goes through Strasbourg,
with a change towards,
towards ... towards Orléans.
I don't want to miss it.
-Read again the program, because ...
(Laughs)
You're not sure to get there.
-I will eat your body!
Titounet!
(He squeaks.)
-Titounet!
-Go, have a drink.
Come on, Titounet!
(Growl)
Drink a little!
(To laugh)
-Good, are you farting your bottle?
- "Fart"!
Yes, but if there is one left! Ah!
He and you were!
(A bottle tumbles.)
-We were lucky, anyway!
-Are you ready to help us?
-Yes.
It's enough to be stupid,
I also want to be pretty.
(Laughs)
-In my opinion,
no need to do it again.
- I'm going to take off
the implants! Grind you the glottis!
Oh yes !
I want a fucking shovel!
A world champion shovel,
a sick shovel!
I'm going to descale you!
Let me wet the acid for you.
No that's not it.
-But Ghislaine, are you walking?
-Yes !
-It's moving to see you in
front of the Lourdes setting.
-And then I walk ...
(She stammers.)
-Of ?
Now we don't know what you said.
(He chuckles.)
Give him a drink.
-Go, drink, my little Titounet.
- GO!
(Laughs)
-He laps well, the Titounet.
-Wood, my little cushy.
Come on, drink!
Yes, papa, he will take you for a walk afterwards.
(Laughs)
Did you take plastic bags?
(Cadenced music)
Subtitling: VDM