Over there.
Will you finish?
Come.
Are not you ready?
Then get ready.
It's good, I feel good.
Then, come on.
Continue.
Come on...
Did you get ready quickly
with your previous friend?
Treasure?
Please talk to me.
Forget me.
Please, I'm sorry.
Come.
So I will speak to you tomorrow?
Do I see you Sunday?
BRIGHT SUNSHINE IN
Good day!
Shopping in the neighborhood?
Tasty fish, right?
- Very tasty.
Is everything all right?
No.
Not me either, the old story.
We are never satisfied.
Things never go well.
They never fall into place at the same time.
So we satisfy our desires
in various ways,
but it never actually works.
I'm glad I'm bumping into you.
I wanted to call you.
I wanted to introduce you to
something that would do you good.
My mother, who died last year,
left me a beautiful country house.
Come along if you want.
Anytime you want.
You can come and go...
and stay as long as you want.
Not now. I do not feel
very well at the moment.
So how are you?
For me...
Mrs?
What can I do for you?
Just think... I want...
Would not you call me?
Sorry, it did not work.
But I've been waiting
all weekend.
I am in love with you.
Then also take care of me a bit.
I can not always do what I want.
Listen, this is simply not possible.
If you say you are calling, do so.
Or our relationship does not last long.
Dictatorship of the proletariat!
Sorry what did you say?
What?
I said 'dictatorship
of the proletariat'.
Does that irritate you?
It is only annoying when you
can not laugh at it. Yet?
Can not you?
Beautiful chair.
Did you masturbate this weekend?
You?
- No.
You've done the 'love'...
I am married.
Why else would there be whores?
No ice.
Take it back and bring
two empty glasses.
No big Perrier, a small one.
Put it here.
I pour in and you can
take it with you again.
Now you have it.
Fine.
I know Maxime well.
Your new...
collaborator.
Of course, I know that.
We have merged the
two galleries.
I did not know that.
But oh...
Logically that you know her.
In this environment...
As a banker you probably know everyone.
I knew her before she
started with the gallery.
I have known her for centuries.
What you may not know, but she
had something with your... ex...
ex-spouse, ex-partner.
With Mandelbaum. They had something together.
What?
- Did not you know?
When?
Did not you know?
I do not know when.
Come on... did she have anything with François?
Who says that?
- They themselves.
When did she say that?
- I do not know...
Two years ago or so.
At least. I do not know anymore.
When I was with him, or after that?
I do not know.
I think for that.
She would have told me that.
impossible.
She said it very casually...
why would she lie?
Is it bothering you?
I have to work with her,
so it bothers me, yes.
Working with her is
a huge opportunity.
You can work internationally through her.
That's fantastic.
I do not know...
are you really sure?
Impossible... you are mistaken.
Impossible.
She said it and why would
not I believe her?
But it is now out.
I do not know...
Perhaps.
I do not get it.
It is strange.
It is almost bizarre if it is true.
Are you really sure?
I should not have told you.
It is no longer important now.
Put that bottle away.
- I will.
Yes sir.
Do you also have gluten-free olives?
Gluten-free olives?
- Do you have that?
I have to check that out.
And give me a cup of hot water.
Without lemon.
Just boiling hot
water, you know?
Fine.
Why that tone?
He is polite.
Are you falling on him?
Does not seem like anything to you.
You are worth a lot more.
You may not know, but...
I admire you.
For real?
Really.
I think you are a remarkable woman.
There is a man in Paris who
even finds you extraordinary.
Simple, I wish I was you.
I would like to be you.
For real
You do not realize that you have the
most beautiful goal you can do.
There is nothing better.
Why? Do not you like your own work?
You never talk about your work.
Because it is unsatisfactory.
Banking work is not interesting?
My work is alienating.
Be glad that you are doing something else.
My fellow bankers...
never read a book, never go out.
Limited lives with boring weekends
in holiday homes with their family.
Uninteresting bourgeois types.
Unlike you.
Do you think that's funny?
What interests you in life?
The pleasures of life.
The beauties of this world.
The friendliness of this world.
Touch me.
He's a little excited.
The fabric is happily soft flannel.
I will answer the question
that you do not ask.
I will never leave my wife.
You are enchanting, but
my wife is extraordinary.
Difficult sometimes, exhausting
even, but extraordinary.
But you are very exciting.
If we play this smartly,
we can have a lot of fun.
Very much.
Your hot water.
I have to go through the office.
I feel like walking.
Take my car.
My driver can drop you anywhere.
Thank you very much.
Have A Nice Day.
Bye.
It just does not work.
To be someone's secret
mistress is impossible.
Am I with him?
Am I with him? Or not?
I do not know.
I'm tired.
Is this my life?
I want to find love.
One true love.
I am emptying a wall.
Why can not it go differently?
Why why why?
I do not get it.
Fantastic that you come
to the gallery with me.
I will take good care of you.
I will do everything possible.
Whatever.
You will see it.
You're a great artist, you know.
Sorry, but can I ask you something?
Go ahead-
I find it pretty embarrassing, but...
Sorry...
Say it.
Then, if there is
something, say it.
Please?
Go ahead.
Then I say it outright.
Sorry, it's very hard for me.
I find it terribly embarrassing.
Sorry.
Just say it.
Listen...
This is ridiculous.
It does not concern me either.
If I do not say anything,
the loops will stick to us.
That's just how it is.
Go ahead, say it.
I have to say...
otherwise it affects our work.
Sorry if I mention something
that does not concern me.
Listen...
I heard someone say...
that you ever had something...
with François Mandelbaum.
No not at all.
Who knows in the future?
Weel who told me that?
Vincent Briot.
The banker?
I get sick of the daily routine.
That's part of the theater.
But that also makes it heavy.
The public on such an evening does not notice anything.
But it makes it heavy night after night.
I'm sorry to interrupt you.
Congratulations.
You were fantastic.
I saw it for the second
time and was still moved.
Your interpretation of the role is...
so modern.
And personally, I think.
Thank you.
- I must thank you.
I'll look again.
He's good, is not he?
Maybe it is personal.
My own private problem.
Maybe I'm just tired
of the routine.
The same thing every night.
For personal reasons.
That daily routine
really gets me too much.
Your daily routine?
Yes, my daily routine.
In my life.
And that means?
In my current life.
In my current life I suffer
from that daily routine.
You say...
that you do not know what
to do during the day,
that your days are
empty and meaningless?
No, my life from day to
day, at this moment...
is just...
almost a burden for me.
My wife and I are separating...
my desire lacks in my life.
Ah, it will come back again.
I can also look for the desire
elsewhere, like the moel.
'Elsewhere? Where?
The unknown.
The unknown?
Does your life annoy you?
No, I never really get bored.
Put me behind the geraniums
and I'm not bored.
I drink a lot, and
that causes oblivion.
Unless I go too far.
Then one word can be too much.
Then I sometimes become somewhat...
violent.
How so?
- Home.
The truth is...
only I know that it
is over with my wife.
I'm leaving her,
but only I know.
I always let everything
escalate, out of cowardice.
I let everything escalate.
I do not dare to say that it is finished.
Afraid of what it
can bring about.
But is it really over?
I do not know...
I just do not have everything in hand.
And that I meet you here
does not make it any easier.
Are we going to eat?
Are you hungry?
You decide.
Are you hungry? Do you want something to eat?
I like something.
We would go eat anyway?
To discuss our project?
I do not know anymore...
What you bring up now...
so personal, I am suddenly...
of the wise.
I did not expect this.
Me neither.
I just asked...
Let's go eat.
To talk.
Was that not the intention?
And we're already being praised.
I just wanted to say that
my private concerns...
not necessarily...
more important than
our meeting here.
All possibilities are
still open, but...
But?
What I want to say...
I suggest to go out for dinner.
With something to drink.
Can I drop you somewhere?
Best
So...
It's as if we did not say
anything tonight. Nothing.
I'm tired.
We said something...
and immediately
claimed the opposite.
I am free tomorrow.
We can watch a movie.
I'll call you.
So...
I see you tomorrow.
I'll call you when I wake up.
- I do not know.
I'll call you and we'll see.
I do not know if you should call.
Park a moment, then
we talk about it.
We do not have to
spend hours about it.
What you want.
Let's not do it.
It leads to nothing.
What are you looking at?
I feel rather rejected, hence.
But you do not understand that.
I really do not understand...
how you can feel rejected.
Serious...
I do not get that.
You just said 'it
leads to nothing'.
That's what I said, yes.
Do not you understand why?
That's what I said... but you should
not take everything so literally.
Oh no?
All right then.
Well...
Well... well...
It feels like you
want me to get out.
I'm not in a hurry.
You do not have to leave me.
Sorry...
but I have the impression...
that you want me to get out.
Not true.
Do you want me to stay? Yes or no?
Stay.
Then come in.
But your daughter is inside.
She's with her father.
The whole week.
I like a drink.
I do not have much.
Nothing really.
Only this.
Is this good?
What do you want me to say?
No idea.
What do I feel like now?
Say it.
No...
Absolutely not.
Why should I?
No idea.
And what concerns you?
Could you do that?
Can you pronounce them?
Would you know what to say?
Probably.
But I would feel naked.
Reported to...
Shall I go anyway?
That feels good.
Sometimes no words are needed.
What do you want?
Will I stay or go?
Stay.
I could not stand it anymore.
It feels good not
to talk anymore.
I thought there was no end to it.
Sometimes silence is more pleasant.
Let's just close the door.
Where to?
Do you mean which room?
Over there?
Come.
Beautiful room, Isabelle.
So I will speak to you tomorrow?
Fantastic...
If we see each other again,
will not we make love?
We did not have to go
to bed with each other.
We should have
listened to music.
This was not love.
Just a whim, no love.
Why did I start my private life?
Boaster? To decorate you?
But this is not love.
I have just returned from Brazil
and I wanted to catch you.
Sometimes I'm weird, is not it?
Can be, but I'm busy.
You are not funny and your
offer is not my goal.
You never said anything like that before.
Did you cry?
I'm tired.
You will not like it,
but I will tell you.
Crying is for little girls.
And sneue people.
Do you know what is happening now?
You open the door,
you leave and you
will never return.
I'll open it for you myself.
Go away.
- I thought...
Stop thinking.
Never come back.
I decide what happens here!
And everything in bed
was a cheap farce?
You are a bastard!
Look!
Well, we meet again.
I hope everything goes well.
Or better, or at
least good enough.
I thought of two things
since last time.
Two things.
I have two proposals,
both decent.
First, it would be good for me
if we can dine soon,
if it suits you.
Second,
I invite you back to the Lot.
Next weekend, or
the 24th - 25sle.
A wonderful art
festival in the region.
Now that the house has been adequately refurbished,
I have a chambermaid again
so that we do not have to
interfere with the household.
I am there all week, or partly.
You can stay as
long as you want.
That is really nice...
Mathieu.
Are you feeling better already?
Yes, it does.
And you?
Without going into
details, yes, yes...
Fortunately the weather is improving.
You mean a lot to me.
That's sweet.
Think about it for a moment.
Keep me informed!
Do not yellow, you know!
I promise!
What?
I'm not defeating you.
Bad reception.
I will call you back.
So...
You regret it.
Yes, I regret it.
But meeting you was wonderful.
I have never encountered
such a person.
And that will not happen anymore.
An exciting night and then
the next day regret...
that happens so often.
You're always over that
quickly, but not with you.
I'm sorry it went like this.
This has nothing to do with love.
I would not have
made it that far.
It would have gone badly.
Or not at all.
I felt bad afterwards.
I regretted it.
How did you feel afterwards?
What did you think?
- Was I happy?
Yes, how did you feel?
I felt good.
Listen...
you had bars and I did not.
AI imagine that it was not 'love'...
you can not pretend that
nothing has happened.
If you are sorry, you are sorry.
But we can not pretend
that nothing has happened.
We can not pretend like
nothing has happened.
Then we'll only stop with it.
I liked it as it was before.
Ready.
It has happened.
Too fast.
I just did not see it coming.
Now we have ruined everything.
Now this has happened, while I found
our earlier Contact more pleasant.
Now that is no longer there.
Maybe not.
Maybe we can go back.
Just again.
And what has happened, we forget.
And so there is...
just another new beginning?
Done business do not
take time, right?
So there is still...
a future for us?
No, that's over.
There is no other solution.
Agree.
I thought you wanted to see me again.
I did not think you
would agree with it.
You're crazy. I
told you I agreed.
All right then!
By the way, there are
no other solutions.
I'm going again.
I promised to take a pizza home.
Long live the family.
Can I call you back?
I'm busy.
When do you call him back?
About a few minutes.
'A couple of minutes?
What are you doing tonight?
"In a few minutes?
There is a play tonight.
But you are prevented.
'In a few minutes'.
I do not know.
Do I have to say anything else?
That's up to you.
To me.
Can I also say anything?
- Best.
How are you?
Good?
How so?
I'm not okay with me,
so I wondered how you're doing.
I do not feel like
kittens and calves.
I really want to talk...
know if you are happy.
It is not easy.
I'm going home.
I'm exhausted.
My day was...
very heavy.
Do you want a bit of music?
Or rather silence?
What do you want?
We can set up some music.
I'll turn on the radio.
That will do us good.
I choose the moment.
I chose a moment every day.
One panel per day?
- Every day.
I think...
I look at the sky and
choose a moment.
Sometimes I only had...
10 minutes, because the
sky changed quickly.
The weather conditions.
I had 40 minutes maximum
with a calmer air that
did not move as fast.
So you did that every day?
It was important that
I did not miss a day.
Good evening, Isabelle.
Would you like to drink something?
Love.
What?
Perrier, if you can find that.
Good evening, Isabelle.
Isabelle, I'm sad.
I can not talk.
I'm on the other line.
Can I call you tomorrow?
Are you free with lunch?
I am really sad.
We can not throw this away
as old dishwashing water.
I'll be right back.
With that banker, do you
know what made me cum?
Money?
- No money.
The thought that he was a bastard.
An old bastard.
I thought, "He's a bastard..."
and I finished.
Or I introduced him to a whore.
Or with his wife.
Ugly with her lifeless face.
Just a corpse.
Fucking him out of
pity made me cum.
That kind of filthy stuff.
"Tossing bastard" was enough.
At least in the beginning...
I concentrated and thought:
'What an asshole'...
and then I got an orgasm.
I did not need more.
Easy to sit.
Fantasies always contain
an element of truth.
But I swear to you,
Ariane, it worked.
At least at the beginning.
Later...
much less.
I can not even tell
you some things.
It was a real bastard.
It became unbearable.
I do not think I can
go on like this.
It is as if my love life is behind me.
All over.
It's all over.
There is nothing left.
That's nonsense...
Are not you in love with your actor?
I do not know.
There is a real problem.
Why did I leave François?
François was crazy about you.
You have a child. That counts.
He supported you in your work.
That also counts.
Do you know he called me?
He came along...
Did it go well?
Yes, he stayed overnight.
We had sex.
And it was...
The next morning, I
thought I was so happy...
that I was so lucky that
my life was extraordinary!
The next day I realized
that it was the opposite.
We saw each other, we spoke...
but we spoke as two
depressed people
who once loved each other, but
could not do that anymore.
Not together, not separated...
They do not want to hurt each other.
They protect each other. They lie.
They play safely, in case
they never find anyone else.
And that is why they
only stay together.
He asked me to go on
holiday with him.
Come to Corsica.
We rented a house there.
I'm going to work this summer.
Besides...
You let me talk, but you do
not say anything yourself.
As?
How are you?
Gaal it well?
Very well.
It is getting better between Pascal and me.
In every sight.
'In every sight'.
Do you think I do not
know what that means?
Probably.
'In every sight'.
Isabelle?
I'm here.
François?
What?
What was that?
That is not for you.
It is.
It is not natural.
It does not suit you.
As if you are a voyeur.
Not at all.
As if you are imitating
something you saw somewhere.
That's how it comes to me.
Of course not. Fake.
I want to be alone.
Sorry.
I can not do this.
CONTEMPORAINE ART FESTIVAL
Nice huh?
Superb.
Yet? It is beautiful.
The countryside is beautiful.
Look at that house.
True?
My lawyer had a country house here.
Maybe you can see it from here.
When we still had our
house in the Gard,
my wife and I went to visit.
It is so peaceful here.
You're crazy when you lie
down on a busy beach.
I always love those
hilly landscapes.
We also want to buy something here.
It is also beautiful here.
Bravo!
We, on the other hand,
always enjoy sailing.
We rent a boat,
invite some friends
and we go out.
Then we stay at sea
for a few days.
Or we'll moor in a quiet bay.
Where no one is at all.
Only wild nature.
We have been doing that for years.
How delightful.
- Very pleasant, yes.
Look up there!
a group of wild geese!
They are falling.
What fascinates me is that the
landscape is actually nothing.
Shapes, colors, a sunbeam.
Yet it is part of us
and does us good.
It is completely intact.
Rare, nature that really
looks like 'nature'.
That is why I ask myself something.
Would a 17th-century farmer who
awoke in this environment,
just as captivated by
the beauty as we are?
I thoroughly disagree with it.
By which?
- The question is not right.
Your statement is wrong.
Yes, we know it now!
It is all yours!
Earth, sky, mountains!
Everything, including all knowledge!
No panic, we do not
steal anything.
Even the birds!
They are also yours.
They are gone now, but
they are coming back soon!
Do not panic,
everything is yours!
Everything is yours!
Everything!
Are you all right?
Even the landscapes are yours.
Are you still going hiking?
It was freezing cold.
Here he is also freezing cold.
You managed to escape.
I stayed in the hotel bar.
With the journalist from Limoges.
Ah, landscapes in
the countryside...
I like to look at people most.
Are you in love, are you?
If you are not, what do you do?
Then I do nothing.
No sex? Nothing at all?
Nothing.
That must be heavy.
It can sometimes take a long time.
I know.
During such a long break...
do you never do something wild?
Making love is better
when you are in love.
But it's good to
let yourself go,
before you pick up the routine again.
I never let myself go.
It would do you good.
You're not in love, so
get out of your roof,
you meet a waitress,
a scientist,
a dentist, a puppeteer,
or an artist!
I'm going.
I take the train from 07:00.
Are you going too?
- Yes.
He dances well.
I'm sorry if I last hurt you.
I'm going.
Listen...
We tried it...
The moment was probably not good.
I want to ask you something.
Can I return the keys?
Unbelievable.
I did not want to keep them.
And you gave them to me yourself.
I know that, François.
Why do you have to have them?
For someone else?
Have you found the 'true'?
I hope it's a good guy.
I am worried about Cécile.
- How so?
She sometimes tells me something.
For real?
So I refuse...
I prefer to keep the keys.
Does my daughter not live here too?
And half of this house is mine.
Even more than half.
When Cécile is with me,
she tells us everything.
She says that you cry almost every night.
And she sees you crying.
Is that healthy for a 10-year-old?
Your life does not concern
me, but its well-being does.
I keep the keys for certainty.
Give them to me.
- I do not have them with me.
Can you see that man again?
We traveled back
to Paris together.
So yes.
- And?
We came back together and
we are still together.
I'm jealous.
Do you live together?
We know each other for 3 weeks.
We do not live together.
But do you 'go' with each other?
I'm sorry to ask, but why did
he fall in love with you?
No idea. That is not me.
I understand that he fell in love.
But I do not understand the other way around.
How so?
- Come on.
Do you often talk?
Yes.
Much even.
Does he understand how it
works in our profession?
No idea... what does it matter?
Nothing.
Sorry, I do not mean anything with it.
What do you discuss?
Everything.
We just talk.
Do you also do things together?
Do you see each other's friends?
Never?
- It's not that far yet.
We're just at home with me.
We walk...
That does not hold.
A couple survives only
within a social environment.
Does he have friends?
Why does not he introduce
you to anyone?
Because he is afraid
that I have no interest?
Perhaps he does not
feel at ease then.
Or they feel uncomfortable.
Or does he think he is in two camps?
They are two different environments.
Sometimes you do not feel at ease.
I understand what
you have to offer.
Explain.
Why is it clear what
I have to offer?
It is obvious that you give him
an unprecedented legitimacy.
But apart from his
exotic person...
what you have fun with...
and that's nice of course...
Have fun with him...
but keep your distance, otherwise
you will certainly get hurt.
He can never offer
you what you need.
Why not?
Trust me.
Enjoy it. But he never
met your friends?
We have known each other for just 3 weeks.
Who will know if one of
us wants to continue?
What does he live from? A payment?
No idea. I did not ask.
Take someone from your own environment,
otherwise it will not work.
The old, familiar story.
You always have your own work.
But...
you want more.
You've looked for more.
You want to be happy?
Of course.
What is his name?
Sylvain.
Has he already met your daughter?
Your own environment, believe me.
It does not work...
I'm not happy with
those people, Fabrice.
You have a wrong picture of me.
Okay, you're looking for something new.
And I understand him.
But not you.
If you do not believe in it.
How can you live with
someone without any belief?
Do not get too involved.
I would not bet a cent
on that relationship.
Did he study?
High school?
He finished high school, yes.
You are unbelievable.
To love, I have to
admire someone.
I can be best at a hairdresser
but I'm not going to live with 'r.
I want to go to bed with her.
No more.
See you, thank you.
Beautiful coat. Saves you well.
Sylvain, where are you?
I really want to see you.
I have everything to tell.
Specific questions...
about our relationship.
Why do we never see
your friends together?
my friends together?
Fabrice says I gave
you more respect.
He said that I should
enjoy you, but not more.
That I had to find someone
from my own 'environment'.
He asked if we saw friends
together and I said 'no'.
He said that this
would not hold.
Then we stop it.
I do not want that.
Then stop that criticism.
That is not very nice.
He is hurting you and now you are hurting me.
Not very smart.
Why aim a smart girl like you?
The truth is that you
are just like them.
I am different.
- Not true!
You are.
Stay with them.
I'll keep it with my friends.
So right?
He was right after all.
What did you answer when he said that?
Nothing.
Nothing?
No, I did not say anything.
Too bad for you.
What could I say?
Something along the lines of...
"Do not crack my beloved."
He said something terrible.
Do not say it.
- It said more about him.
He could go to bed
with a hairdresser...
Who is he? What does he do?
He has a gallery.
a gallery...
So he is smart and
should know better.
See how he upset you.
Look at it anyway.
Why would you deal with them?
Come with me, Isabelle.
Come with me.
I feel good with you.
Me too.
- For real?
Of course.
But I did not know if you...
That's my problem...
nobody knows what I think.
It is nice to hold your hand.
Glad you handed me that.
This is very important to me.
But I have to go.
Before I do something stupid.
Would you like to come in for 5 minutes?
I live nearby. 10 minutes.
Then I put tea.
It is not a good idea.
I do not walk so fast anymore.
Why did you kiss me then?
I do not get it.
You took my hand.
So I kiss you.
So it is courtesy.
- No...
How can you say that?
I do not want to rush anything.
Stay with me. Please...
Please, stay with me a little longer.
Otherwise it means nothing.
I understand your reaction.
But if you put me in front
of the block, I close.
Completely close.
I am going on holiday
with my children.
Then we see each other in a
month, if you're still here.
I like it, our contact.
We're going slowly from here...
to there.
I like it when you
talk like that...
gently, in my ear.
I'm feeling good.
I do not know what to say.
I would like...
And at the same time, no.
I mean, I do not...
Enough.
You're a good man, David.
What does that matter?
It is important.
See you.
- David!
Do we still see each other?
I do not think so.
How could I have been in here?
The only thing you have
to be careful with...
is that you do not get
involved emotionally.
Because you are
vulnerable in that area.
I also get the impression
that you recently...
a period of uncertainty.
Not an easy period.
Nevertheless, I think
that, gradually...
still make steps forward.
That's how I see the current situation.
At the same time...
I would just evoke manifestations
of an artistic nature...
full of creativity, et cetera.
You like my synthetic spirit.
As you feel things...
things see...
she analyzes deeply in yourself.
We can only watch
how he develops.
Painting is perhaps
very important to you.
At least that's what I feel about.
We will come back to that.
To begin with, I would
like to know...
whether these elements appeal to you...
in general.
That is important to me.
I hope so.
In which case I keep
investigating things...
in detail.
And do I have to respond now?
Indeed.
On what I just heard?
Yet?
That's right.
Exactly.
The most obvious, as a rescue...
You were talking about painting.
I am an artist.
That is my life.
That's how it is.
So you're right.
But I...
Honestly, the question is...
It is my emotional relationships...
who remain an obsession for me.
Last year I met
someone who really...
effect on me.
I even have photos with me.
I'll look at that.
And then there is also...
someone else that I
want to talk about.
No pictures. He just
popped up in my life.
I would like to know if...
So he is...
the one who came into
my life last year.
Good...
It must not have been easy...
Perhaps even slightly...
disruptive.
But it also gave satisfaction.
But I do not know if it's over.
How old is that other person?
50, but I do not have a picture.
And nothing happened to him.
I do not know...
You must help me,
because I do not know.
This will come back again.
With a new way of thinking.
He may see things differently...
..with a newly
acquired maturity.
That's how I feel it.
He will try to make
contact again.
Problem is that he
can sit on a border.
He must be careful...
do not lose themselves...
I think he can bring
satisfaction.
But you have to be careful
with his mood swings.
Because that's...
the impression I get from him.
Because that can lead to his...
departure.
He quickly flees for things.
It is true, yes...
You will see him again.
For real?
You get news about him.
He pops up again.
He will shine in his profession.
He will do something
that is not wrong.
You get news from him.
He wants to see you again.
I suggest you do not close
your door that day.
Look what he has to say.
How he behaves.
Sorry for the expression...
but will he make
another approach?
I would say... probably.
But is he the perfect
person for you?
No.
Is he your future...
who you want to go
through life with?
I do not think so.
Something else is coming.
It will be a lot thicker...
heavier.
In fact, too.
That is what I feel.
Shall I tell about
that other person?
You will see the person
in the picture again.
And others will come.
Others?
Other people who will
stand on your doorstep.
I wonder if you will
meet someone...
who is an actor or something.
You'll notice.
You attract such people.
Such people?
Actors and stuff.
There is one who will
feel attracted again.
To begin with, I think
he has dark hair.
And it will also...
click.
Less out of balance than this.
This is somewhat incoherent.
uncomfortable.
At a given moment...
have you ever had enough...
of that incoherence.
That's why I say that something new is coming...
to show you in...
that your future might be...
more in that direction
than with him.
So...
even if my future is elsewhere...
with someone else...
Then I will not completely drool him?
He is not easy.
He does not just
accept 'friendship'.
Unless it develops further.
That remains to be seen.
So that other...
Those of 50 years?
Without toto.
Do you want to know his name? Marc.
He works in a museum.
I met him...
in a professional context.
And I...
That's what I meant.
You need unusual people.
Perhaps someone...
that just a bit more...
more adventurous...
and that suddenly comes into your life.
Or a messenger.
Someone who experiences
things from a certain part.
An authentic person.
You need someone like that.
I feel that you need
an authentic person.
The one from the museum?
This is fairly brilliant.
In what I feel...
without shortening him...
he can abuse that.
Use or abuse.
And that means?
I mean his brilliant side.
He can abuse it.
He is an important man.
He represents something.
But be careful...
I think this man...
... is in a period
of transition...
... also emotionally.
You're there...
... but you are not a
woman who is used...
... as a transition element...
... to help him cross
over to the other shore.
Therefor...
you have to be careful.
How?
Do not let yourself be used.
Because...
I get the impression
that he is a man...
that can be erratic.
Attractive capricious.
"Tics.
You fall in love...
Best...
but what should I do?
Fine, but I do not
want to be used.
I am not just an individual...
that is used as a
tool or step-up...
to help someone else further.
Impossible.
Because...
you can not get damaged here.
Because he pays credit to you...
he feels fine...
And then, sorry...
I am satisfied and what now?
So those of 50...
Certainly is not the
love of your life.
I doubt it.
I think...
that someone else is
the love of your life.
From now on you do not
close yourself anymore.
Which is also better.
You will still...
other people can meet...
that open themselves up.
Be 'open'.
But...
By the way, he's going...
I do not get him drooled?
He is coming back?
Which does not mean that something
does not happen sooner.
He is coming back...
and that 50-year-old
wakes 'hello' at you.
Let him come.
'Open'.
Do not let yourself be stifled.
That does not lead anywhere.
Live your own life.
Do not fall into the trap.
More I do not ask of you.
Because the 50-year-old...
He is a trap.
Because he is a chimera.
Show me another picture
when it pops up again.
We will not waste time...
and beat two flies
with one stone.
I know I'm right about
that 50-year-old.
I imagine you with better
people than him...
with more charisma,
more depth...
And you have enough of that.
You will see that
my actor reappears.
If I were you, I would
not torture myself.
Focus on the most
important: yourself.
I, my work and my insights.
I let things happen.
I do not focus on the rest.
I try to find a beautiful
sunlight inside.
That is all I ask of you.
Good...
so the idea is that
I come back here...
one day...
if the other person ever comes back.
Is that it?
And you...
are "open" in the meantime.
Open.
That is all I ask of you.
Translation: Fred & Eric Karreman