Good day, Mr. Finley.
Good day, Ms. Miller.
Well...
[Chuckles]
[Whistling]
[Kissing]
Rooster!
You out, boy?
Got him, Mr. Finley.
Morning, Mrs. Baker.
Morning.
[Whistling]
Hello, Mr. Perryfield.
I am sorry
I’m a little late.
It’s about time.
I was about to go inside.
There’s a storm coming,
and my hip’s killing me.
I’m sorry
to hear that, sir.
ay
Now, you don’t think
I’m gonna sit around all d
waiting for you
when the cold comes, do you?
No, sir.
Be careful with
that top step there.
It gives a little.
BOY: Here goes.
Uhh.
Ah. Yuck!
Blech!
MR. FINLEY:
And good morning to you!
SHEILA: Good morning,
Mr. Finley!
Ah, good morning, Sheila.
Beautiful day, isn’t it?
Sure is.
How’s Jimmy?
He’s doing real good.
Good.
You take care now, huh?
All right. You, too.
[Door closes]
[Whistling]
Les? About this
Brady McDaniels--
he’s already missed
several days this month.
I can’t keep covering.
Hey, Mr. Mullins,
go look up the word
"fragile".
Uh, "Les"? When did I
become "Les"?
Sorry, uh, Lester.
Mr. Stevens.
Boss, the guy’s
a screw-up.
It’s like he’s asking
to get canned.
How many days this month?
Hey, Cathy.
Congratulations, girl.
Thanks, Mr. S.
Four.
Four?
That’s not so bad.
It’s only the 12th.
Look, Carl...
I just think there’s
something there
worth saving.
[Scoffs]
I thought you were
gone already.
I need someone good, Lester.
This has been my route
for ten years.
I’ve been voted
Best Postal Carrier
seven years and counting.
I know, Walter, but it’s
slim pickings right now.
What about that
new kid Trevor?
Oh, he’s slow as mud
through a straw.
Kay.
Kay’s got a month left
on maternity leave.
And before you ask,
Pete just got
his knee scoped.
Look, Walter,
it’s your time now.
You’ve always wanted
an extended leave.
You’ve earned it.
Go, enjoy.
I’ll find
the right fit.
Promise.
Okay.
But there are a few things
you should know.
237, the old man--
Cornelius Perryfield--
checks the box every day
at the same time.
Good-bye, Walter.
e,
It’s one trip out,
and if the mail’s not there
he’ll call and complain.
.
And the Bakers’ dog--231
-
He’ll take a chunk
out of you if you don’t-
Go now.
All right.
One more thing.
Oh, Lord have mercy.
Take a look at these.
244 Laurel Lane.
Can’t just shred ‘em,
but they keep coming.
It’s like...
finding a kitten
on your back porch.
.
You can’t just walk away
I’ll take care
of them, Walter.
Go on home.
I’m staying in town,
so call me if
you need anything.
Get a life, Finley!
No. Get a wife.
[Beeping]
Oh. Ah! Ooh!
No, no, no, no.
Ah-huh.
Ohh, no. No, no, no.
Oh, another
gourmet dish?
Yeah, something
like that, Mom.
Ohh. Ohh.
Honey, nobody expects
you to be Supermom.
Yeah, well,
lucky for that.
Gosh, I just wanted to make
a nice meal for my kids
before I went
back to work, and I--
Sweetheart, you’ve got
enough on your plate.
Here, let me
have these. Come on.
Ohh.
Mom, listen,
I really appreciate
you dropping everything
to come here,
but it’s not fair
to put it all on you. I--
Yeah, my schedule
was so busy!
Tea with the Queen
and all.
Honey, that’s what
moms are for.
Maddy,
you need this job.
I’ll tell you when
it gets to be too much.
Hot! Hot, Mom!
That’s hot!
I’m sorry!
Sorry, sorry.
Ah! I gotta go.
Thank you!
I love you!
Right back at you.
Honey, was that meatloaf?
BOY: I’m busy.
Come back later.
Busy, huh? Have you
finished your homework?
It’s not due
till Friday.
And what’s your excuse
gonna be on Thursday?
I don’t know.
I’ll think of something.
Nobody likes
a smart aleck, Ben.
And your room
is a wreck.
Clean it, please.
Oh, and stay home
while I’m gone so Granna
doesn’t have to worry.
Sure thing, Mom.
Like I’m gonna ride
my bicycle around town
and just tear it up.
Bed before 11:00.
Help Granna,
and check in
on your brother, all right?
[Kids shouting on television]
Okay. Good.
Aw, dude, he lost it.
Okay, Jimmy’s got it.
Jimmy’s got it.
Oh, man,
he lost it to them.
Okay,
he’s stolen it back.
Yes! Yes!
[Continues indistinctly]
Hey, Tybo.
Wait, wait.
I’m just about to--
and score!
Okay.
Sometimes I think that
gorgeous smile of yours
is about the only thing
that keeps me going.
[Sighs] You tired?
A little.
Stomach?
Good to go.
That’s my boy.
How about your--
Mom. I’m good.
Okay, okay.
I gotta go. Mwah.
Listen, you can call me
any time. You know.
Yeah, I know.
And Granna will be helping
with the meds, okay?
Okay.
Uhh! Do you even know
how much I love you?
I love you...
this much.
That isn’t very much.
Oh, but it is.
Because my love for you
starts here
and goes all the way
around the world,
and it ends up
right back here.
[Laughs]
Ohh! Whoa? What’s this?
That’s how much
I love you.
Mmm!
[Sighs] Anyway...
Granna’s doing
something for dinner.
I sort of...
messed it up.
Really? You?
Yeah. Stop it.
I’m not that hungry
anyways.
Oh, sweetie.
Please try to eat something.
Okay.
I just don’t like
to get sick
when you’re not home.
I know.
I gotta go.
Mwah.
I love you. I’ll see you
in the morning.
I’ll be here.
Okay.
[Turns TV on]
WOMAN: Computers.
That’s the third time I've
had to reboot this thing.
Heh-heh. Mm-hm.
Hello, gals.
Well, looky here!
Finally!
[Laughs]
Hey, girl.
Hi.
Glad to
have you back.
Ha-ha-ha! Sure is
an improvement
over some folk.
Ha. That’s funny.
Just what I was thinking.
e.
Well, I can see things
haven’t changed around her
How’s Tyler?
He’s good. Yeah.
You know, as good as
a little boy can be
after having brain surgery
and 30 treatments
of radiation.
But he’s home.
For now. So...
So, what does
the doctor say?
The same. "Medulloblastoma
is a rare and aggressive
brain cancer.
"
Don’t get your hopes up.
Yeah, like I can
control that.
But you know what?
The good news is,
my mom is staying
for a while until
things settle down.
Oh, that’s great.
Yeah.
Can you give me a report
on my patients, please?
Yeah, let me--
Okay, so, Mrs. Riley
is in 406.
That little boy Matthew
is in 402.
And Mr. Samuels
is back again in 410.
Great.
Uh, Granna?
Mm-hm?
You sure you’re okay
with doing this?
Oh, piece of cake.
Your mom taught me
how to do it.
Um, are you sure you know
how to do this, Granna?
Cool it. You’re
making me nervous.
BEN: Tyler!
Mom’s on the phone!
[Sighs] He’s up here
and he’s busy!
Now slow.
Make sure you don’t get
an air bubble in my heart.
Yes, sir.
Tyler? What’s wrong?
Tyler, Mom wants
to talk to you.
Aaaaah!
Tyler!
Oh!
Aah! Tyler!
Aaaah!
Tyler!
Oh, for heaven’s sake!
That’s really not funny.
You’re a jerk, man.
Ben!
I’m sorry, Granna.
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
Silly.
MADDY: Mom!
Maddy?
Mom, is Tyler okay?
Everything--
Everything’s fine.
Everything’s okay.
You don’t have
to come home.
Mom, everything’s
fine here.
Just stay at work.
[Chuckles] Right.
Oh, fool me once.
[Grunting]
Oh, Maddy, I’ve got
to call you back.
[Sighs]
Okay. Call me back.
Hey. Is he okay?
Yeah, he’s okay.
Are you okay?
No. This whole thing
stinks.
Well, I get that.
[Sighs]
You know, when I’m
struggling with something,
it really helps me
to pray about it.
[Scoffs]
Pray? Yeah.
What are we supposed
to pray for, exactly?
Dear God...
don’t take Tyler.
You have Dad.
Isn’t that enough?
Oh, Ben.
Prayer is just
telling God
what’s in your heart
and asking Him
to help you with it.
Well, maybe I don’t want
to tell God
what’s in my heart.
I’m afraid to ask God
to help Tyler.
I mean,
what if He doesn’t?
No, I can’t.
Come on. Come on.
Dear Heavenly Father...
TYLER: "Dear God...
"how many people
are in heaven?
"Must be a lot.
I know two,
and I’m only eight."
GRANNA: We are
struggling, Lord.
We’re scared,
and we need your guidance.
TYLER: "I learned
a new word today.
"Medu...lloblastoma...
or something.
,
"My mom says
I’ll be sick for a while
but it’ll be okay."
"Why am I sick, God?
"The medicine stinks.
"But I don’t have to take
my spelling test this week,
so that’s good."
"Can you see the stars
from heaven?
"My dad said
You made them all.
"I’m really glad to be
home from the hospital.
"But most of all,
"I really just wish
my mom would laugh.
I miss that the most."
GRANNA: In Jesus’ name
we pray.
Amen.
[Banging]
Ahem.
Do I have to fill out
a form or something?
Spoken like a true
government worker.
Yeah.
[Sighs]
So, you’re having
trouble
quieting those demons
tonight?
You having trouble
remembering you’re just
the bartender?
You know, McDaniels,
if you keep pushing
people away--
Save it. You’re not
my C.O. anymore.
Ohh.
Uhh.
All right.
Oh, and, Jack...
Jimmy Buffett called.
He wants his shirt back.
Ha!
Michael Gleason
Singing : [Throw Me a Line]
[Dog barking,
police siren blaring]
%%  Haunted heart %%
%%  Tortured soul %%
%%  I don’t know %%
?
%%  Why it needs to be free ?
%%  I don’t know %%
?
%%  Why it needs to be me ?
[Baby crying]
%%  Wounded pride %%
%%  Cuts so deep %%
%%  I don’t know %%
%%
%%  How to make it all right
%%  I don’t know %%
%%  How to make it
through the night %%
%%
%%  Somebody throw me a line
%%  ‘Cause I’m hanging by a thread %%
%%  Hanging by a thread %%
%%
%%  And it’s,
it’s just a matter of time
%%  Till it comes undone %%
[Police siren blaring]
[Sighs]
[Ring]
Uhh.
Ohh.
[Ring]
Yeah?
LESTER: McDaniels,
have you lost your mind?
I leave you a message
to get your keister
in here early,
and not only
are you not here early,
you’re not even here
on time again.
If you’re not in my office
in 30 minutes--
Yeah.
There’s a line a mile long
of people who want this job.
McDaniels,
are you listening to me?
McDaniels?
[Knock on window]
Sam!
[Knocking continues]
It’s about time.
I’ve been waiting
for an hour.
My grandpa told me
you were back.
My mom wouldn’t let me
come over till later.
I figured
this was later.
Are you better?
I’m working on it.
Let me look at you.
Hmm. You don’t
look so bad.
I’m much better.
I think I’m going
back to school even.
Oh! Thank goodness.
If I have to eat lunch
one more day
with Ashley Turner,
I’ll just die!
I mean, it’s horrible.
She--She smells
like liverwurst.
Ugh!
[Laughs]
[Sighs] Well, here.
I got you this.
Sweet! Thanks.
MADDY: Ben, get up!
Quick!
My mom’s coming.
Hey, Tybo,
you’re awake.
Yep, I’m awake.
Just sitting here...
being awake.
Oh. Is that a new hat?
You mean this thing?
Mm-hm.
Mom. So, uh--
So, I’m going back to
school today. Right?
[Sighs]
You think
you’re up to it?
I think so.
I don’t know.
What do you think, Sam?
[Laughs]
I think he’s ready.
Way to be
stealth, Sam!
[Laughs]
Hi, Miss Maddy.
Hi, sweetheart.
How are you?
I’m fine. My grandpa
told me Tyler was back.
Hmm. How is
your grandpa?
He’s good.
Good.
And grumpy.
[Laughs]
Okay. Good
and grumpy, then.
[Laughs]
Well, I guess if you’re
going to school,
you ought to start
getting ready.
Yes!
Ah-ah-ah!
Front door, please.
Sure, Miss Maddy.
Thank you, young lady.
See you on the bus, Ty.
,
Oh, no. You know what?
I’ve got to check him in
so he’ll
see you there later.
Scoot!
Oh, come on.
A walking route?
Yes. You know, one foot
in front of the other,
point A to point B,
deliver the mail
in between.
If it’s all the same
to you,
I’d rather just keep
working the line.
I can’t do
a walking route.
Oh, you can
and you will.
Uh, here’s the keys.
The truck is in 27 outside,
loaded and ready.
.
Here’s your line of travel
Heh. Follow the mail,
and you can’t get lost.
Nancy’s got
your uniform out back.
You’re already
two hours behind,
so I’d step on it.
[Knock on door]
Yeah.
You ready?
Mom?
Mm-hm?
Do you think
the kids at school
will make fun of me?
Some will.
Only because they don’t
know what else to say.
Hmm.
What should I do
if they do?
Wait. I know.
I’ll do what
Jesus would do.
You don’t have to go,
you know.
No. I have to go.
Sam needs me.
Ashley Turner
smells like liverwurst.
[Laughs]
Mmm.
I am so proud
of you.
Mmm! You’re gonna
have a great day.
[Sighs]
I’m in hell.
[Growls]
[Barking]
Good dog. Right?
Good dog.
Stay. Stay! Stay!
Uhh!
[Growling]
Let go!
[Barking]
[Barking continues]
Ohh!
[Sighs]
Whew! Whew.
[Barks]
Aah!
Ohh! Okay.
Bad dog. Bad dog!
Alex?
Can I catch
his disease?
You know, if he spits
on me or something?
No, you knucklehead.
He has cancer,
not cooties.
Samantha, we don’t
call people names.
No, Alex, cancer
is not contagious.
And Tyler’s been
through a lot.
He’s missed over
two months of school.
He’s probably gonna be
a little scared at first,
so let’s all welcome
him back to class
with big smiles and hugs...
and kind words, Alex?
If that’s possible.
Whatever.
Okay. While we’re waiting
for him to get all signed in,
everybody put away
your notebooks,
and let’s get ready
for lunch.
TEACHER:
Tyler, welcome back.
KIDS: Hi, Tyler!
Mrs. Doherty, we were
just getting ready
to go to lunch.
[School bell rings]
Okay, class, line up.
Line leaders?
Everybody, line up
behind Amy.
We are so glad
to see Tyler.
Oh, thank you.
Is there anything
I should look out for?
Um, no.
Oh, you know what?
He might get tired.
If he does,
just call me.
I’ll come right back
and pick him up.
Okay. I’ll keep
an eye on him.
Thank you.
Oh, oh,
you know what?
He still has a central
medicine line,
so just make sure
he doesn’t get
submerged in water.
[Laughs]
Sorry, that’s silly.
You can stay
if you’d like.
No, no. No, I’m fine.
Thank you.
Okay.
[Overlapping chatter]
Bye.
He’ll be fine.
[Kids chattering]
TYLER: I’m going back
so they can give me
medicine from a bag
for a few days
every month.
BOY: How does that
make you feel?
Makes me feel sick.
They do that for a while.
Then I get my cells back,
and then I’m done.
Did they
call you "Baldy"?
Heh. Is that why you wear
that funny hat?
I’m warning you, Alex.
Whatever. I bet that
radiation stuff hurts, huh?
Especially on
a little wimp like you.
Nah. But they made me
lay real still,
like,
for five minutes a day,
while this big machine points
at my head and my back.
That’s it?
Is that it?
Is that it? No.
There’s a big laser beam
, like in Star Wars,
that shoots out and kills
all the cancer cells.
Right, Ty?
Well, yeah, I guess.
Huh.
Told you.
So...does that
make you sick?
Not as sick as
your liverwurst makes me.
[Chuckles]
Well, not too sick.
But I heard my doctor
tell my mom
that I probably won’t grow
like I’m supposed to
because of it.
Heh. So, you’re gonna stay looking like an alien?
That’s it!
[Kids laughing]
TYLER: "Dear God...
"my first day back at school
was very exciting.
"I forgot to tell Sam
to do what Jesus would do.
"We all ended up
in the principal’s office
to sort things out."
"My mom came
for me and Sam.
"I’m not sure who she was more worried about.
"On the way home,
Mom tried to be very firm.
"But when Sam told her
how mashed potatoes
,
"were stuck up Alex’s nose
"she laughed and laughed.
"Now I know
You’re getting my letters.
"Because only You could
figure out a way
to make her laugh."
"We got home just when
the mailman was at her house.
"I guess all the excitement
got to me,
because I threw up
on his shoes."
"My mom
couldn’t believe it.
All she could do
was laugh."
"All in all, God,
it was a very good day."
Oh-ho-ho-ho.
How was--
How was my day?
Well, uh, let’s see.
I almost got eaten
by a horse,
and some old man tried
to chase me off his porch
with a cane.
Oh, and then a kid
barfed on my shoes.
That’s what smells.
Boss, we’ve already had
four complaints in one day,
which is very good.
Might be a Post Office record.
Four is not so bad.
Oh, and one
possible lawsuit.
Do you know a guy
by the name of
Cornelius Perryfield?
God.
Letters to God.
These are from the kid
who threw up on my shoes.
What am I supposed
to do with these?
It’s your journey,
Brady. You decide.
[Mouths]
You know, if you’d
been here on time,
there would’ve been
a dead letter bin
about right here.
But since it’s
well after 6:00,
they’ve moved that bin
over to the warehouse.
So, you might want to just
gather your little letters
and walk ‘em over.
Thank you so much.
[Clicks tongue]
Ready!
Ready, Jack. Ready.
Isn’t that what you say-
- ready or steady?
Well, I’m ready.
Ah, I think you’ve
had enough.
[Chuckles]
All right.
I’ll just take
my business elsewhere.
You are a royal pain
anyway.
Brady.
Give me your keys,
I’ll pour you one more.
I don’t see you taking
anyone else’s keys
around here.
I don’t see anybody else
staggering around.
You can stay
or you can go,
.
but either way,
I’m gonna take your keys
Hold these for a minute.
What are these?
Uh...
some kid on my route.
I don’t know what to do.
How are you gonna
deliver these, man?
Doesn’t seem right
to shred ‘em.
I don’t know.
Letters to God?
Maybe you should
take ‘em to church
with you on Sunday.
Yeah. Yeah, that’s--
that’s what I’ll do.
MAN: Can I help you?
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
A little warning next time.
Sir. Mr. Reverend.
I mean--
No. Please,
call me Andy.
Andy, sure.
And you are?
Uh, Brady.
And I was just
dropping those off.
I wasn’t stealing
anything, I swear.
I’m sorry. That’s a bad
choice of words.
I just--
I just came in...
.
just because--
it’s just that I think..
this sick kid
on my route
is writing these--
these letters to...God.
And I thought you could
at least read them,
and send him, uh,
a gift basket or something.
That’s very kind of you,
going out of your way
to make sure that Tyler’
s letters are protected.
You know him?
Oh, yes. Yeah,
we love that family.
They’ve been members
here for...
quite a while.
With all that’s
happened, it’s been...
difficult for them.
But we certainly
keep them in our prayers
and check on them often.
You know, it seems to me
that God put these
letters in your hands
for a reason.
So, maybe you should
hold on to them.
No, I wouldn’t--
I don’t know what
to do with them. I, uh--
Well, first thing
you’re gonna do
is go home
and sleep it off.
And then...
listen to God.
Let God tell you
what to do with them.
After all, they are
written to Him.
And you know you’re
always welcome here.
This is a great place
to find answers.
Hey, can I, uh--
can I pray for you?
No, no. Really, I’m good
. That’s not necessary.
It’s, uh--
It’s what I do.
Thank You, Lord,
for Brady.
Thank You for
making him caretaker
of these letters,
and for his heart.
Your plans
are always good.
Lord, I believe
You have a plan
and a purpose in this.
Help Brady
discover that plan,
because, Lord,
I know you’re about
to do something...
wonderful.
Something
more wonderful
than we can
possibly imagine.
In Jesus’ name
I pray.
Amen.
Hmm.
Well, sir,
how does it feel
to be on a mission
for God?
[Chuckles]
Heh-heh.
Perfect.
Shouldn’t you be
in school?
No. My mom
thought I should
take it easy today.
Is your mom home?
No. At work.
Oh.
But my Granna’s here.
Granna!
[Sighs]
I’m sorry about
your shoes yesterday.
Ah, it’s all right.
Cujo down the street
pretty much ruined them
before you
got to them, so...
You mean Rooster?
Oh, he’s a big
teddy bear.
You just gotta know
what he likes.
Rooster?
Rooster, the dog.
What is it, honey?
Oh, hello.
Brady McDaniels.
I’m filling in
for Mr. Finley.
Oh, yes.
And, uh, this is from
down the street. Uh...
[Laughs]
That would be Linda Baker.
She’s such a dear.
Eight months pregnant,
and her soldier
husband’s away,
and still she’s thinking
about other people.
Honey, it’s time for you
to come in now.
Can I wait for Sam?
She’s gonna be home
from school any minute.
.
Well, all right,
but just don’t overdo it
Nice to meet you,
young man.
Likewise.
Uh...
[Bus approaches]
Here you go.
Oh.
Excuse me!
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Where’s the fire?
Tell me everything.
Okay. So, Alex and I
had to write 500 times,
"I will not fight."
But Alex had to write
another 500 times,
"I will not make fun
of people."
[Both laugh]
People are always
gonna make fun of me.
Come on. I think I know
something that could help.
Okay.
Every day?
You’ve got to drink
that stuff every day?
Barf!
Barf yourself,
Mr. Doherty.
The doctor says
drink it, I drink it.
Like it or not.
[Whispering]
That explains it.
Explains what?
I’d be grouchy, too...
if I had to drink that.
Grandpa,
we need your help.
Can’t. I’m busy.
Grandpa, please?
It’s big-time.
Hmm. Okay.
Make it quick.
So, you say they’re
picking on you at school.
Well, one kid, really.
Alex.
Oh.
Don’t let it
bother you.
They’re jealous,
that’s all.
Jealous?
Because all my hair
fell out?
And my eyebrows
are almost gone?
No.
They’re jealous because
you’ve been chosen
for the role
of your lifetime.
You’ve been
handpicked by God.
You don’t believe me?
Well, maybe we’d better
ask Baron Dedushka.
Dedushka?
Are you in there?
Dedushka!
!
Good news, Dedushka--he’s here
Ooh-la-la!
Ooh-la-la-la!
[Both laughing]
Ooh-la-la! Ooh-la-la!
Ooh-la--
[Laughing]
You’re him!
You must be
the famous Tyler.
Why am I
the famous one?
Because God has chosen you--
the strongest, the wisest,
the smartest--
to receive the honor.
Honor? Like a gold star
at school, Mr. Perryfield?
No, not Perryfield.
Dedushka.
And Dedushka mean
not that kind of honor.
.
The honor of being chosen
as one of God’s warriors
Wow!
I want to be a warrior.
Oh, well...
Samantha, I talked
to the principal.
He said you need
a little less warrior
and a little more...
peacemaker.
Samantha
the peacemaker.
It doesn’t sound
as good as warrior,
but I’ll give it
a try.
PERRYFIELD: Okay, good.
Now, where was I?
I’m a warrior.
Ah, yes,
you are God’s warrior,
which means you can
ride forth victoriously
in truth, humility,
and righteousness.
Dedushka is honored
to know you.
Now, come here, Tyler.
Tyler, come here.
Even though you’re sick,
when people see how
strong and brave you are,
why, it makes them take
a look at their own lives.
And so, maybe that’s
why they make fun of you
like Alex.
But, Tyler, there is
a glorious truth.
God is truth.
And it’s your job,
Tyler,
to point them
toward Him.
And if they
turn to Him,
they find the truth.
Wouldn’t that be
a wonderful victory?
Tyler,
do you understand?
I think so.
Grandpa...
I don’t.
Ah.
I don’t feel so brave
because of...
PERRYFIELD: Ah.
[Sighs]
I have an idea.
SAM: Grandpa, can I see?
Samantha, be still.
Now, you hold still.
We’re almost done.
All right.
SAM: Grandpa,
can I see?
Samantha, be patient.
How do you feel?
They feel great.
Good. Now raise them up.
Right.
Now your right one.
[Laughing]
Your left one.
Finished!
We’re done.
Yes!
All right!
Just a moment.
Fantastic!
How are they?
They’re awesome!
They’re fantastic!
They’re awesomely
fantastic.
[Laughs]
I want to see!
Here you go.
Cool.
Awesome.
[Laughs]
All right.
Now, will you
get out of here?
Dedushka is tired.
Thanks, Grandpa.
All right.
Ohh.
Oh, you’re home early.
Yep.
Made your favorite.
That’s Ty’s favorite.
Oh.
Well, now,
don’t tell me.
Don’t tell me.
Let me guess.
Yours is...
carrot cake.
Mm-mm.
Uh, marble?
Nope.
Black Forest.
No.
Oh, gosh.
Premature senility.
I’ve always been
afraid of it.
It’s okay. Forget it.
It’s all good.
Ah-ah-ah-ah.
Come here.
Sit down. Stir.
Why don’t you tell me
what’s on your mind?
Nothing.
Everything.
Well, that about
covers it.
I just feel weird,
you know?
About Ty and what
he’s going through.
All the attention
he gets.
I mean, I know that sounds
totally stupid and selfish.
I just hate
that he’s sick.
Oh, sweetheart, we all
hate that he’s sick.
Sometimes I think
it’s worse for us
than it is for him.
So go easy on yourself.
I just want normal,
Granna.
I mean, do you know
how many times
I’ve asked for Mom just
to take me to get my license?
No.
Well, you can’t count
that high.
Oh, Ben.
We can’t do anything
because we don’t
have any money
and Tyler’s always sick
or he’s in the hospital.
Well, shall we accept
good from God
and not trouble?
.
It just seems like
all we’re getting is trouble
MADDY: Hey. Ben, did you
take the trash to the curb?
Honey, we were
talking here.
Well, that’s not
gonna get the trash
to the curb.
Talking doesn’t even
matter to her anymore.
All she does
is bark orders.
Ben, don’t talk to me
like that.
Okay, then, fine. I’ll jus
t stop talking altogether.
Because I’m practically
invisible anyways.
Benjamin!
I’m sick of all this.
I just wish--
It’s all about Tyler.
Benjamin,
I am warning you--
All of our time,
all of our money,
everything.
I just--
I just hate him!
[Clatter]
Tyler, wait!
Maddy, let Ben
handle this, honey.
[Sighs]
Come over here
and sit down.
Ohh.
Come on, sweetheart.
I can’t do this.
Oh, sweetie.
Yes, you can.
[Sighs]
He didn’t mean it.
Were those eyebrows?
[Laughs]
Yes! They were.
[Both laughing]
Go away, or I’ll jump.
[Sighs]
No, you won’t.
How do you know?
Well, because
it took me a week
to get you out here
in the first place.
Come on, sit.
Look...
I just wanted to say
that I’m sorry
and that I didn’t mean
any of those things
that I said back there.
What do you see
when you look at me?
Ty, don’t be like that.
I’m serious.
I know you’re mad at me
because I’m sick.
Ty, I’m not mad at you
because you’re sick.
And I don’t hate you.
I guess I just miss you.
I miss all
the fun times we had,
and I guess I’m just
afraid that--
that we might not have
any of those ever again.
You’re such a dweeb.
You’re such a toad.
[Chuckles]
I want you to write
a letter to God.
I want you to tell Him
how you feel.
I’m sure that He can
help you and Mom.
Not to sound mean, but...
Ty, that’s really lame.
It’s not lame.
It’s my favorite way
to talk to God.
It’s like texting
your best friend.
You’re right.
Okay.
All right.
[Sighs]
Here’s your pad.
All right.
I’m a warrior, you know.
Heh. A warrior, huh?
Well, I think
you’re gonna have to be,
with those eyebrows.
[Laughs]
[Sighs] So, uh...
is Sam your girlfriend?
Yuck! No way!
Okay. Sorry I asked.
Well, she’s my best--
like a boy--kind of friend.
Hmm, right.
Enough said.
You have any kids?
[Sighs]
I have a boy.
Uh...a little bit
younger than you.
He lives with his mom,
though, so I don’t--
I don’t see him much.
Oh. That’s too bad.
Yeah.
Well...
[Grunts]
Aw, cool.
Like that?
Yeah.
Nice.
Heh. Hey, maybe you can
show me that move.
Okay, come on.
Nice! Not bad.
So...are you on a team?
Yeah.
I haven’t played
since I got sick.
I want to, though.
Yeah.
Hey. Buddy,
go wash up for dinner.
Okay.
Hi.
Thanks for the game.
You got it, tiger.
Hey! Be quick!
Heh.
Uh, Brady.
I’m Madelyn Doherty.
But everyone
calls me Maddy.
Anyway, it’s, uh--
it’s not serious, is it?
I mean, he’s gonna
be okay, right?
We hope so.
Good.
Yeah.
He’s a good kid.
Thank you.
Um, Brady?
Your...bag.
Oh. Heh! Okay.
Gonna need that.
Yeah.
Whoops.
Um, my--my mail?
Oh. Right.
Yes. Uh...
Here. Sorry.
[Laughs]
It’s mostly bills
anyway.
Yeah. "Urgent".
[Telephone rings]
Oh. More bills.
[Laughs]
[Ring]
Um, hey, listen,
thank you for taking
some time with Tyler.
I really
appreciate that.
BEN: Mom! Phone!
I’m coming!
Okay. We’ll see you.
Bye-bye.
Bye.
Whew!
Hey, buddy.
Hi, Mom.
Whatcha doin’?
I’m writing
a letter to Alex.
Alex? From school?
Yeah.
Hmm.
You see, I just
want him to know
that I’m not mad
at him,
and that I can
understand why
he makes fun of me.
Mr. Perryfield said
that I’m God’s warrior,
and that I can make him
feel things that...
he doesn’t want to feel.
But that’s good.
Because maybe...
he’ll turn to God
for the answers.
Well, Mr. Perryfield
is a very smart man.
So...what’s up?
Well, sweetheart...
um, it’s time to go back
and finish your medicine.
Really?
Yeah, really.
Okay.
[Sighs]
Ohh.
POLICE RADIO:
Roger. Unit 72 responding.
D.U.I. suspect.
We have a minor boy
in the back seat.
D.U.I. suspect
being booked.