- Alright, Eve,
go on in have a seat.
Okay, Eve.
How are we doing today?
- Fine.
Very good.
We're gonna do something
a little different today.
So what I want you to
do is close your eyes
and imagine you're
walking through a forest.
Can you see the forest?
Yes.
- Can you
describe it for me?
- Coniferous
trees, dirt, it's cold
and I'm the only one there.
Very good.
What time of day is it?
- It's still light
out, but it's getting darker.
It reminds me of a place
my parents used to take me.
Mr. and Mrs. Webber?
- No, my real parents.
- Oh, okay.
You continue walking through
the forest and you see a bear.
What do you do?
Can it see me?
- Well maybe, and maybe not.
- Well, I guess
I sneak up on it with
a sledgehammer and
beat it to death.
It would have killed me
if I didn't kill it first.
- Okay.
Next thing, you're
still walking through
the forest and you see a wall.
Can you describe
the wall for me?
It's a big, ugly wall.
I don't know how
else to describe it.
How tall is it?
- It's too tall
for me to reach the top.
- So, let's say
the wall has a hole in it.
What do you see
on the other side?
My brother.
Okay, very good.
Do you want to be on the other
side of the wall with him?
Yes.
- So how are
you going to do it?
- Well, I'll drag the
bear's dead body over
to the wall and use it
to help boost me up.
- Hi, um, do you have
a key to the bathroom?
- There is no key.
It's probably just stuck.
- You sure?
It felt locked.
- Nope, no lock.
- Okay, thanks.
- Did you get it open okay?
- Yeah, I'm not
retarded or anything.
I got the door open.
You know what's
cool about texting?
Is that you could have
a whole conversation
with somebody who's
nowhere near as interesting
as the person you're
ignoring, right next to you.
I could use another drink soon.
- What are you doing?
- I'm just kidding around.
I just wanted another drink.
- I just brought you one.
- Yeah, I want another one.
- I think you've had enough.
- Well I don't think the
same things you think.
I think you should
probably do your job
and get me another drink.
- You know, why don't I go
ahead and call you a cab?
- Oh, that's sweet, thank
you for caring about me.
You know what?
Not so much about you,
but the other people on
the road, so let me go ahead
and call you a cab, okay?
- You know what?
Take a break on that.
I'm gonna go use
the bathroom again.
- If you leave, I'm
gonna call the cops.
- Okay, mom!
Be right back.
- Yeah, okay, we'll
see about that.
- Whoa, whoa, hey, hey!
Hey, it's okay, it's okay.
Come on, just unlock the
door, it's not your mom's car.
It's not mommy's car, come on.
It's okay.
It's okay, seriously.
Seriously, get out of my car.
All right, that's it.
Get back!
Get out of my car.
Seriously, get out of
my car before, like,
Chris Hanson shows
up or something.
You don't know who that -
Are you a special ed kid?
Are you one of the
ones that don't talk?
Yeah?
Hello?
Okay, what's your name?
- Eve.
- Eve?
Well what do you want, Eve, huh?
All right.
You probably got lost
or something, right?
It's okay, it's okay, calm down.
Here, $5.00.
Go get yourself an ice cream
float or something, huh?
Don't just look at it,
take it on your way.
All right, kid, get whatever
kind of ice cream you want.
20 whole dollars, plus
the five, 25 bucks.
Take it, take the
money, take it.
Go!
Be gone.
Do you have a number?
Do you have something
that they tell you
to call when you get lost?
Hello, Eve?
All right, look.
I'm gonna get out, I'm gonna
open up your door very slowly,
I'll escort you
outside and then we'll
find out where you go, okay?
Cause I don't know.
- Are you seriously
going to drive like this?
- No, I got a ride.
- Well, I'm gonna get
your license plate
number and give it
to the cops, okay?
- You want to get in trouble?
Here's the keys
to juvenile hall.
Put them in the ignition,
drop it down into "D".
Just get us out of here,
just get us out of here.
No, not "D", not "D", not "D"!
"R", "R", I'm sorry,
that was my fault.
You're doing fine,
just keeping doing it.
Okay, okay, keep going.
Okay, this worked out.
All right, we're out of here.
Go ahead and pull it over.
Are you messing around, do
you know what you're doing?
You take the little foot and
you put it on the left pedal.
Don't look at me,
look at the road!
Oh, okay, that's a stop sign.
Your foot's on the wrong -
Okay, we're gonna wanna slow -
Can you reach that?
Seriously, left
pedal, right now.
Stop, stop, stop the car.
Good.
All right, you had your fun.
Get out of my car,
that was a blast.
- I need a ride.
- What?
I don't care.
I do not care.
There's buses running all night.
Go ahead and have fun.
- I need to get to Colorado.
- Get out of my car.
Don't look behind you, please.
There's a cop behind us.
Please let's just go.
Please, please, we'll
both get in trouble.
Let's go.
Okay, here's the plan.
See that street right there?
We're gonna turn into that,
I'm gonna count to three,
I'll grab a hold of
the steering wheel,
you just jump in the
back, we'll switch places.
Nod if you can hear me
and you're agreeing.
Okay, all right, you ready?
One, two, three.
And go, go, go.
I'll turn it, I'll turn it.
Get back, go.
- Here, put that on your -
Just stay down, stay down.
I'm down here!
- Alright, just
stay down, be quiet.
- License and
registration, please.
Uh, yeah, sure, sure.
Here, I got it, I got it.
Sir, I can't see those.
And your license?
- Yeah.
It must have fallen out.
- Where are you coming from?
- Just had a night out with
some friends, that's all.
- Yeah, what were their names?
- Colby and Zelda.
- Have you been
drinking tonight, sir?
- No, I had a beer earlier,
much, much earlier.
Very early.
- Step out
of the car, please.
- Okay.
- Eve?
- It's very
difficult to punish a child.
They often don't understand
the severity of their actions
or even why they're
being punished.
Instead of trying to
correct the problem,
they often work harder to
avoid getting caught again.
I fear, in this case,
that applies to you.
This is the second time
you've been in my courtroom.
You don't seem to
understand your actions
endanger others and yourself.
My advice to you is you
seriously need to grow up.
- But what happened was -
- This is your last chance.
Show up here again, you're
looking at serious jail time.
For now, your license
is restricted.
You will pay the fine,
you will go to AA,
you will not come back here.
Do you think you can do that?
- I have to.
- What was that?
- I said I have to
stop being so childish.
You're absolutely right, sir.
- Yes, you do!
- One of the
doors was unlocked.
What is the probability
that the first door
he opens will be unlocked?
Copy the problem into
your notebooks and write
your answer in a fraction
using the lowest terms.
Be sure to show your work.
Who's Daniel?
My brother.
- I heard you ran
away again last night.
Why do you keep doing that?
Your parents are always going
to come looking for you.
And then they're
going to find you.
Then you're going
to get in trouble.
- They're not my real parents.
- Hello?
- Yeah?
- Uh, I've got my car in there.
What kind of car?
- White hatchback?
Alright, just a sec.
Yeah, gonna be
$300 to get it out.
- $300?
Yeah.
Just pass it through the fence.
- I'm not gonna -
Look, my wallet is
in the car in there.
Can -
I need to get in.
Thanks.
- Yep.
- Did you happen to
find a jacket in here?
No, not that I saw.
- Funny story.
A little girl stole my
coat, had my wallet in it.
What -
- Lookin' great.
- Oh, Dave.
- Don't make me go out there.
- Did you get anything?
- Yeah...
Let's see.
- Here, I think that
one's pretty good.
That is too cute.
I know.
If I would have kept recording
for five more seconds,
he ends up puking on her.
Slightly less cute.
No, no, it was cute.
She still liked him.
That's gross.
- I was gonna ask you...
Can you pay me in cash,
by chance, after this one?
I got my wallet stolen.
It's just hard to cash checks.
- Sure, where was
your wallet stolen?
- I don't know, I don't know.
Come on!
Look, what I'm asking is...
Since I called earlier,
how long is it going
to take before somebody
gets out here to help me?
- Sir, it's a large city.
This is not classified
as an emergency,
so the next available
police officer
will be there as
soon as they can be.
Which probably isn't
until early morning.
- Early morning?
Like, tomorrow
morning, that's great.
Okay, well I'll just leave
my house like this till then.
Cause that will be awesome.
- To survive a hike
through grisly bear country,
you have to make
your presence known.
If the wildlife
knows you're there,
it will probably
leave you alone.
But what happens when you come
face-to-face with a
thousand pound grisly bear?
There's three clear
options and two
of them will get you killed!
A. You fight.
Bad choice!
You don't stand a chance next to
the brute force of
a mighty grizzly.
B. You run.
Wrong again!
Bears can run at up
to 35 miles an hour.
You run and you're
guaranteed bear food.
There's only one option
that can save your life.
C. Play dead.
This goes against all
our human instincts,
but if they think you're
dead, they leave you alone.
Simple as that.
Lay face first on the
ground and protect your...
Don't, it's broken.
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to scare you.
I'm in the bathroom,
I'll be right out.
It's all good.
- I'm sorry, are you watching
me from the bathroom?
Is that...
- I'm just finishing
my dinner, I'll be out.
Hey!
- Hey.
- Hey dude.
I'm sorry about that.
I'm Ricky.
I'd shake your hands,
but they're still wet.
So what can I get you?
- I'd like to buy a gun.
- Say that, what?
Say that again.
- I'd like to buy a gun, please.
- Gun, okay, relax,
there's no one here.
It's just me and you.
You going to pop someone?
- No.
- What do you need a gun for?
- For protection.
- For protection?
Okay.
It's a five day waiting period.
- You're a pawn shop, though.
- Yeah, this is a pawn shop.
- Look, I just want to
buy a gun, you know?
- It was a test, you
passed, I like you.
Come here, give me some.
You know, when you first
take one of these things out,
You want her, dude,
whoever, to...
You want to let them know
you're the boss now, right?
And you...
Well, come here, come here.
You have to learn
to be discreet.
You see that discreet?
You didn't even see that coming.
You're going to need bullets.
Hey, I don't have to
tell you that if you
get caught with that
weapon, I won't know you.
- I know you don't.
Good.
Ted.
What?
- I think I heard something.
Wake up!
- I didn't hear anything.
Come on, sweetie.
Probably dreaming.
- What time is it?
Carol, the door's wide open.
See if you can unclip it.
Okay.
- That's good.
This is really stuck.
- All
right, thank you.
You're welcome.
- The next ticket
to Denver, please.
- Where did you get this?
- My dad gave it to me for this.
- I'm sorry,
sweetie, I can't take
this without him being here.
Is there a phone number
I can reach your dad at?
They're supposed to be
a background check and stuff.
How did you get it?
- I went to a pawn
shop, the guy thought
I was a pretty righteous
dude, we bonded.
- Dave, you have
to get rid of that gun.
- Why?
I'm, like, totally
responsible with it.
- Dave,
please, that scares me,
seriously, get rid of it.
- Yeah, but what am
I going to do with it
if I get rid of it, you know?
I've got no one
here to protect me.
Besides, after something like
this, I'm a little scared.
- Then get out
of the house, Dave.
- With who?
I'm sleeping, Dave.
Maybe we can get a burger
or something tomorrow.
- What about Brio's?
- Fine, you have
to get rid of that gun.
- Really?
All right, that's great, okay.
- House got robbed, right?
- Yeah, I'm the guy.
Yikes.
Oh, wow, they took the picture
right out of the frame?
- No, that's just
a frame I like.
If you could please...
- Okay, that's weird.
Okay, what is that?
What is that?
- It's not mine.
I don't, I don't
know what that is.
- So that's not your frame.
They brought a frame with them.
- No.
The frame's mine, they're
just empty frames.
I collect them and they're
over there and just...
It's not that, not a big deal.
We don't have to worry about
that, they weren't stolen.
They're still here,
they're on my walls.
- Okay.
Let's just get a running count.
Which frames have
pictures missing and
which ones are just
weird frames on the wall?
- Okay, they're not
weird, empty frames.
It's just something I like.
It's just kind of a reminder -
We're not talking
about the frames!
- So you're telling me these
frames aren't a clue at all?
- No, the frames aren't a clue.
- Do you have any clues?
Do you have any leads?
Did anybody say "Hey, cool TV!"
But they said it, like, you
could tell they
really wanted it?
- No!
- Okay, tell you what.
Just fill out this
police report.
Call this number.
And we'll just hope
that some stuff
turns up that looks
like your stuff.
And we'll say
"That's his stuff."
It's not going to
happen, though, man.
- Do you have any other advice?
This has all been
really helpful.
- They're just things, you know?
Thank you.
- Do I know you?
- Yeah, I was here last night.
- What are you
talking about, man?
- I was here last night, I
was looking around for...
Pawn shop things, alone.
- Test two, you passed.
So how did it go?
- With what?
- You know.
- Yeah, no, nothing happened.
- Hey, I'm not here to judge,
it's your fingerprints.
- Actually, yeah, that's
what I'm here for.
I don't want it anymore,
I changed my mind.
- No returns.
I barter.
- Barter?
- Trade good for goods.
You know, I could buy
that back off you,
but you'd get a fraction
back what you paid for it.
Catch my drift?
- I think I do.
What kind of goods?
- Look around!
Got some TVs, got some stereos,
got some nice
suitcases, footballs.
You ride a motorcycle?
- No.
Hey, Ricky, you got
any camera equipment?
Mm-hmm, in the back,
just not shelf-ready,
that's all.
- You have a really
nice collection here.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
Where'd you get it?
- Sources.
Yeah, do you keep any
records of your sources?
Like who brought
in specific stuff?
- That's not how it works.
- How does it work, I'd
really like to know?
- Why?
- I'm very curious.
I'm willing to learn
anything you can tell me.
If you could teach
me anything...
If we could just work together,
I'd really, I need to know.
- Together?
Are you a cop?
Of course you're not!
You bought an illegal
weapon from me.
- Yes.
- Maybe you should
come back later.
- All right, well, I'll
hold on to this then.
- Can't talk shop
now I'm on the clock.
Don't want to piss of the owner.
Okay.
- Cause that's me.
- You look nice.
Thank you.
- May I have
your name, please?
- Dave.
- Okay, Dave,
it'll be just a minute.
I can take your
coats if you'd like.
- Oh, thank you.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Sir?
- I'm all right, I'm fine.
- I can take
you two, right this way.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing, fine.
Ew.
I was meaning to get rid of it.
I was right on the way
to do it and then...
It's fine.
I don't need the table anymore.
It's very nice, it's lovely.
You can keep playing.
Sar -
Hey, I'm sorry, all right?
- It's okay, I'll see you later.
- No, look, let's just
go grab a burger or something.
- No, I've had enough
of you tonight.
- Why are you still here then?
- Because we came in your car.
- So you want to get a burger?
- No.
Enjoy your kid's meal.
- Creepy little ghost
child again, all right.
What are you doing in here?
How did you get back in here?
- I'm sorry about what
happened last time.
- I really don't care.
I really...
Just get out of the car.
I'll wait here all night,
get out of the car.
Get out of the car!
- I don't have anywhere to go.
- Are you hungry?
I'm hungry, I could eat.
How about you?
All right, what do you want?
- I don't have any money.
- It's all right,
I'll pay for it.
What do you want?
Chicken tenders.
- Chicken tenders, all right.
Excuse me, could I get some -
- And some fries.
- Fries.
Can I -
- And a fruit cup, a
lemonade, extra BBQ sauce.
- Can I get two cheeseburgers
and two cokes, please.
I'm not getting all that.
- Do you know how many
calories are in a sandwich?
- No, how many?
900.
- I don't care.
I saw it on TV.
I thought you
would want to know.
- So what do you want,
what are you doing?
- I have to get to my brother.
- Why?
- Because he's the only
family I have left.
I was adopted after
my parents died.
They're awful people.
- Sorry.
- If I can get to my
brother, he can claim me.
And I know he'd be
better than those people.
- So where is he?
- Colorado.
- So are you just
going to take my car
and drive it all
the way to Colorado?
- It's not that far.
I printed off the maps,
we could still go.
- Colorado?
Yeah, okay, I guess
I've time for a
12 hour trip to
Colorado, why not?
Sounds like a blast.
We're not
going to do that, okay?
- But I thought you
said you'd help me.
Yeah, I am helping you.
You're eating, you're not
walking the street right now.
I'm not going to take you on
some kind of
cross-country roadtrip.
Besides, I'm sure
you've got parents or
something looking
for you right now.
- They're not, I
made sure of it.
- I don't want to
know what that means.
What?
I don't, no.
You stay here, I'll call
you a cab, you can jump in
the back of that car, you
can go anywhere you want.
Anywhere.
Colorado, Disneyland,
I don't care.
- I'm not leaving this car.
- Okay, that's your choice.
But I'm going to
a very scary part
of town where little
girls don't go.
And if you think I'm
going to care about
your safety for one
second, guess what?
I'm not.
I don't care!
Did you get enough to eat?
- I thought
you didn't care.
- I don't!
But they're like 900
calories, all right?
I don't want it.
Hey, give me the fast
food bag under your seat.
- He doesn't want your food,
he just wants your money.
- That guy?
He looks hungry.
Come on, give me the food.
It's just a sandwich, come on.
No.
All right.
Okay, roll down your window.
No.
Come on, it's okay.
Just roll your window down.
Look, he...
Hold on!
You forgot this.
- Yeah,
sorry, could you -
- Want me to throw
that on there for you?
- Thanks, man,
I'd appreciate that.
- All right.
You gotta pop it.
Oh, okay.
- You're all set.
- Hey, man, do you
want this sandwich?
- Oh, God bless you, man.
No problem.
Thank you, thank you.
Yeah.
- Have
a good night, guys.
Stay safe.
You too.
Okay.
Don't worry, it's not for you.
You're the most serious
little girl I've ever met.
It's been a pleasure.
- That's because I have
places to be and things to do.
And I need help.
- You need help?
I need help.
All right, everybody needs help.
Meet me in the back.
What?
In the back.
Hey, blood bro!
- Hey.
- Just talk about it
later, talk about it later.
That's how you're dressed?
- Well, for what?
- You have a lot to learn.
You're going to need gloves.
This is all I have,
but it's better
than what you have right now.
Oh, sorry about that.
Yeah, that works.
Saddle up, partner.
- What are we doing?
- Okay, what's
with the sketch mode?
Sketch mode?
I thought we were going inside.
- I thought you wanted to
see where I got this stuff.
- Yeah, I thought you
were going to tell me inside.
- Okay.
So wait a minute...
Were you expecting
me to videotape
it and then show
it to you later?
We can pull it up via
satellite, but I was
pretty sure you wanted to
know where I got the stuff.
- I just don't know
what we're doing
and I've actually
got things to do.
- You going to leave me?
You were going to
leave me, weren't you?
- I wasn't going
to leave you, man.
I'm not going to do that.
- Then why do
you want to go inside?
- I just would like...
I didn't know we were going
to do, like, a whole van trip.
- You promised
me a ride in the van.
- I didn't, I didn't
make that promise.
- I'm not going without you.
- I'm not gonna get in the van.
I'm not gonna get in the van.
- There's somebody
looking at us, get in the van.
- There's somebody -
- There's somebody
looking at us, get in the van.
- But...
- There's seriously
somebody watching us.
- I can't stay out too
late, you know, I gotta...
- I promise,
it'll be fine, I promise.
- But, Rick, hold on.
- It'll be fine.
- Just one second, I just...
Okay.
Hey, I don't know if this
is such a great idea.
- You're funny, partner!
- Yeah, I'm not really
kidding, though.
- We're driving
by and saw this and it's
now saying that it looks like
there is no criminal activity.
That they -
- What are we doing?
- Goods, my friend, goods.
Going to get the goods.
You wanted to see them, right?
- You didn't really
answer my question.
- This is it.
Grab my hand.
- All right, but the thing is -
- Grab my hand.
- What?
All right.
- Take a deep breath.
Dear Lord, please bless the
hallways we're about to enter.
Make this house nice,
big, and warm, and cozy.
We're about to rock out.
Amen.
This is gonna be good.
- Wait, it just seems to
me like we're about -
- This gets scarier every time.
- Shoot him, be a man,
be a man, be a man.
He doesn't have a
gun, you can do this.
- What are you doing?
What?
I...
- Two car garage.
- What, what, what, what, what?
- I'm just
checking your reaction.
- Okay.
Okay.
Ricky?
What?
- Let's not do it.
There's no one home.
- Let's just get
away from the door.
- In and out,
in and out, in and out.
- This is a citizen's arrest.
This is a citizen's arrest.
Citizen's arrest.
Shh.
I got the goods, go
grab whatever you want.
What are you doing?
Drop the TV.
- What are you talking about?
- This is a citizen's
arrest, drop the TV.
- What?
Hey!
Who the hell's down there?
Hey, hey!
- I thought we were partners.
- You stole my stuff
from my apartment.
I saw it in your store.
- Okay, so your plan
was to arrest me?
Son of a bitches!
- While robbing
someone with me?
- Break into my house,
I'm gonna bash your damn skull.
- You stop right there!
- Buddy, if you pull that
trigger, you better hope I die.
Cause I'm gonna
bash your skull in.
- Sir?
I actually don't know him,
I've got it under control -
- Quiet, partner!
- Just, will you put the
gun down, figure it out?
- Listen to me, okay?
I'm in contr -
Do you know what
I'm gonna do to you?
You really don't
want to test me.
You want to test me?
Do you want to test me, huh?
- I didn't load the gun.
Go!
Okay, we're just gonna
have to go to plan B.
You got to hurry.
- Oh!
- He's coming again,
he's coming again.
- Get out of
the car, assholes!
- Dangit!
He's reloading.
- You live on Gilchrest, right?
- Yeah, what does that
have to do with anything?
- Meet you there in 30 minutes.
Okay, but...
I think you killed him.
- I've never killed
anyone before.
- We should probably go.
- I didn't mean to.
That's what you're going
to tell everyone, right,
that I didn't mean to, right?
- Yeah.
I didn't mean to.
It's all -
- Please don't take
a picture of me.
- It's not.
It's video.
- What, what, what?
All right, don't video me.
- It's just a video,
man, it's just a video.
- Running only
proves you're guilty.
- Get in, I have Google Maps.
- All right.
We just got to get to a police
station and explain things.
- You can't go to the police.
- We have to.
I'll tell them first.
Because if I don't,
they're going to think...
They're going to think I
ripped that guy's house off.
- If you go to the
Police Station,
you'll have to tell
them what happened.
Then you're going to
have to mention me
and I can't let you do that.
- All right, what do
you want me to do?
- Take me
to a bus station.
If you want to get
rid of me so badly.
- It doesn't sound like
too bad of an idea.
- I have to go to the bathroom.
- Great, I'll be right here.
- Hey, buddy, it sure looks
like a long line we're in.
Glad we get along.
- Yeah.
- You know, I'd be willing to
wait for you, if you'd like.
I'd do it for ten bucks.
- I got it under
control, thanks.
- All right.
How about five bucks?
Five bucks.
- You know what?
No thank you, no thank you.
- All right.
- Hey, man, do you
have ten bucks?
- No.
- Is that your
beautiful daughter?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- You like magic little girl?
- You know,
guys, she's not a fan.
- I was just trying to
show her magic, man!
- Know any other bus stations?
- Oh, hey buddy.
- Hey, how's it going, guys?
What do you want now?
- How about ten bucks and
we don't call the cops.
- I don't know what
you're talking about.
- Hey, how about
five a piece, we go.
- Yeah, that's $10,
which I don't have.
Not going to give it to you.
- How about for eight bucks,
we won't call the cops
and we can get you out of here
without you being recognized?
- What are you talking about?
- This man
is wanted for questioning
in the attempted
robbery of a local home.
If you do see this man, contact
authorities immediately.
- How about a dollar
and I don't scream?
- Here.
Enjoy your night.
Eve, go get on a bus.
- Just take me
to Colorado Springs.
My brother can talk to the cops.
He's in law school.
I'm your alibi.
He could help both of us out.
- It's a good idea.
It's a good idea to get
out of town for a while.
So that's probably
what I'll do, anyway.
So it's not that...
You open the garage?
And that's what happened
after you ditched me.
- Dave.
- I'm serious.
There's police out there
right now looking for me
thinking I'm some sort of
master criminal or something.
And I'm not.
And I'm scared and I just...
I got to get her to her
brother in Colorado Springs
because he's a lawyer, right?
And, you know, he
could help me out.
And I'm a witness,
she's a witness, right?
So, I think this whole
thing will blow over.
- Dave, I don't see how
that's going to work.
She's an alibi.
What are you?
- An alibi.
- See, this
is going to work out.
- Fine, whatever.
What do you want from me?
- It's nothing too big,
you know, I just...
I just need your car.
Mine's on the news, so
they'll pull it over.
- No.
- Why?
- Don't put me in
this position, Dave!
I know you're a good guy, kid.
- What?
- I know
you're a good kid.
And I don't want a
kid driving my car.
- Yeah, of course not.
That won't happen.
Can you just wait
in the other room?
Wait, wait.
Why do you think I'm a kid?
- Because you show up
late every day to work.
- No, I don't.
- Because you've never done
anything to make
me think otherwise.
- I just need your help.
- I don't know about that, Dave.
- What part?
- I don't know.
- What are you doing?
Stop following me, okay?
She said no, that's
it, this is the end.
I'm sorry, okay, I'm sorry.
I've got nothing left.
- Is she going to call the cops?
- No, she's not going
to call the cops.
- How do you know?
- Because I trust her.
- Why?
- Because I'm kind of an
idiot and she still likes me.
- Well, if she
likes you and isn't going
to call the police, why don't
we just borrow her keys?
- Hey, that's called stealing.
- Do you want to go to jail
and never see her again?
- I think we have plenty
more options available.
And I don't...
- You need a disguise.
- What?
A disguise.
- Eve, I'm fine.
I think if we just keep
going, it'll work itself out.
- What if somebody
recognizes you?
Hello, Eve.
There's three things you
need to know about me.
I'm a fast runner,
I like mathematics,
and I'm incredibly
mature for my age.
- This isn't the time.
- It's green, I
don't wear green.
You know, I was eating chips
and he had chips and he felt
like he didn't have
enough chips as me.
I said "Back off, my chips."
He took my chips anyway.
And I said "You take another
chip, I'm gonna clock you."
And he took a chip and I
hauled off and hit him.
And then he hit
me back, we rolled
around, it was kind of a mess.
And we both really didn't know
how to fight, still don't,
and yeah, we stopped talking
for I don't know how long.
I don't know, he got
a hold of me online.
And he's like "Hey,
what's going on?"
We were older and I was like
"It's great to hear from you."
And he told me he got in
some kind of accident,
messed up his foot, broke it.
And then when they went
to take the cast off,
I guess they found a
tumor or something.
He said it was no big deal.
And he really wanted
to see my stuff
and I was like "Sure".
I don't know.
Then like happened, right?
Didn't get around to it.
Stuff came up.
Anyway, he got a
hold of me again.
Except it wasn't
him, it was a...
It was an invitation
to his funeral.
And...
I don't know, I just realized
that someone was
reaching out to me.
And I didn't take the opportunity
or the time to reach back.
- I guess we all go through life
with "welcome"
written on our backs.
- Yep.
- May I please
use your bathroom, sir?
What are we doing?
- I just, I need to take a nap.
Just for a couple of hours.
Really?
It's not that far.
Yeah.
Just don't keep the car
running the whole time
and crack a window for me, okay?
You should get some
sleep, too, huh?
Just for a little bit,
just for a little bit.
Eve?
Eve, you gotta shut the car off,
you're going to run
the battery down.
Gotta shut the car off.
Eve?
- Good, you're awake.
- Did you drive
the whole way here?
- Somebody had to.
Coffee?
- Okay, don't drive my car.
- I got us here.
- Just don't drive the car.
Watch your feet.
Okay, you're sure he lives here?
It's what my map said.
- Okay, well...
Guess this is it.
It just doesn't look like
anybody lives here, Eve.
- Well, I
think somebody does.
- Hey, Derek, I think
your daughter is here.
- No, we made a mistake, sorry.
- Nevermind.
- It might be a house
next door, or something.
Or some place close.
All right?
- Eve.
Daniel!
- What are you doing here?
This is Dave.
He helped me find you.
- Hi.
- Hey man.
What about the people that
are looking after you?
- I couldn't stay
with them anymore.
- Aren't they going
to be looking for you?
- Nope.
- Hold on one second, okay?
- Okay.
I told you.
- I know.
But, Eve, I don't think
we should stay here.
I think your brother's
probably really busy, okay?
- No!
- Hey,
turn the music down.
- No!
- We'll come back tomorrow.
- No.
Can we trust him?
- Yes!
Is he a cop?
- No.
- Come on in.
Hey, no, no, no.
Don't go over there.
It's right over here.
Let's go.
Have a seat.
- So, Even tells
me you went to law school?
- I know the justice
system pretty well.
- Are you going to be able
to help us with this mess?
- What mess?
- Dave, he can help
us out in the morning.
I'm just kind of tired.
- Uh, yeah.
Do you want to...
Why don't you just
sleep on my bed tonight?
And you good on that couch?
- Sure.
- Blanket and pillow.
Here.
Thanks.
- Yeah, no problem.
Dave, just keep the TV
really low if you use it.
- How long are they
going to be here?
Just...
Sorry, sorry, really sorry.
- All right,
all right, all right.
This one's good.
It's a little shaky,
but it's good stuff.
It's all right.
- It's Dave
and he's asleep.
He's fine, he just passed out.
Dawg, he's leaving.
Why?
Cause he was watching
me work earlier.
- What are
you talking about?
They just showed up.
I just put them both
to sleep, they're fine.
I don't know, man.
You shouldn't even
be fine if you're
hanging out with
your little sister.
- You're
being paranoid.
- There aren't
many things more terrifying
than losing a child, as Ted
and Carol Webber can attest to.
Ted and Carol are
the newly adoptive
parents of nine year
old Eve Schneider.
After last night's
devastating fire,
the nine year old
was assumed dead.
But after the smoke had cleared,
police found evidence
that said otherwise.
Melissa Duran reports.
- Well, Gary,
I'm standing right in front
of the Metrol Police
Station, where I just
finished talking to
Detective Mark Benson.
He tells me that inside of the
burnt remains, they actually
found no trace of nine
year old Eve Schneider.
What they did find was a
trail of burnt gasoline
that led from the
house to the backyard.
Now police believe
that this fire may
have been a cover-up
for a kidnapping.
And they believe it could all
be linked back to this man.
No.
- Reporting
live, Melissa Duran.
- My friends come here
and smoke you out all the time.
All the time!
- Eve, Eve, come
on, come on, come on.
We need to go, we need to leave.
We need to get out
of here, all right?
- Wait, not
that way, not that way.
Daniel!
- Wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait!
- Hey,
are you spying on me?
No, no, it was just...
- You
watching me while I work?
No!
- Hey, hey, relax, relax.
Stop!
Let him alone.
Leave him alone!
I'm sorry, Dave.
- Sorry for what?
Sorry for what?
Bringing me out here in
the middle of nowhere
just so I can meet
your lawyer brother?
You know, I'm not the only
one on TV anymore, Eve.
It said you burned down
your parents' house.
Is that true?
Look at me.
What?
- I burned my house
down so they would
think I was dead
and not look for me.
- Why didn't you
just go to the cops?
Somebody picks on you,
somebody hits you, somebody
abuses you, you just going
to burn their house down?
Think!
- They didn't abuse me.
- What?
- I thought you said
they were awful people.
- I don't know.
- What do you mean
you don't know?
- I don't know if
they're awful people.
- How do you not know?
- They were never going to
let me live with my brother.
- Oh, okay.
That's great.
You know, he's not going to
let you live with him, either.
You know that, right?
You know, it doesn't matter.
Get in the car.
Get in.
No!
- Ah, that's fine.
- I really need
to eat something.
- No.
No more talk and no more talking
for the rest of the trip.
- Dave, I really need
to eat something.
- Do you have any idea
what you've done to me?
Done to my life?
You know what?
Just say "no", because
you have no idea.
You know, you're just
a walking little curse.
- Dave, I need to eat
something, I'm sorry.
- All right, here's
what's going to happen.
We're not going to do what you
want for the rest of the trip
we're going to do what I want
for the rest of the trip.
And what I want is for
nothing else to go wrong.
Starting now.
- Whoa, shit!
Oh.
Okay.
Okay, let's just sit here.
- Tire blew out?
- Yeah.
- Well let me help you out.
I'll get you back on
the road in no time.
- Oh, you know, I
got it, actually.
I'm all right.
- I don't mind at all.
- Okay.
Thanks again.
Oh, no problem.
Always happy to help, bud.
See?
Twice as fast.
You were right, man.
Thanks.
Not a problem.
Hope your day turns
out much better.
- I hope so, too.
Have a good one.
- Yeah.
- We're going to be fine.
Just...
Eve?
Eve!
Hey, hey, hey.
All right, we'll go,
we'll go, we'll just...
Doesn't look so bad.
- It's no big deal.
Yeah.
- It's a minor problem.
- All right, thanks, man.
- License?
Uh, yeah, but we're...
So it's good, right?
- Yeah, it's just for
precautionary purposes.
Insurance thing, yeah.
All right, yeah.
Yeah, no big deal.
- Oh, let me check
it out for a second.
- All right, yeah, sorry.
- I'll be right back.
- Okay.
- Stay put.
Eve, Eve, you good?
- Sir!
Out of the car, now.
Sir, out of the car, now!
Turn around.
Turn!
Put your hands behind your head.
Interlock your fingers.
All right, officer, can
you please look into the car?
Okay, I've got a sick -
- Start walking backwards
until I tell you to stop.
Please!
- Walk backwards until
I tell you to stop!
I've got a sick girl.
- Sir, put your hands
on the hood of this car now!
Just listen to me.
- Sir, do not reach
into the vehicle.
- Please, you just
have to listen to me.
- Sir, I
will fire on you, sir.
A sick girl!
- All right.
Well, the bullet missed
all your tendons and bone.
It passed through one
side, right out the other.
You're actually
incredibly lucky.
- Yeah, that's what I'm
going to tell all my friends.
And now I get to heal in prison,
so it's even more perfect.
- Now, Dave, I've never
actually been to prison -
- Really?
- And my guess is
that you're going
to be a lot better
off with two arms.
- Cause of the rape?
- Yes, because of the rape.
- Awesome.
- Listen, life's very
long until the end.
Then it's not long enough.
Well, that's lunch for me.
Good luck!
- Sorry, guys, can I
ask her a few questions?
- You be all right?
Okay, be right outside.
Okay.
So how are we doing, Eve?
Do you need anything?
- I just want to see Dave.
- That's not possible.
- Why not?
- Dave's in a lot of trouble.
But let's talk
about your parents.
Did they do anything
to upset you?
- Ted and Carol don't love me
as much as they're pretending.
- And why do you think
they're pretending?
- They're just not my family.
- Okay.
Eve, nobody chooses
their parents.
I didn't.
But they chose you.
I should go.
- Remember what I said about
the bear in the forest?
Do you think if I
would have given him
a sandwich, he would
have left me alone?
- It's worth a try.
- Steve!
Eve, what are you doing?
- I'm gonna get you out of here.
- Stop, stop it.
- I picked at these
things before.
- You're not listening, Eve.
Look at me.
I'm not leaving.
- Dave!
- You're just a kid
and they're going to
forgive you for the
mistakes you've made.
Okay, but I'm an adult.
So I'm gonna try this whole
taking responsibility
thing for once.
So just, you know, go be a kid.
For once.
All right?
You've got your
whole life to ruin,
so just get out of here.
Go on.
- One count of arson,
one count of kidnapping,
one account of driving
without a valid license,
you confess to all these?
- Yes.
- Ms. Schneider, you do
understand that you are
under our protection and
that nothing can happen
to you while you are
under our protection?
- Yes.
- Did Mr. Pilcher influence what
you have to say
today in any way?
- Yes.
- He did?
And how did he influence
your testimony today?
- I used to lie a lot.
And I lied to Dave.
He was the first person I
trusted after my parents died.
And I lied to him.
I regret that now and I'm
gonna try and stop lying.
- Well, Mr. Pilcher.
There's no further
evidence against you,
thanks to Miss
Schneider's testimony.
The only outstanding
charge is resisting arrest.
- That's it?
- Unless you wish to press
charges against Miss Schneider?
- No, no.
- Mr. and Mrs. Webber, would
you like to press charges?
No, of course not.
- Miss Schneider, I hereby
sentence you to two months
in juvenile hall, with a
chance to parole in one.
Mr. Pilcher, I sentence
you to two weeks in
county jail, with
six months probation.
- It's going to be
okay, Eve, all right?
You're going to be just fine.
- I know, I've
been there before.
Plus, I have friends
on the inside.
- You're serious?
- Bye, Dave.
You want to hold
your mommy's hand
with both hands?
Yeah!
Very cute, very cute.
You should smile.
Right here!
I need a second, guys.
You want to go get some
hot chocolate in the lobby?
- Okay.
Okay.
I'll come and get you.
What's this?
- It's a check to get your
car out of the impound lot.
- Oh.
- I'm really sorry.
- It's okay.
- I also wanted to just
talk and explain a lot.
- I think you did some
really good things for Eve.
- Well, I don't know about that.
- She really thinks
highly of you.
- I still made a mistake.
I shouldn't have gone
behind your back.
- Yeah.
- I regret a lot of things.
- There's time to
make up for that.
- Yeah, great, okay.
- Eve, what
are you doing here?
- You've got to hide me.
- No, I'm not going to hide you.
I'm not gonna..
Hey, wait, wait, wait,
wait, wait, wait.
Stop, stop!
- I couldn't take
it in there anymore.
I can't be shoved
in a box like that.
So I slipped through
the bars and got away.
They let me out
on good behavior.
- Well that's not funny.
So how'd you get here?
My parents.
- The adopted ones?
- I burnt their
house down and they still
took me back, so I guess
they're not as bad as I thought.
- I'm sure by the time
you get to be a teenager,
they'll let you slide
with a lot of things.
That's really cool.
So, what do you want?
- I left my bag in your car.
- Eve, I got your...
Dave?
Hi.
Here's her bag.
Thank you.
- Yeah, no problem.
- For taking care of her.
I don't blame her
for running away.
She was just trying
to find her family.
- Yeah, I think she found it.
- Gary, behind me is
the burnt remains of an
establishment many locals
knew as Ricky's pawn.
Police tell me that these
empty walls house hundreds of
stolen goods from all
around the valley and also
operated as a store front
for illegal weapon sales.
I'm being told that the
evidence seized here
is also linked to another
investigation that could land
this small pawn shop owner
behind bars for a very long time.
Reporting live,
Melissa Duran, 8 News.
- Look like you could...
Maybe could use some help, huh?
- Yeah!
I could use some
help from a cop.
Love cops.
- Thank you.
So you're just throwing
it in the back, huh?
- Yeah, you just...
It's just stuff.