Presented by MCI- Korea & Xcalibur
Produced by Dream Search
Distributed by Cinema Service Co. Ltd
Producer Victor Hwang
Executive Producer Jin Seung-hyun
Screenplay
Hyun Chung- ryul Yeoh Gee-na
Line Producer Lee Dong-sung
Jang Yong-hum Lee Chang-hun
Choi Min-soo
Cha Seung-won
Yu Gee-tae Park Sang-myun
Jung Jun Kim Kyu-ri Kim Soo-ro
Lee Ho-jae Park Jae-hoon
Just think of it as a vacation.
I'll see you next time, okay?
Paroled
Cinematography Suh Jong-min
Gaffer Shin Jun-ha
Camera Jang Jun-yang
Editing Park Soon-duk
Sound Mixer Ahn Sang-ho
Music Lee Dong-jun
Sound Sound & Company
Wardrobe/Make-up Jung Hong-joo
Props Jung In-yang
Production Design Kang Seung-young
Set Oh Sang-min
Special Make-up Shin Chae-ho
Computer Graphics Kang Jong-ik
Special Effects Jung Do-ahn
Stunt Coordinator Jung Doo-hong
Co- Producer Hyun Chung-ryul
Director Yang Yun-ho
'Five months later'
Libera Me
Come up!
Run! Run!
Hyun-tae!
Shit!
Sang-woo!
Everyone clear! Everyone okay?
Hey, Sang-woo! Hyun-tae!
This is 3-1, 3-1.
Continue water back-up.
Our exit's gone.
We'll get to it when we head out.
Present situation stable.
We need water, Apt. 503.
Moving on.
Present situation stable. Damn.
Chul-goo! Chul-goo!
Pull the hose! Damn!
...lots of casualties,
can't enter A4... two down.
Sir.
Third floor inspection complete,
no casualties.
Chief, move out, hurry!
We can't do anymore.
Chief! Chief. Help me.
That idiot...
Chief, help me, please!
Please save my daughter!
Our men are in there. We need backup.
ls this a crematorium or something?
Chief, l barely made it out of there.
Let's go, Ax.
Chief, chief... Dammit.
Ready? Let's go.
The hose!
Bring up the pressure!
Water pressure 47.
Let's clear out, Sang-woo.
Wait a second.
There's something,
definitely something here.
Sang-woo.
Chief, please help me.
Help me... Chief...
Sang-woo! Sang-woo!
Sang-woo!
What are you doing, Sang-woo?
Grab it! Grab it! Grab it!
Team 3, meet up with the chief,
Apt. 405.
Taking out the body...
Fifth floor inspection complete,
one dead.
Apt. 405.
It's okay.
Okay...lt's okay.
It looks about 4 or 5 meters.
Want me to measure it?
It's a bit dangerous.
Better be careful.
You're the one in danger.
Go up!
It's not that long, dammit!
I'll be there soon. Hang on.
Respond, Sung-hwan! Chul-goo!
The path's too narrow!
We can't go on!
Sang-woo!
3-1. Entering 405.
Chul-goo! Wake up! Wake up!
- Check! ls he conscious?
- Wake up!
The path is blocked! 18-1 come in!
Respond, dammit!
Wake up!
Sung-hwan! Snap out of it!
Chul-goo, wake up!
- How many wounded?
- Chul-goo!
- Four wounded.
- Get up!
Serious, serious condition.
Back up, quick.
Got it. Start with the kid.
A kid? There's a kid?
Mommy! Mommy!
- Sung-eun! Sung-eun!
- Mommy!
This kid's here. The kid's here.
Don't waste time, get the wounded out.
Can you walk?
- Chul-goo goes first.
- Hurry up.
- Hurry up!
It's the same for everyone, dummy.
Go on.
You think he can hang on?
You want everyone to die?
We're all gonna die, moron!
Hurry up and get out of here!
Now! Now! Get out, now!
I'll be back. l promise you.
You can't give up. Don't give up.
Hurry! Hurry!
- Take him.
- Got him.
Sang-woo! Sang-woo!
If you can breathe,
then l can breathe, too.
Move! They're both gonna die that way!
Hyun-tae! Hyun-tae!
Let me go! Let me go!
You'll kill yourself that way!
They're out!
Hey, take him! Take him!
Careful! Careful!
- Chief!
- It's okay.
Someone, there's someone inside!
There's someone there!
There's someone in there!
Let's withdraw for now.
I'm telling you, there's someone there!
Dammit! Why aren't they
out already? Shit!
- 85-1, 85-1 come in.
- Try the walkie, hurry!
85-1, what's going on?
What's going on? 85-1.
God dammit, respond!
They're out!
Oh, mom. Mom.
You live in Apt. 405, right?
Bro...
Chul-goo...he's gonna be fine.
Let's go.
Hey, Chul-goo. Bro, you're not
gonna die. Hang in there, okay?
Do something, will ya?
Come on! Move it, already!
Hey, get out of the way!
Hold on a little longer, Chul-goo!
- Another fire?
- Yes. He's already the fifteenth.
Respiratory distress.
We washed him with saline
and injected 50cc of medicine.
Are you crazy? If you don't know then
don't do it! You trying to kill him?
But the situation...
There are no more beds.
We're shorthanded so we
paged the off-duty residents.
Transport this patient to
Dong- A Hospital first.
Transport this patient to Dong-A
Hospital first. And the other patients.
What, you bastard? You moving
a dying man to another hospital?
Okay now?
Are you crazy? Get this person out.
Hey. If he dies, so do you.
Can l help?
- We need to move this patient
to a room first. - Okay.
Excuse me. Here. Yes.
Oh. It just went bang! Bang!
You said that before.
Tell me about the family in Apt. 405.
I'm telling you, it went bang! Bang!
I'm Seol In-jae,
the detective in charge.
Sir, a moment over there, please.
Hyun!
How far along are you?
- I'm still investigating.
- Hand it over.
- What have you done?
- I'll be done soon.
- It just went bang!
- One second.
Just hand in your report later.
I'll take a look. You're not
gonna put arson again, are you?
- This way.
- It was a bang! Bang!
Okay, tell me slowly,
from the beginning.
- So it was like...
- Yes, go on.
If it was up to me,
Chul-goo would have been first.
We lost In-soo. Chul-goo could
have gone that way, too.
He could've been burnt
to the crisp like paper.
Let's finish this quickly and go.
After becoming your partner, on
every job, l look for the exit first.
There's no one to help me anyway.
Because I'm alone.
l want to live.
Apt. 405. There was no one.
I'll request a change of partner.
Will that do?
ln-soo...
In-soo. Where are you?
In-soo. Answer me.
In-soo. Answer me, In-soo.
Sang-woo. Come out quick.
Let's have a cigarette.
In-soo, Sang-woo. It's out of control!
Hurry up! In-soo!
In-soo!
ln-soo... ln-soo...
How are you these days?
Oh, I'm good.
Work environment's good. Most of all,
I'm so happy to be around kids.
- So-eun, Jung-uk, Jang-sun...
- 'Family killed, convicted arsonist'
Oh, l hear Jangsun's going home soon.
- He's healthy now. You were big help.
- 'Age 15: killed 6 in fire'
When l first met you,
l was about Jang-sun's age.
l wanted to do the same.
'Regained speech ability' Like you,
l want to comfort the children.
The children seem to look forward
to reading time now.
- Really? - 'Presently
paroled-supervision: Dr. Jung'
l feel like I'm reborn.
It's all thanks to you.
Still, stop cleaning my room now.
l like doing it.
You know Sung-euns back?
Because of yesterdays fire.
Yes. She drew pictures
with me yesterday.
I'm a little worried about her, too.
Can you find my patient records,
from 15 years ago?
- Yes.
- Please bring it to my room.
- Are you kidding me?
Insurance only covers the basics.
Burns infect easily.
With infection, the patient can die.
The patient has to pay for that.
Ha! You're killing me!
You guys are out to drive us crazy!
Shit! Listen. A fire!
It's bad enough he got hurt
putting out a fire! Now pay up?
Wait, so the police and military
get it for free but we have to pay?
Nonsense!
Man, l could just blow a fuse!
Anyway, I've informed the family.
Please make a decision soon.
What? Excuse me. Wait.
Oh, hey.
When did you get here?
Gasoline?
Yeah. The path of the fire
was unnatural.
Even though the window was open, the
fire moved against the flow of air.
It looks like someone kept feeding the
fire, while constantly watching us.
Constantly? From in here?
Um...
I've already told the
police everything.
Sorry to keep bothering you.
It's just that a gas explosion
from your home started the fire.
- Did you use a gas heater, by any
chance? - No, nothing like that.
My husband comes home for lunch every
day. He had lunch on that day, too.
My mom and husband were home.
And l was at the supermarket.
It was about the time my child
came home so l went to
the kindergarten to pick her up.
But the school bus had already left.
So l thought my child was at home.
The gas must have leaked.
It was such an old building...
- By any chance...
- Please...
Please, don't come anymore.
l need to go to the hospital.
My daughter must be hungry.
l hope your husband gets well soon.
Let's go.
Sang-woo. It's so hard.
New member, Jung Jong-Gu.
On Dec. 15, 2000, appointed to
85th Station, reporting for duty!
It's an honor.
What's an honor?
First in early extinguishment.
First in rescue.
The 85th Station is a legend, isn't it?
Legend, whatever. Damn.
Hey, take your bag off.
Take your bag off quick.
Lower yourself.
- Yo, new recruit!
- Yes?
You think a legend just happens, huh?
Hold tight!
Ah! Help me! Ow. It hurts. Help me.
l went through that, too.
l was only in my underwear.
Be thankful, okay?
- Hey, do it right.
- Pull out a chair.
Help yourself. It's delicious.
Hey, you eat now, too.
Yes. Thank you!
Here's to a good meal!
Wow, this is really good.
He was the Chief's brother.
He and Sang-woo were partners.
They were a fantastic team.
Like you said, they were
a legend, a legend.
And it's not a spoken promise
but always leave a place for In-soo.
I'm sorry. l will never
sit there again.
That's not what l mean, buddy.
Uh, it's itchy again.
Damn, so much for
getting married. Follow me.
Yes.
Hmm, go in.
You go first, sir.
Go in, l said. Hurry up!
Have a good time.
What happened?
- Harder, chief.
- Think back when you were young.
- You were really hard on me. You
were, bro. - Don't make me laugh.
- Should we raise it?
- Raise it, come on.
Generate sound effects.
The Young-jun Pharmacy case, at least.
There are some records,
since you investigated, right?
Hey, where's Chief Kang's report?
l asked the chief to hold off.
We're still investigating.
What are you doing?
Our duty's to investigate off
of your report. Our duty!
But why are you here
asking for our reports? Huh?
These are pictures of your boyfriend.
Can you handle it?
- What about the depositions?
- There are none. Zero.
Detective Seol.
Listen carefully. l understand
how you feel but this fire
was just a gas explosion.
A gas explosion. An accidental fire.
You confuse things up like that time
and l won't take it. Got it?
It's not that there wasn't an arsonist,
but you couldn't catch one, right?
What?
Give me the depositions.
This is Chul-goo's equipment.
This is Chul-goo's.
Hyun-tae, l hear your suits trashed?
Yes.
Use this for now.
This is In-soo's.
And this is for you.
I've never regretted becoming a fire
fighter. He probably felt the same way.
Whoever saved 'Chu Chu' last week,
telephone for you in the lobby.
- Say it loudly, okay?
- Yeah, it's a puppy so we'll take it.
- Chu Chu.
- How can we find your mom?
- Okay. I'll put him on.
- Oh, it's Chu Chu's owner.
ls this Sung-jung?
ls Chu Chu fine?
Where's your mom?
You want me to find your mom?
Oh, l have to go. Sorry.
Geumjung 2 Dong Fire Station.
Jo Sang-woo speaking. Yes?
- l can't hear you very well.
- Let's go, bro.
Sang-woo, hurry up. Hurry.
Go.
- 27-2. This is 85-1. - This is 27-2.
Looking into present situation.
Damn, l thought today was quiet.
Why gas? That's the fucking worst.
- This is 85-1.
- 85-4 already on scene. Not a big one.
It being a gas station, look carefully
into a possible second explosion.
And good news for you. Kim Chul-goo
has regained consciousness.
- Thank you.
- Sure. Be well in the cold.
What was that phone call about?
l don't know. A wrong number, l think.
Something like 'don't interfere'.
- What?
- Sounded like a prank call.
- Ha, ha. Chul-goo's back!
- Man, Chul-goo made it. He made it.
Welcome chief. We closed the corner
because of the gas.
Yo, bro. l don't think
we need to unload.
- Sang-woo.
- Yes.
It's our district so be fully prepared
for a second explosion.
- Hyun-tae.
- Yes?
- Go and confirm if the valve
is locked first. - Sure.
Sang-woo, Ax, examine the gas tank
area and make sure of the origin point.
And just in case, go fully equipped.
Let's hurry up and go. It's cold.
Let's finish it quick,
and go to the hospital.
Excuse me. One second.
Do l have to pay again?
Why did you bring two fire trucks?
We don't take money.
Where's the origin of fire?
Over there. There.
- Move back.
- Clear the way, please.
It's dangerous.
- ls this the origin point?
- No. I'm just taking a picture.
l should report the owner. There are
illegal gas tanks in the back.
The temperature of the tanks is rising.
Park Han-moo!
What's up?
Re- examine the tank area.
Something's not right.
What? What's wrong with the tanks?
- Where does that pipe lead to?
- I've never seen that pipe before.
It's strange.
Get out!
Move!
God dammit.
Let's go!
Run!
Water!
Water! Water!
Who the hell are you?
Jae-hyuk! Jae-hyuk!
Take pictures. Take everything.
Pictures of everything.
Move.
Bang.
Move!
Go! Hurry up!
- Get me out of here!
- Grab it.
Uh, damn.
Let's go. Go, go!
- Sang-woo! Ax! Jun-sung!
- Snap out of it!
Jun-sung! Jun-sung!
Gotta save them, save them!
Sang-woo!
Hey, Chul-goo! Get up now, buddy.
Even the baby in your wife's belly
would laugh at you.
- Jun-sung.
- What?
The gas station owner,
is he dead?
Didn't you see the body bag?
Once you're inside, you're nothing.
Still, for a fire that size,
not too bad. Not bad.
Detective Park, that's not the way
to do it. What is this?
Detective Park.
Okay.
Please search this number for me.
It's for Detective Seol.
- Really?
- Yes.
Remember the Phoenix Fire
Insurance case, last month?
I'll give you some info.
Oh, it's okay. It's okay. It's fine.
Young-jun...
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Oh, it's warm here.
You must have been cold.
Shall l turn up the heat?
l left the temperature up before.
They must have rebelled
when l wasn't here.
Hee-soo. Why'd you do it, back then?
The children, 15 years ago.
Help! Help!
Why are you asking me?
Why are you so curious nowadays?
What more do you want
to know about me?
Are you asking
because you really don't know?
They hit me.
It must be a patient.
We'll talk later.
Detective Seol In-jae