Xi'an Film Studio
LIFE
Written by Lu Yao
Under the sky lies the Yellow River
which has many turns and twists
which there are dozens of boats
supported by dozens of masts
which are steered by sailors
Alas...
Directed by Wu Tianming
Don't cry
I'll fight with GaoMinglou
even if at the cost of my life
Jialin!
Jialin! Off your hand
Let me go!
please don't make trouble!
I have worked as a teacher for three years
When didn't I work very well
He has just graduated
from senior high school
Why can he replace me?
It is just because
he is a secretary, isn't it?
He is not only arbitrary but also shameless
Jialin! Jialin! Oh, Jialin
I won't kill him but write to accuse them
If you charge them
our family won't have a way out
They have direct access
to the high government authorities
Look, what a dog's life I lead!
Oh, Oh, Oh
Go! Go!
Oh, Oh
Jialin
Don't dig
Stop! Do you want to tire yourself out?
Put down your hoe and give it to me.
You stubborn guy
don't do it rashly like this!
Do you think the hoe as a pen?
Let's go!
Come on!
Sit down here!
Tut-tut
You see
the yellow sand prevents blooding
At the beginning
you should spend your strength gradually
for the long future
Grandpa Deshun
I want to try all
the painstaking work at the beginning
and then I won't
be afraid of any difficulties
But you shouldn't exert
all your strength any way
I feel very confused
I think the hard work
will make me feel better
Here you are. Drink all the water
Don't dig the land tomorrow
Learn to plow from me and dig the land
after your injury is cured
and I think it will cure itself
Ok, Jialin
Jialin
Hey, Qiaozhen
Uncle Liben, Qiaozhen isn't in now
My relative, Don't yell like this
Are you coming back from the meeting?
Yes
Ma Shuan comes to interview her
That damn girl
deliberately avoids meeting him
Well, what are you shouting for?
It will be time to finish the work soon
Hey, Qiaozhen
Why don't you go home
to see your fiance?
Qiuaozhen, let's go!
Oh, MaShuan, Mashuan
he will tie you up immediately
San Xing is a teacher now, isn't he?
Ah, ha ha ...
You're so capable of achieving
your purpose
I am not so capable as you now
You earn much more money
by doing business
your purse seems to be broken!
You go your way I go mine:
You have power and I earn money.
Hey, Mr. Gao
new term has begun now
but why haven't you?
I am not a teacher any more
Where are you going?
I am going to interview a girl
Who?
The second daughter of the Liu's
Aha, you take the most
beautiful girl in our village
Really...
Don't you know that Qiaozhen is the most
beautiful girl in the neighborhood?
Well, she is really an attractive girl
But I'm afraid I can't win her heart
Ha
Why are you back so late?
Any way, you should
Please talk about it after meal
Anyway, you should give us your opinion.
Why do you just keep silent?
You are not an honorable person
Come back!
no longer a baby now
Can't you see him no matter
whether you agree or not?
My elder sister
please mind your own business!
Sister, do you think
your father-in-law a kind person?
Jialin is a model teacher in our community
But your father-in-law replaced him
with his own son by hooks and crooks
What an arbitrary person he is!
In the Graduation
Examination of senior high school
Sanxing failed in Chinese
and got a zero in Math
Hem, how can he work as a teacher?
Alas, see how just you are!
Others’ dog bites strangers but you two
bite your companies deliberately
It's not my father-in-law who laid off Jialin
but the teaching
cadre Ma Zhansheng did alone
Your father-in-law and Ma Zhansheng
are birds of a feather
The ducks upriver and the goose downriver
Focusing their eyes on their brothers
Cooking the elm fruit and putting
the rice into the boiling water
Picking the fire woods
on the road and glancing at you
The clean glass window are brightening
Chuckling at you with the teeth white
Anxiously opening the door
Dear honey be back soon
Jialin
This is our family plot
I plant it myself
Dad, go home please
The county market will open tomorrow
Let your mother make some bread and
you can go to sell them on the market
That's easier than the work in the field
Then I can buy a carton
of cigarettes for you
I've heard that his uncle
has been an official
now in the army in Xinjiang
We may let Jialin go to meet his uncle
and maybe he can find a job
in the town with his help
It's said the population over there
is sparse so it is easy to find a job
It is so far away and our child
has never traveled such a long journey
so I can't feel at ease
I don't agree
You'd better see him first
in your next meeting
Tl go too. See you then!
Hey, Qiaozhen! Qiaozhen!
Yaping, let's return those books
Where are they. Please try to find them
Ok
GaoJialin?!
Jialin!
Jialin! Hello!
Jialin! Hi!
Where are you going?
To see a relative
Really?
You're really talented
I have read the essays you
wrote on the local newspaper
Your style of writing is so excellent
Jialin, are you still working as a teacher?
Replaced by the son of the Secretary
I am only a community member now
Then do you have less time for writing?
No, much more now
A poet said that
we write down numerous lines
of poetry with the hoes in the land
Ha ha ha ha
Where are you going ?
On a business trip to Taiyuan City
Are you still a buyer in the food company
I have been promoted
as the department dean
but there is a "vice" before "dean"
Jialin, if you want to buy cigarettes
alcohol or something like that
just let me know and I am sure
to offer you some help
please drop in to our broadcasting studio
I want to ask
you some questions on literature
You are now in a high position
It's unavailable for the common people
in the mountainous area to contact
Attention, please
It's time for No.308 train to leave
I see, you have not improved
your stubborn disposition
Passengers going to Taiyuan get
on the train quickly, please
See you then!
It's time for No.308 train to leave
See you
The passengers going to Taiyuan get
on the train quickly, please
Hey, Jialin
Jialin
are you coming to the market here?
To sell bread
Jialin, don't hate me
I am not the decisive guy in that matter
GaoMinglou and Secretary Zhang have
been close friends for so many years
How do you think, I should do?
I know much about you
Mr. Ma, don't mention it any more
I have been transferred to
the Labor Bureau of the county now
It may be called a promotion
I'm now a vice-director in the Labor Bureau
Hahaha, as a newly appointed official
I am busy to death
Leave it alone if you don't want
Jialin, Jialin
did you go to sell bread?
Yeah. Have you also come to the market?
Yes, I come here for nothing
Jialin, I know you
haven't sold a single bread
You are afraid of losing face
Let me sell them for you
and my mother hope you
would have a taste
Hey, Qiaozhen, Stay here for dinner
No, thanks. It's getting dark
Please check it
Qiaozhen, you are so capable!
The sun is setting
so you'd better go home first
Let's go together
I can't carry you on the bike
I'm afraid to throw you off
Then let me carry you
That won't do
Well, we don't ride bike
and walk home
You are tired
so let me push the bike
Green willows are growing tall
What do you love me for?
Horses are not the same height
Brother Jialin
don't struggle too hard
You are getting thinner these days
In fact, it's also good to be a farmer
because there are a large
number of farmers on the earth
There are hills
rivers and fresh air in our countryside
If you have a comfortable family
you can also live a happy life there
Neither can I get a position in school
nor can I do hard work in the field
As a peasant without
strength and farming skill
I might starve my wife and children to
death in the future. What will I do?
if you don't look down on me
Pardon?
You stay at home
and I work in the field
I won't let you suffer
It's dark now. Let's go
Why did you suddenly have such an idea?
Not suddenly
I have been thinking
about it these years
I can't expect it when you were a teacher
Now you are laid off
I feel both sad and happy
I may have a chance
I think, since you are a peasant now
Here you are. Have a cigarette
I have bought a carbon for you
Here you are
Iodine?
put some on your wounds when back home
How did you know my hand
I did know
A teacher's hands are very fragile
Are you feeling better now?
Listen, It's ok now
Well
Don't run away! Stop! Stop!
Don't run away
Hey!...
Ha Ha...
Let me off, please!
It doesn't matter.
I know you didn't
have supper this evening
People like us working
in the field year in year out
always feel too tired to have supper
after a full-day's fieldwork
let alone you
If you don't visit me
I must send it to your home
You shouldn't do that
If your father knows this matter
he will break my legs
Brother Jialin Yeah?
Whenever I see you
I feel you are closer than my parents
Grandpa Deshun
Hey, Qiaozhen
are you going to pick pig-food?
Yeah
Grandpa Deshun
the jujubes on our trees have turned red
Please taste some fresh ones. Ok
Jialin Ah!
Come to taste some jujube
Come over please
Thanks!
Here you are
Jialin Yeah?
Do you want a girlfriend?
Yeah, but none proper
How about Qiaozhen?
I believe that you two seem
to be born for one another
Well
You have a good judgment.
Grandpa Deshun
I have never thought about her
Don't tell lie
I figured it out long time ago
Hum, let's go!
Grandpa Deshun
don't gossip it with others, please
Take it easy
I won't tell anybody
Ha ha ha
Well, I feel so happy for you two
Well, just like the words in the old songs
you two are born a perfect match
Qiaozhen has her boyfriend
Who?
How did you say to him?
I said, that's just you
Really? Yeah
How did you dare to?
Egg shells are used to light
and only half the bed is bright
Small wine cups are used to measure the
rice and your poverty I don't dislike
Neither for your house nor for your land
Are you singing a song called
"Waiting fort brother"
The ducks upriver
and the goose downriver
Focusing their eyes on their brothers
Cooking the elm fruit and putting
the rice into the boiling water
Picking the fire woods on the road
Brother Jialin, Jialin
Look, how tired you are!
You'd better rest a day tomorrow
Twill let you rest
for one day every week
just as you had when in school
Run away quickly!
Don't beat me, Dad
I beat you to death. Shameless!
Please stop, Dad
How dare you want to marry
to that black sheep
By Jove! I can feel
all the villagers smirking behind me
She would lose my face
if I don't beat her to death
Elder sister, run away quickly!
I must beat you
a law-down dirty shame, to death
Jialin
Dad, that's enough!
Don't think about it any more
In this plight we are not able
to pursue a marriage with her
Who is pursuing?
You would
be good-for-nothing all your life
I will make a decision for my own
Just mind your own business
If you don't instruct your son strictly
and if I find him luring my daughter
I will break his legs!
I will scalp you
I won't give up!
Let's go and see!
I don't believe
I can't conquer you two
Hum, there are laws governing you!
Alas. It is nothing
but their love, isn't it?
Damn love!
how can you two flirt with each
other outside every night?
You have shamed us all
Why aren't you open-minded
since you well-traveled
and a man of wide experience?
Today the young are different
from us in the old times
There are so many new things you
have never seen or heard of
Several years ago
Come on!....
When I passed Xi'an and Taiyuan
to visit the famous Dazhai Village
I saw many young men and women
walking on the streets
hand by hand during the daytime
He will ruin my Qiaozhen
What? GaoJialin is
a senior high school graduate
Why do you look down on Jialin
A senior high school student
is good for nothing
He also has to whip the ox ass
Come on
He is not able to whip the ox ass
you shouldn't
look down on Gao Jialin.
GaoJialin is not only a learned young man
but also a hardworking guy
In this village
few people of his age can match him
People now regard
us two as the most capable men
Capable men! It is he that will be the real
capable man in our village in the future
To tell you the truth
I really felt happy
when I learned about that news
You see
If QiaoZhen marry toJialin
you and I both are his relatives
You have said so much pleasant words
so I can't push her
into a dark hole
What can you do?
I will break the legs of that damn guy
Please pay attention
to the punishment of police bureau
Qiaozhen, come down
I have something to tell you
Brother Jialin, what's it?
My father is watching us
Don't be afraid
I deliberately let them know
Did your father beat you?
No. He just scolded me
If he beat you again
I won't forgive him
Jialin, don't get so angry
My father is a kind-hearted man
with a sharp tongue
He won't be too harsh on me
Don't worry
I can make decision in my family
I see
It's too dirty!
Qiaozhen, let's buy some
bleaching powder in the city
Shall 1 go with you? Yeah
Go together. Dare you go?
Yeah. I am going home
to fetch my bike
You go to change your clothes
for a better one
Take off this one
and I'll wash it for you tomorrow
Ha. What a good wife
It sounds too unpleasant
Qiaozhen Jialin
Hey, GaoJialin, LiuQiaozhen
GaoJialin, LiuQiaozhen
Hey, Jialin
I'll let you have Sundays
GaoJialin, LiuQiaozhen.....
Oh, Oh
GaoJialin, LiuQiaozhen
I will have Sundays!
GaoJialin.....
Hey, Jialin, Take care.
Brother Jialin
You should try going out to work
Really I support you completely
if you can find a job in the town
If you really work in town some day
I will plant our reserved field at home
and raise our children
You can come back to see
us whenever you are free
and I will take our children there
and live together with you. If lam free
You let me work outside
Aren't you afraid that I will part with you?
Don't leave me alone whatever happens
For you, it seems that I have got a job
Brother YiDe, Brother YiDe
Come and have some together with us
Please help yourselves
The cadres of our village decide
to fetch some dung in the city
It is an easy task
so I want it done
by Jialin and Grandpa Deshun
Ha...
Jialin, you are really tired these days
Alright. I must go now
Well, ask Qiaozhen go to cook for you
Her auntie has an empty room in the town
Ok. Let's go
See you. Ha. Ha
See you
Youth is never but once
It's good to be young..
The old men with white beard are useless
What are you laughing at?
I am old now
but I feel so happy
when I see you, the young people
Ha ha ha
Grandpa Deshun Yeah?
You are single all your life
Did you ever fall in love
with someone when you were young?
Ah? Fall in love?
Ah
Oh. When I was young
Ha ha ha
Alas. At that time
I was as young as you are now
When I was free
I took my draught animals
outside the village to carry salt
and leather goods for the landlord
When I had a rest in a small inn
on the riverside of Wuding Lake
I met the daughter of the owner
and we fell in love
Her name was Lingzhuan
and she was more beautiful
than the singer in the county troupe
Every time she knew exactly
when I could arrive there
As soon as I turned up
in the corner of their village
she welcomed me with her songs
Her voice was as pleasant as
that of two silver bells ringing
I didn't want
to leave after entering that inn
always gave me cake with mutton
buckwheat, and river snail to eat
As soon as the night fell
she came to my room stealthily
Every time I left their village
she swept sadly
with tears running down her cheeks
She would send me to the riverside
weeping and singing all the way
Did she sing the song called
"Going to Xikou'?
Yeah
Brother, you will go far away
I can't ask you to stay
I have some words to tell you
which you should keep them in mind
not along the path
On the crowded road
you can chat with others
not feeling lonely
Brother, you will go far away
I see you off
Drawing your hand,
I sweep sadly
with my tears down my cheeks
I am really old
so that I feel so sentimental
to make my eyes water
Ah. You might laugh at me for this
Grandpa Deshun, what about the
following story? Lingzhu, she
Alas. It was said that she married
to a businessman from Tianjin
She was unwilling to marry him
but her father forced her to go with him
Oh. Tianjin is a place so far from us
Zhuanling may be alive now
Of course, she is alive! She is alive
as long as I am living in the world
I have her in my heart all the life
Dad, come here to eat the watermelon
Come on. Have a piece
Go to somewhere else to fetch dung
Don't you see some people sitting here?
You the guy are so impolite!
What are you coming to do?
Dare you kill me?
Comrade, there is really no other way
We chose to fetch dung in the evening
just in order to avoid hindering
your work during the daytime
We didn't know you are enjoying
the cool in the evening
Well, that's enough!
Please fill your pails and go away.
Please go away quickly. Go away
Go away quickly. It smells so bad!
I am really dirty
but I find your mind stinking
You say what?
Well. That's enough! Go away please!
What an impolite person!
I must come here!
I have learned so much knowledge
and I am as excellent as them
Why should I be insulted like this?
Uncle Gao, here is your letter
from Xingjiang
Read it for us. Ok
My elder brother and elder sister
how are you
Qiaoling, come here. Sit down to read
I have good news to tell you
that I will be transferred
to work in our hometown soon
It is said in the letter sent from
the local government authorities
I decide to
Labor?
Are you also sent home
to work by the government?
No. Auntie
Wrap quickly....
Grandson, give me room
Auntie Hi
I'll go to fetch my table
Thank you
You pat one and I pat one
a child's driving a plane
You pat two and I pat two
two children are plaiting pigtails
You pat three and I pat three
three children are climbing
the snow mountain
You pat four and I pat four
four children are writing big characters
You pat five and I pat five
You pat Six and I pat Six
Having left home for decades
always dreamed to be home
I am more than fifty years old now
It is said that the falling
leaves settle on the roots
Yes, yes
Yizhi, do you forget
that two of us stole the peaches
of Grandpa Deshun in our childhood?
Ha ha ha
These bowls can't be used
to entertain guests
What are you doing?
Get off, please
Hi, Jialin
Yes?
I don't mention something else
I will offer you a job
as soon as possible
As an aged couple
we have nothing to involve you
In recent years we have
nothing painstaking under
the better policy of government
The only worry is the future of your nephew
He is still doing the fieldwork
after graduation from senior high school
You work as a teacher
in the village school, don't you?
Yes
Now there are fewer students than
before and so fewer teachers are wanted
Thus, he came back
Elder brother
you put me in trouble for this matter
I am newly appointed in this position
How can I
Elder brother, You should understand me
Sanxing, go to call a person!
Ok
Did Director Gao mention
to offer Jialin a job in the town?
You, I think, are the only wise man
in Gaojiagou village..
Today, who speaks
it out clearly for this kind of matter?
Otherwise he must be a stupid leader.
It depends on a flexible mind of
the persons who work directly under him
When you handle the matter well yourself
he may pretend to scold you
But inwardly he can't help
promoting you immediately
Uncle Gao. Here all you come. Oh
They arrived home
Come in please.
Hurry up! Well
Hello, Yizhi
Director Gao
Brother YiDe
Director Gao, Secretary Gao has been
waiting for you for along time
Why doesn't Jialin come?
That stubborn guy!
It doesn't matter without him.
Let's come in and sit down, please!
Help yourself, Director Gao
Help yourselves
Please, drink some more
Cheers!
Jialin, you should always think of me
Yeah
You must love only me
The ducks upriver and the goose downriver
Focusing their eyes on their brothers
Cooking the elm fruit and putting
the rice into the boiling water
Picking the fire woods
on the road and glancing at you
The clean glass window are brightening
Chuckling at you with the teeth white
Anxiously opening the door
Dear honey be back soon
Ah
Anxiously opening the door
Dear honey be back soon
Be back soon
We're now to broadcast
the message sent by our reporter
GaoJialin from the frontline of
the flood disaster in the Nan Ma River
The title: At the Vital Moment
LiuYuhai, the secretary of NanMa River
community was injured in seven points
without sleeping for twenty-four hours
He struggled on the frontline
of flood disaster together
with the cadres
and members of the community
His deeds show the strong
will of a communist party member
Comrade Jialin, return for a rest please
OK
Jialin, Jialin
Hello Welcome back
This time, your article is so moving
Thanks. I'm glad to hear that
It's really moving
Not so good as you said
I was moved to tears when I read it
Really? Yeah.
Please wash your face. Ok
I am so glad that you are working here
for I have a conversable
partner from now on
To tell you the truth
these years I've felt so bored
for I cannot find a proper
person to chat with in the town
You overlooked them
but you don't know much about them
Maybe you are too haughty
for the ordinary people to approach
but I really feel a little bored
The selected collection of Mérimée's novels
How did you get it?
Some days ago
May I read it first? Yeah
Mérimée is a realist
but her works are of romantic color
I like Carmen's character very much
Do you?
She is a liberalist
and she is unwilling to bear
any bandage of the society
I expect more romances in our life
By the way. Did you often write poems?
I just want to ask for your help on this
Do you have any new works?
I wrote a short poem last night
Did you?
Here it is. Please read it yourself
but I can't understand
why I should be a wild goose
Hehe...
I believe you will
understand it gradually
Have lunch at my home, please
I am not used to having meals
in the home of strangers
Am Ia stranger for you?
I meant that I don't know your parents
First time strangers
and second time friends
Thank you for your kindness. But I
Are you afraid of meeting strangers?
No. No
Bumpkin!
I am originally a bumpkin
Who is there?
It's me
Yaping, come to my home for lunch
eating the fresh fish
Eating, and eating again
You only know that
Yaping Don't touch me!
What's wrong with you today?
Hey, Jialin. Ah
Why are you driving the tractor?
It's boring to be a teacher
MaZhansheng arranged for
me to work in the mechanized
construction team in the county
Recently, we've been carrying stones
in GaoJiagou village
Qiaozhen sent a package for you
Here you are
Who replaced your position in the school?
Qiaoling did. She hadn't pass
the college entrance examination
I am in Nanguan. OK
Sanxin, wait a moment
Who is there?
It's me
Mum
Well
Zhenzhen, come here, please
These are the candies Jialin
sent to you and your Dad
Sanxin has also brought some for us
Put over there
so these are all for you
Why do you come here?
This place isn't your self-reserved land
Your words are so bitter and sharp
I meant that it's getting dark
and you are here alone
Not only myself
What about Kenan?
He is not my tail
Then who else?
Just you!
Me?
I want to leave
Are you going on errands?
Where are you going?
Not on business
I will leave here forever
My father will
be transferred to wok in Nanjing
my hometown
and I will also work there
It's beautiful in south
whose sceneries are old friends
The sunrise shining over
the river like flowers in bloom
And the river in the spring
turns green and blue
How can I help recalling
the southern land?
While recalling the southern land
the special is Hangzhou
Seeking osmanthus flower in the moon
when staying in the hill temple
And watching the surging tides
while lying in the pavilion
When could I go back for another tour?
Yea, I always dream my hometown
Are you really leaving?
Sure
Suzhou and Hangzhou
are the two paradises on the earth
Xizi Lake is such an attractive site
I am not able to visit it in my lifetime
Do you want to go there?
Me? I even expect
to visit the United Nations
I meant whether you would like
to visit Nanjin, Hangzhou, and Shanghai
I won't get the chances
to go on errands in these cities
It's meaningless for me to go there alone
You have Kenan for company
I hope it's you not him
that will accompany me there
You know that
I loved you when we at school
We were too young
to understand love at that time
And then you returned
to your hometown later
And now I see you are the right man I love
Kenan doesn't disgust me
but I cannot be stirred by him
In fact, my parents like him more
Let's live together
Go to Nanjing with our family
You'll have
a bright future in a big city
I'm sure to ask my father
manage to transfer
you to work as a reporter in Jiangsu
Qiaozhen
Jialin
right now the doorkeeper said
you were not here and didn't let me in
Well. I went to Liujiagou village
for an interview. Get in
Ok
Are you back now? Yeah
Go to my office, please All right
Here is not the crop field
My superiors are just in the next room
You haven't ever come home since you left
I've been here several times
expecting to see you
but they told me you had gone
to the countryside
Sit down please. Well
Let me tidy it for you
Thanks
The quilt is too thin
I will bring you some new cotton next time
It's getting cold and you cannot
sleep with a single underlay
I'll also bring you my own tick of dog skin
Please don't do that
It's hairy and will sure be laughable
The dog skin is very warm
I am not cold, and, you see
I have a stove there
Sanxin is driving the tractor
and Qiaoling is a teacher now. She failed
in the college entrance examination
Well. Sanxin has told me those things
Your sow gave birth to twelve piglets
with one crashed
by the sow and left only
Eleven piglets left
Yes, eleven left
but one died the next day
Really?
Originally
Please drink some water
I'll go to buy the meal
and we eat together
No. I am not hungry
I must go home early
In order to get a lift in Sanxin's tractor
I left my hoe in the field
and didn't tell my family
Er. It
Brother Jialin
you need more expenses in the town
but your salary is not high
so take this fifty-yuan with you
You can buy something else to eat
if the breakfast is not enough for you
I will buy you a pair of sneakers
Sanxin told me that you often play balls
which abrades shoes very much
The bonus of the first
half-year has been allotted
and I got ninety-two yuan
Now I have salary
and the royalties for my articles
You should keep it yourself
and buy some fashionable clothes
No. This is for you
I, I have my own
Don't reject like that or I'll get angry
Well, I'll keep it for you
And I will give it back
to you whenever you need
Ok
I bought it for you long
time ago but forgot to send to you
Come on. Let me help you wear it
Lingling, I beg you for a help
Tell me please
Could you teach me to read?
I learn ten words every day
and I am able to read and write in a year
My elder sister!
I am willing to be a hovering wild goose
loving the blue sky freely
Your sow gave birth to twelve piglets
and one was crashed
by the sow, crashed
I loved you when we at school
You are the right man I love
Brother Jialin, Brother Jialin
I am your only love
Never leave me alone whatever happens
How to write the word "Gao"?
Which "Gao"?
That's that’s the "Gao"
Gao-Jia-lin
Ha ha ha
Who asked you to write these words
Ha Ha Ha
You want to marry
an illiterate country woman!
Yea
I can't understand
why a talented senior high school graduate
wants to marry an illiterate countrywoman
You are destroying yourself
That's enough. At that time
I was a dusty peasant
Did any city lady like you would love me?
How ferocious you are!
I am a bad-tempered man
and you can't bear me
if you live with me
Did you mean
that you agree to live with me?
Jialin
I have to explain to Qiaozhen first
You know,
I feel so sorry
Yeah, you should
end up your tragedy quickly
Maybe it would be an tragic ending
When did GaoJialin
and Yaping date with each other?
You're a worthless wretch
Hum. How dare that guy bully us?
Under the sky lies the Yellow River
which has many turns and twists
many turns and twists
dozens of boats
Jialin, what's the matter with you?
Yesterday Sanxin took
your message to ask me to come here
I worried about you for the
whole night supposing you were ill
Jialin, please have a look
at the words I wrote
Qiaoling taught me to write
I can't write well now
Qiaozhen
I have something to tell you
But it is hard to speak out
if you have something to tell
Don't hide it in your heart
If I tell you
I am worried that you will cry
Tell me please. I won't cry
Qiaozhen
I will be transferred
to work thousands of miles away
We
what about you?
Qiaozhen Jialin
that's enough
I see what you mean
You, you just go there please
I won't prevent you
Jialin, I have thought
about our relations for numerous times
since you worked in the county
Though I love you dear
I know I can't match you.
I am illiterate
I am not able to assist you
but to encumber your work
You just go outside
and find a better wife than me
Unlike in our native village
you should take more care of yourself
in a completely new place
Jialin
you don't know how much I love you
Qiaozhen
Qiaozhen. Don't cry please
Jialin, I must be off now
Qiaozhen!
You should have
rooted yourself in this land
But now...
you have become a bean sprout
without any earth on the root
Hum!
You have sold your conscience
but you
she is a piece of gold
You leave her alone on the half way
You, you are committing a sin
You
Hum!
When we were about forty years old
your mother gave birth to you
the only child of us
We are always fearing that you might
be caught into trouble in your life
We didn't expect that you
Maybe you are right
But I can't return in the way of advance
Moreover, you have your
way of life while I have my own
I am unwilling to live like you
digging the land
in Gaojiagou village all the life
That damned GaoYude!
Fuck him! Gangster!
He must die a sudden death
The thunders must
burn him as a black charcoal stake
Dad, don't scold him. Don't curse him
Forget him
Zhenzhen
You shouldn't feel too sad
Zhenzhen, don't ruin yourself for you
haven't begin your wonderful life
I embarrassed him
before for the sake of you
Alas. 1 don't compel you in this matter
However, you are old enough for marriage
You'd better choose a husband by yourself
You shouldn't shoot too high
Dad made you illiterate
and you'd better choose an honest farmer
Later, I heard
that you dated with Mr.Gao
and then I felt very disappointed
I heard that Mr.Gao fell
in love with a city girl
and parted with you. And then I felt
I have become a infamous woman
all over this village
Don't you look down on me?
No, I don't. It doesn't matter
The young people always
experience much frustration
What's more, don't hate Mr.Gao
He is a government cadre now
but you are an illiterate country girl so
it's impossible for you two to live together
It is said that the golden
flower matches the silvery one
and the pumpkin matches the cushaw
Both of us are illiterate
and it's just
Qiaozhen
I have so much strength
and a flexible mind.
I won't let you suffer even
if I have to work as an animal
I will make you enjoy all
the happiness a villager can afford
Mum, ask my father to tell Mashuan
that our wedding will be held according
to the local customs completely
It should be the same as yours
at that time
It's of old times
That's also Ok
Come on! Eat sugar
Here are the dishes!
The dishes are coming!
Hi. Attention please!...
Give me a way!
Hey, the dishes come again.
Cheers! cheers!
Hey, eat first
Enjoy yourself, take easy! Hehe...
Come on! Come on!
Cheers!
Hey, put it over there
Here are the dishes!
Hey. Here come the dishes!
No Help yourselves, please!
Give me a way!
Hey, the dishes are coming!
Go away quickly please. Quickly, please!
Go away please!
Go out quickly please!
Go out! How disgusting!
My second elder sister!
My dear little sister
don't forget me
You must come to see me frequently
I'm illiterate
but you like learned people
Elderly sister
I see, you are suffering in your heart
At any rate, I have to live my life
Elderly sister, don't take it so seriously
There are so many things
worth loving in one's life
Don't get dismayed for one thing
Elderly sister
You must come to see me frequently
Yeah
You should always speak these words to me
Elderly sister
Now we can proceed ahead
Proceed ahead, let's walk up front
Hey, the rear catch up
Nannan
GaoJialin will be finished
The regional
investigation group have come to
investigate how he had ever
found the job through the backdoor
I wrote to disclose him
And now we are villains
You good-for-nothing
how silly you are to
speak these damn words with your
lover being induced by him?
Moreover, it's really illegal for him
to get in by the back door
have the duty to maintain
the laws of our party
Mum, you are right in principle
But morally , we are revenging him
in the name of public interests
Fuck your nonsense!
Sanxing, Sanxing
Do you finish the training course?
Yeah
Are you going back
to Gaojiagou in these days?
No. I am carrying
the sands in Zhangjia River
Well. That's just the same
Do you know that Qiaozhen got married?
To whom?
Mashuan
Ma Zhansheng
is also dismissed from his post
No, I must be with you
It's impossible
for lam a peasant again now
I won't go to Nanjing
I want to be a peasant together with you
I, I love you!
I won't live without you
Yaping, you needn't sacrifice
your own interests for me
I know your devoted love for me
I appreciate you very much
However, in my heart
I like Qiaozhen
more though she is illiterate
If, if that's the truth
I wish you happiness!
But Qiaozhen
has got married with another man
Elder sister
Elder sister, go back please!
Don't do that! That's laughable
To laugh at what?
Qiaoling told me all
this matter this morning
You don't
What a torturing person you are!
GaoJialin not only hurts you
but also embarrasses all our family
If you can stand this
you bear it yourself
Today I must embarrass
that guy in return
My good elder sister
he is so miserable now
If everyone hits a him when he's down
how can he live the following days?
I don't care
Elder sister, I beg you!
Don't treat Jialin like that
At any rate I love him
If you punish him like this
you are just poking my heart with a knife!
You, my dear sister
Under the sky lies the Yellow River
which has many turns and twists
The ducks upriver
and the goose downriver
are focusing their eyes on their brothers
Starred by
Zhou Xingjing Wu Yufang
Gao Baocheng
Jia Liu
Li Xiaoli
Qiao Jianhua
Yu Zhongyi
Gao Jialin
Xue Jianshe
Xue Bai
Wen Jian
Li Jinbang
Wang Lan
Zhang Mugin
Mu Mu
Pan Jun
Chen Xuegang
Produced by Xi'an Film Studio