DVD / DVDRip
Duration: 1:29:16
FPS: 25
Here's "Morning Calisthenics"
with Michael Ben-Hanan.
I know exactly what you're doing
with those friends of yours.
No one's going to tell me
what to do.
You can do whatever you want,
but I don't want you around here.
Where are you coming
from at this hour?
Are you telling me what to do?
- Everybody knows what you're up to.
Anywhere I go, I'm ashamed
to show my face.
I'm not a mouse, like you.
When people see me,
they feel brave.
Look at you. Pretty soon,
you'll start crying.
I'd give anything to put an end
to you and your friends.
Rikky, what's wrong?
- Mommy said you should come.
So early? Okay. I'm coming
right away. -I'll come, too.
It's on my way, anyway.
How's everything, Riki?
Shabbazi Films Presents
"Light out of Nowhere"
With: Nissim Levy,
Shlomo Bassan, Abie Saltzberg
Good morning.
Good morning, Esther.
Story and Screenplay:
Nissim Dayan
So early in the morning?
Last night, I didn't feel well,
and I thought it would pass.
I didn't want to call the doctor.
But I couldn't sleep,
so I called for you.
I don't want you to get the doctor.
Just call and say it's Naomi Cohen.
He'll know what to do.
- Which doctor?
There's a note in the closet
with his phone number.
Did you come, too? I probably
woke up the entire house.
I can't find the note.
What's wrong? -Dizzy spells. It's
always like that in the morning.
Avram, since you're already here,
take Riki to school. -I'll do it.
Thank you, Shaul.
- Don't forget to get milk.
Say goodbye to Mommy.
- Goodbye.
Shaul, who is that?
- You don't know him.
I do know him. That's Hezkel,
Anat's brother. She's in my class.
Not Hezkel.
Yehezkel.
Producer:
Ya'acov Elkov
Director:
Nisim Dayan
Subtitle production:
Elrom Studios
You'll never learn to fix cars
working like that.
You'll end up a cripple
Let me see.
Go put it under cold water.
Hurry up, Eli. The guys are waiting.
- Just a second. I'll change clothes.
What happened to you, Shaul?
- Nothing. I'm all right.
I know. It's hard at the beginning.
What else is new? -Everything's okay.
Where are you going?
What's going on, Eli?
- Just a minute!
Listen. Whatever money Eli gives you
keep for yourself.
Don't give a cent to Dad. If he
gets used to it, you're done for.
He's never asked.
- And don't take any crap from him.
Let me see.
It's nothing. Don't be a kid.
- You hate him so much?
I don't hate him,
but I don't love him, either.
You've only been in the neighborhood
for two weeks.
You haven't had a run in with him
yet. Just wait and see.
Let's go.
- Eli, when will you be home?
Rachel, not now.
Make any progress with Dalia?
- She's kind of shy.
They probably didn't teach you this
at boarding school,
but remember!
A woman doesn't call the shots.
The man does.
Shaul, keep working by yourself.
Tired, Shaul?
What have you been doing
at night?
Go buy me some cigarettes.
And tell Yosef to send over
something to eat.
I don't know what he wants from me.
Suddenly, he hit me.
I raised my hand? Believe me,
I have a street full of witnesses.
They saw him go into the car.
I parked it for one second.
Suddenly, he shows up.
Oh go to hell. Why would I hit
someone for no reason?
Believe me. You...
You deserve to get beaten up.
Did you hear that?
Did you hear how he threatened me?
Children, break it up. Break it up.
Break it up, everyone.
Move on, everyone. -Go away.
Hey, Shaul! How's it going?
- Avram, what's new?
Shaul, Shaul, Shaul.
The kids don't want help.
I got what I said I would.
A book. On ancient times.
I got it from an archeologist
who works at the port.
Did you also get me the keys?
Yes, of course. I'll get you
anything that you want.
What's going on, Shaul?
Are you still reading?
Aren't you sick of studying?
Where's Dad?
- He went to Auntie.
Why are you in such a rush?
Take this. -No, I don't need it.
- Just take it. It's not a lot.
Just remember. In life, either you
do the screwing, or you get screwed.
It'll take you a long time to learn
what a shitty life this is.
You're still green.
"The pomegranate tree
has emanated its fragrance
"Between the Dead Sea and Jericho.
"My fortress, your regiment returned
from patrol.
"My innocent, your lover returned
from wandering.
"Treasures of Ofir
and fragrance of Gile'ad,
"Chariots of Egypt
I sent to you, girl.
"Thousands..."
Yohanan, can't you
sing according to the words?
"There was a time I blew a fart,
"From the Dead Sea to Jericho..."
- Stop it! That's enough.
Yohanan, stop it. -You're not doing
us any favors, you know.
You can kiss my ass.
- Did you hear that?
Did you see that? -Your sister
is a whore. You and your unions.
"The Song of Songs,
which is Solomon's.
"May he kiss me with the kisses
of his mouth
"For your love is better than wine.
"Your oils have a pleasing fragrance
Your name is like purified oil.
"Therefore the maidens love you."
Right, so what?
Romanian. So I'm a Romanian.
Koby...
Of course! But take care.
No mess and no noise.
Under the stone, by the window.
Here. Have a drink for good spirits.
- No. No.
You take it.
Whatever will be, will be.
Let's go. -Why should we go?
- This place scares me.
You're making yourself scared.
Finally, we're alone together,
in a room.
But you promised. You said so.
I'm scared. -Of me?
You don't have to be scared of me.
- I'm not scared of you. -So?
I don't know.
I'm just scared.
But now, I'm not anymore.
I'm sick of this! Let's go.
She's back, the slut.
Look at her.
Who are you hanging around with
at this hour of the night?
You don't care about work, anymore?
Just criminals?
Just cruising the streets,
along with the whores.
You'll become a whore
before you become a woman.
Why are you so quiet? Say something
to your daughter already!
Get in the house.
- "Get in the house."
Get in already.
All night, all day.
Not a moment of peace.
Where were you all day?
Did you eat anything?
- I'm not hungry.
Want some tea? -No.
What's the matter with you? Did
you fight with Dalia again, as usual?
I didn't fight with her
or anything.
I spoke with her mother. She
doesn't want you coming home late.
What does her mother want?
What has Dalia been doing, anyway?
Have you seen Baruch?
- What do you want from him?
He's been living here this whole
time and I'm not complaining.
But he just comes in, looks for food
and drink. Thinks only of himself.
We don't owe him anything. He never
asks how his auntie is feeling.
What's new at home? This house could
burn down and he'd... -How's Auntie?
We have enough to worry about.
Uncle Shlomi will return on Saturday.
Let him worry about it.
But if you could pop over there
tomorrow and help her out a bit.
Go to the market,
and stuff like that.
I'd go myself, but we're being
transferred to Ashkelon tomorrow.
Good night. -Good night.
Shaul!
Come on in. -Where?
You made a deal.
Come see how we live it up.
Is this your brother?
- Uh huh. -The scholar.
He's working for Eli?
- Yes. -What a man, that Eli.
Making any money? -You can make more
money if you don't work.
Not everyone is tired like you.
- Guys, cut the crap.
You'll scare him away.
Have you ever been
in a night club?
"Mina, tell me
why you are so angry again?
"What bad thing has he done
to you again today?
"What is all the fuss about?
"What can't you just live in peace,
tell me? Why?
"You're pretty at night.
"You're smart at night..."
Look. Do you see them?
If I wanted to, I could snap
my fingers and have them all.
You smile at them, you laugh
with them, you drink with them.
But they think you're nothing.
Steer clear of them, eh?
If they only could,
they'd kill you.
In life, it matters who's doing what
with whom and how.
Once, you know,
in Little Tel Aviv, when guys
used to meet, they'd say,
"Hello. How are you?"
They'd part with "Goodbye." Today,
it's "How's the health, Moishe?"
"How's the health, Haim?"
"Feel good."
"Feel good." Everyone's always
talking about their health.
Oh, sorry. That was in Yiddish.
I'll translate into Hebrew soon.
The same thing. Be well.
For example...
They're not worth your spit.
Ukshenstein goes into a coffee shop
and one guy says to the other,
"See that Ukshenstein?
He embezzled half a million liras."
The guy say, "Whaddya say!
Good for him!"
A gal goes into the same coffee shop
and he tells him,
"See that gal? In one night,
she makes 200 liras!"
"Whaddya say?
Good for her!"
No hello?
- Oh, it's you. How are you?
Who's that good looking guy?
- Another one. -I don't believe it.
Aren't you bringing something
to drink? -Anything, for you.
Are you angry? -I'm thirsty.
Did you see that? It's a long story.
- Pretty.
Just look at him.
He actually loves European Jews.
They should all be killed while
they are still small, those types.
Excuse me. Where is the hotel
called "Ramat Aviv?"
Yeah, up yours, Ramat Aviv.
- Thank you. What did he say?
What? What?
I... My head... Go. Go.
- Hey, where've you been?
Hello, Shaul.
Shaul, wait. Can you come
for Kaddish, the mourner's prayer?
We need ten men for services,
remember? In memory of my mother.
I'm really in a rush. -Come on!
I've been waiting for along time.
It'll just take a few minutes.
Have some tea. It won't take long.
Really, it won't. Hey,
it's a good deed. There's also...
There are also cookies.
"Peace to all of Israel.”
Who is he? -Sheetrit.
- What? -Sheetrit.
Sheetrit? Oh, fine. Can he read?
- Yes.
Good. Let's start with the Kaddish.
You can answer "Amen," right?
Fine. -Stand up. -Stand up.
Stand up. -With respect.
"Glorified and sanctified
be God's name." -Amen!
"Throughout the world which He has
created according to his will..."
"And may he bring the Messiah."
- Amen.
"May He establish his kingdom in your
lifetime... and say Amen." -Amen.
It's good you got here now.
Have some tea with me.
No, I'm not thirsty. I just
had a drink. -You are so bashful.
You don't have to be shy with me.
Wait. I'll go get some.
Dad asked how you're doing.
He couldn't come this morning.
They went to Ashkelon.
- Yes. What a job he has.
How are you feeling this morning?
- Better.
What do you have?
- It's a woman's thing.
Nothing important. It will pass.
- Yesterday, Dad and I...
I told your Dad not to take you out
of that boarding school. I told him.
Shlomo would have paid,
but your father was stubborn.
Once he gets something in his head,
nothing will make him budge.
I'm not sorry I came back.
At least now, he doesn't yell at me.
He's not so nervous. Every time I'd
come home, he'd yell all the time.
Would you like some of my toast?
Dad always picked fights with me.
Any excuse to start yelling.
"Do this!" "Go there."
Now, he yells at Baruch.
When you see Baruch, tell him
that Naomi is angry at him.
Can't he stop by to see
how I'm doing?
He comes home late every night
and sleeps all day long.
When I left, he still
hadn't come back.
Dad said you might need something.
- What? No, no. Nothing.
No, no. Not here. From the store.
Groceries and stuff.
Well, if you want to,
then bring me...
bread and milk and a dozen eggs.
Put it on my bill.
I forgot to ask. What about work?
Did you leave in the middle?
It's okay. Eli knows it's for you.
Look. Do you see? Scandinavia.
Baruch said,
"Go tell Shaul. Quick!"
"Tell him that today..."
- What do you mean?
For you, too.
Nice, like that. Take it easy.
All white, the snow.
Scandinavia.
You never speak clearly.
Where is Baruch? -Scandinavia.
There. Pretty. What's wrong?
You're not a kid anymore.
Come on.
- Wait till they go away.
I'm going.
I waited for you.
- Was Shimon here? -Yes.
Well, he brought a Swedish chick
over here yesterday.
Who knows were he found her.
- I saw her.
She was here with your friends.
- Come on. Let's go in.
Her name is Bracha.
Shimon just gets me in trouble.
- He said that you brought her.
Liar! He doesn't know
what he's doing. Let's go in.
Bracha, put more fun in it.
Whoah! That Scandinavian.
What a body, eh?
Did you at least sleep with her?
You're pretty smart,
she's a dirty thing.
Who hasn't laid her? Practically
the whole neighborhood's had her.
Have you seen the guys?
Was Hanani here? -Yes.
They're scared of me.
They want the bail money.
Do you know why I called you?
You're the only one who can help me.
Look. I never asked you
to do anything for me.
Remember? When you came home
for vacation, who gave you money?
Dad or me? -Cut it out!
Tell me what's going on.
You know they got me out
by using their money.
They're your friends.
- Not everything you see is true.
You're still a kid, Shaul.
You don't know what friends are.
See, I kind of took a loan
from them. 700 liras.
I had some of my own money,
but now, I'm burned out.
See that one?
Don't think that I like it.
Whore money is dirty money.
But it's temporary.
Besides, she brings in close to
nothing. I really need cash now!
Where would I get cash?
- Hear me out.
I need is a small loan. That's all.
Not from you. From Dad. -Dad?
It's not what you think. Dad is
loaded. All that crying and praying?
It's one big lie.
- Even so. He won't give it to you.
Not to me, but he'll give it to you.
You're the one he loves.
Are you crazy? 700 liras?
So let him give you only 500.
Don't you get it?
Do you want me to beg you?
Do you remember
what happened to Eli?
Do you think they did that
just because of me?
They were afraid someone
would rat on them, too.
Hanani and I have had
a few complications.
Man, if I wasn't burned out right
now, you'd see what would happen.
He won't give me the money.
- Aren't you going out with Dalia?
Yes. -So tell Dad
that you got her pregnant.
No, I won't. -Stop pitying Dad.
It's time you learned what kind
of person he really is.
He won't flinch at 500. I promise.
He's such a cheapskate.
Even 1000 is nothing for him.
You don't believe he ratted on me?
I don't know. -It's the truth.
As sure as I'm your brother.
He'll give you as much
as you want for an abortion.
And if he doesn't?
- Convince him. Shed some tears.
He'll kill me. -Don't worry.
He's down on himself because of me.
I know him really well.
Look, Shaul.
I don't like to have to ask twice.
'I be gone by tomorrow or so.
I just have to finish things up.
Pay off the money and that's it.
I'd do it without you if I could.
You wouldn't hear a peep out of me.
Throw it here! Here!
Catch!
Come on. Catch. Catch it.
Hey, Shaul. How's it going?
- Throw it here!
Come and play.
- Here! Here!
Hey, why are you quitting? -Give me
the ball and we'll keep going.
What else?
Go get it.
- Shaul, go get the ball.
What are you looking at?
Go get it.
Shaul, can't you hear? My ball.
Go bring it back.
Keep sleeping, you sucker. -Fuck you,
sucker. -Your sister's lame.
Shaul, I'm warning you.
Go bring the ball back.
Man, Haim. When his brother gets
back from jail you're gonna get beat.
Oh, you're scaring me.
Where is Baruch in all this?
Now you're in for it, Haim.
Man, Shaul. You are in luck.
Today, Haim is really uptight.
I threw it to you. Why didn't you
catch it? -That's enough.
Stop fighting. You're something else.
You're gonna get beat up.
You're going to punch out a chicken?
- Leave him alone.
Leave him alone.
- Break them up. -Watch out.
Yehiel, come home. Now!
Yehiel, look at yourself.
20 liras for a yard of cloth at
"Beit Romano.” -It's not the same.
What's not the same?
What are you talking about?
Come with me and see.
- The Arabs. Exactly.
We depend on ourselves too much.
- Listen. I work there.
I know them.
They will never be human beings.
Do you understand? They are all
tails. They don't have a head.
You think we're better than them?
- Shlomo, how can you compare?
Well, it seems to me
that you really love them.
I didn't say "love," but why
don't they integrate?
For the life of me, I can't
understand you. I don't get it.
What will happen to you now?
- I'll get a job.
Did you ask how Eli is doing?
- A little rice in the soup.
My husband's a jerk. The same food
for 20 years. -You're lucky.
Integration?
Where do you want them to integrate?
How should I know? In the paper,
on TV, in the municipalities.
In the worker's union. There are
lots of possibilities.
Oh, come on, Zechariah. -You didn't
ask about him at home, did you? -No.
Tomorrow morning, go
to the "Working Youth."
Go early. Be there at eight. Tell
them the situation at home is bad.
You left the boarding school.
Are you listening or not?
How should I talk to you?
- I heard "Working Youth."
I'll go there tomorrow morning.
- Make a list. Parsley...
I wrote it down. -Parsley.
- I wrote it down.
So what will be?
- Definitely not the end.
You said there's not enough money.
- Money. Not just money.
They say there's not enough
just to try and blackmail you.
I don't understand how
people like you talk like that.
Come on. You communist.
Name? -Shaul.
Last name? -Sheetrit.
Age? -17. -Land of emigration?
- I was born in Israel.
Education? -Till tenth grade.
- Ten years.
What would you like to do, son?
Whatever there is. -Physical work
wouldn't suit a boy like you.
Would you like to be a clerk
at the insurance office?
Okay, I guess.
I'll send you over.
How much do they pay?
- What they always pay.
And if they don't accept me?
If I send you, they'll accept you.
No, I mean...
What if I don't like it?
Can I come back here
and you'll give me something else?
We'll see. Don't be picky.
Where are you going?
- To the bathroom. -Go to your right.
I'm sorry, Shaul.
But it just isn't working.
My parents are being really strict.
Dalia.
- I'm not in the mood. I don't know.
Don't think
that I don't have feelings for you.
You're the only one
I can tell everything.
You barely say anything.
- You neither.
Yesterday, my dad took away
everything I'd earned. 700 liras.
If I'd had more, he'd have taken it.
I'm so sick of them.
Every time I go home...
A long time ago,
I signed up at a kibbutz.
They just notified me
that I was accepted.
You're not mad, right?
- No way. -I don't think I'll go.
What would I do there?
- I think it would be best for you.
I don't know.
Now, it seems so far away.
So what will you do?
You have to do something.
I have relatives in Italy.
My dad said I could go there.
Where will you get the money?
- I'll save up.
Dalia, I think the faster
you get out of the neighborhood,
the better it will be for you.
- Where would I go?
I don't know.
There has to be somewhere.
Some place. I can see
what they do to you at home.
You are so sweet,
the way you talk to me.
Anything he asks, you answer.
He knows a lot of people.
Let's see how you look.
Come in. Come in.
How are you, Mr. Sheetrit?
So this is your son? Make yourselves
comfortable. Have a seat.
Can you believe this is your dad?
Well, what can you do?
How old is he?
- He's already 17.
A young man. What does he know?
- He's been at a boarding school.
Agriculture, right? Oh yes.
Now I remember. You told me.
Do you know any English?
Read a paragraph from
the "Jerusalem Post."
I don't know how to read.
- You don't know?
Didn't you learn over there?
He's shy.
That's okay. That's okay.
It might be hard, but we'll manage.
How long till the army? -A year
or so. -That's not a lot of time.
Are you physically able to work?
- Yes, why not?
He went to the "Working Youth"
but he didn't get a job.
He probably was scared to open his
mouth. He says yes to everything.
I understand.
I think he gave the impression
of a lazy kid, no?
Would you take a physical job?
An insurance company? -No.
I already was at an insurance
company. I'll find something else.
Shaul! -What's wrong with that?
Here, look at me.
Ask your father.
I worked at all sorts of jobs.
I ran, I sweat, I patted men
on the backs.
I had to have so much patience,
strength, intelligence. You name it.
What didn't I do?
- Yes. Yes.
Are you interested in advertising?
Really, that's clean work.
- What would he do there?
He doesn't know anything.
- He'll start as a messenger boy.
Then, he'll learn, like everyone
does. But no pampering.
How much do they pay?
That's not bad for a start.
What do you say, Shaul?
I'm telling you. He's shy.
- I'm not shy.
A person like you
and an office like this...
Come to me tomorrow at the office
and learn something, okay, Shaul?
Your father and I are old friends.
If I don't help you, who will?
Come alone and we'll find something,
I promise you.
Hello, Sarikeh. Do you have
a couple of seconds for me?
I just love you, Sarikeh!
- Leave me alone! Leave me alone!
Leave me alone, you idiot.
Hey, Sarikeh.
Welcome to the club.
If I don't take care of myself...
You're bad, this time, Yehezkel.
Well, I have a crazy idea.
Come here, Yohanan.
See that tree over there?
Go hang yourself on it.
- Wait, listen to my idea.
You'll die laughing.
- Let her rip.
Imagine there's only one bathroom
in the whole country.
Imagine, everyone's waiting in line.
Golda, Abba Eban, Yehezkel...
Oh cut the crap already.
- What's wrong? Can't you hold it in?
Just hear me out. What's happens?
Everyone who finishes runs
to the back of the line again.
But the main thing is, wait.
How does it go?
Wait, wait a second.
So what do they do? They all go
back to the end of the line, yeah.
To make it short, the entire country
comes to a standstill.
Listen, listen...
the whole country's become paralyzed.
What does one guy do?
He organizes an underground.
He digs, and digs, and digs.
Starts a black market. -Moron.
Tell me, Yohanan. Did you have
these ideas during the austerity?
About what? Toilets? Hey,
you gave me a good idea.
Look! Here comes
an American car.
Did they release you, Baruch?
- Come on. Get in, Shaul.
Hurry up.
Kushi, turn on the radio.
- Sit down and breathe the air.
Come on, Shaul. You little boy.
Make some food. Baruch. Baruch...
What's going on?
- Nothing. That's all we need.
No one is going to act up. They know
they'd better not open their mouths.
Are you staying here, meanwhile,
or coming home? -Staying here.
You've become mice, both of you.
- Keep your eye on me.
He went crazy. Cracked a bottle on
my head. -Didn't we bet? -Fuck off.
Want one? -No, not now.
Why did you bring your brother?
- Family trouble.
Baruch... you're out on bail.
Food, food. food. Bon appetite!
Baruch, Baruch. Eat.
Leave him alone. What's wrong with
you? Nerves eating you up?
You forgot how they caught you.
- Go away and comeback tonight.
Fuck off. Calm down.
- You've changed.
Leave my problems to me.
Come, Shaul. Sit down.
Shaul, eat something. Don't you
like the food? It's sardines.
Hanani, forget about everything
for now. Come and eat something.
So Shaul, what's new with you?
And Dad? Auntie? Rikki? -Auntie's
really sick. No one knows why.
Is she suffering?
- Doctors come by, nonstop.
Poor woman.
So you're not working?
That's okay. You can rely on me.
- No. It's all right.
Dad knows someone who promised
to get me a job. -Dad.
Watch out for him. -Why? -Hanani,
I want you to stay till the end.
Listen and listen good.
Remember the fight
we had that morning?
Our old man went to the police
and talked about me.
Ask me how I know?
Someone else was going down until
I realized. He's pretty smart.
He went to one of his friends
who just happens to be a cop.
They thought they'd get some
information out of me. Suckers.
I'll settle the account with him
myself, but I wanted you to know
while you're here, with these
witnesses, I'm telling you what
happened so you and everyone else
get the story straight.
I swear that everything
I told you was the truth.
What long faces!
Aren't you guys having a party?
Leave him alone.
How are you, Shaul?
Fine. How are you?
- Are you still working for Eli?
Yes, why? -Just because.
Your dad probably doesn't know yet.
What? -Didn't Eli tell you? Baruch?
- Baruch what?
Are you pretending, or what?
They caught him here this morning.
The entire neighborhood
was up and running.
Didn't you know?
Wait! Shaul, wait!
Shaul?
The police arrested Baruch.
I'm not surprised
after what I heard about him.
When did they arrest him?
- I have to see Eli. They're friends.
He probably knows. -Where are you
running? What can you do?
I'll put the milk in the fridge.
Who told you he got arrested?
Now, Roni.
The whole neighborhood knows.
I don't envy your father.
Oh, it's you?
It took you long enough.
They arrested my brother.
- Know. What can you do?
You know?
How do you know?
Are you interrogating me?
Get back to work. Fast.
Did they arrest anyone else?
- Meanwhile, no one else.
Baruch won't talk.
- Only Baruch?
What's going on?
Are you taking a day off?
I have to find out
before my father gets home.
You're not moving from here
until the work gets done. Get it?
I'm sick of you!
If you want, then after work,
go to Yosef's coffee shop.
They know exactly
what's going on over there.
If not for your brother,
you'd never get to work here.
You're worse than a woman.
Hi, Eli.
- Hi, Moshiko. Hi.
Hello?
What?
The quieter, the better.
Talk less, okay?
Getting arrested is nothing.
They'll let him go for lack of proof.
You'll see. Tomorrow he'll be back.
King of the neighborhood.
And if I don't return it to you,
what will you do?
So I'll sit in jail.
How bad could that be?
Really? What could happen?
Are you going already?
Wait. Wait a minute.
We haven't seen you for years.
- I'm going. -Shaul, have a coffee.
You have one, too.
What's new? We never see you around.
- What can I say.
My head is killing me
after yesterday.
Yesterday, all the guys
were sitting at the Arianna.
I'm not exaggerating.
I drank three...
What's wrong with him? -Poor guy.
His brother got busted for drugs.
He left his wife for a Moroccan.
- Who left his wife?
Tziyon. -Who's Tziyon?
What are you doing here?
Do you want your father to come
and see you? Go!
Have you heard anything from Baruch?
- Since when do you care about him?
He'll get out by tomorrow. That's
how it works at the police.
Don't his friends know anything?
- I told you. He'll get out tomorrow.
Why only Baruch?
What about them?
Yosef, you shit head. What kind
of coffee is this? -I'm coming.
It's a waste of your time.
Shaul, Shaul, Shaul!
Oh, poor Baruch.
Take another book. It's interesting.
The cops. Those dogs.
Now where to? -To Jaffa.
- Are you running away?
No, I'm going to get my dad.
Dad!
They arrested Baruch.
What should I do?
You're asking me what to do?
You go today. He'll go tomorrow.
There is a lot of work to finish.
There is a lot of work.
You go.
I'll be right there.
I don't understand. Why is she so
stubborn? -Because of the girl.
Mr. Cohen? -He's working in the
field. It's not easy to get him out.
If the situation gets worse, take
her to the hospital right away.
What's the difference?
We know.
I'm sorry, Mr. Sheetrit. Goodbye.
Would you like a drink? -Sit down.
I'll make tea. -No. No need.
At least some tea and toast.
She hasn't eaten all day.
Rikki, dear, it's late. Go to sleep.
- I don't want to.
Shaul, take her to her room
and wait till she falls asleep.
I don't want to. I'm not tired.
See what I drew in school today?
Shaul, look!
The tea is almost ready.
I won't drink.
- Go, Avram. No need for you to stay.
It's not the first attack.
Shaul is probably hungry.
Have you eaten, Shaul?
- It's okay. -I'll stop by tomorrow.
And don't berate yourself because
of Baruch. There are lots like him.
They say there was an informer.
I don't like what the doctor said.
I don't understand your problem
with Baruch. He's all trouble.
Let him sit in jail. See what it is.
Maybe make him a human being.
Wait and see. They'll let him out
tomorrow. -It doesn't go so fast.
Why do you want him
to stay there so badly?
Eli, what happened to you?
They're all bastards.
Go call Rachel, quick! -Okay.
Rachel!
Rachel! -What?
Did something happen to Naomi? -No.
Well, talk! Cat got your tongue?
Eli wants you.
- What does he want?
He got hurt. -Hurt?
Hurt.
It's not serious.
A little wounded in the face.
Where have you been all day?
We haven't seen you.
I was at a movie.
See? Sasson is building
another room. -So let him.
What's with you? You're not working
and won't look for work?
I'm looking.
- Were you at Ezra's again? -No.
Of course! You enjoy not working.
Just sitting around all day
with those thugs at the coffee shop.
Playing cards. -I don't sit with
thugs and I don't play cards.
So where have you been all day?
And now movies? From the street
to the movies. Movie to street.
You weren't with me at the movies.
I went with Dalia.
Didn't I tell you I don't want
trouble? Did someone see you?
No one saw us.
We each went home alone.
How long's it been since you visited
your aunt? -I went there yesterday.
I want to tell you something.
- What?
Did something happen?
- No, nothing.
It's about Dalia.
- Dalia? Again?
What again?
What already happened?
What happened?
Are you going to talk clearly,
or not?
You don't let me speak.
- I don't let him speak.
You've been talking for two hours
and you haven't said anything yet.
What's eating you?
Dalia and I... I...
I got her pregnant.
Pregnant? Pregnant?
How pregnant did you get her?
No, not really pregnant.
- You're worse than your brother.
What have you done?
When did this happen?
A week ago.
- A week ago?
And how do you know
that you got her pregnant?
I told you, it's not for sure.
But I think she's...
I don't know.
- Sit down. Finish eating.
What did you tell me all this for?
Pregnant, not pregnant?
If she's really pregnant, I'm scared
her parents will raise hell.
Is it dangerous, or not?
- Well, if she needs an abortion...
Where would I get the money?
You need money? Did you lose
a card game? -I told you.
I don't play cards.
- So what do you need money for?
I go out and have fun, don't I?
I'll give it back when I can.
How much do you need?
How much can you give?
Pay it back when you can.
I'm not telling you
to get a job just for the money.
A guy without a job
doesn't finish anything.
You got in big trouble.
My heart tells me so,
from the minute you stepped in here.
If you don't tell me what happened,
there will be hell to pay.
I'm not in trouble. -You're not in
trouble, but 50 isn't enough.
How much do you need? -A couple
hundred. -I have no patience for you.
Baruch's in trouble. I want to help.
- Baruch? You're with Baruch?
What do you
have to do with Baruch?
Have you connected up with him?
What are you doing with Baruch?
I'm not connected up with him,
but he's in trouble.
Even though you fought with him,
you have to help him.
When did he get out?
- Yesterday.
What's the matter?
- It's the bail. He owes his friends.
And he sent you. He won't get
a dime from me. -Why not.
Just no. We're done here.
- We're not done.
I saw him.
I know exactly what he has.
Do you remember what they did to Eli
when they thought ratted on them?
Now Baruch is scared, too. Hanani
and others won't work with him.
He's alone in Shimon's shack.
- Don't care.
Clean the table.
- I won't clean it.
What's with you?
First, your brother. Now, you.
Why are you ganging up on me?
What do you want from me?
To kill me?
Go ahead. Just kill me.
I know you have money.
I always knew but I believed you.
You stopped my studies.
You said you can't work anymore.
"I don't have enough money."
Then, you sent Baruch to jail.
You ratted on him.
At first, I didn't believe it.
But now, I think I do.
Shaul, what kind of things
did Baruch put in your head?
Look at me.
What did you just say?
What did you say? That I...
I got him sent to jail?
Is that what he said?
And you believe him?
Where is he right now?
- In Shimon's shack.
See him and tell him
"Dad wants to talk to you."
Let him come here and tell me
everything he told you.
Just go and get Baruch.
What's the matter? -Go get him.
Tell him his brother's waiting.
Hi. That was fast.
Hey, what's going on with you?
- I'll show you.
Dad ratted on you, did he?
- Shaul.
He'll kill him.
- Get inside already.
This isn't for females.
You're old. Get inside.
They're brothers.
They'll work it out.
Enough, Shaul. Enough.
Stop it, Shaul!
Shaul, that's enough!
Fuck you!
Go and ruin the houses
of the European Jews.
Where were you all those years
we had it bad?
Where should I have left my kids?
Out on the streets? Like monkeys?
That's what the government wants.
It's okay for our kids to fight
the Arabs for you.
But find them a place
to live tomorrow? No way!
Is that what the government wants?
Leave me alone.
Right. Bring in those pale skinned
Russians to investigate. Sure.
All those years when we ate dirt.
The government didn't come then.
We never got food for them.
Now they're older and we leave them
on the streets to smoke pot?
Are we worse than dogs?
But we won't let you kill them.
Blood will be spilled.
Your blood and our blood.
Do something!
Damn it! Stop this already!
Dalia!
Did you see how happy
my 700 liras made them?
Come in, Shaul. How are you?
- Okay.
What's new?
Don't worry.
That's how it goes.
Come in.
What did I hear? They tore down
your neighbor's room? -Yes.
Esther also set fire to a city truck.
- Oh dear.
Do you have to live here?
What's wrong with you?
Where do you want him to live?
I don't know.
People get themselves in a mess
and then expect someone to save them.
I'm going to make coffee. Want some,
Shaul? -Why not.
Shaul, what happened
between you and Dad?
Just a small fight
because of Baruch.
How do you feel? -Shaul, your dad
suffers because he loves you two.
Not just you. Baruch, too.
If you keep making trouble,
there will be nothing left of him.
See how he looks already?
Baruch got it from me.
From you?
It's still a little hot.
That's how it goes.
Everything will be okay.
Private Menashe, what did they do
to you? Draft you? -Yes.
Are you on leave, dear?
- I got two days off.
Probably to visit his momma.
- No, they must be scared of him.
They sent him home.
The officer comes and says, "At
attention!" He answers, "Me?!"
"Hell no, I won't!" -The guard saw
him laughing and fainted.
What do you want? What a soldier.
- Stop it, guys.
So what do you say, Menash?
- Has momma seen you, Menash?
Not yet. -Not yet?
Whoah! What a man!
Comes to tell the gang, first.
- Private Menashe.
They're tough in the army,
aren't they?
I'm going home.
- Come. Come.
Here. Here.
Give it here, give it here...
Here! -Catch!
What's wrong with you, anyway?
Get insulted, Menash?
- No, why? I'm tired.
Did they tire you out?
Poor guy.
Pass it here.
Here, here, pass it here.
See how he ran away?
Another soldier like that, oh no.
- What a sprint. -Did you see that?
What a coward.
Shaul, Shaul!
Your aunt died.
Shaul, Shaul.
A patrol car chased me all the way.
- Police? -Yes.
Listen what I need from you.
I can trust you.
Go find the guys and warn them.
Especially Baruch.
Wait, I'll leave before you.
If they ask about Kushi,
say he went
to Jaffa, to Yehiel, okay?
Great, thanks.
You! Come here.
Don't I know you from somewhere?
Empty your pockets.
What's your name? -Shaul.
- Shaul what? -Sheetrit.
Sheetrit! Get in the jeep.
Do you know him?
This is the last time
we see you around here, get it?
Tell your brother Officer Franko
sends regards from Rahamim Lolo.
Drop him off.
- Sit down. Not you. You get out.
Oh, Shaul. They destroyed
everything. A pogrom.
They came in the morning
and destroyed...
Every policeman
in Tel Aviv comes here.
What do they want from Shimon?
- If you don't stop it...
I'll rearrange your face!
Stop it, I said.
Kushi said you would hide.
- Good you came to tell me.
What am I doing here,
selling watermelons?
How did you know I'd come?
- I know the place.
They saw you. -Of course they saw.
He'll come, too.
I'm going now.
To Kiryat Ono.
I'll kill him! How much
do I have to tell you to shut up?
You are driving me crazy.
Detectives caught Rahamim.
Kushi went to Yehiel. To Jaffa.
He said you'd better leave.
Unbcle Shlomo asked you to go
over to their house.
He wants to talk to you.
- What does he want form me?
You haven't visited since Auntie
died. Dad will be mad if you don't.
I really don't care.
I'm splitting town anyway.
It's not nice if you don't go.
Besides, you'd better talk to Dad
before you go.
Did he say I should come?
- He hinted.
Go! I don't want to see you here.
- Avram, what's wrong with you?
What happened to you?
- And look who he brought!
One hand! -You wanted me to come,
did you? -I don't know.
He saw us together. Went crazy.
- Come in. Come in.
Shosh, Shosh.
Make them a cup of coffee.
Look what you did. -Stop in, Avram.
No fighting. Shame on you.
You won't work.
You worked enough in your life.
People get killed
for a few lira a day.
Bastard! -Not here, Avram.
I will really get angry.
He'll make a criminal out of me.
Just like him.
They know I'm shut up in here.
I don't come or go.
And that bastard does what he wants.
- Oh, cut the crap.
We're not the only ones sick of you.
Why do they have to suffer?
What about your promise?
What's with the job?
Shaul, all these troubles are
because of you. Go get a job.
What does everyone want from me?
You made him into an invalid,
by worrying so much. -Shut up!
You are eating yourself up.
You took him out of school.
Now, your heart is burning.
- That's how it is. All the time.
Not a day goes by
without anew problem.
Now go separate them.
- Don't worry. I'm going.
Watch out for all of them.
They are all sly foxes.
They will eat away at your soul.
Your dad is like a drug.
You'll get over him, like I did.
Shaul, Shaul, wait.
- Baruch, wait a minute.
Shaul, come here.
Go to this address.
It's my cousin's welding shop.
Tell him I sent you.
Comeback tomorrow.
- Not now. Avram, that's enough.
And don't do anything foolish.
Your brother isn't right.
He's not right.
I already know what to do.
- Do you have a plan?
Maybe Germany. We'll see.
I have some friends there.
Meanwhile, I'll go to Eilat.
What's with you? -What'll you do
there? -In Eilat? -In Germany?
Don't worry. They don't stifle
a person over there. Not like here.
But how will you leave the country?
What about the police?
- It's no problem.
Now listen. Hanani has to go
back to the neighborhood.
They talk about you. They say
you have a head on your shoulders.
They'll all offer you things.
Don't be a sucker. Don't take it.
They're burned out now.
Like me.
The neighborhood has no one anymore.
Like a single girl.
Get it? See you around.
- Okay.
Well, we're going now. Come.
Where will you be tonight.
- At the billiards, at eight or nine.
Good. Take care. -See you.
We'll go to my place.
No one will bother us.
No. It's better to go
to the old market. -Okay.
First, listen. Yehezkel, tell him.
- We'll tell you.
David and Moshe are both jerks.
- Tell him what it's all about.
I think I'm not ready yet. -You're
probably rolling in the dough.
Oh, you're funny.
You don't do anything. Just stand
there and whistle if someone comes.
Don't you get it?
This is a golden opportunity.
How much is there, Yehezkel?
- I saw a couple thousand.
Where is it? -On Rothschild Street.
David and I moved furniture there.
You don't see that kind of place
every day. Marble everywhere.
The walls, the shower, the kitchen.
The living room's full of books.
All lined up in rows.
- Wait, didn't David see it?
David was talking to the lady
behind the bar with the drinks.
There was lots of jewelry. -No cash?
- Cash, but lots of jewelry too.
Very old stuff.
- I don't know if I'll come along.
Think about it. We're doing it
on the weekend, so tell us by then.
If you want to come, come.
If not, then no.
I got my enlistment papers.
Really? When?
- Two days ago. -Look.
I don't want to take a chance.
- We're not forcing you.
But think hard, before you say no.
Now, you're like a fool,
with your tongue hanging out.
What are you waiting for?
For God to bring you money?
We don't want to do this
all the time.
Just one big hit, and that's it.
Dalia. Dalia!
I thought you moved already.
- I'm not sure I'm moving.
Are you working already?
- Yes. At the welding shop.
That wouldn't suit you.
Which way are you headed?
- To town. To an English lesson.
Well, I have to go.
Come in, Shaul.
Have a seat.
How are you doing?
- I'm okay.
Don't worry. In another two days,
everything will be fine.
What's new at work?
What could be new?
Did he pay you?
- Not yet.
Looks like he's a cheapskate.
Didn't you tell him it's urgent?
- I told him.
I don't think I'm going
to stay on there.
Do you think I just shut
up all the time?
You're getting mad at me
for nothing. I think about you a lot.
In a month or two, I'll have paid
all the debts and then...
everything will be fine.
Have you heard from Baruch?
- No. He's probably in Eilat.
It's better that way.
Here, have something to eat.
- Eat. You probably haven't eaten.
Hi, Shaul.
It's good you came.
So? -How much do I get?
- One third.
You don't do anything. Just stand
outside. Leave the rest...
Leave the rest to Roni and me.
Here.
Take some cash for the meantime.
Forget it. -Take it. Buy something,
a shirt. I don't care.
Remind me and I'll pay you back.
- A quarter to eleven, okay?
Give some change.
Let's play a round.
Five, ten minutes. -Where's Yehezkel?
- I'm going there now.
Oh shit. -Why did you jump?
- I heard voices in the apartment.
There are people in there.
- Hey! Where are you going?
Somebody could come by!
Quiet.
It doesn't matter.
We'll act like we're peeing.
I think it's not from this
apartment. -Come here.
Don't get us in trouble, now.
- Okay. Now you climb up.
Maybe it's this apartment.
- Shaul, you go.
You'll go far, the two of you.
Next time you plan a break-in...
Let's say... -What will you have?
- Just a minute.
Lucky they didn't catch you.
- Oh, get off my back.
Who was it, Shaul?
- Just some poor old man.
What did you want to do? Kill him?
- Enough, already! -We're through.
He went out a minute and came in.
Good, enough! We're finished.
If you set out to do something,
go all the way.
Look who's talking.
My God, I quit my job because
of you. -Hear that? Because of us.
Decided yet?
- Bring something strong.
Did you see the look she gave him?
I'm telling you, a horny old gal.
Would you do her?
- If she's ask nicely.
Well, we're off.
- I'm sticking around some.
Where to?
- Home. -Where's Baruch?
In Eilat, I think. -Did you hear
that, Kushi? He went to Eilat.
Bus driver, get going!
Maybe he's around here anyway?
- I haven't seen him for a while.
Too bad.
What do you want from me?
- We miss him.
Do you know Clara?
I asked you, do you know Clara?
- No.
You lied twice. -You lied twice.
About Eilat and about Clara.
And Shaul? -Bring him along.
Baruch will be happy.
Wait!
Hanani! There he is.
He tried to run away, the bastard.
- Kushi, keep an eye on Clara.
Hey, Baruch. How's it going?
Do you know Shaya?
You sick of the gang?
Shaul here, he misses you too.
You're brother is not a man.
Believe me, Baruch.
No one's mad at you.
But we got insulted.
When you took the money, we said,
"It's cool. The boy has expenses.”
But little birds chirping
to the cops don't sit well with us.
Shaul, you go home.
I'll come around later.
Go.
So we finally get to see you.
I was looking for you
all night long.
I won't ask too many questions.
Tell me something.
I don't have anything to say.
What did you do all night long?
- What do you want from me?
All I want is for you
to come home. That's all.
I don't know what's going on
in your head,
but now,
it's time to come home with me.
Okay. I'll be there in a little bit.
"Light out of Nowhere"
Subtitle production:
Elrom Studios