No!
Let me down!
It's snack time now.
Sit still
Hello. I am Ms Li
I'm the head teacher of this class.
And you are...
I am Qiang's father
What is your name?
Why are you crying?
Don't you like coming
to our kindergarten?
His name is Fang Qiangqiang
He's almost four
The principal said he could
join the intermediate class
He's been cared for by his granny,
but she is leaving
His mother works
for our ministry in another city
As a pilot,
I'm often away from home
So I'm putting Qiang
into a boarding kindergarten
He won't have to go home
on weekends
OK
All of the kids here
are 4 or 5 year-olds
There are two teachers
and two assistants
This is Ms Tang,
Ms Ma and Ms Fu are the assistants
Go play with the other kids.
Stop crying
Old wolf, old wolf,
what time is it now?
Two o'clock
Old wolf, old wolf,
what time is it now?
Three o'clock
Old wolf, old wolf,
what time is it now?
Four o'clock
Do you know
how this game is played?
Ms Li pretends to be a big wolf
All the kids pretend to be lambs
They follow the wolf and ask...
..."Old wolf, old wolf,
what time is it now?"
The wolf says, "One o'clock"
Then two and three, and so on
When it's nine o'clock at night...
...the wolf turns around,
catches a lamb and eats it
Nine o'clock
Come here, Qiang
Let me look at your pigtail
Who braided it for you?
Quickly! Catch him!
Fang Qiangqiang
Fang Qiangqiang,
stand up
It's neat and clean now
You won't grow head lice,
or get heat rash in the summer
This is for your own good
If you let us
cut off your pigtail...
...I'll reward you
with a little red flower
Don't move
Try to remember, raise your
right hand straight up for extra rice
Jin, you raised the wrong hand
This is your right hand
Raise your left hand
for extra soup
Watch me
Make a fist. Good
No talking during meal time
Don't stand up,
Fa! Raise your hand. What is it?
- I want to pee
- Pee?
This means you didn't pee
before washing your hands
You must form the habit
of peeing before eating
I won't allow any peeing or pooping
in the middle of a meal
I'll take away one
of your red flowers
Take it out. Quickly.
Give it to me
Why aren't you taking
off your clothes?
Nanyan, Qiang doesn't know
how to take off his clothes
It's your turn now
Don't cry
Nanyan,
go back to your bed
Get up!
Stand up, Hai
Listen, if you disobey me
I'll take away your red flowers.
- Did you hear me?
- Qiang wetted his bed
Stand straight
What are you two doing?
Put on your clothes. Quickly
1, 2, 3. Squat down
Who is still talking?
Listen to me
You must form the good habit
of pooping every morning...
...to excrete the dirty things
in your body from the day before
And parasites
won't grow in your tummy
I know
Qian is finished. Ms Li,
Qian succeeded at pooping again
Good girl, Qian. You've done it
for a whole week now
Qiang, what's the matter?
Have you finished pooping?
- I can't do it
- Then forget it
Get up to wash your hands
Will I lose my little red flower?
Your little red flower?
Not this time
But you must promise me that
you'll produce some poop next time
And I'll reward you
a little red flower
Raise your hands after washing them
Line up
The first line-up can go now
Ms Li, Qiang didn't wash his hands
For that you'll lose
your red flower today
Whoever receives five flowers
each day, for a whole week...
...will be next week's
class leader
Let's see who have received
little red flowers today
Qian, five flowers
Mao, four
Hai, one
Jin, three
Fa, three
No flowers for Ning and Dou...
...because Ning
bullied a classmate again
Dou, you must learn to dress yourself,
and wash your hands. OK?
We'll all keep working hard
What is it, Qiang?
Why haven't I received
any flowers?
Because you wetted
your bed again last night
You didn't dress yourself
this morning...
...or wash your hands
after going to the toilet
So you don't get any flowers
Nobody told me that.
It doesn't count
All right, I'll give you a flower
if you behave yourself tomorrow
Also, next time you have
a question raise your hand first...
...and then stand up
Sit down now
Qian has received five flowers again
You must emulate her
There are five opportunities everyday
to compete for little red flowers
Those who don't wet their beds,
dress and undress by themselves...
...wash their hands before meals,
go to the toilet on schedule...
...and do not talk at bedtime
will receive a little red flower...
...for each good behaviour,
plus one at his name on this board
Those who receive five flowers
everyday for a whole week...
Excellent!
I've got five flowers too
Put on your little shirt
Match each button for its hole
Left shoe, right shoe
Buckle up and you can go
Good.
Put your hands behind your back
Please sit down
Who wants to come up
and demonstrate the moves?
Beiyan. Hai. Maomao
Come over.
Ready? Go!
Put on your little shirt
Match each button for its hole
Turn a pullover upside down
And back to front
before pulling it on
Distinguish back and front
of your trousers
Extend one leg in each trunk
No left or right for socks
Only the heels
must be on the bottom
Left shoe, right shoe
Buckle up and you can go
Very good.
Please go back to your seats
Most children
can dress themselves now
Who still can't do it?
Stand still
Stick out your chest
and raise your head
Hold your fingers tight.
Well done
You see, anything can be learnt
Now turn around
and face the class
Who helped you get dressed
this morning?
Did you do it on your own?
Answer your teacher's question
with vocal sounds
- No, I didn't
- Who helped you?
- Ms Zhang
- Louder
Ms Zhang
Why must we learn
to dress ourselves?
I will choose someone to come up
and answer me
Qian
Children should learn
to dress themselves
Did you hear that?
There are only four or five children
left who cannot dress themselves
For those who can,
what should we do?
Help them!
Let's help them, shall we?
Yes!
Who will volunteer to demonstrate?
Raise your hand
Qian, you do it
Come over
Don't take off your underwear.
Go to Ms Ma
Qiang, come over.
Did you see it?
Practice now
Just keep dawdling.
No one will help you
You can get off
when you've mastered the skill
I dressed myself this morning
I strained to poop,
and washed my own hands
Why can't I get a little red flower?
Qiang has made progress today
Why don't we give him
a little red flower?
No, we mustn't pamper him
Qiang, you must continue
with your effort and obey the teachers
- Ms Li, Qiang is peeing
- Sit down
- I can't hold my pee either
- Go to the toilet
I will report you to the teachers
Creep!
Teacher! Teacher!
Get off your bed
Follow me
Stand here
Do you dare to climb up this chair?
Of course
Can you climb any further?
Let me down!
Get down!
How did you get up there?
Did you hear me?
You brat!
Quiet!
How did you get over here?
Did you fly from the window
to the bed?
- Yes
Nanyan, I saw with my own eyes
that you hit Beiyan
You lied and talked back to me
What a pair of sisters.
Helping each other out
Fine. Stop crying
You will each lose a little red flower
Nanyan...
Did you come to laugh at us?
I want to show you something
What?
A little red flower?
- Did you steal it from Ms Li?
- No
Since Ms Li has taken
one away from you...
...I want to give this one to you
I don't want it
First net goes empty
Second net comes with small fish
Third net catches a fish
with a tiny, tiny, tiny, tail
First net goes empty
Second net comes with small fish
Third net catches a fish
with a tiny, tiny, tiny, tail...
Ms Li, this is Hai's father.
He's come to take Hai home
Hey, son!
Let me introduce you two
This is Ms Li,
head teacher of Hai's class
- How do you do
It's still two hours
from pick-up time
Hai's father is the Deputy Minister
of Logistics in our ministry
He is very busy
He has some free time today
to pick up his son on his way home
It's quite an honour for us to welcome
Minister Wang to inspect our work
How do you do,
Minister Wang
Hai must have caused you
a lot of trouble
Not at all. Hai is very well-behaved.
He is smart and quick-witted
Did you make this evaluation board?
Oh, yes. They...
Ms Tang
is in charge of the pictures
Well done.
Wow, you are so young. Excellent
So many talents
in this kindergarten
Principal Kong
must be a good manager
- Not at all
- With diligent teachers
Hai, it appears
that you are just mediocre
He's been very well-behaved lately.
Very well-behaved
What's the matter with this child?
He hasn't got any little red flowers
- You must help him
- Yes, of course
We haven't evaluated today.
They'll each receive one
Dad, I want to wear
trousers with braces
Just carry on as usual
- Don't spoil him
- Yes, sir
This is from my dad.
You can't touch it
May I have a look?
This is a grown-up's thing.
Don't touch it
Can't I just have a look?
All right
Thank you, Qiang
- I want to play with you
- Sissy! Traitor!
Can I hold it?
Let me touch it
Freak!
Come on! Let's catch small fish
There are fish in it
I can't catch them
There are some over there too
Come here
Freak!
Beiyan, can I play with you?
It's been a while since
anyone played with you
- All right
- Let me push you
OK
- High up?
- A little
- Is it high enough?
- No more
- Is it fun?
- Yes
- But not so high
- Is it fast?
Yes. But not so high
- You must swing high up
- Yes, but not so high
- Shall we play another game?
- OK
- Let's pretend you are injured
I'm sick.
Give me some medicine
- Where do I find medicine?
- Let me see
- We'll use these buttons as pills
- OK
- Feed them to me
- All right
- Can I give you an injection?
- Yes
What are you doing?
Shameless!
Come here
Are you stupid?
Letting a boy take off your trousers!
Qiang, stand against the wall
Remember, don't ever let
any boy take off your trousers
Halt!
Turn around!
March!
Attention!
Salute!
At ease!
Get up, Qiang
One more offence
and I'll put you in confinement
- Did you hear me?
- Yes
Stand up. Hurry
What are you doing, Qiang?
No talking, no standing up
Please stop following me.
You are something else
Do you know what you've done?
- A monster chased me in the water
- Where is the monster now?
I flushed it away with my pee
- King of bed-wetting!
- You are the king of bed-wetting
Bravo, Qiang
Good morning, Ms Tang
Really smart
Put the train in the tunnel
Good
You are so capable
Put on your shoes
The seventh moves
Ready. Go
One, two, three, four...
...five, six, seven, eight
Two, two, three, four...
...five, six, seven, stop
OK, get in
The eighth moves.
Ready. Go
One, two, three, four...
...five, six, seven, eight.
Two, two, three, four...
...five, six, seven, stop.
Good. Discharged
- Freak!
What are you staring at me for?
I'm asking you
Stop crying
Eat your breakfast
- Why is he crying?
- He knows why
I hand out apples to my friends
only two are left in the end
A big one and a small one,
a big one and a small one
The big one goes to a friend
and I'm left with the small one
I'm left with the small one...
Ms Li, Ning is fighting
Ning!
I'm warning you,
stop bullying your classmate
Return to your seat
Let's sing the song again
Ready. Go
Who was it? Who farted?
Stand up!
Stick your bottoms up
Don't laugh
Ms Ma...
Qiang and Nanyan
Go to the toilet
Nanyan, go
Go now to the toilet
The rest of you, sit still
Call me after you've pooped
You stink.
Don't come near me
I hand out apples to my friends
only two are left in the end
A big one and a small one
The big one goes to a friend
and I'm left with the small one...
No, no, it's not like that
The big one goes to myself,
and the small one to my friend
Stinker!
The big one goes to myself,
and the small one to my friend
Stinker!
Eating radish and veggles
Jumping around like a cutie pie
Riding my little white horse
Little white bunny, oh, so white
Two little ears stick up right
Little white bunny, oh, so white...
Come on!
Wrong tunnel!
Ms Li has abandoned us all
because you stink too much
Let's go out and play
Come on!
I'm tired
Stop running!
- Salute!
There are nicer flowers over here
Hospital!
I want to be sick
so I can stay out of the kindergarten
I can eat yummy things
Mum and dad will come and see me
Let's play the game of sick patients
Let me ask you...
...would you follow me wherever I go?
OK
You have to be hygienic
when you are sick
What are you doing?
I don't like it when you kiss my ear
Let's run around
What animal was Nanyan imitating?
Don't speak
Raise your hand
- Pang
- A peacock
Now let me imitate an animal,
and you guess what it is
All right? Watch me
Ms Li has turned into a monster
Let me tell you a big secret
You weren't born by your mum
It's you who wasn't born by humans
Remember,
Ms Li has eaten your sister
- I'm not one, right?
- No
- Do I have a tail?
Neither of us has a tail
What if Ms Li only eats children?
Stand still
Stand still. She can turn everything
into anything she wishes
- Does she like eating children?
- Definitely
Qian must be a little monster
created by Ms Li
Does Qian have hair in her armpits?
They have hidden their hair
- Will Ms Li eat us?
- Definitely
I can turn into a girl
- Why did you touch my bum?
- To see if you have a tail
Neither do you
May I hide under your bed?
I'm afraid Ms Li might eat me
OK
- Can the two of us defeat Ms Li?
- I don't know
- Let's try
- No. Let's not
All of us put together
cannot defeat Ms Li
Where are you going?
- I want to look at Ms Li
- Don't. She'll eat you
I want to see what she looks
like as a monster
Quieter!
Let's tie her up
so she won't be able to eat us
- What with?
- With a rope
- I've got shoestrings
- They're too short
I also have shoestrings.
We can tie them together
Let's look for other things
Monster!
What are you doing?
What's going on?
What happened?
- Ms Li, what happened?
- I don't know
- What's going on?
- Tell me
Yes?
Tell me what happened
Monster?
What monster?
Monsters are made up
to scare little kids
- Don't cry. Speak to me
- Speak, Maomao
Yes, speak to me
Tell me, who is the monster?
What? I am a monster?
Says who?
- Who is making it up?
- Ms Li...
- Who is the rumourmonger?
- Calm down
Tell me who told you so?
Stand up, Jin
- It's you. Get out!
- Ms Li!
Bang! Bang!
Go away
- I'm not scared of you
- Nor I of you
Creep!
Get out, Qiang!
We are playing a game
Remember, wolves are bad
Run away when you see one
to avoid being eaten
That's not right.
We should kill the wolf
You dare to refute me?
What is it?
- Who bullied you?
- They hit me!
You three are the black
sheep in our class
You are the ringleader
You are the go-getter
You are the evilest of all.
A villainous conspirator
All the bad ideas
come from you
You're giving me a nasty look?
Come again?
Come again!
I dare you!
You deserve a good beating
Your parents are too lenient with you
and you become a troublemaker
You'll end up in the hands of
the police if you go on like this
You are too timid
If you keep quiet when others
bully you they'll step all over you
Next time someone bullies you
report them to a teacher right away
The three of you apologise
to Mao one by one
Starting with Ning
I was wrong
and I'll never do it again
Say you are sorry.
Didn't your parents teach you?
- I'm sorry
- Go away
Mao...
Did I call you?
- Hai
- I'm sorry. I'll never do it again
Fang Qiangqiang
- Fang Qiangqiang!
- Sugar bun
- What did you call me?
- Fuck you!
- No!
- Let's go!
No!
Get up! Get in!
Call me when
you've decided to be good
Open the door!
Who are you?
Principal Kong,
come and rescue me
A monster is about to eat me
I was wrong
- Who taught you that dirty word?
- Nobody
There must have been somebody
Nobody in this kindergarten says it
What a rude word.
Do you know what it means?
- I said nobody taught me!
- What kind of attitude is this?
You are in the kindergarten
and must obey the rules
Don't contradict the Principal!
I don't want to go to kindergarten.
I want to go to school
I wouldn't regard leaving
the kindergarten as a happy event
This is happiest,
the most carefree time of your life
You can never come back to it
You'll understand it
when you grow up.
All right?
Put Qiang in solitary confinement
He cannot talk to any classmate
without permission, and vice versa
Isolate him
Qiang hit me
I've told you to ignore him.
Return to your position
Listen carefully,
Qiang has been disobedient
You are not allowed to pay
any attention to him
Beiyan, why are you crying?
What's wrong?
Now, now, don't cry.
Go back to sleep
Why are you smiling at me?
Who smiled at you?
How shameless you are!
I'm laughing at a dog!
From now on
you are allowed to join the others
Follow tightly
I'm out of line.
Report me to the teachers!
Qiang!