Yeah! Come on!
Don't worry about it.
Everything's gonna be
all right.
God! Is he dead?!
Where's his wife?
Gloria!Aah!
Don't worry about it!
Whoo-ee.Is he hurt pretty bad?
I don't know.
Somebody said
broke his back.
My! How'd he do that?
Cycles is a mean toy, lady.
Mahhh!MAN : Wait a minute.
Who's that? Get that man
off the course out there.
Hey, Red, get that guy
off the course.
There's no walkin'
on this course.
Everybody, stay back, now,
till the races are over.
We've only got a little ways
to go,
and these guys are tired.
And for outsiders, around here
we don't want anybody
out there on that course
till everything's all over.
Is this supposed
to be supper?
Hmmhh.
You just taking pictures
for yourself or what?
I'll tell you who you ought
to get a picture of.
Damn.
Dumb thing's jammed.
You let Little
look at it.
If it's broke,
he'll fix it good.
Comes to anything
mechanical,
Little's all but eerie.
Get your cheeks on that bike
and get off the track.
Now, move it. Come on,
let's get goin' there.
Hurry up.
Move it!
Crowd, we're gonna come
back in a couple more weeks...
You did good, Little.
That was good, son.
Thought the buzzards
gone and got you.
Did you see me
wavin'?
I was goin' as fast
as I ever went
in my whole life,
and then I fell off.
Well, you go
too fast.
If you stay on,
you win.
That's how you win.
You gotta stay on.
What's that, movies?
Come on. Now. Hurry!
Oh, Ma, now, don't--
Don't bother that fella.
I told him
we'd pay him
if any of 'em
was any good.
Just me and my bike?
Uh...
Sure, Little.
Hey, what do you think
of a boy, anyway,
that sleeps in his room
with his own motorcycle?
Just one for the mantle.
That's all I want.
We haven't got
a single picture
on the whole mantelpiece,
Seal.
Yeah. Hey, is that
one of them
instant machines?
I'll get your address.
All right, now.
Now, hold it.
Stay loose as a goose.
That's it. That's it.
Relax. Relax.
That's it! That's it!
Oh. Oh, hold it...
Life's too short,
darn it.
Mmm. Oh, ho.
Ha ha.
Someone's had
herself a brew.
Goes by too damn fast.
Yeah.
Now, keep it there.
Keep it up. Now, let's--
Let's see
that great big smile.
Yeah, hold it.
Hold it! Hold it!
That's it!
That's--you got it.
Oh, that's perfect.
That's beautiful.
That's lovely.
Yeah, I like it.
Give the man
our address, Dopey.
Okay, boy.
I can get it
off your facilities.
Oh, no, no, no.
I insist.
Here, you take one of
my business cards.
I told him the day he starts
bringin' his work home's
the day I move out.Well, you can laugh at me
if y'all want to,
but it's a fact
I ain't had a stool since
I been in Portable Potties.
That's a fact.
Look, I want-- No. Here.
I want you
to read that. See?
"Portable Potties." P.P.
Pee-pee. Ha ha ha!Yeah, it's, uh...
You get that? Mom
thought of that one.
I did not,
Seally Fauss!
You did.
I was goin' as fast
as I ever went
in my whole entire life.
Yeah, but
you fell off.
Yeah, I fell off.
Try and stay on,
son.
Try.
Aw, come on, you...
Damn!
Careful, now,
Little.
We don't want to put
no scratches on 'em.
Hey, how about you guys
givin' us
a little push, okay?
We happen to be
a little busy.
Oh, hell. Sure,
take your time.
Come on, now, son.
Push.
Just a little further.
Unhh!
Unhh.
Are you pushin' any?
I'm doin'
the best I can.
These potties, they seem
more trouble than they's worth.
Me and the wife
come down from Mendoza,
dang thing cuttin' out
on me every five minutes.
Now dang thing
won't even start.
My wife's getting
hotter 'n hell.
She's expecting
a steak dinner,
and I said, "Honey,
you just cool on down,
"'cause those folks
over there
is gonna give us
a little push."
Say, you got all
your beer locked up?
I don't sell no beer.
Little...you can go
load your bike now.
Sure like to buy y'all
a beer, damn it.
Monkey-haired,
sideburned son of a--
Now, don't
get riled, Seally.
Well, he can just go
straight to hell
with his flair,
for all I care.
Well, they'll
be stranded.
Well...I ain't
givin' no hand
to no undesirable.
Got a cigarette?
Don't smoke.
Aw, damn it.
Just gave my last
cigarette away.
Damn it.
Just spent my last 2 bucks
gettin' here today, damn it.
Blew my pickup
comin' on over, and then
burned out my bike
in the trials,
so I didn't win nothin'.
Then I lost my sponsor,
if I'd had any luck,
which I didn't have,
so now I don't
even have a smoke.
You ready, son?
This guy wants
a push, Dad.
Hey-o, just a little shove's
all I need to get her goin'.
Aw...
Hey. Hey,
how 'bout a push?
Hey, what the hell?
Come on, aren't you gonna--
Hey, I need a push, damn it!
Let's have
a nice big smile.
Come on, ice cream.
Oh, that's great.
Hold it.
Okay. Hey,
that was a-number-one.
That's really good. You
want to take another one?
Hey, how 'bout a beer?
You want a beer?
Oh, sure, sure.
Okay?
Hey. Goddamn.
I forgot my wallet.
It's in the pickup.
Uh...
Oh. Well, here.
Here.
Hey.
Here you go.
I'll catch you.
I'll catch you later.
You remember? Okay.
Gimme three beers.
Hey, man you was really
workin' out there today.
Cranked around them corners
with the big boys.
Yeah. You race today?
Ho ho! On that
dumb-ass course?
Not me, buddy.
Didn't think
I seen you out there.
Hey, man,
what class you race?
You'd'a seen me, babe.
I'd'a had you at the fence.
What class
you race, man?
Hey, you're gonna gimme
three steaks, too, huh?
And put it on my tab.
My manager's got it.
Who in the hell
is that?
That's the cat got
suspended out at Ascot.
Boozin' it up
in the pits, man.
Hey-o. Bubble
for the system.
You...
Sorry. Oh, damn it!
I forgot your change.
Oh, oh, oh... That's
all right. That's all right.
Hey, where was I at?
Hey, you were gonna tell me
how you broke your spine.
Which is what first
caught my eye.
And to this day,
I can't sleep in a bed.
Hell, man, where
do you sleep, on the floor?
That's right. That's
where, on the floor.
Must make it pretty hard
on the little lady here.
I mean, if your husband's
sleepin' on the floor all night.
What I mean is,
it, uh...heh heh...
must be pretty hard
on you.
Him?
Yeah, well,
it would on me.
I haven't seen a floor
since I met him,
much less a bed.
Mm-hmm. Mm-hmm. Hmm.
The whole two weeks
we been in love.
We been sleeping
in the car.
Oh, then you two
aren't married, then.
No, this is my buddy.
This is my bosom buddy.
Aren't you, honey?
Show him your bosoms.
Hey...well...
Why don't I just get
a room out here, then,
and, uh,
we all just settle
down for the night?
Hey...
My name is Halsy Knox.
Hi.
This here is
what's-her-name from Simi.
Ooh, yeah.
Sylvene McFall.
Hi. How do you do,
Sylvene?
I just guess we're all
free, white, and 21, huh?
And, uh...
Anything goes?
Gotta keep movin', honey.
Look out. Get outta my way.
I'm gone.
Hey.
You got any lube nipples
for a Yamaha 250?
No?
No got.
Shit.
Oh, boy.
You got head gaskets?
Oh, head gaskets we got.
Owner around?
He's out to lunch.
Thought I'd promote myself
a couple of tires
if the boss is around.
Them I got
seen too many races
if I head out to the desert
on Sunday. You goin'?
That's a buck-59
for the gasket.
Hey, let me use your,
uh, torque wrench
for about 5 minutes.
Thought you said
he wasn't around.
He'll be back.
After lunch, you said.
Hey.
It's a buck-59.
Hey, it's a buck-59.
Hey, incidentally,
um...
It's a buck-50
for those gaskets
plus, let's see...
9 cents tax.
You sure got some small
ideas about friendship.
Hey, what's the matter,
you think
I ain't gonna pay you
or somethin'?
Hey, forget it.No.
I always pay my own bills.
Where is that?
Oh, well, if you're
gonna use that gasket,
you'd better
seat it first.
Seat it?
Yeah, so you don't get
any blow-by.
Well, I'm no scientist.
I just ride bikes.
Is this coffee for
the general use here?
Customers.These sponsor guys
are a pain in the ass,
anyway. I hate 'em.
How you doin' on sugar?
What?Sugar.
What about it?
Don't have to
stay up all night
workin' on a bike
the night before.
They just stay up all night
lovin' the women
and drinkin' it up and
doin' whatever they damn want.
How about
a little cream?
Hey, where's your...
Where's your wife today?
My who?
Uh, you know,
I met your wife.
Oh. Uh...Yeah?
Yeah. She's, uh...
She's a stewardess.
Had an early flight
out this mornin'.
Didn't have no time
to fix me any breakfast.
Whose doughnut is this?
Is this somebody's?
Come on, I'll let you
buy me a beer.
What's so funny?
Hyah! Hyah!
Yahh! Yahh! Yahh!
Whoo-hoo!
Hyooh! Hyah! Hyah!
Come on, hyah! Yahh!
Hahh! Hahh!
Yahh ha!
Hyah!
You know, Seal,
we want to hear
Little's side of it
before we start
leapin' at conclusions.
What we got
for dessert, Mom?
I got whip 'n' wonder,
wet 'n' warm,
and slit 'n' serve.
Well, it don't make
no never-mind to me.
Well, whichever.
Speak up.
It won't stay
with me 20 minutes.
It just don't sound
like Little to me.
Houndin' sheep
on a cycle.
Well, where is he,
then, huh?
It's not humanitary.
Look, Frazier
done seen him.
He seen him!
Someone on a cycle.
That don't mean Little.
Specially bein'
two of 'em.
We're the only friends
Little's got.
You know that.
He don't have
no friend.
Oh, come on,
let's eat.
Ya-hoo!
Hi, Ma! Hi, Pa!
Little!
Where've you been?
Ohhh...
Hey, Ma...
I just had
one beer, Ma.
I just...
Hi.
I'll have my whip
'n' wonder now, Mom.
Uh, this here--
This here's my friend.
Uh...my friend.
Hello.
How you doin'?
Dinner is done.
Well, we ate.
Yeah, we ate already, thank you.
Howdy Frazier
called me up.
He said two bums
on bikes
was tearin' up
his river-road acres
till he run 'em off!
Well, that's okay.
We ate.
I think
I gotta wash up.
Now, you hold on
a minute, Little.
You hold on!
Son, your father's
speakin' to you.
Well, I know that,
Mother.
Ahem. I know that.
But I don't feel good.
I don't wonder.
Hey, babe, you got that job,
you want to look good.
You better be clean.
Okay, Sideburns,
I told you
I want you two fellas
to hold on a minute!
Seally, peace.
My friend Sideburns
is waitin' here
on a part from Tulsa,
and I--
he's waiting on a--
For a part,
you know, from Tulsa,
and, um...ahem...
I invited him over,
uh, for the weekend.
Just till then.
Just through
the weekend.
Huh. Well, you know,
I think I should
wash up. Excuse me.
I gotta look for a job
for me, too, in the mornin'.
I can't collect my unemployment
out here till May.
So...uh...
you wouldn't know
about any positions
or anything open,
would you?
Had a job out in Texas.
But my old lady wouldn't
leave her girlfriends
and go on out there.
To hell with her,
though, right?
I mean, shoot, I had this job
right up until Christmas,
and she wouldn't
come out there.
Well, I don't give a damn.
I mean, I can get a job
over at Mira Linda
anytime I want.
Well, I suggest you just
go to Mira Linda, then.
Do you want a cup
of coffee first?
Nope. No, I--
Boy, these flies are...
somethin', aren't they?
Where did Little...
Where'd Little go to?
Hey, buddy.
Do you want instant frost
on your whip 'n' wonder
or just plain?
It don't matter
beans to me, Mom.
beans at all.
It'll just...
go right through me
tonight, anyway.
Okay, let's everybody
have their attention now.
Let's get
your attention here.
All right, now we got
about three minutes
until starting time
or less.
We're gonna have
a hare and hound.
We're gonna run it right.
Come on now,
let's everybody get back.
Give these riders
plenty of room...
What do you say, Halsy?
We've got a long way
to go and it's hot.
Riders, come on now.
Everybody get back.
How's it going, Halsy?
Hey.
Get off the line!
Can't you hear me?Sorry.
Come on, dude!
Come on! Come on back.
There you go.
Hey, dude.
The gun'll go off
at the same time
that flag'll drop.
Riders, let's get ready.
Knock off that conversation.
Let's be ready. That flag
can drop any time,
and anybody jumps that gun
is gonna be disqualified.
Ready? Watch that flag.
Go!
Get over! Damn it.
Yee-hah!
Yahoo! Woo-hoo!
Yah, yah!
Hey, man,
get it over!
Hey, get over!
Okay.
Hey, Hals, you dead?
You okay?
Hey, Halsy? Hey--
You ran right under me,
you bird-brained creep.
I think I broke
my leg, man.
What the hell you run
right under me for?
You hurt any?
Broke my chain, I think.
Goddamn it!
Out the way!
Goddamn bike!
What are you
gonna do, Hals?
Halsy, I can't get
out of my pants.
My leg's broken.
Yeah, go on, okay.
Get out!
Go on, you mother...!
You got matches?Matches?
How the hell am I
gonna find you
if when I come back
it's dark?
You'll be back
before dark.
They'll send somebody
back before dark.
Oh, not these Mickey Mouse
country road shows, man.
They don't take
no responsibility.
You're on your own.
Heck, Halsy, you'll
be back before dark.
It's only 4:00.
Oh, yeah.
Only just light a match
when you hear me coming,
just in case.
That's right, you bastard!
In case what? You're
coming back or not?
I got a broke leg.
Hey, don't panic, man.
You panic in this weather,
it'll kill you.
Here you go.
What's this?
It's what's to do
in case of snake bite.
Read it.
One machine's coming
in,
and let's everybody
now remember
this race is only
for trophies here today, gang,
so let's give everybody
a nice hand
when they cross
that finish line.
We've still got a lot
of riders coming in,
a lot of winners
to sort out.
And all of you guys
now that think
you've won trophies here,
why, get your machines
and get over there
by that trophy table.
All right, now,
let's get over there
by that trophy table.
What do you say?
Say, you ought to
be a model.
Oh, would you please
quit it?
No, I mean it. Oh, hey,
listen, now,
I'm an expert.
You know how many
races I've won?
Do you have to do that?
Every time, out comes
some trophy chick
who thinks
she's Ann-Margret.
Well, I never said
I was any Ann-Margret.
Listen, these hands
have held the boobs
of more top flight
actresses and trophy girls.
Well, I'm not any
trophy girl. Now, come on.
Please?
You've got 'em
all beat, my dear.
Oh, by a mile!You!
Two miles.
Yeah, but you know
they don't have
trophy girls
at Desert Enduros.
Yeah,
the cheap bastards.
All this racing,
no ass.
Would you please take
you hands off my things?
Some people
really don't know
how to take
a compliment.
Well, I thank you,
but, my gosh,
I mean, there's a lot
of people here,
and it's kind of embarrassing
in public and everything.
Why?
Well, I don't know,
but one thing is
you haven't even gotten
your trophy yet.
Oh, damned if I don't.
Hey, what're you doing?
No, put me down!
Put me down!
Yee-hah!
When are the other guys
getting back, Joe and Bill?
Aw, they'll be back here
any minute now, Don.
Hey, would you care for
a cup of coffee, Spike?
How about you, George?
Thank you, Joe.
Well, you're welcome, Fred.
I mean Bill.
Where you working now,
uh, Joe?
Oh, you know, down by
the railroad tracks.
Oh, you are? You like it?
Well, you know, it's, uh...
Oh, yeah.
Oh, well, uh, would you
care for an orange?
No, I don't want to
ruin my breakfast.
Hey, dude. I hate
to tear you away
from your friends...
We gotta split.
They got pro races
every weekend
out there in California
some place,
and if we split out
there, who's gonna know
who's you and who's me?
Oh, no, somebody's
gonna find out.
Oh, boy, you think
you're famous.
Ow!You know, it's a funny thing,
but nobody knows me
out there.
So how they gonna
know who's who
if I'm there
with your bike,
your license,
and your number,
and you're standing
right there to deny it?
How'll we split it up?
Halves. You see--
Hold it, excuse me.
All points go automatic
under your name,
not mine, towards
your expert card,
your standing
in the nationals,
which the way you ride
is the only way
you're ever gonna qualify,
if somebody raced for you.
You're acting like
you're doing me a favor.
Shit.
Seems like a good deal
to me the way I see it.
Yeah, for Sideburns.
If I want to race pro,
where could I race pro
around here?
What are you talking
about racing for?
You're his tuner,
Little.
He's racing, dummy,
on your bike
with your license
'cause he got throwed out.
Meantime, I could hit
all the main events
across the country, Dad.
I can't do that
around here.
Meantime, who pays?
You know, I think
he done it a'purpose.
Broke my leg?
What's a broke leg
to his kind?
Oh, you'll have to
prove that to me.
Well, I might
just do that.
Well, I gotta go.
Hey, come on, dude!
Little? Little...
Uh...
The best fortune
to you, Little.
But I still don't
see no good out of
hooking up with
an undesirable
like that, though.
That goes ditto for me.
I know what y'all mean,
you know.
But if I want to race...
there's a lot I can
learn from him,
and, uh,
there's a few things I can
teach him, too.
Anyway, what else
is there to do?
And we're gonna split 50-50,
so, um...
there ain't nothing
to lose.
Let's get going!
Wait a minute! And as Fauss
went by out there
he just took the front wheel
right out from number 80.
Halsy, come on!Come on, Halsy!
Come on, baby!
Come on, Halsy!
Hey, man.
Uh, great, Halsy.
Great, man.
Hey, out of
sight, man.
Man, this bike, whoo!
Used them other
scooters for traction.
One more lap,
wasn't even half mile,
you would've been first.
You know what even
second pays?
$30. Screw first!
Hey, the beer's on you
for a week.
Beer nothing.
I'm getting me a pint!
Halsy! Halsy!
He fell right
in my groove, man.
Hell, I took two laps
before they could
even get him out there.
Did you see that?
Is he dead or anything?
It's just so
darn much fun.
Even though I'm
working so hard,
just sitting in there
in that position
it is just so exciting.
There's just one thing
I want to ask you, Halsy Knox,
and that's who
the hell is she?
Who in the hell am I?
Who in the hell
are you, you bitch?
You know, if I could just
get in there
and stay there all night
long even though--
Hey, hey!
Huh?
Hey, what are you
sleeping in the car for?
Somebody's gotta
guard the bikes.
I'll guard the bikes,
go on in.
Where'd you get
that flashlight?
Hey, man, look at this.
It cleans up lint,
it air conditions your face.
It's even got
a table on the side
that gives
weights and measures.
You're just gonna
cop it off her?
Well, listen, you get
stopped by the highway patrol,
man, they're gonna
give you a ticket
if you don't have
the proper safety equipment.
You going in or not?I guess I better not.
All right, go on.
Come on, go in.
Tell 'em I said
it was all right.
It's okay by me.
Go on.
I think I'm coming
down with a cold.
Oh.
Okay. Let's split.
You just cut out
on Moneth?
Yeah.
Hold on a second.
Hey, I thought
you said you had a cold?
Well, it's not
that bad.
Man, we're leaving.
I just thought I'd go
say goodbye to Moneth.
Oh, the hell with her.
What's she to you?
Nothing.
You know,
but, uh, if it's
such an easy set up
like you said...
Forget it.
Well,
now's a good time
to take care of this
shyness I got
and strike while
the iron's hot,
because nobody cares.
Well, Little,
you had your chance.
Couldn't I just...
take a peek?
Ohh.
To this year's crop
add to the surplus
carryover.
As of the end of this year,
the surplus is expected
to be down
to about 12 million bales.
And on the basis
of current guesses,
the surplus could be cut
to about 9 million bales.
There has been a new proposal
for a compromise plan
to provide supplemental
financing...
It comes from
a Kansas congressman
who wants a scaled down
version of the program...
They're gonna feel
awfully bad, Halsy,
when they wake up
and find out
you're not here.
The bank would get
its initial funds
from the private
money market.
The system would make
loans to co-ops
who can afford to pay
higher interest rates...
No, sir, man.
Once a chick swings
AC-DC on you, split.
Once it's cool,
twice it's queer.
Hals?Yeah?
Are you awake?
I better be,
I'm driving.
Hey, man...
What the hell?
What did you do
to this car?
I was sleeping
in it.
Look at it,
look at the gauge.
That dude's
all the way over.
Well,
it's not my fault.
Well, you were sleeping
in the car all night.
What've you been
doing, man?
Exactly what I was
doing: sleeping.
Well, what were you
thinking about in there?
You better
get on this, dude.
Unh! Son of a bitch!
What's it gonna
do now, rain?
Hey, if I tell you
something,
you gotta
believe me, okay?
Well, I usually believe
what people tell me.
Well...heh!
Not this you won't.
Well, I don't know.
You know
what the truth is
unless it's what
people say, you know?
I bet you think I make
out really good, huh?
Well, I don't, I don't.
I don't make out good.
You know those girls?
You think I don't know
they're dogs?
I didn't know
if you knew or not.
I don't know why
with all I got
going for me
all I get
are the dum-dums.
They mean well, I guess.
You think I don't
know who they are?
What they are?
I didn't-- I didn't know
if they were or not.
Hey.
You know, sometimes
when I'm drunk...
I really think that
they're princesses,
and then I wake up
and they're just pigs.
I just figured
you liked pigs.
Hey, that old Moneth
was bad, huh?
I just figured, you know,
if you wanted a pretty girl
or someone decent,
all you had to do
was snap your fingers.
No, man, I mean, that's
what I'm telling you.
It's just these gland
cases and hurting whores
that'll have me.
Where the hell are we?
I...I don't know.
Stay clean, man.
Hey, I'm not so clean.
I don't mean pure.
Aw, you should see
my thoughts sometimes.
I mean decent.
Hey, Halsy, you know,
just because...
Just because I don't
yak it up all the time,
you know, heh-heh!
I'm not just your pure
St. Peter, you know?
You know what?What?
All I say is...
It's just talk.
Uh, you sure--
You're a sure good
talker, man.
You had two chicks
in the sack.
And stupid me, man,
sleeping in the car.
It's pretty noisy again.
We gotta get
a colder plug.
If you guys
want to step it up,
we're running
a little bit late.
This will be a 250
through 650 class.
Uh, we're gonna run
a quarter of a mile
on the asphalt
for at least 2 miles.
Are you gonna
pay attention
to what
this guy's saying?
Heh-heh! Over there.
Jesus Christ!
Oh, my hell!
Okay, get rid of her.
Me? It's your truck.
Well, you're
a good Samaritan.
You're the Don Juan.
Hey, man,
just dump her out.
Get rid of her.
I don't care how.
And just
leave her there?
Well, they did,
didn't they?
Yeah, but they're
undesirable.
Hey, I don't want her
there when I come back.
Okay? Now I got
a bike to ride.
Hey, this is our truck.
Hi. This is our truck.
Uh, you need a dime
or anything, you know,
to make a call?
Um, lady?
You where a gym is?
Hey, ma'am...
A gym?
Yeah. If we come to
a town with a gym in it,
just let me out at the gym
'cause I gotta
start working out.
Man, I wouldn't pay
no attention to her.
I don't think she knows
what she's doing
or talking about
or nothing.
Who's your friend?What are you doing, lady?
I don't think you can
find a gym around here, lady.
Because that's
the first thing you do
when you start
getting straight.
You just start eating,
putting on fat.
Uh-uh. You guys don't
turn on or what?
Now, listen, damn it.
I told you
about that light.
I'm just trying to
exercise a little.
You don't have to turn
around and pull me.
I don't see why I can't
do exercises.
Just don't push.
Come here.
Get out of here.
Hey, wait a minute, just--
Get out of the car.
Hey, hey, hey!Get out of the car!
Hey, come on, I'm just
trying to exer-- Okay.
Want to taste
something good?
Wow. Wow, man.
Hey, Halsy?
Yeah, I heard, man.
A grubby chick.
You want to taste
something good?
Hey, no,
that's not funny.
It's just bad.
Hey, you don't have
a guitar, do you?
A guitar?Do you have a guitar?
Heh-heh-heh! We don't
have no guitars.
You play guitar?
Yeah.
In New York City
I play guitar.
Let's go, buddy.
Yeah.
Somebody stole
my guitar.
No shit.
Hey, listen.
It'll be okay.
You'll find a guitar.
It's okay.
Don't stay, just split.
I don't want you
in my karma, anyway.
I gotta be very careful
who I let in my karma.
Your what?
I'm not letting
nobody in my life
when I get straight
this time.
Hey, did you ever notice
that you can drive
all day and all night,
and wherever you stop
it's the same
greasy hamburgers?
The same fried eggs
served by the same
fat waitress?
Yeah, it's--
It's just like you never
went nowhere at all.
It's like you
never went nowhere.
That's just what I said.
That's what
I said, dude.
It's always the same.
What're you gonna do
about her?
That's her lookout.
What's your hurry?
Where are we even--
Where we going?
Just some other
greasy spoon down the road.
Yeah, just some
other greasy spoon
down the road.
I gave her 5 bucks.
You gave her 3 bucks.
Oh. Was it 3?
What's she gonna do
on 3 bucks?
Big lover.
I'm not the big lover.
I knew you'd get
yourself in trouble.
Well...
Well, you get
yourself in trouble,
why can't I get
myself in trouble?
Hey, because I can
get myself out.
I can get myself
out again.
I want her.
You want her?
I can want somebody,
too, you know.
Oh, now, man,
I can get you somebody.
I can-- You could've
had Moneth.
I want somebody
that's my own.
What is that?
Dope-head community
screw, man?
She's nothing but some mama
for all them freaks.
No, man.
She's all alone.
You know what I wish?
What?
I had me
a Geiger counter.
A Geiger counter?
I'll marry me the first man
comes up with a Geiger counter
and we'll live at the beach.
You know how much treasure
there is buried
in the sand alone?
Plenty.
You know what I wish?
What?
That somebody'd ask me
what I wished.
Okay, what do you wish?
I wish that we'll
all be friends
and have good luck
and be happy.
How'd that happen?
Well, I was going
as fast as I ever went
in my whole life,
and I fell off.
Oh, him or me?
Yeah, how'd you
break your leg?
Hey, uh, remember
what happened in Digger?
He was working
on the oil rigs.
Digger?
Isn't that in Oklahoma?
Uh, where the whole town
blew up or something?
Never heard of it.
He wasn't expected
to live at first,
and then he was
never supposed to walk.
Sure.
Shit, the way he said it,
I thought it was famous.
Mm. Well,
the spine's integrity.
His is broken.
What's the leg?
The leg?
The leg's support.
Slow down! Slow down!
Over here, over here!
Oh, you son of a bitch!
Watch where you're
going, you jerk!
We got a real celebrity
here with us
this afternoon, folks.
Rick Nifty's
in from the east,
so, this is the guy
that's the guy to watch
here this afternoon.
Let's get all the riders
over here
for a riders' meeting,
and we'll be back...
All you tuners and sponsors
have got to conform, too.
No more of these
weird outfits.
We got too many of these
weird outfits in the pits.
Now, you all want
to keep racing something
you can be proud of,
so we gotta get rid
of these high heels
and these tight pants.
I see there's some pretty
illustrious people here today.
Okay, now let's get back
'cause we got
a lot of things to do
and we don't
have much time.
Now, come on, men,
let's get going.
Hey!
How you doing, Rick?
You probably don't remember,
but a couple years back
when the Army had me
for a couple years
and I got this back
messed up in Vietnam,
you and me went around
together at Sears Point.
Oh? Is that right?
How's it going, Rick?
When Uncle Sam calls
you gotta do your duty
and you do your duty
even if it costs you,
and you gotta begin
all over again.
Look, I gotta get to work
if I'm doing any racing today.
Oh, hey, no, sure.
I just wanted to extend
my apologies
for this rotten track--
Excuse me, honey.
This rotten track
and to tell you
to be sure and watch out
for that transmission fluid
on the track
and them grease stains
that they left
from the drag races
last night. Hey!
I wanted to tell you
it's a real pleasure--
A real pleasure
to go around
with a top professional
go-faster here today.
Maybe again next year
at Sears Point.
Oh, hey, when is
Sears Point this year?
You see that?
That's ol' Rick Nifty.
Rick Nifty.
He's an old buddy
of mine.
It ain't even legal,
I got him so panicked.
Only way that dude's
gonna see the finish
is to get in my draft.
I'm gonna blow
that son of a bitch
right off the course.
Hey, hold it, Halsy.He just better watch his ass.
You just better
watch yours, man.
What they ought to do
is to pay me extra
just for making it
interesting.
That's what these
square Johns want
is to see the real
muscle fighting it out.
Two top fast go-getters,
fighting it out
to the finish.
The World,
starring Halsy Knox.
How's that,
Lady Godiva?
Hey, get that flag up there!
Hey, get it up!
Come on!
Go!
And there
they go into the first turn!
Now we've got
Fauss up front.
Nifty's back in second place,
Fauss is up front.
Nifty doesn't look
so nifty right now.
This could be an upset
because Nifty's not used
to running behind.
Boy, if this doesn't look
like the national--
Nifty's back
in the lead again!
Look at him
charge there, folks!
Look at him go!
Whoa! And there goes Fauss!
Fauss gets
a California bath!
No Scott Roddy,
Rick Nifty,
Van Dusen,
Jim Dandy Sinclair's
gonna lift his leg on me
and get away with it.
That bastard think
he's the only one
ever been up
to Sears Point?
When were you
at Sears, Hals?
He don't know I wasn't
ever at Sears Point.
It rained the year
I was at Sears Point.
Drove all the way
up to 'Frisco,
got up there,
and it rained.
I heard they race
rain or shine up there.
Not during
earthquakes.
Oh.
Who couldn't
win a race?
You fly in in the morning,
you fly out at night,
you got the top tuners
working a top bike for you.
You carried your mad
into that race, Halsy,
which is
the dumbest thing, man,
that anybody could do--
I gotta get me
a sponsor.
And that's where
you goofed, you know?
Somebody who knows bikes,
much less throttle
return springs.
That throttle return spring
was perfect.
Man, I couldn't
stop nowhere
on that Mickey Mouse
scooter of yours, Little.
Hey, you missed
the trail, man.
Hey, you can't ride.
That's it, you know?
That's--
Yeah, you can't ride, man.
Hey, what, are you drinkin'
all the beer, ol' buddy?
Well, it's
on your side, dude.
Naturally.
Halsy?
What-ee?
Never mind. What?
What's "what-ee"?
Never mind, damn it.
What do you want?
Didn't you ever say what-ee
when someone said your name?
I just want
to tell you something.
Okay, what?
What I was wondering was,
when your suspension's up?
What're you, homesick?
If you're homesick,
go home if you want.
No, I want my--
I want my bike back.
I want my license back.
And, uh...
I want to be
Little again, you know?
Sure, man, screw it.
Right away.
I don't give a damn.
You don't have
to be dragged about it.
They'll cancel
my suspension.
I pay my dues anyway.
Don't worry about me.
It's just my leg's better,
that's all.
I'm not bugged.
Who says I'm bugged?
Only to tell it true.
It ain't your gimpy leg
you want to exercise.
I just want
to race is all.
Sure, man, it's your bike,
you race it.
Only don't tell me it's your
bike you want to race.
Yeah, well,
what is it then?
It's the chick.
Yeah, well, she ain't
your chick, you know that?
She sure as hell
ain't your chick.
Yeah, well, it was my idea
to bring her along.
Whose truck is it?
It's your truck,
but it's my bike
that's winning all the races to
pay for the food and the gas.
Damn it, I'm trying to bust my
ass to score points for you
and you're trying
to take my chick from me.
You're trying to take
my chick from me, man.
Anyway, you don't
want her none
except maybe that
she ain't no whore.
Well, if that's friendship,
I'm aghast.
I never said I was
your friend, Halsy.
I don't even
fucking like you.
Oh, so he finally
blurts it out.
I don't have to blurt it.
I'm telling you
cold and clear, man,
I don't like you.
I never did.
And everything I had to
talk to you about, man,
I had to think up.
Hey, if we're gonna
settle this, Little,
before I bust you
in the face,
maybe we'd better
call out Rita
and see how
she stands, huh?
Hey!
Ask her.
Little, I got it.
Little, see, here it is.
Like I told you, after you
left with Sideburns,
I found this
in your room.
See?
The photographer's camera.
Why for all we know,
Sideburns could've committed
foul play to get this,
and they could've took you
as his accomplice.
He don't have
to get rough, old Halsy.
As long as nobody
ever steps up and says,
"Hey, man, you ain't
tellin' the truth."
that's what he's got
going for him.
As long as nobody
ever steps up and says,
"Hey, that ain't
what you said yesterday."
You know?
Well, where--
Where was--
What was I saying?
Oh.
I just as soon as died,
and half the time
I thought I did already.
and I'd hear conversations
with other bodies.
"Are you dead?"
"Oh, yeah. Are you?"
And just when I knew
that I wasn't,
they bored two holes
in my head and they was--
They was pullin' my head
in one direction
and my feet in another
and they was turnin' me over
every half-hour like some
barbecued chicken on a spit.
Just to keep my poor
old spine from sagging.
People die
with broken backs.
Usually people die,
but sometimes things happen
that aren't usual.
I mean, a guy can fall off
a 12-story building
and he don't die.
I fall down five steps
and I break my neck.
And all because
of some dumb broad
named Bunny Patchen.
I was hot,
and I was running
from the bathroom
to the bedroom, you know,
and I was-- It must've
been the excitement
of the big date and all,
because I got
to feelin' kinda dizzy
and the next thing I know,
I'm fallin' down these stairs
and then I'm--
I'm in the intensive care
on that spit,
and then a body cast for--
I was in a body cast
for three months.
And all I get
from ol' Bunny Patchen is
this get well card saying,
"Oh, I'm sorry, Halsy.
"It just can't work out
between us
"due to the fact
of all the things
you place so much
importance on and I don't."
Yeah, I know.
Same thing
happened to me--
No, it didn't happen
to you, damn it!
Now, it happened to me!
It didn't happen to you!
What I mean is you're looking
to be responded to.
Aw, bullshit.
It's not called bullshit.
It's called moving
off your center.
If I told you
I was being tortured
by wild Persian tribes
while I was travelin'
around the world
for the FBI,
you'd listen to me,
but I told you the truth,
and you wasn't listenin'.
You wasn't listenin'.
So, what good is
the truth?
To the right!
...crosses the line, folks.
Unofficially,
here is the results.
First was Ken Loman,
second was Merle Fromm,
third, Don Dobbins,
and just out of the money,
Halsy Knox.
You asked me
where my Mars was.
You kept on buggin' me
about my Mars,
and I tell you
where my Mars is,
and now you come up with
"Where's my Venus?"
Shh! Please, be quiet.
What's the matter?
Am I makin' it nervous?
Well, you're moving me
very much off my center.
Aw, hey, babe, I don't know
about your center.
I don't know
where your center is,
where my planets are,
I just know we're broke.
And unless you come up
with something here today
besides these bottle caps
and pennies,
I'm gonna hock this toy.
You hock your own toy, sonny.
You don't hock mine.
Hey, wait a minute.
You mean hock my bike?
Hmm?
You haven't made dime one
since you went 100 percent.
I think that ought
to tell you something.
What? Okay, what ought
to tell me what?
You need Little.
You did it! Ha-ha!
Little! Little!
Little!
Whoo-hoo, Little!
That's your
best time yet, son.
You broke your own record.
Well, I couldn't have
done it without you
and your flag, Ma.
Oh, you!
I'll get you!
Get away from me,
Little.
I'm gonna get you,
Little!
Hey, come on, Ma.
That's okay, Ma.
You shouldn't--
Hey, Ma,
quit fooling around!
You get down from there!
Hey.
Well, howdy, folks.
How ya doing?
Ma'am, how are you?
How's about a body
gettin' some gas
for a broke-down truck
up the road?
You sure got
a lot of nerve
coming out here
on an empty tank.
Oh, man.
Hey, you may let me starve,
but you ain't about to let
no motor go hungry.
How's your old man?
He's dead.
Oh.
I'm-- I'm sure sorry
to hear that.
I was genuinely fond
of the old gentleman.
That's more than he had
to say for you, man.
No, I'm...
I am much shocked
to hear of his
untimely domain.
How the hell
are you, buddy?
What is it you want,
Halsy?
Aw, you're mean,
Little.
Now, you don't
respond to people.
Now, damn it,
that's a bad trait.
People want
to be responded to.
Looky here, I gotta
bend over backwards
just to catch
your eyes.
I was saying
to Rita this morning,
boy, this reunion
with ol' Little,
that's gonna be a tough one,
but, damn it, worth it.
Hi, Rita.
How are you?
I'm fine, Little.
I'm fine, too,
thank you.
When'd you get that?
I wondered when the heck
you were gonna notice.
Ridin' sidehack now, huh?
Who with?
Well, ol' Jimmy Fast
got killed
up at Corriganville,
and his wife said,
"Here, take it."
Said she never wanted
to see it again.
How's Herrera?
I gave him Rita's
Geiger counter for his half.
No, I mean how is he?
Oh, he's great
except he's got no nose.
Well, uh...
Who you ridin'
sidehack with?
Well, now, I truly hoped
that it was gonna be
my old friend,
Little Fauss.
Hey, you might tell him
half that thing's mine.
You know, my Geiger counter
paid for it.
Yeah, we couldn't
hustle up enough loot
to hustle up
a doctor soon enough,
and now it's too late.
And, hell, I'd marry
her like that,
except they just
caught up with me
for not supporting
one family, and, hell,
I don't even know
if I'm divorced yet.
Hell, you know me.
I'm not the kinda guy
who can just cut out
on some girl.
And, well, so, remembering
how much in love
that you two were,
I just kinda figured
I'd maybe just step
right outta your ways
if you thought you might
wanna get together
and team up again,
get something going.
You mean come back
and be your tuner
and take a shot at Rita
every once in a while, right?
Well, you have
a low mind, Little.
You just wanna pawn
that chick off on me, man.
I figured you'd
think that.
Yeah, well, that's
how it is, right?
Hey, I don't even know
if it's my kid!
Sure, for all I know,
it may even be your kid.
Yes, sir.Aw, man...
Man, she can't even
tell me whose kid it is!
It'd just break my heart
to give up poor Rita,
but if that's
what I gotta do...
It'd be just like
old times, remember?
Lots of laughs,
plenty of ass?
What do you say, babe?
I ain't a tuner anymore.
I race.
I want you to race.
That's what I'm here for.
I need you to sidehack for me.
Halsy, I ain't climbing
on no sidehack
to hold you down.
I race solo 100 percent.
She's havin' a baby, man,
and I don't have a dime.
I'm goin' to San Francisco.
Sears Point?That's all I'm gonna do.
I ain't ridin'
sidehack no more.
I ain't gettin'
screwed up.
I'm just goin' to Sears Point
to race and screw people.
Hey.
Yeah?
Well?
I make it a rule
never to make
no promises.
So?
I just want you
to know, though, that--
That you can
count on me.
I make it a rule...
never to count
on anybody.
Good...
then maybe
we'll get along.
Next rider up
will be number 62,
Red Perkins
on a Harley-Davidson.
There they go.
He's off for a good run.
Halfway up now,
and look-- Oh!
And up and over and another
of the slide riders
didn't make it there
as he slides back down.
And the next rider'll be
one of the Tulsa riders--
number 8 junior...
Well, it doesn't make
any difference there.
Uh, only his pride,
maybe his butt
got hurt there. He's okay.
Rita?
And the next rider
up will be one
of the local favorites,
Little Fauss on, uh,
number 191 on his Yamaha.
He's set to go.
There he goes, and it
looks like a good run...
Ohh, Little...
Oh, whatever happened to...
Whatever happened to...
Ohh...
Whatever ha-happened to...
...Halsy?
Ohh...
He knocked up some whore
there a while back
and, well,
he probably had to
get married by now.
Woo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
We did it, baby!
Ahh. Hey! Whoo!
Just shut up
and hurry up!
How we doin'? Easy.
Ohh! We got plenty
of time. Hold on.
Halsy, first aid
and a big smile
is not gonna
get me through this.
What a prima donna.
You're supposed
to exercise...
I got you, baby.
You're supposed
to exercise and eat
and take breathing lessons,
and I didn't do
any of it!
Put that baby out there,
huh? We're comin'.
I got you, now.
Just take it easy.
Hey, Halsy, you ain't
gonna win this race!
Huh? Well, who the hell
are you, smart ass?
How come
I didn't see you?
I didn't see you 'cause you
was behind me, that's why.
Easy now.
Ohh!
What the hell
were you ridin' in?
Take it easy, will you?
I got the leg,
I got the leg.
Where's my helmet?
We'll have you
there in a jiffy.
Throw me that helmet,
will you, Jay?
Come on,
I gotta get movin'.
Hey, wait a minute.
Easy.
I got it.
Right with you,
baby.
Okay, Mac, go ahead.
I want somebody
to call my father.
No one needs to call
your father, baby.
I'm right here.
I'm your father.
If we--
If we go to 'Frisco--
That's where they live.
I could call them
and blow their minds.
Oh, we're
gonna go to 'Frisco, baby,
and we're gonna blow
your old man's mind,
and I'm gonna win
the old 200.
Community hospital.
Can I help you?
Mr. Knox.
Are you Mr. Knox?
What-- Huh?
What? Uh-huh. Why?
Congratulations. It's
a healthy 6-pound baby girl.
What? Huh?
Your wife,
Miss Nebraska.
Yeah?
She's asking
to see you,
if you haven't,
heh-heh, "split."
You guys! You can't
even say goodbye
and thank you!
I was gonna say goodbye
and thank you, Moneth,
but I thought I'd let
you get your beauty sleep.
Yeah, well, if you see
your boyfriend down there,
you sure tell him he taught you
all the wrong things!
'Cause you two sure like
to leave a girl high and dry,
you know that?
Could be you, Moneth,
Who, me?And, uh,
don't you
"you guys" me,
'cause I'm me.
Yeah, well, maybe
you used to be,
but you sure ain't anymore,
you know that, Little?
'Cause Halsy and I ain't
even friends anymore,
much less what you say,
boyfriends.
Can't you just...
Please...
say goodbye?
Goodbye, Moneth.
"Sears Point,
you big-time beguiler,
"I long to enter
your 200-miler.
"Lest I forget,
though it's needless
to mention..."
"Your cow palace trade show
"commands my attention.
"Good to see Good Year
"and Triumph and Harley,
"Nixon and Bauman
"and Odum and Charlie.
"top hot-shoes and go-fasters
all racin' together.
In spite of the mother-humpin'
California weather."
They'll
never print that.
Oh, they printed
all them stories
and articles
on how I cycled
through South America.
In-juh. In-juh.
Huh?
You told me
it was India
you cycled through,
not South America.
Did I say India?
Oh, that's right! It was.
That's right.
It was India.
Turkey and Turkistan,
all them places.
Burma...
There's the fuzz.
Fuzz is here!
Everybody's here!
God,
that is beautiful.
Yeah, it sure is.
Is he here?
Huh?
Who?Mmm...
Hey...
All I'm lookin' for
out of this
is a factory contract.
I'm just tired.
I'm tired of leaning
on dealers
all over the country
to ride them name brands
in every fairground
and county fairs
all over the country.
Just to get
on some factory team
at 40 or $60,000 a year.
That's all Sears Point
means to me.
High dealer wins. It's my beer,
it's my house.
We're gonna be here all night.
All right,
come on. Let's go.
Come on, Halsy.
Deal 'em.
I have Frank up.
Come on, Frank. Come up.
All right, well,
let's go.
I'm in. A quarter.
Everybody in?
Yep.
Oh, my God.
I thought we were bein' raided.
Hey, is poker legal
in California or what?
Lock the door,
will you, babe?
I ran into an old friend
of yours downstairs.
Who?
I asked him to come up.
Well, if it ain't Little Fauss,
my old tuner. Good deal.
How are you?
Come on in.
Grab a chair.
This is a hell
of a time for a raid,
into me for 10 bucks.Who's into who?
Somebody's into somebody.
You want a beer?
You know Rita?
Oh, yeah, you met. You--
You seen our kid?
Yeah, you got
a nice baby.
Thank you. Well,
how do you know, man?
You haven't even seen her.
She's over here.
I seen her when your old lady
dragged me up here.
Yeah, there's nothin'
like a kid in the world.
Nothin' like a kid.MAN: You playin' or not?
Yeah. Hell, I'm in.
For cryin' out loud--MAN 2: Get in or get out.
So you're in
Cockroach Manor, too, huh?
That's what I call
this place, Cockroach Manor.
It's ritzy enough for me.
Huh?
What?
Ritzy enough for me.
Oh, no, man,
I'm only kiddin'.
Sure, it's beautiful.
TV...
You're only in San Francisco
once, I always say,
and all my friends are here.
Well, I better
get some sleep
if I wanna get
some practice laps in
in the morning.
Yeah, man. Sure.
You better get some sleep.
How are you?
I'll go 2 bucks
just to get you out--
- Two bucks. Okay.
- I'll see you for 2.
Me, I do all my partying
before the race.
Then I'm so hung over
all's I wanna do
is get that race over.
And damned if I don't
race better just trying
to get that race over
and back on the road.
I'll, uh,
raise you half.
You look for another
greasy spoon, right?
I'm gonna call,
but gimme a hole card.
You don't think big, Little,
and that's your problem.
Probably from racin'
in dirt too much.
No more suckin'
around for tires
and candy-assin'
spark plugs for me, babe.
No, sir.
One year in
the national circuit, then out!
Out while I'm on top.
Go on TV as a famous
sports celebrity.
Racing ain't the only way
to make money.
The dealer folds.
Best of luck to you.
Yeah, I was even
sayin' to ol' Rita,
I thought we might go up
and visit her folks and...
kinda make 'em
feel good.
You have a kind heart,
you know that?
All right, come on.
Deal 'em, man.
Let's go, will you?
Hey, it's not my deal,
damn it.
Whose deal is it,
anyway?
I ain't runnin'
a casino around here.
How's she supposed
to get any sleep?
Somebody grab the pot.
Yeah.
Let's get some beer.
See you later, Hoss.
Halsy.
It's Halsy, man!
Later, man.
See you later, man.
How you doin', Rita?
I'm doin' good, Little.
How are you doin'?
All right.That's good. What's happenin'?
Draft board's got me.
Thought you said
you had to go home
and get some sleep,
Little.
Draft board's got me.
I got drafted.
Crash your bike, man.
Get reclassified.
You mean, uh,
hurt myself on purpose?
That's what I done.
Well, I don't
feature that.
I don't feature that.
Ohh...
Except when you go to wreck
yourself a little,
you end up wreckin'
yourself a lot.
Operator.Operator, uh,
I'd like to make
a long-distance call
to Pebble Beach,
California.
What's the party's name?
Uh, to the country club. Do you have the number?
No, I don't
know the number.
And that's person-to-person
to Mr. and Mrs. Jack Nebraska.
That'll be 75 cents,
please.
Okay.
Twenty-five cents more, please.
Just a minute.
I'm coming up with it.
Thank you.
Hello. Who is it?It's Rita.
Look, would you speak up?
I'm sorry, I can't hear you.
We got a bad connection here.
Who is it?
Rita!
She's gone.
Who?
Aw, hell,
who do you think, man? Rita.
She cut. Split.
She's not with me.
Oh, now, I know she's
not with you, man.
What's she gonna do
with you?
She cut out on me.
She didn't
even say goodbye?
Oh, come on.
Who cares?
Screw her.
Once a whore,
always a whore.
Hey, what do you say
to something to eat?
Let's get something
to eat. How 'bout it?
Some greasy spoon
up there.
Come on!I already ate.
Come on, have a cup
of coffee with me.
I had coffee, too.Oh, well, then have a crumb.
Hell,
have a toothpick.
Come on, watch me
eat. Come on.
I turned down Suzuki,
did I tell you?
Good for you.
I told them to take
their contract
and shove it.
Ain't nobody gonna run
my life like that, man.
All right.
Sponsorship
is nowhere, man.
Politics.
That's right.
I had--
I had this offer
to go race in Europe?
Uh-huh.
I had to turn it down
because of Rita
and the kid.
Shit.
You didn't have
no offers, Halsy.
Hey, ma'am, can I
have some coffee?
What a day for her
to leave on, huh?
Ohh! Oh, no.
If a chick's gonna go,
she's gonna go
on your birthday
or on Christmas Eve.
They got their timin' down!
They know just when to cut you.
How's it goin', Halsy?Hey, what do ya say, babe?
What do you know?
You hot today?
Yeah!
'Frisco.
We made it, didn't we?
It ain't how you do, babe.
It's where you been.
Ain't you learned that yet?
It's how you do, Halsy.
With the temperature here
on the track at 111 degrees
and under a cloudless sky,
the North American
Grand Prix,
and already we have
the largest crowd
to ever witness a professional
motorcycle road race,
and we have people spaced
all over this racetrack
high on the hillsides
at the north edge
of San Francisco Bay
here at beautiful Sears Point
International Raceway.
With the start
getting underway
in just a few moments,
the factory teams doing battle
for the final time
this season...
And the starter flag,
and we're off...
The most challenging course
in the United States.
Still taking the lead is
Cal Rayburn,
number 25
on the Chief Harley-Davidson
from San Diego.
He's the pre-race favorite
along with Duhamel
on the Yamaha from Canada
and Art Bauman from
San Francisco on the Suzuki,
looking for his first
championship road race win.
Checking the back of the pack,
we've got a duel going between
two of the unknown
first-time entries here.
It's number 10 Halsy Knox
and number 58 Little Fauss.
Incidentally, Fauss was
a former tuner for Knox,
and they're really
seesawing it back and forth.
With number 58 Fauss
on the inside there,
getting up to about
a half a bike length.
But, wait a minute,
back comes number 10 Knox,
and they're seesawing it
back and forth there
through the turns,
and they should come
down the front straightaway
side by side,
and we'll find out
who's got that horsepower.
But wait a minute,
approaching turn seven there,
number 10 Knox
starts to stretch it out
as he moves by off of nine.
He's out about one length.
He gets up to two,
and apparently 10,
Knox has broken that duel
and is starting to move up.
There he goes
from fifth to fourth
as they come
down that front straightaway
around that bend,
and he's got the lead.
Number 10 Halsy Knox
apparently is coming up
with some trouble there.
He's slowing down.
Once again we notice back
in the pack is number 58,
a first-timer, Little Fauss.
Now he's starting to put
the pressure on
as he works his way by
Ron Hurtle on the Kawasaki,
and he goes up to eight.
And across
the straightaway area we come,
and we've got
a brand new duel going
with Little Fauss,
number 58 from Oklahoma.
Fauss again, and he picks up
another position.
He's running seventh.
Up to sixth he goes.
There he goes past
Merle Freeman
on the BSA. Into fourth
as they come down
the front straightaway
and around the bend.
And he's
in third position now,
getting ready to take a shot
at the big boys up front
with only ten laps to go.
If Fauss can continue
the pace,
we could have an upset
this afternoon
here at Sears Point.
So keep your eyes
on number 58,
Little Fauss from Oklahoma.
...with only 10 laps to go.
If Fauss can continue
the pace,
we could have an upset
this afternoon
here at Sears Point.
So keep your eyes..
Keep your eyes...
Number 58...
Little Fauss from Oklahoma...
Little Fauss...
So, keep your eyes on...
Keep your eyes on...