Hey, where's Ryota?
Mr Suzuki wanted to see him.
Is he getting detention again?
Again?
- You're late!
Sorry, sorry!
All right.
What shall we start with?
What else?
Yeah.
Obviously.
You're right!
Here we go!
Don't worry! Be happy!
It's my life!
Little Love Song
Another beautiful Sunday morning
Start of a day both short and long
I've got nothing on my schedule
Think I'll take a walk about town
Keep the door closed when playing.
Keep the volume down.
- Is that them?
- I think so!
You and me, just the two of us
Until a starry sky rises overhead
Happiness is spending time
With you
Don't worry
Be happy
Happy Sunday
It's my life
Don't worry
Be happy
Happy Sunday
It's my life
What's the matter?
Why are you looking so blue?
There's nothing to worry about
Let's go!
Because tomorrow...
is Sunday!
Don't worry
Be happy
Happy Sunday
It's my life
Don't worry
Be happy
Happy Sunday
It's my life
One more time!
Don't worry
You there! Stop that!
Happy Sunday
It's my life
Don't worry
Be happy
Happy Sunday
It's my life
Thank you!
You rock!
How many times is this now?
Well, Ms Moromiri?
I am so sorry!
You, too.
We're sorry.
Enough is enough.
Ikehara, Maeshiro, Shinzato!
Fukumura!
You disappoint me.
Keep this up and you'll be banned
from the school festival.
Not just your band.
All the other bands too.
We're sorry.
You need to shape up
and keep your friends in line!
What a prig.
- Shush.
- What did you say?
What's his problem? Everybody liked it.
We can't get banned from the festival.
Shinzato! That was so cool!
- Really? Thanks.
- You see?
Wait...
- Give me her number.
- No way.
Oh... Shinji's sister.
Mai.
Don't tell Dad.
Are you stupid?
Be proud of what we did!
Everyone had a good time!
- Idiot.
- Dummy.
Let's continue jamming!
You're banned from using the club room.
Move, Kotaro!
Yes, I win!
All right.
Mr Nema!
- Hey, Mr Nema!
- Mr Nema!
- You there, Mr Nema?
- Let us use the studio!
- Guys! Quiet!
He's here.
I told you about him.
The guy from a Tokyo record label
who's interested in your band.
Wait... wait!
Sorry, sir.
These are the boys I told you about.
Shibuya?
Have you ever been to Shibuya?
So, I'd like to ask you boys
if you're interested
in going professional.
Going professional?
Wait up!
Hey! Which way is Tokyo?
Let me see...
- That way!
- That way?
Are we really going to Tokyo?
After we graduate.
We can make it!
Our music rocks!
We can do it!
But Tokyo is where
all the best bands are.
Bring them on!
Hey, Tokyo! We're going to kick butt!
Just you wait!
We did it, Tokyo!
We're coming!
Tokyo! T-Tokyo Tower.
You're an idiot.
Come on! Do it with me!
Tokyo Tower!
- Tokyo Tower!
- You, too! Tokyo Tower!
Tokyo Tower.
Tokyo, why do we have to go to you?
You come to us!
Come to Okinawa!
Nishi-Nippori, right? Gotanda, right?
- Where's that?
- Or Otsuka!
- You're such a hick.
- See you!
Let's get sushi at Ginza!
- Whatever!
- In your dreams!
Tokyo, huh?
This is serious stuff.
Are you going to tell
your American girlfriend, Lisa?
- About Tokyo.
- What?
It's a good chance to ask her out.
"I want you."
Cut it out, idiot.
No, I'm serious.
Well...
I'll ask her out when we take Tokyo.
Wow, I didn't expect that from you.
You surprised me.
You've got to start with a kiss, right?
Right in her face.
Oh, shut up.
And she'll whimper, "Oh, Shinji..."
Somebody call an ambulance!
Hurry!
Daiki!
Are you Mrs Maeshiro?
- Yes.
- This way.
Ryota.
Ryota! You're OK!
Thank goodness.
I'm so relieved.
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?
What are you talking about?
It's me, Shinji.
Amnesia?
Yes. The trauma of the incident
has caused some impairment to his memory.
I don't know you.
Get your hands off me!
Where are you taking me?
Hey...
You're just pulling my leg, right?
You are, aren't you?
Huh? What are you babbling about?
What's with you?
You really don't remember?
Me?
Our band?
Get in here.
Do you remember?
Remember what?
You don't recognise this place?
Should I?
What is this about?
Look.
Here!
- Yo.
Hey.
- Later.
- Bye.
- See you.
You're early.
- Ryota came up with the lyrics.
- Lyrics?
For the song I wrote yesterday.
Shinji, let's change the chorus.
To "I'd die to see you."
- "I'd die to see you?"
- Yeah.
Try it.
I'd die to see you
Die to see you
Better?
- I like it.
- Let's do it.
Yeah.
I don't believe you.
OK. Look over there.
Do you see it?
See what?
Our view from the stage.
Let's rock this place.
Ura High Courtyard Live
Oh yeah, we changed that part.
You're nervous.
- Hey, Ryota.
- Hey.
- What are you playing?
- An original.
Seriously? An original?
It'll blow you away. Just wait and see.
- Good luck!
- You'd better get pumped!
- Yeah, man!
Ryota.
One, two, three!
Come on...
When you were so kind to me
I learnt how small I really am
Ashamed for ever doubting you
You've made a believer out of me
The days flow by so quickly
I drift in an ever-changing world
But one thing that won't budge
Is my love for you
So don't you cry, my dearest
There's joy in the anguish of love
Before you know it, you will see
Just how much you mean to me
More today than yesterday we'll be
Before you know it, in my arms
I'd die to see you
Die to see you
We won everyone's hearts
with that first gig.
I knew from that one show
that we found our place.
How could you possibly forget
something so important?
Yeah! That's awesome!
You guys rock. You really do.
And I don't say that to just anyone.
Ever!
Mr Nema said that
and introduced us
to a Tokyo record label.
You say that, but I don't remember...
Come on!
You can't possibly have
forgotten it all!
All the time we spent making it happen.
Fine.
So I guess we're friends, then?
- Sorry, I forgot.
- Not just friends!
You and I aren't just friends!
We're a band.
Hi.
You're Shinji's sister, right?
And Shinji?
What's he doing now?
Wait a second.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- On the rocks?
- That's fine.
OK. Enjoy.
Is Ryota in?
Ryota! Shinji's here!
Sorry. No response.
- That's Okay.
- Oh, sorry!
Ryota.
- Let's go.
- Where to?
- You'll see.
- What?
I thought we were going to your place.
Lisa.
Hi, Ryota.
I ran into her on the way over.
We meet here a lot.
At this fence?
She hasn't been on
this side of the fence.
What do you do here?
What?
What did he say?
What do you do here?
Us?
Yes.
Shinji lets me listen to his songs.
Songs?
Yeah, like this.
Through the ear buds.
Across international borders!
- What?
- I mean...
This is Okinawa
that's an American military base.
You're crossing national lines!
Not physically.
I know, but...
You make an interesting couple.
Shinji.
This song... did you write this too?
Yes.
I think you should
tell Lisa you like her.
Say "I want you!"
I know.
Invite her to our next gig.
The school festival!
That would be the perfect chance, right?
Hey...
What do you say?
Listen.
It's not funny.
You idiot.
I'm sorry.
Why have you forgotten?
I said, I'm sorry.
Hell.
I wish you'd remember.
I really wish you'd remember.
My bad.
My god.
What's up? What's wrong?
Shinji...
I'm glad.
I'm really glad.
Call an ambulance! Hurry!
Shinji...
Shinji!
Hey... come on, Shinji!
Are you OK?
In highly stressful situations
the mind can suppress certain memories
as a form of self-defence.
To prevent further trauma
from recalling the stressful event.
It can't be.
I'm glad.
I'm so glad you're safe.
Don't say that, Shinji.
You can't forget us, OK?
You made our band complete.
You put lyrics
to my songs and gave them life.
You can't forget any of that.
Hold on a second.
Tell me this isn't happening.
You know what, Ryota?
Being in a band with you
was the best thing in my life.
Stop it!
I'll never forgive you if you do this!
I'm so glad.
I'm glad you finally remember.
Shinji, stop saying that! Don't go!
- Wait!
- See you around, Ryota.
Shinji, no!
Shinji!
Okinawa police are still
looking for clues
in the fatal hit-and-run
of a high school student on the 3rd...
They're following up on a witness report
that it was a
US military base vehicle...
The central government
is investigating the case
through its foreign ministry.
The perpetrator has still
not been found.
Meanwhile, citizen groups have begun
protests around the military base...
Ryota suffered only minor injuries.
I think he has been discharged.
I see.
I still can't believe it.
Daiki has joined another band
so he can play in the school festival.
Bassists are in great demand.
And you?
What will you do?
I was in the band...
because I love those guys.
Ryota!
Answer me when I call you.
Are your ears stuffed with wax?
It's Kotaro again.
He has been calling all morning.
Oh, he hung up.
Here.
Have you picked up your soul?
Your grandma thinks it got left
at the scene of the incident.
You need to go retrieve it.
This is important!
Yeah, all right.
Your soul, huh...
Stop kowtowing to the US military!
Shinji will not rest in peace!
Ryota!
How about this?
Maybe she came to do the same thing.
Retrieve Shinji's soul.
I'm home.
You're back.
Any word from the police?
They're dithering.
How hard can it be to
track down the driver?
They're dragging their heels.
The driver must be
someone from the base.
You don't know that!
But if it's true, what will you do?
Can you continue working there?
We'll cross that bridge
when we get there.
You need to prepare yourself.
I mean, if it's true
you can't return to the base, can you?
Can you change jobs so
you don't have to go?
I said...
we don't know anything yet.
There's no point thinking about it.
According to eyewitness testimony
the getaway vehicle had a Y number plate
of a vehicle from the US military base.
In response,
local residents have gathered
in protest outside the Kerana Air Base
near the site of the accident.
The fugitive remains at large
but as a
military connection is suspected
we urge all military personnel to...
I hope it wasn't one of us.
This hit-and-run case.
If this were really true
we'd all leave them a bad impression.
Just because of one rotten apple.
We could even be restricted to the base.
Right?
The MPs are investigating.
- Right?
- Yeah.
Well, I guess it's not as easy
as it could be back home.
Hope we can go back soon...
Lisa, dinner's ready!
Untitled
Hey.
Do you have a minute?
What is this about?
I found this song
on my brother's laptop.
What is this?
I think it was his new song.
I've never heard it before.
You know all of your brother's songs?
So... what about it?
I want you to play this song.
Play it? Why?
It'd be a shame if this song
goes unheard.
Who's going to play it?
Let's do it, Ryota.
We'll play it.
We? What are you talking about?
We don't have a guitarist or a bassist.
We'll find a guitarist.
Like who?
Everyone's busy with the festival.
There's no one left.
You play the guitar?
Daiki!
Daiki.
Shinji...
Shinji had written a new song.
Let's do it together. One more time.
- What do you mean?
- Never mind. Just come!
Wait! I can't!
What are you saying?
I've already joined Kengo's band.
Sorry, but still...
No buts.
The festival is coming up soon.
I joined late...
so I have to rehearse
like crazy to catch up.
I can't join you.
Oh, where did Ryota go?
Ryota... Ryota!
Sing! I want you to sing!
Ryota!
- Ryota...
- I can't!
I sing with my heart.
I sang Don't Worry, Be Happy
to cheer everyone up.
I can't sing it if I don't feel it!
I bare my soul when I sing.
Everyone will know if I fake it!
I can't...
I can't even imagine singing right now!
I envy you.
You just have to wave
your drumsticks around.
How dare you!
You!
Idiot!
You have no idea
what I'm going through!
Right back at you!
We have to do this!
Who else will, if not us?
How can you act like
everything's normal?
I do it for Shinji!
Shinji's dead!
If you don't sing for him, nobody will!
Ouch.
What are you looking at?
I was thinking, all it takes is a swing.
An awesome thing it is, that swing.
Shinji.
I heard your song.
What do you think?
You're awesome too.
It's a really good tune.
Yeah?
Did you play it for her?
For who?
- Lisa.
- Of course not.
Not before you've put lyrics to it.
In that case...
I'll make it a love song.
A love song?
Why not?
You?
Shut up.
I'll write a killer love song.
Just you wait.
A love song so good
you can use it to ask Lisa out
and get a kiss from her.
Stop it.
- Nice.
- Great, huh?
Yeah.
Here, I'm right beside you
Like a loved one ought to be
With a little love song
Delivered to your ears only
Ryota?
Ryota.
Ryota, is that you?
Oh, I didn't expect to see you here.
Hi.
How are you?
Good.
Well...
Actually, I was hoping
to tell you something.
Tell me.
I'm leaving Okinawa.
Soon.
Leaving?
Yeah.
In...
one month, I think?
My father is transferring.
Transfer?
Transferring.
We're going back to the States.
Back to America.
I see.
Shinji had asked me
to come see your band play.
Shinji did?
I'd have been able to see you sing too
if I had gone.
It's too bad.
OK then.
Come!
Come to gakusai!
The school festival.
What?
I'm singing.
I'm singing Shinji's song.
His song's great.
So, I'm singing.
You're sure it's one month, right?
- Yeah.
- Please come!
Really?
OK... I'll be there!
I'm sorry.
Please be our guitarist.
I'll have to play bass.
I'm 17.
Really?
Mum.
Let me borrow this.
Hey, wait.
I think she's adorable.
I approve.
What? She's Shinji's sister.
- I'm taking this.
- Oh, sure.
Kotaro.
Let's go.
Ouch.
Hey!
Hit-and-Run Investigation Hits A Snag
Citizens Protest at US Base
Mr Nema!
Hey.
A girl?
Then do this...
Thank you.
A three-piece band, huh? Cool.
- Really?
- Really.
I didn't know his little sister plays.
Mai, hit the pedal.
Too loud.
First time on an amplifier?
You can strum now.
That should work.
Hold on.
You know all of Shinji's songs?
Show us.
Good... good!
Real good.
I need to buck up.
Tell me, Ryota.
How did the three of you get together?
My brother's song...
For the school festival.
Yeah, we're performing. The three of us.
- No way!
- Does the teacher know?
You're telling me this now?
Listen. We've already drafted the setlist.
Every band has been assigned a slot
and are rehearsing their songs.
Isn't that right, Ms Moromiri?
Well, yes, but...
So...
we can play if the
other bands are okay with it?
Is that what you're saying?
Please! Just this once!
I guess it's OK.
Really?
Hey, are you guys going to do
something crazy again?
We won't. I promise!
Do you mean it?
- Yeah...
- Thank you!
- Okay..
OK, guys. Let's shorten our set
so they can perform.
Thanks, guys!
Thank you all.
- Hi.
You know...
I thought you were Shinji.
There's a guitar on your back.
I started playing the guitar
and I joined a band.
A band?
Ryota's band?
Really?
Great! That's... awesome!
So, it's you!
You're playing with Ryota
at the school festival.
Yeah, the school festival.
School festival... it will be
great!
So, please come.
OK!
Hey, Mai.
This song? Ryota said that
you guys will be playing this song.
- Yeah.
- You're playing this song, right?
This song is my favourite...
of Shinji's songs.
It's my favourite.
Maybe Ryota knew.
By the way, what's the song about?
About?
About...
- Love?
Like?
What's koi in English?
- Small love.
- Small love?
Small, small love.
Lisa!
Oh, I have to go.
- I should...
- Okay..
- See you!
- See you.
- Who is that?
- Nothing.
What were you talking about?
- Nothing!
- Lisa, wait!
You're aware we've
been restricted to the base.
The protests at the gate... it's serious.
Listen! There are people out there
that don't think well of us.
You need to be careful!
Lisa!
Go back! No base!
No Osprey! Protect our children!
Protect our future!
An angry crowd has gathered
protesting loudly in front of the police
guarding the base.
The incident occurred
near the Kerana Base on the 14th.
Protesters clashed with the police
who were there to disperse them.
A protestor was knocked down...
Oh, you're home.
What's going on?
The Okinawa Defence Bureau
held a press conference.
What's with all the protests?
Wait, was the hit-and-run driver
someone from the military base?
We don't know yet.
What will they gain
by turning their anger at the base?
Their anger is misdirected.
What should they do then?
Mai.
Are you studying hard?
Keep your grades up
and get into a good university
on the mainland.
When you've experienced life outside
you'll understand the issues
that plague this tiny island.
You'll see that nothing has changed.
That's why you've got to study hard.
Another beautiful Sunday morning
Start of a day both short and long
I've got nothing on my schedule
Think I'll take a walk about town
OK, stop!
Mai, your playing sounds listless.
Is something wrong?
I can hear it in your music.
You can tell us if
anything's bothering you.
Yeah, that's what we are here for.
You're talking sense for once, Ryota.
Right?
Don't get carried away.
- Again!
- All right!
One, two, three, four!
Yeah.
I'm so excited.
You have it good.
Stop... stop!
Bass is going too fast, Ryota.
I'm moving the song along.
No, follow my drums.
But you have no sense of rhythm.
How's practice?
So hard!
And we need lyrics.
What?
Mai.
I think I know why Roosevelt
chose this island.
I bet everybody here
used to all be really nice.
Have you been to other base
in another country?
Yeah.
Because we usually move
like every two years.
But we already bought
a house in Florida.
Florida?
Yeah. We're going to live there
once my father retires.
Many families buy a house
a place they like
while they move around.
I should go.
My parents will be home soon.
OK.
Mai...
My father works on Ospreys.
Are you against Ospreys?
I don't know.
Sorry...
No. Don't worry.
Can you really come?
To the school festival.
Yes. I'm coming.
- See you there.
- See you.
So, did you hear about the rumours?
The one about the Y-plate
running over the Japanese kid?
What the hell is the
Japanese police doing?
I don't know, man, but they need to
get the restrictions lifted
because I can't stand it.
Yeah, I wanna go surfing, man.
Tell me about it. I can't stand it.
Sweet little thing.
What are you doing over here?
Hey, kid.
You all right?
Looking for someone?
One, two...
Hey, one, two.
Mr Nema, turn it up a little more, please.
OK.
Hey, one, two...
Hey, check, one, two.
Hey... one, two.
Check, one, two.
All right, good to go.
OK. Thank you.
Mr Nema.
- A live gig tonight?
- Yeah.
The band members are
outside taking a break.
You guys can take the stage.
Really?
Let's go.
OK, guys.
Let's see how you sound.
May we?
- Let's play.
- Yeah.
Hey, welcome back.
- Thanks.
- We're back.
Sorry, give them five.
What?
You like being on stage, don't you?
I'd die to see you
Die to see you
Play a song.
I'll record it for you.
Which song?
- That one?
What's "that one"?
Don't Worry, of course.
OK.
One, two, three, four!
Don't worry
Be happy
It's my life
They're good.
Another beautiful Sunday morning
Start of a day both short and long
I've got nothing on my schedule
Think I'll take a walk about town
Under a crystal clear blue sky
Even the sun seems in the way
The two of us, a happy lunch time
Love and stomachs set to full
Well? What do you think?
They're really good.
- Yeah?
- Awesome.
That makes me happy.
I like these kids.
- Hey...
- Welcome back.
- Listen to this.
- What is it?
These kids rock.
Let me see.
They're playing at a school festival.
Come see them.
- Give me one.
- Of course.
Oh, Mr Nema.
I went to this high school.
- You're alumni?
- Yeah.
Go support them.
I'll put this up at my store.
- Really? Hold on.
- Give me some.
I was hoping you'd say that. Thanks.
I'll pass them out too.
Support your juniors.
Mum?
You're not coming to
the school festival, right?
Why? Why are you asking?
No reason. It'll be boring.
We don't want to show up
and cast a gloom over the event.
OK. See you later.
Have a good day in school.
Oh, Mai?
Your father...
will probably quit his job at the base.
We don't know if the driver is American
but your dad can't
take off work anymore.
But don't worry.
He has the qualifications.
I'm sure he'll find work quickly.
OK.
- Got to go.
- See you.
18th Ura High School Festival
Welcome!
Shaved ice, please!
That was fun!
We're not done and don't hit me!
I thought we were.
Snap!
Enough with the selfies!
After riding the roller coaster...
Where are you going?
- The theme centre.
- Okay.
- Dad?
- Yeah?
Have you gone off the base recently?
Off base?
You do know we've been restricted
to the base, right?
Sure, but it's been lifted.
Well, I...
still don't think it's a
good idea just yet.
Sometimes, even a small incident
could lead to something much bigger.
- Dad...
- Yeah?
Do you think that it's better that we...
you know, try to get along
with the local people?
Honey, of course.
But in reality
some things aren't so simple.
So, we just do
what we're assigned to do here.
I'll just...
Is it true we can't perform?
It's not fair.
Why can't we perform?
Look at this.
It's all over the Internet.
That's us.
The school got flooded with calls
from people asking if we're playing.
So the teachers got wind of it.
Explain yourselves!
Outside activities are forbidden!
- We were just...
- You're mistaken.
Mistaken?
How do you explain this then?
"Breaking band's debut concert"!
You're using the
school festival to debut?
What? Who made this?
I don't know.
But we've got nothing to do with this.
The teachers are
too mad to listen to us.
There you are, guys!
This is going to be your big break.
The band you met at
the studio the other day
posted a clip of you jamming online
and now it has gone viral.
The people I've shown it to
are all blown away by you guys.
So I told them about your festival gig
and word got around.
Today's going to be a big day for you.
Huge!
I kept running out of leaflets...
Yeah, that's the one.
I'm the one who made this leaflet.
What's wrong?
So, you just need a ride, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Power's on, Shinzato!
OK, plug in this cord.
OK!
- I'm counting on you.
- Okay!
Is this OK for you?
Yeah. Thank you.
We're ready here.
- Thanks.
- Good luck.
This is all I can do for you.
You're on your own now.
Are you sure about this?
Of course!
I saw the video.
To be honest...
it really made me regret leaving the band.
But...
the three of you make an awesome band!
Go kick some butt, yeah?
ID, please.
You see that?
I know it's pay day
just try not to have
too much fun out there.
I'm just a driver for my niece today.
Miss, ID?
Just don't drink, all right?
Half the guys in Camp Hansen
are in there for drinking.
I hear you. And the other half
is there for women, right?
All right.
Peace to Okinawa!
Go home!
Go home... go home!
OK. You guys ready?
I wonder if Lisa's here?
I hope so!
Mic test, mic test.
We have a song. Hope you like it.
In a corner of vast space
On a world resplendent blue
Faint feelings of love
Come delivered...
- Isn't that live?
- To you
Now that I have met you
Has the concert started?
The time just rushes by
The rhythm of two hearts
Beating happy, beating sad
Reverberating far as it can go
A gentle song
To change the world
Here, I'm right beside you
Like a loved one ought to be
With just a little love song
Delivered to your ears only
Here
Feel that, my little love song
You came to realise
I'm walking by your side
On streets plunged into night
We're lit by pure moonlight
Hand in hand, we depart
We can't be pulled apart
A love so strong
It vows to last forever
And if we reach the edge
Of eternity we'll pledge
The words of love
That keep us tied together
But if words are not enough
Tears and joy will be the stuff
And we'll just embrace each other
We'll just embrace each other
Here, I'm right beside you
Like a loved one ought to be
With just a little love song
Delivered to your ears only
Feel that, my little love song
Here
If it's all a dream, don't wake me
If it's all a dream, don't wake me!
Our time together will
Become an shining star
Here, I'm right beside you
Like a loved one ought to be
With just a little love song
Delivered to your ears only
Feel that, my little love song
Here, I'm right beside you
Like a loved one ought to be
With just a little love song
Delivered to your ears only
Feel that, my little love song
Here
One more!
One, two, three, four!
Don't worry
Be happy
It's my life
Another beautiful Sunday morning...
It got cut off. Why?
Must be a malfunction.
Where were you trying to go?
I spoke with the sergeant too.
I could tell he was really
just trying to help you out.
Why did you want to go off the base?
Is it something you
can't even share with us?
You know about the protest outside.
Did I tell you? The other day
I caught her speaking with someone
through the fence!
Your car, being surrounded
and blocked by protestors...
You were about to be pulled into a mess!
I am already!
Lisa!
You're suspended for two weeks.
Suspended?
I was hoping he'd at least
get through high school.
It's not expulsion, ma'am.
It's just a suspension.
We tell our son to follow his heart
so we don't mind, but...
Stand up.
We apologise for his
influence on your child.
Come on!
Apologise.
It's all right.
My son probably put them up to it.
We're sorry.
Our apologies.
I'm sorry.
It'll be a learning experience.
Stop grinning, kids.
Are you really sorry about this?
What are you chuckling about?
What am I going to do with you?
Dear! Stop!
What are you doing?
Dear! Stop that!
Don't...
Wait!
No!
Dear!
Playing music at a time like this...
What's the matter with you?
Why did you do that, dear?
How dare you!
Have you even listened
to a song Shinji wrote?
Have you ever seen him perform?
He was really good, you know.
He was amazing.
What he did was way more important
than just getting good grades.
His music moved a lot of people.
But you have no idea, do you?
Music can teach you a lot about life.
I learnt that from Shinji.
Not from you, Dad.
Shinji was the one who taught me
everything that really mattered!
What do I do now?
Business is really bad.
Now that the Americans aren't coming
will we have to shut down?
Silly boy.
We've been through this before.
So many times...
I lost count.
Here, I'm right beside you
Like a loved one ought to be
It's your song, right?
It's a good song.
Hey.
Oh, Mr Matsumura!
Your son's taking over?
He's still in school.
- Just helping out today.
- I see.
You're a good boy.
Good luck.
You don't have to, you know.
Become a fisherman like me, I mean.
You can be what you want.
It's a farewell doll.
Farewell doll?
It's sold on the base.
Soldiers get transferred a lot, right?
So when they leave
they write messages
on these for each other.
Dear Mai, Ryota, Kotaro
I'm leaving Okinawa
sooner than expected.
It's a really short time
but I'm really glad I could
come to Okinawa
to meet you guys.
Even though I'm really sad that
I couldn't see you guys play.
I remember Shinji had taught me
an Okinawan expression.
Do you know "ichariba-chode"?
Icha...
- Ichariba...
- Chode.
- Chode?
Yes.
What does it mean?
Once we meet...
we're family.
I love this expression!
Life is a journey.
I was only on this island
by chance this time
but I'll come again
next time to see you guys.
With a passport.
See you again.
Until then... bye.
Mai: I wrote a song.
Mai.
Can guitars be repaired?
Don't bother.
No. I want to fix it.
I want to fix your guitar
New song?
We want to record it.
And give it to Lisa.
Along with the rest of our songs.
I see.
Is the new song all finished?
Yes.
OK, I got it. Let's do it.
Listen, do you want to play a gig?
I'll get you the space.
My amends for the other day.
I'll pay for everything.
But you're suspended, right?
Forget it.
What am I saying? You're suspended.
I'll only get you into more trouble.
No.
I'd love to.
Me, too.
A band has to play live.
That's true. You're right.
Let's do it!
Include this song too.
What are you doing?
Sorry, ma'am. We'll be done soon.
Sorry.
Hey!
Ready to go!
Maybe she's gone.
Mai... Mai!
Mai!
Ryota! Kotaro!
Lisa.
My brother left a song.
What?
We named it Sayonara Doll.
We'll play one song for you.
Please listen.
OK.
I had a dream
A long, long dream
Long ago on this very island
I met you and fell in love
Like Romeo and Juliet
We were caught in a forbidden romance
As the world battled around us
We nurtured love in a dance
Reality's unfair, borders
And language raise walls
Over which love leaps in a bound
Those who profit from conflict
Leave only pain and malice
Spears raised aloft
The weak as their shield
Feeding like flies on the peace
But never forget our island
And this sea
Over ages and lifetimes and then
Never forget the song we sang
And the promise
That we'll meet again one day
Over ages and lifetimes and then
I had a dream
A long, long dream
I had a buddy
who loved music.
If he were here
he'd tell us to kick it up a notch!
So here we go!
Everybody...
sing!
When you were so kind to me
I learnt how small I really am
Ashamed for ever doubting you
You've made a believer out of me
The days flow by so quickly
I drift in an ever-changing world
But one thing that won't budge
Is my love for you
So don't you cry, my dearest
There's joy in the anguish of love
Before you know it, you will see
Just how much you mean to me
More today than yesterday we'll be
Before you know it, in my arms
I'd die to see you
Die to see you
On a sleepless night
I await you in my dreams
I'm thinking so hard
I just can't fall asleep
But when I see you there
You ask, "Where shall we go?"
But as long as you're with me
I don't really care
I'd die to see you
Die to see you
The time will pass us by
The seasons will depart
In a world as this
We strive to understand
Who we're meant to trust
Who we're meant to walk with
So will you take my hand?
Little Love Song