Look at me.
When we go inside, you
just listen to your cousin.
Mm-hmm.
'Cause you'll be
the boss one day.
What's wrong?
Those people?
Those people are waiting for us.
For what?
We'll clean up the neighborhood.
- All of this?
- Yup.
But not like janitors,
more like Superman.
- Dad.
- Like Batman.
Like-
Like the Guardian Angels.
Yeah, like Guardian Angels.
'Cause there are two things,
best things for a man:
provide
and protect.
And I'll protect you.
Always.
Pavel.
Vlad.
The people outside.
Hello Uncle.
Speak English now, Pavel.
- Where they speak English?
- American.
He forget all of his Russian.
It's always the same.
How long you gonna
keep this shit up?
Maxim, show Daniel
closing rounds, hmm?
Now Pavel, what is this?
What is what?
That ugly thing.
It's new sign.
- That's not a sign.
- This is Yuri.
He cooks and shit.
Sometimes all at once.
English, shithead.
Daniel, meet the animals.
You wanna get your
fat ass kicked again?
Pick that up.
Ooh, I'm telling.
Still short!
Let's go.
Muah.
Yes, baby.
Come on.
Suka.
- Yes.
Vlad, be quick with that shit.
Yes, yes.
Quick, okay.
Okay, okay. Time
to go.
What I have said?
Let's go.
Come on, come on.
Okay, come on.
C'mon.
Why are we here?
But we paid on time, right?
Yes.
Checking up on Amerikashka.
Your uncle make
good money with us.
Good?
For peasants.
I'm here to make great.
But we made our payments, right?
And then what is your
concern beyond that?
Vlad, Vlad.
Maybe Mr. Ivan have good idea.
Nostrovya.
Pull up your drawers,
boys and girls.
Five minutes.
You ready?
Okay.
I was born ready.
The line is: "I was born ready."
Geesh.
Hey, what's the opposite of fun?
You mean the antonym?
It's Daniel.
Yay, Danetchka.
Your new name is Auntie Nim.
Daniel-san.
Yes, a crane
technique if do write.
No can defense.
- Nostrovya.
Tomorrow, I throw party here.
What party?
After hours.
$700, your cut.
Bullshit.
Who keep junkies and Italians
from shake you down, huh?
We are partners.
We're nothing.
Ah, Maxim.
You check everything?
Oh, we have a visitor.
Come here.
Come.
Looks just like you, Pavel.
A gift
for my partner's son.
Please open it.
Open it.
Go ahead.
Put it in your hand.
Feel the weight.
Knife was used.
Sorry, I clean.
Like new.
Leave him alone!
Daniel!
Daniel.
Get the car.
Shut the fuck up.
You know, funding
should be a portion
according to the needs
of the district, right?
Now we need affordable housing
in my district this cycle.
If we go into that room
sounding like Karl
Marx's cliff notes,
then we're gonna need
new jobs in November.
Now you all know Mr.
Dan Reznick Esquire
from the Newark Works employment
outreach in my district?
Hammer of the gods.
I'm sorry?
Well you're 3/5
of the city council.
You have Mayor
Apple gate at your mercy.
Okay, so how's that gonna help
to get affordable
housing in my district?
Well respectfully,
this is already one of the
most affordable communities
in the county.
Right.
So then why do I have
four overflown shelters
in my district?
Many of the people in those
shelters were my clients.
Hmm, I get it.
So you'll agree then?
We just need to stick
our heels in the dirt,
build affordable homes while
there's still HUD money.
Our friends at those shelters
wouldn't have a problem
finding affordable homes
if we could fix their
problem finding employment.
I like where you're goin'.
Bras tacks.
Brass tacks?
You form a voting block
on the HUD allocation.
Promise Mayor Apple gate
smooth sailing
on the downtown
development if and only if
you control the resident
employment allocations.
Mm-hmm, see?
Trade votes for higher
paying jobs in our districts.
How many jobs?
Well fast and dirty?
With a maintenance contract
guarantee tacked on,
I'd say at least 300 jobs
in the first six months.
Hire them
right outta the shelter.
I took the liberty
to begin drafting a bid
and the hiring
practices guidelines
for your review of course.
Counselor, flip me your card.
I have a few good constituents
that could use help
staying in their homes.
I'm not practicing
at the moment.
Oh, well I expect
we'll see a lot of you.
Keep up the fight.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Yes?
They're comin'.
When?
24 to 42 hours from now.
But I told 'em that
I would go to them.
I know,
but they don't want that.
So what do they want?
They wanna
make an example of you
in your home.
Am I just supposed to take that?
Listen to me.
Get your wife and your
family outta your house now.
I'm sorry.
How are you?
Good see you tonight.
Me?
Fucking great.
Good week. Pretty, pretty good.
You know, my offer still stands.
Crazy we still do this.
I work this week.
You work next.
Either one of us own
only half business.
At least sit down with me.
I make you fair offer: buy
out your half of the business.
Until next week.
Yo, what the fuck you
doin' out here, white boy?
Nice rims.
I could sneak up on
Snowden in this shit.
Oh yeah. Yeah, definitely.
Conflict minerals sure
are stealthy in that.
Fuck I tell you about this shit?
I do need that bread, man.
Three months.
Um.
Fuck you, man.
Fuck you.
Ah come on, man.
Yo, the council boy's doin'
you all right down the way?
Yeah, I don't have
the formal approval yet.
But I'm tellin' you I
got these guys right-
Listen, listen, listen.
I told you you supposed
to call me, all right?
I told you call me.
C'mon, let's go.
I knew all about
your little meeting.
No coincidences, huh?
Shit.
This is my town.
It was a no-brainer for them.
I did all the work.
I wrote the proposal.
I drew up the playbook.
Did you tell the councilwoman
that you got disbarred?
No.
No, I was suspended.
Not disbarred.
Same thing. Shit
came up anyway.
When?
Right after you left.
I just got the play by play.
Well you know, it's a
matter of public record.
It looks like a reason for them
to shift this grant money
in another direction.
You mean all this
work for nothin'?
No.
They'll use your playbook
but probably without you.
Yeah. And if I
raise the stake,
they just tossed the whole thing
and nothing good
comes out of it.
Catchin' on quick, son.
Fuck, man.
They'd be walkin' to City Hall
with their tail between their
legs if it weren't for me.
You're right.
Listen, I told you, all right?
You ain't from around here.
Your shit wasn't
gonna go any farther
than what you could
already finance on your own
unless you had a born
and bred on board.
Born and bred?
Like who?
Me, for one.
You?
You wanna be in the
job placement business?
No.
I wanna be in the Daniel
Reznick business, son.
Fuck outta here.
Listen.
People in this
community, they love you.
They love you in
this neighborhood.
You've been helpin'
people for years and years
for no other reason but
just because they need it.
Shit.
And I know that a nice
little Jewish boy like you
don't mess up no bill payments.
So you got to be fucked up
if I'm sittin' here waitin'
on three months rent.
I told you I was gonna take
care of that this weekend.
I know, I know.
You can go home and run
to your pops and get that.
But what I'm saying-
- Really?
- Listen, what I'm sayin'.
What I'm offering
is a chance for you to
get out on your own.
Get you some of
that grant money.
Get you a nice little
six-figure salary,
your little office and
your rent paid for,
electricity paid for.
What's in it for you?
My name already ring
out in the streets.
A restaurateur or producer,
real estate magnate.
But with you?
I am going to be Newark's
homegrown savior of District 6.
I'm in charge.
That's fine.
Listen, I just wanna
make a few calls
and give you a big enough
lane to run right through.
So?
Make your calls.
My man, my man.
Yeah, just listen.
You're just gonna godfather
this thing through, right?
I don't do well
with partnerships.
Oh, this ain't no
partnership, see?
We gon' Batman and Robin
this motherfucker.
Go home, D.
10 minutes and I'm out.
It's gonna be too big.
Oh.
This I like.
Think so?
Absolutely.
Thank you.
You look good to me.
It's beautiful.
Can't take your eyes off?
Really will match perfectly
with the living room set
in our new house in the country.
Bid 95.
Thank you.
Are you familiar with
von Ostrowski or Serrano?
It's very important.
Yes, I remember.
Von Ostrowski worked
in fecal matter.
Like Ofili, right?
Right, but he also
worked in ejaculate.
Sorry?
He use it as a glaze
in some of his painting.
Oh.
Actually the influence
runs throughout this show.
Maybe we should-
It'll change color as it ages.
Yes, with a wonderful
organic patina.
That might not work.
We're gonna take a look
at a few other pieces
before we decide.
Sure.
Take your time.
Not a word, Maxim.
15K.
That's some money shot.
Egg whites.
Liar, liar.
I only told them influence.
Expensive pomposity, cousin.
Nate Dogg, you catch that?
I'll need five minutes
alone with him.
You just love rejection.
That old Jack is ready to sell.
This time it's real.
He's meeting me tomorrow.
I need 3 maybe 4 million
from Nathan, tops.
Oh, that's all?
Fuck.
And when you figure they'll
be finished over there?
First part of the
Market Line, 2019.
That soon, huh?
The high line meets
Italy via Brooklyn Fleet
but more upscale.
And at the base of a couple
hundred thousand square feet
of the hottest condos in town.
Okay and our targets, where
are the current rents at now?
It's in the gutter.
I'll work these
buildings like a maniac.
I'll evict the
non-payees, the non-B&Bers
and relocate the stragglers.
That's a tall order.
I'm gonna make 'em an
offer they can't refuse.
Can we do that?
I've worked this with a
few of Mr. W's buildings.
I know the tenants.
I know who's a deadbeat,
who's a drug dealer,
which little old lady's
ready to move to Florida.
All right, so how long 'til
we can clear them all out?
A year, 18 months tops.
What's the catch?
You're getting an amazing price.
The pricing is the by-product
of a decade of
indentured servitude.
All right.
I need a quick
answer for the old man
before he has time
to reconsider.
Do I have a partner?
15 million?
When can you get a copy
of the PPM to my attorney?
Next week.
Not a problem.
Come by, we'll have a drink.
This guy.
Don't scare me like that.
I'm sorry.
Look, Vlad. One,
two, three, four.
Four place settings.
- Right.
- I just set the table.
Right.
I'll be back at 2:00.
Da, da.
You're a good boy.
Always happy.
I try my best.
Those three walk ups on
Delancey, you got your price?
12.
12 million is a gift
for those three buildings.
Of course, keep
it in the family.
Boychik, I gotta know
you got the money, hmm?
Two weeks, I got 100 brokers
chasing me down the street.
I'll get you proof
of funds by tomorrow.
Good.
Now go hump something
young tonight, hmm?
My dick hasn't worked
since the 1980s
and you're not getting
any younger yourself.
Moshe! Yeah, you.
Bring my shoes.
Unc, everything all right?
Yeah.
I got the TV for her room.
She'll be real comfortable.
Look.
I'm usually in the old
neighborhood in the mornings,
so I can pop in on Pavel
and check in on things.
Sasha, just make sure she
takes her pills every day.
Sasha.
I was just thinking.
I know you don't like me there,
but Pavel needs someone
checkin' on him.
No, no, no.
Police!
Put your hands up!
I'm teachin' at Rutgers
again this semester.
Yeah. With Amtrak,
it's really easy.
So I promise we'll make
it happen this time.
Hit one of those
Rodezio spots on me.
Where's his head?
He's good.
You know, considering, right?
What're we lookin' at?
Daniel, you know I can't.
Okay.
Thanks.
You got it.
Mr. Reznick.
Look, don't talk details.
He's been in solitary
the last three days,
so just be together.
'Kay.
Just one?
15 minutes.
You look good.
Yeah.
Yeah, you too.
And you're going to
see your mother tonight.
Yeah.
Good. That's great.
Dad-
Yeah, just tell
her that I'm strong.
I'm good. Everything is fine.
And you'll take care of
her while I'm here, right?
Of course.
Your Uncle Sasha will
be there for a week.
Dad, what happened?
I'd like to ask you.
What happened with you?
I didn't know.
I was in Newark.
I'm helping someone.
Well you're in Newark.
You're always in Newark
with those junkies
running like crazy.
They're not and I'm fine.
What happened this time?
A little boy almost died.
Oh, sorry.
So you're a doctor now?
No, they need my help.
Can you help?
- Yes.
- Like an attorney.
Well not in this instance, no.
But you are an attorney.
Well uh, the thing I wanted to-
I can't hear you, Daniel.
I got suspended.
You got suspended.
My license to practice law.
For how long?
Three years.
For how long didn't you tell me?
Let me walk the
streets like an idiot.
Dad, I was gonna tell you.
I tried to so many times.
How long did you?
- Six months.
- How come?
I was doin' the right thing.
You're not an attorney anymore.
Not for three years.
I was thinking this is
the time when I need my son,
the big shot lawyer to help me,
to protect me.
And instead, you're
helping those people.
Dad, those people needed me.
I needed you.
What happened?
Doesn't matter.
Telly will take care of this.
- I can help.
- No.
- That's why I'm here.
- No, Daniel.
Listen, all I want you is
to take care of your mother.
I can help.
And Maxim will take care
of my week at the banya.
- Maxim?
- Yes.
Why Maxim? I'm your son.
And you have to see Anielka.
- Ani?
- Yes, Ani.
Ani, she's been taking
care of your mother.
If you want me to
look at your account-
No.
'Kay, just gimme
five more minutes.
Come on!
Kid.
You all right?
Yeah.
Oh, Prince Danetchka!
Sit, sit, sit.
We miss you so much.
Law degree like 100,000.
He practice seven years.
Shit, that's like 300%
return on investment
before they revoke license.
Dad, enough.
What?
Just like when I
get credit card,
buy thousands worth
of stuff, hmm?
Throw card away, report stolen.
Can't keep forever.
What?
Hit up the Koreans
last week in Coney.
Hey Kostya, where you been?
- At the Sweet Shop?
- What happened?
What happened to the inspector?
Hey.
The sidewalk may
crumble under foot.
Ani?
She's all grows up
and she's all grows up.
The most overrated movie ever.
I can't believe it.
You were just-
14.
Right.
- Yeah.
Drink, stranger.
You look great.
Not as good as he did
at your eighth grade prom.
Shut up.
Max.
What?
I wanted to take Nana to
the prom, but she dissed me.
I'm good.
My father asked me
to come see you.
He looks good?
Yeah.
Well.
Bunch of shite's what it is.
We'll have him home in no time.
So
Newark, huh?
Yup.
Daniel hated makin' bank.
Not true.
I was rooting that
he would leave this
white shit behind.
Well they didn't need
me in that world anymore.
We all have to find
where we are needed.
Speaking of where
we're needed, excuse me.
Are you going to
stick around this time?
No, I'm just here
for a few days.
I have responsibilities
in Newark.
And whose
responsibility is that?
He's a good egg,
but he will really benefit
from a steady-level head
like yours around here.
My father doesn't
want me involved.
Your father listens to me.
Ani.
I don't think I should be here.
You haven't been here a
lot, not since I was a girl.
But for some reason,
this place seems complete
when you're around.
I'll come back more often.
I promise.
Keep this one off the floor.
You will slip.
And we need this head
of yours in one piece.
They rob us!
Damn shakedown!
Rob us?
They can shut us down.
What, your hand's broke?
You can't make call?
Only numbers you know are for
bookie, OTB and loan shark
for when you lose
to bookie and OTB.
You're going to bankrupt us
with this shit, fuckin' suka!
- Suka?
- Suka!
Come here, I bend you over!
Make you my suka!
Stop!
Three days!
Three days, my father's gone.
This place is already-
Danny.
Get your father upstairs!
Come on.
Hurts more than
you think, you know?
I mean all that stuff
you see in the movies
about people gettin' cut
and people gettin' stabbed,
you wouldn't think it
hurt as much, but it does.
You know I gotta
get an eye patch?
Yeah, I'm gonna be
like Snake Plissken.
What's he say?
"I don't give a fudge about
your war or your president."
"Escape from New York".
Daniel?
Daniel.
Come on, Daniel.
Any sound in there?
Danetchka. Daniel.
They're gonna be fine.
Just make sure they both take
their full course
of antibiotics.
- Thank you very much, Doctor.
- That's it?
I'm done?
Yeah.
Hey, hey. Don't play with that.
You'll be back in a couple days
to see the plastic surgeon, Max.
So just relax.
The name's Plissken.
- Excuse me?
- And I don't give a fudge
about your war or
your president.
Thank you, Doctor.
Thank you very much.
"Escape from New York".
- Thank you.
- Take care, gentlemen.
Hey, look what
somebody brought for you.
Whoa.
How 'bout that?
Young Guardian Angels.
Let's go home now.
Let's go. Mametchka had
cooked some lamb for you.
Let's go. Just be careful, yeah?
That everything?
Speak English here.
Collect 50% from that
asshole selling coke.
Make an example of him if
he says anything, okay?
My pleasure.
Be back at 11:00.
Daniel.
Nyet.
Katya.
Katya!
Hey Robert, Robert, Robert.
How 'bout another coffee?
Katya.
Robert.
It's a dangerous neighborhood.
I think I'll be okay.
Whoa.
Robert here thinks that the
Russian mafia is after us.
I'm not on the clock.
No?
Were you on the clock when
we're having coffee inside.
That could've gone wrong
in 100 different ways.
Thank you.
This only gets worse.
By the way, we can
take care of our own.
What are you?
I'm Julia Shields.
I'm from the firm, Mr. Reznick.
Where is Telly?
I'm very familiar
with your case.
Telly brought me up to speed.
Where is he?
He's been indicted in
connection to the case.
I suggest we don't
waste any time.
Racketeering, murdering?
This has nothing to do with me.
RICO, conspiracy.
They're grabbing everyone.
And how long is
this going to take?
It could be a couple of years.
What about bail?
Maybe 500.
500,000?
Possibly.
Plus the legal fees?
No, I can shift
costs and billable.
You shift nothing.
I'm not a charity
case. I'll pay it.
It is going to be a fight
getting your private
accounts unfrozen.
We got joint accounts.
Yes and I've been
through all of it.
And if we don't
get you out soon,
Kat's going to be in trouble.
Go to the banya
and find Anielka,
ask her to go to the Albanian.
She'll get you paid.
Okay?
Ruslan Arshavsky,
Alexei Shapiro,
Aaron Abromovitz.
43 co-conspirators, I
know only two of them.
Verkovsky, you lent him money.
Yes, for his Internet cafe.
How the fuck does this
make me a murderer?
Verkovsky gave
cover to Arshavsky
and Shapiro's group
of Internet scammers.
Because they're his tenants.
They traded cryptocurrency
for stolen credit card numbers.
So?
And they were infiltrated
by an FBI informant
named Ilsa Sokolov who was
found dead three weeks ago.
More than 40 stab wounds
inflicted by a paring
knife from a cutlery set
bought in bulk with Abromovitz's
stolen credit cards.
What do they want from me?
Evidence.
I don't know these people.
You know Verkovsky.
And if you can help them
paint him into a corner,
then they can turn the heat up
on the next guy up the ladder.
What's going on?
One of your client's buddies
just got got in the shower.
You listen to me.
I will work. Hey, hey!
I will work this out.
Keep to yourself.
Listen, go to Anielka.
Tell her to feel the Albanian.
I will need a new partner.
Please.
Okay.
What?
You keep texting me
about getting comped
bottle service at the club.
You're my hookup.
I am outta the club scene.
100%?
100%.
Out.
Thought you were just playin'.
Mm-hmm.
How's Uncle Vlad?
Under the
circumstances, he's fine.
And you?
I'm okay.
We're gonna get
through this together.
You're here for the monthly.
Um, not exactly.
He asked me if you can do half.
Half?
Your balance.
I don't have that here.
No, of course not.
But tomorrow,
I'll make it happen.
Thanks.
I'm sorry.
Don't say my name.
How did?
Are you okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Did you get my message?
I'm with her.
The balance, the
number that I sent you,
that's her balance.
Get half of it.
I understand.
Collect the rest
from all the others.
We need all of it.
'Kay.
Are you safe?
I'm okay.
I just need to get out of
here as soon as possible.
I will.
V, baby!
I am sorry I missed
the grand opening.
Zim, we missed you.
Next one.
Yeah, next one.
Vince at the club
sends his love.
Aww.
And Jojo at Withdrawl asked
me to give you her cell.
I'd love to see Jojo.
I tell 'em, "She's
off chasin' her dreams.
Hit her up on the 'grams.
She got 90,000 followers."
120,000.
120,000 followers.
Watch and learn, boys and girls.
I mean shit, I own
six nightclubs.
Your family owns them.
Six nightclubs, four
restaurants, one hotel
and I barely get
15,000 followers.
We're gonna go grab a
bite with Chuck and Agron.
Wanna join?
Two cafes and tattoo parlor?
No partners.
Wow.
Long hours, but you know.
I know, don't I?
Hey, V ever tell you
how we met each other?
V and I dated college
year in freshmen upstate.
After we broke up, she
still needed me for weed
and rides back home from school.
So we made an arrangement.
Okay, that's enough.
A dime bag meant a hand job.
Coke was a blow job.
And a ride home, that meant
I was gettin' that
sweet, sweet ass.
No strings attached.
You're an asshole.
Her dad disappeared on her
and her mom could
barely pay her rent,
so I guess I get a scholarship.
Get out.
Now I don't even
get a return call.
I told you I am done.
Done?
Yeah, done.
Bull.
Hey, hey!
Nobody tells me shit since
I'm 14 years old, bitch.
Stay down, Zim.
I'll get ice.
Russian deadbeat dad.
Vetone!
The fuck happened?
Hi.
This is our first time.
Oh, wow. First time.
Fuck your mother
with a chainsaw!
Uncle Kos!
Sorry, Katya. Sorry.
I have excellent
idea for shark tank.
Website called
kostyakorolneudachi.com.
What does that mean?
Kostya: king of all losers.
Hi banya?
No. No, you didn't leave.
No nothing in lost and
found, no bathing suit.
Don't call bookie this time.
Bet with me on next race.
The seventh?
How much you down today?
500.
I got like 10 bucks left.
Shit.
Okay, I give you 50 to one odds.
Any horse you want.
I take the
favorite, number nine.
You could take
Moses riding unicorn
with rocket up its
ass, you'd still lose.
- Vetone.
- Hey.
Daniel. Daniel, Vetone.
My pleasure.
Same.
Boxes.
Yo, we good?
They behavin'?
Yeah, yeah. They're fine.
I gotta talk to you
about the bills, man.
I don't know how
this place survives.
I don't get it.
There's a guy named
Nathan comin' by tonight.
Somethin' I need to worry about?
Nah.
Remember Fat Jack's buildings?
I'm buyin' 'em.
12 mil.
I gave him a higher number,
improvements and whatnot.
How much?
15.
They don't know you're
flippin' the contracts.
That's why I'm gettin'
3 mil in a month.
Shit.
Oh, sorry.
It's my fault.
Hey, who's Vetone?
Family friend.
She's here to help.
How?
She owns your father.
I don't think I wanna know then.
I helped her to
fund a coffee shop,
a tattoo parlor and
an online art auction.
Not everyone can walk into
the bank for a business loan.
All right, I know. I know.
Pillar of the
community and all that.
I get it.
What do you think
of your father?
I think he's running
this place like it's 1978
and I don't know how
he has enough money.
It's enough money to
take care of your mom
for another month or two
and the rest to pay
your father's bail.
Yeah, then what?
Can I count on
you to stick around?
Yeah, of course.
Just need to go and
make a few deposits.
Well I'll go with you.
I'm black belt
and kung fu, jujutsu
and the art of seduction.
All Russian women are.
Paulius?
Bank is further down.
Leave the money
here and get out.
What?
Do it now.
You fucking kidding me?
Your hand will heal.
If your old man is gone
for good, I've got nothing.
Take a cab.
Get out.
Moshe, rub some on my feet.
Valuables in the box.
Is Maxim or Anielka here?
Nathan?
Yeah.
Oh great. Yeah,
please have a seat.
He'll be right back.
Hey Uncle Kos, can you
grab me some change?
What, you don't want
my help, Danetchka?
I thought it was your week off.
I didn't wanna bother you.
After this race.
Hey mom, I'm goin' to the back.
I'll be right back.
Just stay here, 'kay?
Uncle Kos, keep an
eye on her please.
Hey, you should try it.
I don't have any mud.
Why are we hiding up here
like we're skipping home ec?
'Cause I don't wanna share
my best shit with everybody.
You good?
One more.
What's in there?
Treatment room.
I've known Anielka for years,
yet this is my first time here.
Sure, it's the secret to
a wonderful life, boychik.
What's your game?
- They're closing in, bitch.
Art dealer primarily.
But I'm about to buy
property in the neighborhood.
No!
- Where?
- Yes, yes, yes!
Mother fuck!
Down the way on Delancey.
Really?
How much?
What happened?
I just fall and twisted it.
Come, sit down.
Can you get her some ice please?
Lemme see.
Are you all right?
Are you okay?
We should get her to a hospital.
Yeah, good idea.
Can you get her a car?
Yeah.
Lemme see this.
I just twisted it.
Paulius?
Paulius did this to you?
Just say the word and I'll
get your money back, baby.
He robbed you?
My father's bail money.
V?
Yeah, baby.
Okay.
I'm comin' with you.
Are you sure you wanna do that?
We're gonna give
her a few minutes.
When she drops her key
card, that's the signal.
What this guy do?
Cheated on my girl.
Wait.
Do you like fucking with
people that are weaker than you?
Poor baby. So powerless.
And you have a gun in your hand.
But I still win.
What the fuck?
He doesn't have
the money with him.
He's gonna lead us to it.
Boom!
Prince Danetchka, this is
from Maxim, me and your aunt.
Say spasba.
Spasba.
Aww, sorry
Maxim couldn't be here.
He's still on antibiotics
and needs to rest, hmm?
I know.
Come.
I think I may have way out.
What do you mean?
- Kostya!
- Hey!
Where's the birthday boy?
How you doing, buddy?
- Good.
- Yeah?
It's good birthday?
Just so many adults here, right?
And nobody is interested
in the same things you
are interested in, right?
Yeah. Right.
Okay.
So I think I have the cure.
An Apple lie Plus?
Awesome!
Can I plug it in?
You plug it in when you get home
and with your father, okay?
- Okay.
Danetchka. Happy
birthday, big boy.
Kostya.
Kotya, that's too much.
We can't.
What? I had a good year.
Come on.
I thought you said
market was down.
Up, down. Does it matter?
Just need to be on the
right side of trade.
How's Maxim?
Oh, you know kids.
Resilient.
He'll be okay.
But those bastards
from Brighton beach,
can't get them off our backs.
What did you guys do?
We borrowed some money.
Are you behind them payments?
No.
No, no.
It's just now they think
that they're our partners
because we owe them the money.
How much is the note for?
It's for $100,000 plus
the deed to the banya.
How much is the bank loan?
No, there's no bank loan.
It's just them.
100,000.
Yes.
What percentage of this
business you give me today
if I pay it off?
What?
You gonna pay $100,000 today?
Yes.
This is very early, gentlemen.
We wanted to thank
you for your generosity.
The business is doing great
and we wanted to pay off
the loan, make you full.
Um no.
Um, make you whole.
Full, what the fuck?
This loan should've taken
10 years to pay off.
We calculated your lost interest
and paid you for five years.
I can't help but think
that this is due to my
nephew's ambitious techniques.
He told me what
happened with the boys
and that it was accident.
Your generation,
the necessary risk you take.
Wait.
We wanted to pay you
while we had the money.
In any event, we look forward
to doing business with
you again in near future.
Receipts.
I be right back, okay?
Oh.
Dad?
Yeah?
Are we safe now?
Yes, we're safe.
Uncle Kostya said those
men won't come back.
No, they won't.
We're cleaning up the
neighborhood, remember?
Next time, mind
your fuckin' business.
Pick him up.
- Get up.
Yeah, I know but.
Katya.
I miss you.
Ma, who're you talkin' to?
Hello?
Don't say my name.
Just listen.
I might not be able
to talk to you again.
Daniel.
I'm very proud of you.
I just can't believe
we managed to raise
such beautiful person.
Dad, I love you.
I love you too, son.
- Yeah.
- I'll see you soon, 'kay?
Did you think about what
I asked you last night?
The loan.
It's just for a few days.
You know I can't
access that kinda money
without it raisin' a red flag.
Hey, come on.
It's gonna be okay.
Let's talk about this
room full of amazing work
you won't let anyone see.
I'm not ready.
So you say.
Are you just
changing the subject?
You should at least let me
get you up in another gallery.
When I'm ready.
And when's that gonna be?
When I am.
It's a shame.
So when is your
divorce happening?
Timing
is bad.
Timing's been bad for two years.
I can say the same
about your work.
Hey.
I have to make a
breakfast meeting.
Tell Maxim he owes me a call.
Hello Vetone?
Yeah, it's Anielka.
We have a problem.
What?
Can you get something
for me from the outside?
Yeah, size?
It's a SIM card.
Yeah, got fresh papers?
It'll cost you double.
- No problem.
- 10th Street, right?
Goddamn, man.
- What?
You drink too
much fuckin' coffee.
What do you mean?
This tastes like shit.
Oh, literally?
Yeah, literally.
What the fuck you lookin' at?
Break it up!
Break it
up!
All right, let's see
how you two shit bags
like a night in the hole.
How the fuck did you find me?
I stopped by your cafe.
Caught someone that
didn't recognize you?
Yeah, I suppose.
What are you doing here?
Is this how you
greet your father?
You are nothing to me.
I've thought about you every
day for the last 15 years.
Not enough to cut your
bullshit when I needed you most.
I've come to tell you I'm sorry.
And I'm in the
middle of something.
So if you wanna play your
imaginary reconciliation,
it's gonna have to wait.
I was selfish,
but you're goin' to need
me now more than ever.
Need you?
I never needed you.
Not even after what
you did yesterday?
A mutual friend
brought your name up
in connection to a missing
Albanian club owner.
I don't know what you mean.
Don't lie to me, Vetone.
I am the only one
who can help you now.
Huh?
You do everything
I tell you to do.
And why would I do that?
Because I can still save you,
even though I haven't
been a father to you.
And if I don't?
You will lose everything
and I will lose the only
thing that ever mattered.
Wait.
I will need you.
So what did I miss?
Miss?
I'm just getting
warmed up, Junior.
So how we doin'?
Are you ready to turn
over the files this week?
Boychik, I gotta hand it to you.
You outdid yourself.
With what?
15 million is a great price.
- Huh?
- What price?
My buildings on Delancey.
15 mil, what are
you talkin' about?
The deal's for 12.
No, no, no.
That's when you were with Vlad.
But you brought in Nathan
for 15, he told me.
You and Vlad?
Ah, take it easy, Pavel.
No, that cocksucker won't
talk to me for 15 years
and you are buying
property with him?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Maxim brokered the deal.
Kiddo, I'm going to
pay you a commission.
Don't worry.
Let's say um,
30,000.
30,000?
"Hey, thank you,
Moshe."
Who the fuck do
you think you are?
Hey.
Come back, you bastard.
Come back here.
I'm going to kiss you.
Hey.
Hey. Kostya, right?
Yeah.
What you up to, Uncle Kos?
Nothing.
We're headin' over to the Baths.
Oh, maybe I meet you later.
Okay.
We're gonna chip in
in the first at Belmont.
Are you in?
My uncle, he's a trainer.
Six to one. It's a lock.
I won 20 grand last time.
Going for 40 today.
Okay, maybe one race.
Attaboy.
- All right.
- Oh yeah.
Let's go.
What the fucks are you doing?
Get the fuck out of here.
Baby, what's wrong?
What's wrong?
Have fun.
Hi Maxim.
V, got a sec?
Is she good?
Nah.
No, maybe we should
hang out later.
Give it another shot.
Are you coked up?
No, I'm fine.
Where you goin'?
Bathroom. My meds.
Leave the bag.
We'll watch it.
I have to change.
Come on.
Hey.
I really need to lay down.
Sure.
Hey.
Thanks for doin' this.
I mean I feel as if
she were my own mom.
Yeah.
You look like you
haven't slept in a week.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I really like this one.
Nathan and V are always
trying to get me to exhibit.
Whenever you're ready.
Yes.
What's this?
This is my signature.
It's
beautiful.
14 years in the making.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
I should go.
Sure, sure.
But just let me know when
Vetone gets back to you
and I think we just need
to get him out today.
'Course.
I'm gonna make it happen.
Hey, come on.
The race starts in 10 minutes.
Let's get some quick heat in.
All right.
Oh, I gotta make a phone call.
I'll be right down.
Just you and me, old man.
Hey.
Who we like in the first race?
C'mon.
You gotta have a tip.
You're not gonna
tell me who we have?
What do you got? Come on.
Open it.
You got three options.
One, I tell Vlad everything.
Maybe he takes some pity on
you, but I wouldn't count on it.
Two,
we drive you to the middle of
the woods and you disappear.
My personal favorite.
You sell your piece
of the Baths to me
and our secret stays a secret.
The drugs are yours.
Should net you enough money
to pay off your bookies.
Hey.
D, come sit.
We good?
We're good. Relax.
Then what?
We stopped by his
apartment this morning.
He must've forgot it there.
Kostya, tell him
about the other thing.
I'm gonna retire
and V's gonna buy my
piece of the business.
Excuse us a second.
C'mon.
Let's talk.
Get the fuck over here.
Why?
Danetchka.
My father's life for what?
For what? Answer me!
How could you?
You're pathetic.
Get the fuck outta here.
Don't ever come back here again.
I don't know you anymore.
Daniel.
Yeah.
Lawyer.
Everything okay?
Yeah, I'm on my way.
Thanks.
Danetchka.
You got it, Pop.
Thank you.
Yeah.
- Thank you.
- You got it.
You got it.
You okay?
- Yeah.
- You all right?
Dad, you don't have to thank me.
Nah, I never intended
for this to happen.
My problems to
become your problems.
Oh no, no, no.
Take that.
Take that and take care
of the people in Newark.
No, it's okay.
I'm here with you guys.
Daniel, it's not okay.
I was supposed to
take care of you,
not the other way around.
Listen.
Hey, I'll be fine.
Just go to Newark.
Katya.
Katyusha.
Oh my god, thank you.
Welcome back home.
Thank you.
Daniel, go.
Go!
Seriously, go.
Do you have to go?
Yeah, just a couple hours.
Maybe just stick around here.
We could have something to eat.
Yeah.
Listen, how well
do you know Vetone?
Why?
You know what?
Never mind.
Another time.
Tonight we have dinner, yeah?
Sure.
I'll be back soon.
Ivan.
Welcome home.
Thank you.
Ooh.
To family.
Mmm.
Hey dad, one more
thing I wanted to-
Danetchka?
Prince Danetchka.
How long has it been?
Long enough.
Ivan is a friend now, Daniel.
I come in peace.
I'll explain it to you.
Danetchka, you look like ghost.
Oh.
- Pavel.
Nice to see you.
- You too.
- Mr. Ivan.
Nostrovya.
Is Ivan here?
I am Ivan.
- Hey.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- What're you doin'?
You wanna hear a funny story?
Sure.
My young brother
Zim goes missing
after he goes chasing some
hooker he used to fuck.
We don't know shit.
All of a sudden I get
a phone call from you
tellin' me you know where he is.
That's right.
So where is he?
I can tell you
where his body is.
His body?
Bergen field Park, New Jersey.
You drive exactly 1.2
miles into the park,
then you go into the
woods on your left.
You'll see a large pine
with your brother's
tongue nailed to it.
That's where he's buried.
How do you know
he's buried there?
I'm the one who put him there.
Can we talk?
- Shut the fuck up!
- No, no, no, no.
It's okay.
- Just talk.
- It's okay.
I'm the one who killed him.
Ivan.
No one else here had
anything to do with it.
Ivan.
No witnesses.
Daniel.