A state of emergency has been declared
throughout the country.
The articles affecting freedom of speech,
freedom of residence,
freedom of association,
and habeas corpus,
have been suspended.
MADRlD, JANUARY 1970
Move your arse!
Minority actions,
systematically carried out in order to
disturb public order in Spain,
have been occurring in recent months
and are obviously
part ofan international plot.
The defence ofpeace
and progress in Spain,
and ofthe rights ofSpaniards,
as desired by all sectors ofsociety,
obliges the Government
to take urgent measures
which will put an end to these outbreaks.
Therefore, invoking the powers
set out by law,
in particular those contained
in the following articles...
- Dona Centro, what's up?
- You get back to work. l'll see to it.
Centro!
Don't shout - you'll wake the whole street.
l feel awful!
- Like my guts are scrambled.
- Don't exaggerate.
Christ!
- What?
- Nothing.
You weren't exaggerating. Far from it.
Get up, love, you're in labour.
We have to get you dressed.
lsabelita, you really put one over on me.
When you came to this house,
you weren't exactly alone.
Be careful. Come on, that's it.
Wait, l have to close the door!
Take it slowly.
Going into labour tonight!
You might have warned me.
- How was l to know?
- Well, if you didn't...
- But l can't count.
- lgnorance! What a terrible thing!
Stop! Stop!
Bastard!
Come on, lean here.
Careful.
Stop!
Centro, for God's sake!
Stop! Stop, dammit!
Fucking hell!
Now, don't worry.
Come on, love, hurry. Hurry.
Are you crazy, or what?
l could have killed you!
These high heels will kill me.
You can't get on.
l'm going back to the depot now.
My friend's in labour.
What do you want me to do?
l told you not to get on.
Sit down there, love.
Don't do this. Please, get off.
You don't have to adopt the baby!
Just get us to a hospital!
But l'm off duty.
Don't you understand?
Senora, it isn't my bus.
Take it easy, hang on!
Close your legs! Breathe!
Fuck! 30,000 drivers in Madrid
and it happens to me!
Now don't cry!
lf idiots like us didn't decide
to give birth occasionally,
the world would be empty,
or full of old people.
See? The cologne cools you down.
- lt's falling.
- Press your legs together.
l mean the angel.
lt looks like it's going to jump.
As if the poor thing wanted to kill itself.
l've wet myself.
No, it isn't that, love.
You've broken your waters.
Stop, please!
My friend's broken her waters!
l'll park where we won't be in the way!
Put your legs up here.
That's it. Now the other one.
Take it easy.
Don't worry, l'm with you.
Let's go for it.
Come on, that's it.
Push! Push! Push!
Keep going!
That's good!
Very good! Keep going!
Good!
Push! Push! Push!
Driver! Come and help me!
Push!
Keep going!
That's it! There it is!
lt's a boy!
And he's really noisy, eh?
Just what we need!
First of all, we have to tie the cord.
Have you got anything
to tie the umbilical cord?
l know, your shoelaces.
Give them to me.
You did really well.
Does he have everything?
Everything? This kid's got it all!
Your other shoelace.
And now we have to cut the cord.
Have you got any scissors?
Anything to cut with?
- No, no.
- God, you've got nothing!
l know! l'll cut it with my teeth.
This doesn't hurt.
Give me a cloth for the baby.
- Poor little thing.
- Here, take this.
My baby!
There he is now! There's your baby!
Aren't you beautiful!
Now where do we go?
To the hospital. She's in no shape
to come home with me.
Hold him tight. You're very weak.
Don't drop him.
You mustn't fall asleep.
Careful, we're moving.
You can't go to sleep.
Look at how beautiful he is.
The pains have started again!
That's the placenta.
Give me the baby.
You have to push again.
Again?
You have to get it all out.
Come on, love. Push.
Hurry up, this woman's bleeding!
We're on our way!
Rest for a while.
You couldn't wait, could you?
You were in a big hurry
to get to Madrid, and here you are.
- What are you going to call him?
- Victor.
Look, Victor.
Madrid!
LlVE FLESH
ln the heart ofMadrid,
defying the harsh weather,
a young woman has given birth
inside a city bus.
The news ofthis unexpected birth
has been greeted with delight.
The mayorpresented the baby
with his first layette
and made him an honorary citizen.
The director ofthe city transport company
was not to be outdone,
and, accompanied by the chiefcouncillor
and their respective wives,
presented the mother and son
with lifetime passes
which entitle them to free use
of the bus service.
With such enviable prospects,
we can assure the impatient young man
a ''life on wheels''.
20 YEARS LATER
Down in the Coto Donana
they've killed...
They've killed my dog.
A deer among the green rockrose,
he was following.
Throughout all ofAndalusia
you'll never find another dog like my dog.
Dogs! That's how they treat us
and that's what we are.
Dogs.
Look at the lambs we have to protect.
He was so happy when he returned.
He took such care
bringing my flock back to me.
He was the key to my farm,
and the guardian ofmy flocks.
There wasn't a wolfthat would come near
the lambs on the riverbank.
He was the bravest ofthe brave...
Look at them.
Stealing, scheming,
betraying and corrupting each other.
There'll never be another dog like my dog.
We're the guardians of a sick flock.
Here, have a drink to celebrate it.
No, thanks.
You drink enough for both of us.
Yes?
lt's me.
What are you doing?
Watering plants.
Are you angry?
Not angry - bruised.
Forgive me.
l'm sorry l left like l did.
Forgive me?
Sancho, l don't like discussing this
on the phone.
Well, we'll talk later, all right?
l'll be home as soon as l can.
So long, my darling.
My wife's cheating on me.
What?
Clara's sleeping with someone.
Come on, Sancho, don't talk rubbish.
l don't know what to do.
Try drinking less.
Non-drinkers think
not drinking solves it all.
l really don't think alcohol helps you.
lf l don't drink, l'll kill her.
Quit talking shit!
lt's the only way a woman won't cheat.
Of course, l could kill him.
But l don't know who he is.
Could it be one of them?
To think that any of those creeps
could go screw my wife
while l'm working.
The thought makes me sick.
Beautiful!
No, my father isn't here.
You can come round.
Learn to wait?
l don't give a fuck what Lou Reed says!
lf you aren't here in 1 5 minutes,
l'll call the Pirate.
Yeah, she sells shit,
but at least it's something.
Bring me some chocolate too.
lt'll save me going down.
HOSPlTALS: STATE OF EMERGENCY
Yes, who's that?
Victor.
Victor who?
The guy from last Saturday.
What guy?
The one you screwed
in the toilets, remember?
l was very high.
We arranged to meet tonight.
l'm about to go out.
Where?
With a friend. Call another day.
A friend?
But you arranged to meet me!
l told you, l forgot!
But l've brought you a pizza.
You said you liked them.
This guy's dumb!
lt's still warm.
Then you eat it!
l've changed my mind.
Don't call me again.
REHEARSAL OF A CRlME
Next stop's Eduardo Dato.
We've done a full circuit of Madrid.
l know.
Aren't you getting out?
No, l'm going on.
Where to?
l don't know. Nowhere.
Nowhere? This isn't a hotel.
You must be going somewhere.
l'm not. So what?
Going to stay here all night?
l'll get out.
When?
Later.
lt'd better be soon. And watch it.
Fucker!
So she had to go out. Liar!
How long ago did he leave?
Tell me the truth,
or l'll go somewhere else.
There he is!
About fucking time! Come up!
Wait in the sitting room.
But don't touch anything.
What are you doing here?
- You let me in.
- Me?
l thought you were somebody else.
Well, it's me.
And we made a date a week ago.
Who do you think you are, anyway?
You were expecting a dealer, right?
What's it to you, arsehole? Get out!
Watch it, eh?
l wasn't rude to you.
l'll go when l get an explanation.
Fuck, don't take it that way.
l just wanted to talk for a while.
l met you a week ago.
We had a really great fuck.
lt was my first time.
You know what that is?
And it's the first time
l've stolen in a pizzeria.
l did it to be with you.
Get out.
Can't you see l'm pointing a gun at you?
Get out of here!
Just because you came between
my legs the other night,
you think you can sneak in here
demanding explanations?
What is this, you shit?
Don't insult me!
A really great fuck?
You wanker! You didn't even stick it in!
You've got a lot to learn!
Shut up!
At that moment, l was sure that
it was l who killed the woman.
And l assure you that this morbid
thought gave me a certain pleasure.
A woman has reported hearing
what may be a shot in her building.
No.18, Eduardo Dato Street.
The caller lives on the second floor.
That's near here.
- Night K to H 50.
- Go ahead, Night K.
We heard your message.
We're on Eduardo Dato Bridge.
We'll check it out.
Very well. The caller didn't seem too sure.
When you've finished, call in your report.
We'll do that.
Still here?
l wasn't going to leave you
here unconscious.
Who do you take me for?
lt really hurts!
You cut my head.
Get out, or l'll call the police.
Oh, God, l need a fix!
Someone called downstairs.
l said you weren't in.
He was pissed off.
He had some chocolate for you.
Are you crazy?
You want me to hit you again?
There's No. 18.
- Who is it?
- Police. We got a call.
Yes, that was me.
My friend here says l'm crazy
but l swear l heard a shot.
- lt was the TV.
- lt wasn't the TV!
Can you let us in, lady?
The lady ofthe house
is away atpresent.
- We're the domestic staff.
- Just open the fucking door!
There's an armed lunatic in there
about to rape your neighbour!
A rapist!
- That's all you think of.
- See, it's Elena!
Give me the radio.
Lay off!
l'll go first. You cover me.
But, Sancho...
We need backup. This is a rathole!
You want to wait till that girl
is raped and killed?
Of course l don't, but this isn't the way.
Scared shitless isn't, either.
l'm scared because l haven't
drunk two bottles of whisky
and no one's screwing my wife!
What was that?
Never mention Clara again!
Cool it, Sancho! Shit!
There's the door.
Now what do we do?
How do we get in?
Give me the radio,
we'll call a squad car.
- We have to get in.
- And how do we do that?
We knock.
Don't take the gun.
lt's my father's.
There's your fucking gun.
Police - open up!
Open up!
Don't move, or l'll shoot!
Take it easy! Let the girl go!
Why are you here?
l haven't done anything!
Tell them it's a mistake.
- lt's your mistake, arsehole.
- Sancho!
l haven't done anything!
That cut on her face?
What cut?
Did l hurt you?
lt must have happened just now!
Let her go, or l'll rip your balls off!
- Sancho, don't provoke him!
- Don't you provoke me!
What's your name?
Victor... Plaza.
l know there's an explanation for all this.
Put down the gun.
Let me have the girl,
then you can explain it all.
Deal?
All right, but tell him
to stop aiming at my balls.
Let her go,
or l'll bounce them off the wall!
Stop!
Give me your gun!
What are you doing?
You've flipped.
You're aiming at a superior!
l'm aiming at a lunatic and a drunk.
Give me your gun.
Victor, here's the deal.
My partner will give me his gun.
Then you put down yours.
Let me have... What's your name?
Elena.
Pleased to meet you.
All right?
Yeah, well...
All right. Sancho,
give me your fucking gun!
Let me go!
Victor, take it easy, all right?
We made a deal. Now it's your turn.
- Yeah, but what'll happen to me?
- Nothing at all.
Put down the gun.
Put it down, please.
Slowly.
That's the way. Miss...
Put down the gun.
Drop the gun!
Sancho, drop the gun!
Sancho, please! Fuck it!
What are you doing? Get out of here!
Go! Get out!
At the Barcelona '92 Paralympics,
Spain has won a medal
in wheelchair basketball.
The Spanish team beatArgentina 56-52.
The ball is passed to No. 5, David de Paz,
undoubtedly the best in the game.
De Paz holds out against
the Argentinian defence and shoots.
ln the stands, a special spectator
celebrates the decisive shot.
lt's Elena Benedetti, his wife.
David de Paz,
an ex-policeman paralysed by a bullet
has had an excellent tournament...
What l want
is for you to suffer
the way l suffer.
And l'll learn to pray
to make it happen.
What l want
is for you to feel
as useless
as an empty whisky glass
in someone's hands.
And l want the heart in your breast
to feel as ifit belonged to someone else,
and for it to hurt.
l wish you death
wherever you are.
And l'll learn to pray
to make it happen.
Dear son, l've got cancer.
l won't last until you get out ofjail.
l'm leaving you the house,
if it isn't demolished first,
and my savings,
if this disease doesn't eat them up.
l know l wasn't a good mother.
Whatever l had, l shared with you,
but all l got from the street was misery.
l'm sending the photo
and the news clipping....
Mother,
you'll be glad to know
l'm not on drugs.
Nor have l contractedAlDS.
l study a lot.
l spend the day going to classes
in education, metalwork,
handicrafts, and even theology.
That way l reduce my sentence,
and learn as well.
A Bulgarian inmate
is teaching me Bulgarian.
l'm reading the Bible too.
Right now, l'm into Genesis.
You'll think l'm cracked,
but ifl don't want to go mad
l must keep my mind busy,
and not think.
4 YEARS LATER
Bastard!
Hello, Mother.
l got out two days ago.
l've been cleaning the house since then.
lt was a mess!
l went to the bank today.
For my inheritance.
1 50,000 pesetas.
On my way here,
l was trying to work out
how many tricks you had to turn
to save 1 50,000 pesetas.
At the very least,
1 ,000 tricks.
l get the same amount
without ever having fucked.
lt isn't fair.
However you look at it, it isn't fair!
- l'm sorry, Elena.
- Thank you.
Senora, l'm a friend of David.
Elena, mi dispiace molto.
Ti sono molto vicino.
Mi dispiace molto.
Senora...
- l just want to say l'm sorry.
- Yes...
Chi è?
l'm Ana.
l work with Elena at El Fontanar.
Senora, my deepest sympathy.
- You need more?
- No, that's enough.
- Chief...
- What is it?
May l take some flowers
for my mother's grave?
Take all you want.
l don't think Mr Benedetti will mind.
- Thanks a lot.
- You're welcome.
We're just about finished.
- You need any more?
- Just a bit.
''El Fontanar Children's Shelter.''
''Be brave, Elena. We love you
and need you. From all of us.''
ls this the funeral for Mr Benedetti?
This is the grave,
but the family left ages ago.
l've been wandering around here
like a zombie.
lt was really dull.
And they all went off in a terrible hurry.
- l was disappointed.
- Are you a friend of the family?
Of Elena, really.
All l know about her father
is that he was an ltalian diplomat,
and he had a gun.
And you?
Actually, l know David best.
You think they're happy?
The dead?
Perhaps.
l wonder that too.
No, l meant David and Elena.
l don't know! Ask them!
This way.
Do you know her?
- Or rather, did you know her?
- Not very well.
She was my mother.
Thank you.
l left my car at one of the cemetery gates.
lf you help me find it, l'll give you a lift.
lt's a deal.
Honestly, l've got absolutely
no sense of direction.
l'd get lost in my own back yard.
Can you remember the model and colour?
Come on, l'm not that daft!
My God, this looks like Sarajevo!
- lt's going to be expropriated.
- When?
l don't know.
They're going to build a big avenue.
''The Prince of Asturias.''
Can l offer you a drink?
To be honest,
a drink would help warm me up.
The furniture's coming...
- Maybe we should leave it...
- But l can buy you a drink.
- Look, 1 50,000 pesetas.
- No, another day...
Listen, l didn't steal it.
This is an inheritance.
- An inheritance, get it?
- What's the matter?
My name's Clara. And don't get angry.
We'll meet another day.
All right, l'm sorry.
My name's Victor.
Bye, Victor. See you again.
Ti sono molto vicino.
What did you say?
That feels good.
Even better.
Up you go.
l saw Victor Plaza at the funeral.
Victor?
Are you sure?
Yes.
l didn't see him.
You had your back to him.
You were going to the car with Sancho.
Fucking son of a bitch!
Did he say anything?
He sympathised with me.
He's a psychopath.
How did he know about the funeral?
l don't know.
Maybe he followed you.
We have to tell the police.
No, David, don't do anything.
l'm not going to let that madman
follow you around.
We can't report him for expressing
his sympathy to me in public.
People think charity is giving away
the worst things you have.
And it isn't that.
Sure, we get lots of worn-out T-shirts,
but what about anoraks?
We'll have to hit Elena for money again.
You know this is illegal entry?
l don't give a fuck.
Why were you in the cemetery
the other day, spying on my wife?
l wasn't spying on anyone.
My mother died while l was inside.
l just happened to be near
your fucking funeral.
You always happen to be
where you shouldn't.
l'm not as lucky as you.
You always win,
even in the worst moments.
lf you go near my wife again,
l'll crack your skull.
How?
What a goal!
What a fucking goal!
Look, look, look!
Did you see that dribble?
Caminero's brilliant!
You're fucking great!
Well, Victor.
l've warned you.
Help me, l've brought you something.
Great!
We put it like this.
See how good it looks?
- Now it's a sofa.
- Great.
And it opens into a bed.
Thanks a lot.
- Here, read this.
- A Bible.
Yes, it's my Bible.
- What's this?
- Read it.
Go on, read it.
''Tonsillectomy in childhood.''
- ''No toxic addictions.''
- Not one.
- ''Haemoglobin. Haemato...'' What?
- Haematocrits.
''lron.''
''Anti-HlV, negative.''
So, l'm really healthy.
Yes, you are.
l didn't tell you before...
l've just got out of jail.
Well...
- Hot, isn't it?
- Nice...
What is that?
Bulgarian. lt means...
lf you want, we can open the futon.
Stop looking.
l've never seen anything like it.
Me neither.
Come here.
Here l go.
How was it?
- l didn't even notice.
- l don't have much experience.
- Why don't you teach me?
- You can't teach that.
You can teach anything.
And l learn fast.
Really fast.
l want to become
the best lover in the world!
Tell me the things you like to do,
what you think about
when you masturbate.
l've got time to learn.
Look, Victor,
you treated me like a hen's arse.
Christ, what a put-down!
First of all,
don't dive at my pussy so fast.
l mustn't dive at it.
Not to eat it,
or stick it in.
You have to prepare it first.
And don't worry,
it'll tell you when it's ready.
How will it tell me?
- lt'll tell you. You'll notice.
- l hope so.
That's the first lesson.
Making love involves two people.
Great! And the second?
- Hi, Clemen, how are things?
- A mess.
l had to send Josep home
before he gave us all the flu.
- How are the kids?
- Fine. A volunteer turned up.
- Does he have references?
- He knows a lot about boilers.
- Has he fixed ours?
- He has.
- Great! But who is he?
- Well, he studied education.
He's promised to stay the whole year.
l took a real shine to him.
l can see that!
When he saw that l was so busy,
he offered to help with the kids.
And they're having a ball.
They're just crazy about him!
Mr Wolf! Come over here!
Victor, this is Elena.
She's the big boss.
Miguel! You're obsessed with legs.
Let go!
Pleased to meet you.
- What are you doing, Victor?
- Me? l'm helping.
By following me like a psychopath?
l'm not following you.
Since you got out, l see you everywhere.
l'm sorry, but we live in the same city.
- l don't think you can stay.
- Why not?
Clemen said that
my teaching diploma was acceptable.
Your diploma!
When did you study teaching?
ln jail, by correspondence.
Did you tell Clemen that you were in jail?
What's up?
l can't stay because l've been in jail?
lt was your fault.
What is this?
An NGO or a ministry?
This is a shelter for 12 children
who have suffered enough.
l don't want our problems to affect them.
''You will be damned in the town,
and in the country.''
''Damned will be the fruit of your body,
the produce of your soil.''
''You will be damned coming in
and going out.''
Deuteronomy.
Chapter 28.
Moses was thinking of me
when he wrote it.
Lesson number 1 1 . What's it to be today?
Whatever you want.
No, no, no, not whatever l want.
Lesson number 1 1 .
The greatest pleasure for a woman
in love is pleasing her man.
Clara, don't fall in love with me.
You should have warned me before.
WELCOME
What are you doing here?
l live here.
l married you long before
you got Alzheimer's.
Where were you?
l was at a class all morning.
Dance class?
Yeah, dance class.
What are you cooking?
Bull's tail in brandy.
Are we celebrating something?
Our 12th anniversary.
l took the afternoon off.
God, l'd completely forgotten!
l'm sorry.
l can see that.
Go inside, l'll see to this.
Will you fix me a drink?
You lie down like a man to watch TV.
l never knew that only men
lay on the sofa.
So now you know.
l'm tired.
Well, it's no wonder
after all that dancing.
You gave it up seven years ago.
Why start again now?
Maybe l'll go back to it.
l need to be busy.
Then take care of us.
Sancho, why don't we separate?
Why don't we separate?
As long as l love you,
you're not leaving me!
One day l'll stop being afraid of you.
And l feel that day isn't too far off.
l have to get back to the kitchen.
And never hit me again!
lt hurts me more than you.
All the more reason!
You stay here.
l'll set the table.
Forgive me.
Even though you may not believe it,
as God is my witness,
this will be our last meeting.
You will understand
that even ifyou pretend
to be in terrible pain,
you're not going to die.
But abandon now
that illusion.
To no one in the world
shall l give my heart.
Return my love so l may kill it.
Return the tenderness l showed.
You don't deserve to keep it.
You mean nothing to me now.
Give me back my mother's rosary.
Everything else you may keep.
Your things l'll send you one evening.
For you are not to see me any more.
l'd do anything for the kids,
but you owe me two months.
The council is slow in paying us.
That ltalian woman's loaded.
She can fork out.
Really, Rosa.
Clemen, we're going to the dentist.
lf he mentions the bill, get him to call me.
400,000 pesetas...
- Hello.
- David!
- ls my wife here?
- Shall l get her?
No, it's all right, thanks.
Come on, just give me two days.
Well, go and buy them this afternoon.
Thanks, Elena.
Hello, David.
You look awful. Are you all right?
l saw Victor come in here.
He works as a volunteer.
What?
Please, don't make a scene.
How could you accept him?
l didn't. l came in one day
and he was here.
l don't understand.
This isn't the army.
l can't countermand the others
without giving a reason.
And Victor's a good worker.
Fuck that!
What can l do?
- Victor, can't you see l'm busy?
- Excuse me.
- l'd like a word before you go.
- Yes, l'd like that too.
Would you mind leaving us alone?
Yes, l'd mind a lot!
Don't worry, my love.
Nothing will happen.
This is the last place
where you should have met.
Victor, let's be frank.
That woman who's just gone out
is my wife.
l'm crazy about her.
l'd do anything to defend her,
because she's all l have.
And like all cripples,
l've got a filthy temper.
l'm sure you love your wife
and have a filthy temper.
But it's not my business.
Come on!
lt is a bit, l think.
Before l met you, l looked up
at the sun, the stars, the moon.
Since l met you, l have to look down.
l have to look at dog shit
so l don't stain my hands,
at kerbs so l don't crack my skull!
You condemned me to look down!
l didn't condemn you to anything!
- l don't give a shit if you fired by accident!
- lt wasn't an accident!
- You mean you did it on purpose?
- lt wasn't me who shot you!
lt was Sancho! Clara told me.
How could he have shot me?
You had the gun.
Get off!
Victor, get off! Let me go, please!
Victor, please!
l didn't want to press the trigger!
l didn't want to shoot you!
- Take the gun!
- What are you doing?
Put your finger on the trigger,
but don't press it.
l pressed the trigger,
but Sancho pressed my finger.
He did it because
you were screwing his wife.
Clara wanted to leave him for you.
He knew that.
That's why he shot you.
l spoke to ''Messengers of Peace''.
They have a house for children with AlDS.
l'm seeing them tomorrow.
lf they accept me, l'll leave El Fontanar.
l've already told the others.
How can you leave?
This way, Victor will have
no excuse to see me.
l thought you'd be pleased.
No, and l don't like you being a martyr.
How can the others let you leave?
You set up that house.
l'm not abandoning them.
l'll still help financially.
What about the kids? Your kids.
l don't know how l'll leave them.
But l can't think about myself.
Come here, Elena.
Come on, we'll smoke a joint
and relax a bit, all right?
We've both had...
..a tough day.
Come on.
- You look pretty relaxed to me.
- l've already smoked one.
What did you and Victor talk about?
- Didn't he tell you?
- No.
l didn't ask him.
l'm asking you.
So what did you talk about?
Here.
About the shooting.
Victor says it wasn't him.
But he had the gun. l don't understand.
There are things l never told you.
They happened before l met you.
l was very close to Sancho.
And also to Clara.
Specially to Clara.
Let it out. lnsult me if you want.
Do whatever you want,
but say something.
Say something!
Go to sleep, Aitor.
Be careful, you'll catch cold.
l needed some air.
David told me about the shooting.
And?
l can imagine how
you must have hated me,
how you still hate me.
How could l hate you?
Do l look like l hate you now?
Until recently all l wanted was
to get revenge on you two.
l even had a plan.
- A plan of revenge?
- Yes.
A ridiculous plan.
Of all that happened that night,
what hurt me most was
that you called me a wanker
and said l couldn't fuck.
l swore l'd make you
eat those words someday.
Worst of all, it was true.
So l decided that when l got out of jail
l'd become the world's best lover.
My plan was to spend
a whole night with you.
During that night,
l'd fuck you non-stop,
until l split you in two.
l'd give you more pleasure
than you'd ever dreamed of.
And, naturally, you would fall for me.
But l'd dump you,
and l'd never go back to you,
not even if you begged me.
That was my revenge.
That was my plan.
Goodbye, Victor.
Don't go so quickly.
l'm leaving in a few days.
l suppose we won't meet again.
ln order to forget Elena,
l got ajob, and started
reading the Bible again,
as l did injail.
On the first day,
God created the night
so that lovers couldn't sleep.
He created water so that it would
drip constantly from market roofs.
And he created fish,
not to fill the seas with them,
but so that l could unload them
before dawn,
and, in that way, not think about Elena
and not go insane.
What a fright! Give me a kiss.
Give me a kiss!
Squeeze me, come on.
- Where were you these two weeks?
- ln Portugal.
- You smell different.
- lt's fish. What were you doing?
- Tourism, and a cure.
- Tourism.
Didn't you get my card?
l couldn't tell you before.
Sancho suspects something,
so he's reforming to try to win me back.
We even went to a clinic.
- The bastard's stopped drinking.
- And you?
l'm drinking even more, can't you see?
l'm going to shower.
Anything wrong?
No, nothing, l'm tired.
l'm working at the market now,
as well as at the shelter.
Unloading crates.
- Why are you working so hard?
- What do you mean, why?
l can't leech off you for ever.
Why not?
The things you say...
Wait.
We must stop meeting.
Don't tell me that.
l don't want anything from you.
Just to see you occasionally.
We both have to sort out our lives,
but...
we must do it separately.
But why?
l'm not asking you to love me!
l love you enough for both of us.
Clara, do you notice an odd smell?
Clara, l smell something odd.
Christ, the frying pan!
Are you crazy?
What's up with you?
Christ! Shit!
Fucking hell!
- l thought you weren't coming.
- l'd a problem at home.
They're asleep. lt's all been done.
Great, thanks a lot.
Go and see your girl. And happy birthday!
Give her a kiss for me.
l didn't know you were here.
l came to get my things from the office.
Don't go. lf anyone has to go, it's me.
Be quiet.
Promise that you won't look for me,
and we won't meet again.
Promise me.
Yes, l promise.
We are an impossible dream,
seeking the night
to forget in its shadows
the world and all else.
We, in our daydream,
painful and beloved,
two leaves that the wind
brought together in autumn.
We are two beings in one
who, loving each other, die
to keep the secret
of their love.
But what will life matter
when we are separated?
We are two teardrops
in a song.
But what will life matter...
Dawn's breaking.
We are two teardrops
in a song.
Nothing more
are we,
nothing more.
- David...
- Yes, did l wake you?
l didn't expect you so soon.
l came back on my own
from Seville, in a taxi.
l didn't wait for the team.
Go to sleep, you must be exhausted.
No, l'm not tired.
What's up? Not in the mood?
lt isn't that.
lt hurts.
lt hurts?
How come?
l was fucking all night.
What are you doing?
l'm leaving.
To go where?
Far away.
Clara, don't start.
Give me an Alka-Seltzer.
My head's exploding.
Let me past.
Why not forget last night?
Take it easy, Clara.
Give me the keys and let me go.
We deserve another chance.
We've had too many.
Get out of the way.
l can change.
l proved it last week, didn't l?
- Fuck, forgive me!
- l forgive you.
Who was it?
Knowing that won't help you.
You doing it hasn't helped me.
lt was Victor.
Bastard! l knew it!
lt was my fault.
lt won't happen again.
Why should l believe you?
l never lie, David.
That's true.
Yes, you're offensively honest.
What will you do now?
Stay with you, if you don't throw me out.
Didn't you enjoy it?
l didn't say that.
Then why the fuck stay with me?
You need me more than he does.
Right, l'll keep exploiting
your guilt complex.
David!
David, open the door!
What are you doing?
So long.
Please, open the door!
- Where are you going?
- Training.
Are you sure?
Of course l'm sure.
Who are you worried about?
Me or him?
The three of us.
Who did he speak to?
Yes?
Clara, is that you?
Clara, answer me.
Wherever you hide, l swear l'll find you.
This time you've had a serious row.
No, not at all.
We were doing really well.
l'd stopped drinking.
But she flipped,
and belted me with her beauty case.
ls that a bullet wound?
Yes, but she didn't mean
to hit me. lt's just a scratch.
lf you'd had your back to her,
you could've ended up like me.
l wouldn't mind ending up
in a wheelchair
if l could get Clara back.
You stupid bastard.
- What?
- Nothing.
- You got any coke?
- Coke?
No, why do you want it?
l don't want to cry.
Cocaine dries up your tears.
lt cools you down.
Let me help you.
Come on, let me help you.
Fuck!
Give me that.
Thanks, David.
What did you want to tell me?
Clara sent you, right?
- No.
- Really?
Clara hasn't seen me in ages.
But l've seen her.
Look.
You love Crispies.
Why won't you eat them?
And what's up with you?
You're big enough to feed yourself.
Oh, he didn't like that at all!
Yes?
- Hello, Clemen, this is Elena.
- Hi, Elena. What's up?
ls Victor there?
No, he isn't.
Where is he?
Listen, Elena.
You said you didn't want to see him.
lt's important.
You said that ifhe asked
for your address
we weren't to give it, and now...
Now l'm asking for his. What is it?
Really, l can't believe this.
Don't think that because you fund us
you have the right to boss us around.
Don't torture me.
l've tortured myself enough.
Don't be like that.
Victor lives in La Ventilla,
in one of the prefabs.
Not only did she fix up his house,
he's been screwing her
since he got out of jail!
Where does he live?
My boy!
Dear Victor,
l'd like you to keep this note
among the pages ofyour Bible,
along with the things you most love.
When you read this l will be dead,
or running away.
You mustn't feel responsible, orpity me.
When l came to your door,
l knew l'd end up like this neighbourhood,
expropriated and destroyed.
But l have no regrets.
Nor do l blame you, my love.
Before l met you,
l was already condemned to disappear.
l'm leaving your key and some money.
l couldn't get any more because
l'm running away from Sancho.
Get out ofMadrid.
l know you have more reason
than ever to stay now,
but Elena will understand too.
Keep away from Sancho.
lt would be pointless to confront him.
People like you and me
weren't born to kill.
We may hurt others.
l would even say we have
a special gift for that,
but we don't kill them.
There he is.
l'm sure it's him.
l know the way he hammers on doors.
Goodbye, Victor.
Where's Victor?
He's gone. He doesn't live here any more.
Where does he live?
l don't know.
What are we going to do now?
Shoot each other?
Tell me another way to settle it.
That depends on you.
This sums up my life.
Dragging myself along to be near you.
l should have ripped
your balls off that night.
Shoot!
What's keeping you?
Will l have to shoot for you again?
You stole six years of my life.
You stole much more from me.
Clara didn't belong to you.
Your life didn't belong to you.
No one ever owns his youth,
or the women he loves.
lt can't be!
David!
What are you doing here?
Elena, l'm in Miami.
l'm spending the holiday here
with some friends.
lt's my first Christmas in the sun,
and the first in six years without you.
Although it hurts me to admit it,
l understand you more than ever.
l understand your lack ofjoy,
why l so rarely saw you laugh.
Don't feel guilty about anything,
because l'm to blame
for what happened in Eduardo Dato,
and for the massacre in La Ventilla.
Look on this declaration ofguilt
as a declaration oflove,
and as my Christmas gift.
- Victor!
- Yes?
ls it time?
Come on!
Goodbye!
- Josep!
- What?
- Hurry.
- Which way do l go?
- The fastest way!
- Where's that?
- Through the centre.
- No, we'll never make it.
Everyone's watching the big
soccer game. We'll make it.
Come on, breathe.
Hang on, my love.
And you, don't be so impatient.
Come on, do the seal.
Come on, Josep, the seal!
The contractions!
Don't be so impatient. Hang on.
l'll try to convince him.
l know exactly how you feel.
26 years ago, l was in the same
situation, about to be born.
But you're much luckier than l was.
lt's so different now.
Look at the sidewalk, full of people.
When l was born,
there wasn't a soul on the street.
People were shut up at home,
scared shitless.
Fortunately for you, son,
in Spain we stopped being scared
a long time ago.
DVD Subtitles: Visiontext
Xvid Subtitles: SOUTHSiDE 2002