(LOCKED IN SOCIETY)
going to drink that!? You're not
Oh, but I am.
A staff room coffee Nothing beats
that's sat 6 or 7 hours on the hotplate.
Combined with delicious oat milk,
this bitumen-like substance
becomes a full-fledged latte.
From a food-chemistry perspective... BERND:
Let him poison himself if he wants to.
It's for the nerves. It's not poison,
a stack of exams by 5. I have to correct
No, I... Do it at home.
Speaking of which, I got to go.
Pleasant weekend, adieu and see you.
One second. What?
Something to discuss. We have
I beg to differ.
I've got to get home, shower, eat,
and get to my wife's store.
If I'm not behind the counter by 3:30,
it'll be the last Friday of my life,
predilection for Fridays.
And that despite my
You parked in my space again this morning.
Oh, it's yours?
Your own personal parking space?
I didn't see a sign. I wasn't aware,
Don't act dumb.
Don't bother, Klaus. He's not acting.
Particularly from you! That hurt,
There are rules at this
high school, Mr. Mertens.
Near the entrance has been
mine The parking space
since Dr. Clausen retired.
Eleven years ago, Mr. Mertens.
Have abided by that. All our colleagues
Yeah... Phew...
I really like the spot.
The school quick, You get into
and more importantly back out again!
So, nice talking to you.
Hasta luego, muchachos.
You're an oaf! Have a nice weekend.
And what's more, I'm off!
That was a knock.
We all heard it.
Who could it be? Who cares?
There's one thing I can't stand,
I hope it's not a student. If
it's students at 2:30.
Students at 10:30 are no better.
On the door since forever:
There's been a notice
Students are unwelcome in the staff room.
Yet they're a daily occurrence.
This is a school. It's almost like
The staff room is reserved
as a place of retreat and preparation.
Grubby senior lounge couch.
I don't hunker down on the
Maybe you should. To get
closer to your students.
That's the last thing I want.
There it goes again.
Maybe it's just a woodpecker.
If we just ignore it, maybe it'll go away.
Or we just open it.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
Who are you, anyway?
Sara Schuster.
For Biology and English. Trainee teacher
I've already introduced myself.
Trainees come and go.
Is the job description. Trainee Teacher
They come and go, too.
Are you one of those modern
feminists, Miss Schuster?
To be addressed correctly. It's Ms., I want
I recently had
a student who wanted me
to use her chosen pronoun.
According to "them," I'm now
to refer to her as "they."
What the heck?
It offers no improvement
in scientific terms.
As non-binary chemistry.
There's no such thing
But we could still discuss it
among the staff. Providing...
"staff" is inclusive.
Right?
Before the tension kills us all.
Somebody better get that
How about our young colleague?
Ms. Schreiber?
Ms. Schuster!
Whatever. Please.
Why Ms. Schuster and not you?
It's fine. I got it.
It's no problem.
Male and female trainees begin at
the bottom of the ladder. KLAUS:
How's it going to look if Mrs. Lohmann or I
open the door to a student?
We're locked in! Come on, Peter.
It's for you, Mr. Engelhardt. Ah!
I don't talk to students at this hour.
It's not a student. It's a father.
Worse still. What does he want?
Tell him I left.
He can hear you!
So now he knows.
I'll take care of it. All right,
Yes, I want to speak to him.
Uh, Mr. Engelhardt?
Great, come in. PETER:
Really? PETER: Yes!
May I ask your name?
I'm Fabian Prohaska's father. Prohaska.
Look, it's Mr. Prohaska, Mr. Engelhardt!
Fabian's father!
My consultation hour is Wednesday at 10.
But it's urgent!
Everything is always
urgent, urgent, urgent.
Climate change is urgent,
or the refugee question.
Why do people take their
petty concerns so seriously?
That's quite fair. I don't think HOLGER:
People with concerns need a friendly ear.
And if it's urgent, we need to be here.
How can we help, Mr. Prohaska?
Has something happened,
does Fabian have a problem?
Is Fabian's problem. Mr. Engelhardt
So I'd like to talk to you, Mr. Engelhardt.
Very briefly. In private.
Please.
What's your son's name?
Fabian Prohaska. I'm his father.
Yes, I know your son.
He's a very nice boy.
Your colleague doesn't think so. Nonsense.
I have neither sympathies, nor antipathies.
The only thing that counts for
me is a student's performance.
Well... what's the case in point?
Had a conversation Mr. Engelhardt
with my son yesterday in which...
I explained to your son that,
according to my records,
he's looking at a D.
Ah. Precisely.
Admissible to the baccalaureate.
One more point and he'd be
of one single point. It's a matter
Which he could have earned.
Knows begging is useless.
Everyone who knows me
I'm just trying to convince
you not to spoil his future.
Listen, Mr. Prohaska.
We have our big conference on Monday.
We'll discuss all of our students.
I'm sure Fabian will
be given a fair chance.
But Mr. Engelhardt would
have to change his opinion.
Which is why I'm here.
I don't have an opinion,
and they're impartial. I have results,
I told your son as much.
In giving students hope I don't believe
where there is none. It's immoral.
Has to take the baccalaureate. Not everyone
But Fabian needs to.
Your son has had over a
decade to prepare for it,
is at least 5 years too many.
Which in his case
under-performers in the system.
I don't believe in keeping
I'd have winnowed him out long ago.
Winnowed out?
His first apprenticeship by now.
Yes, he could've quit
Is that how you talk about my son?
It's like a cancer diagnosis.
It's hard to face at first,
but recognition and
acceptance come with time.
Sometimes it's the genes, or the character.
One has to live with it.
Uh...
Would you let me by? No.
Kindly step away from the door. Uh...
I need to leave.
You're staying.
You're staying. Sorry?
You're all staying!
I'm afraid I have to get
back to my department.
There's an experimental
setup simmering away.
You're staying, too! It could explode.
I don't even know your son.
So? Mr. Engelhardt doesn't, either!
What do you hope to achieve?
Won't change my mind. This approach
The day is still young. We'll see.
As three minutes ago. Not quite as young
Enough. Step aside.
You'd like that, huh? Step aside!
Step aside. No!
Sorry.
You hit me.
Flowing to your brain.
It'll get blood HEIDI:
Is this how you deal
with concerned parents?
No, but if it stops them
from hamming things up,
I'm fine with it.
Argumentum baculinum. It's known as
Sit down.
Sit.
Sit down. Sit. Sit.
Move! All of you!
Mr. Prohaska, please calm down.
Why the gun? This is foolish.
Please put it away.
Nobody move.
Or...
I'll have to shoot.
Don't worry, Mrs. Lohmann.
It's not a real gun.
I've seen them before. It's an airsoft gun.
What?
Like the good old BB guns,
only better designed.
Are you crazy?
That coffee maker was a gift
from our twin school in Toulouse!
Couldn't you have shot Mr. Mertens instead?
What do you think you're doing?
Taking hostages?
If need be, yes.
As I already mentioned,
Mr. Prohaska, HOLGER:
we have our big conference on Monday.
To get ahead of ourselves.
So there's no need
You're having your conference here.
Right now.
Thanks for this.
My Fabian will get his point.
At the end of it,
He deserves it!
Or else you'll shoot us?
That won't get your son the baccalaureate.
I think we can just give him that point.
Right, Mr. Engelhardt?
Fabian gets a point and the
rest of us can go home in peace.
I'd be happy to oblige. Over my dead body.
If we submit to your
threats, then from Monday on
with firearms here every day.
We'll have parents
We cannot and shall not
allow that to happen.
Of space your son represents
You won't turn the waste
into a good investment
by employing violence.
You're talking about my son like that?
My God! Do you know how many times
I've had this pointless discussion?
Parents project God-knows-what
onto their genetic vegetables
while the rest of us pay the price.
What a way to speak about your students!
You're cynical! No.
Oh, no. It's honesty.
Of congenital non-academics
We funnel millions
into university education,
only to clog up the job market
with college-educated non-starters.
It's the truth.
I think you're going too far,
Mrs. Lohmann.
We're not here to decide whether
Fabian is suited for college,
but rather if we should give
him one more year to mature.
He's repeated a year twice. Nonsense!
So this is his last chance. Hm!
Is that you don't spoil All I'm asking
of taking the baccalaureate.
His last chance
Fine, we'll do that.
Fabian will receive the extra point.
No further discussion,
you pocket the pistol,
we can all... go home happy.
Hmm?
What? No.
That's not what I want. Then what?
To judge him fairly. I want you...
You're not giving him due consideration.
He's gifted.
Yes. I'm convinced. Really!
If you ask me, I also think SARA:
there are exceptions to the rule.
No one asked you.
I have to get back to my department.
My experiment will explode... Otherwise,
want to call the police.
Come off it! You just
The idea never crossed my mind. I promise.
And will be right back.
I'll turn off the gas
Enough!
You're having your conference here and now.
And how did you imagine that?
You all talk about my son. It's simple.
You discuss his achievements,
behavior and prospects,
before coming to a joint verdict
based on your discussion.
Yeah?
Rather than petty-minded
notes in your ridiculous book.
Is the basis of fair
assessment, This ridiculous book
nor your pistol can... and neither you
This is mob rule.
No.
It's self-defense.
Because I've had it.
I have four children.
What four children means? Do you know
Two times twelve,
and two times thirteen years of schooling.
Not to mention repeated years.
That makes a total
of 50 years of school
that my wife and I have gone
through with the children.
Quite the balance sheet!
Our own school years. Not counting
They were presumably negligible.
Fifty years of school!
And a sense of inadequacy.
Nothing but worries
I'm sick of sitting
opposite people like you
and advocating for my children
just so they get a chance.
How humiliating it is Have you any idea
to spend decades of one's life
begging for one point
here or a D-minus there?
From fifth grade on,
they'll never make high
school kids are told
with this or that attitude!
It's terrorist tactics!
But did you never consider
alternative forms of school?
There are many... I know.
They're all wonderful
options, at private schools!
The rich take their kids
out of state schools
in private ones, and place them
but I'm not rich!
The municipal administration. I'm with
Condolences.
Said to me yesterday? Know what my son
"I won't make it, Papa.
I'm a huge disappointment."
So I'm asking you, Mr. Engelhardt:
feel like a failure Should a boy of 19
because he's missing one fucking point?
I'm not talking about 20
points, but one single point,
which here is the measure of human worth.
To your question. I won't respond
I want my son to be happy!
And so you're rushing
headlong into misfortune?
That makes no sense, Mr. Prohaska.
Please... be reasonable.
It's still not too late.
True, but I still need to get home
or my wife will be the one to shoot me.
You...
will now
hold your conference.
We like to hold our conferences
at the conference table,
in the conference room
not in the staff room.
All right, then push three
or four tables together
your conference table. and you'll have
Move it!
Put them together!
What's with you two?
Don't you want to help? By no means.
Nor do I.
What about you?
You'll oversee our conversation
whose opinion you don't like?
And shoot anyone
I don't want to influence you.
I'll leave the room.
Cellphones, though... If I might have your
We don't have cellphones.
Hand them over! Of course not.
He's right. We don't have telephones here.
They're with the principal
in the device box.
In the what?
The device box.
We hand them in in the
morning You can check.
And pick them up before we leave.
There's one device box for the students
and another for us teachers.
With the student government.
We created the project
I co-initiated the pilot plan
for a cell-free school...
And what a brilliant idea it was.
So none of you has a phone?
No.
Honestly.
I believe him.
Where does that door lead?
The principal's waiting room.
Uh-huh.
Fantastic.
Very good. Fantastic.
We'll proceed like this.
The clock on the wall reads 2:50.
I'll return at 4:00 for your decision.
You're off your rocker.
That's locked.
Don't shout out the window,
I alone will hear you.
And... no tricks, all right?
I'll occasionally look in
to verify that you're
holding your conference.
Right. 4:00.
Forgive me, I almost forgot.
Your names, please.
What do you want our names for?
You know who you're dealing
with, so it's only fair.
You're Mr. Engelhardt.
You? Peter Mertens.
Uh, that's Mrs. Lohmann.
No need to ask. You're legendary.
For my children, too.
That's Mr. Arndt. And
your name, if I may ask?
Vogel. Bernd.
Schuster. Schuster.
Thank you all.
4:00.
What now?
We'll discuss his son.
You can't be serious.
Why not? The sooner we're done,
the sooner we're out of here.
Such a bad idea. It's not
It'll also advance us as a group.
Excuse me? "Advance us."
What is this jargon?
The communication structure I mean,
at this school may be viewed as fossilized.
Fossilized? How so?
It's possible to innovate
how performance evaluation is achieved.
We had a seminar at college...
a college seminar. Yes, precisely:
I don't need a seminar. Spare me,
I've been here over 30 years
with performance evaluation.
And never had trouble
Please, don't imagine anything.
I simply imagine...
Knowledge is what counts. Know it.
Not perceived truth or intuition.
Education doesn't consist of half-knowledge
it's about knowledge. or approximation,
Understand?
We're here to prepare young people,
not to entertain them or to raise them,
have failed to do so. should their parents
You've got a lot to learn.
Knowledge anymore. They don't want
They want to be blown away.
Teachers as clowns.
But what has education become
when I cater my classes to immature,
disrespectful children, spoiled,
and their violent parents to boot?
It's out of the question. Exactly.
I didn't imagine so.
Stop with the imagining, damn it!
Why am I even discussing this?
How old are you?
How old do I need to be to
count as a worthy interlocutor?
There's anything to discuss If you think
about the young man's
grade, you're mistaken.
There's no need.
It's open to discussion. Well, I think
Why one point too few?
Ah. That's what my notebook says.
Yeah. Sure,
some basis, right? but it must have
One could review his performance
and perhaps find there
an oral contribution or homework,
that might yield for example,
Are you insane? the missing point.
You think I distribute
grades any which way?
Of course not, but... But what?
That I can cook the books?
I know you and many colleagues do so:
make contracts with students,
come to arrangements,
and all the rest of it.
Manufacture consensus
That's not what we're here for, Mr. Arndt.
And I fulfill it. We have a remit
What's your remit?
It's not open to question. KLAUS:
I didn't mean to question it.
I just wanted to
understand why you're here.
You meant to question it
just like everyone else.
These eighth-graders A few days ago,
in which I asked them questions.
Wanted to debate the order
So what? There's nothing to discuss.
"Strict but fair" is my motto.
It's simply done.
That's how it is in Latin.
Really want to know, My remit, if you
is dictated by the syllabus,
and those who can't clear the hurdle
find another game to play.
Must, nolens volens,
love's labor lost. Klaus, this is
The two of us are a dying breed
in a mediocre school system.
Excuse me, Mrs. Lohmann,
but that's condescending,
not to say insulting.
I don't care.
It looks that way from below.
You're arrogant.
I think she's envious.
Mercy me! Why on earth would I be?
Because you belong to that
dying breed of teachers.
That bothers you at work The only thing
is the presence of students.
And pay you back. They sense it
Nobody likes you. At all.
But Ms. Schuster here, or Holger,
or even Our Chemical Lover
is appreciated by weirdos.
Why "even?"
how supremely indifferent
I am If only you knew
to whether the students
or you or Mr. Vogels like me, honestly!
My name is Vogel, Mrs.
Lohmann, and I find...
to be portrayed as a witch
It can hardly please you
in every school magazine.
I receive mail from
former students every year
and get invited to
weddings and christenings.
No wonder. You're probably
the father as often as not.
Touché!
What's that mean? Nothing.
Ignore these frustrated,
elitist power mongers.
They know no better because
no young person has ever
thrown them... a BBQ!
The idea of forcing down dead
mammalian biomass
And industrial-quality
ketchup makes me retch.
To the tune of vile hip-hip
No doubt it's served
or whatever it's called. or hop-hop
Who can still sing "The Girl
From Afar" or "Spring Song?"
It's Franz Schubert. You, I fear.
Real education for God's sake! The canon,
♪ The air is blue The valley green ♪
And the primroses bloom ♪ ♪ The May bells
♪ And meadow land so colorful ♪
♪ Takes on more color By the morn ♪
That's our cultural identity!
Children should take their lead from that,
not from an emaciated blonde
which of her little whores deciding on TV
but for fashionable rags!
Walks the streets bare
You go too far, far too far!
No, let her finish.
I think it speaks volumes
about our Mrs. Lohmann.
Your amateur psychology. Spare me
Feel free to leave. Very funny.
Stare out the window.
Practice tying your shoelaces.
Do anything that won't overly
exert your cognitive capacity.
Why am I even talking to a gym teacher?
And he calls himself an academic.
You and that loser Prohaska
are cut from precisely
the same ragged cloth.
Maybe, but at least we're human.
Ah. Here we go again:
sentiment triumphing over reason,
and the touchy-feely over the intellect.
Get anywhere here. Klaus, we won't
This is irrelevant. No.
Let's get back to the issue.
The Chemistry Department will
explode in less than an hour
for what it's worth.
The grade, we must hurry,
If we want to discuss
otherwise, lengthy and expensive
renovations will ensue.
There will be no discussion. Fine.
So what do we do?
What you will do. I have no idea
a Cox's Orange Pippin here Luckily I have
and a penknife and a napkin.
Anyone care for a piece?
No? Fine.
Keeps the doctor away. ""
An apple a day
We should really use the time.
Ms. Schuster is right:
This situation is an opportunity, Peter.
Please. We can get in touch
with one another and talk.
And discuss our way of communication.
As well as Fabian.
I think he has a right to a fair hearing.
At the certificate conference.
He'll get that on Monday
Come on, Mr. Engelhardt.
We're all fallible.
Of the students' business.
Maybe, but that's none
One mustn't let one's
weakness become a target,
to a loss of authority. as it leads
We've had flagrant cases of that.
Can we change the subject? What cases?
It relates to him. Why should we?
Please.
And his personal foibles,
Thanks to Mr. Vogel
we have this abstruse ban on cellphones.
We can leave it at that. Right?
It's a scandal that not even I,
as vice principal, can use my cell phone.
It's unheard of,
and if I had my druthers... Klaus!
Changes would be made! Klaus!
What!?
I've got one.
Got what?
A cell phone. I've got one.
During morning recess. I confiscated it
You've had a cell phone all this time
and never mentioned it?
I forgot.
Give me it.
It must be locked, right?
May I?
Here.
It's...
four digits.
We can guess.
If you mean to crack it that way,
how many attempts will you need?
I teach Biology and English, not Math.
Ten to the fourth combinations.
There are precisely
in layman's terms, 10,000. Or, to put it
Going from 0000 to 9999.
If you manage 20 combinations a minute,
it'll take you more than...
though probability dictates eight hours,
the last combination, it won't be
so count on 4 hours.
Maybe it's something simple. Have fun.
Is a frequently used PIN. I read that 1234
No, I'm afraid not.
Or 0000?
This won't work. Nope.
It'll go dead after three failed attempts.
Or the Chemistry Department will explode.
Any pertinent ideas? KLAUS:
Let's derive the PIN using a biographical
rather than hermeneutic approach.
Translation for the gym teacher:
the student's birthday. We could try
Whose device is it? Benjamin Mehltau.
An unconscionable 12th
grader and lout to boot.
We all know him well. My friend Benny.
He was involved in the cell ban,
by the way. Right, Mr. Vogel?
Wait. Can I try something?
Um... What's the plan?
I'll hold you responsible if you damage it.
Oh!
Bam!
Hey nonny nonny! Here. Translation for you:
How did you do that? Well...
Mehltau is a swine.
He's been drawing his dick
all over since 5th grade.
An older teacher's skirt. And he looked up
So the combination was worth a try.
So what was the code, Sherlock Holmes?
6453.
Come up with that? How did you
a numerical combination: It's not actually
Each digit corresponds to a letter.
So what does 6453 spell?
M.I.L.F.
Milf! Milf?
Does "milf" mean? And what
You don't want to know.
It's not applicable to you.
But it worked.
Just as Emergency Call would have done.
You don't need a PIN.
Say so at once? Why didn't you
on the epic fun? And miss out
absolutely unbearable. You are
We should call
The relevant police department...
before that man returns.
Fine.
Should I call them?
I have seniority.
It's incumbent upon me to make the call.
The device. Hand me
Police Precinct IV, Florian Beinacker,
what can I do for you?
This is Vice Principal Engelhardt
from Rudi-Dutschke High.
Do you wish to report? What situation
A hostage-taking.
Please describe the situation.
We're locked in here. It's as follows:
Please state the location if you know it.
Of course I know it. Then speak up.
Don't take that tone with me, young man.
What age are you, anyway?
Excuse me?
Ahem. Excuse my colleague.
He's a bit confused.
I beg your pardon!
Put it on speaker.
And what does this concern? Who's speaking
My name is Peter Mertens.
At Rudi-Dutschke High. I'm a senior teacher
I'm in the staff room
I see: a volatile situation.
With five other teachers.
We've been taken hostage. You said it.
Is in the next room The hostage-taker
demanding we confer on his son's grades.
Were perilous for me as well.
Those conferences
Yeah...
please liberate us? C-could you
Not from the schoolyard,
might see and shoot you. the hostage-taker
Of course.
Have you understood?
The situation is serious, deadly serious.
And you were?
Vice Principal Engelhardt.
Or you'll be in big trouble!
Follow our instructions
I'll be expelled or what?
Give me your name,
rank and badge number this instant!
I'm the Director of Willy
Wonka's Factory, asshole.
Outrageous!
Your authoritarian tone! Always with
Let me try. HEIDI:
Right here.
No, redial.
Police Precinct IV, Florian Beinacker,
what can I do for you?
From Rudi-Dutschke High.
This is Heidi Lohmann
just spoke to you. My colleague
Oh, yeah, I remember!
The situation is as described,
please come here at once.
Please come quickly,
I have an experiment running
in the chemistry room
that could explode at any moment.
The Fire Department. Then we'll bring
of Engineers, too. and the Corps
The situation is serious.
We'll see what we can do.
Are you available for queries
at the indicated number?
Of course. Then remain calm
and we'll look into it.
Maybe we'll bring along drinks.
You guys sound like fun.
Did he just call us "you guys"?
Should I call back?
The officer didn't sound interested
in resolving our problem.
All calls are recorded. No. They'll come.
Imagine something happens
the police ignored our call.
And it turns out
And the police never have those.
It'd be a scandal.
I find your permanently
ironic undertone insulting.
For your sandals. The same goes
against my sandals? What do you have
They're fantastic and
conducive to good health.
Right!
Leave Mr. Vogels in peace
and worry about your own inanities.
The name is Vogel.
As you wish.
Something in hand We should have
before Mr. Prohaska returns.
Maybe he's right
enough effort all these years.
And we haven't given Fabian
to hold this discussion.
It could do us credit
Without foregone conclusion.
Had you been paying attention,
conclusion was intended:
you'd know a foregone
The man threatened to shoot us
if we don't vote as he wishes.
We could at least try it.
Vote? To what end?
And it definitely won't be that.
He wants a unanimous decision
where we stand. But we'll know
of awarding Fabian one point?
So, who's in favor
Do we have to vote publicly?
I'd prefer a secret ballot.
The complicated way.
Fine, we'll do it
A slip of paper. Everyone gets
If you want to give the kid
a point, put a dot on it.
Then draw a line. If you don't,
Then fold them up,
and I'll collect them.
This is ludicrous.
Maybe, but we've got nothing better to do.
Everyone done?
Then I'll go around.
An election officer, We need to appoint
and two deputies. secretary,
Your slip, please. Very funny.
Many thanks. There.
Thanks.
Holger, you're taking notes? Mm-hm.
Line.
Two lines. Another line.
Reason prevails. Line.
Mm-hm. Dot.
Dot.
Yes, sir. Another dot.
That makes three votes for Fabian
and three against.
This woman shouldn't be able to vote.
This woman is a faculty member, Mrs.
Lohmann.
She's a trainee, for God's sake.
What does she know about such things?
We'd have reached a majority.
If she hadn't voted,
How do you know how I voted?
Firstly, I don't need a
crystal ball for that.
Secondly, I don't care how someone votes
who wiggles her ass to
tantalize the seniors.
Thirdly, the vote is null and void anyway.
It has to be unanimous.
What was that about wiggling? Leave me be.
No, that's enough.
Towards Sara is pissing me off.
Your condescending manner
She's a trainee, Apologize.
He's a gym teacher. I rest my case.
What's wrong
with being a gym teacher?
Where should I begin? It
was a rhetorical question.
Gym isn't a school subject,
but a leisure activity.
One could spend one's
time more meaningfully.
How?
Making garlands with Nazi maidens
and singing your Schubert?
He's not my Schubert.
A little cultural education And yes,
your locker-room-scented life.
Would've improved
You might've become a real teacher.
This is getting us nowhere.
This isn't about our
antipathies, but about Fabian.
We really will be guilty if he fails
without our having discussed him.
Goodness!
It's obvious why Engelhardt and
Lohmann voted against Fabian,
but why did you...
Mr. Vogel?
It was a secret ballot. How would you know?
Correct.
So no one would know As you wished,
against Fabian's future. you voted
I don't have to justify myself to you.
But you could at least explain
your decision, couldn't you?
I don't know.
If Mr. Engelhardt sees
things the way he does,
who am I to question him?
Might be mistaken. Mr. Engelhardt
Actually...
I've never known
Mr. Engelhardt to be wrong.
So you always share
Mr. Engelhardt's opinion?
Why should Mr. Vogels answer that question?
His name is Vogel, and he
should answer the question.
If you only ever go along
with Mr. Engelhardt,
you have no opinion of your own.
Of course I do.
Namely?
Whatever it is, I'm not
voting against Mr. Engelhardt.
Because Mr. Engelhardt protects you?
What are you insinuating?
That porn scandal You know
would've cost you your job without him.
Nothing to do with it. That has
What has nothing to do with what?
Stop. It's irrelevant.
I wasn't found guilty.
Ahem. Our Chemical Lover
circulated pornographic material...
That's not true. in his classroom.
He didn't circulate anything.
Strictly speaking,
It was like this:
a projector to his
laptop Mr. Vogel attached
about some chemical reaction.
To show a film
It was about redox reactions
converting chemical BERND:
into electrical energy,
which is fascinating.
But not as fascinating as
what then ensued. PETER:
He set the class assignment and
left the room briefly. HOLGER:
A student, our Benny Mehltau,
had the glorious idea
of checking Mr. Vogel's browser history.
Everyone in the class was able to see
Mr. Vogel's most recent tabs:
several short clips...
That had nothing to do SARA:
with fuel cells, I guess.
The little shits recorded it
all on their phones PETER:
and shared it on Insta.
My favorite title was:
School Girls Fisting.
School girls fasting? So what?
This was nothing involving Lent.
Dear colleague,
No?
An embarrassing affair. It was doubtless
students should never Like I said,
witness teachers' weaknesses.
Stay reserved.
I never showed it to anyone.
Be that as it may, since then,
abstruse cell ban: we've had this
No one is allowed to take photos
or film on school property,
a smartphone, phones are banned.
And because everyone owns
Whether that's permissible...
It's in the school ordinance.
That's not everything:
disciplinary proceedings.
Mr. Engelhardt blocked
I considered disciplinary
proceedings ineffective
and advised against them.
They'd only fan the flames.
In lockstep with Mr. Engelhardt.
That's why Mr. Vogel is
But we're not voting for
or against Mr. Engelhardt,
but rather for or against Fabian Prohaska,
if I may remind you, Mr. Vogel.
This has nothing to do with Mr. Engelhardt.
It has to do with Mr. Mertens.
Maybe you're only against Fabian Mr. Vogel,
against Mr. Mertens? so you can be
Ah.
You and your Mr. Mertens!
You dislike him, correct?
It's irrelevant who likes whom.
People are all the same to me.
Hm. So it's true what they say:
that you're an outsider among the staff.
I'm an individualist.
That explains the sandals.
Leave me in peace. Ooh!
Oh. It's agitated.
Maybe chocolate will calm it down.
Let me be.
I just want to be left in peace.
I've never bothered you.
Always picks on me. Everyone
Mr. Vogel! HOLGER:
"everyone" and "always?"
What do you mean by
What's upsetting you?
Would you like to share?
I see the looks you give me,
how you talk about me behind my back:
I wear funny shoes, I have no family,
I always reek of sulfur or whatever...
I know I don't have the assertive voice
or the charm of Mr. Arndt.
Of Mr. Engelhardt
"Our Chemical Lover." I'm always just
No one listens to me.
Everyone interrupts me At conferences,
like I'm not even there.
No one responds to what I say
for my expert opinion. and I'm never asked
all just laugh at me. The students
in the law of mass action,
No one is interested
yet everyone must know Schubert's songs.
Nobody loves Bronstedt's acid-base theory,
but I do.
I love it.
It's...
Exciting.
But if I admitted that,
I'd suffer Peter Mertens' ridicule.
Among colleagues. It's banter
We aren't colleagues.
Mrs. Lohmann has been getting
my name wrong for years.
Periodic table's beautiful
logic I console myself with the
and the two students in each grade
out of polysaccharides. who get a kick
And if I do happen to make a splash,
no one wants to know.
What splash?
Twice, I've managed to get my students
of Young Scientist of the Year.
Into the final round
Twice! In 2019.
And in 2016.
And you know why no one noticed?
You never mentioned it?
Mm, no, that's not the reason.
Then tell us.
Why don't we know about it?
Forget it. No, please tell us.
I put it on the bulletin board.
With the certificate and everything.
It was my success story.
Before going to my department.
I hung it up at 7:40
By morning recess,
my notice was in the trashcan
under the bulletin board.
Someone had simply removed it.
Who would do such a thing? HEIDI:
Nonsense!
Did you take it down? Is it true?
He was with his lab rats.
How would he know?
That's what Mr. Mertens calls
advanced chemistry students:
"lab rats."
how I know who tore down And I can tell you
my laudatory certificate,
as it had been replaced by an invitation
volleyball tournament: to a beach
"Starting at 7:00,
grilling and chilling
with DJ Pete Mertens."
I needed the pins.
Sometimes you're such an asshole, Peter.
Would apologizing improve things?
I'd ever vote along with you.
You needn't imagine
Never!
Okay, Mr. Vogel. HOLGER:
I understand that.
But if you could decide it all by yourself,
if no one else had a vote,
what would your opinion
on the Prohaska case be?
It wouldn't interest anyone.
It does. It interests us.
Don't include me. His opinion
interests me not a bit.
Tell us what you think. Mr. Vogel,
I think we're...
taking ourselves too seriously.
Won't make any difference at
all This one point in Latin
to Fabian Prohaska's life,
regardless of whether we grant it or not.
He'll scarcely remember it in 10 years.
Just as it should be.
He should remember other things:
the smell of bread,
the sound of a ripe apple
falling from the tree,
a won game of beach volleyball, even.
If we award him this one
point, he'll go one way.
One point, he'll go another.
And if we refuse him that
So what the hell? He's young
as far as I remember. and not stupid
important to any of us?
And is that one point
Not to me.
Nor to Mr. Engelhardt.
He's awarded thousands
of points in his life.
If he gives one away, then Lord knows,
he'll have done something
good, for a change.
One point fewer because of it?
Will someone else get
No.
In which I've been making a
deal You see, I teach a subject
with the students for years:
the essential elements, They retain
the composition of air,
maybe, the oxyhydrogen test,
and, with a little luck,
the basics of the Bohr model of the atom.
In return, they let me
and the three or four
preserve our dignity. interested students
For my honest opinion, I'd
say: So if you're asking me
We shouldn't act like gods
with grading superpowers.
In the way of the kids.
And we shouldn't stand
Which is why I'm in favor
of giving Fabian Prohaska the point
go his way in peace. and letting him
Please,
let's vote on it again.
By a show of hands. Publicly,
of giving Fabian a point.
All those in favor
Peter?
What's this?
Why have you changed your vote?
For the hell of it.
It makes no damn difference who votes how.
It still stands three to three.
Mr. Mertens,
welcome to the land of reason.
What's up, Beinacker?
Hey, Boss, it's about those
hostage-calls this morning.
Another one came in.
Today because of that crap. So?
We went out five times
To five different schools.
Five false alerts.
But this call was different.
How so?
The other times, there
was only one male voice,
though he pitched it differently.
This time, there were
at least three voices.
One was a woman.
Take the word
of an experienced colleague: It's students.
Then his friends want a go.
One of them calls,
They'll laugh their heads
off if we go out again.
So we're not gonna, got it?
Something else. But there was
Get to the point.
The calls this morning,
and the call just now,
weren't from the same cell.
Give me the number.
A fucking Saturday to me ♪
♪ Every weekday's RINGTONE:
I'll speak to the officer.
Where is it, who has it?
Give me the phone or else...
Are you the boss?
Nothing. No answer.
Can we go back to work
and take care of important
stuff, Mr. Beinacker?
Yes, sir!
You lied to me. No cellphones?
What did you expect?
Of course. The police. Did you call anyone?
Half an hour ago.
The officers will be here any moment.
You called the police? Indeed.
And spoke to Police Precinct IV. Indeed.
That's fine.
But not for you. Fine for us,
How can you be so sure? They won't come.
They won't come. Believe me.
Carry on and no more tricks.
You have 20 minutes left.
Fabulous.
So, what now?
We still haven't discussed Fabian at all.
But without the students,
we wouldn't even be here.
Precisely: Where would we
be without Fabian Prohaska?
We'd all have been home long ago.
You of all people should save us
sociological lectures. the kitschy
I preferred you on mute.
When I was on your side.
And like I said, I'm sick
of everyone picking on me.
Let's discuss Mertens.
That could get interesting. Huh?
But for no one else. Maybe for you,
I'd be curious.
What's there to know about Mr. Mertens?
You'd prefer us not discussing Nothing.
Why Ms. Trainee is here today?
On a Friday after school's out.
I'm warning you.
Tell us. I'll tell you nothing.
Why were you still here? Then Ms. Schuster:
I missed the bus.
It looked like rain, so I came here
to avoid spending 30
minutes at the bus stop.
There you have it.
To discussing Prohaska. Let's go back
You hadn't gone home, either. BERND:
your lamentable part-time
job Before going to
at your wife's cheese shop,
you had to take care of something urgent.
This is your last warning.
I'm afraid of you? You think
I know exactly what's going on.
With matured Gouda at home Why make do
when you can enjoy fresh cheese here?
Peter!
It's not worth it. Want your ass kicked?
What isn't worth what?
It's irrelevant now. Let him go.
Would someone please explain
what the devil's going on?
Ms. Schreiber?
The name is Schuster.
So why were you still here?
With Mr. Mertens? For a rendezvous
If that's what you call it.
To having a relationship
So you're admitting
with a married colleague?
That's none of your business.
You've signaled virtue All this time,
the do-gooder... and played
While the contrary is true.
Put a sock in it!
Not to mention you!
To the students every
day, Playing super teacher
while only having one thing on your mind.
Volleyball and barbecues?
Don't make me laugh! You
are an incompetent fool.
And an adulterer to boot!
A disgrace to us all
drawing your victims Not to mention
young colleagues. from defenseless
What makes you think I'm defenseless?
Because.
Women are a priori victims to you?
Woman might take what she wants?
Have you ever considered a
So you're a floozy.
No, I'm a modern woman.
Ever heard of casual sex, Mrs. Lohmann?
What's that supposed to mean?
And will get you into trouble.
Mr. Mertens seduced you
Yes. Me in trouble?
I only do what I please. On the contrary,
With whom is a matter of some indifference.
What? But...
I thought we were something special.
Come off it, Peter.
On grubby equipment room
mats You think fooling around
between dirt and high bar
of a beautiful relationship?
Was the beginning
I risked my marriage for you.
And my career.
That's on you. I sure didn't.
I just like doing married men.
Personally addressed, Not that I feel
but what's so good about it?
It's simple:
They treat you nicer than their wives.
They make more of an effort in bed.
They get lost quick to get
back to their families.
They don't bug you on the weekend.
On stupid little holidays.
They don't want to go
And they always have bad consciences.
It's fun.
It's all relish and no regret.
Repulsive.
I wanted to share everything with you.
All my free periods.
You two apparently share one brain.
Sara!
Don't make a scene.
This is truly a pitiful
performance, Mr. Mertens.
Behold the disappointment.
He's not used to dealing with real women.
Enough with the innuendo.
It was always the other way
around for the big stud.
Women were your toys,
inasmuch as schoolgirls
can be called women.
Affairs with schoolgirls?
Is that true? You had
Of course not.
Of course he did.
That's why you changed schools.
It's all slander. Dr. Clausen
told me as much.
Then tell us the truth, Peter.
You all know how it is. Fine.
Just admitted it herself. Ms. Schuster
grab whatever they want. These young things
if it's a married man They don't care
- they're dealing with.
- Cry me a river.
You mean to cast yourself as the
victim of what might be minors?
No, they were all 18.
You're so nauseating.
A most apt epithet.
Great. That's all I need. Thank you.
Boss, I know you said to forget
about it, but I couldn't.
I checked the cell number.
The phone belongs to a kid It turns out
called Benjamin Mehltau.
Does he go to school? And where
Rudi-Dutschke High.
Beinacker!
It's Friday afternoon.
Let alone this "Male-Towel" kid.
No one's still at school,
If we want to get him,
straight to his house. we should go
Mm-hm.
And go to "Mail-Turd's" house.
Get some officers
Really go to town on his ass. Go to town.
To shit his pants! I want the kid
Hello.
Heh. Sorry, I didn't quite catch that.
I'll fetch my husband. One second.
Harald?
Can I help you?
As to remove your helmet,
Maybe you'll be so kind
Is your son Benjamin home? Right.
I'll have to ask my wife. I don't know.
One second, please.
You'd like to see Benjamin.
Yes. Is he in? No.
Where could we find your son?
I can't quite say.
He and his friends meet at that
skate park beneath the bridge.
Tell him dinner's at 7:00.
If you do see Benjamin,
Thanks!
So now? Time's up.
Explain to me why Mr. Engelhardt
was wrong in his evaluation.
Mr. Engelhardt will enter the
point in his little notebook.
Anything to add, Mr. Engelhardt?
No.
Fine. Anyone else?
Mm-hm.
You had over an hour.
And I imagine
petty-minded bureaucratic crap.
You wasted it on
made good use of the last hour.
I, on the other hand,
By doing what?
I thought about you all.
And about what possessed
you to punish my son
for still being a child in so many ways.
Nobody is accusing your son of that,
but now you mention it,
as the "coming-of-age" test.
The baccalaureate is known
It's supposed to indicate
a certain maturity.
What my notes indicate That's not
in the case of Prohaska filius.
He doesn't have what it
takes to do a baccalaureate.
You have what it takes to be a teacher?
Indeed. I've had nigh 40 years' experience.
Latin was still alive when he began.
So you could teach us what integrity is,
you being a splendid
example to the children?
From saying as much, but...
Modesty prevents me
yes, absolutely.
Interesting.
What are those files? What's that?
Your personnel records.
Where did you get them? What the hell?
In the principal's filing cabinet. MANFRED:
Now read them to each other.
No one's reading my file.
On examining your files,
one starts to wonder
what gives you the right to judge my son.
Or, as Mr. Engelhardt might have it:
Ex iniuria ius thing-a-majig.
You what?
Ex iniuria ius non oritur.
Right doesn't arise from injustice.
My opinion remains
unchanged: You're insane.
I was by no means only referring
to you, Mr. Engelhardt.
Are also morally dubious. Your colleagues
Sorry, Mr. Prohaska, but
we've already learned
plenty about ourselves today.
That an extra point for my
son Yet not enough to conclude
would be the most minor
mistake of your lives.
I don't doubt it,
but sadly there was no unanimity.
It's three to three.
Wrong!
I've changed my mind.
Fine, then it's four against two.
In Fabian's favor.
I said it had to be unanimous. Screw that.
So if you won't read them to each other,
I'll reveal who you're all
dealing with respectively.
But we know that.
Not in your case.
Mr. Arndt.
You act like everyman's friend,
but in reality, you send your
colleagues to the slaughter.
What? Come on.
I'm not listening to this. Arndt, sit.
Would you like to hear Mr. Engelhardt,
Mr. Arndt made of you? the evaluation
Not in the least.
"Engelhardt is a
cold-hearted, petty bourgeois
students and colleagues alike.
Whose pedantry torments
His megalomania alone
outstrips his vanity."
put it better myself.
I couldn't have
You don't come off any better.
"Peter Mertens is infantile,
and character-wise professionally
ineligible for promotion.
He distinguishes himself at parties
by being overly sociable
to female colleagues.
An embarrassing millstone P.M.
could be termed
around the school's neck."
Wow.
On to Mr. Vogel. MANFRED:
"Vogel is an opportunist and a square.
He has a stench, Furthermore,
and appears unkempt and neglected,
the baccalaureate ceremony." even at
he got your name right. Hm. At least
"Heidi Lohmann MANFRED:
thoroughly frustrated governess.
Is the prototype of the
nor an understanding of youth.
She has neither charm,
She'll be grudgingly kept until retirement,
and then forgotten."
Heidi.
Would you care to comment? MANFRED:
Why did you do it?
It's hard to explain.
Sorry.
I apologize.
Why, Holger?
Everyone expected Mr. Engelhardt
to be appointed principal.
Then, to everyone's surprise,
Mr. Eckhoff was brought in from outside.
He made me an offer.
What kind of offer?
He said he didn't know the staff,
and asked me to put
something together for him.
After Engelhardt's pensioning He said
plus the... corresponding...
I'd get the deputy post
his parking space.
Fuck. Here come the cops.
Maybe we should dispose
of the doobie, guys.
That shit is over the top. I guess so.
Mr. Arndt's dossiers.
Most revealing, MANFRED:
But the other personal
files aren't bad, either.
Mr. Mertens... Hm?
We've already discussed me.
Sorry to disappoint,
They all know.
You're said to have had
up to four student lovers at a time.
You're scum.
Who's been saying that all along?
I don't have anything on you. Ms. Schuster,
You're a clean slate.
She likes doing married men.
I'm quite new here. I'm a trainee.
Then you'll learn a lot today.
Do you have the impression
You could say that again.
Pursue the education your colleagues
of the children? and well-being
You want an honest answer?
This school has zero interest No,
in the students attending it.
My dear young colleague. That's nonsense,
It's not.
Remember last week's big conference?
We discussed if the school
day should begin at 9:00.
Has long since established Chronobiology
improves performance. that a later start
aren't awake at 8:00. Young people simply
Their first class is a waste.
Scientifically proven. This has been
Proven? How so?
And always will begin at 8.
School always has,
That's stood the test of time.
One could simply try it.
Other schools have been
trying it for a while.
Only not this one. Why not?
Ah.
There were two arguments against it.
Number one:
his wife's cheese store on time.
Mr. Mertens here has to be at
if school ends later. He won't make it
Family reasons apply to about
thirty other staff members.
All schedules and bus times Number two:
would have to be adjusted.
That would mean work.
Precisely as they did So things went
over the last hour in this room:
Everyone against everyone
else and each for his own.
If you want the truth:
No one here is interested in your son.
Mm-hm.
And you still want to be a teacher?
Believe it or not, yes.
To do things differently.
That's so naive, it hurts. Outrageous!
Is that your students What's outrageous
can only reach you by fax.
The test of time, too. That's stood
This school's never heard of digitization.
Though home schooling is now so topical,
no one here is interested.
Is in the secretary's office.
The only router
one email address. The school has
They shut themselves off, can't be reached,
There are also budget concerns.
And nay-say innovation.
You're just praying you retire Come off it.
Before this broken system
collapses around you.
That's a harsh allegation.
What if Ms. Schuster's right,
and you're all just sitting it out
at the expense of our children?
Come off it!
You act like we're to
blame for every E or F.
You go face a fifth-grade class
full of screaming kids.
Prepare lessons for 16-year-olds
who tell you to your face
what they can google. they won't learn
who threaten to sue Talk to parents
if their spawn repeats a year.
Or worse!
What do you expect?
You get three months' vacation yearly.
In which I attend training
courses, among other things.
Things aren't that simple, Mr. Prohaska.
That every single one
of us I can assure you
has good intentions.
Maybe you once did. But
nothing remains of them.
You'll go the way of steam engines
after the discovery of electricity,
being washed away by digitization.
It'll be no loss whatsoever.
And by the looks of it,
How dare you, you vile wench?
Wiggle your butt, You come here,
seduce a married man and imagine
you're a pedagogical authority.
It's absurd.
No, it's just time.
The school has to change
as must its teachers.
If the school is to be
reformed by people like you,
God help us all.
What do you like least about Ms. Schuster?
Or unapologetic opinion? Her butt
tell me how to do my job.
I won't let some floozy
Ms. Schuster in the face, too?
Or else you'll punch
Once.
It happened once.
It's all in here.
You will not detail that
in front of everyone.
Injustice for all.
Was Paula Sonsbeck. The girl's name
An insufferable girl,
a downright harlot.
And what did she do?
She made my blood boil.
That morning, she and her
friends were going upstairs.
I had homework and my bag, a heavy load.
And the dizzy-lizzies were cackling away.
I squeezed by them,
and she tripped me.
Seriously?
At least, she almost did. HEIDI:
not to loiter there. I told the girls
They should go to or prepare
for their next class,
instead of striking
poses like scarlet women.
Pretty young women SARA:
prostitutes for you. are automatically
Yes.
No.
It's how they talk and dress,
and lack of decency! their directness
everything is displayed.
Nothing is a secret,
The dirt, greed and... Love of life?
For Shakespeare's
sonnets, One can feel love
a string quartet or even a little couplet.
But what young people today rejoice in
is nothing but base instinct.
Is all about screwing. Shakespeare
Even gym teachers know that.
To cut a long story short, MANFRED:
and the girls didn't back off.
Mrs. Lohmann started a fight
The girl offended me deeply.
Well, you called her a prostitute.
There were many witnesses. Repeatedly.
A teacher can't start something.
You started it.
Paula Sonsbeck's insult was in retaliation.
What did she say?
I will not repeat it.
"Unfuckable shrew." Here it says:
You hit Paula Sonsbeck so
hard, she lost a tooth.
That'll teach her. Her
parents reported you.
There was disciplinary action.
Your pay was cut.
Your promotion suspended.
You had to apologize to the student.
If you say so. Right?
You despise youth. All that because
Maybe you're just envious of the girls?
If you say so, Stasi-Arndt.
Listen: I don't hate the young.
I just can't stand them. Hm.
To make you so hard-hearted?
What on earth happened
Your softness,
understanding and tenderness:
They're not worth it.
You only get disappointed.
You're better off without
that romance nonsense.
Then you don't get hurt. So you were hurt?
None of your business. Like I said:
That's true. SARA:
But maybe others, or at least we,
would treat you differently
if we knew you have a heart
that beats for someone or something.
Georges Moustaki.
Hm?
Sorry?
Georges Moustaki, the greatest
chansonnier of all times
with the most beautiful
lyrics, for Edith Piaf, too.
I admired him as a young woman.
From high school in 1976, After I graduated
I even followed his tour
through half of Spain and all of Portugal.
♪ No ♪
♪ I am never alone ♪
♪ With ♪
♪ My solitude ♪
Once I was very close to him.
In Lisbon.
And again. I loved him.
I had to see him again
I still do.
I waited behind the venue.
Monsieur Moustaki! YOUNG HEIDI:
in my homemade jeans skirt...
And I stood there
and sassy jacket. Evening.
I'm a great admirer of your art.
Thanks very much.
Very pretty.
Pleasant evening.
Ooh-la-la.
Then there was this little slut,
her tits almost tumbling out.
That hurt you. I understand
But that happens to many girls
who fall in love with a pop star.
It passes.
Yeah...
Superficial crushes may pass,
and everyone is interchangeable.
When there's no foundation
with Moustaki within me. But I had a future
I lived for the man. I lived with him.
I had children with him, a family.
You're crackers, Mrs. Lohmann.
Well, Mr. Mehltau,
let's get to it:
Why the hell did you do it?
Don't you know it's punishable?
It was a herbal cigarette.
No biggie.
Show me your phone.
I don't have it on me.
Are you shitting me?
I don't have my cell on me. No.
By whom? It was confiscated.
Who's Mrs. Lohmann? Mrs. Lohmann.
A teacher? At my school?
Rudi-Dutschke High?
During morning recess. She took it from me
You made no calls from it this afternoon?
How?
Mrs. Lohmann has my cell.
What the hell are you doing?
What does it look like? I'm having a smoke.
The smoking gym teacher. How fitting.
Athletes are people who smoke and drink
And still perform without a kink
Sit back down.
Shoot me if you must,
but I need a cigarette.
Where's my damn lighter?
Smoking is prohibited
throughout the building.
Our Chemical Lover is back.
Call me Our Chemical Lover again.
Mr. Prohaska, tell Our Chemical
Lover not to wet himself.
If you start a fire
here, I'll extinguish it.
I'm warning you.
Oh, yeah, Chemical Lover?
Really?
Pity, I was hopeful.
Same here.
Can we finish up? MANFRED:
There's only one left.
Mr. Infallible.
Propriety personified.
Go on, play your trump,
so your little mind can find some peace.
Let me summarize.
Class 10a wants to take a trip to Rome
of the Latin language. to the roots
Homeroom Teacher Engelhardt
creates a varied schedule,
and finds a hotel and a bus company.
And divides them by 28 students.
He then calculates the costs
This makes for a contribution
of 410 euros per participant,
including travel, hotel, and admission fees
for museums and educational institutions.
So?
But that's not the real price.
In fact, the bus operator
had bribed Mr. Engelhardt
to get the contract.
The hotel price was wrong, too.
A discount for years, It had given him
pass along to his students.
Which Engelhardt didn't
And he also hid the fact
that he charged his students
for individual tickets,
but ordered group ones.
Every student 410 euros in cash
So he collects from each and
though the actual price per person
Mr. Engelhardt? was how much,
Hm?
295 euros.
Ah. So each student is paying
you 115 euros too much.
With a class of 28, that makes...
Well? Say it, it's all in there.
It is.
3220 euros.
Not bad, old lad. And who
knows how often you did it?
I did it once.
Her gall bladder operation. My wife had
a year abroad in London. My son was doing
The car was broken.
Do you know what it costs to feed a family?
Yes, I do.
I still don't steal.
It all blew up in your face
noticed the group-ticket trick.
Because two smart-asses
They confronted you,
and you threatened to
discipline them with bad grades.
Klaus.
Is this really true?
First you steal from
children and their parents,
to wiggle out of the affair?
Then you use such means
Klaus!
I paid it all back
and never became principal because of it.
What more do you want?
For years, you've acted the role model
and worn a halo of infallibility
after committing such a lapse?
Klaus, I don't understand.
How can you hit a girl for being
joyful, carefree, and pretty?
Let me recap:
A brawler,
a snitch,
a pornographer, an adulterer,
and a con man
are to decide
if my son is or is not entitled
to one single additional point.
You think that's fair?
It seems a justice gap has emerged.
I'm appealing to you again, Mr. Engelhardt.
Under the circumstances,
and because none of us are flawless,
how about that point?
Kiss my ass.
Mr. Prohaska said it himself. Klaus!
Ex iniuria ius non oritur.
Right does not arise from injustice.
He meant that because of our wrongdoing,
to pass judgment on his son.
We have no right
But it's a double-edged sword:
Our having been taken hostage is wrong,
and no putative right may arise from it.
Then one injustice must outweigh the other.
Our failings have nothing
to do with our grading.
Our having been taken hostage,
is a direct result of it. however,
So it's the greater wrong.
Stop twisting things, you asshole!
My son is getting that point now.
When the school explodes...
Or the moment has come...
I'm begging you,
let me go make sure things are fine.
One way or the other. We're nearly done,
Mr. Engelhardt, please reconsider:
still find that point? Where might we
more intriguingly still: Or, wait,
How did the point disappear? Hm?
What do you mean? Maybe he had 5 points
and one was deducted.
Has very scrupulous methods
Our colleague surely
to deprive students of points:
Poor handwriting here,
stained homework there, things like that.
Open your little notebook Mr. Engelhardt,
and tell us what it says. Hm?
It's none of your damn business.
And check for myself. I swear I'll take it
You wouldn't understand my
system, anyway.
Of tallying up points and marks
It's a sophisticated method
that takes into account all the
parameters conceivably relevant
in assigning grades.
Namely? Topic-relevant quality,
style of presentation, that is, neatness.
Correctness I rate as a priority,
at about 71 percent. weighing it
Then comes style and handwriting,
of an oral performance, or the eloquence
if it's not written work,
in further deductions, that can result
additional points. or, rarely,
Now I want to know concretely, what...
get for his assignment? What did Fabian
What is entered there?
Grades.
And which is the grade?
Fine.
I'll give in to the pressure.
A D grade, as you knew. Here you go.
I bet that's noted there.
Were there deductions?
You do. I don't have to tell you.
Or I'll break your fingers to get that.
One point.
"One point" what?
Had to be deducted.
Because of tardiness. Why?
Meaning what?
Handed his work in late. The student
How much too late? Explain what that means.
I'd agreed with the class It's simple:
that the big assignment had to
be with me by Tuesday at 1:00.
Everyone was punctual except Mr. Prohaska,
with his assignment. who was late
By how much?
Two.
"Two" what?
Days? Weeks?
What? Minutes.
He handed it in Two minutes.
While babbling something
about a jammed printer.
Among young people. A ruse typical
Everyone was on time except Fabian,
a one-point deduction. so he got
How was my son's assignment?
Fair in terms of content.
A tendency towards six, Five points.
But not enough to give them.
And a one-point deduction for tardiness.
You shitbag. PETER:
hypocritical old shitbag. You repulsive,
Two miserable minutes!
Two minutes?
He's not baccalaureate material
because of two minutes?
It's a question of justice!
The rest were on time.
Small-minded malice and
power, No, it's a question of
you miserable old bastard.
Klaus!
Give me the notebook.
Who loves chemicals now?
Klaus!
Now... we vote.
Okay, come on.
Oh, man.
Fine.
Now we vote.
Of awarding one point? All those in favor
Klaus, I'm sorry.
With you anymore. I can't go along
You can't pocket money from a class trip,
while sealing a student's fate
because of a two-minute delay.
That won't do.
It won't do!
Raise your hand now.
Go on, Engelhardt, raise it.
Raise your hand!
Please, Mr. Engelhardt, please.
So this all finds an end.
I will not raise my hand. Never.
Give him the point, Engelhardt.
Klaus, do it!
Do it.
Just do it, Engelhardt.
Police!
Drop the gun!
Drop it!
Down on the ground!
On the ground!
Get down!
That's right, nice and easy. EMT:
Just around here.
Take a step up.
And be seated.
Go buy some. Got a spare smoke?
Snitch.
Dick.
Listen, officer,
I need to get into my chemistry room.
You're staying here. We need a statement.
I've told you all I know.
With something else. You'll come up
Beinacker!
How are things? It's all fine.
Good work. No injuries.
Nothing beats experience and intuition.
I didn't mean you. Thanks, Boss.
Can I use my phone?
I'm afraid not.
I just wanted to call my wife.
May I, please?
I can't remove the cuffs,
but I can unlock your phone
and put it on speaker.
Thanks.
It's here, in my pocket.
The code is:
1, 2,
3, 4.
You have voicemail.
Want me to play it for you? I won't listen.
Worried that I missed dinner.
It'll be my wife,
My son will be waiting, too.
I fought for him.
Hey, Dad. It's Fabi. VOICEMAIL:
Listen, the thing is...
where you are right now, I don't know
but by the time you get home,
well, I'll be gone.
I'd wanted to tell you yesterday, but...
after our conversation. I didn't dare
You were so upset.
I've thought about the baccalaureate,
studying and all that.
Maybe Engelhardt is right. You know,
university material. Maybe I'm not
And maybe I shouldn't
take the baccalaureate,
but do something else.
Maybe that one point is like a sign
on the wrong track. that I've been
I know it's a bit late, but...
to me yesterday, and he said
Engelhardt came and talked
as an opportunity I should take it
to change my perspective.
I guess he's right.
He's pretty okay, really.
So what I wanted to say,
is you don't have to be pissed with him
about that one damn point.
Really. It doesn't matter.
Anyway, I think I just
need to get away for a bit.
I got from Grandma for my 18th.
I took the money
It's enough for a ticket to...
you know, to go surfing.
Okay.
I gotta go.
In a couple of months, that is.
But I'll be back soon.
Then I'll start something else.
You'll see.
So don't worry now, okay?
Okay.
Don't worry. I'll be in touch.
Bye, Dad.
Yours, Fabi.
THORSTEN MERTEN 1 YEAR 6 MONTHS