- Shut up!
- No!
We got it, we got it. We got it, here.
- Please, please, please.
- Look, look.
- That's nice.
- Good, we're good. We're good.
Don't!
You fuck.
Come on, Maggie.
Are you the one causing all the trouble?
Lee!
Lee! Lee!
- Breathe, breathe, honey.
- Okay.
You're gonna be fine. Breathe.
- Drink.
- Thank you.
It's oxygen for you.
This is crazy weather.
- Okay, you're gonna be fine.
- Oh, God.
- Gonna be fine.
- I thought I had it under control.
Yeah, well, that's what I said
about my second marriage,
and look at me.
I thought you quit.
If Pilar asks, I did.
- I'll have to remember that.
- Mm-hmm.
I thought you were scared of heights.
I'm claustrophobic, Lee.
I'm not afraid of heights.
Hell, the only thing
I'm scared of is my wife.
What is going on, Lee?
You told me you'd be done.
- I'll fix it. I'll fix it.
- How? How are you gonna fix it?
I'll talk to her. No problem.
Hey, that's my locker.
You can't just go through my stuff.
Maggie, I got this.
It's not your stuff. Not anymore.
My deal's with Lee, not with you.
Well, what does Lee have to do with this?
You don't pay, you can't stay. Period.
Maggie, listen. Maybe we can give him
- another month, okay?
- Yeah.
- I already put it in the system.
- I know.
You can't take it off the block.
I'm not moving till she puts my lock
back on this locker.
Lee, what the fuck?
- You said you were gonna fix it.
- I will.
- Show me. Fix it. Do something.
- Hey, please.
- I'll buy you a beer and we'll talk.
- Buy me a beer?
Yes.
She could use a beer.
- I know.
- Not me.
I got you this.
What the hell's that?
- Something for your wall.
- Where'd you get it?
No, thanks.
- Are you angry?
- Nope.
You did what you had to do. Right?
Then why don't you take the trout?
It's a bass, not a trout.
I know. I was just testing you.
Is Pilar coming to get you?
Yes. She's coming. Any minute.
Are you going to the park for lunch?
Yup.
Do you want me
to close out Harris's account?
You should be the one getting credit
from corporate.
- Credit?
- Sure. He's your customer.
Maggie, we just stole the man's things.
You shouldn't gloat.
Hi.
You don't pay, you can't stay.
Not another one.
What the heck?
Maggie?
Lee.
The light was blinking.
- I thought maybe it...
- Go home.
I'll lock it up.
Whose locker is this?
It's for a friend, off the books.
You aren't going to report me, are you?
No. No, of course not.
Go home.
Philadelphia police are still
investigating a diamond heist
that left one woman dead last week
in the famed jewelry district.
The two thieves are considered
armed and dangerous.
So, how much did they get?
Official numbers not immediately released,
but some police sources say
the number could be in the millions.
Come on. You better be
on your phone this time.
Your service is temporarily disconnected.
- For further assistance, please call...
- Damn it!
What are you doing?
Happy birthday.
Blow out your candle.
I can't believe you.
I know it's not till tomorrow
but I just thought, why not?
Why are you spending money on presents?
We need that money for real food.
It's… It's my money.
Your money?
Where are you getting money from?
- I got a job.
- Really?
Teacher's assistant after school.
- Since when?
- Just... Whatever, Mom. It's for you.
Yeah, well, the rent's not due
for another ten days.
Freddy said he's gonna come by later.
Such a vagina.
Tarin.
Daddy used to say it all the time.
- Here, try some. It's really good.
- No, I don't want any.
- Mom, just try some.
- I don't want any!
- You hate everything.
- No.
- Yeah, you do.
- I've…
Hey, Freddy.
Look, I didn't wanna bother ya
'cause I know how hard
it's been since Rich left.
He didn't leave, Freddy. He went to jail.
- I need the two months, by tomorrow.
- What are you talking about?
I just paid you.
Your last check bounced.
I can't cover for ya anymore.
Well, how am I supposed to get
two months' rent?
Tomorrow or I gotta ask you to leave.
Sorry.
Freddy, please. Can...
Can you just give me
till next week to figure this out?
Please?
Freddy, you gotta help me out.
I'm begging you.
Well, maybe there's
an arrangement we can come to.
- Come on, Freddy. I'm married.
- Not from where I stand.
I'd rather sleep in my car.
You may have to.
- Mom?
- Yeah?
Is everything okay?
You got a beautiful daughter.
God. Come on.
Are we gonna have to move out?
Why would you say that?
I heard Freddy say
we're gonna have to move into our car.
Come here.
What do I always say?
- That only God can make us do anything?
- That's right.
So did God make Dad go away?
Dad made Dad go away.
That is not how I remember it.
I'm not having this conversation
with you again, Tarin.
Come here. Read.
"Men do not despise a thief if he steals
to satisfy his soul when he is hungry."
But if he be found,
he shall restore sevenfold.
"He shall give all the substance
of his house."
What does sevenfold mean?
Tarin. Shoelaces.
- I'm driving.
- No, no, no!
No way! Give me that back.
Mom, don't be such a vagina. Come on.
What did you just call me?
Okay, I'm sorry.
Happy birthday. Can I drive?
What if you get
into an accident or something?
Well, how am I gonna learn
how to drive, Mom?
Mom, come on, let's go. Mom!
- What are we doing here?
- Just stay here. I'll be right back.
Okay.
What am I doing?
Oh, my God. Lee!
Hello? Hello?
Oh, my God.
- Hey.
- Turn that off!
- Geez. Turn that off!
- What? God! Fuck.
- What's wrong?
- Something happened to my boss.
I think he may be hurt.
Your service is temporarily...
- Shit!
- Did you just curse?
- Do as I say, not as I do, Tarin.
- Great, Mom.
All right, just stay in here
and keep the doors locked, okay?
- Okay. Wait, you're taking the keys?
- Yes.
I'm driving when I come home.
Please, just let me go,
and tomorrow I'll get your money.
We can't wait anymore.
Now, we need our money tonight.
You think I'm stupid, huh?
Are you nuts? Are you crazy?
Every cop in Philly is looking for you!
I don't give a shit. It has to be tonight.
You saw it in the news
and you thought we'd blow town,
that you could keep our money?
Tonight, Lee. Tonight.
- No more waiting.
- Okay.
You go get our money
and put it in two bags
- like we asked.
- Please, you gotta believe me.
I don't... I don't have your money.
- I don't...
- We want the diamonds.
- Yeah, you see...
- The woman you killed, she had a family…
- So what?
- So what!
It means you guys got
a bounty on your head.
No fence in town will touch your property,
so settle the fuck down.
They're in one of these lockers,
aren't they?
Yeah. I already told you,
your property is safe.
What happened to you, man?
I fucking looked up to you.
- Look at you now! You're a fucking mess!
- I should say that to you!
You… You really spoke to the cops, Lee?
- You spoke to the fucking cops?
- What? What?
Hey, don't!
Lee! Fuck, man!
Why did you do that? Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Lee! Lee!
- Fuck! We're fucked now, man!
- Yeah.
Who are we gonna get…
How are we gonna get the diamonds?
Fuck! Look, look! Man, look!
We got a fucking bigger problem now.
Fuck, let's take him in...
Let's put him inside.
Tarin.
Tarin!
Tarin! Oh, my God…
Damn it. Where is she?
- Tarin.
- I'm in here.
Tarin. Oh, my God.
- Tarin. Tarin.
- I'm in here.
- Tarin.
- In here.
Tarin. Open the door.
I'm on the toilet! Weirdo.
- Open this door right now.
- I can't. It's literally like, coming out.
- Please, open the door.
- Mom!
What is that?
- Tarin, stay in there, okay?
- Okay.
- Keep the door locked. Don't say anything.
- Okay!
Oh, God!
Sorry, I thought you were Lee.
We… We're friends of his.
What are you doing here?
He gave us access to our locker,
just for the night.
He shouldn't have done that.
Yeah, well, like I said,
we're close friends.
You work here?
Yes.
I'm Margaret,
but everyone calls me Maggie.
- Can I offer you some coffee?
- Sure. Mel, coffee?
I can get you a clean one.
That'll be good.
Do you want… cream or sugar?
Lots of sugar. What kind is it?
- Kind?
- Yeah…
Costa Rican, Brazilian, Kenyan, what?
It's American, I think.
Where… Where are you from?
I live about a half hour away.
No, I mean, "Where are you from?"
A small town in Florida.
You probably never heard of it.
What, Disney World?
- Lakeland.
- I know it.
Well, not many people do.
I grew up north of Tallahassee.
My old man was a truck driver.
My stepdad was a truck driver.
Maybe they knew each other.
Well, I could care less who he knew.
My old man was a piece of shit.
- Sorry, is it too much sugar?
- Tastes like dookie.
Sorry, Lee bought it.
I see his taste in art
is the same as his coffee.
It's got its charm.
- Maggie, right?
- Uh-huh.
Look, Lee hasn't been
really helpful with us lately.
You know how he can be
a stubborn old geezer.
I don't follow.
What I'm saying is,
I think we can help each other out.
In what way?
Lee and I, we made a deal, off the books.
Okay.
I need something
that he kept for us in a locker.
The only thing is,
I don't know which locker.
And I don't wanna bother
the old man again.
What do you want me to do?
Help us find the locker.
You do, and the $2,000
in my pocket is yours.
- What is the name on the locker?
- Lee Fenton.
I could get fired if Lee finds out.
You want it, or not?
Come on.
Where are you going?
Stop!
Hold it. Hold it! Stop.
Who was in the bathroom?
He asked you a question.
There's no one.
There's nobody here but me.
Let her go, Mel. Let her go. Let her go.
Let her go.
What?
Pick her up.
Let me out of here!
Let me go! Let me go!
Calm down.
I get... I get panic attacks.
- Calm the fuck down, lady.
- I can't be inside a space that small.
- Please, please, please.
- You claustrophobic?
- Yes.
- Let her go. Let her go.
- Let me go. Let me go.
- Let her go.
Breathe.
- Just breathe.
- Oh, my God!
Sorry about that.
We had no other place to put him.
Why did you kill him?
- He lied to me.
- To us.
See, Lee was a scumbag
that pretended not to be one.
For me, that's worse than
admitting who you are and accepting it.
Are you gonna do something to me?
Look at it this way, Maggie.
You either help us out, or you can go back
to playing house with Lee, there.
It's up to you.
You see…
the lockers are empty.
Maybe what you want isn't here.
Maybe I didn't make myself clear.
We're not leaving here
until we get what we want.
You understand?
Let's walk.
I can't find any other locker
registered to Lee.
- Those are the only two.
- We don't have all night.
Lee had to have had
another locker besides 206.
This is a waste of time.
She can't help us.
If you can do better,
then why don't you do it?
Your husband put up with that lip?
My husband doesn't live with us.
Us?
My daughter.
She's very young. If I don't
get home soon, she gets scared.
- She knows you're here?
- Yes.
This is bullshit!
Calm down, Mel, calm down.
Okay.
Talk.
There was another name.
I didn't think anything of it,
but Lee inputted it this week.
So what?
So I'm usually the one who does that
because he hates computers.
What's the name?
Harris.
Keys.
What?
Give me your fucking car keys.
- Why?
- We need your car, Maggie.
Can't have cars in the parking lot.
Too suspicious.
Don't make me ask again.
You control her or I will.
So, your husband leave you
for another woman? Nope!
That's not it
'cause you still got that ring.
Can I get something from my car first?
Wait, I got it.
He left you for the babysitter.
Only thing is, she's your younger sister.
No?
Please, I need to get to my car.
What is it, your purse?
- Mel's not the thief. I'm the thief.
- No, it's not my purse.
Whatever it is, it can wait.
I wanna know more about your husband.
I'm not telling you
anything else about my life.
Why, 'cause it's so goddamn boring?
- You remind me of my husband.
- How is that?
He used to joke like you all the time,
and then he got caught.
This is it.
- So, he… he's in prison, huh?
- Yes.
How old is your kid?
Seventeen.
I always wanted kids.
I don't like this place.
It reminds me of prison.
What were you in prison for?
Armed robbery, assault,
whatever came my way.
- What about your husband?
- Armed robbery.
So, why'd you marry him?
- I'm sorry?
- Come on.
I'm not the first person to bring it up.
You're more likely
to be his mom than his girl.
What is that supposed to mean?
Look at you. You're like a goody two-shoe.
What are you doing with a bad boy?
I thought you were a thief.
What's taking you so long?
I'm working on it.
Now you're sounding more like my old lady.
My husband, Rich, saved me.
What, you were drowning?
Let's just say, no one's perfect.
So then what, you tried to change him?
He married me when I got pregnant.
He didn't have to.
If he was such a good guy,
why is he in prison?
We were happy.
That wasn't good enough for him.
Once a crook, always a crook.
Fucking slobs.
Okay.
What are we looking for?
None of your business.
Well, if you tell me what it is,
I can find it quicker. Is it money?
No.
Then what is it?
Just keep pulling stuff out, will you?
We both want the same thing, Ross.
- What's that?
- For you to leave.
- You want us out?
- Yes.
There's 200 uncut diamonds
in a black velvet pouch.
You help me find that pouch,
I'll give you Lee's cut.
I don't want anything from you.
I just want you gone.
No one's a saint, Maggie, not even you.
Well, at least I can sleep at night.
What'd you say? What'd you say?
Listen. I ain't a killer.
But someone crosses me,
they get what's coming.
And I sleep just fine.
You hear me? Just fine.
Ross.
What's the holdup?
It's not here.
- I can't hear you.
- It's not here!
You gotta press the button.
The black thing.
It's... It's not here.
- It's gotta be.
- We've looked, man.
- Did you move her car?
- Yeah.
Lock it up on your floor and get up here.
What about the video cameras?
- How do we delete the tapes?
- There's no tapes.
It's a remote system. It sends a signal
to the database off-site.
- So there's no way to delete the footage?
- No, not that I know of.
Fuck it.
We'll be gone before it matters.
Get up here.
Can I help you, Officer?
Maybe he had another locker.
I doubt it.
Where the fuck is Mel? I need a knife.
- For what?
- Open this thing up.
Here we go.
You think he put it in a boxing bag?
You have a better idea?
- No, not really.
- Doesn't work.
Fuck!
Lee seem like the outdoors type to you?
I wish you would stop talking about him
like he's still alive.
I didn't think so, either.
Why would someone using
a fake name to rent a locker
put that name on shit he's got...
Cold out there tonight, huh?
Mm-hmm.
- You have ID?
- Yeah. Right here.
How long you been on the force?
- Two years.
I just wanna say
I'm a big supporter of the police.
I appreciate
all the hard work you guys do.
- Yeah, well, it's a job.
- Yeah.
How come you don't travel in two?
I thought there was always two of ya?
Sometimes.
Want some coffee? I got some coffee.
- No, I don't drink the stuff.
- No?
- First cop I ever met don't like coffee.
- Yeah?
You should ask me if I want a doughnut.
- Mind if I take a look around?
- No, no, go ahead, go ahead.
Where'd the call come from?
The call came from inside the facility.
Copy that.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
Just one more question.
Dispatch said the call came from here.
Well, that's not possible.
I'm the only one here.
I need you to get your hands up.
And lay on the ground, face down. Now!
What's the problem, Officer?
Keep your mouth shut
and lay on the ground.
Take it easy. Look, look.
Everything's all right.
Come on, sweetie. It's okay.
Who the fuck are you?
I think I should be asking you that.
- What's your name?
- Tarin. My mom is...
Tarin! Run!
Mom!
That's why you should travel in twos.
Son of a bitch!
Oh, my God!
Damn it! Where are the keys?
- Oh, my God, what do we do?
- Stay in the car. Shit.
Leave us alone.
- Where's Ross?
- Where's my car?
I only saw one person
come out of that locker.
Show me the key!
- You found them, didn't ya?
- I don't care about the diamonds.
I just wanna leave in my car.
So you do know about the diamonds.
Congratulations.
If I tell you where they are,
will you give me my car keys?
Yeah.
Show me the key.
Where are the diamonds?
Throw me my car key first!
You're a smart little bitch, aren't ya?
If you kill me, you won't ever find them.
- Run to the gate, Tarin!
- Goddamn it!
Tarin, run!
- Let her go!
- Turn that shit off!
- I said turn that shit off, goddamn it,
or I'll snap her fucking neck!
Let go of me, you fucking vagina!
- Some mouth on you, you little tramp.
- Mom!
Put it down. Put it down.
Who the fuck are you?
You're a cop?
You noticed.
This is Officer Harris. Cancel that 10-78.
I'm sorry.
- Backup will be here soon.
- Why can't we just go now?
Sorry, but we're gonna need
full statements from the both of you.
Can't we just do that
in the morning, Detective?
Listen, when the time's right,
you'll be the first ones to go home.
- Where's the other guy?
- You said he was upstairs, right?
Yes, he's locked up in 509.
- My locker?
- It's the only one I could think of.
Nice touch. What about Lee?
How long were you following these guys?
It wasn't them I was following.
- What do you mean?
- I was following Lee undercover.
He was a fence for stolen goods.
We think he's got his fair share stashed
down here somewhere in these lockers.
Bet he's got a ton of shit
hidden up there.
Well, if Lee had any other locker here,
it wasn't under his name.
Did these men tell you anything else?
They were after diamonds.
The thieves responsible
for a diamond heist last week.
Lee had 'em fixed up
with fake passports, the works.
What heist?
Stole $1.2 million in diamonds,
took a hostage.
That hostage is dead, a mother of two.
Oh, my God.
Where are the other cops?
- They're already here.
- Where?
My team is two blocks away,
waiting for my signal.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Lee's buyer. There was a meeting set.
I've been instructed to make sure
that we get the diamonds first.
Oh, my God.
What?
He had a gun.
Ross, the one upstairs,
I left him with a gun.
Find a safe place, lock yourselves in.
I'm gonna find this Ross.
What about the video closet?
Yeah. That's a good idea.
Why does this room have to be so small?
Hey, Mom?
Yes?
Are we gonna make it out of here?
Of course.
That cop…
He killed her right in front of me.
I know, baby.
They did the same thing to my boss.
I'm sorry that I brought you tonight.
Don't be.
I mean, how… how else am I
gonna learn how to drive?
Tarin.
I smoke when I'm nervous.
Where did you get all of this stuff?
Stole it.
I'm a shoplifter. Sorry.
Your grandfather…
He caught me doing the exact same thing.
I promised him that I would stop stealing,
but then I met your father.
Wait.
You were a shoplifter?
Yeah, a long time ago.
- Hey, Mom.
- Yeah?
Happy birthday.
Maggie?
I'm here.
- He's not here.
- What?
He shot his way out.
Can you see anything on the monitor?
There!
Harris, he's on your floor. Get out!
Harris, get out of there, now!
- Mom, do something!
- Don't shout at me, please. I don't know.
Oh, my... Harris.
Thought you were smart, huh?
I know you can hear me. Answer me!
Okay, please, please don't hurt him.
Either you find my diamonds
or the detective here dies.
You have five minutes.
Okay. Okay.
- What are you doing?
- I'm looking for something.
Mom, we should just go.
The cops are two blocks away.
We could go, we could find them,
and we could bring them here.
Detective Harris came back for us.
I can't just leave him up there.
There has to be some weapons
in the lockers that we can use.
- Hello?
- Stop it!
I need you to go into the video closet,
just lock the door. Do you understand?
God, why are you being so stupid?
They're gonna kill us.
I have to help Harris.
It's the right thing to do.
- Really?
- Yes, really.
So were you doing the right thing
when you sold out Dad to the cops?
He wanted to get caught.
He wanted to go away.
But who told them where to find him?
Tarin. He would've been hunted down.
Us, too.
Do you think that your parents in jail
and you in foster care
would have been a better choice?
I did what I had to do.
Why can't you just admit
that you stabbed Dad in the back?
What?
You're the reason my dad
got taken away from me.
You think everything you do is perfect,
but it's not, Mom.
You pushed him away
and you made him feel small.
And you try to control me
the same way you tried to control him.
And soon enough, it's just gonna be you.
Maybe that's just the way you want it.
Ticktock, ticktock. Five minutes are up.
Please, let me help you. You need my help.
No. No.
- You need to go into the video closet.
- No. Mom, no!
Lock the door. If I don't come back soon,
you need to run
as far from here as possible.
Do you understand? Go!
Lee. Lee.
I found it.
What did you do, Lee?
Perfect.
Son of a bitch.
I'm here!
That's a hell of a backswing
you got there, Maggie.
Slow it down.
- I found the locker.
- I'm not sure if I believe you,
but I'm sure you can
understand my distrust.
Slow it down.
- James Lee.
- What?
Lee's real name was James Lee Fenton.
That's how he hid the locker.
James Lee. That sneaky bastard.
Slow it down, man.
Get outta here, Maggie.
He's not gonna let you
or your daughter go.
Daughter? She's here?
Mel's been shot, Ross. It's over.
What the fuck did she say?
I shot him.
I don't fucking believe you!
Look, I have what you want!
Half the force is around the corner, Ross.
If you run now, maybe you make it.
Maybe you don't.
- Stop!
- Shut up!
Don't you fucking move!
Okay.
Fuck.
Come on.
Walk.
Fuck this.
Where are you going?
Who said I'm going anywhere?
I know Lee was getting passports
for you to go somewhere.
Out of the country?
Brazil.
Well, you're gonna have to leave Mel
behind. You can't take him onto a plane.
This is the one.
Wait.
What?
I want five.
I can do $5,000.
No, five percent.
No one knows about this locker
except me and you.
- What the fuck are you saying?
- Whatever we find in there,
I can hold on to it until it's safe
for you to come back and get it.
Your husband taught you well.
Maybe I taught him.
What am I looking for again?
A black velvet pouch.
Ross. Ross.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
I'm downstairs.
I can see you on the monitor.
You okay?
I took one in the shoulder,
but I got the girl.
Where was she?
I caught the little bitch
coming down the elevator.
Please don't hurt her.
You should've thought about that
before you brought her along.
- Just let her go!
- Shut up!
Any sign of more cops?
Just the piece of shit that shot me.
I got him tied up on the fifth.
He ain't going anywhere.
We gotta hurry. The flight's in two hours.
- Okay.
- Mom?
- Tarin!
- Would you shut up!
That's... That's for my head.
- What about the girl?
- Take her to the roof with you.
For what?
The cop says
he's got half the force outside.
Let's call his bluff.
Then what?
If it looks clear, we'll meet you outside.
Get your ass in there.
- Let's go.
- I'm not going to the roof with you.
Get in here.
You a virgin?
What?
It's a legitimate question.
Are you still a virgin?
You're sick.
Judging by that attitude
and the way you look, I'd say no.
You still in school?
Yeah.
How old are you?
I'm 17. Why?
You don't look 17.
God, you're disgusting.
Have you ever even seen a vagina?
Ross.
- What?
- I think there's something in here.
How much is it?
You are a genius.
You really think the cops
are gonna let you see them?
- They're hiding.
- Shut up.
I bet there are 50 of 'em out there.
Yeah.
Half the force, my ass.
Son of a bitch.
There's like 20 grand in here.
Then it'll have to do.
No, fuck that.
- The diamonds are in here somewhere.
- Well, I can find them.
After you leave.
Really?
You would do that for five percent?
It's ten percent now.
Now you are negotiating?
You have nothing to trade with, but…
I can delete the footage.
All of it.
You said you didn't know how.
Do you want the diamonds or not?
The deal stands at five percent.
I can find out where Lee hid the diamonds
by going back
in the footage a couple of days.
- Let's go do it.
- No, I can't do it now.
System doesn't allow access
until the morning.
By then, you'll be gone.
What about the police? They're gonna be
asking for the files, too.
Not if I delete them first.
You fuck me over and it ain't me
you'd have to worry about.
Believe me.
Mel would rather gut you
from side to side,
and your little kid too,
than be sitting on some beach in Brazil,
drinking margarita and shit.
You understand me?
Yeah, so, ten percent?
What else you gonna include
in this ten percent?
Walk.
Slow down. Stay back.
Ross...
Let go of the fucking gun!
Give me the gun! Where are the diamonds?
- I don't know!
- Where are they?
Let him go! They have Tarin!
She'll be fine.
Where are the fucking diamonds?
Harris, listen to me. Mel has Tarin.
Maggie, shut the fuck up.
Where are the diamonds?
My people are around the corner.
They're waiting for my signal.
Where are the fucking diamonds?
Get off!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
- Get the money.
- Harris!
- Get my fucking money.
- Oh, my God, no, Harris.
- Come on, we gotta go. We gotta go!
Hey, asshole!
You alive?
Oh, shit.
God, I thought you were dead.
I guess not.
That cop's already dead, Ross.
Mel killed her.
Where is he?
How would I know?
We'll take this car to pick up our car,
the one you're driving us
to the airport with.
I wanna know where Tarin is.
Where the fuck is Mel?
Mel!
Can't you call him or something?
With what cell phone, huh?
We dumped them. It's too fucking risky.
God. That was smart.
Why don't you fucking figure out
how to fucking delete the footage
or some shit, huh?
Not until I see Tarin!
Mel! Mel! Don't you fucking move. Mel!
Why did you come here tonight?
You could've met Lee anywhere. Why here?
We went to his house.
Paid him and his wife a little visit.
Poor bastard had no idea
we even knew where he lived.
Where's Pilar?
I tell him Mel wasn't fucking joking,
but Lee didn't listen.
My God. What did you do?
I didn't do shit.
Look, I didn't do nothing.
I just let Mel off his chain, that's all.
Is she alive?
If I had to guess, no.
- You fucking bastard!
- Hey, calm the fuck down!
- What did she ever do to you?
- Hey.
- Hey, calm down.
Okay, so just…
Where are my diamonds?
I want my diamonds!
Please. Tarin.
Please, what?
I just want my daughter back.
And I want my fucking diamonds.
Okay. They're on the roof.
Bullshit.
Lee was up there three times this week.
I know they're there.
All right, get your ass up and show me.
Fuck! No shells.
Listen, you stay here
until I can go find your mom, okay?
- No, I'm coming with you.
- Not a good idea.
You stay put.
Stay put.
What the shit?
"Tap to ignite."
Fuck yeah.
Gotcha.
Code, my ass.
This shit ain't even backed up.
Bet you didn't see that one coming.
Yeah.
I'm getting tired of you.
Where are the diamonds?
I don't… I don't… I don't know.
You're not going anywhere, Ross.
At least let someone else enjoy
the fruits of your labor.
Maggie.
She knows where they are?
Suck my...
Suck on that.
Cool.
How much further?
He was always around this back area.
- Now what?
- Now we dig.
- Are you gonna help me?
- No.
Thought you guys had a flight to catch.
Just keep digging.
Fine. But you should know that…
- I made a deal with your partner.
- What deal?
Ten percent of the value.
I guess he figured
you'd be okay with that.
Shut up and find the diamonds.
Or what, you gonna kill me
like you did Lee?
Pilar?
Was that her name?
She wasn't much fun.
- What?
- She didn't put up a fight.
If there's no struggle, it ain't no fun.
You're sick.
You.
You're gonna be fun.
I think I found something.
Show me.
Nice.
Help!
That's for Lee, you piece of shit.
What is that?
Evidence.
Why are you hiding it?
I thought backup was just two blocks away.
No one's calling backup
until I have those diamonds.
You remember?
I thought Lee was your contact. And then...
You're too smart for your own good,
aren't you?
- Wait, you?
- Surprise.
- There is no backup, is there?
- No. Just me.
What about the cop? Aren't they sending
someone to check on her?
They did. I canceled it.
Wait, so you turned into a dirty cop,
just so you could steal some diamonds?
No. Not just any diamonds.
When they're considered stolen,
cops have no incentive to find them.
They just wanna find the guys that did it.
The insurance does the rest.
Then I retire from this shit job
protecting people like you.
I thought you were Lee's friend.
How long you been there, Maggie?
Long enough to hear everything.
The diamonds, where are they?
Where are the rest?
Let her go first.
First, you tell me,
what were you gonna do with this?
I made that before I knew you were a cop.
Last chance, Maggie.
Mom.
- Follow me.
- Hey!
Maggie!
Behave yourself.
I trusted you, Harris.
I haven't trusted anyone in a long time.
You know, I used to be an addict.
I was a junkie.
I was sick.
Just when I…
didn't think that I would make it to 30…
my husband Rich helped me get clean.
It was Rich who saved me
after I OD'd on his couch.
I've done a lot of things
that I'm not proud of,
that I tried to put away,
forget about.
Am I supposed to be impressed?
I already died once.
I'm not afraid of you.
- Mom.
- Tarin, shoelaces.
Goddamn!
Fucking little bitch.
- Where are the keys? Where are the keys?
- They're on the cop's body.
Oh, my God. Come on.
Wait, wait. He won't know the code.
- Damn it.
- Mom!
It still works.
Mom!
Come on.
- Come on.
- Where is he?
Oh, fuck.
Where's Tarin?
You want your diamonds?
Come and get them.
He hid them in here, huh?
Pretty smart.
Not as smart as this.
No! No!
No!
Run, run. Run…
Oh, my God!
Hey, are you sure it's 206 coming up red?
That's what it's showing.
Okay, I'll check it out.
Who turned off the AC?
Maggie? Maggie, you there?
Everything okay?
I'm okay.