VIVA LA LIBERTÁ
Long Live Freedom
- Is there a bathroom?
- If you told me earlier, there was one in the VIP room
- Well I need it now.
- Then we have to go back.
- We are very late.
- If you like, there is the service one.
Real time survey
Enrico Olivieri   17%
Olivieri!
Do you know why you are silent?
Because you never had anything
fucking worth saying! Ever!
Didn't you get that you are
ruining the party?
And that we will stop you?
Didn't you get that you must go?
You must go!
You're a scourge sent
to shut our mouth!
To make us forever harmless servants!
But Time is gentleman,
Secretary.
Sooner or later shame
will paralyze you.
"In the dark night
sparkle stars" (Latin)
You must go!
Enough!
Even Jesus Christ didn't want
to be killed without a trial...
because it's much more shameful
to die through a trial
rather than for a rebellion...
after all...unjust.
Looks good tomorrow?
Then, thanks.
Her name is Federica Civatti, 44 years old
and none of us know her.
Someone sent her on purpose.
You mean them?
Who else?
- Why did she speak Latin?
- She is a high school professor.
This is the data you asked for
the meeting with the European Left.
There is also a draft of the speech.
Have you got something to say to me?
Nothing
See you Andrea, take care.
- Yes?!
- Hi, I called earlier but no answer.
- I just came back.
- I am in Beijing.
I stayed till the conclusion of the
convention, I'm exhausted.
Tonight there was a meeting
at the embassy.
I didn't feel like, but I had to go.
How are you?
Nothing important. I go to bed early
...as usual.
OLIVIERI: CHALLENGED AT
THE NATIONAL ASSEMBLY
I saw on the news about that
woman who defied you
Are you listening?
Yes
You're tired?! Don't get upset.
You know how this country is.
I recommend, have a good sleep.
A kiss.
- A kiss to you too.
- Bye.
- Sorry for the time.
- Come in.
I sleep little.
You are fearful
you are worried...
...and want to be comforted,
but that it's impossible.
We were wrong, we were really
imbeciles to focus on him.
But there was no alternative,
he was and still is the best.
He is, so much so that he'll
save us from a slow death.
What do you mean?
After him, there will be no trace of us!
OLIVIERI
The courage to change
Opposition is dead
and it's your fault
You are wasting our best years.
You talk about change,
party leaders must change first.
It is a sad situation! Enough!
Every year the same story!
Ridiculous and embarrassing!
- Rocchi, where are you?
- At home, why?
His Honor called me at midnight to
say that he would come on his own.
- Has he changed his mind?
- Sorry, but why didn't you tell me?
His Honor said that he told you already.
Sir, what should I do? Should I come?
No, no, stay there.
Eventually I call you back.
But how? Last night he was calm,
he was going to sleep.
- What could have happened?
- Nothing, don't you worry, Anna.
It's just confusion, you'll see he is coming.
Sorry I called you, I apologize
Have a good trip.
Andrea!
What happens?
- No, nothing,
- How nothing? Why isn't he here?
- He had a health problem, cannot come.
- Are you joking?
No, I swear.
- Call him I want to talk to him!
- No, it's off, now you can't.
- Why? Where is he?
- In consultation with a doctor.
He'll call me later.
- Rather, you should communicate that there
was something unforeseen. - Of course.
Enrico!
I go to take a look.
The Prime Minister said ironically
"When fatigue is more than
pleasure, it's time to stop"
Is it a message from His Honor?
No, no. It is something
I left behind.
- Shall we go?
- Yes, please.
I am ready to fight...
but I need a few days on my own to
get back on track.
Andrea will be able to justify my absence
without alarming anybody.
Are you listening Anna?
Yes, keep going.
I will be in touch,
do not worry
It is the price a public figure
must pay sooner or later.
Nothing else.
Where could he be?
I have no idea.
Nobody comes to mind?
A friend?
A politician has no friend.
Is it OK?
What's his name?
Enrico, he's an old friend who I
have not seen for a long time.
He looks lost, has not said
a single word since he arrived.
I think he needs some rest.
I don't know.
Ah, Danielle!
Sorry to show up here all
of a sudden.
I must have created you some
embarrassment.
I just need some time,
to breathe.
Yes, yes
Tell me the truth. Do you think
I am making a mistake?
Yes. I think you're running away,
that you are making a mistake
No, I am not running away.
I am perfectly aware of the consequences
that will be triggered in Rome.
I want to see what these
morons will do without me.
You look better without glasses.
Your husband, your daughter
where are they?
They left early, she goes to school,
he goes to work.
What does he do?
- Director.
- Television?
Cinema.
Do I know him?
Mung!
He's one of the directors I prefer!
You are not the only one, he's
adored like a rock star.
- Did you tell him about me?
- Sure!
- What did he say?
- He said...that you have a beautiful face
- Good morning everybody.
- Good morning
I think it is clear the reason why
the urgency of this meeting today
In light of Secretary's health.
We have to manage a temporary substitution
It's needless to try to hide
That it arrives at a particularly
difficult moment.
Good morning to everybody,
sorry for the delay.
I had to make copies of
Secretary's speech.
Here the machine is broken.
I want to make sure that even today
you get his voice loud and clear
Here you have it.
Bottini, tell us something.
We are all ears.
Well, Enrico is well
and greets everyone.
And you'll be happy to know that
he'll return to his roles in a few days.
- How many?
- I do not know for sure.
Doctors talk of a few days, you know,
with the usual caution in these cases.
Then why doesn't he give interviews?
If he doesn't, he will induce the
suspicion for something serious.
Firstly, for understandable
privacy reasons.
And there is an extremely lucid
political assessment,
that is, images of his
hospitalization may suggest...
...a party in bad health.
Things move differently from the way
you intellectuals see them, Bottini
For me this illness is
an unexpected gift.
Then I ask you,
why don't we use it?
People love human factor,
gossip.
They even love shit, Francesco, it doesn't
mean you ought to give it to them
I say we have to talk
directly with him.
Meanwhile we make him feel our
affection, and then perhaps...
it is better to deal with him about the
public opinion question, isn't it?
- Let's call him?! What do you say?
- Yes, I call him.
No, let me call him.
I'm not in, I cannot answer
It is perfectly useless
to leave messages
Too much stress,
too many ambushes
- You'll see, he'll call you.
- I doubt it.
- Perhaps there is a person who can help us.
- Who?
- Giovanni, his brother.
- The professor, but isn't he....
No, he has left the madhouse.
They believe he's harmless.
The only time he told me about
he said they do not see each other
Do you know why?
I realized that I know nothing
about his young life...
...except the bullshit reported
in the newspapers.
The listless child prodigy,
his passion for film,
his sudden infatuation
for politics...
Bullshit!
Within minutes the president will go
through the Hall of World Maps.
And you could meet him.
If you like to follow me.
Thanks
Mister President.
It seems to me things are not very clear
Is he really sick?
Sure, it is a minor operation
A trifle...which will have
no consequences.
Then why all this mystery?
I know Oliveri since he went
into politics and...
Right now the country cannot afford
inactivity by the opposition.
There are those who cannot wait
to take advantage of the situation.
The Secretary is aware of that,
I assure you it is only a matter of days.
An unexpected condition imposed
few days of hospitalization...
to have a health check-up
to MP Enrico Oliveri...
Secretary of main opposition party.
Causes of Mr. Olivieri's health
problems are unknown.
His colleagues speak of
overwork...
the MP, 50 years old
with a lean physique
has always been in good health.
The President
of Italian Republic
has sent his best wishes for
a speedy recovery
Giovanni Ernani is the pseudonym behind
which hides one of the greatest...
Italian philosophers. Born in Rome
on the 12th of August 1959
Who is it?
Hello, I am looking for information
on a patient of yours.
Professor Giovanni Ernani.
Excuse me, Crocceta Street?
See those houses over there?
I am seeking Professor Ernani
Pardon, who is seeking him?
It's a long story,
a private and personal matter.
I am sorry, but the professor
is not at home.
It's about his brother, Enrico
Is he dead?
No, no, no, no my God!
I am sorry, it wasn't my intention
to scare you.
Why should I get scared?
Excuse me, can we get inside?
Can we talk?
If you like...
Please. Leave it open.
As you can see, I am not
ready to receive.
You like books?
Take it, take it!
At first it will seem
a little tough.
But then, little by little, even one
like you can succeed to understand it.
- Take it.
- Thank you.
Excuse me professor, I wish to ask you...
If we talk, there is a small
restaurant just ten minutes from here.
It's good food.
This time at the clinic
dinner was over.
Any dinner tonight?
Not hungry.
Poor him, tell him to come.
He cannot stay locked in the room!
He can come whenever he likes,
he is not locked up.
Maybe He found
his ideal condition.
At night he could go out
and get some air.
And why not during the day?
He is a person a bit special,
nobody knows he is In Paris,
someone could recognize him.
Why? Who is he?
An Italian politician,
very important.
- Like Hollande or Sarkozy?
- Like Obama!
I am Mung,
please to meet you, take a sit.
- Sit down.
- I do not want to intrude.
I finished my medicine drugs.
If you could tell me
of a chemist open...
No problem, I can even go myself,
and it might be more prudent
No. I'd rather walk a little.
I don't think there is any
particular risk at night.
I go with him,
I like having some fresh air.
Thanks, very kind.
Professor, I do not know
how you can help us
Your brother must have asked
someone for a place to stay
Certainly someone outside
your circle. However...
it's very difficult to enter his head.
Enrico never managed
to be truly himself.
I am sorry
Your Honor!
I'm glad you've recovered.
Do you mind if we exchange a few
words? Maybe a little interview.
Obviously, before publication,
I will let you review it!
- Please.
- Thank you.
And that gray hair...
Is it due to your recent illness?
It is a message to Italians:
be honest, stop dying yourself!
Evelina, in a few
days he will be home.
Andrea, but there is no margin left!
The doctor has advised
for a few days of rest.
Your voters do not have many
reason to rejoice.
I read harsh criticism on
your blog and the party's.
My voters are right to be
tired of me.
Me too I often get tired of them!
Perhaps, sir, I better
do not write this.
No, no, no...What's more,
write this as well:
If politicians are mediocre is
because their electors are mediocre.
And if they are thieves, it is because
their electors are thieves...
Or they would like to be.
You should immediately contact
him, right?
You know I'm the only one
he has confidence with!
Andrea?
There is always something to uncover
in the past of someone powerful.
Someone powerful can always...
be crucified at the right moment.
Fear is the music of democracy!
Fear?
Someone powerful tries to challenge it.
He has the illusion to tame it
and in the end he's attracted by it.
For this reason there is no western democracy
that can do without Secret Services.
And it is exactly for that very reason
that politicians sooner or later
try to fake their own biography.
Lookalikes, copies, fakes
In parliament there isn't a single
jerk who knows to be one.
And now, please let me eat in peace.
I do not know how to thank you, I hope
I have not bothered you much.
No problem.
Excuse me
What the fuck illness did he have?
He seems different!
This interview is a bomb!
He fell right into the trap!
I have not done this game for years.
When young, my brother and I
exchanged each other often.
I could imitate him without being
discovered, he couldn't.
What's the name of that journalist?
Arrighi, from Corriere della Sera.
You don't mind if an article comes out,
do you?
It may even be useful.
What's up?
Did he show up?
Not exactly.
Maybe I found a solution,
but you must agree too.
Yes, I'm in.
And you know why?
To bother him.
But I warn you, you are putting the
party in the hands of a madman.
He maybe mad, but he's got method.
And above all he's funny.
Pleasure,
Giovanni Ernani.
Anna Oliveri.
Are you going to show him the house....
the room?
Can I leave you two alone?
Excuse me.
If you like, I was thinking of
letting you stay here...
Come on, my dear,
let's be more friendly.
That's your cupboard.
As you see...
Enrico has taken almost nothing.
Here are his glasses.
- Did I scare you?
- So identical to him.
Yes, I can be if I want.
- Any service personnel?
- A house maid comes for a few hours.
Your brother does not like having people
at home.
I do not mind.
Perhaps It might be better to ask her
to stay all day.
Do you leave him here?
I can't take him with me!
I would not have time.
I can't deal with his problems
while I am working.
In short, I'm not his babysitter!
But he is here for you!
You know, you are one of the filmmakers
I love most.
- Danielle told me that.
- Really?
I would have never thought of having a fan
among Italian politicians.
Maybe I'm the
exception to the rule.
In reality politics and cinema
are not so far away.
They are worlds in which deception
and genius coexist.
And it's often difficult to distinguish.
Here we are.
Sir, this drug
does not exist in France,
I can find a similar one
But you should specify to me
the pathology it was prescribed for.
You suffer from depression, don't you?
Yes, he suffers from depression.
I'm feeling...
This piano is mine
You know it?
- No, I don't.
- Your husband never learnt.
I know, I have never seen him play.
- I apologize for waking you up.
- Never mind.
- Hello sir, is His Honor back?
- Of course!
That's better.
Welcome back Your Honor.
We can go.
Here it is the interview.
Ah, really?
Oliveri: Fear is the music of
democracy.
I don't like the picture,
it doesn't look like me at all.
No. The interview is extraordinary,
it's great, really.
Hegel used to say that reading
newspapers is...
...layman's prayer.
Right! A real shit!
I never read them.
LEMIDAL
(antipsychotic)
They will ask a number of questions.
They want to know what you had.
Try to stick to what
we have established.
What should I talk about?
This is the speech, just read it.
It is a forum organized by
the Faculty of Economics.
There will be plenty of youngsters. Will
talk an economist, a unionist
and one of those journalists who know
everything and do not understand a thing.
And besides, there will be Rezza from the government,
they want to understand in which direction we are going.
And want to know if we are going to make a
"mea culpa" on social pacts.
I think I'll improvise.
Are you mad?
So they say!
Your Honor Oliveri,
is it true that you will resign?
Have you read the surveys, Your Honor?
You return after a mysterious
absence, and immediately surprise us
proposing a change of line. Is it
repentance for the disastrous outcome
of your leadership?
A belated admission of guilt?
What's this journalist's heading?
I'm Corsini, Your Honor,
you know me very well.
Corsini, tell me the truth.
Do you ever tell the truth?
What do you mean?
I just said the truth
about my party.
Would you ever write the truth
about your editor?
Well, we are an independent newspaper.
True, in the header it's
written "independent"
Thus you begin to lie from
the very beginning.
Are you familiar with the paradox of
Epimenide's liar?
Excuse Your Honor
I asked you a question.
And I have just demonstrated that
you do not deserve an answer.
- Your Honor!
Not too heavy?
Wait here, I'll get the key
from the neighbor.
Keep an eye on him,
so he doesn't make problems.
Today I will talk...
...of catastrophe.
A great French philosopher
said that catastrophe
is the only true resource of south.
Today we can see how
that has become
DOCTOR CERTIFICATE.
The patient Giovanni Ernani shows no more
interpretive delirium of reality...
LEMIDAL to be continued in equal doses.
Today we realize how it has become
the only real resource of Italian society,
which it seems to have for itself
as a program only...
...to live on the edge of abyss.
Today we keep hearing of new
catastrophes, real or alleged ones
We keep looking at politics,
at industry...
that thrive on catastrophe.
I wonder how people can
tolerate all this.
Indeed they begin to have enough.
And...talking of catastrophe...
I want to say also a word...
about...my party
We should have been the first
to stop this bad habit.
We have been very soft,
uncertain, undecided,
vacuous, available.
In a word: Accomplices!
We have been without a clear voice!
Although from time to time
someone tried to speak up,
people heard nothing.
I can assure you that from now
on, it will never be like this.
I am here so that
tomorrow cannot be said
times were dark,
because they were silent!
Mom told me that you've
known each other for a long time.
Yes
About...
25 years.
We met in Cannes.
Are you a film lover too?
Yes.
Were you together?
Look.
Dad said that
you're still in love with mom.
it shows from your look.
- Welcome!
- Welcome back, all right?
Yes, thanks.
You are  back in great shape.
Well, what a pleasure!
You are different!
So different that, when I heard
about party criticism,
I was doubting you were the one
who brought us at this point!
Who says that I am the same person?
Listen, Nolfo called me. He is
concerned about our silence.
Concerned about the versions
circulated on your absence.
Without the alliance with the center Nolfo's center,
we just lose the election.
No question about it.
It's spring,
subtle veils of mist
Also surround the nameless mountain.
Is it mine this figure whose back
is walking away in the rain?
- Here it is, here it is!
- Your Honor good morning!
Welcome back Your Honor Oliveri!
Can you tell which is the decision
on the electoral alliance?
I'll make you a question:
To defeat this government,
which as you know is the worst
in our history,
is it right even to partner with the devil?
Who would the devil be, Nolfo?
No, I am talking of the devil himself.
The devil in person.
He exists you know?
Only this catholic country never
believed it.
It has always preferred substitutes!
However, I fear that this man,
the devil,
has already partnered with our adversary.
In real terms, Your Honor,
would you make the alliance or not?
The consensus...my boy,
the consensus is something serious.
It has nothing to do with alliances.
The only possible alliance today is
with people's consciousness.
Is it mine...this figure whose back
...is walking away...in the fog?
In the rain!
What is it, a puzzle?
It's a "haiku"
(traditional Japanese poetry)
I'm looking for Danielle, have you seen her?
- Danielle...
the script girl? - Yes.
- Up there
- Thank you.
Close the door.
You can't stay here!
Wait downstairs.
"NEVER WORDS WERE CLEARER"
"the only possible alliance is
with people's consciousness"
It's right, you look good.
Thank you.
Hello?
What is it?
I can hear breathing.
It's you!
Hello, I'm Mara,
Danielle sent me.
If you want to attend
shooting, we start now.
As we begin to roll,
make no noise, do not move,
otherwise I get reprimanded.
You'll see, it's a rather
particular scene.
- Good morning Your Honor.
- Hello, dear.
Outside there is a
crowd waiting for you.
Really? Thanks
Bye.
Enrico, you must stop
looking at me like that.
Apart, someone could see it.
Also that story...is over.
Isn't it?!
What's up Bottini?
Our president wants a meeting next week.
I could not avoid it.
Good!
Professor, you must go alone,
it's a private talk.
All the better.
- Hi Enrico.
- Good night dear.
- Do you need anything?
- No.
So I am going out...
see you tomorrow.
About the appointments?
This afternoon I have something to do,
cancel all obligations.
This venue really sucks!
Whoever designed it?
what?...You did.
You were so happy when we opened!
Where are you going in such a hurry?
Bottini, were you ever young?
Or were you born like that?
- Who is it?
- Giovanni.
Bottini, let me introduce my friends.
I had a nightmare,
but it's finished.
Thanks.
You have children, Enrico?
No
Can you drive?
Yes, why?
Tomorrow I meet with my friends
and then go skiing.
Mom asked a driver
to take me.
Can you take me?
Sure!
- Can you turn off the lights?
- OK.
- Good night
- Good night.
- Do you still go the movies?
- Not really.
The last time was...
three years ago.
You politicians don't have a healthy lifestyle!
Right.
I try to see at least
four films a week.
Your mother was like you.
This week I have seen
"E.T", "Big Hopes"
"Avatar"...and
"Last Tango in Paris"
Whoa! That's for adults
don't you think?
I was sure! You and sex
don't go along very well, do you?!
Hello.
- I am Simon's mother.
- What a pleasure!
- Are you with Helene?
- Yes.
But I know you!
- I have seen you on TV!
- I think you are mistaken madam.
- I will miss you so much,
- Me too.
Nice trip.
- Me too!
No, me too.
My dear old friend is back.
I feared a lot for you.
And I feared much for all of us.
We are few left to reason.
All around I only see stoned people,
thieves and bankers.
You said it right:
it is a catastrophe!
We're asked concrete actions!
What would you do?
I would try not to step on the dignity
of those who cannot defend themselves.
If Europe and the world have become
a miserable shopping store,
Then what are we?
You, President?
But it's not my fault!
It is politics that has...
...disappeared!
To be or not to be,
that is the question.
Is it better to be as if we
have already disappeared...
Where are you going?
Or to disappear altogether
to come back being?
Where are you?
He disappeared!
How do you feel?
Do not ask about me,
not worth it.
Eventually, you tell me something.
Well, have you seen?
Let's say that the rest was
good for our Secretary
that doesn't miss a beat and is climbing
back in the surveys.
Do not pull my leg!
Until the other day Oliveri
was a boiled fish
and now he is a shark
that spares no one.
I do not believe in miracles.
If I tell you, you are the only one
to know it, besides me.
Agree?
If you do not trust someone in this
condition, who can you trust?
In fact, I tell you the truth,
just because you're dying.
Up yours!
We are in deep shit!
Just today that the art department
is under pressure.
- What happened?
- Michel got sick.
- Who is Michel?
- The assistant toolmaker.
- Ready Enrico?
- Yes
One, two, three...
Slowly.
Is that okay?
I did not think you would do so well
If you want to take a bath with me tonight,
I have got the key to the pool.
But we have to do it after nine,
when access to customers
is forbidden.
Lady Chancellor is waiting. Please.
It is a real pleasure to meet you
And exchange views on the current,
difficult situation in which we find ourselves.
In this dark period your always
surprising words
have become a light for us.
You know you are aloof?
That is?
You seem to feel
always out of place.
Not always.
Now, for example, here...
I feel good.
You look like someone who
has lost something.
What have you done to your hair?
It's gray!
Can I stay?
Sure.
- You got cold feet.
- As always.
- You look better with gray hair.
- Really?
You look more like ...
a philosopher.
- A poet.
- Yeah?
- Unpredictable?
- ...A little crazy.
Dreamy...
Hi Giovanni, how are you?
You instead
have nothing to tell me?
- What do I have to tell you?
- What are you up to with Mara?
With Mara?
I am not going to tell you.
Then don't tell me.
You should mess up your hair slightly
Bottini, you'd look better.
De Bellis called me.
He would like to invite you for dinner
after the party's closing speech.
- He wants to have a chat with you
- What would my brother do?
He would suspect a trap and not go.
I will go instead.
What's the matter?
Sooner or later your brother
will be back.
And you would not like it,
would you?!
No.
I would not like it. No.
I want to confess something.
Just to think about it gives me the chills.
To someone like you I would give my vote.
And you feel guilty, why?
Don't worry,
it happens.
It happens when you are afraid of winning.
Let's be more friendly, Andrea, OK?
Have you seen how many there are?
We haven't seen a crowd like that in years.
There is a word I love
in particular.
And it's not here!
Passion!
A key word not only for politics,
but for life as well.
Excuse me, I am talking to you.
You say:
Our movement is in a bad shape.
The Darkness is increasing.
Our Powers are decreasing.
Now, after we have worked all these years,
we are in a worse condition
than at the beginning.
But the enemy stands stronger
than ever!
Their Power seems to have increased.
They have taken on an appearance
of invincibility.
We have made mistakes,
it is undeniable.
Our numbers are dwindling.
Our words are in disarray.
The enemy has taken our words
and twisted them
into something unrecognizable.
Now, what is wrong about what
we have said?
Some parts or everything?
On whom do we still count?
Are we left over, thrown clear
out of a living river?
Are we going to be left behind,
Understanding no one,
and understood by no one?
Do we need Luck?
So you ask!
Expect no other answer
except your own!
I've never seen you eating
with so much appetite.
As a matter of fact, since I know you
I've never seen you eating.
What's happening to you?
You talk of passion...
This morning you almost managed
to move me!
It would have been a miracle.
How far do you want to go?
This country is tired,
rotten...afraid.
One cannot afford to be naive.
I...could be helpful.
I do not know exactly how far
you think you can get, on your own.
To free Italians from fear.
From fear! Interesting, yes.
And commendable, but I know
you too well.
I am sure, this
unexpected exuberance,
this speech that has become
sharp, I admit,
really effective, it is not yours.
It is not part of your DNA.
Meaning?
An eminent politician once told me
about his experience
with certain chemicals.
He said they were a tremendous help.
That they even solve certain
disturbances of personality!
It seems to me that, for sure, you
are taking something strong.
Why don't you propose to our
leadership a drug test?
I wouldn't mind!
Good idea!
But, look, I'm being serious,
what are you hiding?
Look, De Bellis what you do not
seem to understand
something much bigger is happening.
Instead people got it very well.
Even the elephants inside the party
understood that music is changing!
Accept it De Bellis.
What?
This time we will win.
You go ahead and I'll catch up
because Bertrand asked me
to buy a box of colors.
Yes?
Hello?
Hello, who is this?
Hello, who is it?
You waste my time playing?
Hello? Hello?
It's me.
How are you Giovanni?
Are you well?
I wanted to thank you.
- Your pill.
- I took it already.
Who was it?
You want to go out with me
somewhere? Such a beautiful day.
Can you?
No, but it's a long time since
I've been by the sea.
Where is Enrico?
Enrico!
Where is he?
- He is going to come.
- Danielle, look for him.
Calm down.
NEVER WORDS WERE CLEARER
- Hello!
- It is a surprise for Danielle.
As you can see: zero autonomy.
- The country did you good!
- Yes, thank you.
I understand why Danielle
is in love with you.
Now you're a different man!
I want to show you something...I did
a research for my new film.
Come.
Under what condition will you soften
your position?
Personally under no condition,
no condition.
It is not a question of trading
one interruption or two.
There should be no interruptions.
Is it an ethical, moral question?
Yes, it's also respect for
ourselves, not only for the authors,
who make a craft of storytelling,
who are inventors of situations,
characters, who cannot undergo
this continuous aggression,
this barbaric villainy.
How can one respect oneself
in this continuous getting slapped,
spitting in the face and insults?
You see, Fellini is the artist who
more than anyone else has fought
so that indecency would
not become a habit.
When TV channels
went to spy on his death,
Their real mission was to
announce the end of a world
and the birth of a new cycle.
Politics...
as permanent invention
of reality,
as an imposture.
You surprised me, Enrico.
You are testimony of a failure
involving everyone.
Could you please chop the onion?
Yes, sure.
I'm making curry pilaf rice.
It's Danielle's favorite dish.
Is your movie telling a story?
I do not like films of which
you can tell the story.
Hi, my love.
How are you?
I found it in the closet,
hidden. Who is she?
She was our fiancée.
I did not think I would be again
in the middle of your games.
You shouldn't have done it.
It's not my fault, people from the
the party in Rome did everything.
But you allowed it.
Perhaps it was wrong of me to help.
You saved me.
You told me that you don't
see your brother anymore.
It's true,
I have not seen him for 25 years.
- You?
- Me neither, haven't seen him since
- Since when? Cannes?
- Yes!
The book you found at home,
it's the only thing I received
in all these years.
Helene showed me the photo
you keep where you are with him.
She thought it was me that
man in the photograph
So?
You have never forgotten him.
No
I never forget anybody.
I always keep with me
all the men I loved in my life.
You too I haven't forgotten.
Otherwise you would not be here
with me now.
I loved both of you.
I don't believe you.
But it is true.
I loved your right eye...
and his left eye.
Giovanni!
Giovanni, are you here?
- Andrea!
- Anna what's up?
- Anna, what's happening?
- He disappeared!
Again!
- Hello?
- Andrea? Are you asleep?
No
Where have you disappeared?
Have you seen the surveys?
No
Enrico, literally he's
taking him to bits.
I want to see the faces of
TV news directors tomorrow,
But where is he?
The president is looking for him.
- Andrea?
- Yes, here I am.
What's the problem?
You have a strange voice.
No, no, nothing.
I have no problem.
He's already in bed.
In short...you know him.
I'll tell him tomorrow. OK?
Anyhow, thanks for the good
news, I'm happy, thanks.
- Bye, good night
- Ciao.
Forgive me, I'm dead tired.
Tomorrow I have to be on the set at 6,
I go to sleep.
Good night, my love.
"In Rome, the triumphal rally
of Enrico Olivieri
during which he has recited
by memory a Brecht's poem
it reversed the trend
giving courage and optimism
to Italian left
for next elections.
"Dear Danielle
it was beautiful finding you again,
I had great pleasure seeing you
closely at work
You have been entrusted with a very
delicate mission
to protect the order of events
from approximation,
from folly.
As you know, good-byes make me sad
therefore you give a kiss
to Helene from me,
say hello to all friends from the crew,
especially to Bertrand and Mara
who taught me a lot
and remember me."
Eh! You gave me a fright!
You gave me!
Fuck!
You seemed dead!
Bloody hell!
- Good morning sir
- Good morning
THE LONG ITALIAN NIGHT IS ENDING
Oliveri, the politician who sparked
hope back into Italians
Surveys give the opposition party at 66%.
Is that you, Andrea?
Where were you?
I have been searching for you all night!
Why are you staring me like that?
Have you seen the surveys?
We will win this time.
Pascal bet on the existence of God
basing on calculation of probabilities.
We politicians bet on the
meaning of history.
You have preferred to bet on a madman.
You must be tired.
Why don't you go to sleep?
We have many things to do.