THE CZECH REPUBLIC - NORWAY
Hey, guys... If Norway wins, I'll buy
all of you a trip to the World Cup!
Hey, Edgar!
You'll have to stick to your promise!
No, there won't be any trip.
The EdGarage hasn't got the money.
Itjust popped out of me.
You'll just have to start saving, guys.
Doesn't the EdGarage
have any money, Edgar?
7 MONTHS LATER
Kurt Nilsen here on P4. 20,000
supporters are now in Germany.
And there's at least half a million
who'd wish they were there...
- Quit stealing!
- I was just getting some change!
There's a lot less there.
What did you do with all the money?
- I needed money for the parking metre!
- Won't get to the World Cup with this.
What was that all about?
Who was that last guy?
- Did you hear what he said, Edgar?
- No, he whispered.
If I was supposed to hear it,
it's stupid to whisper.
Are you always this bloody hilarious?
But that's not why we are here.
We're sick of this!
Mobekken is sick of this damn crap.
When you sell on commission,
that doesn't mean it's your money.
I know you're thick, Edgar, but I
never thought you'd be this stupid.
You've got 30 days to come up with
the money and put them on the table.
If not, we'll take over this...
Mobekken takes over
this entire goddamn shop here!
My wife is a partner here too.
She'd better prepare herself
for a change of partners.
- Have you seen her?
- No, but...
If I were you, I'd pass.
Thirty days!
Damn it, he doesn't understand
a damn shit, that little gnome.
Do you understand
what we're telling you!
I've heard something about you, Edgar.
You havn't got any kids yet.
And if you can't settle this in thirty
days, you can forget about that.
No sacks, no kids!
- Did you hear him?
- Yeah, he didn't whisper this time.
- Kari, come into the storage room.
- Edgar, what's going on?
That was Mobekken and his goon.
We owe them a lot of money.
- We haven't borrowed any...
- I wasn't talking about a loan.
I owe him commission for car sales, -
- but I've spent the money
on salaries et cetera.
- How much money are we talking about?
- 890,000.
And with caps, too, fashionable.
If you buy today,
you'll get winter and summer tires.
He'll get there quicker
with new rubber, you know...
If you'll just sign here.
- OK, we'll take care of it.
- And there goes the Volvo!
- There goes the Volvo anyway.
- That's great, Øyvind.
Hello!
- Won't get to the World Cup with this.
- No, we'll need a miracle.
For example, you could start
selling cars to women.
Hey, wake up. Back to work!
Looking slack.
Hi!
I'd like to buy a car.
And there goes the Opel?
Øyvind, come into the office.
- Why do you only sell cars to men?
- They're the ones who buy cars.
We do have quite a few women
who want to buy cars.
Jesus Christ! Here's a list
of 15 cars, three months...
- Well, that's quite a few.
- Sure, but they're all men.
I can't see any ladies
anywhere in here.
What's your problem?
- It's not that easy to sell to...
- Tell me what's troubling you.
- I haven't shagged.
- What?
I haven't shagged.
There are lots of people
who haven't shagged.
- Really?
- But we can fix that.
- We might be going to Germany.
- Yeah, that would be nice.
All right?
I had my debut in Germany, too.
Norway will go far
in the World Cup, you know!
But being in the World Cup
is an accomplishment in itself...
- 4 summer tires and 8 winter tires...
- We're out of toilet paper, too.
Tonight's the crucial game
in the group play-offs!
- It's time for playing wide!
- What does that mean?
We're talking about how
the ball moves along the surface.
- It should be a completely flat pass.
- Just say so, then.
You must have heard it before.
Is it possible to be that stupid...
Guys! I have good news and bad news.
Which do you want to hear first?
Let's hear the bad news first,
and then move up to the good news.
If we start with the good news,
then it falls...
OK, guys! I'll decide.
- You will get a new boss.
- And the bad news is?
- I have to sell the EdGarage.
- You're selling the EdGarage, Edgar?
I've got a problem with Mobekken Auto.
Breach of contract and so on.
But we've plenty to do.
Busy like hell!
Yes, but the cars that have been sold,
were sold on commission.
The money he was supposed to get,
I had to spend on pay checks.
What's the good news then?
If we win tonight,
I'd like to buy you a trip to Germany.
Without the women!
What are you laughing at?
You haven't even shagged yet!
There goes the wistle!
Norway has defeated the USA!
Norway has advanced
to the round of 16 finals!
Take out a mortgage on the house,
and come to Germany!
See this?
We're driving it to Germany, guys.
Open the hood, Edgar!
- Is it a two- or four-port?
- What do you think? It's four!
Do you have a couple of minutes?
That was really cool
with the trip to the World Cup.
Have you thought about
how we'll get there and stuff?
I know a nice route,
if we drive down through Hamburg...
- That's the easiest way to get there.
- Something else on your mind?
Well, we could...
swing by the Reeperbahn.
Look around a bit, you know.
Wouldn't that be cool?
- What about Laila?
- She's not interested in football.
And me, I don't look at other women.
- How is it with you two, by the way?
- Oh, things are... they're great.
Lots of sex and stuff, you know,
it's brilliant, really...
Oh, Lord...
- Do you have a couple of minutes?
- Sure, Kai. Sit down.
I've thought about Mobekken Auto.
This trip to Germany was really nice
of you. Lots of good food and stuff...
- I think it could be fun.
- I'm looking forward to it!
- I think it'll be nice.
- A real blast.
But terrible that you may have to sell
your life's work. It makes me nervous.
- That's just the way it is, Kai.
- But that Mobekken...
- He probably needs a good mechanic?
- Do you mean yourself?
What about your drinking?
Have you quit, or...?
Yeah, sure, sure.
Haven't had a drink for ages.
- And I can trust you on that?
- Those times have gone.
Christmas Eve,
New Year's Eve, Easter Eve...
Midsummer's night...
Your birthdays...
Then I don't see why you should be
nervous. I'll put in a word for you.
That would be nice of you, Edgar.
And I'm looking forward to the trip.
- Don't go around being nervous.
- Thanks, Edgar. I'll go pack, then.
Boy!
- Do you have two minutes?
- Sure. Come in.
It's about that trip to Germany.
There's not much left!
I only got 250 euros for 2,000.
- Can you buy as much with them?
- A lot more. Germany is cheap.
- Now, tell the guys.
- I'm not going to Germany.
You're not going to Germany?
No, I've landed some gigs.
I've got to focus on my music.
- But we're going to the World Cup!
- But I don't even like football!
Everybody likes football, you too.
It's just that you don't know it yet!
So now we're one man short!
- Which letter were you again?
- N.
- Have you ever heard of "Orway"?
- But you have room for two letters.
Damn it, I'll show you two letters!
Let go of me, God damn it! Hey!
- Do you have ten minutes?
- Yeah.
About that trip to Germany...
I need an advance pay, Edgar.
I'm broke as usual, you know.
I can't give you an advance
as long as you are on sick leave.
I can work for black money
and then get an advance out of that!
We both benefit.
You might not have a job to take
sick leave from when you get back.
- Hello.
- I can't live here anymore!
This goddamn racket!
She's crazy!
- I can't can take it anymore!
- Here he comes again.
Dirtbag!
Damn dago-soppy-crap!
Just put it on the bill, OK?
Hi, mum.
Well, well! What's this? After Eight?
I don't like After Eight!
- And are those flowers for me?
- Yes...
I am allergic to roses!
But then you've never given me
any roses before! Sit closer!
Do what your mother tells you!
Look, your hair is even thinner.
Stop that noise over there already!
All you do is go to football games.
Can't get yourself a woman at football
games! You have to ask them out.
- But I have to meet the one first...
- At a football game?
And besides, you have me,
so you don't need anybody else!
- Will you stop that horrible music!
- If you go over there and talk...
You're exactly like your father.
No, you're not really.
Your father was tall and handsome,
and he had lots of hair on his head.
But you are similar in that he travelled
the country to see horseraces, -
- and you have that football of yours.
Stop making that noise!
Hear that? They're killing me...
When are you going to take me home?
Us guys are going on
a football trip to Germany.
Germany? Only drinking and
whores there... Can't you just stop it!
Good grief... If you can't stop,
then I'll have to put out the electricity!
NORWAY - ARGENTINA
May Berit Bergh rest in peace.
About that trip to Germany,
I really need an advance.
We've talked about this before.
This is a funeral, Karsten...
Poor Øyvind!
First the EdGarage and...
- And then FFK lost this weekend.
...and then this with his mother.
- And they were in the lead, too!
- Edgar, I need to get an advance.
Could you move a bit,
I'm covering up this hole here.
- At least give me five minutes!
- I'm going home to watch the game.
Is Mrs. Bergh doing better now?
She's dead.
You guys are finished
with these, right?
Excuse me,
I have to go to the bathroom.
Norway is 2-1 up against Argentina,
another South American team...
Come on, Øyvind!
Øyvind! Øyvind! Øyvind!
- Go on, grab a beer, Øyvind!
- And the vicar!
Vicar! Vicar! Vicar!
Edgar! Edgar!
Olé, olé, olé!
Guys... Guys!
I have a new N.
Helge!
Here's the guy who's going
to replace Freddy, guys.
This is Helge, my nephew,
a real party boy...
He's a member of the Free Church.
- Helge.
- Satan.
See you tomorrow.
Mummy!
Petter? What would you say
if we were going to have a kid?
Yes! Yes, wonderful!
Did you see that? In the top corner
from thirty metres! Straight in!
- Do you want me to rewind it?
- No, that's OK.
Wanna go to bed?
So it was the real deal, then...
And remember to change underwear
and socks everyday.
Now?
I'll throw in some detergent in case
you need to get some stains out.
- Hi, Øyvind.
- Hi.
I've been thinking...
I'm not going to Germany.
I have some stuff to take care of
after mum's funeral and...
But I'll come down to Gothenburg, -
- and I'll tell the guys myself,
so you won't have to tell them.
I understand, Øyvind.
And maybe buy
some cheap bacon too.
Bye.
I don't think this trip was meant
to happen. First, I get us a new N...
- Now we're one O short.
- So that was Øyvind at the door?
- Now he tells me he's not going.
- That's understandable.
- We're leaving early tomorrow.
- He couldn't see this coming.
I wonder if it's a sign...
I could come along, you know.
I can take my top off, too.
Just one thing... Now that we
are going to the World Cup and all...
We've talked about
a break sometimes...
Is it OK if I take
that break now?
- Yeah, that's fine!
- It's fine?
- Sure, we can take a break.
- We? But...
Bye now, Petter!
I meant that I should take a break,
not both of us! Hello? Hello!
- Darn it!
- Thanks, I'll take that.
We're going to have a nice time
without mobile phones.
- Well, OK, 15 minutes a day.
- 15 minutes?
Phone. Thanks.
Bye!
- Bloody hell... This is my seat!
- I get carsick from sitting in the back.
- Do you think I care? Get lost!
- But, I get stomach pains from it.
- You think you're so special?
- Yes, we are all special.
Jesus...
OK, let's go, guys!
And water for you!
- Here, Øyvind!
- Wanna listen to some music?
Is that Neil Young?
I was wandering in the dark,
when Jesus called me to salvation...
- Fucking hell!
- Turn that music off!
No...
Hallelujah.
Edgar, about those 15 minutes...
If I accumulate those during four days
can I talk for an hour on the last day?
Maybe I'll want to talk
15 times one minute per day.
I don't even have a mobile.
You can have my minutes.
- Then everyone gets 20 minutes!
- No, 15 minutes, take it or leave it.
Kai may want to call later, too.
Will you or Mobekken be the owner of
the EdGarage when we return, Edgar?
It's making me nervous.
Nice.
- When are you going to tell the guys?
- It's not that easy...
You should tell them
before we get on board.
Sure. I'll just go out
for some air first.
- Sorry!
- Sorry, it was my fault.
Here.
Thanks.
You take good care of it, OK?
I'd very much like to see it again.
Come on, Edgar, let's go!
To Germany, of course!
- Beer!
- One beer!
Water.
Guys, cabins...
Petter, Karsten and Øyvind.
Hell no, I can't share with Karsten.
He farts like all hell broke loose.
Do you want my intestines to explode?
The air's got to come out, right?
Kai, you'll stay with Helge and me.
We'd like to inform our passengers
that the duty free shop is open.
The waterjust goes straight through me.
I need to go to the loo.
I need my phone.
And then I'll have three minutes left.
Hi, uncle Edgar.
- Hi...
- Hi, Karsten.
I'd like an orange juice.
- Henrik!
- Cheers! Bottoms up!
Oh, that was the best orange juice.
Can I please have another?
Incredible...
Coach Hareide can't keep making
substitutes at the 83rd minute.
- Got to make a call.
- That won't do it!
What's up with him?
He was going to look at women
and Reeperbahn and all that, -
- and now he's
calling home all the time.
- Hi, Petter! Are you all right?
- Yeah!
Hi, it's Petter again.
Call me when you get the time. Bye.
- Are you feeling sick?
- No... Did you get hold of Laila?
No. She won't answer.
I think she is... trying to avoid me.
I'll just be there a little later on.
Hi!
How are you?
I got a huge bump.
Did you get one?
Can I touch it?
Oh, it's big!
Wanna feel mine?
Are you seasick?
No, no. Our family's
got salt water in our bloo...
I'm such a happy Christian, Karsten!
- Come on!
- He's calling for you.
Hallelujah!
Karsten!
- I don't know what happened.
- I have my suspicions, Helge.
Uncle Edgar, please...
Kai wasn't in his cabin all night.
I think he started drinking again.
We'll have to check
when we get off the boat.
We're all special, you know.
Cool moves you had yesterday.
Do you think you can teach us?
Yeah, I suppose.
- No, not like that.
- Not like this?
With jumping.
Good, like that.
They haven't seen Kai.
We have to go through customs.
When we're through customs,
we'll find Kai and get out of here.
And nobody mess
with these guys.
Out of the car! Out!
Look at this.
Just his size, huh?
What's that?
That's deter...
Bingo.
- And what might this be?
- It is dete...
Cavity search! All of them!
Guys, I'm going into the police station
to ask about Kai. You stay here.
What letter does Kai have again?
In case we have to replace him.
Kai's been arrested.
For attempted child abduction.
- Attempted child abduction?
- I can't talk to him until tomorrow.
- What about tonight's game?
- We're not leaving without Kai.
- What about those expensive tickets?
- I haven't bought any tickets yet.
- They weren't that easy to get.
- You haven't bought any tickets?
No, but I'll get them.
I've got connections down there.
There are more important things
in life than football.
And those things are...?
This is where we're staying.
Should we check out our rooms first, -
- or should we find a pub
showing football and go there?
- I for one need to go up to our room.
- To put on some ladies' underwear?
- It's my mum's.
- As if that's any better.
- I wasn't going to come along.
- Huh?
I used the bag as a cover-up-bag.
I brought her bag to...
- Are you going to betray us?
- I was going to tell you in Gothenburg.
- We would've been one letter short.
- You can't betray your mates!
We're in the World Cup and all...
Betrayer! Judas!
- We are yelling at Øyvind.
- This is our mate.
You shut up, when we're yelling at him.
Now, where were we?
- Oh yeah. Betraying us.
- I can take some bags up with me.
Good day. May I help you?
Norway... yes...
Wenche Myhre.
Derrick.
There are some seats over there.
Bye.
Six beers, please.
Here you go.
There you are, Edgar, thanks.
- There are lots of Germans here.
- Lots of Germans in Germany.
A toothbrush.
They're showing all the highlights, -
- and tonight, it's the quarter finals.
It's gonna be great!
- But Øyvind's in his room.
- Call him on his mobile.
- I've got his phone right here, so...
- That's right.
- I'll get him, but I want my mobile.
- You're out of minutes to call.
- I've got three minutes.
- Karsten's right.
- How do you know?
- I just do.
Give me my mobile.
But guys...
Even if he brings Øyvind back
with him, we're still one A short.
- Been here long?
- I... I just came.
- I... came just now.
- Get a move on, put some clothes on.
The guys are waiting at the pub.
The game starts any minute now.
Hello, it's Petter again.
Please call me
when you get this message...
Bye.
I've really screwed up this time.
Laila won't even answer the phone.
She's not returning my calls.
I don't know what to do.
I think she's messing around
with other guys. Yeah, I do.
- The elevator...
- Hurry in, then.
- The paint, Edgar.
- OK, go to the loo. I'll get the guys.
I don't know what to do.
Laila won't return my calls...
- Are you going to wear that?
- Yeah, isn't it nice enough?
We've found a German
who can be A.
- He's as good as gold.
- He's dead drunk!
- Hurry up, we're running out of time.
- Off with his clothes, let's paint.
Norway has defeated
England in Hamburg.
- Did you see that goal?
- Really awesome.
What the hell's Edgar doing?
We've got to thank this guy.
What's "thank you" in German?
It's "danke".
- Are you Norwegian?
- Sure, I'm from Sarpsborg.
Øyvind, what's this extra bill
for 100 Euros on your room?
It's for a toothbrush.
100 Euros for a toothbrush?
Electrical, or what?
Thanks a fucking lot, Kai.
Now move it!
Kai, you idiot.
You wrecked our entire quarter final.
- Sinner.
- No, come on, now.
- Hey, you be quiet.
- Petter... I think he's got the picture.
But I've got a little secret.
South Korea didn't advance, -
- so I bought their tickets
for the semi finals.
- You've taken the wrong road, Edgar.
- It's just a quick detour, guys.
- I want to show you a beautiful church.
- And where exactly is this church?
- Well, it's in Rostock.
- That's 200 kilometres extra!
- What if we miss the game?
- When did you become religious?
It's just old memories, Petter,
from back when I was a sailor.
We're going to church, uncle Edgar?
Thanks, uncle Edgar.
Damn, look at that restaurant, guys.
I am so unbelievably hungry.
Forget it. It's the most expensive
restaurant in this entire country.
Let's go into the church. Many years'
worth of culture to see. Come on.
Karsten!
You don't smoke in church!
Put it out.
It's about respect.
"...our beloved parents in peace".
Where's he going?
Guys!
Time for food! Over there!
- I have to talk to you.
- There's nothing to talk about.
Our son.
Whom you have not seen
in twenty years.
He's doing fine.
- Every day should be like this.
- I am so full.
Here comes uncle Edgar.
What the hell is this?
Edgar... come here for a second.
Come on...
What is it?
It's good that you had
a nice time, guys.
I was really against this, Edgar.
This money was for tonight's hotel.
And you sat here and drank it up.
Damn it!
- It wasn't me!
- What do you think you're doing!
What is it, guys?
- What the hell have you eaten, Kai?
- It still hangs in the air.
- Did you fart like this in jail, too?
- You leave him alone!
Edgar, you have to stop here.
I need to pee.
Yeah, me too.
Anne...
Go Norway.
Øyvind, they had electric toothbrushes
in there, at 18.90 Euros.
Man, have you been fooled!
Damn, we have the police behind us.
- Stop the car!
- This is going straight to hell!
You guys sit calmly in the car,
and I'll talk to him.
You guys shut up.
Put that bottle away!
It reeks of alcohol in here.
He says it smells
of alcohol in here, guys.
Better now?
Out of the car!
- There went another 50 Euros.
- It's impossible for Karsten to shut up.
- Will we make it to the game on time?
- I got us the tickets...
I'll make sure we get there on time.
Start painting yourselves, guys.
Come on, guys! Looks like
the game has started already!
What the hell...?
Edgar! It's the wrong semi final!
Edgar! Wrong game!
- Good seats.
- But it's the wrong game!
A game is a game.
- Yeah, a game is a game...
- Not when it's the wrong one, it's not.
And Norway scores! 2-2,
and we've played for sixty minutes...
Thank you. That was "Prison".
And now one of my new songs.
Here's "My Life".
This sucks, Edgar!
We're missing out on Norway's game!
I can call Kari, so we can watch
the game on the phone.
Hello, Kari.
Could you hold the phone up to the TV?
Up to the TV,
so we can watch the game.
I thought you were at the game?
Hang on, I'll hold it up for you.
This is very, very exciting. Here's
John Arne Riise in a good stride.
Riise's had a good game for Norway...
- What do you think you're doing!
- We can't hear a damn thing!
- Can't you keep it down?
- I'll take care of it, guys. Go back in.
When I booked you, I didn't know that
Norway would reach the semi finals.
- But I'm playing rock'n'roll.
- Let's just go in and watch the game.
Score's 2-2,
Norway's got the advantage...
And it's a goal! 3-2 Norway
by Thorstein Helstad...
This is a magical moment
in Norwegian sports history!
3-2 against Sweden.
The display of happiness
is understandable.
This is Norwegian sports at its best.
We have just received news
about six Norwegians in Dortmund.
Have they gone to the wrong game?
Because that's Germany
against South Africa.
But football is football,
a game's a game.
It's not this game.
My game.
Mein Kampf.
Carew, and it goes wide...
Bittman, Bittman, Bittman...!
And there goes the whistle!
We are in the final!
We now have a match
against Germany in Berlin!
We're in the final, guys!
Two beers, please.
There's that substitute
who scored the final goal.
Klaus Bittman.
This is a really dodgy neighbourhood,
so I had to watch our luggage.
I'm going after the guys to Germany.
I need a car.
Take any car you like, Freddy.
And you need to take this with you...
Stop the damn car.
Guys, what were you thinking?
- Damn it, Edgar, he's an adult.
- And we did leave money for him.
Edgar, he deserved it.
He was an embarassment to the gang.
To all of Norway.
You heard what he said to the Germans.
Of all that we've been through,
this must be the most insanely...
...funny thing I've ever heard!
Should've done it ages ago!
Let's pull over to this side here, guys.
I think we're lost.
Petter, you have a new text message.
It's from Freddy.
"Hi, Petter. I'm not sure
if I should tell you this, -
- but the other night,
I met Laila with another guy."
- Give me my phone.
- Sorry, Petter.
I want to be alone now.
Petter...
I know how you feel.
Petter, wait a minute.
- Might as well get off here, guys,
- I'll stay here in the van, Edgar.
There are so many bars here.
It's making me nervous.
I'm not moving an inch,
until I get something to eat.
I've got a low blood sugar level.
- I told you I wanted to be alone.
- We are alone now...
Edgar.
- Yeah?
- What are you up to now, Edgar?
I'll go get something
for your blood sugar levels.
- Trust Edgar to fix your blood sugar.
- Yeah, Edgar fixes most things, Kai.
May I be of assistance to you?
- What on earth is he up to?
- I think I know, but I can't tell you.
I can't tell you, either.
Hey, boy!
You can go.
I haven't ordered anything.
Klaus...
Give me the phone.
I was so looking forward to this trip,
and then I screw it up.
Damn it, I regret it.
Asking Laila for a break.
I don't know what I was thinking.
Now she won't even
answer when I call.
Have you tried dialling +47 first?
I'm such an idiot, Øyvind.
Had the finest woman in the world, right
under my nose. Still I didn't see her.
What took you so long, Edgar.
It made me really nervous.
I'm bloody starving to death. Did you
bring anything for my blood sugar?
- I forgot.
- You don't forget things like that.
So this is all about you, then?
I arrange for us to go to Germany, and
all you do is think about yourselves.
It's always you, you, you,
and I've had it!
- I think I've lost her forever.
- I've never had anybody.
Never? Not once?
Almost... just once.
I'm not lucky with the ladies. Maybe
that's why I can't sell cars to them.
- Well, it's hard to tell.
- Can you be gay and not know it?
Do you get a tingling sensation
downstairs when you see naked guys?
I've never seen
a naked guy before.
Feel anything?
Nothing?
That was nice...
Hi.
Don't get the wrong idea.
I'm not...
- He's the reason we're here.
- Me?
That's fine, Øyvind.
There's nothing wrong with that.
- We were just here to check if...
- He was the one who wanted to try.
You don't have to excuse yourself
to me. Maybe I'll see you around.
I don't want her to think that I'm gay.
You're the one who's uncertain.
- Thanks a lot!
- Øyvind, come on...
- What will you do now?
- Go home.
To see if I have a home
to come home to.
Instead of spending several weeks
walking home, -
- let's go home tomorrow, after
the game, with Edgar and the guys.
Huh?
- Don't you agree? It's better that way.
- Sure...
- Damn it, I've never had anybody!
- No... Poor thing...
But we were on a break, and
I was the only one wanting a break...
- Are you up already, Edgar?
- I haven't had any shut-eye all night.
I think Kari knows.
Every year, someone sent Klaus
Christmas and birthday presents.
The only one who knows, is you.
Did you say anything to Kari?
- While you were drunk?
- You don't lie to Kari.
I'll take my 15 minutes, now.
Father.
Klaus...
- This is my son, Klaus.
- Hello, Klaus.
Klaus, we have to go now.
I'd like to introduce my father.
- Klaus, we really have to go now.
- OK, just a minute.
Damn, that son of yours is all right,
letting us borrow this suite.
- Let me see your suite?
- I could have two letters, guys.
- Why don't we just paint "Norge"?
- "Norge"?
Freddy's here, guys!
- When did you come here?
- Just now.
- It's some important lawyer-stuff.
- Not as important as the World Cup!
We'd better move it, guys,
the game starts soon.
- I can't flush, Edgar.
- Let's have a look, move.
But for fuck's sake, Kai,
you've been shitting in the bidee!
Nice of Klaus to get us these
good seats. Look at that stadium!
We've beaten Argentina
and England.
Now we're here in a packed
Olympic Stadium in Berlin.
There are 10,000 Norwegians
here today. There's the team...
Og now for the national anthem.
Hats off, guys!
Norway, with no key players.
Germany, of course, huge favourites.
And so, the World Cup final
of 2006 begins.
The Germans are coming on strong
right from the start.
Panic save!
And here comes Germany again...
Isn't he offside?
That was close! Another wrong pass.
The Norwegian defense is on thin ice.
What's going on?
Do you see the same as I do?
This is a one-way street!
The Norwegians, yeah,
let them come.
Norway is under
enormous pressure.
No!
Penalty! Wonderful!
This is Norway at their most
unmotivated and unwilling ever.
If we win this, I will walk barefoot
back home to Norway.
We'll just have to hope for
something better in the second half...
Only celebrities, guys.
- I'm nervous, Edgar.
- Relax, Kai, it'll be all right.
Thank you.
Nice outfit.
Hello...
Listen, I don't work here.
I'm on a football trip with the guys.
- Are you interested in football?
- Yeah, sure. That's why I'm here.
To meet real,
down-to-earth people like you.
I'm working on this book about
people and high-level sports...
I'm trying to focus on people
like you, who... Hi.
How nice to see you.
We'll talk soon.
You know, how healthy is it really,
for the soul, in a healthy body?
If you see what I mean...
Long time, no see.
Say hi to the missus.
Freddy...
That guy who Laila hooked up with...
what kind of guy was he?
- I don't know. I took a photo of him.
- Let me see.
There.
This is her brother!
You're just the best!
- I am?
- Yes, you.
- I'm going to be faithful forever!
- Congratulations.
Well, I'm not...
Edgar, my phone!
Excuse me.
You're that lady from TV.
I was wondering...
where can I play this?
I think I saw a video player
and a TV in here.
Just looking at the label, Edgar.
If Freddy hadn't come,
we'd be one letter short again.
- And that would be no good.
- But you've got room for two letters.
- It's not working.
- Let me take a look.
Let's see...
Who hooked up this?
Edgar...
Hey, Edgar.
So you can afford this...
Hello, Øyvind.
When you see this, I'll be dead,
but I'm sure you're aware of that.
As you know, I trust no-one, so I've
recorded my last will on video.
But I have to trust lawyer Krogstad
to take care of this video, -
- so it doesn't end up with the dirty
porn movies you bought at Svinesund.
I bet you didn't think
that you'd get anything from me.
You won't, either.
But there was some money left
from your dad.
Always a gambler.
He did win some money
before he died.
But I didn't want that money
to destroy you.
But, I'm dead now, so you
might as well have it now.
Yes, I bet you want to know
how much it is. It's...
Let's see, it was...
Twelve million four hundred thousand.
Twelve million. That would just about
cover half of the EdGarage, Edgar.
Yeah, I would think so.
Now you can finally afford a Porsche
and still have ten million left.
- Wow. Hi.
- Hi.
- What do you think of the game, guys?
- Amateur football.
Sure, but we'll take them down
in the second half.
- Hey, Norway!
- Norway! Norway!
My God, Stig, the guys
don't even seem motivated.
Look! Germany's got cheerleaders.
Look, what we haven't got.
Hey, you guys with the letters!
Can you do me a favour?
Not bad.
- We can't just stand here.
- Let's do the dance Helge taught us.
- No, my leg hurts...
- Sure, let's do that!
Look at this, guys.
Look at the screen.
OK? Are we gonna go get them?
Øyvind.
Anne!
Let's hope this ecstatic athmosphere
rubs off on the players.
And there's the second half
under way. It's now or never.
And Norway is in fact passing
the ball forwards.
Won the ball once again
in the midfield...
My God!
- Where did Petter go?
- I havn't got a clue.
Another chance for Norway...
This game has completely
turned around!
Surely that's a free kick!
Yes, it is.
And in an excellent position.
It's a goal...
It's a goal!
Norway has scored!
What did you say to Åge?
I told him to wait until the 87th minute
before putting in Super Ray.
He'll be so eager
that he'll run right in and score.
Ten minutes left, and it looks as if
Hareide is putting in Raymond Kvisvik.
Strange, he's also trying to establish
contact with a member of the crowd.
Hareide changes his mind!
He always makes substitutions now.
NEW MESSAGE
FROM LAILA
Kvisvik is going in now. Three
minutes left, the score is 1-1.
Our seasoned player is on the pitch,
and he goes straight into offense...
In the crossbar!
Øyvind!
Look!
Edgar!
I'm going to be a dad!
Here's Norway, five seconds left,
pass to Kvisvik, he shoots...
It's a goal!
The miracle of miracles!
Raymond Kvisvik
has lifted Norway sky-high!
We are World Champions!
THE KING CONGRATULATES
HEROES
KLAUS BITTMAN
TO FFK
ÅGE'S NEW ADVISOR
A PILGRIM'S RETURN
FFK CUP CHAMPIONS
7 MONTHS LATER
Hello...
Yes, we are all here to celebrate
the new sign, "Bergh & EdGarage".
- The sign says "EdGarage & Bergh".
- It should be "Bergh & EdGarage".
- No, Edgar founded the garage.
- But you saved the garage.
- This is a gesture from me to you...
- Your contribution saved all of us.
- You founded this garage...
- You have to go first, it's your money.
He saved all of ourjobs!
The sign says "EdGarage & Bergh",
and the sign stays.
He has invested his capital...
- Maybe you should change his diaper?
- No, he needs to burp first.
Subtitles: Prima Vista