Movie re-ecoded by ViZNU or P2PDL.com
Check out more releases at P2PDL.com
"Day after day down below
it nourished life"
"The Multitudes flees with different
kinds of burdens on their back"
"Writhers all through the way as
the time flees"
"At these times, tale of
time is narrated"
"the coquettish talks right from
morning on this earth..."
"searches for one period of time
but other periods are lost"
"plays in tunes with thesounding drums"
"all around the world,
it is a regime of bad times"
"someone among us is chanting
the first chant of "Om""
"on earth, time is being manipulated"
"who else is there to speak on a
different dimension"
Hey! What happened dear?
Come, l"ll take you to the washroom.
Get up.
Wake and sit, don"t cry dear!
Come! Move.
"destiny is decided by someone else before"
Aunty is here! Okay!
Look at that mirror.
No!
"the time sings it"s song"
"we search for the tunes"
Hey!
Hey! Get up.
Hey! l made rasam, taste and see.
Hey! Wake up.
Don"t you want?
Okay! Let me try.
"at a distance, all are watching as spectators"
Are you mad? ldiot!
"didn"t anyone see this beating of hands and legs"
"the time sings it"s song"
Oh the late comer has arrived
l missed the Baypore bus.
That"s why l"m late.
Daily it"s the same excuse.
Give some other excuse today
- Why is she crying?
Why are you sobbing?
That old man in room no. 12 abused me.
He only abused you isn"t it?
He used to hold on my bum
You don"t make an issue of it.
What is this Vilasini sister? Has
this letter come to some bus company?
lt has come wrongly come here.
See it"s full of cross marks.
You just read out that name.
- Okay!
C.K.A.K Menon.
- Retired.
lAS.
- That"s that old man.
Which old man?
That old man from room no. 12.
Menon sir,
do not urinate here.
And please don"t bite her.
lf you repeat it.
We will have to inform your relatives.
This is a warning
They will come and take you along.
Did you give him the medicine?
- Yes l did.
Close the door, close the door.
- Okay.
Badru! Yesterday this letter
was handed over to my grandfather
You please hand it over to,
Shamshu brother. - Okay.
l"m leaving
Father! A letter for you.
Letter?
You must have seen many
plays and magic tricks.
Now the trick which you
are going to see is nothing else.
This is a mango seed.
lf the mango seed is placed in the
hole where the basket is kept, then..
From that hole within
seconds this mango seed..
..and soon it would
transform to a mango tree.
Watch here.
Kept this, in this hole.
Covered it, up with basket.
Also covering it with this cloth.
Everyone should clap their hands.
Come fast.
Going to take off this cloth.
lt"s been taken off,
have a look at this.
Sir! Sir! Today"s letters.
Sir! Sir!
- Tell me Ramannujan.
Sir, we tried mixing Sodium
hypochlorite with isopropyl alcohol.
Chinnappa, fainted sir.
Who is Chinnappa?
Do you know Marcal Vogel?
- No.
No, but l can call him, sir.
Oh! Foolish devil he is a scientist,
Who invented red colour in television.
He says plants can
react to our thoughts.
Sir!
lf you don"t get a new product out of
this month we will be totally doomed
Clean right has taken over
All our market.
- l will come babe..
What to do with Chinnappa?
Gone?
So, you have decided to go for sure.
l hope you know the seriousness.
l feel it would be good if,
you take a second opinion.
You are also a doctor.
You give me a second opinion
Doctor, Krishnamurthy.
Are you sure? You want to go to
this place mentioned in this letter.
Surely, l should go.
Have you heard of Kopi Luwak?
World"s most expensive coffee.
lt comes from animal excreta.
Do not wrinkle up your face.
Asian palm civet.
Asian palm civet. You know that.
lt"s found in lots of area including,
lndonesia.
And in lndonesia these Asian
palm civets eat coffee cherries.
Which partially
digest in their bodies..
..and they defecate it intact.
And that partial digestion
adds flavour to it.
And it"s sold for hundreds of dollars.
Sir!
-Yes.
lsn"t our class about
Protozoan Giardia Lamblia.
Don"t you guys go
to toilet in the morning?
That"s a kind of dung.
Waste dung, like useless cow dung.
So you better understand..
..the significance of animal
excreta and. - Oh! Escaped.
He and his Asian palm civet"s shit.
Move fast.
lgnorant idiots!
Foolish kids. Fit for nothing!
Damn fools!
What"s the matter today?
Leela Kumari, l might quit.
lt"s better than teaching
these worldly dumbs.
What is it? Tell the matter.
Leela Kumari,
you are a ¤oology professor.
These animal excreta
and their specialties.
And their qualities, do you know that?
For that my PHD..
..isn"t like Neelakandan"s
in animals shit and urine.
You should know this.
Do you know what this is?
Crocodile shit. - Oh!
Do you know the uses of it?
During ancient ages.
Women in Egypt used
it as contraceptive.
Do you want to know how it is used?
No! l don"t want to know all that.
lt"s time for my class.
This too is a class.
Madam! There is a call for you.
Yes! Venkat.
- There is a call for you.
Yes!
Hello!
Madhu! Shilpa here.
- Yes.
There is some bad news.
We did our best.
Madhu as you know,
since Madhvi is no more.
Vivek has all the
rights to take away, Montu.
He was with me his entire life.
And only l know what
he wants and when he wants.
You know right, the law
doesn"t have such emotions, Madhu.
But.
- They have given us a date.
Can"t we try in a higher court?
We could, but the result
will be the same, Madhu.
lt will only cause
you more heart aches. Ok
Shit!
Sir! Tea.
Brother!
- What happened?
Don"t you get mobile signals here?
l think you will get at some distance.
Sir, have you come
to take photographs?
No. l"m actually a nature lover.
Simply came to explore the forest.
Thanks!
- lt"s okay sir.
How much?
- Five hundred.
Ammanpati?
Where is this Ammanpati?
Yes! This is that place.
Rest you can ask him.
Go dear.
l have told you earlier.
Forest, forest.
What forest man?
- Forest!
Seems like he too
belongs to the group.
No, that"s not, wait for some while.
Hey! lt"s enough say properly,
where to go?
lt"s the same said earlier,
forest, forest. - What?
Forest! What?
- Forest.
He has been saying the
same thing all this while
What is it? - We want to
go to the village not to the forest.
Haven"t l told everyone?
Haven"t reached the right
place?- Now what to be done?
Haven"t got the letter?
So, want to go to forest.
This guys seems to be crazy.
l don"t understand a thing he says.
- Why dear?
No! Dear after, after.- What?
We are just wasting our time here.
Sir don"t go to jungle,
there are ghost over there.
Look he is that sorcerer's man.
- Get lost!
What did he say?
- lt"s a ghost!
Enough! l"m going.
- He is going.
lt"s not there. Excuse me.
- Wait dear.
This guy is saying something.
He has no sense.
He is saying the village
is in the forest.
l"m going.
- Not that.
Where do we start from.
But the villagers said
the forest is haunted.
They are simply saying so. Simply!
They are cooking up stories.
You guys coming or not? Let"s leave.
- Someone is coming.
Cycle or what?
What is your name?
l"m Madhu, Madhumita.
l"m Ananda Krishnan.
Okay! Where are we going?
Come, come, come.
Come fast, fast.
See l"m coming from Bangalore.
Excuse me! What is the
name of the village we are going?
7000 Kandi.
- Kandi?
May l?
- What is the meaning of Kandi?
ls it the Kandi one in Classic Tamil?
Yes! lt is that. Measurement of earth.
1 Kandi equals to 60 acres
Come fast, come, come.
Even the weight of
woods is called Kandi.
Sure.
ln early ages the piece
of land was named so.
My Grandfather's ancestral
home name is Chakachan Kandi.
Chakachan Kandi? lnteresting name.
"As rain comes, flows along
the flower's smell in the forest."
"With flower smells flows,
shall flow the honey.."
"..and as honey flows,
the sparrow shall come."
"Happiness within me
and happiness in the forest."
Are you okay?
- Yes!
"Happiness in the forest."
The woods are lovely,
dark and deep, l sleep.
But l have promises to keep
And miles to go before l sleep,
And miles to go before l sleep..
Armed with a plunger he
stares down into the toilet bowl.
As the waste, he has just expelled.
Captivates him.
And a whole swirl
of ideas comes flooding.
Name?
Neelakantan.
C.K.A.K .Menon. Appukuttan.
But you will have to
add Menon and call. - Okay.
Okay.
Come on young man.
No.
- Yes, careful.
Fresh water, try it.
Disgusting.
Will we have crossed 10-25 kilometers?
No sir, have seen in this mobile app.
Guess we would have covered
some 1 lakh 10 thousand steps.
Which would be approximately
16 kilometers. - Oh! Oh!
These Unniyappams were packed
for Chitrammal. l shall eat it now
My sister,
That is, My mother-in-law, prepared it.
lt"s very tasty.
Thanks.
Okay! Let me see?
What is that?
lt"s unniappam.
- Oh, unniappam? Wow!
Catch it.
- Thank you.
lsn"t it like deer's shit?.
Hey..
But it does not taste"s so.
Leave me!. Hey!
- Leave.
Hey! Don"t.
Leave!
Thief, thief. Where is it?
Letter.
- Said to leave him.
Please.
- Read the letter?
This letter is also the same as we got.
- Please!
Please stay clam.
Lets see what"s in that letter.
You may not know me
But, l know you.
And it is in the delight of that freedom
that l am writing this letter to you.
l"m in a village called 7000 Kandi..
..of which you may not have heard of
lt could be the world"s
most beautiful village.
The village with lots of treasures,
which is not yet stolen by anyone.
But any time this
treasure could be robbed.
Forever this village could
be wiped off the face of the earth
As a single battler, l am helpless
lf possible, from your busy time.
Few days from your precious life time.
Will you be able to
keep aside for this village?
lf so. Then come here.
The Money you will need
to get you here comfortably..
..is enclosed with this letter.
My aide will be waiting to get you
to his rare and beautiful settlement.
Near Ammanpati village,
south of Murganpet.
l promise you a journey of a lifetime.
A treasure of treasurers
and a new life.
l sincerely hope to see you there,
Yours truly, Philipose John Varkey.
Lord livingstone Trading Company.
Manchester, England. 1839.
Do, l need to help you?
What happened young man?
Nothing sir.
The young generation of today, do not
have energy and stamina of your level.
Hat"s off to you sir.
By the way are you
here for an adventure?
l"m a fugitive. l have escaped a jail.
Jail? Which jail
have you escaped from?
A jail for people like us.
l escaped from there.
Reached here 5 years ago. Oh,
the five star facilities they provide!
l could not marry as l
was planning government strategy.
That"s why l did not
have children either.
When l reached my native place after
Retirement and commission service,
Those who l thought would look
after me, never even cared to do so.
Anyways it was the right time, when
l got Philipose"s letter and money.
Then l didn"t think much.
Now l enjoy my freedom.
Sir, walk, walk.
- No chance.
Coming, coming, coming.
See! Lorry lorry. lsn"t that a road.
Then we could have gone by road?
lf you go by road then
it would take 8 days.
lf we go by forest then within 3days,
we shall reach 7000 Kandi.
Only to trouble humans.
- 3 days?
We will have to listen to him..
..as we do not know
the geography of this area.
Hey! Climb and come.
l got scared.
lt"s a good bed.
When l had gone to silent
Valley at the time of my research.
We had used similar beds.
Hey! This bed is for old man.
Hey! Brother help me.
Oh! God.
Okay! Thank you.
Hey! That one is for sister. Go man.
Go! go l sleep.
Okay! Goodnight.
Goodnight!
- Goodnight and sweet dreams.
What?
- Come and sleep here.
Come, come.
- Okay!
How much distance more?
Come, come let"s go
Shall we go?
Hey..Jump!
Come on..Jump!
Jump your suitcase.
Will the suitcase jump on it"s own?
He doesn"t understand a thing.
Hey! Ananthuu, "petti chaduka"
means to throw the suitcase.
To throw the suitcase?
-Yes.
There will be long
distance to be travelled..
..no need to carry huge weight.
He is asking you to
Lessen your luggage weight.
Carry only what is necessary
l had asked her not to pack so much.
She didn"t listen.
Stay there.
Shall we go?
- We shall go sir.
Let the suitcase be there, you come.
Brother! Why are you dumping
plastics in forest? - ls it so?
Please help me pick it. Pick it up.
Okay.
Come let"s go.
"little one has come descending the hills,
the woods danced flurtering it"s feathers"
"whom have you waited to welcome?"
"is it someone?"
"the breeze wa¤ on palm leaves & flowers
bee searches for honey"
"very slowly humming a silent song"
"slowly..."
l have to go Philipose.
Hmm. - He seems to
Be an interesting guy.
l too have noticed he is a survivalist
like we watch in discovery channels.
Service list?
l"m a big fan of Philipose.
Yes!.
- lt makes me very peaceful.
Even l have heard some of them.
Recently l have heard his composition.
OmVed, it has all
the elements of Jungle.
lt sound"s really interesting.
And his dessert mix it"s so awakening.
lt"s itching.
l feel it"s leech.
Aren"t you Swami? ls there no thread?
- What?
Thread.
l believe in science.
Who is this? ls he your son?
He is my nephew.
Nephew? Who is that?
Son of my elder sister.
- Oh!
What happened to him?
Montu!
The precious gift which
my sister had given me and gone.
He is the one who taught
me to love with open heart.
Montu! Will you not
go to school today?
His father went away saying, it
is difficult to bring up a sick child.
Even after 12 years..
..he is still like an infant,
wants me for everything. But..
One day, his father
came back to take him away
l had to let him go.
Hi Madhu, how are you doing?
Oh, you look disturbed.
l have heard about, Montu.
not even able to do minor things
Satisfied. Now it"s peaceful.
Why are you sitting like this?
They have gone.
Let"s go.
- Yes.
Ah! Watch out be carefull.
Listen, then.
- Yes.
My story is also somewhat like this.
- ls it? Yes.
ls it?
- Yes.
Me, l was.
- Do what l say.
l was supposed to go
to US but l didn"t want to go.
l was happy here,
doing my research and all.
My wife, Meghana
she wishes to live in US.
Don"t you have MS degree
from Colombia university and UCA.
lf you be there, how good..
No, sister for me.
Here comes my great lndia.
lt"s not too late Ananthu, after all.
You are one of the best
chemical engineers out there.
How much will you earn at Stanford?
This one is for Sita aunty.
Call as soon as you land in Dubai.
Later when you go to Frankfurt,
call me from there too.
Once you reach JFK, uncle
and aunty will come to receive you.
When l got this letter l came here..
..l did not think it
would be the same here.
Swami, who are you among this?
- What?
Her sister's son or she herself?
You have to be brave? Be courageous!
How will it do if you
leave all your wishes..
..because you are afraid of you wife?
Self-decisions,
it should always be quick.
So, is all you decisions quick?
This is the fifteenth time.
Fifteenth complaint!
Today also instead of the
lecture on protozoan Gambia..
..your lecture was
on Asian palm civet.
How old are you dean?
- Why?
No, just wanted to know.
l will turn 53 in this April.
Not on April 1st, is it?
Dean! You can shove this job.
l needn"t tell you where to.
Always your decision
should be fast and brave.
Did you understand?
- Yes.
Hey! Walk fast. Fast.
Why is it stinking all over?
See! The elephant has no tusk.
Thieves have taken it away.
These days they don"t
even spare elephants.
Dam! Poachers.
Cruel devils, who don"t value life.
Come.
lt"s stinking too much. Oh!
How many days have you been waiting?
He won"t come.
Come! Come.
Come give me your hand.
Excuse me.
Come!
Careful.
Come! Come.
Walk!
Watch out, carefully.
Yes! l know. l know.
Oh! No what happened?
Those are just bats.
Don"t be afraid friend.
Ananthu, why are you screaming
like a small child when you see bats.
lt"s bat, an innocent creature.
These vampire bats drink blood.
Oh! He says they drink blood.
Where were you Mr. Vedan.
ls it Phelopia?
- Yes!
l don"t eat fish.
Lake fish.
You can eat it,
where can you get such fresh ones?
Hot! Hot, hot.
Excuse me.
Riluzole. lt"s heavy dose.
Yes! lt is.
lt has been an important
part of my life since one year.
l cannot be, without it.
What"s your problem?
l have been noticing you.
Even l came to know it, a year back.
l have a disease like this.
MND, Motor Neuron Disease.
My muscles are getting
weaker day by day.
lt"s seems only big people
get disease like this.
l believe Steven Hawkins
is also suffering from this.
l have always seen life positively.
For an extremely
outdoor person like me.
lt was as good as death.
Should you go?
lt"s a big risk.
You could collapse somewhere.
And you may end up
in a comatose state.
You have already told that,
my life will end up in 6 months.
Let me just enjoy it.
Sam, you should
know the seriousness.
Doctor, let him go.
Thank you.
l have always done
whatever l have felt.
And that letter has
made me come here.
And l really want to do this.
Okay!
You are in the right place,
at the right time.
Nature, is a great healer.
Thank you.
Sir! - Yes.
Look there.
Hey! Everyone come, come fast.
What? What happened?
- Come.
What happened?
- Lets see.
Oh! My God.
Wow!
lt"s amazing.
True!
Hey..Hey! Unbelievable!
Hmm..
Oh! No.
You will slip.
What is he doing?
Now what happened?
You had said so much.
What?
Go away.
Hey! Be careful.
He doesn"t understand.
Don"t drown.
Crocodile!
Crocodile?
Oh! Crocodile, crocodile.
l"m not there. l"m going.
This man.
He was fooling us.
- Then what?
Come fast! lt"s 8"o clock.
You can say the time looking
at the sky? - There is a watch.
"twig carasses but get hurts when it is throned"
"shall go through the paths to know more"
Come!
Be careful.
Have to climb a small hill.
A small one.
ls this small or what?
How will you climb it?
l will throw the rope down.
Shamsudin, come!
Be careful!
Pull it. Pull it
"climbs all the woods,
swims all across wild brooke"
"has seen the shore, also saw
the kingfisher catching the fish"
"twig carasses but get
hurts when it is throned"
"shall go through the paths to know more"
Watch out!
Hey! Don"t do.
What?
- lt"s slough.
lt"s slough, it seems
leg would sink.
See! See!
So beautiful.
Amazing!
Wow!
- Oh! My God.
What is this?
lt"s nothing, but Peacock.
Fantabulous!
Come, follow me,
be careful and come.
Old man! Carefully.
Phosphorous! Phosphorous!
Be careful.
- lt"s Godmother, Godmother.
Forgive us, forgive us.
- Are you mad or what?
Come! Come!
- Forgive us.
Godmother! Walk, walk.
- Forgive us mother.
lf Godmother gets angry then
everything will get destroyed.
Everything will get destroyed.
Uncle you got scared, didn"t you?
- No!
What for?
- l know uncle got scared.
Got scared isn"t it?
That"s quicksand.
You know, slough.
Have saved us, have saved us.
- lt"s all that phenomenon.
Like the combination
of phosphorus and sulphur.
Sometimes it could be blue balls,
or it could be red balls .
lt"s a myth.
They might call it an idiot
and stupid girl. And then get scared.
Where did they go?
Got tired! Shri. C.K.A.K Menon.
will there be leech here?
No, only snakes
won"t hurt, poor ones!
has reached here
Elder brother!
Where did he go?
Elder brother! Or what?
Elder brother! Elder brother!
Coming, coming.
Elder brother!
How many have come?
These many have come, rest have left.
Come this way.
Walk, walk.
What is it bunker or what?
That"s a grave.
- Come here.
Thanks!
- Catch.
Come on.
lt"s very interesting.
Please be. Please be comfortable.
Where is Chukku?
l"m Philipose John Varkey.
Hello!
Menon sir.
- C.K.A.K Menon.
l know it sir.
- Oh!
My father was your subordinate,
Mr John Varkey.
John Varkey?
- Yes!
John.
- Long back.
John Varkey?
- Me Nee..
Professor Neelakadhan.
While you were doing PHD,
l was yourjunior there.
Everyone knew me.
l was quite famous then,
you know with all my activities.
Anantha Krishnan Subramanian,
from Haripaad.
Father, Subramanian lyer
was clerk in treasury. - Yes!
A child prodigy, first rank in SSLC..
..and passed degree at the age of 16.
ln 1992 along with Ola A George,
the Nobel laureate.
Published a paper about super acids.
Madhumita Krishnan.
Madhu!
Father, Krishna Kumar was chief
engineer of Machine Tool"s company.
Mother, Mamtha Bakhery
a Pune resident.
She had a sister.
She is no more.
One of lndia"s ace gun testers.
A silent brain behind bringing
multiple trigger machines in lndia.
From where did you
get all these details from?
These haven"t been
published any where.
Shanmughan llangovan.
- You can call me Sam.
Yes!
Adventure junky, nature lover.
One of the founding members of 200¤
Bay of Bengal anti trenching campaign.
l was also a part of it.
ls that so? Where you there too?
Yes!
- lt was a crazy campaign.
Shamshudin.
Shamshudin?
Look even l too got the letter.
Oh! The famous street
magician of Charplechery"s.
The man who does the
great lndian mango tree act.
Yes! That one only.
So you know magic and all.
Oh! So you are that crazy fellow.
Varkey had told.
That he has a traveller son
with his craziness and mother's music.
Do you know what these
people are saying about you?
A survivalist, sound engineer
and about your experiences.
Everything isn"t right,
whatever Menon sir has said.
Many things in my
blog are fictionalized.
To make symphonies like jungle chimes,
desert mix.
l Have wandered a lot for it.
Have been trapped in some
places with no humans and animals.
That too without
drinking water at times.
ln those days, l use to go
to any extreme to escape such traps.
Without fail l used to post
all travel experiences on blog.
l had to eat worms and the like.
Had to make a raft to cross a beach
And whatever things did to
escape such trap became survivalism.
To go and survive in any jungle
And also learnt to run and
escape in any emergency situations.
And once trapped in a net
which was laid for an animal.
From there l met this Mountain tribe.
From there became my
constant travel companion.
And that"s how l became
his elder brother..
..and he became my confidant.
l called him Mala.
And thus Mala took me to many forest
and hillocks which l hadn"t seen before.
Along with that Mala
told me about 7000 Kandi.
About those who get trapped in the
forest and cannot find their way out.
About the hidden ghosts in the forest
and evil spirit those ablaze in night.
And heard many such
mysterious stories.
Only after gaining confidence over me.
Mala showed me the
safe routes to 7000 Kandi.
And disclosed many hidden
secrets about this place..
..when l learnt more
about 7000 Kandi.
l came to know about
the British history here.
149 years ago.
ln the era when places
like Ooty, Silion..
..and Da¤eeling were
changing lnto tea gardens.
This place known as Parindhumudi.
Was noticed by a British company
named Lord Livingston Trading Company.
You must have seen their foundation
stone on your way. Didn"t you?
lt was sold for ¤6
Rupees at that time.
Kozhipara Mana Datthan Namboothri..
..the one in charge
of the forest then,
Leased out this forest for 150 years.
As per the lease Parndhimudi
had to be converted..
..into a tea plantation or
any other industry within 150 years.
lf not..
Lord Livingstone
Company would lose it.
Only few months are left
for that agreement to get over.
So? What will happen it gets over?
Forest has to be returned
to lndian Government.
Few months back..
..when companies men
came here and tested the soil
They came to know that,
this forest has with rare minerals.
Like amaranthine,
bauxite, titanium and chromium.
Found out that there are so many
rare minerals and gems stone minerals.
From that day they started
mining and cutting down tress here.
while saying chopping the trees, in a day
they almost chop off atleast 5 hecters
To know more about it..
..l went to meet Supreme Court
Environment issues la¤er, Mr Venu Gopal.
Through him l came to know about
some hidden clauses of the agreement.
Within 150 years Parindhumudi.
lf turned into a tea plantation
or other industrial area then.
The lease could be
extended to 350years more.
Oh! ls it?
For that reason,
these contractors are in a hurry.
Oh! That was which
we saw while coming.
Carrying the chopped
trees in the lorry.
But, why are we here man?
For 7000 Kandi.
lsn"t 7000 Kandi, a village.
Okay! Before 2-3 centuries ago.
There was war between 2
rulers which lasted for 18 years.
See! This is the place where you saw
that Lord Livingstone"s foundation stone.
lt was 2 nearest ruling kingdoms then.
Singanagowla and Konacherinadu
These two regions were in constant
war which lasted for many years.
A war which brought only losses
Ruling kings Thimmasara
Adhipan and Veera Raya Odheyan
Fought for land, earth and river.
After a long battle of 18 years.
Thimmasara couldn"t
overpower Singanagowla..
..it was understood by
the younger elderly person.
Kochirangandoth Parangodan.
Parangodan"s intuition
did not go wrong.
Singanagowla started wining the war.
People of Konacherry slowly
stared becomes their slaves.
Parangodan preferred death to slavery.
With ghost, evil spirits and demons.
Parinthumudi was a dense
forest with black magic.
A place where no one could reach.
Going to Parinthumudi
was considered equal to death.
Parangodan, who believed
that death is better than slavery..
..along with his family and with
some disciples went into the forest.
Following him, Small groups
of weavers, shepherds, potters.
And people with other
skills ran into Parinthumudi
But instead of death what
they received in Parinthumudi..
..was a new life.
They understood that forest
protects and provides shade to man.
They made a village inside the forest
That Village is 7000 Kandi.
The villagers here believe that the war
between Singanagowla and Konacherinadi
ls still not over.
But where is it?
Where is this village?
Take a peak.
What is it?
Oh! Periscope.
Where did you get it from?
l got it when a submarine
was torn apart in Alang.
Move aside.
- This man.
What is it?
Let"s see.
Come on.
Outer world denote them as ghost,
evil spirit, etc.
lf truly said they are not all those.
Very much nature lovers
and alert all the time.
Fearful to everything
and an innocent bunch of people.
But some negatives that
are seen in between us are..
..the same with them too..
..aydhu, bheta, Tarler.
These are considered lower caste here.
But they are the shear
Existence of this village.
The people who drives
hunger out of the village.
Look! Did you see them catching fish.
They are Tarler,
a group who does hunting.
The village is guarded
by people of this caste.
Wow! We can hear their
sound in these speakers.
That is technology.
l have kept microphones in
many places without their knowledge.
lf we look at their weapons,
it seems to be of ancient ages.
But, Sam they use
weapons only for hunting.
They don"t have an
enemy country to fight with.
Because of that there are
not many changes in their weapons.
Watching them seems like reading
Ta¤an"s comic. Very gymnastic.
Till now l haven"t seen
any one falling from tree.
Or being hurt.
These trees a part of their family.
Hey! Come, come!
Fast, fast.
- Coming.
Namda! Come this way.
Fast.
What are they putting
into those baskets?
Madhu! That"s the funny part of it.
They are giving food
from to Madhyamadhi.
This is what l told earlier,
negativity.
The similarities between them and us.
The caste differentiation.
Didn"t you see this village?
lt"s in three different levels.
Kelamadhi, Madymadhi, Mukhaymadhi.
This is all over eve¤here.
Where? Let me see.
-Yes!
Kunjathan and Karyathan
The eyes of 7000 kandi.
They are watching me the same
way from the time l have come here.
They must have followed
you too when you had come.
There is complete
industrial revolution here.
This is Madhymadhi.
All are self-sufficient.
- Here are the weavers and the potters.
People in Kelamadhi
should not enter Madhymadhi.
Oh! Oh! Cow dung rolls.
Very interesting.
Who is that?
That is Neeli.
And this is Kariyan. The blacksmith.
Belongs to Kabanar caste
making weapons for Kelamadhi caste.
lt"s long time that blacksmith
has started flirting with..
..Thiritha from Mukhara caste
But here also the same social stigma.
There should be no marriage"s
between these two castes.
Mangalam? What"s that?
Marriage.
What are they filtering there?
People who have taken collection
as their hereditary work.
The people from arms department.
They are collecting
metal ore for blacksmith.
Didn"t you see the water ways?
lt"s lnnyappa"s creations.
He seems to be an
adventure junky like me.
That"s lnnyappa.
He is the chief
engineer of 7000 Kandi.
He has the responsibility
of the village"s maintenance.
All the machines seen
here are his inventions.
This is Madikaer portion.
ln Hindi "Madke" means mud pot.
See Kunjathan and Kariyathan
have reached down.
Put.
North! South!
Look, Look! See.
They might be the roadside Romeo here.
lt is said that if lacuna bean is
Ripened the itchiness will increase.
Watching North and South
even at old age. ldiots!
What are they drinking?
Some kind of alcohol?
lt"s their spirit. Matth!
Matth?
- Yes.
Madhu! Come and see.
What are they spiting.
That is a kind of tuber crop.
Here is the irony. Though they
are not allowed to touch each other.
lt is from the juice of what
these lower caste ladies spit.
That The Matth for Mukhyamadhi
and Madhyamadhi is made.
That is Pargangodan,
the wise men of this place today.
Main activity is wasting time just
playing around and losing every time.
Oh! l forgot to say.
This is a matriarchal society.
This is Meenkanni,
Pargangodan"s niece.
You can even say the
Mother of ancestral house.
She is very naughty? lsn"t she?
Ponni! Younger sister of Meenkanni.
Next in the line to be
mother of ancestral house.
She doesn"t care about
the caste and race systems here.
Goes eve¤here and touches
everyone.- Sister is calling.
Because of her all children
here from all caste can go anywhere.
How many times have l told?
How much have l warned?
Your Legs will rot.
You should come before called.
Take her along.
Meenkanni is a tough nut.
There is no word called mercy
and compassion in her vocabulary.
They may be primitive.
But They have their own fashion style.
And A stylist.
That is Cherkun!
And the other one is his assistant.
l haven"t understood his name.
That man is in a bird nest? lsn"t he?
Oh! That is the jail here.
The man in the jail is Aaythan.
He tried to steal "Pala-pala"
for his second marriage.
That is his family,
have come to give him food secretly.
Madhu just look upward.
That house seen is Gugutai"s hut.
lt"s a strange hut?
Ah! Here she is!
lf anyone new comes in this forest,
Gugutai will come to know about it.
How are you?
Gugutai is the astrologer
and weather predicator here.
Are you a thief?
She is also the doctor here.
You can call her a witch doctor.
Are you a girl?
Bear or monkey?
Gugu is Vedan"s smoking companion.
Ours one and only connecting
link with 7000 Kandi.
And this is Chatha Gugu"s apprentices.
Went away?
They come and go
according to their will.
l Came to know more about This
village"s history through Gugutai.
Different libraries and archives
Could give only little details.
Rest are all assumptions.
Can"t you make it public
that there is such a village?
lf l reveal it, press will come.
lt will become tourism and
these people will be mocked at..
..7000 Kandi"s way of
living will be destroyed.
Have you approached the
Environment protection force?
Tried everything.
- How?
Environment departments in Kerala,
Tamilnadu and Karnataka.
And also went to their
department sectaries.
There were no benefits
other than giving bribes.
See Mr.Philipose.
The forest you are talking
about is not just in my jurisdiction..
..it"s across 3 states.
Well, apart from this
can l help you in anyways.
Sir, before this you.
To protect the forest l had
gone to some 3rd rate politicians.
lt will be a great help if you agree.
For all these you require lots of
time and money, but have time for it.
When is that meeting?
lt"s after half an hour.
But villager's petition
against this forest has gone.
They believe that
the forest is haunted.
l had lot of expectation in you sir.
Thank you!
Then l went to..
..many Hypocrites who call
themselves social activists.
They were only interested
in those activities..
..which would give them
instant fame and goodwill.
As a last ditch effort l
went to those Mangalore brothers.
l went to the contractors,
and pleaded to them.
There is justice in what they said.
They aren"t doing anything illegally.
See Mr Philipose, we are business men.
And we have invested
lot of money in that project.
So, we have continue the work.
Remove at least 20 from there.
Did you understand brother?
Understood?
Sir, this isn"t a normal forest.
lt"s a reserve forest
and it should be protected.
For that Green Tribunal had objection.
lsn"t it?
Haven"t we paid the Tribunal..
..and various environment departments.
So you may empty the space.
Don"t waste my time.
Sorry Mr, everyone is not like that,
there are nature lovers too.
Have some heart, Guru.
Look, Mr. Nature lover
you may please leave.
Carry on with your love for nature.
Rest we shall look after.
Tried protesting by
being on hunger fast..
..it did not help either than l had
to stay empty stomach for 3-4 days.
Don"t pick me up. Me!
Eat the rest.
When all my efforts failed,
as a last attempt.
l wrote letter's to you all.
A gamble for man power.
A play with the last 1 .5
lakh rupees in my bank account.
l had written letters to 100 people..
..about who l had
noted down in my dairy.
l expected at least 50 people.
l"m helpless.
So, now what can we do?
We are only few people.
We could have done something
if we were a few more in number.
But, l cannot abandon
these villager's.
lf the forest is destroyed,
there won"t be a life for them.
Because they only
know to live like this.
Their innocence.
There are no diseases which
are known to outer world..
..and there is no taint.
The only problem is that they
don"t have unity among themselves.
To give light everyday
Velliyyal climbs up.
Earlier there was a deity here.
Later when that tree grew,
it grew along and reached on top.
That is their deity now, Thaiyadhe.
Now these are my
apprehensions concerns.
Before 7000 Kandi
is completely destroyed.
Will l be able to
make them understand?
Or without knowing anything
will this 7000 Kandi get..
..perished along with the forest.
lf we go according to the
number of trees they are chopping..
..within no time they will reach here.
Then, within few days.
This 500 year old village will perish.
But what could a few people do,
it"s a waste of time.
He is right.
Anyway, l won"t leave
them even if you leave.
This is their forest
Where will they go and live
if they are thrown out from here.
Brother! l"m with you man don"t worry.
Thanks!
Okay! Anyways we will see tomorrow.
Can stay here tonight.
There are hammocks outside.
Those who want to
go can leave tomorrow.
Tied well, isn"t it?
- Yes
This will not break. Sleep.
Sir, you can sleep in my bed down.
Thank you, thank you very much.
Okay!
My god!
Kandiappa!
What is this?
Look! That"s my ¤shirt.
Don"t be afraid they
7000 Kandi"s children
Hello! Ponni!
Madhu! Meet Mr Glappan.
What?
- Glappan
Glappan.
- Glappan.
Glappa, let"s go!
Kurma, walk fast
Hey! Give my ¤shirt and go.
- Come fast.
Went away.
Good morning!
- Good morning.
Morning Sir!
Good morning everybody.
Good morning!
Hello!
Give it to me.
No matter, sir!
lt"s okay!
You say!
Yaamba! - Amblee. Yaamba!
- Amblee.
l think the game has begun.
Don"t you want to see?
Kakapooi has started playing.
Kakapoyee?
lt"s the name of the person
playing along with Pargodan.
Playing along are
Vellayal and Chakanja.
They are Pargodan"s ministers.
The healthy fellow sitting behind ls
Hidumbi, Pargangodans younger brother.
He is a glutton.
What is that thing?
Those blue and green ones.
Those are the Pala-pala,
colourful stones..
..we get them from the
blue lake you saw on your way.
They are worthless but
if you want to marry here.
You need to give women,
a set of pala pala.
Ambli, ambli.
- Come come.
Kakapayee one more time.
That"s not right.
Everyday it"s a foul play.
Our Kakapoyee has all
attention on Meenkanni.
Only if he wins and gives her
a set of pala pala can he marry her.
And if you lose you will
have to keep the horny fruit.
After keeping it
repeatedly Pargangodan..
..and chakanja have
difficulty in walking.
Why isn"t anyone ready yet?
Don"t we have to go back?
Come we will get late otherwise.
There is a travel of 2-3 days.
Okay!
Anandu will drop you.
Who?
The mountain tribe.
- We aren"t coming.
You may go.
No, l will go only with you.
l need to get fresh.
There is a river nearby.
Okay!
- Go and see.
l"m stuck.
l Don"t know where to start from.
Curiosity.
- Curiosity?
Create curiosity.
A weapon to attract humans.
Sir! what are you intending.
You will get to know. Philipose.
What is the way for it.
Where is the treasure?
Treasure?
lt was mentioned in the letter.
About a treasure.
Treasure..This village
is the treasure.
Village?
- Yes!
This is a kind of fooling man.
So he came so far in
search of some treasure?
Come fast.
- Come, come.
l"m very irritated.
l don"t give my dress
for anyone to wear.
So this was the treasure
mentioned in the letter.
So what did you think and come here.
Give that one.
l was actually supposed to go.
Then why didn"t you go?
The thought of leaving
all of you held me back.
lt"s tingling.
Glappaa!
l know Shamshu brother very well.
His Great mango tree act.
l have seen.
He is my father.
Why didn"t Shamshudin come?
- He asked me to escape.
Escape? Murder?
l hit some people who
couldn"t treat women well.
Now you are going to watch.
l was living in my
homeland doing petty jobs.
Could be because l do
not have a mother or sister.
lf anyone speaks ill about women,
l lose my marbles.
You just wind up everything. Fast.
l will come back now.
What happened?
There is no time,
Shamshu brother come fast.
When that monster did that
in front of me, l whacked him.
Doing all such notorious deeds,
police is following you.
Bheraan! Bheraan. Wake up.
Bheraan, wake up!
Leave the place as soon as possible,
police will come now.
Make it fast, Saidhuali is no more.
Saidhuali?
The person whom you whacked yesterday.
l will call.
- Okay!
lt was later that l noticed
the letter inside the box.
Then, l headed here.
Did that man die?
- No idea.
Don"t you remember
Shamshu brother's magic.
Give me that mug.
Let me see if l remember anything
l"d learned when l was a kid.
Run fast boy!
- Fast, fast.
Run fast
Watch that.
Smoke! Smoke!
Fire! Fire.
lsn"t it enough.
You haven"t forgotten?
- Remember certain things.
The magic has worked out.
You"ve made them curious.
Now, we need to find ways
to attract other villagers.
l have an idea.
Don"t know whether it will work.
- What is it?
l used to play a note.
And they respond to it.
Why don"t you try it then?
- Yes!
Why did you stop? Continue it.
l had composed a track.
A bit boring though. But let"s try it.
Guys please! Come and watch this.
Come.
Hey! Anandu. Hey!
"A new song has emerged here"
"will there be a tune out of dreams"
"it is a change from top to bottom here"
"today we are one body and one soul"
"we shall write ballards"
"from your beauty arises small stars"
"someone is singing"
"we shall unite into one"
"shall see and know unknown sights"
"the body is antoxicated
with spirit, so as the soul"
"stars are singing"
Hey! Help!
Sam!
Hey! Where are you going
With this baggage? Are you leaving?
Going to keep it in sun light..
lt hasn"t received
any sunlight for days.
What?
Sunsign! Box! To show it.
Sunsign? Box?
Stupid fellow!
Your hair has spoiled, let me see.
Shall l show you a trick?
Shall l show?
There is a Jin, inside this box.
Puppy!
What is that?
Okay! Then catch it, catch it.
Okay! Then shall l go? Nabesukutty?
Neelan!
- Yes! Got it.
The same result.
Mobile phones can be charged
using solar energy, isn"t it?
Why not?
Look it"s perfect.
- Wait.
What should be done
for a bar to appear in this?
Mr Beraan.
lf you go up on the rock
you will get some range. - Oh!
Okay! Here you are!
Hi!
- Hey! Sam.
The man has changed completely.
l feel like a new man.
l feel so rejuvenated.
l"m at the right place
as you said the other day.
Thank you! Sir. Thanks for everything.
There are many such hidden secrets
in this forest which are unknown.
Right! There could be many treasures.
That"s it..
..it would be good if everyone
understands it and act accordingly.
Yes! Yes!
He did not die.
- Die?
Yes! - Who?
The person whom l hit.
lt was his grandfather who expired.
What is he saying?
- Has beeran gone mad?
Who is he talking about?
- l don"t understand.
Look! That much has
been cut in just two days.
That"s a big area.
This will soon reach 7000 Kandi.
Did you see there?
Where?
- There.
Look! They are the
Famous Mangalore brothers.
Now! There are so many out there.
They have chopped
and destroyed everything.
They are continuing cutting. Aren"t they?
- Yes! Yes.
They will destroy everything in,
no time.
lt is sad to know
that they are going..
..to make paper napkins
and toilet papers with these woods.
See! - Give it.
Gone ! Everyone will die,
7000 Kandi will be destroyed.
Goodness! Gone! Gone!
Don"t be afraid. Don"t be afraid.
Wait, wait.- Come. come.
Sister! Sister! Everything
is gone sister. Everything is gone.
You will have to save us.
- What?
No!
First, step down.
You will have to save us.
Sit! Be seated.
We will save you,
but you will have to stand by us.
Parangodan doesn"t
understand the seriousness.
He plays and plays
and loses it every time.
Okay! What if we help him win?
Lift it! Taka!
Snake! We won.
Wah! Wah!
Sir! Have a look.
Roll it once more.
Rolled, rolled now show.
Roll fast shall stop.
This is cheating.
Roll it.
Shall we tell Glappan?
l think it is the right time.
Thhaka. Amble!
Let me see.
Want to see.
- He will tell them, won"t he?
Be careful.
Let me see.
Lost!
Hey!
No, need.
What happened?
Sit! Roll once more.
Needed?
Meekannai!
- Sit down.
Now start.
You all run, run.
Go! Get away.
ldiots!
Now, l shall roll.
Roll, roll.
Star!
- Me, snake.
Snake?
Kakapoyee, you lost, you lost.
l have won, l have won.
l think We are on the right track.
Now you shall roll.
- They are there.
Minnkanni. Roll.
Kakapayee has lost.
See!
Say the symbol and roll the dice.
Cheater!
Guards.
Hey!
- Not me, not me.
Betrayer's son.
Uncle! Those people out there.
We won because of them.
Who are they?
He Has seen us.
Mother! You cheaters.
Forgive! Forgive!
We won, we won.
The Alert signal!
Run.
Why are they running?
lt"s their distress signal
They have sensed some danger!
Come! Come! Come!
Hey! lt"s okay!
Come, come on.
They are frightened seeing something.
Guys kneel down.
- What happened?
What happened?
See!
lt"s the first time that
they have come this close.
Somehow only if some miracles
happen can 7000 Kandi be saved.
They have come to
cut down this forest.
Trees will go, hutments will go, and
this village too. Everything will go.
You tell us. We will do anything.
But save us please.
We will try.
We will do whatever we can.
As they have reached here.
Will have to talk to
the contractors once more.
l don"t think there will be any use.
But still..
Philipose,
you go and try speaking once more
lf it still doesn"t work,
we will give them an answer.
But that should be a surprise.
l have a medicine for that.
l"m also game for it.
But, there is one thing.
No one should be seriously injured.
What is a way for that?
Didn"t you speak of that ghost
the other day? l will bring it.
But, Mangalore brothers
should not come back here.
No human should be injured.
Total calamity.
- Yes.
They will not come. l will see to it.
l know how to handle it.
For that one should know
how this forest will help you.
For that we will go out in
team and will find out how and why.
l want to some soda
tonic with quinine.
ln this forest?
- Yes!
l will send Vedan to town.
lt might take 4 days though.
Quinine
Kunine!
- Quinine
Quinine.
Kolan!
- Quinine.
lf it is so then l need some
potassium nitrate and sulphur.
l will prescribe it.
We will need it in more amounts.
l too want more quinine.
What if we frighten them?
Fear!
Fear! That"s the biggest shock
which can be ever given to an enemy.
Rest all is,
as the fate of 7000 Kandi.
Greeting Sir!
- Greetings.
Are you fine?
Why Guru? Have come
again to get under our skin?
Haven"t we told you.
Not to come here over and
over again saying the same thing?
lt"s very important for us.
The forest.
ln that Kodalibeda,
that is Tevar's forest.
lt"s precious nature. Don"t ruin it.
l"m saying it for your own good.
We have seen many forests.
What"s so great about this one?
Simply don"t try to frighten us.
lt"s not so simple.
150yrs back.
This forest had scared off the
Prestigious Lord Livingstone company.
During fearful dark moon lunar phases.
Natural forces are
at their highest powers.
So, only 3 days to
go be a little vigilant.
l have told whatever l had to say.
The rest is up to you. May l leave?
ls he making porridge?
Not Porridge. Magic!
An elephant that
reproduced 2 weeks back.
You are too fond of animal
excreta and shit, right?
These Buffalos..
Buffalo! Not wild
buffalo the domestic one.
There is no use off.
Move away!
Brave man, brave man.
Hurry!
What is the technique of it?
Bheeran, That"s the trick
of a soon-reproduced elephant"s dung.
ls it?
What are you doing brother?
Have powdered all the tuber crop.
lt"s as smelly as the
transport stand"s toilet.
lt is the fresh shit of bats.
That all is there! Man.
Come let"s go.
What happened?
What is it?
Quinine on electric water.
What is this for?
What a foul smell.
Don"t you have any aversion for it?
That"s sulphur! Now we need
to add some potassium nitrate.
That is, bat"s shit.
Pity!
- Yes! Bats poop!
Have you all heard
of the war for bat"s poop.
The battle of Angamos,
or the war of the Pacific.
That war was held for bat"s poop
War? - Battle, yeah, now you
know the power of Bat"s shit.
That"s okay, but,
what are you going to do with this?
That"s our surprise.
Bhoom!
You"ve been saying
that for a long time
Come, come. Everyone come.
Now the villagers will
transform into forest ghosts.
Please turn of the light.
How is this?
Great job!
So this is the ghost.
Come.
Sit! Sit.
Coming, coming.
You go in front,
l will come behind and you stay here.
Here! Hold.
Pull it, pull it.
- Pull it, pull it.
Swami! Don"t roll over and fall down.
- You pull it man.
Pull it without making noise.
Tie it, tie it.
You see there.
Where has it fallen from?
Who did this?
Oh! God.
What is happened to our car?
Professor did you
see their trepidation.
They have got really panicked.
Look!
Queen!
Peeko?
"Paccha maandeeni"!
Cat scratched or what?
No, " Paccha maandeeni "! Did you
understand? " Paccha maandeeni ". Did you?
God!
- But it is hair.
Hey! Look carefully man!
What is it? Buffalo?
What is it?
lt"s a raging bull. A raging bull.
You are an adventure guy you
must be having some kind of body art.
Oh! Bird.
Let me see!
Oh! Phoenix rising from the ashes.
Yes! Phoenix.
Sam, is now like a phoenix bird.
You have risen from your ashes.
Cheers! For that.
- Cheers!
Haven"t anything tattooed over you?
This was tattooed
when l went to China!
And this is an aztec tattoo
it was done from Peru. - Nice.
And this is a Hawaiian friend"s.
Looks like geometry!
And.
Mayan from Mexico.
- Elder brother!
My Vel.
Spear.
- Vel!
Have you tattooed?
- Too, too.
Tattoo!
What is it? Tattoo!
- Tatoo!
l don"t do tattoos l"m
even scared of injections.
Bheraan! There is no chance
of Ananthu having any of this.
Do you know Mardi Gras?
That"s a festival in New Orleans.
Yes! Yes! Yes. l had a Puerto
Rican girlfriend over there.
Girlfriend?
- Yes, girlfriend.
l have tattooed her face.
Show it.
- What?
- Oh! No.
Show it.
Show it man.
- Show it.
Do l need too
Show it.
ls it on you leg?
"the brave tale of warriors, brave in action
the cry of success at the war front"
"has inbibed the courage takes
maticulous steps for success"
"blessed with courage to reach the aim"
"a soul to awaken and to protect"
"let the soul arise boldly, like dawn
like wind in the woods"
"like live cool, let the courage
smoulder within you"
"the sky flowers, the clouds sways on it"
"shall win and shall take steps forward"
What happened?
Check it out!
What happened, sir?
Up there..
- Yes, up there..
Hey, go and check.
What.. what"s happening?
Run! Run! Run! Run!
Run! Men Run! Run!
Hey! some one save me!
God.
Save me.
Save me, save me.
7000 Kandi is not the
village it was earlier.
There is no Melamadhi
and Kelamadhi now.
All have become like Ponni,
full of love and unity.
As Menon sir wished no
one was injured in the war.
The magic you gave.
The evil spirits and
the courage you gave.
And the weapons you created.
With all these there is no trace
of the Mangalore Brothers here now..
And then as you know.
Lease period is only for 4 months
After that this jungle will be
taken over by the lndian government.
This is not the problem now.
Have you heard of Vincci Rual?
construction co-operation.
lt"s one of world"s biggest
construction companies.
They have taken up the
place of Mangalore brothers.
They don"t require 4 months..
within 2 months they can
cut off the forest and destroy it.
lt"s not enough if Pargodan,
me and the villagers think of it.
lf you still have that same
Youthful will and boundless spirit.
Please come.
Malavedan, the villagers
and l are waiting for you.
Yours truly..
..Philipose John Varkey.
Movie re-ecoded by ViZNU or P2PDL.com
Check out more releases at P2PDL.com