Pablito!
Come here, sonny.
Sorry, kid, you're fired.
But why, if I'm doing my job well?
It's because you're so young,...
and of an age to still be at school.
I don't go to school because I need to work.
Yeah, sure, but I don't want trouble with the authorities,...
so you're out of here.
¤ If God lets me grow...
¤ I will ask Him at once...
¤ to never let me be...
¤ just one more ill-fated creature of Him.
¤ I want Him to teach me...
¤ how to struggle and defeat life's challenges.
¤ Don't want to be no general,...
¤ let alone president,...
¤ neither do I want to yap...
¤ like so many people do....
¤ those who earn their bread...
¤ with the sweat of their brow.
¤ When I'm grown up, I want...
¤ to choose my own fate,...
¤ a love that doesn't deceive,...
¤ to feel decent...
¤ and to live a stranger to hunger...
¤ where there aren't so many people around.
¤ Nor do I want to consider...
¤ a full career...
¤ only to be forced to clock in...
¤ way early in the morning...
¤ just to be grumbled down...
¤ by an illiterate boss.
¤ When I'm grown up, I want...
¤ to choose my own fate,...
¤ a love that doesn't deceive,...
¤ to feel decent...
¤ and to live a stranger to hunger...
¤ where there aren't so many people around. ¤
I'm hungry.
Well, see what you can find,...
I dropped the eggs.
Oh, get out of the way!
I'll fix them.
You're a dreadful cook.
Why not add some jam?
What for? Use your finger instead, it'll taste better.
What a laugh!
So you don't burn yourself...
You got most of it.
~ They ran me out of the shop.
The shop foreman said: "No, kid, beat it,...
"you're too young to be a car repair apprentice."
The Spaniard in the bakery said the same thing,...
that he didn't want problems with the authorities.
It's not the first time we've been chased out of our jobs.
And it won't be the last.
It'll be this way until we're adults.
Tomorrow it's the same old same old.
It's your turn to wash the dishes.
And your turn to dry them.
~ You know what, buddy?
~ What?
The tenth of May's only three days away.
Give me a break, you've been saying that for a month!
Well, yeah, buddy,...
you said so because you don't have a special someone to give a present to.
Sorry, buddy.
I didn't mean that.
I forgot that your mom is gone.
My mom died when I was born.
I grew up in an orphanage.
At my very first opportunity, I escaped...
and here I am.
Yes, but let's not talk about it.
You see, look, I don't have a father.
I have my mom, but she's in prison...
accused of theft,...
unjustly.
Look:...
I've got forty pesos.
You save up twenty...
and soon we'll have the amount demanded by the bondsman...
to get your mom out of jail.
No, buddy, I can't take your money.
You always do the same thing!
You and your mom have done much more than that for me, you've accepted me into your home like it was my own,...
and we're blood brothers forever, right?
That's right.
Well, with what you earn and with mine,...
God willing, soon we will have the amount...
so we can spring your mom.
OK, take this. They're one...
Another bloody day has gone.
You should give thanks rather than curse.
Each day that passes, we're closer to freedom.
Thanks, lady, but...
you only got two years for your theft.
I haven't stolen anything.
The owner of the jewelry store blamed me for everything, and...
they sentenced me.
Oh, baby, don't play innocent!
Everyone in here sings the same song.
But I stole from the old dear I worked for.
And if I left right now I could break her neck.
That's what you should do to your employer.
No. I have my son to think about.
I'm just waiting to finish up this sentence so I can make up for all the lost time.
Hey, Sister,...
you're really taking it bad!
You should be a soap opera star...
or something like that.
You speak like that because you don't know the joy of having a child.
You're right.
I lost my child at birth.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
Don't sweat it.
You still haven't told me who your son's father is.
His name's Cristóbal,...
he's a rich guy.
Let me guess.
He abandoned you and took up with someone else, right?
No. I left him when I learned he had someone else.
You never considered getting back with him?
No.
He's a strong guy with a violent temper.
He'd never forgive me.
He's stubborn and obsessive...
Sonia,...
are you asleep?
What's up?
Whose turn is to use the pajama shirt?
Don't play the silly, it's yours!
I'm asking for the bottom bunk, OK?
I know!
But turn off the light.
There we go.
NO OPENINGS
¤ How I miss the streets of my home town.
¤ Unfortunately I had to leave them.
¤ But my mother was taken to the Eternal...
¤ and I had to leave to find work.
¤ My beautiful homeland I remember...
¤ when I roam the vast capital.
¤ I thought I was an abandoned child,...
¤ an orphan, and overwhelmed by my problems...
¤ but I believe that fate has sent me...
¤ a friend to suffer the same. ¤
BOY NEEDED
¤ I've fought luck to a draw.
¤ People know us as the two buddies.
¤ Misery has us cornered...
¤ but we're real friends...
¤ although there are beings so malicious...
¤ who want to catch us in their talons.
¤ They don't understand these two kids...
¤ who, though poor, we understand real friendship.
¤ We're going now, goodbye, goodbye, friends.
¤ We love to travel to many places...
¤ if fate brings bad things...
"THE GOLDEN CUCKOO" WATCHMAKER
¤ one day I'll sing my songs again.
¤ If we get trapped into an orphanage, like a prison...
¤ recite an "Our Father" for our two buddies. ¤
No way, brother,...
today wasn't my day.
I was already holding it just right forh pedaling...
when suddenly a damned truck got in my way.
I was already a seasoned expert with my stilts...
and unexpectedly, those dogs got in my way...
and I fell all the way down.
You two, both of you.
You want to earn a few pesos?
What do we have to do?
Come on,...
I'll tell you all about it.
Look at this guy.
Thinks we're going to steal the brush.
At least we didn't waste the whole day without work.
It's the work of a Chinaman.
Oh, count to 10!
What for?
It's a cure for anger.
How far have you counted?
Me? Up to 500.
I always count past 500.
Listen, you guys.
I didn't hire you to stand around yapping.
Back to work if you want to earn those pesos.
What do you think we're doing...
playing marbles or what?
Shut up, or you'll piss him off!
Hey, you're wetting me, take that hose away!
We're looking for Don Cristóbal.
Why are you looking for him, Francisco?
You know where the main office is,...
and his house.
We were in these parts and we heard he's around here.
Don Cristóbal has other building sites like this one.
Have you already been to the other building sites?
Don't play stupid, Tomás...
he ought to be here.
Of course he should be here!
Fine, will you call him, or should we go look for him?
I don't think that suits you,...
especially you who have families to support.
Don't play smart with us, Tomás.
Call Don Cristóbal.
What the hell do you want, Francisco?
I want to talk with you.
Wouldn't it be better if you got to work?
I do not neglect your interests, boss, but I also represent the interests of my peers.
OK.
Let's end this once and for all.
You come in.
And you, who are you?
I'm Toño and he's my friend Pablo.
They're just scrubbing the path, Don Cristóbal.
There's really nothing you can do to help kids like those, Francisco.
No employee who works in my companies will be unionized.
We have the right, Don Cristóbal, to improve our living conditions.
What rights are you talking about?
I pay them enough money.
If then they decide to spend it in bars, that's their problem.
We want to be part of the union...
to get better earnings and working conditions.
Absolutely not.
So you better give up those ideas...
if you do not want to end up out of work.
If you do that, Don Cristóbal, we will go on strike.
What, you're threatening me?
No, boss. Just think about it before brushing us off.
Those workers are very angry. How come, buddy?
Beats me.
Well, we'd better go collect, right?
Here's your pay.
If you want more jobs, just drop in here.
There's always something needing doing.
Thank you, sir.
Did you see the site boss,...
Don Cristóbal?
Yes. What about him?
I don't know...It felt like I'd seen him before somewhere.
Are you feeling all right?
Look, pal, you'd better pay the back rent due to Don Rodolfo.
All of it?
But we only owe him five payments!
Anyway! If we pay him we'll be out of the money...
that we should be giving to the bondsman to spring your Mom.
No, kiddo.
If Don Rodolfo throws us out of the room, then he throws us out...
but Mom is the first thing..
Well, do as you please.
The room's yours,...
I'm only a guest.
No, buddy, I didn't mean that.
What I meant was that I wouldn't mind sleeping outside.
Don Rodolfo is a nice old guy,...
maybe he won't complain if we pay him just a single payment.
Listen, Toño,...
don't you miss your parents?
Yes. I think it would be nice to call someone Mom and Dad...
and to know who your parents are.
Hey, Toño,...
I don't care if you call mine mom, too.
Anyway, she loves you as much as she loves me.
¤ Give me, for God's sake, your blessing,...
¤ oh, my beloved mother,...
¤ I beg your pardon,...
¤ for you having suffered so much.
¤ Where you are now, in Father's house,...
¤ a sight I crave,...
¤ oh, Mother dear,...
¤ pray for me to God.
¤ You who are in the mansion of the heavenly throne...
¤ send to my heart a motherly sigh.
¤ A maternal sigh send to my heart,...
¤ may it reach, oh, may it reach my heart.
¤ Look, mother, there's no one in the world who loves you as I do.
¤ See that a mother's love is as great as God's.
¤ mother's love passed by, and it was my only delight.
¤ You who are in the mansion of the heavenly throne...
¤ send to my heart a motherly sigh.
¤ A maternal sigh send to my heart
¤ may it reach, oh, may it reach my heart.
¤ Look, mother, there's no one in the world who loves you as I do.
¤ You'll see a mother's love is as great as God's.
¤ Mother's love passed by, and it was my only delight.
¤ Give me, for God's sake, your blessing...
¤ oh, my dear mother,...
¤ and I beg your pardon...
¤ for you having suffered so much.
¤ Where you are now, in Father's house,...
¤ a sight I crave,...
¤ oh, Mother dear,...
¤ pray for me to God. ¤
I'll get some refreshments.
Coward!
Don Rodolfo! Blessed are eyes that see.
Why are you visiting?
Quit fooling around --- I'm here for the rent.
Come on in! Come in!
Do you want a glass of water?
Speaking of rent arrears, you owe me six.
That many?
What do you mean, "that many"? You haven't paid me a thing in six months!
Time sure flies, doesn't it. Don Rudi?
Don't change the subject. I want my money.
Coincidently, I have it right here.
What's this?
This much only covers one month's rent.
This is better than nothing.
There isn't any money, Don Rudi.
Look, kid, I've given you a lot of breaks.
It's not my fault your mom's been banged up in the slammer.
She and I had an understanding, so either pay me or move out.
What a child of your sainted mother!
Did you see the old man?
He says that if we don't pay him what we owe, he'll run us off.
Then let's work hard.
Shall we go visit Tomás?
Maybe he's got work for us.
OK. Let's go.
OK, but I can only keep you on part time.
You're both school-aged...
and I don't want a hassle.
Do not worry, Tomás, we're used to working odd jobs.
But what is there to be done?
Come along. I'll show you.
Tomorrow's visiting day.
I can't resist the desire to see my husband and children.
Me, too.
You want some?
Of course, to relieve the tension.
How long are you going to be here?
Two years!
That's nothing.
It feels like an eternity to me.
Hey, girl!
You should try to see the good side of all this.
Here we get fed,...
and free clothes,...
and even a bed.
But no company.
Who cares about that?
I'm used to being on my own.
I am alone inside...
and I'm alone outside.
So why should I care?
But you're different. I've got a son,...
he's eleven years old.
Oh, cutie, you're very worried about your son!
And within three years he'll fall in love and drop you like a dead pigeon.
Pablo? Like Hell he will!
No, he's different.
My despair is that he's out there all alone,...
not knowing what to do...
Such is life.
We get hit over and over again.
But have faith: your son will end up being a man.
You don't have someone you can make him stay with?
He lives with a friend of his own age
who has it even worse than he does.
Why?
My son has me, even if I'm rotting in jail,...
but Toño, as far as I know, has no one.
The poor kid!
Now, into formation, come on, quickly!
Fast, move it!
Right face!
Move, move!
Ditch the cigarette!
Come on, let's go.
Quickly, quickly, let's go! Let's go!
What's your name?
Toño, Ma'am.
You can call me Manuela.
Everyone else does.
Hey, is that other guy your brother?
Almost.
Almost?
We're just like family.
You don't have parents?
Why are you asking me that?
Well, don't answer if you don't feel like it.
I'm an orphan.
~ You know what, Toño?
~ What?
We've got something in common:...
I'm an orphan, too.
I don't have anybody.
And what you see here is my home.
What's your name?
I'm Pablo.
And what are you doing here?
I'm cleaning the window glass.
But I'm almost done.
Go on, beat it.
Is something wrong?
That boy.
What's up with him?
I don't know.
I have the impression of having seen him somewhere before.
Your coffee. Extra strong, sir.
Like you like it.
Julián.
Sir.
Do you remember my wife?
Sure, she was very good looking.
And Pablito, our boy?
Yes, sir.
I saw him today, Julián.
Sir!
It's been eight years since...
Yes. Since she left with the boy.
I'm sorry, sir.
He's the spitting image of his mother.
He ought to be 11 by now.
Yes.
He's been at the construction headquarters these past few days...
laboring,...
with a little buddy.
Excuse me. Have you told him who he is?
No.
I prefer that it all be forgotten now, as it has been all along.
But she's your wife, sir.
And that boy is your son.
Miss Marisa is coming to dinner.
Have everything ready.
Certainly, sir.
200 pesos, pal!
It won't be long before we get the 2,000,...
so we can pay the bondsman to get her out of jail.
I'd wanted to rob a bank.
You'll see we'll soon have saved that much, buddy.
Go on, take it.
I'll hide it in the broken chair.
In there's a good hiding place.
Bring the musical instruments to rehearse tomorrow's gig.
OK.
Now what? I broke it!
¤ The calf hasn't sucked,...
¤ the calf hasn't sucked,...
¤ because the cow did not come,...
¤ because the cow did not come.
¤ My grandmother feeds it,...
¤ my grandmother feeds it,...
¤ with the trash from the road,
¤ because that was its destiny.
¤ Lasso it, lasso it,...
¤ lasso it so it doesn't leave.
¤ Give me your arms, my soul, granny, if you really love me.
¤ Lasso it, lasso it,...
¤ lasso it so it doesn't leave.
¤ Grab me into your arms, my soul, granny, if you really love me.
¤ The calf hasn't sucked,...
¤ I have the pleasure of the calf,...
¤ I have the pleasure of the calf.
¤ Up and down the hill,...
¤ up and down the hill,...
¤ I walk among the cows...
¤ even if I neither drink nor eat,...
¤ Lasso it, lasso it,...
¤ lasso it so it doesn't leave.
¤ Grab me into your arms, my soul, granny, if you really love me.
¤ Lasso it, lasso it,...
¤ lasso it so it doesn't leave.
¤ Grab me into your arms, my soul, granny, if you really love me.
¤ I have the pleasure of the calf,...
¤ Calf, what are you doing there, calf, what are you doing there,...
¤ trapped in the horns of this ox,...
¤ Here does my mother hold me,...
¤ here does my mother hold me,...
¤ to turn me into its proper son,...
¤ to turn me into its proper son.
¤ Lasso it, lasso it,...
¤ lasso it so it doesn't leave.
¤ Grab me into your arms, my soul, granny, if you really love me.
¤ Lasso it, lasso it,...
¤ lasso it so it doesn't leave.
¤ Grab me into your arms, my soul, granny, if you really love me.
¤ The calf hasn't sucked. ¤
What's up with the furniture?
What the Hell's going on?
Don Rodolfo!
Don Rodolfo was the one who took the furniture.
He didn't want to wait for us to pay the back rent.
So what do we do now?
The old grunge!
The furniture, buddy! The chair.
Yeah, he took it.
Don't be silly,...
the couch's where I was hiding the can...
with the savings we had to get my mom out of jail.
No, pal,...
the old guy couldn't be that mean.
That old guy is a dried up old mummy.
Let's find him and demand that he return our money.
Man!
We don't have his address.
He'll come here to collect the rents of the others.
We'll be waiting for him. Come on.
And where do we sleep now?
Beats me.
Shall we go to the construction headquarters to see if they'll have mercy on us?
Yeah, let's go check.
Look, they even took the nails for hanging our helmets.
We want our money.
What money?
Don't play dumb, our money.
Yeah. It was hidden in the sofa.
Well, if you'd had money hidden,...
it's probably because you stole it, right?
We're not thieves, Don Rodolfo,...
and you know it.
This money was put aside to get my mom out of jail.
I took the furniture because you owe me a lot of money.
All right. Keep your filthy room,...
but we want our money and our furniture.
I sold the furniture to cover the debt you owe me,....
and if you had money in there, then it's as good as gone.
Now let me through. Go on, beat it.
Old thief!
That old jerk will remember us, Toño.
Yes, give him his due.
I have an idea, Toño. Come on.
At least he'll have to spend it on new paint for his car.
Yes, we really let him have it.
Don Cristóbal!
There won't be any work until he recognizes our union.
No work!
Look, buddy,
this is going to be bad.
What we ask for is just fair.
Sign or not a single truck will budge.
Sign, Don Cristóbal, so we can get back to work!
Sign!
Gather your people together and throw them out.
Yes, sir.
UNION RECOGNITION!
Attack them!
Let's go!
Why are you heating the water?
To heal up the hurt guys.
What? Could you be on Francisco's side?
Well, yes. Yes, I am. Yeah.
So why not take part in the demonstration?
No, I'm too old to mess in those things. No.
Besides, I need the work.
Send a coffee to Don Cristóbal.
You take it him yourself.
Wait.
So that old guy took away your room...
what a pity!
So where will you sleep?
Where the night finds us.
That's what I wanted to talk to you about.
If they let us sleep in the cellar...
my blood brother and I would work real hard .
Well, that's no problem for me, but...
only Don Cristóbal can authorize that.
And he's a sour man.
That guy's evil.
Look, let's try one thing:...
the first chance I get I'll mention it to him, OK?
Meanwhile...
I'll give you some money, here.
~ Thanks, Manuela.
~ To get a hotel room.
OK, help me get breakfast ready, or no one eats today.
Thanks. Hang on.
How old are you?
Eleven, sir.
Don't be afraid. I won't hurt you.
I'm not scared of you, sir.
Do you have a family?
Just my mother.
And where is your Mom?
My Mom?
Mom's on a trip.
Has your mother told you anything about your Dad?
No. She never has.
Fine, Don Cristóbal,...
goodbye.
Doña Manuela is as generous as can be.
She said she would talk to the owner of the building site...
to see whether he'll let Toño and me sleep in the cellar.
But don't worry, Mom.
Thank God!
I was worried about not knowing where you were sleeping.
Old usurer!
He couldn't wait a few months for me to pay him the rent.
I don't know, Mom,...
people are very strange.
Also, the owner of the building site was asking me many questions.
If my mom would talk about my dad,...
how old I was,...
and where you were.
Why would he want to know all that?
Who knows? But I didn't tell him a thing.
Don Cristóbal will pay for all the treatment for Francisco García,...
and is willing to compensate him.
I regret what happened, Juan,...
but I accept the responsibility.
Look, Cristóbal, the police have not intervened in this...
because it's a labor dispute,...
but we can't stay on the sideline...
if the row is repeated today.
I advise you to reach an agreement soon with your employees.
And now, you. What's up with you?
I'm worried about my son.
What's up with him?
The owner of the building site where he works...
has been asking questions about me.
Hey, woman!
You still care about those things.
Your son is very smart.
He can surely take care of himself.
At this point,...
he knows more about life than you and me together.
And that, Sister,
is really saying something!
The two kids are homeless.
Don Cristóbal, Pablito's mother is in jail,...
wrongfully convicted.
Toño's an orphan.
And how does that make them my problem?
OK,...
I only wanted,...
I want you to let them sleep in the cellar.
Well, if you find a place they can stay, fine.
Thank you.
Thank you, Don Cristóbal.
You say Pablito's mom is in jail?
That's right, sir,...
on a theft charge.
By your leave.
You can sleep here.
If you want something, you already know where the kitchen is.
Thank you, Ma'am.
~ Good night.
Sun.
Eagle. Hard luck.
You lost, you get the bottom.
Well, at least it's better than sleeping on the street.
Yeah.
150 pesos.
152.
At the rate we will never get the 2,000 pesos we have to give the bondsman...
to get my mom out of jail.
Look, you work here on the site,...
and I'll work the streets.
Sure, but here we're better as a pair. Look,...
we've got food and somewhere to stay.
Yeah, but they're not paying us very much.
Look, brother,...
if I go out on the street I'll have a chance to earn more money.
Sure, but we've always been together.
Always.
Working the street.
Don't be silly, brother.
If both of us hit the streets, they'll kick us out of the cellar and take away the food.
You're right.
But why are you doing this,...
when it's my mom who's locked up?
Because we're practically brothers, right?
What's mine is yours and what's yours is mine.
Now let's go to sleep!
Where are you going, Pablo?
To see my mom.
Where?
The woman's prison.
The other day I misled you.
My mom's not on a trip.
Don't worry. You don't have to be ashamed just because someone should happen to be stuck in there.
Yes, sir.
Why's your mom in the woman's prison?
They accused her of being a jewel thief.
I swear to you that she was innocent.
Her boss was heavy...
and infatuated with her.
She never payed attention to him.
I'm sure he framed her for something so she'd be put away.
I'm going to help you get your mom out of jail,...
but you have to promise me something.
When you learn who your father is, you forgive him,...
and you learn to understand him.
I've forgiven him.
I misled you, when I told you...
that my mom'd never spoken about my dad...
she did all the time.
And she spoke well of him.
If you want, I'll take you. Get in.
He's as generous as can be, Mom.
He pays great money, and he's willing to help you.
I don't understand why he wants to do this.
Because he's a good guy, Mom.
He's good, I like him.
I hope you get to know him.
Bravo!
The fight was a result of the stubbornness of Don Cristóbal,...
but also gives us evidence that he's about to give up.
We must strike harder.
We'll go for a complete strike!
Cristóbal Márquez has no choice but to accept the existence of our union!
Whoopee!
Don Cristóbal isn't here.
I can't allow the flag in that position.
It doesn't matter whether you agree or not,...
so don't step in, Tomás.
You haven't learned your lesson, Francisco?
Do you want to repeat the dose?
Look, we don't want problems,...
but like it or not, we'll put up this strike flag.
There aren't a lot of you.
I don't think that you're in any state to stand up to us.
Strike!
I think Don Cristóbal has lost the battle.
Whoopee!
Don Cristóbal will help us get my mom out of jail, man.
Great, brother!
I've got good news, too.
I got a job.
Working in that building.
How unexpected, buddy! How'd you do that?
Because the boss is a straight arrow.
When he saw my knowledge and abilities...
he gave me the job.
He gave you the job!
CONGRATULATIONS
Bravo!
I hope you had a nice day, Mom.
Thanks, son.
Thanks, Pablito. And thanks for coming, Toño.
My pleasure, Ma'am.
Let's hope this is the last May 10th you spend here in jail.
Yes, Mom, next year, God willing, you'll be with us at home.
¤ Lovely one that God has given me...
¤ to love,...
¤ you, lovely one who loves me without condition,...
¤ Heaven gave me love without earning it,...
¤ by looking at her eyes you'll learn who it is.
¤ With her no pain could lead to despair...
¤ lovely one that loves me with sweet love,...
¤ for her there's no pain she won't comfort away,...
¤ by looking into her face I'm looking at God.
¤ Oh, how happy I am...
¤ when I hear her talk!
¤ How much love I bring her...
¤ into this song!
¤ Oh, how happy I am...
¤ with her I'm happy.
¤ Live your life, my love,...
¤ the love I carry here inside.
¤ Oh, how happy I am...
¤ when I hear her talk.
¤ How much love I bring her...
¤ into this song!
¤ Oh, how happy I am!
¤ with her I'm happy.
¤ Live your life, my love,...
¤ the love I carry here inside.
It's been a fine day.
Take care of yourself, son.
Yes, Mom,...
and rest assured we'll have you out of here soon.
Yes, I know you and Toño are working to save up for the bondsman,...
but it's more important to take care of yourself and eat when you should.
Don't worry, Ma'am,...
Pablo and I know how to take care of ourselves.
How good you are!
I know how much you like each other.
Like brothers, Mom.
We'll come to see you next visiting day, Mom.
Goodbye, my love.
Cristóbal is bringing people together.
He wants to break the strike.
Can he do that?
I'm afraid so.
We must expedite the process for entering the union.
Meanwhile, do not be intimidated.
We support you.
I know my rights,...
and your strike is illegal.
Since they're not unionized,...
they're committing a crime.
So tomorrow I want you to bring together as many people as possible...
and you'll break the strike for me.
There'll be brawl, Don Cristóbal.
That doesn't matter.
I want them to know once and for all that I'm serious.
~ Thanks.
~ Thank you.
Hi, how are things?
How was work?
Fine.
How about your problems?
Better.
I hope they are being resolved.
Let's have an ice cream --- on me.
Good, that's fine.
Have a seat.
Two ice creams, please.
Why do you fight so much with Don Cristóbal?
We're trying to form a union...
to help all the workers,...
but he won't go for it.
Don Cristóbal isn't a bad guy.
If what you're asking is the right thing, maybe he'll finally go along.
Well, maybe...
he knows what to do.
I'd better go, Francisco.
I have to look for my blood brother.
See you.
Good, but what about the ice cream, hey?
You can eat it.
Another day we'll share one. See you, Francisco.
Buddy!
~ What's up, brother?
~ How are you, bro?
Fine, let's go.
Time's up, pal, shall we go?
Yeah, I'm dead tired.
You should be happy, you're making a lot of money.
It's not like it used to be. I like to be by your side.
Nothing's going to change.
We are only separated by day.
It's not the same.
This job is hard.
Cheer up, man. I brought some cake.
Of course, since you don't have to come here...
If you want, I'll come help you every day.
But hurry up, buddy, it's getting late.
Hurry up, let's go, move!
DANGER ZONE!
WELLS CLOSED!
Pablo, Pablo!
Are you all right, Pablo?
Pablo, answer me, pal!
I'm going for help, Pablo!
DANGER!
DEEP WELLS!
Help!
Help, Toño!
Buddy, someone help me!
Toño, help me!
Toño! Bro, help me!
Let them recognize our rights.
Here comes Tomás and his people.
Remove your men, Francisco,...
and there won't be any problems.
No one's leaving. We'll still be here at dawn.
This is the last warning.
We're removing your strike banners...
and you'd better not get in our way.
Do so and the blood will flow here.
Gentlemen!
I've warned you that this strike is illegal...
so return to your homes...
and then nothing will happen.
How are you planning to end the strike?
You'd have to kill me this time, Don Cristóbal,...
I'm determined to stay here with my men until you recognize the union.
Don't think that I won't!
I'm sick of your rebellion!
Don Cristóbal, Don Cristóbal!
Pablo fell into a deep well.
How? Where?
Where the buildings are going up.
Let's go.
Let's go help that boy.
Let's go!
Pablo!
Pablito!
Answer me!
Pablito! Are you all right?
Help me!
Mom!
I can't climb out!
He's alive. He's alive!
Quickly, boys. Bring ropes and lamps.
Help me, please! Mom!
Blood brother!
Pablito, hang on!
We'll have you out in no time!
Mom! Help me!
Tie yourselves to the machines.
Pablo, son!
Listen carefully!
I'm going to lower a rope.
Wrap it around your waist.
Can you do that?
I'll try, sir!
I'll try! Oh, Mom!
My God!
Help, help!
Please get me out!
Pablo, that rope should be right by you.
Look for it and strap it on!
~ I can't.
~ Make an effort.
Look around for it.
I can't see it. I can't see a thing.
I'm going down for him.
It could be more than 100 feet deep, boss.
So what? I'm going down for him.
Help me!
Hold it right, eh?
Hang on.
Hold the rope there.
Be careful, boss!
Let the rope go, slowly.
Little by little, little by little.
I can't get by.
I don't fit.
The boss doesn't fit through.
Pull me out.
Slowly, slowly.
He can make it by.
It's very narrow.
That's right.
Don Cristóbal, I can get down that hole.
We could drop him head first.
That would be very dangerous.
We have to do it.
We have to try whatever we can.
We can't lose any more time.
That's good.
Be very careful, boy.
When you get to Pablo, give him your arms.
We'll draw you out.
Yes, sir.
Tie him snugly.
Real well.
Buddy!
Where are you?
Can you hear me?
They're lowering me down to you, Pablo.
Pablo!
Is this a dream?
You'll have to grab my arms...
so they can bring us up.
Harder!
Hold on!
Pablo!
Son!
Pablo, are you OK?
Toño.
Hold on my hands --- hard.
I can't, I'm slippery with mud, Toño.
Harder.
Toño!
Answer me!
Are you together?
Pablo!
Let's go!
I told you I can't.
I'm slipping.
Hold on.
Try again.
Come on, again!
Toño!
Are you already holding him?
Pablo!
I can't!
My hands keep slipping!
Try again!
Come on, boy, try again!
How are things going?
My son fell down a well.
We sent another boy to get him out by the arms.
How long has that boy been down there?
About half an hour,...
but he can't get a firm grip because of the mud.
He must be removed immediately.
We'll try something else.
Bring him up!
Bring him up, he can't do anything for me.
I'm going to try once more!
It's a landslide!
Slack the rope, it's dangerous!
Get back!
Stop.
We'll dig another well parallel to this one.
I want the charts for this whole surface.
But that'll take too long!
My son and that boy may still be alive!
Calm down!
We'll try to reach them as soon as possible.
Come on, Dolores.
What's going on?
No questions. Let's go!
You?
What are you doing here?
Pablito,...
our son,...
has had an accident.
Toño!
Toño, Toño!
Where?
Where are we, Pablo?
They're going to save us.
They're going to save us, buddy.
I can't budge.
I can't feel my body.
It's because of the mud.
We're in a muddy well.
Tell me the truth --- is there any hope?
I hope so.
According to the calculations, these kids ought to be...
between these two points.
But there's a risk, sir:...
it could produce another landslide.
I think if we approach from this other side...
we'll avoid the most fragile part.
No, we can't do it.
That would delay us for at least two hours.
We'll have to take risks and continue with the plan.
Over there, man.
Yes, sir, sure. Light up my way.
I can't see a thing.
Careful, careful.
What's that noise?
What's going on?
It's a landslide!
Landslide!
It's over.
Relax.
Yeah, it's stopped.
Pablo, buddy!
Don't be scared, Toño.
Don't be scared, blood brother.
They're going to save us.
Cristóbal, I can't stand this waiting.
You've got to have faith.
~ I'm sure they'll find them.
~ But when?
They've been digging for eight hours.
It'll be dawn soon...
and they can't hold out much longer.
You have to have confidence.
Thanks for warning me,...
thanks for having managed to get me out.
You won't be going back to that place.
Everything is arranged.
Why did this have to happen?
Maybe for the two of us to meet again.
Look, Dolores, when I figured out that Pablito was my son,...
I realized how silly I had been with you.
You know I'm a man of few words.
Maybe this is a new opportunity for us.
I need you.
I need Pablito.
Come back to me.
Shine some light so I can see, man.
Go, go, man!
Full throttle ahead!
The light!
~ What's happening, Francisco, don't you see them?
~ Light!
Don't you see them?
Yes!
Are they all right?
Prepare a stretcher!
It's Toño!
Bring another stretcher.
Step aside, step aside.
The other stretcher!
Pablito!
Careful! Quickly, let's move!
They'll be fine, Ma'am. I assure you.
Thanks, thanks very much!
Let's go. Quickly. By your leave.
There'll be no more problems between us.
I recognize your union, Francisco.
Thanks, boss.
Thanks a lot.
Bravo, bravo!
¤ To you, Daddy dear,...
¤ who brought me into this world,...
¤ my mom and you together brought me,...
¤ I carry your blood in my veins,...
¤ you have many fine points,...
¤ I want to be like you.
¤ I want to follow your example...
¤ and our house is a temple...
¤ and you're my God, Papa.
¤ I pay attention to your ways,...
¤ how proud I am to be your son,...
¤ thanks for being my Dad.
¤ Maybe I've been a bad boy,...
¤ because I ask and I demand...
¤ for what you're not able to give me.
¤ I've caused you trouble,...
¤ anxieties and terrors...
¤ because I behave very badly.
¤ I want to follow your example...
¤ and our house is a temple...
¤ and you're my God, Papa.
¤ I pay attention to your ways,...
¤ how proud I am to be your son,...
¤ thanks for being my dad.