'Now we have a news alert
coming in at this hour…'
'from West Bengal's Purulia district…'
'A short while ago,
a bomb exploded...'
'in the convoy of cars,
passing through a village.'
'Number dead or injured,
are yet unconfirmed. '
'As per sources, van has been stolen.'
'And it may be a land-mine blast.'
'We are getting fresh
reports to keep you updated. '
'Do stay with us.'
Sir, we want to
report a missing case.
We are tired running
from pillar to post
Every police station says,
it's not under their jurisdiction.
We're very upset.
Sir, if you could...
Name?
Ishan Bharti.
Age?
26 years, approximately.
How is he related to you?
He is my brother.
Your name?
Namita.
Namita…
Bharti!
It’s Yadav…
He is my husband.
Aman Yadav.
What does your brother do?
He is a graduate in Political Science,
from Maulana Azad College.
Is he a student?
No, he is a theatre artist.
Oh, you mean unemployed, right?
Address?
2/137 A, Jhama Pukur Lane,
Amherst Street, Kolkata - 9.
He is missing since last two weeks.
Last when I tried calling him,
his phone rang...
... but he didn’t answer my call.
His phone is switched off since then.
Is he into drugs, or any substance?
No, not at all.
He is a street theatre artist...
so has to travel places
but he is not into drugs.
And... any girl related issues?
Err, Ankita Chauhan,
she's his friend,
a very decent girl.
We don’t have her contact details though.
Do you suspect anyone?
- Anyone you know, who intends
to cause any harm to him?
Thank you so much.
- Yes, ma’am.
- May I take a call please?
Yes, ma’am.
Good night.
Sure!
I know this,
and also, Kunal believes,
you are quite sharp at
sniffing important stories.
Varman is a heavy weight.
I know you won’t be
swayed by rumors.
Unless you have proof
of his involvement,
you will not write anything
against him.
that can later attract a
defamation lawsuit against us.
Exactly!
Okay?
Mr. Ranjan Varman,
thank you so much for
being our guest...
and for handling all uncomfortable
questions with such aplomb.
We’ll see you again next saturday,
on ‘Khaas Mulakat’.
Stay tuned to Metro News.
(Next station is Netaji Bhavan.)
That night, at the police station,
I didn’t realize, Namita,
or this story,
would become
so important to me.
I am time the eternal...
Hmm.
The destroyer of all people
at all levels of existence.
Even if you don’t act,
your opponents will disappear
in the near future.
Whatever is destined...
… can’t be changed.
Now explain why were
you late last night.
War!
Who was your poor opponent?
Kunal Da!
- Kunal?
- Yeah!
Why?
He feels I may get targeted.
I have no clue.
This is just a story.
What’s to worry about?
A story of someone 'missing'.
A boy who is lost.
So?
No!
It’s not just a story
about a boy who is lost.
In fact, to start with,
it’s a love story.
Come on, aren’t love stories
supposed to have romance, etc.
Will you allow me
to narrate first?
Before jumping to
conclusions, as always.
Ishan Bharti…
Crazy about theatre...
and a girl, called Ankita.
He was never into practicality
or any mundane things.
According to his friends,
Ankita loved him for what he was,
which also scared her
for the same reasons.
Let's try something new?
My salary is delayed again.
I really don't know how
long this channel will last.
Great, atleast one hate
factory will shut down.
Why don't you find some work?
Mere love can't run a kitchen.
I came from a UP government
school, and got till here...
I don’t want to struggle all my life.
I need to speak to my
parents about us.
Hearing "Ishan Bharti", your folks
won't know what hit them...
...it won't matter if the boy's a
shopkeeper or an artist.
We'll have to elope and marry.
What say?
Hey...
Hey, come…
...let’s go now to
the marriage registrar’s office.
Okay, I am game.
Are you sure?
Yes, of course.
Brother, cheque please.
She is Ankita Chauhan,
one of our brightest anchors.
Please sit.
There's something about you...
… you hit us hard with
your sugar-coated questions.
rest of the anchors ask
mundane questions,
but act like they are
pelting stones at us.
May I have your number please?
Hello.
Ankita ma’am?
Mr. Varman wants to talk to you.
There is something I wanted
to speak to you about.
It’s a job offer.
Ankita is quite ambitious.
Although her channel
is small...
... and also, on the
verge of shutting down.
So, should I stop?
You always interrupt
my story, Nanu (Grandpa).
Let me explain,
A child is the father of a man.
In this case,
you are the father; I am the child.
Nanu!
Hi!
How’s the new job going?
Good sir.
I heard you are
very hard working...
I have a gift for you.
Sure sir.
So where would you like to go?
Darjeeling or Goa?
Hmm.
That can be arranged.
Ishan,
I need this job badly.
I promise to not stress
you out with anything.
I know theatre is your life.
Let’s be selfish for a change.
You can discreetly
come over to my flat,
I don’t see any problem.
Sent you my address.
Whenever you visit me,
just don’t make any entry
in the security register.
Can you really
afford this place?
It's that groom, whose
on his “funeral” procession.
Why do you look so sad?
Is it about some woman?
Who the hell are you guys?
Don’t bother me.
We're bothering you?
You seem to be a nice guy,
so, we are just sharing some advise.
When your girl is
beyond your league...
... you should stop calling her.
Absolutely...
Else,
You won’t be riding a horse like this,
rather it’ll be your funeral procession.
I speak from experience.
Quite experienced, huh?
Yes of course.
When did you learn
about the threats to Ishan?
I heard it from Namita.
Rest... we don’t reveal
our sources, Nanu.
Okay, okay...
go ahead.
Nothing, I had to stop.
Kunal sir, asked me to
terminate my investigations.
He feels it’s dangerous.
Despite getting threat warnings,
Ishan didn’t back out.
And you know
what happened...
Actually, we don’t
know what happened.
What happened?
What’s wrong?
WHAT’S WRONG?
You tell me.
You were the hot shot
anchor at a news channel.
What’s wrong?
Theatre is good to issue
public service messages.
In real life,
one has to use
strategies to survive...
And even more
if you are a woman.
Grow up Ishan!
Grow up?
Ankita, this isn’t growing up.
It’s something else.
Hey what did you say?
How dare you?
Listen, I am running little late.
I have to go to ‘Lal Bazar’.
And that was the last
time when anyone saw Ishan.
Ouch.
Mind your step.
Where does Ishan live?
Jhama Pukur Lane, Amherst Street
Are you sure that,
this is going to be,
like you quite often say,
A micro to, macro exploration.
“Bindu mein Sindhu”, (Single
droplet contains the entire ocean.)
As you Bong say.
All the best, mad cap.
We will wait for the Sindhu,
the bigger picture.
Always the bigger picture.
Namita?
We spoke on phone
sometime back.
Vidhi?
- Ishan’s room?
- Yes.
May I?
My mother...
I am sure you know...
... how stressed she is...
Ma!
Please sit.
Are the cops troubling
you ma’am?
Yeah!
It all started right after we
filed the missing report.
Just a minute.
Can I record this please?
Yes.
Sure, thank you.
The cops landed at my,
mom’s house the very next day.
Interrogation is just an
excuse for torturing us.
They just want to silence us.
Mom’s health deteriorated.
I asked permission from my in-laws
and rushed here.
I was here.
But next day, police came knocking
to my in-laws place too.
Did he get a passport made?
What?
I asked did he have a passport?
No.
Did Ishan ever
visit Nepal or China?
Did you know,
your brother Ishan had
links with an extremist group.
We were not aware.
Any group...
or party you know of?
No, he was only a street theatre artist.
- that would keep him busy...
- Andhra...
Maharashtra, Jharkhand...
He has visited all these
Maoist areas.
Show them the pictures.
Look carefully,
do you know this man?
Of course, I have seen
him in the newspapers.
Err... that’s how I meant;
I know him.
Have you heard of ‘PLUG’?
People’s...
Liberation...
Underground Group.
We have found the minutes...
of a meeting of this group,
from his room.
Ishan was never
interested in active politics.
He was happy
with his street theatre.
Cops kept bringing up this same topic.
But when I informed them
about Ankita and Ishan’s relation.
They turned deaf to me.
They didn’t give a damn about it.
You look so pale
and famished.
Eat something dear.
You are right,
I am pulling on, with just
a cup coffee and tea.
You expose quite influential
people through your stories.
Don't you feel scared?
If I get scared,
I'll have to quit my job.
Are you married?
No!
I got married
didn't I maa?
The one who should protect
instills more fear in me.
"Don't do this", "don't do that",
"don't wear those clothes".
He has made a whole list of people
I should stay away from.
I believe husbands,
see no difference between
expressing love and advice.
Love, according to them,
is all about dominating their wife.
You won’t believe,
I learnt this fact from a man.
From my brother.
Ishan.
Okay...
Just move a little.
More.
Smile please.
Yes, a bit more.
Today is the anniversary
of a messy divorce.
Let’s celebrate together.
Boss, freedom should
always be celebrated.
But boss, I am busy.
I am sorry, I really wish I could.
So what’s this new scoop about?
You had a closed-door
meeting with the chief as well.
Ping me if you need any help?
Yes, tell me.
What can I do for you?
I know you won’t
call me otherwise.
Listen, I don’t want to
fight any more.
I am tired of this
long-distance relationship.
Let’s meet up and
sort this problem once for all.
Jeet, I have told
you several times.
I can’t relocate to
Mumbai just for you.
So please stop insisting.
So are you not
interested in meeting me?
Obviously, I miss you.
But I have something important,
and I can’t quit or take a break.
So, I don’t know
what more to say.
How about having
lunch together?
Two PM?
Flurys?
What?
Yes!
I just landed in Koklata,
we are setting up a new
office in the eastern zone.
Oh God, I wish I could
meet you right away.
Okay, I have an
appointment now.
How about catching
up in the evening?
That's all I ask...
Okay, bye...
See you.
- I know... I know...
- Where is Datto sir?
Sir,
Yes…
Ma’am, it’s no longer in my control now.
Even after our preliminary enquiry,
we failed to ascertain if this boy
is absconding or missing.
He would’ve fled had
he committed a crime.
Ishan has no criminal record.
I have confirmed this.
This case is going
to blow up soon.
Jantantrik Party’s MLA,
Mr. Umashankar Mukherjee called up OC sir,
he was quite curious
about this case.
And you think it’s not important
to interrogate Ankita Chauhan?
We have been advised
not to disturb her.
And you won't be able to name
whose advise this was, right?
Thank you.
[SET FREE]
Do not hesitate…
Your situation will never improve.
Nothing will change.
Kushal’s phone is switched off.
What’s going on?
where is he?
Kushal Da has stopped coming here.
He was interrogated by the cops…
... was told not to talk to the press.
Do you know Ankita?
Ankita Chauhan?
Yes sure we know her…
but Kushal da knows
a lot more...
Ishan used to confide in him a lot.
Kushal Da is quite scared.
He suffers from anxiety and depression.
He has started drinking again.
We believe Ankita is responsible
for Ishan’s disappearance…
But, we can’t openly
accuse anyone.
Orijit…
I need to speak to Kushal da.
Kushal Da,
police are claiming Ishan
is a radical or a Maoist...
… with a lot of confidence.
It’s all bullshit.
He was against violence
and this so-called red revolution.
We faced a lot of issues
because of this.
I know the motive
of the special branch.
I agree we have staged several
shows in tribal areas.
Police is now trying to link us to
the Maoist presence in those areas,
and Ankita's involvement
is being overlooked.
Do you have Ankita’s
present address?
Here, note it down.
I am making some stuffed
bread for you.
Okay Nanu,
will eat and then leave.
What is this?
I made it for you.
I can see that…
Listen, my office revamp
will take 3 months.
Every fortnight, I have to
go back to Mumbai.
Okay, that means in 3 months,
- we will have 2 dozen fights.
- No, please Vidhi...
...I am here to end all our fights.
Is it!
Impossible, I am not buying it this time.
Come on, just take 2-3 days off,
we have so much to thrash out.
On a serious note,
I am working on
a very critical story.
Special branch…
has suddenly got interested…
… in a missing story.
What’s the case?
It’s confidential.
Vidhi, this is sounding
really dangerous.
Won't it be better,
to stay away from this?
What?
Reminded me of something, someone said.
Anyways.
Not possible.
I can't abandon the
story from here.
“The road ahead is dark and dangerous,”
“be careful,”
“while walking here.”
“Always be ready...
to die,”
“you may get killed,”
“or backstabbed.”
“Everyone here,
is playing a game.”
"No one can be trusted."
“The gamblers are on the prowl...”
“...playing the
dangerous game.”
"You take care oh dear,
beware, be careful."
I met Ishan’s mother…
… and she looked like,
a suffering angel.
One thing you can’t deny,
I cook the best
Upma and Sambhar.
- Right?
- Yes…
and one more thing…
since my childhood, I’ve observed,
you always cook something,
and keep fishing for
compliments the entire day.
These compliments
are my real earnings…
… and when my granddaughter
compliments me…
it adds a few more years to my life…
Aww…
Didi have you eaten?
Yes!
Get me a glass of water please.
There is one more
weird thing about you…
What’s that?
Are you really not
interested in politics?
This behavior in itself is political…
to act not to be
interested in politics.
But, it’s not possible to stay
completely away from politics.
So, if someone suddenly gets
branded, a 'Maoist'...
what are your thoughts on this?
I have issues with
all such labels…
Jihadi...
Maoist...
I can very well digest my food…
But not violence…
And if someone tries
to achieve a purpose…
violently, in the
guise of a brand name...
then the purpose stands defeated.
You hate your enemy so much...
that you eventually ape him.
My God!
Historically it is proven that,
this is the biggest irony,
and the biggest tragedy of violence.
But,
I will ask you once again,
how's the Upma?
I am sure it’s better
than my political views, right?
Yes...
So you want to meet
Mr. Umashankar.
As he is showing great
interest in this story.
Right?
Yes.
He was my junior
during Presidency college.
Poor man…
his honesty turned him into…
… the black sheep
of Bengal politics.
Can you really fix up a
meeting with him?
Where does Ankita Chauhan live?
Second floor, the door as
you come out of the lift.
'Breaking news.'
'A bomb exploded at
the state MLA hostel.'
'As you can see, minister Ranjan Varman
is being escorted to safety.'
'According to our sources,'
'Bhishm Rana has claimed
responsibility for this explosion.'
- I am preparing you
to serve our country.
And you are worried
about a lame street theatre artist?
Interacting with pseudo intellects will
only attract more negativity.
It will lead to poor decision making.
So, just forget it.
It's a request.
Okay?
Okay, sir.
This is the right frame what I'm looking for.
- So, what you have submitted here,
- makes complete sense to me…
but, Sneha what we need to concentrate
on is whenever there is a crisis,
that has to be our first priority
and it has to be our first destination.
Those are the places we go to first.
Moving on…
How have you been?
Sir, I have good news to share.
Jhanavi is expecting.
- Congratulations…
- Thank you so much sir,
Sir, I need your blessings.
Congratulations!
You might get a call
from ‘Daybreak’ news...
although I am trying
to neutralize them.
Their journalist, Vidhi Sahani,
will try to approach you.
Yes, she has been
calling me frequently.
So, why aren’t you answering her?
This will become an issue
for no reason.
Tell her everything
like you have been asked to.
I have a question,
hope it won't offend you...
That night, Ishan visited
my apartment.
He is missing since then,
Where is Ishan?
Is he alive?
Just needed to know this much.
Why are you asking
me this question?
I think there is
some misunderstanding.
Unlike what you may think, I am
not against the radical youth.
In fact, I look forward
to initiate youth groups,
in every low-income area,
to help these young,
disturbed people.
Soon I will propose
this project to our CM.
Let the cops do their
job of searching Ishan,
you have better things to do.
I have proposed
your name to the CM,
for the upcoming
municipal elections.
In two years,
you could become an MLA.
But, I have no experience in politics.
You have a
'Political Science' degree.
You were ‘General
Secretary’ in your college.
Isn’t that enough?
Yes, Nanu...
Pass my watch please…
Your mobile?
yes, of course…
looks like you want to talk.
Do you feel you are being trailed?
Quite possible, please pass my bag.
Thank you…
Yes, we chase stories,
and sometimes we are chased by
people who are in those stories.
This cat and mouse
game goes on forever.
I get worried dear.
Why?
Perhaps, its age related…
I meant, my age…
Yes, I know…
No one who does good work,
will ever come to a bad end.
Straight out of Bhagwad Gita,
just for you...
Ah, taste of my own medicine?
Okay bye,
please eat, and don’t
wait for me.
Do you have a battery pack?
Yes ma’am.
The ₹500 one...
There you go.
Can you please guide
me to Aman’s shop?
The third shop on
the opposite lane.
Third one, right?
Yes.
Didi... (Sister)
Excuse me…
Your phone…
Thank you!
Should I take you to Aman’s shop?
Sure.
- What’s your name?
- Naeem.
How do you know Aman?
He lives close by.
Oh…
… since you know Aman,
I am sure you know Ishan as well…
He was like an
elder brother to me.
He admonished me for
being a school dropout.
He paid my tuition fees too…
He was kind enough
to lend his laptop too…
But now…
Now what?
Police confiscated his laptop.
Don’t know what
may have happened to him.
I need a favor…
If you hear anything
about Ishan,
will you inform me?
Okay didi...
Please call me on this number.
That’s Aman dada’s shop.
Oh... the shopkeeper
gave me wrong directions.
Aman?
Come on in…
How have you been, Naeem?
I am doing good.
Okay didi...
Take care...
So Aman what are the
special branch officers up to?
What else,
They made me wait outside,
for over 3 hours.
- Aman Yadav…
- Yes…
I was asked the same
questions as Namita…
Just, their attitude was
quite different this time.
Some tea, coffee?
Tea?
Listen, get some tea and biscuits…
Speak only the truth…
Don’t mess it up.
Tell me honestly,
was Ishan connected
with this guy?
Sir, I have seen
this guy's picture...
… in Hindi newspapers.
My father reads, so I know...
I don’t remember his name.
Bhishm Rana.
I believe he was linked…
… with some Maoist terror attack.
Sir, believe me,
Ishan cannot be
linked with such a person.
He was…
least concerned about politics,
and such movements.
We had our differences,
agreed, I never liked him…
But, he is not…
… a Maoist for sure.
Okay for now…
… we’ll call you over,
if required.
I’ll take your leave sir.
Have your tea at least…
It's okay sir. Thank you…
I could sense,
they didn’t buy my statement.
I am quite worried.
Yesterday, I spotted someone discreetly
clicking pictures of my shop.
I believe, MLA Umashankar,
is quite curious about this case.
When Namita was being
interrogated by the cops.
My father had a word with him…
This didn’t go well
with special branch too...
They accused us of
creating undue pressure.
Truth is, Umashankar
doesn't weild any clout now.
Anyway…
Okay Aman,
you take care.
- Nothing new about it…
It’s a personal issue…
but brand him a terrorist and
end the story.
Umashankar ji, don't you think Ankita-Ishan's
relationship being ignored by cops,
is to protect Varman’s image?
I know…
Everyone suspects Varman.
But it’s not easy to
prove his involvement.
- He is sharp…
And look at me…
People elected me…
but I am helpless…
Everything is orchestrated by Varman...
Even you will be unable
to dent his image.
You will be unable
So,
you believe Ishan is
not linked with Bhishm Rana.
Dear, understand one thing...
it's very easy for...
...the educated lot…
...to get trapped into
Bhishm Rana’s ideology.
A human being is attracted
by emotions rather than truth.
Bhishm Rana…
is not a genuine Maoist activist.
They are all just manipulating
people with their ideologies.
For their own benefit.
- Bhishm Rana…
once floated a militant political party.
He quickly gained
power and popularity.
This made Varman and Shibu
quite uncomfortable,
and they banned his party.
This triggered him off…
resulting…
… the massive explosion
at the MLA hostel.
We all know what happened next.
Reaching Nepal, he first called,
the police commissioner of Kolkata,
… and next, our editor-in-chief.
He took all the responsibility
for the bombing…
… and also…
… threatened to expect
more such bombings.
Still,
it must be ascertained whether...
Bhishm Rana had any
links with Ishan or not.
Tell me,
do you have any contacts
in college square? Burtolla?
Do you have any contacts?
Nope.
I know someone
who can help you.
Who?
Zia.
He owns a tailoring shop.
Tailoring shop.
- Komol, get tea for didi.
Hello, mom…
We are on our way to Kolkata...
your father has a
few meetings lined up.
I have planned some shopping.
Mom, why didn’t
you inform me earlier?
I am busy, I can’t spend any time
with you both.
Don’t you ever feel like
spending time with us?
Oh mom, please…
Anyway, let me try.
Okay, bye.
- Can you guide me
to Zia’s tailoring shop?
- Zia?
He will be at the mosque,
in the evening.
“Oh Almighty…”
“What you seek,
is very much within you.”
“Why are you so restless?”
“What are you looking for,
oh wanderer?”
It’s okay, take it.
Thank you…
I have had several interactions with…
… the cops and journalists…
This is the first time I am
seeing a lady crime reporter.
You are quite gutsy…
I am sorry to say,
I can’t accept your offer.
I have quit this job long back.
Now it’s just…
spiritual practice and Sufi recitals.
This is my life.
I visited Ajmer last year.
Ajmer Sharif…
Had food from the community kitchen,
heard the hymn 'Dua-e-Roshni'.
I have heard this qawwali
(Islamic devotional singing) too.
That’s great…
Ajmer Sharif, 'Dua-e-Roshni'.
I went alone.
I’ll take your leave…
… will see you some other time.
Take care…
Taxi…
'He was very passionate
about street plays. '
'He was against violence
and this so-called red revolution.'
'But brand him a terrorist
end the story.'
'And you think it’s not important
to interrogate Ankita Chauhan?'
'We have been advised
not to disturb her.'
Hello…
Our relationship ended
much before he went missing.
We both were...
quite incompatible.
Of course, we met a few times,
but isn’t it common to stay
friends even after you breakup?
I heard from your close friends,
you both were in
quite serious relationship.
I am from a very small village,
with very conservative upbringing.
How serious do you think,
I would’ve been about
an unemployed guy?
I have some screenshots
of your social media account.
Quite elaborate posts
against classism, casteism...
You seem to be quite broadminded,
very liberal thoughts.
Nice.
I guess you deleted your account
to conceal these facts, right?
According to your call records.
Ishan was last seen here,
in your house.
Yes...
Yes he did come here...
just the way you landed up here.
From here, if you
go missing today,
am I to be held responsible
for your disappearance?
Read this,
Bhishm Rana’s interview...
It’s a 6-year-old interview
for 'The Weekly Tribune' magazine.
He addressed the youth,
asking them to support the less
fortunate countrymen...
... instead of being glued to IPL.
Quite patriotic, I must say...
Patriotic? Or idiotic?
I can’t decide...
I thought this will be
helpful for you...
... and what’s his name?
Ishan...
Ishan was inducted
by this guy, right?
Suspected...
I thought that...
What made you think, I would've
missed reading this article, joy?
But I really appreciate it.
Thank you...
May I get back to work?
Hey, hope this bitter gourd
juice will not kill me.
Hey, just make some
carrot juice for him.
He can never handle bottle
or bitter gourd juice.
Namaste, sir...
Peace to you. Sir.
Namaste...
May peace be upon you.
Do you guys know me?
Oh sir, you are an
illustrious personality.
Okay...
Sir, can you teach us to focus?
Focus on...?
Yes.
Perhaps teach your granddaughter
to take her focus off certain things?
Her job is so dangerous.
Sir, it will be good,
if she quits, what do you say?
I am sure many powerful people
turn foe in this profession.
Many influential people
befriend you as well.
Sir, crime reporters
write about mafia,
politicians...
and often there is a
nexus between them.
I am sure her life is
endangered all the time.
Not just her, danger
looms over her family too.
What if, her family is harmed,
because of her doings.
It could be our dear professor.
Ah, only a stupid person
can think of doing that.
I mean...
Someone, who has lived
his life to the fullest,
and is also enjoying these
extra years of happiness...
... it’s so stupid to
threaten such a person,
what are your views?
You are right sir.
They should just kidnap you,
That’s enough to trouble her.
Wow!
That’ll be fun.
Quite thrilling at this age.
Super adventurous.
What if, your
kidnapping is successful...
and while at it,
you accidentally get stabbed, and die...
I have good understanding
of Bhagawad Gita.
I won’t die so easily...
also, I am not someone
who is scared of death.
So get these lame
ideas out of your head.
Get going dear...
have some juice...
carrot juice...
is good for your health.
I know the truth.
Rana is hiding.
I want to talk to him in person.
Not possible.
He connects with
people as he pleases.
Sir, this is important.
I need to talk to him.
Let's not speak further.
I need to go now.
You take care.
Good bye.
If the theory of Ishan’s Maoist
link gets refuted...
Then,
Varman is my prime suspect.
Special branch is going
to stonewall you.
We’ll see.
I have something to tell you.
Just listen to it,
and don’t react to it.
The infrastructure
MNC that I work with,
they have their own network...
Okay...
And...
a colleague from my
Kolkata office was telling me...
About this contract...
a construction company in Durgapur,
deals a lot with Varman...
I mean whenever a government
contract is executed,
Varman gets a cut.
I get that system...
come to the point.
This construction company in Durgapur
is owned by Mr. Sanjeev Sahani.
Sanjeev...
This is for Vidhi...
She spends all her hard earned
money on cabs and taxis...
She should drive her own car.
Her mom wanted me to
wait till her birthday.
I said,
I will buy her something
else for birthday.
It's an automatic car.
Stop...
There's a man,
Ruhel Dabraki
Rana calls him for all his needs.
He is a Nepal resident,
but presently he is in town.
Is he quite close to Rana?
He is his arms
and ammunition supplier.
I know his whereabouts.
Meet me there in 2 hours.
Okay?
Let’s go...
Such a bright girl,
why is she wasting her life
amidst these crooks and cops.
Also, it’s a male dominant field.
She doesn’t care
about our views.
I think only Jeet can
talk some sense to her.
I hope Jeet doesn’t get
dumped in the bargain.
It’s the twenty first century,
professions aren’t gender based.
If you are good, you are good.
Vidhi is damn good at her job.
She is working
on an important story...
about an influential minister.
Who?
Varman!
Sorry,
Rana is a media shy person.
I must talk to him.
It’s about a young innocent lad,
whose life is in danger.
Please.
She is playing with fire.
No point waiting for her.
I’ll be in my Kolkata office
next week, the entire week.
Please ask her to come
see me, at the earliest.
- It's getting difficult sir,
by acting without proper evidences.
MLA Umashankar Mukherjee
is adding to our woes...
by protesting, talking to press,
soon he'll take out rallies.
Has Vidhi met Uma Shankar?
And she is showing a lot
of interest in this case.
Okay...
She is ruffling quite
a few feathers...
Can’t we fix her?
Sir, her father has business
ties with our government.
I am sure you'll find a link.
Sanjeev Sahani.
Sanjeev Sahani...
How about some beer?
No sir, thank you...
Hey come on... it’s Sunday...
The tea is fine...
Probir, I feel we should
fearlessly do our jobs.
We are righteous people.
Truth alone triumphs.
Are you really sure sir?
Truth... alone triumphs?
- You know, for me...
- there is a clear line...
- between my work life,
and my personal life...
but I don’t think that
line exists for you...
Ya, work is life for me.
We’ve had this
discussion earlier too.
I don’t know why you
keep coming back to it.
And I am not sorry for it.
You act as if this is some
very big scoop.
It’s just a local story...
it's not even national news.
It may not be a national news,
but is an apt case for
national human rights commission?
Do you have any idea,
what Ishan’s family
is going through?
Vidhi,
I think you are getting
too obsessed with this case.
It’s so predictable,
for a Dalit boy to turn a Maoist...
It’s not earth shattering,
it happens all the time.
An ordinary person
has gone missing.
That’s it...
What did you just say?
Just come...
sit here.
Every 8 minutes,
a child goes missing in India.
Everyday, 174 children go missing.
35-40 adults go missing
alone in the city of Mumbai.
500-600 adults go missing in Kolkata...
EVERY MONTH!
If you are missing
out your loved ones?
Reach out to me...
#LOST
What do you mean by Dalits?
Aren’t they humans
like you and me?
You are just…
I think you should
just leave Jeet...
Just leave.
Nanu...
Looks like you are too busy...
You have to draw a line between,
your personal and professional life...
I am concerned
about your health.
Jeet is right,
You must learn to switch off
your professional mode,
for yourself, for him.
Did you hear what he said...
How...
casually he just said it.
I don’t know this Jeet.
Clearly, even he
doesn’t know me.
Don’t be judgmental.
Empower yourself to such
great heights that,
before He writes your fate...
The Almighty will have to ask,
what is it you desire?
This is the basic
design of the bridge.
As far as the technical
committee is concerned.
They are very confident
on the commencement date.
If there are any delays due
to contingencies or otherwise,
We should act swiftly
and in haste.
Look,
I never interfered
in your matters.
But, now...
... you have no idea
what you are getting into.
Why?
so that your
business can thrive?
If you've never interfered,
in my matters, in the past.
Don't think you
should do it now either.
Vidhi...
This is for you...
Thank you.
Ms. Righteous.
How long will it take to
shatter your windshield?
10 seconds,
30 seconds...
Which is the most
dangerous acid?
Hope you enjoyed the quiz.
Hey... what’s wrong
with you?
Nothing.
Hello...
Namita here...
This is my friend’s cellphone.
I bumped into Ishan’s friend...
She said, Ishan and Ankita,
had actually, filed their
marriage application.
The registrar’s office is located
between Beadon Street and C R Avenue.
Sir,
I need some information...
Did Ishan Bharti and Ankita Chauhan,
file their marriage application,
under special marriage act?
Who are you?
I am Vidhi Sahani,
Daybreak.in
We are not authorized
to give out such information.
Sir, this boy has gone missing,
his family is going through hell.
Please help sir.
Please.
This is so annoying.
This one sir...
Can I click a picture please?
I swear, your identity will
be kept confidential.
Thank you, sir...
thank you so much.
How can you be so rude
to your father?
Why did you return the keys?
How dare you throw
the keys at him!
He is so hurt,
do you even know that?
What about me?
Did you bother
to check how I felt?
If papa thinks,
he can influence my decisions,
then he is wrong.
You now...
...he won't even
speak a word to you.
Okay,
that’s good, it’s settled then,
neither am I very keen.
Do convey my feelings to him...
Vidhi!
Did you behave so rude?
Did you throw
the keys at him?
Of course kids do misbehave,
but a matured person,
would sit across the table
and sort out their differences.
Anuradha, this also is true...
when kids grow up,
one should learn to
respect their decisions.
Okay... Nanu,
just to clarify...
I merely returned
the keys to him.
I did not misbehave,
the way she is portraying it.
You know me well enough.
Dad,
one should be practical in life.
Yes, being practical also implies
being corrupt in these circumstances.
Anyone who stays with you...
... deserves to be awarded,
‘The Padmashree' for righteousness.
There she goes,
as a kid she always
loved the fritters I made...
God bless you...
Vote for...
Ankita Chauhan...
- Vote for...
- Ankita Chauhan...
Nanu, tea...
[Wanna meet?... At my place?]
No, no I have to go.
Your marriage application
form is in my possession.
Why did you lie?
His family is being tortured.
Namaste!
Ankita Chauhan?
Please come in...
Has he really joined
any terrorist outfits?
... or is he dead?
I am sure you have
a clear idea about it.
“There isn’t any serene
rainy day anymore...”
“nor any hope
of some happiness...”
“My desire to sleep to
a sweet lullaby is all lost.”
“Tell me who is...
responsible for this?”
- Ishan and I were
madly in love...
... but circumstances separated us.
Is he alive?
This question bothers me a lot.
But I swear...
I don’t know.
Why didn’t you go to the cops,
after Ishan went missing?
I am scared of the cops...
Oh really? Don’t you have
Varman by your side?
Or, is he the whole
reason behind this all?
I don’t know...
Please keep this off record.
You have my word.
Off record.
Being a woman, you’ll
understand my situation.
I moved away from Ishan,
for his own good.
Oh, not for your own benefit?
Who would say no to the perks?
But I never had any
ill feelings for him.
If you talk about, or expose
my marriage application form...
...then I will have no choice,
except commit suicide.
- The story is real...
...but what if it costs
someone their life...?
Then...?
What’s...
important for a reporter?
To report the truth...
or to do what’s right...
Many years ago,
when I was teaching
in a college.
During my college elections,
one of my students... very young,
quite powerful and influential.
The government back then,
wanted to control every union.
They lacked majority in my college.
I expected some disturbances...
And I was not wrong.
My office was vandalized.
Cops came over to enquire...
I filed my report.
The presiding cop,
made a weird request.
He asked me to strike off the name
of the said influential politician.
He said, if I refuse to obey,
there will be a few innocent students,
who will be falsely implicated.
and if I oblige,
they will not cause any
harm to other innocent students...
they will be bailed,
their cases will be diluted.
So what do you think,
I did back then?
I struck off his name...
I never judged my action.
Today, you are faced
with a similar situation.
What nonsense is this?
This is an annual function
at his ancestral village.
He goes every year.
He is quite influential
in those parts.
People vote for his candidate.
You met Ankita, right?
Any new leads?
No!
The rumour at the
Press Club is that,
Varman has secretly
tied the knot with Ankita.
During Ankita’s campaign,
Party workers talk about
supporting their sister-in-law.
Your story is already very late.
Can you publish it before
the municipal elections?
I am almost ready.
Okay great...
What update do
you have on Zia?
It’s very difficult to
crack the Naxal angle.
Hello!
- Vidhi ma’am...
- Cops have picked up Naeem.
Naeem?
Yes...
Why?
Can I talk to you?
Yes...
Did you arrest a minor kid?
Naeem?
Yes or no?
Ma’am it’s a routine procedure...
So, that means "yes"...
Please sit...
Where is he?
Please cool down...
He is inside, chatting
with our senior inspector.
Oh, chatting is it?
since last night?
It's 12 noon now...
Did you inform his guardian?
Did you serve him 49A?
I want to see the copy of 49A.
Ma’am please cool down,
it's nothing serious.
So there is no question
of serving 49A.
Okay then...
I have recorded
your statement.
Where is he?
Ma’am...
What mess is she up to?
Ma’am... please wait...
Listen to me please...
- I swear you will rot in prison,
all your life.
Don’t you know...
... he is a minor?
What is this, Sen?
Ma’am... please...
You’ve arrested a minor,
without serving 49A.
You have been
unlawfully torturing him.
This news will be reported
along with your pictures.
Your officers may let this pass,
but the honorable court
will have you suspended.
Madam please come out, please.
Madam please calm down.
Can I get you some tea?
Instead of this
blackmail drama,
you could’ve done
a sensible story.
You've abandoned journalism,
and got into activism now?
What was the need for all this, and that too,
to protect a suspect?
I had an earful
from their officer.
Who called you?
The joint commissioner from
the special branch, right?
Okay,
let me handover this case
to the human rights commission,
and quit...
Come on!
Don’t get so emotional.
Please sit down.
Is it a crime,
to call a spade a spade?
Vidhi...
...there is something
called ‘Practicality’.
Practicality?
I have heard enough of it...
Have you heard of, ‘Conscience’?
Listen...
Black coffee?
Cool down.
Hello...
Take him.
My party strongly
believes in...
- Truth,
- Deed,
- and determination.
Look, with all due respect,
- the oppositions methods,
they are archaic.
- For us to move into the
twenty first century,
what we need to
create, is jobs.
We need to evolve,
We need to progress.
So, we have to
empower the youth.
Which is the only way we
can then, empower ourselves,
that we need some change.
Okay... I will talk to you later.
Do you remember,
I got you, your first case?
Yes of course...
I am interested in this,
present case of yours.
Why are you...
going around enquiring
people about Ishan?
Let my story get published...
then we can discuss it.
Your act, can jeopardize
special branch’s investigation.
Should I just end the story here,
and publish it along
with your quote?
University college professors
have ruined it all...
in the free time, they go around
in the guise of human right activists...
...and you 24 hours
professional reporters,
are ever ready to soft
target police officers.
And these two
adversaries of yours,
are always proved wrong.
Right, Mr. Ghoshal?
You know very well
what happens at every level...
but,
you conveniently
turn a blind eye to it.
The entire department
cannot be implicated,
because of just one
partially corrupt officer.
Sorry...
with your permission,
I’d like to correct
your sentence sir.
Just one partially honest officer...
cannot brand the
entire department clean.
It’s impossible
to argue with you.
Let's come to the point.
Vidhi,
we are pressurized to investigate
with suspicion as the main angle.
By whom?
- More coffee?
- Name?
You are well versed with the
tactics of Bhishm Rana.
Powerful men like Uma Shankar
Mukhopadhyay,
are scared of him.
It’s too soon to conclude,
that Police is relying on stereotypes alone.
Please...
Looks like we’ll need
some more coffee.
Hello, Nanu...
Yes...
What?
I am staying home tonight.
I need some time to think.
There are quite
a lot of confusions.
Why is our life
so complicated?
I badly need the
tea you make.
Are you heading out?
Yes...
What’s the matter?
I mean, the nature of your job,
are you entitled to any security,
protection in this job?
Come on Nanu,
I am a journalist.
We don’t get any security...
And for what?
Hope you have not
received any threats.
Why are you asking this
all of a sudden?
Nothing... just...
Nanu...
... what happened?
Nothing, I am perfectly fine.
I want you to be very careful.
Wait!
Follow me.
Varman sir is ready
to meet you, sir.
Please come...
- So, what we need to do,
- is recognize the ones that have made
- significant contribution
in the constituency,
- and then highlight...
Please come...
Please sit sir...
Like good old days, would you like
to insult me in public, or...?
should we talk in private?
You know, I don’t beat
around the bush.
Order sir...
I am not here to order you...
It’s a warning.
You very well know
the reason for this warning.
Varman...
I have never caused any
harm to anyone all my life.
I know you are
used to violence.
and sabotage people’s work.
Let me be very clear...
If I find you causing
any trouble to her.
I swear... I will strangle
you to death in public.
I am sure you still remember
the strength of my hands.
Right?
Kunal Da,
someone has sent this is for Vidhi…
the sender said,
it’s extremely urgent.
Thank you,
'The mobile subscriber you have called,
is currently not reachable.'
Quiz…
Which flower is
showered at a funeral?
Lilly. Rose. Marigold.
It’s become difficult to
meet someone at home.
All our activities are monitored.
Aman has decided to…
relocate to Nepal.
He intends to take up a job,
or start something on his own.
We’ve been fighting
a lot over this issue.
I don’t want to abandon
my home and relocate.
This is my home,
I want to live and die here.
And Ishan is being
blamed for our situation.
My marriage is on
the verge of breaking.
I have made up my mind…
I will not tolerate
any false allegations.
Have it.
It’s their special
You’ll love it.
It’s very tasty…
My mom will stay with me.
It's decided.
It’s nice.
What is this?
I need to know, everything that
you have been hiding from me.
I never took this
seriously at all!
Come see my inbox...
There are several such rape,
attack threats…
Here at least the sender has put in
some effort to create this.
I want to know your
opinion about me first.
I am answerable to
the editor-in-chief, not you…
For your information, the editor-in-chief
had greenlit this story.
So the legal fallout,
political stance,
and drop in advertising
revenue due to this story,
should it all be ignored?
No pain, no gain.
News portals reap huge
benefits due to such stories.
Vidhi…
promise me one thing…
You have to inform me
if you receive any kind of threat.
- Namaste…
- Namaste!
- How are you?
- I'm good. How are you?
Good…
'Long live, Ankita Chauhan!'
How well do you
know Ankita Chauhan?
As much as I am
supposed to know her.
Do you know,
she was in a relationship
with Ishan Bharti?
Was…
That’s the past tense…right?
The past shouldn’t get anyone tense.
There is a rumour that
you got him kidnapped.
Being a journalist,
you should talk with proofs,
and not on mere suspicion.
Is it true, the house
Ankita is living in,
belongs to an NGO, registered
on your mother’s name?
is that true?
Ishan went missing from there.
Two unrelated facts.
What’s your question?
Witnesses are being threatened…
Now, is that also a rumour?
Ishan’s close friend
Kushal is dead too…
His body was found
at the tram depot.
Are you accusing me
of murder, Ms. Sahani?
No, no…
I don’t have an accusation…
yet.
Just a few more questions…
Did you inform the police
and special branch,
about Ishan’s links with terrorist?
I am not a police
informer by profession.
It’s believed that you are doing
this for your personal gain.
It’s all politics…
they are out to malign me.
You are right…
According to my sources, Mr. Varman…
Young activists are being tortured,
interrogated…
without any reason…
Is that true?
Special branch is
under the Home Minister.
Well that takes me
to my next question.
Are you guilty of interfering
in the affairs of other ministries?
owing to your closeness to the CM?
I should be flattered,
that you think
I am this powerful
I am just a humble
soldier of the party,
and a damn good minister,
if I may say so myself.
That’s it.
Have you married Ankita Chauhan?
That is a personal question.
Am I expected to answer?
No!
And I shall not.
A woman can be successful,
without needing the help of a man.
At least a progressive woman
like you should appreciate this fact.
That’ll be all…
Thank you…
Thank you!
Your father is here…
He drove all the
way from Durgapur,
He is waiting to see you.
Yes…
...I have received threats stating
new projects will get stalled.
I am not giving you a guilt trip.
You are a journalist,
you should know the facts.
I know that…
I told your mom
about the threats,
do you know what she said?
What if they really
shut our businesses…
how will we survive?
I said, I have enough
investments to feed our family…
We may not eat exotic food…
but we can surely wash it down
with some Indian red wine,
which is not bad now-a-days.
But finally our daughter...
... may accompany us at the table.
Can I leave the keys with you now?
Heading is good.
I will need to get it cleared
by our Editor-in-chief.
But…
this story is going
to be a huge hit.
Can I call it a day then?
Of course, you deserve an off.
Go home, and relax.
Thank you.
Vidhi, I wasn’t here just
on an official visit,
I thought we could
rekindle our relationship.
But I realize, for you…
… your work comes first.
It’s who you are…
and,
I need to understand that.
I think, in the process
of trying to fix this relation,
we have become
a liability to each other.
If you ever need me,
I will be there for you.
I took a day off, today…
How about another
round of tea?
“This lovely city,
is like a beautiful sea.”
“Where our hearts sailed like two
inseparable boats in this sea.”
“It all looked so beautiful
when we were in love,”
“...just when a storm
wrecked it all for us.”
“I have lost my love,”
“my dreams…”
“...as my boat sank in this ocean…”
“ending this beautiful relation,
forcing us to walk away as strangers.”
“It’s like losing the moon,
“the beautiful moonlight …”
“...plunging the sky into darkness…”
“…ending this beautiful relation,
forcing us to walk away as strangers.”
Your summons have come.
“This vast city is
like a beautiful sea.”
“Where our hearts sailed together,
without any worries…”
Hello, Kunal da…
Please hold the story.
There is some new development.
I might have to add something.
Okay, thank you.
Ruhel Dabraki…?
On the first floor,
room number, 118.
I kept my word…
He’ll be on call soon.
Come sit.
Namaste!
I did a background check on you.
I believe you are not someone
who chases news just for sensation.
You believe in thorough research.
Were you linked to Ishan Bharti?
as the case was being transferred
to the police and special branch?
None, whatsoever.
Did you know him personally?
I saw him during one of his
street plays.
Where the skirmish broke out.
For how long will we be
treated as untouchables?
For how long should we be
deprived of our basic rights?
No. Not anymore.
We can save ourselves
by using our only weapon…
And that is…
Education...!
Stop this nonsense…
Do not try to instigate
innocent people.
My name is Ishan Bharti.
I am a Dalit (Backward Class),
I am fighting for their rights.
Education...!
I liked his ideologies.
His play was quite
thought provoking.
It showed how our so-called
mainstream political parties...
... manipulate lower caste
population for their benefit.
Is he alive?
Yes, very much…
but on a different identity.
When police were looking for him,
I received an intel, that,
he was abducted
by Varman’s goons.
We found out that, he was held
somewhere in Varman’s home town.
Their plan was to kill him.
Fuckers…
Shakeel…
My men saved his life…
After this incident,
Varman was livid.
He had only one
route left to tag Ishan…
as "Maoist Ishan".
You will be killed by the cops,
if you try to escape.
And they will be the heroes.
We never force anyone to join us.
He was free to walk out.
But he was left with no choice.
Listen…
Listen to me…
I did exactly, what I do
with every new comrade…
Do you believe in justice?
I got him a new identity,
a new passport…
So, you brainwashed him…
… influenced him…
Yes, just like media
has been doing for ages.
Influence.
No point beating around the bush.
Everyone has their
own definition of Justice.
I gave him an offer...
… an offer to live a dignified life.
From here, a simple ‘missing’ story,
became newsworthy for you.
I know…
you want to fight for justice…
but power is…
...under the CM's foot...
poor people forget everything
in the garb of caste politics.
We forgive our leaders easily.
I have a request.
Will you please ask Ishan
to return to his family?
And who will guarantee his safety?
In these circumstances, can
any Ishan return home easily?
Till we have leaders like Varman,
‘Ishans’ of this world
will remain ‘Lost’.
Last question…
You offered Ishan
to live a dignified life?
What did it mean?
I can’t answer that…
It’s for you to probe.
Namita?
Ishan is no one to us...
You have no son...
I have no brother...
He can't be my brother...
Kunal Da, we’ll have to...
... withdraw the story.
I am just...
... just going to rewrite again.
I am really sorry.
I am sorry...
'Ankita...'
'listen to me carefully...'
'A terrorist plot is being hatched to
assassinate you and Mr. Varman.'
Sir...
'Ankita...'
'listen to me carefully...'
'A terrorist plot is bei      ng hatched to
assassinate you and Mr. Varman.'
'On your return journey
from his ancestral village...'
'Please protect yourself.'
'God willing, we will meet again.'
Pandit...
Ankita and I are staying
back for one more day.
You may leave tonight, with
others, as per our schedule.
Yes sir.
Your wife is expecting...
I will see you in office
in a couple of days.
Okay sir.
'The convoy of Ranjan Varman,'
'Urban Development Minister
of West Bengal,'
'has been attacked by
suspected Maoist rebels.'
'Preliminary reports say,'
'that an explosion rocked
the Chenapetti village road,'
'in Purulia district...'
'... when the minister
was passing through.'
'A car in the convoy, went up in flames,
witnesses claimed.'
'The car, a white SUV, is said
to be Varman’s official vehicle,'
'in which he was supposed to
be travelling back to Kolkata,'
'from his ancestral village,'
'near the Bengal-Jharkand border.'
'Ankita Chauhan,'
'recently elected councillor
of Uttarpara,'
'was also said to be travelling
back with the Minister.'
'Details about casualties and injuries,
are awaited in what'
'appears to be, a landmine blast.'
'Let us listen in, to the local SDPO.'
'We hear that,'
'a local Maoist group has claimed
the responsibility for the blast.'
Ishan turned into...
... exactly what they claimed
he would become.
I lost...
The world doesn't function
according to our whims,
...neither do we follow
the dictates of nature.
The equation may look strange...
but it is what it is...
...laugh with it...
or accept it.
Just do your work...
don't think about results.
Mr. Varman, how did you
escape this attack?
Whom do you suspect
in this attack?
Don’t you think this
was pre-planned?
- Is Bhishm Rana involved in this?
I was their prime target.
- Bhishm Rana wanted
to eliminate me.
- Ishan was a pawn in this game.
- I pray to the Almighty...
- who protected me to prevent
these youngsters from getting entrapped.
- When did you learn
about this bomb blast?
- With very heavy heart,
- I announce, four of
my companions perished.
- Amongst the deceased, I have lost
my most trusted personnel.
I pray for their souls.
And please note, their families
will have my full support.
'A terrorist plot is being hatched to
assassinate Mr. Varman and you,'
'on your return journey
from his ancestral village...'
'... please protect yourself.'
'God willing,
we will meet again.'
'Ankita,'
'listen carefully,'
'A terrorist plot is being hatched to
assassinate you and Mr. Varman...'
'on your return journey
from his ancestral village...'
'... please protect yourself.'
'God willing,
we will meet again.'
'Sometimes, when the dark
clouds cover the moon,'
'... creating darkness all around us.'
'We lose all our hope,
and we feel defeated in life.'
'Had Ankita not shared,
Ishan’s warning video,'
'we would have
misunderstood him...'
'A day after the attack,
Namita received a letter...'
'from Ishan,'
'He said, he escaped
the clutches of Rana.'
'He had not fallen victim to
vendetta politics,'
'nor violent propaganda.'
'He harbored no
hatred for Ankita either.'
Hello...
Vidhi...
don’t skip your meals...
Yes mom.
Bye.
'Ishan realized,'
'rebels, politicians,’
'political parties, every outfit...'
'... only work towards
their own ends.'
'Life of a common man,
mean nothing to them.'
'He also wrote,'
'someday he will
return to his family.'
'It seemed like a ray of hope,
poured in through the window,'
'moon-light was peaking
through clouds...'
'illuminating the darkness around us.'
'Bright and pure rays of light,'
'that instills faith in our lives.'
'Making people believe
in good deeds.'
'Best wishes to you all and...'
'let truth prevail.'
"Finally, there is
brightness around me."
"This newly found radiance."
"Every tender buds hope...
...to flower someday."
"Like there is light..."
"...at the end of every tunnel."
"In sunlight...
"In the cool shades..."
"There is brightness
all around us."
"There is brightness..."
"... in the depth of our hearts."
"Open your eyes,"
"speak lovingly..."
"... you will experience this
brightness within yourself."
"This brightness, has illuminated
a new path for us."
"This new world is lit up so bright."
"There is happiness,
in the chirping of birds"
"This brightness keeps us going."
"Every path we take,"
"we will find this
brightness of positivity."
"Wherever you go,
you will find this brightness."
"You will find light all around you."
"Open your eyes,"
"speak lovingly..."
"... you will experience this
brightness within yourself."