LOST SOUVENIRS
Good evening, Paris.
Recognize her?
What about the Place de l'Etoile
and the Arc de Triomphe?
The Place de la Concorde
and the Obelisk?
Rue Royale and Maxim's,
my little Madeleine?
The Montmartre hill
and its bell tower?
And what about this street?
It's in the 15th arrondisement,
Saint-Lambert neighborhood,
Convention metro station.
It also has its monument.
MORILLONS STREET
You only enter it with a lot
of anxiety and a little hope.
Let's do that, shall we?
Please, after you.
Shh, close the door.
This place has seen
many heartbeats yet.
Heavy hearts.
Light hearts.
Dry hearts.
Where are we? Guess. Turn around!
Are we in a junk shop?
At some collectors?
A pawn shop? Let's see!
Respect the tag!
Stop guessing.
We are in the temple
of absent-mindedness,
at the museum of distraction,
at the lost and found.
Look.
You can't believe your eyes!
This leg didn't just walk here!
Is this your dresser, Henri II?
Your straw hat, Italy?
Your bugle, Deroulede?
Your boots, Bastien?
Are these your bells, Corneville?
General!
How did all these particular things
end up in here?
Following what drama,
comedy, or vaudeville?
Take this small statue
of Osiris for example,
with her unusual tutu
and her bow in her hair.
Well, this small statue of Osiris...
In the past, when evening came,
the night fell like a curtain
over the masterpieces of the Louvre.
And for the visitors,
it was the end of the show.
Today, everything has changed.
And you can see,
on this Christmas Eve,
the wonders of Egyptian art
in full sunlight,
and in fact, in the middle of Egypt,
as if you were there.
-It's beautiful, isn't it?
-It is.
What about these?
It's alive!
There is nothing like
living statues, living paintings.
Isn't Egypt beautiful?
It's nice, yes.
Very nice.
Especially at night.
For the wonders of the world,
especially on Christmas Eve,
there's no place like Paris.
I thought I already asked you
to space out your visits.
The world is full of mummies
less alive than these.
You have to thaw them out a bit,
to make them regain a taste for life.
Look, I warned you.
If you ever set foot in here again...
You must admit that for some time
now, I've made myself scarce.
I'm an Egyptologist.
A day like today, I had to, right?
And here is Osiris!
The Egyptian legend tells that
he was killed and butchered
by seven gods of darkness,
and his remains were locked
in a chest and thrown into the sea.
The chest landed in Veneto
and was transformed into a column.
Isis discovered her husband's body
in the column, pulled him out
and gave him back his life
through her kisses and tears.
Osiris now rules over the dead.
Please follow me,
ladies and gentlemen.
Philippe!
Florence...
I'm glad to see you again, you know.
I'm glad to see you, too.
It's not the same thing
since you left me.
After so many years,
are you still mad at me?
I don't hold grudges. You know that.
You've stayed the same.
As beautiful as ever.
-And yet...
-Yet what?
I don't know. You've changed.
-You're more...
-More elegant!
Expensive.
You have beautiful jewelry.
I'm glad, you know.
Without a doubt,
your luck has changed.
-What about you?
-Well...
Yes, yes, mine's changed, too.
In a good way.
That's probably why you left me
without news for years.
-Yet I haven't forgotten you.
-Of course.
No.
To be fair, you did send me
a statuette from Cairo.
-Osiris!
-Yes.
-You still have it?
In a drawer.
-It's a worthless object.
-Which made me happy.
At that time, in Cairo, I was
going through difficult times.
-Whereas now...
-Today, it's not the same.
I'm a real pharaoh over there.
I have a nice big house.
I mean, here,
they'd call it a palace.
-Are you working?
-Yes, for pleasure.
A big book on Egypt.
That's the reason why you had left.
Yes, and that's why I stayed there.
Yes, Paris wasn't built in a day,
but neither were the pyramids.
Still, Paris,
there's nothing like it
to take your mind off things.
Will you be staying long?
I'm afraid not.
I regret it after seeing you.
No, I'm leaving tomorrow morning
at dawn. By plane, of course.
I just came to enjoy myself,
to spend the holidays.
I stayed at a great hotel,
the Regina,
up the street from the Tuileries.
-I'm glad to hear it.
-Why?
Because we met
at the Tuileries.
Why do I have to remind me
of such nice memories?
You don't know what it's like for me
to see you there,
beautiful and happy.
Who told you I was happy?
You don't lack anything.
If this is happiness...
Sorry,
-I have to go.
-Why? Are you in a hurry?
Yes, it's Christmas, you understand.
-You're not free on New Year's Eve?
-No, but I can arrange it.
-Really?
-Yes!
Where shall we meet?
-What time?
-I don't know... midnight?
-Since it's Christmas.
-Yes, but where?
At your hotel? At the Regina?
Of course, at the Regina.
It's so much easier.
At the Regina then, at midnight.
We were looking for you, Florence!
Where were you?
In Egypt, in Cairo.
-Cairo?
-Yes,
in a castle in Spain.
There's a lot of them out there.
Thank you! Florence's turn.
Where is she?
There you are!
-Yes, I'm coming. Are you done?
-I am.
-So?
-Stand here.
Here? No!
How about here?
-I think it's better.
-Yes, maybe.
Very pretty. Don't move.
Yes, we will have a very nice shot,
and it will make some noise.
The most beautiful woman in Paris
in the world's most beautiful museum.
A smile wouldn't hurt.
-Think of something happy.
-That's easy.
-Aren't you happy?
-A little.
And being a little happy is a lot.
Come on,
Paris hasn't changed that much!
Still, we don't have
the fun we used to.
The little women in Paris,
it's over! It's over!
A small wave of modesty,
you need an advantage to bask
in the little women of Paris,
as beautiful, as desirable
and as undressed as ever,
but a little more discreet,
that's all.
What? What does he want?
To go get them!
That's it!
Gay Paris has no secrets for me.
Let's have a drink together.
-Get in!
-You're our guest.
-No, no...
-Yes, we're just passing through.
I have my own car.
There it is!
I'll send my driver away,
and I'll be right with you.
No need to wait for me.
I'm with friends.
Go home without me.
We're going to Neuilly.
Do you know it?
I'll sit by you.
He's nuts...
-Done?
-Yes.
Forgive me for robbing you.
-It's a shame.
-You can keep the coat for tonight.
-I didn't dare ask you.
-You were very wrong.
What if I asked you
to keep the dress, too?
Since it's done?
I couldn't refuse you.
Thank you.
Betty!
-Yes?
-Has the child been good?
Very good!
-So?
-She ate well, laughed,
asked for you a bit,
then fell asleep.
Merry Christmas, Gaston
Merry Christmas to all
Merry Christmas, Betty
Merry Christmas, Gaston
Merry Christmas to you, too,
And a good year...
-She's asleep.
-Got it.
Quiet! We're not here to disturb
the sleep of innocence.
Betty! Betty, listen!
Look, I'm a little embarrassed. I...
What? You've never been so cheerful!
Listen, I want to tell you...
I'd like to explain...
Sorry, I can't stay tonight.
-No way!
-I have to.
I'll explain later.
I had an unexpected encounter.
Something unexpected!
Everyone's bummed out,
especially Frederic,
who mostly came for you.
The party is ruined.
Everyone is sulking now.
I like Frederic and everyone else,
but I'm meeting
someone I haven't seen
in a very long time tonight.
-Someone I loved.
-Philippe?
-How do you know that?
-I have a good memory.
One night which you don't remember,
you told me everything.
But you didn't tell me if he loved
you. If he still loves you.
If things were that simple,
he'd be my daughter's father.
-What a pretty dress!
-Isn't it? It's not to dazzle him,
but I don't want to embarrass him.
He became very rich.
And since he's a psychologist,
Egyptologist or so on,
he guessed I was very rich, too.
He's leaving tomorrow,
so I want him to have the same
peace of mind I have for him.
My wallet is gone!
You can search me!
Excuse me,
but are you sure you didn't
-lose it before coming here?
-I am!
It was in my pocket. I'm sure of it!
-Did you have a lot of money?
-No, not much.
Maybe 40 or 50,000 francs.
It must have been this gentleman
who was with us.
-Do you know him?
-Mr. Philippe?
Yes, Mr. Philippe.
Wait for me here.
HOTEL OFFICE
-Is anyone here?
-Yes.
Hello, Mr. Philippe.
Yes, I'm leaving Paris,
I'm in a hurry. Give me the bill.
-You're paying your bill?
-That's why I'm asking you.
I'd asked you before,
but you always had another idea.
I know. It's easy words.
I knew you would.
You have nice luggage.
Yes. I'll take the train
right away and go far.
-If any mail came in...
-You never get any.
All the more reason
not to forward it!
You have to fall asleep now.
Well...
she wants a doll now,
a dancer. And with a tutu!
Hurry up. You're running late!
We're neighbors.
She might as well be here.
I'll handle the dancer.
Kids are easy.
Nice, isn't it?
Since it was Mr. Arthur Bacon
of the British Museum who sent you,
I'm glad you like it here.
Alas, I'm leaving tomorrow.
I am indeed happy, as we
haven't heard from Mr. Arthur Bacon
in a long time.
-Yes.
-The last news was pretty bad.
Oh, really?
Yes, we had the unfortunate surprise
of reading his name, two years ago,
in the obituaries section.
The papers...
For fake news... they fear no one.
Especially when they're bad.
But Arthur is a nomad!
He's not ready
to take his last journey yet.
-Glad to hear it.
-The last time I saw him,
it was in Cairo.
I'm going back there tomorrow,
by plane.
-Don't forget to wake me up.
-No, no.
Say,
do you think it's entirely necessary
for me to dress up for dinner?
-No, I'm afraid no one does anymore.
-No.
You won't be the only one.
"Midnight.
"Like the big needle
with the little one."
"We'll be together at midnight."
-You haven't forgotten.
-No.
-Not even the day you found it.
-I found it in a book.
It doesn't matter. It was a good
find anyway. I liked it.
Earlier, as I crossed
the Place Vendome,
I remembered the last day
we saw each other.
It was spring.
I was on Castiglione Street.
I was going to the studio.
You were waiting for me. We'd known
each other for three months.
We loved each other.
And to find you there so early,
since you're not an early person,
it meant a lot to me.
You took me by the arm and said:
"I guess you won't be working today."
Then we headed for the Tuileries,
and we both walked
without saying anything.
Then we stopped
by the wooden horse arena
where, for the first time...
...we kissed.
It was winter. It was a bit cold.
You told me you were leaving
for Egypt that evening,
for a great archaeology project,
but that, of course, you'd come back,
and we'd get married.
And I walked you to the station.
It was our honeymoon.
But you left me on the platform.
Anyway, what's done is done.
After all, if we'd stayed together,
we might not be here.
And your daughter
would be a little bigger.
I'd be her father.
We'd live in a modest dwelling
without any comfort.
-Does that make you laugh?
-Don't pay attention.
I think I'm a bit lost.
-In memories?
-No.
I'm just happy to be here.
Is the man,
the lavish man you live with,
keen on traveling as well?
Are you thinking about him tonight?
No, I forgot about him tonight.
That's nice.
-Forget him, too.
-Done.
You know, tonight, I have a lot
to forget along with him.
Have you suffered?
Yes.
As little as possible,
every time I couldn't do otherwise.
Suffering on purpose is disgusting.
Well, for years,
my life wasn't easy.
-Are you still into fashion?
-Yes.
I was a model.
I even posed for fashion magazines.
For painters, too.
Don't you think I had my share
of hardships over there, too,
at least at first?
Another bottle.
Egypt is beautiful,
but it's not always paradise for me.
Well, you know me.
A bit. Do you still drink too much?
Less, but I drink better stuff.
And I have the means to choose.
But before,
it was pretty painful,
even a little sleazy.
For an Egyptologist,
I was driving tourists around.
I wasn't showing them
the pyramids, the Nile...
No. Cairo at night was my specialty.
Even...
To be honest, an American tourist,
a fat tourist who wanted to have fun,
I borrowed from him, on the sly,
discretely,
the very modest sum of 55,000 francs.
But...
It was the first and last time
something like that happened to me.
I did it for a very beautiful girl.
Very beautiful but too rich.
And for nothing in the world
did I want her to suspect
that I was in a situation that was,
to say the least, precarious.
I mean, lousy...
Desperate...
Did you love her?
You're the only one I've ever loved.
-Did you marry her?
-No.
I would've liked to, of course.
But...
But what?
I married another.
She's a lovely woman.
A real little sphinx
with unprecedented luxury.
Do you love her?
I've always loved luxury.
-It's late.
-No one is waiting for you...
Yes, Yvette is.
Little girls get up early,
especially on Christmas Day.
-Do you have your car?
-Yes.
That one.
But I'd like to walk a bit.
Tuileries.
-Do you live far?
-It doesn't matter.
I'd like to...
I'd like to... I don't know.
I would like to get some fresh air,
walk alone for a bit,
-to take my mind off things.
-Alone?
Were you not happy with me?
Too happy.
Wait for me a little.
Look, this may be silly,
but I just made a bet,
so I'd like you to leave, now.
Not far,
just around the block.
For your eyes?
-I didn't say that.
-I did, because they're pretty.
What a pity that we're going
our separate ways again,
both of us,
-on a trip.
-A honeymoon trip?
She looks like you.
I didn't pose for that one.
You still look like her.
You have a good memory.
I sure do.
Philippe,
kiss me.
-You know I'm leaving for Cairo.
-Of course.
Of course,
it's not paradise every day,
it's not spring every day,
but it's nice and happy.
A happy night
is a loving memory that
can light up an entire life.
That's pretty.
-Who is it from?
-It's from you.
Well, it's for you
because I said it thinking of you.
So?
Not even this dress is yours?
No. No but give it to me anyway.
Thank you.
-What about your car?
-My car?
It was Cinderella's carriage.
You know, things that appear
and disappear just as quickly.
What about your driver?
I simply asked him to go
around the block, for my eyes.
I never would've thought of that.
Yes, but tell me...
Why did you hide the truth?
Maybe it's silly,
but I didn't want to embarrass you.
I didn't mean to make you feel bad.
Yes, you're a wonderful girl.
I understand.
All right...
Can you help me?
So why did you tell me the truth?
I had nothing left to hide.
Hold on.
Hello?
What? The plane?
Yes, of course!
It's time!
Run up my bill.
Done? Great! How much?
All right, perfect, perfect.
For peanuts...
There.
-What was it about?
-The plane.
It's almost time. But I'm early.
-What I would like to do...
-What would you like?
To drive you home.
That way,
if I ever come back to Paris...
If you want to see me again,
you'll know where I am.
I would know you hadn't changed.
-Still, I do feel bad.
-Why?
Because I love you.
Since you're surely as delicate
as you once were,
if I offered to help you...
You know I'd refuse.
Besides, I can't complain.
I'm very happy with my daughter.
Of course, I work.
But you know, I always have.
Mommy!
You're ugly!
Still, life isn't fair.
For example,
imagine if we lived together.
I too would be...
economically weak like you.
-Maybe we'd be happy.
-No, no.
Certainly derisory.
If we lived together happily
and without a penny,
at some point, I'd be an asshole.
-With me?
-By force of circumstance.
But with others, out of necessity.
Being an asshole
to the woman you love,
even if you aren't one deep down,
that's far too much.
What do you think?
I'm thinking about someone
who used to say:
"No money, no problems".
-It made me laugh at the time.
-What about now?
It still does.
Well, maybe everything will fall
into place with a little bit of luck.
Imagine that my wife leaves me
and I'm ruined.
Money wounds aren't fatal, I hear.
Maybe I'd get better.
Then I'd come back.
Here?
Yes, here.
Mommy!
My little dancer!
I met Santa Claus.
He gave me this for you.
Where are you going?
-Orly.
-No.
Isn't it where the plane is?
No, I changed my mind.
I'm just going south
to spend the holidays.
-To end the year in style!
-As you say.
So the Lyon Station?
That one or another...
The Lyon Station is best to go south.
In style...
You might be more right
than you think.
Last night was how
my beautiful year ended.
It hadn't started well, though.
Don't even tell me
about the next one,
what a happy new year it'll be.
Don't complain.
You'll start it in the sun.
Or in the shade.
Santa is nice.
He didn't forget me.
Yes, he's nice in his own way.
Especially on Christmas night.
It's his day, so he's happy.
And he wishes it
to all those he loves,
to everyone he thinks he loves.
Will he be back next year?
Maybe.
Perhaps the crime is the revenge
of the beasts we have killed.
This wreath, which seems to be
the end of this story,
is really just the beginning
of the next one.
Liliane, don't cry.
Isn't it beautiful?
It is. That's just it.
-Do you like it?
-A lot.
We're leaving each other
on a good note, aren't we?
This is all my fault.
When I saw you,
I got dizzy right away.
What an effect you had on me!
You're not even handsome.
I thought I was meant to be
with Jean-Marie before.
Not at all! It was you. It's funny.
Can't you try and stay?
What if I get arrested
and get 15 years?
What good would it do?
I have to enlist.
Tomorrow, at this time,
I'll be in Marseille.
You know who I am. I'm a hunted man.
My darling little rogue.
You know, I wrote it all down.
-What did you write down?
-Yes, on my calendar.
Since the first minute.
That's nice!
"Sunday, May 17: met Jean-Pierre
at the movies in the morning.
"He put his hand on my right thigh.
"Fresnay was playing in Mr. Vincent".
That's right!
"I closed my eyes.
The movie was very short.
"At the end, Jean-Pierre
kissed me on the neck.
"I let him do it. I asked
Jean-Marie for forgiveness.
"He bought me lunch.
We ate the same thing:
"sausage, butter, veal chop,
beans, gruyere, custard.
"We went home together.
"It was barely 10:00 p.m.
when we went to bed.
"Then he...".
-Did I do that?
-Keep going. It's not over.
Yes. "We fell asleep at 4:00 a.m..."
Oh my!
"At 5:00 a.m., he woke me and..."
Again?
I'm amazing!
But it's over. There will only be
blank pages in my calendar now.
Listen, Liliane, don't get emotional.
Am I crying?
And yet, I'm leaving you.
Are you leaving yourself?
You'll still sleep with yourself.
In the meantime, I'll be
one, two, one, two.
I'll go from Gafsa to Tataouine.
I'll smell like warm sand,
and with you in mind, my love,
I'll sing the melancholic song
of the wheaten with the others.
Here's some blood sausage
What's that?
That's the legion song,
don't you know?
For Alsatians, Swiss and Lorrainers
-That's funny.
-Let's sing together!
Here's some blood sausage
It's too sad.
No, it's happy!
It'll be our love song.
Get up. You'll be late.
You have five minutes left.
I wonder what pleasure
you can have, sir,
in pretending to be someone
else to these ladies.
I don't want to be loved for myself.
I want to be loved for what I'm not.
Your impostures, sir,
are no less regrettable.
Regrettable?
You have a short memory, Armand.
The few times I've had the temerity
to be loved under my real name,
you weren't very proud.
Neither was I, actually.
I can't be blamed for anything.
Liliane, whom I just left,
will have been loved
at least once in her life
by a unique character.
She had her piece of a dream.
She'll look with melancholy
at the little ring he gave her
before leaving forever
where a tragic fate awaits him.
-What ring?
-Grandma's ring.
You gave her Grandma's ring, sir?
But it was a real diamond!
Something had to be real
in this story!
Take a left!
To the Champs-Elysees, go!
Sir, remember that
your uncle's funeral is later today.
-Are you sure it's today?
-I am, sir.
You wouldn't think of being buried
in weather like this.
It's not even raining.
You know me and funerals...
I like the racetrack better.
At least you know what you're losing.
Are you serious, sir?
I can't stand my uncle!
He's dead, sir.
All the more reason!
And he hated me.
He was a mean guy.
Do you have a black suit, sir?
They'll get what they get.
Thankfully, I took precautions.
I also bought a wreath.
-No, Armand! No, crazy purchases!
-On sale, sir.
Half off.
It must be nice.
You'll see it, sir.
It's being delivered this morning.
What is this?
Your latest songs.
That's the record I made as a joke!
That was nice!
It's a surprise for my girlfriends.
We remember the good memories!
It's an all-purpose record.
Listen, I think it's pretty good.
You'll give me your opinion.
I'm very interested.
Hello!
It's me again.
Don't look for me.
I'm here, embedded in the wax.
Do you know that
you're still as pretty, as lovely,
and you don't look like anyone?
Your eyes that go in pairs,
your boobs, too,
your lips that are
sometimes four when I add mine.
See?
All that, my love...
Very nice, sir,
but we're running out of time.
We'll be late for the funeral.
I don't want to go!
It's not usually for pleasure.
Only the dead guy amuses me.
But he's not worth the trouble.
And will they even notice my absence?
Your uncle's widow,
whose grief is certainly deep,
-will not be able to...
-The widow? But my poor Armand,
it's the best day of her life!
Everyone knows that she's been
the mistress of my uncle's secretary,
her husband, for three years!
No way! Mr. Gustave?
Yes, Mr. Gustave!
A fine scoundrel, by the way.
What is this?
It's awful!
That'll be me in ten minutes.
What kind of hat is this?
It's a loan!
-A loan?
-Yes, from the concierge.
It belonged to her husband,
who himself belonged to the police.
She didn't give you the moustache
that went with it?
Let's see.
She should've lent me
her husband's head, too!
You can hold it.
I had better, yes.
What a small head I have!
-That explains a lot!
-Armand!
So where were you?
At the business ball?
Can't you hear the doorbell?
What's in your ears?
A shock absorber?
Is this Mr. Jean-Pierre
Delagrange's residence?
Yes.
This double-sided figure,
that saddleback look,
that crooked smile
borrowed from a dentist!
I do have the right address!
This is Jean-Pierre Delagrange's!
If I looked like that,
I'd wear closed pants.
I recognize you! He told me
about you. Your name is Armand!
You look like it, too.
I wouldn't trust you
with my little sister.
-Carcassonne!
-Carca...
-Excuse me?
-Carcassonne, doesn't ring a bell?
He never told you about me,
of course.
I'm not a topic of conversation.
-Ma'am...
-Ma'am?
Be polite! What do you take me for?
Ma'am? Not ma'am, miss!
Your boss is handsome.
But he'll get what's coming to him!
Smile, buddy, smile.
Enjoy it. Enjoy it!
It's an occasion...
Well, what are you standing around
like a fishing rod on a bank for?
Are you waiting for it to bite?
Announce me, please!
Carcassonne!
-But...
-Don't you want to? I'll go myself!
Please, miss, calm down!
Calm down and we'll see.
But I am calm. I am very calm.
I am extremely calm.
Know this, poor Armand,
that if I was not, I would've
broken everything, starting with you!
Remember this.
-It's June 24, isn't it?
-Yes.
When were the September massacres?
The mass...
But I don't blame you, miss.
On the contrary.
-Carcassonne is a very nice town.
-Silence!
I'll count to 100!
One, two, three,
-four, five!
-Miss.
Six, seven, eight,
nine, ten, eleven...
What was it?
Carcassonne!
What about Carcassonne?
A lady asked me to say
"Carcassonne" to you, sir.
Carcassonne?
Carcassonne is not very lively.
She's keeping her hand in her bag.
I'm sure she has a gun
and wants to get rid of you, sir.
A gun, it's Suzy!
She never knew whether
to kill herself or me.
She seems to have made her choice.
One of the few women
I was sincere with!
You see... the reward.
You didn't tell her I was here?
I'm used to it, sir, but she seems
determined to camp out here.
-What is she doing right now?
-Counting to 100.
To... Listen, Armand, do you like me?
-Really?
-Yes.
Do what you want, lie if you must,
but she has to leave.
She must!
She...
94,
95.
Is this the Delagrange residence?
-Yes.
-It's the wreath for Mr. Delagrange.
-A wreath?
-Yes, ma'am.
Indeed...
Alas...
It can't be.
Since you've guessed, miss,
I can tell you that he is no more.
He's not?
Your wish came true, miss.
He died without your help.
Enough, enough! Don't make it worse!
I didn't know what I was saying, sir!
You say you'll kill someone,
but if you do it every time,
no one will be left.
My Jean-Pierre!
My Jeannot! My darling Pierrot...
I don't want to leave you
with a bad impression!
I'm going to join you, right now.
Adieu, Pierrot.
Come on, come on! Give me that!
Give me that right now!
You brute!
Where do you think you are?
One death is not enough for you?
Do you need two?
Let me kill myself
since that's what I want!
Not here! Elsewhere, if you like.
Go kill yourself at home.
Why didn't you tell me right away
that Jean-Pierre was dead?
Out of thoughtfulness!
To spare you grief.
How did he die?
With his family.
When's the funeral?
Today.
-Already?
-Youth has to happen.
-Your name is Suzy, right?
-Yes.
Alas...
-Suzy...
-It was his last word.
Really? He's so nice!
He did not dare write to you.
He felt unworthy.
Yes. No!
Come on, how silly of him!
He said: "Happiness
is not big enough for her.
"We'd have to come up
with something." So...
He was looking! He was looking!
The brain did not hold.
That's what he died of.
Meningitis, lightning fast,
you could say.
-Scum!
-Huh?
-Scoundrel!
Wretch! You hear? I'm a wretch!
I'll pay for this.
I will pay with my life.
That'll teach me!
No, you have to live,
so he can live
in your memories of him.
Don't blame yourself.
-No!
-Leave in peace, miss.
-Goodbye, miss.
-Goodbye, sir.
You're right!
You're never quite dead
when those who love you live on.
I'd like to see the place where
he lived. Show me his room.
It would be too painful.
You're too emotional.
I've come to terms with his death.
Show me his room!
So be it...
Come in, Ms. Suzy,
come in his room!
I didn't touch anything.
I wanted the room to remain exactly
as he left it.
It looks like
he'll be back any minute.
My little silk pajamas!
-What's over here?
-That's the bathroom.
But it's a mess.
I drew myself a bath
before heading to the funeral.
To think he looked at himself
in that mirror every day!
He called me his "little razor."
He was very good with faces.
And here's the studio
where he worked
when he was still alive.
That's where he wrote his songs.
It is.
He didn't even finish his last hit.
What a pity!
He was so talented!
It's so beautiful!
Who's playing the accordion?
It's Leon...
Who's playing the trumpet?
It's Anael
Who's playing the kazoo?
It's Gaston
Who's playing the trombone?
It's Simon
It's moving.
Only he could come up
with such ideas.
Only him!
Bless you.
I was so looking forward
to seeing him again.
-Now my life is...
-You're still young.
I was young ten minutes ago!
Now...
Now I could be your mother, Armand.
One last look in his bedroom!
-Again?
-Yes.
Will you stop flirting with my wife?
Don't you dare shush me!
What's this show you're putting on?
I'll kick your ass! I will!
I'll get you!
And here his view when he'd wake up.
His little terrace...
And the idiot acting like a fool!
Always the same thing...
The good ones always leave first!
And the bad ones stay!
You, up there, I'll remember this!
-Who?
-God! It's all He does.
-Adieu, Armand!
-Adieu, miss.
My bag...
Hello! It's me.
I'm back. Hello!
Don't look for me.
-I'm here.
-Can you hear this?
Can you?
No, miss.
I can't hear anything.
His little voice!
His little voice just for me!
Miss!
-My poor friend!
-He liked you, you know.
How long has it been, ma'am?
Thank you for your beautiful wreath.
Yes, yes, you spoiled him!
That's the least I could do.
Do you know Mr. Gustave Chartin?
Jean-Pierre's secretary.
Yes, we met under better
circumstances, I'm afraid.
At the opera, at the intermission,
you were with Mrs. Delagrange.
Yes, indeed.
It was a lovely show.
Lovely.
He didn't suffer too much, I hope?
Not in the least.
Isn't that right? It went very well.
Good thing.
He was so afraid of death!
Yes, it was a good surprise.
I mean...
He was sitting there listening
to the radio and suddenly...
He didn't realize anything.
He thought it was
a technical accident.
It's a wonderful way to die.
He died in good health.
We are so insignificant.
Michel! I'm not too late, am I?
We'll leave in five minutes, sir.
Perfect, buddy, perfect.
You're already leaving?
Hello, cousin.
No, I have to talk to the priest.
Really?
-Can you believe it?
-What's wrong?
-His death!
-My uncle! I know about that!
He took all the regret with him.
Yes, he took away all our regrets
and left us none.
See you soon, cousin.
Auntie...
You're late.
Good things I'm here!
I almost died, too.
What happened?
I'll tell you about it later,
but it was this close.
Gustave, buddy!
You look tired.
I spent all night with your aunt.
That, of course, is very tiring.
Hello, how are you? Hi.
You could have come earlier.
You act so casually!
Please don't ruin my day, OK?
At ease!
This is Mr. Moussenard.
Jean-Pierre Delagrange.
Jean-Pierre Delagrange!
Don't worry.
My name is Jean-Pierre too,
but I'm not in that coffin!
It' must be a funny feeling.
Very funny.
I really liked your uncle.
-Really?
-Just imagine,
we were born the same year.
We went to law school together.
We got married on the same day.
We graduated in the same class.
We always followed each other.
Well, I hope it continues.
Sorry!
Gentlemen?
Yes.
-Hello, sir.
-Hello, miss.
Suzie Henebey.
And you are?
I'm the hotel manager.
Nice to meet you, sir.
But? What are you...
What are you doing in my room?
Did you at least respect me?
You don't think I...
Don't be rude!
I don't think anything!
I'm just asking! Answer yes or no!
No, miss.
"No, miss."
It's nothing to brag about!
By the way... By the way...
It's amazing!
-What is it, miss?
-I'm not fainting anymore!
Obviously.
Couldn't you say so?
I remember now.
But who brought me back here?
A tall gentleman who said
he'd found your address in your bag.
He gave you to the doorman, who
gave you to the baggage handler,
and I got you to your room.
How long was I out?
About 45 minutes.
Do you know where the funeral is?
What funeral?
Jean-Pierre Delagrange's funeral!
I don't know.
All you have to do is call.
Just call...
Hello? Hello?
Good thing I'm here.
I don't know what I'd do without me.
Hello, miss? The cemeteries, please.
Yes, all the cemeteries.
Here, hold the phone.
I'll get dressed.
There's my dress.
He was so nice!
A boy like that is extremely rare,
especially in this day and age.
What are you looking at me for?
Where do you think you are?
With the grief I have,
I have other things to think about!
Hello? This is
the Pere Lachaise Cemetery, miss.
Hello? Pere Lachaise?
Would you put me through to
the concierge? It's for information.
Hello?
Are you receiving
Mr. Jean-Pierre Delagrange today?
Delagrange, in one word.
No?
I'm very sorry.
Hello? Hello, miss?
Next one, please!
Jean-Pierre, you can turn around
and look back
on your accomplished work,
because if you leave us,
it's without owing us anything.
You retire after making a fortune.
Finance is also an art.
If numbers have their eloquence,
they also have their poetry.
Stock market speculations
are also intellectual speculations.
They are not just a money game
but a mind game.
Yes, my friends,
Jean-Pierre Delagrange was
in his own way an artist,
a poet, a musician, finally,
because he was running
his business like a maestro!
Jean-Pierre...
It may seem irreverent
to speak like this over a grave,
but your grave
is not like the others,
because you're not just
another dead man.
You are a dead man standing!
You're a living dead.
No, no regrets, no tears, no sorrow!
We're not saying goodbye because
even far from us, you are present.
Present! It is the cry of the soldier
always ready to do his duty.
Present in joy and sorrow!
Present in our regrets!
Present in our hopes!
Present in the past!
Present in the future!
Present in the present!
We won't conjugate you in
the past definite or imperfect tense!
Only one time for you: the present!
Death may be strong,
implacable and uncompromising,
but she can't make you disappear!
Your work is there, continuing you,
affirming you, fulfilling you,
testifying of you, demonstrating you,
that proves, verifies, certifies
and makes you clear.
It scrutinizes, discounts
and credits you,
defines you! Yes!
Defines you, Jean-Pierre!
My love...
How true, my darling!
-She said "darling."
-Did he have a mistress?
Where you are, be happy.
You, whose eyes have only closed
to be see inside yourself.
Adieu, Jeannot! Adieu, my love!
Adieu, my life!
It's me, Suzy,
your little Suzy, your Suzinette!
Please don't stay here, miss.
Come with me.
Follow me, ladies and gentlemen.
Be reasonable!
If everyone did what you do...
Your uncle had a mistress.
-No? No kidding?
-Yes, she's here.
She's at the grave.
They can't move her.
What did she say?
How is she?
Amazing. She'll come shake your hand.
Bravo!
Thank you. I'm very touched
by what you have just said.
That is some consolation.
-Did you hear?
-I did!
-Amazing!
-Only here!
Two widows! This is really
a first class funeral!
-My condolences.
-Sir!
-Have you heard, sir?
-Have I!
You shouldn't stay here!
Why? I want to see her!
-What if she makes a scene?
-All the more reason!
Come on, it's really funny!
Ma'am! You only you knew...
To lose such a beautiful boy,
it's sad for a mother's heart!
Ma'am, your son was an elite soul.
My son?
She went to the wrong funeral!
You're staying here!
You're not leaving until the end!
I need to talk to Armand!
Don't you move!
My condolences.
Bastard! Bastard!
My love... you're dead!
You're dead!
You won't get away with this!
-No, no.
-Armand! Armand!
So, is he dead?
Is he dead?
Answer her. Am I dead?
-Did he tell you I was dead?
-Did he?
Is he dead?
Me? Dead? Me?
This is an abominable slander!
I hope you didn't believe him?
Am I dead?
I don't understand!
There is no possible explanation!
Yes! He was paid by the family
to keep the intruder away!
To separate us forever!
Armand, is this true?
Tell me it's not true!
You know how much I cared for Suzy,
how worried I was about her silence!
It's kind of your fault.
Why didn't you answer my letters?
-But I never received any letters.
-What?
-Never!
-Do you hear that, Armand?
But I've always
sent your letters, sir!
So I'm a liar?
Not another word! Go home!
I'll deal with you tomorrow! Go!
Good thing you were dead.
I was about to kill you!
I wouldn't have survived you.
In short, Armand saved our lives.
That's true. Without him...
We'll keep him, but we won't
give him any more letters to mail.
He'll do it very well, as usual.
And now we'll never leave
each other again.
-Never again.
-I'm yours for life.
-For life.
-And we'll always love each other.
-Always.
-I'm so happy!
I know.
On second thought,
I think I lied to you.
-What do you mean?
-I'm not a music composer.
-Are you kidding?
-No.
-I'm an explorer.
-Here we go again.
I hunt lions in the Sahara.
-I'll have to go back soon.
-I'll come with you!
Oh dear! It's far too dangerous.
What's this?
Keep it. You never know.
No, it's useless now.
The morale of the story: to succeed
in love, you must know music.
What does this
faux sable rabbit skin represent?
Authentic news.
You may recall the facts.
It was in all the papers at the time.
On October 19th, Gerard de Narcay,
committed for the last four years
at the request of his family
for his extravagance and prodigality,
escaped from the asylum.
It was a Thursday.
The Comedie Francaise was playing
Le Misanthrope that morning.
Julie Perrin played Celimene.
She was about to go on stage.
Crime at the Comedie Francaise!
Paris Presse!
Thank you, sir!
Julie Perrin strangled
in her dressing room!
Crime at the Comedie Francaise!
Thank you, sir!
JULIE PERRIN STRANGLED
IN HER DRESSING ROOM
Two crimes in three hours.
The police found out Julie Perrin
was Gerard de Narcay's mistress.
They also knew Mr. Dalmet,
the second victim, was the notary
of the demented man's family
and his perpetual guardian.
There was no doubt on whom
the murderer was.
But where was
the murderous madman lurking now,
for whose capture the police
had promised a large reward?
Hello? I'd like to speak
to Dr. Mansart, please.
Thanks. I'll wait.
Dr. Mansart!
You're wanted on the phone.
Hello?
It wasn't me. It was the notary.
God rest his soul.
-A man was just killed!
-What is it?
A man was just killed!
-Where?
-There's the killer!
He's getting away!
POLICE
He shoved me. He went like
a madman towards the Seine!
He went that way!
It's not a good time yet.
Now you can.
It's safe now.
If you were to call them,
they would come.
Scream.
-Scream!
-Go away!
I'd like to.
You could help me. Come with me!
Leave me alone.
Why didn't you let me die?
I've lost the nerve to do it now.
Come with me. I'll help you die.
You'll see, it's easy but later.
But definitely not that.
I want to live. I have to live.
A few more hours, one more task.
Come with me. You'll help me.
Aren't you going to ask
why I'm wanted?
I should be dead by now.
Help me get through then.
I'm wary of doors.
They close and keep you prisoner.
Are you praying?
If it's for me, don't bother.
Christ is on my side.
He has to be, since I was betrayed.
He too was betrayed.
He was locked up, just like me,
in a tomb.
But he escaped on the third day.
It took me
five years.
Three times, Father.
Priests are funny. They always
want to know how many times.
Such accounting!
"How many times, my child?"
"Three times, Father.
"I have delivered
justice three times.
"Yes,
"I punished them, Father.".
My own justice.
I delivered it myself!
Be quiet.
My family locked me up
to steal my money.
I don't care about the money,
but my freedom...
It's awful.
Five years
like an animal in a cage behind bars.
Hearing the screams
of the other victims in the cells...
There was never any silence.
It's abominable.
I thought I was the most unhappy.
The most painful thing
was those who laughed.
They couldn't stop laughing,
as if they were going crazy.
Two more traitors to punish.
Come on.
Do you have a cigarette?
Let me see.
Thank you.
What's wrong? Are you sick?
Did you eat anything?
I don't think so.
This is where I lived.
It's not very cheerful,
but you're safe here.
Get some rest.
I'll put on a pot of coffee.
Would you like some milk
in your coffee?
What are you doing?
Keys are ugly.
They have teeth,
one mean eye.
That's true.
Take off your coat. Rest a bit.
Do you know what they did
to the king?
-Which king?
-Louis XVI.
He made keys, locks.
Not for a living.
He was King of France.
He was doing it to distract himself.
Distract himself...
from being king.
They locked him up in a prison.
Like me.
Yes, I know.
Then they cut off his head.
No more head.
Don't play with keys.
It's dangerous.
Don't open it.
It's bad luck.
It was bad luck to the people
who locked him up.
Thank you.
We couldn't even try to pick
the lock to escape.
We couldn't see it.
We couldn't even see the door.
Four walls,
smooth walls.
We couldn't even try to kill
ourselves against the walls.
They were padded.
And do you know
what they dare call this hell?
An asylum.
A word that means "refuge".
Are you scared?
Of me? Why?
Yes, I understand.
You really thought I was crazy.
And a crazy man who promised
to help you die.
Why did you believe me?
Why would I kill you?
You helped me. You were kind to me.
If I killed you,
I would be completely crazy.
I'm not crazy.
I never was.
I told you,
my family had me locked up.
They claimed that I was,
on the advice of the notary
and the doctor.
And the other one.
It was silly of me to be scared.
No, it's my fault.
I talk, I talk,
I'm telling you bad things.
Five years locked up alone,
all those words you want to shout.
That choke you, that hurt you. Yes.
Of course, when you have someone
in front of you to talk to,
all the words want
to come out at once.
You understand.
Yes, although it's
the opposite for me.
It's kind of the same thing.
You were locked up,
and I was forced to flee.
I was forced to leave
from everywhere, all the time.
So I didn't have anyone
to talk to either.
And to think
I'm only talking about myself.
You wanted to die...
Sit down.
Drink your coffee while it's hot.
Yes.
Can I take two?
-Of course.
-Thank you.
Heartbreak?
-Want some cigarettes?
-Yes.
There's one left.
Thank you. You're kind.
It's amazing.
I thought you were going to kill me.
Yes.
I was scared.
-So I don't want to die anymore.
-It's wonderful.
I don't even know why I did.
It means you're crazy, like me.
I just feel like
everything's changed all of a sudden.
I try to remember,
but all I can find is ghosts.
This man...
-What man?
-My father-in-law.
I too have a nice family.
My mother was a poor woman.
She remarried a drunkard.
I was 17, so he...
Do you understand?
He'd chase me around.
It was untenable.
So I was forced to leave.
-It's pathetic.
-Then,
after him, all the others.
And the head of the workshop,
the cardboard factory where I worked.
I had to leave, too.
Then I worked in a hardware store.
It was the boss, there.
He was afraid of his wife,
so he'd take me to the basement.
It's despicable.
It's always the same thing
everywhere I go.
I thought I'd see my father-in-law,
so I'd go away, and it'd start again.
It's over now.
The last one was a widower.
He was a stamp dealer.
He seemed gentle, kind, delicate.
He was inconsolable
over his wife's death.
He was always looking at me
with his pleading eyes,
big eyes full of water.
He ended up being
even more despicable than the others.
It's over now.
You'll forget all about it,
this whole nightmare.
You'll see, you will live.
There is more to life.
Where are you? Where are you?
I'm here.
You must be tired.
You're falling asleep.
-I think so.
-Get some rest.
You're safe here.
You cried?
Don't. It's over now.
Life is beautiful.
You'll see. It's very beautiful.
I'll take a head of lettuce,
two kilos of potatoes
and two slices of ham.
All right.
Here. Someone gave me those.
They'll look better on you.
Thank you.
Where are you?
Miss?
You're awake already?
I was very careful.
About what?
To not make noise.
It was the silence that woke me up.
-The silence?
-Yes.
You're hot?
Yes, very hot.
Was Bluebeard mean?
Of course. He couldn't love
a woman without killing her.
Maybe it's because they couldn't
love him without betraying him?
He had his reasons
for not letting them touch the key.
-The key?
-The key to the closet.
Oh, yes.
Do you know the language of flowers?
-No.
-No?
Do you know what the pansy means?
It means "tenderness".
I bought you cigarettes.
Thank you.
Don't worry. It's nothing!
-What are you looking at?
-Nothing. The street.
Two girls are playing hopscotch.
It's odd. I always thought
that street was awfully sad,
but now, it almost looks happy to me.
Everything seems to have changed.
Everything seems brighter
with you here.
She told me that, too.
I loved her.
I was madly in love with her.
Madly, yes, that's the right word.
When I was taken to the asylum,
she was sitting in the car next to me
to make me think
we were going on vacation.
She was their accomplice, for money.
It's terrible.
I'm begging you,
don't think about her anymore.
Don't talk about her anymore.
Yes.
It was a nightmare. It's over.
You'll see, everything will
become brighter for you, too.
But...
She was holding my hand,
just like you.
She kept telling me
she loved me.
That's a word I've never said
to anyone before.
And when you really love someone,
the difficult thing
isn't to say it but to hide it.
You have to see it
in the person's eyes.
When they locked me in the room,
she was in the doorway.
Yes.
She still dared to look at me.
How could she look at you
without loving you?
Such a pure forehead,
such soft, bright eyes.
My love, why did you take the key?
You shouldn't have.
You shouldn't have!
So much water has passed!
Let's move on.
The famous violin of Ingres!
The violin is often
an instrument of torture.
So is the piano, actually.
Raoul!
It's a song
That resembles us
You loved me
And I loved you
We lived
Together
You loved me
And I loved you
But life separates
Those who love each other
Slowly
Without making
A noise
And the sea erases
From the sand
The steps of the lovers
Who are no more
Here, while you're at it.
Ah, it's so boring here
It's so boring here
Silence!
What's wrong with you?
I thought you liked music.
I was dreaming. I thought it had
happened, and then, suddenly...
-What is this?
-Nothing. Buskers.
Ticket and identity verification.
They should've been out a long time
ago, but they were playing so well.
Do you call that music?
I think it's noise.
Like you know anything about it!
A little, yes. When it comes
to rhythm, I'm unbeatable.
No more clarinet, all right?
-Guitar!
-Yeah.
Get the hell out and don't come back!
You understand French? I said out!
Yes, gentleman!
Gentleman? Watch your tone!
-Don't come back!
-You hear that, Enrico?
He thinks we broke in.
Are you making fun of me? If I see
you again, you'll get eight days!
OK. If we get hungry at Pentecost...
Hungry?
Get smart with me again, and...
Scram!
Gentlemen...
Come on...
-Coffee makes you angry.
-Coffee makes me sleepy.
It even makes me dream.
Just now, without these two,
I was having the dream of my life.
-Anything else?
-One kilo of sugar, please.
-Here.
-And one kilo of tomatoes.
The kid sounds like
a saw with his violin!
I live here. Can you imagine?
I forgot! Give me
a pound of cherries, too.
Who's making all that noise?
My son. He's only ten years old!
I can hear that.
If I had a kid and a violin,
I'd either take the violin apart
or put the kid in the fridge,
but I'd never leave them together!
Don't exaggerate!
The kid was born gifted.
What do you want?
I respect his poor father's wishes.
His poor father was second violin.
-He wanted him...
-To be second violin?
No, first.
Disillusions of grandeur!
It's the best way
to get him to behave.
As long as he's playing,
I know what he's doing.
Raoul, come here!
Come on! Come on!
Come on! Raoul, come on!
Come on!
For the kids, what a pain!
Tell me about it! When I see
Thursday coming, I can't sleep.
The street belongs to them.
If I were the government,
I would eliminate Thursday.
Look at that. Will you stop that?
Come try your luck!
Little bastard!
Little bastard! Come here!
You'll pay for this!
I'll tell your mother!
-What's going on?
-It wasn't me, sir!
I had nothing to do with it!
I don't even have a slingshot!
What? I saw you!
Did you see him, too?
-I didn't.
-I'm telling you, it's him!
I'm telling you it's not him, got it?
Raoul! Raoul, come here.
Come on, kid.
Who will pay for the broken glass?
You are. And pick up the pieces
if you don't want a ticket!
Come on, buddy.
And that how they spend our taxes...
You're so kind.
Go home and let me hear you play!
You know, a woman alone
with a boy like that...
When children don't make you mad,
it's because they're sick.
And yours, thank God, is healthy.
And to be fair,
he does give you satisfaction.
He does... Listen.
How's that for satisfaction?
That kid's an artist.
What he's playing is really pretty.
-You think so?
-I do.
Hearing him play
makes you want to cry.
I'd shed a tear
if I wasn't in uniform.
The violin always moves you.
He's very lucky to have
a beautiful mother like his.
You see the horn over there,
-let's get it!
-Yeah, come on!
Not here, over there!
Yes, yes!
I really think that.
If he had the right support,
he would become someone.
It's obvious when you listen to him.
If all policemen were like you...
Can you come for coffee tonight?
-Really?
-Yes.
But come in plain clothes because...
You're not inviting the policeman
but the man.
No, it's the friend.
With all due respect.
-But the friend is also a man.
-We'll see about that.
-That's great.
-What?
Do you believe in dreams?
He has it in his arm and his wrist.
He has the wrist, the vibrato.
This is called vibrato.
We have vibrato in our whistle.
-So?
-So what?
-Where is it?
-What?
-The fire!
-What fire?
You don't know where it is?
How should I know?
Who else should I ask?
I don't know!
I'm not the fire alarm!
-The horn was pushed!
-By whom?
Unbelievable!
It was right next to you,
but you didn't hear anything?
I'll make a report.
You'll deal with your superiors!
It's not my fault if there's no fire!
So, Mr. Raoul,
will I see you tonight?
Yes.
-Around 8:30 p.m.?
-Right.
-Bye, then.
-Bye.
-Is that all?
-Yes, but I can do it again.
-It's not another song?
-No, it's the same.
That's enough.
You can see what he can do.
-Time for bed.
-A little longer!
-I said in bed.
-Later!
That's enough!
I'll spank you!
You didn't hurt me.
May I?
Will you go to bed, or do you
want to take a trip to the station?
All right, I'm going to bed.
Because I want to.
He's just as stubborn
as his father was.
Don't get upset. Children are fickle.
Thank you. But yours,
musically speaking,
he sounds like a record.
Raoul! Raoul, will you stop?
-Why are you laughing?
-Because my name is Raoul, too.
No?
Sometimes,
when you call him on the street,
I turn around randomly.
You never know.
I wouldn't dare.
What would your wife think?
I haven't had a wife since July 14.
She left me for a colleague.
I don't see the difference.
And yet, in terms of tenderness,
I've always been...
affectionate and not at all jealous.
I sweep the floor, I do the laundry,
I carry breakfast to bed.
I'm just naturally happy.
And then, physically...
I see another one.
So you're a widow, too?
Yes.
Now with my kid and my business,
there are times when I feel quite
alone, without anyone.
If I can help in any way...
I'm mostly worried about my son.
After what you told me
about his violin,
-it's a shame he lost his teacher.
-Is he dead?
No, he didn't come back.
I hesitate to take another one.
I'm telling you, he's a champ.
Yes, but you could be wrong.
You're not in the business.
Before I pay for it, I'd like to have
the opinion of an artist.
It'd be very helpful if you knew one.
Well, you can't just find an artist
everywhere.
Companions of bad days
I wish you a good night
Sleep, dream
I'll take my hat
And two or three cigarettes
From my pack
And I'm leaving
Companions of bad days
Think of me sometime
Later when you're awake
Think of the one who sings smiling
An air of desolation
Somewhere in the night
By the sea
And who then begs
To buy food and water
Companions of bad days
I wish you a good night
Sleep, dream
I'm leaving
Take your equipment and follow me!
-Don't be mean!
-Don't make it worse!
Don't exaggerate!
Why would I get in trouble for this?
There are better excuses.
I'll make my report, you'll see.
He's so nervous!
Nervous? Watch your mouth.
Insulting an officer,
that's six months.
I didn't insult you.
I said you were nervous.
All right! All right!
Let us go. You can't be serious!
Who's in charge here?
I'll decide if you can go.
I'm willing to let it go
but on one condition.
Go ahead.
No reason why we can't
get along like good people.
-Yeah.
-So here it is:
I know a kid who plays the violin.
Well, playing is a big word.
He sounds like he's sawing iron.
It sends shivers down your spine.
What do you want us to do?
Steal his violin?
On the contrary. I want you
to listen to him as an expert,
compliment him
in front of his mother,
tell him he has a bright future.
-Not much.
-That's all?
-Yes.
-I don't get it.
You have to leave
an unfortunate widow her illusions.
That child is all she has.
It's her only consolation.
I'm giving you the opportunity
to do a good deed.
-How's the mother?
-She's a grocer.
I'm not asking you what she does
but how she is.
That's none of your business,
but you'll see her.
I'll introduce you as an old friend,
married, of course.
Why married?
It'd validate your opinion
more than if you were single.
Agreed?
I have a choice between two violins.
I'll choose the lesser.
What are you doing on Sunday?
Nice bouquet!
I don't know if the child
will be happy,
but the mother will be thrilled.
You and your insinuations!
Go have a drink!
-On your dime?
-Yes. Even two, if you prefer.
Let's have a drink, let's have two
Let's drink to a lover
Leave me be.
A music lover, of course!
Still, leave me be!
What a way for a peacekeeper
to express himself,
even in civilian clothes.
-Hello.
-Hello, Mr. Raoul.
Cute kid!
That's for you, and that's for you.
You're spoiling us, Mr. Raoul.
I'm interested in the boy wonder.
Raoul, say thank you to Mr. Raoul,
come on!
Thank you.
May I? Excuse me.
I have another surprise for you.
Another one?
I just met an old friend of mine.
An artist of great value.
He's in Paris.
I told him about the boy,
and what I told him interested
him so much, that he asked
-if he could hear him.
-Is he coming here?
Yes, in a minute.
Do your best.
Go wash your hands.
My friend always speaks his mind.
He never gets carried away.
He'll listen to the boy,
will think about it,
and he'll let you know
what he thinks,
whether you like it or not.
Sorry to bother you,
but someone is asking for you.
-Good.
-That's the friend I told you about!
-Hello, my friend!
-Hi.
Nice hat.
-Cheap.
-Even better.
I'll show you the boy. After you.
Don't bother us.
We're having a meeting.
Three adults and a kid.
Ma'am. Pleased to meet you.
-The honor is mine.
-Thank you.
Sit down.
-A cup of coffee?
-Yes, please.
This is the phenomenon!
He's a little shy.
Hi, buddy, how are you?
-Not bad, you?
-Be polite, will you?
So, you're the artist?
-Let's see it.
-Go!
Don't hurry!
We have plenty of time.
Exactly. We have plenty of time.
-Lucky me.
-Go ahead, buddy.
That's it.
Good wrist, huh?
Do you play like this on purpose?
-Or is it involuntary?
-No,
it's instinct!
He plays like he breathes.
Let him answer!
I do it on purpose.
Yeah.
-So?
This kid has no talent.
None.
Well, at least now we know.
He has more than talent.
I've never heard it played
that way before! Never!
In his own way,
he's some kind of genius.
A new Paganini.
When he was a kid.
-That's it.
-Thanks, buddy. Thank you.
Thanks to you, I've experienced
something unforgettable.
I don't regret coming.
You can go play, go.
You've earned it.
We must drink to such success!
-What will you do with him?
-He needs to practice!
Yes, but with whom?
Too bad you can't stay in Paris.
It's a man like you that
he would need.
You flatter me.
With you, one feels immediately safe.
It's true. You're nice and kind.
And you have kind eyes.
No matter what we say,
an artist is not the same as others.
If you wanted
to take care of the boy...
Unfortunately, that's not possible.
He has to leave tomorrow morning.
Not at all!
I'm not leaving.
Didn't I tell you?
I've cancelled all my contracts.
-You're kidding, right?
-No, not at all.
He can't anyway, but he'd love
to refer you
to a good teacher, right?
I'll do better than that,
out of friendship for you.
I will, if you will permit me,
take care of this child myself.
Yes, yes, I insist!
I'm confused.
I don't know how to thank you.
Please.
I'm being paid by making
an old friend happy!
I'll be back in a few days,
and we can have a useful chat.
-Goodbye, dear.
-Bye.
Are you coming or staying?
-I'll go with you.
-Mr. Raoul,
I'll never forget your help,
introducing me to your friend.
-Thanks again.
-You're very welcome.
Are you happy now?
You've been playing me!
-Me?
-Yes, you!
That's not nice.
-After all I've done for you.
-There's a bastard I'd like to beat!
Where? He'll have to deal with me!
You can't in civilian clothes.
He might teach you a lesson.
Be careful,
or go put your uniform on.
But you were right about the boy.
He sounds horrible.
He showed great promise
but for the guitar.
-Trust me, I...
-Trust you?
I'll never tell the mother
what you said about the boy.
We wouldn't want
to hurt her feelings.
She's lovely.
I'm going to get into my uniform.
That's right!
So, after what happened
between us today, let's be informal!
Who needs a ticket?
Come get your tickets!
Come try your luck,
ladies and gentlemen!
Who needs a ticket?
Come get your tickets!
Every ticket wins!
Drawing next Wednesday.
Who needs a ticket?
Come get your tickets!
Drawing next Wednesday.
Who needs a ticket?
Come get your tickets!
Come try your luck!
Who needs a ticket?
Every ticket wins!
It's weird to be closed
on a Thursday.
All three of them
went to the countryside.
-Three?
-Yes,
Mrs. Solange,
the boy and your friend,
-the handsome guy.
-You think he's handsome?
-Yes, not bad.
-Well, they're not here.
But they're not far!
It's the kid's day.
It's Saint Raoul's day!
Saint Raoul's day?
Give me a ticket, at random.
You look like someone in luck
tonight.
Here.
Who needs a ticket?
Come get your tickets!
Come try your luck!
Every ticket wins!
Every day of the week
In winter, in the fall
In the sky of Paris
Factory chimneys only smoke gray
But the coming spring
A flower on his ear
A pretty girl on his arm
Sunflower, Sunflower
It's the name of the flower
The name of the girl
She has no last name
She dances on street corners
In Belleville, in Seville
Sunflower, Sunflower, Sunflower
Waltz of the street corners
And the good times came
The good life
With them
The genius of the Bastille
Smoking a blue Gitane
In the sky of love
In the sky of Seville
In the sky of my city
And even from anywhere
Sunflower, Sunflower
It's the name of the flower
The name of the girl
She has no last name
She dances on street corners
In Belleville, in Seville
Sunflower, Sunflower, Sunflower
Waltz of the street corners
Well sung, kids!
Ready for your first lesson?
-What are you waiting for?
-Go ahead, Raoul, go ahead!
Raoul is going to play!
Sit here.
Listen to him.
See, it's not very difficult. And
it's less dangerous than a violin.
Yes, but it's less
annoying for everyone.
What's your first name?
Solange.
Funny you should ask.
-Why?
-Just saying.
Not long ago, I met someone who
often told me what his name was.
He never asked for my name.
-Wasn't he curious?
-Not like you.
-Are you curious?
-I am.
-What's your name?
-Raoul.
-Like my little boy.
-Yes, that's good.
Today is his day.
And it's mine too.
Yes.
I know someone who'd love to be here.
-Who?
-Your friend.
Oh yes! I had completely
forgotten about that one!
It's not good to forget your friends.
Who needs a ticket?
Come get your tickets!
Listen, Mr. Raoul,
it's your day too,
so I thought of you,
because I like you.
After what you did for my son and I,
it's thanks to you that
he's learning the guitar
and that I've met your friend.
You've been a godsend for us.
So I thought you might want
to keep this violin.
To remember the three of us!
Who needs a ticket?
Come try your luck, ma'am!
Drawing is next Wednesday!
Come get your tickets!
Who needs a ticket?
Mr. Raoul!
Mr. Raoul! My mom said
she forgot to give you this.
Come try your luck!
Every ticket wins!
Here. It's for the lost and found.
That's it.
You see how intrusive
an object can be.
Sometimes, it tells the whole story.
And if you don't want us to know
anything about your personal life,
take care of your things.
THE END
Subtitling: Hiventy