Can't you open your yap?
Have a cozy chat or something?
You start then.
I am, aren't I? But you sneak off.
My Sarie Marais
is so far from my heart.
But I hope to see her again.
There under all the corn
near the green tree with thorns...
...there lives my Sarie Marais.
Why I can only think of Sarie Marais
I have no idea.
There where my Sarie lives.
There under all the corn
near the green tree with thorns...
...that's where my Sarie lives.
Don't you know another song?
- I'm thinking.
At my dovecote I love to be.
Being there is a pleasure to me.
You can still know everything there.
You won't have forgotten anything,
I swear.
At my dovecote I love to be.
Being there is a pleasure to me.
At my dovecote.
It's been so long since I sang
that I can't remember anything.
I've got nothing here anyway.
All music is gone.
Are you confused?
- I'm completely confused.
I've done a lot of singing,
but I can't remember anything anymore.
And I didn't bring anything.
It's already a quarter to twelve.
- It will get even later.
Once I drove too far in the car.
I had too...
I don't remember where I was going...
...but I drove on
where I should have stopped...
...or turned around or turned off.
And that story.. I drove back
and got home all right...
...but I told that story
Perhaps that was stupid.
After that they said:
You should be locked up.
They didn't use those words, but that's
what they meant. I forgot too much.
I used to have a good memory
but not anymore.
It fades.
Why is that? Because of getting older.
There are enough of you, or should I help?
- Help! Look what's still there.
I don't have a cutting board.
There's no cutting board in the factory
either Use your hands.
We're not at the factory are we?
No, but I'm saying they don't use
a cutting board at Van de Poel's.
That's their business.
My goodness,
that's enough to make me sick.
You shouldn't.
- It doesn't bother me.
It shouldn't make you sick.
- I already am, I guess.
Yes, apparently.
Is it all right? God, you're not
wearing your hearing aid again.
I don't hear what you're saying.
- You're not wearing your hearing aid.
Your hearing aid.
Where is it?
There's no battery in it.
It ran out.
O, the battery ran out.
The battery ran out, honey
I don't feel I'm as mad as a hatter,
but I do forget things.
I have what's called Alzheimer's.
I don't mind admitting it.
It's clear
I'm not pathetic. Normally speaking
I'm a normal human being.
But I forget everything
and that's a real nuisance.
That's about the only thing I can say
I don't feel sick.
I don't feel unhappy.
Nothing like that.
I live as I used to,
except that I forget everything.
It's a phenomenon
that other people have as well.
I don't mind talking about it.
Hordes of people have it
and now I have it.
How you get it? You just do.
I don't know if it's related to anything.
I don't know.
I should ask a doctor.
I think it just appears.
It's in your brain.
It suddenly appears in there.
What a lovely Christmas tree.
- Yes, come and have a look, Edwine.
It's like a walking Christmastree.
We'll put it beside the cabinet again.
Here's the plug.
- Mariëtte has the plug.
Here's another one.
- Isn't that a light?
What do you think?
Does it look OK?
Let's look at it from a distance.
Alice, what do you think?
- It looks good.
Are they spaced out evenly?
You need some here.
Hang on. We're working on it.
- I'm just saying.
All those finicky lights.
Did you have a Christmas tree, Louise?
- What?
Did you have a Christmastree at home?
- Yes, I still do.
Who trimmed it?
- I don't know.
I'm not there now.
- But when you used to live there?
I did.
What color were your Christmas balls?
- Everything.
Evert color?
- Everything, yes.
And colored lights, or only white?
- A bit of everything.
It's beautiful like this.
I was born aboard ship.
So I lived on board as a child
and as a young woman.
Later on,
when we had a boyfriend...
...we still stayed on board.
But when we were married,
we went on a ship with that boy.
Because he was a skipper too.
But then we set sail again,
except that now there were the two of us.
That's a nice blouse.
- There we go again.
That's not a blouse, it's a dress.
It's gorgeous.
- Oh my God.
What about mine?
- It's nice too.
You've already seen it 27 times.
- But that one is more elegant.
François, do you want some?
Edwine, would you like a glass of wine?
- Yes.
To your health.
Enjoy your meal everyone.
Anita, all the way over there.
We went by ship to France three times
just to get some wine.
By boat?
- For Belgium, yes.
By ship. A boat is not a ship, you know.
What's the difference?
A ship is something people live on.
It's their house.
And a boat is something
just to ride around in.
We went to Germany
to France.
We went everywhere.
Now they're gone again.
I don't know where to.
But...
- Are you talking about your children?
Your children have gone.
Your children.
- My children?
You said your son
was going on a trip.
I don't know...
- No one told me anything.
Lia...
- We were coming too, right?
Can we toast?
- If that's what you want, we'll all do it.
To a delicious meal.
- Cheers.
If you don't drink anything,
it stays full.
That's right. Marieke, but I do think
that you already drank a lot.
Water.
- Yes?
How can that be?
Did I miss anything?
François is wearing a beautiful rose.
Yes. Where did you steal that?
François.
- You're wearing a beautiful flower.
François,
where did you steal that flower?
They just put it on.
- It looks good on you.
Where did you nick that?
Suddenly he's deaf.
- Which girl gave it to you?
You can put it that way too.
- Your girlfriend?
We won't get an answer guys.
You're right, honey
You're right. Don't tell.
Keeping silent is the best policy.
My son is in this photograph...
...and my son-in-law.
In the second row...
...that's my daughter..
...and a son-in-law and my son...
...and another son...
...and a daughter.
And my other daughter.
And that's our Ellen.
And our Jos, and me.
In between.
And that's our Diane.
And that's our what's-his-face.
All right, say it.
I'll be damned if I know.
Our Jos, our Staf.
Our Lief.
- Our Lief.
Now I've lost it completely.
Our Lief...
...and our Greet.
Do you have to peel the potatoes?
- I don't have to.
I may
I'll help you.
Alice, where is François?
He's not here.
He went to the Bijster.
How come?
- Who knows?
I don't know.
- We don't know.
Why did he have to go?
Them and their quirks.
Being sent to the Bijster
is kind of like a demotion.
That means you can't cope here.
That was probably true in his case as well.
He's already been replaced
by that little brat.
That little lady.
Do tell.
- She's sitting on the couch.
It will be Mardi Gras soon.
- I've never celebrated that in my whole life.
No?
- No, I lived in the Netherlands.
Don't they have over there?
- Only in the south.
But I didn't live in the south,
so I never wore a nice costume.
You poor thing!
I bought Mardi Gras costumes
on Saturday.
For the kids?
- Yes, of course.
Caro picked out a nice one for me.
- And?
What does it look like?
- Hot pink.
With a blond wig.
It's called Mega Mindy.
Of the "Pink Ballets" probably.
- You should have a picture taken.
I had to buy a Mega Mindy suit.
She said that they also had them
for grown-ups. That was true.
Then you should have a picture taken.
Or was one taken already?
- I didn't buy it, silly.
You call me silly?
How dare you?
It's a super-tight outfit
that reveals every lump.
I'm not wearing that.
You look beautiful.
You have a nice head of hair.
You're jealous. I get that.
- Me too.
Yes, I get that.
Tonight I'll look different again.
Go for a pee now, Edwine.
Then go to your room and I'll come by.
There's your room. I'll come by soon.
First go for a pee.
Is that her room?
- Yes. Yours is a bit further down.
Come on, Louise.
I'll rub some lotion on your legs.
Is this all right?
First I have to take my shoes off.
- Go ahead.
Could you help me?
- I will. I'll help you.
Come along.
Here are your pills.
Put up your legs.
I'm so tired. Terrible.
Thank you. I'll pray for you.
Great. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Sleep tight.
Are you all going to bed at once?
We can't do it twice.
- I mean you and Mariëtte.
Let's see if you can go in, Alice.
I'll come and help you in a minute.
Hold on. We'll pull this one down.
I'll give you a dry one for the night.
Would you like to sit down?
- I certainly would.
Once you're in bed,
I'll come and see if everything's all right.
I'm sure it will be.
- Yes, but I'll come and check.
Fine.
Sleep tight, guys.
Good night.
Voilà.
That was good.
What do you think? Are you ready?
Can I ask you now?
Do you know what day of the week
it is today?
What day of the week it is today?
Just a minute.
Monday Tuesday Wednesday
Thursday Friday Saturday?
Do you know which year this is?
The year
Anita, do you know the year?
- April, May.
We're not going to call a helpline.
Do you know which year it is?
No, I don't.
I have that calendar in front of my nose.
It says June 4 if I'm not mistaken.
Your eyes are good.
- They are.
But we weren't going to the optometrist.
- No, we weren't.
We were going to the...
The psychologist.
It doesn't matter.
- Something like it.
That doctor prescribes medication
for your memory.
But you still feel that you're not quite sure
which day year or month...
That's not that surprising.
I led a regular life at home.
I did certain things on certain days.
I attended lectures.
Lately I had a singing lesson
once a week...
...and there was something else I did.
It was regular. Here I'm just sitting around.
Sometimes we go to the Bijster...
...and I know that's on a Wednesday
because we eat there.
Other than that not a lot happens.
That's why I don't know
which day it is exactly.
Do you know where we are?
In which town, which country?
Here? In Belgium.
- In Belgium. That's right.
And in which province or city?
Wondelgem.
Are we in Wommelgem?
- Wondelgem.
Antwerp.
- The province of Antwerp.
And in which village are we?
Yes, that's...
Essen.
And how do you call this building?
The house you live in now?
The Bijster.
And our ward?
It's on the tip of my tongue.
I know it has its own name.
Go on.
Maybe it will come to me.
And the address?
- What's the address again?
I don't know.
I just don't know.
86 Nieuwstraat.
16 Nieuwweg.
Iduna.
I was born in this house.
In Ede. I never saw it again,
so I don't know what they did to it.
It's a Heritage building.
Nothing can be changed on the outside.
I don't know what they did
to the inside.
It must still be the same.
My parents already changed the garden.
But the house itself
can't be changed.
That's the Heimans coat of arms.
I don't know how we got that.
My father found it and had it framed.
And now I have it.
It hung in our house
and I took it, of course.
That painting was painted by a painter
in Ede, Jan Eversen.
I was 29.
I don't know why it was made.
For some reason, my parents had it done.
I was...what did I say? 18, I believe.
Yes, 18 is about right.
What else do I have? Nothing.
Just the usual stuff everyone...
...could have in their cupboards.
Right! That's true.
The one at the back is my grandfather.
My father's father.
Hold on, it was my husband.
That was my husband around the time
he died. He was 80 then.
He was a lot older than I was,
but we got along very well.
Beside him is my father
And that's my mother when she was only..
...In her early thirties or something.
That's a very good friend of mine
who died a long time ago.
And that's the son of...
For the life of me, I can't remember.
It's the son of...
Oh, of that friend of mine.
Or a grandson of hers. Something like that,
but I'm not entirely sure.
That's about all I can tell you
about this room.
It's an ordinary boarding room.
That's our Mom.
That was taken during...
...Napoleon's time.
She was English.
That was my grandmother.
She was only 18 there.
She's holding a flower.
And her hair was long.
It was all wavy Down to here.
That was my Mom's sister.
Where do you sit, Bertje? Here?
- That's the chair.
You go and sit over there.
You're sitting over there.
- Oh, here.
It's tea.
Do you drink tea? Then you need a glass.
- It's a cup.
Do you want it in a cup?
Can I have that glass for the tea?
You want tea, don't you?
Who has a nice story?
- Louise, you've got an anecdote.
About those millions
you won once.
We know that one by heart.
I've never heard it.
- I'm sure you haven't. Do tell.
I dreamed it, of course.
- Ah, you dreamed it.
I won something...
...and it was a box of money..
...and I looked at it and thought:
Oh, a bit of money A few lousy francs.
And I opened it
and it was a million.
A million francs?
Was it in bills?
- In my sleep. I told you.
That what I dreamed.
A huge stack of money
underneath my bed.
I got up in the morning. I looked underneath
my bed and there were only dust bunnies.
No million. Nothing.
No, it all disappeared.
I bet you were happy for a short while.
That was at school. I don't know
which school, but it was a school.
No, it was here.
Was it here? I don't remember
Louise calls it a school.
- Yes, but I had to sleep there, didn't I?
Weren't you always at boarding school?
Your parents were skippers, right?
From the time we were ten
the Belgian state made us go to school.
So we had to go to school.
- Compulsory education.
We were...
How shall I say this...
...not French. Not Walloons.
They went in Belgium, but...
...but Wallonia to school. But we
didn't speak French. Just oui and non.
I did a lot wrong with that.
Someone came on shore there...
...and he spoke French.
Oui and non was the only thing I knew.
And he said something
and I said to him: oui, oui.
And then our Mom came...
...and that gentleman said...
...in French
and she didn't speak French either.
Our Mom was English.
And he chattered away in French.
Who knows what he was saying.
He had a package. What was in it?
We didn't know.
Our Mom said: non, non.
Non, non. That was the only thing
she could say and: oui, oui.
And I had said: oui, oui. So he brought
something. I don't know what.
And our Mom said: non, non, non, non.
Give me your hand.
And now get off the steps.
We're here.
We can't go any further.
This is as deep as it gets.
It won't get any deeper
It's the same everywhere.
- Now we can cross the pool.
We can skip through the pool like this.
If you want to try and swim,
you can.
No, I don't want to.
This is fine. You're in the water.
This is fun, isn't it?
And there is Alice.
Yvette, Yvette.
Yvette, get it.
Have you got it, Yvette?
And now right on top
of Alice's head.
What's this?
Kick.
OK. That's great.
Shall we try to swim?
Come on. Let go.
Let it go when you're ready.
Leave it up to me.
I've got you.
Not yet?
You won't go down.
I'm holding you.
You can't sink,
because my hands are here.
I can only tickle you.
Well done. You see?
Are we going that way?
Here, here.
- They're going to bother us over there.
We've been washed thoroughly right?
- From head to toe.
Massage in the swimming pool.
That's the way it's supposed to be.
I'm getting a massage
in the swimming pool.
Now you can't tell they're sweaty feet.
- Is it OK? Boy they're stinky.
You'll be able to dance well.
- Yes, I'm good at dancing.
I love that what's-it-called waltz.
The Weseke waltz.
The waltz?
We danced yesterday didn't we?
- Did we? I don't remember
I do. As long as I remember
it's all right, isn't it?
You're lucky aren't you?
I sure am.
This is me with our Lief.
And this is me with our Lief as well.
Except different.
With different clothes.
And this is me with a former boyfriend.
I had a boyfriend.
- Really?
But it slowly fizzled out.
But I'm still leaving it up there.
Where's your boyfriend right now?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
I don't have feelings anymore for him,
so...
...I don't know.
- The love was over and done with.
For me it wasn't.
But it has to come from both sides.
That's my husband.
- Yes, Rik.
It says Rik in big letters.
I do jigsaws like crazy
I like it.
I can use my head
and it keeps me occupied.
I don't feel like doing nothing
but sitting around all day long.
That was on my wedding day
I was standing on a bench.
The groom was a tall guy
and I was short. That's why..
...there was a bench
Otherwise I'd only reach his armpits.
The people who were going to take
the picture said:
"That doesn't look good."
"You're only this big."
"Being together in a picture doesn't make
any sense. You'll have to stand on a bench."
"Then you'll be as tall as your husband."
That's why there was a bench there.
But you couldn't see it.
All those flowers were in front of it.
You can't see
that because of those flowers...
...how shall I put it...
...there was a bench.
That's it.
Can you hand me that knife?
Hey stop that!
What are you thinking?
You're using the sharp side of the knife.
Alzheimer's is something that occurs
at this age.
So, really I'm not the only one.
I can't even tell
when someone has it.
You can often tell by the responses.
I think: He'll probably have it.
But no one talks about it.
No one discusses it.
No, it's private.
I'm going to say three things.
Repeat after me and remember them.
Book.
Plant.
Windmill.
Those three things I mentioned...
- I have to remember them.
Jeez, my bones.
I think we're up to it.
Do you know "kamer" (room)?
We're going to try
to spell that backwards.
Kamer.
- Yes. The last letter?
Rens?
R? And then? And before that?
Rens? Kamer?
- Kamer.
We're going to spell it backwards.
What's the last letter?
I can't remember.
Rekam.
No, remak.
- And letter by letter?
R...
A... No, E...
M...
A...
Kamer.
- That's it.
I asked you to remember three words.
Do you remember what words they were?
No.
Which words they were.
Rens?
That's your name.
You're called Louise Rens.
Rens?
Mother?
"Kamer" was one.
I don't remember.
You had to remember three words.
Was "kamer" one of them?
In the middle, I think.
I don't know.
I had to put it backwards
and I ended up with "remak."
I don't know.
- You don't?
I don't remember.
It's all gone.
Book? Did I say that?
Book?
I don't think so.
Book doesn't sound familiar.
I'll try another word. Plant?
- No.
Didn't you have to remember that?
- I don't think so.
Let's try another one. Windmill?
- Windmill, yes.
Did I say that?
- I think so.
Windmill sounds familiar
Or am I wrong?
That's the wheels on the road.
I hear them.
The corn looks nice
and those horses.
They are astonished.
Yes, it's us.
- Those horses are looking at us.
Our Lief is working on it.
Your Lief is working on it.
She's courageous.
It's allowed.
- Right.
She knows that. Right, Alice?
Do we have to go straight ahead?
Do we have to park here?
Hi, Anneke.
Hello.
Come on, guys. Run.
Come on, pedal.
- Pedal. We're going uphill.
You sit over there.
Sit over there?
- You always do.
Yes, on the other side.
Louise is in the wrong chair.
You sit on the other side.
- Louise is in the wrong chair
Louise, you're in the wrong chair.
You always sit over there.
Does it matter where you sit?
- Yes. Everyone has their own chair.
With meals and with coffee.
Exactly.
But doesn't Louise always sit there?
- No, I sit here.
You sit there, where Edwine is now.
That's not true. I always sit here.
Mariëtte sits beside me.
Where do I sit?
- Over there, I think.
Yes, that's right.
- Is this right?
I'm thirsty.
Yes, I believe Alice sits over there.
No, that's not right either
Where does Alice sit?
Alice sits beside Louise.
- Where's Alice?
She went home already.
- No, she's sprawled out over there.
Damn it. Jesus.
It's boiling hot.
Too bad.
- Come quickly Anita.
Take those pants off, quickly.
- Come over here.
Hot tea.
You don't do that on purpose, right?
I said: I don't do that on purpose.
Don't you want one?
You should use a sweetener
That won't make you fat.
Sugar will.
Can I have some more tea?
Didn't you have coffee?
Is that coffee?
- There's tea...
Did you have tea or coffee?
She herself doesn't know.
- I don't know.
What do you want? Tea or coffee?
- Coffee.
I'll serve you,
even though it's not my job.
Take your hands out of the way
Your hand!
If I spill any I'll hit your hand.
That just happened to me, so...
Thank you.
It might tip over.
- That's not true.
No?
- That plastic is underneath it.
Why is it lopsided?
She doesn't hear you.
- You have that lying over there.
What?
- Take away that paper from under the cup.
You've got it underneath it. Just put it
beside it. That's the best way.
Is that so hard?
Now she has to put it back on.
Then it's also lopsided.
It's still lopsided.
- My God.
Just put it beside your cup.
Beside your saucer
The way everyone does it.
She should put it in the bucket.
- But then she won't get coffee anymore.
Can't you act normal?
Here's my thing.
You can do that too.
Everyone does that.
Why does it have to lie on top of that cup?
It makes it harder to clear up.
She's always contrary You know that.
When I collect the cups, I first
have to take off that piece. If I don't...
So why is that necessary?
- But you don't clear the table, do you?
Yes, I do.
- No, that's not yes. That's no.
You clear away the cups then. OK?
Tonight she has to do it herself.
- Then we'll have to do it.
My ears are drowning.
Then they'll get a good cleaning.
You're so beautiful.
I haven't seen anything like it for years.
So beautiful.
Right. My singing talent
is recorded too.
My thanks.
- You're welcome.
You may come along.
- You're coming along with me.
Am I pretty?
What do you think?
She's so happy she's coming with me.
I suggest that on the back of the sheet...
...you write a sentence.
I want to write something...
- But you're afraid to.
Don't hold back.
Just write it down.
My house.
Would you like to write: my house?
Try to write down: my house.
My house.
In words. Use words...
- My.. Is that with a Y?
Yes, that's right. MY
I think that's a great sentence.
I'll give you top marks.
You were allowed to write down
anything you wanted.
Now I think: Being crazy causes no pain.
- That's what you wanted to write down.
And that we're cool guys,
we realize.
That's why we go everywhere.
Everywhere everywhere
where there are girls.
Everywhere, everywhere
where there are girls...
...we can have some twirls.
Change.
Your knees are black Melanie.
Wash them, for that I don't want to see.
And when they have a nice shine...
...stick your feet- change -
close to mine.
Oh, Jefke got a wife.
And now he is in trouble.
Oh, Jefke got a wife...
...and now he is in trouble
for the rest of his life.
Humpa humpa
humpa tataraa.
Tataraa, tataraa.
Well done, Louise! Aren't you tired?
Then it's all right.
Louise. Hey good morning.
Did you sleep well? Yes?
Why don't you get up? Then you can have
some tea and a sandwich.
Today it's Wednesday.
This afternoon we'll go to the hairdresser
Do you still know where that is?
There's that big room
where people dance.
You're going to get a room there.
That's where you'll live.
Live?
- Yes.
That's kind of a home too.
You know what that is, right?
Just like here.
You can go and live there.
They have a room for you.
We'll bring everything along.
Your photographs and your clothes.
And we'll have a look at your new room.
Is that OK? Yes?
Let's eat first. OK?
Those are big boxes, aren't they?
Have you looked to see
what's in them?
Is that for throwing out?
- No, that won't be thrown out.
We'll take that along
to your new room.
These are your dolls.
We'll take them along.
They're in the box, ready to be moved.
Isn't that great?
Let's go in here.
Isn't it too hot?
Should I add some cold water?
Go ahead and wash your face.
Freshen up a bit.
Look in the mirror What do you think?
Is it all right?
Let's go to the kitchen.
Ma'am.
- Madame.
They're all looking at us.
- Why do you think that is?
There are all sorts of things on the table
to put on your bread.
Strawberry jam, chocolate paste.
You choose. Enjoy
I'll be back soon.
Ladies, tonight Louise
is going to live somewhere else.
She's going to live in the Bijster
You know that place, right?
Louise will get a new room there.
That's nice.
- And a good bed.
Why is that?
You'll be cared for very well over there.
We can't give you that kind of care here.
As you're getting older,
you have some tough days sometimes.
That's true.
Do you yourself think
it's tough sometimes?
Then it's always...
- You'll be fine there.
I think so too. Anita says
you'll be fine there.
You'll be fine there.
You'll be well taken care of.
There are a lot of nurses there.
Then it's all right, isn't it?
It's always a bit strange
when you move somewhere else.
You'll get used to it soon.
You get to know the other people.
You'll get used to it.
I settled down here,
as you will over there.
Put that in the suitcase.
We'll take it along.
Louise, the pictures.
Shall we put them in too?
There are a lot of memories here.
Memories of the boat.
Of that time you were sailing.
Why don't you put it in the suitcase?
Put it right on top.
You can close the suitcase, Louise.
Everything is in it.
You're ready to leave.
I don't think I can push beside that.
Let me help.
Things aren't allowed to fall out, right?
It's heavy.
- I can't carry it.
Let me carry it.
We'll go that way.
There's no way I would want
to go to the Bijster.
A regiment. Awful.
I would find that awful.
If they had sent me there
I don't know what I would have done.
All those people... No.
That nursing home aspect.
At least here it's homey.
But that's a nursing home.
It would drive me nuts.
Here we are. It's downhill now.
We'll just...
it's cold!
A lot of people are stuck together here.
I grew up as an only child.
I wasn't used to regiments
and now I'm in the company of nine people.
To me that's a regiment.
I've always been
enormously individualistic.
I don't have a real life here anymore,
of course.
I've been put away
just like this whole bunch.
I don't get too upset about it.
I just do as I please.
But I've been put away here, yes.
I was put away because I once
drove the wrong way with the car
I'm stuck in this joint.
I've been written off.
Of course. You don't end up in a joint
like this when you haven't been written off.
So there's no reason at all for me...
Stop for a minute.
You'd better stop.
This isn't working.
It has to be done right.
Isn't that so, Mariëtte?
I can't imagine Edwine ironing.
I don't think she'd do a good job.
This has become undone.
Ah well, no one will notice.
She'd say: I'm tired.
From doing nothing.
This is one of Edwine's skirts.
If I'd say to her: iron it yourself...
...what do you think she'd say?
"I can't."
I'm sure of that.
- For sure.
It's an annoying skirt, isn't it?
It's all silk.
- I wouldn't iron it too much.
You're right.
It's fine like that.
- It's ready I quit.
Good evening, dear people.
We're looking forward to a fun evening
with the family party
it's great to see so many people here.
How much did I have to drink?
Not much. Only one glass of wine.
What can you still sing? Do you remember
the songs you used to sing?
I don't remember anything.
- Nothing?
Down By That Windmill.
Do you know that?
I know that one.
Sing it.
- I love with all my life.
Down by that beautiful windmill...
...lives a girl
I love with all my life.
Down by that beautiful windmill...
...I want to live
when she becomes my wife.
This one is Edwine's. And that...
...that's Bertje's.
We'll take them.
What did you say?
- Here's another box.
A box with picture albums.
- It's Edwine's.
She's been here for nine years.
Then you collect a lot of stuff.
Ah Marietje the roses will blossom.
Even when I am gone.
You'll smile through your fears.
- Tears.
Today we were done.
Even if you think it's all gone...
...it's all gone forever.
Ah Marietje my tears will blossom.
Even when I'm gone.
It's over.
Where do we go now?
- To the Bijster.
We'll see each other at the Bijster.
See you in a couple of days.
I wouldn't want to go there.
Me neither
I think I'd take pills.
I'd take pills so I'd die.
You're not there yet.
They are younger than you are,
but you're not there yet.
I don't want to go there.
I'm not looking forward to it either
but if there's no other way..
You wouldn't go?
That's an option!
I don't think that we have to be
that afraid of it.
I'd take pills
before I'd go there.
I mean what I'm saying.
Boy-o-boy Marieke.
What did you say?
- That I wouldn't go there.
I take pills so I'd die.
- That's one way out.
I'm thinking along the same lines.
- I'd ask Wm to give me pills.
Wm won't do that.
He'll give you one if you really ask.
But it's not easy to get.
If there's nothing wrong with you,
you won't get it. No way.
Doctors are doctors, after all.
They don't just kill someone
because they enjoy it.