Everyone would have emotional problems
when they are growing up
Come talk to us,
it just costs you a hundred
for a drink.
That includes a real
good chat,
go for it.
And that's the style of
''SOHO with love''.
l have my own car,
apartment and l am beautiful too...
men should chase
after me though.
l just want to find someone...
to have a spectacular
romance with me.
l sell insurance to my clients
for a life time guarantee.
And l do want to find someone...
who would fall in love with me
for a life time too.
There is something in your teeth.
Really?
l can't get hard.
ln fact l'm not impotent,
l just can't make love
to my wife.
But l do have sexual desire
to other women.
Why does my boyfriend
bring me to see Keroro
movie every time?
And he always takes me to
Mcdonald or Kentucky for meal.
He won't go out with me unless
there comes the comic exhibition
Would you guys be
a bit mature?
Well, guys used to get
matured late.
l urge him to propose to me for
one hundred times before marrying him
because l want to have enough time
for us to think about it seriously.
And l do hope our relationship
will get better.
But, is it getting
even worse now?
He already proposed
to me for 96 times.
Whenever he buys me anything that
would be something that he likes
and he doesn't care
what l really want.
What do you want actually?
l am kind of falling
for a girl, but...
l don't know how to get
approach to her.
Have you ever gone
out with someone?
Of course l do.
And you are too coward.
She's rich, educated
and older than me...
You can still tell her that you
like her, if you don't...
she never know what
you are thinking about.
lf you do, maybe..
you will have the chance, huh?
Yeah.
That's right.
But l don't even know her.
Love is not rational,
you can't ask why
Otherwise that's not love.
Breaking up is like getting
a scar on the skin.
lt hurts at the beginning,
it'll be covered by the make-up.
As you look carefully,
it leaves a scar there.
l know they said l'm insane.
But someone says, only the insane
knows what love is.
One should indulge in love,
crazy about love
Otherwise that's not love.
Love Hurray
Feel much better now.
lt's getting hard to
find someone like you have the
patience to listen to my story
lt really worths it.
Thank you.
Save the money and
go to Beijing soon.
l know that, bye.
ls someone looking for you
two unlicensed psychiatrists?
What's up, doctor trainee?
What would you like to
talk about today?
l'd like to talk about the fact.
l think there should be
impact to life, failure...
no matter it's about
my career or love,
l will fix that up immediately,
no delay.
You two just listen to
stories of others,
does it work?
Hey, doc,
why do you keep
complaining tonight?
lt's okay,
he is going to
have an operation.
Why did you meet me here,
babe?
Are we gonna have dinner?
l'd like to talk to you.
Let's talk about during
dinner, let's go.
Let's break up then.
What did you say?
Joe Yeung, what did you say?
We have been together
for 6 months,
you suddenly want to
break up.
Why are you just sitting here?
Speak up!
Listen, our passion is gone.
Love will transform to sympathy
if we don't tackle it
l don't want to waste
our time.
ls it?
Some more water?
What's happening?
Operation fails.
You are so early,
where's Maggie?
What'd you like?
l am tackling it.
Honey, please marry me?
That's tacky.
This is the 97th time,
3 more left.
You did promise me,
don't eat your words.
Let's get something to eat
and go for an art show.
Sorry, girlfriend.
l have to dine with
my client tonight,
it's about the stock market.
That's a big client,
you have to go.
My girlfriend is
so considerate, so...
l have to marry her.
Bye!
What the hell!
How can someone blind doing
the delivery work?
Which restaurant are you in?
Who is your boss?
What is it?
What's your name?
Look at him!
The place is so messy...
You go ahead,
just leave it to me.
l am sorry...
You are in hurry.
l am terribly sorry...
Sorry about that,
Miss Ng...
lt's okay,
l will fix that.
l will fetch you
some new one.
What is love about!
Tell me...
Honey, he's up again.
There are so many
new singers,
l can't even identify them.
Everyone is gonna
sing love song.
Love song!
How many of them do really
know what love is about?
lf they don't, how can they have
the feeling in singing...
the true meaning of love,
the greatness of love,
the inscription of love.
They just never taste
the frustration of love.
What are you doing?
You srewed up
the delivery again?
lt's not my fault...the guy
bumped into me...
Sing... stop keep on
watching gals.
You should be devoted
in doing
delivery just like
having a romance.
You should learn to treasure
and getting involved.
Do you really
understand that?
You look great today.
What would you
like to have?
Same.
Do you know the girl
over there?
l haven't seen her before.
Which one?
The one in grey.
Miss Ng.
Please sign here.
Thanks.
My dear, would you marry me?
Yes.
Would you marry me?
You just simply do that
on phone?
Have you got the gift?
lt's from you.
Yeah.
Come on, check it out.
Playing cool.
What is it?
Come on!
ls it touching?
Yeah?
What?
That is... our home sweet home.
Marry me, please?
Two more to go.
Come on, give me a break.
l told you it's gonna
be 100 times.
Just count this call
for twice.
Come on, marry me?
Are you going to check out the
furniture with me tonight?
Please wait.
Well, tonight l have to...
Watch over the stock market.
l know that.
Maybe you check it out yourself.
lf you want to buy anything just use
the credit card l gave you last time,
okay?
l trust your taste,
l just knew it.
Really great, right?
Please hold on, honey.
Yes, Mr. Wong.
941 China Telecom,
it's gonna be dropped .
$126, no problem,
buy in for five million.
ls it five million.
Yes.
Also, 1923...
Please wait for sec,
it's gonna be quick.
Yes, Mr. Wong, it'd be fine
for the call warrant of 941 .
l will keep an eye on that,
don't worry about that, okay.
l will call you later.
What are you doing here, kid?
Just want to tell you...
Just call me get the bowl
back as you finish the soup.
Alright.
Are you upset?
So?
Bye.
Ching.
What's up?
lt's okay.
l know that,won't look at him,
won't talk to him...
Won't sit next to him,
won't even listen to him, okay?
l am going.
Unlicensed psychiatrist.
No more business?
All patients are cured?
Where is Ching going?
She is wearing nice.
She has a gathering
with her old classmates.
Old classmates?
Why aren't you going?
One of them is
her first lover.
Someone is sick,
let's go.
Who is sick? Where to?
Hospital.
What hospital?
Come on, trust me.
Let's go.
What would you like?
Fruit punch.
Thanks.
Looking for something?
There comes the patient.
Hi, remember me?
Do you mind sitting together?
Go ahead.
l am Wylie and
she is Kelly.
l am Joe, Joe Yeung.
He is my friend, Sung.
Tacky!
No, his last name is a Yeung.
Come here often?
No, just to accompany him.
Where are you hanging out?
No really, l have to work.
What's you job?
He is just a waiter.
This is my name card,
nice to meet you.
Are you a doctor?
Yep.
Where are you going
for work?
There is a cafe in Soho,
called ''SOHO with love''
Do you know that?
You are that unlicensed
psychiatrist.
He's not licensed,
he'll soon be get caught.
Come here, l have quite
a lot to ask you.
Can you tell me something
about your cafe?
l have quite a lot to ask you,
come on.
You haven't ordered your drink,
what would you like?
What do you do
for a living?
l am an accountant.
What about Kelly?
She is still studying
in Canada.
Her cousin is getting
marry two weeks later,
she came back as
her bridemate.
She is leaving soon.
Hung.
Do you stll remember
Ko Bo Won?
She will get marry next year,
she invites you for the wedding banquet.
Really?
No way, l have to go back
to Beijing after X'mas.
My father wants me
to go back soon.
Are you going or not?
Probably, but l won't pay
much for the token.
Because Sung and l are saving money for
the tuition fee for studying in Beijing.
Not enough still?
lt would be much
for two of us.
Planning for two-year-saving,
but now...
the third year has passed.
How much in short?
Maybe l could lend it to you.
Hung, we want to
do it on our own.
On your own?
We don't want that,
just lend it to us.
Okay.
Too mild.
l will go and get some
more sugar.
Ching.
Hung is really nice,
just give him
one more chance.
Yeah, he is rich
and faithful.
lf l were you, l will like
be his mistress!
lf he likes me,
l will get sex change.
l will get sex change
to become his mistress.
Alright, as Hung comes out,
l will tell him about that.
ln fact l just want to
save enough money
and go to Beijing to study
with Sung as fast as we can.
The syrup.
Thanks.
How is it? Have you found
someone you love?
Not yet, do you have
any good guys for me?
Of course!
Guys in Beijing are
as good as Daniel Wu...
l want one too.
But a bit short,
four feet something.
But it is good though.
Let's back to the seat.
l leave now.
Ching may back home already
Okay.
Everybody, l back home first.
Bye.
Let's go.
lt is not good to drink coffee
at night.
lt is no good to hang out
so often either.
You have fun that night?
Which night?
The night after l left.
lt is more or less the same.
When should l call you?
Please give this to Sung.
Why didn't you give it to him
earlier tonight?
Just forget it.
l will give it to him.
Thanks a lot.
What's up?
You said it is not good
to drink coffee at night.
Where are you going?
Karaoke?
Okay.
l am not going,
l have to leave.
l am not going then,
see you next time.
Okay.
Bye.
Call me.
Should l take you home?
lt's so late.
Okay.
Time flies, it's been five years
since we broke up.
ls it?
l was too busy in my study and
not paying much attention to you.
Well, my father told me
to go back to Beijing.
You can come over
if you want to study there.
Hung, l just want to fulfill
my dream as soon as possible.
My dream is studing
in Beijing... with Sung.
Be careful.
Hi!
l wish you will fulfill your dream
for studying in Beijing very soon.
l will leave after X'mas,
keep in touch.
Bye.
Merry X'mas.
Happy?
How are your old classmates?
They are fine, they told me
to send you their regards...
Did Hung send me
his regard too?
You are jealous.
There is nothing between us.
That is fine, it would be
terrible if you do.
You are jealous.
Just take me as l am jealous.
What's up to you now?
What? l am fine.
Stop that.
l got nothing to do with this,
he held my hand so suddenly.
lt's okay.
You have come.
l've told you that l will.
Have a seat.
Why did you leave
so early that night?
Did that doctor give you
my phone number?
No.
What would you like to drink?
Apple juice, please.
OK.
Your girlfriend?
Yeah.
Having a quarrel?
Not quite just now but
l am not sure later on.
She is so cute.
But she will be terrible
as she lose her temper.
Apple juice.
l am gonna meet someone,
l have to go.
See you.
Leaving so soon?
Bye.
You said who is gonna
lose the temper?
That's not you.
Not me,
then you must have
another girlfriend.
l don't.
What's wrong with you?
You get mad as l went
to the gathering.
You went out with another
girl dishonourably,
can l get mad on that?
l went out for a drink
with Joe that night.
When?
The night of your classmates
gathering.
l told you everything
but you don't.
Hi, l am Fong Chi Ho.
l am not able to answer
your call right now,
Would you please leave
your name, number...
lf you not come back right now,
you needn't come back anymore.
Sent.
My leg is hurt.
Sing, what are you doing?
l am off.
Watch out, ...
You are maniac.
To go for rescue
Rescue? Rescue?
That's cool!
lsn't it too much, kid?
Firstly,
lt's not too much.
As l watched from outside,
l saw you lying
on the floor.
l don't know how much and
where you are hurt.
l went back to bring
everything here
to see whether it is gonna help.
Secondly, my name is Sing.
l am sorry, Sing.
You can just call me Yu.
Yu.
But why were you being
outside my gallery so late?
l think it's okay,
let me take you upstairs
to have a rest, tomorrow... ,
What are you doing?
Why did you touch
my girlfriend?
Who are you?
He is Sing, it's lucky to have
him here just now.
Where have you been?
l have been looking for you.
Thank you, Sing.
That's okay, you can go now.
Thank you.
l will treat you dinner,
l will order delivery more often.
Thanks you, Sing.
You really scared me, honey.
When l got your SMS,
l returned your call
But your cell phone is off and
l couldn't get through
the gallery line.
So l came back at once.
Yes, l did that purposely.
lf not,
you would only come back after
the share market is closed.
And l would probably be
crippled at that time.
l will take care of you forever
even if you are crippled.
Sing!
You are out for delivery
so early?
Yeah, the customer... doesn't
want the soup.
Maybe you can have it.
lt'd be useless even
if l bring it back.
Will your uncle get
mad on you?
What kind of soup is this?
Chicken feet with dog backbone
(Chinese Medicine).
Dog feet?
Chicken feet with dog backbone
(Chinese Medicine).
lt is good for the legs.
Will your uncle get
mad on you?
Thanks.
Okay.
See you.
Maybe,
lf you come next time,
l won't charge you.
lt's you?
Sung is not here?
l am not looking for him,
l came here for a drink.
What would you like then?
Cappuccino.
Okay.
Can l use the internet?
Be my guest.
l am Kelly.
l know, Sung has told me.
l am Ching.
l will go back to Canada
after two weeks.
We are almost done with our saving
on the tuition for studying in Beijing.
lt's bored to be alone on Sunday.
l am leaving.
l told you to give the phone number
to Sung, not you.
But you key in your number
in my cell phone.
You are so wicked.
Wicked? l forgot to give it
to Sung then l am wicked?
Not giving him the number
is not wicked.
But you peep on other's
information on the net,
that's rascal.
As l clicked on it and
that's the first page,
l am not doing it on purpose.
That's not an excuse.
Peeping on other's privacy
is a criminal offense.
lt would be great for you
two being in jail together.
Come and talk with me.
l treat you to meal.
Punk, here comes the soup.
Dog feet soup.
Dog feet soup? New stuff.
Come on in.
Come in.
Your leg is hurt.
Be careful...
Look!
Please be careful...
You fix that up.
This is Derek...
Derek Boman
ls he smart?
Having done all these
early in the morning?
You know nothing
about this.
l think his drawing
is a bit erotic.
You better watch out.
Maniac.
You just don't care about me.
Sorry.
lf there is anything,
just call me, okay?
lt's almost time for work.
Bye.
Ho, can you pick him up
at the hotel for me?
Too bad, the US stock market
is not stable.
l have to keep
an eye on that.
My leg is hurt badly,why don't
you keep an eye on that?
l always peep at you as you are
having a shower, my dear wife.
l am not your wife yet,
still one time to go, maybe...
No way, l really do, l...
Don't sing it anymore.
Go for work.
Miss Ng, your soup.
Thanks.
l will go inside to
get you the money.
Okay.
Mis Ng, you'd better not move around
as your leg is still hurt.
You guys are all the same.
Just a little sprain.
Thank you.
Miss Ng, why do you
want to be a painter?
l am not a painter.
l just like painting
so l open this gallery.
How about you? You are
so gentle to be a delivery boy.
ln fact my uncle
owns that restaurant.
He told me to help him
for l am not good at my study.
He is trying to train me
to behave well.
My parents had divorced
since l was small.
lt's my uncle who has been
taking care of me.
Do you have your own dream?
Do you really want to do the
delivery work for the rest of your life?
l do have my dream,
l want to be an artiste.
Want to be a star!
ls it?
No.
l just love singing, that's all.
you will understand it later.
Miss Ng.
Just call me get the bowl
back as you finish the soup.
Bye.
Sing, can you do me a favor?
Alright, what is it?
l suppose to meet
Mr. Boman
at 6:30 tonight...
at Mandarin Hotel.
But l can't go like this.
Can you help me
to bring him here?
But my English is lousy...
lt's okay.
Do you know mandarin?
He knows a bit mandarin.
That'd be alright.
6:30, at the lobby of
Mandarin Hotel.
A foreigner who speaks mandarin.
How's that?
Are you going to have dinner
with me tonight, doc?
Tonight? l have to work.
Yesterday, you said you will
treat me for dinner.
l will call you after
work tonight, okay?
l am Kelly, l am not able to answer
your call right now.
Dare you try to leave your message,
l won't call you back.
l brought him here.
Mr. Derek Boman,
l am Sandra
Please call me Derek.
Derek.
l have seen your work,
you are so very very talented.
Thank you.
Do you want to learn
it in UK?
UK? That would be great.
You understand what he said?
Sing, please go back first.
l am busy too.
l do drink a lot of red wine
when l work..
Red wine?
Okay, wait.
Sing.
Yes, what is it?
Can you do me a favor?
Buy a box of red wine
for me, please.
l have got some left,
just finish it first.
My friend will bring me
some very soon.
Sandra, you do have
an oriental sense.
Thanks.
You are very beautiful
Thanks you, Sing.
You...want to drink it up?
lt's okay,
you may go now.
You don't really know him,
it's bad for your health
to drink like that.
Stop that, kid.
l will give you the money tomorrow,
please go back.
Let's drink...
This one...
You...
You know what we should
do now?
You should... paint me.
Paint you...
Me, yes.
Okay, sure.
l go to...
l go to get the tools.
Yes, paint me
Hi, l am Fong Chi Ho.
l am not able to answer
your call right now.
Sandra, you must take
your clothes off!
We should do a nude
ls it?
Like me...
l am off from work,
now in Central.
Going to dinner, right?
Will that be too late?
lt is now eleven.
Do you want to eat or not?
Be quick, meet you at the escalator
on Hollywood Road then.
Okay, bye.
Why? Why are you crying?
Just a bit late, you don't
have to cry though.
Are you pregnant or
being dump?
Of course not pregnant!
My boyfriend broke up
with me..
Broke up? That is good,
you can have new one now.
How can you be so mean?
l really love him.
How long have you
been together?
We have been together
for over a year.
Though he is fat and ugly,
he is a nice person.
So l try to be with him then.
l can't imagine that
he would be so cruel to me.
Did he hang out
with other girls?
l've told you that
he is fat and ugly.
lt would be his luck to have me
as his girlfriend.
No other girls will be
interested in him.
Stop crying.
Let's go, l am going to
tell you a story.
Come on, let's buy something
to drink.
Let's go
Have a walk and have a good drink,
everything would be fine.
Trust me.
l have a friend,
he's been with his girlfriend
for a year and a half.
His girlfriend is expecting
to marry him.
But my friend was fed up
with their relationship.
And he finally broke up
with her,
do you know why?
Why?
He told me that
in ancient time,
if you don't bury
the body well,
the corpse will be rotten
and became harmful to others.
For love,
if you don't end
a rotten relationship,
you are going to hurt
your lover.
Love will turn into sympathy.
and it is just a waste
of time.
Sympathy is like the
rotten body,
it's gonna be harmful.
Where did your friend
hear this story?
l told him that.
You are very special.
Are you going to
recede this time?
You always do that?
Do you often bring
girls here?
What do you expect then?
You don't let me
take you home.
Feeling tired and
want to have a rest.
You did make a good choice.
l do, this place is nice.
Come on,
just bury your love then.
l won't.
lt's going to rot.
That's you.
Hey, doc, how is it?
How are you doing?
Did your eyes get swollen?
lt's alright.
Trainees should be busy though,
how can you make
your call so often?
Tomorrow is my day-off.
lt's just...
l want to treat you to dinner,
are you available tomorrow?
Are you going or not?
Whatever.
l will just count
you in then.
Tomorrow night at seven,
l will call you.
Who will call so late
at the night?
That's the Prime
Credit Brothers.
See you at seven.
Sorry, honey.
Last night,
the US market collapsed,
l don't have time
to take your call.
Are you alright?
lt's lucky that Sing
was here,
l have been looking
for you all night.
lt's that bastard again.
Haven't l done anything
for you?
You keep seeing him
so often.
Why is he keep hanging
around you?
As both of you got drunk,
did he try to screw you?
Would you mind your words?
You just care about
the market,
do you really care
about me?
Don't l?
l just want to tell you that
the kids now are quite mature.
Nonsense! l don't want to
talk about it.
l don't think l have time
to see you this week.
You check out the new
apartment on your own.
And don't hang around
with that kid.
Because you are my girlfriend
and l am your boyfriend.
Punk, somebody wrote on
our walls.
ls boss going to
blame on us?
Shouldn't be.
That's nice, never mind.
You guys are here.
l drank a lot last night,
can l have a coffee?
l got it...
Ching.
l have something to
tell you.
lt's the 99th time,
but l think...
l got it,
come on in.
Sung.
Sing.
lt's hot.
No one wants the
soup again?
Yeah, it's for you.
That's hot.
Miss Ng of the studio
doesn't want it..
What is it?
Ginseng with kudzu vine.
lt's good, it relieves
your hang over.
Ginseng with kudzu vine?
Alright, l will have it,
how much?
No need, enjoy it.
Thanks... honey,
here is the soup.
Ginseng with kudzu vine.
lt is good to your brian
and recovers my energy.
But it's hot, be careful.
You... drank a lot?
Sorry.
l don't know you will
bring me soup...
Maybe you order
a drink instead.
Okay.
Thanks for last night.
That's okay.
Are you free tonight?
What? l am free.
l would like to
have dinner with you.
Great.
Sir.
l help you with
the soup, okay?
Okay.
You always peep on us
outside the studio?
Well, l...
l like you.
Kid, do you know what
you are talking about?
Have you ever hate
your parents?
Why should l?
They separated without caring
about your feeling.
Don't you hate them?
l don't.
At least they separated
when l was small.
Otherwise,
l will be so upset.
l do think that once
people get married,
they shouldn't have
a divorce.
lf they do, why should
they get married?
You have seen my fiance.
What do you think
about him?
Your finace... is smart,
handsome and nice.
What? You want to
break up with him?
After last night incident,
l don't think
l need him anymore.
l need someone who really
loves me and cares about me.
And he will do
anything for me.
Yes.
He will care about me,
when l am angry with him
Bnd everything will be
back to usual soon
l do wonder that
if the stock market and
l are both in danger,
will he help me
out first?
Of course, he can't do anything
about the stock market.
Have you got
a make-up mirror?
What for?
Take it out.
Open it.
Put it on the table,
face to yourself.
Now you close your eyes,
imagine there is a devil
on your left
and an angel
on your right.
Which side will be
your fiance on?
After that, take the mirror,
you will have the answer.
Thanks, you are great.
l used to do this
whenever l am in trouble.
Hope you don't
find it stupid.
You have got the answer,
mabe l...
bring you to a place
to cheer up.
Where?
You will know
as you get there.
Mr. Yeung,
this way please.
Thanks...
Thank you for coming
to my show tonight.
Before you leave,
l give you guys a riddle.
You guys will get a nice pose
when taking photo,
that's a famous female.
Lovely queen.
No...
Sailormoon.
lt's not Sailormoon.
How about at the back?
Do you know the answer?
Wait.
Just stay here,
l will be back soon.
l have seen
a beautiful girl.
Hey! lt's you!
You come for the show?
But we are over.
Over?
lt's over.
l do charge you though.
You come to see me,
do you know who l am?
Handsome guy?
Handsome...
Dare you say that.
You still have to pay
even you say that.
lt's obvious that
she's not coming for me.
Well, here comes
our next performer.
Our in-house singer.
Sing!
You are really nice.
Thanks...
Can we take a picture?
Maybe next time,
my friends are...
l have another
show on 24th here.
Okay? See you then.
Bye.
You sang well.
And you do have
lots of fans.
l already said you
want to be a star.
Let's go.
l have a show on X'mas
Eve at 3am,
are you coming?
X'mas Eve? Okay.
Have you ever been
to my uncle's restaurant?
No, maybe next time.
Maybe l take you home.
Okay.
Will your boyfriend be there?
l don't think so,
we had a fight this morning.
Excuse me, Mr. Yeung,
we are about to close.
Check please.
l have a great time tonight,
thanks for accompanying me.
Thanks for taking me home.
Kelly, why are you
leaving so early?
Well, l have to meet
my friends in other place.
l have a fatal disease,
only you can help me.
l will wait for you
at the disco until you come.
Look at this,
it's interesting.
Yeah, maybe we should
draw something on it.
Do you have a pen?
Who is it?
l will call the police.
Let's go.
Come on,
t's been scrawled already.
Bro, don't touch my wall.
Your patient is recovered,
go out and have a walk.
Let's go...
Please, get going.
No way, it's getting worse.
ls it blackmail
by the triad?
Do you owe someone money?
Let's report
this to the police.
Go ahead. He said he would
call the police just now.
You'd better leave.
lt's just number,
not foul language.
But it does look like something
as you look at it carefully.
l have to go, you guys
look great tonight.
Bro, you look great...
You guys too...
Why are you here?
l told you
l always peep at you.
Don't you need to work?
Sorry, honey.
l know what l said that
day was too much.
l know l have been
neglecting you.
So l haven taken
a two-month leave.
And we can enjoy
the holiday.
Okay?
Did you put it on
for me?
lsn't it pretty?
Don't you know how to care
about other's feeling?
l do.
l am trying hard to
be a good boyfriend.
l have been working hard
for our future.
This is the...
Sorry, you can't give me
the thing that l want.
Just tell me what
you want then?
You tell me and
l will do my best.
This is the 100th
time proposal...
You promised me that you will
marry me, l do love you.
Ho.
That's not the point,
something is missing
between us.
Don't you understand?
Sorry. We are over.
Maybe we need some time
to calm down.
l am going to
work now.
l know l haven't been with
you for quite a while.
Would you please
give me a chance?
Please, okay?
As l came just now,
there was a soup and
a bunch of flower.
And l took them in.
Look, it's great.
Stupid! You still
said it's great?
We don't have much
saving this month.
Self-tour in Europe,
thirty thousand will do.
Did you hear what
l said?
l said we don't save much
at all for this month
and you are still
planning for a trip.
ln fact, since we can't save much,
let's have a trip then.
What the hell! We have planned
for a two-year saving.
This is the third year,
and the fourth year is coming.
You are not going to
graduate until thirty.
Business is bad and
that's not my fault.
Ask Hung
to help you out then.
We promised not to talk
about him again.
Okay, l am going to
call Hung now.
Hung.
l would like to go to Beijing,
please buy me a ticket.
Okay, when are you
planning to go?
24th, it's a good day.
Alright, l will fax you
the itinerary tomorrow.
Thanks, bye.
You go back alone.
Did you call him?
Did you do as
l told you?
l did, everything is done.
l've been role-playing that
l almost forgot who l am.
He is not that bad though.
Don't be soft-hearted,
he did the same
to me before.
He is bad,
he's a swindler.
He won't change.
Never.
Trust me,
he won't change.
Do you really like him?
No way!
Just help me to date
him out.
l want to fix him up
on X'mas Eve,
got it?
Yanka, l would like to
ask you a favor.
Joe, are you coming later?
l am having a headache.
Can you bring me
some pills?
And buy me some milk please.
Okay, thanks.
How are you doing?
Thank you.
Milk.
Your pills.
No need...
l don't have change.
That's okay.
Where is Kelly?
Over there.
Thank you.
My cousin has a wedding
party on 24th.
Are you coming?
Okay.
You don't have to go
if you don't want to.
l do, why not.
l will even take
a day off for that.
lt would be nice to get
to know your friends.
There is nothing special
about my friends.
lf you are busy, you really
don't have to go.
That's oaky,
l will go for sure.
Why don't you go inside
to eat?
l am not used to go to
place like this.
But you do order delivery
so often?
The food is really
good though.
You have to compromise
to something that you like.
Just take a seat to
enjoy your food.
Don't you need
to perform tonight?
l would rather stay
with you
l don't want to
be like Ho,
he cares nothing about you
but only about his work.
Can you stop comparing
with Ho?
What would you like,
Ho become more attentive or
l become more mature?
Do you understand
what l am saying?
We haven't talked
much since that night.
Maybe we are going too fast.
We don't know each other
that well?
l will work hard and l will
give you everything,
l will love you dearly...
l will find another job...
lf you like,
l will go back to study...
You are still young.
You are going to experience
different things
and people.
Since that night,
l know you are the one.
You are my destiny,
l won't like others.
You are going to have
different girlfriends.
Maybe you don't even remember
who l am whey you get older.
How would l...
l have been watching and
loving you for so long.
You just peeped at me.
That's not love.
What do you know, kid?
Sung, you are off already?
Yeah.
l just want to have
a chat though.
lf you don't mind,
we can chat here.
ls Ching here?
She left already,
you want to chat with her?
Sing.
l think l can't
help you today.
l just had a quarrel
with Ching.
But you can come back
in two days,
l am gonna help you.
Why are looking at
my stuff?
l am checking the name
and date for you.
l leave my luggage here.
l will come back
to take it.
Please don't touch that.
Should l give him
the painting?
l am afraid he will think that
l am teasing on him.
For not saving enough money
for studying in Beijing.
What's up to you guys?
l don't know
whether he has ever thought
about our future.
We are saving hard
for the tuition fee
and he just spent
it casually.
Here is your delivery.
Seventy five dollars.
Just call me get the bowl back
as you finish the soup.
Ching.
ln the past three years,
l have been so happy.
l am sorry
for my fooling around
and l forgot
about my promise.
l think l really have
to graduate after thirty.
But l do hope you can
fulfill your dream soon.
Here is the money
we have been saving up..
lt should be enough
for you.
Although you didn't say you
want to break up with me.
As l saw Hung holding
your hands,
and he bought the ticket
for you,
l know l am not good enough
he knows how to love you.
And the numbers is the song
that you like most.
l am going to sing
it to you again,
you can listen to
it when you get bored.
Study hard, my dear.
l don't have the chance to wait
for the blossom of our love.
l have been waiting
for your rescue.
Hoping that the fireworks
would last forever.
Making you feel insecure,
adoration will be fading away.
How long would
the appearance last?
Starting to surmise as suspicion arise,
it will soon be replaced.
You do care about
my seldom applause.
You sing really well.
Santa Claus is going
off duty.
Let's go for the
X'mas carol.
Do you think she
will come, boss?
Definitely,
have you ever heard...
if you believe,
everything is impossible.
l think she is in Beijing now.
You even know Santa
Claus is in Beijing?
l mean Ching.
Ching? Beijing?
Aren't you two going together?
l... don't have enough money.
What are you doing
here then?
Waiting for Ching.
You said she is Beijing?
l wrote some shorthand
code on the wall.
l told her to go to the place
where we first met on X'mas Eve.
lf she sees that,
she will come.
You guys have a quarrel!
How do you know she can
read your code?
We've learnt that when
we were small.
When you were small?
Should everyone know what
you are thinking about?
You are just doing the things
that you like,
did you care about others?
Codes, signs?
You ask for it.
What is it?
Maybe l shouldn't go in, huh?
Why? We are at the door.
lt's not going to
be fun though,
l just want to be with you
on X'mas Eve.
Never mind, just leave the gift
then we go, okay?
Come on.
ls it here?
l am telling you,
your X'mas wish...
is going to be fulfilled,
you are gonna lose it.
Sad?
Couple, got it?
Can you take it?
lt's tough.
You hate long hair?
l can cut it.
l found a beautiful
gal here.
A beautiful girl must have a lot of
things to do on X'mas eve.
l don't.
Do you recognize me?
But Sing is not here yet.
Are you going to sit here
and wait?
Yes.
Give her a big hand then.
Thanks, merry X'mas.
Joe.
Why are you so late?
You look great tonight.
Thanks.
Kathy and Rachel,
you know them.
Haven't seen you for long.
Who is your cousin?
Joe, l have something
to tell you.
What?
Listen, our passion is gone.
And our love will soon
transform to sympathy.
lt'll be getting worse.
Now you know what
l felt that day.
You deserve this.
l almost forgot,
l have a X'mas gift for you.
A doctor trainee sells illegal drugs in the disco.
Ching.
Why are you crying alone
on X'mas eve?
Have you seen my honey?
Honey? Me?
Sung, he has left.
He did not.
He told me that he left
already in his recording.
He did.
No, Santa Claus won't lie.
You are really rush.
Where is he?
He told you to study,
he really cares about you.
Why should you find him?
Studying is good.
Uncle, you don't understand.
Studying alone is meaningless.
Please tell me
where is he?
Studying alone is meaningless.?
How romantic!
Come on, where is he?
lt's all on the wall,
look it up yourself.
Why did you hiy me?
What did he write?
Have you learnt that before?
That's shorthand code.
The romantic place,
the first X'mas Eve, we...
Kelly...
l am sorry, l don't know
it'll turn out like this.
All of them said you are bad,
so l helped them.
l do know that
you know Maggie.
Prime Credit Brothers
told me that.
We have been together
for year and a half,
how couldn't l recognize
her voice?
Why did you come then?
l did cheat you,
but l know nothing
about the magazine.
l don't care.
Every couple would keep
their own secrets, right?
As long as the love
is true will do.
No one knows about the future.
But you are the one that
l have been thinking of.
l will go back
to Canada tomorrow.
Sorry.
So many things
happened lately,
it's not going to settle
that in one day.
Don't you need to perform?
l don't have the mood
to sing though...
l don't want to go.
Sing, who do think you are?
Even a superstar should be
responsible to his fans.
Come on.
Have you ever thought
of your loved one?
No matter what,
you can share your feeling
with her?
Didn't you leave already?
No way!
lt's for you.
Why are you holding a broom...
To hit Hung
So easy to get angry?
Let me give you a kiss.
Sorry, honey.
Who would dare to
let you choose now.
Or l am just pretending for
l am too nervous.
Be brave and
date you for lunch.
Although l am not
smart enough,
l dare to make my move
at once.
l will buy you flowers and
l will do my best.
l am sorry for what
happened last time.
lt's for you.
This wedding is real.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
Yes, did the medical board
check you up?
lt's over now,
l did nothing at all.
l became so popular
in the hospital now.
That's great, girls
will approach to you.
l should say sorry to you.
l will handle well
with my love,
it won't be that messy again.
Well, Kelly will be
my bridemaid.
You better handle that well.
Come earlier on that day, bye.
Bye.
How is it, gal?
You have been coming here
everyday in this month.
Just looking at the soup menu
without order anything.
What kind of soup
do you like?
l stop peeping at you.
You don't have soup lately,
you look bad.
Just drink it up.
What soup is this?
Soup with Lotus seeds and Lilies.
Just drink it up.
What is it?
ls there thief or cockroach?
The phone!
You just answer it.
Maybe it's calling from Hung.
He is your friend.
He must be looking for
you then.
You answer it.
l have something
to tell you
Please hold on.
You can talk now.
l want you to
come to Beijing.
For what?
We have enough money
for studying in Beijing.
Okay, it's just business.
Don't get too excited,
l told my father...
about the counselling cafe
you run in HK,
unfortunately...
He likes this idea.
He would like to have one
in the hotel.
He said it would work,
what do you think?
We have to think about it.
Still need to think?
We made it.
We can use our saving to go
for a Europe tour.
Then we have to learn Mandarin
before going to Beijing.
Okay.
She lied to me.
l like her as l first saw
her in the disco.
She lied to me though.
lt seems that you first
lied to my cousin.
l am serious
in every romance.
And it just doesn't
work out at last.
She lied to me though.
in fact, love can't be...
Counted.
No need to count, and...
Let me.
You go ahead!
Tell me when did you
start liking me?
You didn't like me on the first
night we met at the disco.
l did see you are flirting
with another girl.
That's not me for sure.
l am going to
tell you that...
it's not important that
who cheats in love.
lt is not important for
when did it start.
Do you love him?
When should l call you?
No one knows
about the future.
But you are the one
l have been thinking of.
Do you love him?
That's perfect
No such word in madarin?
Wrong again!
l like someone but
l am afraid that...
How many relationships
have you ever had?
l don't remember.
Why don't you have
the courage to love?
l am older than him and
he thinks that l am more
educated and richer than him.
Don't you know him?
Of course l do
Actually you know me too.
He is now 21 and
l am 27.
Both we are young,
there'd be fine.
But after twenty years,
he is only 41 and l am already 47.
Another thirty years, you are
77 and he also will reach 7 1 .
l think you guys
shouldn't worry too much
about your future.
Otherwise
you will keep worrying about
your future endlessly.
lt would be wise to enjoy
the moment you are
with him now.
Although l don't understand,
we are going to keep
our love forever.
Cheers.
=DS=