What do you think about 'love'?
About love?
What? To care for one another?
Oh, I knew it.
It's when you realize that someone likes you.
Huh? So it depends on your partner, and not your feelings?
She is going out with two guys now.
Wow!
No, no!
So, do you really have two boyfriends?
It's pretty lonely having just one boyfriend.
Don't you think so?
Then which guy do you like better?
I can't choose right now.
Oh, my!
A tempting girl huh?
No, it's not that I can't choose right now.
I just don't know how to make the choice.
Why don't you ask the two guys to live together?
All three of you.
Isn't it hard to love two people at the same time?
What does it mean to 'love' someone?
Did you go to the sea this summer?
No.
No. Did you?
Ah, yes.
I spent my whole summer at sea.
Oh, I envy you.
I wanna go too.
You're not really suited for the sea.
Eh? It is that unpleasant?
You're like "Miss Christmas".
I just found this here.
You should say something about this dress.
So, you like Christmas, don't you?
Not really.
What did you do last Christmas?
Last year?
What did I... do...
What will you say if I say that I came here last year too?
It's ok.
So did I.
Are you serious?
I'm kidding.
No, you should close your eyes.
Why?
Just close your eyes.
Didn't you do something like this when you were a child?
No, it's my first time.
OK. You can open your eyes now.
Wow.
Merry Christmas.
What? All these...
Yes, it's all of yours.
I didn't know what you'll like.
Oh, I see...
Thank you so much!!
Suzuko,
I haven't got a Christmas present for you.
Sorry, but I didn't think Christmas is that special.
Never mind.
Now we're enjoying the Christmas together. That's enough.
I see.
I was just happy that you asked me for a date.
Look at this.
I've got a tattoo on my back.
What? Is this real?
Yes. It won't disappear whether
I take a bath or if you lick on it.
This is good for a wound.
You're completely into Christmas.
It suits you.
Don't it?
Here. You have to open these quick.
These will disappear when the candles burn out.
They will disappear?
Yes, they will.
Your parents said the same to you, didn't they, Sou?
I was the only child,
so I could get as many presents as I want.
Like this?
It is close.
Your dad and mom must have thought
a lot about what to buy for you.
Not as much as I did today.
Come on, open it.
Otherwise these will disappear.
Have you finished tanning?
Not yet.
Finished?
No, not yet.
I thought...
Maybe you won't come today.
Why?
I just felt so.
Do I look like...
No, it's just a problem about myself.
Wow wow, wa wa wait...
Are you thinking to finish it quickly?
Stop it.
I'll get it.
Hello, I've come to deliver your pizza.
What?
Oh,
Sorry, my apologies.
Poor thing.
What about?
The delivery girl.
She's working on this day,
and coming to the hotel alone for delivery.
That sucks.
What are you doing?
I gotta make a phone call.
Phone call?
To my family
in the countryside.
I gotta say Merry Christmas to them.
I'll wait for you at Hotel 555 room No. 304.
You can call here.
It's embarrassing to have someone listening to me
when I am talking to my family.
How do you feel being alone in a lovehotel?
Eh?
And more so, on Christmas day.
Um... it's sad.
Yeah, it's sad.
Wanna take a photo?
You can open anything.
It's all for you.
Ok.
To say the truth,
I was worried that you may not come today.
Why?
When I asked you,
you seemed to be considering a little bit.
I didn't have much time.
It was already Christmas when I asked you.
That's nothing...
I was spending Christmas all alone till this year.
Really?
Yeah.
I was working last Christmas.
I see.
I'm glad to hear that
You're such a cute girl.
I thought you already have someone to spend the day.
I was little worried.
No, I don't.
Oh, I'll get it.
Have you ordered pizza...
Oh.
Something happened?
Suzuko?
I was really working till this year.
on Christmas...
I was delivering pizza on Christmas like that girl.
Suzuko...
I just didn't want to be alone on Christmas.
I hate to be alone.
on Christmas...
I won't leave you alone.
I'm sorry.
Dear Kosuke,
You were sleeping so soundly,
and I didn't want to wake you up, so I went home.
See ya, Suzuko.
Dear Sou,
You were sleeping so soundly,
and I didn't want to wake you up, so I went home.
Thank you for the lovely presents.
Love, Suzuko.
Give me a little bit of that too.
If I could...
I wanna eat you.
My love could make me eat you,
I love you so much.
Looks yummy.
Yeah, it does.
Hello?
Hello, oh it's you, Sakura?
Yes, it's me. Misaki?
Of course it's me
It can't be the little one, can it?
No, I suppose not... Is Toru there?
Toru? Yes, he's here.
Hey why don't you come over
sometime instead of just calling?
We haven't got together since graduation.
Yeah, ok I will.
Anyway, are the cherry blossoms out over there?
Nope, not yet...
Hmm well,
we're planning on going over for a picnic,
so let me know when they're blooming.
You should come and see us this time.
You missed it last year, but no more! Got it?
Uh-huh
Oh sorry, I'll get Toru. Hang on.
Toru!
Hello, it's me.
You free today?
I can't today...
Toru, it's your birthday today, isn't it?
Yeah...
So for my birthday,
my family are going out for dinner.
I'm sorry.
No, no, it's OK.
Sorry, I have a customer...
ok I gotta go now.
Hi,
Do you have some cherries?
Do you want some cherries?
You can't right now.
It's not in season yet...
So when?
Maybe just before summer.
I know you want some right now,
but if you really want some, you have to wait.
So,
Be patent , don't rush.
You made me come after all...
Why isn't daddy here? It's his birthday!
Daddy couldn't come home. He has to work.
Why?
It happens sometimes.
Why does it happen?
Because daddy's a grown up.
Hmm.
It can't be helped.
Let's go get something nice for dinner, just the two of us.
Only the two of us?
Well, I already made the reservation.
This is a special present for you.
We can't get them all the time, so I froze them.
When I want some so much that I just can't wait,
I melt them to eat.
Don't chew... Not yet...
Yes,
Take your time... Slowly...
Let it melt slowly in your mouth.
Now it's OK. Go on.
Daddy! Mommy, look! It's daddy!
No way.
Really, it's daddy. Over there.
Where?
Sorry.
If I could...
I wanna eat you.
Maybe we shouldn't meet until things calm down.
I'm OK.
Leave me alone for a while.
when you...
want to meet me again, call me.
I'm sure that you will call me again.
But I wonder how long it'll be.
Three months? One year?
Maybe you won't call me ever again.
That's ok... just when you want to meet me.
I've been patient.
I'm just waiting for the season again.
I'm sure that you will give me a call... definitely.
Because, I could not live anymore if you don't.
If I could,
I wanna eat you.
My love could make me eat you.
I love you so much.
Sometimes, you get really passionate because
you don't know much about your partner.
Yeah, that happens sometimes.
Some people just have sexual relationship, and that's all.
Hello? You're just sitting there smoking.
but I know about all your relationships.
Wow you have that kind of relationships?
Yeah. there are girls that I can have good sex with.
I mean sex is like your instinct. You can't resist it.
So you don't try to control yourself?
Why do I have to control myself?
Wow! That's wonderful.
Nice!
Didn't you ever feel like you love the girl.
Or like you want to go out with the girl?
So, for you, it's always like having sex, feel ecstasy,
And that's the end of it?
Don't you ever feel like that?
No, I don't.
What? by sex?
Oh, I know what you mean.
So, if you never find another girl that you really like,
then your partner is always your sexual companion?
Maybe you won't break up with your sexual partner
even if you find somebody else?
Because you get along so well sexually?
Maybe I won't.
Please. Make love to me just like you do all the time.
Sachi.
Sachi!
It's OK, so just do it!
Taku has been a good friend of mine for a long time,
But I guess he's more than a friend to me.
I thought you were here.
You come back so suddenly.
You angry?
When are you gonna go away next time?
I knew things would turn out this way
Taku and I made love, desperately,
so many times throughout the summer.
Just like we did a long time ago.
2 months later
Wow. It's finally here, huh? Took a long time, didn't it?
Not that long.
Really? The summer's almost over.
It's almost two months since you came back here.
Whatever. I was pretty demanding on the colors.
Well, yeah. That color is really great.
Where did you take that picture?
This? Cayman Islands in the Caribbean.
Cayman Islands. I wish I could dive there, too.
How long were you there, Taku?
About three years, this time.
Wow. That's too long!
You should go there, too.
I want to...
but I can't take pictures like you.
And...
I don't think this is such a bad place after all.
I'm sorry! I'm a little late.
OK then! Let's get going!
I'll catch up with you guys later.
I still have some pictures to put up on the wall.
You need help?
Don't worry. Go ahead.
Well, OK. Give us a call later.
All right.
Sachi, let's get going.
The fireworks will start pretty soon.
Ah... OK.
What exactly is our relationship?
Lovers?
Friends?
Sexual companion?
I was watching what Taku was watching.
I was feeling what Taku was feeling.
We were not fnends.
We were not lovers, either.
I just wanted his existence and the assuring touch of his body.
This boundlessly uncertain relationship between us continued.
The touch of his body kept controlling me.
Why is Taku taking so long?
You're right.
I'll run over and take a look.
Wait here, Sachi, OK?
OK.
I realized that 70% of the world around me was dominated by
the touch of Taku's body and what I got from him.
Just like 70% of the Earth is dominated by the ocean.
Taku, please...
Inside of me...
Please come inside of me...
What? What's wrong?
I'm sorry...
What? Taku?
I can't do this.
Taku?
I'm sorry... I can't do this.
Why? What's wrong?
I'm in love with another girl.
What? What are you saying?
Since when?
Before I knew it...
Before you knew?
I don't know.
OK! I just found myself in love with her!
So you were thinking about her
when you were sleeping with me?
She is always on my mind recently.
Taku, this is great!
You take really beautiful pictures.
Not that great.
This is the first time we talk like this,
just with the two of us.
Normally, other people are in the shop at this time of the day.
What a coincidence, huh?
It's not a coincidence.
Did you sleep with that girl already?
No I can't do such a thing with her.
Why?
Come on, tell me why!
Why can you sleep with me, but not with her?
If nothing happens between us,
then there will never be an end to us.
What the hell!
I'm really scared.
I'm scared if she would love me forever.
Then what about me?
You had sex with me so many'times!
Having sex with you was really good.
I'm serious.
Then why? What's wrong with it?
This is crazy! I just can't understand this!
I can't understand it either.
I don't know what the hell I should do!
You love the girl so much?
Yeah, I love her.
I love her so much that it feels like there's a pain in my heart.
What's going on!
I don't know what to do.
What...
I have never been in a serious relationship before!
Even with you, I just suddenly found myself in such a relationship.
I'm sorry.
I was just scared. I've never felt like this before.
Don't apologize.
Why now?
Taku was afraid to see the end of his relationship with another girl,
a relationship that hasn't even started.
And he tried to run away from it.
But... that's me.
Oh, you're back. Where's Taku?
I think you should stop seeing Taku.
But we're not really...
How long are you gonna do this?
Why can't you make it a true relationship?
You know, Sachi, you can't be happy like this.
You should stop seeing him.
Can't I be the one for you?
I've always loved you.
I will definitely make you happy.
Then...
Please make me forget him.
Please! Make me forget Taku!
I promise I'll make you happy.
I'll make you happy...
Don't you have to answer it?
You'll talk to Taku about us right?
Hello, Taku?
Please don't.
Sachi is with me now.
No!!
Here? We're in a hotel, now.
Yuji! Dont!
So please break up with Sachi...
No!!
Sachi...
Don't you dare do things like this!
Sachi, you really love Taku so much...
Leave me alone.
Sachi...
Leave me alone!!
I really really loved you Sachi.
But I guess I should forget it.
Hello... Taku...
I want you to come here right now.
Right now!
Nothing started between us, but let's end it.
You'll be fine, Taku.
You should go ahead and go to her place.
And you should start a real relationship.
And you will be happy...
And she will love you so much...
and I will find someone who...
Why am I crying?
For just one second,
I felt the scent of his skin.
Taku...
I really love you.
Sachi? Are you sure about it?
Yes, I am!
You serious? Really?
Come on! I'm saying YES, aren't I?
I know what's going on.
But it's the first time for me...
It's the first time for me too...
I'm just fine with it as long as it's Taku.
Well, then let's put it this way,
Taku and I are sexual companions!
Then we don't have to care too much, right?
Sexual companions?
Yeah, just friends having sex.
Ah, he's here!
Come sit here!
please, come on ,come here!!!
Don't bother.
So, what were you guys talking about?
Ah, you took a lot of pictures!
Wow, you go right into the subject.
Oh, I'm not interested in those kinds of girls.
Oh, yeah! You gotta be kidding!
I heard you play with a lot of girls, Haruki.
My body just doesn't react to those kinds of girls.
Are you sexually impotent or something?
No way. I'm just saying that having sex isn't equal to making love.
Having sex is just simply having sex.
What did you say? What do you mean by making love?
Making love is...
like developing true love for someone.
Like, she's the only one for me.
Maybe like a twinge in your heart?
Ah that's pretty close.
A twinge in your heart.
And then you have hard on
What?
So it's like a twinge in your heart, right?
Are you serious?
I really think that making love is how having sex should be.
Now that's the real sex.
There is a "love hotel" in my town.
This is the one and only "love hotel" in my town.
So everybody knows about it.
And my house is just behind this "love hotel".
Actually, this "love hotel" was built in my house's backyard.
Well, in other words,
my dad is the owner of this "love hotel", which pisses me off.
Today, my dad died.
My mom passed away a long long time ago.
Miss Ai, we are truly sorry for your loss...
But we don't have the time to wail over your father's loss.
Couples in this world will keep developing their love
no matter what happens, 24/7, 365 days a year.
No holidays exist in the world of love!
Therefore, we must keep operating our "love hotel".
From now on, Miss Ai, the daughter of the deceased...
Miss Ai!
It is the dying will of your father!
When I die, Ai will manage my love hotel.
You gotta be kidding...
Yes, the coupon card is inside the convenience box.
You can use it from next time.
Yes. Thank you very much.
Phew...
Yes, I think you're picking it up, Miss Ai.
You have to learn the front line cutting edge.
I know how to do it...
Hmm That is an unforgivable remark!
Just because you learned a little bit about your job,
that doesn't mean that you have learned about the front line.
Then what do you mean by learning the front line?
Let's put it this way... to know more about the people here.
"Learning the front line" is to "know more about the people".
I don't give shit about other people's sex life.
Wow...
How come there are so many people having sex
at this time of the day?
What are they doing for a living?
What kind of people come here at such a time?
Ai! Oh, please! Please don't say anything to the school!
Don't worry I won't say anything.
Your homeroom teacher was here yesterday, too.
Don't worry.
Oh my... Urasaka?
Hi, Teacher.
Why are you...
This is my house.
Oh please, Urasaka. Don't say anything to the school!
Thanks toots.
Hey, toots.
How much?
One hundred million.
Ewww...
Hey, watch me closely, OK?
Come on, let's do it! Quick!
Yes!
Hey girl, getting excited, huh?
I've always loved you so much!
Getting harder!!!
I'm coming!! I'm coming!!
Come on, give me more!!
Why is everybody having sex?
I used to come here and have sex all the time.
With a different girl, every time.
All young guys are like that.
And then, one day, I got into this huge trouble.
Some people are really strange,
and this one girl really, really fell in love with me.
But, for me, it didn't mean anything.
And I was still doing bad things.
I guess she couldn't forgive me.
She started saying she's gonna die right away.
And, you see that window?
She tried to jump off from that window.
Oh my God!
I tried to stop her immediately,
but she just kept yelling and crying.
And this whole hotel was in a huge fuss.
The employees and everybody, they just gathered around her.
Your dad took me to the office
and gave me this big lecture all night long.
What did he say?
He asked me if there is "love" in my sex.
What?
You see, he told me that he feels sorry for the girl
if I'm having sex without real love.
Which is quite right.
Having sex is a loving action between a man and woman.
In English, you say "having sex" is to "make love", right?
To "make love" is to have sex!
Hmmm.
It really got to me.
Sounds cool, doesn't it?
No way.
Yes it is cool.
He said these embarassing words to me
without getting embarassed!
Not many people can do such a thing!
And then I found myself asking him to allow me to work here.
Huh?
From that day on, I promised myself
that there is nothing but to "make love".
Wow.
"Making love".
It just sounds wonderful.
Hmm? From that day on?
Two years? No, three?
This is bad. This is getting real bad.
What's bad?
I haven't had sex for three years!
Oh is it?
This is bad. This is getting real bad.
Well, then why don't you have sex with somebody?
No way!
Why?
Because...
I've got a crush on a girl.
If I'm the only one in love, then it wouldn't mean
"making love" with each other, right?
So I'm just waiting for the day to come
when we are in love with each other.
Just the way it is.
Just about a year has passed since my dad passed away.
Which means that it's about a year
since I started working at the "love hotel".
I've always thought that a "love hotel" is
a place for men and women to have sex,
but I guess there's more to it.
There are various types of people in this world.
Some people make love by having sex,
but some people don't.
Hey, Mr.! Is there anything wrong?
Would you please open the door?
What's going on?
Miss Ai!
We haven't been able to get in contact with
the customer here for more than a day.
Open the door.
Right away!
Miss Ai, please go ahead!
Please go ahead!
Please!!
Some people find pleasure in things other than sex.
You didn't see anything did ya?
You really didn't see anything, did ya?
But these cases are really rare.
Basically things are the same and
people are having sex all the time.
It's just unbelievable how people are having sex all the time.
Very long. Too long.
In English, to "have sex" is to "make love"
and it is an action of loving each other
between a man and a woman.
Because I was born in such a family,
I just didn't like the thought of having sex.
and couldn't understand what "making love" was.
What in the world is going on?
Senior Mitsuru!
Senior Mitsuru's next target must be Miss Urasaka.
Oh my God! Unbelievable! Give my virginity back to me!
What? You too?
Ai you don't look so cute at first glance.
especially to a guy like me, the school body president.
But I think you'll look really good
if you took your glasses off.
OK, then,
I think you'll look really cute.
OK, whatever.
You look cute with your glasses on, too.
Intelligent, talented in sport, extremely handsome,
and serving for everyone as the school body president...
Will you go out with me?
Ah, you will, won't you?
No, I won't.
I'm not interested in you.
I'm intelligent, talented in sports, extremely handsome,
and serving for everyone as the school body president...
Oh, My Lord! Am I being dumped?
I still find myself unnatural
when I think about making love,
or in fact when I even think about men and women.
Ai, you're a virgin, aren't you?
Don't tell me... Not even a kiss?
Yeah, yeah, yeah... I'm almost a college student,
but still haven't experienced anything.
What can I do about it.
Fucking Dad!
Bon appetit!!
Yes?
One Soba, please!
Yes, I'll bring it to your room right away.
Hey, Haruki!
Can you bring Soba to the customer?
Hey? Haruki?
OK, then
You don't know how to eat this, do you?
Where's your mom?
There's my mom.
Most people will find it tiring
when you keep seeing these kinds of things with your own eyes.
There are, of course, a lot of happy men and women as well.
And these people are having sex all the time.
And these happy faces.
Am I ever that happy?
When I see these people in front of me,
I just feel uncomfortable.
It's like, seeing someone solving formulas
with sine and cosine really quickly
It's like, something I can't understand
but people in the world take it that way.
To be honest, I envy that kind of person.
Maybe just a little bit.
But...
Come on everybody! "Have sex and become happy!"
Have sex and become happy.
Let's fly up to the blue sky!
Now happier!
Have sex and become happy.
Fly up to the blue sky!
I just can't solve this formula.
Excuse me, Miss?
My son wanna say thanks to you.
Ah, yes.
Hey, come here for a second.
Face this way just a little bit.
This was my first kiss.
Yeah, it was from a kid...
But I guess kissing isn't that bad.
Next, Ai Urasaka.
Solve that problem on the board.
Bring more drinks someone! Drinks!
OK, I got it! So who said you can throw things?
Oh my god!
I gotta go pee!
Bathroom's over there.
So where's our food?
I'll bring some food later, OK?
Oh shit.
Wow. Miss Ai,
you look really beautiful today. Ho ho!
Ah! I found ya, Haruki!
Oh! Hey, Tomomi!
I've always thought that you're quite charming!
Let's do something exciting!
Oh no! Please don't! Tomomi!
I'm not that different from usual.
No, no. You look so quite different today, Ai.
Ah! Two fried noodles, please!
Ai is gonna come!
Come on, don't be such a hard-head!
Oh, I want you to be hard here though!
It's already hard!!
Well, then!
I know everything you've done with many girls
you know.
Tomomi! I quit doing that kind of things!
Why?
Are you in love with somebody, or something?
YES!
Don't worry. That doesn't matter to me at all!
Hello? Are you listening to me?
OK I got it!
No, no, stop it. I wanna make love but not with you, Tomomi.
Watch out!!
*gasp*
Haruki... What are you doing?
Ai... Why are you dressed up today?
Why am I dressed up?
Is it wrong for me to dress up?
I have to tell you I didn't do this for you OK?
I did not dress up for you, OK?
I didn't even dress up or anything!
I am just as usual!
I think you have the wrong idea!
I didn't say anything like that...
I didn't say anything like that either...
What? What are you saying?
AHHH! SHUT UP!
I'm sorry, I have to go.
Bye, Tomomi?
Ai! I think there's a misunderstanding!!
Good for you! I guess you found somebody to make love with.
No, it's nothing like that!
You have lipstick all over you!
This is really stupid!
You suck!
She's the one who put this all over me!
It's nothing like that
Nothing like that?
Ah I see. It's just having sex and not making love.
Ahh! NO!!
You just want to have sex after all!
No, that's wrong! Please listen to me!
You're the one that I love!
I will never have sex with you!
I didn't say anything about having sex...
Ah
Hey, veteran?
Yes?
Why do girls get so angry all of a sudden?
Ho ho ho! I guess you still don't understand women.
Understand women?
Women are as fickle as autumn weather.
Very fickle, they are.
That's why?
Asking why doesn't solve anything, you know.
What? Then what should I do?
Just a little thing can turn into sunshine
and just a little thing can turn into rain.
Veteran...
I don't understand what you're trying to say.
If you want to be in a good relationship with a woman,
A bit of gentleness will be very important.
Gentleness?
For example,
Don't you ever forget her birthday,
Christmas, and other anniversaries!
That is so foolish.
From a man's point of view it may seem quite foolish.
But, if you buy a bottle of wine and some flowers
and give a word of appreciation to your girlfriend...
She will be moved by such small ceIebrations.
Are you sure?
I'm sure about that.
Yes. Just like a ray of sunshine,
a bright smile will appear on her face.
Oh.
Well, I should be going now.
I have something important to do.
Tomorrow is an extremely important day...
What? What about tomorrow?
You know it, don't you?
It's the first anniversary for Miss Ai.
Hotel Completion Anniversary
- Papa & Mama & Ai -
Hi Ai! It's me! Your daddy!
I guess I must be dead by now,
now that you're watching this film.
Long time no see!
Well, now that you're watching this film,
It means that tomorrow is the 1st anniversary
since you took over this "love hotel".
I believe you're working quite hard.
I really want to thank you, Ai.
But sometimes, you try to take all the
responsibilities and have a hard time.
Don't force yourself too much.
Well, maybe your boyfriend is cheering you up now!
Wow! You cutie pie!
That has nothing to do with you...
Did you see mom and dad kissing? Lovely, huh?
I was able to survive because of your mom.
Well, I just wanted to say that you can be happier than ever
if your loved one is beside you.
So, be good to your boyfriend. With tons of hugs and kisses.
Huh? You understand that?
Tomorrow is the first anniversary...
Ai! Banzai!
Ai! Well done!
You've worked hard, Ai!
This sucks.
I can't go down from here.
Haruki!
Hey, Haruki!
We just had an order...
Where the hell is he?
Long. Too long.
Haruki! He must be sleeping again.
Haruki!
Hey, Haruki!
Happy anniversary, Ai!
Eh?
Well, Ai, you've been working here for a year
and today's the first anniversary, so...
Thank you.
Uh-huh.
Eh... Was that your first kiss?
Not exactly the first...
But the second one was...
A lot better than the first one.
In this kind of situation...
Yeah?
Do you feel that you want to sleep with me?
Ah, yeah...
Of course I do.
Desperately?
Desperately.
Are you trying to control yourself?
Well, I guess I'm trying to.
Do you remember how much it
is to spend a night in this room?
You don't have to go too far, you know.
Um... I know.
We'll just go step by step.
Yeah, step by step.
We have a long night ahead of us.
Yeah.
Just get undressed and it makes your heart twinge.
So will your girlfriend.
Are you sure about that?
Really?
I don't think so! Not so suddenly.
OK, OK. Hold on guys.
It's truly necessary. It's the ultimate.
It's truly necessary.
Even God...
Even God wants to see that kind of things... live.
Really? Do you think that God wants to see that?
Yeah, of course.
That's why human beings were separated into men and women.
Then Adam and Eve were pretty satisfying for God, I guess.
Really?
Adam and Eve.
So which one was Adam?
I think the guy is Adam.
So Adam...
Cut! OK!