My name is Vicky.
...Vicky...
I'm the son of Sudhirbhai;
the don of this city.
So, I do what I wish.
This is my friend,
Mahesh Goswami.
Nobody will raise their voice.
Get me?
The heir of the Goswami family.
And all these are my friends.
That girl is Mahesh's sister
Reema, my girlfriend.
Today is Mahesh's birthday.
Why aren't you singing?
Why should I sing?
-Speaking in English, eh?
What's he speaking?
- English!
What will he be speaking now?
He will bark like a dog.
- Come on, bark.
What are you doing?
Please leave him alone!
Ladies deptt...- Leave him.. he
made a mistake.
Bark like a dog.
Keep barking!
That chap there... See?
No, spare me. I'll take money
from Daddy for a V.C.R.
There's no excitement in that.
And we want some excitement.
How about my V.C.R.?
- You'll get your birthday gift.
Now watch the fun.
I'm a poor working girl.
I've got to take a bus.
Could you give me
change for 100 Rs.? - Sure
Here you are.
-Thank you- It's all right
Let me go! Please!
Leave me..
lf we take that money without
beating you up how...
...will we enioy ourselves?..
Fun and excitement!...
We have the money, too.
Isn't this fun, friends?
Eat something first! The
newspaper isn't running away!
Let Amit come.- What affection!
If he keeps sleeping the whole...
...day, will you keep reading the
newspaper?
It's better to be childless
than to have a son like him.
Amit has grown up, Shanti.
He knows the difference
between love and hatred.
Oh, leave it!
l am the one who has been...
...tolerating this useless fellow
for the last 15 years.
lf I weren't his step-mother,
l would've poisoned him by now.
Make him see sense.
He was born in a poor family.
He must live like the poor.
I'm not poor. I earn enough.
10000 Rupees a month.
Nor is Amit poor.
His grandpa has left him
a fortune of 2 lakh Rupees.
Go and wake up your brother,
Munni.- Very well.
Don't you dare move from there!
He will get the breakfast
only if he wakes up on time.
Or he gets no breakfast at all.
Okay?
Wake up at least now, son...
It's very late.
Come on, wake up. The tea's getting
cold. I've got to go to work.
Papa, you're here again.
- Don't be stubborn.
I've been asking for 2 minutes
from two hours.
But you aren't listening.- Wake
up. Don't be stubborn.
It's too late.
- Alright. Heat the tea.
You want hot tea?
I'll get it right now.
Here's some hot tea!
This is foul
- How's that?
You asked for hot tea
and I gave it to you.
Brush your teeth first.
Even tigers in the zoos
don't brush their teeth.
Really?
And what tiger are you?
I'm the tiger of the iungle
of your affection.
l brought something very
special for you last night.
What?
- First drink the tea...
...and I'll show you.
- Really?
Yes!
- So here I finish the tea!
Which is why I ask you to wake
up early every morning.
Where are you going?
Show the gift to me first!
Okay! First close your eyes.
Open them only when I say.
Did you like it?
It's the most beautiful thing,
after you.
What affection between
father and son!
Where did this cycle come from?
- From the market.
And don't worry. It won't run
faster than your tongue.
Squander all your money
on him!
Have your ever thought that
your daughter is growing up?
Mother! Am I growing up?
- Shut up!
Oh God! What sin
had I committed...
...that I became a stepmother
to this ill-fated boy?
Oh God! I don't want to live
anymore. Take me away!
C'mon!
- Leave me alone, mom!
She'll always be the same.
You'll go to the college
on your new cycle today.
Hey! Walk straight.
Great!
Let's go to the class.
I'm going.
Isn't he the same guy
of last night?
Yes! He is the one.
The chap from last night.
A new bicycle!
Shall I give him his bicycle?
- Yes!
- No!
No!
Shall I give him his bicycle?
-No...
Friends, shall I give his bicycle?
He's a new student.
Shall I give him his bicycle?
Shall I give his bicycle?
-No!
Friends! The little boy
will start crying.
Let me return his
bicycle to him.
Pick it up.
He's not picking it up.
Maybe he's angry.
But we had to teach him
a lesson.
My name is Vikram.
I'm the boss in this college.
My father is the
boss in this city.
The one who acts smart with me
gets destroyed like your cycle.
Remember this henceforth.
Sudhirbhai!
- Welcome, Mr.Goswami.
What brings you here?
- I wanted to talk to you.
The doctor anyway insists
on an evening walk.
l thought it was a excuse.
- Well?
Don't worry about him.
He is completely deaf.
The shipment has
Ieft yesterday.
The shares of the police and
politicians will go today.
As far as the M.P. Somnath
is concerned...
..we'll have to do
something about him.
Just assume that he is spent.
- What does that mean?
ln our parlance, it means
to bump off someone.
You've been my partner for many
days. And you aren't tough yet.
Why should you fear a dead man?
Think that I'm the agent of death
Tell me if there's anything else.
C'mon.
The other thing is that our...
Bless you, son.
- Son, tonight you are...
Not tonight, dad. Tonight we are
going to the disco.
So I'm calling up Reema.
My only son and your daughter
are getting on well.
l must leave now.
Reema, are we going to
the disco tonight?
Munni... where are you?
You've broken it, haven't you?
Nothing's safe with you!
Your father isn't so rich that you
can keep breaking things like this!
Are you listening?
You dimwit!
I'll teach you a lesson.
- Run!
Munni, hold the cycle.
Mother! Atleast listen to me.
Munni! Don't leave the cycle.
What's going on?
Where will you run?
- Papa, please protect me.
A new problem!
-Tell me what happened?
My head! Your son has broken
the new cycle worth Rs. 1200.
You've broken the cycle?
What happened?
Dad, now you don't
say anything.
Neither this is the world's
first broken cycle,...
...nor she is the world's
first mother who scolds.
Why don't you saystepmother'?
- Saystepmother' !
Don't laugh.
Ask him how it broke.
How did the cycle break?
You've broken a bicylcle
worth 1250 bucks!
Tell me how did it break?
What happened?
Last night some people
were beating up someone.
And I saved him.
Now you tell, is this cycle more
precious than a old man's life?
No, son.
You did the right thing.
A cycle is not more precious
than anybody's life.
Go on, enioy yourself.
Oh sure!
Your father has a treasure.
He'll get you a new cycle.
Go on!
Sing, dance, enjoy yourself.
And today you can dance
with anyone you want.
This evening is dedicated
to those...
...who love...
-Love,...love and love!
Leave me alone...
Don't you wish to stay alive?
l do, but only in love.
Then you'd even like to die.
- Yes! That too for love.
l see!
l want to live in love.
and die in love
Those who fear death
can never fall in love
l want to live,
in love...
and die, in love
Those who fear death
can never fall in love
l'd happily accept
the noose...
and offer my heart
for a bullet
And this what love
is all about
l want to live
in love...
and die, in love
Those who fear death
can never fall in love
Love, love, love!
l found love in you,
the first time I saw you
How will I ever forget you,
my love?
l don't care for
what the world says
l heed my heart
I've given you my heart;
I'll give you my life too
l found love in you
the first time I saw you
How will I ever forget you,
my love?
l don't care for
what the world says
l heed my heart
I've given you my heart;
I'll give you my life too
I'll accept every sorrow;
I'll play with the storms...
This is what love
is all about
ln love, I want to live
ln love, I want to die
Those who fear death
can never love
Love, love, love
Come, let's romance...
and dance like the waves
in the seas
Don't you go away...
don't leave me alone
How will I spend my time
without you
Come, let's romance
and dance like the
waves in the seas
Don't you go away...
don't leave me alone
How will I spend my time
without you
I will sing and
make you restless
This is what
Iove is all about
ln love, I will live
ln love, I will die
Those who fear death
can never fall in love
I will accept the noose
I will take the bullets
in my heart
This is love, love, love
ln love, we will live
ln love, we will die
Those who fear death
can never fall in love
Love, love, love...
Nobody dances with that girl
except me.
lf you are seen around her again,
I'll bash you up.
I'll give you such a punch that
you won't need bed tea tomorrow
Amit, you will be killed...
you'll surely get killed.
A murder is a game for Vicky.
Then why isn't he arrested?
- His father bribes the police.
And he gives lots
of money as donation.
He is an underworld don
of this city.
And Reema belongs to
the House of the Goswami's.
Her father Goswami and Vicky's
father are business partners.
Shut out all those fancy ideas
from your mind.
So that you don't even
think about Reema.
And there's no living and
dying in love with her.
There's only death with her.
C'mon.
Hitler had inaugurated the Berlin
Olympics with just one statement.
That I declare the
Olympics open!
But if I say this, the organizers
of the fair will feel bad ...
...that Sudhirbhai has
avoided saying something.
lf a leader or minister was invited,
he'd lecture on for atleast an hour.
My dear brother and sisters!
I'm not a leader or minister.
I'm an ordinary man.
l won't say much.
I'll only say that we ought to
cut the ribbon and open the fair.
Open Sesame!
Think again. - What's there to
think about?
l can't bunk college
for the picnic.
What are you saying, sister?
She wants to study.
- I'm not coming!
Amit Verma, come to
my office immediately.
Sit down.
Whatever Ms Goswami has told
you...I'm completely innocent.
What are you talking?
-Yes, sir!
ls there some tension between you?
- Yes, sir! - No...! - No, sir..
There's nothing of the sort.
We don't even know each other.
You will know each other,
of course.
Because it takes 18 hours
to travel to get there...
...and 18 hours to return and
stay there for another day.
l don't understand, sir...- On
Delhi TV's quiz time program...
...the two of you will
represent our college.
l?
- Yes!
When you had represented your
school in such a program...
...l had seen you on TV. You
were quick with your answers.
You gave such appropriate answers
to those 4 questions...
...whose answers
even I didn't know.
But without daddy's permission...?
- I've taken his permission.
He wanted to buy an air ticket.
But I didn't think
that would be right.
The college team must go
like a college team.
So tomorrow, the two of you leave
for Delhi by the Rajdhani Express.
Now for the last question of
this quiz time program.
Who is the greatest lover
of the world?
Team A -Romeo...
Team B -Mainu...
Team A
-Farhad.
Team D
-Me!
Reema left for Delhi last night.
- Don't tell me!
Why didn't you inform me
over phone?
How could I tell you?
We returned at 2 a.m.
l got to know when I woke up.
l didn't know either.
I'll go to Delhi then.
- Now what's the use?
The program must be over.
She must be preparing to return.
So who is your beloved?
She is yet to become my beloved.
Your beloved must be
the greatest lover, isn't it?
Sit on my mobike,
I'll give you a lift.
Come...
-No, thanks...Come on!
It's a beautiful moonlit night.
C'mon! Sit..
Didn't I say no thank you?
- Who asked you?
I've spoken to her.
Come and sit down.
Sit on my motorbike iust once.
How will I let you go
just like that?
Forgive me.
You wanted her to sit
on your bike, didn't you?
No!
- Why not?
This wish will surely
be fulfilled.
Not like this!
...like this.
Here's what you'll do.
Pick this motorbike from the gutters
of Jantar Mantar tomorrow.
And also take these skates.
l thought you were
just another boy.
So how do you find me now?
- I'll tell later.
l want to tell you something
before that.
What?
Hang on...
Come and sit with me
Listen...
to what my heart says
l love you
You are my love
Hang on...
come and sit with me
Listen to what
my heart says
Whenever I get the
opportunity to be with you...
l wish I could forever romance
with you throughout my life
The way you lovingly
talk to me...
it sounds like a love-song
When you walk with me...
it appears as if
the earth were dancing
l love you
You are my love
Wait... come
and sit with me
Listen to what
my heart says
l have walked through your lane,
all days and nights...
l waited for that
window to open
So I could have a glimpse
I will now live...
in your arms
every moment
Promise me your love...
You belong only to me
l love you
You are my love
Shall I throw a party?
- Go ahead!
Promise me that you'll come?
-Definitely!
The party is fixed!
At my house.
Come here.
You guys iust loaf around!
Cancel the swimming program,
we made for Sunday.
Why?
Reema is going to the party
with that fellow.
Hold this.
- Where is she?
She's in the canteen.
And don't grab my collar...
...deal with that guy!
So friends, the party
is fixed for Sunday.
I'll break your legs if
l see you sitting close to her.
She's my classmate.
I'll have to sit close to her.
I'll ...
- Now look, Vicky...
you can't behave like this
with my classmate.
I'll get your section changed
at any cost within 5 minutes...
...l am not my father's son.
As if the college belonged
to his father!
So the party is fixed?
- Will you come even now?
On Sunday at 4 o'clock.
Don't you know that you must seek
permission before entering my cabin?
What's the matter?
- I had come to ask you...
...to change the section of
Amit Verma, who's in F.Y.B.A.
Why?
Because I say so.
- Mind your language.
Dad, I'm talking from
the principal's office.
He's not doing
a small job for me.
Give him the phone...- My daddy
wants to talk to you.
I've heard a lot about you.
- That makes it easier.
No! It makes things difficult.
Because you haven't
heard about me.
Go on.
- I know that you are...
...the undisputed king
of the underworld.
But I don't belong
to the underworld.
l also know that you can
get me killed any moment.
But what you don't know
is that...
...you can't make me change
the section of any student.
Get back to your studies...-
That wasn't a nice thing you did.
You'll pay for this!
-Get out..
Johnny! -Yes, sir- Just find out
who is the chairman ...
...of the Managing Committee
of National College.
Dad
-Yes, son?
My friends want a party to
celebrate my victory in quiz time.
Sure. Have a party then.
- Before that...
...I'll have to get them insured.
- Why?
You know how Mom loves
chewing on people's brains.
Don't worry about her.
I'll take her to break
your uncle's marriage alliance.
To break his marriage?- He
wants to have a love marriage.
And you know how strongly
your mom is against love.
At what time is your party?
- At 4 p.m.
I'll take her out
at 12 o'clock.
Now what?
- Well...
Here you are.
Where are you going?
No! Not now...
I've got to go somewhere.
Which place in Bombay
is called 'somewhere'?
Where does Reema want to go?
=Somewhere'.
And where is somewhere?
- Out there.
It's here... not there!
Before leaving, you must tell us
where you are going.
Well...
Where does Reema want to go?
- There!
Not there... it's in there!
You guys have ruined my clothes!
l hate you..
You take the ioke seriously?
- This is no joke!
There's no point in waiting
anymore, Amit. Shall we go now?
Know something, Amit?
You can't trust these rich girls.
How was the party?
- Fine.
Looks like you had
a grand party.
Yes! It was fine.
Hasn't Mom come?
I've left her at your uncle's house.
We can sleep peacefully for a night.
May I know who are
you waiting for?
lf you ask, I'll
have to tell you.
Then forget it.
l won't ask you today.
Come on.
Give it.
Welcome, Mr.Malik. Why wouldn't
l come when you called me?
Please sit down.
- Thank you.
Perhaps you know that
I'm the Chairman of ...
...the Managing Committee
of your college? -Yes.
You will also know that I run
many other colleges in town.
This isn't social work for me.
It's my business.
And no businessman can take on
the government or Sudhirbhai.
So you will have to change
Amit Verma's section.-No, sorry!
You'll be sorry when your young
daughter or sister is abducted!
Before that happens, I resign
from your college.
Hey! Where are you following
her?
l wasn't following her.
She's walking in front of me.
Don't you know she's my sister?
- Did I say she's your mother?
lnsolent rascal!
Mahesh, you fool! Why did you
come in the middle?
No! I've got to go.- C'mon, let's
have an ice cream.
You? Here?
Have you gone mad?
Vikki, My brother and all his
friends are downstairs.
What if they see you here?
- They'll kill me, isn't it?
So be it.
- Go away.
Are you in your senses?
Go away!
lf you promise to go to the
movies with me tomorrow evening...
..I'll go away.
- Which movie?-Love story!
All right! Go away now.
I'll come tomorrow.
Promise!...
Tomorrow 6.30 pm at Regal.
Give my love to Vikram.
Whom were you talking to?
- I was practicing.
I've been knocking for so long!
Why didn't you open the door?
I'm not a servant
you can order around!
Go downstairs,
I've get ready and come.
Yes, he'll return from Delhi.
Reema? Don't worry...
She'll be with me.
Are four hours enough
for you to get dressed?
What for?
Sudhirbhai has invited us
for dinner.
You may go.
I've got to go somewhere else.
So call it off. What's the number?
I'll tell them.
There's no phone where
I'm going for dinner.
Why must you go to a place where
there is not even a phone?
There's no need. Go and get
ready for the party.
lncidentally, there are no
telephones even in a temple.
But we go there with
all the devotion.
It's me...
I'm coming over, too.
Right. We'll meet there.
You're still here.
Go and get dressed.
Yes, I understand. Even you must
try to understand.
Reema, you've changed.
You are not the Reema of old.
Go ahead and finalize
the business deal.
I'll be right back.
Listen...!
Where are you going?
Don't touch me.
l don't like it.
Come here. Get a drink for the
commissioner.
And remember that
he has it plain.
Reema, what's the matter?
Why are you standing aloof?
l don't enioy such parties.
It's okay for your age group.
My dear girl's getting bored.
I'll scold Vicky right now.
He must take care of you.
After all he has to
do it forever in his life.
Why forever?
- That's because...
...you'll be marrying him in future.
- Marriage?
You don't understand, dear.
Vicky is my only son.
That he does not get what
he wants, is impossible.
What is it?- Does Ms Reema
Goswami live here?
Give it to me. - There's
registered mail for her.
Reema madam!
There's a letter for you.
There's a registered
Ietter for Ms Reema.
I'll sign it.- No, sir! Her
signature is necessary.
You fool!
- Don't touch my beard.
I'm her fiance!
Give it to me.
l don't care about that. I want
her signature; call her soon.
What happened? - There's a
regd. Ietter for Reema.
Call her here.
- One moment.
Reema, there's a registered
Ietter for you.
Come 8 sign it-Call her quickly.
I've got to go elsewhere too.
Who is it from?
Come on.
- This fellow is a big fool.
Dear Reema; whenever I call
Vicky or Mahesh pick up the ph_ne
lf you want me to forget that
you ditched me at the movies...
come over to thèDisco Dandia'
I'll be waiting for you
Madam Reema!
Now what?
- She didn't return the slip.
Address her as Madam, okay?
- You can madam her!
Reema, Just get rid of this
aSS.
I will surely come.
l wanted the partnership of our
families to be put on record.
So Mr.Goswami has named the
chain of our motels and hotels...
as the R.V.M. Group of Hotels.
This means Reema,
Vikram and Mahesh.
The three of you are equal partners
in the venture.
So to celebrate this,
we'll go out for dinner.
So V and M will go
and fetch R.
What happened?
- I have a splitting headache.
lt isn't a fever, is it?
- No! It's just a headache.
Control your headache. Dad is the
Chief Guest at tonight's function.
l won't enioy it without you.
- No Vicky!
lf I go with you, I won't ...
-What?
So what if I don't attend?
Go ahead, all of you.
Come on, let's go.
She's such a big bore.
Go on.
I'll wait here at her bedside.
No Vicky! Will that
relieve me of my pain?
Please go ahead.
lf there's any problem,
you'll find me downstairs.
Go away!- I'll be downstairs...
l won't go to the function- Go..
Mahesh, take him away.
- C'mon, she'll feel worse.
Go on, Vicky.
Now look; only couples
can dance here.
Bachelors are not permitted.
No admission without girlfriend
How about the one whom somebody
has promised to come to?
She had also promised
to come to your party.
Don't insist. She won't come
and you'll be insulted.
Shall I tell you something?
These rich girls are not trustworthy.
Even I've tried to
score with them.
I'm not trying to score with her.
She will surely come.
We'll begin the program.
lf she doesn't come before it ends,
I'll commit suicide.
What did you say?
- Suicide!
Disco Dandiya...
She has promised to come
She will certainly come
She will come and
bring joy to the heart
She has promised to come
So she will come
She will come and
bring joy to the heart
We will be merry and sing...
and dance the
disco dandiya
We will be merry and sing...
and dance the
disco dandiya
I've got the idea!
When she comes
into my arms...
she'll upset the
rhythm of my breathing
She'll look into my eyes...
and send my heart afluttter
She's like the
wand of flowers
When her stick
meets mine...
my heart will sway
and I will be joyous
She will make me dance
around her little finger...
I'll enioy that
I will be merry
and sing...
I will dance
the disco dandiya
We will be merry
and sing...
we will dance
the disco dandiya
Why hasn't your
Iover arrived?
l have faith
in your word
You can't break your promise
You have been with me thus far
You will not
desert me now
l have faith
in your word
You cannot break
your promise
You have been with me thus far
You will not desert me now
When I call out to you...
You will appear
My love is being
put to test today
You will keep your word
l had promised
to come...
and here I am
l have taken on the
world for you, my love
We will be merry
and sing...
We will dance
the disco dandiya
We will be merry
and sing...
we will dance
the disco dandiya
We will be merry
and sing...
and dance
the disco dandiya
Your stick and mine meet
As if it produces
a spark...
and our breath quickens
This has never
happened before...
there never was
a moment like this
We will kick up a fuss together,
come what may
Never again will someone dance
the disco dandiya like this
We will sing
and be merry...
and dance
the disco dandiya
We will sing
and be merry
and dance
the disco dandiya
Disco Dandiya!
I've read in stories that the cruel
world doesn't allow lovers to unite.
But this world is truly very cruel.
Then what is to be done?
- Only love, love and love.
But for that, it is
necessary to meet.
It's difficult to meet because of
your dad and Sudhirbhai's men.
There's an idea.
But if you like it...
you'll have to kiss me with
this lonely road as our witness.
And what if I don't like it?
- Then I'll kiss you.
Stop laughing and tell me
about your idea.
These rich people wake up
very late in the morning.
We'll meet on the pretext
of morning walks.
We both will come iogging
from opposite directions.
That's it. And nobody will
even get to know.
Where were you?
- I was with Amit.
Don't you feel ashamed
to go out with him?
lf I were ashamed,
why would I go with him?
You shouldn't have done this.
You shouldn't have raised hand
on my future wife.
What did you call me?
- My future wife.
Stop dreaming about that.
I will never marry you.
What rubbish are you talking?!
I'm in love with Amit.
And that's for sure!
What's up, Vicky?
Dad, what the use of being
Sudhirbhai's son...
if the girl I love, tells me...
...that she loves a taxi-driver's
son and not me? I'll kill him.
Wait, my son!
Anger is precious wealth.
You must spend it
very carefully.
lt'll be a waste to shoot
an ordinary taxi driver's son.
Killing is our profession,
no doubt.
And we don't do it for free.
Give me the revolver.
And here's what
you will do.
Beat up that boy and he'll
come to his senses. Go on!
Are you ioining me today?
l had told you that Reema is mine.
Do not get close to her!
Reema is mine.
Only mine!
Atleast think about your father.
You're always troubling him.
Why're you always scolding
him, mom?- You keep quiet.
Peace, lady! That's what
your parents had named you!
What happened?
- Ask him.
l think he's...
- For God sake, keep quiet.
Why must I care? Let him get
beaten up some more!
Who has beaten you up?
- Never mind.
How can I not mind?
Tell me, who has beaten you?
Who was it? Tell me.
No, Papa. This is my battle.
When a family member is in trouble,
it becomes a family issue.
Nothing is personal. You are
wounded but it hurts me, too.
You are not an orphan
anybody can beat you up.
Tell me, who did this to you?
I'll tell you when
my pain lessens.
Go and lie down,
I'll get the doctor.
No! Not the doctor.
There'll be a police case
and it will lead to problems.
Then I'll apply medicine
on your wounds. Come on.
Munni, bring in
all these things.
Sudhirbhai! Please come in!
What can I do for you?
l know that you
own two taxi-cabs.
One, you drive yourself,
and the other you hire out.
Besides, you have a son, a
daughter, a wife and this house.
Your other taxi can meet
with an accident in five minutes.
This loss will be paid
by the insurance company.
But what will you do if
your son loses his life?
Even then it will
give you 25,OOO Rupees.
But will that money bring
back your son's life?
So tell him to keep away from
my future daughter-in-law.
ln any case, Sudhirbhai never
goes to anybody's house.
l would've called for you
if it was something else.
And I would've forcibly abducted
you, if you wouldn't come.
But because it is concerned with
my son, I had to come here myself.
You've come to my house
for the first time.
You are my guest.
l heard whatever you have said.
Because it is my duty
to respect a guest.
You are smart to understand
what I was getting at.
Haven't you gone
to sleep, son?
What am I to do?
l know Sudhirbhai has
blown up our taxi.
Yes. And he has also
threatened me.
That if my son does not
give up meeting Reema...
..he'll kill me.
Sudhir is a powe_ul man and
he can reach anywhere.
But if you want Reema
at the cost of my life...
..l don't care for my life.
She means a lot to me...
but not more than you.
I'll go far away from Reema.
You love her very much,
don't you?
l loved your mother
very much too.
So I can understand
how you feel.
l didn't want Amit to go.
Greetings!
- We don't want to buy anything.
Thank you!
-ls Amit at home?
Aren't you Reema?
- Yes.
Come on in, dear.
Have some tea.
- I won't serve any tea.
l came to ask why Amit
didn't come for a walk today.
Actually, we are
poor folks dear...
Amit found a good iob,
and he left immediately.
He said he'll write a letter
as soon as he reaches there.
But where has he gone?
To Calcutta! Anything else?
- No.
Just let me know if
you receive a letter.
Sure, I will.
You've made the right decision.
Just as I chose to resign,
rather than change your section.
Reema's a very nice girl.
But your life is
more important.
And your final years' exams
are even more important.
I've got your admission done.
Now start preparing for your exams.
Come on.
They don't let me live...
these memories of yours
O beloved, you have gone away
Come back to me...
or call me over to you
There isn't a letter...
there's no word from you
Flowers are blossoming...
and I wear a forlorn look
l hope I don't die
thirsting for you
There isn't a letter...
nor any word from you
How times have changed...
what days are here
Life is like
a shattered mirror
l can see nothing
Come back to me...
Or call me over to you
There isn't any letter...
nor any word from you
Hardayal, I'll go in. Just lock
the door and throw the key inside.
Why? - Reema will come to
ask for Amit.
l can't face her.
- Very well!
And take away the taxi.
- All right!
Seasons change and
come back again...
but you haven't returned
Every day, every moment...
l bear this excruciating pain
Without you, who will rescue me
from these pits of grief
There isn't any letter...
nor any word from you
Get in from the window quickly.
- Okay!
When did you come?
- I came at 3 this morning...
so I could meet you
before the door is locked.
I've been coming here
for three days.
l don't want anything else
except Amit's address.
Please give me his address.
Shall I say something?
You and Amit belong
to different worlds.
You must live in your ivory tower.
That would be good for both of you.
Ordinary people like us can't
take on people like Sudhirbhai.
lf it was iust the question of
my life, I wouldn't have bothered.
But when Amit is concerned...
...as his father, I have
to be careful.
l'd like to hear this from Amit.
I will not leave this place
until you make me meet him.
Alright, keep sitting there.
Ask him when he comes.
l can't endanger his life.
One moment!
You may go.
-Ok.
So, you do remember my face.
There was no other choice.
- What are you talking about?
What right do you have
to this face?
You are right. I shouldn't
have any right to this face.
Because I'm a middle-class boy
for whom his degree, ...
...a iob or a small business,
is more important than a girl.
Don't lie!
Just tell me,...
how could you come here
without even informing me?
Didn't you consider what l'd
go through, without you?
l did think about you.
But a dream always
Ioses out to reality.
You must think that my dream
has lost to my reality.
To which of your realities?-
That my daddy is a mere cabbie.
Sudhirbhai is an
underworld king.
To the reality that I also love
my family very much.
I'm not ready to risk their lives
for the sake of my love.
Tell me, what else could I do,
other than sacrificing my love?
You mean we'll
never meet again?
Why won't you meet?
lf the earth and the sky
can meet at the horizon...
even you both can meet too.
But after a month.
Because the exams will
get over after that.
After his exams,
I'll get him a job in Assam.
l know some people there
in the tea-gardens.
Even Sudhirbhai won't
get to know of it.
I'm all yours
l belong to you
l ought to be yours
l must belong to you
Here and there...
- they must talk about us
Anybody who sees us..
- must say...
We are in love, love, love...
we are in love
We're in love, love, love...
With your arms in mine,
we will stroll on the path
Let them watch, if they must...
why must we be shy?
With your arms in mine,
we will stroll around
Let them watch, if they must...
why must we be shy?
When you walk with me...
l like it very much
Everywhere around...
- let them talk
Anybody who sees us...
- Must say...
We are in love, love, love...
we are in love
That isn't Hi in English...
I'm actually groaning
in Hindi
What for?
l had a dream last night;
l just can't forget it
What was it about?
Tell me
Enemies of our love
snatched you away...
you were screaming for help
Be someone here
or not...
I will say it
and so will you...
Everywhere around...
- they've got to talk
Everybody who sees us...
- Ought to say...
We are in love, love, love...
we are in love
My daughter is obsessed with
that two-penny boy nowadays.
Children often do such things.
Even we used to be like that.
Let's make one more drink.
When I was 15...
l fell in love with
a 24-year old maid.
When father got to
know of this,...
he got her married
to someone else.
Now whenever I see that maid,
l get a very strange feeling.
The country is affected
by epidemics and socialism.
Reema is still young.
She's infected by love;
she'll be all right.
ln any case, she is
my responsibility now.
Because she is my future
daughter-in-law.
Just fix the wedding date.
And drink peacefully.
I've warned the boy's father.
He won't even dare to
Iook at Reema again.
So begin the
wedding preparations.
Come, dear.
Sit with me.
l didn't like what you
just told daddy, uncle.
It's okay, Mr.Goswami.
Let my daughter-in-law
say what she wants to say.
Go on, dear.
To begin with, I'm not going to
be your daughter-in-law.
No, dear! You have
wrong information.
We were about to decide on a
date for your wedding with Vicky.
Then don't decide it. Because l
won't be marrying Vicky.
Neither do I like him
nor his criminal background.
It's difficult to decide which is
worse...Vicky? Or his background?
You can't even imagine
how bad his background is.
l am his background.
lf only I wasn't so
affectionate to you...
..you wouldn't be
so rude with me.
lt is clear that the marriage
can't happen forcibly.
Forget it, Mr.Goswami.
I'll find another girl for Vicky.
But..-Thank you, uncle..
-That is all right
But don't forget to go to
the J.J. Hospital tomorrow.
And ask the duty officer ...
What's that guy's name?
Oh yes, Amit. Find out how many
bones in his body are in tact.
He'll tell you the exact number.
Because tomorrow all his
bones will be broken.
Very well, Mr.Goswami.
I'll leave now.
Hi..That's not what I meant.
l was actually groaning.
When did you arrive?
- I haven't arrived yet.
l got down from the bus
to call you up.
l felt like hearing your voice.
-l want to meet you immediately.
Shall I come now?
- No! I'll come to meet you.
Where?
-Narsee Park..
Alright. I'll wait for you.
Bye..
Come, dear, I'll give you a ride.
- No thank you, uncle.
My best friend's daughter will go
in a taxi? This is not fair.
Come, I'll drop you. ...
This is your car, too.
Get in.
Driver, start the car.
Play the cassette, driver.
Let's have her listen
to some classical music.
Amit, I want to meet
you immediately.
Shall I come over now?
- No! You don't come here.
I'll come to meet you.
- Where?-Narsee Park
You must've understood by now.
lf you love that boy,
you wouldn't want him to die.
What are you talking about?
- That which is going to happen.
What's going to happen?
You mustn't put questions
to me, little girl.
I'm taking you to Narsee Park.
You want to go there, right?
Look at that.
Killing someone
is no big deal.
l don't find it proper to kill
an ordinary taxi driver's son.
But now his life
is in your hands.
Don't fear, if you are in love.
It's a nice song.
But it sounds nice
only in a film.
Learn to fear for the one
you love.
My sister has agreed
to marry Vicky.
That's great!
I'll give a party on
Reema's birthday.
After which, our fathers
announce our engagement.
Before that party, Reema will
come with me to invite that...
...taxidriver's son.
What wrong with it?
He's her classmate;
he should be invited.
Great! But what
about my V.C.R.?
When he comes to the party,
we'll insult him so much...
...that he 8 his seven generation
will learn a lesson forever.
He has insulted me enough.
Greetings! Whom do you
wish to meet? -Amit...
How are you related to him?
- Not at all.
What's the matter, Reema?
- Give him the card.
Tomorrow is my birthday
and I've come to invite you.
Tell him the truth.
Tomorrow I'm getting
engaged to Vicky.
lf you really have the guts,
you must surely come to the party.
I will wait for you..
What happened, son?
Who came in that car?
What's this card about?
This is an invitation for
Reema and Vicky's engagement.
They themselves came
to give me the card.
That nasty chap said that
if you have the guts...
you will attend the party.
Will you go to the party?
- Don't go there, brother.
He's a very bad guy.
- Yes, son! Don't go there.
After all, I am your mother.
No, mother. Don't worry.
l want to go and see how much
the rich can insult a poor man.
How much will they play
with my feelings.
He's right.
A life of humiliation
is not worth living.
Most people in this world
are decent.
But these people live under
the fear of some hooligan.
You mustn't ever do this.
Just listen to your conscience.
Yes Papa. I'll do that.
Good wishes for the birthday
and engagement.
Let's see what present the
cabbie's son has brought.
No!
Be careful.
It's a special gift.
lt appears to be worth
a million dollars.
Isn't it, friends?
Make some deductions, buddy!
- How is that possible?
It's a street Romeo's present.
It can't be cheap.
Shahaiahan is dead but he left
a model of Taj Mahal for ...
... such Romeos to present to
their unsuccessful love.
Beggar! You should've thought
where you are going...
...before you got the present.
You don't have any status.
But the girl who will be receiving
the gift, is Mr.Goswami's daughter.
And Mr. Vikram Singh's fiancee.
Here's what we'll do.
We'll blow up his gift
like his love.
Let's ask everybody...
Shall I destroy it?
With your permission,
l destroy this special present!
I'm crazy at heart...
l do as I feel
I'm crazy at heart
I will not fear anyone
in the world
I will proclaim today
that it's you I have...
Loved you... my love
It's with destiny that
one finds love
You lose your heart
only once
You meet someone
only once...
and fall in love
Once you're in love...
nobody can ever stop you
Love, love, love...
I'm crazy at heart;
l heed the dictates of my heart
Come to Hotel Blue Diamond
with your telescopic gun.
You've got to bump off someone.
Look into my eyes
Embrace me
Hide me in your arms
Let them all be iealous
Who will ever do what
we have done?
Love, love, love
I'm crazy at heart
l heed my heart
Goswami! See what
your daughter wants.
And what are you giving her?
Are you a father or
just a businessman?
She is your daughter!
She's no wad of notes...
which you want to invest
in Sudhirbhai's black business!
Does her happiness
mean nothing to you?
See what a beautiful couple
they make.
These young children
are challenging Sudhirbhai.
And you, you only want to
save your skin?
Even if the world
is our enemy...
we have a promise
to keep
We're young
Let's make a story
that's new
Let the myopic world now see
what new things we do
Love, love, love...
Don't be afraid, son.
Reema is all yours.
As her father, I give her away
to you today.
Go far away from Sudhirbhai.
Papa
-Yes, my child!
Be happy. Go on!
I've brought her with
her father's consent.
This means Sudhirbhai will
first come here looking for you.
This also means that they
have only tonight.
Run away with her before dawn.
No, mother. I can't run away,
putting you all in trouble.
Don't worry about us.
I'll send Shanti and Munni
to Kanpur right now.
You go away.
- Right.
May you always be happy.
l had secretly made some clothes
for Amit's bride, dear.
Take them along.
Bless you, dear.
Every love story normally ends
with the death of the lovers.
You both will write a new story.
Wake up a priest
and get married.
Go on.
Where is that rebel
of your daughter?
Well...
l just went to her room.
l found a letter in which
she had written ...
Daddy, please forgive me.
l can't marry Vicky
because I love Amit.
So, I'm going far away
with Amit.
Goswami, you are my friend
as well as my partner.
But I regret, if your daughter
does not marry my son...
...then give her up for dead.
You won't do that.
Daddy,
what the hell is all this?!
It's nothing, son. Reema has run
away with that guy.
No...
-Come to your senses.
How will I come to my senses?
lt is all because
of this old goat!
Mind your language!
lf your daughter does
not marry me,...
I'll destroy your family
from this face of this earth!
Have patience, my son.
To begin with, bring the
cabbie's family to Store # 14.
Then thrash all his friends
and make them reveal...
...where has he gone with
my would be daughter-in-law.
Search for them in every nook
and corner of the city.
At every railway station,
taxi stand and bus stop.
So that they don't
get out of the city.
Once they are caught,...
..bring my would-be
daughter-in-law to me.
And have the guy bumped off.
Verma, where is your son?
Where is he?- I don't know.
- You'll tell us right now.
Ask him!
Bastards! I use these hands
to change the gears in my cab.
I'll change yours now!
You too want to know
my son's address?
C'mon!
So Ms Goswami has also
come with you! Sit down.
She's no longer Miss Goswami.
She is Mrs. Amit Verma now.
l like brave children.
But I'll give you some bad news
alongwith the praise.
There was news on T.V.
that the Vice President of the...
...Taxi Driver's Union was shot
by some unknown men last night.
He is in St. George Hospital
and is out of danger.
We will go there, sir.
C'mon, Reema.
l think you must leave her here.
And go and see your father quietly.
No, Sir, I will go with him.
- No, Reema. He's right.
Please look after her, sir.
Don't worry, son.
-Take care of yourself, Amit
Reema, you are iust like
my grand-daughter Sangeeta.
You don't need to worry.
Nobody can harm you
till such time as I live.
l'd lay down my life...
Bloody cheat!
You've deceived me!
You have betrayed me!
No!
- Hold it!
Tell Amit that if he wants to
cure himself of the obsession...
..he can find me with Reema
at the Disney Fair.
Tell him to come there.
Do you love that
cabbie's son Amit?
Yes! I love him
and I hate you.
l didn't ask you what
you feel about me.
Did I ask that of Ms Goswami?
Tell me - No...
Have you heard?
You only hate me now.
ln a short while,
you'll be afraid of me.
You'll be very scared.
You'll say, No Vicky...
For God's sake, don't do this
I'll say, Whatever I do,
l do it for my own sake
Not for God's sake
l haven't been
introduced to God
Do I know God, guys?
-No,No...
Heard that?
You'll have to change
those lines...
You'll say,
Vicky have mercy on me
Mercy, Vicky!
And I'll say, I can't
have mercy on you; I can't
How can I have mercy,
when I can only love?
l won't have any mercy on you
It's a habit, you see.
Once I come to like something...
l either acquire it...
..or finish it in a way that
it can't belong to anyone else.
So I'm going to rape you now.
No!... No!
Love, Love...
-Please leave me..
Hold it, Vicky!
l won't let you do that!
Leave her alone!
Don't you dare touch her!
Goswami Jr... nobody can
save her from me today.
No..Bash him up.
-Vikki, Let her go!
l won't spare you!
- Vicky, let Mahesh go!
Leave him alone?
He has affection for a sister
who hates me!
There's going to be a big drama
now! Great fun!
Just bring that here.
This is blood-red colour
which my dog really hates.
He attacks anybody who wears
this colour on his face.
Now he will attack you too.
The real prey is Amit.
Mahesh is iust an example.
Now look what I'll
do to your sister.
No Vicky!
l won't let you do this.
Try to act smart with me,
and the dog will attack you.
You hate me?
Where's the girl?
She ran away.
- Ran away? Come on.
Sir, what happened?
Life for decent people
is tough, my boy.
But who has beaten you?
Don't worry about me.
Save Reema!
What's happened to her?
- Vicky has taken her away!
Where to?
- Disney Fair.
Fan out everywhere!
Look for them! Go on!
Go up there.
Did you find Reema?
Go and look for her!
Amit is somewhere around!
Look for him.
Take off your clothes!
l want revenge for the death
of my friends!
Take off your clothes! Strip!
-Leave me alone.
You hate me!
...don't you?
Say that again!
And I'll give you a reply.
You thought you'd get my Reema...
that you could make her
the object of your lust...!
and that I would
Iet you do that!
Reema is my love.
She's my life!
Look out, Amit!
You boy there... you haven't done
the right thing!
l didn't want to kill you.
And that is exactly what
l always told Vicky too!
That you must combat only those
who are your equals!
A mere taxi driver's son
can't compete with us!
This is the corpse
of my only son.
And it has made you my equal.
Come out, you bastard! come out.
Else, this girI will be killed
before you!
Amit...
Hold it... Freeze there!
Look how I make a sieve
out of your lover's body!
No...!
When I had myself moved away
for my daughter's happiness...
...Sudhirbhai was nothing.
Go, my child.
Be you be happy.
But always remember one thing.
This life has only one aim.
Love, love... - Excuse me, sir
-Love...