It's Father Giulio with the holy oil.
Tell him to wait,
I've had it twice already.
What am I?
- A Chinese.
- And now?
- A sad Chinese.
- I dreamt of someone like that...
...who brought me a telegram.
I was too scared to open it,
then I opened it
but nothing was written inside.
I want to be alone.
And all those people waiting outside?
They can come in later,
they can all come in later...
Feel the tension in your hair.
Relax.
He talked about this simile:
A man had a fig tree
planted in his vineyard.
He went to look for fruit,
but didn't find any.
Force the tension
into the bottom of your eyes,
force the tension
into the bottom of your ears,
down into the nape of the neck,
feel the difference between
a relaxed head...
and the tension you had in your eyes,
in your ears and
in the nape of your neck.
So the man said to the vine-dresser
who was with him:
"I've been coming here for three years
to harvest the fruit of this fig,
there's never any fruit.
See to it that it's cut down.
Why should it occupy the land?"
Let the tension leave
through your scalp,
the nerves and blood
under the scalp.
And he replies:
"Master, let it live this year.
I'll hoe the ground all around it,
and I'll use manure as fertilizer,
and if it then produces fruit, good.
If not, we'll cut it down."
- Have you got a light please?
- Yeah, sure.
Here...
Thanks.
- What are these holes for?
- To get by...
- What a nice smell!
- I'm meeting my girlfriend.
Oh, that's why.
Good idea... and the flowers?
My girlfriend is bringing them to me...
How come you're working
when you're so old?
You want me
to come to eat at your place?
Talking of which,
I'm hungry granddad.
It seems like only yesterday
that I was like you.
Riccetto, Riccetto listen to me...
Can you hear me?
Listen, Riccetto,
this is God talking, God, God!
Don't you understand Riccetto,
God's talking to you.
Will you listen to me now?
No.
But I'm speaking simply...
Give me a sign, just one sign,
and I'll understand
that you want to listen to me.
Can't you hear me? Are you deaf?
Don't you have ears?
- Hey, let me get in.
- Alright, be careful, get in.
- Are you working?
- Yes, you have to...
I don't know...
I don't know about these things.
You're right,
but I've got a wife and son.
He was born three days ago,
did you know?
I'll talk to you anyway, Riccetto,
even if you don't want
to give me a sign.
Anyway your son
drinks his mother's milk...
But you've got to work anyway...
Bloody hell,
I haven't got a job, damn it!
The nice thing
about work's the satisfaction.
- Yeah, sure...
- At 5 past 5 there's nothing as nice...
...as finishing work.
- I'm off at 8!
[In French]
Gimme a kiss... gimme a kiss...
[in French]
Another one... another one...
You're happy, aren't you?
This is what I want from you...
From you I want your fruits,
your first fruits.
What are these fruits?
The fruits of your knowledge
and your will...
What do you know, Riccetto?
What do you want, Riccetto?
- Hello, Mr. Street-cleaner.
- Hey, Riccetto...
They told me you were dying,
is it true?
What are you saying, kid?
I've still got lots of
sweeping to do...
I've got to sweep
the whole of Via Nazionale.
You're innocent, it's true.
And those who are innocent
have no knowledge.
And those who have no knowledge
have no will.
But I who am your God,
order you to know and to want.
I know it's a contradiction,
perhaps without a solution,
because if you are an innocent,
you cannot be otherwise.
And if you are innocent,
you cannot have conscience and will.
Tell me, to whom did Christ,
my son,
spoke, if not to the innocents?
And why?
Because he wanted them to know.
...you, like the fig tree,
might say it's too early,
that it's only March,
that you can't give of your fruits,
that you'll give them in September.
Nonsense...
'March', 'September'...
For me, God,
they are nothing but empty words.
If faith can move mountains,
just think
how unimportant it is
if it's March or September...
Listen to me, Riccetto, listen to me.
I'd be satisfied with a nod of your head
or a glance towards the sky.
Listen to me if you don't want
to lose yourself.
Innocence is a fault,
innocence is a fault, understand?
The innocents will be condemned
because they will no longer have
the right to be innocent.
I cannot pardon those who go
through injustice and wars,
through horrors and blood,
with the happy air of innocents.
There are millions of innocents
like you in the world
who would rather disappear from history
than lose their innocence.
And I have to make them die...
Even though I know
they have no choice...
I have to damn them
like the fig tree,
...and make them die, die, die.
- What?
There's no time without time.
And I've been waiting
a long time for you.
Time has all the time.
They loved each other, and time
didn't change their love at all.
The old time fairy tales
enter his life today...
Because...
there's no time without time.
I've been waiting
a long time for you.
Time has all the...
MADE IN CUBA
[in French]
What's that?
I don't know what it is.
[In French]
You don't know what that is?
Perhaps they were
the first images of a film.
[In French]
The first images of a film...
[in French]
Oh, yeah, maybe...
But I don't know which film.
[In French]
What kind of film?
Maybe it's an Evgeniy Onegin film.
[In French]
Maybe it's an Albert Norisseau film.
Or maybe, it's a J.L. Godard film.
[In French]
Maybe it's a Christian Dior film.
In any case it's in
Techniscope and Eastmancolor.
[In French]
Yeah, it's in 'scope', and in color.
Are there any actors?
Yes, there are actors...
[in French]
And who are they?
Nino Castelnuovo and Christine Guého.
[In French]
And what role do they play?
He's Italian and she's French.
[In French]
The French girl leaves her family for him?
Yes, and he also leaves
his family for her...
[in French]
And he leaves his family for her.
Yes, they love each other,
so they do
the same thing for each other.
[In French]
Good, they want to marry
because they love each other.
Yes, they want to get married.
[In French]
And what about us?
We'll wait and see.
[In French]
We'll wait for what?
Because we've got to be
the witnesses at their wedding.
[In French]
We are the witnesses.
What's the title of this film?
I've forgotten the title...
...it's something about "Children".
[In French]
"The Children"?
"Les enfants terribles".
["The terrible children"]
No... not 'terrible'.
[In French]
The humiliated children.
No, not humiliated' either.
[In French]
It's crazy that you forgot the title.
Yes, it's a shame...
They told me,
but I don't remember it anymore.
[In French]
Didn't they give you a script?
There isn't any script.
[In French]
So, how do you know what's going on?
To know what's going on
you just have to watch.
If we're witnesses,
we're observers too.
[In French]
Yes, it's true...
[in French]
...to be a witness is to be an observer.
[In French]
We must watch.
Let's watch.
[In French]
When... the world...
[in French]
Will be... will be reduced...
To a black forest...
The world is reduced to a black forest.
[In French]
For four astonished eyes...
Four astonished eyes.
[In French]
A beach for a faithful couple.
We'll meet again.
The war that China will wage...
[in French]
Yes. The war that China will wage...
...against the rest of humanity...
[in French]
...will be a bridge to a new age
in the history of humanity.
[In French]
...will be a bridge to a new age
in the history of humanity.
[In French]
Listen... it's here and now...
that our voyages start and end.
It's here and now
that our journeys start and end.
[In French]
It's here that we'll defend our lives...
[in French]
...and look for the world.
Yes, this summer is violent.
[In French]
It's an hot summer.
All the world's peoples are revolting
against the exploiters.
[In French]
All the world's peoples are revolting...
In Aden, South Yemen,
the revolutionary forces
are increasing the pressure.
Yeah, sure...
Yeah...
[in French]
Quiet and nude...
We pass among our peers...
[in French]
Without losing ourselves.
In Bolivia, in Venezuela,
the guerrillas checkmate...
they checkmate
the powerful repressive forces
organized by American technicians.
We must be actively
and solidly behind their struggle.
[In French]
We must be actively and solidly
behind their struggle.
[In French]
Plains, snow-covered roofs,
the luxuriant tropics.
[In French]
The sky that changes.
A single couple united by a single garment.
A single couple, a single garment.
[In French]
By the same desire.
The same desire.
[In French]
Laid down at the feet of their own image.
An infinite couple.
There is no other way
that will lead us to the radiant society
heralded by Marx...
...when he said it would offer everyone...
...bread and roses.
Socialism.
MADE IN CUBA
[in French]
All I want... is to love you.
[In French]
To look in your eyes and see only...
To look in your eyes
and see only...
[in French]
...what I think of you.
[In French]
The days and nights
are measured by your eyelids.
[In French]
Or to laugh together on the streets.
Or... to laugh together on the streets.
[In French]
What time is the marriage?
The wedding? At 11.
[In French]
I'm sure they will be late...
Why should they be late?
[In French]
The couple is embracing.
It's normal that they embrace.
[In French]
Did you understand what they said?
No, I haven't heard what they said.
What did they say?
[In French]
Eternity started and will end in a bed.
Eternity...
started and will end in a bed.
Did they say that?
[In French]
Yes, yes, that's what they said.
The film might last an eternity,
if they said that...
[in French]
So, this film will last an eternity?
[In French]
I hope they will argue and break up...
Should they argue and break up?
Why?
[In French]
That way, the film will end quickly...
Yes, obviously.
That way the film will finish early,
and there won't be a wedding.
[In French]
No, there won't be a wedding.
In fact, I'm amazed by this wedding...
[in French]
They will break up...
Why are you amazed
about the wedding?
I don't think they'll separate.
At the end of the day
they're not Tito and Berenice.
[In French]
Yes, right, they're not Tito and Berenice.
They're neither Arabs, nor Jewish.
[In French]
They will surely break up...
No... his father was of Arabian origin,
but not him.
And her mother was completely Jewish,
but she isn't.
They won't separate.
[In French]
Wanna bet?
Alright... let's bet on it.
[In French]
Ok, let's watch.
Alright, let's watch.
[In French]
It's a way of saying the opposite.
Yes, I said the opposite, so what?
[In French]
So they were just lies...
No, they were not lies.
[In French]
But it wasn't the truth...
Yes... it was already
a part of the truth.
[In French]
Oh, yeah...
[in French]
So, it's the truth born of contradictions?
Exactly.
The truth is born of the justification
of the contradictions
in the hearts of the people.
[In French]
It's the solution of people's contradictions.
Yes...
that's where you find the truth.
[In French]
So it's alright for us?
I'm afraid not.
Everything's going wrong for us.
[In French]
Why? We're opposite types.
I'm part of the people, and so are you...
Because between us there's no contrast,
just antagonism.
[In French]
We're antagonists, and not opposites?
You aren't the people,
you're the middle class.
[In French]
Yes, I'm not the people, I'm the middle class.
I'd like to stay with you...
but I'd like to leave you.
[In French]
Yes, stay with me, I don't want to leave you.
Yes, but you see,
we've already separated,
you're not a revolutionary.
[In French]
It's true, I'm not a revolutionary.
And we've already separated.
[In French]
When are you leaving?
Soon.
I'm catching a plane for Mexico City at 5.
[In French]
And a plane from Mexico to Cuba?
Cuba's surrounded...
you have to go via Mexico.
[In French]
I thought there was a direct flight.
I didn't know Cuba was surrounded.
The old time fairy tales
enter his life today.
Because there's no time without time.
And I've been waiting
a long time for you.
Time has all the time.
Your hand comes towards me...
The love of these moments
You know you only live once.
Because...
there's no time without time.
And I've been waiting
a long time for you.
Time has all the time.
Time.
So, what are you doing?
[In French]
Yes, what are you doing?
Can't you see we're talking?
[In French]
What are they talking about?
Considering the images, probably love.
[In French]
But sometimes, images lie.
No, images never lie.
[In French]
Yes, images often lie.
In fact, cinema is a world of lies...
[in French]
Why are you laughing?
I've got the right to laugh.
[In French]
Yes, but why?
I'm laughing because of what you said...
that cinema is the art of lying.
[In French]
So, why is that funny?
Why's that funny?
Because you're of a certain age...
but you're speaking about something
that's very young.
[In French]
I'm not that old, I'm just 20.
But Cinema is not so young...
[in French]
It has the age of Roosevelt, Churchill...
...Stalin after the war...
Yes... Cinema has
the same age as Stalin,
Churchill and Roosevelt,
but they were old...
...and that's why everything's
going wrong today.
[In French]
Is everything wrong 'cause they were old?
Why?
Because they were old people
who lead a new world
without knowing it was new.
[In French]
Oh, yes, I see.
Like Kosygin, de Gaulle or Johnson today.
[In French]
Old men who don't know
[in French]
They're leading a new world.
Yes, like Kosygin,
de Gaulle or Johnson today.
[In French]
Yeah, alright, but...
[in French]
What's the relationship between cinema and me?
What's the relationship
between you and cinema?
It's that you talk about
something you don't know.
[In French]
I talk about things I don't know?
It's not true, I go to the cinema very often.
Perhaps you often go to the cinema,
but you see very few films...
or, on the contrary,
you see lots of films,
but you see little Cinema.
[In French]
How can you say I see little cinema...
if I watch lots of films...
Because Cinema doesn't exist yet,
or films either.
[In French]
Cinema doesn't exist yet?
So it's like mathematics before Euclides...
[in French]
And before Einstein...
It's a stuttering... it's clumsy.
It's like mathematics
before Euclides and Einstein,
it's a stuttering, clumsy science.
[In French]
And the things we see, what are they?
Nothing.
[In French]
Really nothing?
Sometimes...
in an old Murnau film,
or... a young Bertolucci film...
you see something happening.
[In French]
Yes, it's true...
[in French]
Sometimes in a young Dreyer film...
Or in an old Rouche film...
[in French]
You can see something different...
Like a flash... that is the truth of Cinema.
Like a bolt of lightning,
that represents the truth of cinema.
[In French]
Let's watch.
Yes... let's watch.
[In French]
Down there, the withered flowers
of other people's holidays.
[In French]
Even when we are...
[in French]
Far from one another...
Even when we're separated...
[in French]
...everything brings us together.
[In French]
The prisons of freedom are falling.
A hint of the view was enough.
A fragment of a view was enough.
[In French]
The sun's eyelid falls on your face.
The sun's eyelid covers your face.
[In French]
Our unmovable weight digs our path.
A womans nudity is wiser
[in French]
Than a philosopher's teachings.
A woman's nudity is wiser
than a philosopher's teachings.
[In French]
Is it your hand, a dazzling souvenir in the sun?
Is it my hand, this dazzling souvenir
in the sun?
[In French]
That sacrifices time
[in French]
To the eternal youth of the perfect flame.
Yes, I sacrifice time
to the eternal youth of the perfect flame.
[In French]
Poor is your hand, to be so indifferent
How poor your hand is,
to be so indifferent...
[in French]
To the twilight, who let everything go.
[In French]
Your hand, that will never be able
[in French]
To distance me from you.
Your hand, that will never be able
to distance me from you.
I am the mirror...
[in French]
I think about what they said...
...so I am the observer,
[in French]
I am a witness...
So I am the image.
[In French]
And I say what they think...
[in French]
So I am the observer.
I am the witness.
[In French]
I am the mirror.
I think about what they said.
[In French]
So I am the reflection.
If existence is not free,
it becomes empty, or neutral.
If it's free, it's nothing but a game.
[In French]
There's a tragic reality... Vietnam.
This country who embodies the ambitions
[in French]
And the hopes of a forgotten world...
...tragically alone.
The earth...
until it gave birth to just trees or birds,
was a free universe.
[In French]
If we analyze Vietnam's loneliness,
[in French]
We fall into distress
Because of this illogic moment of mankind.
The charm of freedom...
lost its splendor...
when the earth...
produced for the first time...
a being who demanded...
freedom as if it were
a law set above the universe.
[In French]
If it's not free, existence becomes empty.
Or neutral.
[In French]
If it's free, it's a game.
There is a tragic situation... Vietnam.
A nation that embodies...
the aspirations and hopes for victory...
of a whole forgotten world.
Vietnam is tragically alone.
[In French]
The earth... until it gave birth
[in French]
To just trees or birds,
Was a free universe.
If we analyze Vietnam's loneliness,
we fall into distress
because of this illogic moment...
that mankind is going through.
[In French]
The charm of freedom lost its splendor
when the earth produced for the first time
a being who demanded freedom
as if it were a law
set above the universe.
Beyond what I am...
[in French]
We have long believed that...
Which fills me with anxiety.
[In French]
...America will be the theatre of great wars...
I meet a being...
[in French]
...fought by all humanity.
And to live only for what fascinates us.
[In French]
The struggle in America...
[in French]
Will happen when the time is right,
Because it's a question of innocence
[in French]
Of size of the continent
And of crimes committed for its liberation.
You have to refuse boredom.
[In French]
Beyond what I am...
We...
have long believed that...
[in French]
Which fills me with anxiety.
...America will be the theatre...
...of great wars...
[in French]
I meet a being...
...fought... by all humanity.
[In French]
...and to live only for what fascinates us.
The struggle in America...
will happen when the time is right,
because...
it's a question of innocence...
of size of the continent...
and of crimes committed for its liberation.
[In French]
You have to refuse boredom.
Because the enemy is there,
always present.
The enemy strikes every day,
and threatens us
with new attacks every day.
These attacks will unite us today,
tomorrow, the day after tomorrow...
[in French]
Because the enemy is there,
He strikes every day,
[in French]
And threatens us with new attacks.
[In French]
These attacks will unite us today,
[in French]
Tomorrow, the day after tomorrow...
To be nude means making the effort...
to climb beyond the first words
in the dark sex of silence.
[In French]
To be nude means making the effort...
[in French]
To climb beyond the first words
In the dark sex of silence.
The nude then becomes
the black and white,
it becomes something that
is no longer a subject
and has no substance...
It is the mortal... silent monster.
[In French]
The nude then becomes
[in French]
The black and white...
It becomes something that
[in French]
Is no longer a subject
And has no substance...
[in French]
It is the mortal silent monster.
Those who prepare
for this necessary union
will be the object
of the people's gratitude.
[In French]
Those who prepare for this union
[in French]
Will receive the people's gratitude.
Without an armed struggle
there is no definite avant garde.
[In French]
There is not a definite avant garde...
[in French]
Without an armed struggle?
[In French]
So what?
Today the Marines are shooting
everything that moves.
[In French]
The Marines are shooting everything that moves?
So what?
After the Cuban revolution...
...after Santo Domingo,
after Greece,
after the Arab-Israeli war,
after the resistance in Hanoi,
after the mercenaries in the Congo,
there's a state of urgency.
[In French]
Is there a state of urgency?
So what?
So there are urgent,
principled reasons,
that entail armed revolutionary
front lines everywhere,
which are disowned
by the European left.
[In French]
What are these revolutionary front lines?
It's my family...
It's revolution.
Your family... is democracy.
[In French]
Yes, revolution is your family.
Democracy is my family. Right.
[In French]
So what?
So, these two things
can't live together.
[In French]
They can't live together, even if they're alone?
No...
not even if they love each other.
What are they doing?!
[In French]
They're still, they don't move.
If they're not moving,
it means it's the end of the film.
[In French]
Is this the end of the film?
Yes.
[In French]
Did you remember the title?
I remember the title now.
It's "The Departure and Return
of the Prodigal Children".
[In French]
The Departure and Return of the Prodigal Children?
What does it mean?
[In French]
Sounds like a biblical title.
It is a biblical title.
It means that each of the prodigal children
returns to their own families.
[In French]
I was right, they will break up
[in French]
And return to their homes.
Let's watch the images
for the last time...
[in French]
We're gonna watch the images again?
[In French]
We can't, the door is closed...
Well, let's listen to the images...
[in French]
Yes... let's listen to the images...
It was the first and only dream.
The first...
...the only dream.
[In French]
Well, goodbye...
No goodbyes...
featuring a group of students
from the University of Rome
- How is it?
- Fine!
Well now...
'Poetry resembles a sun's ray
that shines on this darkness,
covers it with its light
and illuminates
the hidden countenance of things'.
So it's not a work
of empty souls and dull minds.
So artists who,
in the false name of pure art"
or "art for art's sake",
close themselves off
from the commotion of life
and the anxiety of thought...
Ho Chi Minh, cha-cha!
- Get out, you reds!
- Enough, go away!
Don't forget your good manners!
Take your hat off and
your hands out of your pockets!
The students' assembly has decided
that all of today's didactic activities
must be suspended.
What assembly?
We don't recognize any assembly!
All today's professorial lectures
must be suspended.
After my lecture!
Listen, if you want to talk to me
take your hands out of your pockets...
We don't want to talk to you
but to our comrades!
Listen comrades,
I think the most useful thing now,
especially for those
who weren't part of the assembly,
would be to ask us questions.
We want to listen to the lecture!
It's much more interesting!
- You're desperadoes!
- Hooligans!
We've all got the same problems...
Why don't we talk it over together?
Listen,
this isn't the time or place to talk.
According to the timetable
at this time I've got to give a lesson
and no-one will stop me from doing so.
We don't want
to argue with you, professor...
...it would be a waste of time!
- Why?
Do you want to stop me
giving my lesson?
Be honest, have the courage to...
Look, you should change your tone.
Perhaps you don't know
that you're talking to a professor
who's been in a concentration camp
for two years,
I've been in Dachau!
You've been in Dachau,
and now you're talking crap!
Why did you wipe it all off?!
Rewrite everything!
Anyway kids,
why don't we talk about
occupying the university
and about academic authoritarianism?
- Get out, go away!
- No!
Is this the only answer you've got?
And I know why, because university
doesn't teach you to be
an individual with ideas...
but just how to repeat,
to repeat by rote.
It teaches you
how to stay in your place,
to respect the hierarchy...
It teaches you how to command,
but not in a real way
because it's about executing commands
like we obey orders today...
...it's not occupying the university,
bivouacking inside it
or scribbling on the walls
that you will resolve anything.
Given the current crisis
in the representative bodies,
the occupation for us constitutes
the only means of rebellion
able to challenge the abuse of power
of the academic body...
Secondly, the occupation
has meant the discovery
of a common way of working,
breaking the solitude,
the division and individualism
which are the best weapons
of those who wish to keep us
in a passive state.
The university organizes consensus
with the system
whereas we want to organize dissent.
So the occupation
has constituted an effective tool
for all the student movement...
...and for each one of us
was a time of individual growth.
- Leave alone the university!
- Look at that ignorant!
Don't you understand that
while we continue to live
in the professors' pockets
our dissent is impossible...
Stand up!
Hail the "Duce"!
- Buffoons!
- Ruffians!
As the President of this faculty,
I have to say...
that this is lesson time,
so you are obstructing
the execution of a right.
Whether you like it or not,
we're in a democratic country
where there's a parliament
that legislates in harmony
with a constitution that sanctions
equality for all its citizens.
The state is the totality
of the institutions...
...destined to defend the interests
of the rich...
against those of the poor,
maintaining the exploitation
of the workforce.
The law is always enacted by the rich
against the poor...
...and is administered by magistrates
recruited from the ruling class,
who apply it...
with precise class-consciousness.
This coercion is the systematic exercise
of legalized violence
against the exploited.
In every country,
the workers' movements
have had to conquer
the right to be recognized
and to strike through battles...
How dare you insult the professor,
you piece of shit!
...in the conflicts between
capital and work...
the army never intervened
against capital
and always against work...
...to respect this legality means
letting them deceive you.
Think about what you're all doing
before it's too late.
What you're doing is illegal and
I have the duty to tell you that.
We know what we're doing's illegal,
if it was legal
it wouldn't change anything.
That's enough.
I also believe
the university needs some reform,
but I don't think a lot's
needed to make it work well...
more rooms,
the right teaching staff...
No to the masters' schools!
If you stop this agitation,
I'm ready to negotiate with you all
and to organize a schedule of meetings
with the professors...
The problem needs to be faced globally
without stopping this agitation!
You're like a slippery eel!
I'm neither an eel nor a buffoon.
You're buffoons because
you don't know what you want.
Mr. President, I continue to insist
on doing the lesson!
Afterwards I can talk until midnight
standing on my feet here in front of you...
the Germans also kept me
standing up for hours.
I declare, Mr. President,
that I was violently stopped
from giving my lesson,
which was a crime to which
you are all witnesses!
Like the North Vietnamese
are ready to negotiate
as long as the Americans
stop the bombing,
we professors are ready to negotiate
as long as you stop this agitation.
You are the B-52's
who bomb our brains...
...with your stupid stories!
I don't give way to violence,
Mr. President!
You don't need reforms,
you need a reformatory!
Violence has never given good results.
Remember Victor Hugo,
"There's nothing as stupid as winning...
The real glory is in convincing".
You have all my understanding,
believe me kids,
but I can't place myself
outside the law.
- Slave!
- Who said "slave"?!
Slave! Slave! Slave!
Mr. President, just give me the order
and I'll sweep this trash!
Listen Mr. President,
since primary school
they told us to shut up
and obey with no arguments.
We want to free ourselves from
this inferiority complex towards
teachers behind their desks.
If you want me to come out
from behind my desk
during my lessons,
you just have to ask.
There shouldn't be any more desks,
lessons or exams.
Lessons are natural events.
As oysters produce pearls,
so teachers give lessons.
Let's not go too far,
I learned something in university.
What's taught at university
is how to obey
and hence to command,
because what's learned
with authoritarianism
can be taught only
with authoritarianism.
But if there's no exam,
how can you tell
whether or not
the student has learned?
It's not right that
a person who's studied is treated
in the same way
as someone who hasn't studied.
There have always been
the clever and the stupid,
...people of merit or not.
- Racist!
No, it's completely natural.
I think it's our precise duty
to verify who is the cleverest
because it's on them
that the future of our country depends.
The sole merit of your "clever people"
is to have been born into
a rich or cultured family,
while those you call stupid
come from poor families!
You give good votes to those
who can speak well...
...to those who can come here,
to those who can live and breathe
your middle-class culture.
Your discrimination is based
on class, not merit!
That's not true, there are children
of country people and workers here.
Yes, but only 7%, and of those
just 1% manage to graduate.
The middle-class forms
10% of the Italian population
but supplies 90% of the graduates
which will form the future ruling class.
The remaining 10% are supplied
by 90% of the Italian population.
Assuming that you're not so racist
to believe that the stupidity
of the working class is innate,
you can't avoid recognizing
that Italian universities
are universities of class.
Yes, but I can't resolve those problems.
I do my best to understand students
from any class,
and no-one can deny that
when I examine a student I always say:
"Use your own words,
use your own words".
Paternalist!
Paternalism's the mirror image
of authoritarianism,
two sides of the same coin.
Let's speak openly...
Even though I should have power,
I feel I have none.
You don't know this,
but people have been bad
ever since the Twelve Tables.
The strongest survive...
It's pointless to object...
"Homo homini lupus".
You'll understand when
you'll have a family,
a job and children...
You're young now and it's normal.
No, for us "being young" doesn't mean
"not being adults yet".
There's no difference between
the generations,
there's just
the difference between people
who have a critical,
dialectic position regarding reality
and those who passively submit to it.
The logic behind your arguments
is the logic of the inevitable betrayal
in becoming an adult.
It's the logic you followed
and since you don't want
to assume your responsibility
you're trying to devalue our movement
to a matter of age,
youth or other similar banalities.
I won't permit you
to use that kind of language!
Stop arguing with these stiffs,
it's a waste of time,
don't you understand?
You're a scoundrel, a buffoon.
Show me your card.
I won't show you anything!
You don't scare me, you know!
You ARE scared!
Ho Chi Minh!
Calm down, calm down!
You won't get anywhere
by hitting each other!
Let's discuss, let's discuss!
That's enough,
return to your places!
Let me give you my thoughts
about this agitation.
You must understand
that the university
is in a disastrous situation
on every level:
Students, professors, structure.
You could genuinely say
that the established order
is in reality organized chaos.
The professorial chair
as baronial fiefdom,
the police-like attendance checks,
are all elements
of a crisis and putrefaction
for which and against which
you've acted.
Obviously one could talk
about all this in more detail,
but in any case...
In my opinion it's necessary to move on
from this nebulous stage
and build the basis of a collective,
democratic organization
which alone makes possible
the new experiments and hypotheses,
that are...
Fire, fire!
Good! Good!
I'm sorry about
your little book, professor,
but we don't care about your fetishes.
But this is a violence
that hides your lack of ideas.
No, it's a provocation.
But you're putting
yourselves at the level
of fascists and Nazis,
they burned books too.
What's your indiscriminate
hatred for culture all about?
What you call 'culture',
with a capital 'C',
is just the bad conscience
of middle-class society.
If you were a true Marxist
you wouldn't be here accusing us.
You've shown
that you haven't understood
that when a middle-class person
condemns political violence
he masks his fear
using skilful moralistic accusations.
"There's no politics here",
says the middle-class person,
but we assert
the political nature of our action.
The system is violent
in dividing society into classes
and maintains itself
through institutions like schools
at the beck and call of capital.
But you all have a great fear,
a middle-class fear of violence,
and you're indignant about police violence
as if it were illogical,
unnatural and irrational.
But it's not true,
it's the necessary violence
of the system defending itself.
Against this violence of the masters
you persist in defending lawfulness,
the masters' lawfulness...
...which is of itself violent.
So, like Brecht, we say:
"Only violence serves,
where violence reigns".
That means theorizing in favor
of insurrection and terrorism.
Don't you realize
that's playing the fascists' game?
But fascism is neither a concept
nor a moment of the spirit,
it's the masters' weapon.
Miss, I agree with you.
But as long as you continue
to theorize in favor of violence...
For us violence isn't a principle,
it doesn't interest us.
If you place obstacles in our path
we'll overcome them,
if violence is necessary we'll use it.
We're for the abolition of war.
We don't want war, but war
can be abolished by war alone.
Until there are no longer arms,
it's necessary to take up arms.
Don't you realize I'm not your enemy?
You keep saying a horizontal line
separates the academics from the students
but in my opinion the line's vertical...
On the one hand there are
academics and students
who think the university's
got to stay as it is and,
on the other hand,
there are those who want to change it.
It's clear which side I'm on.
We agree you're not all the same
but it's pointless
looking at each individual case.
As professors
in our class-conscious university
you're our enemies because
you're tools of a repressive system.
That's absurd!
Students against professors...
If the students and professors
made a united front
then the struggle
for reform would be...
Reform and batons are two means
to reach the same objective:
The consolidation of the system.
That's extremism, stupid extremism!
Why don't you want to understand
that every struggle for progress
is a struggle that moves towards
the socialist objective...
...I say that if you're able
to transform and improve
the structure of universities,
it will be your best contribution
to the struggle for the country's
socialist reform.
You mean for its
capitalist rationalization!
We believe that a struggle
isolated in the universities
would have no revolutionary results.
That's why our movement
rejects making simple demands.
Today, becoming organized
like trade unions
means delegating
your own struggle to the parties
and refusing to be political,
and we reject that.
That's just cheap indifference...
and mistrust of political parties!
No, it's not a general rejection
of every party,
it's a conscious rejection
of a certain kind of struggle
that tries to imprison
every revolutionary drive
in middle-class parliamentarianism.
That's just hot air!
Be concrete, if you can!
Silly, stupid idiots!
Ignorants!
We believe in
the student movement's potential
that being closely connected
to the university structure
must understand
the relation of this structure
to the whole capitalist
structure of which it's a part.
But you don't see how
the struggle will develop over time.
Out of your struggle will come
a democratic university
no longer aimed at
preparing you for the industry
or subject to capitalist interests.
It won't be just technicians
who come out of this university,
not just the passive executors
of social exploitation.
That's why I'm talking about
the institutionalization
of the results of your struggle...
It would be a great result
against the conservative forces
to undermine them
in a centre of privilege.
Then tomorrow you can
take up the struggle again
from a more advanced position.
So you don't really
want to understand.
We don't believe
in a university that's different
or even legalized
to be against the system.
University can't become
a happy island of socialism
inside a capitalist society.
You speak in bad faith!
The system only tolerates
those reforms
that don't change
current class relationships.
This means that
the system is unassailable
so what are we struggling for?
You might as well just wait
for it to blow itself apart.
There's no need to prove that
you're even stupider than we thought.
You know very well that a new system,
a socialist system,
can't gradually build itself
inside the old capitalist system.
The current ruling class
wouldn't allow itself
to be expropriated bit by bit,
sector by sector.
A global strategy is needed,
the question of power
must be addressed.
- Right, that's what I was just saying...
- "Right" what?!
Listen, I'm ready for
the inevitable wolf-whistles
but I'll say it in any case
since it's what I think.
The problem, in my opinion,
isn't to conduct
a sectional isolated struggle
but to return to the fundamental
political crux of the matter,
to reconnect to those political forces
that have been fighting for decades
for democratic socialist change
in our country.
- That's enough about the CP!
- Revisionist!
- Sell-out!
- Conformist!
Chairman Mao says,
"Some Western capitalist countries
tolerate the legal presence
of communist parties
only to the extent that they
do not damage
fundamental middle-class interests.
Beyond those limits
they are no longer tolerated."
Student power!
- That's enough stock phrases!
- You're a stock professor!
Student power means much more
than power to the students.
It means not accepting the role
of the professional in society,
it means overcoming
the isolated condition of the student,
it means mass mobilization.
The whole movement must stem
from a clearly
anti-capitalist conscience.
With this conscience
the students make social actions
and connect
with forces against the system,
and they mature through direct contact
with the needs of the working class
which they try to interpret
in a way that provokes
revolutionary conflict.
That's why "student power"
doesn't mean trade union demands
but fully-involved political work.
For God's sake,
that's not the problem!
The problem is
that you're all intellectuals
so you can only find opportunities
for revolutionary struggle
within the Party!
Why can't you see that if
the students demonstrate today
it's not to have more rooms
or to have the accounts published,
it's because they're fighting
against the system
or at least
they're starting to fight against it!
- Yes, of course!
- 'Of course' what?!
Why do you think they're not doing it
in the traditional way?
Why do you think they no longer pass
through the parties?
Because they're fed up with
the democratic route to socialism,
with the appeals for anti-fascist unity.
You must understand that our power
comes from the crisis in your strategy.
What crisis?!
You're making me lose my patience!
Is it just you
who has the right to lose patience?!
And why do you always
take it out on the Communist Party?
Just look at you!
For aggressive revolutionary politics
you need a self-discipline
that you can only dream of,
plus heroic willpower
and a capacity for suffering.
And let me say that you seem
to have fun with your revolution,
but remember a revolution
is not a variety show
and this is not a stage!
This is a farce that's teaching us a lot.
First of all to despise
those who we used to fear.
Look, if you talk like that
I'll tell you what I really think
about you and your comrades.
You're a shoddy
minority of pro-Chinese,
you're irresponsible and fanatical,
you want to deceive
the majority of students
who want to change the university
and who know the how,
the when and the limits.
And I must say something else...
you're ungrateful,
because if the Communist press
hadn't been on your side,
if our MP's...
You would have been...
Children!!!
The police!
I'm against it in principle,
but these are provocations...
they're irresponsible provocateurs.
I'm against it in principle,
but in this case it's necessary.
We're here to restore order
to this chaos!
You'll be sorry for what you've done.
You've overstepped all the limits...
Every limit...
of reasonableness. Inspector!
In the name of the law
I order you to leave this room.
Come on!
Hit them hard, go on!
Why don't they feel any pain?
Give it to me, give it to me!
Bastards, I know you're
in the service of foreign powers.
You're crazy,
where do get this courage?
Rogues! Jailbirds!
Long live the police!
Ripped by:
SkyFury