The 2020 Tokyo Olympics!
Our panelists will discuss
the Olympics we're hosting in 5 years.
The 1964 Tokyo Olympics symbolises
our economic miracle.
What will the 2020 Tokyo Olympics
be for us?
Some worry about the negative impact
of urban renewal.
Well, internationally...
the nuclear crisis isn't over...
From the point of view of
brain science
trying new things
increases dopamine levels.
That's a no-brainer!
No, really!
Sports isn't the great unifier
it once was.
The Olympics isn't for kids.
It's the children who enjoy the games
not adults.
They're hopeless!
They lie around doing nothing!
They won't even watch this show.
They're so lazy!
The 2020 Olympics will make Japan
great again.
It will bring prosperity
to all of us.
Everyone... except one person.
Only he will miss out.
I mean that pathetic
Ryoichi Suzuki.
He's so behind.
This man is hopeless.
A national disgrace.
Ryoichi Suzuki is out of date.
No one would want him.
That's the opinion of the
brain science community too.
His name repulses me.
Why does he exist?
33-year-old Suzuki
is an ex-rock singer.
He had a band when he was 21.
He quit because no one came
to his 3 concerts.
And he became a clerk.
Mr. Tahara, say something to him.
Suzuki, you're history.
Ouch!
Open up!
- You loser, Suzuki.
- You're hopeless!
You're finished!
Wait!
Watch it!
Sorry.
Ouch!
Hi, loser!
Not well?
Good morning.
Excuse me.
Loser! You coming or what?
.
What music's that?
See here?
Do it, please.
Yes, sir.
Sorry!
I haven't spoken yet.
Piece. A piece of music.
There'd be no music without
our components.
They're valuable.
Unlike you!
Go.
Work!
Don't let him get to you.
Ouch...
Hazardous Waste
Um...
If you have a stomach ache...
Take these.
Bargain Sale
Turtles for Sale
This one.
I want it!
70 years ago atomic bombs
were dropped in Japan.
We asked people
which country dropped
the atomic bombs.
Little Turtle.
This is who I really am.
I'm a clerk by day but
this is the real me.
Which country dropped A-bombs
in Hiroshima and Nagasaki?
Dunno. Not the USA, they're
our friends.
See the penguins on the iceberg?
There are various shapes
of icebergs.
They don't taste salty.
I'm an iceberg.
Are you listening?
You only see an iceberg's tip.
You listening?
I'm actually big.
Most of me is underwater, Turtle!
Turtle...
You deserve a better name...
Get Rich Quickly
A little turtle with no name
What's a good name?
.
We asked 100 young people what
"pikadon" means?
What does "pikadon" mean?
Can you tell me?
I don't know.
How about you?
You don't?
A kaiju?
A kaiju!
Pikadon... Just like a kaiju!
Pikadon!
Pikadon.
Atomic bombs were
nicknamed "Pikadon."
"Pika" is a flash and
"don" is kaboom!
I'm like the tip of an iceberg.
The biggest part of me is
underwater
Ryoichi Suzuki will be big and
leave this place.
Help me become big.
Help me become a huge iceberg.
My hopes and dreams are with you!
Off you go!
Good!
Win office contest,
Collect $150,000!
Find oil field. $200,000!
Stock Price Increase!
Win horse race!
Nobel Prize!
Win a big bet!
Millionaire / Homeless
Good. Go to the mansion!
Homeless
No, idiot, don't go that way!
No!
This is my treasure!
It's from Yuko Terashima.
I love Yuko Terashima!
I want to date her.
God, please!
Did you hear that?
Yes, Ryoichi loves Yuko
What a joke!
The 2020 Olympic preparations
are underway
with the completion of
Nippon Stadium.
The 80,000 capacity stadium
won't only be for sport
it'll be a concert venue too.
Start!
Form a band.
Main act at O-East in Shibuya
Top indie band.
Major label deal.
3 concerts at Shibuya Hall.
Big break! Sexiest man alive!
Live at Budokan!
Million copies sold.
Number I for 3 weeks.
Live at Nippon Stadium!
Done!
Onto Nippon Stadium!
Form a band!
O-East, main act!
Shibuya!
The sexiest man!
Platinum!
Live at Nippon Stadium!
I made it!
Nippon Stadium...
You listening, Pikadon?
Pikadon, we'll go to Nippon Stadium!
It opened!
And this one?
It opened! Pikadon!
Good morning
Nippon Stadium. Nippon Stadium...
Work hard,
Loser.
- Off we go.
- See you.
Nippon Stadium. Nippon Stadium...
To the goal, Pikadon.
Zap! Zap!
Kaboom! Die, kaboom!
Wiped out!
Go, Kaiju Pikadon!
To Nippon Stadium!
Off to Nippon Stadium you go!
Kaiju Pikadon,
my hopes and dreams are with you!
Go to Nippon Stadium!
Congratulations!
LOVE & PEACE
Look, Pika. It's raining.
Look.
Yuko.
I'll be big one day.
When that happens
will you be my girl?
Dinner's ready, Pikadon.
You two are close.
Say "Hi!"
Hello!
You know my dreams.
Help them come true.
You're my only friend.
Hi, buddy
What is it?
Are you happy?
Ask Suzuki about these.
Can you tell me what these
receipts are for?
Look, it's a turtle!
Oh, my God! He has a turtle!
Show me!
It's his girlfriend.
What's going on?
Suzuki, come here.
Yes.
With the thing!
- Sorry!
- I didn't speak yet!
That your missing piece?
Is it?
Loser!
Don't worry.
Pathetic!
Turtles are bad news.
- Very bad.
- No turtles.
Sorry, Pika...
Get rid of it! Get rid of it!
No! I didn't mean it!
Oh, Pikadon!
Get away, freak!
Forgive me!
Get off me!
- Pikadon, sorry!
- Stay away!
Pika...
Pikadon!
- A new one.
- Who?
A new friend!
Come on!
A new friend.
Who is it now?
I want to see!
Hi, little guy.
You found us.
Welcome to Lost & Found Heaven
- It's a turtle
- Yes.
He's so cute!
There's one more.
It's no good.
It's in pieces.
Sulkie, get the tools.
Okay.
Pa, can you fix it?
Where are the tools?
Let's see... Is this it?
My name is Maria. What's yours?
- He can't talk!
- Not yet.
Not without Pa's candy.
Besides, down here
you can forget your old name.
After our former owners threw us out.
- But Sulkie...
- Am I right?
Stop feeling sorry for yourselves.
I love the name my owner gave me.
It was my owner's parents
who threw me out in her absence.
My owner still...
Yes, you told us that before
Don't sulk.
Don't waste your time.
It's so battered.
- He can do it.
- Pa, give it up.
Can you fix it?
He can't.
Oh, no.
What a shame!
It's so sad.
Pa, I knew you could!
You did it!
I don't know how you ended up here
but...
you're here now.
You can relax and recuperate.
Right?
Everybody here has a similar
story to you.
- We're friends.
- You're one of us.
Everyone, be nice to your
new friend!
Yay!
I'm off to bed.
OK?
It's still early.
Pa.
- Give him a candy.
- Why?
So we can talk.
Good idea.
You want to talk. Okay.
One candy, coming up.
Oh, boy.
I want to know his name.
It's ready.
Ouch, it's hot!
Oh, Pa!
Oh, boy.
Now you've done it!
Where's the Speech candy?
- Can I have one?
.
- Help me, guys.
Help me clean up.
Looks yummy.
Celebration!
Turtle! Turtle!...
What's your name, Turtle?
It's time for the ceremony.
Have a candy, Turtle.
Here.
How's that? Can you talk?
I'm Maria What is your name?
Hey?
- Turtles are quiet.
- He won't talk.
Pa, don't fall asleep.
Okay.
Say something
Turtle?
He won't talk.
It's the humans' fault.
They throw away their things
when they're bored.
He's too hurt to speak.
Be quiet!
Don't sulk.
What was your owner like?
I used to live with
a lovely family.
They loved me so much.
Then why are you here?
My owner's name is Yuri.
She's a very pretty girl.
She held me when she slept.
Guys, don't start
Don't leave me...
Why did you throw me away?
I want to go home.
Don't leave me
Please keep me...
I want to go home.
I won't ever forget you...
I won't...
I'll never forget!
Pikadon, I won't ever forget you!
Pikadon
I won't ever forget you
With the Tokyo Olympics ahead
The whole nation will
get richer and prosper
I'll try to throw away the
bitter past
With my eyes closed
Ears covered
And my mouth shut
But no matter how hard
I pretend to be happy...
Turtle?
Oops...!
- Turtle!
- What's wrong?
What's going on, Pa?
- It's a mistake!
- What?
What did you do?
Listen, Turtle.
Remember the candy I gave you?
That wasn't Speech candy.
I gave you the Wish candy instead.
You had such a candy?
You never mentioned it!
We want it too, don't we?
Yes!
It's unfair. I can talk
but that's all.
Look at my old dress!
I have a wish list too.
Give me a candy, please.
Why didn't you tell us?
- You want Wish candy?
- Yes, we do!
You could have one
if you want it so badly but...
Listen. Your wishes will get
bigger every time
and you'll grow big
like Turtle here.
I can live with that!
Guys, get a grip!
I guess you can have
one little wish but...
Is one wish enough?
I just want to go home.
- Yes.
- Me too!
Amen!
Listen, Maria.
What if you went home
and your owner asked you
"Maria, can you make my
wishes come true, too?"
Then what?
I wouldn't mind.
But you don't know
how greedy people can be.
It'll be one wish after another.
Finally it'll be
monster-sized wishes!
No!
Then what would you do?
But I...
Now listen carefully.
I know what you'd wish for.
I'll make your wishes
come true before the year ends.
That's how I help guys like you
find happy lives.
Your turn will come soon.
It's almost the end of the year!
Not me.
Sulkie?
.
I'll stay. I don't want to go
back to my old life
and be thrown out again.
I'll stay here with you, Pa.
Sulkie, listen to me.
Turtle is in a dangerous
condition now.
He's in pain
and he's getting too big.
His owner must have asked him for
a big wish.
I can't imagine.
Pa, how much bigger do you think
he'll get?
He could get much, much bigger...
All Turtle's thinking about
is the owner who threw him away.
He loves him so much.
Whoever threw the turtle away is
in for many good things.
Many good things...
Pikadon
It's that guy!
Hello again!
Come with us.
Sorry! Sorry!
He appeared out of nowhere and...
He freaked me out.
Pikadon!
Get off!
Let me go, please!
The wait is over!
I brought along
an insane guest for you!
Give him a big hand!
This man...
He goes crazy
when he sees this!
Listen up.
This is the universe as imagined
by ancient people.
It's hilarious!
The world rests on top
of a turtle.
The world is supported
by a turtle!
See? He's insane.
Here!
You can use my guitar.
Why don't you sing?
Go ahead and sing.
Sing!
Use the mic.
Is this OK?
"With the Tokyo Olympics ahead
The whole nation will
get richer and prosper
I'll try to throw away the
bitter past
With my eyes closed, ears covered
and my mouth shut
But no matter how hard
I pretend to be happy...
Pikadon, I won't ever forget you!
you're burned into my brain
your ace when you were washed away
f
How can I go on
pretending that I'm over you!
Pikadon, I won't ever forget you!
You've got to get him.
I'd do anything to get you back now!
Because it's impossible
to put you behind me
to put you behind me".
Wait!
Not so fast.
Who manages you?
You're great!
The turtle!
Get him!
Pikadon, come back to me!
Pikadon!
Why did he get so big?
- It he OK?
- Is he in pain?
I can't figure him out.
He's very happy.
What?
.
Turtle, give me this
when it's done.
No turtle today?
Come on!
Thank you.
Ryoichi Suzuki.
What did you do yesterday?
.
Go out with your pet?
- Sorry.
- Never mind! You're our little pet.
Hey, where is your pet today?
Not here today?
How's your turtle?
Forgive me!
Pika...
Pikadon!
Pikadon, come back!
Get to work!
You have a visitor.
- Coffee for me.
- Get her coffee.
Suzuki. She's here to see you.
So you're Ryoichi Suzuki?
May I help you?
I saw your performance yesterday.
You were amazing!
- Follow me.
- But...
Please sign with our label
right away.
No song has ever got me
so excited!
I promise that I'll make
you a star!
You were born to be a star!
It's about not forgetting
the A-bomb.
Uh, right.
It's a unique anti-war song.
Everyone's forgotten
those miserable times.
Including the A-bombs.
A message about A-bombs in this
apathetic country
is so powerful.
Uh, well...
Remember the A-bombs!
Don't forget the war!
This song is so relevant
right now.
Uh... Right.
I'm Inagawa.
I loved your Pikadon.
Welcome aboard.
Welcome.
There's someone I want you to meet.
Hey, Shu!
Sorry about the other day.
"Pikadon, I won't ever forget you"
"Love & Peace, I won't
ever forget you"
Love & Peace Love it!
You're now with a band
called Revolution Q.
Revolution Q...
The members are, Shu, Dead,
Nega and Jane.
As of today, you're Wild Ryo.
Wild Ryo...?
Sign the contract, Wild Ryo.
Can I call you Ryo?
Quit your job, Ryo.
What?
Yeah, you should quit!
It doesn't suit your image and
you don't have time for it.
You will be busy.
Listen. You're a hero fighting
the establishment.
A modern-day protest singer.
You're a tough and rebellious agitator!
I do think pikadon should go
How about Love & Peace?
Love & Peace, I won't
ever forget you
That's dope!
Ryo.
Love & Peace, I won't
ever forget you!
I'm on your side.
I have to piss.
It's unreal...
Ryo, listen well.
At the end of the year,
quit Revolution Q.
And you'll be left with the fame
And I'll still be your manager.
But...
It'll make headlines
Maybe...
I'll go home and think it over.
Hey, where are you going?
To my apartment...
Look in there.
We went ahead and moved in your stuff.
What?
This is your home.
But how...?
I'm kidding! It cost a lot
to replicate.
Just like your place.
You can go home.
It's still there.
I'll put this here.
You'll understand tomorrow.
Why don't you sleep on it?
I'm sorry!
What's wrong with you?
You're late!
Do you hear me?
Are you listening, Turtle?
You have a problem, Turtle?
Say something!
I'll get you fired!
I'd like you to come.
A live show?
A turtle band?
I'm a vocalist.
A vocalist!
I'm called Wild Ryo, as of today.
It says that.
Wild Ryo?
OK, we'll come.
Is it at a pet shop?
Ready Ryo? Take 1.
A week after Revolution Q's debut
"With the Tokyo Olympics ahead
The whole nation will
get richer and prosper
I'll try to throw away the
bitter past"
10 days later
"With my eyes closed, ears covered
and my mouth shut
But no matter how hard
I pretend to be happy...
Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you!
Your face when you were washed away
You're burned into my brain
How can I go on
pretending that I'm over you!
Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you!
I'd do anything to get you back now!"
You're incredible!
Not bad. Not bad at all.
Thanks.
You came.
- Welcome home
- Hi, Pa.
Turtle looks content.
Yeah, he does.
I'm happy for you.
Something good must have
happened out there.
This is the hit song, "Love & Peace".
It's not a wimpy love song,
it's a real song!
Revolution Q are our heroes!
He's having fun.
I bet.
He'll become big,
like Turtle here.
Right.
He's back.
Pa's home.
Welcome home!
Hi, Pa!
I'm home, children!
Home sweet home!
Oh, yes.
Oh, Turtle, you've grown so big!
Pa, Turtle is so happy.
Don't laugh it off.
If he gets too big
we won't have space for him.
Pa, listen to the song.
I think this song's
for Turtle.
What?
.
Is that why you're happy, huh?
Love & Peace!
What's wrong PC-300?
Uh, Pa...
Yes, Maria?
Don't be mad...
What is it?
Well...
Tell me.
PC-300 drank your whiskey.
What?
I didn't.
Oops!
OK, I did.
I'm drunk.
You...!
Hic! I'm totally drunk!
I won't ever forget you, Turtle...
Pa, can you fix him?
Silly old robot.
Pa, when do you think
we can leave this place?
Let's see. In about a month.
A month?
But I'm not a puppy anymore.
I can't go back home.
He's right. How can we go back?
Tell us!
I'm not a cute puppy anymore...
- Come on...
- It's so sad.
- Don't you agree, Bunny?
- Yes.
Pa.
Okay, everybody, listen up
Let me tell you what
I do every year.
I take care of kids
in circumstances like you
and help them go home.
This is like a school and
you come for a year.
Maybe I'll find you a nicer place
this time, I mean...
You know what I'm trying to say.
You know don't you?
,.
It's cosy here but
you can't stay forever.
It'd be packed with kids!
There'd be too many of you.
That's why we have this amount
Because you go
to a nicer place.
I'll help you...
You know what I mean.
I think I'm thirsty.
I need something to drink.
I'll drink some water.
Pa.
I'll have some water.
Look at me, I'm so dirty!
Me too!
I want to go out!
Guys...
Leave if you want to!
Go back to your old home.
Do you expect your ex-owners
to be glad to see you?
"Oh, you're home!
Come in and have some milk."
It won't be like that.
Look, Tama!
You'll end up like them!
- Don't...
- You'll go out and get caught!
If you don't want to be impounded
stay here!
"Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you
Love & Peace!
Your face when you were washed away
You're burned into my brain
How can I go on
pretending that I'm over you!
Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you
Love & Peace!"
I can't bear this...
"I'd do anything to get you back now!
Because it's impossible
to put you behind me
to put you behind me"
Turtle...?
I can't do it!
Who am I kidding?
I can't write a song.
Help! What am I going to do?
Was this open...?
What's going on...?
What?
Pik...
Pika!
Pikadon!
Oh, my God, you're so big!
Hold it there.
And...?
Lyrics?
What?
What is it?
What do you want?
"Even now - they're not - severed"
"The ties - that bind - us"
"There's no end - to our friendship"
"Nothing's - changed between us"
"That's right - we're brothers"
"Forever and - ever
We'll be together"
Sorry, Pika.
I was horrible to you.
Do you forgive me?
Pika...
Yes! I'll be right there!
Hold on!
Pika.
Hide under this and stay still.
Who is it? I'm in the middle
of something...
Hi. Your eyes are red.
- Really?
- I'll cook something.
No, today's no good...
What is that?
- Can you cook me something after all?
- What's this?
- My favorite chair. So life-like.
- It's cute...
Stop!
It's the latest technology.
Like clap-on lights.
How do you like my intro?
It's the turtle!
What turtle?
- The one you had at the office
- Please go.
- It's the turtle!
- Go!
It's OK. Don't be embarrassed.
- What are you talking about?
- Cute.
I'm Wild Ryo, not the Ryoichi you knew!
Please go!
- It's OK. It's cute!
- Go!
- The turtle...
- Leave!
Turtle!
Huh?
Pikadon, where are you?
Don't go yet! Pikadon!
"Gnash your teeth hard
Let's go!
Gnash your teeth hard
Now gnash and gnaw
Let's fly!
Keep 'em nice, Ga-Ga-Ga
with Gi-Gi-Gi!
Keep 'em shiny and clean!"
I love you all!
Thanks for coming to see me.
I want you to hear my new song.
From yours truly
"Even now, they're not severed
The ties that bind us
There's no end to our friendship
Nothing's changed between us
That's right, we're brothers
Forever and ever
We'll be together"
- How was I?
- The best.
How dare you end with a solo?
Relax, it'll sell.
No way. Don't put our name on
that song.
Go ahead, leave!
- Encore?
- I'll go.
We do anti-establishment songs,
not ballads!
Shut up! You wouldn't be here
if it wasn't for me.
Are you ready?
I'm all revved up now!
Buckle up, y'all!
"Even now they're not severed
The ties that bind us
There's no end to our friendship
Nothing's changed between us
That's right, we're brothers
Forever and ever
We'll be together"
Cheers!
Someone came
Ryo, it's a woman named
Yuko Terashima.
I don't want to see her.
Ryo's not here.
"Even now they're not severed
The ties that bind us
There's no end to our friendship
Nothing's changed between us
That's right, we're brothers
Forever and ever
We'll be together"
Here's the genius!
Keep making great melodies!
That was great.
You're the man.
They're on sale! Buy more!
A bargain sale.
- Clearance sale!
- No way.
You can't mark down lives.
They're on sale!
They are not. You'll get bored
and chuck them anyway!
- Go away, bum!
- Don't be deceived.
Buy one! They're on sale.
Hey!
Hang in there
Don't touch it.
You like reindeers?
- I love them.
- OK, go.
- They're my friends.
- Go away.
My friends.
Check this out, it's Christmas!
- Don't get trashed.
- Go!
They're on sale!
Oh, bull!
- They're not.
- You still here?
They're not cheap.
Are you buying?
You're Santa?
The next song
I want the next song...
Come on, I need the next song!
Pa, you're up working so early
See this gate? It's not here
to lock you in.
It's to protect you.
"Out in the streets
the breeze is cold
You'd be left frozen
and you know it
That's why you're
better off inside"
Oh, Turtle, look at you.
You're so big!
Humongous!
Turtle.
Pa says you should never
go outside
But he has to
take the new song to his owner.
Turtle...
Ryo, every song you write is good.
Sing something for me.
It's not that easy.
Recent sightings of
an unusually big creature in Tokyo
indicate that it could be a
large turtle.
Every night around midnight
the turtle has been seen
in this area.
There are photos of the turtle
on the web...
- Hello.
- Don't you want to see me?
Hazardous Waste
Tell me the truth What did you
think of me back then?
Answer me.
- I don't know...
- You mocked me.
Now you like me.
Is this about the turtle?
Are you ashamed about it?
It's not about the turtle!
"Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you
Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you"
How about another shot, Pa?
Right, Maria?
Yes. Bottoms up, Pa.
Right, PC?
Right! And you can sleep all you like!
Yay, Pa!
"The whole nation will
get richer and prosper
I'll try to throw away the
bitter past
With my eyes closed, ears covered
and my mouth shut
But no matter how hard
I pretend to be happy..."
Are you ready?
Pull!
Open gate!
"You're burned into my brain
f
your ace when you were washed away
How can I go on
pretending that I'm over you!
Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you"
Here comes the main street.
Turtle, now you can finally see him!
"I'd do anything to get you back now!
Because it's impossible
to put you behind me
How can I go on
pretending that I'm over you!
I want to get you back,
Love & Peace!"
I'm going to
teach you a lesson, people!
I am Sulkie who always sulks
That's me, Sulkie!
- How noisy!
- Hush!
Whoa, whoa!
Turtle?
The condo isn't this way.
Hey!
Turtle what's wrong?
Hey, Turtle!
Maybe this is good.
Why?
.
This will take us to
his owner's concert.
Look! It's the shop!
What?
.
I was at that shop before.
- Which one?
- There!
I was in the show window like them.
So pretty
I wonder how Yuri is.
Were you a Christmas present, PC?
I was a birthday present.
Oh, the memories! Yuri got me
for Christmas and it was snowing.
- It was beautiful.
- Nice.
"Even now they're not severed
The ties that bind us"
We're almost there
Wake up, Sulkie! Come on!
Sulkie, we're headed
for the music venue!
What's wrong with that?
We can't go in.
Let's go back.
Turtle, stop!
You going alone?
No, you can't!
OK then. I'll go with him
so you two can go back.
Let's go, Maria.
Off it goes!
Oops! Keep moving!
Walk faster!
Maria!
PC-300, stay with Maria.
Aye sir!
Turtle!
Get moving!
PC...
Let's go back.
Listen, I have an important
announcement to make.
Tonight Revolution Q will disband!
We are one!
Keep your cool! Not now!
Wait. He has a press conference.
Let's go.
Chill out!
Have a nice life.
Once you go in there
there's no turning back.
I see. This is goodbye then.
That owner of yours...
Ryo!
Don't quit!
To maintain integrity as
an anti-war rock singer
Wild Ryo insisted on Revolution Q
disbanding.
Why now? How about
the others?
I heard there's animosity.
Ryo! Don't quit!
Well?
Calm down.
My rebellious
rock 'n' roller spirit
might rot while I'm
with a major label.
You going solo?
Who are you with?
A turtle!
Relax. It's under control.
Believe it or not
I called him with telepathy.
Yes, telepathy.
You see, my next song will be
about preserving nature.
And I'd say he's a victim of
nature's violation.
I just thought of a new melody.
I know. I'll ask the turtle
to sing it for us.
Little turtle can you sing it?
I'm sending you my telepathy.
That's my new song.
He sang the melody that I came up with
Revolution Q disbanded
so I can spread my message
about nature, nuclear issues
and war.
And the human ego.
These issues are all connected.
I want love & peace for the world.
That's what I sing for!
Ryo, you're so cool!
Everyone, take photos of
us together.
We're Love and Peace,
the turtle and I.
The turtle is Love
and I am Peace.
Love baby, bring peace to everyone
Love & Peace!
Cool, Ryo!
Give me a break!
Tell me about the turtle!
Don't shut me out!
You're not in charge!
You exploited us!
- You're no rebel.
- You fraud!
You just used us!
What are you saying?
Ryo brought you success.
You're the ones who used him.
You...
You're famous.
Now leave Ryo alone.
Ryoichi.
Aren't we friends?
Pull yourself, cry baby!
You too!
Grow up!
Alright, I'll let you stay.
You can play for me.
OK?
Thank you.
Fascinating.
The turtle was named Love.
He appeared with Wild Ryo...
Where's PC?
He went back.
Let's go.
No, there's nothing back
there for me.
Pa will worry...
He's a liar!
He promised us great things
just to silence us.
I don't care. I'm staying.
Why don't you all disappear!
That cat talked!
It's a talking cat! It talks!
It talked!
Bye-bye, Sulkie.
Maria, we're going now.
I'll stay here!
Suit yourself.
I must meet him once a week...
Right.
Love!
You're not hurt?
You can't form a band with
a turtle...
We're one, the turtle and I!
Wait for me!
- Ryo?
- You don't get it!
Let him go!
Amazing!
What kind of mutation is this?
.
This is my treasure
What's that about?
Wild Ryo Live on Dec. 25, 2015
It's snowing!
How beautiful...
- Look at this.
- Cute!
So is yours.
- Girls, let's go!
- Okay!
That's Yuri!
But Yuri, why...?
Yuri, don't go!
Christmas bargain sale!
Merry Christmas!
We're having a sale!
Why...?
Yuri...
Why is everybody feeling down?
.
It's Christmas!
Maria and Turtle have gone...
I should have brought Maria back.
Pa, you lied when you said
nice things were ahead.
You made it up.
Turtle has disappeared...
What about Maria?
Yeah!
OK, kids. I know that you have
your doubts
But I promise that
Turtle and Maria will come back.
Don't worry.
Pa...
And something nice will happen
to all of you.
I think this occasion
calls for a toast.
I'll get you all one of my
special drinks.
Wait here.
Hey, what's going on with
you guys?
Pa's trying to make you feel good.
When he comes back,
pretend to have fun.
- Okay.
- Alright.
Copy that.
Let's have some fun, shall we?
Huh?
Merry Christmas, Pa!
- It's party time!
- We should do it more often!
Merry Christmas!
Merry Christmas, Pa!
Take a break! Come down
for a special drink!
Yay!
Go on.
Thank you, Pa.
How about you, Gori?
Thanks.
One for you, Bear.
This is delicious!
Thank you, Pa.
- Hand these out.
- Shall do.
I'm stuck...!
Everyone! When Maria and Turtle
came back, we'll have another party.
Yes, let's!
You know, I've been to the ocean.
Really? That's amazing!
.
Yeah.
Pa, there's a reindeer!
- So there is!
- It's big!
Goodbye.
Maria.
Pa...
I might be just imagining it but
didn't you carry me like this
once before?
Long ago.
Isn't that funny?
Sweet dreams, Maria.
This time it'll work out.
Don't come back here.
Take care, Sulkie.
You too, PC
Have a nice life, everyone.
Off we go!
The dreams you give out
will return next year.
OK, let's go!
Wild Ryo, Live at Nippon Stadium
At Nippon Stadium
Tomorrow!
Line up and hold out your ticket.
Concert T-shirts are available
only today!
Ryo! Ryo! Ryo!...
Looking good!
Yuko, get closer!
Go ahead!
Autograph, please!
That's cool!
My dream has outgrown
this stadium.
I want to grow bigger
You will.
I'll go worldwide.
Go to the top of the world!
Ryo!
Hello.
There's Turtle!
Turtle.
Hello.
Little Turtle.
I guess your owner has
another big wish.
You'll grow even bigger than this!
Won't he?
Oh! They can't see me
Because they only believe in science.
Little Turtle, hang in there.
This will end soon.
I'll give this to you
so you can speak for yourself.
The goal is near.
Merry Christmas.
I wish you happiness, Turtle.
"Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you"
Welcome to the Wild Ryo Concert!
Oh, no! Evacuate immediately!
Just go!
Out of the lab!
Come on!
"Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you
Love & Peace!
I won't ever forget you"
Live from Akihabara.
A giant turtle escaped a
lab and trampled Asakusa.
It's headed west.
It might be Love the turtle
who appeared with Wild Ryo.
This is Shinjuku. A state of emergency
has been declared.
Love!
Love leaves destruction
in his wake.
So far no casualties
have been reported
Love's slow pace meant citizens
could escape.
To Nippon Stadium you go!
My hopes and dreams are with you!
Kaiju Pikadon!
Go to Nippon Stadium!
"Because it's impossible
to put you behind me
Because it's impossible
to put you behind me"
Pikadon...!
I'm an iceberg.
Are you listening to me?
You can only see the tip of it.
Love!
The biggest part of me is hidden
underwater.
I'm actually big.
Are you listening to me?
Ryoichi Suzuki will be big!
I'll escape this place someday.
He's a star!
A star on the rise!
I love Yuko Terashima!
I love her!
I want to date her.
God, please!
He's talking about you!
Yes!
Pikadon?
Pikadon!
Ryo!
Are you OK?
Hey, Ryo!
Hey!
Ryo!
Let her pass please!
Ryo, what's wrong?
Ryo...
"Last night I slept in the car
Holding my girl's hand
Parked in the city ballpark lot
We were wrapped up in a blanket
On the radio a slow ballad played
The fog settles around the windows
I knew nothing bad
could happen to us
I heard her talking in her sleep
I mean it, I really do
On the radio a slow ballad played
The fog settles around the windows
I knew nothing bad
could happen to us
And we both had dreams
Our dreams might be almost the same"
Hi, Turtle...
Is it you?
Hiroki Hasegawa
Kumiko Aso
Kiyohiko Shibukawa
Eita Okuno
Makita Sports
Motoki Fukami
Toru Tezuka
(Voice)
Gen Hoshino
Shoko Nakagawa
(Voice)
Inuko Inuyama
Ikue Otani
Miyuki Matsuda
Toshiyuki Nishida
Executive Producers
Hirofumi Shigemura/Shuichi Nagasawa
Hidetoshi Yamamoto/Naoto Mliyamoto
Producers
Atsushi Moriyama/Masao Teshima
Eiichi Kamagata/TsutomuYanagimura
Senior Production Manager
Tsuyoshi Suzuki
Line Producer
Keiichiro Sato
Music by
Yasuhiko Fukuda
Cinematographer
Shinya Kimura
Lighting
Eiji Oshita
Production Designer
Takeshi Shimizu
Property Master
Kenji Iwai
Sound Recordist
Hajime Komiya
Sound Effects
Masashi Saito
Film Editor
Junichi Ito
Script Supervisor
Yuko Sadaki
Special Creature Effects/
Special Makeup Effects/Special Effects/Wireworks
Moriaki Uematsu
No animals were harmed during
the filming of this movie.
International Sales
Asmik Ace & King Records
Theme Song
RC SUCCESSION "Slow Ballad"
Produced by
"LOVE & PEACE" Production Committee
King Records/Asmik Ace, Inc.
GYAO Corporation/Fields Corporation
A film planned and conceived by
GANSIS Production
Distributed by
Asmik Ace
Written & Directed by
Sono Sion
"LOVE & PEACE" Production Committee