Man, I'm so nervous.
Yes?
Hey, lookin' sharp!
Oh, isshiki. Why are you here?
My best friend's getting married!
So, why wouldn't I be?
But I don't remember inviting you.
Well, you should've! I mean, I'm pretty
sure the invitation just didn't arrive.
Oh, I guess that means you weren't invited!
Don't talk like I don't matter to you!
But anyway, I can't believe
you made it this far.
Who would've expected that you'd be marrying
the fourth cutest girl in our class?
I've gotta try harder!
How are things going with kumin-senpai?
Perfect!
It's open.
Togashi-kun, it's almost time.
Kumin-senpai, long time no see!
Oh, umm... nice to meet you.
I was in the same club as togashi-kun.
My name's kumin tsuyuri.
Kumin-senpai...
It's me, makoto isshiki!
Isshiki-San? How do you know togashi-kun?
Look!
That was a wig?!
Oh, you're a monk?!
Was togashi having a
Buddhist wedding ceremony?
Oh, kumin-senpai...
You should seriously give up.
It's been two years since we met.
I never expected things would
turn out this way, though.
Rikkal
hey, are you all right?
Today...
I'm marrying rikka.
Well, stay strong, okay?
Thanks.
Don't worry about it.
Anyway, is that idiot really going to
skip out on the wedding?
She isn't inside?
No, I checked earlier.
Dekomori is my servant, one who has shared
the same fate as me until now.
I'm pretty sure she
cannot accept this pact.
It's almost time, so please get ready.
See ya.
Yuta...
What is it?
I'm embarrassed.
No worries.
I am, too!
Yutal
Congratulations!
Rikka looks so pretty!
I'm so happy for them.
You should wipe your nose, morisummer-chan.
Don't call me that!
Now, you may kiss the bride.
Rikka...
What?!
Hey, look! A dark beast!
Hey, knock it off!
Yuta, that hurt!
Where do you think we are?! We're in
a church... at a wedding, you know!
What does that matter?!
Even if it's about to be
concealed by a barrier of light,
I can summon the power of darkness
with my wicked lord shingan!
What are you talking about?!
Besides, our pact ended when you saw
my wicked lord shingan.
What is the point of having a ceremony
corrupted by ordinary society?
You wanna call it quits, then?
No way.
Then what do you want? Spit it out already!
Oww! Yuta, that hurts!
Enough of this charade!
Whose voice is that?
Huh?
That idiot!
As master's servant, I, sanae dekomori, will
never approve of your wedding and new pact.
Look! Up there!
Master is my master!
Now... master, come with me.
Dekomori, I...
Master!
I'm sorry.
Fine, then...
Then I'll reduce everything to ash!
Yutal
Is this barrier a new power of yours?
Schwarz zx prototype Mark iv's
miasma degeneration barrier.
It blocks all magic attacks.
Everyone, get out of here while
you still have a chance.
Be careful, rikka.
Let's go, yumehal!
You're so cool, rikka!
Spirit of the atmosphere,
let us join forces!
"His hook, he baited with a dragon's tail."
Huh?
Ah! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Get a good taste of your punishment
for trying to take master away from me!
Morisummer-chan!
Kumin-senpai!
Isshiki!
Kumin!
Don't worry, I received powers, too!
9:08 is kumin time!
The time has come. Awaken, hypnos!
You should sleep for all eternity!
Explosive sleeping!
What good is it if you fall asleep?!
What good does it do if you fall asleep?!
Wedding cakes are the most
dangerous food in this world...
Yutal
hmph!
I have no choice!
Emerging from the deepest darkness of
carnage, dark flame master... has arrived!
Damn you!
Just the mere thought of challenging me with
a dragon was a mistake, sanae dekomori...
Or should I say Mjolnir hammer?!
Wh-what do you mean?
Hmph.
Have you forgotten about
that which dwells within me?
The dark dragon?
No, the dragon within me
is beyond that level.
It has evolved into the dark flame dragon!
In its 4000-year history,
the dark flame dragon only allowed six who
possess dark power to be its vessel...
That is what's inside him?
Deko!
Then, it seems my only option
is to use my special finishing move, too.
Here I go!
Apocalypse hammer!
Yuta, let's do it!
Rikkal
bridal attack!
In sickness...
And in health...
To love and to Cherish...
And I promise to be faithful...
Until death do us part!
What an awful wedding souvenir!
Rikkal
yutal
yuta...!
What an edgy dream.
Rafflesias are better with sauce.
Oh, master!
How was the battle in the parallel world?
It was a fierce battle.
Really?
L, dekomori, wish I could have joined you.
Hm?
Where's yuta?
He's not here yet.
Don't worry. Dark flame master
told us to believe in him.
So, let's trust him.
You should trust the dark flame master
you believe in, master.
I don't really get what
you're saying, but okay.
I'm sure he'll bring back a
win in this final battle.
Yeah...
Anyway, can you tell me what happened
between you and dark flame master?
Huh?
Like, how you two ended up together
when you met in the ancient past.
Dekomori...
I want to hear it, too!
All right, I'll tell you...
About how wicked lord shingan and
dark flame master met,
and how we wound up joining forces.
Nemuru Mae ni dakishimeta
before going to bed
ano makura ni kimi o kasaneta ato
I imagined the pillow I hugged was you
suiheisen no mukougawa ni iru after that, I
dreamt of you standing beyond the horizon
kimi no yume o mita after that, I dreamt
of you standing beyond the horizon
konkyo no Nai tsuyosa mo
strength without reason
riyuu darake no yowasa mo
weakness full of reasons
otagai dakishimeaeta Kara
we were able to hold each other tight
ano koro no itami wa kaze ni midarechitta yo
so the winds blew away my pain from the past
mukougawa ni tsurete itte
take me to the other side
koishii Kara naita dakedo
I cried since I miss you
itoshii Kara motto waratta
but laughed more since I adore you
“inaku naru" to obieru yori
it's more precious to believe you
shinjiru hou ga toutoi naa
than to fear you'll disappear
ima ga dondon kasanatte the present
accumulates and paints your days
kimi no hibi o irodotte iku the present
watashi no sonzai wa nani iro o shiteru?
What color is my existence?
Kore wa tokenai mahou
it's a spell that can't be lifted
“tabun zutto suki da yo" o chikau ne
I swear to probably keep loving you
Embarrassing! Embarrassing!
Embarrassing! Embarrassing! Embarrassing!
Forget it! Forget it! Forget it!
Forget it! Forget it!
When wicked lord shingan
and dark flame master met,
dark flame master was suffering
from the dissonance between his past
and memories he created in the present.
So I extended a helping hand.
That was the beginning.
Ow!
You saw?
Huh?
Uh, no!
Wanna see?
Huh?!
It opened!
My name is dark flame master.
Be enveloped in the flames
of darkness and die!
Mm-hmm!
Sealed! Up! Forever!
Our paths have crossed at last, eh?
My eye! My eye is resonating!
You know her?
Uh, no, I don't know her!
How many months, years have passed
as I've searched for you...
My eye! My eye!
My eye...!
They said the nurse stepped out,
so you should use some eye drops.
If we don't hurry, the entrance ceremony
will start without us.
You were on my veranda
last night, weren't you?
What are you up to?
Because of my eye... it resonated.
Yes. In times long past,
you and I knew each other.
The moment I saw you, wicked lord shingan
told me of our karmic fate.
So I sought a chance to encounter you.
This bitterness! It must
be the dark organization.
Therefore, I seal this.
Wicked lord shingan uses the sacred heart
to repress the powers of darkness.
Thus, to those sullied by darkness, purified holy water
is fundamentally dangerous and cannot be handled.
I almost fell for the enemy's trap.
We must be careful... dark flame master.
Be enveloped in the flames of dark-
stop that!
How do you know that?
Where did you hear it?
My wicked lord shingan has the power
to see through all things.
Even you, yuta, he with the power
of a level 7 magic user.
Where did you hear that?!
He knows all things, past and future, with but
a glance... ugh... where did you hear that?!
He knows all things, past and future,
with but a glance... ugh...
Where did you hear that?!
Yuta, that hurts!
For the last time, where
did you hear that?!
I can't see! Yuta, I can't see! For the
last time, where did you hear that?!
I can't see! Yuta, I can't see!
I heard you when I was outside the gym.
The gym?
I thought no one was listening!
Listen up! You mustn't
tell anyone about this!
I understand.
The laws regarding distortion above the invisible
boundary line and event-based structural variance-
no!
I mean, about my past! About dark flame master,
or being a user of the fires of darkness!
Why not? It's cool.
It's not cool!
Listen. I've decided I'm
through with all that.
Really?
Yeah.
So you're finally a level 8 magic user?
No!
It's just "chunibyo"!
I'm not dark flame master!
I'm just a normal high school freshman!
Can you please stop acting so surprised?
I hate to break it to you,
but you're a normal high schooler, too.
I have wicked lord shingan.
That has nothing to do with it.
It doesn't exist, anyway!
It does.
Does not.
You wanna see?
Huh?
My eye. Wanna see?
Sure, show me!
N-no way.
You've gotta be kidding!
Oww...
Owwie.
Ahn!
Hold on. I'll put it back in.
It's just a colored contact?!
When did you start living there?
I thought a single office
lady lived upstairs.
I moved in two days ago.
Toka takanashi is my big sister.
I get it. So you're
living with your sister.
That is the story.
But she's really a sorceress from the invisible
boundary line administration bureau.
The enemy!
Now look here...!
When she awakens, she'll be impossible to
contain, even with wicked lord shingan...
Ugh! How scary!
She's that bad?
Don't lose, rikka! This is it!
Obviously that nonsense will make her mad.
With the power of the dark flame master,
we could break through the bureau's resistance
and find the invisible boundary line for sure!
I told you not to mention that name!
I've come up with a new technique for you.
Judgment Lucifer!
Well?
You wear roller shoes?
Are you a kid?
They provide excellent mobility.
Also, with these, when I
come under enemy fire...
Clang! Clang! Skreee!
"You got two or three of my ribs, huh?"
You can do that. How cool!
Don't do that here!
Which do you want? It's my treat.
Hold on.
Up, up, down, down.
Hey, takanashi-San...
Left, right, left, right.
The train!
Okay, now put your coins in!
Huh?!
Now's the time! B, al
what do you mean, "b, a"?
This drink will replenish your magic.
The bureau stores it in secret.
But the friggin' train left!
You win 1 drink
you win 1 drink you won!
Good job!
Heh heh heh.
Now you know the depth of my power.
Nope. You looked like you
were not expecting that.
Oww!
B-brother, who is this?
The younger sister of takanashi, the
neighbor above us. She's moving in with her.
Oh, really?
Why do you have so much stuff?
Isn't this a bit much for one person?
All of it is important.
Not everything in these is junk, right?
I also have practical items.
It's automatic!
It turns into a weapon: Gungnir! Take that!
And for defense...
Schwarz shield!
All right already.
Here.
Just take these.
All right, fine!
That's the last of 'em.
Thank you. I'm grateful.
Yeah, you better be.
Where's your sister?
She always comes home late.
Really?
Oh, you're takanashi-San's sister?
You're both so pretty.
Yuta, you'll have to work hard.
At what?
Um, is your eye okay?
Don't worry about it. There's
nothing wrong with it at all.
Wicked lord shingan has long repressed
the forces of darkness with holy power-
you don't have to give her an explanation.
Understood.
Begone!
Ow! Begone!
Yumeha, you can't just
grab whatever you want-
take that! Yumeha, you can't
just grab whatever you want-
ow!
So cool!
It's not cool.
It's cool!
If you put that on your
back, it'd be perfect!
Perfect?
Brother used to do that. He'd have that
on his back while he was in a black coat.
Kuzuha!
You were a little strange back then, yuta.
You'd chant spells or
whatever before eating.
Mom! It's time for your night shift!
Hmph.
Fine.
I swear!
I told them this is trash, so
they shouldn't go touching it.
Trash?
Huh?
Yeah.
That's dark flame master's lifeblood.
I told you, didn't I? I'm
through with that stuff.
Why?
'Cause it's embarrassing.
It's cool.
It's not cool.
Not somethin' like this!
Besides, all that stuff is meaningless.
The flames of darkness and
the dark flame dragon don't exist.
It's childish.
No, it has power.
It doesn't.
It does.
Now look here...!
So...
I don't want you to throw it away.
Be enveloped in the
flames of darkness and disappear!
Don't get me wrong.
I just think it'd be a
waste to throw it away.
I'l make some money
selling it in an auction or something.
Yeah!
My place is on the second floor. Takanashi-San
lives in the apartment above me.
Disabling magical code.
Just open it already.
Shhh!
It opened. At last, it opened!
You sure are a pain.
Just a moment.
I'll search and make sure
nothing is amiss here.
Well, it was wrong of us to
just invite ourselves over.
She's a lady, after all.
Welcome to the dark side.
Enter the formless chaos.
That's kind of the same thing.
You like cute stuffed animals, don't you?
That's genbu, protector of the north.
It's a military mauser!
That's an unexpectedly cool hobby!
It's a holy pistol that can destroy evil.
It sure looks like it.
Can I see it?
Sure.
Mausers sure are cool.
Ra-ta-ta-ta-tal ka-blam!
U-um! You know, this pistol...
The real thing was an awesome weapon
made over 100 years ago!
And, uh... this is the m712 model...
Togashi-kun, you're into
that type of thing, huh?
Uh...
Whose cat is that?
Huh?
Closing secret partition!
Flooding radiation defense barrier!
All hands, evacuate!
What?!
Togashi-kun, let's run to the
ends of the earth together.
I'll really do it.
The ends of the earth meaning here?
I mean, the planet earth is round!
Hurry up and run.
She's one of the bureau's top priestesses.
How fun. It's like a horror movie.
It's not fun at all!
Something flashed just now!
Tsuyuri-San!
Go! Schwarz zx prototype Mark il!
Be destroyed, real! Blow up, synapses!
Vanishment this world!
In accordance with the covenant of blood,
I summon thee!
Konigin der nacht!
Dark matter Blaze!
Takanashi!
Nergal blast!
Gun tinkle!
Cut it out!
It's like, "cheerleaders go whoosh up
in the air. I wanna try!" She said.
You sure you're okay?
In the battle to locate the
invisible boundary line,
I flew to a height of several
thousand meters in that world...
No problem.
What is she talking about?
Who knows.
Well? Think you're up for it?
Not good?
N-no problem.
No problem.
Sorry, I know this is sudden.
What is it? What did you want to tell me?
I'm embarrassed, so I'll only say it once.
That is, how I feel about you...
L, o, v, e.
Love!
That tickles... that tickles!
All right, I get it...!
It seems you've finally
returned, dark flame master.
Who are you?!
Heh!
You're supposed to say your name first
before asking someone for theirs.
I-I'm joking! I'll tell you my name!
Who are you?
Please untie me first.
I am an agent of wicked lord shingan,
rikka takanashi's no. 1 servant...
User of the Mjolnir hammer, sanae dekomori!
I have arrived.
Go home!
L, dekomori, shall purify your soul!
Mjolnir tornad-
I can't move.
Idiot.
This chick's... the real thing!
I will have dekomori join our
far-east magical napping society.
That makes four members.
And because it takes five
members to start a club...
Unfortunately...
A cat doesn't count as a club member.
But chimera is my servant,
just like dekomori.
That's right. Just like I, dekomori.
Don't admit that!
Got a minute?
Wh-what is it?
I've been thinking of joining your club.
I just turned in my application!
Far-east magical napping society
summer thereof
wh-what's this?!
Hey. It seems the dark flame master
has been summoned.
That's the saturnus summoning circle for you.
Such power. It will beckon others upon others.
Now look here...
What is this?! What did
you draw on the floor?
How can you not know what
a summoning circle is? Are you an idiot?
I know what it is. I'm asking
why there's one on the floor.
I told you in class. We're
holding a witches' sabbath.
Correct! And we have prepared a sacrifice.
Heh heh heh!
Nepenthes plants... so delicious...
Look, stop bringing that cat to school!
This club was formed to find
the invisible boundary line.
Chimera is required.
Master, let's hurry and replace this victim
with a newly summoned subject!
Very well.
In the name of wicked lord
shingan, I summon thee.
Thy name is murderer of the darkness.
Your blood, flesh, and
bones, all without form.
Whoa!
Huh?
We're just getting started.
You even made it light up?!
Master, that was just the right angle.
Do it again.
Go master! You're so cool!
You wanna try it out?
Yes, I do! I, dekomori, will try it!
Dark creature of twilight,
he reddened from the flow of blood...
I bestow upon thee a fitting end!
Drag slay!
The heck is this?
Sun weak wheat flour
sun weak wheat flour wait,
what are you doing?!
Wait, what are you doing?!
Hello there.
N-nibutani!
What's this?
I-I-it's nothing!
Ahn!
Could this be a summoning circle?
So, you really are studying magic?
Give it back! Give it back!
Give it back!
Baaarf!
The heck are you doing?
Thank you for the explanation.
How long have you been there?!
I searched diligently, but unfortunately, I found
nothing regarding the invisible boundary line.
What I did find is this one volume.
Melon gal!
You've been poisoned by
this human world, eh?
I'm very sorry... huh?
Wait, I'm not the one at fault here!
You are. Dark flame master,
you mustn't look at such things.
What?
Seriously! Where is it?!
Hey, what are you doing?!
Do not open where could it be?
Huh?
What's this? Is it in here?
H-h-h-hey!
Don't open that!
Oww...
Where is it?
Huh? Where's what?
The mabinogion that idiot had.
Why?
Just tell me!
Uh... I think it's...
Oh, here it is. This thing is pretty heavy.
Wh-what?
Huh?
"I've lost my memories, but I am a true magician,
one who has lived in this world for 500 years."
"These are my notes, those of one
who commands the spirits."
"My name is...
Morisummer."
Stop! I don't want to hear this!
"I believe everyone knows that in this world,
there are white worlds and dark worlds..."
Embarrassing! Embarrassing!
Embarrassing! Embarrassing! Embarrassing!
I went around the Internet,
deleting blog after blog...
I never thought someone would
have it all printed out.
Still, it's hard to believe
you wrote that kind of stuff.
Now listen! If you tell anyone,
I'll curse you to the grave!
S-such heat! It's over
2,500,000 degrees celsius!
Hang in there, dekomori.
Until I finish my chant!
Unfortunately, due to the cloudy weather,
the special point did not appear.
But since I've come all this way,
I shall retrieve the mabinogion.
Huh? Oh, yeah...
Come! Hurry and hand it over! Where is it?
There.
Wha-?!
It's burned completely to ash.
Too bad.
Now, the "eternal future record"
has been completely lost.
Wh-what have you done...?
How could you...?
Hey, you all right?
L, dekomori, treasured that!
Ummm...
Boo-hoo.
Boo-hoo?
Boo-hoo, boo-hoo...
Boo-hoo-hoo, boo-hoo, boo-hoo, boo-hoo.
Boo-hoo, boo-hoo-hoo.
D-dekomori?
Boo-hoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
No need to worry! I thought this
might happen, so I set aside a copy!
Wha-?!
Yes, back then, I was...
The spirits are once again whispering.
Die, die! Die, past me!
I am the user of wicked lord shingan.
And so, after having recruited fake morisummer,
society no. Zero, rikka takanashi!
Our club became more active.
Society no. Zero, rikka takanashi!
I am the servant of wicked lord shingan,
user of the Mjolnir hammer,
society no. Zero, sanae dekomori!
The... night siesta of horror!
Society no. Zero, kumin tsuyuri.
You fool child!
Th-that's...
White water!
Either suits me fine!
Now, drink! Drink it up!
Stop! Stop it!
Good luck, deko-chan!
Look closely, fake morisummer! I will death
drive you to the horizon of limitless power!
Seven-colored Tome of
mabinogion, chapter 3, verse 1!
"When the whispers of the spirits,
the thoughts of light and water reach us,
the door to the white world shall open.
I have searched the world
these 400 years, so I know.
What this world needs most is..."
"Love!"
Stop! I don't want to hear that!
Deko-moron
deko-
[Looking for missing cat!!
Name: Dodomenh female
Issue an emergency alert.
Huh?
Hey...
Stop the background music!
Math?
Yeah. If she fails next semester,
she has to disband the club.
Oh, really? That's fine, isn't it? After
all, you have no real club activities.
That won't do!
We finally have a napping club.
We need to be more energetic!
Is she asleep?
Probably.
Go be energetic by yourself.
Morisummer-chan is pudgier
than she seems, isn't she?
What a fool.
I don't want to hear that
from the likes of you!
I command you in the name
of wicked lord shingan.
Fuse spirit, flesh, and bone into one, and
drive failing grades away from math exams.
Yes.
Now you're asking the gods?
I ask nothing. I'm commanding it
in the name of wicked lord shingan.
Yes!
Cut that out! You'll be cursed!
It'll be all right, rikka-chan.
When you're stuck for the right answer,
use this. It's my beloved pencil!
I'll lend it to you.
Whoa!
Question 1: What is the angle of angle a?
Four! The answer is...
Three!
Please don't let rikka-chan
get a failing grade.
These guys are hopeless.
Well, here goes!
Mjolnir accelerator!
Here's an explanation!
The Mjolnir accelerator focuses a magical
infusion into the nerves of the lower body,
making motor performance 3.88
times greater than normal
and allowing for high-speed movement. Yes!
Such accelerating force...
Here goes! To the speed of sound!
"She's gonna crash!" Is
what I'll make you think...
Then stop in the Nick of time!
That's enough.
Hurry up and get busy.
Anyway, why did I have to get
roped into this as well?
Nana-chan said all the
members had to do it.
I don't recall becoming a "member."
Uh... but you applied...
Ow.
I was just trying to get
close to that brat.
I'm a member of the cheerleading club.
Sorry, my hand slipped.
Ooh!
This is... Genesis! The old versus the new?
What foolishness are you on about?
Just put the hose down already!
I cannot comply!
Leave it to me, dekomori.
I'll lend you my strength.
Oh, master!
Evil eye shoot!
Such power... it courses through me!
May the hose be with you!
Move, move! Move!
I'll ask one more time: Do
you truly intend to study?
Of course.
Just so we're clear,
you need high t-scores at our school,
so if you want to get an "average" grade, you'd
better be ready for some serious studying.
I am prepared.
All right, then I'll teach you.
First, let's start with a basic problem.
"Find the probability that the sum of
two dice, when rolled, will be 3."
Can you do that?
No problem.
Still... this place is as messy as always.
If you cleaned up a little...
I don't get it.
I thought I'd understand if I knew how the person
tossing the dice felt, so I tried imagining it.
But it's more than I can do.
I don't know what this person is thinking!
In other words, that's the
extent of your ability?
No. I have yet to give this my all.
That's what you'd like to say, isn't it?
Then it can't be helped.
Let's try more from the beginning...
We're going to do all the ones from there?
We start from one you understand and then go
through them in order. That's how we do it.
Let's see here...
Who's there?
No one's there.
Someone was!
Yuta, look out!
I'm not falling for it.
Sometimes, yuta, the magic
imbued in the number 8-
I'm not falling for that, either.
Damn!
You just said "damn," didn't you?!
Sit!
You said you're serious about this, right?
I am.
You said, "I'll try hard,
so please teach me," right?
I did.
But... I'm no good at math.
I have no idea what they're thinking.
Anyway, even if you do know the probability
of the dice's outcome, how is that useful?
Don't suddenly make a valid point!
I just don't get it!
Ooh!
Yuta, your code is cool!
Huh? "Cool"?
It's pretty normal...
E-mail address
it's pretty normal...
E-mail address oh, no!
E-mail address
it hasn't changed since middle school.
Divine exseed Freya magna!
Stop that! Don't say it out loud!
I'll change it right now. Hang on a minute.
No.
Address book rikka takanashi
address book rikka takanashi mine
is the normal one. I'll change it.
Address book rikka takanashi
I've got it. Yuta, assign my code!
What?
I'm sure you'll come up
with something good.
No, uh, I think it's plenty good as-is.
Then I'll use your code.
Don't do that!
Wait, can you just suddenly change it?
Why not?
I mean, if you change it, you have to tell
your middle school friends and your family...
No problem. I'll just inform
the priestess and dekomori.
Oh, really?
They are the only beings cognizant
of my presence in this dimension.
But if you decide on a code for me,
I'll tell you, nibutani, and kumin, too.
Come here a minute.
Huh? But the heartleaf tea...
I'll do my best to teach you
right up to the day of the test.
So you do your best and study.
Yuta...
This is your club, right?
Yeah.
If you get an above-average score, I'll think
of a protocol code I'm sure you'll like.
Okay!
Oh, no.
I'd neglected my own studies.
No good, huh?
You all did poorly this time.
The average score was a 50.
What?!
Study harder.
Such power!
Just walk once in a while.
Oh! That's right, I forgot!
Yuta, give me my protocol code!
Huh?
What are you talking about?
I'm kidding. I've thought of one!
This is special, just for today...
Huh...?
O user of wicked lord shingan!
In acknowledgment of
your efforts and deeds,
I, dark flame master, have compiled the dark
powers and distilled for you a fitting code.
You would do well to carve
it into your breast.
Protocol code... engrave!
Received mail yuta
togashi subj: Carve it!
"Black raison d'étre"?
It means one's dark reason for existing.
It is a fitting code for you, yes?
How cool... it's so cool, yuta!
Of course.
How long am I gonna keep this up?
Hey! Hang on a...
Thank you
I think some stuff happened
after that, but...
Dark limited unknown shield! Engage!
With summer here, my wicked lord shingan changed little by little
due to the bureau's attacks. Did you say something, phonysummer?!
With summer here, my wicked lord shingan changed little by
little due to the bureau's attacks. Huh?! No, I didn't!
With summer here, my wicked lord shingan changed
little by little due to the bureau's attacks. Really?
With summer here, my wicked lord shingan changed little by little due to the
bureau's attacks. I believe I heard you and skinhead here say something about me!
With summer here, my wicked lord shingan changed little by little
due to the bureau's attacks. Who are you calling "skinhead"?!
With summer here, my wicked lord shingan changed
little by little due to the bureau's attacks.
You're suddenly motion sick?
That's why I said she's
an elementary schooler.
Sh..shut up-
just look outside. At the far-off greenery.
Shut... up.
At a time like this, I'll look over the words of
the mabinogion and drive off the evil spirits.
"The heart-"
it won't be much longer.
Hey.
Rikka?
What?
Have some kind of reaction!
You look amazing in that bikini!
Hey, what's with your outfit?
Even your swimsuit is all white?
Well, this is all I had.
Does it suit me?
It seems that the kraken
lurks in these waters!
Now is the time for us to test the power
of these marine-use magical garments!
Feast your eyes on this!
With those magic garments,
one can move 3.88 times faster in water.
Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
3.88 times faster.
All right, then. Hurry up and go.
I'l remember this!
True, that's pretty fast.
Thanks for the food.
Is there cheese in this?!
Deko-chan, you don't like cheese, either?
Who could eat something
that smells like rotten dishrags?
It's made of milk! Milk is rotten.
It's the worst!
Eat it.
B-but milk...
Yes, ma'am.
Whoa!
You're doing great, deko-chan!
What's the passphrase?
Huh?
"Wicked lord shingan is most powerful."
Wrong.
It's wrong?
It seems you've suffered damage from
the priestess' psychological attack.
You are not yourself, yuta.
You thought as much, did you?
Rest easy. I am the dark
flame master of old.
You okay?
Don't want to go look for the
invisible boundary line?
Really?
Why would I lie?
W-well, mama and my sister,
and grandpa and grandma did.
But this is me, right?
Yuta... my sis-
the priestess surely has her guard up.
Breaking free won't be easy.
So, wanna give up?
When shall we go?
N-now!
Now?
Yup. Now.
What do you think you're doing?
Beats me. I don't really know, myself.
Ar! That was kinda cool!
Look, you just be quiet.
Unbelievable. Turns out
you really are dangerous.
Yutal
Rikkal
come on!
Come on, rikka!
Jump!
Avalon smasher!
How long do you plan to
keep up this nonsense?
Is it fun?
Is it fun to keep acting this
way, like a selfish child?
Gun tinkle!
Do you hate mama?
No.
You want to make grandma
and grandpa unhappy?!
No!
You get it, right? You know what can't be
changed! When there's nothing you can do!
What'll it take to satisfy you?
Nothing can be done, right?
Evil eye.
You idiot!
Yutal
jeez. I barely made it!
Why...?
That's what I'd like to ask.
Where are you going?
The bureau's strength is amplified in
this region. The field is too powerful.
I'm retreating.
So, you're going home?
Yuta...
Where did you acquire the dark flame power?
Look, that's not even really...
I want to forget!
What is it? The bureau's interference?
No.
Now, look-
our eyes met.
Huh?
This has bound us in a rather strong pact,
dark flame master.
Suit yourself.
Be enveloped in the flames of darkness-
stop that!
It's gotten so late...
Yuta! I can't get inside.
The entry code has changed.
You mean you forgot to bring your key!
Jeez. Guess it can't be helped...
Thank you very much.
You're really okay with this?
Since seeing you eat these at school,
I've been intrigued by their construction.
So, you purge this here...
Extricating the outer skin.
Just grab both sides and pull.
Ooh!
How very cool.
That's cool?
Mmm!
It's delicious.
I bet toka-San would be
mad about this, huh?
Here. We have chicken nuggets, too.
A queer taste.
What does that mean?
What flavor is yours?
You wanna try?
Uh-huh. You wanna try?
Here.
Was it spicy?
Yuta!
Sorry 'bout that.
Replenishment complete.
Okay. Well, let's go back.
Yuta.
I don't want to.
Huh?!
I will bathe in the moonlight.
Whoa... hey!
Yuta, is this Mjolnir hammer?
You have an active imagination, don't you?
Come on, it's late.
You can sleep in this room.
Brush your teeth and-
it smells like you.
S-stop that!
Why?
It smells like you...
Stop! It's kinda embarrassing!
Okay, here go the lights.
Night is when wicked lord
shingan comes alive-
just sleep.
My heart races. They may have drawn closer.
I need to stay alert.
Now look...
I'm turning it off.
My heart races.
You'll feel better if you sleep.
My heart beats fast.
That's the same thing.
My heart is pounding!
Are you a commercial for a theme park?
I'll blow up!
Why would you?!
I don't know!
U-uh... um...
Look, just go to bed.
Wait!
Now look-!
Don't go.
Yuta, close your eyes.
Huh?!
Just a little... just a little, please.
What is this?
A fragment of absolutely powerful magic.
Proof of our earlier pact.
Please put it somewhere
where it doesn't stand out so much.
It's most effective here.
It doubles the powers of darkness.
You can release the dark buster,
even more powerful than the dark flame.
Time for bed.
My heart pounds!
This feeling...
Who's there?!
Yuta.
Kumin...
Kumin?
Oh! Rikka-chan!
You okay? Did the spatial paradox get you?
Paradox? I was just napping
since it's nice out.
No.
It's all because of the spatial paradox
caused by an evil singularity.
Yuta... and myself...
Something must be done.
Rikka, you here?
Do you realize what time it is?
Yuta...
What?
I'm sorry.
What, you called me here for that?
Huh?
I will defeat you!
Wha-?
Ow-!
Indeed, I can see it! The singularity!
What are you talking about?!
Yuta, the bureau has made it such that an
evil singularity has taken root within you!
I shall remove it!
Master!
Be destroyed, real. B-blow up, synapses.
Vanishment this world!
Huh?
Uh... huh?
Master! This calls for that!
Dekomori!
Master!
How's this?! Can you tell us apart?
I am rikka.
L, dekomori, am dekomori.
Which is rikka?
Which is the master, yes?
Hmph.
That was plain as day.
What's the point if your
body double has to save you?
Oh, no! He has a point, yes?!
Jeez, what were you thinking?
I can't believe I worried about you.
You okay?
Here.
What's with you?
Love?
Yeah.
Can't you tell? You're in
love with togashi-kun.
It's so obvious!
Hah!
T..takanashi-San, are you okay?
Wicked lord shingan is the strongest.
I've already formed the
ultimate pact with yuta.
There is no need for the
pact to become one of love.
But your heart pounds
whenever you're with togashi-kun, right?
Don't you imagine it when you go home?
The two of you holding hands,
or kissing...
B-but, wicked lord shingan's power is...
Ah, but...
I don't get how your chunibyo delusions
can overlap with real-world love...
Whoa! Hey!
Ow, ow!
Schwarz shield!
This renders all psychological
attacks ineffective!
What do you think of me?
Esi I reir er sseac ieee
== == sorte see caries ee
why do I have to do this?
Listen up. When it's just
the two of you, say this:
"What do you think of me?"
Y-y... yuta!
Huh?
What do you...
Hm?
What do you think of my
wicked lord shingan?
Huh?
Wicked lord shingan is
me, through and through.
In times like this, I, that is,
wicked lord shingan, is...
What are you babbling about?
The two of us, alone in the library. When he reached for the book, I knew. After class, having been asked by the teacher
to arrange the books... when his face drew close to mine... it's my chance. It wasn't accidental... 1 think he, too...
The two of us, alone in the library. When he reached for the book, j khew. After class, having been asked by the teacher to arrange the books... when
his face drew close to mine... it's my chance. It wash't accidental... 1 think he, t0o0... this time, you don't have to say anything. Just do this.
1 raised my head ahd... our eyes met. This time,
you don't have to say anything. Just do this.
And gently, he... this time, you don't
have to say anything. Just do this.
I swear by wicked lord shingan-
you don't have to swear.
Ginkgo festival
ginkgo festival
where did you go?
Ginkgo festival
ginkgo festival grab
that tape there for me.
Ginkgo festival
ginkgo festival there's
no time for games.
Ginkgo festival
ginkgo festival jeez.
What the heck?
Jeez. What the heck?
Yes. Then, when his face gets close...
You okay?
Look up right away!
Yutal
ow... what are you doing?!
Yuta. You were wide open.
Whoa. This is higher than I'd imagined.
Rikkal
yutal
Dammit!
Hang on!
Move! Move, move!
I've got you!
Easy now... easy.
You can let go now.
Yuta...
Yuta! Yuta, yuta!
Rikka...
I... I was...
Far-east magical napping society
“summer thereof
master!
Whoa! I never thought that, with the darkness,
we'd be visited by the night of the demon!
Master?
Wh-what is it, master?
Gasp!
Could it be master cares for me, dekomori?
Uh...
Master, you mustn't!
I am your servant.
It isn't right to harbor such feelings!
Still, I know that the more something is
forbidden, the more it is hungered for!
Master?
Yuta and I embraced.
What?
I like yuta.
Master?
Gasp!
Could you be a fake master?
First a fake morisummer,
now a fake master?!
It's me.
Meaning, in other words...
The master is taken with dark flame master?
I-I-in love?
Master! I, dekomori,
have someplace to go, so I shall leave.
Dekomori...
I'll stop this!
As a servant, I'll find he who
stole your heart, and to the darkness-
what should I do?
You say that wicked lord shingan has protected
you thus far thanks to dark flame master.
Yes...
I'm sure such strong emotion has been
conveyed to dark flame master, too.
I don't know...
It's been a little over two
years that I've served you.
Your servant sees right
through you, master!
Dekomori...
There's no need to worry.
Wicked lord shingan is the strongest.
I'm sure everything will go well.
Right.
By our covenant, hear now my command.
What's that?
A magic stone. To Grant my wish.
Dekomori gave it to me.
Wish?
I can't say the specifics of my wish!
Uh, no one asked.
Hm?
You dropped it.
Whoa. It's warm.
A strong wish makes the magic stone
give off heat. Meaning-
no!
Ow...
Things can't keep going like this, huh?
So, look...
So, look!
Schwarz zx prototype Mark il!
Quit rattling off its full name!
Hey!
What is it?
The lights...
The lights are dancing.
Rikka...
I like you, yuta.
Huh?!
Yuta, I...
I like you.
W-wait! I should go first, right?!
No. By wicked lord shingan,
it was decided that I would go first.
But I'm dark flame master, aren't 1?
Wicked lord shingan is the strongest.
Wha...
Nope, I won't have it.
I've thought about it,
so I'm going to say it.
Okay...
You who are enveloped in the flames of darkness:
Become the love of dark flame master by...
Forget it. At any rate-
keep going.
Yuta.
Okay.
You who are enveloped in
the flames of darkness:
Become the love of dark flame master
by entering into this pact.
Okay.
Aren't you supposed to be in my arms?
You embarrassed?
Yes.
How about holding hands?
Just my pinky.
Fine, pinkies then.
Yeah.
Yes?
M-m... 'Morning!
Nibutani told me to
change how I speak, too.
She did?
Yes, she did, yuta-kun.
May I be of assistance?
What are you, a maid?
What can I do for you?
You're a Princess now?
What, pray?
Enough already!
What?
That sounds the most natural.
It makes me embarrassed.
Hold it.
'Morning.
Do not "morning" me!
Today at last, I shall release the demon
that has captured the master's heart!
Be destroyed, real! Blow up, synapses!
Vanishment this world!
Master!
Open your eyes!
I'm over this.
Master...
Master!
There, there.
It's none of your business.
Still...
This was when dark flame master awakened.
Tails, huh?
Guess it can't be helped.
Rikka!
Yuta?
I have to water them.
Yutal
I am not yutal
rikka takanashi...
Rather, wicked lord shingan!
There's something I wish to show you.
Yuta...
Make... a pact with me!
Who's there?!
You a thief?
What're you doin', dammit?!
Oh, no!
Dear, get the gun! Bring my hunting rifle!
Rikka, come on!
But...
Will you return to mundane reality?
Or do you not wish to change
reality together with me?!
Yuta.
Dear!
Rikkal
yutal
rikkal
Rikkal
The lights...
Pretty, aren't they?
But they're just lights from ships.
Ordinary lights.
Get off.
This is the power of darkness:
Be destroyed, real.
Blow up, synapses.
Vanishment... this world!
Yutal
it's the invisible boundary line.
That light is watching you.
You should share your thoughts...
The thoughts you've wanted
so long to express.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, papa!
Rikka
goodbye!
Yutal
crap! Let's run!
Neighborhood watch on patrol you two
on the bike, pull over immediately!
You two on the bike, pull over immediately!
I repeat, pull over immediately!
And now, dark flame master
is off fighting in the final battle.
The bureau's threat still remains despite
finding the invisible boundary line.
Master!
Being that I am wicked lord shingan,
this was my battle to begin with.
I can't leave everything to yuta.
Even so, dark flame master
asked you to leave it to him.
He wants you to wait for him.
Yuta...
Has togashi-kun gotten back yet?
No, not yet, morisummer-chan.
Why are you dressed like that?!
I had drama club rehearsal.
He said he'd call if he had trouble...
What could a fake like you
do in the final battle?
I'm good at negotiations, you know!
I doubt you would in that getup.
Shut it.
But, morisummer-chan, you always come here
in your drama club costumes.
I don't feel like changing.
Besides, it's just you guys here.
Oh, I totally thought it was
to make deko-chan happy.
What?! Why would I do this
for that middle school-
take this!
Ow!
I'm not in middle school anymore! This spring,
I'll be a high schooler just like you!
But I'm older than you, so
get off your high horse!
What are you doing?! Mjolnir hammer!
I hope everything goes well for
togashi-kun. Ow! That hurts! Why, you...!
Yeah.
Ow! That hurts! Why, you...!
Yeah. Behave yourself!
Behave yourself!
Mjolnir tornado!
I kept you waiting, huh?
Yutal
sorry, my phone died.
How'd it go?
You better get ready,
'cause you'll be living on
your own starting tomorrow.
Yutal
whoa! Hey, come on. Yutal
yuta, thank you!
Yuta! Yuta, yuta!
Settle down now.
I knew dark flame master was the strongest!
Yeah, yeah.
You're the strongest!
Rikka's mother had to move away
for two years due to job training.
So I went to see rikka's grandfather, who
didn't care that I'd take care of rikka,
and ask him to let her live on her own.
Rikka's grandfather just wouldn't budge.
But rikka's mom and toka, who suddenly appeared,
supported me, and he reluctantly agreed.
At any rate, this sure is a lot of stuff.
All of it is important.
If your grandfather saw all these boxes, he might
have let you live on your own without me asking.
Yuta?
Yeah?
What did my mom say?
She said she'll come over to sit down
and have a talk next time...
And that once she's done with training, she
wants to live with you for real this time.
Really?
Yeah.
It's snowing.
But it's almost April.
Snow?
Yes.
"Rikka" means "snow."
The winter I was pregnant
with her, it snowed so much.
Did you know that no two
snow crystals are identical?
They're unique and
absolutely irreplaceable.
That's why we named our daughter rikka.
I like snow.
I used to hate the cold.
But now...
I love it.
We'll start moving things now.
Oh, but...
Yutal
yes. Yes...
What? Really?!
Yeah, grandma just told me.
It seems grandpa terminated the lease
and called the movers a while back.
No way...
Grandma just called to cancel,
but I guess it was too late.
What can we do?
She finally got permission to live alone.
If her stuff is delivered here,
it could rehash the issue.
That's true.
Oh, grandpa is here. I'm hanging up.
Wait, hello? Are you there, toka-San?
Yutal
I've got no choice!
So it's back to this again.
Togashi
this déja vu... there's a chance
that the bureau is controlling our memory.
It's reality, not déja vu.
Then we went back in time...
Wrong!
You can't use your room anymore.
Jeez. What are we going to do?
The new semester's about to start, too.
Heilichwasser.
This isn't the time for that!
Yuta, that hurts!
You might not have a place to live.
Don't worry.
In the meantime, I'll just move my base of
operations here until I decide on a new location.
How can you have the gall to say that?
I mean, that won't work!
How come?
What's this?
Mom, kuzuha, and yumeha
started living in Jakarta this spring.
Kuzuha and everyone?
What?!
Whoa!
They're living overseas?
Yeah.
Really?
Yes!
I see... so they're living over-
what?!
That means, if you live here,
it would just be the two of us living here.
Oh, umm...
I was joking earlier.
Then what are you gonna do?
Um, well...
It fell off again.
And so, rikka and I began
our new life together.
Owaranai monogatari...
A tale with no ending...
Himeta chikara, daichi o tomose
o hidden power, illuminate this earth
Dare ni mo wakaranai, ano hi no samusa nante
no one can understand the cold of that day
dare mo ga kakushiteru, keburu shikai no
riyuu Sura mo everyone hides something
dare mo ga kakushiteru, keburu shikai no riyuu Sura
mo a reason one's field of vision becomes obscured
boku ga ikura hoetemo, sekai wa sakana no me o shiteru no
matter how much I cry out, the world remains oblivious
dakaratte hikeru ka yo, toge no shibuki o kurete yaru even
so, how could I back down? I'll rain down a shower of thorns
hikari wa dare yori mo hayai to, kanchigai o shita I
had the wrong idea, that light is faster than all
yami wa kanarazu sono saki ni machikamaete iru tte
noni yet darkness will surely be there first, waiting
konton o itadaita tabibito yo
o traveler who has embraced chaos
owaranai kaze to umi
the endless winds and oceans
bokura no hi ga kibou ni naru
our fires will become hope
ishi o motsu koto ga, kodoku e no jokyoku demo
even if having volition is a prelude to solitude
haiiro no oka ni tachi, tatakaitsuzukeru sa we
can stand atop that ashen hill and keep fighting
shijin ga jounetsu o furuwaseta
the poets have incited passion
sou... bokura mo "genijitsu" o warau
yes... we, too, ridicule "reality"
Inside identity
ibasho wa doko?
Where do I belong?
Kanchigai ga haji da to ka
"misunderstanding is shameful"
sunaosa ga itai to ka
or, "it hurts to be straightforward"
dare ga na to iou to
no matter what anyone says
tadashisa nante wakannai ze
I don't get what "correctness" is
futsuu ni nagareteku nichijou ni
these regular days that flow forth normally
muri shite najimaseta
I've forced myself to grow used to them
shizunjimatta koseitachi o
the individualities that drowned
kande nonde haite warau I'll bite them,
drink them, spit them up and laugh
konna boku o wakatte hoshii
I want you to understand, this is who I am
litai kedo ienakute
I want to say it, but I can't...
Nande dare mo wakatte kunnai no to
"why can't no one understand?"
Omou no wa zeitaku na no ka na? Na no ka na?
Is thought an extravagance or something?
Omou no wa zeitaku na no ka na?
Na no ka na? Or something?
Kanjouteki na taiyou wa
this emotional sun
netsu o agesugite dounika narisou is getting
too worked up and could get kinda weird
sakebitakute shou ga Nai
I wanna shout so bad, I can't stand it
gamushara ni motometeru identity
an identity I'm frantically lookin' for
inside my feeling, inside my justice
jama shinaide
don't get in the way
ibasho wa doko?
Where do I belong?
Hup!
I wonder if he's doing well...
My hero.