Valentine's Day is two weeks away,
but Cupid is very busy.
His arrow's struck Lynn Weaver...
...a talk-show host
worth $ 100 million...
...whose popular program
has spawned a TV empire...
...announced her marriage
this afternoon.
The lucky groom-to-be...
...is former NFL quarterback
and aging playboy Mike Gambril...
...who is a sportscaster
for NBC in Los Angeles.
You look good
with your collar up like that.
Mike, nice catch!
Lynn Weaver and Mike Gambril...
...the aging sports stud
and the popular talk-show host...
...have everyone talking
about their engagement.
Mike is a sportscaster
for an LA affiliate.
But how he got that job
is the real news.
Sources say Lynn got Mike the job...
...but so far the quarterback
has been fumbling.
If that doesn't
make her think twice...
...there's Mike's reputation
for playing the field.
This is my favorite part.
I like this.
Who's standing
on the cake with her?
One-time NFL backfield coach
Mike Gambril.
Perfect timing.
When you get back from Australia...
...we go in,
we renegotiate your deal.
Mike, what time is your flight?
Can I make a call?
People are batshit over you two
getting married. It's perfect.
You're the lawyer.
Don't hold me to it,
but in the next few weeks...
...I can get in excess of $200,000.
If Lynn can get you on a Wednesday
night special, the sky's the limit.
I mean, who's going to say no
to Lynn Weaver?
Did you hear when I said
"the sky's the limit"?
- You got a date?
- For what?
The wedding.
The wedding!
We're getting there.
What do you mean?
Don't louse this up for me.
- Would I do that? Calm down.
- I am calm.
I was thinking we should have it
on TV. Ever think of that?
I'm joking. I'm joking.
I'm glad I caught you.
You forgot your watch.
- I wondered where it was.
- The editing room.
The editing room, yeah.
Thanks.
- Safe trip.
- Bye. Thanks.
- Who removes their watch in editing?
- I do.
Sweet. Very nice.
What did she take off?
Don't louse this up, huh?
I'm telling you,
he's not on the flight.
Wait, I see him.
Don't worry, I'll get the picture.
You'll get your
Lynn Weaver story.
You wanted a picture of the tattoo
on Tom Arnold's ass.
I got you a picture.
You think you can do better?
- Mr. Gambril, welcome.
- I'll take those.
Thanks.
The flying time for the L.A. Leg
of our New York to Sydney flight...
...should be 13 hours and 47 minutes.
- What can I get you to drink?
- Only a pillow.
The temperature in Sydney should be
the same as it is here, 68 degrees.
Excuse me, I think that's my...
I thought these things were extinct.
Mike Gambril, what a thrill!
I've been watching you sleep.
How are you?
I've seen you play 1000 times.
I'm Herb Stillman.
This is my wife, Nora.
She's a fan of yours, too.
You've given us 1000 thrills!
I'm glad you stopped coaching.
I'm trying to watch the movie.
Mike Gambril.
Really? Hi. Terry.
- How are you?
- Good.
I'd like...
It's true,
he's given me 1000 thrills.
- But coaching is a thankless job.
- Herbie?
- Yes, Nora, sweetheart?
Excuse me.
Can you help me? I can't figure out
23 across and 15 down.
I have an empty seat here.
You two can come up here
and sit beside each other. Come on.
Your son wouldn't have to...
I hate to tell you,
but this is my grandson.
It's Matthew.
Shake hands with Mike Gambril.
- Come on up here, I insist.
- Thank you very much.
Did that look stupid? I know I looked
stupid. Was anyone watching?
- No.
- Good.
I must say, at my age 14 hours
is 14 hours, know what I mean?
It's 14 hours of my life.
We only have six more hours, but...
I don't even know
what time zone I'm in.
I took off from LA...
...9000 miles to Sydney on Friday...
...then back to New York
for the weekend...
...and back to LA on Tuesday.
- Can I help you?
- I'm sorry, I'm in the wrong place.
Literally.
I'm up in the air all the time.
You do that on any kind
of ongoing basis...
...you become...
...completely...
- Disoriented?
- Disoriented.
Disoriented.
And... and...
Isolated?
Isolated, yeah.
Isolated.
How long are you gonna be in Sydney?
Two days.
Two days!
- Actually, two and a half.
- Me too.
But I'm lucky, I don't travel
on an ongoing basis.
I don't worry
about feeling isolated.
That's good.
This is your captain.
Please fasten your safety belts.
- Let me get that.
- No, I...
- I'll get it.
- No, really, I...
I'd rather...
This will look fantastic.
- Is that for a coat or a dress?
- A sailboat.
A sailboat?
- Don't want to lose these.
- Thank you.
All right. Here we go.
- Good-looking guy.
- I think so.
Stockbroker?
He's an investment banker.
- What firm?
- Shearson Leahman.
- Don't tell me he runs it.
- Actually, he does.
What is he, 30, 35?
He's young.
- Amazing!
- What's that?
Memory loss is not necessarily
related to aging.
- Memory loss?
- Absolutely.
It's usually stress, change.
Change creates stress.
The bigger the change,
the greater the stress.
It must be overwhelming.
The mind is like a computer.
It can only process so much
information before it farkles.
- Farkles?
- Breaks down. Crashes.
Don't be embarrassed.
It's experience overload.
That's why you have a black book.
- What are we talking about?
- Us. You don't have a clue, do you?
Don't be embarrassed. You've been
a very busy man for a long time.
I'm a big girl.
You look clammy. Are you all right?
Me? I'm fine.
Mike, it's no big deal. Not every
experience in life is memorable.
You've been with many women.
It's understandable.
I hate root beer.
Come on, it's funny!
What? To hear you call a wonderful
experience forgettable?
What would you call it?
You didn't say anything,
so I didn't.
I'm not going to embarrass you.
That's hilarious.
One thing about me, I don't forget.
I know when I forget something.
If you know what you forgot,
you didn't forget it.
We've been experiencing trouble
with one of our engines.
Actually, two engines
on the right wing.
We have to make
an unscheduled landing.
There's a landing site
on a Cook Island atoll.
Attendants, please review
the emergency landing procedures.
We should be on the ground
very shortly.
He found an atoll.
We got a place to land.
It's a sunken volcano.
He's got a place to land.
There's nothing but water out there!
No lights, no land!
They do this all the time
with coordinates and vectors.
With no engine on the right wing?
He can land on one engine.
It's fine.
I spend my life on planes.
Don't worry.
Let's hear it!
- What?
- Excuse me.
As we're on a rather small landing
strip built during World War II...
...there's no immediate possibility
of moving you by air from the island.
But we have three ships nearby...
...to ferry our passengers
to Fiji, Tahiti or Hawaii...
...one of which you can see moored
to our right.
We'll help you make connections
from any of these airports.
If you'll return to your seats...
...our flight attendants will
give you information.
Thank you.
Tahiti, Fiji or Hawaii?
Go with what you know. I know Tahiti.
They're all 2 or 3 days away.
Days?
Forget Sydney for me.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I gotta call New York.
Do the ships have phones?
- Sometimes.
- Really?
Well... congratulations.
- For what?
- Lynn Weaver.
Tell her from me
she has a gallant fiancé.
I know Hawaii, so have a nice trip.
Thank you. You, too.
Don't get too disoriented.
Terry, I want you to read this
and give me your opinion.
Chernobyl. That's good. Chernobyl.
That cloud went around the earth.
Want hear a poem? Listen to this:
Oh, Chernobyl cloud
Chernobyl cloud
What did you do?
Yesterday I had one head
Today I have two
Excuse me.
This boat does stop at Raiatea?
Raiatea, Tangiroa,
Huahine and Morea.
- Is Raiatea the first stop?
- Can we talk?
I'd like to make a phone call
to Sydney.
No telephone! Send telegram.
How do I send one?
Form in stateroom.
Fill out. Hang on door.
- Do you happen to have a form?
- Form in stateroom. Fill out!
I understand! I'm asking nicely,
do you have a form?
It's 5:30. If you don't go to bed...
...we'll sleep all day tomorrow.
The toilet in my room doesn't flush!
Good morning, Miss McKay.
Welcome to our beautiful Belorussia.
You'll be in stateroom 21.
What happened to Hawaii?
It was another 4 hours.
- That's terrible!
- I know.
Where is the telephone?
There is none.
There's radiotelegraph.
You fill out the form
and hang it on the door.
Will you be sure Miss McKay's bags
go to her room?
- Excuse me.
- Oh, hello.
Smooth.
We can work our way around here.
- Is this uncomfortable for you?
- What?
Given our history and...
I don't think we want
to give people the wrong idea.
- Why ask for trouble?
- Right.
- You do attract attention, you know.
- As do you.
- And very deservedly, I might add.
- Thank you.
But I'm nothing if not discreet.
That's common knowledge.
If it were, you wouldn't be discreet.
I'm fine with our history.
Thank you.
- You know what it is? Your hair.
- Longer.
- It was a lot longer.
- Now it's longer.
That's what I mean.
But there's more red in it.
- Not really.
- No, not really.
It probably looks more red
because it's longer.
But that's not how I get a sense
of someone. This is my room.
There's 21.
Mike, you were nice on the plane.
You serious?
Let me ask you,
when you think about us...
...what do you remember most?
We only saw each other once.
You tripped on a bag
in front of a hotel as I got a cab.
We never met.
Beautiful luggage.
I do have a weakness for nice things.
Me, too. Nice things are nice.
Better get to work
on those telegrams.
He says, it's honor
to have you all aboard.
That we are proud to offer help
in moment of crisis.
- We love Americans.
- Watch.
We were in Hawaii last year...
...at the same hotel as Alex Trebeck.
- Really?
- Don't drink the water.
Hey, the coach is here!
Mr. Gambril, I'm the captain.
On behalf of captain,
welcome to our happy table.
- Herb, Nora.
- And you know...
We met briefly.
- Miss...?
- McKay.
- Nice to see you again.
- Certainly nice to see you again.
Please, sit there.
Over there is good, too.
Wally Tripp.
Good to meet you.
Radiotelegram.
If you don't make a friend of TV
it exploits your misery.
You're miserable, you watch TV,
you escape, you see more misery.
- Violence, war...
- I tell you, TV has been good to me.
Mike, you're in local TV now, right?
You have to make a friend
of television.
$ 75?
Small school, tiny school,
no money, no bucks.
How do you say, "You can be great?"
- What's the toughest thing?
- Getting them to listen?
- Or getting them to think?
- The great ones don't.
What do you mean?
They react.
They don't have to think.
What're you talking about?
Are you saying a football player
is greater if he doesn't think?
I like watching you move.
Excuse me.
Basically, I'm in TV, too, now.
Hey, you.
Hi, how are you?
See the heavyset guy at the bar
with a camera?
He was traumatized by the landing
last night. He's so sweet.
I couldn't even get him
to come to the table.
- I can do that.
- Would you?
I'll do that for you.
That's so nice of you.
What are you doing?
Watching you move.
I saw what was going on
with you and the captain.
I'm not gonna put up with it
another moment, understand me?
They may be pretty faces,
but they're shallow.
Thank you, dear, I just...
I needed to hear you say that.
Did she fall for it?
The silly story of the plane going
down and moving to a Russian ship.
She doesn't ask a lot of questions.
- Is that good?
- I think so.
You don't play around, do you?
No, but I think I might have to if
I were involved with someone like you.
But you wouldn't.
You're way too fussy.
- Fussy?
- Cautious.
Playing around is like this.
Too much is bad for you,
but a little raises the HDLs.
- HDLs?
- Good for the heart.
Is it?
I think that might be
difficult for you.
Is that so?
It might be.
But you can get a little wet,
even if you're fussy.
Miss McKay.
Radiotelegram.
I'll be right back.
Alka-Seltzer, for headache.
My wife has a headache.
It's me.
Hello, honey.
- She was drunk.
- You're drunk.
- I'm not drunk!
- I see you're drunk.
- You're at the bar, flirting.
- I do not flirt!
You do flirt!
You gonna marry him?
Forget that.
What do you mean, a sailboat?
A coat or a dress I can understand.
But a sailboat?
That's what I'm doing in Sydney.
I'm decorating a sailboat.
- A red one.
- You're a decorator?
I'm a musician.
What do you play?
Piano, I guess.
I don't know. I teach it.
But I also write songs and I sing.
You sure sound like you sing.
Yeah, I sing.
I'm big. I'm very big.
Ray Charles sings, "You got the right
one" and someone goes, "Uh-huh"...
...in certain South American
countries, that's me.
Also, I have dabbled in waitressing...
...but at the apex of my music career
and my food service career...
...I met a man and I helped him
decorate his apartment in New York.
Then I decorated his Hampton house
and his house in Palm Beach.
Then I decorated his apartment
in Sydney.
If his acquisition
of Virgin succeeds...
...I'm sure I'll decorate something
in London.
But at the moment, it's a sailboat.
It's red. It's nice.
- You gonna marry him?
- Yeah, I guess. I hope so.
I'm madly in love with him.
What?
Come here.
All right?
- I really should go.
- No, don't.
I think so. I think so.
- Don't think.
- Right.
The great ones don't, huh?
- How you doing?
- How are you?
I'd like to send the lady a drink.
A glass of tomato juice, two raw eggs
and a shot of vinegar.
About last night...
Listen...
You don't want to mess up your life
any more than I do mine.
Well...
You can get a small plane tonight
to Tahiti, then to Sydney.
This boat will take two days to reach
an airport. You can get there tonight.
I'm gonna run along.
Big shuffleboard game?
As a matter of fact, I know a woman
who lives on the next island.
I'm shocked and amazed.
She's amazing. Want to come?
Do you feel you need a chaperon?
- She's my aunt.
- Your aunt?
A couple hours with a guy and his
aunt... Meet me in 20 minutes.
Do you have an aunt on every island?
Your aunt?
Sure.
Oh, ducks!
Out! Go on.
Holy Moses! Get!
For God's sake, Michael!
What are you doing here?
- You're the only restaurant in town.
- This is a surprise.
She's a surprise, too.
You, her, what a surprise.
You certainly have got yourself
a handful.
Actually, no, I don't.
He's got the handful? Good.
Very good. It's about time.
I like that.
You've got the wrong girl.
I say, you're a knockout in person
and look so much younger.
Do they make you up on television?
This is not Lynn,
this is Terry McKay.
We were on a plane together and
we had to land on the islands and...
Why were you
on a plane together?
- We were going to Australia.
- We're friends.
This isn't Lynn.
Friends?
- This isn't the girl you'll marry?
- No.
Well...
- We gotta be back on the boat by 5.
- It's nice to meet you.
Friends?
Rau, come and look who's here.
So...
Well...
How's the new job?
How is it? Is it fun?
Is it satisfying, at least?
Say no more. Say no more.
Eloquent, isn't he?
A born broadcaster.
How are you doing?
This is Rau. Terry McKay.
- Look at you! How big he is!
- Come see the little one.
We're going to see the baby.
Be right back.
What do you think of your brother?
Tell me, as a friend, what do you
think of Michael's fiancée?
Well, we just met, Mike and I.
- You're a new friend?
- I haven't met Lynn.
Neither have I, as I'm sure
you've gathered by now.
- Are you in broadcasting?
- No.
- What do you do?
- Music.
- Music?
Your house is beautiful.
It's rather nice.
I'd never leave here.
I hope you don't feel awkward
being here with Michael...
...when he's engaged.
I'm engaged myself.
Are you happy?
I'd better be.
I have everything I want.
- That's what Michael says.
- Why do you think he's wrong?
I didn't say he was wrong.
Naive, maybe.
The trick in life isn't
getting what you want...
...it's wanting it after you get it.
For people like you and Michael,
the getting is easy.
Would you like something to eat?
Thanks, but don't go to any trouble.
No, it's no trouble at all.
Your horses are beautiful.
They seem devoted.
Bernard and Sophie? They're devoted,
but then they're stuck on an island.
Horses are not monogamous.
I made this tea cake yesterday.
Could you slice it for me, please?
Swans, of course, are.
- Are what?
- Monogamous.
- They are?
- Unremittingly.
You make them sound almost boring.
- I mean...
- I know what you mean.
- Roosters?
- Not monogamous.
You've heard?
- Do you find them boring?
- Depends on the rooster.
What about ducks?
They're worse. They're promiscuous,
and they are terribly indiscreet.
- I try not to make judgements.
- About what?
About whether or not
somebody wants to...
...if you'll excuse the expression...
...fuck a duck.
Please don't misunderstand.
I'm not recommending it.
But I don't necessarily view it
as a moral failure.
No. I mean, no.
How long were you married?
Dearie, I am married,
although he died 12 years ago.
I am married.
Haven't we forgotten something?
Yes. Forks.
If I'd known
I was going to live to 86...
...I wouldn't have let the maid go.
You like it?
Very much.
Michael did it.
- Back when he played football.
- Does he still paint?
I don't think so.
I doubt he has the time.
He's so busy...
...in other places...
...pursuing other things...
...if you'll excuse the expression...
...other ducks.
Other ducks.
But I'm not sure Michael is a duck.
He does a pretty good
imitation of one.
Sometimes I feel he's desperate.
Impostors are usually
desperate to behave...
...like what they know they're not.
But as a duck...
...I have no doubt he's very credible
and highly energetic.
You're worried about him?
I didn't say I was worried about him.
I hope you won't turn out to be
one of those irritating women...
...who think they can read minds.
Okay. I'm worried.
Why?
I just...
I just want him to have what I had.
I've been lucky.
I always knew what I wanted.
He's settling down, isn't he?
Michael may just be the ugly duckling
who doesn't know he's a swan.
He thinks he's a duck. He'll probably
continue to behave like a duck...
...until he finds another swan.
Maybe he's found one.
I'm quite sure he's found one.
Five o'clock.
- You must go?
- Yes.
- May I...?
- Thank you.
Thank you.
I wore this when I was married.
Beautiful.
Well, off you go.
These petals are
supposedly the hands...
...of a Polynesian princess.
It's been hanging around
for 62 years...
...and it's still holding together.
I wish I could say
the same for myself.
We'll see you soon.