Subtitles by explosiveskull
What was the question?
Um..
I mean, what's happy?
Really, I mean, it's..
...so arbitrary.
I... I'm... I'm..
Look, we had a fight
so I'm not, like,
"Oh..
...I'm happy."
But I'm happy.
I like Rebecca.
She feels like family.
Sometimes I feel like
she validates
how I feel
about the world.
I think she's smart
and that makes me
feel smart.
But..
...sometimes it feels..
...it's all too clean.
You know?
But I'm happy.
Are you?
Sometimes I'm happy.
Can't always be happy.
That's true.
What makes you happy?
I just love my kids,
you know.
I do.
Seeing you,
I wanna see you..
...you know, I wanna see
you happy and fulfilled.
Just love my boys.
What can I say?
And your dad's
pretty good in bed too.
I need you to teach me this.
Nah. I've got a blanket
for you.
I could do that part.
There we go.
Alright, thank you.
Guys, this is Paul,
he's an old friend.
This is Alex, and Graham.
- Really old.
- I'm sorry.
- This is John.
- Hey, welcome, my friend.
No, check that out.
Hey.
You hiding out?
I thought I had an hour.
You had it.
John.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
Hi. Emilie.
Thank you so much.
- You mad at me?
- No.
Are you mad at me?
- I just wanna finish this.
- Okay.
Are you mad at me?
Oh, my God,
you're intolerable.
I love you, old man.
Uh, I love you more than
all the other old men.
Can I ask you something?
Does he, um, does he do soliloquies
when he's going down on you?
What are you asking?
She's fucking
what's-his-face
the Duke of Athens
over here.
- I did not say that! He's a freshman.
- And?
- I don't tolerate freshmen.
- Since when?
- You want wine?
- Glenn, Glenn, when do you start?
- Sorry?
- When do you actually start?
Immediately. I'll be
up there on Monday.
- Wow.
- Will you commute?
- If my wife has her way.
Glenn's afraid
that his marriage is over.
- I'm not laughing.
- Uh, I'm taking this.
- See, this is his thing.
- Yes!
What's my thing?
Before you do something selfish,
you, like, broadcast it.
You think
it makes it okay.
We're in love, so we're
allowed to say mean things
to each other, I guess.
You're showing me tits.
There're these pictures
I made.
- You've got tits?
- Look.
It's fine.
- You know, it's getting dark.
- Okay.
Should probably
get 'em home.
When are you going
to grow up?
Did you have any?
Have it, it's good.
Quit now, James.
So now he's affectionate.
She'd run
the other designer off.
- That's not true.
- Yes, it is.
Glenn, it's not true.
She took another job.
She went to,
I don't know where.
UT, I think.
She resigned.
Yeah, she resigned. Her
assistant was fucking her boss
What else
is she gonna do?
- No, it's not.
- So, what, it's true?
- Oh, my God. Chris.
- It's true.
No, no, it's not.
I went out with him once.
One time.
I was an idiot.
I thought that, you know
he was being professional.
When she came along, I couldn't
sign the papers fast enough.
- Oh, how romantic.
- You..
You would've been
on marriage, what?
Your marriage number two?
Wait, wasn't that
your, uh, open marriage?
Yeah, she was a swinger!
- No, I wasn't!
- That's what she said. Is that not what she said?
Being in an open marriage is not
the same thing as being a swinger.
Close enough!
Three marriages.
- Pear?
- I don't like pears.
No, these are,
um, poached pears.
They're not normal.
Great.
- Do you know what poached pears are?
- Yes.
Try one.
- What?
- Nothing. Go ahead.
- I, I'm just offering them pears.
- I see that.
"All days are nights
to see..
"...till I see thee.
"And nights bright days when
dreams do show thee me.
"When most I wink, then
do mine eyes best see..
"...for all the day..
...they view things
unrespected."
- Thank you.
- Beautiful, Glenn.
- Cheers.
One more time, dad.
Leave him alone.
Stop it.
I'll bust your butt.
- Come on, then.
- Don't think I won't.
- Okay.
- That sounds terrible, Glenn.
Yeah, he fell asleep
in the bath.
I don't feel anything.
- I just can't talk.
- Is that true?
Let's go.
- That's the only way he can get any rest.
- Stop it.
Hey. Thanks.
- Hi.
- I've been circling for half an hour.
I didn't see you.
I tried calling.
You didn't pick up.
I, I don't have my phone.
Well, you could've
just parked and come in.
Well, you said you were
gonna wait outside.
It's good to see you too.
- Okay.
- Lift him up.
Alright, there you go.
There you go.
- That's it, dad.
- Okay.
One, two, three.
Ah!
Glenn, this is so
you can breathe easier.
I want you to try and
breathe through your nose.
Okay, hold on.
Here you go.
It's okay, it's okay. This
is gonna help you breathe.
It's alright.
- I'll get them.
- Okay, sweetie.
Here we go.
If you can lift
after this. Just wait.
- One second.
- Alright. Hold on.
Okay, now.
Watch his head.
Okay, back.
Really gentle.
There we go.
Good job, honey.
- It's almost done.
- There you go.
We're not gonna..
There you go.
It's okay, sweetheart.
Do you want me to get you
up or do you wanna sleep?
Mm..
You asked me
to get you up.
Just five more minutes.
I came here
to support you
but it feels like
you don't want me around.
- You can't answer me?
- I'm, I'm sleeping.
Okay, we've got him here.
Okay, just give me
a second, please.
- Alright.
- Okay.
Back him up just a bit.
Please, just a bit.
Just a bit.
There you go.
- Are you alright? Is that good?
- Yeah.
There we are. Okay.
- Alright.
- Okay, you can sit him down.
- There.
- We shouldn't be in here.
- It's okay.
- He's embarrassed.
He's just sitting there.
It's humiliating.
Let's just wait. Just...
- Suzanne?
- Oh, thank you.
- Wait, he's falling.
- Hang on.
There we are. It's okay.
There we go.
Hold on. There you go.
Alright.
Here we are.
I think that's it, okay?
- Alright. You ready?
- Come back up.
...a ride around
the back roads.
We always had stuff. They
had an ice cream place.
They hadn't had that
before they'd come home.
They liked to talk with
us, and we'd walk.
When you'd go away
and let them go away
and have a good time.
- Oh, wait, wait.
- What?
I'm gonna, I'm gonna
cum if we keep going.
Cum. Cum. I want you to.
You don't wanna finish?
Oh! Oh!
Oh. Oh. Oh.
Hmm..
- Good?
- Yeah.
- ...fucking bed like an animal!
- Just stop, stop for a...
- What happened?
- Just, it's.. Wait.
- She restrained him.
What are you smiling at?
- Just.. Chris, that's enough.
- Chris. Stop that.
- I was only trying to make him comfortable.
- I'm...
- I'm not an idiot!
- Chris!
- Enough!
- I'm not making it up!
- Please!
- I'm sorry.
- No.
- I'm sorry. Okay?
- No, that's okay.
You know, you can go, I mean,
I, I really appreciate it and..
...thank you so much for
everything, and, uh, you know
I'll ta... I'll talk
to him. I'll talk to him.
How's the wine?
Anybody want
a little more?
- That white's really good.
- The white is good.
- Isn't that good?
- The red's good too.
Hey, do you want some?
You're inconsolable.
Huh?
- Like an infant.
- Can we not say mean things?
Inconsolable
little infant.
I'm not doing this, Nick.
- You're inconsolable.
- Can you stop?
You have determined
that you're being ignored
so you behave like this,
like an infant?
And so I ignore you.
What am I supposed to do?
- I think we should go to bed.
- No!
You are not the center of
anyone's attention right now.
And you shouldn't be.
Full fucking stop,
Rebecca.
Ma.
- Hey.
- Hey, we're gonna, um..
Sorry.
- You're off?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry
I can't stay longer.
Oh, stop.
We'll see you soon.
- See you at home.
- Yeah.
Wait.
You'll wanna pick out
some clothing
that Glenn would be
comfortable in wearing.
He may have been
very involved
and already picked out his
clothing, I don't know.
Yes, he was
very involved.
And then lastly, we'll
follow up in a day or two
and see how you're coping
and how you're doing.
- Um..
- Well, thank you.
And if there's any questions,
you know, feel free to ask me.
I don't think so.
- Hi, hi.
- Hello.
Hello. Hi, I'm Suzanne.
- I'm Lauren. Nice to meet you.
- Yeah.
- Can I take your stuff?
- Oh, thank you.
I'm okay.
Thank you so much.
- Hi, I'm Chris.
- Lauren.
- So nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Thanks.
- Hey, what's your name?
- Tia.
- Well, hello.
- Come on. Come on in, come on in.
- Hey. You got here.
- Hi. Yeah. Yeah.
- You look great.
- You look beautiful.
- Welcome. Hi.
- Oh, hello. Hi.
- Oh, hi.
- Can I introduce you..
- Hey, it's me, your brother.
- I know who you are.
Uh, mom, this is,
uh, Greg and Margo.
- Oh, hello. So nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
- Suzanne.
- Yeah, it was a pleasure.
That's me. Emilie.
- This is for...
- Oh, I got you these. Oh, sorry.
- Thank you. You shouldn't have.
- Oh, thank you. So nice.
- Hello there.
- Come on in, we'll have some drinks.
Oh, thank you.
Excuse me.
Could I interrupt
your conversations
for just a moment?
Uh, it might be
timely for me
to propose a toast.
Uh, we're gathered here not
just to celebrate the holidays
but to celebrate
the engagement
of my darling youngest
daughter Emilie and Nick.
And it fills Margo and I both
with a great deal of joy
to have Nick and his family,
Suzanne and Chris here
along with our friends.
Let's raise
our glasses to... marriage
long-lived and fruitful.
Hear, hear.
And to my mother.
- Hear, hear.
- Cheers.
- Cheers, mom.
- My pleasure, Nick.
- Thanks, dad.
We moved one step ahead.
- What.. Oh, shit.
- Whoa!
Nice one.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
- It happens.
And what about you,
what do you do?
I work at the college with Suzanne
in the, in the theatre department.
Oh, interesting.
I... I really work
in th... this marketing
for the plays
that they do.
Also a little bit
of consulting for the kids
when they're getting ready to go
out into the, the real world.
- Uh-huh.
- I used to be an actress myself.
- And Chris, what do you do? What kind of work?
- Oh. Me?
I'm, uh..
I write whatever I want that
no one will want to read.
- Like novels or..
- Hmm, uh, yeah.
But, very, very short.
Oh, come on, dad. You were
such a hippie back in the day.
It's the shop, it's
like coming up off Craigslist.
We didn't celebrate our weddings
by getting goofy on mushrooms.
It's you.
- No. Really?
- People do this.
I shouldn't be laughing.
- I think it's a good..
- Sorry.
...bonding experience
and to bring the family
together, I don't know.
I don't think
it's funny.
- No, I think it's.. Okay. I get..
- I'm excited.
- You were excited.
- I am excited.
- Okay.
- I get that it's, it's unusual.
But, that's okay.
We're okay with people..
...being confused by it.
I mean, I think the..
What are these?
These are Italian
wedding cookies.
- Well, can I have one?
- Yeah.
Do you guys work here?
- Here?
- Like, all the time?
Uh, we work for the catering
company, if that's what you mean.
Yeah.
Good.
♪ Feel so nice
right on.. ♪
I haven't even
seen your ring.
There isn't one.
What, you haven't
got a ring?
- No, we got earrings.
- Show 'em off, will you?
That's so pretty.
She told me what she
wanted, we went together.
Oh.
- Doesn't she look pretty?
- Stop.
- Right, mom?
- She's beautiful.
- Great.
- See?
- I didn't see the earrings.
- Hmm.
- Sweet.
- Yeah.
♪ Feel so nice
right on ♪
♪ Feel.. ♪♪
"'Twas brillig,
and the slithy toves
"did gyre
and gimble in the wabe.
"All mimsy
were the borogoves
"and the mome
raths outgrabe.
"Beware the Jabberwock,
my son.
"The jaws that bite,
the claws that catch!
"Beware the Jubjub bird, and
shun the frumious Bandersnatch.
"He took his vorpal
sword in hand
"Long time the manxome
foe he sought
"so rested he by the Tumtum tree
and stood awhile in thought.
And, as in uffish ..."
- Nicholas.
- Hey, man.
- What's up?
I want to tell you that..
...I'm proud of you.
And, I love you.
Okay. Okay, Chris.
And, uh, and I'm just
really proud of you.
I know. I just..
Thanks, man. Thank you.
- I love you.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
- Jesus Christ!
- Oh!
Ah!
- Are you okay?
- Ow!
- Alright.
- Nicholas has got me.
Okay.
- Oh, wow.
- Take it easy. Okay.
- You had a little fall there.
- Yeah.
You're good.
- Because he's the good one.
- Alright.
- I think we got it.
- You're the good one.
- Uh-huh.
- You can't hear enough of it.
You're the good one.
- You're good too. Sometimes.
- Aww, I'm okay.
- You wanna sit down?
- I don't wanna sit down.
That's a bad idea.
- You wanna lie down?
- I wanna... pee.
I just wanna pee
and then it's fine.
- I'm gonna go pee.
- You need a hand with that?
I am so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
- You okay, buddy?
- I'm... I'm... I'm okay.
Yeah?
Then, they..
That's..
It's good.
Someone's gonna carry him
home tonight.
You okay, man?
Chris, what are you doing?
Chris!
Stop it.
Jesus! Are you..
- Get outta here!
- Damn it!
What are you doing?
- Oh, shit.
- Mom!
Okay, I'm going!
- I am sorry to you.
- Sit down.
- I'm so sorry.
- Whoa!
I... I'm...
Uh, it was like
a dog food commercial.
Oh, no.
It was
a dog food commercial
and, um, I was a..
- Wet or dry?
- Um..
Didn't get that far. That
was in the callback.
- You didn't get that far?
- Yeah, they had, like, plastic dog food.
And I was, like,
a dog owner
and I was supposed
to be with my dog, like
"You like it? I like it."
And, um, it was
so humiliating, right?
'Cause it was, like,
plastic dog food.
- Yeah.
- Was there a real dog?
No. It was a fucking
shaggy puppet dog.
And I went.. I slumped over visibly.
I was just like..
And he put his hand on my
shoulder and he was like
"I know, man. I know."
- Oh, man, Chris.
- And then, that's it. That was..
Were you supposed to make a
face, like, you didn't like it?
- Or you liked it?
- No, you were supposed to like it.
It was, like, "Can you give me one where
you just really love this stuff?"
I don't understand
this commercial.
- Yeah, it doesn't make sense.
- The commercial is...
Yeah, it's their fault.
They're a bunch of idiots.
I came in
as a true artist.
It sounds like it's actually a
snack for dogs and, and humans.
I read the proposal, but for the
benefit of my colleagues here
can you explain, um, how you
see it as a hybrid of memoir
and, and history
of Shepard Stuyvesant?
Uh, well, it intersperses chapters
that are taken from my own life.
Yet I think, there's also a historical
and critical element that, um..
...that really, I think, kinda
marries itself to the memoir section
in a way that's unique and I
think will speak to readers.
Do you think
it will upset..
- They're all their life?
- I think so.
And I think that I'm trying
to speak to that line.
You're.. Are you
straddling that line?
I think I'm on the line.
- You're on the line?
- I am the line.
You are the line. Okay.
And besides yourself, what other
characters feature in the book?
Well, there's historical
figures, so there's James Weeks
who founded
the Weeksville settlement.
Um, there's
my roommates, who..
Um, I don't know, it's really a..
That's a Diego question.
Or Rebecca. She's in..
Uh..
Well,
by day's end at least.
No, I... I... I like it,
too. I just..
No, but that's... that's what I'm saying.
I like it too.
I just can't go
any further until
we have a... a... proper
conversation about it.
No, with everybody.
- Knock, knock.
- Hey! Nick said you were here.
- He's stuck on the phone.
- Oh. Come in, come in.
Honestly, I... I... I don't even
care if it is. That's your problem.
Yeah, I heard that.
All set?
Okay.
- Merry Christmas.
Suzanne, they're ready
for you downstairs.
Okay, I'll be right down.
"Yes, we shall live,
Uncle Vanya.
"We shall live all through the
endless procession of days
"ahead of us and through
the long evenings.
"We shall bear patiently the
burdens that fate imposes on us.
"We shall work without rest for
others, both now and when we are old.
"And when our
final hour comes..
"...we shall meet it
humbly..
"...and there,
beyond the grave
we will say that we have known
tears and suffering ..."
Okay. very good.
Um, Thank you, Ashleigh.
Uh, that's, uh..
Who... who wants
to go first?
- Suzanne?
- I have nothing to say.
- Is that good?
- No.
O... okay. Is that all
you're gonna say?
We've done this once a semester
for three years, Ashleigh.
Done what?
This is not the outfit of someone who
takes herself or her work seriously.
- Oh, come on, Suzanne.
- Excuse me.
I take this very,
very seriously.
And I'm trying
really hard.
Oh, Lord, help me.
Why are you so mad?
If you want me to wear
a sweater, I will.
I don't want you
to do anything.
- Why are you yelling at me?
- I'm not yelling...
Yes, you are.
- You're yelling at me.
- I'm not yelling at you.
I'm trying to help you.
Okay, um..
- Suzanne, I think your point's been made.
- Scott! Stop it.
Let's just move on.
Karen. What?
- Stop undermining me.
- Oh, okay.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, Karen.
- It's okay.
- Go ahead.
I... I don't think the
outfit is, is that bad.
If we're approaching this
practically, we have to be open
and... and supportive of the
possibility that, in some cases
and certainly for a beginning
actor, especially for a woman
there is a certain value placed
on physical appearance...
I don't know
what I'm doing here
if I can't expect support
from my colleagues.
Oh, I'm not dismissing
your point...
I hate the way that
you are speaking to me.
- Either of you! Fuck!
- Suzanne.
- Fuck!
It's alright.
- Sorry.
- It's okay. Really.
Crazy, but it's okay.
I said, "One more tantrum
and that's it."
So..
...sure enough,
10 minutes in
he starts going off
on Jane...
Were you in on the cooking
at all? No?
I just said, I stopped the
meeting and I said, "Excuse me."
And I said, you know, "Tim,
can we go out in the hall?"
We walked out,
about five feet down
and I just... just, I may
have said a word to him
but I swiveled back
in the room
and I locked the door.
And I just continued
the meeting.
We had a pretty
long agenda.
You know, we got the..
How we doing tonight,
folks? Alright.
How are you tonight? 102, right
straight through, please.
Okay. At the end of their life.
Sorry.
Foul! Foul! Foul!
You're outta your mind.
No! Come on,
get your act together!
Defense!
Oh, the kiss cam!
The kiss cam.
Maybe it'll be..
♪ We are we are
Washington High ♪♪
- It's not bad. It's good.
- Well.. Pretty good.
It's rich, you know.
It's got a lotta hops.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, it does.
No doubt about it.
I'm not a beer connoisseur
or anything, but..
You can say somethin'.
What?
We can talk, you know.
I don't... I don't know
what to say.
I feel like I'm,
I'm havin' an affair.
Hey. I'm, uh, brewing
some tea. You want some?
- Yeah, that sounds nice.
- Okay.
You can, you can take
your coat off.
Oh, I'm gonna go soon.
♪ Bet it hurt a ton 'til they
pissed where he was bitten ♪
♪ I remember
what you said ♪
♪ What you said to me ♪
♪ I remember
what you said ♪
♪ What you said to me ♪♪
Hey.
Hey. You're here.
I just walked in.
What's going on?
You repainting?
I told you that.
No, you didn't.
Well, I'm repainting.
I thought Emilie
was coming.
She's on the phone.
She booked a commercial.
Why are these here?
- Ma?
- What?
- Did you hear me?
- Yes, Nicholas, I heard you.
Well, don't just throw
my things away, okay?
- I live here too.
- You do not live here.
"Lived."
I said "lived."
Come on.
We made coffee.
Thank you.
- Do you want some?
- No thanks.
This is fine, right?
Of course.
- Who was it?
- A package.
For me?
What is it?
Ah, feels like books.
Did you order books?
- Is this for now?
- It is if you want it.
Um..
I got a letter from
Rebecca the other day.
It must be hard on her
havin' you in the office.
No. We don't
really interact.
Our departments
are separate now.
Still.
It's actually easier now
than it was before.
What does that mean?
Just the whole thing
was such an effort.
We were always trying.
Not in the beginning.
In the beginning,
you were in love
I don't think so.
I was there.
Okay.
If she didn't return your calls,
you were out of your mind.
- You were distraught.
- Okay.
- I was never distraught.
- You were obsessed.
- That's your word.
- I wanted her to love me.
That's not the same
as falling in love.
It was like a goal.
Rebecca was a person
of real consequence.
- Okay.
- What?
What?
What do you mean "what?"
Why do you wanna
do this now?
Why do you always
fucking do this?
Jesus. "A person
of real consequence?"
What the fuck is that?
- You mean as in Emilie is not that?
- Excuse me.
- Who said anything about Emilie?
- Oh, please.
- I didn't. I don't even know Emilie.
- Okay.
So don't try to weasel
some opinion out of me.
If I want to say somethin'
about Emilie, I'll say it.
And this is
the living room.
Oh.
Oh, the ceilings.
- Pretty great, huh?
- Great light.
- Such good light.
- We love it.
Oh, those bay windows.
Yeah, we're really lucky.
Do you have the backyard?
- Yeah.
- We share it.
- Share it?
- Uh-huh.
But still. Very nice.
Do your... kids ask
where you go?
They're not really
interested.
- Sure, now.
- I know.
Do you hate me tonight?
What?
Do you hate me?
Of course not.
- I'm very hateable.
- No.
Then there's no hate.
Hope I hate anybody.
I can't stick it out.
Is that okay?
Mm. There's nothing
to do now.
I'm just re-reading
her emails.
- She's an idiot.
- You want me to call Paul?
- No.
- Wait, are you angry?
It's the second time she's pushed.
She's being a shit.
Yeah.
She's just embarrassed.
She'll send you a long
apology email tomorrow.
I left some Szechwan
in the fridge.
You hear me?
- Are you leaving now?
- Uh-huh.
I'll walk down with you.
I called a car.
Are you taking
the train?
Yeah, traffic's
gonna be shitty.
Okay. Well,
I'll see you later.
Night.
Hi. Thanks.
Do you have the address?
Whoa, whoa.
I'm sorry.
- What are you doing?
- Whoa!
I just, uh, I realized I
don't have anywhere to be.
So I thought I could just
ride with you and..
Drop you off and take the
car home, if that's okay.
- Okay. Yeah.
- Great.
I mean, we should probably
have an answer if we're goin'
in the morning anyway,
right?
Uh-huh.
What?
I.. I don't know,
it's just..
- I'm having a...
- I know.
You know what?
Like..
...like, emotional spins,
right?
- Emotional spins?
- Yeah.
I don't even know
what that is.
- So, um..
- Goodbye, Nick.
Alright.
See you tomorrow.
Goodnight, Nicholas.
Uh, Becca,
just wait a second.
- Nick, this is weird.
- No, it's not.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Just go home.
I just, I need
to use the bathroom.
- Whose bathroom?
- I'll be fast.
- No, you can't come up.
- Why not?
Nick, go.
Why are you being like..
I'm..
We're just talking.
What, I can't
talk to you now?
Okay, fine, fine,
but don't leave like this.
I'm not leaving like anything.
I'm going to my apartment.
You can't just stop
for a second?
Go home, Nick.
You're making this worse.
Okay, come on.
Becca.
- Come on! Rebecca!
- Oh, my God! Enough!
What, you're just gonna
leave like this?
- Come on, let's go.
- Nice, Rebecca!
Real fuckin' nice!
Nice job!
- Hey, come on.
- Oh, fuck off!
...old people next to, or,
like, at the same table
as other people, and it
was kind of a disaster.
I'd have like hives up and
down my arms that's what..
That's what they gave me
the Benadryl for.
- Yeah.
- Um, yeah.
I didn't last too long
there, I loved it.
I stole their muffins.
Do you remember them?
I think that's a classic server
move to steal all muffins.
All muffins
should be always stolen.
Yeah.
That's crazy, though,
so when..
...when you were, like, serving people,
you had, like, hives on your...
I don't know what it was. I think
I was just allergic to something.
It wasn't the cleanest..
...diner experience.
You should have seen
the place we stayed.
- She wanted to move in.
- Oh, it was unbelievable.
Old original architecture
with this beautiful balcony.
You know, it just feels like
you're in another country.
God, that smells good.
Make some room over there.
Here, let's just
put that down there.
Yeah, there.. Yeah, there are all
those weird people who just don't..
- May I?
- I ju.. I... I..
- Don't use money, I guess.
- Thanks.
I don't know.
You decide, Karen.
- Mm-hmm.
- I have friends who live there.
Terrific music.
Michael loves jazz.
Always have.
I mean, Coltrane, Monk,
you know.
Uh, I even like bad jazz,
really.
It was so.. It was just so funny,
you know, he... he... he..
We would go looking for
these out-of-way places.
He would go up to people
on the street.
I didn't want to get trapped
in the touristy places.
You know..
I mean,
you're in New Orleans.
I wanted the real thing.
Do you know a man
who has been in love
with only one woman?
There certainly
are such men.
Are they amongst
your friends?
Tell me his name.
I have no name
to tell you
but I do believe
that there are men
capable of loving..
...but once.
How often
can a true man love?
What are you trying
to find out?
Ask.
I'll answer it.
Am I right to stay
in the convent?
No.
- Cool, right?
- Yeah, I liked it.
I've never been
backstage before.
Oh, there he is.
- Oh. Matthew.
- Hey.
- Congratulations.
- Oh, thank you!
- You were just wonderful.
- Thank you. I think it went pretty well.
So do I. Matthew,
this is my friend Michael.
Michael, this is Matthew.
- He played Perdican.
- Of course.
- Hey!
- You were awesome.
- Thank you!
Ashleigh, you were fantastic.
It was great.
Oh, thank you.
Hi, I'm Ashleigh.
- Hi. Michael.
- Hi, nice to meet you. Hi.
♪ Do whatcha feel
whatcha feel ♪
♪ When you're
getting down ♪
♪ Ooh get down ♪
♪ Get down ♪
♪ Do whatcha feel ♪
♪ Do do do do ♪
♪ Oo ooh ♪
♪ It doesn't matter
if you're young or old ♪
♪ Every man or woman ♪
♪ Every boy or girl ♪
♪ Just do whatcha feel
whatcha feel ♪
♪ When the music
hits ya ♪♪
♪ Monkey right on ♪
♪ Funky monkey
right on baby ♪
♪ Funky monkey right on ♪
♪ Funky monkey
all night long ♪
♪ One more time ♪
♪ Funky monkey right on ♪
♪ Funky monkey
right on baby ♪
♪ Funky monkey right on ♪
♪ Funky monkey
all night long ♪
♪ Is your monkey funky? ♪
♪ Is your monkey.. ♪
♪ All you do
is dance funky monkey ♪
♪ Do it baby ♪
♪ Is your monkey funky? ♪
♪ All you do
is dance funky monkey ♪
♪ Is your monkey funky? ♪
♪ Get down over there ♪
♪ All you do
is dance funky monkey ♪
♪ Alright get down ♪
♪ Is your monkey funky? ♪
♪ Come on let's do it ♪
♪ All you do
is dance funky monkey ♪
♪ Funky monkey right on ♪
♪ Funky monkey
right on baby ♪
♪ Funky monkey right on ♪
♪ Funky monkey
all night long ♪♪
Yes!
I thought I had them
in this pocket.
- What, your phone?
- No, my keys.
- My house key.
- Oh, no.
- You lost them?
- Oh, got it.
Um..
Hey.
- Why are you up?
- It's morning.
Where were you?
Oh, I just, uh,
took Karen home.
How is she?
Nicholas.
How is Karen?
Uh, I don't know
what you mean.
You don't?
She's alive.
Come on, Max.
Uh, what time
did you guys get in?
Ma? You're not gonna
answer me?
What does it matter
what time we got in?
Why are you pissed?
Well, good morning.
You smell.
Okay.
Well,
I'm going to go to bed.
I did that. Yeah.
- I loved that job.
- You did?
Yeah, I actually did.
Like..
Let's see.
Let's give you this one.
Hey, Miss Floy.
Mm!
- Look who it is.
- Hey.
I'll take that.
Is this free?
- Yeah, yeah.
- I'm gonna use this.
That's just
orange juice there.
Aren't you hot?
You're wearing
a sweater too.
Hey.
- You want some juice?
- Yeah.
Perfect.
Um, silverware?
Oh, this,
this drawer right here.
Last night..
What do you think
of this guy?
It should be
the other way around.
- Michael?
- No.
Um..
I don't know.
He's nice enough, right?
- I feel bad.
- No, you're fine.
And if that's
the real question or not.
If it is..
I don't know
how to behave.
- Chris, can you get these?
- Yeah.
- I can do it.
- Chris!
- Ma, I'm doing it.
- What?
He's doing it.
You hear her?
What?
Oh,
who needs some coffee?
- I'll have one.
- I have some.
We should say
something.
- I think...
- No, no, I think I'm gonna say something.
No, no, no, no.
It's fine.
What? No, no, no, no.
Just a little.
I just want to say
a little something
in honor of our
new guest.
Happy birthday,
Michael.
We are very happy
to have you here.
Very happy.
Thank you.
And, of course, to, uh..
To little,
uh, uh, Zachary.
Um, who's also here.
To Michael and..
...to, um..
...this..
...special..
...thing that's happening
right before our eyes.
Even though..
...we're desperately trying
not to notice, it is.
And I think it's right
that we celebrate that.
So, to Michael and mom.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
Hear, hear.
You wanna say something,
Michael?
You don't have
to say anything.
I think you're
doing great.
Thank you.
Nothing?
- Would you like me to?
- Yeah.
Sure. Uh..
This has gotta be
really hard.
Ah..
I thank you for
welcoming me here.
Uh, however you have.
It can't have been easy.
I understand that.
And it had to call on
some reserves.
And I had
a great dinner.
And you were very nice
to my guy.
So, thank you.
Hear, hear.
To Michael.
- To Michael.
- Cheers.
It's hard to know,
you know, what to..
It's right to ce...
to celebrate it in..
...some fucking way,
but it's..
I don't know what to say.
- You did great.
- Thank you.
It's not like
there's, uh..
there's a card for..
...good luck with your
new relationship
older people.
That's enough, Nicholas.
It's hard to know, isn't it?
It's hard to know what to say.
Stop!
Thank you.
Zach, uh,
you wanna help me clear?
- You're so selfish.
- Nick.
- You're so self...
- Nick!
Shut up.
Where are you..
Wait. Wait!
- Let her go! Nick.
- You should've asked.
- You should've asked!
- Don't do that to her!
- Dick!
- You should have asked!
- Ah!
- Nicholas! Nicholas, no!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Come on!
Nicholas! Ugh!
- Come on! Come on!
- Get off him, Nick!
- Get off him!
- Goddamn it!
Oh!
Jackass.
And, um, he comes along
and he..
...he's got his
own tricks.
He's got a few of his
own tricks up his sleeve.
I mean,
he can walk on water.
He can turn water
into wine.
Ain't he? Uh, you get
what I'm saying?
I think everything he did
was kind of a step down
from the old man.
Like..
...water into wine?
Congratulations,
that's a great trick.
Um... you... he, your dad
made both of those
out of hydrogen
and oxygen
which he also made..
...out of shit
that he made
out of shit that he made
that we don't
even know about yet.
Um, okay,
so Jesus multiplied
a bunch of bread
and fishes.
Like, that's a great trick
if your dad is David Blaine.
But, um..
...that ain't shit
when we're talking about
wormholes, and antimatter.
That's like,
that's some
Frank Sinatra, Jr. shit
right there
is what I call that.
That's not even..
That's not even
Julian Lennon.
That's like a Sean Lennon
body of work.
"Hey, Dad."
"What?"
"Um, uh,
I make cabinets."
"I want..
You want an armoire?"
"I created light."
"Back off, moron."
I don't know, I just feel,
I lost my dad
so I feel a little..
It's hard
to live up to him.
Maybe that's coloring
my thoughts right now.
Uh, apple falls far
from the tree sometimes.
I did, um, I did,
I just lost my dad.
Uh, my father
passed away.
That's something that Jesus
never had to deal with.
One of the perks
of dying at 33.
When your dad's
immortal anyway, like..
He didn't have
to go through this.
Or like,
sell a house ever.
Jesus never had
to do that.
And I feel like,
oh, if my dad just died
I'm starting to worry about
myself 'cause I've heard
that kind of thing runs
in the family, you know?
Anybody else
lose anybody recently?
Yeah, it sucks.
My dad, gone.
Just like,
that whole stick figure
just wiped off
the back of my minivan.
That must be a sad job
down at the gas station.
That takes an auto detailer
with a certain finesse
to be able to, like,
scrape the family member
off the back of the..
...van.
Um, but you know,
it's tough.
It's tough when you go
through losing a loved one.
Someone you grew up with
someone you admire
or hate or..
...hatemire.
Um, and then, like,
you... you
you put them away
forever.
Put 'em away? What? I don't think
that's the right terminology.
Yep.
Put that away.
That's the wo..
I don't underst..
When you have the ashes,
what are we saving them for?
Uh, it's a bit like,
it's a ho..
It's like, when you save
ornaments for Christmas
but it's not every year.
Every 50 years,
they, they get up
and dance like
Tinker Bell.
I don't understand
why we save the ashes.
I couldn't convince 'em
to get rid of 'em.
Um, but you know..
...you lose somebody and then
you're like, "Well, what next?"
And you've, we've all
lost somebody or..
If you haven't,
then you're gonna lose
a whole lot all at once,
I guess.
Sorry.
Um, but then you're like,
"Oh, okay.
"This is sad, this is
very sad primarily.
And then what?
What's next?"
And... nothing.
Nothing happens.
Everybody, like, wipes their
hands and they're like..
"Great. You good?" "Um, I guess.
Yeah, I guess I'm good."
"I'm hungry primarily."
"Yeah, let's go eat."
And then, well, we got
a large group of people.
"Uh, Olive Garden." And, so
you end up at Olive Garden.
My dad was dead
for like 12 minutes
and we were diving
face-first
into pans of lasagna.
Okay.
I feel like
I'm at a..
I'm at a funeral here.
But I guess
I'm trying to say
as shitty as death is..
...it's almost worse
how easy it is to get
over somebody dying.
Like, you expect
that when you die
everyone
in the whole world
is gonna be consumed
with grief.
Like, they're gonna thr..
Like CNN is gonna,
like, weep
and they're gonna throw
themselves on a funeral pyre
which they brought back
into fashion for you.
And none of that happens.
Everybody at the funeral
is drunk that night
and they're back to work at
most, like, later that week.
"Your loss." And then
they're just at work.
It's just an excuse to be 10
minutes late to work for a month.
"My dad died. Yeah.
"Yeah, it's tough.
My dad died.
I'll, I'll get right
on that, I promise."
- Hi. You all set?
- Hi.
You guys are great.
I feel comfortable talking
about death with you guys
'cause it feels like I'm halfway
in the grave right now with you.
Wake up, dumb-dumb.
Um..
I'm almost done.
We all are.
Just a few more decades
at most.
Oh, no,
don't do that.
Every funeral is basically the same.
We're not that special.
Whatever, whoever
the fuck you were
they have, they have, like,
a script they read from.
"He was a loving father."
It's all cliches.
Every funeral.
"He was a loving father,
he's in a better place."
"She's in peace now."
Have an original thought!
Why are these cliches? What
are you, Jon Bon Jovi?
Get into some
deep shit for me.
"I wonder if he was
still alive
after he died
for a minute?"
Say that
at the gravesite.
That's what the kids
are thinking.
I won... I wonder if like,
his kneecap's still alive.
He's coming up.
You there?
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
What do you think
of this?
- Your shirt?
- Uh-huh.
I like it.
I've been buying these.
I thought I liked the cut.
It feels so bright now.
No, it fits well.
Thank you.
- You didn't read it?
- No.
I'll read it
when I want to.
I'm not gonna sit here
in front of you.
What are you getting?
Uh, maybe a soup.
Are you gonna eat?
Can't decide.
So I've been staying
with Chris.
He told me.
Right.
What are you thinkin'?
Nicholas.
Becca, what?
Nicholas..
Let's not do this.
Thank you.
- Have you seen Nick?
- He went downstairs.
Well, he's got my shoes.
Um, do you know
if he's all dressed?
He had a problem
with his key.
- So he's gonna come back here?
- Chris.
What? My shoes
are in his room.
Would you want me to not
wear shoes all day?
I want you to take care
of your own sorry self.
I'm trying to,
but I'm wearing socks.
Oh, hey!
You know,
that was beautiful.
Thank you.
Good to see you.
Hey, they're still warm.
- Right over there.
- Hey, you made it.
- Hello.
- Oh, hey, Paul.
She said..
That means I'm taller.
Yeah!
Claire wants
to say goodbye.
- Come help me with the table.
- Okay.
I'll be out
in five minutes.
I will!
Is it nice?
- It's fucking genius.
- So nice!
I haven't used it yet.
You know, uh, Chris
doesn't like your place.
Yeah, that's what I said.
- That's exactly what I said.
- That's what he said.
I was like, "I don't
like mom's new place."
What do you mean,
you don't like it?
I didn't say anything
and that got construed as
"Chris hates
mom's new place."
Chris, what are
you wearing?
Are you naked?
I didn't wear
any underwear.
To your grandmother's
funeral?
- Chris..
- Oh, my..
What do you want from me?
Underwear.
It doesn't
affect you, man.
Nick, will you help me
with the table?
Just... stay a minute.
Whoo! Mm!
Yeah, give it a sit.
Nice.
- Right?
- Yeah.
Chris, would you just
cover yourself?
Why?
I am totally beautiful.
- Come on, Nick.
- Okay.
I'll be up in a minute.
♪ I run after you ♪
♪ Like a fool would do ♪
♪ But mama didn't
raise no fool ♪
♪ And I should know ♪
♪ That baby you got it ♪
♪ That all I can
say for you ♪
♪ You got soul
too much soul ♪
♪ Foxy clothes
the cutest nose ♪
♪ A movie set ♪
♪ There's nothing fake ♪
♪ About you ♪
♪ Baby you got it ♪
♪ People can be cruel ♪
♪ They say
I've lost my cool ♪
♪ But it's very hard
to keep my cool ♪
♪ When I'm around you ♪
♪ 'Cause baby
you got it ♪
♪ That's all
I can say for you ♪
♪ You got soul
too much soul ♪
♪ Foxy clothes
the cutest nose ♪
♪ The movie set ♪
♪ There's nothing
fake about you ♪
♪ Baby you got it ♪
♪ Now that I found you ♪
♪ Gonna cling to you ♪
♪ I'll give you
love and money ♪
♪ Everything to you ♪
♪ No matter
what they say ♪
♪ No matter what I do ♪
♪ I'm never gonna love
another girl but you ♪
♪ 'Cause baby
you got it ♪
♪ That's all I
can say for you ♪
♪ You got soul
too much soul ♪
♪ Foxy clothes
the cutest nose ♪
♪ The movie set ♪
♪ There's nothing fake ♪
♪ About you ♪
♪ Baby you got it ♪
♪ My friends
say no can be ♪
♪ You're not
the girl for me ♪
♪ But I see a
lot of things in you ♪
♪ That they can't see ♪
♪ And baby you got it ♪
♪ That's all I
can say to you ♪
♪ You got soul
too much soul ♪
♪ Baby you got it ♪
♪ Foxy clothes
the cutest nose ♪
♪ Baby you got it ♪
♪ The greatest shape
there's nothin' fake ♪
♪ Baby you got it ♪
♪ Groovy lip
that makes me flip ♪
♪ Baby you got it ♪♪
Subtitles by explosiveskull