Nothing in this world will have as many
barbed wire fences around as love does.
Nothing comes close to love in
being the cause of many great wars.
In a field beyond time,
tradition, winning and losing...
Love stands alone, shining bright.
Are you done?
Mom, get me a haircut. I should look
like Chiranjeevi. Will you get me one?
Make it fast. It's getting late.
Mom see that photo… I
need a haircut like that.
Mom, look at me...
He should cut here...
and here... Mom, look at me.
Here and here...
Hey, wait… Your place
is not here… Go there…
You know how it works, right Manamma?
Teach your kid! Go there.
Not there… here it seems.
As though the village is his…
Sit… Just because you went there.
Why did you go?
May he burn!
May he have wounds in his hands!
We, who work hard,
have no entry inside. Shut up!
Mom, why can’t we go in?
That's how it is.
Because they are different from us.
This won't change until
that difference exists.
-Sir, I’ll payback in 3 months, sir
-You fail to pay interest? Take your kid.
You won’t pay back loans.
We can’t snatch your fields.
-What else can we do? Take this away.
- Don’t take away the door, sir.
-Oh, God! Such a tough time, Manamma!
-Don't cry, mom.
Be strong, Manamma.
Mom… It would have been
great if dad is alive, right?
I’m still alive, right?
We have to
get back our field within a year.
How, mom?
What ‘How’?
If we are out of money, we have to work.
We have to work and earn money.
That’s the rule.
Revanth, I heard that
you are not attending school!
Your mom is complaining that
you are dancing on the roads.
-I will study, teacher.
-Take this.
-You have to complete it.
-Ok, teacher.
-Mom, until here?
-Up to there.
Did we get our field back?
Yeah, we got back our field.
Our Revanth is killing it!
Hey, come here. Show me your hand.
For me?
Thank you, sir.
Mom mom, I danced well.
Narsimham sir gave me a rupee.
I have earned a name in the
school, and also some money.
Now there will be no differences!
How did he give? Did he place
it in your hands? Or did he drop it?
He dropped it.
Did you see it?
How can you call it a prize?
He threw it at you without any respect.
Remember this, son.
For these differences to end...
We have to give them money one day.
Our hand should be on the top.
You have to work really hard for that.
House, land, job, mindset...
Whatever it is.
We have to lead a better life.
Our hand has to give
money, not take it.
Dheeru, get up.
Dheeru, it’s time… Get up.
Come fast!
Let's go.
“Burn fat… Get fit… Do Zumba”… Start.
Again again…
Jump jump…
Superb! x5
This has to reduce, sir.
This? Ok ok, let’s try something
in the next class, madam.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, madam.
-Morning, sir.
-Anu ma’am… tell me.
Sir, that’s… My husband asked
me not to pay the fee, sir.
He said I haven’t reduced a
bit, and not to pay the fee.
-Is it ok, sir?
-Haa… How can that be?
Did we give you a guarantee? Should we
teach you Zumba without payment now?
-You can stop coming.
-Hey, let me handle this.
How can you say that it’s our
fault, madam?
-Even you have to try, right?
-I did, sir.
-‘Try’? Seriously?
-But it still didn’t work.
Won’t move your legs or hands. You just
stand still, staring at people around you.
-How will you reduce?
-Mind your voice!
I have video proof.
Do you want to see it?
-Is it? Show me.
-Stop making a scene.
Bro, wait.
See… See how she’s working out. See…
Sir that’s not me.
- Not me.
-Yeah, please don’t feel bad.
Hey, how can you behave rashly with
the clients? Go sit in silence.
It’s ok, madam. Let’s change your
workout routine.
Pay us only if you like it. Ok… No
problem at all.
-See you tomorrow, madam.
-Sir...
First, fire this short fellow and hire
a girl, sir. He has no manners at all!
-Leave now… Go.
-Get lost, idiot!
What’s with you brother? As if we
gave her a guarantee or something.
How can you let her go without paying? It’s
tough for Goddess Lakshmi to favour you.
No matter what I do,
your Goddess Lakshmi won’t favour me.
Right!
Who’s the God of Wealth in Christianity?
The bank manager is
our God of Wealth.
Once he approves our loan,
we can escape all this mess.
Hey, did you guys come there?
Yeah, he called me, brother.
They are waiting for us at the bank.
-We have to be there on time.
-Ok, brother.
Revanth… Wait wait…
What did you do about the drainage?
I have been asking about it for 3 days…
You are taking me very lightly you know…
No, sir.
Yesterday was a holiday, sir.
Today I have some work at the bank.
I’ll get it done.
Ok, go go... Even I have some work to do.
The tuition center guys complained
against your Mumba for sound pollution.
-I will have to talk to them…
-It’s not Mumba, sir. It’s Zumba.
Whatever… It’s sound pollution.
I’ll be on your work tomorrow.
This is really urgent. I’ll get it done.
-Ok, go go.
-Don't leave them this time.
-When will we leave this place?
-Bro...
-One minute...
-Let the loan get sanctioned.
-We’ll rent a new place near the main road.
-If that happens, we HAVE to celebrate!
All your papers are perfect…
You’ll get the loan.
But it will take six months.
And 50 thousand.
[all]: 50 thousand?
For what, sir?
To bring you into progress.
-Into what, sir?
-Up!
How can that be progress, sir?
Buy a new riksha to a rikshwala,
he will still be a riksawala.
Where’s progress in that, sir?
Of course, you are right. But the
government fixed this. What can we do?
I started from level zero, sir!
I managed to put up my own Zumba center.
I work really hard sir. I even have a
great plan. Do something, sir. Please.
Sir our business is clear sir.
These days everyone is suffering from fat,
overweight, stress, strain, and thyroid.
If we ask them to spend money on their
health instead of on hospital bills…
They will form queues in front
of our Zumba center, sir.
Of course, you are convincing me.
But you can’t convince the bank, right?
Do this, bring some
property papers as security.
I’ll make sure you’ll get
the loan as soon as possible.
As if we any properties, sir!
You have a half-acre land
in your village, right?
That belongs to my mom.
She won’t agree to this.
How can the bank believe in
you, if your own mother doesn’t?
Our land? I’ll kill you both if
you even try to talk about my land.
-I bought it with the money I saved starving.
-God, stop it!
I don't want it. I was just telling
you what he said. As if I don’t care!
Ok... Did you guys eat?
Rajesh keeps asking for
Haleem… Get him some. Ok?
Brother...
How shall we pay the rent?
We even lost some customers.
Brother, bring the shovel. Fast.
Brother, he’s asking for the shovel.
Brother brother hello hello…
Brother… Brother, my name is Sunny.
I need a part-time job at
your Zumba center, brother.
I’ll come in the morning. I’ll clean the
room, I’ll prepare breakfast, make tea.
I’ll do whatever you want me to… I
don’t even need any salary, brother.
-You don't need a salary?
-Huh.
But you’ll give us tea.
Do I look that foolish to you?
Do you think I don’t know why you want
to be here? You are here for Geetha.
I’ll thrash you if I see
you around again. Get lost!
-Brother, please...
-Hey, get lost!
-At least you tell him.
-Go!
-Is it done with, brother?
-It won’t cause problems, right?
-No no.
Let's go.
It's done, sir.
It shouldn’t leak again.
No no, it won’t, sir.
Did you get the loan?
We will, sir. Soon.
I rented the space to you,
as you’ll be of help to us.
But you are not paying the
rent from last two months.
Hey, stop. Stop stop! Here here…
This is the house. Stop stop!
You have to say that a bit
earlier, madam.
Hey, you didn’t give back the five.
Five?
I don’t have any change.
Give me five, and I’ll give you ten.
I don’t have a five.
-I don’t have a five.
-What should I do?
No change. Ma'am, why are you
making a scene just for five rupees?
I am saying that I don’t have
change, right?
-You have to.
-Is it?
Is this your house?
Go get a five. I’ll wait here. Go.
Wait here. I’ll be back.
Yes, I’ll wait. You go.
Where do these people come
from, just to irritate others!
Brother… My five rupees!
You thief!
Mouni, what’s with this sudden visit?
I’ll tell you…
What happened to your leg?
Nothing. That auto driver is heartless.
He stole my five rupees.
Five rupees?
He’s not heartless, you are voiceless.
You have to make a scene and catch him
by his collar. Want to have some tea?
No. I haven’t brushed yet.
Kavya called me saying that they
have openings in their office.
She even sent me the question paper.
This job is mine!
Thank God. Best!
You have to throw a huge party this time.
God, let me get the job,
I will throw whatever you want.
I am dying here.
Did you parents say ‘Yes’?
Was very difficult.
I cried and made a scene.
Mom managed to talk down dad.
But my grandma and that anaconda tried
to stop me until the last minute.
-Anaconda?
-My uncle…
Ok.
He gave me one month. If I don’t
bag this job… it's back to maid duties.
Did you prepare the answers?
-Poor girl, she even sent me the answers.
-Is it?
I learnt them by heart.
I have to get the same paper
and my job is guaranteed.
I have to just manage the interview.
You’ll get the same paper.
Hey, I’m getting late for my class.
Hey, I’m feeling really tensed.
Tell me something nice.
Mouni you can do this… You can
do this… You can do this… OK?
Bye!
Well done! x4
-Arent't you ready yet?
-Ask the fees, brother.
On the way.
-Go see.
-I’m coming. Did you revise?
-Is she your friend?
-Yes, sir.
Get her also to join. She’s in a lot of
stress. I saw her at the auto this morning.
Eh, she won’t join, sir.
Come on, get her to join and
you can just pay 1500 for each.
She has some other problems, sir.
She’s in job search. She won’t join.
Is it? Ok,
let’s ask her once she gets a job.
Ok, sir.
-What is this? What’s with this sound?
-Sir, we are done. Done!
Please come, sir.
-Ok?
-Yes!
Hey..congrats You got the
highest in written test.
-Thank you, sir.
-Oh, Armoor? Even I’m from Armoor.
Only 48% in engineering! Why?
Not like that sir…
1st year lecturers didn't come.
-2nd year Chicken Gunya, sir.
-What?
-Little louder please.
-Chicken Gunya, sir.
3rd year I tried to make up, sir... but...
It's ok.
Can you solve this simple
java program for me?
Sir?
Yeah, you scored THE
highest in the written test.
Just do it.
You already wrote this, right?
-Sir.
- It’s the same thing.
How did you score the highest? I don't
know why you are taking so much of time.
Don’t take any tension, ok?
Let it go. We’ll try another job. Bye.
Anitha... Where's Mouni?
-Stop!
-How you can ask me to stop so suddenly?
She didn't answer my call.
Call her and ask her where she is.
-Here.
-Madam, change.
I'm here at your room.
Hey, your uncle is here.
He’s waiting for you at the house.
I saw him.
He’s waiting at the gate.
He’s here to take me away.
Please say something
and send him away.
Tell him that the interview is done
and I need to attend the second round.
Say something and send him away.
Ok ok, I will.
The job is confirmed, right?
Confirm?
I’ll never get a job.
I fainted during the interview process.
It’s ok. Calm down now.
Don't get tensed. Did you eat anything?
Eat something. I'll manage your uncle.
Brother brother… Client…
You got the same paper right?
What happened at the interview?
They are really heartless.
Who asks technical
questions in an interview?
God, you have no brains at all.
How can you answer all
the questions correctly?
You have to give some wrong answers.
Right? My bad luck.
I got full marks for the first time in my
life, but still eneded up without a job.
They will doubt it if someone
gets full marks, right?
You have to be little sharp.
You can't bag a job being this dull!
How will this work? You tell me.
Mouni, you there?
Ok I'll call you back. Please send
away that Anaconda first. Please!
Yeah yeah ok.
Come, it’s ok. Please sit.
We have morning evening
batches...5:30, 6:30, 4:30, 5:30.
1500 for two. 1800 for one.
It’s good to have a juice daily at the
jucie center and that’ll cost you 500.
But that is not compulsory. Ok?
I can’t give you 1+1 offer.
You came alone and missed the offer.
Brother, the pamphlets…
What time will you come at?
What batch? Morning or evening?
What’s Zumba?
Zumba?
Zumba means energy… Fat, weight, stress,
strain, thyroid… Any solution one problem.
I mean, any problem one solution.
[both]: Revanth Zumba centre.
Hello!
Hey, he says he’ll wait.
You uncle is not leaving.
I’ve got some urgent work. Will tell
you the timings later. Thank you!
Here, keep this. This is the number.
Brother, button up properly.
[chatter]
Peanuts... Fresh peanuts.
Helloooo… Five hundred.
I don’t have the change, brother.
1000?
Hey… getlost. You bloody… Move!
Leave me!
-Is this land your dad’s or is she your girl?
-Bloody!
If a boy sits alone in a park...
you’ll think that he lost his job, or ran out
of money, or that his girlfriend had left him…
But if a girl sits alone, ‘Will you come
with me’, ‘How much will you charge’,
‘Will you sleep with me’,
what’s with all this?
Of course you are right, brother.
But the girl looks hot.
Bloody… Get lost from here. Move!
-Hello.
-Who’s he? Do you know him?
Eee, let it go. Just some random fool.
You didn’t get the job?
How do you know?
It’s written all over your sad face.
Don’t take tension.
It will work out next time.
Shall I tell you something…
Join Zumba… I bet you’ll
bag a job within one month.
Timing full flexible…
Let’s say you have the 1+1 offer too.
It feels good.
-What’s the problem?
-Money problem.
I don’t even have money
for my mobile recharge.
You have no money?
Madam madam Revanth
fitness centre madam.
-Fat, weight, stress...
-Do you think I look fat? No!
Madam madam we will provide
you with the 1+1 offer.
Do this… Distribute these pamphlets.
No one is taking from us.
I’ll pay 5 rupees per pamphlet.
If a girl hands it, it will work.
- What say? Here.
-Hey!
Are you freaking kidding me?
Do you know my qualification?
B.Tech. I have 20 acres back at my home.
You want me to distribute pamphlets?
What do you think of me?
God, look at you talk about prestige.
Didn’t you make a scene for just 5 rupees?
You just told me that you are out of money.
B.Tech! 20 acres…!
See I don’t need this.
You know who he is? He’s a broker.
I came here to make him leave you alone.
Or else, why would I be here at all?
Try to understand.
Madam madam any problem one solution
Fat, weight, stress, strain, thyroid...
-We are ok.
-We are fine, leave.
Madam, we have 1 + 1
offer… Give it a try madam…
Hello, mom…
How many times should I tell you
mom… Not to let him come here.
He’s your uncle,
you need to have respect for him.
Grandma asked him to go. What can I do?
Where is a girl staying in
such a huge city? Who’s she's with?
We have to know, right?
Give me that phone.
You can’t do those jobs
and all… Just come home.
Give the phone back to
mom… Give her the phone…
Here. She only wants to
talk with you it seems.
Actually, he’s there in the city
looking for a match for Reshma.
He said he’ll visit you and give
you some money. How can I stop him?
He took over our 20 acres and now he’s
throwing little money at us every month.
And he acts as if he’s taking care
of the entire village. Shameless!
We wouldn’t have been facing these
problems if dad was of any good.
What is he doing? Is he drinking?
Give...
I have sent you a photo over WhatsApp.
Take a look.
Ramya study well. Don’t waste time.
The job market is very tough here.
Arey, you only talk to her mom!
Shall I ask him to send
some to your account?
You went off without
any money at all.
You have to ask that Anaconda, right?
No need.
I’ll send some money.
No need, mom.
Ok, take care.
Mouni...
Mouni where are you? Mouni…
Why are you sitting here?
What happened?
I thought I’ll get this job for sure.
Let it go. Lite!
Now I don’t have any hope.
Hey, our ‘Lizard’ fellow is working for
Google. He’s in a nice position there.
Why don’t you call him once?
The Lizard?
He’ll irritate with his extras.
Hey, nothing will happen.
What’s wrong with it?
Remember, he was mad about you while in
college. He might set you up with a job.
I’m hungry. Come on, let’s eat.
Is your Zumba sir a good guy?
Why do you ask?
I shouted at him in the evening.
is it? I don’t believe you.
Hey, true.
Don’t know what he might have felt.
He won’t feel bad. Let’s go.
Left right…
Left right… Againagain once more…
-Anupama madam, you have to work hard…
-Anitha… keys...
Sir, I was able to lose
weight through your exercises…
But my backside still needs to reduce.
Hey Dheeru... Go make her work out.
Ok, ma’am… Let’s change your
workout next week and try.
-Yeah, ok. Do this for now.
-Ok, sir.
Keep going. Yes… Yes…
Hey, I asked you to leave, right? Go.
Go!
I’ll distribute pamphlets…
In the park.
You asked me yesterday, remember?
No need. That work is done.
No need?
There are some more left, right?
Yeah, there are… But you can’t do it.
You can't do it. You can't do it.
You can't do it.
-I can do it.
-Is it?
You are an engineer. With 20 acres
of land… You can’t. Let it go.
Hey brother… What is this, brother!
Hello, one minute.
Here… There are 100 in this bunch…
You said you’ll distribute, right?
No… You are heartless.
You keep arguing… And
throw attitude… No need.
You did a mistake. I did a mistake.
We are equal now.
Hey, Dheeru is looking at us,
and this won’t look good. Here...
Who’s he?
My villain…
Hey, what’s with the money?
I didn’t ask you for money.
I just wanted to help you.
You helped me in the park, right?
You have to work if you are out of money.
If you work, you have to take money.
That’s the rule.
I didn’t work yet, right?
You will… Some money might come handy…
No no, let it go.
Hey, I will feel bad.
Why will I care if you feel bad?
I helped you in the park, right?
So what should I do now?
You have to distribute these pamphlets,
earn money on it, and be happy.
-Revanth.
-Sir?
You didn’t pay rent from last 2 months.
But now you’re paying
5 rupees per pamphlet?
Sir, I will pay, sir.
I will… Next month, for sure. For sure.
What is he saying?
That girl has some problems it seems.
-Please cook chicken today.
-No.
It’s been so long.
Last time the smell was so great.
We didn’t pay the rent, right?
Let’s cook with the fan turned on.
He can’t even smell it.
Hey, stop!
Ok, you go get the chicken.
I’ll wait here.
Yeah, ok, brother.
Peanuts… Peanuts…
-These are mine.
-How can that be?
Hey look… Look at my photo.
-Don’t blame me. Go ask that girl.
-Get lost!
She gave me these.
Who told you?
Brother, I have seen it on YouTube…
Rotate like this 50 times a day and
your back will reduce… Listen to me…
Won't work.
-It will.
-How will it reduce?
-Belly will reduce, not the back.
-It will work… Rotate fast.
This has to reduce… Not like that…
What? Are you cooking chicken?
Brother, she is here.
Don’t look that side.
-You go check on the chicken.
-She is laughing at us!
Chicken curry?
Did you distribute the pamphlets?
Yeah I did.
To the peanut vendor?
How did you find out?
Waste of pamphlets… Waste of
money… Waste of everything…
I already told you that you can’t do it!
I tried, but it failed to.
I’ll return your money.
What will you pay? 100 pamphlets… Oil
paper… You took them voluntarily, right?
I saw people from my village.
I felt shy!
Shy?
Didn’t you feel shy to sit idle at home? And you
feel embarrassed while distributing pamphlets.
Is it work only if you have ACs and computers?
Are we all jokers to you or what?
What did you say?
I’m not jobless… I
did my engineering…
Engineering?
Then where is your job?
You failed to get one even with the question
paper handed to you. That’s jobless…
Watch your mouth… You are jobless…
I’m jobless? Hey, why do I even care?
I came from zero.
I started a center on my own.
I make 50 thousand per month.
Did you even earn a single penny?
You are just hopping around and
making money… What’s there in it?
Hopping? This is dance. Zumba.
What do you even know uh?
With this behaviour, you’ll never
get a job. I’m sure about it.
Also, you can’t do it… You can’t
do it… You can never do it. Leave!
So…I was saying…
What’s with the English, you Lizard.
Why are you irritating me?
Tell me if you have a job.
Or else, just sit silent.
It’s really tough here. You can’t do it.
Mouni… Mouni listening…. Mouni. Mouni.
Mouni...
Mouni, ok ok there is a job.
Data entry work at my friend’s startup.
But he can’t pay much salary.
Not more than 5 thousand.
A maid will get paid better.
Mouni… Mouni...
I heard you are falling unconscious in
the interviews, how do I refer you then?
I get dizzy with tension.
And you are joking about it? Damn you.
Hey… What will you get from scolding me?
I’m telling you the facts.
You have to know something.
You have to have some talent here. Mouni…
I told you that you can't do
it, right?
Is it work only if you have ACs and computers?
Are we all jokers to you or what?
You can't do it... You can't do it...
You can't do it...
Some crazy dreams!
All these layers of love!
My heart crossed all of them…
And it flew!
I won myself...
These are the moments I do…
All these words…
They don’t stop flowing.
There is a crazy tune in my heart!
That’s the crazy tune of our tale!
I feel like I have new wings.
I just roamed all the skies.
I feel like I can breathe better.
It made me take a dip in excitement.
I finally got my freedom.
And my heart started to sing like a nightingale.
Droplets shinned over the flower petals.
And tears of joy smiled back at me.
– I never thought of this.
My heart just quivered.
It was just falling…
Into a calm dizziness.
Oh, God!
How did this even happen.
My joy turned into a raindrop…
And it jumped onto me.
There is a crazy tune in my heart!
That’s the crazy tune of our tale!
I have been writing
love letters in my dreams.
I have never seen this.
all this magic inside my heart!
I have never met this.
Just a second with you…
I’ll save each one of
them like it’s a boon.
Seasons change while I’m with you…
Let me save all those memories safely.
Don’t know which direction.
No idea!
But let’s go for a ride…
Let’s go!
The balloon of my silence popped…
And I was even singing.
Like the rainbow wore an anklet…
It started dancing…
throw the umbrellas to the wind.
not cover up our freedom.
Our steps has to cross the borders.
Even the thunderbolts
have to fear our energy.
What’s all these silly secrets…
That we both share!
What’s all these silly dances…
They have grown a thousand folds.
What’s with collecting all the hopes…
This has never happened.
What’s with my concentration
taking a side track…
This feels strange!
What a dance!
Such a great dance you did!
Like a peacock in the rain.
Hey hey, forget about these jobs.
Come join me.
I can’t do it, right? Now can I?
Sorry… Sorry, it’s a mistake I said so.
You have some magic with you.
If we can come together,
the Zumba center will be magical too.
Girls will form queues to join us.
And boys will follow.
Trust me, ah.
I even know an idea to reduce this.
Hey hey, how? Tell me… Tell me…
I won’t. I don’t need this.
I got a job.
-Eh eh listen to me.
-Forget it.
Mouni... Mouni...
Looks like you got a job at the station.
You saw me? What?
Are you following me?
Forget about me following you. If the police
observe you, they will start following you.
If you have no work to do,
why don’t you stay home?
I’m going mad sitting idle at home.
Then join me.
It’s better than here. Your stress will
go off. You can earn and also be fit.
My parents won’t say ‘Yes’ to this.
Let it go.
Hey, what’s wrong with this?
You are only dancing…
Ok, I’ll give you partnership.
You can tell your parents that
you started your own business. Ah.
The money you make out of a job,
will it be sufficient? Will it feed you?
Business has future!
-Mouni... Mouni...
-Brother!
-Mouni.
-Brother brother… Hear me out once.
Get lost!
How will you even do a software job? You’ll
have to wear glasses. Your back will hurt.
You’ll lose hair too. Think about it.
Brother, you too think about me once.
Please!
What do you want?
Brother, you have a feeling that sister
is not understanding you, right? Right?
You feel it, right? I have the same feeling.
You are not understanding me, brother.
You touched my heart. Come on.
Make me understand. Come.
Brother, Geetha and I have been
in love for the last 2 years.
There is a curfew going on in her house.
Brother, your center is a safe
place and no one will doubt it.
Just one job.
I’ll be very happy if I see Geetha.
Do you think my center is
a hangout spot for lovers?
Ah ah ah… Brother, nothing like
that please, please… Sorry sorry…
Just this one help.
Hey, can’t you understand?
The girl is very rich.
Her father paid full
year’s fee in advance.
Do you know who they are?
What is your identity?
Hey, listen to me. We don’t have
properties and we don’t get loans.
No one will rent a house to us.
Don’t waste your time. Study well.
Brother brother I study well… I’m
an engineering student. College topper.
I’ll get a job in the next 6 months through
campus placements. Minimum 1 lakh salary.
Do you think they will say ‘yes’ to your
marriage seeing that one lakh salary?
They won’t. It won’t happen.
Why do you want to get into this mess?
Brother, who wants to
deal with all this mess?
I just fell in love, that’s it.
When you struggle for a chance to
just see the girl you love everyday…
Then you’ll understand my pain, brother.
Hey, do it. These jobs and
night shifts… You can’t do it.
-But my parents won’t agree, right?
-Keep trying for a job.
Teach Zumba in the morning and evening.
Tell them that you got a job.
What’s complicated in that?
You did great.
Such a great dance… wow wow…
He’s correct. Think about it.
I’m telling you, you are happy doing this.
Your sir sent me a friend request.
Accept it. But ask for a huge salary.
Nothing less than 20 thousand.
You are an engineer.
20 thousand?
Too much? Want to go back home?
He asked you because he needs you.
So you get to demand now.
Right? Ah… go go go…
Go right now. Go.
Revanth sir... Sir...
Revanth sir... Sir, over here.
I thought about it. I’ll join you.
Hey super… Thank you. Thank you.
Eh, stay there.
I’m coming… I’m coming wait.
-What?
-Come on.
There?
I didn't think you'll say 'Yes'.
Sit, Mouni.
-What are the timings?
-Morning evening.
Salary?
Let’s do a partnership. 50 – 50.
Business will thrive. The partnership
will give you a great advantage too.
The partnership is ok… But I
need 20 thousand per month.
20 thousand per month!
And partnership on top of that!
Ok, right?
It won’t work out, Mouni.
Hey eh, sit sit.
I did B.Tech, right? Anything less
than 20 thousand won’t look good.
Eh how can that be?
B.Tech is B.Tech and Dance is Dance.
What will Prabhu Deva say if Bill Gates asks
him for a job? He’ll ask him to get lost.
And you are a good for nothing engineer.
You have to be realistic, right?
Then will you pay me 15 thousand?
Is that ok?
Let’s see.
I have to arrange the money, right?
Ok… Think of it and tell
me your decision. Bye.
Will you tell me tomorrow?
I’m ok upto 10 thousand.
What ok? Such miserly
calculations you have.
As if you are so out of money.
You opened up this huge center.
You are earning 50 thousand per month.
Can’t you pay me just 15 thousand?
Of course, you can.
Hey, what are you doing there, brother?
I jumped in.
-Mom...
-Tell me…
I want to ask you something.
-What will you ask early in the morning?
-Listen to me.
A girl came to our center yesterday.
She danced superbly.
I asked her to join me and
she asked for 15 thousand.
Even we are almost
begging here… 15 thousand?
Also, do you need these
dances with the girls?
To teach the students.
No need… Ask her to leave.
Where will you bring the money from?
I can’t send you money for
the next 4 months. What will you say?
I’ll pluck your teeth and
place them in your hands.
I’ll develop a lot, mom.
Give me that money and I
will develop you even better.
Will you do Zumba?
We go from door to door and get kids…
and then we shout until our throat pains.
Still we are not getting
even 10 thousand.
And you want to pay her 15
just for hopping around.
Shut up!
Mom… What's this?
Ok… Last word… Tell
her 10 thousand.
Or else, no need… Ask her to leave.
She’s didn’t agree, right?
But she’s really rich, brother.
It’s true about the 20 acres.
She’s from Armoor.
Anitha told me.
-Armoor?
-She’s from your place. But chill!
She came here for a job.
She’s pea-brained.
Even 10 thousand is too much for her.
Who are they?
Her uncle is very affluent.
His name is Narasimham.
They are really rich.
It’s good that we
didn’t commit anything.
I mean to say you didn’t
commit to any money, right?
-Hey my brother is here… Bye!
-Ok ok, bye!
Why is he here all the time?
Ask him to come join. Also, tell him
not to meet up with her on the roads.
He will get thrashed if caught.
It’s you who said that we don’t
need all this mess, right?
Who wants to be in a mess?
-Love just happens…
-Love?
They both are in love.
Let’s help as much as we can.
Love just happens. What can we do?
Is it, brother?
First love happens, then shit happens.
Hey, ask Mouni to meet me.
-Her, why?
-Need to talk to her about the job.
What about the salary?
One can't understand you, brother.
Here are the keys.
-I’ll pay you 15 thousand.
-Thank you.
Dad’s name and address…
-Even I’m from Armoor.
-Is it?
My dad work used to work in your fields.
Mom continues to stay at the village.
You got settled well.
Don’t tell anyone…
My parents won’t accept me dancing…
I’m telling that I got a software job.
Best… That’s best… Do that.
It won’t be a problem, right?
Don’t make any videos.
Don’t tell anyone from our village.
But publicity needs videos, right?
They won’t accept.
It will be a problem for me.
Ok, as you wish.
I won’t make any videos.
Touching me and putting hands on me…
It won't happen while dancing, right?
We have to touch while dancing, right?
I don’t like such things.
I need two feet distance.
Yeah, ok.
Thanks…
Hey...
Mouni, what’s that? Careful!
My first salary.
I’ll give my best… My
best… Keep watching…
Winner winner bro.
Chicken dinner bro.
Just dance bro.
It’s a killer!
– Bro bro bro pump up your chest a little.
Bro bro bro your attitude is set bro.
Bro bro bro I swear on my mom.
Bro bro bro your cutout is a hit bro.
We have been from zero of life.
We’ll glow like a hero in the future.
We can’t follow the flow like sheep.
We are so high!
Yeah bro.
Winner winner bro.
Chicken dinner bro.
Just dance bro.
It’s a killer!
If we are stressed.
We’ll lose a life.
Let’s be open and free.
Let’s see who’s going to stop us!
Let’s earn decent money.
Let’s burn our problems.
We’ll make a mess.
We’ll behave as if this
land belongs to our dad.
We'll rock the world.
We don't care what you say.
Mouni...
Mouni what happened? What happened?
Sorry... Sorry, Mouni.
I said 2 feet distance, right?
That’s why I said ok to dance.
Even you said ok…
Happened by mistake Mouni…
Sorry, it won’t happen again.
Sorry, Mouni.
We have been from zero of life.
We’ll glow like a hero in the future.
We can’t follow the flow like sheep.
We are so high!
Yeah bro.
No matter how much they
talk behind your back.
They will always remain backward.
They’ll talk until their throats pain.
We have to work even more harder.
No matter what others say… Just
don’t listen to that. Get up!
Make a huge sound,
slapping across their face!
Winner winner bro.
Chicken dinner bro.
Just dance bro.
Bro, Mother Lakshmi is here.
It’s a killer!
We have been from zero of life.
We’ll glow like a hero in the future.
We can’t follow the flow like sheep.
We are so high!
Yeah bro.
We have been from zero of life.
We’ll glow like a hero in the future.
We can’t follow the flow like sheep.
We are so high!
Yeah bro.
Call the Lizard. Where the hell is he?
Sunny, click a picture.
-Mouni, hi!
-Hi!
-Revanth, that way…
-Hey, Mouni.
-What?
-Keep it.
What’s this? No no..
Keep it. Rates here are really high.
You can pay me back. Keep it.
I have never thrown a
party for my friends.
People who get married, who are leaving to
America, who got a job… Everyone threw a party.
First time I’m throwing one.
I feel really happy.
All this is just because of you. Thanks!
Eh, nothing like that.
Dheeru, come on.
Mouni, come on. Come fast.
Let's go. Guys fifth floor.
-Revanth… My boss.
-Hi!
Eh not boss… Partner.
-Sunny... Dheeru.
Yeah, the lift is here.
Cheers! Cheers for our dizzy queen.
For her greatest dancing job…
And For your Boss... Sorry... Partner!
[all]: Cheers!
Hey, let's dance.
Come on... Let's go!
-Come on, let's dance.
-You go. keep dancing all day anyways
Ok, we are going.
What’s your qualification, brother?
Degree… Did it in open college.
Oh!
Are you just business
partners… Or more than that?
What’s Zumba? Something like Cultfit?
Hey not of that level…
I just started on the roof of a
small building. Now it grew big.
After Mouni joined,
we have become a group of hundred.
In our area, Revanth Zumba
centre is like a landmark.
How much profit do you make, bro?
Good enough… We are happy…
In the next 2, 3 months we are planning
to open a bigger center with 15 lakhs.
Will you do that even without Mouni?
I mean without Mouni… Will you invest
the 15 lakhs you are talking about?
Why won’t Mouni be there, brother?
Did Mouni tell her parents?
Do they know about this?
No they don’t…
If they do, do you think they will
let her stay here even for a minute?
Do you know who her uncle is?
He’s a bigshot.
They won’t even allow people
like you into their house.
Brother, don’t feel bad.
Don’t take this the wrong way.
You say there’s lakhs of investment
involved. You are betting your life.
I’m telling you this just for
a reality check, that’s it.
Let her be friendly with you… If you have
any ideas about love, just forget those.
Dinners and dances are
ok in the city, but...
She won’t even look
at you back at home.
She won’t even touch you. She’ll
maintain a minimum distance of 2 feet.
Let’s say she got another job…
She’ll just fly away. I guarantee.
Also why do you need this
business, brother?
Why don’t you bag a government job?
You get them for free, right?
Up... Left... Right...
Hey, what are you doing? Come on!
How many times should I tell you madam?
Not like that, this way… Common do it.
Brother...
The broker for our new center.
Break!
-We'll start after Mouni is here.
-One minute, brother.
What? Trying to act smart?
Why do you need Mouni? You do it…
-Do it… Will she stay forever or what?
-Come on, do it.
Hi!
Why do you look serious?
Because I was late?
I danced like hell last night, right?
Got tired. Was so sleepy. Sorry.
I’m paying advance for the new
Zumba centre. I’m tensed about that.
Did the place get confirmed?
Yeah, beside Gandhi statue.
I have to see, right?
Why are you not smiling?
Nothing like that.
I’m going home this evening.
Got some urgent work to do.
We have a festival in two days, right?
Even I’ll come home.
Good. Go!
Hey, Gangavva…
Hey, fair skin boy… all good?
This is how I am.
How are you doing, Snow White?
Hey, you went to the city
and have become so sharp!
Where is my mom?
Your mom is at school teaching
all the kids to become Collectors.
Ok… Ok… Take this, I’ll be back.
Hey hey, at least have some water.
Mom… Mom… Ok, come on now.
-Hey, when did you come?
-Yeah, just now. Come on.
My stock will be here soon.
I’ll come after that, you go home.
The maid will take it.
You come with me. Come come.
-My bag!
-Come on...
-Move move move.
-What’s with you?
What? Why are you so silent?
-Mom...
-Haa.
Let’s sell our half acre.
What?
-Mom what happened? Mom get on the bike.
-Get lost! I’m not coming with you.
Mom where are you going?
-You… You want to sell off my land?
-Mom, it hurts!
-Stop! Stop... Mom!
-Speak out!
-Please get on the bike.
-I won’t get on your bike, get lost.
-Mom, where are you going? Get on...
-Hey, get lost!
You never listen to me! Mom...
Mom mom… Stop!
Dude, how are you?
Hai dude… I’ll meet you later.
Will see you in the evening. Bye.
I made chicken for you.
He don't deserve that.
He says he wants to sell the land!
Did you say that you
want to sell the land?
I won’t give you any
chicken, get lost.
How can you sell the land she
bought with a lot of hard work?
-What’s up, aunt? How are you doing?
-You haven’t been around all these days…
Now Revanth is here
and you came running.
Eh government works, sister.
What can I do, tell me?
Brother, come on. Sit.
I informed about our land in
the administration office.
Yesterday Narsimham’s man called
me… He said he’ll talk to him.
He might buy.
He’s buying a lot of lands these days.
What? You put it up in the market already?
-To that Narasimham? Damn you…
-Sister...
Mom!
I won’t give it. I won’t agree to this.
Get up. Get out of here.
Sister sister, don’t get angry.
Listen to me.
Sister!
Mom, sister is here.
It’s been so long since I saw you…
Mom...
-How are you?
-I’m good.
What’s with these clothes
and the hairstyle?
Hey, keep quiet. Everything looks good.
Sister, what did you bring for me?
-I’ll show you.
-I’ll make dosas. Go bathe and come.
Haa… Leave me.
First change out of those clothes.
Mom… Mom… Sister brought
jeans for me. See…
-What's this?
-Looks nice!
How much is it? Is this nice quality?
This is for you. Did you like it?
-It’s nice. Hold this.
-Keep it there.
You sit. Eat a dosa.
Didn’t you make groundnut chutney?
Hey, Mouni when did you come?
You didn’t even call! Is everyone
doing good back there? How’s Anitha?
She’s good.
Dad, wait.
What, dear?
My salary. From the past three months.
Very good, dear.
Mom, did you see?
My daughter gave me her salary.
Good!
Hey Mouni, uncle asked about you.
Go see him once.
I will...
We can’t do business… We can’t!
This is what they say.
We have to win somehow.
I am very confident. Why will I start
this for nothing?
They are demeaning us.
Hey, who isn’t demeaning us?
Is this new to you…
Just because someone is talking low of
us, should we lose all that we have?
If we sell this now, we can never
buy it back. That is our strength.
What will happen? Let it go.
What will happen if it goes?
We’ll be zero. We came from zero and we’ll
go back. We can’t go any lower, right?
This time I will do it.
Listen to me… Haa… What say?
Narsimham won’t let it happen.
Let’s see what he says.
Ok, as you wish.
Hey, our land costs 12 lakhs.
-Need in two days.
-It will be done.
Talk carefully, ok?
-Whom do you want?
-I want to meet sir…
Sir, Das's son is here to meet you.
[both]: Namasthe!
What? Are you Das’s son?
Yes, sir.
What are you doing?
Zumba centre, sir.
I teach dance in the city, sir.
What? These days are they
paying even to dance around?
The street dancer here is running
a Zumba center there it seems.
How much land do you have?
Half acre, sir.
What number are you thinking?
Say ten...
Ten, sir.
Ten is impossible.
Five we can think about…
Ask who the buyer is.
Who’s the buyer, sir?
Me…
-Hey, stop!
-Bye, sir.
-How dare you to talk back?
-Keep calm! Don't make a scene.
You’ll get 5 crores selling 10 acres.
We can bargain ten lakhs in that deal.
But you are selling just half acre.
Who will go against me and
buy your land in this village?
Don’t you think we will
maintain the same stand…
I’m giving you this offer just because
your dad worked for us... Got it?
Hey, You just dance around… How
can you even understand all this?
Go learn some dance.
Let's go!
He and his bloody life!
Go on. You play properly first.
-Go on.
-Play this...
Here... Play. Hey, that’s an out.
Take away the bat.
Hand the bat.
-Stop cheating.
-Ok bowl again.
-Ok, go on.
-Go on.
-What are you looking at?
-Someone is here…
Is teacher here?
-Mom.
-Who's that?
Someone is here for you.
What?
Who’s are you?
Venkatesham’s daughter.
Come inside.
Hey, Why is Venkatesham’s
daughter here?
How can I know?
Sit sit… Sit... What brings you here?
Do you know my sister, aunty? Ramya.
She’s very weak. She's eating rice.
I’m here to pick up some iron tablets.
Oh!
The school is closed.
That’s why I’m here.
Here... These four days are
holidays, right?
Hey Revanth…
Yeah, mom…
Revanth, come here.
My son… He’s running a
Zumba center… In Hyderabad…
Revanth Zumba centre,
has become a landmark.
Hey, sit.
I'll go see if I had stock.
Sit.
Why did you come to my uncle’s house?
Why did you come here? Do you
know how dangerous it is?
Why are you not answering my calls?
What happened?
-Do you want some sweets?
-Sweet?
Aa, mom… Bring her a sweet…
Revanth…
Narsimham is not giving
you the right rate, is it?
Bloody idiot! May he die of a dirty
disease. Bloody fool… How can he do this?
-Mom is inside, go!
-How will you get the money now?
I beg you… Shut up and go inside.
I’ll talk to you later.
Who’s this girl?
Shh… Slowly…
You granny.. Move… Move!
I don’t understand you… Who’s
that girl and what’s happening?
My grandma!
Are you selling the land?
It’s ok, I’ll adjust the money.
No problem.
Who’s that girl?
Keep calm… I’ll tell you. Move…
Here.
-Wait.
-I’ll take leave.
Take this.
-It's ok.
-Take it… my mom makes great sweets.
Have some. Eat it.
-Bowl properly.
-Bye!
-Bye. Take care child.
-Take his wicket!
Hey, 15 runs for 10 balls.
She looks nice. Marry her.
I’ll give her my earrings.
Do you kow who she is?
Venkatesham’s daughter.
Such bad luck… That
she was born to him!
-You leave.
-Move!
-When did the load come?
-Sir!
-Unload it fast.
-We have some more lands for sale.
If it's ok for you,
we'll plan the registration.
You have to decide the rate and all.
You know, right? The land will
have value only if it rains.
What Mouni, how are you?
Aunty...
-Hi, Reshma.
-Hi, sister. When did you come?
-Yesterday.
-Come sit.
Mouni, doing good?
-Yeah.
-Is the job good?
Do you want to have some tea?
-Yeah.
-Ok, wait.
-What did you bring for me?
-This is for you.
-[all]: Bye, brother.
-Ok, let's meet again.
You didn’t get anything for me?
How your job? What’s the pay?
10 thousand...
But... if I get trained with new
software, they’ll pay me 25 thousand.
What software, sister?
Cloud computing …
Oh... ok ok.
It will cost 1 lakh for the training.
1 lakh for training?
It’s a certification…
Yeah, dad. She’s right.
The future will be great.
This time we got a nice profit
over the harvest, right?
I want 1 lakh from our share.
-I'm in need.
-Ok, you don't get tensed.
-Come inside... Let’s talk.
-You be happy.
Go, sister. Ask him.
Nothing to worry about, go.
He’ll give you the money, go.
Come!
What share are you talking about?
Your share?
Do you know how much
loan your father took?
Do you?
Come, sit.
I’ll show you some math. Sit.
-What happened?
-Mouni, what happened?
Did you feel dizzy again?
Go get some water.
Nothing will happen… It will get better.
Have some water.
The kind of money we have spent on
the doctors… But she never got well.
Mouni...
What happened? Mouniii…
Open the door.
Mouni, listen to me. Open the door.
Mouni...
What’s with the anger?
Where are you going?
I need to go and I’m going.
The festival is in two days. Mouni…
How can you not stay for the festival?
Stay for two more days.
Didn’t your uncle give any money?
Great sons you gave birth to!
How dare you talk like that?
Whatever he does,
he does it for your well-being. Shut up!
Only he has to get you married one day.
Your dad can’t do anything.
He won’t get me married,
he’ll get me killed.
-What?
-What are you talking about?
What? You are leaving already?
Study well. Take care.
Mom… Don’t touch the
money he sends you.
I’ll send you money every month.
-Keep this.
-Mouni...
Bye!
-Bye!
-Ok, bye!
Bus will stop for just one hour here.
Make it fast.
What are you doing here?
-Are you following me?
-Or what?
You called and said that you were leaving.
I would be worried, right?
I’m returning.
You are not staying for the festival?
I had a fight… And came out.
-What happened, Mouni?
-Nothing!
Hey, what happened?
I asked for some money… For our
Zumba centre. Couldn’t adjust.
You fought at home for me?
They are not letting you
sell your land, right?
I thought he will give me some money.
But didn’t work.
Here... Jewlery…
What’s this?
These are mine.
My dad got them made for my marriage.
Hey, Mouni I don’t want them.
What? Are you feeling sentimental
that they were made for my marriage?
Have you gone mad. Mouni?
I don’t want them.
They are not more important
than our Zumba centre…
Sell them and we’ll at least
get money for the advance.
Ok, keep them with you.
I’ll ask if I need them.
Hey, Mouni...
You are very different from your people.
You are different!
Your uncle is not a good man.
Not a good man?
He’s a blood thirsty devil.
They call him ‘Bloody bugger’.
Bloody bugger? He’s
spycho, sadist, moron, creul and vicious.
Loafer, useless…
He’s a filty dung bettle…
We should slice him into pieces
and feed him to crows and eagles.
I hope we kill him and burry him.
May worms eat him up… May he die…
What happened, Mouni?
I need to go to the bathroom…
I have to change urgently.
Where’s your bag?
In the bus.
Stay here, I’ll go get it.
Ok, sir. Ok. Tell me.
-Brother, need a room urgently.
-Single or double?
-Single.
-Ok. I need your ID card.
-Do you have sanitary pads?
-Yeah, we do.
I took a room. No problem.
Brother, stop stop stop…
Brother...
Waste fellow! He didn't stop, Mouni.
-Shall we go on bike?
-No.
Another bus will come. Let’s wait.
You have to walk . Is it required at
this time? Why don’t you get on the bke?
Nothing like that. I fear bikes.
If I get on and touch you, I feel scared.
I get dizzy.
I have no problem with you.
The problem is completely mine.
I’m comfortable with you.
Or else, will you go?
Ehyy, let’s wait.
Brother... One passenger. Ladies.
-Get on.
-Mouni.
-Mouni, here... I'll follow.
-Ok.
I'll take care of the case.
-Namasthe, Narasimha.
-Namasthe! I'll call you back.
-How are you?
-I'm good.
I went to Kaamareddy on some work.
I saw our Mounika there.
Don’t know what she
was doing there alone?
She’s a girl and these
are really bad days…
I just came to tell you that.
Are you here to cross the bridge?
No… Why do you ask?
If lovers cross this bridge together,
their love will be a success.
-Is it?
-You’ll always be together.
-Let's go.
-Hey, have you gone mad?
-[both]: Bye!
-Did you have to tell him brother?
-He’ll stay here forever.
-Let him stay.
Didn’t Quli Qutub Shah stay for Bagmathi?
He swam in a flood for her.
It’s because of his risk his
father built this bridge.
Their love is a huge success.
Those who will cross this bridge of love
together, their love will also be a success.
Why is he believing in all this Mouni?
Let him. What’s wrong in it?
What about the girl’s
status… And look at him!
What’s with you?
What generation are you in?
How may people are going for
inter-caste marriages, right?
You have to check every
vertical before marriage, right?
What do you have to check?
Is he a good guy?
Does he have a job or not?
Does he like me or not? That’s it.
What else do you have to check?
-That’s it?
-Hmm!
What are you all doing?
She has to stay for the festival, right?
Why did she leave?
Nothing. New job, right?
She went off on urgent work.
No… She went off shouting…
She wants properties…
That’s why she came to meet
you… She went off cursing…
She’s just young… She knows nothing…
She just said what she said.
It’s ok if she shouts out few words…
But she shouldn’t disgrace us, right?
Call her… Inquire
where she is… Call her.
She didn’t go to the city directly…
Chandrasekhar saw her in a hotel it seems.
Where are you?
Where will I be? In my room.
That’s what... When did you reach there?
This morning. Why do you ask?
This morning?
What time did you leave! Where are you last
night? Why are you not answering your phone?
If I had called Anitha,
you would have made a scene.
At least you have to call me, right?
What happened now?
Why are you making a scene?
You didn’t arrange any money.
And you are shouting at me now.
Mom, listen.
I got my date while I’m on the bus.
So I had to stop at a hotel.
And I missed my bus.
What happened now?
Have you no sense?
You have to be prepared, right?
The times are not good, right?
Hey, she’s up to something.
I’ll see about that.
I asked our SI to check at the hotel.
I’ll pull everything out.
-Hey.
-Sir?
-Go get some tea.
-Ok, sir.
-Does the vehicle have diesel in it?
-No, sir.
-Go get it filled.
-Ok, sir.
-Open the entry register…
-Here, sir.
Go mind your work.
Sir… She didn’t book any room, sir.
I checked the entire CCTV footage.
Maybe she went to the restaurant.
Or else, your friend might
have seen someone else, sir.
Ok, keep this to yourself.
Ok, sir.
It’s about a girl, right?
Ok, sir. Bye!
Something is not right.
I'll look into it.
I found a card in her purse.
Maybe she works there.
Don’t let sister-in-law know about this.
You went to a hotel with
Venkatesham’s daughter!
Do you think you will live after that?
How did you know? Who told you?
Her uncle asked me to go
to that hotel and enquire.
The CCTV footage captured our hero.
I managed and told him that it’s clear.
How did you even know that girl?
Revanth… This…
Mouni… Come in.
He’s my brother. SI in our village.
I told him everything.
He’s really close to me.
See this.
What’s all this?
She’s working in my Zumba center, brother.
She stays next door.
His uncle will kill you both
if he sees you like this.
Fire her.
They are always good to their own people.
You’ll get sacrificed for all this.
Listen to me.
I failed to sell the land back at home.
This is the city… Is this
his dad’s kingdom or what?
Let’s see what he can do.
Did your mom know about all this?
Stay away from her. Listen to me.
Don’t know what this might lead to!
What?
Ask her to be careful too.
Got it?
…this is how my life has always
been, right?
What shall we do now?
You say.
But ask me to leave. I’ll kill you.
Will you work for 5 thousand?
The job that the Lizard offered you?
Have you gone mad?
I won’t quit dance.
Fix! Come what may.
No need to stop dancing, Mouni…
That’s why I’m giving you this idea. You
have to show your parents a job, right?
That’s why morning and evening Zumba.
And the job in between.
I know it will be tough.
But what else can we do?
There will be no greater hell
than to live in fear, Revanth.
My entire life is like that.
It’s filled with fear.
Nothing will happen, Mouni.
I’m here for you.
It’s just a small adjustment.
After we become really famous
and earn a lot of money…
Then you can announce to everyone…
Then they will shut their mouths.
-Excuse me, sir.
-Yeah?
-Mounika.
-Oh, yeah. Please sit.
Mouni.
What are you doing here?
Tell me this first... How is your work?
I can’t do it.
You’ll get used to it, Mouni.
The office is only up to 5, right? Now Zumba…
Papers to my land in the village, sir.
Application form.
So your mom finally agreed!
She have to, right sir?
Very good! You’ll definitely get a loan.
-I'll see to it. All the best.
-Thank you, sir.
Thank you, sir.
-Hello!
-Is Mounika there?
Mounika, phone… Your uncle.
Do you want to talk?
-No, sir.
-She really busy, sir.
-Tell her that I called.
-Ok, sir.
-It's too late for that.
-Shut up and go to sleep.
Mouni we are partners, right?
Agreement…
Congrats! Super!
-What sign? Is she mad?
-Shut up!
Thanks!
Congrats!
Hello! Ok ok, brother.
Mouni, my mom is here.
You go inside, I’ll go get her.
Oh, it’s ok.
Dheeru, take care of things here.
We’ll start once I’m back.
Ok, brother.
Hey, what’s happening?
What’s happening here?
You stay silent.
-Hey, what?
-Brother.
-Mom. come on.
-Revanth!
Close you eyes.
-What?
-Close your eyes.
-No!
-Listen to me...
-Shall I open my eyes?
-We are here.
-Shall I?
-Yeah, go on.
Mom, see this.
See… Revanth fitness centre.
Very good!
Brother, come here.
Here... Click a picture.
You decorated it well. Nice!
Mom, cut it.
Shall I?
Sir sir… Switch it on, sir. Play it.
-You did well!
-Nice, right?
What’s this?
-Yeah, thank you.
-Hey, what's all this?
Do you even understand
what you are doing?
-Hey!
-I'm coming.
Ehyyy, where are you going?
-I’m going to take a look.
-That’s not ours.
Is this all our half-acre land has got us?
This is not Armoor.
This is what we get in Hyderabad.
Mom… Brother got some work to do and
he’s starting now. You go with him.
Why to take a bus?
-Brother...
-What?
Brother, she says she’ll come with you.
Take her.
Come, sister. Let’s go. Hey, come on.
-Come on guys.
-Take care and eat well.
-Come on.
-Bye!
Anyone can be anything… Correct sentence.
Looks good.
What happiness! Your face is glowing.
We can switch off the lights.
This is ours…
Do you know how I was as a kid?
A jute bag. Rusty cycle.
My dad uses to work in the fields.
After dad died,
mom has been everything to me.
She worked really hard.
You’ll laugh at my face if I
tell you my childhood dream.
I wanted to take my mom
to a huge supermarket...
...and tell her to take anything she
wants, without bothering about the rates.
Looking at my mom’s face today…
I never thought I will start
this huge a center this fast…
This is just because of you, Mouni.
Ey… I feel like I can do
anything with you by my side.
We will be partners… We
will start this center…
You danced in the rain that
day, remember?
Right then,
I knew all this would happen.
Shall we dance?
-Hello, Mouni! Where are you?
-Mom!
Are you at your room?
Your uncle came to Hyderabad.
He's coming to see you.
I heard your dad and grandmother talk.
Are you there?
He came to the city for some work.
Do we need him in our lives?
He said he’ll come to see you on his way.
Meet him once.
What will happen if you do?
Do we need this mess right, now?
Mess? This is my life…
-Why don’t you let me live my life?
-Mouni!
If anyone has to worry about me, it has to
me dad. Who is he to tell me what to do?
Let him come. I’ll teach him a lesson.
I'm not scared now!
-Hello, Mouni!
-Where are you?
We didn’t settle the bills, right?
So going to the tent house.
You come to my room now.
I have to tell you something.
Come right now.
I’ll be waiting.
Ok, I’m coming. I’m coming.
-Hey, Raju. What happened?
-Sir sir...
The engine broke down, sir.
You have to check before we start, right?
Go take care of it fast.
How long will it take?
It'll take time, sir.
So this is where you stay!
Mouni...
Hey… Mouni…
Here is the money.
Why did you come back, brother?
Didn't you go to meet Mouni?
Her uncle is here.
-Then let’s go see a movie. I have tickets.
-Yeah.
-Let's go.
-Ok.
Mouni, what happened?
Why are you so scared?
Mouni, open the door, dear.
Mouni!
Stop acting smart!
Hey, Mouni…
How can you even live
without my permission?
Mouni…
Hey!
Why did you keep the door open?
-There’s no one here?
-Who will be here?
I can’t work these night shifts.
Can you make me some tea?
Yeah.
What happened?
Nothing!
Here are your new centre’s keys.
Why do you look so dull?
I’m not coming back… Can’t make it.
Did you parents find out?
I don’t like working with you.
Eh eh, are you kidding me?
You bought a new center… Now you have
nothing to do with me, right? Now leave.
Nothing to do with you?
What are you talking about, Mouni?
I’m talking facts.
Don’t act innocent.
I called you to dinner last night.
You said you will come.
But why didn’t you?
You went to see a movie, right?
Mouni, you uncle...
Your students increased and you bought a new
center. Now I’m of no use to you anymore.
That’s why you didn’t care about
me, right?
That Lizard fellow warned me about
this… But I’m too dumb to understand.
All you people are one and the same.
Trusting you will only cause doom.
We people? What do you mean?
Here is your contract.
We don’t need you. We don’t need you.
We’ll be better off this way.
It’s a good thing that I came
to know about you this soon.
Thanks ah… You showed me your true
colours. Your uncle is better than you…
He’ll talk in public, out loud… Real
clear about ‘We people’ and ‘You people’.
But the word you just said…
You proved to me what I am to you.
I don’t need you.
Damn!
What happened, brother?
Nothing…
Anupama ma'am, get ready.
We have to start the class, right?
Sandeep, are you ready?
Today’s class is cancelled.
Why? What happened, brother?
[busy tone]
Sorry!
Sorry! Sorry! Sorry!
How many times should I say that?
Let it go now.
I don’t think like that.
I don’t have any caste feelings.
Someone or the other keeps
saying that all the time…
We too take it and move on.
But I never thought that
you will say that too.
First time in my life…
I have been lesser than zero.
I was just angry and it came out.
Do I have to face this
huge a punishment for that?
Will you listen to me once?
We people don’t need to, madam.
What’s with that ‘We
people’ and ‘You people’?
It’s you who started it.
Ok… I did… It’s a slip of tongue…
Sorry!
I’ll tell you what happened.
Will you listen?
Eat something first.
Even I didn’t eat anything. Haa… Eat.
No need…
What did you say? Tell me now…
What’s with ‘We people’ and ‘You people’.
Say ‘We people’.
Mouni...
Mouni, the thing that happened last night…
I know it’s a mistake…
I’ll try… I’ll try and understand…
Let’s be like we used to be.
Don’t take any tension.
Of course, that’s an accident…
But I don’t know how to say it…
I like you…
I love you…
For me, it’s ‘I love
you’ at the first sight…
Hey girl, let’s get a rush.
Let’s get away together.
Come to me, jumping off the fence.
Get to me fast.
Pick up the rainbow…
And make it a bridge between us.
Lot of thoughts. Lots of pain.
Even if my life is a mess…
Just like a kite…
My dreams fly.
Hope and Disappointment are
two sides of a coin.
Like day and night.
I have a very little to my name.
But all of it is yours now.
I don’t feel any filters between us.
You are my life from now on.
I have brought my past,
present, and future together.
And made it like a pillow for you.
Rest your head on it, open your eyes…
And look at my glittering world.
I see light at every
turn that comes my way.
It’s raining love.
Like a beautiful jasmine plant…
Let it tie us together.
Playing all day,
without knowing any strain…
Just like the kids.
I have a very little to my name.
But all of it is yours now.
Hey girl, let’s get a rush.
Let’s get away together.
Who cries when kissed!
I have dreams that flow like a river.
They are finding their path.
I opened up my heart very carefully…
And handed it to you.
I have slept on your chest and saw…
How beautiful the world is.
The gift that the clouds send…
It will be seen on the lands.
The shadows that keep changing…
Look at the images that float.
The milky-ways that moved to the city…
Still hold the village in their hearts.
I have a very little to my name.
But all of it is yours now.
Brother you eat off.
I have got urgent work.
-Why are you in so much hurry?
-Geetha is going to Singapore, brother.
It’s like a vacation.
I’ll go send her off.
-Is she going alone?
-No. With her family.
Then how will you meet her?
Geetha will be waiting for me.
I’ll wave her bye from a distance.
What?
Geetha is going to Singapore.
He says he wants to go to the airport.
I feel it’s risky.
-Bye.
-Bye, sister.
Bye!
He have to go.
Your heart drags you away…
-Hello!
-Calling from Hanumakonda PS. Revanth?
Your friend, Sunny, met with an
accident at Hanumakonda highway.
We are taking him to Hanumakonda
general hospital. Come there.
Who’s this?
Dad, where’s brother?
-I already told him not to go to the city.
-Why are we here?
-He said he’ll get me a gift for my birthday.
-No one listened to me.
Yeah, he said he’ll bring you a gift.
He called me and told me the same.
-Nothing will happen to him.
-What are they doing inside?
-What happened to my son?
-Nothing!
Where is he?
-Hey, come here.
-Don't cry!
We are done with the post-mortem.
Go to the station, sign the papers,
and take the body. Go fast.
Haa come on… Sign here.
Sir, who’s bike is that?
It’s your Sunny’s right?
He ran into a tree with it.
That’s not his bike, sir. Someone left it in
front of his room. It’s been a week or so.
He don’t have a bike at all, sir.
What’s this? RC.
He ran into a tree and was spot dead.
Sir, try to understand.
Why will he get onto that highway, sir?
Hey, who are you?
-Friend.
-If you have any doubt, file a case.
Sign here and take the
body if you want to.
Do you want to write a complaint? You
have to keep travelling back and forth!
Your daughter?
Seem like she’s your only kid now.
Take care of her at least.
Make sure she won’t fall in love.
What? Or else, this will repeat again.
[screaming and sobbing]
Get up… You said you’ll make
me get on a flight, right?
You said you’ll take me to America…
Get up!
I don’t want to go to
America, let’s just go home.
Listen listen, ask him to get up.
Ask him to get up.
Sunny…
Sunny, get up let’s go home.
You called me in the morning and
you said you’ll come see me, right?
Sunny!
Brother!
Geetha committed suicide!
What? You didn’t sleep yet?
I’m talking with my SI brother.
About Sunny?
You?
I’m having some… crazy dreams.
I don’t feel good.
Don’t be silent. Say something.
I’m scared right now.
Mouni... I’ll go home once.
And tell my mom about us.
To your mom?
Why? Will she agree?
What if she won’t?
Nothing of that sorts will
happen, Mouni.
You paid her salary by selling your bike!
To that Venkatesham’s daughter!
What else did you do?
Bloody red scorpion faced idiot!
-You even risked our land, you moron.
-Mom!
-Mouni is a really good girl.
-Is it?
Do you even know anything about them?
The apple doesn’t fall far from the tree.
Do you know anything about her uncle?
Who’s he in between all this?
Mouni’s parents are good people.
Her parents? Ok…
I’ll take you to their house.
I’ll wear a costly saree.
See what happens after we go there.
Without looking at our legs if
we have left our slippers out…
Without offering us water
in separate glasses…
If they just talk to us normally,
you both will get married. Or else, no!
-What’s with you, mom!
-Don’t say anything else.
I’ll agree to this marriage
only after you prove me wrong.
Or else, never take her name again.
Ok?
What, teacher?
Isn’t sir home?
He is. Let me call him.
Is he your son?
Yeah. He’s running a huge dance center in
the city. And he’s earning good numbers.
What? What’s happening?
Didn’t you get a deal on your land yet?
No, not that, sir.
My brother told you, right?
His words are my words.
You can go.
You have great timing.
Here are my brother’s clothes.
They will suit you well. They are new.
He wore them just once. Here.
What? Will you leave me?
Mouni, don't say that.
I’ll die. I’ll die if needed,
but… I won’t leave you.
A little trace of doubt and
I would have killed you.
Back in the village,
they won’t agree to our marriage.
What if we get married
against their wish?
My uncle won’t leave me until I’m dead.
I don’t know, but let’s do something.
I can’t live in this hell anymore.
Come on… Let’s go…
Have you gone mad?
You asked me whether they will kill
you if you love their daughters, right?
Listen to me carefully…
Yes, they will kill you.
Get us married, brother.
What? Do you want me dead too?
Brother, you are an SI, right?
So what?
Brother, the SI in that village killed
Sunny and framed it as an accident.
What are you doing then, brother?
What the hell is he talking about?
At least you tell him.
Get us married, brother.
Hey, they can do anything.
They have lots of money.
They have lawyers, goons…
Whom do you have on your side?
We have you, right brother?
I can’t do this. Forget it.
We have no other way out, Revanth.
Let’s run away from the village.
We have no one here.
Don’t tell anyone about us, brother.
At least do this help.
Did you decide where to go?
No matter where you take
her, it won’t take more than...
...a week for her uncle to
know that she’s with you.
Do you think he will keep calm?
Hey, I have thought of it a lot…
I have read the entire
charge sheet of Sunny’s case.
They manipulated a murder as an accident.
We have to do the same.
We have no way out of this.
-What to do, brother?
-You have got settled in the city…
No one knows that you know her.
We can convince your mom somehow.
Mouni has to…
Aa ha… My people will kill me.
For your uncle to not come behind
you, eloping is not the answer.
We have to fake her death.
-I didn’t get you, brother!
-Let me explain.
Now...
This girl will go back to her home.
She stays silent for six months.
One morning, she’ll write a note - ‘No one
is responsible for my death’, and come out.
Then you can go somewhere
else and get settled.
I’ll write my uncle’s name.
It’s better that way.
Damn no! If a case get’s filed, I have
to catch you two. Let’s not do all that.
I’ll go the bridge and throw your
anklets, scarf, and sandal there.
Once you write the letter and come
out, I’ll send you away in a jeep.
You both get married and
leave to someplace else.
But there is a problem…
She can never go back home.
It’s ok… Hum…
That’s ok, but what will
you do in these 6 months?
I have to stay away from her anyway,
right? I’ll go to Dubai, brother.
I’ll gather some money and will
take Mouni to Dubai with me.
God!
Now we have to change her name
and make a passport on that name.
Haa... It’s Mounika Rani, right?
What if we make it M. Rani?
Think about it again.
Then I’ll tell you what to do.
We need an address proof
for her in the city.
Go to a notary and change the name. Apply for
Aadhar card on the same name and address.
With all those documents,
we have to apply for a new passport.
After that, you go meet
a Dubai agent for work.
You shouldn’t have
any kind of contact.
Throw away your old
phones and sim cards.
My strength just took a
hit, looking at your beauty…
All the beauty that covered
every inch of her had chose you…
Hey… Mouni, you are back… I told
you, right? You can’t do it.
All the beauty that covered
every inch of her had chose you…
The rangoli I make in front of my house
everyday… Let me make it on your heart.
Let that be my place for a hundred years.
The commotion in our way
is your wedding bells…
These scattered voices are the
traditional wedding chants.
You walk you way and
I walk towards you.
Let’s count each step as each
life we are going to be together.
Such strange will this
love had made of our names.
It has hidden me inside you, but is
asking me to leave you and walk away.
I’ll be one step ahead of
time and will win over it.
I’ll turn the clouds into chariots
and will take you to a ride.
Our love is like the sky and
darkness won’t stay for long.
I just want to be the holy
power on your forehead.
Such strange will this
love had made of our names.
Inter-caste and inter-religion.
Did you have any local address?
-How much time will it take, sir?
-One month, easy.
Do you need a date?
Anything is ok, sir.
At least plan it on an auspicious day.
You are getting married, right?
Hey, I’ll ask Mouni.
If she has any sentiments…
-Ok.
-Sir… I’ll just be back, sir…
Brother, is Mouni there?
She's here. Here...
-Hello!
-Mouni...
Mouni how are you?
How will I be without you?
I’m dying here.
You left me alone, right?
Mouni Mouni please don’t
cry, Mouni…
Nothing, I’m good. I’m good.
How are you?
I’m good.
Mouni, we have to get married.
We have got all the papers, right?
We have to get married
before flying to Dubai, ok?
I’m waiting here.
Will you give me a ring,
or marry me with a mangalasutra?
Let’s do… both… But first, let’s
sign in the registrar's office.
Mouni, do you have any sentimental date?
I mean, do we have to look
for an auspicious day?
I just want to come to you right now.
I’m scared to be at home.
But my uncle’s daughter is
getting married this 6th.
I don’t want to cause trouble for her.
Let’s do this after her marriage. The
suicide plan can wait until the marriage.
So is 10th ok for you?
I’m ok with whatever you are ok
with, Mouni.
So should I book a date here?
Here? Where are you?
In Hyderabad.
You came to Hyderabad and you don’t
tell me that! Won’t you meet me?
You are heartless… Get lost, you…
Mouni Mouni, won’t I be dying to meet you?
But it’s too risky.
Mouni, please don’t cry.
We have stayed separate for 6 months,
and now it’s just 10 more days.
Don’t cry, Mouni.
Ok.
Mom!
Mom, open the door.
-Revanth!
-How are you?
What’s with the sudden surprise?
I’m here to surprise you…
How are you?
-Did you miss me?
-Come on in.
Humm, here, eat some.
-Humm… Enough enough enough..enough.
-Eat some more.
Mom, here is some tea.
-I’m going out with brother.
-Where to?
-Hey, at least have some tea.
-We'll just be back.
Hey, Revanth… Once Mounika come
out writing a suicide letter...
She’ll throw her anklets here.
She’ll throw the scarf inside.
The level is high, so they’ll think
that the body got drifted away.
No one will doubt anything.
Then I’ll give her a burkha…
I’ll get her out of the village
and she’ll catch a bus there.
You both go somewhere
safe and get married.
Mounika told us that her uncle won’t
even look for the dead body, right?
But for safety, I’ll keep one
of Mounika’s dresses with me.
If something goes wrong, I’ll put that dress
on some other dead body and manage them.
Hey, I’m here to help you, right?
Move…
-Ok, brother.
-Come on.
I'll just come.
-Hello, tell me brother.
Mounika, all the arrangements are done.
You come out and you'll get married
as soon as possible. Are you there?
Wife of Revanth, care of Dubai.
That's it!
Ok.
There is a pot on her right shoulder.
Her saree is shinning.
She won’t come to your call.
She’s Saranga Dariya.
There is a pot on her right shoulder.
Her saree is shinning.
She won’t come to your call.
She’s Saranga Dariya.
There is a pot on her left shoulder.
Her saree is shinning.
She won’t come to our call.
Her name is Saranga Dariya
-Mom...
-What?
-Your passport…
I'm coming to Dubai? Oh my, God!
What’s with this new habit?
Silver anklets to her legs.
Her walk makes a beautiful
sound even without them.
Jasmines in her braid.
Even without them, she smells great.
Her smile won’t drop pearls.
But it shines for sure.
She likes betel nuts.
Or a betel leaf.
With her front teeth…
If she bites her lips
with her front teeth…
Your heart will turn read.
Look at the mascara…
She’s like a knife
that had mascara…
She won’t come to your call.
She’s Saranga Dariya.
There is a pot on her right shoulder.
Her saree is shinning.
She won’t come to your call.
She’s Saranga Dariya.
There is a pot on her left shoulder.
Her saree is shinning.
She won’t come to our call.
Her name is Saranga Dariya
The clothes that had no color…
Once her braid touches it,
it gets filled with color.
Her words are strong as a clove.
Mess with her and she is a lioness.
She’s a sarangi without strings.
Try to play her and she is a cannon.
She’s a doll.
a bird you can’t catch.
She won’t come to your call.
She’s Saranga Dariya.
Her cheeks glow like moonshine.
Her ear rings shine bright.
She won’t come to your call.
She’s Saranga Dariya.
If the fold on her hips shine…
Guys just lose their world!
She won’t come to your call.
She’s Saranga Dariya.
There is a pot on her right shoulder.
Her saree is shinning.
She won’t come to your call.
She’s Saranga Dariya.
There is a pot on her left shoulder.
Her saree is shinning.
She won’t come to our call.
Her name is Saranga Dariya
-Revanth, M. Rani...
-Sir.
Rani is not here yet.
She will… She got a little late, sir.
-Kiran Vandana?
-Yeah.
You guys come in.
Ok, brother?
Brother… What happened?
I’m here at the bridge…
Mounika is not here yet.
Brother, what happened?
Mounika didn’t come…
-What?
-Brother is still waiting there.
Brother, here are your
Dubai tickets and passports.
-Thanks!
-Thanks.
Give me the bag.
Brother, did she come?
Not yet… It’s already late… It’s
risky for me to stay here for long.
Brother… She will come. You stay there.
Ok ok… I’ll wait here, ok?
-Hey, side on that side.
-Thank you so much.
-This is all because of your support.
-Congrats!
-Thank you!
-Congrats, dude!
-Giri's house is all set, ok?
-Thank you so much.
-I have arranged everything.
-Yeah!
We have to have a party!
-Finally!
-Thank you so much!
Mouni...
What happened, Mouni?
-Did you think that I cheated you?
-No!
No no, never…
Don't cry.
I came there… I came running…
Eh Ramya, where are you going?
Going home, uncle.
-Come, get on, I’ll drop you.
-No, I'll walk.
Eh, come sit.
Ramya!
Sit close.
What happened, Mouni?
That Anaconda won’t leave kids…
He destroyed my life…
You danced well…
-This chocolate is for you, come on.
-Thank you, uncle.
No, uncle!
I got really scared. I stopped dancing.
I stopped playing.
I was scared to go to school,
thinking if he’ll come to drop me off.
-Mom… I won’t go with uncle.
-Mouni!
What? Don’t act smart!
Mouni you have to go to school, right?
You love school, right?
No, mom. I won’t go with uncle.
I used to hear his bike’s
sound even in my sleep!
Don't tell anyone about
what uncle did, ok?
-If you do...
-Mom!
Will you?
Now he has his eyes on my sister.
I can’t come out leaving her with him.
This is not the way, Mouni.
This is not the way.
We have to speak… Speak about
this in front of your family.
Not for us to get married, but for
the sake of your sister we should.
We have to drag him onto the roads!
Mouni you are scared even after all
these years. Then what about your sister?
Will you keep protecting
her all your life?
How long will you do that for?
Mouni come on. Listen to me, let’s go.
What’s this?
Where’s dad?
You first get inside.
Call your husband too…
Let’s talk right here.
Look, there is a marriage happening here.
Making a scene here is not good for you.
-It's about our respect.
-Hell with respect...
Your daughter needs to talk to you.
Mouni, go on.
-Mom...
-Enough.
I’ll talk to her. Please leave.
Did you ever talk to your daughter?
You’ll ask if she’s talking to a boy,
wearing decent clothes, where she is going…
But did you ever ask why she’s not eating, or
playing, or why she’s scared all the time!
You keep saying, ‘Go to the uncle’,
‘Aunty will take good care of you’…
But you never think why they don’t like
certain people, or not going to their house.
Your daughter not falling in love
doesn’t mean raising her fine…
Even a 10-years-old girl should be
able to talk to you. Talk to them.
Talk to your kids.
Who will talk to the
kids, if not the mother?
Hey, how dare you come here?
Hey!
How dare you touch me!
Dad… It’s because of him.
It’s because of him...
My childhood got destroyed.
I stopped going to school.
I stopped playing.
I was scared to even be at home, dad.
What’s with this new drama?
What? Are you drunk or what?
Have you gone blind?
See see… Can’t you see the new
drama your daughter is putting up?
She brought this on to our house.
She'll get married to this low caste filth and
ask for a bed for their first night. Will you?
-Who’s the filth here? Who’s the filth?
-[commotion]
You spoiled a girl’s life, you are hiding
behind caste! She’s like your daughter.
-Unethical moron.
-This is just because of you.
-Is this what you are doing in the city?
-Don't believe him, dad!
-Who's low caste? Come out!
-Dad, listen to me.
Who is low caste!
-Open the door.
-You...
-Stop!
-Open the door!
-I'm going to kill you today.
-Dad, stop!
Let her go!
Touch my daughter again and the street
dogs will be feeding on your bones.
Listen to me, son.
You guys just go away.
She kept all this pain to
herself and lived life like hell.
I did nothing as a mother…
You take her away.
These people are not even humans.
Hey, he’s eloping with our girl.
I’m at my brother's house, come here.
Mouni, it’s not safe for
you guys to stay here.
Mom...
-Go… Go…
-Mom!
I’ll take care of your sister.
I’m there for her.
Open up!
You leave before he gets out.
They will kill this boy.
Listen to me.
I’ll take care of your sister.
I’ll protect her.
Come on, son. Come on.
Brother... Are you dead? Stop her.
Go fast…
Go… Go… Go…
Go… Go…
Revanth!
-Mouni!
-Revanth...
-Revanth, come on.
-Mouni.
Mouni, come on.
-Mom... Mom open the door!
-What...
What happened?
He took a loan on Zumba.
He sold Zumba to go to Dubai.
Now he left Dubai
and brought you home!
-Mouni.
-Drink. That's how we have to live now.
-Mom, come fast.
-Shut up!
-Move!
-Look at what you did!
Put this on.
-Come on.
-Fast... Come on.
-Move.
-Fast!
Mouni, this way. Come on.
Search!
-Where's Revanth! Hey!
-[commotion]
-Mom...
-Aunty!
-Come out. Where's Revanth?
-I have no idea.
Mom, come on.
-Not in my house. My uncle will kill me.
-We have no place else to go.
-Dude, please!
-No no, please leave. Please!
Mom! Mom, are you hurt?
No, I'm ok.
-I can't... anymore.
-Mom, what happened?
-What happened?
-Nothing.
-Does it hurt?
-No, it's nothing.
Mom, we have to keep moving.
Let's go.
Come on, mom.
This way...
Mom, backwards… More.
Hey, this belongs to them.
What, mom?
This graveyard belongs to them.
What if someone sees?
What doesn't belong to them?
Huh... What?
Our lives belong to them.
We are different until death.
And now even after death
there is a difference!
We are the ones who work hard.
And we are not allowed in!
Hey, have you gone mad?
Of course, I have gone mad.
These lands belong to them and they rule.
Our lives belong to them.
Where should we stay, how much should we
sell our land for, where should we die,
where should we go
after death… With them
dictating all this,
of course, I have gone mad!
Don’t run, they will kill you.
Let’s escape silently.
Where should we go to? And why?
Why should we escape?
No, Revanth. Listen to me.
Let’s call SI brother. He’ll help us.
Let’s go to the city.
They will kill brother too.
Your uncle will kill us.
He’ll kill your mom too.
I even feel that we did a
mistake leaving them behind.
Not that I want us to die...
But I can’t live running.
Let’s die if we have to.
But let’s fight back hard.
Didn't find them?
Search properly.
They'll be here somewhere.
Don't let them go.
Once you find them, kill her frist.
Then kill him and his mother. Get it?
You, bloody!
How did you even touch her?
She’s like your daughter.
Are you even human! Damn you!
Let go of him.
You might kill him. Let him go.
Revanth!
Where will you run off to?
-Bloody! Can't you be quiet?
-Leave!
How dare you spoil my image?
-What will he do now? Huh?
-Don't touch me.
-I'll kill you in front of his eyes.
How dare you mess with my name in
the village? See how I’ll kill you.
Mouni... Mouni, are you ok?
-Did he die?
-Mouni... Mouni are you ok?
-Hey...
-Mouni!
He would have killed her.
Can't you see that?
Mouni... Mouni, why are you crying?
We just killed an evil person.
Not just for our sake. For the kids
and the people of this village too.
It's his mistake.
Will they send me to prison? Let them.
10 - 20 years... I don't care.
How can we live seperated?
I'll kill myself. I can't do this.
We have to, Mouni. We have to live.
This world exists only
for people like us.
Not for the ones who calculate life with
caste, religion, and family respect.
Sir, my son did nothing wrong.
Sir, I beg you, plese!
-Narasimham is not a good man.
-Let's go.
See what you did. You killed my son!
-Mouni, it's ok...
-I won't let you go.
Ma'am, please move!
He's going to pay for this.
We won't leave him. She brought
a street dog into our house to...
Hey!
Say one more thing about
Revanth and you are done!
You should have been this angry on your
son and he would have grown up better.
You should have kept an eye on him,
not me. And I would have been saved.
-I can't live without you.
-Don't cry, Mouni.
-Move aside!
-Revanth!
-Move aside.
Mouni, everything will be fine.
I'll be back soon.
-Mouni, stop running. Mouni!
-Revath.
Mouni, take care!
This is not done on purpose.
Late Saitlu Narasimham tried
to hide his wrong doings...
By killing Mounika Rani.
Only in an effort to save her...
Accused Revanth pushed
Saitlu Narasimham away...
And he died taking a fall.
The court believe so.