My name is Giri...
I am waiting in
my lawyer friend Maya's office.
Oh! God!
She is
Maya...
Last night I took the tablet late,
it's gotten late now!
The reason she woke up late
I have so much work to do!
is not laziness...
Whatever may be the case
she is confident of an easy win!
In every case...
She will use some trick and win!
I will tell you about a tough case...
The son of a powerful MLA's divorce case...
Arguing for the opposition was
the one who defeated defeat itself...
Senior lawyer Sachidanand!
The proof is here...
Whatever the argument
or counter argument there be...
When it comes to the judgement of the court...
Do you have any proof with you?
Is the proof that is weighed!
Look here ma'am,
they have so much proof!
Even I have checked...
Everything is correct!
After lunch
I will pass the judgement.
But even without proof she won the case!
Your Honour, I want to tell you a story...
To win a case prove a case,
you need proof
but to prove the love between
a husband and a wife
emotions are enough!
In one story
she emotionally connected the husband
and united him with the wife!
Your Honour! The judgement?
See, that is the judgement!
She won the case...
Winning the case without proof
not only in the court
but even in the media it became a sensation!
To solve my friend's case...
I thought she is the right person
and I have come to meet her!
Remove the dead leaves from there man!
Thank you.
- Hi Giri...
- Good morning madam.
Sorry, I think I kept you waiting...
Stop this acting of yours...
You always do this!
How many years have we been friends?
You could have called and told me!
This is my friend's personal matter,
his is a love & arranged marriage.
It was better when he was newly married...
Now they are making mountains out of molehills
and are now on the verge of getting divorced!
Come here...
They are asking for a divorce
but you will have to personally
do something and counsel them
and unite them!
Where are they?
Are they coming?
Hi!
I'm Maya.
Hi...
Deepak.
I'm Pooja.
You want a divorce, right?
But your friend
asked me to counsel you both
and wants to unite you!
I don't know what to do...
Giri, what is this!?
No I... Not like that...
Are you playing the fool?!
No dude, I...
I trusted you as a friend
and you are cheating me properly!
After all, he is your friend...
He knows how to cheat very well!
When he was my friend,
he was nice only,
since I introduced you to him,
he's started behaving like you!
You don't talk so much!
You too don't talk so much! Keep...
It's fine if you fight over one thing
but you are fighting over every single thing!
Fine, leave it!
It's my mistake only!
Sorry!
See, how you guys have united to berate me!
Hello, look...
Giri has said nothing wrong,
he meant well when he told me
but whatever be the relationship
there should not be double speak!
So... Till you get the divorce,
I would like all of us
to be honest with each other...
Okay!
Instead of being a lawyer,
become a Guru in some Ashram
you give good sermons!
You're still here?
That's what,
my friend's case and everything...
Look...
The footwear is worn till the house
not inside them!
Understood ma'am.
Okay!
So...
If I have to understand you,
I have to know everything about you!
That means...
From the scratch!
Madam...
If you tell me where to sign
the divorce application
I'll sign and go...
Let's start the procedure!
Look...
Pooja and Deepak want a divorce
all the judges in the world won't be waiting!
Without knowing everything about you,
I cannot file the case!
Not just me...
No one in the world can!
So...
If you are convinced you can stay,
if not...
The door is open!
Madam I will tell...
Madam...
After I got married,
if you know what difficulty I faced...
not just for the two of us
for every couple in the city
you will file divorce!
Then even I will talk...
I will talk!
- I will talk!
Please...
The two of you don't have to be together...
You wait in this room
and you wait in that room...
I will come.
Hi Pooja...
Deepak...
Try to be comfortable,
make yourself at home please!
If you want anything
like coffee, tea
anything you want
please let me know...
I will arrange for it.
I'll record everything you say on this.
So...
You may begin now.
I am Pooja.
My name is Deepak.
I am a fashion designer.
Software engineer.
One minute!
I said...
That I want to know everything about you...
That means from the scratch!
Your father, your mother,
your background,
where you were born,
where you grew up, that much...
I need to know everything!
Because I am not just your lawyer...
I'm asking as your family counsellor
So, to analyze the root cause of your problem
I have to know all that.
It won't work!
To know everything,
convince us and do you want to solve this?
Don't try to unite us both!
To unite you both?
No.
To convince the judge
and I will try to get you the divorce quickly!
Are you okay with that?
Continue...
My father is Balappa Sharanappa.
Yes dude!
He is from North Karnataka
Unable to live there,
he came to Mandya.
As he had a banana in his name itself,
he started working in
the Banana Wholesale Market.
There is no grass that the sheep has not tasted
and no trade that my father has not indulged in!
My grandfather on seeing his growth
Got my mother married to him.
My father is from Mangaluru
but he settled in Chikmagaluru.
My grandfather had a lot of property.
All my relatives wanted to cheat my dad
and tried to snatch it,
but my father doubled the property.
Financially however well my father was
his mouth was not chaste!
Because...
[Incoherent Chattering]
Somehow...
My son found a girl aged forty years.
If you had waited ten more years
then you could have taken
a grand-daughter too man!
What an ass!
Oh! Crap!
It's Seegehalli Saroja!
Do you know her?
You have been saved dude!
In the next village,
it's called Chembunayakanahalli or something,
isn't that so?
There's a Saroja there!
What do I say about her!
[Muffled Sounds]
Why dude?!
A month ago...
The one who has settled in Seegehalli...
That Saroja is this one only!
The wedding is cancelled!
Let's go!
I told you so many times,
you did not heed my words!
Yes dear! It is true.
Your very birth is of no use!
After mucking up royally...
What!?
Your mother hits your father!?
What does he do in retaliation?
What does he do?
Acting as if nothing has happened,
he simply walks away.
My dad is very cool.
Your son roams all over
and is getting wasted no dude!
Who merit does he have
for us to marry our daughter to him?!
But he has only one weakness...
If your son had money,
even if he had a torn face like this,
I would have given him my daughter!
Whose face is torn dude?!
Is the torn face mine?
Your mother is the one who is torn man!
You son of a gun!
You idiot!
You're talking about how handsome I am?
I will kill you!
Ears?
Isn't it like a fruit?
Am I so-so to look at?
Nice, right?
For this glamourous figure,
won't I get a beautiful girl?
Awesome pair!
Dear daughter!
At a very young age
I lost my mother.
My father is everything for me...
He is my life...
I am more than life to him!
My mother is a proper
true-blue Mandya Landlady!
Local...
This is why my father,
being an outsider,
could not say anything and kept quiet.
That means...
in your father's life,
your mother plays havoc, I think!
That was during the era of the Nokia mobile...
After the Apple phone came my mother
became a gadget freak!
What?
After that all her games
were with the Apple phone!
What are you saying?
Hey Alexa!
I am pasting cow dung
Tell today's weather forecast...
If it rains
it will be very difficult!
Don't worry!
It's a sunny day,
carry on!
Cool!
Are you serious!?
How?
Her sister is in the United States of America...
For her grandchildren to know Indian culture
Is that so child! All this is there?
- She keeps sending all this!
- Super!!!
Teaming up with them...
She's like this!
My mother's latest peeve is that
in our town, there is no Swiggy or Zomato!
Really?
As she could not study English
so she sent me to the Convent!
After finishing my studies
I came to Bengaluru...
I got a job in a good company too...
Got an abundant salary
and good friends.
On the week days...
I used to work really hard!
But during the weekends...
My life was perfect...
And it was...
My life!
Even though we both lived in the same city
but I grew up in the hostel...
For that my father had a logic...
Look here dear...
For you...
If you think 'My father is here for me!'
You will win only one battle!
But if you rely only on yourself...
You will win the whole world!
Remember this...
I have always been independent...
But my father invested in my boutique...
He made me financially independent.
But any day, whatever problems I faced,
I never went to my father,
cause I can handle myself!
I was completely independent...
And those where the best days of my life!
Interesting...
So one is from Chikmagaluru
and another from Mandya
Both have different cultures...
So how did your story begin?
Fate!
Destiny!
No dear, tell me when have I ever lied to you?
No!
Hi! Giri...
Wife! Wife! Wife!
Ramya was calling you then dude!
You get married
and you will realize
what my difficulty is!
Hello!
Where are you dear?
Mama, I just reached the office.
Why so late?
I had some work at home,
it got a little late.
Good morning sir.
That's why I've been telling you...
Get married fast!
Mother...
For that, you don't try to
get me married to a village girl!
If I get married,
it will only be to a girl from the city!
You can't stay there
and look at girls here
let's postpone the wedding for two years,
leave it!
What is this, my son?
What age are you in?
The iPhone itself is getting updated annually
and you're talking like a Nokia basic model...
This is a remote world!
Remote world!
I don't have to come there and search for girls.
Sitting here
I can operate everything.
Did you know dear
in a matrimony agency
I have taken a platinum membership!
The introductory offer they gave 25% discount!
Along with that...
For using HDFC Card
they gave another 20% discount!
Look here son,
listen to what I say!
The ID and password I will send in Whatsapp
or Telegram...
No need...
Why all these?
These are all outdated!
Insta, Snapchat...
Or Tinder inbox is there right?
I'll send it there!
You see...
Understood?
Bye, bye, bye, bye!
Bye!
Deepak.
Sir.
Yes, coming sir...
The project target time has come
we are running short of time.
Speed up!
And inform the team too
Okay?
Okay sir...
Stop looking at your phone and work dude!
Okay sir!
So many missed calls?
My fans have increased!
On the hangers, you...
Hello.
I got a missed call from this number...
Are you Deepak?
Yes?
From Oriental?
Yes, I am working at Oriental.
How senseless you people are?
Even to an extent isn't your family cultured?
What school did you all study in?
What did you all go to school and learn?
Why madam?
Initially you spoke so sweetly
and now you're grinding me like this?
Your mother's name is Kamla right?
Your mother even before the marriage
tried to make me a mother...
She saw my profile on the matrimonial site,
I believe...
She called me and said...
Now dating, chatting and meeting
have become very outdated
have a live in relationship with my son for a week.
Is she your mother or your pimp?
My mother is like that...
If I ask her to chill at home
She acts like she is Elon Musk's cousin sister!
On her behalf,
I'll say sorry madam.
Only because you're saying sorry
I'm sparing you...
Otherwise, I would have filed a police complaint!
Madam for minor things like this,
why a complaint...
One minute madam!
I'm getting another call...
No...
Not for you, for me...
Someone called Sadhu Belliappa...
What!?
Sadhu Belliappa!?
That's my father!
We have to work it out and try!
Really?
Why is he calling you?
How would I know!
Don't tell him that I am here...
Take him on a conference call.
Yes madam.
Hello...
I am Sadhu Belliappa.
I'm speaking from Chikkamagaluru.
Seeing my daughter's matrimony profile
your mother called me.
Such humility, such humility!
Such culture, such character your mother has...
In this day and age of dating and chatting...
Without even meeting your mother
approved my daughter!
If you want, I'll convince her!
One minute, stay in the call...
I'll connect her also.
Daddy...
Daughter!?
You're there only!?
Before I connected, it's been connected!
Very good! Very good!
All the best!
If both of you meet up and agree
Papa...
I will fix the marriage!
- Okay!
- Papa...
Daughter, all the best!
- Son-in-law! All the best!
- Papa... Papa...
- Hello!
- I will disconnect the call.
I won't be able to say no to my father.
To my mother,
even if I say no, she won't let me!
Fine!
Then let's meet this weekend...
We'll meet at 12:30 at King's Club.
Done!
Okay.
Mother...
Son...
Did you like the girl?
When shall we have the wedding?
Mother, one minute...
There were so many girls here,
how did you know that I like her only?
No dear...
When you see the profile...
Won't it show here as 'viewed' to me?
Dunno how that they have given you a job and
lakhs and lakhs as salary!
Enjoy your life son...
Life is beautiful!
Fine, thank you.
Another time my mother
shouldn't even talk about my marriage.
The torture I will give her tomorrow...
She shouldn't show me another girl!
I'll do like that!
Hello madam...
Menu.
Sir is coming, please wait.
Okay!
Dude, give the bill quickly!
Am I not giving?!
Get it ready soon!
- Okay.
- I'll come!
Madam, menu...
Did it get ready?
Sir will come, wait man!
- What about yesterday's?
- Okay ma'am.
I am getting the slip ready, wait!
Hi.
Fine, I am giving it.
We planned to meet at 12:30.
I came on time!
In this country
if we go at the agreed time
they will think that we are jobless!
You are lucky...
I made you wait only one hour!
I make my friends wait for 3-4 hours minimum!
Ma'am, menu.
I need a little time.
I need it now.
Yes sir.
Shall we talk a little.
Let's talk.
Actually, when it comes to food and opportunity
we should grab it!
I'm a foodie, you know...
In my house
more than my alarm
I have woken up more to
my mother's cooker whistle!
First we'll eat and then we'll talk.
Give it sonny.
He has made it so expensive!
Two buffets.
Okay sir.
The buffet order is yours...
I will order whatever I want.
Do it.
One Chicken Biryani,
one Chicken Kebab,
one Mutton Dry,
one Fried Rice,
one Manchurian,
one Dessert,
one Lassi,
one Lemonade
And one Jamoon.
Okay ma'am.
If I marry her,
my salary won't be enough...
I'll have to take a loan to take care of her.
In one meal she is
fleecing me of ten thousand!
I'll have to make her pay the bill!
Madam...
Go and come.
Give me one Lassi...
- Fast!
- Dude...
Sir?
I will give you 500 rupees,
this bill...
Take it from her.
I don't want it sir.
Why my boy?
Sir,
taking girls to restaurants,
and paying all the time!
Today...
I have ended up working in this restaurant sir!
Sir,
boys must stand by boys!
What now?
The bill should be paid, right?
Just wait and watch.
You are a poor person's benefactor dude!
Ma'am,
here's the bill.
Sir is coming, please wait.
Ma'am bill.
Sir will come. Wait!
Ma'am, bill ma'am!
Did you ask him and order?
Like a rank student asking for
extra sheets in an exam,
you ordered extra chutney, extra sauce,
you asked for everything and took it!
Now are you playing games?
The counter is closing.
Wait, wait, wait!
I will give it to you.
How much is the bill dude?
Madam gave it sir.
You first give it back to her!
Take this.
Swipe from mine, swipe, swipe...
Take it!
What are you sir?
If I ask you to regurgitate
what you have eaten,
will you be able to regurgitate it?
Can you do it sir?
No.
No, isn't it?
Exactly like that,
once the receipt comes,
that's it sir!
How can you take money from girls?
Go away, go away!
What is this?
He makes a girl pay the bill!
Madam...
Madam, madam...
Madam.
Pooja!
I'll come.
Okay.
What a surprise!
Come, let's party?
No...
I had come for a meeting.
I will leave now.
Madam,
you said party!
Will there be booze at the party?
All the brands are available.
Madam,
please come madam.
It has been a while since I enjoyed free booze!
You've paid such a huge bill!
Let us recover some of it.
Come...
Can you keep quiet?
Madam, you tell her.
Come Pooja...
Please...
Come, come, come, come!
No!
- Please come Pooja!
- Take her... She will come.
Please...
Thank you.
You people carry on.
I'll come.
Hi Madam.
Hi...
Hi sir...
Madam, what would you like to have?
One Mojito.
What about you?
If you look at my face, what do you feel?
That you would drink everything
that is available for free.
Then bring 1 peg each, of everything.
Okay sir...
Do you only drink or smoke...
Booze and cigarettes are like a couple,
they are always stuck with each other,
one cannot live without the other.
Hello madam!
Drink a little less.
Did you just see?
How you bumped against me?
Hello, I'm not drunk!
What!?
You haven't had any drinks?
Even without drinking to this level
if you've bumped against me,
do you like me so much?
Shut up and keep moving!
If my boyfriend comes,
he will thrash you all over town!
If your boyfriend comes,
he will thrash me all around town!
Lady, who is that punter,
that fighter?
Where?
This guy.
- Is this the guy?
- Yes, it's me!
Will you thrash me all around town?
Why should I thrash you around town?
I just came here for free booze.
Why are you setting me up?
Sir, nothing has happened.
She bumped into you by mistake.
Please leave.
If I trust and get married to you,
I will be done for!
Useless!
Madam...
- Enough!
- Okay...
Sir, sir, sir, sir, sir!
I will tell you everything sir!
Please leave me sir.
What will you tell?
Sir,
all this is a drama, sir.
Drama?
Yes sir.
To this party,
the lady you brought with you!
That too is a drama sir.
It's a set up.
Junior artist?
Yes sir.
By paying 300 rupees per head,
this madam
has set up all of them sir.
Whoever comes to marry her,
she brings them all here
and tests them sir.
Sir...
I am not involved in all this sir.
I have to report for shooting sir.
Sir, I have to go sir.
I have to go.
I have to go!
I will go!
Drama?
You fought when you met for the first time?
Then how did you come together?
Don't ask me.
It's a crazy drama.
Actually!
Before the deluge,
I believe God gives a warning.
We should pay attention to it,
if we ignore it,
life will be like...
It will get spoilt.
Why hasn't my mother called me?
Mickey mouse!
Run, run, run!
Hello... Tell me son!
Dad... Why is the house so silent?
Is mom not around?
Your mother is in mourning.
I'm in a joyful celebration mode.
Don't know whose daughter she was,
in Northern Karnataka
the way people eat pan parag and gutkha
and spit it out vigorously...
That is how she spat at her!
She is sitting in a corner.
Has not eaten breakfast or lunch!
She is sitting silently like a ghost.
Look son,
I don't know what you will do
but that girl must become
the daughter-in-law of our house.
Okay?
Dad, give the phone to mom for a minute.
Okay, okay!
To your mother?
Your son dear.
Please take it.
Take it.
Deepu,
After the meeting I just called her
and asked her opinion
and that girl...
For water on the streets
you know how they scuffle and berate each other!
She scolded me worse than that son!
I don't know what you will do,
that girl must come and fall at my feet.
That's it!
Else,
I will remove my Whatsapp DP
and put up a sad status!
I will do it, wait mom.
Don't you want this?
That color is dull.
This is alright.
Let's look at that.
What madam...
Is it your boyfriend?
Take his call.
Why have you come here?
To buy clothes.
Then do just that,
else get out!
Come on, let's go.
Is this the only store?
Next time we shouldn't come here.
I told you not to come here earlier itself!
I will teach him a lesson!
If I don't pick up your call,
it means I don't want to talk to you.
Same with me,
if I'm calling you continuously,
it means I want to discuss something.
Are you Shreya Ghoshal
that I'd want to hear your voice again and again?
Yes! That's why.
Don't call me.
I have no interest in talking to you.
I'm busy in Madikeri.
Do not call me!
Hello, hello, hello, hello!
I'm in the same Madikeri that you are in.
What!?
Turn a little to your left please!
Why madam?
I believe you called my mother
and abused her.
At least, you only call and torture me.
But your mother...
She is next level!
Not only Whatsapp and Facebook.
She is messaging me on
Phone Pe, Gpay and Paytm
asking me if I liked her son!
That is the love my mom has for me.
How will you understand that?
You are the kind that tests boys like vehicles.
Yes... I will test.
How does that bother you?
In the test you conduct,
you will only know pass or fail...
By chance if I pass,
you will have another test
to figure out how I passed.
In this world
there are no boys who will be 100% perfect.
By chance you get one,
they will only be 50% right,
the other 50% we have to compromise!
Look I will tell you something,
listen to me properly...
If you talk to someone
and feel like you want
to keep talking to them,
if you see someone
and want to continue seeing them,
if you feel very comfortable
in someone's company,
they are your real-life partner!
You cannot test and get them
by searching like this!
Hello!
So according to you...
I will never be able to find
the kind of guy I'm looking for?
There is no chance.
Watch me!
I will find a guy exactly like
the one I'm looking for,
make a raw almond reel with him
and send it to you.
Watch it and feel envious!
Almond challenge!
Fine!
Challenge!
I will see.
Almond! Almond!
I already have a large car company.
For that car company,
I'm the sole proprie...
When you see someone
and want to continue seeing them,
they really are our real-life partners.
Think about it!
Its your decision.
Believe it or not,
when I talk people just want to listen to me,
It's like,
my voice...
I am unable to listen to this!
When you talk to someone
and want to continue talking to them...
They really are our real-life partners.
Deepak and I
in the same company
have been working together since 2 years.
Okay!
He's a very good boy.
You can surely marry him.
Okay.
Thank you.
If they are not around,
but we still are thinking about them,
they really are our life partners.
Please give me a buffet.
Sir, 2 buffets?
No, no. Just a buffet for me.
Please order whatever you'd like to order.
Is he enacting a drama or what!?
And in desserts...
By chance if I pass,
wondering how did I pass?
You will keep a test for that too!
Vanilla flavor,
chocolate flavors are there sir.
Okay, I think that is fine for me.
That flavor is ok.
Do you want anything else sir?
- Wherever I go, he is always on my mind!
- You please ask her...
What you want...
Please check...
Okay sir!
I will go and bring some starters.
Yes, carry on.
Did he tell I am quarrelsome?
That I will test everything!
Whatever I am doing is a drama?
No, not at all.
Then...
In life when trusting a boy,
she will leave her house, parents
and everything and come.
If she checks out if the boy is good or bad,
what is wrong in that, he told!
And in such a big city
without anyone's help
if she is running a boutique,
can't she run a family?
She will make a very good wife
he told madam.
He told another thing after that.
Very important!
Many people will come
and many will go in life,
but with one person only...
We feel like spending our entire life.
If you find such a person,
you shouldn't let go.
This girl is like that girl.
Don't miss her, he told.
Wait, wait, wait!
Whatever you told him,
is it true?
Indeed, it is true!
Tell her it is true sir!
Your opinion about me,
is it the same?
Is it not so?
Whatever is in the mind comes from the mouth!
Tell her sir.
Actually, I overacted a bit...
So...
I am really sorry!
People with a pure heart only sir
have the magnanimity of asking for forgiveness madam!
Sir, you leave it sir,
you are super!
Actually...
You had told me that day
that when you see someone,
you should feel like seeing them only,
when you talk to someone
you should feel like talking to them only,
when you are with someone
you should want to keep being with them,
when you are not together
you should miss them!
Now I am feeling all that...
You have to feel that...
When you see a good boy like me
you should feel like that...
With the same happiness give me a hug!
Come...
Madam, madam, madam, madam!
Madam, what are you doing?
Come...
You got confused and instead of me,
you hugged him!
It's me that you came to see, isn't it?
Come hug me!
Come on, come on, come on!
Hug me!
She will hug me!
Bye!
When you have been secured,
For other dreams...
Where is the space?
Oh! Life!
All my tomorrows...
Are with you only!
My life is reserved for you!
Oh! Life!
The only thing left is for me to go mad...
When in such a state of joy!
That you are mine forever...
My heart is bursting with pride!
In all of your moments...
Let me partake of them!
When you have been secured,
For other dreams...
Where is the space?
Oh! Life!
Actually, you know what...
To build our own home on top a hill
and settle there only is a huge desire!
On the Mountain!
Likewise, for us to roam about
we should buy a small cute car!
When we enter our house
in the foyer,
there should be a big portrait of Ganesha!
Our best memories
should be displayed in a photo gallery!
Our living, dining, kitchen should be open
and our bedroom
should be romantic!
Everything should be in blue!
There should be a Home-theatre at home,
you and I
should sit on weekends
and watch a good movie...
With popcorn!
Our hearts have intermingled...
Our song is the one only!
By earning, saving, come let's build!
Our own little nest!
Pain or joy...
Whatever it may be...
Give me an equal share!
Let the happiness, boredom be equal.
Let them be too!
You should give sweet kisses...
A hundred every hour!
You should ask for forgiveness
Whosever mistake it may be!
Always together everywhere...
Our names should be seen!
When you have been secured,
For other dreams...
Where is the space?
Oh! Life!
All my tomorrows...
Are with you only!
My life is reserved for you!
Oh! Life!
Bye!
Be careful!
My thoughts and prayers
They all are yours!
[Humming continues]
Isn't this drive wonderful?
Deep!
Shall we eat on the way somewhere?
Or shall we cook and eat at the flat?
Let's cook and eat, it will be fun!
Are all the groceries there in your flat?
In my flat?
Groceries, is it?
Poo...
Your flat is bigger than mine,
isn't it?
So I thought it will be convenient for you,
I sold my flat!
What!
You sold it?
I too have vacated my flat!
Poo,
whom did you ask before vacating?
At least did you inform me before?
Why I have to inform you Deep?
I will anyway come to your house
after marriage,
It's your responsibility, right?
Where do we go now!?
Poo, my friend has a flat,
let's do one thing!
We will stay there today
and tomorrow I will make
some arrangements!
First day itself we have to stay
in your friend's house!
Ridiculous!
I cannot stay there Deep!
Only one day you have to adjust!
- Please...
- No Deep, I can't!
Just one day!
Please Deep,
can you please turn the car?
We shall go back.
Why have you brought me here?
Won't I be uncomfortable here?
Nothing like that will happen, come!
Just for a day!
Why are you forcing me?
I don't like this one bit!
Please, come.
This is my friend's house.
My friend is a staunch admirer of
Kannada language!
That's why, see here...
To show that he reads Kannada newspapers
he has displayed the Kannada newspaper.
Is this a joke?
This seems to be a joke to you,
do you feel it's a joke?
Enter your password!
Bro, be careful!
Go!
In your sparkling eyes...
The expanse of light!
Is mine from now on!
Oh! Boy!
Oh! My sweetheart!
Your whispering words
And my longing for them
I don't see the end to it!
Oh! Boy!
Oh! My sweetheart!
I will give you space in my lap...
I will become a child!
Below your crossed feet...
I will keep my heart!
From now, I will be with you,
Forever & ever!
You are from my intoxication!
In your sparkling eyes...
The expanse of light!
Is mine from now on!
Oh! Boy!
Oh! My sweetheart!
This place is ours!
What?
Ours?
Seriously?
You wanted a home on the mountain, right?
Build it!
Thank you!
The entrance should face this side...
It should have a hut shaped roof!
The sunlight falls here,
let the window face this side.
Let's have a garden all over here.
Online business is a trend!
In your being, my...
Happiness is enclosed!
In myriad ways, you held me...
How you cuddled up to me, I remember!
You are my father!
You are my mother!
You are my everything!
I feel so...
What cannot be seen even in dreams,
To that wonderful world!
Your fond love that beckons to me!
Is there a comparison?
From now, I will be with you,
Forever & ever!
You are my intoxication!
In your sparkling eyes...
The expanse of light!
Is mine from now on!
Oh! Boy!
Oh! My sweetheart!
Everything looks so perfect!
According to you,
Where do you think it went wrong?
So now it is the last saree for today!
Saree number 20.
It is a beautiful, beautiful
combination of grey and blue.
This is a customized saree.
So, this saree costs 3999/-
Tomorrow I shall come back
with my new collection.
Till then, see you guys!
Poo...
Yes.
Can I get a glass of coffee please?
Even I'm tired after my work since then!
You are asking me for coffee?
How selfish!
Sorry!
Yes, please come!
Keep it here!
What order is it?
You have ordered something.
I did it yesterday,
- bean bag!
- Is it?
Red, is it?
Isn't it superb?
No, it is useless!
Doesn't suit the house Deep!
Sir!
Wait a minute please!
Poo...
You were struggling to cut your nails, right?
So, I got it with love!
In the name of love,
don't try to convince me!
I didn't like it.
Sir, bill!
Stay quiet please,
ma'am is throwing arrows at me
and you are talking about bill!
Poo, the salary has been remitted, right?
I had to get you some gift,
hence I got it, that's all!
It's okay to get a gift,
but I too must like the gift, right?
If you buy something that you like!?
If I didn't like the gift at all,
for me,
it doesn't make any sense to keep this!
Sir, if I take it back,
my boss will scold me!
To keep it inside,
my boss must allow right?
Sir, let's do one thing sir,
I will call my boss and give you.
You talk to him sir.
Hello!
Sir...
It's...
To surprise my wife,
I had ordered
but she didn't like the color.
The one who is hurt only
will know the pain,
I'm married too!
You return it,
I shall repay your money.
Thank you, sir.
Yes, okay!
Sir, next time, when you book,
ask madam and do it sir!
Deep...
Now...
In front of the house on the board
you have put both our names, isn't it?
Why is it?
Whatever has to be decided,
both of us should decide that,
isn't that right?
The problem that started in such
a simple manner,
no idea how it developed to this extent!
Simple, is it?
It looks complicated!
Yes!
It was complicated.
Poo...
Your friend Maadevi...
She's so vexed!
Not Maadevi!
Her name is Madhavi,
Same.
Her husband is a big psycho!
He tortures her a lot!
She was very upset,
just to give her some relief,
we have come to this trip.
Give me that.
Careful!
You go and get another.
Will you have both?
Take the soup.
I'll come, wait!
- Careful!
- I'll pour it.
Where is the other soup?
You don't have to serve her soup Deep.
If she needs,
she will go and take it herself.
She was very sad right,
That's why I gave her.
What's the connection with that and you?
Do not overact!
Poo...
It's okay!
Don't think otherwise.
Drink it.
You have come without
even informing me, right?
Wherever you go, I will not spare you!
I have come with my friends only, right?
Who friends?
Who's he?
- I haven't come alone.
- Her husband!
Don't spoil my head.
I have told you before,
- I will kill you!
- They are fighting!
Deep!
Where are you going?
There's a fight going on there.
What will you do?
It's their personal matter.
They will solve it.
- It won't be right!
- You don't have to go!
What won't be right?
It isn't romance, there is a fight!
How many times haven't I told you?
Don't leave home and go anywhere!
Are you playing the fool?!
What is it?
- What is happening, man?
- There's some issue there!
- Who are you to interfere in my family issues?
- Dude!
All this isn't required,
don't come and create ruckus here!
- Who's he, who's he?
- See this guy dude!
Look, how he's creating issues.
What do you want man?
Look dude, he's beating up his wife,
I asked him not to.
Who are you?
Just stay quiet.
Just move away!
Come here man! Come!
Stay quite dude!
Just move away!
Don't raise your hands on women!
Get lost!
Did we really need all this?
What's the difference between you and him?
How would you interfere with my wife's matter?
You nutcase!
What?
Will you hit your wife?
No, no...
Come here madam.
You think you are a cat?
Hit him, hit him!
Thrash him!
I will never forget this help of yours.
Please forget all this and be happy!
Thanks a lot!
No problem.
Thanks.
Poo...
I need to talk to you.
Hello!
Are you still asleep?
Yes aunty.
Why is your voice so dull?
That! I had a headache and vomited too!
What dear?
Dizziness
and vomiting?
It isn't that aunty,
I had been to the trip yesterday...
You please keep quiet!
For men to vomit
there can be a hundred reasons.
But for women to vomit,
the reason is always one!
This is that!
Fine, fine, my dear!
Do not strain yourself!
Rest well alright!
I will call you in the evening.
Bye...
Yes, papa!
What dear,
I'm still struggling to adjust
becoming a father-in-law,
You have already made me grandfather?
Who said this to you papa?
Your mother-in-law,
she's broadcasting this all over town!
Papa! I'd been to a trip yesterday...
I can make out everything!
Very soon... I will come.
Tell me dude!
Congrats dude,
you were online all the time,
when did you go off-line for all this?
You are great dude!
You win everywhere!
Cut the call, I will talk later.
Actually...
Isn't my mother very cute?
Very innocent?
Does your mother have any sense!
God has given two ears!
To listen well...
Why has he given only one mouth?
To talk less.
Your mother listens to half
and speaks double!
Get up!
They should not get involved in
our personal affairs!
Clear that!
I will call and clear it later!
When?
After your mother broadcasts after this!?
No...
I will talk to her now!
Yes? Tell me son...
That... Stomach upset made Pooja vomit,
not to make me a father.
Mother... About that...
About having children...
That, my...
We will decide when we want a child,
this is our personal matter.
You don't have to interfere
has your wife told you to say this!?
She's creating a rift between us!
I knew it my boy...
That demon...
Had an allergy since the start!
When I met her itself,
I should have messed her!
Give the phone to that demoness!
I'll talk to you later mother!
This...
This is my stature!
What was that!?
What did your mother say on the call?
Some lady, lady!
No... She said milk lady!
One minute...
I'm getting a call from the office.
Even though your mother talked so much
you can't even stand up for me!
No use talking to you!
I'm 'Live' after many days...
Latest saree collections are there!
Poo...
Who are you!?
Why are you repeatedly saying Hi!?
Can't you mind your own business!?
When I needed it, you did not support!
Why are you disturbing me
when I am live online?
Do you want a break?
No.
In life, all the good moments
pass by so fast...
But the bad moments
we pray should get over soon!
Let's finish it.
Hi Papa...
Why are you looking so dull?
What happened?
I had to take an Ayurvedic medicine
I won't get it here...
From Bengaluru, can you...
No need dear...
You should have told me!
I too forgot!
It's okay dear...
After marriage,
I didn't want to trouble you.
Why these formalities with me?
I will send!
Okay dear!
Be careful...
- Send it with the driver.
- Bye!
Deep, one minute...
There was a call from your house...
We need to send the documents, it seems.
I've taken them.
They said it's urgent.
I'll send them.
And father's Ayurvedic medicine
should be sent too.
On the way while going...
They'll bring the medicine to Malleswaram,
if you call the SRS driver
they'll collect it and go.
Is this why you're now talking to me?
Leave it, I'll send it.
I was only joking.
It's fine, anyway it's my work.
Poo...
Why do you take everything so seriously?
It's my father's health issue,
it's important.
Your father is my father-in-law,
send me the number...
I'll send it.
Bye!
Thanks.
It's urgent.
- Can you send it fast?
- Okay sir.
- Is that so sir?
- Don't forget.
Sure sir.
Okay sir.
One minute sir, I'm coming...
Hello Giri...
Hello dude!
There's just five minutes for the meeting,
in two minutes, I will reach...
Where are you?
First check your eyes...
It's not in five minutes,
it's in the evening at 5!
You get your eyes checked
didn't another mail come yesterday?
That the meeting has been advanced.
I didn't see it...
Leave it dude...
You're newly married,
you will be busy.
Shut up and cut the call!
I'll be there.
Take these sir.
Thank you.
Do you all know that
we have clients from
South America,
South Africa...
And Deepak, you'll head the team.
Is that fine?
All the best guys!
Dude,
since morning he bored us!
What he was talking,
did you understand anything?
I took tablets to cure the headache!
What!?
Tablets for headache!
Tablets!
Sorry!
- I have told him...
- Sir...
I need to deliver these quickly!
Quickly means?
Shall I send it by WhatsApp?
Sir comedy should make people laugh,
not burn them!
Give it to the driver, he will deliver it!
Give him the money too.
Wow! Super!
I saw YouTube and made it.
It's okay!
It's super!
Hi Papa.
Look here,
I've made your favorite dish!
Why are you so dull, Papa?
Did you not take your pill today also?
If not sad, what else!?
You said you will send the tablets with the driver...
Where is he?
Really?
Deep...
You delivered the tablets?
I sent them...
Why this doubt?
No, I gave it to the driver!
Papa, Deep says that he has sent it...
Where did he send it?
No driver came and gave it!
I'll call the driver and ask him.
Enquire and call!
Hello, tell me madam.
Did you deliver the tablets to my father?
What madam,
I called him so many times,
he didn't pick up only...
When your husband called,
I was already in Hassan.
Tablets are so important...
He lacks seriousness!
Today however long it takes,
I'll deliver it madam.
Fine sir, deliver them urgently!
Thanks.
Fine madam.
Why did you lie?
Where did I lie? I gave it...
Lies again!
How irritating!
I gave it last evening!
Evening?
I told you to give it in the morning!
I couldn't give it in the morning,
so I gave it in the evening.
Mother...
Son,
we got the license...
If you had not sent it at the right time
your father would have been in deep trouble.
Will you ever let your father get in trouble!
A son should be like you!
Fine mother, I'll call later.
When did you send the documents
to your house?
Yesterday...
Morning or evening?
Morning only, just listen to me...
You showed your true colors...
Don't say true colors and the such things...
Please listen to what I'm saying
with a little patience.
If I'm ready to listen,
then you'll state one lie after another.
You are such a liar!
Don't call me a liar!
I'll get really angry!
Showing you a mirror makes you very angry,
right?
Poo...
Simply don't make me angry!
If you get angry, will you hit me?
You will not flinch to hit me!
Speaking to you is such a waste!
If it's a waste, why are you standing here?
Go!
Oh! My love... Oh! My love...
Is this separation justified?
Akin to a rainbow...
Will you fade and become an illusion?
Oh! My love... Oh! My love...
Why do you come thus!?
After building a nest in my heart,
Will you fly away!
The initiation was surely existing!
Everything then was mesmeric!
Towards the end why
Do you become so lethal!
Once the glorious subsides!
Peace is hijacked!
Commotions and bickering is
a daily occurrence!
Oh! Love Birds...
Oh! My love... Oh! My love...
Why do you come thus?
After building a nest in my heart,
Will you fly away!
The dawn of dusk...
Clear breeze...
The whispers...
Where are they?
The pleasant moments
Like they no longer remain!
As if the address itself is incorrect...
And the orphaned message
Not being delivered!
The star scattered and fell!
Oh! My love... Oh! My love...
Is this separation justified?
Akin to a rainbow...
Will you fade and become an illusion?
Oh! My love... Oh! My love...
Why do you come thus!?
After building a nest in my heart,
Will you fly away!
When the two of you fought so much
to solve it
did no third person get involved?
They did get involved...
Son!
You!
Why are you shell shocked?
Won't you invite us in?
People get scared when they see
someone without make up...
But you are with make-up
that has scared him!
Please put a little less powder...
No, you showed up so suddenly...
I got shocked!
Come in...
Bring them!
His mother and her arrogance!
I have to bomb that!
What is this my son?!
There is no charm in your home
And none in your face too!
Where is that daughter-in-law of mine?
She is not to be seen!?
Father!
Where are you off to?
Daughter-in-law...
I'll call her...
Come this side!
Come, stand here!
Stand!
Poo...
My parents have come...
Come and talk to them.
Who?
Your mother, is it?
Tell her I won't come!
It will be better if you come quietly...
The house is so nice, right?
Mama, she was sleeping due to a headache...
I told her about your being here...
She got up happily and rushed to come...
But...
I told her to take her time.
Poor child!
I'll freshen up and come.
Go, my son, go.
Go, get ready.
What a cat!
Look at how he lies!
He is born to you, right!
Only to me?!
No, I was also a part of it.
You have come now with the lemon!
The bus was late...
They are both inside together!
Everything will be okay!
Be quiet and come inside.
Come inside...
My son...
Your father-in-law is here,
come outside!
- Brother, welcome!
- Dear... Your father is here...
Get some water!
Slowly, slowly!
Are you out of your senses?
Why so loud?!
My native place is Savannur!
That's why!
Slowly, slowly!
It's just that I came to the city for a purchase...
Also wanted to give my daughter a surprise!
Papa?
Papa!
You too talk like me!
That is your disease!
Shall I give you a tablet?
Hi Papa!
- What a surprise!
- How are you?
- You didn't even tell me that you are coming!
- Take this!
This is from Kukke Subramanya temple...
Thank you.
Look at that girl!
When her father came how she ran out
and started talking!
But didn't even come to see as well.
How insolent!
Surprise, it seems surprise!
Now we have not come here to fight!
We have come here to sort out the fight.
How are you papa?
You just be quiet.
Where is my son-in-law?
Is he inside?
Papa!
I will call him,
I will go get him.
Deep...
My father has come,
please come and talk to him once.
I have taken a vow of silence for today,
go tell your father.
Look, this is too much!
I have seen it!
No big deal! Go away!
Poo...
Your father is here.
I should go and talk to him...
Did you have to call me for this?
Wouldn't I myself have come?
How come even in the bedroom,
you are standing so far away?
When we are in front of them,
they will stand far from one another!
Excuse me!
Any problems with each other?
No problem!
[In unison]
We are made for each other!
Close the door.
Do you think they got to know about our matter?
What do we do now?
What else?
Till they are here we will be together.
Act like we are there together.
I have come now,
we shall solve it.
Don't talk too much,
go and sleep on the floor.
I am male dear,
so I will sleep up only.
I trust myself,
if you have trust yourself,
sleep or go away!
Deep, everyone is at home,
if they hide and listen.
Is your family so cheap
that they will eavesdrop?
There is no need to ask about your family.
Moreover your mother is
not at all a flirt that she will hide and listen!
Keep quiet, Deep...
Come dear.
Careful!!!
Dear...
Some places are fragile,
if you hit his head like that,
he will die!
Gentle!
Gentle, gentle!
Everything is alright, thank you.
Bravo!
They have come.
They have come!
Deep, will you drop me to boutique and go?
Sure!
So sweet!
Bye...
[In unison]
- Bye, bye, bye!
- Bye...
- Bye dear!
- Super.
Sir, sir, sir...
You saved a drowning ship
and made it reach the shores safely.
Now shall we go back to our city?
Reaching the shore is not important,
we should see to it that
the ship does not drown again,
that is important.
Yes, yes.
How sir?
I will go to my place and get a powder,
we should mix it in milk and give it to them,
they will not go to work.
He will work from the house itself.
Both of them now will become three.
If they have twins
then they will become four!
It is their risk, they will only know.
So you are saying that
we should see our grandchildren,
finish their naming ceremony and then go!
One who finishes the work
and goes is not great!
One who sees to it that we don't
return here again is great!
You are the greatest ever!
He talks very smooth!
No, he is right.
Once our grandson comes
only then will we go from here.
Let it happen.
The grandchild!
Even if they are not like us, it is fine!
Even if it doesn't resemble us, it is fine,
as long as it does not resemble him,
it is fine!
Keep quiet.
Oh! God!
What is the meaning of your words?
Joke, it's a joke.
What joke?
That means my face is so bad, is it?
Bad, no, not bad.
What then?
What are you saying 'No' for now?
If you talk, talk about your face,
talk about your stomach,
talk about what is below your stomach...
Yours abs are six pack, is it?
See lady...
What stomach!
- What are you telling?
- Your husband's is big or mine is big!
Mine is big!
What are you showing my wife man,
to my wife!
Your hair is yucky!
If you speak about my hair,
I will cut your tongue!
What tongue man!
God only has cut everything
and made you a dwarf!
You will show your stomach to my wife is it.
Your stomach!
Hello!
Who man... Who?
Come here son.
- What father?
- What?
- Come here...
- Tell...
What?!
Tell to his father!
Will a dog feel bad when called so?
Will a pig feel bad when called so?
This bloody b^&%s%^&d
when I called him scrap
he got vivid!
Son of a bitch.
Your death is in my hands!
If you speak another word...
I am a wrestler! Wrestler!
Who is a wrestler?
Pint sized dude!
Go man.
Uncle!
See daughter!
Mind your tongue.
Whatever it is, he is my father.
Son!
Protecting her father
see how she is quarrelling.
Insults to your father is still keeping you silent!
You also talk son.
Mother, keep quiet mother.
Uncle you please go inside,
I will talk.
What!
Why should I go in?
Ask your father to fall at my feet
and apologize,
then I will go in.
My husband?
I will ask sorry
please uncle, be inside.
Why should we ask him sorry?
This is a Mandya and North Karnataka
combination man.
See... If we have made a mistake
we should apologize,
if we have not made a mistake
we will not apologize.
We are from North Karnataka.
Tell your father to go in.
Why should my father go in?
Your father's talking nonsense,
send him out!
Nonsense!
What did you say?
I have not called my husband nonsense till now.
Who are you to tell this to him?
Why are you valuing him?
He is subdued by his wife.
Why should we value him?
Go man!
Uncle please get inside...
Daughter, your husband slapped me.
Deep...
Did you slap me?
Not your cheeks man,
if you act more, I will punch you.
Go man, go.
- You will beat me!
- Yes.
- Yes!
Go man.
My son...
I was trying to talk and he just slapped me!
Hitting isn't enough!
I will kill you!
[Incoherent fighting]
However proud a father is
when it comes to his daughter's future...
I washed your feet and gave my daughter to you...
You know why?
Because his daughter's life should be fine
that she should be happy.
If she is only not happy in this house,
she shouldn't stay in this house.
She shouldn't stay in this house.
Come daughter.
Poo...
Okay...
Got it.
If you don't mind...
Can you step out for two minutes?
Okay.
Deepak, Pooja...
Come.
Incompatibility, miscommunication,
lack of love, lack of trust,
difference of opinion,
this and that...
Your case is too complicated!
Please take it...
Okay...
Daughter...
Hello.
Your father-in-law is ruining my reputation.
If I catch him, I will hit him with a slipper!
With slippers!
Who is he going to hit with a slipper?
Your father!
Father-in-law!
Meet me in person!
I'll turn this divorce case into a murder case!
What he's talking!
Who are you going to murder!?
Who else? Your father!
You are talking about my father!?
Pooja!
Deepak...
Please...
Stop it!
By chance if you decide to become
a couple again!
I won't allow it!
I will make sure you get divorced!
Hello...
- Sorry Maya.
- Maya sorry.
It's okay...
The past should be left behind,
future is the only thing under our control.
So...
Let's move on.
All your documents are ready...
If you come tomorrow and sign it,
we can apply for the divorce.
Okay.
- Okay Maya, I'll come.
- Thanks!
- Okay...
- See you tomorrow.
- See you...
- This file... Keep it over there.
- Is it ready madam?
They are here...
Just two minutes.
- I'll sign it and return it.
- Okay, thanks madam.
Yes, please sit down.
For small things,
I turn this place into my office.
Giri!
What are you doing over there?
Come here!
Before the divorce
you two are still husband and wife dude...
Why should I come between the two of you
and get hit by slippers and brooms?
Revenge?
Just a little...
You continue...
Okay!
Both of your divorce documents are ready...
Look through it once.
For 2 - 3 days
I have been studying your case...
There is a serious problem!
- What is it?
Both of you
'Made for each other!'
that you will be together for life
all your documents
and all assets
are in both your names!
Your Chikmagaluru site
is in both your names!
The car is in your name
but you are paying the EMI.
Accounts, investments, insurance,
are in both your names!
To apply for divorce
it will take 90 days.
Before that
split your joint assets equally.
Are you joking!
My hard-earned money
I should give it to her
so that she can romance someone else!?
I want my money!
Him being in my life!
I want no trace of that!
Let him sell everything!
I want what is mine, that's enough!
Madam,
I'm a software engineer
not a salesman!
This saree, jacket sales is in her line...
Let her sell everything!
Don't talk about my profession...
It's called a boutique!
Saree and jacket he says!
Where will it go?
Village blood and cheap mentality!
Pooja...
She has Queen Elizabeth's blood?
If a forest officer sees her father
thinking it's a chimpanzee
he will take him to the forest!
You don't talk about my father!
Look...
If the two of you keep fighting like this,
it's waste!
If you want a divorce
the assets need to be separated.
You decide!
You have 90 days time.
Now sign it.
Thank you.
What's with you dude!?
When we go there, you stay here
and when we come here, you go there.
No, I am playing Kho-Kho by myself.
You keep talking, I'll come.
Please send all the documents with Giri...
I don't want to see your face!
You think I want to see your face
and am walking around with your DP!
Fearing that you'll appear in my dreams
I've stopped sleeping!
Giri come here!
Dude...
Please sell the car.
If you want to know anything, ask her.
You go now...
I'll come tomorrow and collect it.
Thanks.
I ran around for their wedding,
Helping them get a divorce is very sad!
We who adjust to anything life throws at us
when it comes to a wife and husband
why do we grow such an ego?
If we see someone drowning from a far...
It looks like they're playing in the water.
To each their own problems...
We should respect their decision.
Hello, tell me uncle!
It's me, Giri!
Yes Uncle!
Apparently, you're selling my son's car?
That shorty
seems to have an eye on my son's car...
Look...
I don't know what you will do
but you have to sell that car in my presence!
Understand?
I will come.
That bugger!
Okay uncle.
Hello?
Hello!
This is me speaking.
Who is me?
Do you think I recognize your voice
like you're some celebrity!?
Tell me your name.
You are Deepak's friend, right?
You also have an attitude like him!
Pooja's father!
Hearing that the car is for sale...
That broker father of his
will try to steal the money!
I have some work with him.
I will come there...
The car deal should happen
in front of my eyes!
That's all!
Okay uncle.
In this case,
half the problems is due to these two only!
Somehow, we need to
teach these two a lesson!
For all this...
That car dealer Syed...
He is perfect!
He's a dealer by name only...
A big rowdy!
Take these two to him,
I'll tell you what to do there.
Repairing them royally
he will do that!
Okay!
What is it dude?
Brother, that party I told you about.
I saw your car...
It's not in a good condition for sale...
It will be a little difficult.
Brother Syed...
How many kids do you have?
Nine!
Didn't it hurt?
It didn't hurt while conceiving them...
Now when I'm raising them it does pain!
Sir you look very weak,
how do you have so many kids?
That's my personal performance.
Is that so...
Our vehicle also has
the same kind of performance.
What do you think?
Okay.
How much are you selling it for?
Ten lakhs.
Before running off to London that Mallya...
I bought a Kingfisher flight for six lakhs.
Am I bonkers to pay ten lakhs for this?
I have to somehow see to it that he suffers a loss.
- Hello!
- Syed, it's...
Bro eats lamb...
But that dunce...
He is not!
That's it...
Vehicle is my daughter's!
I'll bring her with me and sign it.
Fix it for only four lakhs.
Intelligent!
Dude, this car is owned by my daughter and me.
Do you want samosa also?
No, tea is enough.
Listen to me...
You are a waste!
Go! Go!
We have to get RC book.
Insurance card.
Just because I am wearing a half sleeve shirt...
You think I'm a village bumpkin!?
I sleep in Frazer town
and wake up in Shivajinagar!
For all your mafia Dons
I'm the one who supplies weapons!
I told you right?!
You're a waste!
Go!
Go...
- Change the color of the vehicle.
- My God!
His talking!
[Incoherent mumblings]
Customers are there...
I'll give as you say
10 lakhs...
Come, I will give it inside.
Not in front of this animal!
Come...
What are you talking?!
Go!
Four lakhs!?
Bear town guy!
Go away!
He'll put you into biriyani...
Go!
If he compromises?!
Brother Syed!
Fortune is what this is!
Ten lakhs!
Ten lakhs?
Enough!
I'm a village bumpkin,
an illiterate man.
That car won't even go for two lakhs,
he told me to say ten lakhs
and he'd say four lakhs.
He only taught me to say that!
That Syed won't know the difference
between a chicken and a goat.
He said that!
Like that?
Yes!
Okay...
Don't tell him any of this.
Simply go and send him inside.
Yes sir!
He held my leg...
And gave me Biryani rice.
Are you kidding?!
And this?
After finishing the deal
he gave some betel leaves and nuts.
I thought it was soup!
You also go in...
He'll give you a pumpkin!
Go in uncle!
- Go in!
What is this man!
Serve me biriyani rice,
soup,
betel nuts...
You...
Uncle?
Uncle, did it work out?
He said pumpkin but he gave watermelon!
It worked out fully!
Give me your hand dude!
Uncle slowly...
I thought he'll give biriyani rice,
but he only gave soup!
Then father-in-law wants to
sell the property too
why don't you stand and sell it?
For this only my face broke...
For that my whole body will break!
Go!
I won't come to this town itself!
It worked out the way I said, right!
Yes!
You know next time what we should do?
For his mother also,
like this...
They came, they came...
Hi dude!
Hello!
- Maya madam...
- Hi Giri...
Yes!
We need another help from you...
What is it?
Actually...
Two major properties are in our names
so if you only sold it...
Am I your lawyer or your broker?
Maya, can you please do it for us?
Because if our families get involved
there will be many complications.
Because you are asking so much,
I'll do it.
Let's start with your major properties,
your Chikmagaluru hill property,
let's sell that first.
I know a lot of people in Chikmagaluru...
Shall we go this weekend to sell?
Super!
Shall we go on bikes?
Yes, yes!
It will be like a road trip!
Sure!
Super dude!
Why not!
You?
No, no...
I will come by car.
See you guys.
Why?
When she goes on bike
she gets sweaty...
Hi!
Good morning!
Take this!
Are you ready?
Come!
Let's go!
Let's eat here and go!
Okay dude.
Was the sweet not good?
It was super!
Sir anything else?
One button idli.
Okay sir.
Dad is calling...
I'm getting a phone call...
I'll just be back.
I've ordered button idli!
I can't have more...
I'm done.
I'll just be back.
Dude...
Smoke?
Yes father...
I ate breakfast.
I'll take it...
Here...
This hotel.
Hello madam!
Madam order please...
Two minutes.
Okay madam.
Do you want anything else sir?
Get her a masala dosa.
I asked if you want anything
not what I should serve to others!
I'm her husband!
Trouble!
Look now sir,
how I'll patch everything!
He will patch us up, he says!
Do it!
For me, a masala...
Madam your masala dosa!
I didn't even order?
For someone who understands your mind
doesn't need words madam!
What are you talking about!?
Madam your husband ordered it!
Which husband!?
He's there...
Please come here!
She made the order out of order...
Madam, my bill!
Let the bill be there
go and tell him...
If he shows concern like this
it will go like this in the dustbin.
Okay madam.
Sir, madam told that...
Tell her...
That throwing the masala dosa in the dustbin
it is of no use.
Her head is only a big dustbin,
first tell her to clear the mess in there.
Go tell her...
Madam, that...
If someone marries someone like that
their head will turn into a dustbin.
Not that madam...
Bill...
You also stopped here for breakfast?
Yes!
Sir,
madam has agreed that her head is a dustbin.
Now the bill...
She agreed finally, right?
I'm happy.
Just for that keep a 100 tip!
Thank you sir!
Are you married?
No sir!
My family is looking for a girl.
Anytime now...
You idiot...
For a monkey to become a man
it took centuries,
but for a man to become a monkey...
One marriage is enough.
It's my duty to tell you and I have!
If you don't listen, it's your fault,
suffer!
See you!
I've spoken to them about everything...
You don't worry.
Okay!
Let's meet at the location.
- Okay bye!
- Bye!
[Incoherent chattering]
We shall enjoy!
Let's take it, don't worry!
Idiots!
You shouldn't smoke in public places
don't you know that!
What did you say!?
I'll inhale what I want
or be consumed by flames,
why do you care!
Don't mess with us!
Keep going!
No dude...
Just because I'm alone
you'll talk however you want!
I've come with my friends!
Hey Giri!
What?
Come here!
Who's Giri!?
Come dear!
Come!
Giri...
Put your hand in a snake pit
but don't interfere with matters about a girl!
Heads will roll!
Dude...
My father, in my birth certificate...
Marked me as a man!
Today...
I'll prove it!
Don't dude...
You'll have it!
If you just go quietly, it is fine!
Or else...
If Brahma has written your date of birth,
then I'll have to write your date of death!
Who is this guy dude?
Such a big build up?
Give him one!
I told you but you didn't listen.
Dude!
Now what?
My husband is here...
Husband!?
Is it him?
If he comes then you'll know!
Are you the husband?
Boss...
Following Clean Bharat...
She put me in the dustbin.
She and I are far apart...
Your husband left!
Slap her!
You said you had nothing to do with her!?
Why did you come now!?
I was going...
Not only doing something wrong
but seeing wrong being done
quietly is wrong too!
I remember my mother told me...
That's why I came.
You know how to fight?
So do I!
Girls should speak their minds
but they should see the situation
and then speak...
I won't always be around to save you.
Bye.
Come!
We'll go... Okay?
Come carefully.
Brother,
let me find out...
Please wait.
He initially agreed for a crore...
But now he's asking for 60 lakhs.
Mostly...
They have found out about your divorce.
They are misusing our urgency!
I'll talk to him, come!
Look sir...
Saying one price on the phone
and calling us to meet here
and saying another price is wrong.
If you don't like it, tell me...
I have another ten people
willing to buy it.
I've got everything ready
and I've come here.
If you don't take it, there's no problem.
Leaving that, heeding gossip
that they will divorce
don't think that we'll sell for your rate.
Look... They're happy together!
Okay, leave it madam...
We'll pay a crore and buy it.
Today only we'll register it, come!
Go ahead!
What sir!?
When we boys asked, you said no.
Deepak...
Pooja.
Success!
The deal is done for a crore!
Super.
Did you see...
If the two of you are separate,
the price is less.
If you are together,
you are priceless!
Without reaching the goal
In the journey!
You joined me...
Why so?
Did it all end
All the dreams!
What's left at the end
Is just pain!
Without reaching the goal
In the journey!
You joined me...
Why so?
What has been shaken and scattered
That love cannot shine again!
Without warning
It will leave in a moment.
In the heart of ocean,
Will the waves not rise?
The fond memories of the past
Will it come to stop you?
The name engraved on sand
Can be erased.
But the name etched on the heart,
Can that be erased?
Again, drops of rain are falling...
The wish to get drenched in the rain?
Can I arrest that?
Without reaching the goal
- Every thing has been divided properly...
- In the journey!
- If you come to the court tomorrow
We can move the divorce petition.
We will come.
Yeah!
You joined me
Why so?
For two weeks compulsory use this!
Hello!
Maya madam,
both of us have come.
Sorry Deepak,
I am a little tied up in another case...
That day, for the signature
you were near a table, right?
Yes, I know.
Please come there.
- There's a document ready...
- Madam, madam...
- You should have asked me. I would have...
- Keep quiet!
I have kept it all ready.
You go through the documents.
Tell them my name,
get it signed,
notarize it and come.
Okay?
Alright madam.
Okay.
I'm trying something alright!
Sorry madam.
Just come.
What happened to your leg?
When you stepped into my life...
Compared to the pain,
this isn't bigger than that!
Do what you have come to do!
Whatever happened
has happened correctly!
Come!
Sir, Maya madam had told us...
Yes, it's ready!
Sign here...
Are you the one's getting a divorce?
Nice couple...
I can't believe it!
You can't believe it.
A tiger and a goat if put together in
a photo frame
they will look good.
Only if you put them together in a cage,
will you know the reality...
For everything you have to
say something smart!?
That doesn't keep you quiet either?
Am I to blame for everything then?
You are perfect?
Think and you'll realize!
However much I think
it's the same...
You started it!
When I gave a chair as a gift...
You couldn't see the love there
you only saw the colour!
If you gift me what I like...
That is called love!
If I have to accept what is given by you
then it's by force!
Simply between you and me
didn't your mother interfere?
After speaking foul about me,
don't they have any sense?
I have already explained it to you.
Look,
my mother is like that only...
Either you should have adjusted to it
or accepted it.
Even in war there is a break...
Look at them!
Non-stop!
Trying anything is a waste!
Come!
I'm telling what's there only...
Only people with brains will understand!
You have brains and I don't?
Yes, I do have!
Don't you have the sense of where you are!
It's the court,
not your house!
Your case is next...
Come!
- Case number MC-852/20-21.
- Madam, ours only!
Stand here...
Have you both applied for divorce
by mutual consent?
Without being pressurized by
anything or anyone...
Have you decided to take
divorce on your own?
It's not out of wish
but when the other party wants it
I have to give it!
It's all on me?
But you won't accept your fault!
- Both of you stop it!
- It's only when we err that we accept!
This is a court...
- To accept one has to have guts, right?
- The judge is watching!
Don't talk about guts...
- Look...
- Keep quiet...
This isn't a market place!
Keep your fights outside!
Respect the court first!
You look like educated people...
Behave yourself!
Tell me in one word...
Do you want a divorce or not?
If both of you want to discuss
and tell me, do so!
I will give time for that too!
He can't understand anything sir...
Please give a divorce.
I can't understand her either sir...
Both parties have agreed to
the mediation of the court.
The case is decreed!
Madam
Both of you have to sign there.
Next!
- Wait outside.
- Case number MC 440/18-19...
- I'll get the divorce copy.
- Quick!
I'm very upset...
In every case,
I use some trick and win,
but in your case...
Joint assets, road trip...
Nothing worked out!
I'm sad that I lost
but I tried my best.
At least now...
Stop fighting as a couple
and start a new life...
You both are more than clients to me.
I wish you both the best.
Thanks Maya.
Thank you.
I have another case...
I have to go...
Poo...
Come, I'll drop you home.
After you have done so much
if I sit in your car...
I will feel ashamed of myself.
It's not to be good in your eyes,
it's raining
and there are guys here...
Come, I'll drop you.
Will you let me be in peace, please?
Don't be adamant!
Why are you forcing that girl?
She's my wife...
If she's your wife or elder
or younger sister
it doesn't matter!
Otherwise,
you will not go out of the court!
Wait, let's ask her only...
Do you know this guy?
Communication...
After it stopped, I felt lost!
This silence...
What does it whisper!?
While we edged away from each other...
It was as if a bond still held us!
Utterly orphaned!
Stated the soul!
Felt like someone held our shoulder!
Communication...
After it stopped, I felt lost!
This silence...
What does it whisper!?
Poo...
At some point in my life,
you became my wife.
Together we even travelled...
In that journey...
If I have made any mistake
or if I have hurt you,
please forgive me...
I'm really sorry.
Deep...
Dee...
Poo!
Yes Deepak...
Tell me.
Maya...
Pooja has...
What!
What!?
Oh! My God!
I am near Re-life Hospital...
I know all the doctors there,
you also come there.
Stay here sir, wait here.
Sir you sit there...
We will come and inform you.
Come...
Mr. Deepak...
The doctor is calling you, come in.
Before this...
Did anything like this happen?
I don't know...
You don't know?
How long since you are married?
A year...
You are saying that you don't know?
What do you think your wife is?
A housemaid?
For the person you love
shouldn't you care that much?
Doctor...
Please tell me
what has happened to Pooja!
She is very serious...
Your wife is suffering from
Cerebral Aneurysm.
Meaning?
The main blood vessel connecting to the brain
has been dilated.
At any moment...
It can rupture
and the patient can collapse!
It is even more dangerous than cancer.
Cancer at least has symptoms
This has no such symptoms.
Doctor however much it costs...
Start the treatment now.
If it was in the early stage,
we could have done the surgery.
Now it is too late,
it is not possible at all.
If we attempt the surgery now
the chances of the patient dying are higher!
Doctor,
is there no other option?
No, I am sorry.
Meaning...
How much time does she have left?
Exactly how many days
she has left we cannot tell
but maximum she has 30 days!
If anything like this happens again
Within 6 hours she will be no more!
Beyond the very skies...
I mean...
Even I feel very sad to say like this
- Let's go...
- I am sorry to say like this.
Come...
Till she is alive...
Look after her well.
In an hour
I will discharge her.
Please be seated over there.
On this world
Everywhere...
Let's walk across, come!
Come along!
Pain of any sort...
Should be none...
Let's reach a new world... Come!
- Let's reach a new world... Come!
- Madam, all the files are here,
- please take it.
Everything is okay, right?
Beyond the very skies...
Yes... Everything is okay.
- Beyond the very skies...
- Shall we leave?
Let's go...
Come...
One minute.
Pooja!
Poo?
What happened?
Poo!?
- Open the door, Pooja!
- Poo!
Pooja!
Poo!
Are you okay?
Yeah...
What happened?
Poo...
Is everything fine?
I feel like being alone,
can you...
Please...
Sure...
Deepak... Let's leave.
Poo...
I'm going to ask you something?
Please don't say no.
For another 10 days...
Can I stay with you?
Please Poo.
Please...
I know...
That you don't like to be with me...
At least for me!
Beyond the very skies...
Let's go...
Come...
From this second
till the last second...
I'll live for her now!
On this world
Everywhere...
Let's walk across, come!
Come along!
Pain of any sort...
Should be none...
Let's reach a new world... Come!
Beyond the very skies...
Let's go...
Come...
Sir, whatever is there...
Make my husband the nominee for that.
Okay madam.
Sign this application...
I will look after the rest.
Thank you.
Sorry Uncle...
It's my mistake.
These are usual in families...
Even I can understand!
You guys have to be happy, that's it!
Now are you happy dear?
Come dear...
Sorry Aunty.
Don't talk about that...
It was different when I was a mother.
It will be different after
the daughter-in-law comes!
I should have understood that!
Please forgive me...
Talking all the comforts of the world
I will place them at your feet...
To the moving time...
Let's put a stop!
Just hold my hand...
I will push the swing.
I will sing a lullaby...
Sleep like a child...
Without a care in the world!
Beyond the very skies...
Even after the divorce order,
you have assigned the will
in your husband's name...
Beyond the very skies...
Is that okay?
Let's go...
Come...
On this world
Everywhere...
Let's walk across, come!
Come along!
When you will see this video
I won't be there Deep...
In the time I had left
Whatever I wished to do for you...
I have done it all.
You have to be happy.
And show!
I lost...
I'm very late...
I have a client meeting.
So I have to push.
- Another game...
- We could have played another...
Even I want to stay
but I'm getting very late
I'll call you both...
You guys continue, okay?
Okay bye!
- Bye!
- See you!
Poo...
I also haven't gone to the office
since many days.
I've got a mail that there's a meeting...
Only two hours...
I'll go to the office and come.
Okay.
Deep...
Can I talk to you for a bit?
Tell me.
I really want you be happy.
Anyway we both are already divorced...
Will you marry Maya?
Poo...
Are you joking?
I am serious...
She is good.
So?
You both will make a good pair.
Every day, all day...
Why did we fight?
Why did we even think of divorce?
Now I am happy with you.
Maya has helped us a lot
for that I respect her a lot,
that doesn't mean
what you think will happen.
Deep...
I won't be with you for long.
I mean...
To do the fashion designing course
I'm going to Paris.
I've talked to father...
I will settle down there
I won't come back from there
so you will be alone...
Also...
I think Maya has feelings for you.
Hey Poo...
Not like that, Deep...
If it's too uncomfortable
I'll talk to Maya.
Don't talk all this!
I forgot my keys.
Sorry...
I heard what you were talking.
Pooja...
You are a good person
in your tough time as a moral support
I was here as your friend, but...
I don't have any feelings for Deepak.
Maya...
Actually, I was telling Deepak...
Before you came...
Please...
What's on your mind is what
will be spoken Pooja...
I mean...
I never expected this from you.
We spent so much time together
But if you thought like this of me...
It will be tough for me to
spend time with you both...
So it's best for me to leave,
- anyway I wish you both the best!
- No Maya...
Bye!
Maya...
What have you done?
I didn't expect Maya to overhear us, Deep.
Now what we do Poo?
Deep, I did it with good intentions only,
Deep.
Deep...
I know that I'm not going to live, Deep!
What are you saying!?
I heard what the doctor said...
Poo?
Poo!
Emergency!
Sir!
The doctor is calling you.
Doctor.
Take the tablets without fail ma'am.
Yes ma'am...
- Poo...
- Okay!
Come!
What happened?
Deep, what happened?
Why are you going so fast?
What happened? Tell me!
Simply sit down! I'll tell you!
Are you a doctor!?
Are you a doctor?
- What happened?
- Why, Deep?
Why are you holding my collar?
Just holding your collar!?
I'll kill you for what you have done!
Deep, stop!
We went to a different doctor
do you know what they said?
I've checked all the reports
Nothing to worry...
I'll write a tablet for 30 days.
If you take that it will be cured.
Look after her properly.
Otherwise she may have a brain stroke,
she has anxiety issues.
She does not have anxiety issues...
It's Cerebral Aneurysm.
Who said that!?
Which doctor said this!?
Either he has misguided you
or misjudged you.
No doctor,
he's a very big doctor.
Which big doctor is he!?
As a doctor I have 50 years of experience.
Is he even that age!?
It's people like you...
All the doctors' in big hospitals
they give certificates
and make them big doctors!
Look there!
Your wife...
How nicely she's talking to everyone.
Are you sure doctor?
Damn sure!
Look!
Your wife has no problems!
If needed, I'll come to any place and prove it!
Why did you lie!?
I didn't lie.
Cerebral aneurysm is true!
But not for your wife...
Then?
For lawyer Maya!
She only changed all the reports.
I have nothing to do with this!
If you let go of my collar
I will go to the OT
and perform her operation
I will definitely try to save her life!
I forgot to tell you
Lawyer Maya sent me a video
and told me to forward it to you.
I have already forwarded it to you.
You have to watch it!
I'll finish the operation and see you later.
Should I say 'Hi'
or 'Bye' I don't know!
I am now going for operation now
but I don't know.
Anyway,
the reason I'm making this video
is that you two should be fine.
Have you ever thought...
At the start of the marriage,
a husband and wife...
How happy they are?
But eventually...
How that happiness gets ruined?
If you think about it,
you'll find a 1000 reasons.
But the real reason is
both of them!
Actually marriage
is a big change that happens in life.
What begins as 'We' and 'Ours' in
the newly married phase
eventually becomes
'Me' and 'Mine'.
In your case also that is what happened...
My partner is like this
and understanding and accepting it
you have to celebrate it.
Your relationship
was ruined to such an extent that
to understand yourselves
death had to come between you!
Because...
It's only when you face death,
that you understand the value of life.
Life is very short!
Learn to be happy...
To bring out your love for each other,
what disease I had,
I lied that Pooja had it!
If you were hurt,
please forgive me...
Till now
I have never lost a case
but in your case
I really wish to lose.
Please think about it...
Bye!
Look over here!
Don't look at your grandfather!
Hit him! Hit him! Hit him!
Take the apple and hit him!
Hit him!
What Deep!?
Can't you do what I told you!
I told you that I'll do it.
Okay, it's fine.
- Why do you worry? I told you that I'll do it.
- Hit him...
Sweetheart!
My child...
You are not like your grandfather!