They're the new owners of the villa.
- She's Rassimov's heir.
- Professor Rassimov?
Alex...
- ...look, we're here!
- Finally.
I couldn't stand it anymore.
Igor!
Our masters are here!
- No one is here.
- It's better than what I had hoped for.
- Yes.... sure.
- There's Boris.
- Welcome home. Miss Anne, Sir....
- Thank you.
This room belonged to my father.
You'll like it as soon as it is cleaned up.
My room is in the other wing of the house.
It's so beautiful!
Isn't it wonderful, Alex?
A lot of time must have gone by since
someone has come into this room.
- I'm so happy! I feel like a child again!
- I noticed.
Come!
Please.
Alex, look how beautiful.
Boris, we must tidy up everything.
- Unfortunately everything's been abandoned.
It's been years since someone came in here. - Be careful.
One could brake a leg here. Was it absolutely necessary?
- Please, just one moment.
- Yes my dear... as you wish.
This is my father's grave.
This is the only room in the castle which I kept up
in respect to the professor's memory.
We still mourn his loss.
There's a lot of work to be done to fix everything.
- Are you sure about what you want?
- Yes.
It's a big house, Alex, but I was happy here.
We'll like it here. You'll see.
- I like your determination.
- But we'll both have to work at happiness.
A perfect job.
- You can put those books over there.
- Yes, Yes.
This is the silk you ordered.
Alex...
- What do you think of this color?
- Great choice.
- Fine, we'll take this one.
- Thank you.
- We must think about the garden, Boris.
- I already took care of it.
Here's Doctor Walensky, our neighbour.
- Pleased to meet you, Mrs. Nejinsky.
- Thank you.
- I'm glad to see you're among us again.
- I'm happy too.
- Do you plan to settle for good in this house?
- I think so. - Very well.
Before your arrival this house seemed like a menace,
but now that you're here it will be like the end of a bad dream.
- Thank you.
- I'll come back to see you.
- It was a surprise to know of your
intentions to re-open the house. - An occasion to rest.
- That is a good idea. Nothing ever happens here.
- Of course, Inspector.
- We're not in a big city.
- The only one who has something to here is the Doctor.
Fortunately not too much, they're all ancient here.
So yours is like a mission.
I have some properties that allow me
to dedicate myself to my mission as you say.
My husband is a doctor too though he quit a few years ago.
I don't appreciate you treating my guests that way.
I see the lady already feels like a countess.
Seeing that I cannot feel like a wife.
- I'm sorry, dear. You see, we're unhappy again.
- It doesn't matter, dear, it was my fault.
Listen, if we keep acting like this  we'll never save our marriage.
I don't want it to fail. We must help each other.
- I'd like to be sure of it.
- How could you doubt it?
I'll try to make you forgive my moments of jealousy.
(''I, Professor Kowalsky, Medical Doctor,...")
(''...on this day, October 15th, 1875,...'')
(''...leave these notes regarding my experiments,...'')
(''..so that humanity may draw some benefits from my work,...'')
(''..correcting me where I went wrong.'')
(''Courage is sometimes desperation.'')
Your garden has been enriched with the most beautiful flower.
They're so beautiful it would be a pity to pick them.
It would be a greater pity to let them wither.
Why have you moved to this small village?
You'd be successful in the city.
- Maybe I'm looking for something also.
- Also?
Well, we're all looking for something.
- Have you found what you are looking for?
- Maybe I have.
We don't have many distractions but it's so peaceful here.
I'd like to help you Anne both as a doctor and as a friend.
- I can't see you so unhappy.  - You shouldn't think that I'm
unhappy and need a doctor. I don't need anything.
Forgive me, Anne, but I'd be happy to do something for you.
Then be a sincere friend. It would be enough.
- Will you allow me to come visit you?
- We'd be glad.
(''The task I wanted to accomplish through the
construction of the machine,...'')
(''..was to discover the mistery that exists
between life and death.'')
(''The studies I conducted...'')
(''..allowed me to establish the necessity of a force
from an electrically potential source.'')
(''All the instruments called on a reaction of human organs,...")
(''..and the constant presence of electricity.'')
(''This force was also necessary to maintain
the movement, at the right temperature,...'')
(''..of the blood that sustained the bodies of
the subjects spoiled by me.'')
Good morning.
- Your breakfast Miss.
- "Mrs", Boris.  - Excuse me... the habit...
Thank you. Have you seen my husband?
- He might be in the library. He spends most of nights there.
- Yes I know.
- I'm worried about his health.
- He hasn't slept in his bed for several nights now.
There you go, Madam. The biscuits just come out of the oven.
We'll made the for you.
Thank you.
(''The necessary tension must be
between 7,000 and 10,000 Volts.'')
(''Under these values the success of
the experiment would be compromised.'')
(''Once the electric connections have been made...'')
(''..and the mechanical functioning of
the system has been tested,...'')
(''..one will have to calculate the exact quantity
of acid to be introduced in the batteries...'')
(''..so that these will insure the experiment of
the necessary potency.'')
(''At this point the machine will be ready and may be used.")
(''However, creating life in this way is againts nature.'')
(''It's like killing good and freeing evil.'')
I can assure you it's like this, Anne. I'm very worried.
You have no reason to worry, Igor.
Things that are seen from the outside sometimes
appear worse than they really are.
- Don't refuse my help, Anne.
- You can't help me.
Oh, our doctor is here.
Is it a professional visit or a friendly one?
Both.
- Please.
- Thank you.
Is one of our servants sick?
Actually it's not your servants.
- Then who is the patient?
- You two.
Don't exaggerate, Igor.
Except that the doctor can't do much even if his
diagnosis is correct.
- We must recognize a remarkable acuteness in our friend.
- Please, Alex.
Why hide the evidence?
My dear, also our coming here was a consequence.
I just wanted one thing: a little peace to find ourselves.
But this wasn't possible.
I can assure you, despite my will as a doctor and
as a husband.
- From the way you're talking about it, it seems
like a desperate case. - Anyway, my case.
Don't you agree?
I was just worried that the sickness doesn't provoke
incurable wounds for both of you.
- This won't happen.
- Right.
I'll say good-bye then. Madam, Doctor...
- Alex...
- Please, Anne, you must excuse me.
I can't stand intrusions in our intimacy.
I might be exaggerating but...
..but I think it only concerns us.
Don't you agree?
Also, there's something else,...
..I'm sure I'm over my crisis and can prove it to you.
Sasha! Where are you?
- Have you seen the dog?
- I haven't heard him in a while. He must be out in the park.
I'm worried about him.
Sashiska!
Sasha, where are you?
Come here!
Come, Sasha!
Come on, dear, come on!
Sasha!
Alex! Come here! Quick!
- What's going on?
- It's terrible, Alex.
He's dead?
- Be strong... It is dead.
- Oh, no!
He was poisoned.
Kills the good and frees the evil.
Mommy! Mommy! Come play with me! Please!
I have things to do now. Be a good boy.
''Be a good boy. I'm busy. Be a good boy.'' Uff!
Daddy! Daddy! I have to tell you something!
- Hi!
- Hi woman! I'm hungry!
- What do you want?
- Come with me. There's a strange thing over there.
- What?
- Why do ants go all in one row? Look!
Good question. Do you see that hole?
It's the entrance to their home.
They come out of there to look for food
and then bring it back home.
Why don't they eat it right away?
Don't we put food away for the winter?
They're just like us.
Ants have their problems too and they obey to their own laws.
- Don't they ever get mad?
- Why should they? Humans work too and they dont' get mad.
- Go home immediately! - Daddy!
- Don't argue! Go home now!
- Go away!
- Daddy!
What do you want? Go away!!
Daddy!
Daddy! Monster!
Stop for a moment.
- The police station.
- At the end of the road, Madam.
- Have you found anything, Inspector?
- It's not easy to find traces of a vagabond.
- A vagabond?
- Who else could have killed the dog? Evidently just a stranger.
- You must find him.
- We'll find him, don't worry.
They killed them all... They killed them all... Cowards!
An innocent soul! An innocent soul!
It's better if you go home, Madam.
What should I do, Madam?
Do you want to keep waiting?
- Did my husband say where he was going?
- We haven't seen him all day.
- You can go ahead, Boris.
- Yes, Madam.
Forgive me, dear... An interesting book made me forget
about time and I...
I don't know what to say.
It's a shame about the meal.
The meat must have lost most of its flavour.
Why don't you sit down?
You should eat something.
- Please.
- No, thank you. I feel tired. I'd like to rest for a while.
- Do you mind if I go to bed earlier?
- As you wish.
- Do you need anything?
- No, thank you.
- Looking for a man in the woods...
- Is like looking for a needle in a haystack. - It's true!
Oh Yes!
- Yes, kiss me. - Yes, dear.
- Kiss me again. - Yes, dear.
I love you. I love you.
What do you want?
What are you looking for?
No!
No! No!
- Hey! The dogs found something!
- Quick!
- To this side!
- Don't let him go!
- It's the killer!
- Ssh...
- Over here! Quick!
Look for him, Ivan! Look!
It's there, quick! All come here! All come here!
No-one's here.
It's just my size.
- Over here! Quick!
- This way!
- Don't let him escape!
- Come on, you, run! - Hurry up!
- He killed another two!
- Murderer! - This way!
- Hurry up!
- He must not escape!
- He can't have gone far!
- Let's go! - Come on!
- Follow us!
- This way!
Hurry up!
- There he is!
- Come on! - Over there!
- Let's run! Hurry up!
- There he is!
- Ehi?!
- C'mon, let's go!
- Get him! - It's him!
- What did I do? Ehi! - Hurry up!
- Calm down! - He's escaping!
- You go over there and you come with me!
- Yes!
- Over there!
- It's here!
- Get him!  - There he is!
What do you want from me?
Ehi, stop!
Stop!
Let him go!
Let him go! You kill him!
I'm innocent!
Let him go.
- Have you all gone crazy?
- It's a monster! Leave him to us!
You killed him! Beasts!
I hope we found the right man or it would be
a terrible mistake.
- Right! Good morning doctor.
- Good morning judge.
- Inspector, I examined the man that was killed.
- What can you tell us? Could he have been the killer?
For what I could see he was capable of committing
the crimes he was killed for.
For his mental conditions it's too late to examine them.
- But it could have been him.
- There are no elements to establish that.
In any case, no-one in town could have done something similar.
My men checked every single home, every individual suspect.
- I think I can consider the case closed.
- Me too.
I don't think we should keep worrying.
I agree but I feel it's too much of a simple solution.
Infact, not too have any unpleasant surprises,
we decided to continue our surveillance.
Come in.
- You don't like me, right?
- Liking or not liking someone is a luxury I can't afford to have.
Did you hurt yourself?
- Do you need anything, sir?
- No...
- Perhaps the doctor...
- Get out of here.
- Go away!
- Yes sir... Yes sir, sure.
Come in.
Are you going out?
I'm going to the village. Shopping... Visit some friends.
Are you going to see your doctor?
Don't be foolish.
- What did you do to your hand?
- Nothing.
Are you worried about me now?
Your jealousy makes you hateful.
Do you need anything?
No, thanks.
(Vedi il tuo dottore. Vedi il tuo Dottore. Vedi il tuo Dottore.)
(Your jealousy make you hateful. Hateful. Hateful.)
- I didn't hear you knock.
- I didn't.
But we had agreed on it.
What's wrong?
I'm losing myself...
..and you.
We lost each other a long time ago.
How did we get to this point?
Why did we lose each other?
Ann, I love you.
I believe you, Alex.
Then why can't we go back to how we were?
Because one can't forget.
You must give me time to cure my wounds.
To find each other again.
Your absurd jealousy offended me.
- You condemn me like this.
- You wanted it.
- It's late.
- I'm sorry.
- Come on, don't make me wait.
- Don't be impatient.
Undress yourself.
- Come here.
- No.
- Don't you like it?
- You're a little witch.
- I can't resist you! Come here, I want you!
- You're so impatient! Be nice!
Let me do as I wish.
Ehi, what's wrong with you? Go away!
(Anne!)
(Aniuska!)
(She doesn't love you anymore.)
- Can you doubt it?
- (No, no, no. I love you.)
(I love you Ann. I love you so much.)
- I love you.
- I love you too, Igor.
(No, no. It's not true!)
You condemn me like this.
You condemn me.
- You condemn yourself.
- (No, no. I was not me.)
- Only a mad man could have done it.
- (No. I'm not crazy.)
- Sometimes you scare me.
- (No.)
(Don't say it! Don't say it!)
(The book.)
Monster!
- (The book...)
- What do you want?
(No! Not me!)
Daddy!
(No, no!)
(I don't want to! I don't want to! I dont' want to!)
Professor! What's wrong?
You're the killer?!
You won't kill her! I won't allow it!
Speak! Speak, damn you! Speak!
It's your fault! It's your fault!
I didn't want to... I didn't want to.
Why? why?
If you kill good you free evil.
This time we can't let him escape! Let's go!
- I knew it...
- Excuse me...
With the kind of life he was leading sooner or later...
- How did it happen?
- It's the work of a mad man.
One can't explain it otherwise.
The same man who killed before...
Look, he broke the neck with one blow.
A fast death and no-one heard anything.
Do you think it was the same man?
Yes, I'm sure of it. I've sent out all my men to find him.
- This time we can't let him escape.
- Yes, we must find this killer.
Look for him everywhere!
You may go.
- He can't be other than a mad man.
- There's something evil in these acts.
- You're right.
- And you must do everything in your power to catch him.
- Of course, Judge. Good-bye.
- Good Luck - Thanks.
- Hey! Here's one! He's got the face of a criminal!
- Who can be?
- He's the killer! I'm sure of it! - Let's get him!
- He's covered in blood! It must be him!
- What are you saying? What blood?
- Stop! Come with us!
Let me go! I didn't do anything! It was just a chicken!
- Let's hang him!
- What do want to do? It was lost and abandoned!
- Ehi, you, stop! Let him go!
- Please policeman, protect me!
- You, come with me.
Killer!
- I don't know anything! Why?
- Keep walking! - We found this vagabond.
- What's all this confusion?
- He's the killer. He's still dirty with blood.
- Can you explain all that blood?
- It must be from the chicken.
- A chicken? Very well, we'll make sure of it.
- Don't believe him. That's the girl's blood.
We'll examine it immediately. Take him in!
Sir...
..listen to me, I didn't do anything.
I just stole a chicken because I was hungry.
- He's the killer! Let's hang him!
- I'm sincere! - Take him in now!
- Please, I didn't do anything!
- If you're innocent you have nothing to fear.
- Believe me, Sir!
- I've never heard such bullshit!
Believe me! I didn't do anything!
Well?
It's a sort of shock. He just needs some rest.
His immobility frightens me.
He's been like this for more than five days.
He must have fought against Boris killer.
This is the only explanation, Anne.
What I don't understand is...
..what was he doing in my father's lab?
I thought it had been destroyed after the accident.
Your husband must have restored it...
..and after fighting with the killer,
he went there to cure his wounds...
..after that he fainted.
It must have been a terrible experience.
- Will it have any consequences?
- No, I don't think so. He'll just need a few days of rest.
- Don't worry, Anne.
- Thanks, Igor. - My duty.
I'll show you out.
What amazes me is that the machine seems to have worked.
Yes, how is that possible?
Anne, excuse me if I speak to you like this
but I'm afraid for you.
- But there's no more danger now.
- I'm worried.
Is there something you're hiding from me?
There have been no more incidents after the vagabond's arrest.
Or is it not so?
Yes of course, the have been no more murders...
..but, despite everything, I'm not calm.
- Are you worried about me?
- Yes.
Anne, you're aware that I care about you very much.
- I love you.
- I'm tied to someone else.
Yes, Anne, I know...
..but I would like to see you happy. Just that...
There he is, sleeping like a baby.
- He'll be judged in a week. Have you finished the investigation?
- Yes.
- What conclusions have you reached?
- He has no alibi.
He admits of having spent the night in the barn...
..but since we arrested him there have been no more murders.
It wasn't me! Believe me!
I just stole! I didn't kill anyone! It's not true!
I've never heard the accused declare himself guilty.
We won't need his confession.
- Yes, everything points to his guilt.
- Very well.
- I didn't kill anyone!
- That's what you say.
You'll be put on trial and the court will
establish your responsibilities.
- Let's go Inspector.
- Well.
Listen to me! Please! I'm innocent!
Believe me! Believe me...
- How do you feel, dear?
- A little better.
Do you need anything else?
No, you're enough.
Igor told me that the worst is over
and in a few days you'll be as good as new.
He has always been near you. I don't know what
I would have done without his help.
- I'm in debt with out dear Igor.
- He just did what you'd have done in his place.
I had the opportunity to think a lot whule I was sick.
About our life, our relationship...
I've become a burden for you.
Nothing has changed.
Yes, Anne.
I've seen you come and go: an excellent nurse.
A joy for any sick person.
- But I never felt you were really close.
- We've had this discussion before.
But we never ended it.
- And now there's another problem.
- What other problem?
Igor. Our doctor is crazy about you...
and you're not indifferent to it.
- What are you saying, Alex?
- Please, Anne.
At least no lies. No I don't blame you for it.
I still love you, even if I know I've lost you.
You're being foolish! It's not true!
- Don't worry about me, it would be useless.
- But I'm tied to you.
Can you tie the wind? Or imprison the waves?
From now on you can consider yourself free.
It's better for both of us.
Silence! Silence!
This court has been called to judge Fiòdor Polanski
of the terrible crimes he's been charged with.
The violent and savage murders of five of our townspeople.
We've listened to the absurd assertions made...
..by the accused to justify the spots of blood,
an evident proof of his crimes.
But nothing that we've heard has changed the opinion...
that the accused is the only and real responsible
for the charges he's been indicted for.
It's enough to look into his eyes to be convinced of his offense.
- Theodore Polanski!
- Stand up. Hey, stand up.
Do you have anything to say to this court of law
before I pronounce your sentence?
You want to condemn me but I haven't done anything of
what you accuse me of.
- You're making a big mistake.
- We are the ones to judge, not you.
But you want to condemn me for having
killed all those people who I didn't even know.
I didn't kill anyone. I just stole a chicken.
Have pity on me, listen to me. I'm innocent.
- It would be an infamous act to condemn me.
- Be quiet! Impostor! Stop offending this court!
- I'm sorry. I didn't do anything.
- Silence!
God is witness to my innocence.
This court finds you guilty of the murders
you've been accused of...
..I therefore condemn you to hanged by the neck until dead.
The sentence will be carried out as soon as possible.
No! I'm innocent!
May God have pity on your soul.
It wasn't a good idea to come to the village in your conditions.
But i...
..feel better now.
I felt very sorry for that man. He's seemed sincere.
- Yes, I agree. I'm dubious too.
- Why?
There can't be any other explanation.
He's a psychopath. He's guilty.
I looked at him carefully during the trial...
But you didn't recognize him as the man you fought with.
It was very dark that night. I'm not sure.
In any case, it wasn't necessary.
There were already much proof against him.
But what if he was really innocent?
It would be a terrible crime...
..and this nightmare wouldn't be over for us.
It's crazy just to think about it.
Excuse me, but it's late. I have to go, Madam.
Doctor, I wanted to ask you something.
It was just out of curiosity, for a hobby
that I reactivated the machine.
- A very dangerous hobby, I would say.
- You've been careless, Alex.
I wanted to... I wanted to know...
..if you were the one to find me when I fainted in there.
Yes.
You were very sick.
Yes, it's true...
.. I had a... I managed to... tell absurd words?
You were unconscious. Why do you want to know?
Just curious...
You were sick but, luckily, I found you rather quickly
and now you're well again.
I don't remember anything.
No.
Nothing.
- You'l regain your memory.
- No! No, it's not that...
You shouldn't worry about my memory...
So...
It's rather hot tonight...
No, no...
..my memory... You must excuse me...
- Do you want me to take you home?
- No, thank you. I'm fine.
I think he's suffering a lot and I don't know how to help him.
- What can we do, Igor?
- Very little, Anne. He must come out of it on his own.
His behaviour frightens me.
That's why...
..you have to leave him.
I would if he were normal.
- But you can't go on like this.
- I can't look inside myself, Igor.
What can I do?
You're free!
Free to do whatever you want!
I can't kill you twice! No!
- No! - No.
- I don't want to!
Stop it! Damn you! No! No!
No, Never! No!
What can we do, Anne? We have to think of ourselves,
don't you think?
I can't decide like this. I have to wait until he's better.
Don't worry about me. I'll wait if necessary.
I know, Igor. I've never doubted you.
Whatever you decide I'll always love you, Anne.
I'm convinced of your feelings.
- I worry about you being alone.
- Once locked, this house is like a prison.
I'll be back early tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
- I'll keep an eye on the house.
- Good night, Igor. - Good night.
No! Alex!
What do you want? What's happening to you?
I don't understand!
What do you want to do?
Ah! No!
Igor!
No, Alex! No!
No, no! I don't want to! No!
Not like this! Let me go!
No, no! You're killing me like this! No!
Anne!
Open the door! Open up!
Let me go!
Anne! My love! Open the door!
Open the door! Damn you!
No! I don't want to!
Damn you! Open up!
No! Let me go! Let me go, please!
Anne! Open the door!
Igor! Igor!
Anne, my love!
No, no!
My god, No!
I love you , Anne. I love you.
No, no!
Aniuska.
Listen to me.
Don't treat me like this. Don't leave me, please.
There's nothing that can't be solved between us.
Nothing is beyond repair.
What is this?
My God! What happened?
What happened?
Aniuska.
It can't be.
You can't leave me like this.
Aniuska, please my love... You can't abandon me...
Tell me, aniuska, tell me!
What lovers haven't felt the bite of jealousy?
They are proofs of love...
And you know that I love you more than anything, Aniuska.
I can't love any other woman as much as I love you.
No other woman.
My friend... Tell me you love me... Aniuska.
Tell me, Aniuska. Please.
Aniuska, forgive me.
This is how it is, Alex. This is how it is.
- No...
- You wanted her to be all yours and now she is, Alex. She is!
No...
This is not what I wanted. I didn't want to, Aniuska.
Please believe me.
Aniuska...
It wasn't me who wanted all of this, Aniuska.
You must believe me, my love!
Don't punish me with your silence.
I need you, Aniuska! Answer me! Answer me!
Answer me! Don't punish me like this!
Aniuska!
Believe me! No...
Accept the truth, Alex. She's dead!
You killed her! And now you're mine!
You're mine, Alex!
Murderer!
I promise you, my love, I won't allow him to kill again.
I won't allow him!
No! You'll never have me! Never! Never!
Never! You'll never have me!
- Move it! Come on!
- I don't want to!
No! Let me go!
Wait! Stop!
Wait!
God, what did I do wrong?
What did I do wrong?
It's me... It's me you have to kill!
Stop!
Get up.
Wait! Wait!
I'm innocent.
Justice has been made.
Murderers!
- Idiots! It wasn't him! - Be careful, Judge!
- Are you crazy?
- Stop!
- He's innocent!
Forgive me! Forgive me!