Hi, Natalia.
Hi, Lucas. Did you come back?
I'm back because I missed you,
are you leaving now?
I'm not going anywhere.
Why are you looking at me like that?
- I don't have the glow anymore, right?
- Calm down, Lucas.
Tell me! I don't, do I?
Here, it'll look after
you until you return.
Bye, Natalia.
Mother superior is looking for you.
I was informed your
parents had an accident.
They've been looking for you for two days.
An accident?
Your mother died.
They didn't give any more details.
I'm very sorry.
You can leave when you feel ready.
I don't want to leave here, mother.
Natalia, this place is not a hideout.
We will pray for all of you!
Ángela?
- Where is Ángela?
- I'm Mauro, her boyfriend.
Where is she?
Went to deal with the old
lady's ashes at the funeral home.
- And my dad?
- Upstairs, in the attic.
Your sister asked me to come back
tomorrow, and every day from them on.
Please let me know if you
make any modifications.
He's resting now.
I'm very sorry for your mother.
You're the little nun, aren't you?
Dad...
She cut her wrists and
painted all that shit.
He tried to stop her,
but she attacked him.
Ángela.
Who's that woman?
Who knows.
Is that blood?
I don't know, I was at the university.
Why don't you ask him, the family doctor?
Maybe he will answer to you.
He went into shock and
doesn't want to talk.
I'm not coming back to this room.
Wake up, Natalia! Mom didn't
sleep with him anymore.
She was living in the attic!
And now he doesn't want to come out.
All the better, I don't want to see him.
The nurse comes twice a day to clean
his ass, unless you want to do it...
- How can you talk like this?
- Let go of me!
Don't come to criticize me now, OK?
You disappeared for two years.
You went away, and didn't
leave a note or even call.
I have nothing to do with
this house, and you know it.
I could never stand being
here, it makes me sick.
And I left because I have a vocation...
Bullshit! I believed you at first,
but then I realized everything.
You got away...
and left me here alone,
stuck with those two.
What are you talking about?
You saw something too.
Mom tried to tell me,
but she couldn't speak.
In less than two months,
she was completely lost.
- That thing wasn't Alzheimer's.
- What thing?
She looked possessed.
She locked herself up in that room,
and screamed she was being worked on.
Black magic, witchcraft...
Ángela, you're delusional!
It's this stuff you take, look at yourself!
OK, you're right,
stay with your vocation here,
I'm leaving.
Where are you going?
Like dad used to say.
The best kind of charity starts at home.
I swear it, the guy was a freak.
He fucked every living creature.
He has a tremendous energy.
It's unbelievable!
Anyway, I think if you
have a lot of shit in you,
and you're a real son of a bitch,
everything will come back to you.
That German guy was found
dead in the jungle.
No, he wasn't German, Mara.
No, he was Swedish. He was Swedish!
The guy was called Jacek Slawec.
It's true, the news said:
"Foreigner goes into coma in Iquitos
due to Peruvian drug."
- Well, this one was in La Paz.
- In La Paz?
Yes, he wanted the demon inside
of him to be expelled,
and jumped from the bell tower
of a church in San Francisco. Naked.
- Like a poet.
- Naked!
- Hey, you want some?
- No, thank you.
Sure? Come here, sit with us.
- We don't bite.
- Mauro, leave her alone.
Is it true you're a virgin?
Yes, I am a virgin.
What, you're like saving
all of that for God?
What is your problem?
They're my beliefs.
Well, did you know older virgin
women are at risk of getting cancer?
- Really?
- Yes.
No, it's a lie! But I had to say it.
Your beliefs are a bit medieval.
Perhaps we should look at the real reason.
Everybody hides something.
- I have nothing to hide.
- Oh, confidence as a shield.
I think you are hiding something...
That you would love to have some of this.
Leave her alone, dude!
Don't touch her!
What do you think you're doing?
Are you crazy?
Are you out of your mind?
Calm down, Mauro!
Guys! No, guys, no!
Sick bastard!
- Please, stop.
- I'll beat your ass.
Stop it, stop it, calm down, man!
Dude, we're just having a conversation!
Ángela.
What is it? Did the freak
get all horny with the nun,
and want to give her some?
Fuck you. I was leaving anyway.
Are you OK?
I told you it wasn't a good idea
to bring this asshole.
Well, tell that to Ángela.
She thinks the rite can help him.
First we need to know what she needs.
He only comes for the effect of the drug.
- Let me see.
- No, it's fine, thanks.
If you leave it like that,
it will keep bleeding.
Please?
The Immaculate Natalia.
The Virgin Natalia.
Dad is hiding something from us,
that's why he wouldn't talk.
Where are you going, Ángela?
When you left, I got pregnant.
I was dating someone,
I didn't see him again.
That asshole thought he was the father.
And who was it?
I don't know.
I didn't use protection.
I didn't realize until three months later.
I went to the house of a nurse.
Do you know how they do it?
It was awful.
A needle went through my uterus,
and I almost die of internal bleeding.
Why didn't you tell dad?
After my abortion, mom
started to get worse and worse.
She locked herself up in the attic,
and started drawing those uteri.
She didn't want him in there.
He killed her, he did it
so you would come back.
What? You're crazy, Ángela.
I know they're not our parents.
I need to know who I am,
and why the fuck were we stuck
in that house all these years.
We're going to do a rite
with a sacred plant in Tigre.
It's going to show us what
they've been hiding from us.
I need you to come with me, please.
No, Ángela! I'm not following
you on this crazy journey.
- You need to know the truth too.
- The truth is you're avoiding the problem.
We're leaving tomorrow morning.
Papa?
Natalia...
Shh, calm down.
What are you telling your sister, huh?
What do you want?
Do you want her to be castrated like you?
Yeah?
Or are you jealous of her?
Do you want some of this?
You know what I think?
I think you're no saint.
Let see how right I am.
Listen carefully.
If Ángela leaves me,
I swear I will kill her, understand?
It's our secret. OK, I'm leaving.
Dad?
Dad, can you hear me?
Dad, I have to go.
You'll be fine.
I need to look after Ángela.
I'll be back in a few days.
Wait!
Look who's coming with us.
See you there.
Nati? I mean, can I call you Nati?
Your sister is brilliant at University.
Best sophomore student in Psychology.
Yes, until she started dating that moron.
Why do we have to go so far away?
It's a rite, Abel. It has to be done
far from the negative energy of the city.
It's OK. We've already done it,
it's nothing.
Besides, he's no ordinary shaman.
And the place is wonderful.
We met him with Mara about a year ago,
when we were doing our final project.
It's a Peruvian man that cures
with a psychotropic liquid,
made from plants of the Amazon.
The ayahuasca creeper,
I don't know if you've heard of it...
Well, that along with the Chacruna bush,
which is the stuff that
contains the hallucinogen.
But it's a medicine...
Well... I don't know.
The shaman says
it cures the diseases of the soul.
I'm agnostic, no offense, but...
I think it's like a journey
to your subconscious.
To what's suppressed in your memories.
Drugs are an escape.
I didn't see any of the kids
in the meal center doing OK.
But this is no ordinary drug.
"Ayahuasca" means "rope of the dead".
For the indigenous people it is
the rope that allows the spirit
to come out of the body without dying.
Did you ever do drugs?
- You know. Alcohol, cigarettes, coffee
- Where is the spirit if the rope gets cut?
Why would it get cut, Abel?
I don't know, if somebody dies,
if the body is killed during
the journey, during the rite.
Why are you looking at me like that?
I'm not the only one who's fucked up.
Want me to talk about the hospital,
Osvaldo? What about you, "long-sleeved"?
The shaman will take care of that.
Look, look! Incredible!
This belong to some nuns
from early nineteenth century,
and this is only the entry.
The abbey is in the center of the island.
In the 70s they were evicted
and a mental asylum was placed here
But the nuns hold on and from
that shrine, they reported abuse
among patients and abortions.
Then everything was deserted.
- Did you call him?
- He doesn't answer.
That's odd. They should be here already.
So? What do we do?
I don't know. Let's wait a bit.
Let's go to that bench over there.
Let's go, Nati.
Be careful and don't get lost.
- Did you call him?
- He doesn't answer.
Hi, are you in charge of this place?
Did you see some kids earlier?
I dreamt about this place.
It is not a good moon for
what you are going to do up there.
One of you is lying.
Hello?
The Lady of the Unborn.
Sorry. My dad is a deacon
and my brother is a priest.
Too much religion in my family.
I'm allergic.
This is the only place I'm at peace.
We weren't instilled anything.
Despite my vocation,
I'm not even baptized.
That must be the best
way to get into religion.
Why are you with them?
You don't study Psychology.
I used to, but I dropped out.
I, uh...
For completely different reasons to yours,
I'm also a virgin.
But it's not something
I've decided, it's...
I was born with a cerebral paralysis
that destroyed my nervous system.
It's a rare disease, like epilepsy.
And since I can recall, I've been locked up
in my house or under treatments...
And I'm getting worse.
I'm so sorry.
Osvaldo says this plant can help me, I...
I don't think it can...
Well, I was born with something too.
Sometimes I can see a light behind people.
It's something that leaves
me blind for a few minutes.
I never told this to anyone.
A light? Like a glow?
Like that.
But sometimes they're not shiny.
They can be black... Dark...
There you are!
We need to leave, it's getting late.
I'm telling you! I saw a woman.
- How do you explain that?
- No, impossible, Nati.
Those nuns went away 20 years ago.
Can't you see it's all abandoned?
How do we know they're here?
What if they never left the coast?
I don't have a signal! See?
Why didn't you tell me that before?
I need to call home!
Come on, go.
We're getting there.
You see?
- Let me go, get off me!
- You won't let me in?
I don't give a fuck!
Ángela!
Wait, Nati, Nati, Nati!
Wait, Natalia!
Ángela!
What happened?
He's angry and the shaman says
he can't drink.
- Let go of me!
- What are you doing?
- I'm going in, Mauro.
- You're doing shit.
- You're coming with me.
- Leave her alone!
- Fuck off, bitch!
- No, Mauro. Calm down.
- You want me to calm down?
- No, hey!
What are you doing?
- Put that down, Mauro.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Calm down, calm down!
- Shut up, you punk!
Put that down!
What's wrong with you?
You touch her again,
I swear I'll kill you, Mauro!
Dead. Dead.
It's ok now.
Dead.
Easy, Mara.
Look at me. It's ok now.
You little fuck.
You OK?
It's alright.
Yeah.
You know something about dad?
No, I lost signal as soon
as we got into the island.
Thank you for coming.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know.
I feel like I've been in this place before.
The shaman is waiting for you.
We must begin.
Guys! Come on!
Ángela!
Take it.
For what?
I don't know, to look after you.
No need, thanks.
- Everything will be fine.
- Fine?
This is madness. Mara has a gun.
Drugs, weird people,
there's no signal...
Well, look, this is
something of the real world
so you won't get lost.
It's a watch.
Excuse me.
Generally, it goes on the wrist
and it gives you the time.
- Thank you.
- Remember to give it back to me
or I will get lost, OK?
Abel, here. As a token...
If anyone doesn't want to participate,
this is the moment to leave.
Today, you will heal your heart,
your thoughts, the spirit and the body.
Today, you will cleanse your soul.
Hello, Natalia.
We've been waiting for you.
This is the sacred plant,
the entrance to the spiritual world.
Everything that you brought
will be revealed tonight.
Let go of me.
She's my sister.
It's the ayahuasca.
It was him. He abuses me.
Dad! He's behind the closet,
I can see him.
The black mass.
Please help her! It's my sister!
You're not alone in this.
I've seen the prophecy.
Don't be afraid of what
you're about to see.
Goodbye, Natalia.
Papa!
Please!
You have to help me,
they're killing someone!
Help me, please, help!
They're after me.
They tried to perform an abortion,
we need to place her in a higher position!
Quickly, she's having contractions!
Clean towels, hot water!
Scissors, gauze, alcohol!
Hurry, hurry!
Listen to me, listen!
What's your name?
Clara. My name is Clara.
Clara, I'm sister Gregoria.
Relax, relax. I'm a midwife.
- Please, save the baby!
- Yes, yes. We'll take the baby out
and you'll be fine, but you need to help.
No! Kill me! Just save the baby!
They put the devil inside of me.
He wants her for himself!
Clara!
Quickly, tie her up!
Quickly! Hurry!
What is happening, mother?
Tie her up!
Clara, can you listen to me?
Clara! Clara!
I am not Clara, you fucking midwife!
Mother, be careful!
I am the Mahonin that will devoir
her soul and her baby.
I do not recognize you, nun.
No, no! Not with that disgusting veil!
Quickly, quickly! Scissors!
Hurry, hold her legs!
Tight, tight!
I don't want to hurt her.
Hold her legs, hold her legs!
Hold her tight.
I don't want to hurt her.
She is leaving with me, nun!
Clara, you need to help me!
Push your baby out now!
We exorcise you, evil spirit,
in the name of Our Lord, Jesus Christ.
The Holy Cross commands you!
I know you are here.
Fight for your child!
What do we do?
- We cannot do it.
- Yes, we can. Stand her up.
Clara, don't let him take your child away!
Fucking midwife!
The child and the mother
will both die tonight!
And so does your faith!
Clara, fight for your daughter!
Fight for her!
Fight for her! Come on! Push!
Clara, Push, push!
The baby's coming!
I have her, it's a girl!
Thank you, God!
I love you, my daughter!
Please, forgive me!
You fucking nun!
I christen you! I give you light!
I name you, flesh of my flesh!
Ángela.
Ángela!
Ángela?
- Ángela!
- Don't get any closer!
Mara, easy!
It's me, Natalia! Calm down!
He's here! He won't let us out.
Who?
The devil.
I brought her here to leave my dad.
Give me the gun.
- It's my dad's.
- Give me the gun.
- It was in his closet.
- Give it to me.
He left just like that.
Now he's telling me I won't get out
until I finish what I started.
Mara, please!
Shh!
Shut up or I'll rip your
tongue out, you got it?
We need to leave right now!
I didn't do it!
Where is Ángela?
What did you do to her?
- Get off of me! Where is she?
- I don't know where she is.
I heard screaming.
I heard Ángela's voice,
I came in and found it like this.
- I don't know where she is.
- What did you do to him?
Nothing, I didn't do anything!
Shh!
Slut!
Abel.
Natalia.
What happened?
I woke up and I found her like this.
No!
Ángela!
What are we going to do?
He brought us here and won't let us out.
This thing I drank...
It reminded me of who I really am.
He's here.
Inside of me.
That voice I hear since
I was a child isn't mine.
He always called me
cockroach, like my dad.
You need to leave, Natalia!
Oh!
Did you know on this island
they perform evil rites?
I was brought here as a
child to cure my disease.
Where are you going?
"Everything that you brought
will be revealed tonight."
You will feel me, my virgin.
Abel!
You will serve me like your mother did.
I told you I didn't do it.
No!
Son of a bitch!
Let
You killed her!
You killed Ángela, son of a bitch!
- He's not Abel
- Get out!
Son of a bitch!
Let go of me, freak!
Please, call the police.
We need to leave.
He killed everyone.
We're in danger.
Calm down. He can't come in here.
You don't understand, he's gone mad.
He is not mad.
He is possessed.
Powerful men like your father came to this
island to perform rites with the devil.
And they sacrificed the babies.
You're cursed, Natalia.
You survived a satanic rite.
How do you know my name?
This is the place you were baptized.
I wasn't baptized.
Who are you?
It was the devil's touch
what made you so rare.
I knew you would come back.
Natalia, it is time you accept your gift.
Clara, you need to help me!
Push your baby out now!
The child and the mother
will both die tonight!
And so does your faith!
Push, push!
I love you, my daughter!
Please, forgive me!
MAY THE CROSS GUIDE YOU
INTO THE LIGHT, BRAVE WOMAN...
She came to me to save you.
My sister was right.
Why did all of this happen?
The devil brought you here,
and nothing will stop him.
Sooner or later, he will find you again...
And the story will repeat once more.
Why didn't he kill me like the others?
To recover what he lost when you survived.
A baby.
What's the boy's name?
Abel.
Abel is a virgin too.
And that is not a coincidence.
He is also a victim.
- You felt something for him.
- What?
The same forces that trap you
give you the key to escape.
It is a universal law.
Abel is your doom and your salvation,
it is no coincidence that you
are destined to fall in love.
He killed my sister and tried to rape me!
The devil murdered your sister, not Abel.
You have the gift to see this.
Abel!
As soon as the devil appears, we
need to catch him and finish the rite.
What rite?
The one that started with
your christening...
The rite of exorcism.
The devil anticipated the
ceremony and gave you a name.
Our name is our identity, but
it also subdues us if we lose it.
That is why we need you to recover it.
Abel has been possesed since he was born.
The ayahuasca did not wake the demon.
It woke the boy asleep in him.
It made him recover his memory.
The ayahuasca will expel what is
left of the demon out of his body.
Natalia, we have to keep going.
He's here.
I invoke you on the name of light
and life.
And you, mother plant,
old and wise,
along Mother Earh, Pachamama,
and all the elements
that live inside her,
and also echo in me,
so they can give me enough strength...
- What are you doing?
- A boundary between him and us.
He will not be able to go through it
as long as the demon is inside of him.
And this is our circle of protection.
You must not come out when he wakes up.
I beg you to give power to this
salt creature, your creation.
To keep the snake's head
and its evil forces
trapped inside its boundaries.
The exorcism is performed
from the inside to the outside.
The sacred plant will
look for the light in him.
You need to make him drink it.
Quickly!
- Me?
- Yes, this is between the two of you.
Ayahuasca, mother plant, protect the mind,
the heart, the spirit and body
of these inocent souls,
and give them enough strength
to recover their light.
Deliver them from evil.
Hurry, hurry! Get out!
Get out!
I exorcise you, filthy spirit.
Infect diabolic legion,
so you come out and escape from this recint
and this soul created in God's image.
- Let me out, midwife!
- These are God's children.
And I command you to leave them alone.
They carry the mark for me since birth!
And who is claiming?
- You have no power over me, old woman!
- What is your name?
You're told to do it by the Father,
the Son, the Holy Spirit,
and all the forces of nature.
You're told to do it by
the Holy Sign of the Cross,
in virtue of all the mysteries of faith.
Natalia.
It's eating us from the inside.
Please help me!
- What did you give me to drink?
- Holy water.
Do not lie, midwife!
It is holy because it
comes from the sacred plant.
That is why you could not recognize it.
And you think it will harm me.
It is not for you, it is for Abel!
That cockroach does not exist.
He has always been an insect
and today he will be squashed.
But first he will
serve me to fuck this one.
These grimoires will not be of
any use to you, menopausal bitch!
I raped your sister every night
and I devoured her soulless child.
That's not true!
- And I will do the same with yours.
- Do not listen to him!
Your baptism does not exist, demon!
It is God who claims us!
Spit rocks, female!
That's the quaternity
state I'm taking you on!
What is the name that you
gave her, filthy beast?
There is no way you
could expel me, midwife!
I am inside her too!
The connection is inevitable...
I want you to come.
We are going to do this
in front of the midwife.
You are not going to take her!
This is the sacred plant!
The entrance to the spiritual world.
You have your light, Natalia!
The soul is in the eyes.
Abel!
Abel.
Natalia, your light can revert
the evil you suffered.
Abel.
It's very dark in here.
I...
I was able to steal him your name.
Luciferina.
I christen you.
I save you.
Go away!
Leave, now!
"The same forces that trap you
give you the key to escape."
"Abel is your doom and your salvation."
"Why didn't he kill me like the others?"
"To recover what he lost
when you survived."
"A baby."
I'm here.
God is not with us anymore.
We are alone.
Like Adam and Eve in Paradise.
And the serpent.
He has no light.
The cockroach died.
I dreamt about this place.
But this wasn't the dream.
Abel?
Abel!
Abel, look at me!
It's me, Natalia!
I told you the insect died!
He didn't die because he
has the cross I gave him.
You revealed my name,
now I know who I am.
I'm Luciferina, bearer of light.
On that name, I invoke your light!
This doesn't belong to you.
This belongs to the man I love.
Abel.
I know your name, and
by your name I expel you.
Son of the morning,
creator of dawn,
Lord of Light. I expel you, Lucifer.
You are not the bearer of light anymore,
you are just a shadow.
Natalia...
Hello, Natalia.
You need to help me find the other two...
Before they do it.
Do not worry.
You are in good hands.