THE DOG TRICK
Simon here.
Oh, is that the time?
I'm on my way. I'm just going
to watch... I mean, get dressed.
I've just had a shower.
But I am coming!
Right. See you.
Wrtten and directed by
Christian Eklöw & Christopher Panov
Why can't he let it go...
But maybe they'll recognize him.
Recognize who?
It's been about five years!
- Two years.
- OK. Two years since he was in...
Robinson Survivors.
It's me - Survivor-Micke.
- Hey... I'm a star.
- I haven't got time.
I realize this is
a stressed scene for you...
A couple of friends from out of town,
who haven't done Stockholm...
Famous or not,
everyone queues here.
Go to the back.
- But...
- To the back! Now!
Did it do the trick?
No. It makes no odds, famous or not.
Everyone has to queue.
No shit!
- How's things?
- Great.
- Lot of people this evening...
- Shit!
I thought he'd broken my neck.
The frigging idiot!
- When you called him 'Belgian Blue?'
- Whose side are you on?
- Simon, you're on my side, eh?
- Well, I feel...
See? Simon's on my side.
Mario here.
Hi, sweetheart.
I'm at some dump
with Simon and Robinson-Micke.
Love you too. Kisses. Bye.
How long have you two
been going steady?
- Three years.
- Three?
Bloody hell.
- Still in love?
- You bet we are.
Hey, Mario.
Same chick for three years.
- Problems?
- Not that again!
Simon, come by work tomorrow.
I'll buy you lunch.
- Bye. Say hi to Sanna.
- See you, Micke!
Right, Mum's gone.
Now for some booze.
- I'm tired...
- One more beer, Simon.
Simon here.
What d'you fucking think!
I'm getting the beers.
Four?
You're insane!
I'm nearly unbeatable at survival.
- How long since Big Brother?
- You mean Survivor. Since Survivor.
- It wasn't kid's stuff like Brother is.
- I meant Survivor.
A year or two back.
- Were you in the papers?
- Quite a bit, for a while.
Were you?
As a star
you've got to watch your intrepidy.
Too much media
can make you a 2nd class star.
You've got to stay on top...
...if you see what I mean.
- Yes!
- Can we see your Survivor tapes?
- Watch some?
Of course you can watch Survivor!
Micke, please. We've seen it
so many times. Not again.
Well... no.
Forget it, then.
It tickled...
I'd better leave. I've got
to go to workin the morning.
- I enjoyed meeting you.
- Yeah, me too.
Bye, then...
Bye, Emma.
Listen...
lf you want to watch it
I can put it on.
- If you want to.
- I couldn't give a damn.
But if you want to...
No. Okay.
- Simon! Was it you?
- Eh?
- Must you?!
- Ooh, Roblnson!
Just a quickl ook, then.
- Right, I'm off out. Have a good time.
- Thanks. See you.
Welcome to the first new episode
of Survivor.
You viewers will know...
He's absolutely gorgeous.
I mean, he's much better
than the new guy.
- I'll tell you something about him...
- That's you!
You bet.
So you're rearing to go.
And your single possession is:
A condom.
So cool!
But if you want to roll round
in the sand more than once?
Easy-I'll recycle it!
"Recycle! Recycle..."
Did you see that? Oy!
Jesus!
...a winner. In this year's
Survivor series there's a new game...
lf it hadn't been for that bastard...
Let's say it's gonna be muddy.
- Watch Sports Newslastnight?
- No... I was out.
Hammarby could well move up.
- I'll be getting tickets.
- That won't be easy.
But you can always get hold of some.
So Micke got the usual going
after the party, did he?
Yeah.
A bit of heavy kissing?
Rather, not me.
But Micke got the heavies.
The chick Iw as with
was a bit... shy.
She was shy?
Well, it was me that was.
Christ, you know what I'm like!
- I'm like a...
- You needn't get angry with me!
Honestly, Simon...
...Iove- "the Hollywood life," as
you call it- can't be found in a bar.
You're hardly going to find someone
any old how.
But you don't have to go chasing
disco chicks with Micke.
I'm sick of being single.
I want to meet someone, fall in love.
Sooner or later you'Il find someone.
Look at me.
The local grocery, three years ago.
- You forgot your ketchup.
- And?
Otherwise
you'd never have met Sanna.
- Coincidence... It happens.
- But all this waiting!
Did he put Survivor on?
Staff to dell counter, please...
Hi.
- Hi there!
- Hi.
I've only got a little ketchup
and stuff. Could I go first?
- Go ahead.
- Really kind of you.
I... think I forgot my ketchup.
Have you taken it?
Eh?
- My ketchup, you haven't got it?
- Ask him.
Hey, your ketchup!
- In your bag maybe?
- It's at the check-out!
When were you last
really in love with someone?
Let me tell you about "love."
Chicks... they can fall in love.
But guys can't.
Lay off.
I really want to fall in love.
I've never had a real relationship.
I want someone to share everything
with, all the fun, all the rough going.
- Just like Mario.
- It's an illusion.
You were in love with Bella.
You and Mario know what love is...
I wasn't in love with her. I wasn't!
I was too young to know any better.
- Sure...
- Today I know better.
We both know it's just not true.
You just say that
because you got so dumped!
Look at me, how I'm hung!
I can have any girl I want.
It was a stupid teenage love affair!
You were stunned for two years
by a "stupid teenage love affair."
Know what your problem is?
You're in love with love.
- See?
- At least I'm in love with something.
- Yippee!
- Good. That takes care of that.
- Let me thrash you at Tekken.
- I've gotto go...
- I've got a French lecture at 8 a.m.
- Shit...
- Could you lend me my bus fare?
- In my jacket.
- Thanks for the pizza.
- Okay. See you.
- Teenage love affair...
- Have you found my wallet?
Thanks. See you.
Oh, shit! Hi there, Micke!
- You're upset...
- I'm sorry!
...but this isn't what you think.
- Shut up, Pontus!
Micke...
Let's get started:
Sweden v. Yugoslavia. You're
gonna get good 'n'thrashed, Mario!
- Remember last time?
- I've deleted that from my memory!
- Hiya.
- Have you already started?
- No.
- You're Brazil?
- Of course.
Why are your pants down?
- Ask Mario.
- Get your pants off!
- Sorry?
- Did you come on the Tube?
- Yes?
- Get your pants off, then!
What d'you mean?
How many junkies used your seat
before you did?
The filth they leave
gets sucked up into your pants...
- "Sucked up!"
- And then dumped in my new sofa.
Get'em off!
- I'm serious. Get them off!
- You're sick. You need help.
- Please remove your pants!
- No.
- Let's skip the rest.
- It's the final...
Let's go out and have a beer
and then see.
I said I was going to rent a video.
Lay off.
- Simon... Sippy?
- Quit it.
- One beer!
- Quit it!
Fuck! What is it?! No,
I'm not coming. I've got reading to do.
- Goal!
- Re-run! That wasn't fair!
- You needn't get so worked up.
- Don't interrupt, then!
I won't bother talking
to you again, then, ever.
- Hi, guys!
- Hi, Sanna.
- Hello.
- Hello, sweetheart.
- Hi, Simon.
- Mmm.
- What's the score?
- It'll soon be 6-0.
- And... Are you watching? There!
- For Christ's goddam sake!
So frigging bad.
That's enough humiliation for one day.
- Hi, Sanna! - I'm off home.
See you tomorrow.
- Hungry, sweetheart?
- Abit. Shall we make some food?
- How about you?
- No thanks.
Erik Jansson?
- Here.
- That's you then, loud and clear.
Giorgos Astrapopolis?
There!
Dad's a cop, is he?
I mean 'police'-
'Astropo-police'...
Emma Larsson.
- Emma Larsson?
- Here I am.
Simon Svensson.
Simon Svensson?
No? Svensson's a deserter.
- Cross him out, then.
- Here!
You didn't hear me
call your name twice?
- But...
- Or at least once?
Perhaps you think I mumble.
Perhaps all the others
just guessed I'd said their names.
I doubt it.
D-a-n-i-e-l K-a-r-l-s-s-o-n.
K A R L S S O N.
Hi, Micke. It's Simon.
Guess who's at my French course.
Emma!
No kidding!
So what happened?
- Micke.
- Unbelievable!
Micke, lend a frigging hand!
I've gotto go.
Mario called.
We're playing a TV-game at eight.
- Okay?
- Micke! Shit!
See you.
- You can certainly talk on the phone.
- I'm sorry...
...that mymum's in emergency.
Forgive me, if I'm a bit worried
about her health.
Hi.
I feel so frigging afwul.
What's happened?
- I've got such a hell of a problem.
- Come in...
I'd rather stay put. Such a terrible
problem because I can't...
...make my mind up as to which
of these wonderful girls I want.
- Feel at home.
- No, Micke...
Don't spoil it all now.
The redhead's got
a wicked crush on you.
Got any beers?
Little sis been watching
a tear jerker?
Go easy on Simon.
He's never been in love-
- so he escapes
into Hollywood movies.
- No picture in my wallet...
- Don't mumble!
At least I don't have a picture
of my only, old love in my wallet.
Have you been snooping in my wallet?
Shit-face.
You call... just to hear her
on the answering machine...
He got out of bed on the wrong side.
We're off. The party's over.
I'm sick of you always moaning.
- Always?
- Yes, always.
Always belly aching: "Look at Mario...
I wantto be really in love."
Snap out of it!
How can you meet a girl if you're
home watching Pretty Woman?
Right, girls! We're off.
- Simon. I've got this great thing.
- What thing?
I'm talking to Simon.
Simon!
- Don't walk across...!
- I'm only going to say it once.
- Say it, then!
- Right!
This friend of mine
has had a girl problem like yours.
But now he's got so many girls,
he can't make his mind up.
- Do you know why?
- Please. I'm bursting to know.
- Okay... The dogtrick.
- What?
The dogtrick:
Buy a nice pup.
Walk it in the park and the girls'll
all be hanging round your neck.
You mean he's got to buy a dog?
Or borrow a damn dog.
Who cares whose the thing is.
It's fresh, solid girls - none of your
disco chick types.
And how would you know,
Mr. Expert?
Dogs bring out the mother in women.
They see you patting the dog-
- and think: "He'll be sweet
to our children, too, if we have any."
You really believe it works?
It's absolutely nuts.
I don't care.
It says so in 'IIlusionated Science.'
Professors have written articles
and proved it.
- And it worked for your mate?
- His wedding's in a month.
- Oh, that guy with all the girls?
- No. That was Jonas.
- Has it worked for lots of people?
- For everyone! It can't fail.
- Even for you, Simon.
- Why not try it yourself, then?
You know I don't want
the cozy suburban life.
- Right.
- I pick up chicks at bars instead.
Gotcha!
Luck.
Hey... Sanna's sister's just got a dog.
- You are kidding, aren't you?
- Of course I'm kidding.
- What a lovely little dog!
- Isn't it.
- And where are you going?
- To the vet.
Is he not well?
He's going to be run down...
I mean put down.
Oh! Whatever for?
He's a schizophrenic. He thinks he's
a cat, scratches and meaows. Listen!
- Poor thing!
- It's terrible.
- Oh, no! He's having one of his fits.
- Get him away from me!
Run for it! Or he'll bite you!
He's attacking! Run, lady!
Let's go.
- Sorry!
- It's quite all right.
- What a sweet dog!
- Dachshund. It's a dachshund.
Hi. - What it's name?
Fido.
- He seems to like you.
- Yes...
- Love at first sight.
- Yes. Really.
I'm Simon.
Hi. Maria..."Mia."
- Are you going that way?
- What? Yes! I am.
Good. We can walk together.
- Do you live round here?
- No...
Well, yes... not too far off.
- How old's...
- 25.
I meant the dog.
- Oh... er... It's 25 - dog years.
- The same as you, then.
Yes. Same as me!
Unbelievable! Everything was great
between us- it all came together.
- Okay! Didn't think it'd work, Micke.
- My ideas always do.
- When's your next date, then?
- Dunno. I can't call her.
- Don't you dare?
- No. I mean yes...
We never swapped phone numbers.
- What did you say?
- It's so stupid...
...we talked for hours and then...
You meet your dream girl and
you don't swap numbers! You're nuts!
I come along, I put the ball
on the spot and Itie your boot laces-
- but how do you thank me?
By shooting over the bar!
- You're worse than the Yellows!
- Oh thanks. I feel much better now!
Worse than the Yellows
Worse than the Black 'n' Yellows
Mia.
Mia... Wait!
Hell! Mia, wait!
Get a move on!
- To Odenplan...
- No pets.
- He's ill. We're in a hurry!
- No pets in the cab.
Wait!
- Come on!
Wait there. Don't go away.
- Drive towards Odenplan. Hurry!
- What address?
Listen... that bus has got
the girl of my dreams in it. Okay?
I might never see her again.
So, foot down!
Just like in the movies!
Right, we'll tail them like Miami Vice.
I'm Tubbs and you're Crocket.
Great!
Look at this, my friend.
- Beautiful, isn't she!
- Yes, she is.
But she's gone, for good.
- I'm sorry.
- I'll never forgive myself, myfriend.
- Oy!
- It's a crosswalk!
Just drive, please!
My friend's beloved is in that bus.
Thanks for ruining his life!
Thanks a lot!
People have no respect for love
anymore. No respect!
The bus. See it? There!
Letme off here and I'll run.
- Is 100 enough?
- No problem.
Thanks, Tubbs!
What the...!
Shit-the dog!
The French verb
can be compared with to have.
It's conjugation stems
from the basic form: Avolr.
- Sorry...
- Beg pardon?
- I'm sorry I'm late.
- Late? Really?
Perhaps this lot
were 15 minutes early.
Turn that cellphone off!
Or is it my head buzzing?
Where was I?
The basic verb form is av...
Sorry I'm late.
Not to worry.
Would you step forward here, please.
Come on... up front!
- Hi.
- Hello.
- I'm Roffe.
- Mia.
Could you help me read this, loud
and clear for all your mates here?
- Shall I...
- Read it!
'The basic verb form is... '
'... avolr.'
Just read it.
- Don't let me bother you. Just read.
- I can't...
Read louder and clearer
so all your friends can hear you!
- Hard going, was it?
- Yes.
Get the gist?
Be on time in future. Sit
where you want, I'm feeling generous.
For Christ's sake!
Hey, you!
Come here a sec!
It's really weird,
our doing the French course.
I started late. I was fifth reserve...
Why are you doing French?
- I worked in Paris for six months.
- I see.
Then you must be fluent.
Afraid not!
You forget it very quickly.
- There's a soccer game this evening.
- What?
I've got an extra ticket...
if you'd like to come.
I'd love to. How did you get tickets?
They sold out days ago.
- Contacts.
- Okay. Yes, I'd love to.
- 6 p.m. At the south gate?
- Right. Great. See you there.
- Great. Bye.
- Bye.
Thank you.
- Hi. Two for the game, please.
- Sorry. Sold out.
- Eh?
- That guy bought the last ones.
Oh, shit!
Hey, you! You've got to letme
buy your tickets...
- Never. Never, mate!
- Hang on...
...I mean it, I'll give you 500.
- No. I've been waiting for this game.
A thousand-two for a thousand.
Help me out! Please!
1,500.
- 1,500?
- Yes.
- It's a deal. Okay?
- Each!
Three thousand for a soccer game.
You're nuts.
But I told her I had tickets.
- Shit, it's too small, isn'tit?
- Tight's cool.
But I don't look...
...I don't look faggy, do I?
- Well, yes, actually.
- The scarfll have to do, then.
I was joking. You look great.
- No kidding?
- No. Girls like the feminine touch.
Very funny.
Let's get going, then.
Won't you need these?
- Hi. Sorry. Have you been here long?
- No. I've just got here.
- Hi!
- Big crowd.
- Yes, but then it's...
Two Stockholm clubs, yes.
But in any case it'll be... fun.
Cool T-shirt.
So's yours!
Shall we... get in the queue?
Yes, why not?
35 D. Still with me?
Over here!
- Great position!
- Are you're sure this is right?
- Are you sure it's right?
- Yes. 35...
...D.
YELLOWS!
Filth ytackle! Warn 'im!
Christ, how cool!
Christ, howcool! Great!
- Where's Simon?
- Not coming.
- Not coming?
- Doing something with Mia.
- But Wednesday's always boules!
- He's in love.
Leave him be.
You know what it's like.
- I'm not playing with him again.
- Lay off! Let's get going.
Don't be so grumpy.
What's the one with... Debra Winger?
- An Offlcer and a Gentleman.
- Isn't it great?
Wicked! The last scene's brilliant,
everyone doing a standing ovation.
- So wicked!
- A pity it only happens in films.
Yes.
- Don't say you like that film, too!
- A real favorite...
- You can't mean it!
- It's true.
So beautiful...
...with Julia Roberts in the car,
crying, looking out of the window!
And they play 'It MustHave Been
Love'- Roxette. It's so beautiful.
It's so sad...
Though you know from the start
it'll end okay.
- And yet you cry.
- Yes, each time you see it.
I always think the last scene's
when they aren't going to meet...
...but then the real end comes.
- Richard in his white limo...
...with a bouquet.
- Her knight on a white horse...
...that she's dreamt about all her life.
So beautiful.
Go for it!
Are you trying to kill me?
- 40- love. Match point.
- It was out!
- What?
- It was In, partner.
Shit, it was about six inches out.
- You can still see the mark...
- We're 5- 0 down.
Does it matter?
Just play!
If they want to win by cheating,
that's cool. Great fun.
- Leave it now! We're winning!
- Can we play? It's getting cold.
40- love. Match point.
Yes, match point.
Bloody cheat.
Come on, Mario! Think "love all."
This is our point. No problem.
Shit!
- Cool down!
- She fucking aimed atme!
- Bloody unsportsman like!
- Thanks for a very exciting match!
It was an unbellevably fun
game of tennis.
Thanks a lot.
- He's so...
- Why can'the...?
Sorry we're late. Micke's hair needs...
Hiya, Sanna...!
- Hiya.
- Hi.
- Want a ride?
- You bet.
- We're going out tonight. Okay?
- Eh?
No... No, I can't.
We agreed to.
I know, but I've got things to do.
Study and stuff.
Forget it.
Want a ride to the Tube?
- No...
- Walk? -We'll walk.
Thanks anyway.
- What's the problem? Let's go!
- Get going. We'll walk.
- Bye.
- Nice to meet you, Mia.
- Same here.
Mia here.
My mum.
No, he's still believes it all.
Why, has he said something to you?
No? Then what's the fuss!
I amg oing to end it,
but I can't just leave, now!
All right, all right.
I promise this is the very last date.
Yes! Right. Bye.
- What did she say?
- Nothing.
Can we go on watching?
The moment we've all been
waiting for this evening:
The prizes!
I can't hear you... The prizes!
Will the winner be
Miss Rinkeby- SubiZimseck?
- She's great.
- Or Miss Alby- Gabi Bolopa?
Or our own honeybunch,
Miss Kista- Linda Johansson?
One of these ladies is about
to become 'Miss Suburb, 2002.'
The big question: Who has won?
And it says here:
The winner is...
Can you feel the excitement?
The winner is:
Miss Alby!
Dead right!
Wicked!
All right!
- Hiya.
- Hi.
- Is Sanna at home?
- No. She's on night duty.
- Can I sleep here?
- Yeah, but...
...what's happened?
She's there, kissing...
...well she's getting in close
with that idiot from Survivor.
Micke...
About to shove his hairy tongue
down her throat and choke her.
Micke, I know this sounds
a bit like a cliché...
...but you've got to forget her.
- I can't.
I know it's really hard...
...but she has really hurt you.
- Yes.
Wait a sec. Put it this way:
If she was to come back to you,
do you really think it would work?
- Yes.
- Honestly?
Well... yes. I think it would...
Listen to yourself, you're hesitant.
Yes I am.
So what the hell do I do?
- Mario...
- Yes?
Don't mention this to Simon.
You mean about our sleeping head
to tail in my super-narrow bed?
Precisely.
Simon.
Hi.
I can hear who it is!
What's cookin'?
Come here and chill out, then.
Just zap around a bit.
There's someone on the other phone.
I'll come over to your place later.
Bye.
Mia here.
Bonsolr, honey. What are you doing?
Listen, I've spoken to Olivia
at Air France. She said...
Exactly. Which day
would suit you best? Friday?
Yes...
No- I'm about to go out.
Can't we discuss it tomorrow?
Call me around ten.
Yes. Great.
Kisses.
Love you, too.
Right. Bye.
- It's piddling down!
- I can see it is. Hi.
- I bought some food.
- Great. Put it there.
- I'll get you a dry shirt.
- Thanks.
- We need to discuss something.
- Just coming.
Oh, my God...
Well, I thought...
- You're...
- Wonderful.
- Crazy!
- Thanks!
- You did say you were hungry.
- But all this!
- What's in the envelope?
- Open it and see.
- Say...
- Open it!
- Jesus, how great!
- Dlrector's cut.
I can take my sister.
She loves Pretty Woman.
Oh... Okay.
I'm pulling your leg.
Of course I'll see it with you.
Right!
What's the matter?
- She just left.
- And?
- I don't see... Everything was great.
- Didn't she say anything?
Just got up
and said she was sorry.
- Why did she say sorry?
- No idea.
She said: "Sorry, Simon.
I can't explain it," and then... left.
- You've called?
- Answering machine.
- Cell?
- Same there.
- Hell! What can I do?
- You can't do anything about it.
The ball's in her court.
It's up to her to make contact.
Shit!
Always fucking tilting!
Three wonderful weeks...
- Call, put some pressure on.
- Buthow long can I do that for...?
Could that be her?
It could be Mia!
Where the hell's my cellphone?
- Christ, it's her- Mia.
- Answer, then!
Simon here.
Hi.
Whatthe...!
Mia, my battery's running out.
Can you call Micke's cell?
0730649424.
Did you get...?
She's going to ring yours.
That's for me! That's for me!
Take it easy!
Micke's phone. This is Simon.
Hi.
Yes.
Ofcourse.
In an hour?
Bye.
- Did you sort it out?
- I don'tknow.
- Why's Mia's number on your cell?
- Her mates dug Survivor-Micke...
...so I offered to date them.
- I see.
- What did she say?
- She sounded so weird.
- She said we had to talk.
- About what?
- I don't know.
- She didn't say?
I just don't get it.
See you later.
- Wish me good luck.
- Good luck.
Good luck.
High score!
- Where are you off to?
- See the boss. It tilts all the time.
- Hi.
- Has something happened?
- Let's walk a bit.
Simon...
Yes?
I think it's been really fantastic,
meeting you.
But?
But...
...there's something I haven't told you.
What is it? What's happened?
Nothing's happened. Well, yes,
something has happened, or rather...
I don't know how to tell you.
I've got a boyfriend.
What?
It sounds pretty rough,
but it's not rough really.
So it's not rough?
Well what the hell Is it, then?
He's in Paris. I'm not sure
we're still steady. Well we are...
...but we never see each other...
- Why didn't you tell me?
I would have, but I didn't want
to spoil what we had going.
As if you hadn't
spoilt anything now!
Fuck...
Okay...
So what happens now?
What happens now?
I need to think
about what I really want.
Fooling around a bit
until you leave for...
- It wasn't like that!
- What was't like, then?!
I really like you, Simon.
But I need time to think. Okay?
Take all the time you want. I don't
care what the fuck you decide!
Wait a min...
A vodka- cranberry.
A beer, please.
Are you on your own this evening?
Eh?
You ordered just the one beer.
So?
If you'd been with friends or your
boyfriend, you'd have ordered more.
- The beer's for my boyfriend.
- Woops. Is he French?
Goodbye.
- Hi, little sis'!
- God, how I've missed you!
And I've missed you!
- Is that all you've got?
- Thailand next.
- Are you kidding?
- No.
- How long will you be there?
- Six months.
- I can't face it!
- How are you, then?
- I'm fine.
- Are you?
Just a bit hungry.
Let's go home and have something
to eat and a glass ofwine. Okay?
How are you, love?
You're so quiet.
I can see something's up.
I've made such a fool of myself.
Is it that bad?
What's happened? Is it Andrés?
No.
- I've been so damn stupid.
- Oh, sweetheart.
So damn stupid...
It'll be okay.
- Are things serious, you and...?
- Simon.
- How did you meet?
- That's the... problem...
There was this conspiracy-
our meeting had been planned.
- A blind date?
- Well, not really. It was a bit...
I met an old friend at a bar-
- and I bet him I could get this
friend of his to fall in love with me.
So stupid. But I thought
it sounded a bit of a laugh.
I was moving abroad anyway.
But I started seeing this guy and...
- And you fell in love with him.
- Head over heals in love.
So you won't be moving to Paris.
I don'tknow.
No, I'm...
I might as well move there.
Simon hates me now anyway, so...
Could you answer?
Mia's phone. This is Lisa.
Hi, Andrés.
Fine. And you?
No. She's notin.
Oh... Hang on a minute.
B J H, okay.
Yes, I'II tell her.
Bye.
What did he say?
Hey... tell me what he said!
He's booked your flight.
- I've got the number.
- Oh, fuck!
Hi, Simon!
Hello.
Want to see Simon?
There was some blond chick here
but she just split...
For God's sake! Mia!
- Who was that?
- Eh?
No one.
- I put your T-shirt on the bed.
- Thanks.
- Hope we meet again some time.
- You bet.
- See you.
- Bye.
Bye!
Why did she have to turn up
just then?
- Why? Is that a crime?
- But she's already got a guy...
...so she's playing it wrong. Not you!
- Perhaps she came to say...
...that she'd dumped the French guy.
- That's just your imagination.
Forget the whole thing.
Yeah, maybe.
What if I've ruined everything
due to a stupid one-night stand.
All you can do is
find out how she feels about it all.
- That'd be heavy shit.
- But it could hardly make it worse.
Forget her now!
That's my opinion. She's been
lying to you. You deserve better.
The bloody soap stings!
- We've got to talk.
- Well... come in.
- You mustn't let Simon in on all this.
- I've got to!
- Don't. It'll onlym ake things worse.
- Maybe...
...but I can't go on lying.
- Notlie, just say nothing!
- You're not seeing him anymore.
- No?
- But you're moving to Paris!
- Micke, don't you understand?
- I'm in love with Simon.
- In love? Correct me if I'm wrong...
...but, only yesterday,
didn't he screw some other girl?
You've won your 2,000.
So now it's over.
D'you think I'm stupid?
To hell with the bet!
- Who's that?
- It'll be my sister.
- How old is she?
- Shut up!
Just a joke... just fooling.
Simon!
- Why are you here?
- Can I come in?
What?
I think we ought to talk.
Yes, but... can't we...
Can't I come over to your place
this evening? I've got so much...
- Right. About eight?
- Great.
- Is Micke here?
- How come?
That's his jacket!
- Hiya... Simon!
- Hiya, yourself!
- What are you doing here?
- What I'm doing here?
Well, Mia... borrowed one of my CDs.
ACD?
I thought I'd just... pick it up and...
...well, I'll be going.
I'll call you later...
"Meditation."
And when did you start meditating?
- So you didn't know I did?
- Quit it, Micke, for God's sake!
There's something
we've got to tell you, Simon.
That girl with a crush
on Survivor-Micke is nuts...
Shut up, Micke! Let Mia speak.
- I've got to split...
- Stay here, you!
Well? Out with it. Let's have it!
I met Micke down at the bar
and we started talking a bit-
- and he told me about a friend
who'd never fallen in love. That's it.
- Really? And?
- And...
...so... he bet me I couldn't get you
to fall in love with me in two weeks.
- What?
- We bet 2,000.
We set it up like a Hollywood movie.
Right, Micke?
Like a what?
You wanted the Hollywood movie life.
I thought I'd help you.
- You're fucking crazy!
- You weren't meant to find out...
How kind!
So that justifies it all?
It's... just not true!
- It's so crazy!
- I'm really sorry, Simon...
That dogtrick...
Was the whole thing fixed?
Yes, it was.
Yes...
Jesus, Mia, you're so damn...
It's so goddam sick!
And you, Micke...
You can go to hell!
My back's hardly turned
and you're screwing someone else!
- Who's got a boyfriend!
- I don't screw around!
I'm damn glad I screwed her!
She didn't get paid.
Or have you fixed that, too,
Survivor-Micke?
Christ, couldn't you goddam see
I was so in love with you?
Simon here.
Please leave a message.
Hi, Simon, it's me... Mia.
I just want to say I'm very sorry
about what's happened-
- and I'd like to talk to you.
Would you give me a call, so I can
explain? Please let me do that.
I miss you.
Goodbye.
- How could you be so fucking stupid?
- I wanted to help him.
Can't you try and explain to me...
As a friend, how could you
think up something so idiotic-
- without realizing
it might end in disaster?
- Well, I thought she might...
- You didn't think at all, it seems.
- You've got to sort it with Simon.
- Don't you think I've tried?
I've been over there, but he won't
open. He won't answer the phone.
I even went to his college,
but he's not been there for days.
God knows what you can do. But, if
I were Simon, I'd never forgive you.
No...
Hi.
Oh... 2114.
I always thought it was 1421.
I've only been getting
your answering machine.
Perhaps your cell's
been playing up...
Sorry.
I'm sorry... I wanted to help you feel
what it was like to be in love...
...as you never had been.
I thought you might think it was cool.
Listen to me! I'm apologizing!
At least you could...
Hi, Simon. It's me, agaln.
I would really Iike to talk to you,
but you're not at home, or...
...maybe you'd rather not talk to me.
Simon, I'm...
Never mind. I'm at home.
You can call me. Bye.
I might as well move.
Simon'll never forgive me...
Andrés may feel far off, now.
But, once you're in Paris...
Do you honestly believe
I'll think anyless about Simon there?
But you've hurt each other so badly!
It'll be good to get away,
so you can long for each other a bit.
But...
...I don't even know if I'm going. First
I want to sort things out with Simon.
And Andrés?
It's a damn pain. Get it?
- Eh?
- What's the time?!
Mia... Look at this, it's way out!
I'm going...
I am going to Paris.
Bella!
What's happened?
It's over. Well, we've had a fight...
...and Pontus, he's...
- Come inside and have some tea...
...if you like.
Shall I see if the tea's done?
- Do you want a sandwich?
- Yes. But...
No butter
and only one cheese slice.
I haven't forgotten!
I'll see to it.
Hi, it's me.
Did I wake you?
No... It's just that it's a bit late
in the evening.
Good.
No, I was just...
I'll be there on Sunday.
Brilliant. Okay, then. Kisses.
Bye.
Who was it?
Just my mother.
- This is cozy.
- Yeah.
- Excuse me, Micke, but...
- What?
Have you ever thought...
...what it would be like
if it was still you and me?
Well... I have thought about it
on and off.
With Pontus it was never
like it was with you and me.
- Wasn't it?
- No.
- Micke... do you know what I believe?
- This is fate.
- You think so?
We're meant to be together,
you and me.
Yes.
I've missed you so much.
- I've missed you, too.
- Have you?
What do you want?
It doesn't matter where I am,
as I'm not...
What?
Do you really want that?
Ooh!
You're not kidding?
Okay, I'll be there.
You are fantast...
Kisses!
I've gotto go.
It was Pontus. This is crazy...
but he wants to get engaged!
"Hi, Simon,
as you won't talk to me or see me"-
- "this would seem to be
the only way to get through to you."
"I'm really sorry about how it turned
out. It wasn't meant to go this far."
"And I wasn't meant to fall in love
with you, either. But I did."
"When I realized I was falling in love,
I wanted to explain."
"But suddenly it was all too late."
"I could understand
your never forgiving me."
"You will always be in myheart."
"I won't be bothering you again.
Today I'm flying to Paris, to Andrés."
"Just as well,
after all that's happened."
"Forgive me, Simon.
Mia."
"PS Don't be too hard on Micke.
He means well."
Mia.
Mia, it's Simon. Open up!
Mia, please, open the door!
- Hey...
- What?
No point in knocking.
They're not home.
- D'you know where they are?
- Left... for Taiwan.
- When?
- An hour ago... more or less.
Damn!
- Hi... Howmuch to Arlanda Airport?
- I can run you out for 400.
- 400?
- Yup.
Forget it!
- How are you feeling, sweetheart?
- I'm okay.
Mario.
Hiya, Simon... What?
Cool down...
Okay...
Now?
Mia!
Faster, Sanna, please! If we don't
make it... You're only doing 20...
Cool it! We're doing the best we can.
What's that?
- What are you doing?!
- There's a queue, Simon...
I just don't believe this is happening!
For Christ's sake!
Why the hell's she moving to Paris?
Could someone please explain!
- You're sure you'll be okay now?
- Of course I will be.
But things'll be great in Paris!
Yes, I suppose so.
I'll miss you.
I'll come and visit as soon as poss.
Hi. Listen...
Forget that now.
Micke, we can talk later.
When's the next Paris flight?
What! In 15 minutes?
We won't make it.
It's Mia.
Right... of course.
Listen, Simon...
We'll talk later. Right. Bye.
- What are you doing?
- Christ!
Who's that idiot, honking?
Hey, you!
Christ, it's him!
- Hiya, friend!
- You've gotto help me... The airport!
I've gotten minutes.
- Is it the girl?
- Yes.
We'll be there in five minutes.
Jump in!
See you at Arlanda.
I'll explain later.
- Hi, man.
- You're a hero.
Passport and boarding card, please.
- Bon voyage.
- Thanks.
They're chasing us.
The police.
Hell! Could've known!
- Stop, then.
- Are you crazy?
- It's the cops, for God's sake!
- But she'll be gone if we stop!
- Remember my Vinnie?
- Eh?
- The girl in the photo.
- Yes.
She vanished, because the cops
stopped us. But they won't this time!
- They're getting closer.
- Cool it. Just you wait!
- Move! Run!
- But the police...
Forget it. I'll deal with it.
- I'll never forget this, Tubbs.
- Give her my best!
Damn!
- Information.
- Sorry?
- Where's Information?
- Down there.
Hi. Can I help you?
- I'm sorry?
- Gate 2.
- You want Gate 2?
- Gate 2. Quick!
Down to the end, then right.
Don't mention it.
Hi! Can I help you?
Well... Hi, there...
..."Veronica C."
Ready for me?
- What's the time?
- 1.25 p.m.
Really? I thought I'd be on a flight
to Geneva at 1.25 p.m.
So sorry. There's a one-hour delay.
It's fantastic for me to know
you're so sorry. Do you follow?
Knowing you're sorry will get me to
Geneva much faster. Or am I wrong?
- Get in the queue!
- Slow down! Wai there!
- Passport and boarding car...
- My girl's waiting in there.
Passport and boarding card.
Please!
Micke, baggage handling, Survivor-
Micke... Open the door for God's sake!
Showme your passport and card,
or go to the back of the queue.
- You're a frigging idiot!
- Just doing my job.
- Straighten your tie.
- Next.
- Hiya!
- Hiya, mate.
- Is this the Paris load?
- Yup.
- Hi!
- Hi, there!
I found this little guy over there...
...crying.
He must have lost his parents.
Poor fellow.
Lost your mummy and daddy?
Have you?
- No...
- Yes. Right. They must be around.
Can you look after him?
I've got my flight.
- Gate 2?
- Right.
Come round.
There now...
What the...!
- Sorry. I've gotto do this.
- Don't close... Open it! It's a break-in!
Can't anyone help? Security,
come here! God, you take your time!
- What is it?
- Break-in!
- He works here?
- No!
Come out of there!
Mia! It's Simon. Are you listening?
I've got somethingto say.
I was drunk.
Itwas so stupid, so idiotic.
What in God's name's he up to?
Don't leave because of that, Mia!
I know I haven't answered
when you've called-
- but I've needed time.
I'm still angry with you and Micke,
and you are with me.
Forget it all, Mia!
Because I'm deeply in love with you.
I realize now it's you I want,
only you.
So, Mia, if you can hear me...
Don't get on that plane!
Paris isn't for you, I promise you.
We've got to give love a chance,
you and me.
Mia...
...I love you.
I want to be with you.
Hollywood movies aren't like this,
they don'thave unhappy endings.
Great stuff, mate! Great stuff.
- Thanks.
- You'll have to come with me.
What are you up to?
Have you gone nuts?
I'll call Micke,
so he can sort it out.
Are you okay?
Simon!
Go on, feller!
It's cool.
- You came!
- Of course I did!
- How did you know I was here?
- I got your letter.
What d'you mean? What...?
What is it?
Great, man!
Aren't you Survivor-Micke?
- Yes. That's me.
- Could I have your autograph?
I should think so.
- What's your name?
- Emma.
There you are, Emma.
- Thanks.
- That's okay. Emma!
You can have this, too,
seeing as I like you.
- There you go.
- Thanks. Great!
Bye!
Mario doesn't know
about our little bet, eh?