REQUIEM FOR A VIRGIN KING
PART l
THE CURSE
l am posh Lola
the favourite of the season
I have a pianola
at home in my salon
I proclaim the curse of Lola Montez,
the cast-off mistress of Ludwig l,
the grandfather.
Cursing all that follows.
The incest of the parents,
Max of Bavaria
and Maria of Hohenzollern.
The birth of the second Ludwig,
the last king of Bavaria.
in the grip of royal madness,
furor paranoicus bavariae.
The House of Prussia will come
and annex Bavaria.
Found a German empire.
Curse!
A new era will come.
And with it
the proletarian breed.
l hear the proletarian masses.
l see
the fall of the Wittelsbachs.
King Ludwig
has no chance.
l proclaim his eternal life
in the memory of the people.
l see his torment!
l see his bliss in another way.
He will return in our dreams!
The finish: Environmental pollution!
- Pressure to produce!
Crimes against nature!
Over the span of years
the sore ate away the forest.
The leaves yellowed
and the tree withered away,
sadly the spring dried up.
Cursed be his descendants too.
IN THE LATTER YEARS OF HIS LIFE
LUDWIG II HAD HIMSELF WASHED AND
DRESSED WHEN HE ROSE IN THE EVENING.
HE LIVED AT NIGHT.
ON A NIGHT LIKE THIS HE SAW HIS LIFE
AS THE LIFE OF ONE NIGHT
HOW BARON HIRSCHBERG
FALLS INTO DISFAVOUR
De Varicourt,
a lovely name.
Cabinet Secretary Eisenhart
requests an audience.
Leave me be.
l can't stand
the sight of his stupid face any more.
Whoever looks with love upon
the night of death,
whoever is
entrusted with her darkest secrets,
the lies of daytime,
honour and glory,
power and riches,
no matter how dazzling,
are all blown away
like the vain dust of suns!
in the glare of the treacherous day
he has but one desire.
That slut Bulyowski can go to hell.
Hirschberg,
I'll make you cabinet secretary.
No, you are too pretty
to be cabinet secretary.
Then I'd have to annoy you.
Shall l make you a count?
How about a villa
like Wagner or Hornig?
A saddle-horse would be enough.
And a transfer
to the Foreign Office.
l have no possessions.
What belongs to me
belongs to everyone.
You belong to me.
l am the King;
whatever l like is right and proper.
Every subject must submit
to his Sovereign's will.
You must be mine.
Let them stay.
l never wish to see him again.
NEWS FROM THE COURT HAIRDRESSER,
HOPPE
Without your work,
l cannot enjoy my breakfast.
What's new, Hoppe?
People say
that Madame Bulyowski
did not reciprocate your affection
when you laid
your head on her shoulder and
asked her to stroke your hair.
Apparently
at night
you sobbed the name
of Madame Bulyowski.
What do they say about my fiancée,
Duchess Sophie and me?
A handsome couple.
A handsome couple
and that Wagner received her.
He is clever,
only he doesn't know
that l won't marry her.
Go on.
- Malvine Schnorr von Carolsfeld insulted
Corsima von Bülow because of her
liaison with Richard Wagner.
The ''Rhine Maidens''
were referred to
as aquarium whores
in the paper.
There'll be a libel suit.
Count Dürckheim
has been posted to the provinces;
a duel with His Highness
Prince Arnulf
over some woman.
Tell Prince Ludwig
not to keep pushing himself forward.
And Prince Luitpold shouldn't address me
without being spoken to first.
l am the King.
l still am.
I’ll dismiss
all my father's old servants.
l want to see only young faces.
THE KING LOVES DE VARICOURT
AND IS DISAPPOINTED IN HIM
Majesty,
the people's 12 oldest men are ready.
The ritual of feet washing
can now begin.
lf the King can ride
for 8 to 10 hours
without damaging his health,
he can also
spend a few days with his army.
The princes should
lower their heads more.
The Prussian State rewards Bismarck
with a million marks
for every war he wins.
The loveliest death would be
to die for you.
lf only this could soon come to pass.
A death more desirable than anything
this world can offer.
Varicourt,
you sleep
while your King is talking to you?
Take care of him.
l have acted my role as King badly.
LET'S GO ON AND PLAY GAMES
WITH THURN AND TAXIS
A sofa for the decrepit Hartschier.
The poor man can't stand for very long.
Yes, a sofa.
Bismarck is delighted
with his war with Austria;
he can at last
kick her out of Germany.
I'm going to the Rose Island.
There is no telephone there.
To play games
with Thurn and Taxis.
We've been successful.
Our troops are in Thuringia,
and have already consumed
1,500 Prussian beers.
l can't stand the sight of these
cropped heads any more.
Let's go.
Let us listen
to their kingly babble.
Remove the sofa.
AUDIENCE
What are Gudden,
Holnstein and Lutz doing?
Gudden,
a German intellectual.
Power is nothing,
but the power of seduction is, eh?
Quite correct, Majesty.
All l will say
is that Wagner's time is coming.
Lutz,
l hear that your intrigues
have kept Wagner out,
with the help of the press.
But Munich's still become
the leading musical centre today,
with the help of the press.
Let's make him a minister,
otherwise he won't be afraid of me
and won't be able to depose me.
Holnstein,
we know each other well.
Allow me to introduce
my head stableman.
The master of my 200 horses.
My bosom friend
and betrayer.
He'll be my guardian.
The son of a bitch,
a faux pas
of my great-grandfather Wittelsbach.
It stays in the family.
My successors won't have to
worry about such things.
l shan't leave any children,
apart from my castles, of course.
So, what are we going to do today?
Bismarck said
that after a successful war
there's only
power and self-interest for him.
King Ludwig is a dreamer,
who does he have? What does he want?
according to Bismarck from Prussia.
Don't come so close,
l have bad teeth.
Bismarck asks
how much is required?
He refers to the distribution
of the Guelph treasure
if the Bavarian King offers
the King of Prussia the imperial crown.
Stay there
and look into the water
till it hurts your eyes.
They'll say l am mad
because of this as well.
It's an exercise,
looking into the water facing the sun.
l want to torment you.
Gentlemen,
who's going to
break into Rothschild's
in Paris, Frankfurt or Stuttgart?
Nobody?
All right,
but we do need money.
My teeth are bad.
l know you can't understand me
because I’m mumbling,
and because you are too far away.
Let the Prussian heir
to the throne be punished.
He could be captured
after his vacation in Montone.
He could be blinded and tortured.
But take care
that he doesn't die too quickly.
But nobody will do it.
l, the mock King,
want it that way.
Count Dürckheim,
you have
a duel of honour with Prince Arnulf.
You will be promoted
and from today
be my adjutant.
Until the end,
do you understand?
Majesty,
l beg of you,
you must be careful of Holnstein.
He is very controversial.
Bismarck drinks nothing
but his wines,
and his trusty Great Dane, Sulte,
is a gift from Holnstein.
Let him be.
Every court needs its intrigues.
It’s always been so.
Lutz,
how much beer do you drink?
Two half-litres a day.
Disgusting.
l hate Munich.
l hate this city!
I’m a very conservative person.
You take it into account
with every sex offender,
predisposition and childhood, l mean.
l love the mountains,
the forest air, horses,
Richard Wagner,
Edgar Allan Poe.
l love the night,
the mystic and inexplicable
and believe in the immortality of the soul.
I’m against the pollution
of the countryside by English industry,
against so-called progress,
against the Prussian Empire,
against nationalism,
against socialism
and against mass meetings of people.
We'll now go out riding.
Tell the princes
to stop shooting in my forests.
l want some peace.
His eyes are incredibly beautiful.
His madness to come
shines out of them.
THE BASTARD COUNT HOLNSTEIN
SINGS THE SONG OF BETRAYAL
l loved kissing women
l didn’t ask permission
''Take them,''
l thought to myself
l am one of the King's cast-off lovers.
And that's why
he needs me as a guardian.
l will be his guardian.
That's how I’ll get my revenge.
You must tempt him to build castles,
to run into debt.
Every king falls for that.
He believes in
his acquired privileges.
And then the democratic,
legal
trap will spring.
And he eats out of your hands,
whatever you want.
LEGENDS
in the mountains freedom dwells,
in the mountains there is beauty,
Where King Ludwig’s
castles tower
Much too soon he had to quit
The dearest place of all,
Neuschwanstein,
proud fortress,
you were the King’s most precious jewel
Greetings, friends.
The King!
Still at work so late?
300 florins
for my peasants
and a golden watch to boot.
We'll never forget this!
We will be
loyal to you forever.
Till death.
They are my subjects.
They are loyal to me.
And the American widows,
thanks to Mark Twain.
He spoke of me favourably.
Farewell, friends.
With bandages and chloroform
They came in person
And you had to leave your castle,
Which you will never climb again
MORBID FEARS:
THE TALE OF ANNA VOGEL, THE PEASANT
The first time l saw him
was in the dead of night.
l can't have been more than eight.
l was dragged out of my bed
without being told
why l had been wakened.
It must have been
something very special.
There was tremendous excitement
throughout the whole house.
As nobody bothered about me,
l sat by the window
and watched the torchlight
flickering among the fir trees
and lighting up my room
and casting huge shadows
on the walls.
Suddenly my mother came in
and said:
''Be a good girl,
the King is driving past.''
It was really him
in his gilded sledge
drawn by six horses.
A moment later
the procession halted.
His arrival cast
such a glow
that our home was illuminated
like the altar of the Blessed Virgin.
Our dogs howled and barked.
An outrider
banged on our door and shouted:
''A glass of water for His Majesty!''
My mother looked for a glass
but couldn't find one
suitable for the King.
So she took a coffee cup
with a rose pattern
which seemed close
to being worthy of His Majesty.
She ran to the well,
filled a carafe
and carried everything
to the sledge.
l was alone in the room,
enchanted by the
fantastic sight.
The King used to travel in a sledge
from the era of Louis XIV.
Suddenly l made a decision
and walked down the stairs
in my nightgown,
with bare feet on the cold floor;
it had been snowing
both day and night.
l was entranced
as l stood in front of him.
For me he was an archangel.
l only heard the stamping of the steeds,
the tinkling of their silver harnesses.
The bells on the horses' harnesses
sounded like church bells.
The foam-covered beasts
shook their manes.
Atop their heads
plumes of white feathers danced.
l was intoxicated
by that magnificent sight.
Suddenly l felt dizzy
and when l came to myself again,
l found myself
next to the King,
who looked at me with his big blue eyes,
like in a fairy-tale.
He was still holding the funny cup.
He made me drink some water
and kissed me with no more ado.
Then he got out
and asked to see the house.
Why is It that a woman
should have no love affairs?
No love affairs
no love affairs
lf she's pretty they will say
she's bound to have one anyway,
she's bound to have one anyway
lf not it'd be a shame
Let the human race fear the gods!
Their eternal hands
hold firm the power,
which they can
draw on as they like.
Let him whom they raise up
be doubly afraid!
On
rocks and clouds
seats are prepared around
tables of gold.
Battistella.
Battistella?
A robber and murderer.
His appeal lies before the King.
A dangerous type,
definitely should be executed.
My dear Lutz,
if l know Ludwig
he will not sign.
He is against
any form of bloodshed.
l can't...
l can't stand it any longer,
being stared at
by thousands of people.
Asking people questions
that don't interest me,
and hearing answers
that have nothing to do with me.
No, no,
l can no longer leave my solitude.
Sometimes
when I've read until l am tired
and all is quiet
l need to hear a human voice.
Then l send
for a lackey or a stable boy
to talk to me
about his family and his home.
Otherwise I’d lose
the habit of speech.
l often send them home
so that they can tell me afterwards
what the other life outside is like.
Descend upon us / O night of love
Give forgetfulness / That I might live.
O sink down
Night of love
Give forgetfulness
That I might live.
Take me up
Into your bosom,
Release me from the world!
Extinguished now the last glimmers
What we thought
What we imagined
All thought
All remembering
The glorious presentiment
of sacred twilight
extinguishes imagined errors...
world-redeeming.
In our bosom...
The young King
is splendid company.
l have never experienced
such an urge to learn
and such eagerness to live.
At last a love affair
that will not entail torments.
Could l give up women completely?
A glance at his portrait helps me too.
What a delightful boy.
Now he is everything to me;
woman, child, the world.
TO RICHARD WAGNER:
l SHALL RAISE YOU
ABOVE WORLDLY TOIL, MY BELOVED,
l SHALL NEVER LEAVE YOU TILL MY DEATH.
LUDWIG
This ''Tristan'' will be dreadful.
They'll ban the opera
unless a bad performance
makes a parody of it all.
... unless a bad performance
Only a mediocre performance can save me.
Good performances drive people crazy.
It’s the only way.
To think that this is what I’ve come to.
They say that after the performance...
They say that
after the performance of ''Tristan''
he stopped the night train,
got out
and walked through the woods
and continued the journey
in the locomotive
sitting with the stoker
in front of the open firebox.
Where else
could l find such a royal audience?
He ordered Cabinet Secretary Pfistermeister
to find me and bring me to him.
As the first official act of his government,
he ordered Cabinet Secretary Pfistermeister
to find me and bring me to him.
Even though
l was an unsuccessful composer
and a revolutionary
wanted by the police.
He was 18 at the time.
A king
with royal presents for an artist
who from now on
was to place his work at the King's service.
Unique,
saintly being,
what delight,
what perfection!
So overcome by rapture!
To drown,
to sink,
unconscious,
ineffable delight.
Divine work.
ELISABETH, THE EMPRESS OF AUSTRIA,
PRAYS FOR LUDWIG:
BEWARE, BEWARE,
SOON THE NIGHT WILL FLEE
The horizon grows ever darker,
the glaring light of day
agonizes unspeakably.
Joyfully l give up crown and glory.
Often l am shaken
with feverish anger
and turn away
from an outside world full of wrath.
Isn't that understandable?
Perhaps I’ll
make my peace with the world
when all of my ideals,
when their sacred fire
which l carefully feed, has perished.
May that never be.
l wish to remain a perpetual mystery
to myself and others.
We two,
we can do what we like.
Poor King Ludwig.
Perhaps l ought to marry?
Or go to war
under Otto von Bismarck?
A vassal for the cousins of Prussia?
Or should l become a democrat,
l, the King?
Sometimes l think
of Sitting Bull
and General Custer
at Little Big Horn.
Sitting Bull
had no chance either against
the progress of the Christian religion,
as his people were massacred.
But he had
the sympathy due to a hero
in his defeat by railway,
telephone and alcohol.
l now take photographs.
Also l want
to build a flying machine
that can fly me over the Alps.
That will also
get me certified as insane later.
A flying peacock throne...
l have given Wilhelm Bauer,
the inventor of the submarine,
a commission.
He is underestimated.
With boats like that
we can defy the Prussian fleet;
we can prevent the world war
that will greatly be due to
the German fleet's arrogance.
Shakespeare's fools, too,
were the only sensible people.
Tonight,
l dragged my father from his tomb.
Tonight, l slapped my father.
Tonight,
l threw him down the stairs.
l broke a carafe
over my mother's head!
Tonight,
l kicked my mother.
l kicked her in the breasts!
On a night like this,
l kicked my mother in the breasts.
my mother spoiled
a performance of ''Lohengrin''
with her chatter.
Now my brother Otto is of age,
l can retire to Switzerland,
to Wagner.
They can tell the public
I’ve gone out of my mind.
MINISTER VON DER PFORTEN TO LUDWIG l
Richard Wagner
received 4,000 florins,
and then 8,000.
Also, to settle his debts;
another 16,000
and then another 40,000.
Also a villa.
70,000 florins as costs for ''Tristan,''
29,000 florins
for ''Tannhäuser'' and ''Lohengrin,''
''Mastersingers'' 45,800 florins,
''Valkyries''
41,500 florins.
It’s for art.
No, for operas
nobody wants to see.
It is not good music.
The people don't like this music.
They want to see the King.
And what does the King do?
He takes trips to the mountains,
organizes separate theatre performances
just for him.
And he's not even musical.
It is incestuous music,
Wagner music.
Scandalous
and amoral.
My grandson pays it
out of his private purse.
The salary of a high court judge
is 2,800 florins.
That of a teacher,
2,200 florins.
That of an assistant secretary,
3,900 florins a year.
Take into account
the recent rise in the price of beer
and the financial debacle
after the Spitzeder scandal.
But it's for art.
Art is the serenest form of existence.
As Brecht says,
or was it Goethe?
THE SUN KING OF BAVARIA:
THE VIRGIN KING
l, King
by the grace of God.
The impossibility of actually falling
is hereby ruled out.
lf there are more kings like this,
soon there won't be any at all.
Am l right?
Of all the lovely women here
my mother is the loveliest.
She receives
what l have yet to give her:
love.
But she doesn't treat me like a king.
l don't like it!
l don't like it.
Hornig got married.
Majesty?
Losing him
is worse than
the whole Franco-Prussian War.
DINER A QUATRE
OR PLEASURE IS A PLEASURE
Do you know
the valleys of the Hindu Kush?
Afghanistan?
Wagner should write
his most magnificent opera
on an oriental subject.
India and Buddhism
have for me something indescribably attractive
which evokes pleasure and longing.
Intoxication would be complete.
Pleasure
comes from pleasure
and pleasure's
a pleasure.
WAXWORKS
Richard Wagner'll have to go.
He disturbs our peace.
lf that's the future of art,
we can do without it.
l have acquired
some property on Lake Starnberg,
with his help,
and I’m interested in
building roads along the lake.
Impossible as long as he's king.
The industrialization of Bavaria
is on its way.
l need a branch in Berlin
and some Prussian shareholders
under cheap domestic conditions.
The forest will have to go.
We need a modern Bavaria.
Trees mean too many dead leaves.
Besides, the King has the habit of greeting
trees and stone columns like people.
He chats with invisible people,
calling them
Marie Antoinette and Cousin Louis.
An art exhibition for Munich
and he refuses
because he wants
his peace and quiet.
Exhibitions attract
international royalty
and he has to retreat to the mountains
to avoid receiving them. Crazy.
Rabbit and dog exhibitions, yes,
but not art like Kaulbach and Piloty.
I’m a good monarchist
but l love art, too.
He has no manners.
We need progress,
our Bavaria,
for roads, for automobiles,
international art,
connection with the Empire,
investments.
l am a man of the people.
lf you do that, gentlemen,
do you even know
what this will mean for Bavaria?
This death,
it must look like a struggle
with Prof. Gudden
who had tried to hold him back.
Get hold of a boat
and four sticks.
Attach the two men's shoes
to the ends
so that you can,
from inside the boat
so as not to leave your own imprints,
leave imprints
of a struggle in the sand.
They will lead to
the spot in the lake
that you choose to be
the place where His Majesty
breathed his last.
His Majesty's damaged clothing
must be recovered.
The body must be
dressed in undamaged clothes.
There must be no witnesses.
l hope l have made myself clear.
Police records
must be confiscated.
We will seize
His Majesty's personal archives.
Do not forget that no records,
no advice,
nothing from his architects,
no records at all
that could possibly suggest
any serious work of Ludwig's
must be made known to the public.
This would destroy his image
as a king of kitsch.
Ludwig can only remain harmless
as a kitsch king.
And most important of all,
don't make a martyr of him.
Incidentally,
l won't appear at all.
l have not said anything.
l have not heard anything.
As Prince Regent
in charge of succession,
l could easily be suspect.
l will withdraw
from this twilight of hell
and be happy
in the twilight of the gods
in the solitude of the mountains.
Far from the day,
the hated enemy.
Far from the daylight's torrid shine.
Far from the profane world of every day,
from the hopeless politics
which smothers me
and suffocates all poetry.
LUDWIG IN THE STUDIO
OF THE SCULPTRESS ELISABETH NEY
Don't make
the horns of the sledge too high
or branches will catch on them.
Carve cherubs on these horns
that can hold the crown, sceptre,
and the other royal regalia,
and if at all possible,
the King's robes.
The nymphs drawn on the front
shouldn't be holding the lamps,
or be the colours of flowers.
l want elegant herding scenes
on the sides of the sledge.
Mr. Hofrat should bring
all the copper engravings
in the style of Boucher,
Baudoin and...
Fragonard with him
to the next meeting.
The drapes hanging from the sledge
shouldn't be so pointed.
They should be more like scarves
and be attached like those
at the Residence Theatre.
The triton at the end of the sledge
is too far away from the body.
The sledge must
be kept as short as possible.
The seat held up by the triton is too high.
It'll detract from the rest.
It is not necessary
for the coachman to have a seat.
A board to stand on would be sufficient.
Send 42,000 florins
to Johann Jakob Mayr.
Words cannot describe my pain.
The old song resounds in my ears.
l forgot it
and forgot it without regret,
the song
which the Fates sang with horror
when Tantalus fell
from his golden throne:
They suffered
with their noble friend;
grim were their hearts
and wild their song.
in our youth the nurse sang it to me
and my brothers and sisters.
''Let the human race fear the gods.
Their eternal hands
hold firm the power,
which they can
draw on as they like.
Let him whom they raise up
be doubly afraid!
On rocks and clouds
seats are prepared
around tables of gold.''
Lola Montez cursed me.
She hated the face of my father.
l will leave no progeny.
She is now
being exhibited in a circus
as the King of Bavaria's mistress.
''When discord arises,
the guests, shamed and insulted,
plunge into depths of darkness
and fettered in gloom
await in vain
their just judgement.
But the others remain
at their eternal feasts
at tables of gold.
They stride from peak to peak:
From yawning chasms they breathe
the sulphurous breath of the Titans,
rising in light clouds
like sacrificial smoke.
The rulers
turn their indulgent gaze
away from whole families
to avoid seeing in their descendants
the once mutely loved traits
of their forbears.''
Do you know what rape is?
Or a bastard son?
Women are angels with wings,
aren't they?
But you can dream of them as such.
Recite Iphigenia.
''When the heavenly powers
assign to a mortal
a life full of changes
and prepare for him
changes from joy to sorrow
and sorrow to joy,
a deeply shattering experience:
Then they find for him
near the town
or on a distant shore
to help him
in moments of distress
a calm and faithful friend.''
BROTHER OTTO
AND PROF. GUDDEN'S MEDICAL NURSES
I’m Albert,
the court photographer.
l have a studio
and over 200 employees.
l am going to photograph the King
from his childhood to his deathbed.
Attention!
Thanks.
Otto,
what's left
of your cheap pleasures:
The ballet, hunting, the army?
Only evil memories torture you.
They will declare me insane
and make you king
in your lunatic asylum
so that Uncle Luitpold can reign,
just as the law dictates,
and call it logic
since you have already absconded.
Alas,
Shakespeare is no more.
l live in vain.
END OF PART 1