BULGARIAN NATIONAL CINEMATHEQUE
PRESENTS
FEATURE FILM STUDIO 1958
Apostol Karamitev
Ginka Stancheva
Lyubomir Bobchevski
Elena Khranova
Pencho Petrov
Georgi Radanov
Nadezhda Vakavchieva
Georgi Karev
Petko Karlukovski
Magda Kolchakova
Encho Tagarov
Georgi Partzalev
Lyubomir Bodurov
Leo Conforti
Georgiy Kaloyanchev, and
again Apostol Karamitev in
FAVOURITE NO.13
script by
Lyuben Popov and Vladimir Yanchev
Producer:
Vladimir Yanchev
Operator:
Georgi Georgiev
Artist:
Nedelcho Nanev
Music:
Peter Stupel
Sound Operator:
Georgi Krastev
Director of the film:
Dimitar Geoshev
Footballer R. Golubov from Varna -
Author of five goals
She loves him.
- Not for sure.
That's unheard of!
They were together at the match.
I was ill for our team.
- Good!
Radoslav? Do you like her?
No!
As he drinks, he sees your lovely image
I would like to gently hug you
at this night's hour
To kiss you in oblivion,
even with a laugh, despising death.
Despising death...
Oh, Columbine, give me
a sign of love
Harlequin strongly desires you.
Open to him again, warm up his heart.
He yearns for you...
Harlequin!
Elena, when you are near,
I can perform the whole
Sofia's "People's Opera" repertoire!
For free?
- So heartless you are!
For myself, your attention is the biggest fee.
He treats her with songs.
- Can't be!
Look at him...
So simple.
Leans toward her...
You die only once.
May no one watch through binoculars!
Good afternoon! How are you?
I apologize for stopping you in the street.
May I escort you?
- Only to the corner, please.
I am very pleased. Golubov.
And what's your name?
Have you watched the movie "Obsessive"?
- Yes!
Oh no. I did not watch.
- Well, we're around the corner.
If you don't mind, shall we
cross the square together?
I can not refuse the author of five goals.
- Ah, speaking of that...
You are the cause of the fifth.
I scored in anger
because you smiled at the tenor.
- Oh, poor adversary.
It's good that I smiled only once.
There's nothing funny
in blocking oxygen off!
Sorry that I prevented
your underwater walk.
If it's not a secret, what are you
looking for on the seabed?
I see that this is for you.
It's actually interesting.
I'm seeking therapeutic algae
for my chronic gastritis.
Furthermore, I'm not angry anymore
and I suggest to get acquainted.
Nikolai Mladenov.
- Goncharova. - Golubov...
I guess you are newlyweds?
- No, no.
But that's great, because
an old bachelor lives lonely.
42 years ago, my Daniela skipped out on me.
And now, as you can see,
I'm looking for seaweed alone.
I know one romantic restaurant.
Only for lovers and friends.
I invite you to a baked mullet in the evening.
- I agree! What about you?
Tonight I was invited to the opera,
and then I leave for Sofia.
Elena, you know... We don't need
to skip out on each other.
Come to Sofia.
Elena, the suitcase.
- Good evening!
Oh, and you are coming as well?
- Yes of course.
Young man, do not be afraid.
I will take care of your fiancée.
I bring luck in love!
But, Elena, I do not know your address!
- Write it down.
Nowhere.
Thank you. Excuse me.
2 Brestovitsa Street, 74A,
third entrance, fourth floor.
Phone number: 9-37-84.
Written down.
The address remained in the wallet!
July 29th, Monday - the eighth pharmacy
"Chamomile for rinsing"
Vitosha! Vitosha!
Controller Goga, it seems to me,
that my employees do not
support their team enough.
Where did you buy this, Fileva?
- On the fish market, Dondukova street.
How big!
Comrade superior, aunt's aunt Pena
and the cashier Fileva are present
at the match only formally.
They don't even follow the game!
Vitosha! Vitosha!
Comrade Strogov! Accountant Lychko
thinks of something extraneous,
like the trade union!
Our union will not tolerate
in their ranks those officials
who haven't a single drop of
football patriotism!
Our Parmakov is something! Believe me, Zhenya,
he scored five goals in front of my eyes!
You know how well he plays.
Goal!
Goal! Bravo, falcons!
Comrade Strogov! Now or never!
The referee judges in Vitosha's favour.
Will you return Stancho Parmakov?
Will you count the goal?
I see that you do not specifically
look into my eyes. Why?
Why are you behaving like
a soulless bureaucrat?
State enterprise "Vitosha"
Devoted to football -
Devoted to the trade union!
Well, he's blossoming.
- Because he has everything forgiven.
Guys, tomorrow is the last day
for physical examination.
We're waiting for you.
- Very well, uncle Ivan.
Please, I already told you.
Comrade Strogov will not be here today.
Come back tomorrow.
Bringing dogs to institution is prohibited!
Pass this recipe, comrade Strogov.
Comrades!
Our institution is going through
period of great tribulation.
The Vitosha's favourite,
Parmakov Stancho...
... is no more with us.
- Oh, when?
He's fired!
Oh Lord, and I thought he passed away.
Laugh at your own death!
How will you play without him?
And this is the final match!
The way we played and won before,
when he wasn't ours.
We will play without Parmakov.
Crazy people!
Such jewels like Parmakov
create Bulgarian football.
Can they destroy our football perhaps?
- So funny.
Parmakov is dead.
Long live Golubov!
Scram! Scram!
May you choke with it!
Went out for a minute.
What was in the papers?
- The fate of Vitosha.
It was eaten by a dog.
Scandal! The fate of Vitosha
is in the stomach of some dog!
Who is this Golubov from Varna?
Golubov from Varna? Elena's friend.
And he was much better than Parmakov.
Where is Elena?
Dear Leni!
Dear Leni, at this moment
your personal happiness is decided.
He will be in Sofia.
You will have a good home,
and everything you need
for a sound marriage!
I don't understand a thing.
Zhenya told me about your Varna romance.
Sorry, but I'm strongly against this...
this sound marriage.
Dear Leni, even Tolstoy said:
"The end justifies the means".
We're facing the final match.
Therefore I immediately ask for
your Golubov's address and photo.
Yes, Tolstoy convinced me completely.
I haven't his photo or address,
I only know that he is an engineer at the
"Chaika" plant, and he plays for their team.
Dear Lenya, my dear! You are unique!
- Yes I know.
Comrade Goncharova, now it's ten o'clock.
From now on, I'll promote you on the job.
- On State enterprise Vitosha's service!
Ball?
Golubov family
Radoslav? Radosvet?
Get up!
You forgot something?
- Give me the jacket.
Radosvet walked at night again.
Look at that, what a photomontage!
What do you have in common with
Yves Montand and Gina Lolobrigida?
Aren't you ashamed?
Listen, boy...
First, how could I be worse
than Yves Montand?
I just do not sing. And secondly,
if Gina Lolobrigida would found out,
she wouldn't be angry, I suppose,
because she knows a lot
about male beauty.
Thank you.
Bye.
- Bye.
"I'm tired of waiting for the money
I sued you in the court for. Kisses, Coco"
Mom, your son is not lucky.
What happened this time, Radoslav?
I fell in love with a girl from Sofia.
- And what's wrong with that?
I don't know how to find her.
- If you love her for real, you will find.
How did your father Kharalambi find me?
I'm leaving for Sofia.
- Because of her?
Good.
Well, 800 thousand metropolitan residents,
God forbid that.
You cut off men, children and grannies,
that's only about 300 thousands.
I have 6 days off, that means
some 50 thousand women a day.
You're so lucky, Radoslav!
And what if she lived in Moscow? Millions!
Goodbye, Mom.
- Goodbye, Radoslav.
Beware of trams!
Do not drink cold beer!
"I sued you"... "Kisses"!
The kiss of Juda.
Mom!
Remember, life is roulette!
Who does not risk, does not win!
Or loses.
Is this also roulette, son?
May I never win poker,
if these aren't judicial bodies.
What shall we do?
- Only over your dead body!
He is not guilty!
Only over my dead body!
Dead body!?
I do not know if he's guilty,
but we were sent here
because we terribly need him.
Please, call him, if he is at home.
I'm an unhappy widow,
I have a sick heart.
I will not survive this...
But he's not at home. Yes...
- It's a pity.
Rasho Chukov from the society
of culture and sport "Aggregate".
We'll wait for him, if you don't mind.
Gocho Polyansky from the
sport society "Gentian".
As you wish, but I don't know
whether he will return soon.
I advise you from the heart
to return to Ruse.
Why?
- Because your poor "Aggregate"
can not pay Golubov.
- Ah, well, you go to Plovdiv!
Why?
- Because your feeble "Gentian"
does not deserve such a player.
Are you still here?
- The funeral is postponed until tomorrow.
They are looking for brother.
What do you imagine?
Your Plovdiv is a real hole.
He's gonna be like a sausage
roasted in the high sun,
and then splashing around puddles
around the Maritsa river.
And you want him to drown in the
turbid and dangerous Danube.
Or to be gobbled by the
evil mosquitoes of Ruse.
Besides, we offer him a solid salary.
How much, Gocho?
- Well, let's say 700, Rasho.
750!
- 770!
Well! It's good to be an athlete!
- 780!
790!
800!
- Wait, let me see...
805!
810!
815!
- Can not be!
820!
- Give me the suitcase!
Why do you need it?
- Give it, and don't ask!
Put it on the table.
827!
- Clean shirts!
Just a second...
Whose women are better -
In Ruse, or in Plovdiv?
If I'm not mistaken, Comrade Golubov.
Well, allow me... Do not worry.
I am a representative of "Gentian",
a solid sport society from Plovdiv.
I'm authorized for you to...
- Come to "Aggregate" from Ruse!
"Quiet, white Danube is worried!"
819 monthly!
So you are "Aggregate", you are "Gentian",
and I'm Golubov?
I understand, I sympathize, but not now.
Papa is a very strict person.
Therefore, in half an hour...
Check the clock.
On the Adam's beach.
Wonderful!
Only we do not have beach suits.
Bye.
- That's some bluffing!
But who is this?
Do not open.
Speak through the window.
Who are you looking for, comrade?
- Radoslav Golubov.
And why do you need him?
I want to make him a happy
and wealthy metropolitan.
Allow me to introduce myself: Vylo Volchanov,
a senior coach of Vitosha, from Sofia.
Nice to meet you.
Where can I see him?
- "Wait in the garden."
He'll be back soon.
Wait in the garden.
He will be back soon.
"I'll make you some coffee."
- I'll make you some coffee.
Please, please...
Do not worry, madam.
Radosvet?
Horch? A solid brand.
Hot Sofia's greetings from Elena!
Ah, great!
And why does not she write !?
She doesn't write because she is waiting for you!
- Ah, I can not come...
Elena and I offer you a contract in Sofia.
Under what conditions?
Apartment in the Oborishche Street,
the diplomatic quarter.
Registration in Sofia, the salary is 840.
850?
- Well, a little more...
I can not offer more, alas!
And who are you?
- I'm a senior coach
of "Vitosha", Vylo Volchanov,
known by the nickname 'Awl'.
A-ah! Documentation.
You are welcome...
Hmm... Well...
I accept.
- Great!
When are we going?
Kisses, Coco! Bye, Mom!
Madam, be proud that you are
a mother of such talent! Come on.
No, I'm not in the prison in Varna.
No, not in prison!
I wish you such a punishment.
Yes, people in Sofia are kind
and well-bred. They adore me!
They are fed five times a day.
They pay for housing...
No, everything is going fine.
What did you say about Radoslav?
Stayed at the hotel "Sevastopol"?
Are you sure?
Yeah... Just because!
No, I definitely need to talk with him.
Bye, Mom!
You're pure gold, mistress.
Pure gold!
I've raised 12 children.
And they were all players like yourself.
Like myself?
- Like you. I've got the thirteenth.
I don't fancy that figure, mistress.
- Yes, do not look at the number.
You see the main thing is, that
the cat did not run across the road.
I remember one was brought from Kazanlak.
He played the right wing.
Another from Pavlikeni,
and the twelfth - Stancho Parmakov.
He was a centre forward,
and scored plenty of goals.
What do you play? - Poker, bridge.
Even the picket sometimes.
Dunno if you'd like here, boy.
- Why, madam?
In Sofia, we play W format.
Such is the strategy.
Congratulations on the position
of the referent.
And in just a few hours
you will be a resident of Sofia.
Vladko?
- I hear you.
This healing herb is like blood.
I feel so young.
Why don't you get married, Nikolay?
How should I put this, Vladko...
Our women in Sofia aren't feminine.
They walk in trousers,
they cut hairs like men...
How did our grandmothers
looked like in the past?
Oh, young man!
Hello!
- Hello.
I do not believe my eyes!
Have you already got married?
- Not yet.
Me neither.
At the station you said,
that you bring luck.
Ah, sure.
Here, look.
Chamomile instead of address!
Have you got the wallet?
Ah, yes, yes...
No no. This is new.
The old one went into the furnace.
800 thousand metropolitan residents.
Young man, do not leave.
And do not despair.
We will seek her together.
On the streets, in the gardens.
We'll go around apartments,
museums, theaters.
In the bazaar, on the beach...
And one day - we'll find her!
- Yes, yes!
And my dog, too.
Love will help you.
You will live in my bachelor apartment.
I raise toast in the honor of three bachelors!
Camomile or mint?
"The Karlovsk Misket"...
Healing seaweed, eh?
Cheers!
It seems that the matter is important.
I called you to let you know,
that you, controller Goga,
and you, the case manager Peci...
- Me!
... are free from work for an
indefinite period of time
regarding the important public task.
Comrades! In our country there are people,
who cannot accept the success
of our dear "Vitosha".
And so they try to kidnap
our central striker Golubov,
who was found with such difficulty.
I assign you as his bodyguards.
Heroes! Before the final match
forget about everything, except Golubov.
Don't let him out of your sight.
Follow him like a shadow.
Is that clear?
- It is.
Here are the portraits of competitors,
drew from memory.
This dumb guy is from Ruse,
and the crumpled one - from Plovdiv.
Remember how sheep were cut
in "Beautiful Elena"?
Where?
In the operetta, which we all went to.
- Ah, yes...
If he is kidnapped, then you are
being awaited the same.
Can't be!
Wait! Wait.
Found. Write it down.
Yes, write it down...
Today, on the 20th of this month,
he moved from cigarettes "Arda"
to "Diplomat".
How can you risk life for the
sake of some cigarette butts!
But this is your cigarette butt, comrade Golubov.
- Where are you going?
Return to the apartment.
Who is this suspicious old man?
- I'm not much older than you.
And I'm still a bachelor if you want to know.
As for Golubov's apartment,
he's going to live only with me.
Yes.
- You are ours! Hold it!
You are not normal!
Someone unhooked them.
It wasn't me. Those uncles did it.
Go back, follow the trolley!
- Golubov was kidnapped!
When?
- Now!
Haven't I forbade you to drink until Friday?
Look how dirty you are.
Go wash yourselves immediately,
and see the boss at 2 o'clock
for a small meeting.
Come on, come on.
SOFIA MINERAL BATH
Believe me, Goga, I would spend
whole my annual vacation...
all 20 days... here in the pool.
Do you believe me?
- Why not?
Only, you know...
It's very humid air.
Now, if there were no roof, so that
sunshine could go through and warm up...
Ah, Peci...
Can you imagine how good it would be then?
Let me know, for this Golubov...
I'm ready to kill.
Dear Chukov, I'm not adherent
to physical violence.
But that highest of meanness, committed
for the sake of our own and our cities',
hardly deserves anything else.
Ruse will declare war on Sofia
because of this player!
Plovdiv will support you!
- Thank you.
And then we will play it by lot?
The lot, the lot...
Wow! Come on...
Rasho... It is forbidden to swim here.
Stop diving if you are a man.
The enemy in the bath!
56 kilograms, Gocho!
And 140 grams, Rasho!
Yes, but with slippers on.
- Right.
And now?
This is another thing... Exactly.
- Same.
It is necessary to approach them closer.
You will go to the vanguard,
and I'll stay in the rear guard.
Dumb guy from Ruse!
- Crumpled guy from Plovdiv!
We found them!
Come here, sweet...
I paid for a separate cabin!
- Quiet!
Go out, please!
Administrator!
Quietly, I beg of you.
Shhh, be quiet!
Let go of that man.
Please, excuse us,
It was absolutely coincidental.
Comrade?
Hello! Hello!
God!
To die in a city bathhouse,
and at the hands of his favorites?
Nightmare!
Comrade boss, we are being watched.
- By who?
By those whom we follow.
What!?
Two provincial swindlers!
You want to leave us empty-handed again?
Funny!
Hey, you there!
Where did you hide Golubov?
What meanness! Where is your socialist,
sporting morale? Thieves!
And you?
What have you lost in Sofia?
Maybe you drove 500km just
to swim in our mineral bath?
We were the first to enter the yard,
and we defend our rights.
Take us to your boss,
so I'd tell him right in the face
that he was a lowly intriguer.
In this case, I invite you
for a small production meeting
in this modest cabin.
And who are you, anyway?
- I'm the boss!
I don't accept visits before dinner.
Tell'em I went to the ministry.
Comrades! I was in the balance!
So, let's talk about Golubov frankly.
Young man, we can proudly note
that we shaken these three
districts thoroughly...
Elena, in what area did you hide?
- I'm sure that in the first one.
Therefore I suggest the following route:
Let's walk by the yellow pavement
boulevard called "Russian".
Fine.
- Yes.
Oh, comrade Golubov! Victory!
- Everybody is waiting for you!
At last!
- Here he is!
Distinguished comrade Golubov,
Profkom did not organized
this small feast by accident.
A minute ago, you just got
your Sofia residence permit.
Now you're one of us!
Let's drink to the bottom.
You two, what do you want from me?
So that you don't jump from
the balcony into the trolley.
And that you don't throw
sticks of apples onto my head.
Who are you!?
- We are your shadow.
In our country, there are people
who want to kidnap you.
We guard you from enemies.
And which of you is Napoleon?
- Napoleon?
Who...
Not me and not you.
I'm telling you, it seems more appropriate
to go see comrade Strogov.
Yes?
Clear.
I'll be right back.
Amateurs!
Aunt Penka, where are you going?
- I'll collect the cobwebs in the corridor.
What cobwebs in the corridor!?
Do you participate in amateur activities?
- I do, but who will clean?
In honor of the Sofia residence permit
and as a token of respect and gratitude
to our favorite Golubov,
our amateur ensemble will perform
a short literary and musical composition.
You will hear "Elegy of Football Patriots."
Text: Comrade superior Strogov.
Music: Neapolitan.
Oh, my football!
Forever in us.
Advance!
... we give an advance (lost in advance).
Our hearts languish only about you.
Oh, my football!
I am forever yours!
Where are you going...
- What are you up to?
Physical education!
Well, I'm here. Maybe we will
continue this... party.
I expected a letter from you, Radoslav.
Or maybe you again saw off someone
on the coastal streets and squares?
- I didn't even look at single woman!
In Varna you were more romantic.
Let's move from away.
- But I ordered champagne!
How do you like it here?
Listen... Do not get carried away.
Night watch will be full of danger.
Do not be afraid! They're now
snoring in some station hotel.
What will you order?
Two mastikas.
- Large ones!
Why?
It's almost empty.
Only for a ticket to Plovdiv.
It's hard, dear Rasho, to fight
with large societies of Sofia.
So far we had the strength...
Tonight or never!
Is the rope with you?
Come on!
There are some words superfluous to us
There are words hidden in our hearts
Virginia, may I invite one
acquaintance for a dance?
Of course.
... if your eyes have said everything.
Keep it quiet, keep it quiet
It is really in our eyes
There are no words waiting for you.
Keep it quiet, keep it quiet...
Elena, I'm inviting you out on a date.
Tomorrow at 7pm near the fountain,
near the university.
My wife is going on a vacation
in Kostenets.
Do you have children, maestro?
- Three! But it does not matter.
I think that they will be
boring at the fountain.
Better go with them to the zoo
or in the puppet theater.
I didn't think you were a petty bourgeois.
I have great respect for you both
as a tenor and tennis player, but...
Meaning? No hope?
Go to Kostenets.
- So heartless!
Waiter!
Speak, speak...
Even in silence we both
expect these words.
Wait. Wait, they turned the corner.
Pec! Peci!
Peci? Pe...
Good evening, Golubov.
You have offended the province
by agreeing to play in Sofia.
Leave the capital!
Choose yourself: "Aggregate" - Ruse,
or "Gentian" - Plovdiv!
Decide immediately!
Wow!
You see...
Ah, come on, go to sleep.
I have played and will only play
in my Varna's "Chaika", you see?
You're lying! Sly. You were
appointed as a referent in Vitosha.
But you will not play in the final match.
We, who suffered through, tell you this:
Chukov and Polyansky.
Comrades, this is some kind of misunderstanding.
- Just a minute.
Do you continue?
- Yes.
Tonight...
- ... or never!
Good.
Do not play an innocent nun.
Bye. Come again.
Katya, is my brother here?
- Yes, there he's at Pancho's.
When you finish, go straight home.
Mother is waiting for you.
But...
- Good. I know!
You're suffocating the citizens.
- Elena!
Finally... So much looking for
you and, suddenly, meet you here!
How are you, what are you doing?
- Do not make an idiot out of yourself.
Idiot!? Maybe I am, although
that is not too polite.
You tell me about politeness!?
So insolent!
Impudence - to love someone!?
Wash your head and sober up
after champagne!
What kind of champagne?
Hypocrite!
You will not deceive me anymore.
Do not be afraid. Consider
that we never met each other.
That's the same! We, women, always become
victims of low male instincts.
Now, tomorrow she will give birth -
to a boy or girl - who will
have no one to call a dad.
Your tears, colleague,
will not work for everyone.
If that's his child, then she
wouldn't have had to push him away.
It seems that the father is somebody else.
Farewell, Elena. I did not know
that you would be a mother.
Whose mother? What nonsense!
This is my twin brother.
Here! I told you that
I bring luck in love!
For violation of the rules of conduct
in the garden - a fine of three leva.
You are welcome.
25 levs!?
Are you laughing at me?
I've got no small change.
Then, keep kissing on for the rest.
Attention!
- Build!
Please, build!
On the right flank, faster!
- No talk in the ranks!
Comrades! Comrade superior Strogov
instructed me to tell you that
this is the decisive match!
Do not spare your strength!
Take an oath!
We're true to football!
- That's right!
Excellent.
The lunch break ended two hours ago!
- How long shall we wait?
Enough to confer.
- Vitosha is the champion!
Ah! There's nobody here!
Hallo? - Is that you, Comrade superior?
It's me, it's me, aunt Pena.
I'm listening. Nobody here.
It's full of people making noise, shouting...
They threaten to complain to the minister.
You're busy? What should I do?
Huh?
Yeah, take it somehow.
Well, okay... Ok, only they
all very evil, comrade boss.
Oh well. Good.
Hey, come in, who's there in turn!
How are you, how are you?
Oh, grandmother Tinka, grandmother Tinka...
You'd better kill me,
than to suffer so much.
He committed fratricide!
Promised and did not come.
- Do not worry, dear. Will come tomorrow.
See you tomorrow...
Tomorrow will be too late.
Maybe you'll still feast at my wake.
Do you understand?
I guess...
- Guess, guess...
Have you ever played football?
- I've only seen others play.
Have you seen it?
- Well, of course, I have!
Come on, come here...
Stand here on the gate.
Do not move!
- I see!
What about the basin, son?
- It doesn't matter, granny.
Who saw a goalkeeper with the basin!?
I'm ready.
Will you beat the penalty?
So come on. Quickly, quickly!
I'm a beast!
- And I?
You, too... 1, 2, 3,
4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9...
Eleven! I learned bridge for a night,
and I can not play football, or what?
Oh!
Please, grandmother Tinka,
I beg you not to die!
Wow, you want too much!
I'm not old yet. Listen:
If you have to beat the penalty at the match,
hit it low, in the corner, son.
Do you understand?
- Oh, I understand, I understand...
They're coming!
Oh granny Tinka, what's wrong with him?
- How could I know. Here, we trained.
Maybe it's cancer?
- I cure cancer, too! Get up and no tricks.
Come on, go.
It's easy, man.
I know that you want a bigger salary!
You'll get it when we win.
- We did everything for you, man.
An apartment, a residence permit, salary.
Play the match!
Have you heard about Awl?
It's me.
You know what I'm capable of?
An eye for an eye, a tooth for a tooth!
I can not play without training,
postpone the match!
Will you get up, finally?
Are we going?
- Come on.
We'll start playing with ten men
until he's gone. But tough!
Have agreed?
- We agreed.
Instead of Golubov in the center - Nikolay.
- Good. Come on.
Vitosha! Vitosha!
Where is Golubov?
- Where's Golubov?
I'm his landlady.
What does he do at the gate?
- Yes, everything is clear.
Will play in defense, and in attack.
Peculiar tactics.
How are you feeling, eh?
- So good that we were avoided.
Siamese twins! Oh heavens, strike with
lightning the captive of yours, Vylo.
I will not survive this masquerade.
An ambulance!
- It's an emergency!
I'll forgive your brother
if you stay in Sofia.
Apartment on the street. Oborishche,
Salary - 1000 and stuff, stuff.
If you agree, you can start
playing in the second half.
Do you know...
I fell in love with the ball in Varna.
There I learned to play.
How can I leave everyone -
Friends, coach, fans...
Do not feel sorry for them. The way
they taught you, they will teach others.
Let them grow as footballers,
and we will take them,
we will provide them with conditions
for further development.
Unfortunately, you already invited my brother.
Do not despair, work with him.
As you can see, he's a clever fellow.
A sharp attack of appendicitis!
Call ambulance! I'm dying!
Where are you taking me?
Comrades, be careful what you do!
I do not want! I do not want!
I am the master of my body!
"Operating unit"
- But I'm alive and well!
Stop bullying!
- Anesthesia!
I'm dying like Jan Hus at the stake!
Misfire...
Tomorrow I will go to Pleven
and bring a real football player!
And there you stay, Vylo.
From this moment on, I'm firing you.
But they can not without me!
Is that so, my falcons?
In these moments of great sorrow
it's hard to hold back.
This favourite turned out to be fatal for us.
The thirteenth!
Comrade superior!
- What happened?
They're running behind me with documents,
comrade superior!
For breaking the rules, behavior in
the garden is fined with three leva.
Be alive and well.
Hold it!
You learned the rules poorly, granddad.
In the light of the moon, it's allowed.
Because this is a park, not museum.
The song I learned in your hometown.
I don't know how would it
sound without an orchestra.
The orchestra is here!
There are some words superfluous to us
There are words hidden in our hearts...
Why should we say it loud,
if the eyes have said everything?
Keep it quiet, keep it quiet...
It is really in our eyes
There are no words waiting for you.
Keep it quiet, keep it quiet...
In the eyes it sounds all what
I feel together with you.
But sometimes even the eyes are silent,
if we stay alone under the stars.
Ah, then do not be silent!
Speak, speak
What our eyes did not say.
Speak, speak...
- Quiet!
There are even words...
Small words with great power
Speak, speak...
Even though we stopped,
we're both waiting for those words.
THE END