Someone's coming! Someone's coming!
Here, man! Money! Five euros, take it!
Stop it!
Stay there!
Go away, man!
If I have to say it again I'll hit you.
Go away and count to a thousand!
Watch out, you'll lose all your teeth.
Someone's coming!
What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Up to mischief again?
He wasn't doing anything, really.
Who do you think you are?
Look, she does what I say!
Let's go. It's late.
Mom!
Mom, the saucepan's burning!
I forgot about the saucepan.
Sit down, the saucepan's burnt.
But I took it off.
What would I do without you.
You're such a good boy.
The bus is coming.
Do you have any proof
that your husband died in the war'?
She says that when he was killed
we were already in Austria.
Is there a death certificate?
- No.
I read that you still have grandparents.
Do your parents still live in Chechnya?
- Yes.
Can't they get proof, a death certificate?
She doesn't dare to...
She's scared they'll get into trouble.
And she doesn't want that.
That's bad. You need evidence,
so the judge believes
that your husband is really dead.
What do you know about his death?
He was a war hero.
- What does that mean?
He fought against the Russians.
Do you know more about that?
- That's all he told us.
There's no way at all to get proof?
We've been through this a thousand times.
It's in the files.
- I know.
But I have to prepare you for the hearing.
If you say it like that
at the asylum court
it won't be detailed enough
and the result will be negative.
Can you translate that?
She asks what we should do.
You already have subsidiary protection.
If your application is rejected this time,
all is not lost, but it would be better...
To change to a Red-White-Red Card
integration in Austria is crucial.
You speak German,
but you have to improve.
Try to speak more,
do another German course.
Speak more, practice more.
Don't use Ramasan as an interpreter.
You can speak yourself.
Do you have a new boyfriend, a husband?
A relationship?
She has female friends,
but boyfriend... No.
Ask your mother if she has a boyfriend.
Go on, ask her.
What does she mean?
If I have a brother.
A brother'?
No.
Sit up straight.
Masud, can I have the blue one?
Let's play soccer with them.
Excuse me. Can I have the ball?
Are you a Chechen?
- Yes.
What's your name?
- Ramasan.
You speak German well.
Who is your father?
My father is dead.
Okay, but watch where you boys kick it.
Thanks.
Ramasan, will you buy me this?
No. Put it back, lman.
We have no money.
We'll buy it later, okay?
I want this.
- No, put it back.
Mom didn't give us money for that.
What are you doing?
What are you doing? Stop it!
Put it all back.
Stop it, will you!
Hurry UP-
Let me see.
Come on.
Come on. We're going home.
I don't want to.
- But I do.
Come.
Let's stay a bit longer.
This is Ramasan, lman and Rosa.
They've grown so much.
Hello.
- Hello.
Take the girls to the other room
and put on a DVD.
Come on!
Put this one in.
How long have you been here?
- Since 2006.
Have you got papers'?
- Yes.
Who's that?
- A friend of your father's.
He's brought a few things
that belonged to him.
What's this?
Do you recognize anyone?
That's us, isn't it?
It's a photo of you.
Your father always had it with him.
Come and sit down.
This is your father's watch.
He wanted you to have it.
Does it fit'?
- It's a bit too big.
Let me see.
It should be okay now.
Now it fits.
- Thank you.
It doesn't work.
I don't know what's wrong with it.
We can have a look at it later.
Ea'?
No, thanks. I must go.
Let me know if you need anything.
Ramasan knows where I live.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Hello, Mom. How are you'?
Thanks. Everyone's fine.
I wanted to ask you
if you've ever heard of a man called Isa.
One of Hassan's friends.
He came to see us and said
he was a friend of Hassan's,
and he brought some of his things.
A photo and his watch.
No, I haven't either.
Don't worry, I'll be careful.
What are you doing?
Hello.
How are you'?
- Good.
I need two pieces of wood like this.
Will you help me'?
See if you can find any.
Like this?
- Exactly.
Where did you get it?
- Over there.
Did you do that in Chechnya too?
Were you a craftsman?
I had lots of jobs.
Could my father do that too'?
Don't you remember him at all?
I was little when he died.
I don't remember much.
Did you hurt your hand in the war'?
Yes, I was injured back home.
Were you really in the war with my father?
We walked many paths together.
Don't you believe me?
My mother says
I'm not to trust strangers.
You should listen to your mother.
Hello.
- Good day.
I've got a watch that doesn't work.
Could you have a look at it?
- Of course.
It's a lovely old Russian model.
What's that golden thing?
That.
It's a clock movement.
Did you make it?
No.
They're usually inside table clocks.
The battery is dead.
We'll have to change it.
It costs six euros.
Shall we do it?
I'll do it myself.
Could I have another look
at the battery?
This size, but...
Let's hope
you don't break something else.
Ramasan!
Come here.
Let's talk later.
How are you'?
- Fine.
Working hard at school?
- Yes.
What's happening at school?
Nothing special.
Are you behaving badly?
- No.
Behave well, Ramasan.
Tell me if you need anything.
I'm therefor my family.
We manage okay.
Look, Bekhan, he's a real man.
Yes, a real man.
You see, that's our future.
Off you go, then.
Goodbye.
- Ramasan, wait!
I never see you at the mosque.
You're old enough, 11 or 12...
You're grown up.
I'll come next time.
Bekhan, make sure he does come.
Good, off you go.
I was going to jump high.
- I'll do a backflip!
That was no good.
I should have jumped higher.
The other mattress too!
The yellow one!
Was that a backflip?
That was crap, man.
Stop that. Sit down.
Man, sit down when you're mm m.
Stop that, Iman.
What are you doing?
Can't you keep still
till I've finished?
Look, she's broken it.
She's jumping around like a goat.
- Stop it, Mom.
You're scaring her.
- I'm not scaring her.
She doesn't listen to you either.
Sit down.
You've got into enough mischief.
Get your hands off me.
Give me the money back now!
Do you think I'll give it to you
if you shout?
Hello.
- Hi.
Our hairdryer is broken.
Can you fix it'?
Did someone drop it'?
- Yes.
I'll have a look at it later. Wait here.
Shame on you!
What's all this noise about?
Like children!
Fighting in public...
I saw a sofa back there.
Will you help me carry it'?
What's up?
Why did you stop?
- No reason.
Is that it'?
No, it's further over there.
That one's too old and broken.
Leave it.
What's wrong with you'?
I don't want to go in any further.
Why not'?
Did your mother forbid you to'?
There's a wolf in there.
What are you talking about?
There are no wolves here.
Besides, I've got my knife.
If we see a wolf
I'll show him...
All right.
Here it is.
Wait, step aside.
It's broken.
Yes, it's too broken.
You see, there are no wolves here
yet you were afraid.
I hear them at night.
How do you know they're wolves,
not dogs?
I can tell by their call.
They are wolves.
I hear them every night.
I can't sleep at night either.
Are you scared of them?
Wolves aren't that dangerous.
Humans are dangerous.
Have you ever done it?
What?
Killed a wolf with a knife.
No, I have never killed a wolf.
What about a person?
Where's the white one?
- Hands off!
None for you. Go away.
I said just look, don't take it out.
Go away! Didn't you hear me?
It's not for blacks.
- Go away.
Go away, man.
You're not allowed to look.
Go away, blackie!
I'm not showing you. Go away!
I'll show you when we're over there.
Let me look!
The black guy is leaving anyway.
Look, I'll show you.
Who's that?
- I don't know.
Let's see who can punch harder.
Come on.
I'll punch the top part, okay'?
Now kick.
What are you doing?
Are you now Karate Kid or what?
What's going on?
- Nothing.
Your heads are full of nonsense.
So?
- Go to the playground.
The playground is too small.
Then play near the playground.
Not in this area!
- Why not? It's public.
People get annoyed.
You kids fool around and are noisy.
Who cares?
- I care! It's not public!
It doesn't belong to you.
No, but I'm paid
to keep things in order here.
The passers-by feel harassed by you.
So?
- Not '80'.
But that's our hobby!
- Go to the playground.
Off you go, go on!
Hey, let go of me!
I'm just patting your shoulder
because you're such a good boy.
You're making me dirty.
- No, my hands are very clean.
Cool it! And shut your trap!
DIGGER THEME PARK
KIDS ON STAGE
How much?
- It's really expensive. 60 euros.
Per hour.
And look at that one.
It's not that big.
That one's bigger.
That one has bigger buckets,
but the other one has a longer crane.
Look what they're doing.
Look at those idiots!
Look at that naked guy!
Yuck.
What are you doing, man?
Are you psycho?
I swear, you've totally lost it.
You gypsy!
- That was awesome.
Swear you'll never do it again.
- But it was fun.
It was fun,
but I'm totally out of breath, man.
So?
We had to run for ages because of you.
- So'?
Why did you scratch the car?
I don't know.
Stay here for a while.
I'll be right back.
Don't go away.
Hey, I'm flying!
Faster!
Get down.
Have you been shopping?
Come on, my girl.
Give me that.
- No, I can carry it.
Give it to me. You look after the girls.
- No.
Take your sisters.
- All right.
Come on.
Iman, Rosa, play over there.
Let them stay.
They're not bothering us.
May I try?
You may, but can you do it?
I think so.
Here, try it.
But be careful.
Just cut the little ones off.
What a beautiful knife.
Start here and go downwards.
Careful you don't hurt yourself.
Do you want the knife?
Sure. I like it.
- You can keep it.
But be careful with it.
Don't play with it
in front of the other kids.
Only use it for working.
And be careful.
Munasar, you haven't got any games.
Are you at home?
Hello.
- Hi, Ramasan.
Can I come in?
Is your mother at home?
- Yes, she's here.
Can you call her'?
Mom, lsa's here with the hairdryer.
Oh, is he? Wait a moment.
What are you looking at'?
I see. You don't miss a thing.
Come on.
Let's not keep him waiting.
Hello.
- How are you all?
Fine, thank you.
I've fixed the hairdryer
and brought it back to you.
Thanks, and sorry to bother you.
Not a problem. ll wasn't hard.
Tell me if I can help.
I will.
- I have to go. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
It's not always easy,
the question of
"to marry or not to marry"...
Marriage is good.
In Afghanistan,
not married, not speak together.
Only family decide, family decide all.
Aminat, you're so quiet today.
How did you meet your husband?
You didn't want to'?
- No.
You mean, the man,
your husband, saw you at some point...
and said, "I want her"?
- Yes.
And then he came to your house
and took you away with him?
I was home with my siblings
when he came,
and lsaid, "No, please!"
But he was with car and two friends,
and just took me. Like, stole me.
I scream, "Please, don't!"
But... that's how it was.
But did you call the police?
He can't just come and take you!
That's tradition in Chechnya.
It's normal.
- Yes, it's normal.
If I say no, there is fight.
So if you'd said,
"I don't want to marry you"
the families would've had a dispute?
- Yes.
But you also have children, right?
Three children.
- How does that work?
It's just like that.
Did you love him at some point?
Difficult.
I told you to be careful!
Now he's getting yelled at.
By his boss.
Shut up!
- Be quiet, will you!
Isa is afraid, I think.
Load this up and get it over there!
See you.
You should be glad
you have a job!
We've been waiting for you.
Hello.
Like we said, your dispute is over,
I expect reconciliation between you.
Give each other a firm handshake.
Forgive me, I'll do my best.
- Shake hands.
I want to apologize.
- Behave yourselves.
With God's help
we will never again lose our temper.
May it please Allah.
May God be pleased with you.
If the boys here see you,
they will do the same.
You were a bad example.
If you don't mind,
I'll go home now with Ramasan.
Goodbye.
That's how it is.
You must not behave badly.
I won't.
Your father was an honorable man.
Don't ruin his reputation.
Understood?
- Yes.
Hello.
- Hello, Ramasan.
How are you'?
- Good.
Are you hungry?
- A little.
I have some meat.
Shall we make a shashlik?
Help me collect some wood!
Do you have your knife'?
- Yes.
Give it to me.
Why don't you pray at the mosque?
There are too many people there for me.
But praying once at the mosque
is like praying 27 times alone. It's good.
That's true.
But...
what's most important
is that you pray with a pure heart.
Who killed my father'?
How was he killed?
Why do you ask?
As soon as I'm grown up,
I'll avenge his murder!
You don't have to do that.
Take care of your family instead.
We didn't do everything right either.
Your father and I made many mistakes.
More out of stupidity than courage.
You might be stupid,
but my father wasn't!
Don't speak of him like that!
I didn't say he was stupid. Ramasan!
I'm going in first!
Shit, it's locked.
Let's move on.
No, man!
- The door's locked!
There's a good view from up here.
Look at this!
The digger's unlocked!
Come on!
You go first.
Move along.
- Only big guys are allowed to sit.
No key here either.
Hey, do you see that white door?
That's where all the keys are.
When me and Askhab were here
we saw a man.
Yeah, let's go.
Shit, it's locked.
Hey stupid,
it opens outwards not inwards!
You'll break your foot. Move.
You need tools for that, man!
Your foot won't do it.
- Askhab's right.
What's he doing here?
- Why didn't you pick up the girls?
Isa brought them home.
Where were you?
What have you been up to?
Nothing happened.
Who did you fight with?
You're up to no good again.
I told you
you shouldn't hang around with those kids!
How did you hurt yourself?
Those kids are a bad influence!
I've told him so often
not to hang around with them.
You're not a child anymore.
Why don't you listen to your mother?
You're not my father!
You can't tell me anything!
Now I can kill you better.
Stop it, you're getting me wet!
I have pliers at home too.
You know that sharp thing?
Seriously. I have one of those...
We need pliers.
- Yes, I have some at home.
Crowbar...
- I have that too.
No, you don't.
- I do. Want to bet?
At home you have two siblings
you have to look after.
That's all.
Shut your mouth, man.
Ramasan, let's go.
Knock it off, be quiet!
What are you doing?
- I said, stop it.
Can't we go now?
Come on, let's go!
What are you doing?
- Shut up!
Will that be everything?
6 euros 29. Are you paying cash'?
3 euros 71 change.
The receipt?
- Yes, please.
Bye.
- Hold on a second.
What did you pay for'?
A battery.
- A battery?
May I look in your backpack?
- Sure, go ahead.
Thanks.
You showed me everything, right?
- Yes.
Are they your sisters?
Will you give me
your sister's backpack?
Let me look at the other one first, okay'?
Thank you.
You didn't hide anything, did you?
What's this?
But you didn't pay for this!
Well...
If you won't work with me,
it's going to be difficult, you know?
I heard your sisters were there too?
Why?
- I picked them up from daycare.
Does he pick them up often?
I work.
When I work,
he picks them up from daycare.
Then you have to take care of them?
Yeah, but only for a couple of hours.
Until she gets home.
So you decided
to take them to go stealing
in the hardware store.
You have an asylum case pending, right?
So you're waiting on a decision.
Ramasan, you have to realize
that these things matter.
If you break the law in Austria,
it certainly won't help the case.
You're responsible for your kids,
you need to make sure
they are looked after.
And you're responsible
tor not getting into trouble, okay?
I look after my children.
But you can't when you go to work.
I already have a grown son.
Does he live with you too'?
I mean...
- You mean Ramasan?
He's not grown up.
I also looked after my...
But he's still a child.
Eleven years is old enough...
Not in Austria, definitely not.
You can be happy about that, otherwise
you might go to iail for shoplifting.
I want to support you, okay'?
Do you have any relatives
who could look after the two little ones?
No.
Friends? Acquaintances?
Isa could help us out.
Nobody, unfortunately. They're all...
in Chechnya.
Ramasan!
What was with the police?
- Nothing.
Tell us.
- What was with the police?
Did you rat on us?
- No, I'm not a rat!
You ratted on us, didn't you'?
Did you? Tell us now.
No!
- What did the police say'?
Does your mom know'?
Don't bug me!
- Yeah, your mom knows.
Did she beat you?
- Shut up.
I know she did!
Get lost!
- You get lost!
What are you doing there?
What's your problem?
Put the knife away.
What's wrong?
What happened?
Knock it off!
What is this?
Do whatever you were planning to do.
Hello.
Sit down.
What's wrong, Ramasan?
Nothing.
Tell me, or else I can't help you.
Nothing happened.
I heard what you did.
Tell me what happened.
- Nothing.
Nothing? You're lying!
I know something happened.
The Youth Office is after you!
You're not a good example
for your sisters.
This is what happens
when you have no father.
Your mother needs support.
She needs help.
You're no help to her yet.
We don't need anyone.
- You're talking back!
You're not grown up yet!
If you were grown up,
you wouldn't talk back to me.
Children need a father,
that's what I mean!
There has to be a grown man at home.
You're not grown up.
Now you don't even greet me anymore?
Don't you recognize me?
How was school?
- It's none of your business.
If it weren't my business,
I wouldn't ask.
But we're friends.
- I don't need a friend.
Wait a second.
I know it's hard for you.
You're so young, and
you've had to go through so much.
I've also lost people I love.
It's not hard for me.
Tell me about the wolves.
Was it when you were fleeing
through the woods?
Who told you about that?
How do you know?
It helps to talk about it.
Leave me alone!
Okay, but I just want to help you.
The way you helped my father'?
That's not what I mean...
Why didn't you help him'?
Did you just try to save yourself?
Try it lower.
I'm using two.
- Ramasan's right.
I have one below,
and one at the top.
Jam it in there harder!
Turn it.
- The top one won't go in any further.
Try to force it. Push it hard!
Shit, someone's coming!
Where are we going?
Stop!
Stop where you are!
You little brat!
Look, there's that bald guy.
Shit, man.
I'm leaving. Are you coming?
Come on, let's go!
Let's gm
That one, that was him.
The boy with the red hoodie?
It was you. You broke into my place.
Where?
- Hold on. What's your name?
Ramasan Magomadov.
Ramasan'? How old are you'?
Eleven years old.
Were you at the digger park
last night?
No, I was at home the whole time.
Home'? Why are you lying?
It was definitely you.
You're often there.
Pulling at the gate with your buddies.
Or are you saying I'm making it up?
And besides, the way you look,
I saw you last night, looking like that,
red hoodie and all.
Where are your parents?
They're not here.
What was your last name again?
- Magomadov.
Hello, what's going on here?
The gentleman says that last night
your son broke into his digger park.
So we're trying to clear this up now.
No, he was with me all yesterday.
Who says this?
- It was him, I'm sure of it.
I saw the jacket...
- How are you sure'?
Besides,
he and his buddies come by often,
climbing over my fence. That's why...
No, he was with me all yesterday.
Don't know what he talks about.
- It was dark, but the hoodie is the same.
And he's come by my place often...
Well...
I can't be 100% sure, but at least
his appearance and size are the same.
Hoodies are common.
- It's hard to tell by size.
It's a serious accusation.
You see lots of kids at your place.
Yes, there are a number of them.
But I recognize him.
Even though it was dark,
it was exactly the same hoodie
that he's wearing now.
Don't know about hoodie,
he was with me.
If you can't definitively identify him,
there's nothing we can do.
You look after your son
a bit better, okay?
He's lying.
He's not my father.
He's not your father?
No, he forces us kids
to break in and steal stuff.
And if we don't, he beats us.
Are you sure you know
what you're saying?
It's quite serious.
- Yes.
Who exactly are you?
- Well, I'm...
I'm his relative. Only one.
Do you have your ID on you?
- At home.
Where is home?
- Here, close.
Okay-
As far as I'm concerned it all looks good.
The apartment looks nice, the children
are doing well, everything's fine.
And it's great that you've made sure
to stay out of trouble.
See that it stays that way.
It's important. All right?
Okay. Then all the best.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Bye.
What's wrong?
You can play on our team.
Hey guys, they're on our team. Okay?
Shut up! Ramasan's with us.
What? We're two players short.
- So what?
I'm playing with Masud.
- He's with us.
We have two players less than you.
Fine, then take him.
But the goal counts! It counts.
Man, what's up with you?
- Get out of the way!
You watch where you're going!
- Shut up!
Get out of the way! Go on.
Yeah, just leave. Go home.
What's wrong?
Ramasan, what's wrong?
Where are you going?