The Day Of The Owl
For Cinemageddon & Karakarga
May 2010
Help!
- Stop! Stop immediately!
- What's going on?
- Open up!
- Why have we stopped?
- I told you to open up!
- The door's stuck!
- There's a dead man.
- Dead? Who's dead?
- I don't know him.
- I think I know him from somewhere.
Really?
Why didn't you stop after seeing that dead man?
- I didn't see him.
- Not true, liar! You slowed down!
- No, I didn't...
- Go to hell.
The truck is from the building site.
- But there's blood there..
- Pass me a blanket or cloth.
- Here you go Sergeant.
- At the next stop, call the Marshal in town.
Tell him, that Salvatore Colasberna
was shot near Fiore.
Is that clear? So go on!
Get on board! Quickly!
I knew, that he'd end up like that.
Some people are dead even when they're alive.
He said he could live without friends.
And now look at him.
- Who's living in that house?
- Someone called Nicolosi. He's not at home.
He went to work early in the morning.
I spoke to his wife.
She said that she didn't hear the gunshots.
Didn't hear anyone, didn't see anyone,
doesn't know anybody, doesnt go anywhere.
- Hello?. Wolf calling wolf
- Roger! Wolf speaking. Tell me Marshal.
- Give me the captain.
- Right away Marshal.
- When did you find him?
- At 7:15.
Here in Sicily they're killing Christians
before sunrise.
They only killed one this afternoon,
Pistilli the public notary
he likes to sleep.
Roger! Captain, they've killed
Salvatore Colasberna near Fiore.
- Colasberna? The one from the construction firm?
- Yes, the owner.
Any idea of the motive yet Marshal?
Perhaps because of the new road?
It's created a lot of interest recently.
Here's La Stella's building firm.
La Stella is that fat slob who drinks a lot.
It's him that built those farmhouses
on marshland.
The house that was smashed by
a cow was built by his firm.
He held a meeting with all the
foremen and said that..
I know, he said 'Whoever does houses with
concrete instead of sand and cowpat is a fool'.
- Or a cop!
- No, no, a fool. It's very important not to be a fool.
A fool is almost as bad as being a cuckold
- but a cuckold is the worst of all.
- They're like flies on a corpse.
- They won't find a thing..
That's Pizzuco,
he has a cousin in parliament.
And a criminal record as long
as the road he's building.
- He has a lot of power around here!
- A man of respect, eh?
- Exactly that Captain!
- And where was he yesterday morning at six?
At home. Sleeping like all the others:
Pizzuco, La Stella, Lancia, Colossimo..
All of them new in town..respectable
citizens that don't kill anymore
Perhaps they'll order a hit...and pay.
Not a lot but they pay.
Stop..look who's walking around here.
Rosa Nicolosi.
She's the woman who lives
near the scene of the crime.
- What are you doing here Rosa Nicolosi?
- I was picking some chicory and cabbages.
And with so much land around why right here?
Why come and look for chicory and
cabbages right here?
And why not?
Am I doing something wrong?
The chicory doesn't belong to anyone,
it's just chicory.
Everything belongs to someone,
even the chicory.
Come on, get on.
We'll take you to your house.
Don't be afraid,
we're not taking you to the barracks!
Well? He's talking to you!
Move it!
Come on, get moving.
The shots must have come from there,
just after the bend.
From there, Colasberna was wounded and the truck
probably went on another hundred metres
up to where the jeep is.
that's where the killer caught up
with Colasberna - and it was all over.
From there, someone must have seen
or at least heard the shots.
- And where does your husband work?
- Wherever he can.
- Does he work every day?
- No. Only when he's lucky.
- What time does he leave the house in the morning?
- I don't know..it depends.
- And what time does he get back in the evening?
- He doesn't have a timetable.
And this morning?
What time did he leave?
Look Rosa, you don't have to be afraid.
I'm not accusing your husband.
If he wanted to kill someone,
he wouldn't do it in front of his house.
It's perhaps a little obvious?!
I'm only looking for information.
Come on, give me a hand?
Excuse me..but where are you from?
- I'm from Parma.
- Near Milan?
- Yes, near Milan.
- And they don't kill anyone there?
Sure they do!
But in a different way.
And do the people there testify
...without fear?
No, it's the same for us too.
Tight-lipped as usual..but not from fear.
It's because the people don't want any
nuisance, or to waste time with the trial.
We've got plenty of time here.
And plenty of chicory too!
Why did you go looking for it near the building site?
Because it's better there!
Chicory is chicory, cabbage is
cabbage - it grows everywhere!
Did you see your husband last night?
Did you hear him come back?
So he might not have come back at all?
So then, say it:
"He didn't come back"
Say it:
"He left yesterday morning and didn't return"
Sometimes he doesn't come back.
Ok, so let's say he didn't return.
Why didn't he come back?
Well, I'll tell you.
Because he doesn't want to be interrogated.
Because he doesn't want to talk.
Because he doesn't want to be implicated.
Ok..Please, when he returns
tell him to come to the station.
Or at least he can call us.
It's just a formality.
Dominici!
Come on, let's go!
This is Colasberna's building site.
They're off for the funeral.
Was Colasberna friends with
the others: Pizzuco, Lancia, La Stella?
No, just a hello and a goodbye.
Colasberna was the reserved type.
He only got along with his brothers.
He was a decent, honest worker.
To steal money from the government
you need company
and he didn't agree with it.
Understand?
He also had a police record too though.
I questioned some of the truck drivers
that are always on this road.
No-one saw or heard anything.
A population of blind and deaf,
but when they shoot - then they can see!
Boy can they see!
Hey! Why are you still using bags?
Isn't it better to use tankers like they are?
- We can't rent the tankers.
- And why is that?
- We just simply can't..
- Have you had some trouble?
They threw an excavator down into a
ravine but they didn't press charges,true?
What type of sentence did Colasberna have?
Six months in confinement for
Anti-Fascism when he was 25.
- But these aren't criminal offences.
- Sorry but according to the law it is.
Then it should also apply to the
President of the Republic too.
Ok. Write down what I dictate to you.
Salvatore Colasberna was killed,
because he was allowed to win a deal
against a friend of the friends,
that paid for the outsourcing of a quarter
of the new road
and he didn't want to share this with anyone.
Signed: "A friend"
No thank you.
I don't smoke.
- So, he was killed for this?
- We knew nothing about it.
How's that? You just put it
in an anonymous letter to me!
You both took turns to write
one word each.
It's a bit of a primitive system
but thanks all the same.
But we didn't write anything Captain.
Ok...but in order to continue,
I have to know more.
And what should we tell you?
Take a look at this lovely map.
There are many flags - black, red and green.
The black flags are for unsolved murders,
red for the ones we're still investigating,
and the green flags for the cases
which have been resolved and punished.
There still aren't many of those...!
The murder of your brother has a red flag.
It's up to you to turn it green.
- So?
- I see a lot more of the black flags Captain.
You're saying that you don't talk
because the killers are still on the loose
but the killers are on the loose
because you won't talk!
And now we're back at the start again!
Fine...
Your letter will remain anonymous,
I don't want you living in fear.
You can go.
- Our respects Captain.
- Good day.
Rosa Nicolosi
Captain, it's Rosa Nicolosi.
Come in, come in.
Come on in, Rosa.
Have a seat. Don't worry,
nobody can see you.
Aren't you going to ask me anything?
I didn't summon you.
I have nothing to ask you.
He didn't come back..
You said that sometimes he doesn't return..
You weren't worried then...
So why are you worried now?
It's been four days.
Ok. Marshal, let's get someone
to look for this Nicolosi.
Yes sir.
But where should we look?
Far away or here nearby?
- Has someone threatened you?
- My husband has a clean record.
I know, I know...but it's difficult
to look for a needle in a haystack
and your husband, in Sicily...
is like a needle..
Maybe at this moment your
husband needs help?...A lot of help.
And what's his wife doing?
She's silent. Doesn't want to help.
- Just what kind of wife is she?
- I'd give my blood for him.
The other morning near your house
there were four rifle shots.
Where was your husband
when they were fired?
Now then Rosa, we're all alone.
No-one can see us.
We won't write anything down.
So then, where was your husband?
- He left early...at five.
- In the dark?
- Yes
- Did you hear the shots?
- Yes I did.
- Did you take a look outside?
No, I thought that it was a hunter.
- But it's not hunting season.
- And how should I know?...
- Where did your husband go?
- To look for work.
- At the building sites?
- Maybe...
So when we saw you that morning
on the road you were looking for him?
- No..I was looking for...
- Chicory and cabbages..
Well perhaps he disappeared
for another reason?
And if so Rosa,
for once, tell me, ok?
- It appears that she has a lover.
- Says who?
Don Ciccio the barber,
he told Corporal Torres.
Seems everyone knows about it.
If you'll excuse me, I have to go.
My daughter's alone at home.
Very well.
- Captain, promise me you'll look for him?
- We'll look for him.
God bless you.
- And who is this lover?
- Well, they didn't say but it's clear it's not Rosa's first time.
It's probably a woman who's been gossiping .
What else do you know?
They also say that her head is
full of strange ideas.
One time she left home to go to
Palermo to be a shop assistant.
Well, I'd hardly call that a scandal.
It's a job like any other.
Sure. But such a beautiful woman
must be unhappy to be the wife of an idler.
- So why did she marry?
- She got pregnant at 16 years old.
- I understand..
- And where's she going?
To Don Mariano Arena.
A wealthy man..
..he has a daughter studying in Switzerland
and a fat bank account.
A high-flyer who's made it good.
A woman's here, she's saying she wants
to speak to you. She's in the front room.
My respects...
- Who are you?
- Rosa Nicolosi, Tano Nicolosi's wife.
And what do you want from me?
Sorry, but my husband hasn't been
back home for four days.
And you've come to look for him here?
No, I was just thinking that if you wanted,
you could help me to find him?
Why not go to the Carabinieri?
They're the ones who look for missing people.
I've already been to the Carabinieri.
You did good.
It's your duty.
I told them that my husband hadn't
returned...nothing else.
I didn't tell them what I could have.
I didn't name anyone.
And what can I do?
If I see your husband,
I'll tell him not to make you worry.
We've always voted
like you wanted us to.
Good. Santuzza!
Come here, Rosa.
Give something to this good woman,
she has a young girl.
Give them one of our hens, ok?
Wait, Rosa.
Ah, give it here!
Here. Eat it tomorrow, ok.
Wait, I'll give you
some jars of marmalade too.
Take these.
- Now, go back home and don't worry, ok?
- God bless you.
Beautiful woman. All beautiful -
the hips...the breasts...
It's odd...that just today Don Ciccio the
Barber wants us to know that
that Nicolosi had a lover?
Don't you believe him?
Look, I'm not exactly left enchanted
by Rosa Nicolosi's ways...
Maybe she's a liar or very cunning.
But what I'd like to know
is if they're going
to start playing tricks to try and
change the motive of the crime.
Which is?
What can you find very cheap here in Sicily?
What thing can be found at the
street corners or on the stalls?
- I don't know.
- Honour. Honour, Marshal!
It's the answer to it all.
We must look for Nicolosi at once
and pull those horns off of his head!
- Marshal, you have a son studying engineering, right?
- Yes, why? What's happened?
- Is he afraid of Carabinieri too?
- No! That would be the last straw!
Excuse me, but have you taken exams
on construction?
- Of course!
- He took thirty!
I want to prove that everyone around
here stole except for Colasberna.
That is - poor construction
and falsified technical data.
You'll need a civil engineer, an expert.
I'm only a student.
If I wait for the court to appoint an expert..
..the investigation will also be at a
stand still for a year.
If the State mechanism isn't working,
it's not the fault of me or my generation.
Captain, my son didn't follow in my footsteps,
he only thinks about his degree.
Yes, I can see!.
And when he finishes his studies..
..his employers will be those that
build these roads.
- And if there'll be a killer amongst them?
- It's not up to engineers to look for killers.
It's up to us all!
If you don't need me anymore...
Bye Dad.
Colasberna wanted things to be clean.
He was stubborn.
He didn't want to pay for protection.
And he refused to blackmail.
Captain!..
But those who pay protection know
that  they'll never get inspected,
therefore they can go on quietly building
their bridges with manure!
If we don't get rid of these people,
they'll kill someone else.
And in the meantime we're still looking
for Colasberna's killer.
And this is my fear above all,
that it's not the last of the killings.
This one's capable of coming
here every day to get on our nerves.
- Add a bit more cement!
- Ok
Without anonymous letters or informers,
we'd be going round in circles
and you know that Captain.
I'm sorry Captain, but it's my experience
that makes me a bit controversial.
You're still enthusiastic
and without kids at university.
Who is our informer here?
Parineddu, I'm here.
At your service Captain.
Parineddu, do you know where
Colasberna was killed?
Yes, he was found dead there.
Murdered.
- By who?
- By who...
Wake up! I asked you who?
- If only I knew..
- So what do you know?
Captain, let's not talk here.
Let's get away from the road.
I need to stay alive Captain.
It's in the interest of justice.
Yes sir, there are plenty of captains and
carabinieri - but informers are rare.
You mustn't send me off to the
slaughter in such a hurry!
Look, if you don't let out what you know,
I'll send you to the butchers right away!
Look, I'm running out of patience with you.
Have you seen Rosa Nicolosi?
She's watching us.
She's switched off the light but
she still spying.
She wants to know what two people are
doing talking near the spot where he died.
Forget Rosa Nicolosi.
Talk instead!
Talk, talk, talk!
Captain, the informer merely hints, he doesn't reveal.
The real truth lies between a thousand lies,
because the informer doesn't trust the carabinieri.
And you told me now that if I didn't talk
tomorrow you'd tell the killers
that I betrayed them, eh?
- And so?
- Or you can summon me to court, as a witness.
- No. I can assure you.
- But who knows?
The betrayal ends up being
wholly unneccessary and turns into disgrace.
Captain, betrayal is a living for me.
This evening I betray the mafia,
tomorrow the Carabineri.
It's balanced.
A little bit for everyone!
Good, now get to the point.
The order came from the cement,
but who was to shoot was decided by a card game.
Two shots, and a cuckold met
the King of Diamonds.
It's not true that cuckolds are lucky!
- And so the cuckold is Nicolosi?.
- Easy, Captain! Not so fast..
We're talking about an imaginary cuckold.
Nameless, just simply a cuckold.
But whoever murdered Colasberna, killed him
because of cement, and not for horns.
Careful Captain.
There is a catch, but you can't see it.
So Parineddu,
you're also in with them too?
Captain, if you're not happy with me
and don't want give me the money,
you can pay me another time
when you feel more satisfied.
How do you manage to be an informer?
You..you're scared stiff!
There's always a little bit of fear, no?.
Or perhaps not you?
Look, with the help of your information,
before I arrived here
the previous person in charge arrested two
fugitives and a smuggler.
Why so much small talk this time Parineddu?
Is it hot stuff?
So they're big shots, eh?
Powerful people?
Captain, cement and horns...
the name of the king of diamonds..
Try to talk to that pretty woman.
If you can find a way.
- Rosa! Rosa Nicolosi!
- Who is it?
- Captain Bellodi.
- What do you want?
I need to talk to you.
I'm sorry, I have bad news for you.
Your husband's been killed.
They shot him.
We don't know who it was,
but we're searching for him.
Zecchinetta!
Zecchinetta?
He killed Colasberna?
- Yes!  - Your husband saw him
and he knew that he'd been seen?
I told him when I heard the shots..
..I told him..
Don't leave the house!...
Don't go out!..
Why didn't he listen to me?
No, no Rosa! Calm yourself,
it's not true! It's not true..
I made it up..
We still don't know anything
about your husband.
I needed a name...
I'm sorry.
How could you!
You do what you want, eh?
- I have to find the killer.
- And my husband? Where is he?
We're still searching for him.
So, that morning after he saw Zecchinetta,
what did he do?
I know, I know
what you want to say to me..
You want to say to me:
"Go to hell dirty cop"
You shouldn't have said what you
did to me...that he was dead..
It's not a joke.
Who is this 'Zecchinetta'?
It's not his real name.
He's called that because he plays (cards), no?
The name, Rosa!
I don't know.
Didn't your husband ever tell you?
- No.
- And you've never seen him in person?
No.
And why did you go to see Don Mariano?
To see whether I could sell him
something...some eggs.
Now..
The plot for 200 million lira,
goes to you.
The one for 250 million is for La Stella.
It's a nice dowry for his daughter's wedding.
We'll leave the 50 million plot to the
brothers of our late friend Salvatore Colasberna.
Martino the bishop's nephew expected some too..
I don't want to ruin the bishop's nephew!
The plot for 50 million is for the
Colasberna brothers.
There's nothing better to help forget
the dead...than economic difficulties.
They'll lose everything they have.
They'll be inspected every day
with routine checks and then..
..occasionally, some little accidents as well..
As for Martino, I'll give him
a waste disposal contract.
Refuse has good returns.
No offence, but his Excellency had
already promised that contract to my cousin.
His Excellency can't promise anything.
He can only handle his affairs..
..because I take care of things here.
And he handles Rome.
- I agree
- Ok
Ok with me also
Me too
Hey, it's lively out there..
Look how the captain's trying to do his best.
They've arrested someone.
Geraci, Cinisi, Passatempo...
- And Zecchinetta!
- Zecchinetta? - Yeah..
- And who's that one?
- Parineddu.
What happened?
- He said they were playing zecchinetta (cards).
- Where?
At Parineddu's house.
You can tell His Excellency, that it isn't
good to have a gung-ho captain like him here.
Saro, bring up some ice cream.
Ignazio! Five ice creams!
Look at that..greeting each other..
My respects..my respects..
and here they are still, these
big shots, they're not going anywhere.
Perhaps they're wondering if I've arrested
those guys for gambling or for something else.
We need to let them know.
Captain, do you plan to let
those we arrested walk free?
- Absolutely!
- And Parineddu, right?
- Sure, and him too, otherwise he's done for.
- Shall we let them go then?
Not right away, later.
All..except for one.
They play (cards) every day,
and the carabinieri never came before.
But it's the first time they played
at Parineddu's house.
That's true.
Never played there before...
So, Zecchinetta goes to play at Parineddu's
house...and then the cops arrive...
The captain's watching us
...with binoculars.
I don't like binoculars...
What are you doing?
You think you know me?
Yeah, look at me...look at my profile too!
You're nobody!
Try and touch us if you have the guts..
Don't assume that these cops are all stupid!
There are those that can tear out
your tongue along with all your secrets.
Men who were born cops,
just as others were born priests.
Bellodi is one that was born a cop..
Parineddu on the other hand..
was born a spy.
Zecchinetta hasn't come out yet.
What did you expect?
They want to squeeze a confession out of him.
We've got a traitor among us,
I'm sure of it.
Don Mariano..
Don Mariano!
May I have a word?.
I have to talk to you.
- Play...well, speak!
- In private!
In private with you?!
And who are you, the Lord?
As you wish then.
Let's go for a walk.
Don Mariano,
did you write that letter?
- Of course, don't worry.
- Thank you.
Zecchinetta sent me and urged me
to tell you that his lips are sealed.
Zecchinetta? And who's he?
In my opinion he can spend his whole life in there.
That's what he said,
so that's what I'm telling you.
Parineddu!
How was the game?
Well, I won..but they
blew the whistle on us all
so I guess we all lost in the end..
You shouldn't have gone
up against the Santa Chiesa.
What can you do now? Nothing.
I'm just saying that you're
dead in the heart of your friends.
- ..34..35..36..
- Let's go Zecchinetta, the captain wants to question you.
Just a moment, I have to do my exercises first.
..37..38..
- Move it!
- One moment, I need to do something..
Come on!
..I should introduce myself
whilst doing my trousers up?
My respects Captain!
I knew the captain,
who was here before you.
A man of good heart!
Captain, if you want to beat me up,
I've something I must tell you first,
I suffered from pleurisy, they
took an x-ray, did you know that?
So, how are we doing Mr Marchica,
alias 'Zecchinetta'?
Given your past crimes, I can't let you go.
However, no one will ever
know what you tell me.
And what do I have to tell you?
I want to get to ones at the top and
if you help me, you won't regret it.
- If I may Captain...
- Very well. So let's talk about the game.
We played a lot to pass time.
There aren't any free women in this country!
And a wife just isn't enough.
Someone who is content with just
one woman loses their imagination.
For example, when I'm in bed with her,
I always think of Stalin.
- How much did you lose?
- Me!?
- You.
- A little.
- How much is 'a little'?
- Let's say about twenty.
- Do you lose every day?
- No, some days I'm up.
- No, you're not the winning type.
- The testimony of your friends shows,
that in the last two weeks you
lost around 200,000 lira.
- Says who? I did win!
- Against who?
Someone from 'out of town', let's say.
My understanding is that the money you
lost at cards is money that Pizzuco gave you.
Why did Pizzuco pay you?
Captain, Pizzuco never gave me any money.
Whoever said that is big...
...a bastard, I know!
- There, exactly!
So you won a game worth 200,000
lira against a foreigner,
and then you lost this money whilst
playing against friends. Is that so?
- Shall we say it was like that?
- ..yeah, it was like that.
- Write that..take it all down.
- No wait,
Marchica may want to clarify.
Have a think about it.
There's nothing to think about Captain.
Liars need to think.
What I'm saying is the truth!
But you Captain..
before you talk you have to think
because you tell lies.
You tell lies for a living! Get it?
- Yeah, yeah. You should be an actor.
- Heh, well...
- Yeah, why not? You've got talent!
- C'mon, you're teasing me Captain!
- Where did you put the rifle?
- What? Which rifle?
The rifle with which you shot Nicolosi?
- Me!?
- Yes, you.
Nicolosi?
Captain! Me!?...
"Me? Me? Me? Me?" - Don't you
know to say anything other than 'Me'?
Ah, you didn't know Nicolosi?
Have a good think about it.
Yeah, I knew him...
so?...
Captain..a bit of that beer wouldn't hurt, right?
Thanks, thanks!..
You said that you 'knew' him, you
want to say that you know he's dead?
The marshal said that I killed him!
I said that you fired - but now
you just clarified that you killed him.
- Captain!
- Yes..
..because Marchica, you
have been accused of murdering Nicolosi.
Haven't you realised?
Prove it! You need proof!
What motive would I have to do it?
Where is it?!
What is this motive?
The motive? Here it is - Nicolosi died because
he saw who killed Colasberna.
He had seen the killer.
- And who killed this Colasberna?
- You! Admit it Zecchinetta, it was you!
Me? Me?! Pull out my fingernails,
and break my fingers
and you'll have a great confession!
Let go! Leave me alone!
I'll jump out the window!
You're taking advantage cos I'm alone..
Let go of me! Let go of me!
I can't take it, cowards! I want to die!
Captain, if you'll allow me to go free,
I'll give you a nice present..
..I'll give you the name of Colasberna's
killer and the motive.
- We're listening.
- Nicolosi killed Colasberna...
...because he caught him
in an awkward position!
- Such as?
- He was on top of his wife, Rosa..
..they were lovers.
Everyone knew that they were lovers.
So then tell me who killed Nicolosi, after he
killed Colasberna to protect his honour?
Nicolosi? Why are you saying that he's dead?
You should say he's missing!
To say that someone is dead, you need a body!
Captain, look for Nicolosi
and let the innocent people like me go free.
Go write it down! I'll sign everything!
I won't keep anything back!
So, after I'm done, can I go?
After I've signed the agreement?
I'm sorry Mr Marchica..
I'm afraid that you'll have to stay away from
your home and friends a little while longer.
Cut it out with this "Mr Marchica".
Zecchinetta's my name and I'm no "Mister".
Get a belt and thrash me!
Break my bones!
Anything but a "mister" and why don't you drop the formalities!
Come on Sergeant! Don't think
about my pleurisy, just beat me!
Don't tempt us!
Read it and sign.
You're cruel-hearted Captain.
Because I have a black mark against me
everything that's happened with
Zecchinetta is my fault.
But you're wrong.
I'm a gentleman.
I'm back on the right path.
And the names of those who saw
Colasberna and Rosa Nicolosi
doing their filth out in the field?
Don't you want to know?
No. At the moment we're only
interested in knowing why
Pizzuco gave you 200,00 lira?
- Business!
Despicable! You're shameful Zecchinetta.
You took just 200,000 lira for two hits.
Well, I'll go now Captain,
but I'll tell you - you're too arrogant!
Too arrogant!
Hey, does the Captain believe in God?
- Move it!
- So can I do it (pee) now?
Go on, move it!
What did he mean by 'arrogant'?
An arrogant person is someone
that wants to know the truth.
Balloons for sale!
100 lira for one!
- Good day Don Mariano
- Good day
Don Mariano...may I have a word?
They put a bomb in the captain's car.
It's ready to explode.
Which car is it?
And where's Pizzuco?
We went inside the bar
to wait for the fireworks.
Greetings Don Mariano.
And so, Don Pizzuco?
You're doing things your own way now?
Without my permission?
If Zecchinetta sings,
I'll be the first that goes down.
- Who took care of the job?
- The boys.
The captain..
Toruzzo...
So you think that with the captain dead,
no one will question Zecchinetta any more?
That Captain's no good for us here.
If no one thinks to take him out,
then I will!
- You're without honour..
- Don Mariano!
One who puts his friends and their
children in danger is a man without honour.
Captain!
You've got a flat tyre, probably a nail.
What a pity, it a new tyre as well...
We can fit the spare tyre for you?
No,  don't want to inconvenience you.
We have our own mechanic.
It's Sunday today, let him rest!
We can do it for you in two minutes captain!
- Go! Go! Go! Put the hand brake on.
- My respects captain!
- Thanks.
- Can I get you a coffee?
- Thanks, perhaps another time.
- With all my heart, ok!
Now try to do what I tell you.
Today, you'll go and see Rosa Nicolosi.
But why?
What does Rosa have to do with us?
- I said that you must go to her house!
- And do what?
That's up to you,
go to bed with her for all I care,
but just stay there for a little while.
Nothing else. Understood?
- Thanks!
- Oh no, no!
- Your keys...
- What, are you joking?!
- God forbid, I wouldn't dream of it!
- Always at your service captain!
- Those two are previous offenders Captain.
- C'mon Marshal! It's Sunday today.
We'll need to tell the mechanic to remove
the dynamite they've put in the car.
Bastards!
I'll slap them straight inside!
Calm down...
Strange. First they rigged it but then
they changed their minds. Why?
Maybe he'd be able to tell us.
- You really believe that?
- Of course! Look at him, he stopped in front
of us on purpose. As if he wants us to
know or tell us something.
Come on, why did you stop?
Are you an informer?
Calm down, I can see you.
I can see you very well.
But remember that it's me
who upholds the law here.
You going against me?
Then I accept your challenge.
Understand? He's telling us
that he has powerful friends
and that it's better to leave him alone.
That's right.
What shall we do Captain?
We need an answer.
We'll prepare a warrant.
- For Don Mariano?
- No, not yet.
What are you doing Captain?
You're not starting it up are you!?
Don't worry, Don Mariano's
allowing us to live a bit more.
Parineddu!
My respects!
Keep an eye on my friend
Pizzuco for me today.
- And then?
- Nothing..just make note of it.
- Good day, Don Mariano.
- Is the secretary in?
- Yes.
- I'd like to speak to him.
At once, please do come in!
Good day, Rosa!
May I?
- Good day..
- Heh heh, what a beautiful, naked, young girl!.
Why are you hiding?
- She's embarrassed.
- Wait, I'll help you!
There! She looks like
a queen in a carriage!
- There.
- There?    - Yes.
Here we go! You're not looking at me, eh?
There you are little one!
- Dry and dress yourself.
- You have a beautiful daughter!
She'll be as pretty as you when she's older.
I remember you were just like that.
- I watched you grow up Rosa.
- So, what did you want to tell me?
I'll have a glass of wine, if that's ok?
I came to tell you that you're beautiful.
Doesn't that please you?
What do you mean?
Haven't you bought news of my husband?
Don Mariano told me the other day:
"If I know something, I'll inform you"
- Ah, Don Mariano..and what else did he tell you?
- Not to worry..
So don't worry.
- In that case, why did you come?
- Out of curiousity.
Ah! Come here beautiful.
I have something for you, come!
Come on, go outside to play, eh!
Bye..
Not too far!
[Sigh] You've ruined my life Rosa.
All those times that you passed in front
of my house or when I'd meet you and
you'd look at me with those eyes. Y'know Rosa?
Don't be a fool,
I've never once thought about you.
That's what you say!
Now that you've had
your drink, you can go.
- What a light dress you've got on..
- Your hand...Your hand!
What did you think? You think
you can do that if I don't want it?
Ah, take a walk! You'll just have
to make do with your whore of a wife!
Don't touch me with those
hands they make me sick!
Think you can molest a woman?!
Get out!
Rosa, what's the matter?
You going to cry now?
So you came here just to
make yourself comfortable.
And you're not afraid?
You're not afraid that
my husband will find out?
Why aren't you afraid?
Why?
You must tell me why!
Ehh! These Sicilian women!
Always so dramatic!
I want to move to Milan!
A breath of fresh air!
Rosa, if you come with me,
I'll separate from my wife, eh?
Will you come?...No?
Cheerio then!
What're you all dong standing around?!
Is this how you earn
the money that I pay you?
Ah, Captain!...
May I offer you something?
A beer?
Or some orangeade if you want?
Mr Pizzuco, you must come with us.
You're under arrest.
Under arrest? If they've killed someone
between 3 and 4 (o'clock)
I can tell you that I was at the house of a woman whose name
I won't mention...
unless it's absolutely necessary.
- Come on, give me your wrists.
- Sure, wait...just wait!...
- You want to resist?
- What's the rush? That I'm going to run away?
- Control yourself, Pizzuco!
- Bravo, congratulations!
It takes all these over-paid members of the State
to arrest a decent man like me!
Poor Italian tax-payers!
Take a good look,
my face doesn't have any scratches
and I'm in perfect health!
And I hope to be when they release me!
Luigi, don't pay them for the time
they were standing around doing nothing!
Inform my mother and tell her to go straight
to the lawyer! And you, wash my car!
You wench!
They've arrested my son!
They've arrested my innocent son!
We had to get a lawyer,
so you need to pay me back
the money we spent, wench!
So, write...
"A greengrocer"
"A greengrocer buys five kilos.."
- Rosa Nicolosi?
- Yes..
- Are you the wife of Tano Nicolosi?
- Yes.
- Your husband sent me.
- Where is he?
- Palermo, he's working there.
- Palermo?
And he's left me here?
Without any word!?
- Where's he working?
- I don't know. I met him in the pub.
And when he found out that I usually
take this route he gave me this envelope.
- Are you sure that it was him?
- If it wasn't him, he said that he was. And why?
- Not a single word?...
- There wasn't time, but he sent the money.
Wait...
Is it him?
- Yes, it's him.
- Where's he staying? The address?...
- He didn't give it to me.
- But didn't he say when he'll return?
He said he'd return as soon as he could..
..but with an expression as though
he was not able to. As if he was in hiding.
Wait! Hey, wait!
Who is it that sent you?
Careful, even though he's away,
if you don't behave like a wife he'll know.
Out the way!
Caterina!
[Singing] Open up!
I don't want to stay in here!
To me it seems like
you're taking advantage too much!
- What's going on Marshall?
- Zecchinetta's yelling that he wants to get out.
He says that the number of days
that we're allowed to detain him are over.
He says that it's his right to have
either an arrest warrant or freedom.
- Captain, are we going to observe the law?
- Sergeant!
Hand over Zecchinetta's
personal belongings and let him go.
Captain, do you really
want to let him go free?
- Of course!
- Didn't the judge sign the arrest warrants?
I've got both of them in my pocket.
But Zecchinetta must enjoy a taste of freedom
and I want you to take him to the square.
It's time to trick him and his friends.
Get out.
Sorry Captain! Me being released
must give you great pain!
Who was it that you got yesterday?
- My respects Don Vincenzo!
- Ah, so they released you Zecchinetta?
Hello my friend!
See you around.
- Yeah, yeah see you later!
- Ignazio!
- A nice sweet black coffee!
- At once.
Did I leave the window open?
Shall we have some fresh lemonade General?
You wanted to know
who we arrested yesterday?
- A dear friend, who you know very well.
- Me?
Pizzuco. Look up at Don Mariano's
terrace..Pizzuco isn't there..
You know, he told us a
load of things about you...
- About me?
- He says that you do whatever he wants.
Your hand is shaking.
Drink up..drink this coffee slowly
so that you'll remember it..
They don't make it as
good as that in prison you know..
You've gone all pale!
Who played this trick on me?
Don Mariano?
- Damn cuckold!
- His mother, wife and sister...
He'll pay for this with tears of blood!
That great big cuckold..
They make the 'horn' sign
and they're all happy.
- Marshal!
- Here!
Prepare a false confession from Pizzuco.
It must say that it was
Zecchinetta who killed Colasberna.
This confession has to be like a work of art!
Like an expose of the mafia code.
A confession that when
Zecchinetta reads it, he feels betrayed.
- And if Pizzuco confesses first?
- Let's hope not
Zecchinetta goes down first.
Prepare the confession!
- And the signature?
- You want to put a real signature
in a false confession?
You sign it!
It could be amusing for me,
I'm good at imitating handwriting!
You'll see, it'll be a good job Captain.
Yes, we should do it -
but without enjoying it too much
..and at least with a little bit of disgust.
Rosa, can we have a photo?
Let's have one Rosa.
Come on, just one!
Hi Annuzza, how are you..
- Bless you, Don Mariano!
- I can wait, I don't want to rush you.
- Here's to you, Don Mariano!
- Cheers..
Right, let's read all the bad news, eh!.
It seems as though someone's looking for you.
Who is it?
Don Mariano, I'd like to
talk to you if you don't mind?
- And who are you?
- Nicolosi's wife, don't you remember?
Rosa please, I'm trying to work here.
Excuse me
but can I speak to you alone?
Alone?
You can't here...
Tonight...when you're alone...
then I'll pay you a visit!
You're provoking me girl,
what should I tell you?
If it's so urgent, tell me!
Speak, we're among friends here.
I heard that my husband is in Palermo.
Someone on a motorbike
came and told me this morning.
Palermo? Good!
Beautiful city. Lucky him!
Is he really in Palermo?
Is he in Palermo or here under the ground?!
You still insist on questioning
me where your husband is!
What am I, your pimp!?
No! No you are not my pimp!
I don't have a pimp!
I have nothing to be ashamed of!
In Palermo it looks like they've
uncovered a house full of women,
from the cellar, all the way up to the top floor.
Nice, eh?
- We need to have one here too!
- But you have to find the goods first?
There's some right there!
What is it?
Are you offended?
Nobody asked you!
The motorcycle was stolen.
A man that comes from Palermo
with a letter from your husband,
isn't the type that arrives riding
a stolen motorcycle. Understand?
A thief doesn't bring money to the
wife of a guy who is known at the pub.
If you follow?..
So, it was faked then?
Perhaps it's not even true that a
man brought money to the house?
- What?
- Yes, come in.
Maybe you're lying to help someone?
What do you mean 'someone'?
And who should I help?
Who can assure me that Don Mariano
didn't send you to purposely confuse things?
So that's what you think?
Even though I came here?!
Yes, but you also went to Don Mariano's.
And it wasn't to sell your eggs..
But if it was your woman, wouldn't
you go to look and to ask someone?
I'm doing it for my husband!
Just accept it,
they murdered him.
Yes, the same way they killed Colasberna.
He was too dangerous alive.
But they want us to believe he is alive.
And to save themselves,
they discredit you.
At the moment they're coming up
with a false testimonies to make out
that you were Colasberna's lover.
Yes, and sooner or later they'll have to judge them.
I've only ever been with my husband.
No-one else has ever seen me naked!
Ok, let's suppose that I'm mistaken,
and that he returns home..
..and when he returns, what does he find?
A person that decent women
don't stop to say hello to, someone
that men stop on the street as if they
could take her to bed whenever they wanted!
Well it's better that he doesn't return then..
Rosa, let these people hang!
Where do you think I live Captain?!
I live among these people,
and when I walk past it's as if they're
undressing me with their eyes. I feel naked!
When I tell you that eyewitnesses saw
Colasberna together with that woman..
..Rosa Nicolosi. It's a precise account
of which there cannot be any doubt about.
Sure the cuckold - that is,
the husband, knew nothing..
Either that or he pretended not to know anything.
This is something you should investigate.
So when the husband discovered them,
he killed Colasberna?
- Exactly!
- Sit down!
After being cuckolded don't you think
he'd have wanted to kill the wife before the lover?
Perhaps he would?
If he's a man of honour he would..
But if he's not a man of honour,
you should investigate this point too.
So you're trying to tell me that the
deceased came down from heaven
or from hell and killed his wife?
What a clown you are..
If he comes back,
he'll come back from Palermo
you can't send money and
letters to the family from heaven!
But I think that someone else sent that money to Rosa.
- Who's that?
- Someone's who's alive. You my dear!
- Me?
- Yes!
- I might have given her some money.
- Ah, you see!
I bought her the money personally,
because I 'had' her in her house, if you will..
So if you're Rosa's lover,
then you killed Colasberna
out of jealousy and the husband
because he discovered you both.
And Pizzuco ends up in jail.
Nonsense!
It can't be..
..because I was with her after
the murder and I also have the proof!
She's a hot blooded woman, you don't know her.
She's money hungry, wants everything!
But she has skin like velvet..
If I had the choice of how I wanted
to die I'd choose to die on top of her!
Well done Rosa! You were Pizzuco's
lover and you didn't tell us a thing.
- Lover? No. We'd just meet from time to time.
- They want to ruin me!
In short Rosa, did you or didn't you
have a relationship with him? Yes or no?
Of course not!
With someone like him!?
- Then you were Colasberna's lover?
- No! No! No!
But it's right that you believe them
more than me. He has powerful friends..
..and I'm all alone.
- Rosa, don't talk rubbish.
- Nah, I expected it..
..making a scene by crying.
Women are allowed to.
And you..
Lies, right?
- No.
- Sit down.
Instead, why don't you tell the
Captain who your husband worked for?
For me? For La Stella?
For Colosimo perhaps? Eh?
I'll tell him who he worked for.
No, I'll tell you.
Last year he worked for 120 days
in Colasberna's company.
Carry on, Pizzuco.
I'll continue. And why did he work for Colasberna?
Why, Rosa? Why?
What does that mean?
So, you do business with Don Mariano
because your wife is his mistress?
Calm down!
Damn it..Fine, I'm not going to
rise to her provocations.
- Yes, you're a cuckold!
- It's useless to deny about us
I have witnesses.
Ask Parineddu, he knows everything.
- He saw me at Rosa's house.
- No! It's not true!
It's not true that I was at your house?
- By tricking me!
- There! I knew it, now she's going to cry!
- Go ahead Rosa.
- He came into my house by tricking me.
Yeah, yeah.."tricks"!
He tried to take me by force but couldn't.
I've only taken money from one
man in my life, and that's my husband!
I'm his woman, and no-one elses!
He received money from
Colasberna to turn a blind eye!
Give me back my husband!
What have you done to him?
If he's dead, you killed him!
If he's alive, you know where he is!
Pizzuco...
- Lower your voice.
- Yeah, ok..
And Zecchinetta?
What can you tell me about Zecchinetta?
Listen Captain. You bring me
Nicolosi's body here and then we'll talk.
Rosa, why didn't you tell me that
your husband worked for Colasberna?
You understand that these are facts that can go against you?
That's their business.
It's up to the man to say what to do.
The woman must always keep her mouth shut!
Be careful Rosa!
Because as a result of denying everything,
and remaining silent, you could end
up laying all the blame on others.
Go on. The morning that Colaberna
was killed, tell me what happened?
Captain, I swear on my daughter's head
that Colasberna never touched me!
I know!
I know this!
What I want to know is,
what did your husband do after?
Where did he go?
He didn't tell me.
He didn't tell me...
Ok Rosa, so what shall we do?
Now you can go home and
write me a nice anonymous letter?
Me?
Yes. You can try and
tell me the truth this way.
Listen, I've never done anything like that.
And plus I've already told you the truth.
- Marshal!
- Yes sir?
- You can go now. How's it going?
- He's a tough nut to crack.
Keep at him,
and don't let him sleep.
And tell...
Parineddu
that I want to see him here in town tomorrow.
Ah..and Zecchinetta in my office, now.
Wait a while and then show
him Pizzuco's false confession.
You seem to know everyone,
take a little look at that distinguished gentleman
who's chatting with Don Mariano.
It's not a new face is it?
No..I don't know him.
But come on, that's Minister Botta.
He's a part of the puzzle.
Which 'puzzle'?
He is the link that joins Don Mariano
and Honourable Minister Passarella.
Captain, I don't know him.
I've never seen him before.
Captain...Pizzuco!
- Sit down!
- A signed confession.
You've been done!
Pizzuco accuses you of killing Colasberna!
- Me?! And on whose behalf?
- On your own initiative.
Pizzuco said he confided in you how Colasberna had offended him
And that you offered to avenge him.
But Pizzuco, a man of principle
and opposed to violence, refused.
But you went ahead and
killed Colasberna all the same.
Me? In that case I'm crazy then?!
You killed him because you owed Pizzuco
the 200,000 lira you lost to him in a game.
Pizzuco claims that
after meeting him, you said:
"Partivu pe astutarinni unu,
e mi tucc astutarinni dui"
Which means:
"I set out to kill one but I had to kill two"
- Two?
- Colasberna, and Nicolosi because he saw you.
Nicolosi? And where's his body?!
Did I eat it?!!
Or buried. There's a lot of land out there!
And the rifle? Where did I hide it?
In the....Rosa?
Read it.
Read it if you don't believe.
Bastard!
Eat!..Eat up but don't rush,
your friend Pizzuco signed two of them.
Don Mariano and Pizzuco
are sending you to jail!
To think that if you'd just talk,
it would be them going to prison instead.
Write!
I'll talk now!
So, who gave you the order?
Don Mariano?
And stop defending him as if he was God Almighty!
Don Mariano's got nothing to do with it.
Pizzuco is the one!
- Pizzuco has called you to testify.
- Me?
He says that you saw him at Rosa
Nicolosi's house and wants you to confirm it.
What happened at Rosa's house?
He forced himself upon her.
I saw him from outside.
- And her?
- She was willing enough.
- Are you sure?
- That's how it seemed to me.
That's how it seemed,
or that's how it was?
If I say that Rosa wasn't willing,
they'll want me dead!
But I want to save you.
Well, you go ahead with what
they've told you to say about Rosa.
..but in exchange,
I want something from you.
- What's that?
- You have to help me arrest Don Mariano.
No, Captain. I don't know
anything about Don Mariano.
I can't help you with this.
If you testify against Rosa,
I'll testify against you.
I'll fry you!
How long will you last after that?
But I don't know anything about
Don Mariano. I'd tell you if I did.
I don't believe you.
I always thought that you knew a lot
about Don Mariano but you keep it hush hush.
Enough playing both sides Parineddu!
It's us who pay you, not them.
- I don't want it!
- Don't talk rubbish.
Afterwards, Zecchinetta took
the rifle to Don Mariano's house.
- Did you see him?
- I live near him.
- And why to Don Mariano's?
- Because it's the safest place.
- You have to testify.
- Me!? Captain, our deal?
No court, you said!
That doesn't count anymore.
Don Mariano doesn't go back on his word.
I want him in front of the judge
and I don't want to hear
anything about lack of evidence.
- Pizzuco!
- Zecchinetta! You bastard!
You'll end up worse than Colasberna.
Much worse!
Pizzuco!
You should be a singer! A singer!
- They should cut out your tongue! Lowlife!
- Bastard! Informer! You're a cop!
You're the bloody spy!
Good day Captain.
Pizzuco has confessed
but it took all night to get him to sign!
Naturally, not a single word about Don Mariano
though. The saints are untouchable!
If you'll allow me Captain,
I'm going to get some sleep.
There's something urgent that needs doing.
After that I'll leave you to
sleep even for 24 hours.
Get the men,
we're going to touch those Saints!
- But do we have the proof against him Captain?
- Yes.
Can't we put it off until tomorrow?
His Excellence Passarella arrives today,
to help him to inaugurate the new road.
No. His Excellence Passarella will unveil the road
without having to stand next to that big shot.
The man who builds with manure and blood!
For the prestige of the State
he must do it knowing that Don Mariano
is incarcerated and accused of murder.
Daddy! Daddy! Daddy!
The Carabinieri are here?
But what for? What's happened?
- Destroy it at once!
- What's happening?
Tell me, please, I want to know!
I want to know!
Tomorrow you'll leave for Switzerland.
And whatever you read in the newspapers
about me, it's not true.
Understand? Go on, go!
- What's happening?
- Calm down! Calm down!
- But sir! Only honourable people live here!
- Go and stay in the kitchen.
But if I woke you up at this hour
then there must be a reason, no?
Sure! Alert our friends.
Wake up the ministers in Rome!
Tell everyone!
One moment!..
Please! And to what pleasure do
I owe this visit at such an early hour?
If you cast your mind back to your youth,
you'll recall that this is the time when
the Carabinieri make their visit
when they want to arrest someone.
The search has already begun
and it won't be long until the handcuffs.
Hah, they came to arrest me!
Give it to me.
These are my savings.
The dates of your deposits coincide
exactly with the dates of the public works.
Public works? I'm a land-owner.
I lent some money to friends
and they paid it back to me.
-  You've no part in the construction companies then?
- No, no...not at all.
Many companies have
obtained contracts by illegal means
thanks to your recommendations.
- I do thousands of them.
Contracts, licences,
sites, subsidies...
- So who do you give them to?
- My friends who are able to do things.
Who usually?
Whoever shows themselves to be the best friend.
- And what do you get out of them?
- Friendship.
Look!
So it seems as though you're
not worried about taxes then?
I'm not worried about anything.
I'm ignorant, I only know a few things.
For example, I know that under
the nose we have a mouth
which is more for eating
...than for talking.
I also have a mouth under my nose,
even if it only eats government bread.
I know...
But you're a man.
They say you're religious..
Well..I go to church every Sunday.
I donate to charity.
- Do you think that's enough?
- Why wouldn't it be?
The church is huge. Everyone
does things their own way in there.
Laura, the coffee!
And what do you think of the Gospel?
Ahh..beautiful words!
The church is all beauty.
Do you think it's right to kill a man?
I've never done anything of the sort.
But if you're asking me, theoretically,
it would depend on who the man is.
Ah, so according to you,
there is man and man?
I divide humanity into five categories:
There are the real men,
the half men, the so-so men...
and then, if you'll excuse me, the faggots..
...and finally, it's like as if they didn't exist,
the gossips who are worth nothing!
There are very few real men,
only a few half men
The majority of men are so-so.
They're like kids who think they're grown-ups
As for the queers, they're
growing to become a real army.
And lastly, the blabbermouths...
A flock of geese.
But, even if you nailed me,
you're a man!
And why do you
consider me to be a man?
Because someone in your place
can trample over people easily.
And I received insults far worse
than death from your predecessors.
They slapped me.
Another put his cigarette out on my hand
and how he laughed!
Can you sleep when
you've been ridiculed like that?
- So, I don't offend you then?
- No, you're a man.
You too, Don Mariano.
But I'll still have to send you to jail.
- Why didn't you arrest me before?
- I didn't have the proof.
Proof? With or without proof,
it's the same thing!
Captain, we found this weapon inside a cupboard.
The proof!
You're a magician!
- This rifle has killed at least two men.
- More than that. It's 40 years old!
But the last were
Colasberna and Nicolosi.
I bought it from a 'picciotto'
(lowest level of mafia hierarchy)
From who?
From Zecchinetta?
- Yes, I think so. That was his name.
- But you bought it the morning of the crime,
while it was still hot,
and you didn't pay for it.
Because Zecchinetta,
who also talks a lot
never said a word about
receiving money for the weapon.
So can you explain to me why,
if I'm so sly and powerful as you say
I would keep the murder weapon in my house?
Because you're so sure of yourself
that you never thought that someone
would come and search your home.
Mariano Arena, in the name of the law,
I declare you under arrest.
You're accused of being behind the murders
of Salvatore Colasberna and Gaetano Nicolosi.
- Look, Don Mariano!
- Don Mariano!
Don Mariano, I swear to you, neither I
nor Zecchinetta mentioned your name.
We were fighting between ourselves like two cocks.
- Have you signed anything?
- Yes.
Idiots!
You deserve to end up here.
Bang your head against here
and dont stop until I say...
I said bang it.
Bang it!
Again!
- What did you do to your forehead?
- I fell.
Don't you think about saying
that it was us who beat you!
No, I fell!
Long live Monsignor!
Take the cuffs off.
Salutai i parenti e gli amici..
..e pure una vecchiarella...
Un pezzo da novanta portarono!
Un pezzo da novanta!
Rosa!
This way! This way!
Sit here and eat this roll.
Sit down Rosa.
Sit, don't be scared.
Have you received news of your husband?
Sometimes husbands can go crazy.
They run off and leave their wife and kids.
To Tunisia, to America..
- To Milan
- To France
- To Switzerland
- Or to Germany..
Do you need help Rosa?
Don't worry
we'll take care of you and your
child until your husband returns.
And if he doesn't come back, you won't be left abandoned
and no one will treat you with disrespect.
Are we agreed?
No one will treat her with direspect.
Even though you didn't show respect to someone.
Someone who didn't do anything to you.
But Don Mariano is a good man,
who'll forgive and forget a fit of desperation.
He knows that you're a good woman.
Rosa said some things that were wrong and untrue!
Yes, she said them - but in good faith
without understanding the consequences.
When Rosa said "zecchinetta",
she wanted to say that that night
her husband came back late,
because he went to play cards.
- It was a misunderstanding!
- A misunderstanding, exactly!
He never met Zecchinetta!
He went to play 'zecchinetta', the card game.
A card game.
But the captain took it another way.
Of course, how could he have known?
The captain is from the north.
He doesn't know us.
They distorted it all.
Don't you agree Rosa?
I'll ask my husband how I need to act when he returns!
Tomorrow I'm going to tell the truth to the judge.
That when they killed Colasberna,
Zecchinetta was watering my land.
If he was working 70 kilometres
from your house, Rosa
how could he be guilty of the crime?
Sure! Sure! My cousin can testify to it too.
It's a disgrace that the gentlemen are in prison.
They'll get out.
And you, if you don't tell the truth,
they'll say you did it to cause harm.
Out of bitterness. Is that nice?
No, it's not - nor is it fair.
Do you agree Rosa?
This dish is too salty.
Rosa, what are you doing?
You're leaving? Where are you going?
Where am I going?
It's just that I'm ashamed of
this dress and these bare arms.
I'm in mourning aren't I?
So I should dress in mourning.
- Who is it?
- Rosa Nicolosi.
- That morning...
- No come on, Rosa. Enter!
Tell me.
- So, that morning?
- That morning Pizzuco called my husband
for work he said. My husband
went and I never saw him again.
We haven't stopped looking for him.
Look at these glasses,
they were found at Pizzuco's site.
None of the workers there recognise them.
Are they your husband's?
- I...I don't know.
- Didn't he use sunglasses?
Yes, but I don't know if it's them.
You must believe me,
I can tell you the
truth in here and I've told you!
What you say inside here is useless
if you won't repeat it outside!
No! I came to tell you
but I won't testify outside.
You won't speak in front of the judges, correct?
I have to think about my daughter.
You know what they're saying here?
They say my investigations is just
a political campaign to sling
mud at certain big shots in Rome!
That the confessions where forced!
That Don Mariano was a victim!
They say that I've blamed an honest man
and that I deliberately ignored to
investigate the crime of passion!
Do you understand!?
I'm saving you from ruin!
And what are you doing for me?
- I did what I could.
- No! Like the others,
you did what I told you to do!
You did nothing of your own will!
But I still managed all the same.
Even though I only got
silence from all of you instead of help.
Well, what is it Rosa?
Are you also thinking that I'm,
as all the others say, 'arrogant'?
Go on, say it!
What do I know?
Who knows you?
"At the inauguration above the
authorities, the dead underneath"
- Captain Bellodi!
- You can't pass.
Let me through!
Captain Bellodi!
Captain, do you want a drink?
- What are you doing, you pulling it all up?
- Piece by piece. Everything.
And who'll pay for it?
Corporal!
Come here!
Come, we've found him!
- Captain, here!
- Let the Captain through!
Come on, hurry!
- Who is it?
- It's who they were searching for..
Rosa Nicolosi's husband.
The one they couldn't find.
Come on, turn him over!
- Parineddu!
- It's Parineddu!
Remove that cork from his mouth.
That letter Captain...you get it?
It's them who sent it.
Masons, builders,
carpenters, labourers, unemployed!
Bring yourselves to the housing projects!
Bless you Don Mariano!
My respects Don Mariano!
Don Mariano Arena is back!
He's a good Christian!
Santuzza! Bring me the
binoculars from the writing desk.
The air in Palermo didn't do me good.
It made me heavy and nauseous.
My head always felt heavy.
Have you read? They arrested
the director of Banco Provinciale.
Why did they arrest him?
He was a good man.
That's why they arrested him.
Because he was a good man, of course!
He'll get out. He'll get out soon enough!
We got out too didn't we!?
You can speak when the hen pisses!
(i.e. Shut up!)
There's a new captain.
Give it to me.
He has a likeable face.
Take it!
You're right, like a father.
I bet he's got a wife and kids.
Even better if he has a big family,
he'll take care of his own business.
- He'll always be a carabiniere.
- Like Bellodi.
Bellodi was a man.
This one's a blabbermouth.
- Blabbermouth!
- Blabbermouth...