The Emperor arrived
with imperiaI relief
As this has been
an imperial hunt
capped by a super finale
You have a great talent
for the chase
Your efforts deserve
a reward
Do you wish to become
my Master of hounds?
Or would you like
an embassy?
I feeI privileged to be
so honored
I refuse to stay here
It's some kind of plot
Why couldn't my husband
simply say...
he would prefer to be
ambassador in London?
Does the Emperor think...
you cannot be both
ambassador and master?
But you can! You can be
one and the other
You will never leave, Madam
Heinberg, it is your turn to choose
Would you rather have the
woods in which we hunted...
in my coaI mines?
I believe you also know
about mining?
I do, but I'd rather have
the woodland
No more than you wished to
become an ambassador
Choice, Your Highness, is
a great privilege
and guard its secrets
"I am part of the part
that once used to be,
I can explain things to the Emperor
I'm sure I can persuade him
I shall have to dismiss my adjutant
No doesn't know
I'm here either
No one does
I don't understand
Your Majesty displayed
such acumen today...
in granting people's
hidden wishes...
that I am sure
you can see to it...
If events are allowed
to take their couree...
Well?
You wanted me to
alter my decision?
Yes.
You thought I'd give way
to a woman?
At last I've got what I wanted.
What did you promise me?
What price your word?
Got anything in writing,
Your Highness?
Frightening the game away!
You'll a man of my word
It would cost you too much
You're in financiaI trouble.
New palaces are expensive
Name your price!
You seem to be an expert
on coaI
No worse than on timber
Whoever went into caI here
acquired...
I mean to that too...
How much,
Herr "von"
I don't want anything
My father and grandfather
served you as wuntsman
I do not intend to-
at any price
One question
Who did better out
of that imperiaI hunt?
Listen to me, Highness
Did I, by ceasing to be
your huntsman...
Are you any closer...
THE MAGNATE
Gentlemen!
I have received sad news
Our employer...
Why is it so quiet?
When a soldier lies dying
there should be noise!
The sirens should be
sounding!
What's going on?
Sirens?
Does that mean I've died?
What did that alarm mean?
Are you afraid to tell us...
there's no work for us?
I'm the one who
switched on the sirens
The Prince is dying
Hans, tell me...
that it's not my fault,
that it's not my doing
Her Highness would like to know...
if her husband is any better
I can't speak for
my Polish colleague...
Sirens...
I know... It was Nelke
Maybe my sons will hear?
Hear the sirens!
Can your
crystaI ball tell your Director Zbierski
I wonder what will
come of this
Look!
Bolko!
Here's Bolko
Last month's business...
and a draft of
the French contract
You work so hard for me,
von Teuss
I'll raise your salary
and make you...
It will crown the history
of our families
I'm afraid I must refuse
Family duties are
calling me...
and the go back to
the 12th century
I find it hard to know
what to make of you Prince.
I can't return
the compliment
A telegram, Count. Urgent
What are you gawking at?
I haven't seen him
for ten years
He disowned me
for becoming a Catholic
He played God with
our lives
For five days I was kept
locked up in a room
To this day I still can't
get out of that room
We shall see
Welcome. Prince
Hello.
Our younger sister
Silly of me - I forgot
Can he also have come
to make his peace?
Hens still lay eggs
The world wasn't fated to end
with my death
I see, Yurek, that you too...
have come to attend my funeraI
Please forgive me
my faux pas
I have no intention
of dying
As I lay there in my bed...
dying my little death...
it occurred to me that I ought...
to have another child
At my age that could be
an achievement
"I will hold out for twenty more years
on the virility front"
You don't know,
you Prussian numskulls!
If the press gets hold
of your joko...
Heinberg and Krupp will die laughing
You've a subject...
That's right. A farce.
I think you gentlemen
wish to be left alone
Is it you who are going
to give him this child?
Sit down Conrad!
You no longer count
Your conversion has
made you a Pole...
I am Franz Friedrich XVIII
and is laughing at us
So you believe the family
is all-important?
Absolutely
it is strong. It grows
effetes if it yields...
to individualist urges
I daresay. Now and then
You want proof?
You marriage to Marisca
You chose a woman
reeking of scandaI
And Conrad's parties?
Nude chorus boys cavorting
on the lawn...
Or Bolko's notorious plunges
at all of Europe's gaming tables?
It's my free will
Free will belongs
to mythology
In reaI lift what counts
is strength of will
- Am I? I didn't know
- Look it up!
Are you talking about
family or fortune?
Property and family
Properly managed,
our property...
...could make us one of
Europe's foremost families
But we already are
As far as debts go,
no question
Maybe you'd like to try?
How broad?
Very broad
In that case I'll be
begging for my bread
It's for the good of
the family and so yours too
And yours
You'll get
your power af attorney
Such youthfuI enthusiasm
does the heart good
But consider one thing
Instead of regent...
You were so wrong...
believing that absurd
pack of lies
Then why does the Emperor
make so much of you?
All those courtesies,
pretty speeches?
that clutching of
little hands?
Not the way you do,
you Prussian numskulls
Because you were his lover
I was not
Know why he treats me
differently from you?
Not because I'm a woman...
instead of just agreeing
like you sycophants
You can't see beneath
the surface of things
That's why you were denied
a diplomatic career...
not because I was
the Emperor's mistress
- So you ware!
- I wasn't
- You just said so!
- No
I said something else
You admitted it!
I did not
Yes! I was!
If it helps you
justify our failures...
I was the Emperor's
mistress
Noooo!
At last you're not
certain of something
When the war is over...
I will find myself a new wife
A bad woman.
with the touch of eviI
Come on!
Where's the fire?
One of ours, at a standstill
We'll move on
There's no work for you!
"Piast", also ours
Working every other day
It was meant to be working
The men reported for work
They're being turned away
There's no market
for our coaI
How I love good old Silesia!
All of this is yours
A cementworks in Ligota
Briquette factories,
brickyads and breweries in Tychy
It is and it isn't
So they don't want
to buy our coaI?
I see you've locket up
the siren
Two days ago! A week ago!
Two weeks ago! A month ago!
Look.
Gangsters, no doubt. From Chicago
Planning to hijack us to Singapore.
Step on it!
They don't have wings
Nothing, nothing...
Have they gone?
Oh no!
Someone's telling me
to make up my mind
Trying to force me
to join them
- Bolko!
- Leave it.
Get in
Get in!
I don't want to know.
I'm leaving
This isn't my thing
Apparently not
I'll represent the family
above ground
Your first descent?
All the best...
Cheers, foreman
Cheers!
Which leveI are you
Foreman Grela
Output - 30 tones
It's a low drift
Why are you so small?
You'll get machinery
when sales recover, Grela
The market's tight now...
Cheers!
You've laid off 400 miners
Get the herrings?
Not now, Grela
Come and see me
and we'll talk it over
It's you who've come to see us
Thank you kindly!
What on earth?
What did you say?
- Is this a breakdown or..
- Or what?
You're learning fast
Got any matches?
You have a candle?
As an offering to
Saint Barbara
So light it
If there's gas here
we'll be blown sky high
Assuming it's coincidence
if there's gas here
you'd better start praying
You'll be ging to feeI faint,
to throw up...
Stop it!
It's all thanks to
your gracions gestures!
It's part of the job
I should have stayed home
Then I would have had to
suspect you as well
Of what?
You mean to say you don't
suspect anybody?
Nobody
We're in luck. It stopped
at a gallery
Mind the step
I wouldn't count the steps
We're fixing it
Please keep calm
We're perfectly calm
Forgive me, Prince.
Forgive me, Count
Those responsible will be
punished. It was sabotage
You're awfully suspicious, Franzel
People should be
open and sincere
Not in business matters
I have to know who's
stabbing me in the back
That's why I can't leave?
I believe you have
an appointment in Warsaw?
He's afraid of us, Conrad.
Afraid!
I wish I'd studied you
more closely as a boy
You could have,
being the oldest
But why can't I leave?
I'll explain. Our family...
I have to be certain that
it won't be impeded...
by you, Conrad or Marisca
Otherwise the whole thing
is pointless
I came to say goodnight
to Conrad and FranzeI
I've already said it to you
Very well. I'll stay here
as long as you wish
Let's see you lead the family to greatness
May I?
I can't be sure...
but if what I think is correct...
I ought to be in Germany
as soon as possible
It is of course secret
business?
It concerns out family, father
might well resort to skullduggery
I've known that
Well... good luck
But if I were you
I'd remember...
...that one of the sources
of our greatness...
A rising?
My congratulations on
a well executed assault
In Polish?
Might you Piast ancestors
not be telling you...
to adept Polish citizenship
when the time is right?
What are you doing, Conrad?
It's only now that I can leave
I'm free at last
Stop!
Unpack the boys' things
You think I'd lot you
take them with you?
You don't have the right
to dictate to me
There's a rising
Are you a Catholic, my son?
Yes, father
Do you have any idea at all
what that means?
It means that I feel Polish
You can feeI Dutch
for all I care
There is no more important
decision in life...
than choice of faith You have taken it
without confiding in the family
It was a personal decision
It cannot be
a personal decision
Religion is a family affair
Bring Count Conrad his trunk
He is leaving with
his mother
Mother's left you a letter
"My dear Hans...
You once said you wanted
an eviI woman to succeed me
I met her a year ago
in Cap d'Antibes
Von Sutzpold, her husband,
committed suicide...
from, by all accounts
jealousy
Remember, Highness
Take no nonsense from them
He owns a beautifuI slice
of Silesia
The Prince's position
is known to you?
But we don't know what
he expects from us
I must show you something
I'm glad you came.
Not a moment too soon
It was high time
But now you must be patient.
This may take time
That is why I have
come to you, Count
I trust you completely
You did the right thing but...
I guessed
You're no goof
A brick was thrown
into your car...
and later you got stuck
in a mine cage?
It's incredible
What barbarians!
Whenever you came near
I had a feeling...
you knew everything
about me
When I realized I'd marry you
I had to, didn't I?
Don't think you can compare
with your father
You don't stand a chance
If I care to I'll use your legs
as billiard cues
If I care to!
If I ever catch you
eavesdropping again!
Damn! The key's gone
It must have been FranzeI
Look at me!
Look! I'm all poppyseed
I'm all poppyseed
All poppyseed
You shouldn't have come here
- I'm all poppyseed
- You shouldn't have come!
Go on! Go on!
You shouldn't have!
Come on now, come here
Well?
Don't laugh
- I love you
- Shut up!
Is Jolanta my daughter?
- How can you
- I most certainly can!
Look!
Come here, shy!
You will, you will!
There's going to be...
scandaI among the nobility!
I wonder how FranzeI
will react...
to this example of...
how did he put it?
yielding to
individualist urges?
I'm pleased you've
joined us, Highness
Look at those lads!
Live money.
He'll be pleased to hear
you accepted our invitation
The peasants of Lippe...
These journalists are a rabble
of Jews and Masons
Tonight, at the palace
Dr Goebbels believes...
it would be ill-advised...
He'll see you at
Schloss Vinebeck
"ScandaI at Von Teuss Seat"
"Footman's Revelations"
Youngest son!
Son!
Prince catches
youngest son!
Catches son!
I have talked to Hitler
He is shocked...
...by such vilification
of an illustrious family
How could it come
to that, he asked
Is there no one capable
of taking charge?
Hitler has not yet retired
Life twists...
- Bolko! I can't!
- Dance!
All these strangers
I don't know anyone
And you won't...
We won't be coming back
Why not? Let's ask
our pet artist
Why didn't we have
a quiet wedding abroad?
Because FranzeI suffers
from a dangerous disease
It's called normality
He couldn't bear the idea
of something as abnormaI...
as a union between
stepson and stepmother...
That's why he agreed to a wedding...
which is the most normaI
and hallowed of customs
You've given...
You've given me
three splendid sons
Very splendid...
Och, Daisy, Daisy...
Laugh, and the world
laughs with you
Is that an English proverb!
No, my dear
How I wish it were!
I lay in my cot
and went like this...
When I became a soldier
I carried myself so...
And when I'm a decrepit
old prince...
I feeI like really
making you suffer
One day you will yourself
claim what's coming to you
That's a possibility that
I've also allowed for
I wish to see the Prince
His Highness is indisposed.
He is seeing no one
Feeling better?
What a beautifuI tree
I'll see we're buried here
Be good to me
From the first moment...
that I set eyes on you...
I laid a course for you
I'm so glad you could come
Count
Franz Friedrich Hochberg von Teuss!
I fancy we know each other
inside out
Me brother, Count Conrad
I believe you've become
a Catholic?
So many people have stayed
away from our wedding...
that something is due
to those who have come
My sister-in-law
I understand the son
and the father too
to as Yurek
to organize this party
I see
He's not eating
Amazing single-mindedness!
The pineapples took off...
and the plane had to
return to Warsaw
Director Zbierski
would you come over here?
Recognize him?
That's one thing
I didn't foresee
You have the floor
Please proceed
I haven't come here
to complain
Oh? Just to look at me?
Nor do any of my three
Polish colleagues...
whom Prince FranzeI has
dismissed wish to complain
Certainly not.
Why demean one self?
There!...
Your Highness!
To communicate
our misgivings
We have worked for you
for so many rears
We know and respect you
and your family
So it pains me to have to
warn you that things...
are in a bad way
Very bad!
Continue, continue
You have tax arrears
running into millions
But what's dos
Prince FranzeI do?
Gets involved in some kind
of hanky-panky abroad!
Mysteriously withdraws
what's left...
of his working capitaI!
Director Zbierski...
I no longer deaI
with such matters
You're in danger of
going...
The Polish government appointing trustees
to administer the property
For how long?
Now old are you?
Sixty-eight
I am seventy
How many more years
do I have? Five? Six?
So I'll still be protected
by the Geneva convention
or I can appeaI...
The question is,
do I want to?
Would it also surprise you...
that your funds are financing Hitler?
Lies, lies!
Close all the doors!
Look the doors!
We'll settle up now
Your allowance will be
remitted by Conrad...
Aesthetically speaking,
this party can't be faulted
with the way Bolko was
softened up for marriage
By plain speaking or
more subteI persuasion?
Whatever you may say,
however you try...
I won't go away with you.
Is that clear?
Very clear. What FranzeI's arguments
lacked in subtlety...
they no doubt made up
in computablity
That's business
And you accept that now?.
What a ghastly place!
What happened?
Let them whistle!
In Poland more steam goes
into whistles than engines
No wonder.
Polish miners
laid off,
Differently?
Which is why we now owe
nine million in taxes
Listen you shit,
don't send me money
to an account...
on which I can1t draw!
Not now, Bolko, not now
- I'm not stopping anything
- Good...
Did you send Bolko
his allowance?
Of course
Using the Ruberg account?
That's right
In a Polish bank?
Then go outside and see
what you've done!
Come to watch a strike?
Even more from the sight of
an owner chased by one
Rear can also be exciting
I made it...
I can do it!
Conrad? I've gotten a hold
over FranzeI
Made your day, have I?
You don't say?
Conrad deflowered!
How's that for news!
Go on, let's have it!
The whole min's been
surrounded by the police
Director Zbierski
They've even seized that
consignment of pineapples
The plane's been grounded
in Warsaw
Yes, Your Highness?
Have the pineapples arrived?
Not yet.
The weather
Weather, weather
How curious!
I'll go to the airfield
and collect them myself
Of course. But...
No buts! Get Joseph
to bring the car round
Of course.
But it's years since
you motored
Stop philosophizing..
Tell me, Casimir, how is it...
that you've stayed on with me so long?
Isn't Poland calling you?
I've never plumbed the depths with Poland
but with you, it's been known
Zbierski?
What do you mean, who?
My dear friends!
As head of that family
it is my duty...
to look after those
who are in trouble
So please, speak out.
We want...
fair working hours
We want meaI breaks
and a rest period...
at midday
We want a full week's
work and pay
The percentage of profits
set aside per worker...
is too low
You go to them.
What shall I say?
all these new things over
Why? They're behaving
peacefully enough
You should be more afraid of
of directors who've never
seen a coaI face
Who are you?
No such engineer is employed in
His Highness's mines
Did you hear what
the miners said?
They ware right
All you have to do is
install steam power...
and put up wages.
He's right,
but he doesn't know...
that Your Highness
has no money
What?
I own all this
and I have no money?
It's a ticklish subject
to discuss...
but vases full of flowers
don't mean
Of course... Go and see them
Yes.
You're are a very shrewd fellow
We'll install your
steam engines
But I expect you want
a job, which I don't have
Is the pressure here
always like this?
What?
I don't knonw...
What does it mean?
That there's seepage
The ground's subsiding...
Look at the blotter
Well I'll be damned!
Mister Zbierski
You'd have to be mightier
than God Himself...
Give me your hand!
What are you doing here,
my good fairy?
Lost your reason?
Adventures at his age!
- I did warn you
- Piss on warnings!
I want to know the facts.
Director Zbierski
ex-Director
in respect of taxes
have been...
disappearing from
a Polish bank...
and surfacing in Munich
credited to Ruberg
You have it in for FranzeI
for dismissing you
Old men outlive their usefulness
They should withddraw gracefully
Like you?
Well, Your Highness,
it's the receiver for you
And that won't be
the half of it
Give me a cigar
Go on!
"I, Franz Friedrich XVII,
acting on behalf of...
my father, Polish citizen
of German nationality...
hereby lodge a complaint to the League of Nations
against the Government of Poland... "
You read it. You wrote it
"... of Poland which is
seeking by unlawfuI means...
to Polonize the preorty
of Prince von Teuss..
in order to recover
taxes wrongly assessed...
for the years 1925-29.
This discriminatory action
which is a reprisaI...
On behalf of my father
I demand...
discontinuance of
all distraints...
placed on the property
of the Prince...
as well as declaration
of the Government...
to be in violation of
Articles 67,68,75 of the Convention"
Why should I sign this?
If and when I withdraw
your powers of attorney...
then I'll start signing
How long will I go on
signing on your behalf?
I never ask you questions
But if it proves to be true
that one mark of mine...
has paved Hitler's way
to power...
I look forward to
seeing Granddaddy
Daddy!
He won't let you in
Then I'll sneak in
Germany.
Then Casimir will
drive us into Poland
- It's very near
- There'll be no car
He won't even see you
I can tell him what I have
on FranzeI...
in writing
I feeI as if were
carrying a bag of diamonds
You are pleased
FranzeI made me look silly,
arranging our marriage
It's me he wanted
to humiliate
Did you ever notice the way
he used to look at me?
How?.
but lacked the nerve
Prince Bolko von Teuss?
No fuss, Countess.
It's vulgar
Step back.
Nooooo
I'm loaded!
I won it at roulette
The Gestapo...
arrested him...
He knew everything
about FranzeI
What's the use of hiding?
I can see you anyway
She's right
Account number: 00033
were two senior
NSDAP officials
Halt!
" I, Hans Heinrich XV
Hochberg von Teuss...
hereby consent...
to, assignment of
all my property.
The mentaI illness
which has affected...
my son Franz Friedrich...
all power of attorney
is therefore transferred...
to my son Conrad...
Signed: Hans Heinrich XV,
Prince of Pszczyna
That still leaves
the sacked directors...
and Polish miners,
and the pit floodings
Discuss that with them
and with Count Conrad
You heard?
I only asked you...
to prevent my brother
from going to Poland
And how did you expect us
to stop him?
We did so
But why has he also
been put in prison?
What will you do with him?
I understand he has run up
large debts in Munich
That will have to be
investigated
I can settle all his bills
You can't do anything, Prince
Are you aware...
all your powers
on the grounds...
that you are of
unsound mind?
The Reich Government...
All that's left to you is
to remain in Germany...
and await better days
When they come
Can I see my brother?
It all went wrong
You were to be sent back
to Munich
I wanted you to...
It all went wrong
Whatever I've done has been
for the family
They want to destroy us,
to strip us of everything
Tell Father that they have
a precise plan
They intend to
take everything
Tell Father that I'm the only one
who can save everything
Only me.
Don't look at me like that
I've done you no harm. It was them
Them! Will you tell him?
I won't tell him anything.
I'm here for good
I'm given injections
to make me beter, they say
I had an abscess. They say
they're treating me
What are they doing to you?
Treating me, they say,
but in fact poisoning me
You'll get out. And go home
Tell Father...
You won't forget?
They have a plan.
Heiberg's behind it all
You'll tell Father?
You won't forget?
I'm sorry, FranzeI, but you
really have gone mad
Don't ever say that to me.
Ever!
I first noticed when you
proclaimed your plans...
and ranted about
the greatness of the family
You'd already become unhinged
I saw the way you looked at us
How you began to suspect us,
to spy on us
Everything had to be
absolutely normaI...
because you'd become
Normality's unhinged you
Did you think you were
the most normaI of persons?
Or the strongest?
That no one could wring
your secrets from you?
Drop your voice. These are
things no one knows about
It was a little ulcer,
a pimple really
I can't hear a thing!
That wasn't nice.
not nice at all
You tried to escape
by the back door...
The bastards!
They said
there'd be no problems
If they ever cross
this border...
Well?
Bolko!
Lay her on the bench!
Fetch some water!
Halt! Stop him!
They're here!
Can you...
Can you forgive me
How did you know...
I wanted to see you?
I've always been curious
to know...
You'll see
Am I dreaming?
Your Highness!
Your Highness - here?
Are you the director here?
That's right. In charge
of the slippers
You are in the vestibule...
leading to the oldest
part of the palace
There's ornamentation
that's Baroque, Rococo...
In 1946, in accordance
with the will...
Mother...
Father, but what year?
That miner was called Grela
What are you laughing at?
What was that dog called?
It was FranzeI's favourite...
Remember?
I don't remember either
I don't remember anything...
Quiet!