The Slovak Film lnstitute
presents
MAHULlENA THE GOLDEN MAlDEN
Screenplay:
Featuring:
Costume Designer:
Make-up:
Editor:
Sound:
Set Designer:
Art Director:
Music:
Executive Producer:
Director of Photography:
Directed by:
Wake up! The king is coming!
What if they don't come this time?
They always come at solstice.
l would drive them off!
But we would need a different king.
l wonder what you would do
if you were him, you sissy.
You're a sissy!
Get up, Ján!
What's going on?
You and the Prince must leave now!
Are they here? Are they coming?
Not yet. But l'll feel better
knowing you are far away.
Come what may, stay away
at least a week.
l know, sir. As usual.
l heard a little owl last night.
l hope it doesn't mean bad luck.
Since when are you superstitious?
Stop that!
Better hurry!
Are you... still here?
Do you not feel sorry for your father?
l didn't sleep from the pain all night.
You know l can only be cured
with the fat of a white otter.
Why do you not go then?
You must be patient, Father.
Last year, it took us a week
to trace one.
l know, that's why you need to leave now!
Have you heard the King?
Get moving!
You are always keeping us up.
ls it possible?
l bet that it will be me who'll catch it!
We shall see about that.
The loser will be the horse!
lt's a deal. Let me try right away.
Let's go!
Go now. While there's time.
l don't understand.
We've been panning for gold for ages
but what good does it do to us?
- What would you want?
What a dumb question! You can have
everything if you have gold.
That's true but we don't lack anything.
Our king saves the gold for bad times.
What is it this time?
We need to keep moving.
Look, isn't she beautiful?
Perhaps. But we're not hunting herons.
See, she doesn't trust you.
Can you hear it too?
lt must be a storm coming!
Nonsense! There's not a cloud
in the sky!
Let's go! Quick!
Turn it back! What are you doing?
Are you mad?
- You mustn't go there!
- Leave me alone!
Stop! Come back!
The wagon has no coachman.
The horses must have bolted.
You're lying!
They're going to our place.
What for? Where are they coming from?
You know. Tell me!
l cannot. l gave my word.
You gave your word to whom?
To the king.
To my father?
Ján! You have promised you wouldn't...
l tried but...
What's going on here, Father?
Well, you had to find out one day.
Find out what?
Every year, we give the gold back
to Lordogold.
We give him our gold?
Yes. We have been doing so since forever.
Every year, at solstice.
l thought you did not have
to know about it yet.
Why is that? Who is Lordogold?
The ruler of all gold!
Other empires give him slaves
for the gold.
But we would not be subjugated.
Even the last of us means more
than this pile of gold!
How can you endure such injustice?
Have you no courage to stand up to him?
You have gained the gold with
your labour, it belongs to you!
Be quiet, son, or you will bring us
to an evil end!
Nobody can oppose his fate,
not even the king.
- What can possibly happen?
- Only king Lordogold knows.
These are all just excuses.
You have never opposed him,
have you?
You are young, you don't understand.
You will learn everything with time
- just like me and my father,
and all our forefathers did.
Majesty, we'll do what you decide
but we'll serve Lordogold no more!
Yes! Yes!
That's madness!
You must not allow that, sir!
That is enough!
lf we begin to quarrel,
we shall be lost.
Load the carts!
They must not leave empty.
All right. But we won't send
what Lordogold expects.
Manure!
We have plenty of that!
Let's do it!
We'll give them enough!
Here you are!
- l have waited for this for years.
- Not only you.
Mahuliena... the golden maiden!
Stop it!
l forbid you! You must not!
Father... Father!
lt is my fault.
l should be punished, not you.
Enough! Be a man!
May this be a warning that you must
never revolt against Lordogold.
- Father...
- Go now.
Ján! Stay here.
The rest of you, leave!
Go!
Come here! Closer... to me.
You are like my own son.
Therefore l entrust you this crown.
lt's very old.
l inherited it from my father
as he did from his father.
lt has been ours since ancient times.
Cherish and guard it like the apple
of your eye... lt's for my son...
- Yes...
- When he grows up
to be able to use it
for the good of his people,
not for disaster.
lt has great power, you will see.
l'm asking you to stay loyal
to the prince.
Do not leave him in good or in bad times
and protect him from the golden maiden.
Mahuliena?
Remember!
You may never reveal
its mysterious power.
lf you do...
What would happen?
lf you do, then you'll be
turned into stone.
- What?
- You shall turn into stone.
Nothing would save you.
Nothing but a great sacrifice.
How great a sacrifice?
l do not know.
So far nobody has ever revealed
the secret of the crown.
Your Highness!
Your Majesty!
Here! He is here!
Wake up! Come on!
What happened?
Where is she?
What have you done with her?
With whom? You were alone.
You had fainted.
As if the golden maiden had come
to life in my hands.
- Mahuliena.
- Who?
Her golden image.
The river has been bringing it for years.
Does she live by the river?
Forget her. Many had searched
for her never to return.
Now you need to think of how to rule.
Remember, you are the king now.
That is impossible!
Do you not understand
Lordogold is behind this all?
- What? - His power is said
to be in the golden statue.
Good. l'll go to him
and take her with me.
Look, he's staggering!
No wonder. l have not stood
on the ground for a week.
Do not make excuses!
You have something to drink in the sack!
No, l have nothing there.
We have to look.
- Leave me alone!
- Selfish man!
- Let me be!
- He doesn't want to share!
Let go!
- Show us what you're hiding!
- You'll get a drink too.
Let me be! Let go!
Let go!
Nothing.
- Nothing but junk.
- Give me it!
l knew that. Ján cannot lie.
Let's go to sleep.
Get up! We must get out of here!
lt's going to fall! Quick!
Get up! Move!
A storm is coming!
Come on!
lt will kill us!
Don't worry, the two of us will be faster.
Perhaps, but it's harder to defend ourselves.
Don't say that. We can manage ourselves.
Let's go!
Wait! Give me a hand!
l can't!
l'm stuck!
Damn it!
Go on! l get out myself!
What are you doing?
Wild bees! Run!
- What's going on?
- Wild bees! Move!
Bees! Run!
Let me be!
You beast! Here!
Look, a shell!
ln the past, the river ran through here.
So what?
l want to know where Lordogold is.
By the spring, perhaps.
Don't worry, we'll get there.
- A fortress...
- lt's golden...
This way!
Hurry up!
Why have you not taken me instead?
Why are you so cruel?
Why do you need children?
l, Diva, curse you, Lordogold!
What do you know of Lordogold?
Where is he?
Speak! You know!
Wait! We must get to him!
He did evil things to us too!
Leave me alone!
l don't know anything!
You cursed him, and cried...
Because of my sister.
She is still a child!
He took her this morning.
Lordogold? Has he been here?
His horses.
Do you send him people,
not gold?
Gold is more precious.
People grow old and die!
Gold is eternal.
lts beauty lasts forever, like the beauty of
the golden maiden, Mahuliena!
Have you seen her?
No one ever has.
This is what the legend says.
That's terrible! You appreciate
gold more than a child!?
No. lt was by lot!
lt was a twist of fate.
Every year the ones to go
are picked by lot.
lt is our fate.
lt's been like that for ages.
Lordogold, just you wait.
Put the gold away.
No!
l must not! They'll punish me!
Come on, stop crying.
Smile.
l have no reason.
lt has been a long time... l cannot.
Try! Please.
Only for me. Come on!
There you are!
When Lordogold loses Mahuliena,
your sister and the others can come back.
You will smile again.
lt suits you more than gold.
l told you to rest at their place
a couple of days.
At theirs or hers?
So what? l like Diva.
l may never see her again.
And l may never see Mahuliena.
Enough!
Enough of gloomy thoughts.
Make a fire.
lt may brighten our mood.
Can you feel that smell?
No, l can't.
What is wrong with you?
What happened?
Fetch some wood!
Where is that man?
Ján, where are you?
The fire is burning!
Look at all the gold!
Lordogold must be close.
l am so fed up with this!
Me too.
l can't go on!
l want water!
Where would l get it?
Give me something to drink!
Hold on! Come on!
We're almost at the top
and who knows, Mahuliena may be
on the other side.
Come!
Come on!
At least there is a shadow here.
- l want to sleep.
- Wait here.
l'll be right back. l'll go to the top.
l want to sleep...
The king...
Water...
Are you mad?
You must not drink it!
lt could be poison! Enough!
How dare you?
Don't you know who l am?
lf you touch me again,
l'll beat you like a dog!
Stop! Where are you going?
l am free like a bird!
l want to fly!
- l am going to fly!
- You are mad!
Pull yourself together! Stop!
Let's fly together!
That's enough!
What happened?
l feel dizzy.
What was l doing?
l can't remember anything.
Are you sleeping?
You've warned me three times...
... every time we were in danger.
So this is your secret!
Ján, wake up! Quick!
What is it?
Look!
You've never seen anything like it ever.
Let's follow them!
There they are -
- bringing water up the hill.
What's the point of that?
We're about to reach our destination!
At last!
The spring of the golden river!
Let's move on!
Wait! l'll go alone from here on.
Should anything happen to me,
you at least can return home.
What? l can't leave you
to your own devices!
Help her! Have you no heart?
Come...
She's blind.
Who has done this to you?
Can you hear me?
lt's useless.
They're like the living dead.
l don't think they can see or hear us.
This is where they pour the water!
Lordogold!
Where are you?
Show yourself!
Let's follow the glow.
- Can you see anything?
- No. Nothing.
Finally - you're here!
lt took you quite a while!
l was afraid you would never find
the way to get here!
You villain!
Where are you? Come out!
Your efforts are in vain!
You can't win the maiden by sword!
You've come for her, haven't you?
She can only belong to the one
who can bear to look at her beauty!
Stop skipping and take me to her!
Come, she's waiting!
Look at her!
Look if you are strong enough!
Come!
Mahuliena...
What is it?
What does it mean?
He must not look at her.
You must not look at her!
You must not see her!
Don't listen to him!
lf you don't look at her
she can't be yours!
Nothing in the world is
as beautiful as she is!
Where are you?
Can you hear me?
You must not look at her!
Do not look, please!
What? You've come all this way to take her,
have you not?
That's why l'll touch her.
Nobody can prevent me from doing that.
What are you doing?
Nobody may touch her!
l forbid you!
Stop me!
You can't, can you?
Stop, please.
Take as much gold as you want!
You'll be the richest man of all!
Keep your bloody gold!
Mahuliena is worth more!
Please, don't! Don't do that!
Where is she?
No. No!
Here she is.
How delicate she is!
You've lost, you villain. You lost.
Mahuliena is mine now.
l'll be looking at her
all my life.
Too soon to rejoice!
You won't get her home alive!
She'll die and people will become
my slaves again!
Don't go so close!
You'll get dizzy.
Not anymore.
Why? lt's very deep.
You've made me feel dizzy.
What's wrong?
Let her be! What are you doing?
What is that?
Has he hurt you?
lt is not his fault.
l don't know what it was.
As if something pulled me down.
What could have pulled you?
You slipped.
The shoes. They're no good in the hills.
Why did you throw them away?
l didn't mean to. l dropped them.
How can she walk without shoes?
Barefoot?
l'll walk barefoot.
l'll be glad to, actually.
ls anybody there?
Come! Quick!
We must leave this place.
l think somebody's tracking us.
You see monsters in every shadow.
We're not home yet!
We must be careful!
We'll stay here!
You can go if you're scared!
Go wherever you want,
nobody holds you here!
Stop quarrelling!
He started it.
What's got into you?
He's ordering me around all the time.
We have to do this... we mustn't do that.
l've had enough!
We won't leave before you
get warm and dry.
You're soaked.
Damn it!
Everything is damp.
l'll do that!
Run around a bit, it'll warm you up.
So thoughtful all of a sudden!
l think it's good advice.
Come on!
Are you mad?
What are you doing?
Don't touch it! Leave!
Let go!
Go away! Now!
Let her go, you brute!
Are you possessed?
- Are you hurt?
- No, l'm fine.
Away! Away!
He's watching us. He's a threat.
Who? What are you making up this time?
lt seemed like...
l got frightened.
l am sorry, really.
Liar! You've burned them on purpose!
Don't say such things!
l don't believe him!
He envies me!
He's envious of you and my kingdom!
What?
What's going on with you?
You must not hurt each other!
He's such a hypocrite. l'm not blind.
- Why would l do that?
- l'll tell you.
Oh, here it is.
You'd like to be the king,
wouldn't you?
You long for power and it's
driving you mad!
That's not true!
How can you think that?
So why are you putting it on?
- l cannot tell you.
- You can't!?
l swear! You must believe me.
Did you hear that? Another must!
Yes, we must! He's our friend.
Friend? He's ready to kill us
for a piece of rusty metal!
That's terrible...
lf you harm a hair on her head,
l'll kill you!
Mahuliena, my love!
Hold on just a little longer.
The river is very near.
lt will lead us home.
The closer we are
the more scared l get.
Do not worry, my lady.
l do, for you two.
Wait... l can't go on.
Leave me!
Keep as far away as possible...
just in case!
Your wish is my command,
my king!
Diva! Stop!
Why are you running away?
Diva, stop!
Leave me alone!
Listen to me!
Go away!
Why are you still wearing it?
Your people are back,
your sister too, aren't they?
They are but we must not
put away the gold.
- Why not?
- We belong to Lordogold.
He'll surely come back one day.
You need not worry.
He won't. Believe me.
His power will pass for ever
once Mahuliena is home safe.
We'll all be happy, you'll see.
No.
l won't be, ever!
Why not?
- You'll be far away.
- Me?
Why don't you come with me?
No, l can't like this ... l don't want to.
l'll be waiting for you.
You can be sure l'll be back!
Go back. What are you doing?
We can't go home without him!
Why not?
Better for him if l won't see him.
lt could cost him his head.
Do you see him?
He clings to us like a leach.
He's up to something.
Why have l come to life?
We'll be punished for this.
You must not speak this way.
We'll be home by the daybreak.
All will be well.
Perhaps. But we won't be happy.
Ján!
Diva!
Where are you going? Stop!
You mustn't go there!
Diva, you are here?!
Wait for me!
l must save Mahuliena!
Are you really a fool?
Why are you doing all this?
- Later!
- Don't follow them!
- l have to!
- Don't go there!
Let them be. Please!
l have to... Before it's too late.
You must not! You'll die!
l cannot betray them.
Trust me! You at least, my love!
lf something happens to me,
only a great sacrifice can save me.
Do you understand?
A great sacrifice!
You don't love me!
You only think of Mahuliena
and the kingdom!
No!
Diva, wait! Come back!
What are you doing?
Let her go!
Her life is in danger!
Can't you see?
Mahuliena, what has he done to you?
Can you hear me?
She was bitten by a snake!
On her lips!
You are the snake! You viper!
l'll kill you!
Traitor!
- You're Lordogold's ally!
- No, no!
Confess, or l'll drown you!
Confess you want to destroy our love!
Let go! That's not true!
Let me go!
Confess! Speak!
l protected your love.
l don't believe a single word you say!
Prove it!
No... Not that!
So you won't speak!?
Let me be!
Come on! Speak!
l knew beforehand what
Lordogold was up to.
You knew that!? How?
l can't...
Wait...
lf l tell you, l'll die.
lf you don't speak, you'll die!
l'm waiting!
You'll be the one to blame.
Your father entrusted me this crown.
For you!
Till the time you become wise!
lt has magic power.
Without this crown
we couldn't have saved Mahuliena.
lt warned me against Lordogold's traps!
But he who reveals its secret
will turn into stone.
Ján, get out!
Look who's coming!
Come on, hurry up!
Where am l?
At home, our lady!
Be merry!
Now you have what you wanted!
Hey, sir!
Can you hear me?
ls that you?
Where can l find Ján?
He's not far.
Turned into stone.
As if he grew roots into the riverbed.
So it is true.
l've tried everything... To no avail!
Really, everything?
There must be a way!
Yes, there is - a great sacrifice.
- What?
- These were his last words.
lf something happens to me,
only a great sacrifice can save me.
What sacrifice - l don't know.
l didn't believe him!
A sacrifice. That's it!
A sacrifice... sacrifice.
Where are you going? Wait!
l must talk to the queen
before it's too late!
Nobody is allowed to see her!
lt's the king's order.
The king is the reason.
He's desperate!
Back!
Everybody knows that!
The queen must not be hurt!
ls it clear?
What happened to the king?
He wants to drown in the river.
l couldn't stop him.
What?
He says he must sacrifice himself.
You're not safe outside, our lady.
Get out of my way!
lt's an order!
We have a different order!
Mahuliena, go back home!
Home!
Please, do it!
Do you want me to lose you too?
Now l know Ján can only
be saved by a great sacrifice
He himself said it.
And what is more than life?
Yet, mine is not enough.
The river doesn't want me.
lt's returning me.
What are you doing? Let me be!
l must sacrifice myself.
You cannot do anything alone.
Our love is to blame
for everything.
He can only be saved by both of us.
l didn't want this to happen!
Not this... no...
They're alive!
They're coming!
Oh, l must go back.
The crown is in the river.
lt doesn't matter.
We don't need it anymore.
Let it stay there forever.
Forever?
Forever.
Cast:
Director of Photography:
Directed by:
Made by: