Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
Malcolm?!
You want your dinner now?
I made fish sticks with mashed
potatoes and string beans, okay?
Did you hear me?
Well, if you're not going to
tell me what you want,
I'm going to make these decisions
for you and you get what you get.
Christ!
The older you are, the more you
remind me of your father.
What's that, Mal?
What is that thing?
Did you just do what
I think you did?
Oh, Mal...
Who....who's going to
clean this up now?
So, how we doin' here?
Fine.
Pull off your hoodie.
What's your name?
Harry Haller.
This is private property, son.
Unless you got business here,...
you have to leave.
C'mon, kid, just put your shit together.
You don't want to get arrested.
You know you don't.
Look, I'll give you a ride.
I'm movin'
Thank you.
I just think it's sad...
What's sad?
That guys like you are
brainwashed by corporations into
de-humanizing yourself by
de-humanizing others...
...and I think it's sad that
guys like me...
...can't just sit wherever they
want to sit.
Okay, let's go.
Big Brother's watching you too!
I don't even know
what that means.
Why would you?
Pull your pants up!
Hey, Jeff.
What's up, Adelle?
Where's the gang?
What'd that cop want?
I don't know.
He was just bored.
Did he ask you to
pull up your pants?
Of course.
Original.
Probably the wittiest things
he's ever said.
It's like what Orwell said.
"We all live in a giant machine.
We're nothing but numbers."
"No one needs to torture me to behave...
no cage of rats around my head.
I have no choice
but to behave."
And that's what they want.
For you to give in.
So think about the rats and the
futility, you know what I say?
Fuck it.
Look...
...they made that sidewalk to
look like a sidewalk
to make this mall look like a
place where people thrive.
But it's not real.
No one walks on their
soul-less paths.
No one cares about
their dystopian landscaping.
This place is like a cardboard
cut-out of a Mall.
We live in a world generated by
computers and corporations.
A reality designed to replicate
a real human experience.
Artificially scented candles.
Mmmm...
Artificial sex appeal.
Cultural simulation.
Nostalgia.
Fabricated memories.
Manufactured happiness.
Hot cookies!
Fresh out of the oven!!
Just like Mom never really made.
Those smell good.
"It's a bad joke.
A violent abortion....
...of the primal mother. A barbaric
and hopeless catastrophe of nature.
To the Steppenwolf,
...man is not merely a partially-rational
animal but a child of the gods,
...destined to perfection
and immortality."
You keep a bookmark in that?
Yeah
So I don't lose my place.
That's cute.
Steppenwolf, huh?
What is it about... a wolf, like,
Whitefang or something?"
Not really.
There's no smokin' here, sir.
Fill 'em with high test.
High test don't work good
on lawn mowers, sir.
I'm not mowin' lawns, chief.
I mean, he's cute!
He's got great eyes.
But his voice is so high...
it sounds like a girl.
Hey, Cherise, hold on.
Got to ring up this freak.
One second.
Uh, forty-eight fifty
with the gas.
And a packet of Reds.
Are you gonna get me
any matches?
Are you gonna get me a bag?
You should think about goin' on a
diet, you're a bit overweight.
You smell.
And have bad breath.
Ya think so?
Yeah.
You think MY breath smells bad,
you should taste my cock
after it's been jammed up your
chubby pink butt.
My sperm's probably a lot healthier for
you than the shit you've been eating.
Would you like that?
Would you like to suck on my
shit covered prick?
No.
Well, then when someone gives you advice,
you be polite enough to take it...
...and say "thank you"
afterwards.
Than....thank you.
Do you want to push the little red button?
Yeah, go ahead!
You just gotta be ready
for the consequences,
cause all I'm doin'
right now is just talking.
And believe you me,
I can do a whole lot more.
That kid's gonna to wake up one day and
realize it's not his wife he hates....
...it's his mother.
But since he married his mother,
it'll be too late to do anything about it.
Where do you come up
with these things?
I collect observations.
You should write
them down, Jeff.
Write a book.
I will.
Tell me some more
of your observations.
Alright.
See that guy?
He thinks stewardesses
like him...
...but that's just how they treat
everybody in business class.
Your shrimp cocktail sir.
He had a brief
affair with his secretary
in Chicago before
things got too weird.
I mean, he loves his wife...
...but he hasn't had
sex with her in six years.
Since they had the last son.
He's been dating
underwear models ever since.
Dinner's almost ready.
It all started with the lingerie
catalogues in his study while his wife was
making tuna sandwiches and his
daughter was practicing the trumpet.
He started to recognize the lingerie
models in the different catalogues.
He would create different
scenarios in his mind...
Ski trips.
...the "mile high" club.
He recognizes the girl in
that lingerie poster over there...
That's the one he saw
in another catalogue.
The one that likes it
where the sun don't shine.
What about her?
Oh, she just quit smoking.
Yeah! Yesterday she ate a whole
pint of ice cream by herself...
...while her kids
were takin' a nap
and her husband was watching the
"Monster Truck" show.
Then she went
digging in the garbage
for cigarette butts and
she found one.
Ugh!...
She looks at herself every
night in a full length mirror
She still thinks
she's sexy.
But her husband doesn't.
He doesn't understand
her appetite.
Sugar makes her
feel better.
God, shoot me if I ever
end up like that.
She thinks about
picking up complete strangers
and fucking them in
motel rooms and she knows...
...one night she's
going to, but hey....
...at lest she's gotten
over her drinking problem.
She hasn't had an episode since
that dinner party last year.
"I am, in truth,
the Steppenwolf that I often call myself.
That beast astray that finds neither
home nor joy nor nourishment...
...in a world that is strange
and incomprehensible to him."
Now, that guy was the biggest, toughest kid
growing up in his neighborhood in Haiti.
He was good with his fists...
...so, he was hired by some local
goons to work to collect debts.
But then he fell in love...
He wanted to start a new life,
so he moved over here.
And the two
of them got jobs...
...working as night janitors
at a high-tech company.
They worked hard.
And every morning at 2:00AM,
they would get together...
...and they would
eat cold chicken sandwiches.
When she died...
...there was an
emptiness left in him...
He began to pray to the
Madonna for forgiveness.
He promised to pay penance for
his sins by working hard...
...and never hurting
anyone ever again.
Every night...
...he goes back
to his empty apartment...
...and he eats his fish stew and
he dreams of his Maria.
And every night, he gets down
on his knees and he prays.
His mind is full of
snakes and demons.
And he can't wait
for the morning...
...where he can get back up and
go back to his post at work.
Wow.
Heavy.
What about this guy?
He inherited the tuxedo store
from his old man twenty years ago.
He hates tuxes almost
as much as he hates his life.
But he knows the business.
He knows that when a tux loses
it's luster,
he can sell it to a store in
a shabbier neighborhood.
He knows that most
guys are only going to wear
a tux twice in their life.
Once at the prom.
Oh!
And once at their
kid's wedding.
He's cornered the
market on both of them.
He had a pointless
and awkward affair
with the girl
that does his books...
...even fucked her the night before her
wedding which gave him a nice little...
...ego boost.
But those days are long gone.
Jeff!
Yo, What's up?
Whacha doin', man?
You smoking?
No...
Look at this guy!
Hey, Adelle.
Hey.
Do you guys want to
go see a movie?
Which one?
I don't know.
The one with...
you know, the guy...
Shel's working the door.
I'll see it.
I heard it sucks!!
Yeah.
Oh...
Are we going to get something to eat?
I'm starving.
Well....it depends on
how much cash Jeff has.
Yeah, Jeff! What do you got?"
Nothing.
Yeah, right!
You still owe me money.
You're an asshole, man!
Jeff...
you boys can figure out who owes who
later, but in the meantime...?
You can have my fries....
I don't eat saturated fats.
Oh!
Aww, jus...
Get me a smoothie,
alright?
Anything.
Dude...
That fuckin' whore gets you
every time!
Don't talk about her like that.
Dude. Whatever!
C'mon, man.
I got somethin' for you.
You got something?
Maybe.
He looks familiar.
Sir.
What're you doin'?
- What?
- C'mon, let's go.
- Let's go
- What?
Let's go!
That's ecstasy?
Doesn't look like "Ex".
It is.
I think it's "acid".
I don't know, man...
Dude!
I don't think it's a good night
for that kind of shit.
Okay. Why not?
I don't know... you know... I just
wanna hang out...
..talk to Adelle.
Fuck, Adelle, man!
Adelle is brain dead.
What's your thing
with her, anyway?
She's nobody.
She's not nobody.
Have you ever had a
conversation with her?
There's not a
thought in her head.
She just smokes cigarettes.
Yeah, and she's also
incredibly beautiful.
She is?
Yeah, she is.
I guess I... never noticed
her looks before.
She has a gravity.
You know, she's not like
the other girls.
Gravity?
An energy.
A sense of purpose, you know?
She's...
You're stoned, son!
No, I'm not.
You know what your problem is, dude?-
-No, Beckett, tell me.
You believe in, like, some kind
of life force-
- Not this
again, Beckett.
You're superstitious.
C'mon'.
I don't want to
do it alone.
Then don't.
I already did.
You did?
Do you feel anything yet?
No... I just did it like
a half hour ago.
Fuck It!
What are you guys doin'?
Nothing.
Dude, I forgot your smoothie.
Ah, that's fine-
Hey, guys, something is happening, okay?
Check it out.
I was having a smoke and these cops came out
of the doors with this pervert in handcuffs.
Pervert?
Yeah! Pervert, man,
peeping tom.
He was hanging around the dressing
rooms trying to scope some bush.
Did he?
Well, yeah, I guess. C'mon!
Aren't you comin'?
I don't want to see a pervert.
Yeah, me neither.
Whatever....your loss.
This way. Go!
So, how's it goin'?
Hmm?
Uh, how's it goin'?
It's going.
Alright!
Are you married?
What?
Your wife can
come pick up the car.
In the meantime, you have
the right to remain silent.
Wait a minute, c'mon.
Am I under arrest?
What do you think this is, you think you
can keep doing this without getting caught?
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can be
used against you...
- But... this is just... but wait a
second, you guys!
- C'mon, you saw her!
- If you can't afford one...
But she did this shit on...
Do you understand these rights
that I have been saying to you?
She did that shit on purpose!
- She was real pretty, right?
- Right!
Okay?
So... look, I'm only human,
you know?
My niece was raped last year.
Now get in the fucking car!
- Let's go!
- Aright, Jesus!
Alright, alright!
Fucking perv!
Wait... Nope, it is. It is him!
Hey! Hey!!
- Pervert!
- Yo, dude!
- That's the perverted man!
- Hey! Hey! You like
what you see, man?
....Pervert!
Busted!
"Life is always frightful.
We cannot help it and we are
responsible all the same.
One is born and,
at once, one is guilty."
You got it! Tomorrow!
Asshole!
You're the fucking...
We're closed.
I told you we're...
C'mon, man!
Is that really you, Malcolm?
My God!
Look at you!
Long time, my friend!
Got to be at least,
like, 4 or 5 years?
You look great, man!
You've grown!
By the way, how's your Mom?
Huh?
Mal, what's up?
Hey, what are you doin'?
What's up, man?
You come to rob me?
C'mon!
You want the tuxes?
You can have'em.
You want the money, you know
where it's at.
Same old place as before.
I don't fuckin' care, you see, I'm insured.
Take whatever you want....
...Get the hell out of here.
You heard me...
Take the money...
And leave...
Through the back door...
Okay?
Because security is going to be
here any minute.
And I need to get goin'.
Fuck!
That's not funny, man!
So, Adelle,
what are you doing in the fall?
I'm movin' to New York,
I'm gonna... model.
Oh!
Well, I think of
it this way...
They always need new models
and you don't have to be...
pretty in an old fashioned way,
you can be interesting.
I think you're beautiful.
In an old-fashioned
kind of way.
..figure the worst
I can do is porno.
What?
I said the worst I can do is porno,
what, does ecstasy make you deaf?
No..I just...
Wait....how did you
know about...?
Duh!...
Beckett did it.
Of course you were going to do it.
But Adelle, seriously...
That would be horrible...
I'm joking.
God.
Oh!
I was serious when I said I
thought you were beautiful.
Jeff...
Are you saying you like me?
Um...
Like you want to go out with me?
Yes.
And fuck me and stuff?
What?
Is that what you're sayin?
No!
N..no, no, no. That's not what
I'm saying...
You don't want to fuck me?
No! I...
You're messing with me, right?
No, I just want to know if you
want to fuck me and stuff.
And stuff?
You know...
Okay, this is seriously
weirding me out.
Why is this weird? You just told
me you thought I was beautiful
which make me think that you like
me and when a guy likes a girl...
he wants to fuck her, right?
Yeah... but.
And stuff.
Exactly what kind of "stuff"
are you talking about?
Blow jobs, rim jobs,
licking your balls, going down,
you know... stuff.
Please stop it.
You don't' want me
to lick your balls?
No!
Why not?
I just want to hang
out with you.
I think I might be
in love with you, Adelle.
Are you okay?
Did I hurt your feelings?
No.
I don't know...
it's just...
We never really...
Talked before this...
Do you really love me?
C'mon...
Do you?
Yes.
Jeff.
Can I something and promise me
you won't... get mad.
Yeah.
You're...
really... unexciting.
This is fucking crazy!
Malcolm? Please...
L-listen to me. I-I have money.
You can get whatever you want.
But you've got to get the hell
out of here before the cops come.
You understand
what I'm telling you?
I won't tell
'em I recognized you.
Swear.
Do you want
a second chance, Barry?
Do I want a second chance?
Yeah.
That's what I want.
Well, where was the fuck was my second
chance when you fired me you fucking faggot!
Huh?
Where the fuck was
my second chance?
You ruined
my fucking life!!
I ruined your life?
You're fuckin'
out of line, man!
Did I shove those drugs
down your throat?
Did I skim money?
You gave me no option, man.
I had to fire you.
You see I... run... a business!!
Not any more!
Fucking idiot.
Don't do this to me, Mal.
Hey, get away from there.
Don't fuck it up, Mal.
Please!
You can take
everything I have, Mal.
Please!
No! No! Please!
Any available units
in the vicinity of East Valley Mall
we have a 4-17 shots fired. Suspect
still at location believed to be armed.
This is Unit 3, we're right outside
the Mall, we'll check it out.
Copy that Unit 3.
I'm going to un-cuff you.
Give you a summons.
Are you serious?
Yeah, today's your lucky day.
"Whoever
wants music instead of noise.
Joy instead of pleasure.
Soul instead of foolery."
"Finds no home in
this trivial world of ours."
"I do want more.
I am not content
with being happy.
I was not made for it.
It is not my destiny.
My destiny is the opposite."
"He went on two legs.
Wore clothes and
was a human being.
But nevertheless,
he was a wolf of The Steppes."
"He had
learned a good deal.
And was a fairly
clever fellow.
What he had not learned,
however, was this...
To find contentment in
himself and in his own life.
He knew all the time...
That he was in reality...
Not a man."
They're sayin' it
was a disgruntled employee.
Set fire to the place, I guess
he killed someone too.
Uh.... Did they get the guy?
I don't think so...
He might still be in there.
That's exciting!
Maybe he'll come here,
we can buy him a drink.
I hate the Mall.
I hope it burns to the ground.
I'm kidding!
Right!
I'm Donna.
Ahh... I'm Lenny.
Hi, Lenny.
You come here often?
Me? Uh, no...
I'm just... passin' through.
I'm stayin' at the hotel
next door.
Hmm...
I'm just a housewife.
Oh!
Just another
bored housewife.
Living in America.
Ha ha ha.
Mm.
How're the rooms over there?
Ah... They're nice...
you know... Not bad.
Wow! Gosh! There's another one.
This thing must be serious, huh?
What kind of name
is "Lenny"?
Ah, it was my
grandfather's name.
Mm...
You know, I'll bet this thing
is like 5 alarms.
Maybe you could see it better
from your room.
I wonder?
Let's go see...
Donna...
Uh... would you
excuse me for a minute.
I have to run
to the little boy's room.
Certainly!
I'll, uh... be back in a second.
Mm.
Ed, where's Tom?
He was right over there
a minute ago.
Oh.....shit!!!
Dude! It's the pervert!!
Oh... Hey, man, did you escape?
I think he's in shock.
Are you in shock, dude?
Look,
he's still got his handcuffs on,
and he's all burnt up and shit.
Dude! The cop car blew up.
He must have flew through the air
and landed right here!
Wild!!
Dude. Are you alright?
No.
Let me see these handcuffs.
Does this hurt?
No, don't do that, man.
- Why not?
- We could kill this guy!
We could throw him in the woods.
No one would ever know!
This is the guy who was looking
at dressing rooms
With girls
in the dressing rooms.
He likes to look at pussy.
I know,
show him your puss, Shel.
Do you want to see my pussy?
No, I wanna go home.
Well,
if we don't get these handcuffs off...
You might never get free.
It'd be like stuck on a
deserted island.
You'd probably starve.
This is like the slaves, man.
This is what it was like
for the slaves.
What slaves?
My ancestors.
The African slaves.
Are you still
trippin', Beckett?
What?
There you guys are.
What the hell?
Yeah, check it.
It's the fucking pervert.
He must have escaped when
the nut job blew up the cop car.
Dude, this is like
that thing out in Arizona.
I heard he's
hiding out in the woods.
I hear he has, like... a flame
thrower or something.
- What?
- Wow? Cool...
Dude! This is going to
be on TV, man!
All over the fuckin' world!
Dude, we gotta get on TV
YES! Let's go!!
Jesus...
Those must hurt.
Everything's going to be okay.
Here... let me help you up.
I'm just trying to help, man,
you don't look too good.
Alright, everybody, let's go!
Split it up.
Six over here,
three in the middle.
Hey.
You just come from the Mall?
Yeah.
What's happening? We're not-
we're not gettin' much.
They said a guy killed a cop.
Maybe a couple of other people?
Yeah, that's what I heard.
God,
I hope it isn't someone I know.
Someone somebody knows.
Uh....what are ya drinkin'?
Some beer.
Yeah...
It's on the house.
Thanks.
I used to always
come here with my parents
before they got divorced.
My Dad always ordered the steak.
Medium rare.
My Mom always ordered the fish.
As if by ordering fish, she was
somehow improving herself.
She was always trying to
improve herself.
I never noticed any change.
You alright?
I just...
...saw a guy on a stretcher.
I think he might
be dead.
That sucks.
Yeah.
So what are you doing sitting
here by yourself?
People suck out loud.
I hate people!
Yeah, especially when there's a
lot of them.
I hate them individually too.
Hate's a strong word.
I don't want to hate anybody.
You alright?
Your eyes are all,
you know, weird.
Yeah.
I'm fine I'm just...
...hanging out.
You know.
Kicking back....
You're hangin' out?
You look pretty
serious to me...
I do?
Uh....
He smiles...
I like to hang out.
Kick back.
Let's kick back together.
Thought you didn't like people.
You're not people.
Yeah, what's your name?
Jeff.
You're Jeff?
Hi, Jeff.
What's your name?
It doesn't matter. So, what...
are you, um, a student?
College, yeah.
Yeah? What are you studying?
Literature.
Really?
What's your favorite book?
Steppenwolf.
The band?
No, it's written by...
Never mind.
Uh, I stick to movies anyway.
Oh, I like that, um, the book, the,
you know, about the vampires...
the ones that take place
in New Orleans.
Anne Rice?
Yeah!
No, I really, I mean...
New Orleans is a very sexy place...
...and I really like all that,
like, kooky voodoo stuff....
I should watch out!
Yes, you should...
You sure you're alright?
Yeah! Nah...
I'm fine. I just,
had a lot to drink.
Maybe you should
get some air...
"Human life is
nothing but a bad joke.
A violent abortion
of the primal mother.
A hopeless and barbaric
catastrophe of nature..."
Dude, snap out of it!
You're being anti-social!
Sorry.
Let me ask you something.
If you could go anywhere...
where would you go?
Vienna.
How come?
Cause that's where Freud and
Beethoven used to hang out.
I'd like to go there and...
...feel the history.
I like that.
Feel the history.
That's cool!
That's intellectual. My husband
would never say something like that!
You're married?
You're supposed to check to see if a girl's
wearing a ring, when you talk to her.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
He's not here, he's home
with the kids.
You have kids?
Yeah...
What, are you surprised?
No, it's just,
you look so... young.
Maybe I am?
Maybe I'm younger
than you?
Yeah.
Do you think I'm attractive?
Yes.
What're you thinking?
That maybe I could...
...kiss you?
Hmm... That's funny.....
I was thinking the
same thing...
Wait! Oh, oh! Easy soldier,
I'm a married woman!
I'm sorry...
I'll call you in ten minutes.
Where you goin'?
Tsk! Just pick up the phone.
Hello.
This is Alonso.
Who is this?
Hi, Sheila!
I'll be right there.
Okay.
You must be Alonso
Yes.
I said 302.
Oh.
What took you so long?
The elevator.
Well, Ándale! Andale.
Tsk.
Hmm...
Would you like some beer,
vodka... wine?
Probably not a great idea.
How 'bout...
...some chocolate?
You're gonna
need it for your energy!
Wow! You really
wolfed that down!
Yeah.
You nervous?
Little bit.
Hey, wanna watch some porno?
Porno?
Mm....
They pipe it into all rooms,
for all the salesmen.
I don't like porno.
It's fucked up.
Well...
Alonso.
Do you like.....
This?
Sí!
Sí...
Now you are speaking my lingo.
You are a very... very...
...naughty pool boy.
You fuck me, Alonso!
I see the way you look at me
in that cabana.
Um....
Oh, yes, with your greasy,
sweaty body...
You want me...
Yes you do!
Is that your car?
Yes.
My keys are in my pocket.
Thank you so much!
No problem.
Here.
Let me just get the door.
You know, if you could just...
...uh, just take me to the Police
Station and they could help me get these-
these cuffs off, okay?"
Aren't you a fugitive?
No, they let me go.
Do they hurt?
Yes. If... if you have
something like a pin or something,
you could get me
out of these...
That only works
in the movies, silly.
Oh, right. Okay
Yo! FUCK!!...
Fuck!! Ah!!!
Is that too tight?
Yes, it hurts!
Why did you do that for?
Why are you doing that?
Please, make it go back.
Please!
They don't go back.
I... just... make it
go back, okay?
They don't.
Well, it hurts, okay?
Why are you hurting me?
Why would I want to hurt you?
I could think of much better
things to do.
What are you going to do?
Um, what are you going to do?
What do you want me to do?
I want you to take the
handcuffs off, please.
What if I can't do that?
Then just leave me alone.
And, uh, go away!
Don't you like me?
Yes, I... I do, yes.
Well, then, what do you want me
to do with you?
You're, like, my total slave
right now.
Isn't that incredible?
Bet you've been with hookers.
No, I've never been
with a hooker.
Bullshit!
You're a business man!
You're always with hookers!
I know guys like you.
No...
I know what you do...
I've never been with a hooker,
okay? I've never been with
a prostitute or a massage
therapist or anything like that!
Look, I didn't hurt you!
Of course you hurt me.
No!
Wha... What are you doing now?
Ow! Fuck!
Fuck!
I don't like it when you lie.
Do you wanna kiss me?
No! No.
You wanna kiss me??
Okay... yes...
Ah!
Okay, okay. Your hurting my...
It hurts my arm!
You're breaking it..."
Take me! Take me! Oh! Oh!
"A wild longing for
strong emotions and sensations...
...seethes in me.
A rage against this toneless,
flat, normal and sterile life."
"I have a mad impulse
to smash something."
"A warehouse, perhaps.
Or a cathedral."
"Or myself.
To commit outrages...
To pull off the wigs of a
very few revered idols."
No! No, please stop!
Please!
Too late for that now, isn't it?
Don't do this to me!
Please, don't torture me, okay?
Do you want me to make you come?
No...
Please, please, please!
No!
Okay, yes, yes, yes!
Say... I'm a pervert.
No...
Say it!
I... I can't....please...
Please. No!
I'm a pervert.
Say it over and over.
God!
Oh, gross!
Now, where are you goin'?
Bye.
It's nice to meet you.
"For those who loved him,
only saw the one side of him.
Many loved him as a refined
and educated man...
were horrified and disappointed when
they discovered the wolf in him.
And they had to
because Harry wished...
...as every
conscience being does...
...to be loved as a whole.
And, therefore, it was just with...
...those whose love he treasured
most that he could least of all...
...conceal and deny the wolf."
Do you want to do it again?
Um... leave your phone number.
I mean right now.
Oh... I gotta get home
to the hubby and rugrats.
Hi!
Yeah, no, I'm still
stuck in traffic!
I know. I heard! It's awful.
Yeah... No, I'm fine.
What did you give them?
Uh, fried chicken's nutritious!
Mmmhmm....
No, don't let Nacho in,
though, because he was
down at the swamp all day
and he's totally stinky.
No, I... I'll deal with it
tomorrow.
Yeah. Love you too. Bye.
So what has-has been going on?
I guess I should know?
Eight people are dead.
Wow!
They think they cornered him
in the woods.
They say he might be
wearing a tuxedo.
Oh... I mean,
that is totally weird!
Okay. Umm... I have to go....
Now, the room is on my credit
card, so don't break anything
Why would I break something?
Mm.
Maybe you'll...
....pick up some....
...innocent girl...
...at the bar...
...break the bed.
I just wanna lie here.
You! Are a very bad boy!!
I'm not going to be able
to walk tomorrow.
Bye, Tiger.
Yeah, I like to ride that cock.
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Fuck.
Jeff?
Are you okay?
It's really fucked up.
Jeff! What are you doing?
You.
Yeah, I'm talkin' to you,
I've got an M-4 pointed
at your fucking head...
Get over here.
What're you doing here?
Walking.
What are you, some fucking
wise-ass?
No.
Do you know who I am?
Yeah.
Yeah? And who are you?
Jeff.
You know, some fucking
spade rental-cop shot me.
Can you believe that?
Nine hundred
fucking cops out there
and this fuckin' spade
rent-a-cop shoots me.
Sit down.
Then you're gonna help me.
I saw the fire.
I saw dead people.
Oh, yeah? How'd they look?
Squished.
That's it?
Just "squished"?
Why'd you shoot them?
Cause they were there.
I used to work at the mall.
You could have shot me.
Oh, yeah?
Where did you work?
Taco Tonight.
Yeah, maybe.
I..I was at Tuxedo Time."
Hey, hey, hey....you wouldn't happen
to have any speed on you, would you?"
No, no. I had some ecstasy,
but Beckett took the rest.
I fuckin' hate ecstasy...
Oh, I hate fuckin' ecstasy.
Yeah, me too.
Okay, so. There's uh, there's a, um...
a .45...
...in my bag.
And you're gonna get it.
Why?
So you can kill me?
No, you idiot!
So you can kill me.
You, you, you,
you don't wanna be the hero?
You don't wanna be the
guy that shoots the madman?
I... I, I can't do that.
Fuck, you'll get laid, Jeff.
This is one of those
life-changing moments, Jeff.
You are willing to
die, you coward.
But not to live.
Jeff?
I am not the
coward in the woods with a gun.
He is stuck.
In his man-wolf dichotomy.
I am made up of
many more elements than that.
I am not stuck.
I am un-stuck.
Dude, you can see everything!
- Quick! We have to send this to this guy's wife!
- Yes!
Hey, hey!
What's your wife's name?
Dude, which one is she? Huh?
What are you doing?
It's the pervert!
C'mon, give me my phone!
Get out of here!
C'mon, man...
Get the fuck out of here!
My phone...
Dude! Chill, we were just
monkeying around!
Hey... are you okay?
No... No, my...
I can't feel my arms, man.
What happened?
It's a long story.
Here, let's, let's...
Please don't.
Just...
...can't do it...
Look, why do you have your
seatbelt on?
So that I wouldn't escape.
Well, okay... I'll just...
Alright...
Are you old enough to drive?
Yes.
Um...
Do you think that, uh...
...that you could, take me home?
Shouldn't I get you to
a hospital, uh, police station?
They could get
the cuffs open...
No, I'd like to...
just go home, please?
Well, maybe I could
find some tools...
Please, I just...
If you could just....
...you know, drive me home
to my wife, you know...
And, um...
...you'll help me with my pants.
Please?
Okay....
Thank you...
One, two, three...
Okay...
Okay, thanks.
You want me
to get your wife?
No. You better get out of here.
Tell me somethin'...
Do you know a red-headed girl, uh,
she's probably around your age...
...she hangs out
at the mall maybe?
Yes.
Is she a friend of yours?
No.
Good.
Babe, I'm home.
Hey.
Did you guys have a fun night?
Tsk! Oh, Nacho!
Nacho, you stinky, stinky dog!
Come here.
You are a bad dog.
You shouldn't be in the house.
One day I would
be a better hand at the game.
One day...
I would learn how to laugh.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org