(gentle, ominous music)
- [Narrator] The mysterious Himalayas,
spanning the entire distance
between India and Tibet,
somewhere up in this vast,
desolate section of our world
live a strange species
whose existence has baffled
science for centuries.
In recent years, many
anthropologists have pondered
the new reports of these creatures.
The question is always the same,
are they man or beast?
(dramatic, foreboding music)
- There's no one here.
- Oh I just hope I can find a bed.
- I'd rather find Erickson.
I didn't see his outfit.
I have hope we're not late.
- If he's left, we'll have to follow him.
- Well that's easily said, Connie.
- We've come this far, we'll keep going.
- Speak English?
- Little.
- We're looking for Dr.
Erickson, is he here?
- Gone.
- [Trevor] When?
- [Man] Tomorrow.
- [Trevor] (chuckles) You mean yesterday.
Do you know where?
- Mountain.
- Hello.
What are you doing up here?
- I'm just too tired to go into it.
- I'm Trevor Hudson.
This is Connie Hayward.
- Steve Cameron.
Hayward?
I met a man named Hayward,
Dr. James Hayward here,
a few weeks back.
- My brother,
and the reason we're here.
- Oh he left 10 days ago to set up camp
for the Erickson expedition.
- And Professor Erickson?
- [Steve] Erickson left yesterday morning.
- Then we'll have to follow him.
- You mean you don't know the purpose
of Dr. Erickson's expedition?
- Only that he's been
preparing it for years.
- Well, his purpose is to capture
one of the abominable snowmen.
That's what the natives call the Yeti.
They're a kind of people
covered with hair,
supposedly living above
the 21,000 foot level.
- Covered with hair?
- [Connie] What do you
mean, a kind of people?
- Nobody seems to know
whether they're man or beast.
Everyone thought they were a fable
until some famous explorers
found traces of them
just before World War I.
Since then, many people have
claimed to have seen them.
- Did you know about this?
- Well I knew Dr. Erickson
was hunting snowmen,
but I thought they were
fossil relics of the Ice Age.
Do you believe these stories?
- Well Erickson's a famous anthropologist.
- Are these Yetis dangerous?
- I've seen four expeditions
go up in search of the Yeti
and each has lost at least one man.
- Well that settles it, Connie,
I'm not letting you endanger
your life by going any farther.
- You can't go beyond this point anyway,
you won't be able to get guides,
you'll never make it alone.
- Why can't we get guides?
- They won't go out on anything
connected with a Yeti hunt
unless a certain guide
named Varga leads them.
And Erickson's got him.
- Mr. Cameron, do you know
where Erickson's camp will be?
- I have a rough idea.
- [Connie] Would you lead us up?
- You know what you're asking?
- Mr. Cameron,
I'm willing to pay any
price for your assistance.
It's urgent that I get to my brother.
- We can get lost up there
and they'd never find us.
- I'll have to risk that.
- You're a very determined
person, Miss Hayward.
- Yes, Mr. Cameron, determined
to save my brother's life.
(gentle, ominous music)
- Well,
we'd have to leave right away
if we expect to catch Erickson
before he reaches deep snow.
- You'll go.
- I know you two would
never make it alone.
- Thank you, Mr. Cameron.
I'm very grateful.
(dramatic, ominous music)
(wind hissing)
(rocks rumbling)
(dramatic music)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
- We could make another couple
of miles before nightfall.
- Let's camp here and
push ourselves tomorrow.
- We'll never catch up
with Erickson sitting here.
- I can't go another
step. (labored breathing)
- This is Hayward's party,
she says stay, we stay.
- We'll go on.
- Connie, this is stupid,
you're killing yourself.
- We'll keep going.
(Trevor sighs)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
- If we're lucky, we
may see them tomorrow.
- You've been saying that for two days.
- I wasn't saying it to hear myself talk.
I don't enjoy this pushing
any more than you do,
but it's our only hope
to overtake Erickson.
- Don't blame Steve, Hud,
I'm the one who's doing the pushing.
We'll stay with our
schedule, daylight to dusk.
You might as well take it gracefully.
- If this isn't the weirdest nonsense,
somebody thinks he saw
a Yeti 40 years ago,
this gives Erickson
the idea to capture one
and I find myself stuck up
in the wiles of the Himalayas
just because your brother happened to--
- Hud!
- I'm sorry,
but you've got to admit,
it doesn't make much sense.
- What do you want us to do, turn back?
Look Hud, I didn't ask
you to come on this trip,
you volunteered.
If you wanna turn back, go ahead.
(Connie sighs)
- He may be getting a
touch of the altitude.
It affects some people.
- He has a touch of
feeling sorry for himself.
I guess you never really know people
unless you go through
something like this with them.
- He'll come around.
You better get some rest.
- Tired as I've been, I can't sleep.
- (laughs) Guilty conscience?
- My brother, Jim,
ever since you mentioned these snowmen,
I've been all the more worried.
What's your theory about them?
- I don't have any.
All I know is what I've read
and heard from the natives.
- Has anyone ever had a good look at them?
- I talked to a man once
who was supposed to have
seen one through his glasses.
He claimed they walked upright like a man.
- How can anyone live in that cold?
- I can't answer that.
Nothing grows up there.
Too high for animal life.
Your guess is as good as anybody's.
- Dr. Erickson really
thinks he'll contact one?
- He certainly hopes to.
I had a long talk with him one night.
- Do you really think we'll
catch up with them tomorrow?
- Oh I figure we picked up a day on them.
(wind hissing)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(Connie sighs)
(labored breathing)
(wind hissing)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
- Take another look.
- What good'll it do?
Even if you see them, we
can't hail them to stop.
- We'd better find them soon
or we've made this trip
up here for nothing.
- Why?
- Because, all this snow,
moving six different directions.
- How could I have gotten
mixed up in this thing?
- Because you wanted to help me.
Or so you say.
(Trevor exhales)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
- I got 'em.
- Where?
How far.
- Straight over there.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
- Is there any way to signal them?
- They may hear this.
(gun blasts)
Did they hear it?
- They haven't turned.
(gun blasts)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
- Doctor,
I hear a gun shot.
Listen.
(distant gun blasts)
- That was a shot.
Who can it be?
No one hunts this high.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
- They're trying to find
us with glasses, look.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
- They're trying to signal us.
There's a woman.
Now who can they be?
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
Well, they certainly want us.
We'll wait for them.
- Are they far?
They're waiting.
- Thank God.
- Come on, let's move.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(wind hissing)
- Cameron, what are you doing up here?
- Miss Hayward.
- How do you do.
- How do you do, Doctor?
- And Mr. Hudson, Doctor.
- How do you do?
- My pleasure, Doctor.
- Miss Hayward will do all the explaining.
- Hayward?
Are you related to Jim?
- My brother.
- You've come way up here to see him?
- I have to.
But I didn't quite plan it like this.
We expected to find you in Kalpa.
We missed you there,
missed you at the outpost
and here we are.
- Well we'll both see him soon,
we're not very far from camp.
Lucky we heard that shot.
We'll be in the snow in a few hours,
you never could have caught us.
Kheon, make coffee.
We might as well camp right here.
Here, let me help you with your things.
- Thank you.
(wind hissing)
- So when I heard that
new tracks had treaded,
and there were fresh
rumors about the Yeti,
I decided to see for myself.
- You really believe it.
- It's hard not to when so many famous men
stake their reputations on the fact.
- Are they really covered with fur?
- Not fur, hair.
Fur has no root, but hair does.
We've definitely established that the Yeti
are covered with a hair quite
similar to our own. (grunts)
Here's the general conception
of most scientists.
- [Connie] More beast than man.
- Maybe to your eyes,
but I believe it's human.
- You really wanna capture that?
- I think that I'd die happy
if I could study them.
They may be the missing link.
If they are,
we've solved 1,000
mysteries about you and me.
- I'd hate to tangle
with one on a dark night.
- Oh I don't think you have
to worry about that. (laughs)
- I wish I hadn't seen that sketch.
I don't think I'll ever sleep again.
- Oh nonsense, they're
probably just simple people.
- People?
Just hope I don't dream tonight.
(doctor laughs)
- Well, I guess we'd all better turn in.
- Yes.
(doctor grunts)
(gentle, dramatic music)
(hissing wind)
- Stop here.
Tomorrow big climb.
- [Doctor] There is is, Yeti country.
- As far as I'm concerned,
you can have it.
- If we're lucky and capture one,
this trip could make you famous.
- [Steve] You can have the
fame. I'll take some hot coffee.
- Magnificent country.
It seems to fascinate you
as much as it does me.
- I'm not going up there.
- I didn't think I'd make that last hill.
It was easy for you.
A nice rest and--
- No.
It's not the climbing, it,
it's the Yeti.
I have a feeling--
- Come on, Hudson, we need a drink.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
- I saw him, Steve,
there's something wrong.
I felt it all day.
- Nonsense, Connie, I can
understand Hud cracking, but--
- He's watching us right now.
(wind hissing)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
Did you see that?
He knows we're talking about him.
- I'll speak to Erickson
when I get a chance.
- Have you seen much of him before?
- He's one of the guys
that works for Varga.
- What about this Varga?
Can he be trusted?
- Everyone hires him.
- And something always happens,
someone always gets killed.
- I'll see what I can find out.
Not a word of this to the others.
I'll keep my eye on the
guy tomorrow as we go up.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- The more I see of this
country, (labored breathing)
the more I'm convinced
the Yeti are a myth.
Look, what could live
in a place like that?
- That's part of the mystery.
- What about you?
Ever see a Yeti?
- No see.
- Ever meet anybody who did?
- See Yeti,
die.
- Let's move on.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- I wonder where they made camp.
I don't see it.
- Camp.
- They were supposed to set up tents.
Let's have a look.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
(dramatic, foreboding music)
- Nothing.
This didn't happen today.
How do you figure it, Doc?
- I'm baffled.
Everything's ripped apart.
- It'll be getting dark pretty soon.
If we're going to be stuck,
we may as well be stuck comfortably.
Better give me a hand setting up camp.
- All right, get that. (grunts)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- Well we're in good shape,
guides took off during the
night, left us up here.
- What?
- They deserted.
Now we're iced laden up here
with no one to lead us back.
- Where's Steve?
- Oh he and Erickson went off this morning
to see if they could find
any sign of Jim and Varga.
This whole trip was a blunder.
- If you felt that way,
why did you come with me?
- Because I thought I could
talk some sense into you.
- Oh look, Hud, this trip has
proved we'll never get along.
It's been one continual argument
ever since we left home.
(hissing wind)
(match clicks)
(men exhale)
- Funny we don't see a
mark, tracks, something.
How do you figure it, Doc?
- I've been afraid to mention it.
- You believe the Yeti got Jim and Varga.
- Is there any other explanation?
- I just can't believe it.
We'd better get back.
What do we tell Connie?
- Just keep the Yeti out
of it, no use worrying her.
(hissing wind)
(dramatic, foreboding music)
- These are the worst (mumbles)
- Varga!
- Doctor Erickson, it's good to see you.
Mr. Cameron, we meet again.
I'm glad you two appeared,
Miss Hayward and Mr. Hudson
have been quite concerned.
- Do you know where Jim is?
- He doesn't.
He's as puzzled as we are.
- Weren't you taking,
didn't you leave the camp together?
- He left alone.
There had been quite a snowfall that night
and I thought I might
find some fresh tracks.
When I returned that afternoon,
I found the camp as you had.
I've been looking ever since.
- He must have left
tracks in the heavy snow.
- I tracked him around to the
east side of the west block,
but beyond that point, the wind
had obliterated everything.
- Mr. Varga hasn't given up hope.
He says there's a good chance
Jim might have holed up somewhere.
- He was anxious to leave,
too anxious I thought.
Maybe he stumbled onto
something and just kept going.
- Knowing we'd look for him.
- [Varga] As we surly will.
- May I have a word with you alone, Varga?
- If Miss Hayward will excuse me?
- Of course.
- We'll make a thorough
search for him in the morning.
God willing, we'll find him.
- Did you find anything, Steve?
- Nothing.
- Do you think there's any hope?
- Connie, I don't know.
- Well I'm not going to give up.
If Jim's out there, I'm going to find him,
dead or alive.
- Come in, come in Varga.
(grunts) Can I offer you a drink?
- Never touch a drop.
- Is that so?
I always thought you
climbers liked your nip.
- You can't mix mountains and whiskey.
- What about Jim, Varga?
- I wish I knew.
- Any ideas?
- You're referring, of
course, to the Yeti?
- How else can you explain
his complete disappearance?
- As I've told you down below,
I think I've made this trip up here
more times than any man alive.
I have yet to see a Yeti or tracks.
- Then how do you explain these rumors?
- I don't even try.
Every new rumor means more expeditions
will make the trip up here.
Expeditions are my business.
- As you know,
I've specialized in the evolution
of man for over 30 years.
- I've heard you quoted 1,000 times.
You deal in theory, I deal in fact.
- I can't believe that such men as DuBois,
Wagner, Hale, Bishop,
could be completely wrong.
One of them, yes, but four
distinguished scientists,
each at a different time, different place,
have seen the same evidence.
Well tomorrow I shall see for myself.
Any plans as to where we can start?
- I suggest that ridge
that runs north and south.
I've tried to take other
parties over there,
but they didn't like the climb.
- You lead, I'll follow.
Well, see you tomorrow then.
- [Varga] Goodnight, Doctor.
- Goodnight.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- Might be well for us to split up here.
The doctor and I will take this side,
you three follow that
ridge as far as you can.
You see anything, fire a shot.
We'll do the same.
Good luck Miss Hayward.
If you do fire a shot, Mr. Cameron,
make sure you're in the clear.
It could cause a slide.
Good luck.
- Something about that guy.
- I've been wanting to say
that ever since I met him.
- He's tried to be helpful,
what more could he do?
- I don't know, Connie, but--
- Come on, this isn't finding Jim.
Let's go.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
(ominous, dramatic music)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
(Connie sighs)
- We'd better get back.
Connie, I hate to quit,
but this seems hopeless.
- Steve, I told you it was
urgent that I find Jim,
but I didn't explain why.
He took some experimental
injection back in the states.
After he left, the doctor told me
that if he didn't return from
this high altitude at once,
he would die.
- Didn't he know that?
- No, it's a continuous experiment.
This altitude factor was revealed
only after Jim had already
left. (labored breathing)
- Connie,
Connie, we've got to go back
and organize a regular rescue party
or we'll never get to Jim.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- It means that I don't trust Varga.
I know what you're thinking,
that I'm afraid,
maybe I am.
But you yourself says
that at least one person
has been lost in every
expedition he has led.
And how do you account for
the two guides disappearing?
- I've wondered about that myself.
- You'll notice Varga
hasn't mentioned them.
- You're jumpy, Hud.
- All day I've had the feeling
someone was watching us,
trailing us.
- We'll take the same route back.
If somebody's watching
us, maybe we'll see them.
Come on.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- From this spot, you can see every local,
where the Yeti are
supposed to have been seen.
That peak was where
DuBois first found tracks.
Over there,
Wagner photographed what
he claims are Yeti tracks.
And right down there,
the spot where Bishop claims
he first saw a Yeti last year.
- Weren't you with Bishop?
- I led the trip, I wasn't
with him at the time.
- Bishop was a friend
of mine for 20 years.
I don't think he'd make such a statement
without some good reason.
By the way, how was he killed?
- We never knew.
A few days later, he
disappeared, much as Jim has.
We searched for days.
- We lost a great man.
I lost a great friend.
Did you ever check his
discovery spot for tracks?
- We didn't have much chance,
there was four feet of snow that night.
- Can we pass that spot on the way?
- If we hurry.
I don't wanna keep the others waiting,
Miss Hayward is concerned enough as it is.
- I want you to know, Varga,
I appreciate your
concern for Miss Hayward.
- I envy Steve.
They'll make a fine couple.
- Steve?
I thought it was Hud.
- You're not as observant as I am, Doctor.
(gentle, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- Take it easy, Connie,
here they come now.
- Doctor Erickson, did
you find any trace of Jim?
- No I, (labored breathing)
I'm afraid we didn't, I'm sorry.
- Neither did we.
- Where's Hud?
- Hud?
- He was the first one to
climb back to join you.
- We didn't see him.
- Something must have happened.
We'd better get out of there
right away and look for him.
- I'll break out the flairs,
it might be dark before we find him.
(Hud shouts)
- Dr. Erickson, Steve, there he is.
(Hud shouting)
Hud, are you all right?
- Yes Connie, I'm all right.
- What happened, Hud?
- I was climbing over an outcropping
on my way to join you, Doctor,
and I saw some tracks in the snow.
- Tracks?
- I followed them for quite a while
'til they led me to a
large fault in the glacier.
I decided not to go any further alone.
- This is what I've been searching for.
Can you lead us back there, Hud?
- Now?
- Yes.
- It'll soon be dark.
- That's all right, we brought flairs.
Let's get started.
30 years I have waited for this.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
(dramatic, foreboding music)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- (screams) Look out!
- Where Hud, where?
- There! (screams)
(Connie screams)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(gun blasts)
(dramatic, foreboding music)
(Hud screaming)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- Steve, we've gotta get out of here.
- Erickson won't leave,
he's so steamed up about his
discovery, he's floating.
- Then we'll go alone.
- We can't desert him.
- Varga will stay with him.
- (sighs) That's what I'm afraid of.
You know,
I'm beginning to think Hud was
right about a lot of things.
- Poor Hud.
(Steve grunts)
If we'd only listened to him.
- This head.
- You're lucky to be
alive after last night.
If I live to be 1,000,
I'll never forget it.
- (groans) I know what you mean.
I'm going over to see Doc,
talk to him about Varga.
- Is Varga there now?
- I don't know, but if he
is, I'll try to pin him down.
- Don't ever let him
think you suspect him.
- Look Connie,
I'm only concerned about one thing,
getting us out of this place alive.
I'll be real cozy with Varga.
Come on.
(hissing wind)
- That's it, they wrote (mumbles)
- I've got to talk to you, Doc.
- Therefore, I threw--
- Doc, snap out of it.
- (mutters) Leave me
alone, don't interrupt me.
- Listen Doc, what I've got
to tell you concerns that.
- Steve, don't interrupt me,
I'll be hours getting down
what I saw last night.
(Doctor muttering)
- You want to get that back to the states?
- Don't ask me such
questions, of course I do.
- Then put it down and listen to me,
and listen closely
or none of us will get out of here alive.
- What?
- Where's Varga?
- Out there somewhere.
- Watch the flat, if
he comes, let me know.
- What's the matter, Steve,
you act as if you've lost your mind.
- I almost lost my life last night.
I don't wanna go the way Hud did, and Jim.
- You've learned something about Jim?
- I learned our chances to
get out aren't worth a nickel.
- Varga says they'll never attack,
they're frightened of guns.
You saw the way they panicked.
- Doc, did you see where
that club came from?
- I didn't even know you were
hit 'til Varga picked you up.
- I know there were no
Yeti on that side of me,
but Varga was.
- Varga?
Why he saved your life.
- And for what reason, I haven't figured.
- You should thank God we have Varga,
he got us out of there at
the risk of his own life.
You should've seen the
way he intimidated 'em,
literally chased them.
- [Steve] Doc--
- He's coming.
- Not a word about this.
I'm going to play this
straight and you play along.
(dramatic music)
- You're looking much better, Mr. Cameron.
- Doc tells me I owe you my life.
I don't know how much it's worth,
but I'll try to get even some day.
- It was nothing.
I'm sure you would have done the same
if our positions had been reversed.
How are you Miss Hayward?
I trust no ill effects from
that harrowing experience.
- I wouldn't like to go through it again.
- Well Doctor, it seems Miss Hayward
and Mr. Cameron don't
share our enthusiasm.
I suppose we'd better start
making plans for the trip back.
But before we go, would
you like to visit the cave?
- I'd like to spend a whole day there.
I have a dozen questions
I'd like answered.
- Whenever you're ready.
- Mind if I go, Varga?
- Of course not, the more the merrier.
- I'd like a day to get over this head.
It's the biggest hangover I ever had.
- Let's make it tomorrow then.
- Tomorrow it is.
- Good, I can take a day
to finish up my notes.
- (clears throat) I'll
be back in a moment.
I'm going to take another look outside.
(wind hissing)
- Keep a look out.
Doc, listen to me--
- You're not beginning all over again.
- Doc, this man is a phony.
Who or what he is, I don't know,
but he's playing us two
ways from the middle.
- How can you talk such nonsense?
What are you implying?
- Because he knew about that cave.
- Steve, I'm becoming a
little impatient with you.
Varga saved your life.
You should be grateful for that at least.
I want no more of your fanciful illusions.
Now if you don't mind,
I'll get back to my work.
- Okay Doc, have it your way.
Come on, Connie.
(wind hissing)
- Steve, what's the matter
with him? Why won't he listen?
- I'm beginning to think
there's something wrong with
all of us for coming up here.
- Are you really going back to that cave?
- You bet I am.
But this time I'll go prepared.
- But what about me?
- Come along.
- Steve, I couldn't, I just
couldn't go in that cave again.
- I can't let Erickson go alone.
I'm beginning to think
Varga is trying to pick
us off one at a time.
First there was Jim, then Hud.
He figures he get Erickson alone,
then he'll come back for us.
- Steve, let's get out of
here, let's go right now.
Please Steve, please, let's go.
- Honey, we'd never make it
down off that mountain alone.
I don't know what Varga's up
to, but I'm going to find out.
- I can't stay here alone, I can't.
- You're not going to
stay here in the tent,
that would make it too easy for him.
I think I can talk some
sense into Erickson
when we're inside the cave.
Now, remember the last
place we stopped to rest
just before we got here?
That's where you're going
as soon as I pull out with Doc and Varga.
Stay there until I come.
- But supposing you don't?
- I'll come back for you.
Now, take all the food you can carry--
- Steve,
if he comes first, I'll jump.
- You know, I think you would.
(metal clinks)
- Steve!
Oh Steve!
- Coming Doc!
Try this, see if it's too heavy.
- I can handle it.
- All right, hide it.
Soon as we're out of
sight, start back down.
Honey, don't lose it or we
don't eat all the way down.
(Connie laughs)
I'll see the doctor.
- Oh good morning, Steve.
- Morning, Varga, how are
things up in the hill?
- I kept watch all night,
not a sight of them.
- Eh, I guess we've seen the last of 'em.
Oh uh, Doc's been up all
night with his notes.
Maybe he'd like a rest before we start.
- Speak for yourself, Steve,
I'll be right with you.
- Is Miss Hayward coming with us?
- Oh she wanted to, but
I talked her out of it.
- I'm glad, she's had
enough trouble as it is.
By the way, I did find this.
- Thanks.
I just hope I don't have to use it.
I'll be ready.
(gentle, dramatic music)
(hissing wind)
- I don't know how you do it, Varga,
these climbs never seem to bother you.
- I've spent most of my life climbing,
comes as naturally to me as
sitting at a desk does to you.
- Seems unreasonable to be
warm in temperature like this.
- I can remember really
being warm in Calcutta.
That heat was just too much for me.
- What does a Himalayan
guide do in Calcutta?
- Good question, my
father was stationed there
so I started my early schooling.
It didn't work out, so
he shipped me to Sweden
where the temperature
was more to my liking.
- Didn't the heat affect your father?
- Not as it did me.
Apparently I take after my mother,
she was a mountain
woman with Mongol blood.
I never knew her, she died at my birth.
- [Doctor] Are you married, Varga?
- Never had the time for it.
- Too bad.
Good blood strain like
yours should be perpetuated.
It makes for strong men and women too.
Well the right woman will come along.
- I'll name my first son Eric, Eric Varga.
Sounds good, doesn't it?
- I'll hold you to that promise.
Shall we move on?
- It was a light snow we had last night,
could move easily.
We'd better spread out just in case.
(Doctor grunts)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
(dramatic, foreboding music)
(Steve exhales)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(rumbling rocks)
- Come on, we've got to get to Steve.
- He's no use to us, Doctor,
no man could live
underneath that avalanche.
- I'm going to take a look.
- You're coming with me!
- Varga, you'll do as I
ordered, this is my expedition.
- Was your expedition, Doctor,
you'll take orders from me now.
- Varga, you're forgetting your position.
- Don't ever talk to me like that again!
Don't even think it.
Start up that hill.
- You're mad, Varga.
- You'll soon see how mad.
Now start up that hill.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
My people will.
Most of them are not developed
intellectually, it's true.
They frighten at the sound of a shot,
but they'll get over that.
The only reason they wouldn't
kill one of you on sight
would be because I told them not to.
- You're mad.
- No Doctor, every move I've
made I've planned meticulously.
- I can make you the
most famous man alive.
- (chuckles) Put me on
exhibition, no thank you, Doctor.
I have other plans for me and for you.
- What possible plans
could you have for me?
- I plan to kill you.
- Kill me?
What good will that do?
- Kept this secret for centuries,
no man has ever seen us and lived.
No man will until we are ready.
Knowing what it would mean to you
to find this out about us before you died.
I thought I'd give you this pleasure.
You see, we are quite human after all.
- Let me help you, Varga.
- I'm not ready for your kind of help.
- It's obvious to me what your plan is,
to breed out the Yeti strain,
but how can you do it without help?
- I, being the 5th generation,
you can see that it's not too difficult
to obtain the necessary females.
- You kidnap women?
- There have been five this year.
Now, of course, there's--
- Connie!
- With her, I should be able
to hedgehop two generations.
Our offspring should be most interesting.
Don't you think so, Doctor?
Come come, Doctor,
a short while ago you were
recommending marriage for me.
Have you changed your mind so quickly?
- I recommended marriage,
not what you have in mind.
I had great respect for you
a short time ago, Varga,
because I thought you were a man apart.
I was mistaken.
You're a devil, Varga, a devil incarnate.
- Doctor, you disappoint me.
I thought we could discuss this
dispassionately, clinically.
After all, it's your own field,
where man came from, where he's going.
I'd hoped to get some suggestions from you
on how we could develop
our intellectual side.
You have nothing to offer?
- No.
- Too bad.
We'll part sooner than I'd expected.
- You don't frighten me, Varga.
My life has been full.
- Well said, Doctor.
I do this with regret, for
I have enjoyed your visit.
We speak the same
language in many respects.
Goodbye Doctor.
Perhaps we'll meet again
in some other incarnation.
(dramatic, percussion music)
(gun blasts)
(wind hissing)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
Miss Hayward, Doctor Erickson
has been seriously hurt,
he wants to see you right away.
- Where's Steve?
- We were caught in a
slide, I saved the doctor,
but I'm afraid that--
- No no, oh!
- Miss Hayward, you
don't have to be afraid,
I'm here to help you.
- [Connie] Steve!
Oh, Steve!
Steve!
Oh Steve!
(dramatic, foreboding music)
(gun blasting)
(fists thumping)
(dramatic, foreboding music)
- Hurry, let's start down
while we have the chance.
- Steve, Varga killed
Jim and Doctor Erickson.
He told me when I wouldn't go with him.
I think it's the madness
to the Yeti, I saw it.
- I know it all figures,
come on, we can talk later.
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
- Steve, look!
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
(hammer clanking)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
(metal clicking)
(dramatic, orchestral music)
(hissing wind)
(metal clicking)
(Vargas screams)
(Connie gasps)
(dramatic, foreboding music)
(Connie sobbing)
- It's all over, honey,
get ahold of yourself.
- (sobbing) Take me away from
here, Steve, take me away.
(dramatic, orchestral music)