Subtitles Nostromo
Hey,help yourself with one,Brown
No thanks,I've to keep
track of one of those
-Nice chap that Brown
-Useful to when there's an occasional(?) strike
-Been here long?
-About 2 years
Come from some rough water I believe
Where have you been Tom?
Haven't seen you for a couple of days
I've been busy
Got no right(?) to buy a ?????
-I should think so
-Right I'll bring him around later
Been busy in "Lander"
But I didn't exactly get him out on the sea
Half a bitter,please
Burden
What's the matter Brown?
You look as you've seen a ghost
Hello Burden
My name is Brown
Oh yes,how stupid of me
You must be careful what we say mustn't we?
You remember me don't you?
Newman,Corporal Newman,
I've just been demobbed
Take me on,chap
All right come on
Nice little place you got here Burden
Better than the Glasshouse(Mil.pris),eh?
Well,what do you intend to do?
I might do nothing, all depends
What made you desert Burden?
If you'd been a bit longer
you'd been out now
-I had my reasons,very good reason
-So have thousands of others
And look at them today
On the run,all of them,like you
You ever thought of giving yourself up?
What for?
No,the war cost me everything
I ever had,Newman
If they want me they got to catch me
They talked about clemency
sometime ago didn't they?
Made a deadline for us to give ourselves up
I know a man who fell for that
What did he get? Two years
hard labour in a detention barracks
And he sent his review every three months
Does that make you
want to give yourself up?
This was a man with a wife and two kids
and three years overseas
service to his credit
I've done my share nearly four years of it
War is over now and I just
want to be left alone
Well,if that's how you feel
What's it worth to you?
What's it worth to?
I'll give this straight Burden
You're nicely fixed up yeah?
It's ten thousand to one
against anyone else
from our lot ever coming within
hundred miles of the place
They're mostly from the north anyway
So there's no reason why you shouldn't
go on in peace and quiet indefinitely
That is if you're sensible
Peace and quiet,you don't
really think that,do you?
Why not?
Why not? I'll tell you why not
Phoney identity card phony ration book
Five pounds to a man up north every time
there's a new issue, always on edge
Still prefer it to the
Glasshouse ,don't you?
Now listen to it, we've
all got our troubles
Take me
Before the war I was down the mine
I've no intention of ever going back
I've been too long above
ground now and I like it
The only other trade I know is killing
And that's gone out of fashion
I'm sick and tired of the army
I want a bit of freedom
But like you I've got to earn money
So till something better comes along
I've taken a job at the local manor
My sisters is married one
of the game keepers
And he needs to fix me up
as a sort of general man
But the money's bad
That's where you come in to help me out
I'll settle for 20 pounds down
and two pounds a week
-Blackmail
-Call it what you like
That's how it is
How much you think I earn,for heavens sake?
I don't know and I don't care
-Well I haven't got 20 £ to start with
-Then find it
Tell me if you want to
And if you don't I'll turn you in
I'll come back tonight
Who is it?
It's me how about some rent Brown
You haven't paid me for four weeks
I'm not going to let it run any longer
All right I'll let you have it
I'm going out in a minute or two
Don't come back without it
or you won't get in again
And don't try to take
your things out either
Or I might start asking some
more awkward questions
-Henry
-All right
"I am sorry that I cannot help you myself
But you will remember that I told you
about the jeweller Collins,
he will convert everything into
cash You understand what I mean"
-Thank you
-Mr Collins
-Yes
Stay where you are and don't move
Don't you move or I let you have it
Thank you
"Don't you move or I let you have it"
Police Constable Martin who was shot
this afternoon in Golden Street whilst
trying to intercept the two armed men
concerned in the hold-up of the
jewel shop has since died
The police under the
direction of divisional
Detective Inspector Mitchell are sparing
no efforts in their hunt for the wanted men
owing to the fact that both men were
masked it's difficult to obtain an
accurate description of either of them
except their clothes and the fact that
one of them was tall and thin
the bullet from Martin's
body has been extracted
and given to the ballistics expert
and the shop is being searched for
fingerprints all members of the CID in
flying and Vice squads and the plain
clothes branch of the Metropolitan Police
have been recalled to duty
and in view of the gravity of the situation
many of them have been issued with arms
Their orders are bring these
men in at all costs
King's Cross,passenger enquiries please
"Scotland Yard is searching for
Martin's murderer. Since this morning,
the best officers of Scotland Yard are searching for the two men
who fatally wounded sergeant Martin in their hold-up of jeweller Collins.
Unfortunately, Mr. Robb Collins has not regained consciousness
yet, but the police hope that he will soon be able to give information.
I want urgently the next train to
Nottingham on the price for 3rd single
9 36pm, 2sh 8 p thank you
I say don't you come
that tetchy seeing me I said
I'm not ignoring you,you
behave like a gentleman
Yes
Light ale and one of
those sandwiches,please
No bottle,beer on draught only now
Half a bitter then
Hello,what's your game?
Bitter-Two bitters,Doris
-What type?this Golden street murderer,eh?
-They'll catch him all right,don't you worry
It's not much help for the
copper that got shot now,is it?
He's just come back out of the army too
What about his wife and kid!
I know my chaps being on the fiddle
but I draw the line of this kind
of thing and I'm not kidding
-Five past you know
-Thank you
Good Luck
-You got any gin?
-Yes
Give it two large ones,will you?
Well what did you do in the
world war daddy? Don't tell me I know
Fire watching ha,ha
You don't mind my having a drink,do you?
-I mean I'm not crowding you out?
-That's all right
Scores of people have been
questioned in and around Golden street
And many were taken to the police station
to make statements
A short while ago Mr Rob Collins the
jeweller recovered consciousness
and has given the police a description
of one of the three men
now known to have been involved
for some reason this man
who was wearing a raincoat
was not masked like the other two
This fact has given the police
a very valuable lead
every policeman in the country
has this man's description
and there is to be an all-out
drive to bring him in
Here,where's my money?
Somebody pinched my dough?
Just a minute where do
you think you're off to?
I don't know what you're talking
about I haven't touched your money
Hey Bert,will you give me
cover have him bagged
I tell you I haven't touched it,
or your rotten baskets?
You better don't do it(?) again
Listen I just getting in here
to get away from that
No need to be frightened
I won't hurt you really
You're living upstairs come on
tell me quickly your place
Right
If I let you go,you won't
scream anything will you?
Will you?
Good
Thank you
What are you running away from?
Don't ask me questions,please
I'm in trouble serious trouble
just leave it like that
I can't go out yet you'll have let me stay
until things die down a bit
I'll get out of here as
soon as I can I promise you
Please
I'm sorry to force myself on you like this
But I had to think quickly
Wait a minute
All right
-Where's your husband?
-My husband's dead
I'm sorry
I noticed you were wearing a ring
I thought perhaps
They're raiding that café over there
Listen I got to tell somebody about this
or I shall go off my head
Did you read about that hold up in
the jewellery shop all are talking of?
-Yes
-That's what I mixed up in that
But I've noting to do with it,
nothing at all,you understand?
It's all mistake
Oh don't look at me like
that I'm telling you the truth
You see this
All right don't worry it's not loaded
Hasn't been for years nothing
since I used it in the army
Somebody told me where I
could get a good price for it
And I went to jeweller to sell it
I'm broke that's all I had
Before I could find out how much
he'd give me I was caught in the hold up
And I'm standing there with this in my hand
Within two seconds they'd
knocked the jeweller senseless
As far as he's concerned I'm one of them
Do you get a 9 o'clock news?
-No,what's happened?
-He's just recovered consciousness
He's given the police my description
That's what that's all about
They've gone
-You're a deserter aren't you?
-Yes
Don't think I'm ashamed because I'm not
For the same reason I'd do it again
I served overseas for four
years before I deserted
And ??? Dunkirk
I gave up my business and everything
Lot of people people I know didn't
My business was pretty good for them
Was that the only reason you deserted?
No
A flying bomb hit the house where we lived
My father was killed outright
my sister was very badly injured
I asked for compassionate leave came home
Fixing up as best as
I could and that was that
Two days before my time was up
The doctor told us my sister
might not pull through
My mother was frantic I wired for
an extension but it was refused
Refused because I was single
So I took it
Three days later my sister died
But I was with her
That's all I asked after four years
that's all I asked and they refused
Within two days my mother followed her
Shock and everything was too much
So I didn't go back
Well,do you believe any of this
or am I just wasting my time?
No,I believe you
The police they must be checking now
-Is any one for roof?
-No
And all the windows  the back at barred
They can see the light
I shall have to open it
Yes,of course
Leave it to me
We're police officers we have authority
to search all premises in this area
Why? What's happened?
We're looking for a man
who was last seen in this street
We have reason to believe he's
hiding in one of these buildings
-You alone?
-Yes
Did you see or heard anything
unusual in the past quarter of an hour?
Only the raid on the café
I saw it from upstairs
-You sure that's all?
-Yes
I see
I think we have a look anyway
You have a look upstairs
-Well?
-No one upstairs
No way out on to the roof
-What's your name,Madam
-Adams,Jean Adams
-Mrs?
-Yes,I'm a widow
-You work anywhere?
-Yes at "Weatherbin" in Oxford Street
Tell me Mrs.Adams
Why did you take so
long to answer the door?
I was just going to bed I'd started
to undress and had to get dressed again
I suppose it's very early for a
young woman,don't you?
I get up very early
I work hard,you know
I'm so tired this morning
I didn't even make the bed
So I noticed
All right Mrs.Adams,sorry
to have troubled you
-All right
-Yes
Thank you
You can't go out they're
searching the street
You're right
If I was seen leaving here
now from this house hard for you
It's a crime to shield a deserter
Especially one in my position
Look I feel terrible about all this
You look as if you could do with a drink
I've got a little brandy
Thank you
-Your husband ?
-Yes
-Killed in action?
-No,died of wound
I'm sorry
Were you very fond of him?
We were separated
He thought he'd find someone else
Divorce?
No,war broke out he joined
up and he let things drift
Everyone seemed to at that time
Just before Dunkirk he was
badly wounded and sent back
When he came out of hospital
He was alone
It was no one to look after him
So I let him come back here
He had a relapse and they operated again
It was no use
Why am I telling you all this?
I don't know
Maybe because you wanted to
talk to somebody like I did just now
What's your name?
Burden,Peter Burden
at the moment I'm going
under the name of Brown
I know yours I heard you tell him
Do you mind if I sit down for a moment?
How long is it since you've eaten?
I was just having a sandwich
when all this started
I'll get you something
you can sleep on there
Mrs Adams I'm a deserter remember?
I can't shield myself behind you
Especially now I know about your husband
I got to get out of here
I can without you getting mixed in it
Look you're safe here
and I'm going to help you
-Why?
-I don't know
Perhaps it's because you so badly need help
Besides it's no use running away
You're caught up in a murder
And somehow you've got to
get yourself out of it
Yes,I could if I knew I
could find those two men
That's impossible
Apart from what they were
wearing all I've got to go on
is the voice of one of them
Tall thin man with half the two middle
fingers missing on his left hand
Where they've been shut off
Yes,a voice I can remember anywhere
with a strong Australian accent
"I'm getting you a toothbrush!"
-Very good morning Mrs Adams
-Good Morning Tony
-You're very early I only just opened
-I know
I wondered if you could
let me have a little milk
I've got it,Rosa put some
milk in her bottle for Mrs Adams
-Thank you Tony
-That's all right
-I want some cigarettes
-Sorry no cigarettes
-20 players that's all right
-That's fine
That's a 3sh 6p for the cigarettes
-I'll give you the milk
-Thank you
How long have you been smoking,eh?
Quite sometime
-Everything for peace
-For peace
There's no peace did you
hear that business last night?
Yes,I was going to ask you about that
I saw the raid from my window
A fine thing to do to a
respectable British citizen
All that fuss till they find the gunmen
No,nothing but they still
think he's around here
I'll bet you the district is being watched
All these lousy deserters
that's the trouble
Yeah,the bottle is quite clean I hope
Thank you,Tony
-I've been just over to the café
-Well?
Apparently the whole
district being watched
Here's the toothbrush and I brought
you some cigarettes and a paper
Thank you
They haven't published your description
They never do it might
prejudice their case in court
It's in the hands of every
policeman in the country
-That's just as bad
-I'll get some breakfast
"Martin's killers: There were three of them. The third one
was wearing a raincoat. A thorough search for the third man is underlay
..All the restaurants and private places in the
respective part of the city are being searched ..."
-You say he had a moustache
-Yes,definitely
It's our man all right
He must have shaved it off between
getting rid of this and going to that pub
Is the raincoat any use to you?
I doubt it these people must have turned
out thousands like
this all exactly the same
No chance for checking any of them
Still will take it along with us
-And thanks for your cooperation
-That's all right
There you are
Thank you
Here you are
-Am I glad to see you!
-Getting nervous
Very I'm afraid being cooped,
up here all alone like this
Not that I'm not grateful Mrs.Adams
Hadn't you better call me Jean
seems you're likely to be here sometime
Yes I suppose I should
Do you mind if I see that?
They know the type of gun that was used
-What's the matter?
-Nothing
-Yes,there is,what is it?
-Nothing,nothing to it really
-Tell me something
-Yes
What type of gun is yours?
Why? What makes you ask?
I just want to know
38 Enfield
Same type that one
that killed the policeman
Yes
-You don't doubt me do you?
-Is that what's worrying you ?
-Partly
-No
If you did I think that
would be about the end
It becomes dangerous to you
must get rid of it
Have you tried to get rid of anything in
a place like London in broad daylight?
We'll get rid of it tonight
I'll throw it in the river
What are you doing,Miss?
Don't think you're throwing
yourself over,are you?
No,of course not
-Just getting a breath of fresh air
-I see
A bit late for that sort of thing isn't it?
-Oh I don't know
-Can I see your identity card,please?
That's all right thank you
-Bert!
-Hello
Come up here a minute
-What's the matter?
-I want to show you something
Look
-Where did that spring from?
-The bridge as we come under it
I heard something fall and found it
They're looking for the gun,aren't they?
It says so in today's papers
-That's the one-God..
-Don't touch it
Leave that for the police
Ain't you ever heard of such
things as fingerprints?
Oh,cut him! Who's been filling
you up with that stuff?
A gentleman by the name of Dick Thorton(?)
Gone it's at the bottom of the river
-I had a little trouble with a policeman
-What?
Nothing serious luckily he didn't
see me drop it over
-He thought I was going to throw myself
-What did he do?
Not much just had a
look at my identity card
-Suppose he makes a report?
-Why should he?
I wasn't doing anything
The second time you've been in contact
with the police through me isn't it?
But I told you he didn't see
me drop the revolver I'm sure
OK may be not
He thought you were going throw yourself
in and he's got your name and address
And last night they searched that address
because they thought you might be hiding me
Well they've only got to get those two
things connected up somehow and they
want to know more about you
They'll come here again
I've got to get out of here now
For your sake you must see that
-Perhaps you're right
-I know I'm right
Look I got a little money
saved from my pension
Not much but enough to last you
for quite a while and I know somewhere
you can go somewhere on the coast we'll
be perfectly safe once
you get away from this place
I can give you a change of
clothes and everything
my husband's things are still here
I'll phone and fix it in the
morning what do you say?
What can I say
-Why not try saying yes
-I can't take your money
You are only alone until you
get yourself straightened out
I can never really do that you know
Yes you can listen
Tomorrow's my Saturday half-day
We'll take a chance on
getting away after dark
I'll come down with you stay over Sunday
That'll give us the whole day in
the fresh air to discuss things properly
Why are you doing all this for me?
I told you last night
I don't know
-Good Morning
-Good Morning,Rosa
-May I use your phone?
-Certainly
-Good Morning Mr Sweeney
-Good Morning,Sir
You're the chap that
found this gun aren't you?
That's right,Sir
It fell off of Waterloo Bridge just
Exactly I'm afraid I got a
disappointment for you
This revolver is the same
type as the murder weapon
but it wasn't one that fired the shot
However it might belong to one
of the other two gunmen involved
we can't tell you
Lucky my mate didn't mess
up with the fingerprints,isn't it?
There were no fingerprints
However thanks for your cooperation
we let you if we want you again
-Is that all?
-Yes,that's all,thank you
Unless you have a guilty conscience
-Good morning
Pity about them fingerprints
You are telling us
He didn't seem to want to go
-Perhaps he likes it here, well?
-Nothing
-No trace of the man at all?
-No none at all
Can't understand it? What is he?
Another Houdini
Look,this is ridiculous
A man can't just run down a street and
disappear he's still in that district
I'll stake my bottom dollar on that
Lawson
You do the rounds at
the cafés again tonight
Take every man you can lay your
hands on them and do the job thoroughly
-Very good Sir
-When somebody's hiding
got to eat somewhere
I want that man he's our one and
only lead and he's not going to get away
A shilling
Who's the driver's cab BLF 405?
I am why?
We have our own car to pick you up
-What for?
-They want a word with you at the Yard
-What me?
-Yes you
-What about?
-You'll find out when you get there
-What about my supper is pie
-Come on get a move on
We can't wait all night
Well I'm going down old Compton Street
when this woman nails me
Hop in lady says
-anywhere you like
-You slay me
-Where did you take her Blackpool?
-She wanted to go Victoria Station
But had to pick up someone first
And Victoria's where I dropped them
You can't tell us what he looked like
She paid the fare the
bloke I hardly so at all
Where were they going do you know?
I haven't the faintest idea
Is that all?
Then went straight back to
the shelter and ordered me supper
And I'd very much like to
go back to it if you don't mind
All right you can
And how may I ask am I to get there?
What's the matter with the taxi
He was a great help
I don't know three men killed one of our
chaps in broad daylight and where are we
Nowhere even though we've caught up with
one of them he runs down
a street and disappears
No it's not good enough those
baskets had all the luck so far
What about this man the
Adams girl went to Victoria with,Sir?
Probably nothing in it at all
Look
There was no one with her in the flat
that night that chap got away was there?
-No
-In fact that lets her out
That bloke tonight could have been anybody
How about boyfriends I know the district
Married man probably
-Still we'll see
-She didn't look that type to me,Sir
Lawson I envy you,you
got a very beautiful mind
-Good morning
-Oh hello
How would you like a swim?
I think I can borrow some things
Nothing I'd like better
-I'll see what I can do
-All right
That's the first time I've seen you smile
-Enjoy your swim?
-Wonderful
-Your name is Peter isn't it?
-That's right
-My name is May
-Where is Andy?
Stealing the ticket(?), oh it
is nice to see you again Jean
I must sit down have a chat
I shouldn't really of course
I'm supposed to be doing
the books this morning
There's always something
to be done in a Pub
-I know
-You were in this line too?
I was,are you very busy
this time of the year?
Doesn't make much difference
really customers are
a bit thirsty I suppose
Only a local chain(?)you know
We only got the two rooms you are in
anyway and they are hardly ever let
Too quiet for most people
What are you going to do?
Perhaps you like the sea
without trimmings like this place
Get's on my nerves sometimes
-Good morning
-Good morning Andy
Can you speed the pop Mary
-Pop that is coming
-You don't mind do you Jean?
-You're the governor
-I sometimes wonder
What's going in town now Jean?
-Go and see any of the old gang?
-No,not now
What do you do with yourself then?
My job keeps pretty busy for one thing
Well I find plenty to do
What do you think of this
Golden street shooting ?
I don't know what things are coming to
They pull a gun on you as
soon as look at you nowadays
It's all these ruddy deserters
that's what it is
Anything about on the wireless?
Not much they're still looking
for the chap they nearly
caught the other night
Why on earth they don't publish a
description of him I don't know
You ever miss the band business Mr Baker?
Yes and no sometimes I think
I'd like to go back to it
But not on the trombone,mind you
Band my own the next time
I'd make a good conductor you know
You certainly would on a bus
You have to say things like that
Why don't you try to relax
I can't
Look at that incident at breakfast these
things with me all the time
Yes,I can see that
Jean,do you know how
many deserters there are?
Nearly 20,000
20,000 men on the run all
over the country
men with no hope and
no future
They say they should like to give
themselves up and go to jail
That's just what they won't do
instead of thinking they will
They all had some reason for deserting
Human nature is human nature all world over
That's what the authorities
won't make allowances for
If those men were allowed to start afresh
From the clean slate it all become
useful members of the community again
As it is most of them are forced to live by
crime,crime of every sort including murder
Now that's what I wanted for
Peter I was wondering if ever you find
this man, the man you want, what exactly
would you do?
Make him talk and he would
How do you know?
Because he's not the man who
fired the shot and I know it
He'd soon open up to try
and save his own skin
And I'd hand him over and make him clear me
You mean you'd hand him over to the police?
-Yes,
-And yourself too?
Yes I suppose so I have to
Then you'd be free wouldn't you?
Free to start again,that's what you really
want isn't it to start all over again
There's no use talking like
this I shall never find him
it's impossible
You got to somehow,Peter,you just got to
What do you make of
Jean and her boyfriend,May?
-What do you mean what I make them?
-I mean,do you think they're in love?
What do you think come
down here for if they are not?
The best thing that could
have happened to Jean
She's been alone far too long
That's natural whatever she thinks
it's no use caring ??around
her for the rest of her life
She's a good kid I'd do anything for Jean
High time she had some
happiness for a change
I'm not arguing I just thought they
looked a little on edge that's all
Wouldn't you'll be in the
same circumstances?
Oh I see what you mean
Nothing of the sort
The trouble with you is you judge other
people by your own low standards
That's because you used to do
that sort of thing yourself
Well you ought to know
I shall have to leave early
in the morning,Peter
I've got to go home
change before I go to work
I hate leaving at all but here you are
-When are you coming back?
-Saturday do you want me to?
You know I do
I feel almost human again
You and this place I'd almost
forgotten the reason I'm here
You've been wonderful,Jean
I don't know what I'd have done without you
Or what I do now
-Jean
-Yes
It happened didn't it?
Yes
-When did you know?
-Today earlier on
What are we going to do,
there's no future for you with me
-Yes there is
-No,not as I am now
We're not going to give up
Where is it all going to end
We'll find a way out somehow
Good morning Mrs. Adams I'm a
police officer perhaps you remember me?
-Yes I think I do
-Do you mind if I came in a moment?
I'd like to ask you a few questions
No,not at all?
Now Mrs Adams we're very interested in
the man you went to Victoria Station
with on Saturday night
I've been being watched then?
We're making a note of anything
unusual that happens around here just now
What's so unusual about a
man leaving a woman's flat?
In the ordinary way nothing but this particular man
didn't want to be seen leaving that's
all so we found the taxi and checked up
on you who was he?
-A friend
-What was his name?
-Brian?
-Brian what?
I think it was Parkson
-You just think?
-I only met him that night
-Yet you brought him back here?
-Yes
I brought him back for a drink
I see
What was he like?
Medium built dark curly
hair and a thin face
Why did you go to Victoria with him?
I didn't,he came with me
I just gave him a lift that's all
Where'd he went after I
left him I had no idea
You mean you were the
one going to the station?
Yes that's right
But he went into the station
with you didn't he?
Yes,yes of course he did he came in with me
but I left him going to the bar
-Where he went after that
-You've no idea I know
You've told me and where did you go?
-Away for the weekend
-On your own?
-Yes,I was alone
-Where?
And I must warn you Mrs Adams,
you'd better tell the truth
If you don't we'll soon know
And that means that I should
have to come and call on you again
-The anchor Hotel Felty in Sussex
-Thank you
About this man again you're
sure he is what you say he was?
Someone you met casually that night
and brought up here
Yes,not against the law is it?
No but you surprised me,Mrs. Adams
I'd never have believed it
Appearances are often deceptive,
you know,Inspector
Sergeant
Some kids have found a gun
in the mud at Wapping
Another Enfield 38 having it tested now
This time we may have got
something,what's your news?
Only the Adams girls ,Sir,according to
her you were right she swear she was
only giving someone a lift someone's had
just met them taking back
with her for a drink
All right there's no need to look
-so depressed about it
-It's not that,Sir
It's just that I don't believe it
Where were she over the weekend?
Sussex the Anchor hotel Fithy
-Alone?
-So she says
I'm going to get the local
police to check-up on it
OK
-Telephone?
-Of course,of course
Peter,you're wanted on the phone
-It's Jean
-Coming
Hello Jean
Something has happened you
must come away from there at once
We have to find somewhere else
Anywhere I'll meet you don't
stay in that place a minute longer
Take the first train to
town and I'll meet in the lounge hall
Better still I'll skip the shop
and wait for you some where
Where can we make it?
Have you any suggestions?
Wait a minute I'm trying to think
How about the Victorian Albert
Museum on the ground floor
where the Elizabethan things are you know
Yes, that'll do
Only Peter they maybe watching Victoria
Get out at Clapham Junction and
come the rest of the way by bus
All right,I'll be as quick as I can
-Good Bye
-Good Bye Peter
-Can I have some toast and coffee,Tony
-You are not going to work today?
No,not today I got to go and
see my brother in hospital
What's the matter with your brother?
Going to have an operation
Well don't you worry
about it,he'll be all right
They make anything work
these days and anything
Jim this of all of those
kids picked up at Wapping
The murder gun
-Any fingerprints?
-Not any thing,not yet
Not on our files
We're getting somewhere and
getting nowhere all the time
It always comes round to the same thing
We don't pick that fellow
up soon I shall go crazy
I've got something interesting
What's that ?
One of the chaps E division
has made a routine report
About a girl he questioned
last Friday night
Thought she were going to
throw herself over Waterloo bridge
-Well ?
-Was the Adams girl
Was it by George
What she want to do that for?
I know the trouble is
Maybe our visit the night before
Why should that worry?
There's was no one there?
Unless she is mixed up in this after all
Yes,you might have something
Wait a minute I have got it
That girl wasn't on that
bridge for a suicide
She was the one who threw this over
Now we are getting somewhere
-Pull her in
-Right
Miss how much do I owe?
Stopped
Look after Jean Adams will you let me
know which department she's in
I can tell you that right
away she is in the ??
-??? Thanks
-She's not in this morning
Must be sick or something
I see
-Hang on just in case
-Right
-What happened Jean
-??
Pretend we look at these
Peter,they came to my
place again this morning
-How on earth
-They saw us leave on Saturday
They know I went to Victoria with someone
But they don't know it was you
And they went there now making
inquiries if I were alone that weekend
-They should know what's all about
-Now I promise tell you later
-Peter,there is something else
-What?
-I think I found him
-Who?
The man you want
The one with Australian accent you want
-It sounds impossible
-But it isn't
Luck has been against
you but I've changed it all
-Yes,if you are right
-Why isn't I?
I would know in a second
if I could hear him myself
Look I'll chance it
-You think he lives there?
-He opened the door with the key
Perhaps he'll open the door to me
Is it to too late for you to get to work?
All right I'll make some excuse
Why?
Well I want you somewhere
so I can telephone you
is too risky meeting like this in daylight
All right,Peter this may be the answer
-to everything
-I know
-Good luck,darling
-I'll telephone you
Let's go this way
What do you want?
I want to see Mr
I can't remember his name the tall man who
-lives here
-No one lives here but me
That's not exactly true,is it?
Who the dickens are you ?
I think we've met before
In a jewellery shop,remember
-Who is this?
-I don't know
I do
-I know who you are
-That's right
And I know who you are
Just a moment Mrs. Adams
-I must ask you to come along with me
-What for?
You're wanted for further questioning
In connection with a murder of a policeman
Now Mrs. Adams we paid a visit to your
place this morning we
found these clothes there
Whose are they ?
They belong to my husband
there are a lot of these things there
Mrs Adams you're not
being honest to this
These clothes was found in a
corner behind a curtain in your room
That is exactly the same as those
worn by the man we are after
The man who run out of that pub on Thursday
The day of the murder
He was in your flat that night when
we were searching after all wasn't he?
You hid him and you threw his gun over
Waterloo Bridge didn't you?
Look Mrs Adams why don't you
be sensible and make
things easier to yourself
We want that man and we mean to get him
He's a dangerous gunman
and he's concerned in
the murder of a policeman
He's not a gunman and he's
not concerned in a murder
So you do know him?
Well supposing you tell us
what he is concerned in and
exactly where you come into the picture
He's concerned in clearing
himself and I'm helping him
This is interesting Mrs Adams
Who is he?
-A deserter
-That doesn't surprise me
But he's done for your service
that's all forgotten of course
Only you want to do now
is put him in prison
That's hardly the point
We're interested in his
connection with a murder
He had no connection with it at all
He went into the jeweller
to sell that revolver
He took the gun out of his pocket
There was a hold-up
I see,go on
You know what happened then
Why didn't he come to us?
How could he in his position
would you believed him anyway?
No his only chance was to
find those two men himself
And I think we have found one of them,today
-Who's in this house?
-What's that to do with you?
Come along we are police officers
-Who's in this house?
-Only me
We'll see about that
Go on up you go
Nothing upstairs only the men's clothes
-Well,where are they?
-You've not right to come here
Don't start that where are
these two gentlemen friends
-You've been entertaining here
-What do you mean?Entertaining
I'll give you two guesses I want to know
where they are and who they are
I don't know what you're talking about
-What's your name?
-Lily
Lily what?
Lily Gatehouse
Lily you are a smart girl I can see that
You know the answers don't you?
I wonder if you know the answer to this one
We're looking for two men
One of them may have two
fingers missing on his left hand
These two men are wanted in
connection with the murder of a policeman
We shall get him in the end,you know Lily
Make no mistake about that
and afterwards we find out
that you've been shielding them
That's puts you in it,doesn't it?
And we should come back for you
on a murder charge
So Lily you're the smart
girl I think you are
You got something to tell us haven't you?
All right
Good well who are they?
-Two deserters
-Names?
The one with the fingers
shot off is called Slim
-Slim what?
-Slim Elfey
-Australian?
-No but he lived there for years
-The other one?
-Dan
-Dan Underwood
-How long have they been here?
Some months now
But I had no idea that
they'd anything to do with
the shooting I swear it
Not until the man
who was at jeweller's shop
What man? We are waiting to hear about him
That man who came to see them
-What did he look like?
-Medium build fresh complexion?
Brown hair,blue eyes is that the man?
Yes I think so
Well what did they talk about ?
I don't know
They sent me out of the room
Where are they now?
They went off with him in a car
Did he go willingly or did
they perhaps persuaded
at the point of a gun
-Slim persuaded him
-Where do they go to?
-I don't know
-Where did they get the car?
-Pinched it
-Where from?
I don't know,honestly I don't
Somewhere around here I think
Very useful
All right that'll do for now
Take her away
It looks to be something in
your story,Mrs. Adams
I'm afraid they've got your friend Burden
They took him away from
that house two of them
In a car
Say he walked to the car that's something
Cut me in please?
What are you going to do?
We haven't finished them
yet that car was stolen
Just as soon as we
get the number we should have to
pick it up inside a quarter of an hour
-Haven't you got its number yet then ?
-No, one they took somewhere
outside a theatre just
after performance started
-Theatre?
-Yes
That gives them two hours before
the loss was discovered by then they ???
-Take it down to records,please
-Yes,Sir
There isn't a theatre open
this time in the morning
There must be
-Stop,they wouldn't dare to risk anything else
-Which one?
That's just what we are finding out now
I bid you to have to interrupt the
picture and make an announcement?
-What's the trouble
-We want to know if a car has been stolen
from outside this teller
get everyone who's parked their
car outside to come out here at once
Hello cars from information
room message number 43
Stolen black Austin saloon
Index number MML eight seven four
Outside Cambridge Theatre Durham Street WC2
Approximate time 1100 hours
Time of origin 11:35
I told you last night not to
come down here again didn't I
-I don't want either of you
-We want him upstairs
You know why,this is trouble
-And I don't want any trouble
-It isn't so much you want it what you get it
You've done pretty well
of chaps I got,Charlie
You have to take the good with the bad
How bad is it then
This is the bloke who
was in Collin's shop last Thursday
Nearly an hour now we're on the right
track that car is
being hidden somewhere
Must have reach there
before our message went out
Where,that's the point
-Isn't it anything you can do?
-Mrs. Adams
We're doing everything we possibly can
You came in on this a little late,you know
It wasn't our fault
Now then between the time the car left
her house and the time it's
description was broadcast it couldn't
possibly get outside a radius of say
three miles from the cherry so to speak
That puts it roughly somewhere here
Wapping
That's where those kids
found that revolver,isn't it?
I can't have you three hanging around here
-I'll tell you I can't have
-There won't be three after tonight
Oh no,oh no you don't
You thought you got rid of
that revolver last night,didn't you?
It was just found out there
this morning in the mud
They've been busy around here all day
I'm not having any stiffs in the house
Why can't you leave me alone
Can't you have other places you can go?
No there aren't and you know it
You've taken anything we've
brought in the past haven't you?
and being glad of it you'd have taken
anything that was going from Collins place
if there'd been anything
You're in this with us Charlie
right up to your ears
and make no mistake about it
-stop whining and start doing something
-What can I do
We got to get out of the country
You can fix it if the money's
there we know that
And you've got the money haven't you?
sooner you get things started
the sooner you'll get rid of us
How about that fellow upstairs? I'm
not having any murder done here
We are dealing with that
as soon as it's dark
-What are you going do?
-Take him down the river
Hold him under for a few minutes
Then let him go suicide
I don't like it,and how about that car?
You got rid of plenty of others you
can get rid of that one
There's nothing to connect us with it
Where exactly was that revolver found?
Just here the children were playing there
at low tide and saw it's
sticking out of the mud
Very well then we'll cover this
section say from here to here
And take one of your cars
You people do the rest
I want every garage dock and yard in the
district opened and searched in that
any place large enough to take that car
Right
Hello
OK
You're dead lucky everything's fixed
He'll slip you on board all three
of you and drop you off at Belfast
Why three of us all of us suddenly?
Because the ship sails in
less than an hour you'll have to go now
and take that chip with
you and alive you understand?
How do you get rid of him
afterwards is up to you
As long you all get out
of here I don't care
But this is going to cost
money a lot of money
All I can afford
The only thing you can afford
Charlie is to let us down
And you would wouldn't you?
if you thought you could get away with it
I wouldn't touch your yard(?)
if there was any trouble
Well there isn't going to be
any trouble so that's that
You can get rid of this
bloke(?) over the side that is if your
girl(?) has given away(?) and
they are on the way in the morning
He wont know anything
as long as he is paid
And you are going
to pay him,aren't you,Charlie?
So there we are they're all set
-How far is the ship from here?
-Not far
OK come on let's get him
He must have jumped out
He's gone away all right
-He's gone
-Never mind about that,look
They're searching the street
they're looking for something
I know what it is
It's the car your rotten liars you told
me they couldn't connect you with it
Those are not local men
there must be Scotland Yard
What are we going to do
You mean what are you
going to do don't you,Charlie?
Everything around for now(?)
This is it
He won't tell us anything
now or any other time
The landlord can have
been dead a few minutes
They've got away
Not with our launch out at that end
Adams
That fellow Burden got
about the way though
Earlier or else he had it too
Jim
Those two men are still here there's no
way onto the roof they must be
They shut the landlord's mouth
now they think they are OK
We'll see
Car is here and so the culprits(?)
If they to try to get
out you know what to do
Listen everybody we're from Scotland Yard
This is a check-up
Nobody's allowed to leave
Anybody thinks of trying as well,I'll tell
you I got an armed police officer outside
All right stay where you are everybody
Pull out your left hand
Stop that
You won't get away
with this you now
Get over there,you too
Not too much of a ? to come after us
Look there
That's that
All we want now is fingerprints
Take him away send for an ambulance
How are you feeling?
I'll be all right I didn't know you
people were here I heard the tail end of it
from in there
I was after those two
myself but I missed out
No,no you didn't,we're talking
about Golden street
-Thank you
-We got the murder gun
We got some fingerprints
and we've got the man
If I'm not mistaken he's
taking a bit lying down
Oh,you've been a very great help to us
You're Peter Burden alias Brown aren't you
deserter ?
-Yes
-How did you know..
-Some just told us quite a lot about you
-That's all it is inspector ?
-Yes I think so,Sir
-Except that
-Yes
Well,Sir,I would like to say that
Perhaps not my business
-Cpt Willerby
-No questions,Sir
That'll be all,thank you,Inspector
As has been brought to
the notice of the court
by the civil authorities the part you
have played in bringing to justice
certain criminals
At no inconsiderable risk to
yourself whilst taking this into
consideration however together with your
excellent war record we have to inform
you that neither of these facts in any
way mitigates the fact that you are
guilty of desertion from his Majesty's
forces or relieves you of your liability
to that service and the seriousness of
this offence must be duly
impressed upon you
-Is it over
-Yes it's all over
Listen Jean I've only got a moment
I'm going away for about a year
And it'll make everything so much easier if
I know you'll be waiting
and you will,won't you?
-You know I will
-Bless you
-When you'll be going?
-Now
It's really better like
this isn't it,Peter?
Yes I suppose so this is something you
can never get away from
It's no solution to the
problem any solution to mine
Now goodbye
Good Bye darling
Subtitles Nostromo