JUNG Hyun-Sung
PANG Eun-Jin
OH Yoon-Hong SAH Hyun-Jin
Directed by KIM Hak-Soon
MAN WATOHING VIDEO aka REWIND
That actress's deer like eyes
resemble a woman
I knew in my twenties.
If I didn't call her for five days
she'd think I'd dumped
Mister...
Where are the others?
I'm sorry... they're still...
Only one, and it looks like this.
If you don't have the others
you'll have to pay.
How much are they?
Three tapes, so 60,000...
Just give me 60,000 won.
60,000 won? That's too much.
They're worth 70,000 won.
Hey, mister...
- Do you like to drink?
- What?
Do you like drinking alcohol?
I'll be back in a week.
Please have it ready by then.
588...
I'm writing this letter
after much hesitation.
I've been watching you for a long time.
Please don't think that I'm crazy.
I feel something for you.
I don't know. Perhaps it is.
A tremor in my heart...
Or the warmth of a spring afternoon.
It's not love I feel.
I don't know.
Perhaps it is.
It's just that you come to...
So cold. You're open late today.
I was here earlier.
- Did you work the night shift?
- Yes.
- Video store.
- It's me, Ho-June.
Kwang's leaving soon for Australia.
We're meeting tonight.
Okay, I'll come.
Hey, mister!
Do you have the new Steven Seagal movie?
He doesn't have many movies out.
Have you seen 'Marked for death'?
I saw that a long time ago.
Seagal's the best in action films.
Why not just crawl into the calendar?
What?
- Oheers!
- Oheers! Drink up!
I don't get you.
You leave law school, get a good job,
and then quit.
Now you're running a video shop?
What's wrong with a video shop?
Here, have a drink.
Do you hear from your ex-wife?
That's all over now.
How do you feel about leaving?
Like I'm just moving far, far away.
Hey, you paid all your debts and now you're set.
You could just stay here.
Yeah, but I feel like my luck is done here.
Pick up the mood a bit!
He's not going to die!
To our beloved friend, Kwang!
Okay, okay. Oheers!
Evening sir.
People buy dolls at this hour?
Of course!
Give it to your wife
she'll love it.
But mister I don't have a wife.
Then how about... hug one to sleep instead.
Alright, pick one for me.
This here's a female.
They say it won't snow on Ohristmas this year.
But still hoping for a snowy Ohristmas,
our next song is White Ohristmas.
One childhood memory clearly springs to mind.
One day, after raining all night,
everything looked clear like glass.
It felt like a fairy tale like
I was in a country village.
Then the thought of going to school seemed unbearable.
If I go past a corner into an alley,
Give me 300 won
to buy a drink please.
- Hello.
- Oh, Hello.
I need to rent this for another week.
- Again?
- Yes.
If I play this my girl stays well on her own.
Without it, I don't think
I could work at the factory.
I'll make you a copy, then.
No use paying for it every time.
Would you do that?
- Stop by after work.
- How can I thank you?
No need. You borrowed it so often
that I made enough on it.
Oh, but actually
I need to drop it at home before going to the factory.
Then I'll drop it at your place on my rounds later.
Thank you so much.
I owe you a big favor.
Mommy!
Mister, where's 'My wife is a gangster'?
Just a minute, please.
Right, here it is.
Thank you, bye.
Mister! Help me, please?
What's wrong?
A man's been following me for a few days.
I was scared, so I came here.
- What does he look like?
- It was too dark.
No one's there.
Are you okay?
Yes. Thank you.
If it weren't for you I'd be in trouble.
Are you going home?
Yes, I'm on my way.
What am I gonna do? What direction are you going?
The phone's ringing.
Just customers looking for videos.
The one with the light on. That's my place.
Thank you very much.
If you're out late,
you should have someone walk you home.
I live alone
so there's no one to do that for me.
We're here. Go on up.
Thank you so much.
Mister? Would you like
to come up for some tea?
No, that's fine. Go on up.
Goodbye.
6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1!
This new year I'll work hard
so that in 3 years
I can buy a small but pretty house.
I mean, apartment.
Thank you.
I hope your dream comes true.
People anticipate a new year full of hope.
And it's just around the corner.
All the hardships
of the past year will be buried...
- Video shop.
- It's me.
You're looking good.
Something new in your life?
Nothing really...
You look good, too.
I put some make-up on to see you
since it's been a while.
How's the shop?
It's fine. Perfect for someone
who can't do anything.
You aren't seeing anyone new?
The owner here
must still remember us.
I have something to ask you.
What would you think
if I get re-married?
Is what I think important? It's your life.
Sure. It's my decision, honey, but...
You were always so good
at counseling me.
Is that why you wanted
to meet me today?
Yeah.
Want a smoke?
No, I quit.
He doesn't like you smoking?
It's just for health reasons.
You're pretty fast.
A fiance in 7 months.
Are you making fun of me?
I think...
I don't know.
Living alone,
I realized we're not well
suited for marriage.
Actually, I'm Ionely at times.
But that doesn't mean
I'll get married.
What I mean is... I'm just not sure
you'll be happier
if you get re-married.
Not sure you'll be happier
We made the right decision.
Sorry, don't worry about me.
I meant to give you this before.
And also...
Well, this is yours.
Take care.
Do you regret taking this train?
No, why?
For every road
the beginning's most important.
You said your husband
might come today.
It's okay.
I have a good man
beside me now.
Who cares
if he beats me to death?
When's the last time I had sex?
Perhaps the things
that are recorded today,
will in time teach me things
I don't know now.
There was a solar eclipse yesterday. It was strange.
I talked long on the phone with Hyun
who's still single.
After being married for a year
couples in love...
eventually begin to realize
something about each other.
That is... the belief they were
perfect for each other fades away
and they are disappointed.
What sort of impression
did my second letter leave on you?
I keep wondering about that.
But, actually,
your response does not really matter.
Most important is...
the longing that stems from my heart.
Everything is so confusing.
I'm not sure
that I'll write to you again.
This all could result in nothing so my heart shivers,
always questioning.
I will stop here.
I hope it can end this way.
Give me 300 won
to buy a drink please.
You can't buy a drink
with 300 won.
Hey, mister.
What do you really
do with the money?
Give me 300 won
to buy a drink please.
I saw you the other day.
You were sitting in front of the shop
looking very tired.
Over your slumped shoulders
was a dark cloud of Ioneliness.
That night... I met some friends and drank.
I even went to a karaoke bar.
I got back kind of depressed.
Did you read my letter?
This is the fourth letter.
I wonder if it got to you okay.
Oould you let me know?
To show that you've read it,
tape a blue paper on the window.
If it's not there,
I will know
you didn't read my letters,
and I won't plan on carrying
this on any further.
This could be my last letter.
The wind is really blowing out there.
Do you have
'The Ionely swordsman'?
It's not in yet.
What?
Found in video stores near you!
That's what it said. Well, maybe it will be in soon, then.
That's what I came to rent...
- thank you.
- Bye.
Three, and four...
Now, four more.
This will develop your sphincter,
and help you
to improve sexual abilities.
Now, let's work on the legs...
- Hello.
Hello.
- How's this one?
- What is it?
- What's it called?
'Magic Sword'.
You look tired today.
I envy you.
Pardon?
I wish that I could just
run a video shop like you.
It's not easy running a video shop.
You don't have to grovel
before the suits above you.
What's your name, sweetie?
- Dan-bi
- Dan-bi.
Bye now.
Yes, video shop. It's not in yet, sorry.
Let's look over the answer sheet.
Student finds knowledge
through senses...
I bought a mini gas gun today.
Want to see it?
- Looks like a real gun.
- Doesn't it?
I wanted to thank you
for the other night.
No problem.
Studying the high school
equivalency exam?
No, I just wanted
to see what I learned long ago.
Oan you recommend me a movie?
I'm going to be a regular here.
Really?
I don't know
if you'll like this one.
Oh... this one.
Mister, we finished
our exams today.
- Oh? Did well?
- Yes.
Ah... I was wondering...
- Stop squirming and ask him.
- I know.
Hey, Mister... um...
I'm not getting any younger here!
Mister, there's no one home
at her house now.
So, let us borrow an erotic video.
We'll return it quick, okay?
You know the TV host of
'Our Sexuality'?
She's my aunt, actually.
- You guys know her too?
- Of course!
We'll watch
it as sexual education.
You want to see
this place closed down?
'Water Bed'?
Oh, just this once, okay?
Mister...
There are lots
of other videos here.
What shitty luck!
This isn't the only
video shop around.
Super ultra shit luck.
You know he likes to watch'em!
You little punks...
- Hey!
- It's snowing!
- Hello.
- Hi.
You have two videos out.
Is anything wrong?
Did you happen to get a tape
that doesn't belong here?
My mom visited and
she returned a tape by mistake.
She returned the wrong one.
It happens sometimes.
We even get a man's sixties
birthday party video
What happens then?
I just return it
to the rightful owner.
I saw the blue paper
on the window.
My entire body shivered
when I saw it.
When I wrote to you,
I thought
it was like writing in a diary.
But with a colored piece of paper
you became real to me.
Right now I feel
happy and nervous...
but at the same time
I'm confused.
How to take you now...
So, I have one request.
I would like to
receive a letter from you.
You can write anything.
Now that you're in my life
I just want to make you more real.
You can leave the letter
behind the phone booth down the three-way junction.
It's been a while
since I wrote a letter.
You said I could write anything
so I'll write about movies.
Right now, in my life
videos are all there is.
What are you doing?
Ah... nothing.
Then why are you hiding it?
Never mind.
Don't you need a part-timer?
- Not you.
- Why not?
You're on my blacklist.
Why am I blacklisted?
You know
that song you always sing?
Who sings it?
Oan you write it down?
- Why?
- I need it for something.
- Here.
- No, in Korean.
You don't know English?
Weren't you a law student?
It figures... O.O.2, here.
Thanks.
- Hello?
- You're still there?
- Who's calling?
- It's me, Miss Shin.
What are you doing?
Taking your call.
I just decided to call and see how you are doing.
- That's okay, isn't it?
- Yes.
I'll call again.
Take care.
Mister, want to buy a card?
I looked everywhere for it. But it's not here.
What do you do
with the returned tapes?
I rewind them first.
- You Do That, yourself, right?
- Yes.
You don't check the tapes first?
Of course I do.
At times when I come in
with a hangover,
I forget to check
and just put them in a case.
Then my tape could be...
in one of the cases in here?
It's possible.
Anyway I'll look for it again.
Would you?
Give me 300 won
to buy a drink please.
Hello?
You've got the wrong number.
You should've come sooner.
Isn't this great?
It's even snowing.
You have to drink
on a day like this, don't you?
This is worth 80,000 won
so I'm paid up and then some.
I'm serious. Look at this.
That's fine.
I didn't come for the food.
You know how stressed
I got every time you came around?
It tastes so good, today!
Must be nice repaying
your debts and drinking.
Don't be so cheap.
I'm drinking to pick up the mood.
Do you remember the titles
of the tapes you lost?
Well... part of it.
Then write down here
what you remember.
Why?
I don't remember, either.
Here you are.
Mister, now tell me
something funny.
I don't know... You try it.
Long ago in the palace,
you know why the eunuchs failed
of forming a labor union?
- I don't know.
- Of course you don't.
If they're going to form a union,
they need to rise up together.
But, you know
they just can't get it up!
Isn't it hilarious?
Oome in!
- Been a while, Miss Shin.
- Why didn't you stop by?
Yeah, so that I can go broke?
You never came that much!
After the fat wife and the skinny hubby
finished dinner,
she brought out a bowl and said,
Honey, come here
and drink this oriental medicine."
After the man ran away, refusing,
she said "Oome back here, right now!"
Know what he said to her then?
He said, "No way! You just want
to get your money's worth out of me."
Right! That's the idea!
So let me get my money's
worth with you.
Please, don't.
Hey, you bitch!
Who is this jerk?
I'm her man! Any problems?
- Are you crazy? Get out!
- Oome here!
- What Are you doing?
- Who the fuck Are you?
Don't do that!
You bastard!
Asshole!
I looked almost everywhere.
- I'm sorry.
- Are you okay?
I guess this is useless.
I'll clean it up.
I'm so sorry... I have to get going.
Goodbye.
- Do you like your Video shop?
- Pardon?
It's nothing.
- Take care.
- Bye.
Why'd you hide
someone else's video?
You're a horrible man.
You're shameless!
Maybe I'm watching
too many videos.
I'm having weird dreams these days.
I usually watch action or comedies.
But when I dream, it turns into an art film.
I'm dying of pent-up anger
toward my daughter-in-law.
I don't think
I'll live out a natural life.
Watch this, and she won't
be able to live out her life.
My wife's having an affair.
I want to see...
what a woman looks like.
This shows a lot of women.
I'm... pregnant.
Should've been more careful.
Oops, that's a porno video
with the same title.
I'll take that back.
Here's Park Ohul-Soo's
'PUSH! PUSH! '
Ohoose a good obstetrician.
Who took my video?
You lost it
because you were careless.
If it doesn't appear, give it up.
I told a lie.
How can I give
her back the video...
so that she won't
suspect anything?
Yes? Video shop.
Mister! Did you know that I still
have the bottle you left behind?
I'm so sorry.
Were you hurt
because of me that night?
Miss Shin.
What? Don't want to talk?
Too bad.
As long as I'm alive
I'll keep calling.
Ah, Miss Shin?
Yes, I'm listening, boss.
You sound like you're drunk.
I'll come by in a few days.
Do you think I'll believe that?
I never saw a man
who said he'll come, ever come.
And I never saw a liar
who wasn't cheap.
I'm sorry, mister.
I didn't mean you.
You're a good man
who cannot tell a lie.
- Oome by soon.
- I will.
- I'll let you go.
- Bye.
Excuse me. Are you okay?
I want... to go to Yangsuri,
and the Korean Folk Village.
In some movie,
I saw some lovers go there.
It seemed really nice.
Later when I meet
someone special,
I'll be sure to go there with him.
Miss Shin, it's cold
and you should get home.
Home? What home?
What's wrong with your face?
Mister... Why is life so hard?
Did you sleep well?
Sorry to put you through
all the trouble.
You're okay?
I made you breakfast at home.
Go and eat.
Breakfast?
I'll be going now.
Oh... hey!
Wait a sec.
Mister, what are you thinking?
What do you think life is?
Life?
Life is...
An egg.
Have some!
Isn't it good?
I'm so bored.
He must've been bored too.
The things he demands...
may be entirely reasonable.
I have things...
that are important to me too...
My work,
the baby to come,
finances...
I don't know.
Now I'm thirty...
When I see the blue sky
just like now,
I become sad for no reason.
This is really great!
Aren't you glad we came?
It's all thanks to you.
No, thanks to you.
Oompared to staying
in that musty old bar,
it's great to be out
in a wide open place.
Spring, silence, noise... depressed, goodbye.
Poor guy, he got dumped.
The owner's not around today?
He left me in charge today.
I'm working for him.
When did he go out?
Early this morning.
Do you have to return a video?
No.
He didn't say
when he'll be back?
It'll be soon.
He pays me 1, 500 won an hour.
He's really stingy with money.
Probably on his way back now. No.
Phone number?
You don't know
how hard I had to work.
I swear...
I'll meet a nice guy like you,
and get married first
then take him to my parents.
I'm sure you'll
meet a great guy.
What?
This is hot!
Ma'am, this hot pepper soup
is really hot!
Of course, that's why
it's called 'hot pepper soup'.
So spicy.
Yes, stationery store... Video shop.
Yes. Fifteen checked out
and seven returned.
And the pretty lady came by.
Pretty lady? Who?
I don't know.
She just asked for you
and rented a video.
What did she rent?
'I wish I had a wife'
Nothing else?
No.
You know it's 1, 500 won
an hour, right?
Mister!
Thank you for today.
- Go ahead.
- Bye.
Mister!
Why did you want
to go to Yangsuri?
You don't remember
what you said before?
You said you envied a couple
in a movie who went there.
I said that?
Did I mention anywhere else
besides Yangsuri?
Oan I ask something?
What is it?
'Far away... '
What song comes to mind?
'Far away'?
'Far away the whistle blows... '
I knew it.
That's why you're
old generation, mister.
Younger generations sing like this:
'Far away... '
'Go even farther away from me... '
- Hello?
- It's been a while.
The last time, you weren't here.
I left the city with a friend to get some fresh air.
- Video shop.
- It's me.
- Doing okay?
- Sure. And you, honey?
I'm doing well.
Did you get lunch?
I snacked a bit.
Be sure to eat well.
I will.
And I'm ready to move on.
That's good.
We really are better apart
I think.
Oan we meet for tea occasionally?
Sure.
Drink some milk
or something to fill up.
What song comes
to mind for 'far away'?
Far away?
'The whistle blows'. Why?
It's nothing. Take care and call me every so often.
- I'll call again.
- Alright. Bye.
Sounds like a girlfriend.
Did you break up?
After 'far away'...
it's 'the whistle blows', right?
But these days it's...
Far way, I saw you... '
At an age when I can't
love without sinning... '
There's a poem like that.
A poem?
At an age when I can't
love without sinning... '
I really like that line.
And also,
'The farthest road in life is returning
to the one from whence you came.'
What is 'the road
from whence you came'?
The beginning somewhere,
I suppose.
But life is about returning
to where one came from.
When someone dies they say
he's returned to the other world.
That's true.
Did you have dinner?
I did earlier. Did you?
I often go to a publishing house
because of work.
The OEO there was my school senior.
I couldn't say no to dinner.
I see. Do you write?
I've collected some past works.
It'll be published soon.
I see.
What's wrong?
Oh, I thought I'd count.
How many times
you say "I see"
It's a bad habit... I see.
It was an accident
on the way back from a trip.
The way lovers live...
My husband wanted
to capture that.
I felt better
when I saw that tape...
That's why I wanted...
That tape...
When you look at people
who like videos,
they tend to have
special stories behind why,
in most cases...
Hey, mister!
Business picked up?
You bought new clothes.
It picked up a little.
Hey, did you hear about
the murder last night?
Some woman our neighborhood...
got stabbed by someone chasing
her around at night.
Got stabbed by someone chasing
They say
it's a case of infatuation.
- Really?
- Yes.
Don't you read the papers?
Some things don't ever come
no matter how long you wait.
Once I realized that
I felt a lot better.
Actually, there's a person
who sends me letters.
Who did send me letters.
What letters?
The kind a woman sends to a man...
Love letters, then.
So, how did you feel?
A little confused but...
after a while
it wasn't bad at all.
First I was really curious
who it was, but not now.
I don't know if it was her.
What are you going to do about it?
I'm not sure.
Why not?
I'm comfortable as is, now.
You like living by yourself?
Not necessarily,
but I think it suits me.
I envy you.
Are you satisfied with your life now?
Yes, I am.
You seem quite sure of yourself.
Unlike others
I don't really have...
any special goals or dreams in life.
A dream is like...
telling me that
I'm missing something now.
That can't be a satisfying life.
Have some more.
What are you thinking of?
When I look at dust
I can feel time passing by.
I guess you're right.
You alright?
A first affair is fate.
I just recalled that saying.
Do you think so?
I do, no matter what happens...
A first affair is all
because of fate.
Then what about
the second and thereafter?
They're not fate?
The person who sent you letters...
What do you think of her?
Nothing bad.
Don't you wonder who she is?
Before I knew you, Hye-Jung, I did.
If she heard that, she'd be sad.
It's not the woman
behind the letters,
it's the one standing
before me who's important.
Well, when I first saw you
on the tape, I didn't think...
Hye-Jung...
Please return the tapes in the drop box.
Sad autumn falls like leaves
here and there.
The ones that dropped
the leaves prepare for spring.
Above the branches
the sky is wide open.
Looking closely at the sky...
eyelashes become stained in blue.
Wash cheeks with warm hands and...
Hello?
No, it's not released yet.
The person you're
calling is not available...
- Bye.
Hello. A letter for you.
Thank you.
That day
I went into the motel.
I wasn't acting on impulse.
I always waited for something
to change my life.
I wasn't necessarily waiting
for a man or a relationship.
But when I first saw you, I thought,
maybe you're the one
I'm waiting for,
that something will
change my life with you.
I think my first letter to you
started in that hope.
But it seemed to me,
you didn't seem to want anything.
I think that you were right.
Fate...
It's just the moment of beginning.
Once it starts
there's nothing more that's new.
Anyway, since I met my fate.
I guess there's no need
to meet again.
Goodbye.
'Things that don't come with waiting'
Essays by Park Hye-Jung
- Yes?
- It's me.
I'm going to America next week.
What for?
I'm going with him there.
So soon? We should meet then.
I'll see you before I go.
You take care.
You too.
You like Meg Ryan.
She's in it.
I never said I liked her.
I just said that she's cute.
There's a sequel out!
I didn't see the first one.
Oan't we watch it?
Just take them both.
I'll give you one for free.
Thank you so much.
Excuse me?
Is the Folk Village open
this time of year?
Of course.
We were there not long ago.
- Really?
- See you later.
Goodbye.
It's not in yet.
They promised to bring it in today.
You'll have to wait a few days
for that one.
Did you see 'The Accidental Spy'?
It's better than 'Oharlie's Angels'.
Yes, Goodbye.
Oh no, it was just rented.
Have you seen
'Mission impossible 2'?
Really?
Yes, Goodbye.