Miss Spruance. Miss Spruance.
Would you like to show me where
it's marked “smearing“ here?
- Because, I swear, I don't see it.
- Sorry, I didn't know I was.
Also, I'd be mildly
content if I could have a
little less delirious
self-appreciation...
and some small regard
for remaining somewhere
in the vicinity of
the goddamn note.
- I wasn't smearing.
- Okay. Come on.
No. I'm telling you, this
is personally motivated.
Now, since I moved out,
he's been doing this.
Now if our lovely soprano would like
to stop grumbling for a moment...
I'd like to take it once again.
- Self-appreciation, my ass.
- Pardon me?
I said, fine. Let's do it again.
Bar five,
- No kidding? Is that where you're playing?
- Yeah.
He never says, “Honey, I love you.
You doing great job."
I feel he don't respect
me as person...
and I'm just not happy with
stature of our relationship.
Mm-hmm. I hear you. Now, I want you to
look at Harry, tell him how you feel.
I feel like he's not
plugged into my needs.
I'm not getting enough
the positive feedback.
Just look at him shake his head.
Well, now, let's see what
he wants to say here.
Harry, how do you feel when
she brings out this material?
Well, I feel like she overheats
on every little issue...
and every time I go and try to
communicate with the woman...
for some unknown reason, she doesn't
believe a damn thing that I say.
- Oh, that's a lie!
- See what I mean?
No. You wanna know what the
whole thing hinge from?
- Mm-hmm.
- He came and rent building from me...
- which is now his place of business.
- He's not interested in that.
That's not what he's
asking, See what she does?
She wants to dig out and
haul up things, uh...
miscellaneous things, that's
got nothing to do with this.
I hear what you're saying.
Go on.
I mean, I agreed to come down here.
Okay.
But I gotta tell ya, Iwo Jima has
got a lot of faulty notions-
Oh, right there. Right now. That's
another thing I want to interject.
Pardon me, but I was
making a statement here.
Yes, let's, um, try to hear
each other out if we can, okay?
Go on, Harry.
Well, I forget the upshot of
what I was saying, but... Okay
This is syndrome where I ask him
to address me by my given name...
and he just go on
ignoring my wish.
- Ignore!
- All right. All right.
I hear you. I hear you both.
We're doing good work here,.
Oh, shit.
Fifty bucks a shot
out of my pocket.
I'm supposed to listen to
some pencil-neck butthead...
tell me that I don't know
how to relate to you?
Daddy, do you want this
marriage to work or not?
I hear you, honey.
But how about just a little more
trust on your end of this thing?
Okay? That's all I ask.
Get in.
You sure nothing of value has
been removed from the dwelling?
Anyone whose dis-pleasures you
might have incurred in some way?
Kind of looks like somebody
doesn't like you, doesn't it?
Well, who could it be?
You're not married I take it.
- She's in the process of a divorce.
- What about him?
What about him? He's our conductor and
an artist. Not someone who would ever-
You mean Lewie? No, he would
never do anything like this.
- Hello. Anybody home?
- 0h, perfect timing.
- Hi, Joanie.
- Excuse me. It's my sister.
I just got back from Hawaii.
Thought I'd drop by for a moment.
What the heck happened in here?
Uh, Andy, this is not the
most opportune time.
- Somebody broke in here last night.
- Oh, that's awful.
- So could I just call you later?
- Could you give me a minute?
I'd like to know if you got
the manuscript I sent you.
Um... Who's that?
It's Helen Dextra.
You've met her before
Oh. I have? Anyway,
did you read it?
Read what? I don't know
what you're talking about.
The book I've written about Red
and me that I sent you a copy of.
Is that so hard to follow? - Oh, no, Andy.
You've written a book about Red Layls?
It's not just about Red.
He's only one of many episodes in my life.
You know that.
- You got a Perrier?
- I'll get it.
No, no. I don't have a Perrier.
Now, can I please just
call you at home later?
I'm not going to be home. I'm
checking into a hospital...
to have a bone spur
removed from my foot...
and then I'm going to
New York to meet with a
top publisher, which I
would not, by the way...
care for Mr. Redmond “Fecal-face“
Layls to know about.
We're gonna be leaving, - Oh, wait.
I need to talk to you.
Do you know what he said to me?
Can't imagine.
Um, I wanted to ask you,
if there is someone...
who for some unknown reason doesn't
like me, what do you suggest I do?
I might put some
bars on the windows.
My names's Melvenos, if
you want to get in touch.
Really, though. You know, I don't see
how this could be somebody I know.
- Maybe not.
- I actually go miles out of my way...
to avoid conflictual situations-
My lawyer said, “Don't worry, they're
just pissing into the wind."
I said, “Yeah, they're pissing into the
wind. It's blowing back in my face.“
Some help I'm gonna
get from him...
- because he's scared to death of Red.
- Andy, are you telling the truth?
Yes, he's afraid.
They're all afraid.
You know, speaking of lawyers, one
fell on me while I was sunbathing.
- I mean are you really going to New York?
- Yes, I'm going to New York...
where I intend to live in semiprivate
seclusion at an undisclosed address.
Great. I could stay at your house. Would
you have your housekeeper leave the keys?
Wait. I-I want you to hear what his
superfluous excellency said about me.
Pardon me, but I don't
care what he said.
My apartment, as you can
see, is a complete shambles.
I have just been informed by a policeman
that somebody doesn't like me...
and I really don't want
to stay here by myself.
Fine. Why don't you
take my house then?
My face hurts and
I got an earache.
Come on, Sluggo. Go
hose out the kennel.
Now, don't give me
a bad time, Laura.
I got enough trouble with Iwo Jima
and all her complaints, all right?
Now the woman don't even
believe you're my niece.
Well, I'm not.
It's not the point I'm making.
Get this, will ya?
Remember, don't say I'm here...
till you find out who it is.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Yeah?
- Ferdy, at B.P. Motors. Is Harry there?
No, I doubt that he's
here at the present time.
When will he be back in?
- Maybe later today sometime.
- Who am I addressing?
- Who are you addressing?
- Yeah. Who am I addressing?
The executive kennel maid.
Listen, Miss Kennel
Maid. He has to make
payments on the van.
Yeah. - By tomorrow.
- Uh-huh. I'll tell him.
- Make sure he understands that, all right?
So Long.
- Yeah, who was it?
- Ferdy at “something“ Motors.
He wants two payments by tomorrow or
he's gonna come and “re-pop” the van.
Slime.
You wanna know what's gonna happen if
I don't pay some of these breeders...
and get some adult
dogs on the premises?
Huh?
Pretty damn quick some asses are
gonna hit the pavement. Believe me.
- Sick of turds anyway
- I can't believe it.
Here I am sitting in the
center of all this wealth...
and the escalation in crime couldn't be
better, and I'm not turning a nickel on it.
Oh, shit. - Huh?
It's Lee.
I'm in Vegas delivering a
couple of dogs to Wayne Newton.
Duke, Fug. You don't
know when I'm expected.
Socorro! Socorro!
Wait a minute, please,
I want to talk to you,
Excuse me, Socorro. Do you mind
if I ask what's happening?
Why are you leaving?
Where are you going? - Esme mijo,
Balthazar. You talk about ok para mi.
Yes, yes. What's going on?
Are you bringing her back?
Yeah. Hey, Monday, I
bring her back later.
I can't possible stay
here alone until Monday.
No, it's my understanding
Socorro lived here.
Otherwise, I would've
made other plans.
Yeah, well, she's gotta have her
time off too, man. You know?
Well, this is just glorious.
Blood and kisses... Hey Andy.
- Opening in theaters everywhere,
- Hey, Andy, it's Butch.
Come on out and say hello
to your old drinking buddy.
- Who are you, honey?
- She's out of town...
and there happen to be several other people
here who are trying to get some sleep.
Well, why don't you
come out and say hello?
- Will you please go away?
- Stick your head out the door.
If you don't leave, I'm going
to call the Foothill patrol.
Well, patrol this, babe, Huh?
Oh, God. Where does she
find these people?
I'm just trying to be nice.
Andy never complained.
What's your problem, huh?
Duke, kommen.
Duke, sitz. Good. Good, Duke.
Always the name first
and then the command.
“Always the name first”-
Now, in regard to any
aggressor seeking to
give you a bad time...
I want to show you what you can
expect from a dog of this caliber.
Here we have the dog's
arsenal, so to speak.
The animal is trained to apply pressure
to specific parts of the body...
until the bone is
more or less crushed.
Iftheattacluriscu1ylrgam
oft-gland...
be it a gun, a knife, a club, a
what have you, the dog will-
excuse me for saying-
uh, automatically go
for the testicles.
Well, what if I don't
want him to do that?
- You'll want him to do that.
- No, no. I just want him to scare someone.
Believe me, this
will scare them...
as well as incapacitate their mind and any
ability they have to maneuver against you.
Das is alles, Duke. Kommen
You know, I have an extremely sensitive
reaction to dog dander, so maybe-
- Let me ask you something.
- Yes.7
I like to get a general picture
of the individual situation.
Are you, uh, married?
Single? Living alone or
with some other party?
Well, I'm in the process
of a divorce...
and I moved up here because
my apartment was burglarized.
But I'm not entirely alone. There's
a housekeeper and several friends.
Well, the hills are hit heaven
as far as burglaries go.
Right up here on Mulholland...
is where they found the fifth
victim of the Westside Slasher.
Please don't tell me that.
Believe me, I know what
you're up against...
being an attractive
and, uh, I take it...
unattached woman
such as you are.
But don't worry, we're gonna
remedy that situation right now...
and get you to feel as
safe as a little baby.
Well, okay.
What have we got there so far?
Um-
Mm.
All right now, Joan.
Give 'im the command-
Duke-
More authority would create an
impression in consciousness for the dog.
Duke-
Good. The dog is now on alert.
Very nice piece of real
estate you've got here.
- Oh, it's not mine. It's my sister's.
- Oh, your sister's.
Mm-hmm. And where is she at?
Am I doing this right? I mean, shouldn't
I be prepared... Never look at your dog.
Ne-“Never look at your dog“?
Okay. - Ha!
Oh, my God!
Oh! Ahh!
Damn it. Don't exhibit
fear until I tell ya.
- Stop! Oh!
- Get control of him, Joan.
- I'm trying. Good dog. Good dog.
- Give 'im the “off“ command.
I forgot. You tell him.
Duke... My legs-
Whoo! Ow! Stop! Be nice.
Sweet doggy. - Duke!
Duke! Duke! Sitz
Sitz Duke.
Oh, my golly. I mean,
that was incredible.
I love this dog! Oh!
Did you see that?
I mean, I can't believe how strong he is.
I felt like a rag doll.
- Well, what did I tell ya?
- Thank you.
Good, good. Good, Duke. Good.
Ordinarily, uh, I
wouldn't do this.
Even on a temporary
rental basis...
because he is the absolute top-trained
security and attack dog in the country.
Is, uh, this your sister?
Yes. Yeah. - Who's that?
Oh, that's her third
husband, Eric Ellerman.
Oh. Uh-huh.
Wait a minute.
- Who's this guy? Is that Red Layls?
- Yes.
You're kidding. Your sister's
involved with Red Layis?
This guy's gotta be one of the five
or six richest men in the country...
with business connections
all over the place.
And she's your sister.
That is amazing.
This is an individual that
I'd like to meet sometime.
Mm, What a figure, Mm-mm-mm
I have to say your sister's a
very attractive-looking woman.
Well, that's quite a compliment.
I'll have to pass it on.
I'll, uh, skip by in
a day or two, okay?
- Just to see how you're doing.
- Okay.
And, Joan, feel free to
call on me for anything.
Anytime of the night
or day, 24 hours.
It's been a great pleasure
doing business with you.
- You big flirt.
- Don't start with that, Dumpty.
This is a quality clientele. It calls
for a certain kind of approach.
Try and soak some
of it in, will ya?
Soak this in.
Start to pattern yourself.
Breed up.
Observe the woman.
Screw her.
- You don't screw this type of individual.
- You would.
This is the kind of atmosphere
we wanna gravitate towards.
Did she even ask me what it costs?
Damn it, I really respect that.
I don't. He isn't even your dog.
Joan, this is Lewie.
Not answering.
Saving your voice. I hope so,
Perhaps you could concentrate on the music
and reduce the traumas in your life, hmm?
Rehearsal, promptly, 9:00pm.
Tonight.
Are you listening, Joan?
This is supposed to
sound virginal, ladies.
So let's just... fake it.
- Don't do that!
- Don't do what?
Well, you're never supposed
to look him in the eye.
You have a dog you can't
look in the eye, Joan.7
He's not just a dog. He's a
Schutzhund-trained attack dog. -
Oh. Oh.
Well, you didn't have to go
through all this trouble.
You know, if you don't
feel safe at your
sister's, I told you I'd
come and stay with you.
- No. No.
- God, you are so damn stubborn.
I am not stubborn. I am so
accommodating it is sickening.
But you won't tell me what's
really bothering you.
You know, why don't you
confide in my anymore?
I do. - No, no. You don't.
Now, come on. Talk to me.
- Let's have a drink after rehearsal, okay?
- Eddy. Eddy?
You better come. He's
rehearsing the tenors.
Not tonight, Eddy.
Well, how about
tomorrow night then?
Let's say maybe.
Well, don't go out
of your way, Joan.
Hey. How ya doin'?
I have to say that this place is
pretty much of a snap to break into.
I knew it. I never
should've moved here.
Don't worry. The dog will take care
of anyone trying to get inside.
Wonder what I should do? Maybe I
should move to a motel or something.
You don't have to do that. This is just
some ding-dong trying to scare you.
Well, he succeeded.
But you don't wanna give
off that impression...
because that invites an aggressive
attitude in certain kinds of men.
- I didn't invite this.
- Well, for instance...
don't go mincing around, taking mousy
little steps and waving your hankie...
because that draws
a target on you.
See? - Do I do that?
Let's see.
Walk back and forth the
way you normally do.
Well, I don't normally
walk back and forth.
Okay. Um.
I can't do this with
you watching me.
Okay. But, uh...
keep in mind that you want to
exhibit a very confident attitude.
You wanna look like you know where
you're going and what you're doing.
Remember, stop short of
appearing a little, uh, dykey.
Because that's not attractive.
I thought that's your point. Not
to attract... No, no, no, no.
You always wanna remain a
little bit attractive...
otherwise that can
set someone off too.
This is just
impossible, you know?
You know, you just
can't win here.
Sure you can. It's just
a matter of degree.
Uh-oh. Now, what's this, hmm?
What's this?
I'm sorry, but this is
really getting to me.
I-I'll tell you what then.
Why don't you let me take you out
of this place and buy you a drink?
See if we can't get your mind
off of these kind of things.
That's very sweet of you, Harry.
I-I think I'd like that.
How long have you been divorced?
Oh-I'd say, uh-
seven or eight
years, around there.
Mmm. Really?
And, um, do-Well, assuming you
live a single existence...
most men don't really seem
to enjoy that... I've read.
I have to tell you the truth.
I've been observing
your hands...
and I have to use the
word, “exquisite.“
Really? Oh.
You're probably
quite a singer too.
I'd love to drop down
and catch you sometime.
Anytime.
Uh, um, do you like
classical music?
Yes, uh, to the degree that
when it's on the radio...
I sometimes have to turn
the damn thing off.
No, no. I just mean that-
it gets to me sometimes.
You know, to the point where I-
I can't swallow my own saliva.
Dinner.
You're full of surprises,
Harry, you know that?
I mean...
that you've actually read Dante's
Divine Comedy, I mean, I-
Well, uh, it was a while
back there that I did. Yeah.
“Yet, as a wheel moves
smoothly, free from jars...
“my will and my desire...
“are turned by love...
the love that moves the
sun and other stars."
Ooh, my.
I don't know why, but for some reason the
sublimity of that always touches me...
for some reason.
Thank you.
You know, it's very sad.
I-I look at my sister and all
her marriages and affairs-
Not to mention the mess
my own life is in-
and I think, how very
sad and very bleak...
that men and women can't
manage to be friends.
What a tragedy that...
sex is often such a barrier to
friendship between men and women.
Not necessarily.
Do you know that Dante and
Beatrice never slept together?
Is that right?
Oh, yeah. I forgot
about that part.
Gee, I shouldn't have had so much saki,
because I prefer to go a little slow here.
We can go as slow as you want.
Why not?
So you think that men and
women can be friends?
Oh, absolutely.
Okay. Go ahead. Who
is it this time?
No, this is not what
you're thinking.
This is a very unique individual
I'm talking about here.
First of all, there is a mind there,
as well as a body and a face.
Didn't I hear this before,
about the hostess at Denny's?
No. I'm telling you, this is
somethin' completely different.
You should meet her.
She sings opera.
She's got hands
like a hula dancer.
There's some people who wanna talk to you.
They're waiting.
Leave this, will ya? - Yeah.
You happen to be talking to the
wrong goddamn party, you know that?
Red Layls and I suggest that it's in
your best interest to hear me out.
No. You hear me out. I happen to have
a very high regard for this party...
and maybe even some feelings
of a personal nature here.
In developing certain
information on you.
It's come to our attention that
your name is not Harry Bliss.
That, in fact, your name is...
- Eugene Earl Axline.
- All right. Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
And that due, I'm sure, to some
remunerative oversight on your part...
both the IRS. And an impressive
number of creditors...
in several eastern cities seem to be
somewhat interested in your whereabouts.
I can't go around stealing
this lady's property.
No, of course not. You see,
I'd like to pose that...
the good name and reputation of Red Layls
is not the property of Mrs. Ellerman...
or her sister to whom, apparently, a
copy of this manuscript was mailed.
Now, you know what it does?
It puts forth a
libelous and grossly
inaccurate portrayal...
of a very decent man.
And it is my hope that
we can just avoid...
any unpleasant
eventualities, Mr. Bliss.
What do you mean, “unpleasant“?
I mean that Mr. Layls
is prepared to do...
whatever it takes to
confiscate this manuscript.
If you should elect to assist
us in anyway by finding it...
turning it over to me, he's
prepared to make you...
a very generous offer.
Look, I hardly know this woman.
I'm renting Hera dog, is all.
What kind of a person
do you take me for?
Sturge.
Duke, kommen. Gorgeous dog.
Oh, you're so soft,
my sweetie boy.
Oh! Now.
Oh, my God. That's not nice.
Ow! No!
No! Now, you" No.
Now, Duke. Now, sitz.
- Now, sitz and behave yourself.
- That's more like it. -
Oh, no, no, pero. Pero, no.
I had a talk with
Helen last night.
I'm extremely concerned
about this situation.
I don't want you
living alone up there.
Now, come on. Wouldn't you feel much
safer if you moved back into our house?
No. I would not feel
comfortable doing that.
Come here.
Darn it, Lewie, I... What? Are you
afraid of your responses to me?
Why are you resisting?
Look, these are
really upsetting...
really shitty circumstances I'm
dealing with, and I'd appreciate it-
Do you have any idea how hard
all this has been on me?
Do you think it's that easy for
me to admit I want you back?
Well, couldn't you just
spare yourself that?
Are you seeing anybody?
Just tell me that.
What? Come on. You're
not the abstinent type.
Oh, please don't judge me by
your scrotal excesses, Lew.
I know you're seeing somebody.
- Are you spying on me?
- Come on.
Just be open about it.
You can tell me.
All right. I'm seeing
someone, okay?
I don't believe you.
Who is it?
Now, I want you to look at
Harry, Tell him how you feel.
I don't want you ever
call me Iwo Jima again.
If you can't call me Adele,
don't call me anything at all.
That's a legitimate
request, isn't it?
Mm-hmm.
Can you look at Iwo Jima,
Harry, and tell her-
No, no, no. Better yet.
Just take her by the hand...
look at berm.
Just communicate.
Oh, that's good.
Because there's a lot of
love here, isn't there?
Okay. Next time I want to bring
out some of our sexual hot spots.
- The hell you are, honey.
- The hell I'm not.
Not my sex We.
You know, I hate
to mention this,
but we're having a slight
problem with Duke.
What?
Well, he keeps getting up and trying
to ride on one's extremities.
Oh. Well, don't
worry about that.
Especially Socorro, who can't speak
English, let alone German...
and sometimes she has to go pulling him
from room to room like a vacuum cleaner.
No, that's, uh, more or less normal
for most of your adult males.
Some percentage of the time they
are going to try to make...
vulgar gestures on your person.
Uh, you just have to
stay on top of 'em.
- It's not affecting you too much, is it?
- No.
It's very nice. - Oh, good.
It's Chopin. It's a nocturne.
You know what is affecting me?
- “Night piece," it means.
- You are.
Harry, I-I think I
should say something.
Don't worry about it.
No, that's the problem.
You see, I-I-
- There's no problem.
- Well, I wanna be honest with you...
because I recently realized
something about myself...
um...
that I have slept with a
number of men in my life...
just because I didn't
want them not to like me.
Mm-hmm. - But, uh...
the thing is, I didn't like
most of them that much, so...
I don't know why I cared
whether they liked me or not.
You know-
I'm not, uh-not one of these
guys who's going to...
look upon you as a-as an object.
Oh, no. I know. I know that.
That's not what I'm saying.
Because I look upon
a woman as a whole.
What I'm saying is that...
I don't know if right now I
might not go to bed with you...
just because I don't
want to be alone.
- Uh-huh.
- Sol thought maybe we could...
try and explore other modes or-
Other modes?
There are other ways of being intimate
that people don't even realize.
Uh-huh.
Which doesn't mean I'm
not attracted to you.
But, uh, you don't want
me to bring you around?
“Bring me around"?
Other modes is fine.
You don't have to
be shy with me.
Oh, God. It's so hard to
pioneer in this area.
Hi, it's Andy.
I've gone out to a
writer's block party.
Please leave a
message at the beep,
loan? joanie? joanie,
are you there?
It's Andy.
I'm calling to inform you that
these people are drugging me.
I have no phone in my
room, or cable TV.
I've had to sneak into
this cell next to me...
with some poor, lithium zombie lying
here like a comatose cabbage.
- Maybe I better take this.
- These are the lengths this assassin...
is willing to go to suppress me because
he does not want me to have my book.
- Would you excuse me?
- Please z/oan/e,
- It's my sister.
- Please, help!
- Andy, it's Joan.
- Oh, you're there. Thank God.
Oh, where are you?
Are-Are you in New York?
No. That's what I'm telling you.
I checked
into the hospital to have
a bone spur removed.
Yes, I know. You told me that.
But, where are you now?
The next thing I know,
I'm transported
someplace the hell else
against my knowledge.
- I was completely medicated.
- Wait. Wait a minute-
Do you understand the
implications of this?
I-I-I have no underpants on
and absolutely no recourse to
my rights-joanie? - Oh, my God!
- Ow! Ooh!
- This is because of Red, isn't it?
Yes, this is because of Red.
Isn't that obvious?
And If he, that lawyer and his
paid employee think that they-
Wait. I think I hear
someone coming.
- What am I supposed to do?
- Find out where she is.
Andy. Andy. You have to
tell me where you are.
I told you I don't know where I am.
These bastards are very clever.
I'm in some private cracker box in the
boonies with goddamn wires on the windows.
- Find out where the first hospital is.
- Oh, yeah.
Andy. Andy. Tell me the name of the
hospital you checked yourself into.
Mount Haven. It's
in the South Bay.
Stop asking these inane questions
and please, just do something.
- Tell her we'll find her.
- Andy, we'll find you, okay?
Shh! I have to get off.
I hear someone coming.
Wha-Andy. Andy?
- Oh, what should I do?
- Sh-Should I call the police?
No. Let's take a run out there.
You mean r-right now?
Ah. “Ellerman, Antonia."
Admitted on the third of the month and
signed out by her personal physician...
following observation... Well, how
do you know it was her physician?
Hell, I could come in here and say I
was a doctor and sign somebody out.
And even if he was a doctor, that
doesn't mean he was my sister's doctor.
Well, it says here that she was under
observation for clinical depression.
Well, that's a lie. She was
here for an operation...
then she was drugged and taken
out of here against her will.
And that she was signed out at 3:45 pm.
On the fourth.
Okay, let's stop
wastin' time here.
Where is this guy,
uh, what's his name?
His name is Dr. Monroe Park.
Doesn't say where he is.
What kind of a business are
you running here, buddy?
If you would like to
call the physician's
registry, there are
public phones over there.
I'm sure he's listed with them.
Nothing. No Dr. Monroe Park.
How am I supposed to find this man
when maybe he used a false name?
- Or maybe he isn't even a doctor.
- I've got a few ideas.
First we wanna connect
up with Red Layls.
Oh, no. I don't wanna have anything
to do with him. I'm terrified of him.
There is nothing to worry
about, believe me.
I mean, you hear all kinds of things
about government kickbacks...
- and Panamanian drug couriers.
- I know these type of guys.
You take away their money and
their power and what are they?
I told her she shouldn't do this. I
mean, to be so maniacally obsessed...
with this soul of mud that she'd wanna
write a book about him is beyond me.
I have to do something. I
have to go to the police.
If only I could find
the manuscript.
Let's hold off on
that for a bit.
I wanna talk to this private investigator
who's a close, personal friend of mine...
see if he can find out
who this doctor is.
This isn't your problem, Harry.
I don't wanna draw you into it.
You're not drawing me in, honey.
We'll find your sister, okay?
Um, Socorro, may I speak to
you for a moment, please?
Um, I am looking for
my sister's book.
No, no, no, no, no.
Um, “Ia manuscripto"
Ia manuscripto.
Andy? Si, Si
I go adolocasa
Um, everywhere, looking y
looking yno es anywhere.
Um, uh, uh-Sabe usted?
Soco!
Soco, I, uh-I left
my watch in there.
I wanna go in there
and look for it.
Okay. - Thank you.
Duke, sitz, sitz
I must say, this is a
dazzling piece of work.
But I've read where you're a little
sensitive about the criticism you've had...
over the amount of sexual
violence and nudity in the movie.
It happens to be a tradition
in this kind of film...
that women make more interesting
and exciting victims than men do.
I understand but... Asshole.
The violence that's directed
at Mimi's character
is an essential component
to the story...
and is, in no sense of
the word, gratuitous.
But, Mimi, what about you? That scene where
you run nude through Times Square...
with multiple knife wounds all over your
body, that must have been horrendous
It was very horrendous.
But what helped me enormously is
that we shot the film in sequence...
and that scene came directly after
the gang rape in the elevator.
- Come on. Let me drive you home.
- Mm. No, wait.
And, also, I love Dick's taste.
Sol knew that he was handling
it very artistically.
It wasn't just going to be
sex for the sake of sex.
You okay? - Yeah.
Oh, my God!
God! - Oh, God!
- Getaway!
- Don't unlock the door!
No'. No'.
Get out of the car! - I can't!
Socorro!
I can't! - No!
Socorro! Duke!
Loan, help! jean!
_ -Joan!
No! No!
Why didn't you have the dog with you?
It's what he's for.
I told you, he was in the house.
What the hell good is that?
You must have him with
you at all times.
Well, I can't have him with me at all
times. He's killing my mucus membranes.
Didn't I tell you right from the
start that it was very dangerous...
to fool around with
people like Red Layls?
No, you didn't.
I said he was dangerous,
you said he wasn't.
That was before he
tried to part your
hair with an ax. I don't
know if it was him or not
- Maybe it was that tree surgeon.
- All right, now wait a minute.
How tall was he, about
6'1 kind of ugly skin?
Excuse me.
Oh! Jesus!
Sorry.
He was about your height.
No, he wasn't. He
was much taller.
Oh, let's not quibble about the
man's dimensions for God's sake.
That can't be the same man who
burglarized my apartment...
because that happened
before I came up here.
Forget about him.
I know what I'm talking about.
Uh, pardon me,
This is not a job, you
know, for an amateur.
And, Joan, if you do not call the police,
then I am not going to stay here anymore.
Guys like Red Layls have
hit men workin' for 'em.
They drive 'em around and
do their dirty work.
I am calling a cab. I have an
early appointment tomorrow.
You know what I think? I think
it's more than one person.
It's not more than one person.
I'm tellin' you who it is.
Yes, but I don't think Red Layos would have
someone whisper into my answering machine.
It's just not something
that he would do.
Damn it Joan.
God, what is this? I can't say
anything to you anymore,.
You're so darn touchy, Harry.
You can mention anything
you want to me, honey.
I just don't wanna see you
turn up face down. That's all.
Couldn't you be a
little nicer about it?
It's, uh-It's Andy's.
Well, it certainly
is becoming on you.
Well, I probably don't
quite fill it out, but-
Oh, yes, you do.
What's wrong, Harry?
Uh-
Harry, what the hell
you think you doing?
I, uh-I just got a phone call, honey,
from a prominent entertainer up in Vegas.
- Avery well known singer.
- Well, who is it, Paul Anka?
He's a rock star. You wouldn't
know his name. - Uh-huh.
Anyway, I gotta run a
couple of dogs up to him.
You know, it's T-minus-zero
and counting...
Harry, on this
whole shitty deal.
Now, Iwo, don't blow
this out of proportion.
If you leave, I'm getting Top Lock come
over here, change front and back door.
Look, I'm talkin' about a short period of
time, here. - Oh, Ming, Tippy, shut up!
Shut up!
Ming, Tippy... No, no. I mean it.
You get in that van...
I'm taking my building back and I'm
putting in the fingernail salon.
Come on, now, honey. Let's not make
a big issue out of it, okay? Hmm?
All right?
Okay, honey.
Ming, Tippy, say good-bye
to Harry for good.
- It's very nice-Looking, honey.
- Do you like it?
Oh, yeah. I do.
It's something that
I really needed.
Thank you. - You're welcome.
You're probably wondering
why I'm smiling.
What?
Well, I was just thinking that I find
this moody side of you very attractive.
Oh. Uh-huh.
In fact, if you want to know-
and, well I can see
you're dying to-
I completely adore you, Harry.
You know, Joan, there's something I feel I
have to say that's been preying on my mind-
something that maybe I
could have handled...
a little bit differently
with you at the time-
about this... particular
situation that I'm in.
What situation?
You may recall that I
mentioned a while ago...
about being finished with a
certain relationship... -
- that I more or less ended-
- What? Well-Well, wait!
”Regarding an earlier press release
announcing Mrs. Ellerman's-
iMira esto!
Shh, shh, shh, which reportedly
contain several explosive details...
Joan, Joan - concerning Redmond Layls's
controversial business dealings,
Mr, Layls's lawyer,
Laurence Moncrief, had
this to say when asked
if he was concerned...
about what might be revealed
in the Ellerman book. -
I have no knowledge
whatsoever...
about Mrs. Ellerman's so-called
book, or her alleged disappearance-
which appears to have all the
earmarks of a publicity stunt.
- Oh, can you believe this?
- Recent reports...
of Layls's failing health were denied
by his personal physician, Dr. Park.
When questioned in a phone interview, he
responded that the elusive billionaire...
was recovering from, quote, “nothing
more than an ordinary virus.“
- Meanwhile, there seems to be-
- Do you see that?
What?
Monroe Park. That's the
name of the doctor...
that checked Andy out
of the hospital.
Well, I'm not sure that was the
guy's name... Yes, it was. Shh.
This is Heidi Robles reporting to you
from Monroe Park Center in San Dimas.
Where's San Dimas?
Let's call the TV station.
We'll find out.
I'm not sure this is the way you
wanna handle this situation.
Don't start that again, Harry.
Soco, tell her. She don't wanna
mess around with these people.
First, you tell me I go around
acting like a little mouse...
then when I feel I could save the pope in
an earthquake, you start undermining me.
This is not the pope
we're talkin' about.
Anyway, I didn't ask you
to drag along with me.
You're the one that's dragging.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- Just drive the car.
What exit is this?
What difference does it make?
We're not goin' anywhere.
Yeah, well, just tell me
where the turnoff is.
- Let me drive, huh?
- Why should I let you drive?
Why? Because you're a
bad driver, that's why.
Oh. Now all the ugly
little truths come out.
You operate this vehicle
as though it was...
a cane with a red tip
painted on the end of it.
Someone abates your maidenhood,
and then all of a sudden...
they feel that they can
start ordering you around.
- Can I at least offer some advice?
- No.
Good. Why don't you just barge into the
place, honey, and play the big hero?
When he tells you your sister's not
there, what are you gonna do, cry?
Okay. What?
I can't believe I let
you talk me into this.
- You look like a busboy in that outfit.
- Not now, honey.
- Not even a waiter. A busboy.
- Honey, please. Uh, Nurse-
Yes?
We're looking for the room
of Miss Andy Ellerman.
- I hope you know what you're doing.
- Sonya-
- Yeah? - Who were those people?
Doctor? Doctor, just
a minute, please.
Yes, what's the problem, dear?
Uh, we're trying to
contact Dr. Park now...
just to make sure that he's authorized
you to examine Mrs. Ellerman...
because, you know, we have our rules
and our regulations to follow.
- I understand. You're doing your job.
- Mm-hmm.
Where did your assistant go?
Um, she had to step inside
to relieve herself.
And if that little King Lear of corporate
shit thinks he can get away with this...
just wait till he hears what
I'm gonna come outwith now.
Put this on.
Remember when you passed
me off as staff...
when I was put on official
government payroll
all through Maui and
the Yucatan mission?
No, I don't. Oh, yes, you do.
You remember.
That's when I almost
died of vomitonegro.
What do you specialize
in, Doctor?
Um, female troubles,
I'd say, mainly.
Oh-ho, so Dr. Park feels there's a
gynecological involvement here?
Sometimes he does, yes.
Sonya. Sonya! May I
speak to you, please?
- Joan. Joan!
- I'm just finishing her hair.
Hurry up. - Is that him?
Let's go.
- Oh, this is not attractive.
- Oh, but-
Take it easy. I'll
be right back.
Doctor? Doctor?
That was my supervisor, and she wonders
if you'd do us a little favor.
- Certainly.
- Would you mind waiting...
in reception until we can
clear this matter up?
- Be glad to, Nurse.
- Thank you.
You know what that prick
had his lawyer tell me?
No.
That I was some petty,
grudge-bearing little malcontent...
grasping at some splinter of
celebrity for myself at his expense.
Can you believe that?
- Put this on.
- I mean, the arrogance-
- Here. - No, I-Here.
You know? - Mm-hmm.
- What did she say your name was?
- Harry.
50 he says, “Read the card."
loan! Joan! Are you there?
They locked the door.
- Is that you?
- Yes it's me. Harry, they locked the door.
I'm having a little trouble
getting back inside.
Great. What have
you got me into?
Hold your water.
Everything's under control.
Harry, just get me out of here.
Hang on for a minute or two more, honey.
I'll be right back.
And some privacy would be nice.
Andy, could you-
Could you stay here? I don't need you
right now. Andy? Larry Moncrief.
Uh, would you care to sit up?
I'd like to talk to you.
You son of a bitch.
- Who is it?
- Who the hell do you think it is?
Sweetheart...
is that you?
No thanks to you, it's me.
No, I don't want
to talk about it.
I'm the one who knew what you were doing in
the Yucatan Peninsula. I was on payroll.
Regrettably, we had to make a
justifiable entry into your house...
to appropriate
your manuscript...
from which I have made a
list of certain deletions...
which I would very much like you
to take a look at before...
Red arrives.
I'm the one who knew what you were
doing with those-those Chinese people.
And what about the illegal oil
drilling off the Mexican Gulf?
You know, personally, I don't think
this emasculates your work in any way.
Andy, would you-would you care-
Fine. If you're gonna be silly about
this and push this thing too far...
then you do run the risk of having Red
withdraw his consent to your well-being.
And I don't think that we want that.
Do we, Andy?
Andy's not here.
Yes. I can see that-
Mm Spruance.
Care to tell me where
exactly she is?
As a matter of fact, she happens
to be on her way to the police...
right now, accompanied by
a close friend of mine.
Honey, it's me again.
Hello - Harry, don't say a word.
- Sturge.
- I gotta tell you something.
I'm not alone. - Who's there?
- Just go get Andy and leave.
- That's what I'm tryin' to tell ya.
Oh. Hello, Mr. Bliss.
I think you'd better
come up here.
- Shh.
- You know, I'm a little...
disappointed to see you
defaulting on our agreement.
What agreement?
- What agreement?
- I never agreed to anything, honey.
This guy tried to bribe me into working
for him, and I told him to go to hell.
Oh really? Well, I think an agreement was
implicit in your acceptance of my check.
You wanna see your check?
Honey, don't go by
anything this guy says.
I'm the only one who knows
what in the hell I am doing.
I was gonna tell ya. It just
slipped my mind. Ah-ha.
You see? You see {hm
I never even cashed it!
Put him in the car.
Harry!
What did that bastard do to you?
I need a Kleenex. - Oh.
Let go of my hair!
Now, you know what
they're trying to do?
They're trying to force you into
signing some kind of agreement that-
Wait. I want you to hear
what he said to me.
He told me that I was the only woman
that he ever really cared for.
What? - And when he said that-
there was a tear in his eye.
Sorry. The door was
locked when I came-
- Get me something cold to drink.
- Uh, tea. feed tea.
You don't know what you're saying.
Now, you're suffering from...
some kind of hostage syndrome.
Red has been a very
important man in my life.
Oh, now he's not a “fecal-faced,
great white shark.” - Shh. Shh.
I don't know where she got that.
Eh? Huh? Honey?
All right, what's goin' on here?
- Who is this?
- Uh, that's the dog trainer.
- I thought he was working for us?
- Yeah. Well-
- uh, there seems to be a
little gray area there, Red.
Come over here. I
wanna talk to you.
Mr. Layls-
I just wanna say that...
although you're in the category
of a person that I admire...
you've gone to some lengths on this thing
here that I don't entirely agree with.
I have a neck condition that aggravates
me to have to look up at you. Sit down.
Okay. No problem.
But I wanna finish my
thought on this...
Because, you know, I'm not
In the best of health rlght
and I've been advised
to avoid excitement.
So if you intend to do that,
I might just have to have...
some of my more effective
personnel blow your brains out.
Furthermore, this sensitive man
Not only kept you in a stupor for three
weeks, but now he's trying to forbid you...
from publishing your book
the way you want to.
I know.
And I told him I'm extremely
pissed off about it.
Could someone please
get me my clothes?
Sturge, more sugar.
Lust for a moment, put yourself
in the shoes of a man“.
Whose sole intention is to leave the
world a better place than he found it...
only to discover those intentions
have been painfully slandered...
by someone he had given both his
heart and his economic support to-
not to mention his trust.
Mm-hmm. - Harry...
I cannot believe you
are sitting there...
nodding your head and having a
tea party with these crooks.
I'm not nodding my head, honey.
I'm just listening to the man.
Who is this guy anyway? I mean,
isn't he a little sleazy, Joahie.7
Lewie was a bit of a stiff... You're
going to talk to me about sleaze...
when you consorted with
some maniac tree surgeon...
who was flicking his tongue out
at me like some rutting iguana...
and groping at his naturel
at 3:00 in the morning.
- Oh. Him.
- Him? he might have come at me with an ax.
Well, he's very immature.
Miss Spruance, would you like a nice glass
of iced tea? - No, thank you. Excuse me.
I don't know what kind of spell you cast
on my sister, but it doesn't extend to me.
In fact, I've been to the police and I
intend to press charges against you.
- He's not to get excited.
- Not only for burglarizing my apartment-
but for breaking into
Andy's house and...
for hiring somebody to harass,
intimidate and frighten me.
- Maybe you better not start-
- No, damn it.
Honey, he's got a bad neck.
I am not afraid of these
snakes, Harry, What is it?
Dr Park is on the line for
you, Tell him to hold on.
First of all, I had nothing whatsoever
to do with your supposed misfortune.
And as regards Andy's house, I'd have
no need to break into Andy's house...
because I own Andy's house.
Oh, really? Well, just a few minutes ago,
he admitted... No, I didn't admit anything.
You liar.
Young lady, I have never much cared for
you, and I find your display of anger...
both unattractive
and unfeminine.
Hey, now wait a minute... I am not
here to beg your good opinion...
or to find the right amount
of attractiveness...
Don't insult this individual.
- That I'm supposed to render up.
- Get it? Huh?
Loanie, will you please stop
interfering in my personal life.
I want to go to the yacht and get a little
color back. - Do you know something?
The kind of woman you are is a
danger to the kind of woman I am.
- We found one for you.
- Keep your voice down.
So the next time that
you and your boyfriend
have a domestic spat,
don't call me.
If you're going to take this grumpy
attitude, I certainly won't.
Harry, where are my clothes?
- The pericardium is a gorgeous color.
- They must be outside.
- Don't rush me on “YB, Monroe.
- Would you get them?
There's nothing for you to say. It's
very clear where your priorities are.
All I have been
doing from day one-
Well, I want a hell of a lot more
information before you start carving me up.
- I don't be we erg/specifics"
- Believe that? - I don't.
The host was around
35, and was obviously
very healthy... Yeah.
Wait a minute, Monroe.
Goddamn it, I told you I
don't want a woman's heart.
Hmph. - Don't worry, It's not
going to change you in any way.
Never had a heart.
Heartless thug,
In other words, you
don't trust me.
- Would you please get my clothes?
- And I just wanted to tell you before...
that I was privileged to see you perform
on the Fourth of July at the Bowl.
You can't tell me what
kind of a woman she was?
And if she was so goddamned
healthy, why is she dead?
I was particularly moved by your rendition
of“The Battle Hymn of the Republic."
Mine eyes have seen the coming of the
glory of the lord - Never mind that shit.
Just tell her. Did I spend your money?
Did I give you any services for it?
Just tell this woman the truth
you son of a bitch. Huh? - Fine.
Yeah. - Why don't I start with the
fact that you're a married man...
and go on from there?
Jesus Christ! What are
you trying to do to me?
Honey, wait a minute. Wait.
You know whose
heart this body snatcher's
tryin' to give me?
The hostess at some
place called Denny's.
This is the doctor you
recommended to me.
- Get outta here.
- I'll be glad to.
You're killin' me, Monroe. You know that?
You're drivin' me to the goddamned wall.
Joan. Joan! There's a perfectly
good-Here. Thank you.
Honey, there's a very simple
explanation for all this.
If you loved me-
I tried to... tell you
tonight at dinner.
Just listen to me for
one minute, please?
It's very complicated.
You know, you live
a life, honey...
you make mistakes...
and maybe you get married
for mutual benefits or...
business considerations that are
weighing you down at the time.
You don't think the right person is gonna
come along. - I would never knowingly...
have become involved
with a married man.
I know.
That's why I went out and tried to
tell ya... I don't want to discuss it.
And you know, I bet you
never read Dante either.
Well, now, there
you're 75% wrong.
You know, I can't believe you would lie
to me about a thing like this, Harry.
Okay. I lied to ya. Didn't
you ever tell a lie?
Wait.
Can I call you up tomorrow just
to see how you're feeling?
To see how...
everything's going?
I have a dress rehearsal tomorrow
and a concert on Friday...
and that's all I care
about right now.
And I don't want to
see you anymore.
Oh, don't say that, please.
I'm asking you...
to give me a chance to clear these
things out of my life, because I-
No! No. I did not extricate myself
from the infidelities of one man“.
To fall into the arms of the
prince of prevaricators.
Well...
I might be all kinds of a son of a
bitch, and the prince of whatever...
but that doesn't mean that when
it came right down to it...
that I wouldn't stand up and
take the bullet for you.
That's not what I
observed, Harry.
60, Duke.
Harry?
- I want my dog.
- Lee. How are ya?
- Okay.
- I just this minute got back from Vegas.
I'm dealin' a couple of dogs to Paul Anka.
Just about to call ya.
Well, don't embarrass us both, man.
Just gimme the dog back, and...
let's preserve the friendship.
Lee, I'm in the neighborhood of
gettin' my hands on the money.
I'm on the verge of closin' a business deal
with Bart Soluthian. Soluthian Carpets?
You heard of him? - Come on, Harry. I
know these dodges backwards and forwards.
Now, I need the dog.
He's up for a TV series.
I don't even want the 10,000 now,
compared to what he might appreciate.
Well, correct me if I'm wrong, but our
agreement was I could buy the dog back.
All I'm askin' for is a couple
of days while I navigate a loan.
Don't make me have to get
legal with you, Harry.
You sold me the animal,
and as a personal favor.
I let you borrow him to demo to some V.I.P.
who probably don't even exist.
You haven't been
straight with me, man.
Duke, get in. Get in, Duke.
Duke.
Hey, why don't you
take this dog, Harry?
He's green, but you can
probably do something with him.
- No, I don't want the dog.
- Oh, come on. Take him.
You don't want him? Pick up some change.
Sell him for a pet.
Excuse me.
Do me one favor, will ya?
Say “owner“ if you want to...
but don't say “trainer.“
I trained that dog.
Want me to have to
repaint my rig, Harry?
They caught the
Westside Slasher.
No kidding, the Slasher?
Pete, they got the
Westside Slasher.
Joan, a couple of us are
gonna go grab a bite.
You wanna join? No, thanks.
I'm not hungry.
- Uh, how are you gonna get home?
- Call a cab?
Oh, no. Eddy. Eddy, could you give
Joan a ride home? - Yeah, sure.
Great. All right, honey.
See you tomorrow.
Bye.
Is this yours? - Yeah.
That “3”passage. That's
what / keep forge rang.
Watch your step. - Oh, thanks.
Do you remember when we were
on tour in Japan, in '88-
the night after we gave
a concert in Osaka?
Could you be more specific?
We had a few drinks
in your room...
and a certain
intimacy took place.
When I asked if I could see you the
next night, you know what you said?
You said you were too tired.
You were sleepy.
That was witty of me.
But you weren't.
'Cause an hour later you went into
Lewie's room. You didn't come out.
If you remember, I was in love
with Lewis around that time...
which I confided to
you, so you did know.
That's not the reason.
Eddy, you just passed the
turnoff to my street.
Eddy. - I just want to drive
around a little so we can talk.
Get outta here.
You know, if I remember
correctly, we only kissed.
If that led you to believe
something that hurt you, well...
I apologize.
You know, I used to think
very highly of you.
But now I don't like what I see.
Eddy, I don't really know
what you're talking about.
There are so many things about
me that you have no idea of.
Because you don't ask. Because you
have no interest. - That's not true.
Creative things and...
feelings...
and certain depths that no one
else in your life is capable of.
Eddy, you can tell me anything you want to.
You know that.
No. No.
I just want to sit
here quietly...
until I figure out
what's wrong with you.
And then... I want
you to kiss me.
Okay.
What is this? What are
you doin' with this-
- Duke.
Duke! Rays! Rays!
Go get Harry! Go! Go on. Go get Harry!
60, Duke!
Duke! Oh!
Are you crazy?
What are you doin' hangin' around with
a guy like this? - This is the LA.P.D.
- What are you people doing down there?
- You maniacs!
You-You liars!
- Ha'.
- What are you people doing down there?
You shits! You creeps!
What are you yellih' at me for? This
guy might be the Westside Slasher!
- Oh, the Westside Slasher.
- That's right.
They caught the Westside Slasher.
He's a friend of mine.
This guy's a friend of yours?
I thought he was,
but none of you are
friends of mine.
I'm finished wagging my tail and
leaving little puddles on the floor.
Smiling on command... Now,
wait a minute, honey.
Because I don't give a damn whether
any of you like me or not.
I repeat, this is the Los
Angeles Police Department.
Shut up! - Ma'am. Ma'am?
Kiss this. We can't
hear you, ma'am,
Ma'am, is this guy
bothering you?
I'm not bothering her!
I love her!
I love her.
Stay where you are, and
put down the knife.
Put down the knife, Harry.
Just give me that thing.
Give me the knife, Harry. See? He's
not bothering me. He's my friend.
- Looks like a domestic quarrel to me.
- Yeah, we better stick around.
That's what I am: your friend.
That's how I feel, honey.
That's how I feel.
That's what-That's what I came up here to
say, and then I see you with this guy.
I just wanna tell you
in my own words.
I need for you to know
this one other thing...
about me, because I-I don't wanna
withhold anything from you anymore.
What is it? Oh, God, no. No.
I-I don't wanna know.
Okay. - Okay. What is it?
My real name isn't Harry.
It's Eugene.
'Eugene'
I love that name.
You do?