Morning, Mr Oliver.
- Morning, Joe.
- Morning, Miss Lewis.
The dust sheets ought to be
off by now. It's nearly nine.
I've been here since a quarter to.
I can't do it all myself every morning.
Don't tell me Miss Bruce is late again?
Yes, Mr Oliver.
I shall have to speak to her personally.
These shelves need dusting
underneath as well, Miss Lewis.
Yes, Mr Oliver.
And some books out of line again here.
I'll put them straight in a minute.
Mr Harman doesn't like to
see that. Better do it now.
Better do it now, Miss Lewis.
Joe.
Yes, Mr Oliver?
Did you borrow the
cabinet keys on Saturday?
Yes, I did.
Look here.
But wait a minute. I never left them ..
- I must tell Mr Harman about this.
But I put those back
on Mr Harman's desk.
You mean you usually do
but this time you didn't.
You are a lucky boy.
If this one had gone it would
have cost you a lot of money.
Look, Mr Oliver. Just because you
had a bad weekend is no reason I ..
I beg your pardon?
Yes. Thank you very much.
I had a lovely weekend.
Mr Quince, better check this cabinet.
Oh dear. Nothing missing, I hope.
- We hope not.
Don't we, Joe?
I'm telling you I put those keys back on
Mr Harman's desk. Same as I always do.
Are you calling me a liar?
Hello. What's all this?
I'm afraid the cabinet keys got
left out over the weekend.
Where were they?
- In that cabinet of all places.
Mr Oliver said ..
- It's alright, Joe.
You're safe this time.
I left them there myself.
Anything missing?
- No. All there, Mr Harmon.
That's alright then.
Well.
I hope that satisfies you.
- Alright. That's enough.
Hello Mary. Have a nice weekend?
Yes thank you, Miss Tracy.
Morning, Stella.
- Hello, sir.
Good morning, John.
Hello, Stella.
Did you have a nice weekend?
- Yes, thanks.
Well, I have good news.
Oh?
What is it?
- Here you are.
Your insurance policy.
- Yes, it's matured at last.
Three hundred and seventy-eight pounds.
And nine shillings.
I know what you're going to do with it.
- Yes, things are beginning to move.
Dr Bell is getting in touch
with the Swedish clinic.
He thinks May ought to
travel by air ambulance.
You'll go with her of course?
Oh yes.
Will it be very expensive?
- No doubt.
There will be enough left to take
her somewhere nice to get over it.
After that, who cares?
She must be terribly excited.
- I know that I am.
That reminds me.
Do you remember what was written on
my medical report when I left the army?
I should. I was your nurse long enough.
What did it say?
'Liable to lose control
in emotional situations'.
You'd better stand by, Nurse Tracey.
Right, Major.
Morning, sir. Can I help you?
Yes. I should like to see
some sporting books.
This way please. Mr Quince.
Here's an order from America.
A big one too.
Arthur's of Boston. A small world.
Do you know them?
- Do I?
I was working there
when the war started.
If it hadn't I'd probably be there now.
Mr Harman, Miss Bruce is late again.
You know Miss Lewis and Joe really
can't get the shop ready by themselves.
Very well. Send her in to me.
Thank you, I feel sure ..
- Stella.
When can we get this off?
I doubt Joe will get them
off before tomorrow night.
That's alright.
I can stay late and check them and they
can go out first thing on Wednesday.
Warn Joe to stand by, will you.
- Very well.
Joe.
Get ready please.
There's a big order to be collected.
Can I help you?
- Thank you.
I just want to look at
the gardening section.
Over here, please.
I really wanted a book
on mushroom growing.
Yes. I think I have one here.
Haven't you anything else?
What about this one?
Miss Bruce.
Do you realize what time it is?
Mr Oliver, the gentleman
is waiting for his book.
I beg your pardon.
Mr Harman wants to
see you in his office.
I've got to take my coat off first.
I think this is what you wanted.
Good morning.
Did you have a nice weekend?
Hello. Lunchtime already?
Can I help you, sir?
No. I'm just looking around, thanks.
I don't want to make a fuss but don't
you think you'd better put it back?
What was that?
You've taken a book. I saw you.
Did you?
I wonder how that got there.
There.
Now call the manager.
Why?
You've put it back.
Very logical. The customer
is always right, eh?
But you were going to steal it?
- Was I?
Has anyone told you what
an attractive girl you are?
Am I?
- Lovely.
Miss Bruce.
When you finish, will you come in here?
- Yes, Mr Harman.
Miss Bruce, eh?
Brenda? Jean?
Ruby.
- Ruby.
You know, I like you Ruby.
We can have great fun together.
I've got to go.
I'll be at the Blue Club at 8:30
tonight in Orford street.
Why not drop in?
I've got better things to do.
- Are you sure?
The Blue Club.
Ask for Jeff Hart.
You wanted to see me, Mr Harman?
Yes.
Sit down, Miss Bruce.
I hear you were late again this morning.
I'm sorry, Mr Harman.
But my train got stuck in a tunnel.
What happened to the train before that?
Did that get stuck as well?
I don't know. I wasn't on it.
Was I?
- You should have been.
Now see here, young lady.
It's one thing to be
late once in a while.
But every day?
It's not quite fair on the rest of us.
Is it?
No.
Mr Harman, I beg your pardon.
- Don't go.
Alright, Miss Bruce. Get back to
work and don't be late again.
What is it?
I read this Hartley Whitfield over
the weekend by Reg Sanders.
I suggest we take fifty.
Seems a lot.
I think this one will sell alright.
It's certainly up to standard.
As a matter of fact there's rather
a novel thrill on the last page.
Oh?
A man wants to murder a blackmailer but
can't think how to dispose of the body.
Then his next door neighbour suddenly
dies of heart failure very conveniently.
He murders the blackmailer and puts him
in the coffin with the man next door.
Sounds a bit gruesome.
Not more than usual.
People certainly seem to like that
sort of thing. I can't understand why.
Alright. Shall we say fifty?
Very well.
By the way, thanks for
speaking to Miss Bruce.
That's alright.
I'm sure she won't be late again.
Hello Ruby. You're right on time.
Hello Jeff.
- Come and have a drink.
Have you signed the lady in, sir?
- That's alright.
Sorry sir. Police regulations.
What's so regular about this place?
Right. Let's get that drink.
What will you have to drink?
I'd like a small gin and orange please.
Do you think I could have a
sandwich? I missed my tea.
Of course. Frank.
Yes, sir?
I'd like a whiskey and a large
gin and orange, please.
And two special grills.
- Two special grills.
Mushroom and onions?
No onions.
Do you come here often?
Now and again.
One of my friends is a
member of The Sports Club.
Yes?
These are only my shop clothes.
I didn't have time to go home first.
Do you like dancing, Ruby?
- Yes, I do.
We'll give these three time to warm
up and then we'll show them, eh?
Jeff.
- Hello, Vi.
I didn't know you were back. When did ..
- I'll tell you some other time.
See you, Jeff.
Come on, let's dance.
Look Jeff, I've got to
go in a minute or two.
Go?
You've only just arrived.
I didn't have time to tell
my dad I'd be back late.
I must be in by eleven.
He'll raise enough stink as it is.
But I'll come tomorrow
Jeff and it will be different.
I couldn't care less, honey.
If that's how you feel, let's forget it.
Please, Jeff. I don't want to forget it.
Let me come tomorrow.
If I tell my dad first, it won't matter
if I'm not back until one o'clock.
I'll tell him I'm going
to see a girlfriend.
Alright Ruby. That's a date then.
After we've had dinner, maybe
we won't worry about dancing.
Alright, Jeff.
Meet me here at seven then.
Can you make it?
Of course.
Hello? Is that the Blue Club?
I want to leave a message.
Can you take it?
It's very urgent.
Yes.
Will you tell Mr Hart I've been
told I have to work late tonight?
Yes. That's right.
I can't meet him until half past eight.
Miss Bruce.
Thanks. Goodbye.
[ Whistle ]
Goodnight, Guv.
- Goodnight, Joe.
Goodnight, Mr Harman.
- Goodnight.
Yes, the food is excellent.
- I'd love to, Clive. But not tonight.
What about a quick drink then?
It's just around the corner.
I'm terribly sorry but I'm late already.
I see. Goodnight Stella.
- Goodnight, Clive.
Goodnight.
Any message for May?
No. Just tell her I'll
be along about nine.
Thanks for keeping her company.
I'm looking forward to it.
Goodnight Jeff.
- Goodnight.
Ready, Miss Bruce?
I take it you have an
appointment tonight, Miss Bruce?
How did you know?
Well.
You look extremely smart and I ..
Can't imagine it being for my benefit.
I'm glad you like it.
What time are you meeting him?
- Half past eight.
Then we'd better get started.
I check them off and you file them.
The invoices?
- On your desk.
Thanks.
A Short History Of The
British People. Three.
Right.
Man In The Making. One.
Ouch.
Look at that.
What a pity.
- I only bought it today.
Can't you mend it?
No. Of course not.
I am sorry.
I'm sorry.
That was quite ridiculous.
That's alright, Mr Harman.
It was this that started it anyway.
I wish I hadn't torn it.
I ..
I only wish I could help.
Uh .. how much?
How much did it cost?
Oh, about three pounds.
Here you are.
Try and get yourself another.
- Thank you.
Come on. If you want to get
away we have to hurry.
Now let's see. Where were we? Yes.
Man In The Making. One.
Got it.
You gave me quite a shock last night.
When did you get out?
About a month ago.
A month?
Reduction of sentence for good conduct.
I'm a good little boy, I am.
And now I'm broke.
You couldn't lend me a
quid or two could you?
I'd love to, Jack. But I haven't a bean.
A pity.
Anyway, I thought you were alright.
- What do you mean?
Your girlfriend last night.
Oh that?
Nothing, just business.
Hmm.
If you're not doing anything
let's go someplace.
I'm sorry, Vi. I can't do that.
I have a fellow to meet here later.
Might be something in it for me.
A job?
- It could be.
Of course, I've to soak him in drink.
Are you sure you can't
lend me something?
The things I do for Jeffrey Hart.
Don't say thank you.
It doesn't suit you.
Sure you have enough time?
- Yes, Mr Harman. Just nice thanks.
Goodnight, Miss Bruce.
Thanks for helping.
That's alright, Mr Harman.
Okay, I'll tell him when he comes in.
Is Mr Hart here yet?
- Yes, he's in the bar.
He already signed you in.
Could look after this for me please?
- Yes, certainly.
Ruby.
Sorry I'm late, Jeff.
Did you get my message?
Yes, sure. Send over a whisky
and a gin and orange, will you?
Yes, sir.
Is it all fixed?
Yes. My dad doesn't
expect me home until one.
That's nice.
Oh.
- What's the matter?
Sorry, but I tore my sleeve.
How did that happen?
I had to work late with my boss.
I got a bit manhandled.
- Manhandled?
He's never seem me in
my party clothes before.
I think the shock was too much for him.
Is ..
Is he married?
Yes, he's married.
His wife is an invalid.
Really?
This boss of yours.
What's he get?
What do you mean?
What's he earn?
How should I know?
I'm only the invoice clerk.
How much money has he got?
I shouldn't think very much.
Oh.
Wait a minute. I know he's got some.
I found a letter on his desk.
How much?
It was from an insurance company.
- How much?
About three hundred and something.
- Three hundred?
I thought you were a smart girl.
Menu, Mr Hart?
- We'll order later.
Very good, sir.
Well, I am a smart girl.
I got three pounds. More than the
blouse cost and it's not even spoilt.
Look. He makes you stay late.
He kisses you.
Right? He tears your blouse.
No. I did that before.
- I think not.
During.
No. You see it was when I passed ..
- Three pounds.
How much would you have got?
A hundred.
Not a penny less.
A hundred pounds?
- Why not?
He has a job.
And a wife. An invalid, you said.
He'll pay alright.
Now you are being silly.
I haven't got any proof anyway.
What's a torn blouse?
I did it on a filing cabinet.
Perhaps you're right.
It's alright.
Tomorrow you're going to
have a nice big bruise.
No wonder he gave you three pounds.
Miss Bruce. This has happened too often.
Mr Harman wants you in his office.
Again?
- Did you hear what I said?
Yes, perfectly. But I'm going
to change my shoes first.
We can have the plane on Sunday.
They are checking costs now.
I only hope ..
Hello? Yes?
You'd like it tomorrow?
I could bring cash. Would that help?
Yes.
Yes, I'll bring the passport forms too.
Thanks very much. Goodbye.
That's that.
Over a hundred pounds.
Now let's see. Plane tickets.
Travellers cheques.
I shall have to cash
more than I thought.
Oh. The ambulance.
I wonder ..
I know what I'll do. I'll cash the lot.
Then, whatever is left over
I can put back. If any.
Will you see Miss Bruce now?
Miss Bruce.
This is the last time I shall
warn you about being late.
I didn't think it would
matter this morning.
After all, I worked late last night.
If you'll excuse me, I have
some things to attend to.
That's no excuse.
I worked late myself last night.
Yes. You did, didn't you.
Do you like this blouse?
I bought it this morning.
I am not in the least interested.
I thought you might be.
After all, you paid for it.
I like it better than the
one you tore, don't you?
It was a bit mean fobbing me off with 3
pounds after what happened last night.
I thought I was over-generous.
Oh .. you did, did you?
I didn't think so.
You see, I happen to know you
have over three hundred pounds.
So?
You read my personal correspondence?
You've got to give me a hundred.
If you don't I will ..
I shall tell about what
you did to me last night.
Miss Bruce.
You could be sent to prison
for saying a thing like that.
I should be very angry with you.
But I'm not.
I can't imagine why.
Just because I've lost my matches.
- You needn't try and be funny.
You wouldn't think it was funny
if I showed them this, would you?
No.
That's a nasty bruise.
How did you get it?
Here they are.
Better get back to work, Miss Bruce.
You're late enough already.
Sandwich?
Well?
It wasn't any good.
Did you show him the bruise?
He wasn't interested.
He wasn't, eh?
Think again.
He was just stalling. That's all.
Now listen, Ruby.
Go back to Harman this afternoon.
It's alright. He'll be expecting you.
Tell him if he doesn't pay you're going
to tell his boss what he did to you.
You mean, write to Mr Pearson?
No Jeff, I couldn't do that.
Don't rush ahead so fast, Ruby.
We aren't going to write to Pearson yet.
That wouldn't be at all clever.
No.
This is for a letter to Mrs Harman.
His wife?
What for?
So he'll believe your
threat about Mr Pearson.
When he believes that,
we get our hundred pounds.
Jeff. I couldn't face him again.
- Now look, Ruby.
You've got nothing to be afraid of.
We are just going to write
a nice little letter to his wife.
Just to show him we mean business.
I'll soon show you I mean business.
You are very young, Miss Bruce.
I don't think you quite realize
what you are doing.
You don't think I'd dare write
to Mr Pearson do you.
Very well, Miss Bruce.
I've had enough of this.
You've just given me an ultimatum.
Now I'll give you one.
You have until tomorrow to decide that
this affair is finished and over with.
Or you will come with
me to the police station.
Now go and get on with your work.
I warn you, mister ..
- Go and get on with your work.
John.
I've written down a list of things
I want for the journey. Here it is.
Stella said she'd help you.
- Alright, dear.
We'll manage between us somehow.
Before I forget it.
You must sign this passport form.
It's all so exciting.
I can't believe we're going.
Neither can I. Just there.
[ Door knocks ]
There you are, dear.
- Thanks.
John, don't forget the vicar's books.
The vicar's books? I had forgotten them.
I don't think I shall have time.
- Couldn't someone at the shop to do it?
He's been so good. He depends
on you for half the book stall.
These jumble sales.
I'll do the best I can.
When does he want them?
He'll collect them from
here tomorrow afternoon.
In that case I'd better
bring them home tonight.
Maybe Joe can find an
old box or something.
There's lots here we don't want.
The whole of the bottom shelf can go.
I can't take those with me now.
Of course not, dear. But you can leave
room in the box and put them in tonight.
Very well then.
Are you so interested in the jumble sale
or do you just want rid of our rubbish?
Both.
I must go.
There. One for you.
- Thank you.
Anything else, darling?
- No thanks. I've got all I want.
Goodbye, dear.
I'll be home sharp and on time tonight.
Good morning everybody.
- Good morning, Mr Harman.
I want to see you later, Miss Bruce.
I'll send for you.
Yes, Mr Harman.
Good morning.
- Good morning, Stella.
Mr Oliver, have Joe pack some damaged
stock in a tea chest or something.
I promised them to our vicar.
- I'll see to that.
Ask him to leave plenty of room.
I've got a lot more I want to add.
Anything for me this morning?
I hope not.
We've got this bookbinding contract.
Mr Pearson wants your comments
by tomorrow. For sure.
He does? Then I'll attend
to it this afternoon.
Off to the bank, then
the airways office.
By the way, do you mind picking
these things up for May sometime?
Of course not.
- Be back at eleven.
This one will do very well, Joe.
Put all that lot in. And those.
Have a word with Miss Rosetti.
She's bound to have something.
I'll see what else I can find.
Hello. Pearson's bookshop.
Yes.
I'm afraid Mr Harman
isn't here at the moment.
Just a minute.
Miss Tracy. A telephone call
for you. They said it's urgent.
Hello?
Good morning, Doctor Bell.
Out of bed?
But she can't even walk.
To burn a letter?
You ..
You mean she's dead?
Who was the letter from?
Yes. He'll be back soon.
Right.
I think it would be
better if I told him.
I'll make a note of the title
and order it for you, madam.
Mary.
Would you excuse me?
Will you take care of
this customer please.
I've got the plane tickets.
Spent 120 pounds already.
We leave for certain on Sunday.
If you want to have an early lunch and
get May's shopping, I'll hold the fort.
Is something wrong?
I'm afraid this is going to
be a terrible shock to you.
Well?
Dr Bell phoned and ..
- Dr Bell?
About May?
Has something happened?
Mr Harman.
I'm afraid she's ..
She's dead.
Dead?
I don't quite understand.
Dr Bell said that Mrs Moss found
her lying on the floor near the fire.
It was something to do with a letter.
She got out of bed to burn it.
Out of bed?
- Yes.
It was too much for her.
Dr Bell is waiting for you.
This ..
This letter.
Did he say who it was from?
No. It was completely destroyed.
Only the envelope was found.
Don't you think you ought to go home?
Yes.
Thank you, Stella.
I shall go home presently.
Would you like me to come with you?
I'm sure there's something I can do.
No. No thank you, Stella.
I think it's better that
I go home alone.
I shan't come back today.
Will you phone Mr Pearson and explain.
Yes, of course.
Wait a minute.
There was something here ..
He wanted me to do for him.
Yes, the bookbinding contract.
He won't expect that now.
Yes, I must do this. I'll come back
tonight when everyone is gone ..
Joe can bring it around tomorrow.
Don't come back, John. Not tonight.
Don't you understand?
It will give me something
to think about.
I couldn't stay in the
house tonight anyway.
I'll probably stay in some hotel.
Oh.
I would like to see Miss Bruce.
Before I leave.
Miss Bruce?
Yes.
I said I'd see her.
Ruby.
Mr Harman wants to see you.
Ruby, you know what's happened.
Please don't say anything to upset him.
Miss Bruce.
Yesterday, when you
said you meant business.
You meant my wife.
Didn't you?
That was your letter.
Wasn't it?
I hope you're satisfied with the result.
- Don't. You're hurting me.
For a moment I thought
he was going to kill me.
Then he suddenly picked up
his things and went out.
What about the money?
- What do you mean?
The money. The hundred pounds.
Where is it?
I couldn't ask him that. Not after ..
- That's when you should have asked him.
Don't you see you've missed
the best chance you've had?
Where is he now?
- I don't know.
He's probably at the house.
You'd better go there.
I can't go there.
Don't you understand? His wife is dead.
I've as good as killed her myself.
Look, Jeff. I never wanted
that money anyway.
If I knew this would
happen, I'd never have ..
But it has happened, Ruby.
And as you say.
You've as good as killed her yourself.
Don't forget that.
I haven't done anything.
If they ask me .. I know nothing.
See what I mean?
Now .. what time will he get home?
I don't know.
He may be at the shop.
I think I heard Miss Tracy saying
something about him coming back.
That's better.
Now come along.
- Where?
To the shop.
Jeff, I can't.
You didn't see the way he looked
at me this morning. He'll hurt me.
What if he does?
All the worse for him.
He won't kill you. I will see to that.
You'll come with me then?
No. We mustn't be seen together. But ..
I'll be around. Don't worry.
If he tries anything, all
you have to do is yell.
Now come along.
Look, Jeff. It's not worth it.
[ Door knocks ]
What are you doing here?
Mr Harman, I've got to see you.
Well .. what is it?
Mr Harman, I want you to know ..
If you came to say you're sorry,
you're a little late, Miss Bruce.
I think you'd better go.
Mr Harman, you've got to give
me the hundred pounds.
If you don't I'm going to tell
Mr Pearson about what you did to me.
If you'd only given it to me yesterday,
all this wouldn't have happened.
One hundred. Two hundred. There.
Now take the lot and get out!
Here you are, Jeff.
Is that all?
Over a hundred.
I said, is that all?
Yes.
It's mine, Jeff.
I'm in a bit of a jam.
I've got to have something.
You give me that.
- Shut up.
No, I won't shut up.
Miss Bruce?
Hello?
Alright. You can get up now.
Ruby.
Ruby?
Mr Harman, this is Mr Bruce.
Ruby's father.
How do you do?
- She didn't come home last night.
Oh? Isn't she here?
- No, she's not.
Come in to my office, Mr Bruce.
Where's Joe?
- In the stockroom.
The box is downstairs. Would you mind?
Ask Joe to give him a hand.
Right this way please.
Has she ever done anything
like this before, Mr Bruce?
She has not.
When I get my hands on her,
she'll be sorry she's done it this time.
All we can do is let you
know if she comes in.
I reckoned you might give
me something to go on.
How do you mean?
- When did she leave last night?
The usual time. A little after six.
Excuse me. Miss Lewis knows
something that may help Mr Bruce.
Miss Lewis, will you come in please.
Well?
I left with Ruby last night Mr Bruce,
and she did say she had an appointment.
Who with?
I don't know. She just told me she
was meeting a gentleman friend.
Ah, so that's it.
I knew it was something,
being dolled up like that.
She was wearing her
new blouse and gloves.
And that barmy umbrella.
She ..
Didn't say who this
gentleman was, I suppose?
No. I am afraid not.
Thank you, Miss Lewis. That's all.
Mr Oliver.
- Hmm?
Something dreadful has happened.
- Yes? What is it?
What is it?
I had an order for six Enid Blytons
and I can't find them anywhere.
They should have gone off yesterday.
- Where did you have them last?
Yesterday afternoon.
Where? Let me see.
I was talking to
Mr Harman in his office.
Then I took them downstairs.
Yes .. I think ..
Yes, I must have done.
Half a mo', chief.
Let's get a better grip.
- Just a minute, Joe.
Blimey, I've slipped
a disc or something.
When you packed this yesterday, did you
put in some Enid Blytons by mistake?
A mistake? Me?
- Yes.
You must have done, Joe.
- Better open up and make sure.
Wait a minute. It took me an hour to tie
this up. I never touched any Blytons.
Come on. Quickly, Joe.
We'll let you know when
she turns up, Mr Bruce.
I do hope we hear something soon.
I'm getting worried.
I'm going home. There are some
books of my own I want to add.
But ..
Joe. What are you doing?
Miss Rosetti lost some
of her Enid Blytons.
Mr Oliver says ..
- Enid Blytons?
It seems to me I saw them someplace.
Yes. She left them on the
small table in my office.
I wondered what they were doing there.
Come on, Joe. The car is waiting.
Will you be back this afternoon?
- Yes, about three.
Can I drop you somewhere?
I go your way.
That's very kind of you, sir.
I wonder where she could be.
Who, Ruby?
She'll be back, if just
to collect her umbrella.
Umbrella?
Together .. heave.
Joe.
Down.
Did you say 'umbrella'?
Yes. She left it behind.
And I put it down by the
side of that bookcase.
Together.
Heave.
So you found your books?
- Yes.
Miss Lewis. Is this
Miss Bruce's umbrella?
Yes. It's Ruby's.
You said she had it with her
when she left yesterday.
She must have come back for something.
I'll put it in her locker.
No.
Don't bother.
I wish people would be more careful.
Miss Lewis, you told Mr Bruce that Ruby
wore new gloves as she left last night.
Yes, that's right.
- These?
It looks like them.
See, this is Ruby's too.
- You mean she wore it last night?
Yes. I wonder where the other one is.
Did she have any other shoes here?
- Yes. Her shop shoes.
These?
Yes.
Will you ask Miss Tracy to come
down here a moment please?
What is it, Clive?
Stella, I want you to see these.
There's no doubt Ruby was carrying
them when she left the shop last night.
Then she must have come back.
- Yes.
There was no-one here when I left.
How did she get in?
Mr Harman was here later. Perhaps he ..?
- He must have done.
I wonder why he didn't
mention it to her father.
Didn't he?
- No.
He'll be back later this afternoon.
You can ask him about it then.
Stella.
How did Mrs Harman die?
It was very sudden, wasn't it?
Yes.
She got out of bed to burn a letter.
- A letter? Who from?
I haven't the slightest idea.
Why do you ask?
When you broke the
news to him yesterday.
Why did he ask to see Ruby
immediately afterwards?
I don't know.
What has that to do with you?
I had to go in the office
while she was there.
He had her by the arm
and was fairly shaking.
I wonder if there's any connection.
What are you talking about?
Joe, that cupboard is for
cleaning materials, not books.
What do you mean?
Well, I'll be baffled.
Here, who's been playing tricks?
What's all this?
These are the books
Joe packed in that box.
And now they're in there.
What was in the box?
Where are you going?
To the police, of course.
The police? Why?
Why not wait until Mr Harman gets back?
You think he will?
When is Mrs Harman's funeral?
Tomorrow, I think. Why?
Tomorrow?
This is the shoe, Inspector.
There are the books.
And this is where the box was.
Is this hers too?
Yes.
Where's the telephone?
Through here.
Excuse me.
Close the shop.
- That's what I said.
Hello, Lang. Chief Inspector Dale here.
Get on to Central Information.
Ask them to send out an urgent
message to locate this person.
John Harman.
26 Kirby Road, Putney.
Wanted for questioning in
a case of suspected murder.
[ Door knocks ]
Now, about this letter that
was sent to Mrs Harman.
Could Miss Bruce have written it?
I suppose Mr Oliver put
that idea into your head.
No, no. I'm just looking for every
possible motive. That's all.
Mr Harman didn't kill her
if that's what you mean.
What makes you so certain?
Because I know it.
I know he couldn't
possibly do such a thing.
If he didn't kill her,
why did he run away?
I can understand that.
He escaped during the war and went
through some pretty bad times.
After that, he spent
months in the hospital.
How do you know all this?
I was a nurse over here.
He was one of my patients.
I don't think he'll ever
completely recover.
He's always been extremely
nervous and if you ..
Come in.
Yes Todd, what is it?
Can I have a word with you, sir?
Excuse me.
We're in luck, sir.
He cashed this cheque yesterday morning.
Seventy-eight one-pound
notes. The rest in fives.
Serial numbers?
The fives, yes. But not
the one-pound notes.
That's something anyway.
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
This is John.
Is anyone with you?
Yes. I'm afraid I'm terribly
busy at the moment.
If you'll just give
me the title quickly.
I'm hiding in a bombed church.
In Blackthorne Road, Ealing.
Stella.
Could you possibly come and see me?
Yes, certainly.
Anything else?
No. But please come as soon as you can.
Yes I will.
Where did you tell me to send them?
Once again.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Get the serial numbers
of those fivers circulated.
And he left his pipe in his
pouch in his overcoat.
So try the tobacconists,
food shops and cafs first.
Get an all-stations message
out from The Yard.
A large whiskey and ..
The same again please.
- Not for me. I'm off.
What's the hurry? Make hers a large one.
- Very good, sir.
You've come to see your
girlfriend, I suppose?
No .. I came to see you.
What is it then? Another two pounds?
Thank you for reminding me.
Thank you.
This is generous.
It's something.
'Honest Jeff Hart', they call me.
Cheers.
- Cheers.
You don't waste much time do you?
No.
All by yourself?
Uhuh.
Jeff. Shouldn't you
lie low for a few days?
Maybe I will.
If you want somewhere to ..
There's always my place.
Uhuh.
That's not a bad idea.
John.
Stella, I had to see you.
There was no-one else.
I couldn't think straight.
Everything seemed to happen at once.
Have you any idea how it happened?
- I just don't know. If only ..
Stella, I didn't kill her.
I know you didn't but I'm
awfully glad to hear you say it.
I know it was mad to bolt like that.
But the shock of seeing
her and the police.
John, let's just talk things over.
And try to see where we stand.
Now, do you remember if you ..
- Stella.
Will you do something for me?
- Yes, of course. Anything.
It's May's funeral.
Yes, John.
I'll see to everything.
- Thank you, Stella.
Now, about the money. Would you take
care of everything for the time being?
Certainly, but surely
you have enough left?
I haven't anything.
But the insurance money?
I thought you had cashed it all.
I did.
Haven't they found it?
No.
But I gave it to Ruby.
Do you want to tell me about it?
Well.
It happened the night we
checked the Boston order.
I suddenly found myself kissing her.
I'm not even sure which
one of us started it.
It was over in a second and we went on
with our work like nothing had happened.
I thought she'd forgotten all about it.
The next day she'd changed.
She twisted things.
Demanded money.
I refused of course. So ..
She wrote that letter.
- Try not to think about that now.
How much did you give her?
- All I had. Over 200 pounds.
Why?
- I don't know.
I just lost my head.
I almost forced it on her.
But the money hasn't been found.
They think you've still got it.
Then whoever killed
her must have taken it.
This is beginning to make sense.
She was a different person the next day.
Do you suppose somebody
could have put her up to it?
Meaning someone she was with?
That's right. She said she had a date.
Wait a minute.
That was Tuesday, wasn't it?
Yes.
I heard her phoning someone.
A club I think.
Something.
Then she must have come back.
He must have killed her in the basement.
But how did he get in?
- Hold it.
I think I've got something.
- What?
It's the basement.
Something to do with that.
Did you hear anything?
I don't know.
But I saw a light and I went downstairs
to see if she was still there.
I think it was something .. I saw.
To do with the books.
- Could I find it?
I don't know because I'm
not sure where it is myself.
But I'm sure it's important because ..
If you went back there do
you think you'd remember?
I might.
Then we must do that.
The trouble is the police are
watching the place the whole time.
If only we could get Clive on our side.
Perhaps he could get them out
of the way for a little while.
John.
You stay here until I call for you.
In the meantime, please trust me.
Try not to worry.
Stella, I just don't know what to say.
You are being so wonderful.
But it's more than that.
You've always been like this.
I've got so used to it I just don't
know how to say thank you.
You see.
It's alright, John.
I think I know.
I'll be back around seven.
Look after yourself.
Home sweet home.
This is the life.
I knew it was a good idea
of yours to come here.
Jeff.
- Yeah?
Why couldn't I help this time?
You always let me in before.
No. It was a one-man job.
I see.
Where did the blond bit come in?
Let's forget about her, shall we.
Search me.
Got any cigarettes?
- Only a few.
Not much food either.
I'd better do some shopping
before they close.
Here.
Get some cigarettes and
anything else you want.
Thanks, darling.
You look tired, my pet.
I could sleep for a couple of days.
Then why not get comfy?
You can't rest like that.
Let's have your coat.
That's perfect.
0-2-0-1-5.
Hello Stella.
Clive, I must talk to you.
Can you meet me in a half hour?
Here, you mean?
Where?
No, that's too far. I can't be away
for long. Scotland Yard may need me.
What's it all about?
I can't tell you now.
But it has something to do with that.
Alright.
I'll meet you in the gardens
off Jermyn Street in about ..
Half an hour. But I shan't
be able to stay long.
I'm sorry I'm late.
- What is all this?
Clive, I need your help. Badly.
Is it you who needs help or Harman?
You've got to help us.
Us? Why should I do anything for him?
Do you know what he's done?
John did not kill Ruby Bruce.
- How do you know that?
Because he gave her some money
last night and it hasn't been found.
Now, whoever killed her must have ..
- How do you know? Have you seen him?
You have seen him haven't you.
Where is he?
If you know you must tell the police.
Do you realise what can happen to you?
I don't care what happens to me.
- That's just the trouble. You don't.
You know. In some ways
you're such a child, Stella.
Clive, please.
You think you're in love
with him, don't you?
Yes, I am in love with him if
that's what you must know.
I knew alright. I felt you were in love
with him since you came to Pearson's.
Or was it before that?
- I don't care to discuss this.
Why not face facts, my dear?
This may be the best thing that could
happen to you. This infatuation.
A nurse in love with her patient.
A married man.
With an invalid wife.
It's all happened before.
For heaven's sake.
John's life is in danger.
And you're in danger of making a fool of
yourself. To me that's more important.
That surprises you doesn't it.
You had your head in the clouds so long
you never realized how I felt about you.
Would you like me to tell you?
- No, I would not.
I don't want to hear
you're in love with me.
Or I'm really in love with
you and don't know it.
Clive, will you please let me
tell you why I've come here.
Alright. Go on.
John believes someone else
was in the shop last night.
But he's got to get back
there to prove it.
He can't.
Not without the police knowing. They
are watching the place day and night.
Couldn't you get permission
to work late this evening?
I think so. Why?
You know the window
at the back of the shop?
Yes. Now look, if we're caught ..
- We won't get caught.
Will you help us or won't you?
Alright.
What do you want me to do?
Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
Yes, madam?
- Let me have a hundred Players please.
Sorry. Forty is all I can manage today.
Couldn't you make an exception?
I'm afraid not. I've got my other
customers to think about.
Thank you.
Excuse me will you. I'm short of change.
I'll be back in a minute.
I can't tell you how grateful I am.
- Come on.
Go back in the office.
There's no point dragging you into this.
That's alright.
Got the flashlight?
That's it.
What?
Look. Those books.
Somebody must have moved these.
Look at the ones above.
I wonder if ..
Lights.
Now I can understand
why this was so easy.
John Harman, I am a police officer.
I ask you to come along
with me to the station.
So a statement may be taken from you
concerning the death of Ruby Bruce.
Very well.
At least, may I explain
why I came back here?
Make it short.
I was in the shop when Ruby
came back here last night.
But somebody else was here as well.
- How do you know?
Those books on the floor.
Someone put them away upside down.
None of my staff would have done that.
Whoever did, must have
used this for a spy hole.
Can't you see? These other books
have been disturbed. The blue ones.
The blue ..?
What was that?
- Nothing.
Was that all?
- No.
I gave Miss Bruce a lot of
money when I saw her.
Whoever killed her must have taken it.
- Why?
Because there was no money found on her.
How do you know?
I told him.
You did, did you?
Where did you give her this money?
- In my office. Upstairs.
Alright. Let's go up there then.
Alright Mr Oliver.
I don't need you here.
Tell Miss Tracey to wait until ..
Where is Miss Tracy?
Gilbert.
Sir?
You saw a lady go out this door?
- That's right. She went on ahead.
Went on ahead?
What the devil do you mean?
I thought ..
- Never mind. Don't think.
Get after her.
- Yes, sir.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
You're not a member are you?
- No.
You can't come in unless
you're with a member. Sorry.
But I've got to meet a member here.
He told me to wait.
That's different. What's his name?
I know this sounds stupid
but I don't remember it.
You see, I just met him once.
He is really a friend of a girl I know.
She was here with him
on Tuesday, I think.
He must have signed her in.
Tuesday, did you say?
- Yes.
What was her name?
- Miss Bruce.
Miss Bruce? I think I remember her.
Yes. Here we are.
Mr Hart signed her in.
Yes, of course. Mr Hart.
I think you'll find him in the bar.
Through there.
Thank you.
Thanks.
If Miss Burley comes in, don't tell
her I've been here. I'll be back later.
Keep the change.
- Thank you, sir.
Yes, madam?
- Which is Mr Hart?
Did you want Mr Hart?
- Yes.
I'm afraid you just missed him.
He was here a few minutes ago.
Could you tell me where he lives?
Yes I could. But why?
I have a message from him.
It's rather important.
May I ask who from?
From a girlfriend of his.
- Oh.
I'll be seeing him later.
Perhaps I can give him the message?
Thank you but I have
to deliver it personally.
I could show you where he lives.
- Don't bother.
If you could just give me his address.
That's no trouble. I go that way myself.
Here we are.
[ Buzzer ]
Must be out.
No point in hanging around.
Why not give me the message?
I'll tell him.
I can't do that.
- Why not?
I promised to tell him myself.
I'll come back later.
- No you don't.
Now.
Vi gave you a message for me.
Come on, let's have it.
I was short of money so
I sold a pearl necklace.
Two hundred pounds?
Where did you get a pearl necklace from?
From my grandmother.
She died last Christmas.
Sorry to hear that.
When did you sell it?
About two weeks ago.
That's odd.
These notes only came
from the bank yesterday.
Are you sure?
There must be some mistake.
- You don't say.
Who did you sell it to?
I don't know his name.
I never saw him before.
Was it him?
No.
What about the next one?
That's Jeff Hart, isn't it?
- Yes.
You know him, don't you.
I used to.
Seen him recently?
About three weeks ago.
But not to speak to.
How is he getting on?
I'll ask you just once more.
Where is Vi?
I tell you I don't know her.
- Then why do you want to see me?
Where do you come from?
Was it him?
- No.
Well, why don't you
look at the next one?
You got it from her.
No.
We know it came from her
and she's dead isn't she.
No.
Murdered last night.
Alright. That's all I wanted to know.
You are in a real mess this time.
But I didn't have anything
to do with it.
Take her away.
Please Mr Dale, you must listen to me.
- Come on.
I'll tell you everything.
So, you're from the bookshop, are you?
A friend of Ruby Bruce, eh?
- You've got to let me go.
Alright.
Go ahead.
Go on.
No, you don't.
Do you think I'd let you go
so you can squeal on me?
You've got to let me out of here.
She's talked. It's Jeff Hart.
He's at her flat now.
Where?
46 Denbeigh Street. Top floor.
What about Mr Harman, sir?
Mr Harman. I'd forgotten about you.
You can go.
Call tomorrow. I'll know how much
of your money we recovered.
May I come with you?
- Of course not. Why?
I want to see you get this man.
I can understand that.
Sorry. I can't possibly take
you with me. I'd lose my job.
Come on then.
That's the window.
The one without the light.
Where is the front door, sir?
- Round the side. Come on.
No, Mr Harman. You'd better stay there.
We don't want you mixed up in this.
Hey Harman. Come back!
Alright. Take him away.
..s-d..