There are times when I just wonder
about the way things happen.
First, comes the day. Then, everything
happens on that day.
Then comes the night-the best part!
But then right after that,
comes the day again!
And on and on and on...
never-ending!
The only thing that hasn't changed
lately is that Santa Cruz...
hasn't won a single game...
not even a title of honour!
And I... haven't found anyone
that deserves me...
Love always goes wrong...
I just wish the whole world
would go and fuck itself!
Good morning Nita, up there
on Paradise Hill.
Good morning Argemiro
and Inácia.
Good morning to all the crowd
up there on the Hill.
And Cannibal, how're doing?
Ronrona, Peste, Marcelo,
Celo Brown, Dito de Oxossi, how's
everything going overthere, brother?
Good morning too, to everywhere
on Shooter's Hill.
A very good morning, and here's
hoping that this 16th July
is filled with happiness.
'Stay full of cheer...
'cos tonight there'll be cheap beer.'
And now, let's turn
to the morning news.
A very respectable housewife
found her husband with his lover.
Things turned rough. She, an
evangelical, pounced on...
Miss So-and-so, and all
hell broke loose.
Result: The loverended up
in hospital and no one's...
seen hair nor hide
of the betrayed wife.
Well, that's it,
the main news.
More news in a few minutes.
This is yourCity Soup,
always keeping you informed,
because after all,
life is not that hard in Recife.
To catch a minibus,
forexample, is easy...
and for a minibus to
catch you-is even easier.
'Stay full of cheer 'cos tonight
there'll be cheap beer.'
That 's the way it goes.
This is City Soup.
Always here with the latest news.
Now, let's go overto the day's
news. More police news.
Another police case. Well,
it would be if the police...
themselves weren't the
main suspects of killing two
boys that were found in the bathroom
of the Jean Paul Sartre School.
They were both 14 and were said
to have been killed by...
2 policemen on routine patrol.
The motive: Cannabis!
The thing is that the witnesses
don't want to talk, and those
who do talk only know from
hearsay. That's the way it goes.
This is City Soup-the truth
every day on your radio.
- Hallelujah, brothers!
- Hallelujah!
We must fear the Devil
and glorify the Lord!
Glory!
We must never leave a space
open in our minds for Satan...
to invade our hearts, amen?!
...to make it his home! Hallelujah!
- Hallelujah!
The weapon against suffering is the
belief in Our Lord Jesus Christ! Amen!
- Praise be to God!!!
- Praise the Lord!!!
If I am capable of killing a man?
Of all the species that walk
this earth, man is the...
one creature that deserves to die.
In fact, I killed a man once.
That 's why they call me Cannibal...
Wellington Cannibal!
Look, the only thing I could
never do is kill Kika!
She's not most beautiful woman
in the world, no, but she's the best
'cos she's evangelical! Yea...
May God keep her that way...
And by God, I'll tell you
something, pal,
I trust Kika more than myself...
she says the most beautiful things...
You took the piss, you're yellow,
this will not go amiss...
inside this box is an indigent body
a body without voice,
a body without feelings...
inside this box is an indigent body,
a body without voice...
Excuse me Aurora...
a body without feelings...
You took the piss, you're yellow,
this will not go amiss,
and inside this box...
Bianor, Bianor!!
What are you looking for?
The store key, Dunga...
Isn't it on the third hook?
Well, I'll be... there it is...
I've been looking all over
for this darned key...
Mr. Bianor, Mr. Bianor! I'd say
you're going half blind?
The key is in the same place as
always and the man can't even find it.
Texas Hotel, at your service...
hmhmm... I don't know... I'll see...
Dunga, is Isaac up yet?
That? Up before ten?
So go and call him. Tell him it 's
urgent. It 's some... Rabecão.
All right, but you
know how he gets.
Looks like a wild beast with those
squashed up piggy eyes.
Mr. Isaac...
what the fuck d'you want?
- Mr. Isaac...
- What the fuck is it?
There's a phone
call for your excellency.
Rabecão would like to speak
to his highness.
Get fucked! Is he still on the line?
Answer you miserable poofter...
is he still on the line?!
Fuck... shit.
Bollocks!
Yes? Of course it 's
me, Rabecão... yeah!
The voice of someone who
just got up, you bastard!
What is it? No... no...
And I'm gonna get upset
because of that?
Hang on...
Fuck! Hey! Bianor.
Put the fucking extension
back on the hook!
Look, I'll meet you at the usual
place in 4O minutes!
Of course I'll take the stash,
for fuck's sake.
No, it 's all planned,
arranged and decided...
I'm telling you... I've hit it
right on the head, OK!
Wow, Rabecão: Great!
Fucking hell,
fucking hell, fucking hell!
- 'Morning, Bianor!
- Morning!
Hey, Dunga was
getting worked up.
Go straight through
to the kitchen, Wellington.
He's expecting you.
God save Wellington... What?
What are you looking at
me like that for?
Hang the meat on that hook. Go on...
Put your meat really near me, go on.
What?
I know... You've started?
You're getting your fangs
ready to pounce, eh?
Yes... but don't get scared.
Don't knock it 'til you've tried it.
Clean all that skin off and leave
it really smooth and clean.
For fuck's sake Dunga!
Why don't you go and throw this
Shit over the bitch that...
the bad luck of having you, eh?!
Fuck and bollocks!
Every day this fucking queer throws
this fucking stuff over me!
You're a fucking pain Dunga.
I'll fuck you good and proper.
Mmm... sure...
You're a fucking pain.
A fucking pain.
And... Kika? How's she?
Thank God, she's on the right
track. An evangelical.
One of these days I'll be going
down the same road.
I should give up smoking.
She's a lucky woman... she likes
her meat then, does she?
No... she's not that good in bed...
but she's a good woman.
A believer...
Modesty is the most intelligent
form of perversion.
Which one, Lígia?
Hang on! I'm thinking.
Last night I dreamt
about today.
You know something?
I've seen all this before.
It 's all already happened.
Isn't today
the 16th of June?
Sure... today I'm another year older.
Ha! You're getting old?
Not old! Experienced...
All right then... I'll play today's
date in the first to the fifth
in both games. And do another too,
with the numbers reversed.
6, 16... a good game, huh?
- What was yesterday's result?
- The dog.
Fuck! And I put my
money on the cow.
Let 's make amends
for our guilt here...
I'm not a rich man, but
I still feel guilty.
To have any sense at all in
Brazil is motive enough to feel guilt!
Oh no! The show's about to start...
I saw this in my dream too.
God! What a miserable life...
Hey, beautiful! Aren't you going
to bring us our breakfast?
- See you, Lígia.
- Bring us a beer!
See you around, Mr. Bianor.
Today is confused,
but happiness reigns.
Long live Denmark!
Heh! Isaac!
What else can
we expect of life?
Fucking hell!
Dunga! Dunga! Little Dunga!
Oh! For God's sake! What?
Where's the fire?
The priest is going to eat
with us today, you hear?
What 's the matter?
Are you crying?
Of course I'm not, it 's
the fucking onions!
Onions... there's always something.
It 's all I need.
May the light of God
shine upon us.
Illuminating our souls...
with love...
Nobody is innocent.
Man's hope lost
a long time ago.
Pain appears and screams
from every corner.
The humanists pity themselves
from the rail of the pulpit!
But, may they pity themselves of their
own souls, because it is exactly
the pride of goodness that
resides in almost every sin.
Man dies, the world burns out
and the flames are consumed...
but excess accompanies the vacuum.
Kika Cannibal!
Lígia, my little mango,
give me my medicine...
and some
gizzards to pick at.
There's no gizzards... but there's
a little liver, will that do?
And why not, flower of my life?
Well, I'm gonna grab that pretty arse!
Another beer! And so I heard this
story about the Argentinians.
Load of wankers! One of them said,
'first we stop being Argentinians
and become Spanish! '
Show me, show me a Brazilian who
can tell someone who's Spanish
from someone who's not?
Well, after a load of bollocks, they
spoke the hallowed phrase,
the real treasure of Brazilian thought!
The phrase that humiliates
anthropologists.
'Let 's buy a car. In Brazil a car is
worth more than character! '
I hate the Argentinians, but I have
to give credit to his phrases...
And the conclusion was brilliant!
'Brazilians foster...
a certain admiration
for wheedling.
The average Brazilian
loves being cheated. '
Go and slap your mother's
arse, you fucking prat!
What the fuck?
Go shove it up your arse! You reckon
my arse is your mother's cunt?
Fuck off, you hear, go fuck yourself!
And you get your
fucking hands off me!
Fuck off to work
you load of bastards!
Dunga my boy, bring
me a glass of water.
And the vegetable list.
I'm off to the market.
Right away. Ah, Bianor,
bring me a box of bobbins.
Where the fuck have you been!
Calm down, calm down.
- So? Where is it?
- Inside.
What state is it in?
Is it very damaged?
Well, the body is a little
perforated, but it 'll do fine.
- Is it cold?
- Cold? Like an iced lolly.
Fucking hell!
Take good care of that. It
doesn't have an owner, but...
...as I said... I'm just warning you.
- Fine. Now, get going.
And, Isaac, don't forget. I'm waiting
for you at the Avenida Bar.
Daisy!
Hang on, Wellington,
you fucking stink!
Look here Well, I'm up
to here with all this!
What 's this, my love?
Huh! What 's this? You're
going to have to choose.
I won't go on being known
as the slag around here.
That I'm no good, I'm bad, a tart...
Yesterday, dad, who can't even
walk straight, looked at me
and in one mouthful just
called me 'a slut '!
- Kika, Kika...
- Fuck Kika!
- Daisy my love... listen...
- Stuff your 'my love'!
You're fucking difficult?
What the fuck are you on
about now, Wellington?
Wellington, my father called me a slut.
And do you know why?
You bloody don't, do you?
Because of you!
- You went and told him.
- Of course I told him, you soft idiot!
But he's beginning to work out
that I am with a married man.
A "ghost-boyfriend" is always married.
I just hope to God he never
realises it 's you... especially with
the way he feels about Kika.
That soft bitch.
Not a soft bitch! Kika is an
evangelical! She's the type that...
Christians are the biggest
sluts of all.
Say that again! Say
it again if you dare!
Christians are the
biggest sluts of all!
Go on, hit me Wellington!
Hit me!
Fuck...
you're man enough, aren't you?
So go on -hit me, Cannibal!
Look here Daisy, don't tempt me.
Otherwise you'll regret it.
You'll come out the worse! If your
father, who knows you well,
calls you a slut, then it 's because
you deserve it! Get it?
And don't think I'm going to beat
your face to shit, because I'm not!
But you fucking deserve it!
I'm just warning you that
it 's the one thing
I'd really enjoy doing.
Now look here, never open your
mouth about Kika again, never!
Show some respect for her!
If not I'll do you up!
D'you get it? Never speak like that
about Kika again, do you hear!
I'm off.
Today I'm going over to the
Santería House... oh yes!
You'll see what I can do.
I'll get you all right Cannibal.
I've already started a spell and it 'll
only be over when I've got you
in the palm of my hand, here!
Right here!
Go to your precious little Kika.
That slimy Daisy! Go!
This is for you!
Rice! Rice!
I'll finish with the two of them!
Fucking women!
Huh! Nothing matches
the fury of a determined queen, dear!
I'll only rest when I'm 6 feet under!
I may not be a woman - but I'll
get what I want. I will!
God forgive me, but I'll do anything,
I'm not playing around here!
And as for that one - 'Jesus is love',
'salvation' -for fuck's sake!!
Daisy... Daisy is just
a shit-bag, a slag.
Addicted to married men!
God forgive me, but they say
she's even had dykes...
licking those tits, dear!
Slag! Slag!
And being the slag
she is, it must be true.
Now Daisy...
I would never swap a man like
Wellington for some old dyke, dear!
Lesbian... I'll get it all sorted out all
right! When she goes to the Santero...
I'll get her sorted. Plant today
and harvest tomorrow.
Be fucked if I'm playing
around! I'll do it!
Dunga my boy, is there ever going
to be any lunch today?
It 's coming, it 's coming Aurora.
Stay talking to Bianor and when it 's
ready I'll give you a call. Right?
You look as if you're up to
no good, Little Dunga.
I've seen this face before...
oh god! Aurora, I'm not in the mood
for jokes today. Stay with Bianor.
If not the food'll never
be ready today. Go on!
You liked the material then?
As yellow as a mango!
Fuck me, but that 's one hell
of a woman! Who's she?
The she-wolf of the Avenida Bar.
She's a crazy bitch.
Looks like a whore but nobody
here has ever had her.
You're joking?
I don't joke, Isaac? And the 'ham'?
Was it too far gone?
What ham? Ah... it 's there.
I don't think it 's any worse
...than it was before.
- And the weed?
- In the car, 5OO grams.
So let 's get going. I'm all out.
Just a minute Rabecão.
I'll tell you what.
You get the weed out of the car,
from under the passenger seat.
I'll stay around here
for a while. All right?
I get you. You want to have
it with blondie there.
Well, if you manage
to bang that one...
I'll give you back the dosh...
and you can even
fuck me up the arse.
Fucking poofter...
keep your arse to yourself.
But, I'll take you up on the dosh.
No deal. You'll have to take
my arse! No arse, no deal.
Get out of here, you fucking poof!
And Rabecão, if another jewel
like that one turns up...
Get the bill, ok?
Heh, young lady! I need one here.
Kika Cannibal!
For God's sake, Wellington,
what 's this all about?
I do everything I can
to stay out of trouble.
I do no harm to any one,
I give no trouble to anyone.
And what do I get in return?
Kika Cannibal...
oh Kika, it 's all just kid's talk.
You know how they love getting
decent people all wound up?
Look at what happened to Suian.
- The manicurist?
- That 's the one.
The kids went and told
the whole villa not to get...
their nails done with her
because she's got AIDS?
Kid's pranks, Kika... little bastards.
Wellington! I've asked you once,
twice, a million times!
If you want to swear, do it with your
friends in the bar. But not here.
Under this roof, I demand respect.
In the name of Jesus.
Sorry Kika, sorry.
She deserved it though,
she betrayed him...
What was that?
Suian! She had what
was coming to her.
She betrayed her husband. Everyone
knew. It was too little for her.
One thing, Wellington...
one thing I really cannot
forgive... betrayal.
I really can't.
Murder, violence, robbing,
all this I can tolerate...
but not betrayal.
I find adultery repugnant!
The adulterer too.
Whoever strikes the first blow,
always gets the blow returned.
I can't even think about it.
- And the capital of Korea?
- Seoul.
- And the capital of Chile?
- Santiago.
- And the capital of Afghanistan?
- Kabul.
- And the capital of Venezuela?
- Caracas.
- And Egypt?
- Egypt is Cairo.
- And... of... of Peru?
- Lima.
Bless you, Aurora.
Bless you? You only say bless you
when people sneeze, she's coughing?
Oh my God, lift your arms, Aurora.
Lift your arms!
Water, water, drink some water.
Here, here, swallow it.
Drink. Drink, drink, drink, drink,
drink, drink. Drink,
dri-dri-dri-drink. Swallow it,
swallow. That 's it.
Breathe slowly. That 's it,
breathe. There you are.
My God, every day... how I choke.
Must be for the sins of another time.
What probation, my God.
It 's always the same.
Seems as though there's
something else!
Leave out the drama, Aurora!
You're putting up the circus tent!
It 's all passed, dear. Go on!
Swallow the chicken slowly,
take water with it.
- It 's the rice.
- What? The rice? Why the rice?
Bianor thinks that the rice has
got to be like porridge so that
she doesn't choke. I don't know
how to make rice like porridge.
My breathing isn't very
good at the best of times...
and then choking like this...
Aurora, you always say that you
are paying for something.
That it 's this, or it 's that. But, just
think for a moment with me.
Forgiveness. Forgiveness is granted
because of what we are,
and punishment is never the
equivalent of what we have done.
And one more thing to think
about-choking. Isn't that an excellent
form of punishment. Think about
your past. Look at your present.
Take the true measure of what
you consider to be punishment.
- And the capital of Syria?
- Damascus.
My little mango. Another one.
And another one over here!
Is all your hair this colour...
or can you only afford to dye
the hair on your head?
Hi, Mr. Sá. Do me a favour, will you?
Keep an eye on the stall
...while I make
a quick call over there?
All right, but be quick, I can't
stay looking after it very long?
You're just great, aren't you, Mr. Sá?
You're the expert in asking for
things, but to help out others.
What a useless tyke you are.
I'm only popping over there to the...
video shop.
I'll be back quickly.
Hello? Just a minute.
Cannibal back from lunch yet?
Cannibal, the phone!
For me? I'm on my way...
Daisy, Uh? Look Daisy, you're
out of order? It 's not right!
You're a fucking cow! Fuck
off Daisy... no, no, no, no!
And don't talk to me like that!
Look! No... no.
You wouldn't dare...
I'll beat the shit out of you!
I'll beat the shit out of you,
do you hear Daisy!
Calm down, calm down!
Today! It 's got to be today?
I don't believe this... you never
give up do you, Daisy? Eh? Eh?
Ah, you're in a hurry?
Today, in Campinho. In Campinho
I just want to tell you one thing, Daisy.
Don't set me up, ok, because... Hello?
Hello? Hello! Fucking bitch!
Hey! You row with your tarts and then
take it out on my fucking phone!
Sorry... This woman drives me mad!
I am not entirely unhappy with
the situation at my church.
One thing I can't complain
about is my flock.
In fact, they don't
bother me at all.
The church is closed.
There are no images any more.
They were stolen. No masses. And so?
It makes no difference to me.
The most important thing is God!
The rest is the rest.
Don't you think I'm right?
Hmm. Who am I to contradict
you? You must be right.
Bianor, these people have plenty of
places to practice their beliefs!
The protestant temples,
the Santería Temples!
The psychiatric clinics!
Why don't they leave
my church in peace?
I can't help thinking that
if things go on this way.
One day it 'll just
come to an end by itself.
You're right!
People like ostentation!
If there's no ostentation
then there's no church.
I am relaxed about it.
I'll tell Dunga to prepare
the soup for dinner.
Texas Hotel at your service.
Just a moment.
Dunga! Dunga my boy! Telephone.
- Dunga?
- Daisy?
What a surprise. Your ears
must have been burning.
Iwanted to ask you a favour. I'll be
quick, because I can't talk long.
I can't go to the Santería Temple
today. Tell Father Adão that...
I have to go somewhere else today.
The queen will be
stamping her foot, dear.
Tell him it's urgent.
Wellington.
Going down on rough trade, dear?
That 's low Dunga.
It 's nothing like that.
I'm finishing everything tonight.
I can't go on. I'm tired of it.
This married man
business is a fucking pain.
And where is the capoeira
session going to be?
Should be a hot fight,
shouldn't it?
Over in Campinho de Euclides.
- Now?
- No, no, no.
Early evening. I'm going to tell
him a few home truths tonight!
I'm going to tell him everything.
I'm finishing because...
I'm fed up with it. I
can't take any more!
You've decided then?
Sure. So you'll do this favour
for me? Talk to Father Adão?
Girl, you're a real friend... thanks!
May the gods send you...
a real hunk of a man!
I just hope they're listening!
- See you!
- See you.
Dunga my boy, make use of the
leftover beans for tonight 's soup.
There's no good delivering the goods
after I've got the whole thing ready!
The soup is nearly ready...
Bianor... I've got
to pop out later...
but I'll be quick, all right?
I'm pulling out of this bar.
I can't stand any more of this shit.
Nor any of these shitty little
customers. Look at that one.
The things we have to put up with...
It 's incredible. Its like we
have to pay to watch this.
Júlia pour me a fire-water.
Your hair brings ideas!
Millions of ideas!
Shut your mouth! Who do you think
I am? Fucking queer! Fuck off!
Ideas! Trinkets! Millions of ideas!
Turn him out.
Throw him into the street. Into the
street! Get out of here! Get out!
You're going to have
pay for what you had!
Get it! For fuck's sake!
I can't take this shit any longer!
I can't take any more of this shit!
The human being is
just stomach and sex.
And inside there is condemnation...
to be obligatorily free.
But he kills and he kills
himself from the fearof living.
And so because of this,
my eyes are blinded...
so that I cannot see even
the spit of these sinners.
My ears hear a voice that is saying:
'Father.
There is no pain in dying.
Father, dying doesn't hurt.'
And we are all condemned.
Eternally condemned.
Condemned to be free.
We're going to have
lunch now, all right?
We're going to have lunch, all right.
Because you're
the only faithful ones...
you are faithful, you...
Branquinha, come here,
let 's have lunch.
Look, look here, take it...
Pitomba, Faisquinha...
You are the only faithful
ones, only you are faith.
Come here, here...
Look-the German is drunk!
Get fucked!
- Well, did you deliver it?
- Yes!
- What 's the number of the house?
- 13, Rua da Bola.
Fucking hell!
Well done boy!
Look, have this. Later I'll
give you something else.
You're almost at the right
age to get your cheese.
Fuck off, you stupid queer!
My dear friend, I don't desire to
cause any trouble for any body.
But when a man is unfaithful,
he needs to be unmasked.
Tonight no...
early evening...
early...
early tonight go to
Campo do Euclides.
That's all lwant to say.
Open youreyes.
An unfaithful husband
has to be unmasked.
Early tonight. That's all.
An acquaintance.
No, a friend...
A friend.
I'm at the door and I nock, and if
someone listens to my voice...
and opens the
door of his heart...
I will enter his house, and I will
leave with him and he with me.
And this afternoon, Jesus Christ
wants to change your life!
Mr. Bianor, Mr. Bianor...
Mr. Bianor... Mr. Bianor...
Bianor! Bianor! Mr. Bianor!
Someone! Someone!
Someone!
Mr. Bianor is dead!
Someone answer me!
Someone help! Help!
- Help!
- Hail Mary, what 's that noise?
My God! My God! What now?!
Calm down Dunga...
drink this sugar water.
I never know what to do at times
like these, I never know...
Mr. Bianor, what a
time to go and die...
Dunga, this is a complicated situation.
There's got to be
a death certificate...
a doctor, a coffin, and then
after... the cemetery.
Don't get me more upset
than I already am!
Oh God! Bianor!
Even when you die
you give me work.
Out... Aurora, you don't know
what happened...
Speak Dunga! What is it?
Mr. Bianor... is dead...
Eh? But he was
alive a while ago?
Of course he was! But he wasn't dead.
The dead don't die do they?
Well, that 's all we needed.
Poor old Bianor...
But I cant ' help in
anything my flower...
And the funeral?
Everything is so confused.
I just don't know what to do.
My head... Please,
give me some light.
The priest, have you told
the priest, Dunga?
And what good can he do?
The man is crazy.
He doesn't even know how to
pray! Oh my God! Oh my God!
I'm no good with dead bodies!
The coffin. Before anything else,
the body needs a coffin.
And with what money am I going
to buy a coffin? Huh? Huh?
Bianor had some money, but God only
knows where he keep it hidden.
Dunga, Little Dunga, you'd better talk
to one of the other guests.
I don't know what to do...
Once a cousin of mine died.
I had to sort out a million things.
I had to get the death certificate.
And the woman who was typing...
it kept saying all the time... I'm
scared to death of making a mistake...
I'm scared to death
of making a mistake.
I'm scared to death, Dunga...
Mr. Isaac! Mr. Isaac!
Please!
What the fuck is it, Dunga?
- It 's Mr. Bianor... he's dead.
- What 's that got to do with me?
We don't know what to
do about the coffin.
Mr. Bianor had some money but
no one knows where he put it.
- I don't know what to do.
- How am I supposed to know?
See if the old man didn't
wrap it round his dick.
Take advantage and wrap your hand
round the old boy's cock and...
see if you can't get some
rabbits out of the woods.
Or find a local councilor.
Isn't there one that gives
coffins out to the poor?
You're a real fucking pain in the arse.
Not even the dead do you help!
Fucking bastard!
Ouch!
My wallet... fucking hell!
But I'll go there...
I want my I.D. Card...
I want that woman...
that fucking fag Dunga
ruined my dream...
fuck...
This is what it's like to
live sorting rubbish...
when there's no education, brother.
What about creating some shame.
Whoever heard of being a
transporterof diseases?
This is what it's like to
live sorting rubbish...
when there's no education,
brother, brother...
what about creating some shame...
whoever heard of being a
transporterof diseases?
Transporterof diseases!
That 's it, really great! Great,
it was really great!
Well, I've got to catch that train.
It 's all OK for Monday?
All right! Hey!
Guys, only good
kids here! Get out of here!
Who's there?
There's no comfort here.
These people should look for
comfort where there is comfort.
Who's there? What do you want?
I know that life is hard, but we
cannot bow our heads before evil...
my guardian, I have only come
to tell you that death
has taken Bianor, and that even
there they need your favours.
Tell me where and I'll go. Bianor...
alive just a short time ago...
I go cold when I think about death.
Play this card, you idiot!
Now you've fucked yourself!
What a mess all this is.
For fuck's sake! You always turn up
at the wrong time! And...
- What?
- Sort out the problem?
I found the money. It was round
the old man's balls... dirty devil.
Didn't I tell you... it never fails.
When it 's no good for anything else
it turns into a safe.
Oh! Everybody, it 's all sorted out.
The coffin is arriving soon, all right?
Daisy? Feeling calmer now?
It 's not a question of feeling
calmer. Get it Wellington?
I can see you're still out of control.
- Out of control?
- It looks that way.
Me? Ha! Not at all my dear.
Just think about a controlled woman.
Thought about one? Well, it 's me.
Wellington, I want a future.
It 's finished, all right?
You're telling me it 's over between us?
- Over, Wellington.
- Everything?
Everything, Wellington. It can't go
on. I can't take any more.
I can't go on with being
'the other woman'.
It 's a pity, because...
you're one fucking hell of a man...
- Please Wellington!
- Don't say that...
Wait, take your hands off me?
Take them off...
This is not the end.
It 's not the last time.
- Just look out, Wellington.
- Go on, let 's have one for the road.
- Traitor, traitor, traitor!
- My love... What the fuck is this?
Cheap imitation - you bitch!
This time it was old Bianor...
sometimes it seems like
everyone is dying except me...
Don't they say that it 's always
the rotten that go last?
But I am so afraid of being alone.
Imagine.
My house always used
to be a party. So many people.
Now it 's only this lack
of air that 's left.
And there's no way I am going
down there. No way!
Not even the ghosts are left any more.
This is good...
it dilates the thoughts...
Yellow is the colourof the tables,
the benches, the stools,
the fish knife handles,
the hoe and the sickle
the bull cart, of the yokes,
of the old hats.
Of the dried meat!
Yellow of the diseases,
of the children's runny eyes,
the purulent wounds, of spit,
of the worms, of hepatitis,
of diarrhoea of the rotten teeth...
Interior time yellow.
Old, washed out, sick.
And that is Renato Carneiro
Campos, my boy.
And so Isaac? You liked the home?
- What 's up, Rabecão?
- Look, who's turned up again?
Now you're going to see
the man who fell in love.
There are many facets to the
human creature...
beating, loving, beating, loving.
I want my I. D...
This is all I needed. Nobody's
got your I.D., all right?
Now just get going, I'm fed up
with bloody wankers like you.
Hang on! My friend
here is not a wanker.
Oh! He's your friend is he?
The body snatcher.
Well, this son of a bitch turned up
here provoking me.
And he got the worst of it,
'cos I'm a woman!
But even big butch buggers
like him are afraid of me.
Well, I want my identity
and you. All of you.
And all your ideas.
Look here, wanker! You've caused
enough trouble here today!
You want more? You want some more
shit beaten out of you, is that it?
I want my fucking I.D.! And now!
Because my patience is all
fucked out. So, let 's get going.
My friend, let 's solve this problem,
with a little intelligence, all right?
Intelligence, huh? When a man
has run out of words,
he always turns to diplomacy.
In nomine Patris, et Filii,
et Spiritus Sancti, amen.
Ave Maria, gratia plena,
Dominus tecum:
Benedicta tu in mulieribus et
benedictus fructus ventris tui Jesu.
Amen.
May the light of God shine upon us,
illuminating our souls
with love, the love of Jesus.
The love, the love of Jesus.
We will be your grateful servants.
The supreme peace of the redeemer,
fill the non-believers,
that go against the Lord with faith.
Our faith is in thee, O Virgin,
and we will be blessed.
We ask forGod, our King.
We ask forGod, our Father.
Amen.
Well, Bianor is gone. Poor thing.
What a good thing he didn't suffer.
Mr. Bianor died as he was born.
Totally anonymous.
Yes. I just think about
one thing, Father.
What on earth
is going to happen to this dump?
Who's going to look after it?
You? Where are you going to eat?
And me? Where am I going to work?
That is not a problem, my son,
because everything in life...
has it 's own time. Look, God made
life with all its mysteries
for us to decipher.
If you look carefully,
Bianor's death is a sign.
A sign of the changes
that we all need.
If not, it means nothing at all,
which is more probable.
Oh for God's sake!
You're going mad.
I don't understand a word
you're talking about.
Dunga, where does your family live?
Why are you so curious?
No, it 's just that the family is
the greatest mystery my son.
And yours? Where is yours?
I lost all contact with them.
I became a priest, didn't I?
- I took the vows...
- Don't come on with this 'mass'.
I know very well the church
where you pray!
I'm fed up with all these crazy
people. It seems like I'm
...the only sane one around here!
- And you are! Yes, you are!
Father, do you think we're capable
of doing everything for love?
Yes. Nothing can go wrong when
we love. Love is above everything.
Even killing?
I avoid thinking about killing...
but, it 's not all together a bad idea.
You just don't exist, father.
My goodness,
what a comic priest you are!
What is it?
Get in...
this stain on your clothes?
Is it blood?
I ripped off the ear of my
husband's lover.
I was a dead woman inside.
I'm sorry Bianor, but I just
can't go downstairs.
There are times when I think that
I'm the only one in the world,
and that I shall never die.
But I'm not going to sit looking
at a dead body.
Even if it 's Bianor.
But Bianor was good, and I'm not.
These days I'm a little better.
But I used to be bad.
But, I'm not that good...
I'm not.
Sometimes I think...
that this world is full
of living ghosts.
I'm coming. I'm coming.
Wellington? My God!
What the fuck has happened to you?
It 's Kika, Dunga...
Kika caught me with Daisy.
She made a right scene, Dunga.
Come in, come here.
Sit down, sit down here.
Come on, tell me about it.
Kika ate Daisy's ear, Dunga.
She used me to get me
away from her.
And... and it was Daisy's ear.
Where is Daisy?
I left her at the hospital.
Fucking cow!
Kika, Dunga... Kika disappeared.
I'm fucked off with Daisy.
Really fucked off, Dunga.
She made me leave the little thing.
And Kika, she's not home.
Oh... oh... no, no, no,
I want Kika.
No, don't cry.
Don't cry.
Come on, come to my room, come.
I'll get you some sugared water,
to relax. Come on.
Wellington, come on!
Oh no! My God...
no, look. It 's there.
What 's this Dunga?
Bianor. He went and died on us.
But don't worry about that.
Come on, the bedroom is over here.
Get fucked! I am not sleeping
with a fucking dead body!
The dead don't bite or kill!
Come on, man!
- For fuck's sake, Dunga!
- Come with me!
Just be fucking careful, all right?
For fuck's sake! Don't be so
fucking soft? You silly shit!
You see, Bianor? You see?
What a day to go and die on?
Shit!
Inside, I used to be a dead woman...
There are times when lwonder
about the way things happen.
First, comes the day.
Then, everything happens on that day.
Then comes the night-the best part!
But then right after that,
comes the day again!
And on and on and on...
never-ending!
Hello, love. What 're we going
to do with your hair?
Cut it and then dye it.
- Like this, just taking off the tips...
- No! Pull it all out and dye it.
And what colour are
we going to dye it?
Something yellowish.
- Something rusty, like clay. Is that it?
- No! No! Something like mango.
A mango yellow.
SubRip by Szabby
(szabby@freemail.hu)