We will hear
from the President
of the United States.
He will address the country
in mere moments now,
speaking from the east room.
It is going to be a confirmation
of a huge development.
Good evening.
Tonight, I can report
to the American people
and to the world...
the United States has conducted
an operation that killed
Osama bin Laden,
the leader of AL-Qaeda.
Tonight we give thanks
to the countless intelligence
and counterterrorism
professionals
who worked tirelessly
to achieve this outcome.
The American people
do not see their work,
nor know their names,
but tonight they feel
the satisfaction of their work.
I think women
make fantastic analysts.
We have
patience and perseverance.
And we're not always looking
for the sexy payoff immediately.
You know, trying to keep track
of all the threads
of various threats,
and which ones are real
and which ones aren't real
and what connects to what.
And, you know, people say,
"Why didn't you
connect the dots?"
"Well, because
the whole page is black?"
To pull a story
out of all of
this information,
but there is no one
single intelligence looking
at all this information.
It's a lot of different
brains looking.
So the more that you
can bring people together
and, you know,
share what's important,
the better it works.
At that time, the people
who had
really deep expertise
in AL-Qaeda...
you know, they were women.
And they did a job that
at first did not make them
very popular
with their managers.
I was counseled once
in a performance review
that I was spending too much
time working on bin Laden.
They said we
were obsessed crusaders,
overly emotional.
You know, using all
those women's stereotypes.
Men throw chairs.
Women cry.
I ask you,
Which one is better?
Yes, we were
borderline obsessed,
but I thought it was
for a good reason.
And were we crusading?
I wouldn't call it
a crusade.
Were we passionate about
what they were doing?
Absolutely.
And that's
another bureaucratic
norm of the time.
You weren't supposed to be
passionate about anything,
which I think
is ridiculous.
How can you do something
like this without passion?
You can't.
"Take a stand.
We drove out the Russians.
"We destroyed
the Russian empire.
"Now we'll drive out
the Americans
"and we'll destroy
the U.S. empire.
It worked then,
it'll work here."
He felt
like the United States
was driving a world movement
against Muslims
and was the driver
for everything
that was happening
that was bad.
Your starting
point is Afghanistan.
Abdullah Azzam is the godfather
of the Afghan jihad.
He is the one who called
everyone to go and fight
in Afghanistan
against the Soviets.
He helped set up a council
of charities to bring
people and money to help
with jihad.
And his partner
was Osama bin Laden.
A link chart
is the visual representation
of a terrorist network.
And it's what terrorism
analysts spend
much of their time
building.
My mental image is
that, you know, I'm doing
Jacob's ladder.
You've got the string
where you're pulling
the strings
in your fingers.
I feel like that's
what I'm doing mentally.
Well, we
certainly didn't know
that AL-Qaeda existed.
We didn't know there was
a terrorist organization.
We knew there was
a very wealthy man
named Osama bin Laden,
who was funding a lot
of terrorist groups.
We knew that there were
people from terrorist groups
from all over the world,
hanging out in Afghanistan
and in bin Laden's
circle.
So you start to see
signs of what looks like
an organization.
But is this bin Laden
as a financial manager
with a bunch of
companies funding
various terrorist groups
or is there a separate
terrorist group here?
And that was
a big question.
Even in the analytical
community, there's
a relatively smaller
percentage of people
who are really good
at making sense
of information that doesn't
appear to be connected.
So this is what we call
pattern analysis...
trying to figure out
what things look like.
And those people, you really
need those people to work
on an issue like terrorism,
counter-narcotic,
international arms
trafficking
because you've got
bits and pieces
of scattered information
from all over the place
and you have to try to
make some sense of it.
And these are
organizations...
certainly AL-Qaeda
was one...
didn't even want to announce
their presence to the world
for a long time.
You have to try to
figure out they're there
when they're trying to
deny, even to their friends,
that they exist.
That takes this talent,
which is also a skill,
and people would refer
to it as magic.
Not the analysts
doing it,
but other people who
didn't have that talent
referred to it as magic.
What I have here
are four half-dollars.
When you're following
an intelligence event,
sometimes things move
and change in ways
that you can't see.
You might think
it's in one place,
and it pops up in another,
and you can't see
how that happens.
So these coins
are gonna jump one at a time
from here all the way
over to here.
But they're going
to do it invisibly.
1, 2, 3, 4. Watch.
See it jump? Heh. Heh.
Reality is changing
all the time.
A single fact may come in
which dramatically changes
your understanding
and your projection
of where something's going.
Two and two.
Are you with me?
Now, an analyst
in the intelligence
profession
is dealing
with highly ambiguous situations
in which information is
arriving incrementally,
in fragments.
Are you with me?
You never get the whole picture.
The picture changes
as these pieces arrive.
Your perception
of reality changes.
You have to be very clear
about what you concretely
know and what you
don't know.
Alec Station was
a collection of people
who had backgrounds
in everything
from analysis to operations.
When you think
about the CIA,
there's a few
different cultures there.
One is an analytic culture...
people who try
to assess things,
figure out what is actually
happening somewhere
and project ahead...
and an operational culture,
that is, people who go out
and collect intelligence,
develop human spies,
handle them,
run them, if you will.
The unique thing
about Alec Station was
the fusion
of analysis and operations.
We pushed the analysts
and the operations people
together, so the operations
people knew everything
the analysts were thinking
and the analysts knew
everything
the operations people
were doing.
Covertly, clandestinely,
secretly, dangerously.
And the fusion
of those two things gave
that organization
the magic it had.
The people I worked
with in the beginning were
six women.
I walked
in my first day there.
I turned around
to my colleagues...
this is a bay
of six analysts...
and I said, "Does
anybody have any Tums?"
And all these drawers
open
with these gigantic
bottles!
I thought,
"Oh, my God.
What have I done
to myself?" Ha ha!
When I moved over, there was
a group of women
that I reached out to.
We were trying to protect
the United States.
Whether we could do that,
it's a big...it's a big
burden.
I was drawn to those women
because of the job
that they were doing.
I mean, substantively they
were so immersed in finding
bin Laden and tracking,
and some of them had been
around working
this subject matter
for so long
that they were
the people I went to.
It wasn't even
because they were women.
Gina Bennett was a mentor
of mine and still is.
She worked on AL-Qaeda
for 20 years.
Gina and Barbara, they put
a stake in the ground
and said, "It's OK if we're
not operations officers.
We can be
just as effective."
The rest of the organization
didn't necessarily think
much of terrorism analysts.
They said, "Well, the terrorism
people are just tracking
"things. That's not...
real analysis.
That's just tracking
things."
So we poor, lowly
terrorism analysts,
we were tracking things.
You're gonna have certain
kinds of people who are
going to be the first
ones to see something.
When you're
the first one
off the block,
by definition
you're going to be
in the minority.
That's what we were.
She was
very dedicated to her job.
She was there a lot.
You know, Jennifer
was one of that first group,
and she was always very
intense, very focused,
really passionate about
it from the beginning
and a real hard-charger
from the beginning.
Jennifer was focused
on finding bin Laden.
She was adamant that she was
gonna stay around
on that team
until it was done.
She could be
really abrasive.
Yeah, but, you know,
teams are made up
of people with all different
kinds of personalities.
And at the end of the day,
that doesn't really matter.
What matters is getting
the job done.
And she certainly
could do that.
We had a camaraderie.
And in the beginning, we
were such a small organization
that we really had
a very close relationship.
On the operations side,
this is where
all the spies work.
Which are the ones
you always see in the movies
running around
recruiting assets
and playing James Bond
or whatever.
It is dangerous.
These guys need confidence
to be able to pull that off.
There is
a fair amount of bravado.
You know, we're
case officers, right?
We're the jet fighters,
we're the gangsters,
we're the doers.
You know, analysts?
Come on, man.
I think a component
of the personality
in some cases for the job.
There's varying degrees
of that.
I was out
in the bush, in that arena,
downrange,
regardless of environment.
Often times,
you see in the movies...
you talk about agents.
You know, he's a CIA agent.
Well, the agents are
the people we recruit.
"Hi. I'm CIA. I'm
assigned to this embassy.
Would you like to be a spy?"
That's why it
doesn't work that way.
A case officer's job is to spot,
assess, and develop...
find people who have
access to secrets,
get to know them,
get them to trust you,
recruit them,
and then keep them safe.
In my particular experience,
because I do speak Arabic...
I have been asked to meet
some of our friends
in risky areas,
dangerous areas.
Obviously, you need
to get to the point
of building trust.
They look in your face,
and they see an American
who has risked a lot
to get there
to sit down and meet
with them.
They do believe, honestly,
that you care
for their welfare,
you care for them,
and you respect what
they're providing you with.
You're playing
this chess game.
He was recruiting
basically very idealistic
Saudi university students
to come to fight
the Soviets.
Then some of them
went to Afghanistan,
including
bin Laden himself.
It's intensely religious.
I mean, coming here was
an intensely religious
experience
for these very idealistic
young Muslim men.
And, you know, these
magazines have many stories
about people being martyred
fighting the Soviets
and their bodies
don't decompose
or their bodies
smell of perfume.
And this was a highly
effective propaganda to get
other people
to come and volunteer.
This
magazine called "Jihad"
was on sale in countries
around the Islamic world.
The very first copy
was published in 1984.
There's a guy called
Abu Abdullah
in these magazines,
and that was bin Laden.
No one really knew who
bin Laden was at the time.
So during
the Afghan-Soviet war,
the camps were set up
by bin Laden and others
to train Afghans
and people from...
who came
from all over the world
to go and fight
against the Soviets.
Towards the end of the war,
some of these camps
got converted over
into urban guerilla
warfare camps.
And this is as,
what we now know
was AL-Qaeda, were taking
over some of these camps,
and they were starting
to train people
to conduct
urban guerilla warfare
in various countries,
like Egypt and Algeria.
One of the prominent figures
in the training camps
in Afghanistan is
a gentleman who went
by the war name
of Abu Zubaydah.
He was definitely running
parts of the camps network.
So now it's after the war
in the early nineties.
We started to get
all these reports
about things blowing up
all over the world,
who were from people who
had fought in Afghanistan.
So that's when we started
to say to ourselves,
What is going on here?
Let's try to figure out,
Is there some kind of
an organization?
Is it a social movement?
What is it?
And we're starting
to warn,
"Look this is going
to be a problem."
And we actually issued
some of that warning
before the first
World Trade Center bombing.
Ramzi Yousef, I'm sure,
everybody knows
from the first
World Trade Center attack.
He is the cousin/nephew
of Khalid Sheikh Mohammed
and the attack
was partly funded
by Khalid Sheikh Mohammed.
The same year there is
the incident referred to
as the Black Hawk Down
incident.
We didn't learn until later
the extent to which
AL-Qaeda at least
was involved.
These plots
are multiple nationalities.
This is not your
typical events, right?
We can't pin this on
any one terrorist group.
What's going on here?
Oh, I mean, it was
bin Laden.
There was no doubt that
the common purpose had to be
bin Laden.
All of a sudden,
it just hit me
that this is
a bureaucracy.
So by 1998, we were
able to say with confidence
this is a worldwide
terrorist organization.
Bin Laden is the head
of this organization.
Their goal is global jihad.
They want to create
a global Islamic government.
It's not
just about Saudi Arabia.
There was still some
debate what it was called
because some said it
was called the Islamic Army.
It was
my analytical judgment
that it was called
AL-Qaeda.
At that time
in '97, Osama bin Laden
had declared war
on the United States
in an Arab language
newspaper,
and no one paid
any attention.
You know, the case that I
made to them was, you know,
if you're going to declare
war on the United States,
don't do it on the BBC.
Do it
on an American network.
And CNN is seen
all around the world.
And also we have
a reputation for being fair.
It was a lengthy process.
They were very concerned.
"Are you agents of the CIA?"
"Will you give
Osama bin Laden a fair shake
if we allow you to do
this interview?"
Eventually after a month
or so, we got the sort of
coded message that we're
gonna go and see bin Laden.
They picked
us up at dusk
in a van sort
of like this, right?
Yeah, very similar
to this. Yeah.
But in the evening. Yeah.
Yeah, in
the evening. Yeah.
And then they gave
us the sunglasses
that had cardboard
inside them.
Right. And sort of
crude blindfolds.
That's right.
Did they put those on...
immediately on us?
Yep, they did.
Right.
The interesting thing is
that when you go
to Kabul,
you go through
these tunnels.
So the fact that we
were blindfolded,
you could hear...
feel the change
in air pressure
and actually hear
the difference in sound
in the tunnel.
So you had something
of a good idea
of where we were
heading?
Yeah, yep.
And on the other
side of this,
this is where
AL-Qaeda had its
chemical weapons,
crude chemical
weapons facility.
Straight down.
Yeah.
So we got to...sort of
this plateau, right?
I think it was about
6,000 feet up maybe
or something like that.
Something
like that, yeah.
And there was
a small village,
the type that would be
used by shepherds
to put their sheep
in at night.
Yeah.
Peter Arnett was a correspondent.
He was at the time
arguably the most famous
journalist in the world.
They put carpets down,
so they made it
respectable.
And then, as I recall,
we waited
for some period of time
and had some sort of
goat-like dinner.
That's right, yeah...
This is, like,
the hostage video.
Yeah, the hostage video.
Do you recall when he came in?
Yep.
And he shook
your hand, right?
Yep. Yep.
Do you remember
what that felt like?
It was sort of
like a dead fish.
I mean, it wasn't
a strong grasp.
Cold, a bit like...
I compare it sometimes
to a bank manager's
shake, you know?
Thank you,
Mr. bin Laden.
Is there
anything you'd like to add?
Hmm?
Anything you'd like
to add?
We should
change the tape.
I think
we'll just relax a minute,
- I think.
- OK, fine.
Just relax now.
Just get my knees.
I'm not used to this.
Not quite
finished. The feed...
Well, Mr. bin Laden's
voice is in good...
Good condition.
It got better as you got...
Hot.
more into the subject,
as you talked about it.
I did think that this was
an amazing interview. Yeah.
He declared
war on the United States
for the first time to
an English-speaking
audience.
We asked him why.
You know, he basically
gave a laundry list
of complaints about
American foreign policy
in the Muslim world.
We asked him to clarify,
Did that mean a war
against American soldiers
or American civilians?
He sort of said American soldiers
were the primary target.
If American civilians
got in the way,
that was their problem.
He said that in his mind,
the United States
was as weak
as the former Soviet Union.
And eventually
the United States,
if it was subjected
to enough violent pressure,
would pull out
of the Middle East,
and basically
he would get his wish.
What
are your future plans?
Can we get a couple
of still pictures now?
Some photographs?
The impact
of the interview at the time
was, I would say,
pretty muted.
You know, it didn't get
a lot of play,
because at the time,
of course,
he hadn't really done
anything.
Imagine if in 1937
the Japanese army had gone
on NBC or RKO to say,
"Hey, we are planning
to attack
the United States."
You know, Pearl Harbor
might have turned out
differently.
These guys repeatedly
said publicly,
"We are planning
to attack
the United States,"
and no one paid
any attention.
I always watched
their latest statements.
Their choices
of what they're gonna say
are very important.
Oh, yeah they were cagey at
first about claiming credit
for anything.
They didn't
want to claim credit.
Then later on, they become
more willing to take credit,
in fact demanding credit
for it.
You know, it's all
this stuff hitting you,
all these horrible
images hitting you.
It's just this rapid fire,
horribly evil music video/
horror film, slash...
Al-Qaeda is
a global organization
made up of people
from over 60 countries
who speak 60 different
languages.
So they really have to
communicate in the clear
through
these statements.
And they're also under
a religious obligation
to warn their enemy.
So for all of those reasons,
it made complete sense
that they meant
what they said.
They're planning
something.
But where? When? What?
Is it going to be
an armed assault?
Is it going
to be a hijacking?
Is it going to be
an assassination?
A bomb? You know, where?
There were no real answers.
The CIA
did very good warning
in that period of time.
There are dozens
and dozens of reports
in which we express the view
that bin Laden is intending
to attack the United States.
We would have weekly
or biweekly meetings
sometimes on exactly
what was going on.
It's so frustrating
when you can't figure
out date and time.
There's always
a large band of uncertainty,
and that's fertile ground
for argument.
And if you warn
about every little thing,
then you're crying wolf
and nobody pays
attention to you at all.
Middle East,
South Asia, Europe,
United States. Where?
You just don't know.
We did not
at this time
and in this report have
what I would call
"actionable intelligence."
"I want to know when,
I want to know where,
I want to know who."
We could not
determine time,
target, and method.
You know, I really
wish I could tell you
when and where.
But it's not that easy with
a clandestine organization.
"Well, if you just had
more human assets and you
"did less analysis,
then we would know
all these things."
Well, that isn't true.
You can say we're pretty
sure it's gonna happen,
but we can't make
that decision to say,
you should do or not do.
We can say that
our bottom line is,
"It looks pretty dangerous."
The headline says,
"Bin Laden Determined
to Strike In U.S."
There were just warning
after warning after warning
all spring.
Well, you know with
the benefit of hindsight...
We knew something
huge was gonna happen.
it would seem that this was
a perfect warning
in August of 2001
that the United States
was about to be attacked.
Everybody was
completely tense.
Why didn't we
do something about this?
The language being used
by these guys was like,
"Oh, my God.
What are they gonna do?"
On the morning of 9/11,
I was sitting
in my office.
My office was here.
The office of the group
chief was right next to it.
And I had my door open,
and I looked,
and there was an analyst
running through the row
between the cubicles.
And it was one
of the older analysts.
And you don't see
older analysts running.
I was in Jordan.
I was at the CIA.
9/11, I was in my office at NSA.
I was at the Executive Office
Building of the White House.
I was in the Pentagon
when it got hit.
The first breaking news
was coming in.
Somebody has it
on RealPlayer
on their...at their desk.
The report was saying
there was a small aircraft
that apparently had hit.
Right then, second
plane into the second tower,
and I knew.
There was no doubt in
that office at that moment
that this is what we were
waiting for.
This is it.
That's the words that went
through everybody's mind.
This is it.
This is bin Laden.
"It's an attack,
it's terrorism,
and it's AL-Qaeda."
I knew who they were.
I knew what
their intentions were.
This is it.
They pulled this thing off.
We're going
to battle stations.
And we were all evacuated
after that second plane
went in because we thought
the next one...that is,
the Shanksville plane...
might be headed for us.
It was complete chaos.
The plane flew in
under my office.
My two assistants looked out
the window and saw a 757
fly in under their feet.
The order then went out
for the building
to be evacuated, except
for the counterterrorism
analysts.
We essentially decamped
from the high-rises
and moved on into
the operations center.
I said, "Look, chief says
we can't go, but, you know,
if you want to leave,
I'll cover for you."
And not one
of those people left.
19 guys.
Look at their faces
and think
about the tragic,
terrible, consequences.
19. Only 19.
19 representing thousands
who went through training
camps in Afghanistan.
19 representing all those
who were sponsored
and trained and blessed
these young men on that day.
This is where
it gets hard to talk.
I have to say the worst
moment in my life
happened
in about November
because right
after the bombing,
you're just so busy.
And everybody, you know...
cry at home; come to work;
be professional;
do your job;
go home; cry at home;
come to work;
be professional;
and do your job.
And people were very
focused, running around,
getting the job done.
On about November,
things started
to slow down
a little bit,
and the guilt sets in.
And that is
just the worst.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna cry now.
Um...
feeling like you wish you
could have done something,
but especially
when all the criticism
starts to come in.
People would say things
in Congress like,
"You were negligent."
I was like, "Really?
"What did you know about
bin Laden before 2001?
"Nothing! You didn't
help us at all.
And now you're blaming
us for having tried..."
This is not a matter of scapegoating.
This is a matter
of accountability.
There has been...
What does the term
"accountability"
mean to you?
Prior to September 11th,
U.S. intelligence officials
possessed
terrorist information
that, if properly handled,
could have disrupted
or possibly prevented
the terrorist attacks.
It seems
from your testimony...
That information was
not distributed to the FBI.
...The CIA analysts
and FBI officials in
the New York field office...
Has anyone in the CIA
been held accountable
for the failures
of September 11th
or the events
leading up to it?
Jennifer called me
not long after 9/11,
screaming at me
on the phone.
And we were just in...
we were,
a two-second walk
from each other
in different vaults.
But, "You did this.
This is your fault.
You didn't report
on..." so-and-so.
Blah-blah-blah-blah-
blah-blah-blah...
And I screamed
back at her
and slammed
the phone down.
And at the time,
I was really angry,
and I actually really
never spoke to her again.
But looking back on it,
I think it's just...
it was just
a manifestation
of her passion
and her sense of...
her own sense of guilt.
I mean,
everybody felt it.
We were told to evacuate Yemen.
The entire team
already boarded the plane,
and I was asked
that I will stay,
I should stay
and to talk to
an individual named
Nasser AL-Bahri...
Abu Jandal.
We showed him
a photo book
that has a lot
of photos in it.
He identified bin Laden,
he identified
Ayman Zawahiri...
He identified
the usual suspects
that there is no way
he would never know.
But he didn't
identify anyone
from the, you know,
second tier.
No one.
And then he closed
the book.
"I don't have
anything else.
Don't know anyone."
So I ask him, "Please.
Can you look at it again?"
But I just said,
"Please. You know,
come on.
Look at it again."
He was annoyed.
He said, "I just did.
There is nothing..."
"For friendship's sake,
you know?
We're now friends..."
So he did. Same thing.
So I laughed.
I went like...
To Bob, I said,
"See? I told you."
"What's goin' on?
What did you tell me?"
"Well, I told Bob...
my friend...I told him
"here...I said that
you're basically faking.
"You're not
cooperating at all.
And I think
I won the bet."
"What are you talking
about? I'm cooperating."
"Come on. Really?
You're cooperating?
"Do you think
I just flew
"all the way from D.C.
to talk to you
"about this kind of
like small talk
"and I don't know
who you are?
I don't know
what you know?"
"This guy,
for example...
"He was in your
guesthouse in 1999.
"He was sick. You were
taking care of him,
"putting soup
on his lips
"and you claim you have
no idea who this guy is?
I know a lot about
your organization."
"Maybe some of these
people in the book are
in my custody."
"Maybe some of
the people in the book
"are friend of mine's.
"Maybe they are
my sources.
"Every time I ask
you a question,
"most probably
I know the answer for.
"And that's how I gauge
"if you're cooperating
or not.
So do you want to start
from the beginning?"
He said, yes.
So we showed him
the book again.
He identified almost
everyone in the book
that we know...
we'd assembled...
from the East Africa
Embassy bombing,
from the "USS Cole,"
to include eight
of the hijackers.
And he still insisted
that bin Laden
would never do anything
like this.
And I insisted
that he did.
And I said, "No,
bin Laden did it."
And he said,
"Oh, bin Laden did it?
Who told you?"
"You did."
And he was mad.
He was furious,
because he thought
I was putting words
in his mouth.
I said, "No, you
told me that AL-Qaeda
was behind it,
definitely."
And I took a manila
envelope that I had,
and I put the photos
that he identified
the seven hijackers...
or the eight hijackers...
I put them all
in front of him.
I said, "Do you want to
know who the hijackers?
Those are
the hijackers."
"You told me they
were Qaeda members.
You told me that."
He was in total shock.
He put his hand
like this,
and he starts shaking,
and he asked for,
you know, five minutes.
We gave him five
minutes, came back.
I said, "So what do
you think now?"
And he said, "I think
the Sheikh went crazy.
What do you want?"
A small group of
people...many of them women...
were blamed.
They were blamed.
"They failed to connect
the dots!"
"Connect the dots."
If I hear that...
The Washington machine
turned on them
and said, "It's your fault."
"Sit and do a line diagram,
where you failed
to connect the dots..."
The dots were there,
It's us who decided to...
we need to erase the dots.
Hello! They're coming at us!
That was...
those were late nights.
You go home, you're driving,
you roll over what
operations are going on,
what threats you
believe are genuine.
You're thinking about your
friends and colleagues
downrange.
Sometimes you're thinking
about some talking head
who launched a bunch
of empty bullets,
you know, of blame trying
to get their face on the TV
and not understanding
the sincerity
of the people involved.
That would cause me
grief the next day
because I knew I was
gonna have to go in
and tell people,
"Listen, they don't
"understand what you do.
"Don't you know that?
Now, let's get it on."
Something that
people don't fully grasp is
how alone the CIA felt
in this period of time.
Just by virtue of
the evolution of events
in history, we ended up
at this moment in time
with kind of
unique knowledge
about this phenomenon,
AL-Qaeda.
I think the feeling
all of us had was,
This is on our shoulders
to prevent this
from ever happening again.
The day of 9/11,
the President pulled us
together and said, "I want
to see a war plan here."
Well, we had been working
on this for a long time.
We were ready to go.
The challenge
when you look at AL-Qaeda
after 9/11 was
to understand it well enough
first to disrupt it
and then dismantle it.
We're not in the business
of disruption alone,
because if you disrupt
an organization,
the adversary's so committed.
I mean, they believe
that what they do is
inspired by a holy book,
that they'll just go on
and plot another attack.
So the business really
became dismantlement:
How do we destroy it?
And that's
a people business.
How do you find
the operators, financiers,
trainers, et cetera?
And how can you know where
they're gonna be tomorrow
so you can pick them up?
The explosion
of intelligence at CIA
after 9/11 is
hard to imagine.
You have a small group
of people in Alec Station
who are looking
at the problem pre-9/11.
They had limited resources.
After 9/11, that small
core group of people
is dwarfed by the newcomers
into the center post-9/11.
It was a foundational
change in the organization.
They needed managerial horsepower
to support the increase
in people and budget.
I did not know enough
about AL-Qaeda.
Just what little I had
read in the press.
Was not my specialty.
But, you know,
if you've had 25 years
of experience, you come
with a pretty good sense
of what needs to be done,
even if it's a new
target for you.
Pretty quickly, you learn
what you need to learn
about that target.
I became the head of
the Counterterrorism Center
just about the time
when we were dealing
with all these threats.
I mean, it was daily
constant intelligence
coming about a second wave
of attacks.
But I had a reputation
for building strong teams.
The phone rang.
A senior came on the line,
basically said,
"We need you to come back.
"You know the gravity
of the situation.
You need to come back
and do what you do."
I basically came back
to be the senior manager
for the worldwide effort
against AL-Qaeda.
I had a multidimensional
responsibility.
I had to protect my people,
you know?
We changed the rulebook
a bit.
We were empowered more.
We did things
more aggressive.
"My job is
to kill AL-Qaeda."
"Either get
shoulder-to-shoulder,
get with us,
or get out of our way."
We had
been focusing on capturing
Abu Zubaydah.
He knew who
the leadership was.
He knew their methods
of attack, their targets.
He was the highest level
AL-Qaeda terrorist
that we had ever captured.
When we captured
him in March, he was
severely wounded,
and we knew we had to get
him out of Pakistan.
And in the past, the way
the U.S. had dealt
with issues like this was
to transfer the terrorist
to a friendly country
for interrogation,
but we needed to take
responsibility
for high level terrorists
ourselves.
So we understood
what we had to do.
And we did it.
We took a lot of
bad guys off the streets.
And they got put up...
and it's now public knowledge...
in a nice little, uh...
let's just say...
boutique locations.
Basically you
have two things you have
to bring with you
to an interrogation room,
especially with
individuals like AL-Qaeda.
You have to bring knowledge,
and you have to bring
empathy.
And if you don't have
those two,
I think most probably,
you're gonna fail.
He gave us a couple of
pieces...information
during that early phase.
But then he stopped talking.
When he regained
his strength,
he stopped talking.
And we became convinced
that we had to come up
with a new alternative
to doing this
because it was not working.
Eight of the 12 techniques,
in my humble opinion,
were pretty wimpy stuff.
You know, like, slapping.
Give me a break.
OK, it might be unpleasant
to slap somebody,
but it's not torture.
Grabbing someone
from the lapel,
bringing him in to you may
be unpleasant
and it's
an attention grabber,
but it's not torture.
We didn't ask for this.
We did not ask
to get attacked.
They did it.
And so if we can't make them
uncomfortable to save lives,
then...we've missed
the boat here.
I believe that
the intention was,
"We can never allow
this to happen.
Let's do whatever
needs to be done."
They're straight-up haters.
There is no reasoning
with them.
Some individuals who were
at the time in places
to make decisions
believe that the only reason
you deal with
these individuals is by
techniques like this.
If you deal with some
of the hardcore...
our detainees...they
might have become compliant
and then maybe jovial
and engaging,
but if you ask them,
"What are you gonna do
if you ever get out?,"
they'll go, "I'm gonna
come kill you, my friend."
All the information that
came from Abu Zubaydah
we got
before waterboarding.
Most of
these things came
from traditional
interrogation techniques...
by showing people
evidence.
by putting detainees
against each other,
by pocket litter.
So the traditional
interrogation techniques
worked tremendously.
We had the interrogators,
and we had the debriefers.
The interrogators would work
with the detainee.
And once they became
compliant,
they would step back
and the debriefers...
the targeting analysts,
the people who knew the most
about the target
would step in
and would begin
to question them.
Jennifer Matthews was there
sitting in front
of Abu Zubaydah,
asking him questions.
There is
a big difference
between being an expert
behind a desk and being
a field expert.
You can't argue
with success.
And the fact
of the matter is
that we were extremely
successful.
Once we started
using the techniques
on Abu Zubaydah and once
he became compliant,
we started to collect
incredible intelligence.
Abu Zubaydah gave us
the play book of how to go
after these individuals.
So in short order, every
chief of operations was
either captured or killed.
Ramzi bin AL-Shibh,
Nashiri, Hambali.
KSM. Remember that guy?
That was a nice one.
But they had him
in an Arab yuppie outfit.
You know, he was looking
very prim and proper.
I'm like, Forget this.
I want every guy, bad guy,
downrange should know
what their future is.
This is their mack daddy.
This is
their chief gangster.
This is your future.
Khalid Sheikh Mohammed
was waterboarded
183 times.
They tried to quantify
the numbers
of pourings of water,
and eventually the pourings
of water used
in waterboarding
became "times."
So 183 total pourings
of water
on Khalid Sheikh Mohammad
became 183 times,
which is crazy.
Look, it's not
FBI versus CIA.
I know for a fact
that everything
that we've been told,
that resulted,
because of
waterboarding,
that's not true.
Only three terrorists
with American blood
on their hands
were ever waterboarded.
In many cases,
it was just a few days.
In the case of Abu Zubaydah
and Khalid Sheikh Mohammed,
it was just a few weeks.
This program evolved
because, you know,
some of the stuff
that they tried to do
is not working.
And during the evolution
process, I realize
that we shouldn't be
part of this
and...I shouldn't be even
a witness for this.
And I put it
to our headquarters,
and headquarters
pulled us out.
We all knew Americans
would find out at some point
about everything we
were up to.
There were no illusions.
And so you have to try to
provide a lens of history
that doesn't exist yet.
I understand people are
uncomfortable with this,
but the options
we had were not very good.
In the aftermath
of 9/11, people expected
and realized he would
probably go to Tora Bora,
which he did.
After Tora Bora, he more
likely than not went up
to Kunar and then somewhere.
Well, it could
have been in...
I always thought of him
as running around...
maybe
in the Afghan-Pak border,
maybe even if Afghanistan.
That's what my favorite
would have been...
having him in Afghanistan,
because that was
his spiritual home,
so to speak,
from the Afghan jihad.
I was asked,
"Where is bin Laden,"
all the time.
When I went to testify
to the Congress,
the first thing they
wanted to know was,
"Where is bin Laden?"
I went to the Oval Office
a number of times.
I was asked by the president
"Where is bin Laden?"
Everybody
would ask the same question:
"Where is bin Laden?"
It was very frustrating to
basically have to admit
that you didn't know.
One time, one of my
colleagues came in to talk
to me about,
"Where's bin Laden?"
And I told him, "Look, you
know, I am so tired of this.
"The next time that
the next person asks me,
"'Where is bin Laden,'
"I'm gonna say,
'You know what? Fuck you.
Fuck you.'"
And later that day,
I went home.
And the first thing my wife
asked me when I get home is,
"Where is bin Laden?
And why can't you find him?"
The toughest
position to be in AL-Qaeda
then was number three,
number four.
Because why?
You had to communicate.
You had to communicate
to get attacks done.
You had to communicate...
and if you were doing that,
we're on you.
Frankly, even though
in the back of our minds,
we knew we had
to get him some day,
we were actually
too busy going after those
who were actually
plotting against us.
Congratulations,
Abu Butthead.
You're now number three
in AL-Qaeda.
That's the good news.
The bad news is,
you're now number
three in AL-Qaeda.
You'd better buckle
your chinstrap
because your
career path is
probably going
to be short-lived.
There is an aspect
of the intelligence business
called targeting.
I think this is a revolution
for a couple of reasons.
Just in the past ten years,
the agency
has transitioned
from strategic intelligence
to tactical intelligence
that helps you identify
the movements and locations
of one specific individual.
I'm not just worried about
what AL-Qaeda
looks like strategically;
I want an analyst
who's spending
all their time looking
at one target
with one name...
and people
whose whole goal in life
is following
one human being.
I went to the other women
who had become
targeting officers
when I moved over...
Jennifer Matthews
and some of the other women
who had already paved
the way...
just to ask them,
"How do I do this?
I have to build this
from the ground up,"
kind of like they did
on the bin Laden side.
You know,
"How do I do this?"
We still didn't have a great
technical tool to do that.
I built a spreadsheet.
And when I reached out
to Barbara and Gina
and a few other women,
they just said,
"That's how we do it.
Go for it. That's exactly
how you get it done."
You're leaving
a digital trail every day.
So are terrorists...
when that person travels,
when that person
gets on a phone,
when we get information
from a courier in AL-Qaeda
about who he's touching
and we bounce it against
information we might have
found out two years ago.
They're looking at
a human terrorist in a field
and they might send
a cable to a station
that results in action
against that target
the next day.
Somebody who wants
in the fight.
That's what a targeter is.
You have to intimately know
the target
that you're going after,
how you think that person
is gonna act, react,
what they're gonna do
that day,
what their strategy is,
who they're gonna talk to.
What are their
priorities in life?
Is it wife number one,
is it wife number two?
I was in Baghdad shortly
after the war started,
and it was kind of like
being in the Wild West.
It was complete chaos.
Bin Laden was initially
excited about this.
He was excited about Iraq.
This is something he
couldn't, at the time,
pull off.
So he was happy
to support the endeavor.
He was such
a brutal terrorist.
I just felt like we owed
it to the people of Iraq
to remove him.
It seems so strange
that I never met Zarqawi.
My former colleagues
in the Jordanian
Intelligence Service
used to call him
my boyfriend.
I felt like I knew Zarqawi too well.
He was a quiet guy...
in a pathological
sort of way.
I mean, he was a monster.
There were calls at
2:00, 3:00 in the morning
from the group chief
every time a bombing
happened,
every time
he set off a VBID,
every time he targeted
a mosque or anything.
You know, I was
thinking about him 24/7,
and it just wasn't
pleasant after a while.
The model
to me is very clear.
Our special forces,
our JSOC operators,
their analysts,
our analysts,
their operators,
our operators,
were working hand-in-hand.
They were downrange.
They were downrange
in our field stations
assisting in operations,
bringing that expertise
there.
And the lessons
and the ability to take
intelligence operations
combined
with special operations
to create a synergy,
a deadly synergy.
And your job
as a targeting officer
in a war theater
is to help point
boots on the ground
or something up above
toward a target and be
as accurate as possible.
Wait!
For me, war is sort of like
something radioactive
that you shouldn't touch
unless you've done
a tremendous amount
of understanding of just
the damage that it will do.
You can flirt with the idea
that "I can cross the line
"and go into the dark side
and then I can walk back
"because I'm going
in the dark side
for a good purpose."
And there are times when
that may be appropriate,
but it is dangerous.
It's easier next time
to cross.
I did not like being
on the raids.
That wasn't...I was
an analyst.
Wasn't...I just didn't...I...
I think there are
questions
about an intelligence
organization
that slowly gets involved
in executing these types
of global counterterrorism
operations.
That's a real
mind-set change.
The war was not
an agnostic video game.
It was a personal game
where you know
you're responsible
not only for the lives
of Americans,
but for going up
against an adversary
that you got to kill
or capture.
August of 2004,
I think we did 18 raids
that month in Iraq,
our force.
Two years later in 2006,
same month,
Iraq, also,
we did 300 raids.
Our ability to collect
intelligence,
act on intelligence,
and then collect more
intelligence had taken
an almost industrial
size and speed to it.
It was definitely
a well-oiled machine.
There were rolling raids.
Sometimes
those were fruitful,
and sometimes not so much.
I think
sometimes the momentum
sort of overtook
the substance
of what we were going after.
You know, it's like,
"There's another target.
Let's go after it,
just because we can."
The machine just kept going.
We had executed thousands
of these kinds of raids
in Iraq
and Afghanistan,
and we got better
and better at them.
So it was that evolution
in particular with the CIA
in ways that we
just couldn't have imagined
in 2001 or 2002,
but were absolutely
critical, as it turns out,
in order to be able
to meet this threat.
But you
definitely need to know
what your moral center is
and how you define that
for yourself in order
to be able to do that job.
I mean, I worked in a center
where my job was to hunt
a person down
to capture or kill.
I mean, I had to be
OK with that.
And, you know, the paradox
of wanting to save
the women and children
of Iraq
and kill someone
in order to do that
wasn't lost on me
by any means.
But, you know, I...
I can justify that
for myself.
The war on terror.
How can you have
a war on terror
when terrorism is a tactic?
You have a war
against people.
So the question
immediately becomes,
Who are the people
that we're fighting
the war against?
And I think still most
people don't understand
why they hate us.
Some strikes are necessary,
but if our solution
to this kind of problem is
to just strike
without trying to take
effective efforts
to prevent the rise of
threats, it's endless.
Shock and awe does
not end wars on terrorism.
It only creates
more terrorism.
Money starts to flow
to terrorist groups,
people become
more radicalized.
Wars on terror
should be fought
under the radar,
as quietly as possible.
But counterterrorist
operations are,
by their nature,
not very satisfying
to a frightened public.
And we were working closely
with the bin Laden unit,
and the dynamic of
the relationship
between Zarqawi
and core AL-Qaeda
sort of turned a lot
of assessments on
what was happening with
core AL-Qaeda on its head.
Bin Laden didn't know,
I'm sure, what he was
getting into with Zarqawi...
how fundamentally
different he was
from some of his
other AL-Qaeda leaders.
He did not have the same
academic background
that a lot of
the AL-Qaeda scholars had.
He didn't have the same...
for a lack of a better way
to put it...
professional sense
of jihad as AL-Qaeda did.
He didn't understand
the rules of the game.
He just thought
he could enact
any strategy regardless
of how brutal it was.
It was surprising
to hear
that Zarqawi was not
being deferential.
He was being insubordinate.
Hassan Ghul was
an emissary from AL-Qaeda.
He was actually
bringing over another letter
from AL-Qaeda central
to Zarqawi about
how he should be conducting
operations in Iraq.
When we realized
that Hassan Ghul
would be traveling to Iraq,
we decided this was
an opportunity for us.
So we actually planned
an operation...
it was my team with our base
and the Kurdish government...
to capture him.
And we definite...
the Kurdish government
kept him, and we
definitely gained a lot
of information out of him,
including
Al-Kuwaiti's name
and the role that he
played with bin Laden.
Did that answer...
Do you know how his name,
Ahmed AL-Kuwaiti's,
came up?
Within the course
of a debriefing
with the Kurdish
government,
Hassan Ghul gave up
the name of Al-Kuwaiti,
the courier.
Ahmed from Kuwait.
It was
significant information,
even though we knew that
the pseudonym AL-Kuwaiti
was a throwaways.
I mean, who...
It's like saying
"Jose the Puerto Rican,"
you know?
It could be anybody.
The key is what
he told us about bin Laden
not using any other
means of communicating.
We asked
Khalid Sheikh Mohammed
about the information
of the courier...
and he kind of just...
He jumped back.
His body language
jumped back. He changed.
And he said, "No, no, no."
Look, we all know,
even as little kids,
if suddenly you react
and go, "No, no, no,"
it probably means
"Yes, yes, yes."
He had not been truthful.
But later...and this
is the benefits
of having black sites...
we intercepted
a communication from him
to some of the other
detainees.
He told his fellow
detainees not to say a word
about the courier,
thereby telling us
a lot about the courier...
that he's of
tremendous importance
and that we were
on to something.
In late 2007,
the bin Laden cell
came to me.
Some of these people
had been doing this
well before 9/11.
I mean, they go all the way
back to Alec Station.
These people had spent
their lives on this target.
They said, "We're going to
try another approach.
"It's got to be
the courier network.
"We've got some information
on couriers.
We're gonna begin
to build from that."
The way it works
is information comes in.
You catalogue it,
you organize it.
You know, that little
nugget there could sit
fallow on your shelves
for four or five years
until something else comes
in that's suddenly
very illuminating
about something that you
may have had for a very
long period of time.
That actually happened
in the work
we did to hunt
for Osama bin Laden
by trying to track
his courier.
It took years
for the agency
to recruit the human source
that eventually gave us
the true name.
That's why we're
in the business
of clandestine
human intelligence,
because in many cases,
all these fancy gadgets
and everything else
won't give you
the information
that you really need...
a true name.
And we finally
got his true name...
which is whatever it is.
Whatever Arabic name,
you know?
But the true name,
we were able to find out
a lot about him.
From then on, you know,
the agency was able to do
what it does so well...
track the guy and find him.
Very soon after that,
I briefed the President.
I said, "I got to tell you,
Mr. President, my guys,
"they seem a little
optimistic about this.
They actually think
this could lead somewhere."
You're projecting
force and intelligence
and assets
across that border.
And that's
what Khost represented.
Their focus was across
over there in Waziristan,
because that's where
the enemy was.
Jen Matthews
was the chief of base,
of the CIA base down there.
She was there
to have her fingers
right on the pulse
of the information
that was coming
through the base.
She never enunciated
that, so to speak,
in such stark terms,
but my sense was she was
there to target and kill
senior AL-Qaeda leaders.
I asked her, "Do you think
we're going to get him?"
She smiled and said,
"We'll get him eventually,
and I hope
I'm a part of it."
So...
He's not at all what
you'd expect as a radical.
He's a doctor; he's working
in a refugee clinic.
It turns out he had
this very dangerous hobby
on the side, which was
writing this blog
and getting himself
in trouble.
Over a period of months,
he becomes one of
the most visible writers
on the internet, and the CIA
and the Jordanian
intelligence
go all out to recruit
Balawi to be a spy.
Over several weeks,
they convince him
to go to work for them.
Balawi finds
his way into Pakistan
and essentially disappears.
Very likely somebody
suspected him
as being an informant
and maybe cut his head off.
Nobody hears anything from
Balawi for three months.
Suddenly he's back
on the radar screen again,
and he's saying,
"I've gotten inside."
Balawi is a doctor.
He is now beginning to treat
the number two leader
of AL-Qaeda,
Ayman AL-Zawahiri.
When Balawi sends
this information
to the CIA headquarters,
the place goes crazy.
Even the White House
gets briefed.
This young man, Balawi,
is gonna take us
right to number two
and maybe even
to number one.
The meeting
has to take place
in a place where the CIA
can completely control
the environment,
and by default,
this becomes
the CIA base at Khost.
It falls
to Jennifer Matthews
to come with a plan
to get Balawi
inside this base at Khost
without being detected.
Well, the problem is
that nobody in the CIA
has ever met with Balawi.
They make
arrangements for him to come
into the base
without even being searched
or checked because
they're afraid
that somebody might
recognize him,
his identity might
be compromised.
People have been
too quick to blame Jennifer,
and that I reject totally
because there were
many people
looking at this operation.
People wanted
to believe that the source
was good.
There were also pressures
coming from the White House
and elsewhere, saying,
you know,
"Pursue, pursue, pursue.
We need to do this."
I'm sure there were people,
voices out there saying,
"Uh, maybe not."
"Maybe we should slow down."
That happens
in many operations.
Didn't happen in this one.
So they set up
a plan to get him
through the checkpoints
without being even looked at
by the guards.
He gets further
into the base,
goes through
a second checkpoint,
goes to a third checkpoint,
and gets all the way
in to the innermost heart
of the base,
the inner sanctum.
There are a total
of 14 CIA officers lined up
to meet him.
Balawi gets out of
the car on the wrong side,
and he's chanting the words
in Arabic "God is great."
Before anyone
could stop Balawi,
he fumbles
for his detonator.
You will be sent
to the hell.
Balawi hits a switch,
blows himself up, and
there's a terrific explosion
that kills almost everybody
who's within direct sight
of Balawi at the time
of the explosion.
We heard the explosion,
but when we saw
the smoke coming up
from exactly where I knew
Chapman was,
then I knew the base
had been hit.
We knew that someone
had gotten
inside the base,
and we knew that
it was the agency
that had been hit.
And we knew it was bad.
By the time we got
on the scene,
it was an ugly scene.
There were, you know,
parts everywhere.
The conventional unit
that was there landed...
the helicopter right
in the courtyard
and evaced as many of
the wounded as possible.
You know, he said
Jen didn't make it.
Uh...
Her logistics chief
that we had worked with
to close the base on a daily
basis didn't make it.
And some of
her case officers
never made it even
back to...you know,
they died on the scene.
When you do this
and do this and do this,
eventually you lose one.
And we lost...
and we lost
really good people.
When I heard that
Jennifer was in Khost...
I was shocked that she...
was taken out by bin Laden.
I mean, that was just...
that just seemed so surreal
that that would happen
to her.
You know, after she spent so
many years trying to prevent
another tragedy by him,
You know, he, in effect,
had anything
to do with her death,
it's incredibly
disheartening.
There was some
criticism of the agency.
Frankly, I understand that.
But you don't get
Abbottabad without Khost.
An agency that's not willing
to take the risks that were
evident at Khost,
which unfortunately
ended tragically...
that agency, if it's not
willing to do that
is not an agency to do
what it had to do
to build that trail
all the way to Abbottabad.
In fact, some of
the human beings who built
the trail to Abbottabad were
actually killed at Khost.
It was kind of Team America
in the hunt for bin Laden
and the fight
against AL-Qaeda.
And there is powerful
connective tissue
between the two events.
The hunt
for the courier to bin Laden
makes complete sense to me.
It was based on all of these
years of experience working
with a very tight-knit
group of people
who really cared about this
and supported each other.
We invented the technique
that works,
and it's the technique that
got bin Laden in the end.
I got a call from another...
a former colleague,
and he said,
"Turn on the news."
You know, I was at home.
"Turn on the news.
The President's going
to make an announcement."
And I had a feeling
that it's been a good day
at the office...
Good evening.
And then finally it's him.
They got him.
They got him finally.
That was...yeah,
that was really something.
Na na na na
Hey hey hey
Good-bye...
Obama, Obama
We fucking killed Osama
Obama, Obama, we...
I'm not sure
America has made the effort
that it needs to
to understand what it
is we just went through.
The really key part is not
how to do these operations;
the thing to understand is,
why are the people
that we are fighting
doing what they're doing?
Why is the enemy the enemy?
If you don't understand why
they're doing it,
it's very difficult to stop.
We don't speak
the language enough.
We don't understand
the culture enough.
We haven't taken the time to
not be blind, deaf, and dumb
in areas of the world
that matter to us.
It's a nice chapter
to close,
nice chapter to close.
It's not over.
Sadly enough, I think
we're gonna
be in this situation again.
Bin Laden achieved,
you know, spreading
his ideology beyond what he
probably expected it to.
How do you kill an ideology?
Killing one person doesn't
end that.
I don't like it.
I don't want it to continue.
I hope it stops.
I hope we don't live
in a world
where you deal
with an adversary
that loses respect for
the sanctity of human life.
But, look,
this isn't a picture
from a video arcade.
This is a human being who
has a family and a soul.
So when you confront that,
what are you gonna do?
There are philosophical
debates you can have,
but at the end of
the day, the question is:
Are you gonna move
or not? Yes or no?
Go or no go? That's it.