Hold on a sec.
Let me call for backup.
This is car 4604,
requesting a backup. Pier 14.
[Grunts]
- [Gunshot]
- Let him go, Cordell!
Teresa, get these cuffs off.
[Teresa]
The keys.
- [Shotgun Cocks]
- [Officer] Hold it there!
[Sirens Wailing]
[Yelling]
[Children] ♪ Brass button,
blue coat ♪
♪ Cannot catch a nanny goat ♪
[Laughing]
[Engine Starts, Revs]
[Man] And what can I
do for you?
[Shotgun Cocks]
Figure it out.
I got not money.
It all goes down
that slot into a safe.
I don't know
the combination.
[Chuckles] The boss don't
trust me.
[Female Dispatcher] In the 22
Precinct, we got a 10-30 in progress.
Silent alarm at Julio's Bodega
at 725 14th Street.
- This one's for us.
- Shit.
22-Adam responding.
[Siren Blaring]
I need the money.
Look. No money.
Take merchandise.
Anything you want in the store.
¡O, Dios mío!
That's gonna be you all
over the walls in a minute.
So, when does your boss come in
to open up the safe, huh?
Uh, 6...
- 6:30.
- I'll wait.
- Okay.
- But you don't have to hang around.
Why don't you try running
for the door, huh?
No. No, it's... it's okay. I-I stay.
Hey. Hey.
Let's open up
some Lotto tickets, huh?
Sure. Sure. See? Okay.
- Maybe I'll be a winner.
- Okay.
I feel lucky!
Nada. Mira. Nothing.
- Keep going.
- Okay.
- Nothing again.
- We'll go through the whole bunch, huh?
Okay. Nothing.
Nada.
I think you're lying!
No. I'm calling them
the way they're coming up.
Nothing. Nada.
No, I think I'm a winner.
I'm telling you.
N... Holy shit.
¡Ay, Dios mío!
Mira. 5,000 bucks.
5,000 bucks.
You won 5,000 bucks.
Thank God you got here.
[Laughing]
- [Whimpering]
- [Laughing Continues]
Can you believe it?
The fucker just won 5,000 bucks.
I mean, I guess he don't win it.
I guess I win it, eh?
[Laughing]
Like they say, eh?
Goodness is its own reward, eh?
[Whimpers]
No.
[Sirens Blaring]
- What for?
[Footsteps Departing]
Hey! Hold it right there!
Drop it!
Now! Put the gun down!
It wasn't me, man.
- [Shotgun Cocks]
- [Whimpering]
- Put it down, man!
- It was one of you!
Hey, call an ambulance,
will you?
Get a broom.
Look at this.
[Police Radio Chatter]
Hey, Frankie, get on the horn.
Come on.
He blew the clerk away too.
[Female Dispatcher] 419, your
request for backup is confirmed. Over.
[Bells Chiming]
[Horns Honking]
Well, Officer Forrest,
Officer Mallory...
[Grunts]
you've been cleared
of all wrongdoing.
In fact, you're gonna get commendations
for your actions.
So, uh, does that mean
we're back on active duty again?
Not just yet.
Commissioner, um,
what about Cordell?
What about Cordell?
[Teresa] You didn't find the body
in the river because it wasn't there.
Current must have
swept it out to sea.
No. He's still alive.
You're starting with these
ghost stories again?
Cordell died in Sing Sing
more than two years ago.
I want you to see
this police psychologist.
- What?
- Her name is Susan Riley.
She's got an excellent rep
at helping officers re-adjust.
Aw, come on, Commissioner,
we're not crazy.
Of course not.
So you shouldn't have any objections
seeing Officer Riley.
She's a cop too.
I set up a meeting
for tomorrow at 3:00.
Be there.
- We've got a 3:00 appointment...
- [Door Opens]
Um, Officers Mallory and
Forrest. We're a little early, I guess.
That's right. Um, why don't
we go get a cup of coffee.
Are you gonna find us unfit
to go back on the job?
Well, I hope not.
What do you think?
Well, I think we're both
just as sane as you are.
Well, then you both realize that
this Matt Cordell was killed in prison.
Yeah, right, but you see, we
both just saw him on the pier.
So, what? Does that make us nuts?
What you saw was a very large
man with a horribly disfigured face.
- Did he say he was Cordell?
- No. He never spoke.
Well, then it could have been anyone
in a policeman's uniform, right?
A homicidal maniac with a grudge
against the police force maybe.
Hey, look, if this is the official line
that the department's gonna use, great.
No, that's a lie.
Would you excuse us for a second?
Certainly.
Teresa, all I know about
is being a cop.
I don't know about you,
but I need this job.
When you think about it, I mean...
what the hell difference
does it make who he was?
Because you can't kill the dead.
Tere... Let her go.
[Sighs]
Doc, do me a favor, will you?
Don't put that in your report.
Jack, I'm afraid I'm gonna have
to give her a negative evaluation.
Let me at least just talk to her, will you?
She'll come around.
I cannot let anyone out on the street
that's got a gun with emotional problems.
[Man Yells]
- [Groaning]
- [Gunshot]
[Groaning]
McKinney!
You okay?
Never better.
We were covering the front.
That's why I came around back.
[Man Groaning]
Too bad you didn't kill him.
Yeah. Too much fucking paperwork.
[Horns Honking]
- [Knocking]
- [Susan] Come in.
- Hi.
- Lieutenant McKinney?
- Yeah.
Come on in.
Have a seat.
Thought there'd be a couch.
- Just a chair.
- Yeah.
So how you doing?
Not bad.
I haven't been to confession
in over 20 years.
But if the priests looked like you, I
probably would have gone more often.
- You mind if I smoke?
- Actually, I do.
Thank you.
So, do you wanna tell me
about the shooting?
Uh...
Well, what's there to say?
I mean, I shot him before he shot me.
Look, Doctor,
let's make this easy.
I feel great about what I did.
If you wanna psychoanalyze someone,
why don't you psychoanalyze
the lawyers and judges...
who put that kind of scum
back on the streets?
First of all, I'm not a doctor.
I'm a clinical psychologist.
- And I realize you're here under protest.
- Well, that's good.
So you can tell me how long
my ass has to warm this chair...
before I satisfy
the mandatory requirements.
Well, every officer involved in a shooting
has to see one of us for
counseling at least once.
Okay. I've been seen.
You counseled me. Thank you.
Excuse me, Lieutenant.
Did you have a partner?
Sergeant Joseph Minelli?
Yeah. Joe and I were a team.
He made an appointment with
me once about six months ago.
He phoned and requested help.
That's a little unusual, isn't it?
One of you asking for help?
[Sniffs] Well, he was a...
sensitive guy.
I never found that out.
He stood me up, never showed.
It was a Friday. The following night he
committed suicide with his service revolver.
I know all about that.
I found the body Monday morning.
I didn't know that.
Well, there's a lot of things
you people don't know.
Well, someone talked him
out of showing up here.
Probably told him he'd be a wimp if he
admitted something was bothering him.
- What are you getting at?
- You tell me.
[Scoffs]
- Please don't slam the...
- [Door Slams]
- Hey, Harry.
- Oh, Officer Forrest.
- How you doing tonight?
- It's you.
They tell me you got
your picture in the paper.
I guess congratulations
are in order.
That's not such a bad picture.
I'll tell you what, Harry.
I'll take a dozen of 'em.
A dozen it is.
How often do I get a celebrity
around here? [Chuckles]
Okay, Harry, give me your hand.
Okay, look, this is a five, okay?
- You trust me?
- I trust you.
- All right. You keep the change.
- Thank you. Thank you. All right.
[Blade Unsheathes]
Okay, let's see
what they said about Terese.
- [Stabs]
- [Groaning]
- [Gasping]
- Jack! What's going on?
What's happening? Jack.
Talk to me. Talk to me.
Police! Police! Police!
Strangled like the rest.
All strippers.
Sure picks the pretty ones.
Lovejoy, you look sick.
Well, I hate being around
stiffs ever since
they made me kiss my
grandmother at the funeral.
Remove the sheet.
Could you do it, please?
[Sobs]
[Groans]
[Sobbing]
Do you have any idea what the family
wants done with the body?
I'll call his mother in Florida.
[Sniffling]
Teresa, can you think of anyone
with a motive to kill Jack?
You were at the lounge
in headquarters.
You had an argument. You got angry.
You walked out. Where did you go?
[Sniffles]
Home.
You didn't wait outside the building
and try to make up with him?
I'd have no reason to kill him.
I loved him.
Well, maybe you loved him
too much. Huh?
Maybe you... maybe he thought
you were crackin' up.
He didn't wanna marry you
and you got angry.
[Sniffles]
This is bullshit!
Why don't you ask Commissioner Doyle
who killed Jack?
Look, I'm just
following procedure.
You know as well as I,
nine out of 10 times...
the prime suspects
are usually family, relatives or friends.
- That's where you find the killer.
- You bastards.
[Teresa] Why don't you ask
Commissioner Doyle who killed Jack?
I don't like what you're asking me
to do to Officer Mallory.
You know as well as...
We're just doing it for
the good of the department.
We don't even consider her a suspect.
It's just our way of putting her
on the defensive for a while,
keep her under control
so she doesn't go to the papers.
My time would be better spent
finding out who killed Jack.
Your time, Detective,
is to put more pressure on her!
That's a direct order.
[Door Opens, Closes]
Damn it.
- I don't like it either.
- You should talk.
Your report described her
as mentally unsound and unfit for duty.
How am I supposed to really judge her?
She's out there on the streets being a cop.
I sit behind my desk
like a social worker.
I just don't like people who try
and get inside other people's heads.
Yeah, you made that very clear to me
in my office yesterday.
Is there
any particular reason?
My wife was under the care
of a psychiatrist for over a year.
You know, standard problems, cop's wife.
Oh, I admit
I'm not the easiest guy to live with.
But she couldn't make a move without him.
Stopped communicating with me, only him.
Now she's my ex-wife.
Is that reason enough for you?
I'm sure the doctor was just doing
what he thought was best.
[Sighs]
I don't buy into this psychology stuff.
I think you're all full of shit.
So you can take your Carl Jung and
Sigmund Freud and shove 'em up your ass.
[Sighs]
And just to clear up matters...
I talked Joe Minelli into canceling
that appointment with you,
and I don't feel guilty about it.
How could you feel guilty?
- You're a cop.
- So are you.
[Metal Clanking]
Hey, stop! Don't do it!
Oh, for God sakes,
you already did it!
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Come on.
Can't we talk about this?
I'll move the car.
I was just coming back to move the car.
- I got here first.
- Yeah, but I'm here. I'm right here.
- You can't tow me away.
- Read the back of your summons.
Hey, look, you're all alone. Can't we work
this out, just between you and me, huh?
- What? You're offering me a bribe?
- Not at all.
But if you tow my car,
I won't be able to get to work tomorrow.
- I'll lose a whole day.
- You can afford it.
You enjoy this.
You son of a bitch.
You got a shitty
nothing civil service job...
Oh, careful of my fender with that.
This is a new paint job.
I just had the whole thing waxed.
You'll be towing fucking cars
the rest of your life. You know that?
You'll never be anything.
You can't even do this stupid job right.
I'd like to see
the piece of shit you drive.
You better start thinking
about getting out to Brooklyn
early tomorrow to reclaim this beauty.
A lot of cars
get stripped in our lot.
Stereo, the tires,
the whole engine.
That's why I wouldn't own
a car in this town.
[Chain Rattling]
[Whirring]
[Whirring Stops]
[Engine Starts]
[Man] Good night, Harry.
[Harry] Good night.
Happy holiday.
- Here you go, Harry. Good night.
- Excuse me.
Hi. I'd like to talk to you.
Do I know you?
I'm from the police department.
I talked to the cops
already enough.
I'm not an investigator like the others.
I'm a psychologist.
I'm trying to do a profile on this killer.
I've got nothing to say.
I'm trying to make a living.
Maybe you could tell from his footsteps
is he a large man...
or perhaps he said something.
No footsteps.
I just heard Jack screaming and...
That's all.
Did you touch him?
Not the victim, the killer.
Why did you ask me that?
You did, didn't you? Tell me.
I lost my sight in combat in Sicily.
A German grenade
went off in my face.
Killed all the others
in the foxhole around me.
I lay there more than a day,
surrounded by these dead bodies,
buried in them.
At night, they froze.
Them being on top of me
kept me from freezing too.
I never thought
I'd feel anything like that again.
Frozen dead flesh.
Then I touched his hand.
Just for a second, mind you,
and I was back there again...
with the dead.
- Ow!
- You killed him, you son of a bitch!
Ow! Take it easy! Look, if he
wanted to tow my car, so what?
You don't kill anybody
over bullshit like that!
Well, if you didn't kill him,
who the fuck did?
You wouldn't believe me.
- Why don't you try me, punk?
- All right. All right!
It was a great big cop.
Six foot three, maybe more, all
scarred up. And he never said a word.
- You know something?
- Ow!
I don't believe you!
Get the fuck out of here!
[McKinney] Take a look at
these reports. It's happening again.
I got on this job two weeks ago.
Give me a break.
I'm talking about a man
who killed your predecessor.
A man who may try to pull
the same number on you.
Then the wrong guy
died in that truck in the river?
When this leaks out, people are not gonna
want to pick up the phone and dial 911.
They're gonna want
to defend themselves.
We're looking at a bloodbath here.
Citizens blowing each other away
like there isn't any law.
Tell me the truth.
Do you think it's a cop?
Some officer
that's gone off the deep end?
Doesn't fit the description
of any cop I know.
Six three feet,
scars all over him.
Except one.
[Doyle]
Don't say it.
Don't even think it.
- What are you talking about?
- Nothing. Nothing.
We've got
to get this killer.
Better assemble a new task force.
- Get some aid from the governor.
- Well, I got a lead.
This policewoman, Teresa Mallory.
Mallory?
Oh, my God. Not her again.
Yeah, her.
Killed the boyfriend.
I figure he's gonna go after her.
I don't get it.
He's had a lot of opportunities to kill her.
Why hasn't he killed her?
Maybe he enjoys making her afraid.
I'm beginning to think
maybe you're not so crazy.
Great. Then you'll be out of a job too.
They've asked me to certify you unfit,
but I can't do it.
I read all about Cordell
and what happened to him.
Look, if you want more
information, just tune in to
Criminals at Large
television show tonight.
- Why would you go on that show?
- Why not?
They alert the public to wanted criminals.
A half dozen or so have been caught
or turned in as a direct result.
And who's gonna believe you,
the lunatic fringe?
- Will you come with me?
- I can't.
- What are you gonna say?
- [Horn Honking]
There's my cab.
[Sighs] All right, I'll go with you.
I'll even pay for the cab.
Oh, where to, girls?
Mayflower Hotel.
Sounds good to me.
I just jumped out
to get a pack of smokes.
I hope you girls
weren't waiting in the cold too long.
No, it's okay.
When I saw the bag, I said,
“This is a run to the airport.”
[Chuckles] Guess
you can't win 'em all.
I don't see anyone following us, Teresa.
Some ex-boyfriend
giving you a hard time?
Yeah, sort of.
The shows are gonna
be letting out now.
Um, maybe I can beat the
crosstown traffic if I cut down this way.
No, no!
Stay on the busy streets.
Hey, what's going on here?
You ever seen one of these?
Yeah, I seen plenty of them.
And it usually means
I ain't gettin' a tip.
- [Thumping]
- Damn.
- What's the matter?
- I don't know.
I think one of my tires
is going flat.
Driver, just stay in the car.
- Don't get out.
- You kidding?
- Drive.
- On my rim?
Teresa, take it easy.
Anybody can get a flat tire.
Look, cop or no cop,
I own this cab.
I'm not gonna fuck it up
for anybody.
Holy shit.
You're making it worse than it has to be.
Nobody's following us.
Just stay in the cab.
When you left your cab
to go for cigarettes, somebody must...
have messed with your tires.
Damn kids, I'll bet.
[Tires Squeal]
- Where the hell you goin'?
Teresa, stop it.
What are you doing?
I knew it. I never should
have let cops in my cab.
- What's he want?
- I don't know.
Keep down!
Teresa!
Shit!
Shit.
Goddamn it!
Jesus Christ!
Teresa!
[Screaming]
No! No, please!
No!
No! No!
[Susan Whimpering]
No!
[Screaming]
[Groans]
- [Screams]
- [Chain Saw Whirring]
[Screaming]
[Screaming] No!
[Bones Crack]
[Screaming]
No!
[Horn Honking]
[Screams]
[Steam Hissing]
[Footsteps]
- [Gasps]
- [Man] Are you all right in there?
Hey, who handcuffed you, lady?
What the hell
is going on?
All right,
easy does it.
We'll get you out of there.
Radio in for a hacksaw up here!
We got to get
these cuffs off of her!
All right,
just take it easy.
We're gonna get you
out of there. Relax.
You better lie still.
Your wrist is broken.
Better fix me up quickly.
I gotta be on TV in a few hours.
I'm Detective McKinney.
I'm gonna ride inside.
You okay?
I was on my way to Teresa's apartment
when the report came over the radio.
I guess you don't have to worry
about her doing any more talking.
[Sighs] I'm not feeling
too great about all this.
I doubted her in the beginning too.
But I saw him.
I saw what he did.
What'd you see? Big guy in a
bulletproof vest dressed up like a cop?
Sean, I saw Matt Cordell.
[Male Host] Tonight, Criminals
at Large goes after a serial killer...
who's claimed the lives
of beautiful young girls...
working as exotic dancers and strippers
in New York City.
And you, the audience,
may help us to catch him.
[Man] Welcome to Club 69,
here in the heart of Times Square.
I'm your emcee.
[Host On TV] Tonight you'll meet
detectives assigned to this case.
But first I would like you to meet
Deputy Commissioner
Edward Doyle of the N.Y.P.D.
[Female Bartender] Do
you want another drink?
Yeah.
[Host] Just what has your
department done about this case so far?
We've contacted and alerted
young women...
who seem to be
the killer's prime target group.
We have a special late guest here.
Actually, she's one of your lady cops.
She's also a police psychologist,
and her name is Officer Susan Riley.
- Susan, welcome to the show.
- Thank you.
Mr. Brady, the murders of these
exotic dancers is a very tragic situation.
Now, my concern is another series of
killings going on that's being covered up.
Pardon me.
Mr. Brady, this is utterly nonsense.
The so-called “maniac cop”
did not drown in the river, as reported.
Well, Commissioner, what...
what do you have to say about this?
Well, the homicides
that Officer Riley is talking about...
were deliberately set up
to imitate the earlier killings.
Then tell me something,
Commissioner.
Why is this being kept
from the public and the press? Hmm?
The killer craves publicity.
We're denying him that.
We hope that his behavior
will become foolhardy...
and he'll expose himself,
show himself.
Then we expect to nail him.
Mr. Commissioner, why don't
you just admit that Matt Cordell
is responsible for these killings?
Cordell died in prison.
[Susan] He was brain-dead but still
breathing when his body was released.
He recovered and came back
to avenge himself...
upon the police department
and the city officials
who railroaded him
into jail in the first place.
You know how many people
have been murdered already?
And yet, their replacements still
insist upon hiding the facts...
[Brady] We're running out of time here.
I'm gonna have to cut you off.
And, punk, if you happen
to be out there listening,
I just want you to remember this.
When it comes time
for your execution,
you can't con Con Edison.
Good night.
Officer Riley.
[Sighs]
That was a pretty stupid thing
you did up there, young lady.
I'm gonna see
that you're suspended.
Teresa Mallory's dead
because she knew the truth.
Let me tell you something, Commissioner.
Cordell's gonna pay you a visit,
and you'll see him.
Just like I did.
[Emcee] Oh, boys, look at this blondie here.
Isn't she beautiful?
Take 'em out, blondie.
Take 'em out. Let 'em breathe.
Oh, boy! Aren't they lovely?
Ooh, baby!
And on the other side, there's Red.
Take 'em out, Red. Let 'em breathe too.
And be generous, boys,
with that cash,
because these girls
are dancing here just for you.
Let's have a round of applause
for these two lovely young ladies.
And don't forget.
They'll be back later, boys.
We're open 24 hours.
Don't go nowhere. Hang around.
- [Patrons Whistling]
- And now for the first time on any stage,
the lovely Cheryl!
♪♪ [Rock]
- Let's have a big round of applause, boys.
Come on.
Let's hear it for Cheryl.
She's making her debut here
in the big city at Club 69.
Isn't she lovely? No one has ever
had this girl on the stage before.
We always are the first ones
with the best talent in New York.
So just keep your eyes on Cheryl.
Oh, boys, tell me.
Isn't she lovely?
Just keep your eyes on her.
You'll definitely get an eyeful.
Oh! God, isn't she gorgeous, boys?
Be generous. Spread out that cash.
♪♪ [Continues]
[Man] ♪ Yeah, yeah, tonight ♪
♪ I won't be coming home ♪
♪ I'll be running
with the children tonight ♪
♪ Tonight ♪
[Female Backup Singers]
♪ Children of the night ♪
[Man]
♪ Yeah ♪
- ♪ I hear them coming ♪
- ♪ Children of the night ♪
♪ I hear them coming
Hear them coming ♪
♪♪ [Continues]
♪ I'm making some new friends ♪
♪ You never know
what the first night means ♪
♪  We'll start us a new trend ♪
♪♪ [Continues]
[Whistling, Applauding]
♪ Tonight ♪
♪ I won't be coming home ♪
[Woman] Yes, Mom, there's
plenty of room for advancement.
Are you eating well?
Yes, I'm getting plenty to eat.
- They have an employee cafeteria.
- [People Shouting]
- Where are you living?
- Well, um,
I'm sharing this
lovely apartment with, um,
a few of the girls from
the secretarial pool.
- Are they nice girls?
- Yeah, they're really sweet.
Make sure you call us when you can.
- Okay.
Well, then, as soon as I get my phone,
I'll give you a call and
give you the number.
- And your address so we can write to you.
- [Horn Honking]
All right. Okay.
But in the meantime, please,
just don't worry about me. I'm fine.
I love you, sweetheart.
Take care of yourself.
Okay.
Oh, and give my love to Dad.
- I will, sweetheart.
- All right.
- I love you.
- I love you too.
- Bye.
[Line Clicks]
- [Shouting Continues]
[Sirens Blaring]
[Baby Crying]
[Horns Honking]
- [Sighs]
[Door Closes]
Of course my typing's
getting better, Mom.
[Knocking]
[Sighs]
Who is it?
[Rattling, Thumping]
- [Shrieks, Gasps]
- [Man] Desk.
- This is 404.
Someone is trying
to break into my room.
I'm telling you,
there is somebody out there.
- He'll go away.
- No. Please, call the police.
- Please, get me some help.
- We don't want any trouble.
Call them! Or give me a line
out, and I'll call them myself.
Have it your way. But if I
was in your line of work...
[Hangs Up Phone]
[Baby Crying In Distance]
I called the cops.
They're coming,
so you better get out of here.
- [Shouts]
- [Screaming]
[Shouting] Whoo! I feel like
John fucking Wayne! Whoo!
[Grunts] Now, you got to
listen to me. Listen to me!
Now, I've been watching you,
and I say you're asking for it. Right?
- Tell me! Come on!
- The police are coming.
I don't care about no police.
This ain't gonna take long.
What are you gonna do?
Think about it.
What do you think I'm gonna do to you?
Come on. What do you
think? What do you think?
You killed those other girls.
No. Let's just say...
that I need another 8x10 glossy
for my collection.
- [Shrieks]
- [Chuckling]
- Oh, trying to do some dirt to me, huh, baby?
- [Shrieking]
I love the way you feel.
[Grunts]
Oh, yeah. Ah.
You got to be proud, because you're the
prettiest one in my collection so far. You are.
And the best dancer clear out.
You could be in a Broadway show.
But no, you've got to be up there
on that stage dancing like some whore!
You never know what type of person's
gonna walk in, now, do ya?
Do ya, honey?
[Phone Rings]
[Crying] That's them in the
lobby. They're comin' up to get you.
It's a slow elevator.
[Phone Rings]
This ain't gonna take a minute.
[Gasping]
[Screams]
[Both Gasp]
[Screaming]
Hold it! Police!
- [Shouts]
- [Screaming]
- Don't hurt me. Don't hurt me.
- [Sobbing]
[Sirens Wailing In Distance]
[Sobbing]
Oh, you ain't no cop, man.
I know who you are.
Damn, she was talkin'
about you on TV.
You was in the headlines
last month and everything.
See, you're front page stuff.
But me, I'm back on page five.
You know why? You know
what did it for you? That uniform.
See, that was a gimmick.
See, that's what got their attention.
I got a real nice apartment.
I mean, it's quiet.
Nobody ever comes down there.
Private, you know?
Uh, you could come there.
I mean, I ain't queer or nothing.
See, but-but you'd be safe there.
And I've got a collection
to show you.
The city at night. That's
where and when I do my work.
You know,
I feel like I'm a crusader...
against the whores of the world.
[Chuckles]
That's me.
Turkell, crusader of the night.
[Cackles]
You don't talk much,
but that's okay.
Was it the accident, the same one
that screwed your face up?
I didn't mean to offend
you now. I'm sorry if I did.
This... This here's my place.
Home, sweet home.
These are my girls.
They ain't gonna dance
in front of nobody no more.
Now they're Turkell's girls.
Uh, my first name is Steven.
Why don't you go ahead
and sit down?
You know, most of the time,
I just talk to myself anyway.
So... So it's okay.
I mean,
I don't hear voices or nothing.
I'm not like those guys that hear
angels and devils tellin' 'em what to do.
You see,
I know what to do.
Here, we'll have a drink.
You hate cops.
So you made
a fuckin' mockery out of 'em.
I mean, for a while,
everybody was scared shit...
to walk up to a cop
in this here town.
And that was 'cause of you.
You know, I-I never thought, really,
that I'd meet you.
Or that...
Or that w-we'd become friends.
All right. All right.
Why should you trust me?
I got to earn it.
I got to make you respect me.
But I-I think maybe you see
the possibilities in me, huh?
Can you write?
I mean, c-can you
write down your name?
See, that way,
I'll know what to call you.
I'll go get a pencil and paper.
[Straining] Cordell.
[Sighs]
Cordell.
That's the name she said on TV.
[Laughing]
So, how'd you like me
on TV?
I loved you.
The mayor loved you, and the
city council was nuts about you.
Here.
Check out your reviews.
The whole city's freaked
over this maniac cop.
Guess I really
started something, huh?
Maybe I should just go home
and wait for the ax to fall.
No chance.
So you mean
I can't do any more guest shots?
No.
You think there's any reason why Cordell
would want to come back and get me?
[Clicks Teeth]
I don't know.
But let me tell you.
If he doesn't shoot you,
the commissioner himself might kill you.
What?
This, uh, stupid rhyme
keeps going through my head.
We used to say it
when we were kids in Brooklyn.
I mean, it's just nonsense,
but I-I can't get it out of my mind.
It goes, uh,
“One bright day
in the middle of the night,
two dead boys
got up to fight.
Back to back
they faced each other.
With their knives
they shot each other.
A deaf policeman heard the noise,
and came and killed the two dead boys.”
- You know that?
- Yeah, I remember that when I was a kid.
“Two Dead Boys.”
What about it?
[Chuckles] I don't know. I
guess I'm just cracking up.
[Chuckles] You oughta
know. That's your specialty.
Yeah.
[Turkell] Did you ever see
anything so nasty?
Ooh! You got a big one too.
[Laughing]
Boy, they really did
a job on you, Cordell.
I mean, an honest cop.
What'd you think you'd get out of it?
You put the squeeze
on the important people,
you end up in the slammer,
not them.
What happened to you?
Why don't you tell me
what happened?
I mean, I've never seen nobody
cut... that bad...
that deep...
and still be breathing.
[Gavel Rapping]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Grunting]
[Grunting Continues]
[Grunts]
- [Stabs]
- [Shouts]
[Groans]
[Grunting]
This young lady
was attacked last evening...
by the man we believe killed those
strippers in Brooklyn, Queens and Manhattan.
What can I do to help?
Tonight we're hitting
similar clubs in Lower Manhattan,
bringing Cheryl here along,
hoping she can identify her attacker.
If he frequents such clubs... and
we think he does... he might show up.
We're gonna be going in and out
of these places as couples.
So we need a policewoman
to make a foursome.
I don't have any experience
on the streets.
[Sighs]
Why me?
Her assailant was rescued by a cop,
who killed two policemen in the process.
A huge, disfigured cop.
[Lovejoy] We put out a story that
Cheryl died en route to Bellevue,
just to put her attacker at ease.
Did he do this to you?
Yes.
Could you tell me
what his hands felt like?
Like ice.
So you want to come along?
- Do I have any choice?
- No.
You're under my protection.
Remember how to use a gun,
Officer Riley?
What difference does it make?
Shooting Cordell
is only good for getting his attention.
Hey, wait! Don't leave me
here. It ain't safe out there!
Oh. You're goin' some place
I can't go, huh?
Got work to do.
Yeah, but you're
comin' back, right?
You know,
I got things to do myself.
But then I'll be back here
waitin' for you.
[Man] ♪ All day long ♪
♪ I've had this funny feeling ♪
♪ That tonight is the night ♪
♪ Right all along ♪
♪ Intuition keeps on telling me ♪
♪ That love is in sight ♪
♪ The stars are shining
extra bright tonight ♪
♪ That means something to me ♪
- How you doin'?
- Hey. Four.
Four. $20.
♪ Love is searching for me, yeah ♪
[Man]
Enjoy the show.
♪ It's a message from above ♪
♪ Telling me to get ready ♪
You girls work hard.
Yeah, we do. I can make
a thousand dollars a week.
How much money
do you make, Lieutenant?
Maybe I oughta take
dancing lessons.
You see anybody familiar here?
Just a bunch of regulars from the other
clubs that I work, but I don't see him.
Why don't we get out of here
and try some place else?
Why don't we have a drink?
What the hell. We paid for it.
♪ Intuition keeps on telling me ♪
♪ Just go with the flow ♪
♪♪ [Continues]
Lieutenant, it's him.
- Hey.
- Hey, watch it.
- Hey, man.
[Gasps]
- Hey, look out.
- [Shouts]
[Glass Shatters]
[Woman Screams]
- I gotta get me one of those.
- [Chuckles]
Hey, you.
I want to see my lawyer.
That's no problem.
What happened to your friend,
the big cop?
He's my friend, all right.
And he ain't gonna forget
about me. [Chuckles]
How did you meet Cordell?
How'd you know his name?
Shit.
That girl that coldcocked me.
She's the one from that TV show,
Criminals at Large.
Hey, you.
It's gonna take more than
a TV show to catch my friend.
[Chuckles]
Hmm.
This your address, Turkell?
Wipe your feet on the mat.
- I think we got him.
- That's great.
You want some company?
Haven't you seen enough action
for one night?
Why don't you go get some rest?
No, I couldn't sleep.
I think I'll go fire
a few practice rounds.
I've never been
much good with guns.
Under the circumstances,
I'd try to improve.
[Gunshots]
[Man] I've never seen
you in uniform before.
I wanted to see if it still fits.
That's not
a very good shot pattern.
Maybe you're better at
shootin' your mouth off on TV.
Did they assign you
to a beat yet?
Maybe Spanish Harlem,
or some nice place like that?
Maybe.
Well, listen, Susan.
Just, uh... Just keep trying.
You'll get the knack of it
in about a year or two.
Just tell everybody that that
broken arm was your good one.
Right.
Come on in, fellas.
We've got ourselves a serial killer.
[Turkell] ♪ Don't you forget me, Cordell ♪
♪ I'm waitin' for you here, Cordell ♪
♪ We'll both probably end up in hell ♪
- ♪ You'll need- ♪
- Motherfucker!
Will you hold it down?
Shit.
Get more privacy when I get back
in the motherfuckin' death house.
Is that where you're goin', man?
Sing Sing?
What the fuck are you,
Barbara Walters?
Shit, man.
Yeah.
Motherfuckin' mornin'.
Shit.
I stalled them motherfuckers
for five years.
Yeah.
The Supreme Court, it fucked me.
And it wasn't even safe sex.
It's cruel and unusual punishment.
No bullshit.
Listenin' to assholes like you
is worse.
Hey, be nice.
When my friend comes to break
me out, I might take you with me.
Yeah.
I will hold my breath...
and my dick.
[Chuckles]
Oh, hi there, pretty lady.
Boy, don't you look great
in that uniform.
You want me to
autograph your cast?
Look, I still want
to talk to you about Cordell.
If you want to know about him,
stick around here tonight.
You might learn somethin'.
What do you mean by that?
[Chuckling]
[Gunshots]
- [Gunshots]
- [All Grunting]
[Grunts]
Hey, hey!
[All Shouting]
[Gasps]
[Susan]
No.
It must be visiting hours,
'cause my friend is back!
[Laughing]
Make sure that roadblock is set up.
- [Man Shouting]
- What's going on?
He blew away half a dozen men
downstairs on the firing range.
I don't know how many he killed upstairs.
We just got the hell out of his way.
That's a good strategy.
He's got Susan Riley as a hostage
on the cell block.
- Is she all right?
- I don't know.
What are we doin' about this?
I got the tactical squad on its
way, and a couple of SWAT teams.
Doyle's been notified. He's on
his way over here to take charge.
- Take charge? That's a joke.
- You got any ideas?
If he comes out, don't interfere
with him. Just follow him.
He had a reason for coming here.
He's got a reason
for everything he does.
Ooh, what'd you do to these cops?
Oh, I'd have loved to seen it.
See, Blum?
I told you, treat me nice.
[Susan]
He's gonna get us killed.
Hey, lady, close your eyes.
You may see something you like.
[Chuckling]
Going home.
How come he don't talk?
It's weird.
Weird!
He just handed me
your transfer papers to Sing Sing.
I ain't goin' back there.
Well, I think that's
what he's got in mind.
Hey, man, they gonna kill me!
No, he wouldn't let that happen
to a pleasing personality like yourself.
You've been in Sing Sing before.
What's back there for you?
Come on. You're a bright girl.
Haven't you got that figured out yet?
We're goin' there...
to break out all them guys
on death row.
There's about 20 of 'em
up there on appeal.
Real lovable types.
Yes, that's...
That's what we're gonna do.
'Cause we're recruitin' an army.
Aren't we?
Sure.
See, 'cause it's, like,
your thoughts are in my mind.
I got you figured out, man.
We ain't runnin' away.
No, we're gettin' stronger.
Yeah!
[Chuckles]
'Cause we got ourselves a leader.
Oh, I don't want no part of this.
I'm not goin' to no state pen...
- Ow!
- [Chuckles]
Uh, say, listen.
We gonna bring her along?
All right, sweetheart.
Here's a jacket.
You lead the way.
If there's any shootin', you'll
be the first to know about it.
[Cackles]
Terrific. She puts on a uniform and
immediately gets taken hostage. Some cop.
- Why is he going back there?
- Shut up and get in.
[Engine Starts]
Bumper cars!
[Sirens Wailing]
Let me give you a ride, Commissioner.
We gotta talk.
I have my limo.
We need to talk.
[Cackling]
[Sirens Wailing]
[Horn Honking]
[Turkell] All right,
hold on, y'all.
- Here goes!
- [Tires Squealing]
[Turkell Whooping]
I'm bad! Whoo!
[Cackling]
That's right, eh, Blum?
Don't change your shorts, baby,
'cause this ride's just startin'.
Do-si-do!
Ah-ha!
Yeah!
What do you think
of that, little lady?
Huh?
Going in the wrong direction.
That's the parkway up ahead.
Same route Cordell took.
I think I know where he's going.
How do you know that?
One of the escapees was scheduled for
a transfer to the death house at Sing Sing.
Cordell's making the delivery.
He's homesick.
How come you didn't
say anything about that before?
'Cause all the cops in the world
can't stop Cordell.
Only you can.
Stop this car.
I'm getting out.
- That's an order.
- You lost the right to make orders.
- You're going with me.
- No. No, I'm not going anywhere.
What's the matter, Commissioner?
You finally believe in ghosts?
You oughta.
You made him one.
Turn this goddamn car around.
[Chuckles]
That's a dumb fuckin' thing to do.
Well, what do you
want me to do, huh?
Shove the gun in my own mouth?
Pull the trigger?
That's too easy.
I want you to reopen
the Cordell case.
Get some judge to set aside his conviction,
and then dig up his empty coffin.
- That's right. It's gonna be empty.
- Come on.
Then I want you to bury it
again with a police honor guard.
You're fuckin' crazy, you know that.
Cordell got too close to you people
at city hall who were takin' payoffs.
So you framed him, put him in
a fuckin' rathole and set him up.
- You murdered him.
- You're pushin' me too far, McKinney.
- Pull over!
- [Tires Screech]
[Panting]
You're right.
I'm responsible.
What am I supposed to do now?
- Sign a confession.
- I can't do that. I'd be through.
Well, you're through now. You're not gonna
see retirement. He's gonna come after you.
[Whooping]
You sure is pretty for a cop.
Do you wanna integrate?
[Knocking]
[Horns Honking]
[Whooping]
This is McKinney.
Deputy Commissioner Doyle wants
to speak to His Honor the mayor.
It concerns the massacre
at headquarters.
Open the gate.
[Gate Opening]
Uh, delivering the prisoner,
Blum, Joseph T.
We weren't expecting
this guy till morning.
I got a tip his friends might try
to create a little detour, you know.
We're just playin' it safe.
Open the gates.
[Gates Opening]
Welcome home, Cordell.
Put me through to the warden.
Warden, Blum's just been delivered.
[Warden] I got word from the city
that he'd been broken out of jail.
Well, he just arrived under escort.
Seal off that section
of the cell block.
- Put all men on alert. We're in trouble.
- Yes, sir.
[Inmates Shouting]
[On P.A.] Attention.
Attention. This is the Warden.
Deputy Commissioner Doyle
wishes to speak to Matt Cordell.
Cordell? He's alive.
I told you so.
If he comes after me,
I'm ready for that bastard.
[Neck Snaps]
[Turkell]
Hey, death row people!
We're here to liberate you! Yeah!
This is Deputy Commissioner Doyle.
I'm here in the prison courtyard.
I'm talking to Matt Cordell.
Cordell,
Judge Arthur Claypool
has ordered your case reopened.
Bullshit.
Like you need a new trial, right?
Listen, Cordell.
This is what you want.
- Hey, you shut up. You hear me?
- Listen!
Keep going.
In your first trial,
perjury was committed.
Even the presiding judge
was influenced.
I myself was involved.
We're the guilty ones.
Cordell, you were a good man once.
A good cop.
Fuck him. Good cop.
- You're every good cop's nightmare.
- Yeah!
Cordell, I repeat,
your conviction will be reversed
by the state supreme court.
[Inmate In Distance] Open this door now!
Hey, come on! Open the door!
[Overlapping Shouts In Distance]
Where you goin', man?
Where the fuck's he going?
I don't know, man.
Don't leave me.
Tell me what to do!
[Panting]
No! Hey!
- Oh, God!
- [Shouting In Distance]
No.
Don't leave me.
[Doyle]
I've signed a confession.
I'm the guilty one.
Good.
He heard you.
I hope.
[Inmates Shouting]
Cordell!
[Grunts]
[Grunting]
[Shouting, Shrieking]
No!
[Shouts]
[Shrieks, Grunts]
[Man Shouting, Whimpering]
No!
[Grunts]
[Shrieking]
You never cared for me.
You were never my friend!
[Shrieking]
[Shrieking Continues]
[Man] We commend our
brother Matthew to you, Lord.
May he live on in your presence.
In your mercy and love,
forgive whatever sins
he may have committed
through human weakness.
We ask this
through Christ our Lord. Amen.
And so the final remains
of Matthew Cordell,
who died three years ago,
are brought to rest with honors.
His remains have been brought here so he
may be placed beside his fellow officers.
But I feel sorrow for all of those...
whose deceptions and lies
were responsible for this tragic death.
That's something they'll have to
contend with when they meet their maker.
[Honor Guard Commander]
Detail. Attention.
Present arms.
Order arms.
[McKinney]
I'll take that.
[Honor Guard Commander]
Detail dismissed.
[Nightstick Swinging]
What is it?
Hmm?
Uh... oh, nothin'.
There's a piece of Cordell
in every cop.
Every time arresting
some mutt isn't enough,
because we know they'll be back on the
streets before we even do the paperwork.
Every time we pull a trigger and...
and it feels good,
because that's something
the lawyers can't reverse.
It all comes down to justice...
and pressure.
There's only that much difference
between a cop and a maniac cop.
[Children] One bright day
in the middle of the night,
two dead boys got up to fight.
Back to back
they faced each other.
With their knives
they shot each other.
A deaf policeman heard the noise...
and came and killed the
two dead boys.
[Children Laughing]
[Man]
Yo, wait a minute.
[Man #2]
What's that?
Something's sneaking
around the corner.
Here we come!
I think it's that maniac.
Hold on!
[Together]
Aaah!
♪♪ [Hip-hop Intro]
Rock!
[Rapping] ♪ You better watch
out when you hear that sound ♪
♪ It means that
the Maniac Cop's around ♪
♪ Once upon a time he was a super cop ♪
♪ But the bad guys framed him
to make him stop ♪
♪ They put him in prison,
where they tried to kill him ♪
♪ But he broke out
Now he's the villain ♪
♪ Bullets won't hurt him
I know it sounds like jive ♪
♪ But we're not sure
if he's dead or alive ♪
♪ Set him on fire,
or shoot him with an uzi ♪
♪ But he'll show up in your jacuzzi ♪
♪ You can run him over
You can feed him poison ♪
♪ Push him out a window,
and it only annoys him ♪
♪ You better believe me
if you think I'm lyin' ♪
- ♪ When he show up, people start dyin' ♪
- ♪ Yeah ♪
♪ He's out for vengeance
and he can't be stopped ♪
♪ That's why they call him
the Maniac Cop ♪
- [Man] You have the right to remain silent.
- [Chuckling]
Huh!
Rock!
♪ When you hear that whistle
out in the street ♪
♪ You're gonna think
it's a cop on the beat ♪
♪ But don't be thinkin'
about police protection ♪
♪ 'Cause this is one cop
with a bad connection ♪
♪ When he shows up,
he's supposed to protect ya ♪
♪ But Maniac Cop is out to get ya ♪
♪ He's an anti-vigilante,
and they can't convict him ♪
♪ So watch out, Jack,
cause you're the next victim ♪
♪ Don't hang around
if you see him comin' ♪
♪ Just pick up your feet
and commence to runnin' ♪
♪ And don't waste time dialin' 911 ♪
- ♪ Forget karate ♪
- ♪ And forget your gun ♪
♪ Don't play hero
Don't try to be brave ♪
♪ This dude's gonna
send you to an early grave ♪
♪ He's out for vengeance
and he can't be stopped' ♪
♪ That's why they call him
the Maniac Cop ♪
[Man]
You have the right to a mortician.
If you cannot afford one,
we'll take you as you are.
Rock!
[Chuckling]
♪ The law is equal
and justice is blind ♪
♪ But this cop's justice
is one of a kind ♪
♪ He's homicidal and maladjusted ♪
♪ But when he busts in,
your ass is busted ♪
♪ You won't get a ticket
or pay your fine ♪
♪ You might as well be dealin'
with Frankenstein ♪
♪ He's big and ugly with a busted jaw ♪
♪ You know
he's the wrong arm of the law ♪
♪ You better stay away
from this man in blue ♪
♪ And don't call a cop,
'cause he'll snuff him too ♪
♪ They killed him once,
but he came back ♪
♪ He's the
ma-ma-ma-ma-ma-ma-ma-maniac ♪
♪ So when you're out on the streets
and you hear that sound ♪
♪ It probably means
that Cordell's around ♪
♪ He's out for vengeance
and he can't be stopped ♪
♪ That's why they
call him the Maniac ♪
♪ The Maniac Cop ♪
Rock!
Wait a minute.
What's that?
I don't know, but I'm breakin' camp.
No, wait, Josh.
Come back.
Aaah!
Ah, man, I ain't with that, man.
Let's break.
Let's get outta here. Come on!
- Hey, man, maybe we should chill.
- I know.
- And check out the movie again.
- I think we should.
Rock!
[Man]
You have the right to remain silent...
forever.