'Manja Satta Pacha Satta
[Yellow shirt Green shirt.]'
"The all seeing and
benevolent great one"
"One who lives in the palace
and the poorest hut."
"The heir of the sun, the master of music"
"The saint of stories, the
protector of performance"
"Show mercy upon us and protect us always."
"One who lives in the palace
and everywhere else!"
"Greetings, many greetings..
I offer greetings!"
"Greetings to everyone who has come here"
"Sir greetings, many greetings...
I offer greetings!"
"Greetings to everyone who has come here!"
"To serve this country"
"A civilised clown has come here!"
"He has made them laugh,
he has made the people laugh"
"The clown who made them
laugh has come here."
Story teller Ucchu Kudumba...
I am present my lord.
Before the guests go to sleep
begin your story Ucchu Kudumba.
What I bring to you is...
Under the 3 thousand crore deities
and the hole in the ozone layer.
Having chopped all trees inside this
concrete jungle, atop this earth.
Where the never drying sewage rivers
that flow next to the Chennai City!
and in the retro city
that nobody has heard of.
There was once that be BOB ATM.
Wow, in trying to sing your story you
have given many messages to many people!
Once man gets a machine that gives money,
his life is sure to be disastrous!
And it is in this idiom
that our story begins.
Amazing, tell me more!
6 km away from this ATM is the factory
behind the old marriage hall bus stop.
And here takes place our first act
Hey, who are you?!
Hey old man, I too I am from around here
What work do you have here?
Will anyone come here for a marriage?
We came here to drink!
No no, you should not come here!
Oh my God!
I don’t know who I am!
I don’t care who you are.
I will break your head open!
Go...
Go!
Hey runaway, quickly now.
Hey quickly get your bike and let’s go!
Hey take this, wait here!
Hey, this old man has beaten
and killed more than 100 people.
How do you know that?
It came as a WhatsApp message
I myself forwarded it to many groups.
Oh no, he seems to be a very violent man!
What my Lord, she said it came in WhatsApp!
Do you still believe him?
Forget about that let’s
get back to the story.
Ucchu Kudumba, who is he?
She is somebody that nobody knows
if you use it good or bad person.
He is the central minister Paagambariya!
and somebody is here to see him!
Is he a good person or bad person?
He’s the one who rejoices, if
the country is split apart.
Is he a performer?
He is not a simple performer
he is in an institutional performer
Corporate-Broker Dilip Judhani
Take this
Please have it!
Tender coconut in the night time?!
When we can cheat in the night,
shouldn’t we be able to give
tender coconuts in the night?!
Come on!
Once you are here as our guest!
Please have our customary drink.
And if you manage to learn
or customs and language...
It will be easier for us.
Minister sir,
20 crores per year
I have negotiated for you!
You will be recognised as one
of the pioneers of Project Welfare,
Your name will go down in history.
It’s okay if my name is there
only on my tombstone Judhani.
Why should I write my name on
somebody else’s tombstone?
Whatever you heard is true.
For money Paagambariya will open wide!
It’s only four MLAs and one MP
I have earned in minister’s seat,
You can make the judgment.
For a profit, I will do
what is politically wrong.
I will do what is politically immoral
I will even do what is politically illegal!
But I will never do what
people say is wrong...
and it’s not because I will not
get the vote next time Mr. Judhani.
By poisoning drinking water
air that we breathe
and the very ground that I stand on,
Where can I go with all
the money in the world?
To the moon? I know
what this project is?
I also know what is the
commission you will get from it.
I will never give my
approval for this project!
This city is the soil are you stand on,
If I cannot live on this earth anymore,
I will oppose anything!
Amazing, Fantastic, Brilliant!
Though the job is to perform Tandavakone!
When it is about money,
you are very diligent Tandavakone
Go ahead!
One who chops up fish food,
can chop up a corpse too!
He is our Jailkodi Prabhakar a.k.a Prabha.
What?
ACP has called for you.
Come, how are you?
Make sure nobody finds out, Prabha.
You are talking to Jailkodi Prabhakaran.
Okay, a dead body has come in.
Your job is to chop it
up and feed the fish.
Only give me the order
not the instructions.
Prabha, do this carefully!
It should not leak to any one!
Even God will not be able to find it!
Just give us the body.
- I will send it.
- Hey come.
Sir!
Who is he that has a scorpion like
moustache and looks like Duryodhana?
My lord, due to circumstances
and certain choices,
he is the Ravanan who lost everything!
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian.
Good morning, sir.
Sir that Arabian girl Chaya who is missing.
I have found a new lead in the case sir.
The girl has not vacated her hotel room.
Moreover, she has gone by running taxi.
We will find her very soon!
For the marriage function
of minister’s relative
they had asked for police protection.
It seems you have refused!
All other stations help out with manpower.
What is your problem?
I came here to discuss another case sir.
Hey, is this an important case?
She must be high in some
or the other ashram!
When she comes to see will return home.
Go and do as I told you.
Come Mujeeb
Get lost you bugger!
Yes, sir.
Okay sir.
Sir, sir has gone out regarding a case.
Okay sir!
What is this?!
That inspector behaves as though
he is the one who discovered law!
Like this moron cops all
are died in road side
Do you know?
When we come here with
the anticipatory bail,
You will take that and make us wait.
It is inspector’s orders what can I do?!
Do I look like a fool?!
Don’t try no how to get our boy out!
Sitting minister is my brother-in-law!
Come let’s go.
Sir can I take a boy now?!
I can see how hurt you are.
The son of someone who is always
doing welfare for people...
has ripped apart the shirt of a
girl in the middle of the street!
Sir!
You horny little dog!
If you ever come here and
say my dad will come.
I will make sure you don’t
have a dad to bail you out.
Okay?!
You can take him.
Head constable get me a tea.
Okay sir.
Brother he hit our boy in front of us!
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian,
it’s a great thing
that he let us go at all! Come.
What have you done about what I asked?!
We can talk when I get back home,
cut the call!
Next, the crows that fell the palm tree!
Have you gone mad?!
Is the humiliation in an
interview, something new for us?!
It’s been five years!
Nobody give me an engineering job!
Including jammers and security protocols
I have seven different projects!
But wherever I go,
they offer me system admin and HR jobs.
I didn’t do engineering
because others told me to!
This is my dream!
I will show this world who I am!
I will show how an ATM can be robbed!
In this world full of CCTV cameras,
I will show it is possible to be invisible.
It is all about frequencies, anything
can be opened any data can be taken!
Any bank can be opened!
For that you want us to steal!
We are going to search for her identity!
We don’t have chance to prove
ourselves in the righteous path!
All of them are going to
play kabaddi in a guy’s life!
You mean, the great Kabbadi league!?
He is our king to be Thannoli
I am next to him is, Ms. Bhanumathi.
Banu, is money everything?!
More or less it is everything.
Then, are you saying that
I am good for nothing?
You are a good guy.
But a failure!
Even if you are a con, you must earn money!
Either you must change
or I will replace you.
Banu,
Banu look at me for a second!
Please don’t mistake the
question I am about to ask you!
In case we had an arranged marriage,
after marriage you had learnt
I was a good guy who is a failure...
who is good for nothing!
Would you replace me even then?!
You must be ruthless in life.
Hence, I would replace you.
So, for money you will do anything?
Come again!
I mean, for money...
you will do anything?!
Even if I was your wife, you have
no right to call me a prostitute!
Goodbye!
Banu, I’m sorry Banu. Banu!
After this love failure,
our hero fails in life...
and for three days he
mourned his six-year love!
What’s new, life is always like this!
The thing years six months before this,
on an auspicious day,
as per somebody’s advice
thinking there is a lot of money
in starting a YouTube channel,
our hero lost the only job he had.
Enough Ucchu Kudumba, I will
see the rest in the visuals.
Hey,
for giving you 10 days leave
now my job is in danger!
This is a stress buster mam.
Those who have lot of stress will go
and do primitive living in the forest.
Just like a system restore.
That is for people who actually
do their job why did you two go?!
Hey bro,
we should have taken madam along with us.
We should have!
You are fired!
Peanuts, this is all your salary!
She is only the side dish,
Who is going buy us liquor Kanniamma?!
That is your name right?!
Get lost!
There you go, the 80,000 I had borrowed.
Do you know one thing,
your guy has just been fired!
What are you saying?!
They built a fire in the
forest but it burnt them here.
Where to?!
Outside!
So it is a treat in the evening?!
She is like an old dog;
you can never change.
Even if he got a job in Giga
he will leave it halfway!
What do I care about him?!
There is 80,000 in here
I cannot go outside right now.
Will you deposit this
in my mother’s account?
This is the account details.
Don’t give this to him,
he will somehow screw it up!
Hey...
come!
Don’t stare at me!
When the world is headed one way,
you are headed in a different way.
Get lost.
Sis, the T-shirts we had ordered
for our party affiliates.
Yes sis, they have arrived.
How much?
One lakh sis.
But sis, I have a doubt.
All our affiliates,
Including the PA system
guys, tea vendor
and cotton candy seller
don’t make 4 thousand
Then why did we order one lakh T-shirts?!
If we make coalition negotiations
as per party attendance,
We won’t even account for the
amount spent on our letter pad
We have to show a mass following!
Get everyone to wear our party’s T-shirt!
Sis, nobody can beat your brilliance!
Get me a sample of the T-shirts!
Sis, the samples you asked for.
What, you are so quick today?!
What Ekambaram?
I asked for T-shirts in the colour of our
party flag, but you have got it separate?!
Sis, it is Rs.40 per piece
for a single colour.
But Rs.60 for double colour.
That is why I said print single colours.
Both the colours are here sis.
What is it?
Even your stupidity has helped us out!
These fans who come to
watch a cricket match,
Dress in the colours of the national flag.
Will they all wear the same colour?
No sis.
One will wear white, one green
and the other saffron, right?!
But when you look at it from a
distance it’s the national flag.
Delhi is a bit distant.
And if you say it is our party
T-shirt nobody will wear it.
Give the to shirts these marathon runners
cricket players and football players.
If it is free, they will
eat curry with a sweet.
That is our people.
When we look from afar our
party flag will be visible!
- Okay?
- Okay sis!
40 lakhs would have been a loss.
Somehow I escaped!
My sister is ready with the money in hand.
Looks like I will have
to lick my wounds again.
You will get eight lakhs
right, take it and be happy.
She gives eight lakhs
she will get the house,
I had give the eight lakhs
I will get the house.
House that is worth 40 lakhs will
be worth 4 crores in four years!
They married me off to this
sincere police officer
and ruined my life!
If you ask for eight lakhs all of a
Sudden, where will I get the money?
Those who joined duty along with you
have houses all over the
suburbs of Chennai.
They also have a wife
each one of those houses,
should I also follow suit?
Person who doesn’t know how to
cut has thousands of lives!
You haven’t yet done anything
with the house you have!
Hey!
Yeah, sit silently.
I’ve had enough of your mastery in bed!
Now show your mastery in
getting me this house!
I don’t care!
You can do whatever you want,
I need eight lakh rupees in the next week.
Look here...
The food that we eat the clothes that
you wear and the house that we live in,
and the respect you get
when you go outside.
All of this is because of this uniform.
I cannot betray it!
You may not betray it!
But I am not like you!
You are my patience has a limit.
There are many who salivate
at aunties like me,
If I only raise my eyebrows and
look at them, that is enough.
Don’t think I am joking here.
I will divorce and leave you!
Don’t talk about justice
and righteousness with me!
Learn to live as the world is!
All in all, be a man!
You don’t know any other way
to prove your manhood, right?
Why can’t you give me the 8 lakhs
and prove your manhood?!
You want the money right?
Go!
Hello,
Sis, Judhani has made his move.
Tonight your house will be raided!
All our accounts are squared up, right?
Everything is perfect!
We have done everything legally sis.
Sis,
Builder Nidhirajan’s 22 has
not yet been laundered.
It is still in the godown,
But it won’t be a problem.
Ekambaram,
It’s not just our house,
They will raid the house
of the illicit wife
of the nephew of our servant!
They should not find the money.
When they are in the godown
we will bring it to the house,
When they check the house we
will put it back in the godown!
There is something in what you just said.
Okay sis.
If we put the money in a vehicle and
let it roam it won’t be caught right?!
What is the police catch
it in night checking?
It must be a vehicle that
the police won’t search.
Super idea sis!
We will put it in your car and let it roam.
It is the central minister’s car,
Who will dare to check it?!
Get a vehicle that puts cash in ATMs.
Put two party workers and
tell them to roam all night!
Ask them to return in the morning
Sis, what if they run away with the money!
Don’t tell them it is money!
Tell them his documents.
Okay sis
They must be my diehard fans at the
same time they must be complete fools.
Sis there are many fools in our party.
Where will I find diehard fans?
Okay sis.
This is your evening show RJ Shiva,
Just like in international football match
Your local private league
match score is 2 each
Let us go for a small
commercial break, stay tuned!
Hey!
As this team always loses to us,
I want all my wife’s jewellery
and everything on this game.
You don’t worry bro; I
will get you the victory!
Please don’t try to do anything!
There is only two minutes left.
Just run here and there while that happens.
Already the score is 2-2
Why the hell did you call me 100 times?!
I only put you in this game
because I don’t have other players.
I don’t have any substitutes!
Is this any way to run a club?!
You don’t even have a proper Jersey!
That way jersey wearers are your opponents
colour dress are your teammates
Please just go and play.
Are you some international coach?!
To always keep your coolers on, remove it!
I have Madras eye, is that okay?!
Thank you.
Hey don’t do it!
What is this?
Why?!
Sorry bro...
Forget it bro,
Winning and losing is a part of the game.
Morning manager fired from the job.
The evening we lost the game.
That’s okay,
Let’s celebrate.
Like this?
Change over.
"Yellow shirt, green shirt
Yellow shirt, green shirt."
"Yellow shirt,"
"Green... green, green shirt"
"Yellow shirt. Green...
green, green shirt."
Brother,
Yes sir,
‘For sister, I will give my life!’
Do a performance to
emote this feeling
Start,
Do you know who sister is?!
Do you know the meaning of sister?!
Do you know love of a sister?!
Which serial do you work in brother?
‘Love Roots’ sir, I come and
drink tea in one scene!
Hello sir.
‘For sister I will give my life’
do a performance for this feeling.
Sir, can I get a stick?
Hey, Madurai is famous for Jasmine
sister is famous for being the best.
He will fight 10 people all by himself!
Will you come?
Come, let us see...
They are calling the next in line.
"Yellow shirt, green shirt
Yellow shirt, green shirt."
‘For sister I will give my life’
come with this feeling.
What? Sis, is in trouble"
Nobody has done this till now,
Do you like sister so much?!
Okay, leave it!
I am going to trouble
you just a little bit!
Do you think you can trouble us?!
I have finally found the correct fools!
What happened to the Ward
president’s house robbery case?
They are suspecting the vice president sir.
Get the role call book and the
duty list and come to my cabin.
Sir.
How many men are there on duty right now?
Sir it is in the duty register,
Where are Dass and head constable?
As per usual they said
they would go on beat
But are playing cards
behind the building, sir.
Ask them to come and meet me.
Okay sir.
Sir?
I have brought them here.
Sir, greetings sir.
What were you doing behind the building?!
Sir, we were getting ready to go on a beat.
It’s been 27 years since you joined duty.
Have you ever caught a single case.
You sign on as joint investigator
in somebody else’s case.
Sir, I am not doing it on purpose!
I even said that police is your friend.
Still they ran as soon as they see me.
I will do one thing,
I will tell all criminals to
commit crimes in the station itself!
You, crime is prevalent everywhere!
Couldn’t you solve even
one case of among those,
Can’t you you will learn
from the media people,
In Konampettai, a goat gave
birth for the first time.
He filled a slot with this news.
Even if you had 25% of his dedication,
you would have caught a case by now.
To solve a case...
there should be a complaint first.
Can I go to every home and ask
Are your children safe?
Are your cattle and pets safe?
Has your husband returned safely from work?
Is anybody threatening you.
Has there been any theft?
Can you go and ask them all of this?
All you can do is talk like this!
Don’t you dare solve a case.
I will give you one weeks time,
If you don’t solve a strong case?
Disobedience
and unfit for service
I will write you up to higher officials.
You have only four years
of service left, so beware!
You Dass!
Sir...
Stop spending time with this man.
Okay sir.
I am doing this for your good, go now!
Hey,
Did you rat me out, because
I earn more bribes than you.
Come outside, I will take care of you!
Sir, sir... head constable sir!
I am in service for this many years
without knowing how to solve a case?!
If I start to solve cases.
This station wouldn’t be able to stand it!
Boss, is this the bag
that has dead bodies in it.
Has sister done any murders lately?!
Sush!
Stupid bugger, it is full of documents.
It is the immovable assets of the party!
If these documents are found in the raid...
Sister will lose all respect and honour!
Your mission is to,
Drive around in the vehicle all night!
Till I call you in the morning,
you have to keep this safe.
Not only that!
You should never open the
bag while you are traveling!
Swear on the lighter’s flame.
What, don’t they usually
swear on camphor flame?
Why, won’t you swear
on the lighter’s flame?
Close it
Have you had anything to drink?
No sir!
Blow...
Shit!
What, is he drunk?
Sir, his breath stinks!
- Hey, go on!
- Go!
Head it’s the police!
Don’t open your mouth,
else we will be caught.
Blow,
Hey, I am telling you to blow!
Sir, he cannot speak.
Sorry bro.
Where are you going?
Oh, is this a bank vehicle!
Go on go!
They look like proper thieves!
Many cash department guys look like that.
What can we do?
Head, just miss. If only we
had drunk like we regularly do!
If I had blonde he would have fainted!
- Head...
- Tell me hand!
We haven’t eaten anything
because we didn’t drink today!
Since we have a night duty,
we will get hungry later!
We need money, look
for an ATM up-ahead!
Okay..!
Hey...
I want to drink a lot,
then I want to gag
and throw it all up!
What do you want now?!
You want to hate her
that’s it right?
Then get married to her,
automatically you will hate her!
Really, will I become better?
Only when we are half mad,
We will have doubts
if we are mad or normal.
If you go completely mad,
we will never realise that we are mad!
She didn’t even look at me for six
years while I worked in that office!
When I was leaving she
came and spoke to me!
That means she is in
love with me, right?
Hey...
where did she speak to you?
She gave the money to me!
Okay...
Did you put the money in
the cash deposit machine?!
No bro!
Come quickly!
Come, come!
Don’t allow anyone inside or out,
Sir, we are from CBI.
Please go to the side
and cooperate with us.
Sir we are from CBI,
this is an investigation of income tax!
I know!
Hey, they are here!
Start the agitation in the market!
It should be thunderous.
Hey...
are you sure!
Fully!
This ATM doesn’t
have a security guard!
The EMP is on.
No cameras in a 35m radius will work
Sir, greetings sir.
How many times have I told you?
You should not have
your shop after 9 PM!
Mutton Biryani with piece is there sir!
Last time you gave me a lot of bones,
My teeth were aching so much!
Put some big juicy pieces and pack it!
It’s the inspector.
Talk and ask what he wants.
Sir, tell me sir.
Head constable, where are you?
We are on beat in the market!
Near the market roundabout some
political party agitation is going on.
Immediately go and see to it?
Okay sir!
What did he say?
Okay, you get the biryani parcel.
I will go and see what is
happening in the roundabout!
You carry on, I will take care.
Hey,
make an half boiled egg!
Okay sir, surely!
Hey somebody is coming here!
Hey, it is the bank’s staff!
Do you have the ATM card?
Is the AC working?
Hey, just a minute!
Head, look down the door is open!
Cover your face quickly!
You sinners!
They are robbing the ATM!
If I am caught, that’s it for me!
I should go and get Dass!
Head, hurry hurry, quickly!
It’s the police, act normal!
Hey,
two men are robbing an ATM over there
It is the big case we need, come quickly!
What are you saying head constable sir!
Head constable sir,
don’t you want to the biryani?!
Hey!
If I see your shop here tomorrow!
When I saw inside one guy was wearing a
yellow T-shirt and one in a green T-shirt
They had open the ATM and
were taking the money out!
Immediately I got afraid!
Finally we got this big case!
I am sure to become
a sub-inspector Dass!
For having trusted you...
I lost a good Biryani!
Turn the vehicle around!
I am telling you
such a serious matter,
The ATM machine is open,
there is a bank van outside,
That means the bank staff is
there to fill cash into the machine!
and you are a mumbling that they were
robbing the ATM, turnaround I say!
What Dass...
does this mean God has made
another April fool of me?
First turn the vehicle around!
Shit, how did our plan fail?!
Are you sure you didn’t
leave any evidence behind?
Pendrive?!
Pendrive is in the laptop right?
Hey, it has my complete info!
Bro going back for it is a very big risk!
100% we will be caught!
If you leave the pen drive there
200% we will be caught!
Come.
These bank staffers are so dedicated!
They are working in
the middle of the night!
I guess they too are like us.
What? Is a bone stuck in your throat?
The cash delivery service people...
Who put money into the ATM machines...
are you supposed to only work before 6 PM?
There must be some emergency today.
Even I doubted those two were in the ATM.
Also the only security
force person wasn’t there!
Won’t I feel doubt?!
Oh my God!
Hey, God. I am sorry I am drunk...
Do you know if there is
a cash deposit machine here?
You’ll only know if you go and see.
Hey, the ATM is open.
That is a good thing right?!
You fool, look the ATM
machine is open like this!
Definitely somebody has
tried to rob the ATM,
Come let us go.
Didn’t I tell you?!
Yellow shirt and green shirt!
- It’s the police!
- They are caught!
Then, have you taken all the money?!
Sir, we came to deposit money sir.
How much?
Rs.80,000 sir. 40,000 each!
See they have followed government
regulations even while stealing!
Take the money out,
Sir it belongs to a friend!
Oh!
So you divide the shares here itself?
Take the money out!
I need that to patch
up with my lover sir.
Oh to patch up with your lover...
You have to rob an ATM
and give the money to her?!
Sure, no sir...
Dass, put the bike up here.
They deserve...
Sir, I came to deposit the cash.
Hey, we never went inside.
Sir, sir!
- Sir, we didn’t do anything!
- I can see it in your face clearly!
Sit here.
Hey, start the auto.
Move
Wait Dass.
Hello...
Sir, a big incident has happened!
And we caught the accused red-handed.
Sure, I am not an accused...
Don’t talk while I am talking!
What is happening over there?
It is an ATM robbery sir.
There’s two of them.
They have clearly broken in
and taken the cash sir.
Which ATM?
The B.O.B ATM near the market!
Have you apprehended the criminal.
Yes we have sir!
We have recovered the money
Now we are securely transporting
the accused to the station!
Please tell him sir!
Shut up!
How much cash did you get?
More or less, around 80 sir
80 lakhs?
Sir 80 thousand, sir.
To hell with you and your...
What kind of a robbery cases is this?!
Set aside 40 from that 80!
Sir, is this really you?!
Head Constable, we should
live as per the world.
Rightly said sir!
Sir, also the other thing is...
I couldn’t go to the riot!
Sorry sir
Leave it, don’t go there!
There is an IT raid on the
central minister’s home,
You have got a big case
for the very first time,
Come to the station,
we will talk about it.
- Okay?
- Okay sir!
Hey, take a 407 with you...
Whoever is there where
the riot is happening,
Round them all up and bring
them to the station.
Dass...
Head Constable sir!
They said we can never solve a case.
What a great case we have got!
Let us go and show
everyone in the station!
Yes, let us!
Dass,
I forgot my cap at the biryani stall.
You keep forgetting everything.
Hey don’t tease me!
Did you get it?
Yes I got it, you go!
Sir, sir. I haven’t done anything sir.
Why don’t you listen to me sir!
Sir, sir.
Sir, please no!
Sir, I will burn myself right here.
Sir!
Hey...
You look a baby elephant!
Is this much for today enough for you?!
Head writer sir, please take down the
statement from both those ATM robbers.
Sir! We haven’t done
any robberies!
There is a murder case,
would you prefer that?
Sir?!
What are you saying sir?!
What is your problem?!
Sure, the Ashram people
took my wife away...
After she’s gone there she’s
making nonsensical videos!
Please somehow rescue and
return my wife to me!
So it’s gone, it’s gone right?!
After all of this what
will you do with her?!
Dass, check their pockets
and remove anything in it.
Why sir...?
Come on empty your pockets!
What is he saying?
Hey, tomorrow we will have to
take the accused to the court.
We will need petrol for that,
so take this and use it!
But petrol is mine sir.
Hey, when your life is not yours anymore.
What will you do with this?
Go on, get out of here!
Sir!
Keep this aside!
What are you thinking?
Person and other things.
Hey, send that guy out of the station!
Don’t shout come quietly!
Long-live sister!
Both of your remove your dress.
Remove it.
Sir...
Quickly, remove it!
Why sir!
Down with IT raid,
Long-live Sister!
Down with IT raid!
Hey what is your problem?!
Is IT companies come from somewhere else,
and are turning our people into slaves.
Yes sir,
They have brought us
to the police station.
Completely wreak the station!
Okay sir!
- Hey, you are an activist right?!
- Yes!
You think information technology
people are conducting the raid?!
Police brutality towards common people,
must be stooped immediately!
Down with Police!
Corrupt Police be damned!
Silence, silence! Go and protest in
front of the house that is raided!
Bring the inspector here!
Police have to answer to us!
Send the inspector to stop the raid!
If you keep making a ruckus
I will put you all in the cell!
Be quiet everyone.
Move!
To protest the police brutality
I am going to set myself on fire!
Hey stop!
Let go of me!
Down with police brutality!
Listen to me!
Corrupt and unjust police
department must be damned!
Let go of me!
Let me go!
Give that fuel can hear!
Move... Hello!
What is that ruckus?
Sir the protesters we arrested, are
making a huge riot in the station!
Hey I told you not to do anything!
Police brutality!
Beat and send everyone outside!
Police brutality be damned!
Lathi Charge!
Good thing they all are now gone!
What, the entire station is empty?!
Sir, I have kept the 40
thousand in your drawer!
The rest I have kept in the safe.
Where are the accused?!
They’re sitting here outside sir!
Why haven’t you put them in the cell?
The cell is full!
Where are they?
Where did they go?
Where, I don’t know!
Sir,
Where are the accused?
Sure, the bank manager is here.
Please come sir!
Constable, check all the
CCTV cameras near the ATM!
The robbers must have been
caught on at least one of them.
One person cannot do this alone.
You told me on the phone you have
arrested the robbers already!
I only told you that the
robbery had happened!
You sure it was two people!
Yes, head constable and
constable had been there.
Those are the two I mentioned.
Then who robbed...
Do you know who robbed the ATM?!
No sir, you proceed with the case sir.
How much cash did you recover sir!
40 thousand sir!
We only found 40,000 in the ATM machine,
How much balance does your account show!
13 lakhs and 80 thousand sir,
13.8 lakhs!
What sir, they say there is no
money in the ATM machines?
Are you trying to do a side hustle?!
Sir I am an honest man!
Come sir, let us talk in private!
I too am an honest inspector.
I will file the FIR for 13 lakhs!
Six lakhs for you and six lakhs for me!
Deal okay?
The deal would be nice but,
We can only do that if we had 13 lakhs.
We only have 40 thousand!
I said mean you are really lost 13 lakhs.
Yes sir, 13 lakhs 80 thousand sir!
Okay, you please wait inside.
Head constable...
What head constable, how can you
want to pocket all the 13 lakhs?!
I am still your senior officer right?!
8 and 5.
8 for me 5 for you.
Sir, I swear I did not take it!
Sir the CCTV footage is here.
Okay, these are the thieves!
Please wait there for a minute.
What, there are two accused in the video!
There too were wearing yellow
shirt and green shirt sir!
So you have given the 13 lakhs
to them and sent them away!
Sir,
I am completely innocent sir.
Now you have two options head constable
Option 1,
Aiding a robbery,
Miss using the uniform and
Letting the accused escape.
and a total of 13 cases will be filed
and I will safely send you to jail!
Option 2,
Get me the 13 lakhs that you have stolen!
I will give you five lakhs from that!
Who did the work and who is profiting?
I will even recommend you for a promotion!
Sir...
Choice is yours.
I am innocent sir.
I have four more years of service.
Don’t cost me, my pension sir.
When did I cost you anything?!
You are the one who is costing himself.
The state government has already
cost us all do you know this?!
Go on.
This way!
Dass...
Dass!
Sir...
Out!
Station is empty.
Manager!
Yes sir!
We will arrest the accused within 48 hours
You can leave for now.
I too should somehow
get a seat on the bus.
Tea stall lady, put two glasses of tea.
Head, what you are reading newspapers!
Do you know how to read?
Do I need a medical degree to
look at Nayantara’s photos?!
A B.O.B ATM has been burglarized!
A man in a yellow shirt and another in a
green shirt are clearly seen during the robbery!
Brother, brother...
your tea?!
Where did they go?
Hey,
I never thought that our
lives would end this early!
I haven’t even begun to live.
Hey what did we do wrong?
What did you guys say?
We won’t be able to get
liquor from Pondicherry!
Now see how I have brought it here.
You are amazing bro!
We can drink inside the
police vehicle itself
We can even have a party in it!
You are superb bro!
Thank you for everything!
We’re meaning to hiring
a shooting vehicle.
Hey, who are you?
What work do you have here?
Sorry grandpa...
we came to take a piss.
No no, you should not come here.
we are very good boys grandpa.
We are not ATM robbers!
I don’t care who you are!
I will break your head open.
Go,
go!
Hey...
We cannot go back into the city.
Our news is out on TV.
Hey,
We need to get through tonight,
we should hide somewhere somehow!
Okay come.
Hey wait! There is another vehicle...
Hey, who are you?
Sir.
What work do you have here?
No no!
You should not come here
I don’t care who you go
I will break your head open.
Go...
go!!!!
Sir,
Sir!
Its me.
Yes, it’s me
Is it you?
I have brought you food.
- Is it food sir?
- Yes
You go sir,
You please leave
I will take care of
everything, you please go.
Please go sir.
Please go.
What sir, you have put a blind and deaf man as
security for this property under litigation.
He’s like a snake,
he is blind and deaf
But you will not let
anybody know about it.
The dialogue his speaks
will match everybody.
and since he looks terrifying
Nobody will dare enter.
He is the best option for this property.
Okay come, let’s go.
Bro, the bike is gone.
Hey, who are you?
What work do you have here?
No no, you shouldn’t come here!
I don’t care who you are,
I will break your head open, go!
Go...!
"Yellow shirt, green shirt
Yellow shirt, green shirt"
Bro, is all of this liquor bro?
Hey be careful with that!
Close it.
Bro come here for a second,
If I leave it with the boys
they will finish it at once.
You bring it to the Marriage
Hall tomorrow evening.
Hey why are you crying?
Get lost.
You are always peeing through the eyes.
and still there is water shortage everywhere.
Head constable...
My father got me this job,
by borrowing four lakhs for the bribe.
Do you know what he told
me when I joined duty?
Hey Dass,
Two months after you get this job,
Please pay of this debt.
Because I am joined with
you I have become useless!
What, six lakhs in two months?!
Dass, I have completed 27 years of service.
I have never seen this
amount in my entire life!
You are cheap bugger!
Why are you comparing me to you?
Okay come let us drink some
tea and think about it!
Give us two glasses of tea.
Sir, we are out of milk.
I will pay you for it just
give us two glasses of tea.
Dass
If we catch those too hardened crooks...
Then all of our problems will be solved.
How are you going to catch them?
And that too within 48 hours.
Don’t worry about it!
Before leaving the station I cut a coin
as an offering to Ara Kaasu Amman!
We will find them very soon.
You and your...!
Believe me Dass!
Just like this, I lost
my mobile one day.
Then my wife gave me this idea.
She said pray to Ara Kaasu Amman
and you will find your mobile,
I found it that very day!
Where was it!
When I finished my duty, I
forgot it in the station itself.
Play that you lost the yellow
shirt and green shirt guys
in the station itself!
Do you remember that?
What sir, are you trying to
solve the ATM robbery?
You should only do
tea stall related work.
Do you understand?
You are looking for the red yellow
shirt and green shirt guys no sir?!
They showed the CCTV
footage on the news no sir!
We are looking for some other
yellow shirt and green shirt guys!
Curly hair, fair skin
Just a little fat,
They came and drank tea here sir.
Dass, I told you right!
It is all the doing of Ara Kaasu Amman!
What else do you know?
Look at this sir!
Was this photo posted by your friend?
Ask for his phone number.
Why do you need the phone number?
To trace their location.
Oh God!
Look at this!
‘Old Marriage Hall Bus Stop’
Dass, come quickly!
What kind of police are they?!
Dass, Ara Kaasu Amman didn’t
abandon us, we got the location!
He has nothing on the outside
of his head, nor on the inside.
The correct location,
look at that board.
Hey, who are you?
Hey, we are the police!
What work do you have here?
We have come for rounds.
No no, you should
not come here.
Hey, you’re talking too much!
We are police!
I don’t care who you are
I will break open your head!
Go away!
Oh my god, save me!
Run away Dass.
Dass,
Head constable sir,
he doesn’t fear police!
He must be a big time rowdy!
He could even be mad!
That is even more dangerous!
Dass, please go and get the bike.
Me?!
Please go and get it.
I will go.
I am not even married.
Head constable sir, for
sure they are not here!
How can you be so sure?
They have looted 13 lakhs.
Will they be here in this
mosquito infested place?
By now they would have
booked a room somewhere
I would have made some setup
They would be jolly in an AC room.
Hey,
tomorrow they will put us in the jail.
Hey wash your mouth with soap.
By the time we went there the
ATM machine was already open.
We haven’t stolen anything!
Why do things like this
keep happening to us?
Sir, what have you recovered in your raid?
No comments.
Sir rumour is that, there are
ulterior motives for this raid
Look here!
We came to my house in the middle of
the night and have trashed the place,
Ask them what they found?
Yes sir, please tell us what you found
You run a train like scroll reading
‘IT raid at Paagambariya’s House’
Now ask them.
Sir tell us what you found.
No comments.
Yeah ‘no comments’ I will tell you!
All they will ever find in
my house is some spices.
I will boldly claim that they didn’t find
anything, let them contradicted it.
Nowadays IT department,
and vigilance are acting like hired guns.
People say that do not want project welfare
I am only echoing their voices,
In four months there will be an election.
Nobody who has opposed me has even
recovered their deposit. Why is that?
Because I am in the hearts of the people.
To defeat Paagambariya
that too in his own fort.
They must first take him out
of the hearts of the people.
Hence they are making many plans.
I will never support project welfare!
More than this political seats,
I will cherish the seat I
hold in people’s hearts.
That is more than enough for me.
Opposing the IT raids on central
minister Paagambariya’s home,
His supporters outcry and people’s
support has risen strongly!
35 years’ political experience Mr Judhani!
Just holding 12 percentage vote bank,
You need exceptional strength to hold
onto a seat in five elections.
Go, go and watch all the TV networks.
I am converting the IT raid that
you planned into my strength!
Though the entire country,
Is ready to oppose this project.
When the concerned department’s
minister opposes it.
There is no bigger
sensation for the media.
revolution for the people.
Trending,
Trending in all forms of media!
Paagambariya is today’s victory mantra.
A true politician is who makes
his weakness is his strength!
The IT raid was not meant to catch you,
I know that isn’t possible.
It was just to show you that
Judhani’s reach can shake
up the IT department.
Though the elephant is very big.
The smallest ant can trouble it!
Beware maybe there is an ant
that is out there looking for you?
Tonight a private bank’s ATM
was burglarised in Retro Nagar.
Two men wearing a yellow shirt and a green shirt are
clearly seen stealing money from the ATM machine.
Every elephant will have an ant Judhani.
Hey, what is this?
It’s like asking the
fox to guard the sheep!
Instead of two fools you have selected two
criminals and handed over 22 crores to them.
There is no chance of that sis,
both of them are complete fools!
I might find it hard to
recognise intelligence,
I will easily identify fools!
It’s like birds of a feather.
Something wrong has happened sis!
You are right Ekambaram,
When they have 22 crores if
they have gone to rob an ATM...
They are truly fools!
It is believed that this was orchestrated
by corporate broker Dilip Judhani,
#Paagambariya4CM is trending worldwide.
After these many years in politics,
I have earned a lot of money Ekambaram,
but a place in people’s hearts
every politician dreams of that throne.
That is why we all fight!
Please sacrificing this money is
the only way I will get power
I will do that.
Today people see me as an idol of
honesty, we should not damage that!
The money, those two boys and
no evidence should survive!
Finish them!
I have just hit the Jackpot!
What sir...?
She is actually a foreigner sir.
I know what the problem is
and I know how serious it is.
That is why I called you.
Sir is not joke, it’s an embassy issue!
But you are the DCP.
Everything is under your control.
It’s not that I can’t do it...
The more zeroes you put after one,
that will determine the entirety.
How much do you need?
It is only a murder if they find the body.
Otherwise she is just missing,
Who did she come with?
Personal call.
Whose number?
Fake number.
Did you get the phone?
Yes, I did.
CCTV?
Then do one thing, delete that feed
and lock it up for maintenance.
I will take care of the rest.
Come, how are you?
I have got a body,
Your job is to chop it up
and feed it to the fishes.
You are talking to Jailkodi Prabhakaran.
Even God will not be able to find her.
Just send the body over.
I will.
Paagambhariya is like a tiger,
he is very dangerous.
One of my ants is out there,
You better take care of it.
Hey Ashok!
Head constable,
We sometimes look for a white goat in
the ditch while it is on our shoulder
With everything that you have told me,
I have realised who the black sheep is!
You said we were looking for a white goat?!
Many times a white goat is a black sheep!
You are only thinking with
the scenes that you saw.
I am going to tell you a
scene that you haven’t seen.
It’s the Inspector,
Talk to him and ask what he wants.
Sir, tell me sir...
Where are you?
Sir we are on beat in the
market both me and Dass.
Ma.Na.Ka party people are protesting
in the market go and have a look.
Okay sir.
Those buggers will come this way.
Go and stand there
so that they see you.
But why should he make
them be seen by me?
Then how will you get a sacrificial
lamb for the ATM robbery!
Why did he select us for that?
Because you both are the
nly f 'n' fs he knows
Don’t get angry, it
means fumbling fools
Sorry, I misunderstood you. Continue,
What sir, he went away?
All he does is screw up.
They will come back,
you wait for them.
Now tell me where the money is.
In Inspector’s house.
Wow, you think like a CBI officer.
It’s because of the many serials I see.
Let that be,
You know what you have
to do next right?!
You have only seen
Annamalai as your friend,
Now you will see Annamalai is your enemy!
Hello sir.
Come, come.
Kareem Bhai,
sit down.
Sir, my name is not Kareem Bhai.
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian.
What is your problem?
Rajinikanth, Kamala Hassan,
what does it matter what I call you?
Other than you, is there anybody else here?
But that is not my name sir,
My name is Karimel Thunjiya Pandian,
What does that mean?
A Pandian who died fighting
a war on elephant back.
Someone died of an
elephant that’s it right?!
Sir please call me Kareem Bhai,
This is the matter...
Yesterday we gave all of sister’s
documents to 2 crackpots
and sent them out.
Those documents should safely return to me.
and those two crackpot should not live.
Also they have robbed an ATM
That is a plus for you.
Kill them in an encounter
and get a promotion.
Whatever I need to do I will.
Whatever you need just ask for it.
If it is an encounter, I can surely do it.
The robbery case is also with me.
Just give me 8.
If I take 8 out of 22, 18 is left.
It is a high price,
I will give you 8 crores.
What happened?
It slipped.
This is the first time
you are slipping in life.
Make sure to get this done secretively.
and the documents must come to my hand.
I will get it done sir.
All the best!
"Where else can I search for this money?"
"I mean, where else can I
search for this money?"
"Where else can I search for this money?"
"I mean,"
"where else can I search for this money?"
"Another form of God is,"
"the money we carry around with us."
"Another form of"
"the God up there is,"
"the money we carry around with us."
"A fool can become a king with money."
"Every sin is washed away with money."
"Even a sage wants this money,"
"The government can be
shook by this money... I mean,"
"where else can I search"
"for this money? I mean,"
"where else can I search for this money?"
"Cash only is God here,"
"Even God needs that cash dear."
"You need to put cash in the hundi."
"Also a special ticket scam you know."
"Every charity donation and gift comes to"
"currency circulation deal!"
I am not opposing temples,
I am opposing temples
being home to evil men
"If you want any position, just give cash"
"I want power, show currency notes."
"Even if you want to love, so some money."
"To get the votes, spread the notes."
"What is heaven and what is hell?"
"If you have a lot of money
then you are God everywhere."
He will ready that money dad.
Okay dear,
Whatever it is he is a man.
I have touched every nerve
that I shouldn’t have touched.
Please tell him to do it quickly.
For me wait just for a month dad.
I am hearing an echo in your voice,
where are you?
I am talking from inside
the bathroom dad.
Why, are you not feeling well?
It’s not that dad.
This is the only place I
get signal in this house.
Please ask him to do it quickly.
That I think he’s here, cut the call
I’ll call you back later
What brother, you are here at this time?!
What dear...
just because I am a head constable, you’re not
even going to invite me inside the house right?!
That’s okay.
Oh no, what are you saying?
Please come inside.
Hey, what are you doing?
Get that chair.
Don’t struggle just sit here silently.
Hey what are you doing?
Get the rope Dass.
Hello...
hello, head constable.
What is it?
We know everything about who
stole the money and where it is.
Where have you been?
I am at your house!
Now your wife is in our custody.
We immediately want the money
and those two criminals!
He has nothing sir.
Now you can’t hear anything is it?!
Cut the call.
I will call you back!
Sir, your phone is on.
Hello...
I don’t understand why he
calls me why I cut the call...
Kariya has to come to this house.
The money must be somewhere here.
We will wait for him.
Bro,
in the morning our faces
will be seen everywhere.
Hello Banu,
Whom did I ever hurt Banu.
I fell in love.
The girl I love hates me.
I want to deposit money for her,
and got caught up in an ATM robbery
Tomorrow I am going to jail for her Banu,
But I don’t know if she will
ever understand all of this
Where the hell are you, you buffalo?!
I will share the location Banu,
Please come and rescue me Banu, please!
Who told him, he robbed the ATM?
I am hand, I am head,
Is that your real name?
Oh no, no!
I am Elvis Presley and I am Bob Marley.
Oh!
So this is actually their problem.
They are thinking of themselves
as Elvis Presley and Bob Marley.
Sir, tea.
Come here.
Sir,
Head constable brought
two accused here right?
Yes sir.
Did you see them?
Yes sir, I saw them.
Are they the same to you guys here?
It’s not them sir, they are different.
Can you identify them?
I surely can.
Go and check all the CCTV
cameras near our station,
If you find any footage
of them bring it here.
Okay sir.
Go.
So the 2 men on camera
are actually insane.
Head constable and Dass
do not have any courage.
Also they are fools.
Then who are those two that
the head constable brought here.
The two of them are
the master minds here.
Sir, I got it.
This footage is from KRC Jewellers
and it is the both of them.
Now I have to hunt them down.
'Intermission'
Ekambaram bag and the ATM robbery
are definitely related.
Why did the crazies with
the bag rob the ATM?
How did the mastermind come into this?
How did they never get registered
on the CCTV camera?
Why is Ekambaram so desperate
to make a deal?
Is that a diversion?
The bag is everybody’s cool.
What is in the bag?
Hey, who are you?
Thannoli... Thannoli...?!
No, no...
you should not come here.
I have to see him.
I am Bhanumathi.
I don’t care who you are.
I will break your head open.
Go away, go!
Banu... Banu!
Banu, I have not robbed the ATM Banu!
They mistakenly arrested me.
Where is my 80 thousand?
Who is that?
I will tell you that later, come.
Hey, who are you?
What work do you have here?
No no, you should not come here.
I don’t care who you are.
I will break your head open.
Go away,
Go!
Do you know we got caught stealing?
Who told you that you robbed the ATM?
They said it in the news.
Look, they are the robbers.
The news is only showing their face.
Hey fool! I told you it wasn’t us.
You are the first to run
away from the tea stall.
Okay bro, come let’s go
and fight with the police.
Hey you brainless buffoon!
Can a young woman go to the police
station in the middle of the night?
Okay I’ll go and sleep.
Thanks for coming as soon
as I asked you to rescue me.
Oh no, I didn’t come for that.
I came for my 80 thousand.
Get lost.
Hey,
How many times can I come
looking for your love?
I’m getting bored of doing
it again and again.
What, you came looking for my love?
Every time I came looking for you!
I came and gave you 80,000
when you lost the job.
I thought you would use
that to get me back.
You blundered that as well!
Okay, go to sleep.
I have to think of something.
Good night.
"A bird that forgot to fly
has spread its wings"
"It painted it wings in the
colour of dreams and flew away"
"In the scorching desert"
"a beautiful new garden blooms"
"The thirst of the ocean"
"is satisfied by a few dew drops"
"The forest burns in a raging fire"
"A bunch of clouds now fall on the earth"
"the roots of love are drenched"
"in the season’s first rain"
"As thunder mimics the child’s first words."
"The inner eyes have lost sight"
"of the ever-changing heart,"
"Just for a few seconds"
"I feel like denying it all"
"You are killing me"
"by giving dreams to both my eyes"
"and add a little bit of
honey and little fire to it."
"The running time pauses for a little while"
"my heart now runs to the beat of love"
"The lips conjure"
"these beautiful lines"
"and completely change"
"where my life resides"
"To trap your fingers"
"in-between my fingers"
"Even this distance"
"feels so sweet now"
"All over my body your eyes travel"
"as though you consume me with your sight"
"In the hot fire my body shrivels down"
"Now light as a feather it rolls over"
"A bird that forgot to fly
has spread its wings"
"It painted it wings in the
colour of dreams and flew away"
"In the scorching desert
a beautiful new garden blooms"
"The thirst of the ocean
is satisfied by a few dew drops"
"The forest burns in a raging fire"
"A bunch of clouds now fall on the earth"
Look here, your crying
is of no use here.
I still want to save you.
You know very well,
this investigation was
ordered by the minister.
National party are discussing coalitions,
When I sit for the meeting,
those two ants should be no more.
Okay sis.
I too am looking for them.
I said don’t be seen by anyone,
now I am not able to see them.
What, water is not coming here!
There is no water where it should be,
but all over the ground there is water
Oh no,
just as I need to go there is no water.
What can I do now?
Okay let me go here.
But it is so dark here.
Many times I don’t have light to eat!
Why do I need it for this?
I am coming.
Come quickly, Kareem Bhai
Why did you call me here,
did you not find any other place?
Nobody will ever come here.
If it stinks so bad who will come here?!
You said it was something urgent.
What, can’t you do it by yourself?!
Sir, as we agreed if I kill those two guys...
your problem won’t be solved.
Two of you are men are
roaming with the documents,
then there is two of our men
and the two who are
controlling these four men!
Only if I kill all the six your
minister will be safe.
So kill them all!
Sir but we only talked about those two.
Think of me as your brother and
please kill all those six guys.
As per the deal I will give you 8 crores,
Sir...!
You won’t get a penny more!
That’s it, as per the deal
you will only get 8 crores.
Oh my God!
This Karimel Thunj and this black face
are making such a big plan.
If I remain a coward,
I will always be poor.
I will come right away!
Hello, why are you calling me at this hour?
Head constable, I can judge by your silence
how much mental torture
you are experiencing!
Can you hear what I am saying?!
You keep silent!
But pay attention to
what I am going to say.
Hey, can you hear me or not?!
The inspector has planned to
encounter both you and Dass.
What, encounter?
Will that Kariya, encounter
and kill on-duty police?
That is why as long as
I am a part of our team,
that inspector cannot do anything to you!
Hey, first cut the call and redial.
How are you able to hear me?!
Are you wondering why
I am calling this our team?
13 lakhs divided by six is 2.3 lakhs
What is divided by seven it is 1.8 lakhs?
Don’t die for the difference amount!
Informer is also very
important, remember that!
Hey, when did we steal that amount?!
We will live by our unity,
but never die by the bullet!
Wait for my next call.
Dass, Karimel knows that
we kidnapped his wife.
How is that possible head constable sir?
He is going to kill us in an encounter.
Head constable Sir!
But his life is in our hands.
Let us see how he manages to kill us.
First we have to pack and move her.
Okay...
Hey Dass! First wrap her up.
You can deal with emotions later.
It’s about to be sunrise.
Go quickly!
Head, there is police everywhere.
We are sure to get caught sooner or later!
We must make sure we are not seen.
Let us stick our heads inside somewhere!
But Hand,
We have promised that we will
drive around the entire night.
That too I have promised on my mummy.
Head, but your mummy is already dead.
Does that mean, I can kill
mummy again and again?!
My God, a face like a snake!
A promise is a promise.
Head,
We made a mistake by stealing, right?
Oh no!
All these big-time crooks have created
a status for thieves everywhere!
Oh my God!
Now we too are men of status, Hand!
Head, why did you stop here?!
The curry is empty!
Hey, who are you?!
We too are poor men like you boss!
What work do you have here?
Boss, the fuel in our vehicle is empty.
That is why, we thought we
can stay here for a day.
No no, you shouldn’t come here!
Please reconsider for us boss.
I don’t care who you are!
I will break open your head. Go...
No...!
Jesus Christ!
Boss, sorry we disturbed you.
This is very important documents boss!
Hello...
Bro everything is safe,
all of the liquor is safe!
You don’t worry I will bring it!
Yes cut the call!
Hi!
What sir, up are you well?!
How can I be well?
What sir, what happened?
It is all about that girl!
But we have already disposed of that body!
Sir there is no trace left!
There is no evidence left!
There are skilled men everywhere,
that is the problem.
Tell me how many zeroes you need after one.
Greetings, today on Truth Seen
we are going to meet...
The party president of Ma.Na.Ka
and central minister Mr. Paagambariya.
Greeting sir.
Greetings.
First question is about
your controversial name.
You are male who has a female name,
Also your party members call
you sister why is this so?
What is controversial about this?
My parents had thought to name
their child after our family deity.
When I was born, they did so.
Because I had a female name...
they initially called me sister to tease me,
but now it is the party’s calling card.
Because you have the name of
a deity from the main caste,
can we consider you as a
religious or caste leader.
Once a child is born
to issue a berth certificate, the government
asks for it’s caste and religion.
So is the government
a religious institution?
A child that is just born,
doesn’t even know the
concept of God or caste!
What sir, they are just going to
apply the father’s religion to it.
Is religion an ancestral property?
You take away the freedom to pray
to any God, and force feed religion.
Once the child grows up it has
the option to change it’s religion.
What about caste?
If we had the option to change
castes it would be so great!
Does this mean you strongly
oppose religion and castes?
I can see, when you ask
questions to a politician,
those questions are framed
in a way to boost TRP!
It’s a competitive field, what can you do?
Politicians talk about politics,
how is it going to be interesting?!
When even other states are praising you,
In the next election, which national party
are you going to have a coalition with?
Ma.Na.Ka will contest as
independent in every constituency
Does this mean you prefer
local self governance?
Now, if we didn’t need
local self governance,
why was this country divided as per
language into so many states?
Not everybody can understand
our culture and customs.
Take a simple issue for example,
in our custom it is usual to
marry maternal cousins.
But in their custom up north, a cousin
is the same as their sister.
They will not be able to understand
all of our customers!
They are not able to.
If they pass a law that cousins
should not marry,
can we go and sit in the
beach to protest that?
Now even that is not possible!
The entire world we are the
only ones to lock up a beach.
Don’t you feel that this
is national separatism.
Which is separatism, to ask for
respect towards customs or to deny it?
In 234 constituencies in the assembly,
and 40 seats in the Parliament.
Makal Nalaachi Kachchi, will contest independently.
(People’s Good Governance Party)
Greetings!
Greetings sir.
As per opinion polls Ma Na Ka,
is leading in 183 constituencies.
Nobody knows what is project welfare,
and those who oppose it get IT raids.
That is the reaction that you will get,
go and look at social media.
You will realise how much support he has.
How long will we trust you,
don’t we need a change for ourselves?
Every party will give us Rs.2000,
we will take and keep it.
But our vote is for Paagambariya.
Looking at the cost of goods, it
would be best if Paagambariya wins.
If the election took place today,
Paagambariya would be the next CM.
Next he is going to win.
Paagambariya.
Only Paagambariya!
My vote is for Paagambariya
Sir,
Sir it is best if he is there.
Okay sir.
What is it?
As usual they are going to
bring some girl and have a party!
So you want to remove the old man.
He is blind and deaf.
He won’t even hear if firecracker next to him.
What is it going to see?
Only we know that they don’t.
I will go and get him.
Hey!
What work did you have here?
You should not come here.
I don’t care who you are.
I will break your head open!
Go!
Sir, sir!
Sir!
Yes it is me it is me.
We will leave for now.
Sir!
Let us go for now.
Get up.
Vasuga...
Get up!
Oh my god!
They shot me they are going to kill me!
Mummy they have shot me!
Sir, sir!
It was all this Thannoli sir!
His Aadhar number is 4321-2223-7173
Sorry bro, bad dreams.
Bad friend!
Where the f is she?!
Your pass time is to play with my life.
Why did you burst the firecracker?
Won’t they have heard the sound outside?
That old man left just right now!
Just because I pitied you and told
the truth you go to sleep like that?
You said you have to go to the
police station in the morning,
what is the time now?
Oh my God!
Is make up very important now?
It is already late come.
Can a young girl go outside
without make up?
Don’t make me use filthy words!
Come let’s go!
Hey take your hand away!
Go.
You go.
Go!
Hey...
we have robbed an ATM!
You are walking so carelessly!
Hey!
Yesterday night she told us to right?
We have not stolen anything!
Hey!
Won’t you ever change?!
"Yellow shirt green shirt.
Yellow shirt green shirt."
He is going to die without
wearing a helmet!
If only he had stopped I could
have fined him Rs.50.
Thanks brother.
Thank you very much.
Sir...
Hello sir.
Hey, why have you come here?
We came to tell the inspector
what the head constable did.
Having done so much already,
why... why... why have you changed?!
Have you forgotten that five others
are dependent on the both of you?!
You must have a plan for that 1.8 lakhs,
Have you forgotten that?!
Did you get scared when you
heard about the encounter?!
What, Encounter?!
Yes,
as soon as he said the six of you
will be killed in an encounter...
Thinking I have taken my
share and left you to die!
My heart slapped me tight twice!
Hey, who are those six people?!
Are you asking who are those six people?!
Once you are asking
only for those six people,
I realise you do not suspect
the seventh one who is me!
The both of you,
Head Constable and Constable,
Come let’s go, come on!
Hey!
Don’t listen to that girl!
Get back in the vehicle, get in fast!
Brother let’s go quickly!
Don’t you dare move this auto!
Brother go!
Hey stop!
- Go quickly.
- Listen to what I am saying, stop!
That Karimel Thunjiya Pandian
plans to kill you by tonight!
Get in!
What did you do with the body?
Am I a government employee
to give you proper documents?!
My word is everything, I will never say!
He won’t talk, let him down!
Get up.
Go inside.
Get inside now.
Let me go.
Safeguard me or lord Kanagavel,
look after me and look out for all evil.
Safeguard me or lord Kanagavel
Hey wait...
Let go of me!
Then let go of the people who stole.
Those ATM robbers should die,
the police who
organised this should die...
Why should I die?
They are going to encounter us along
with that yellow shirt and green shirt!
We are all going to die!
Hey, let me think for sometime.
First go and sit somewhere.
Go, go!
Hand, they have betrayed us.
Now they are going to kill us.
Before that I want to ask him four
questions that will knock him out.
Give me your phone...
My phone is switched off, Head!
So is mine Hand!
Ms. Crood oil.
M S company
Moratta Single.
I too am single.
Talk to me girl.
Head, give me that phone number.
Who is this?
Hello,
we are the super heroes who are
protecting the party’s reputation.
Why are you whispering?
So that nobody else can you hear us.
Boss, why have you sent
the police to encounter and kill us?
So this is completely spoilt!
Hey, how will I do such a thing?
The minister is angry with you
for what you have done.
This plan is to save you from that.
Do you usually have the police
kill someone to save them?!
Hey you fools!
The encounter prime is real,
but that is not for you.
Do one thing,
Return the documents,
and surrender to the police
with the money that you stole.
They will let you escape,
and kill two other men in your place
Yeah we know that much!
How?!
Those two are roaming around here.
Hey, tell me correctly...
tell me where...
Keep quiet.
Dass, it’s a good thing...
The old man isn’t here,
Where else can we take her?!
Success!
Dass, look after her carefully.
Make sure to tie her legs.
I will go and call Karimel,
How hard it is for me to
maintain this phone!
they are hiding here.
Let me go and beat them up!
Hey, they are skilled thieves
It’s very dangerous, don’t do it.
What should we do?
We have to somehow get those 13 lakhs.
Also we must catch them.
If you please sit down,
I will tie your legs.
Please cooperate with me.
You will cooperate, right?
Hey, tell me.
Head constable...?
Hey, head constable!
Either mobile’s signal is weak
Or the mic in your phone is gone.
Since yesterday, whenever
you call it is silent.
Call me from another phone.
All this while I was
calling from this phone!
Oh my God!
The service center boy told me,
not to let sweat seep in.
Insulting!
Sir,
Tell me sir.
What Kareem bhai,
are you playing a double game?!
What are you saying sir?!
They called me up,
Just a minute sir.
Hey, come here.
Sir,
What is the stain on your uniform?
Sir some ink spilt.
Go on.
They called me up,
and asked have you fixed
an encounter for us?
How did they come to know?
How did they know my plans?!
Sir, this is a police game sir.
Let us do our job,
All this while they were absconded,
I soon as I leave this matter
they have come out, see?!
One cannot catch a fish in the dark lake.
You’re a superb policeman!
I have their number,
shall I give it to you?
You can trace it, right?
Yes, tell me sir.
Triple 2, double 7, triple 2
Have you noted it down?
Sir, it looks like a landline number
They seem to have called
you from a phone booth.
Do you will surely call back,
we will catch them!
Catch them and call me.
Dass...
Where will I go for a phone?
Kariya doesn’t know we
have kidnapped his wife.
First you have to let him know.
I need a phone right now!
Ms. Crood...
Kari...!
What Dandapani, there is a
difference in your voice?
What Kari, is it shocking?
You hire someone to steal,
and then pocket the money.
Then you try to blame it on us
And then try to encounter us
Do you think I am
your sacrificial lamb?
I am a lion, a lion!
That is why I have taken away your life!
Bring the 13 lakhs that you stole!
Come and see me!
Let us see if you can kill me
or if I will kill you!
Find out where I am,
Let us play some hide and seek!
He just spoke from the
number that Ekambaram gave.
So, everybody is in the same place.
Dass, I called from the landline,
won't we get caught with a trace?
Why will we be caught? Whose name
the connection is in will be caught!
Yes, you are right!
Dass, she’s trying to say something.
She won’t anything head constable sir.
Head constable sir,
don’t do that!
Wait Dass, let us hear her out.
Oh, just take your hands away.
Head constable sir,
she is going to bathe me.
Oh no, what did you do?!
Have you any sense?!
What did you do, hey?!
Hello...
Who is this?!
I am Hand!
Where are you?!
In the factory behind
the old marriage Hall stop!
Hand, stay there I will send a vehicle.
Registration number TN 42 TN 22
Note it down.
Hand,
I can you read a little bit.
I don’t know to write.
I will remember it by heart.
TN 42 TN 22
Okay boss.
The second one is
TN 22
The hell,
first is TN 42 then is TN 22.
TN 22, TN 42
Hey, forget that.
My wife’s name is on
the back of the vehicle.
Boss, what is your wife’s name?!
My name is in front of the vehicle.
Boss, I don’t know your name!
Ek... Ekam... Ekam brass... get lost!
Okay boss!
I am not able to say my name
clearly as Ekambaram Arasar.
Hair composer vehicle...
it must be air compressor.
Dass...
the Sentry was right.
Those two goons are here.
Inspector, I was told them follow us.
They are his spies.
The hell gave you a police job?
I too thought I wouldn’t get one sir.
They said if you stand upon Rs. 3 lakhs
we will adjust the height requirement.
I thought a bit criminally
and stacked Rs.50 notes sir.
Why, you should have stacked Rs.10 notes.
I couldn’t find any sir.
Where are you off to?
I’m going to the court sir.
Who is here in the station?
Nobody is here sir,
There is some disturbance in
the colony everybody is there.
Okay, I will take care.
Okay sir.
Will you eat biryani?
A Muslim friend has recently
opened a new biryani shop.
Shall I order?
It is just as in the station, right?
Yes sir.
Okay.
Is he here to do a job or just eat?!
He offered me a biryani...
biryani is here.
It is from friend’s shop.
Is there two?
Yes sir.
I should take the one on the top
and give the one on the bottom to him.
- Come sir
- Food received?
I was just about to come
inside but you are here now.
Where is your rifle?
I have kept it inside sir.
Have you eaten?
Not yet sir.
Come let’s go and eat.
Sir you are a senior officer please
go inside, I will eat here itself.
It was the British
who discriminated based on physical attributes.
Without a shirt we are all Indians.
Sir you are a right person,
There is something left in you.
You are not just all
you have a big heart.
Sir, who will guard this place?
Don’t worry about that, come.
Okay sir.
Sir, are you really taking me inside?
I feel so happy.
Sir light....
Thank you sir.
Sir, what is this?
There are no chairs in this room
How will we sit and eat here?
That's okay, you sit there
and I will sit here and eat.
How did they learn
about my encounter plan?
Is he also in on this?
I knew it!
How will a senior officer
not know about this plan?
You are the eighth person, right?
If I am the eighth, who
are the remaining seven?
What sir, as if you don’t know!
Four are the robbers
Head Constable and
constable are the other two,
I am the seventh.
Thanks you are the eight, right?
Is that it?
Sir I have a doubt.
Is it just the eight or are there more?
If the number increases the share
decreases, I want to plan accordingly.
Why are you looking at the stick sir?
Let us do it.
So it’s just the eight.
Oh my, oh god!
Sir please don’t hit me sir. Sir!
Sir please don’t do this, please stop!
In the next half hour...
If I don’t know where they are
keeping my kidnapped wife.
You will tell me!
Why did he just beat me?
He said we equal without our shirts.
What is that because he was
going to remove my shirt.
How will I know who is keeping his wife?!
Hey you!
Tell me sir.
Kareem bhai...
I have got the details
of where those guys are.
I will tell it to you note it down
They are in the bakery
next to the policy marriage hall.
Sir, that is the factory behind
the old marriage hall bus stop.
How do you know that?
I traced them there.
There is a difference
between what you are saying
and what they themselves told me.
Just do what I tell you to.
Hey!
Don’t play with me Prabha.
If you kill us, you will only silence us.
People only give voice to her sister.
Give me my phone sir.
Only then the girl will come.
Switch on the speaker.
Hello...
Where are you?
I am in Chennai.
What is your program?
It is a private party.
Location?
I am sending it.
Prabha...
Will they identify Kajali without us?
They are playing games sir.
But an important play has been revealed.
There is a girl involved in this.
Who is she?
She is the elder sister of the dead girl.
Do one thing,
It’s not take this vehicle.
Call for a police car.
Head, stop head.
Air compressor vehicle.
Hand, where is the driver?
See there.
Boss,
Who are you guys?
Is this the air compressor vehicle?
Yes it is, get lost.
Thank you boss.
Hand, it’s been three days
since I took a piss.
My tank will overflow, come let’s go.
Where is my vehicle?
I have to go to the marriage.
Head Constable you catch him
I will get the other guy.
Hey, come here you.
Hey, why are you catching us.
Hey, take your hand off me.
We know that Karimel Thunjiya Pandian
has give the stolen money to you.
Hey, who is Karimel Thunjiya Pandian?
Hey, how did you get this money?
They stole this money,
why are you after us?
Hey, I have been in service for 27 years.
I can identify the accused
by just looking at them.
Yeah, I can’t see that!
Sarcasm? Do you think you are funny?
Wait just a second I
will take care of you.
Dass, come and get me a rod.
Come quickly, come on!
Get it!
Here you go.
Go on... take care of them,
take care of them!
Take care!
Hey!
Hey...!
Stop it!
Brothers...
Let us talk and resolve this.
Let us talk, put the rod down.
Put it down, come on now.
Yes trust us put it down.
Let us come to a compromise.
I promise I will not hit you.
Let us make a compromise.
Glad to meet you!
We sent you to kill them in an encounter.
Do what you should and go!
I will kill you!
Hey head constable...
They are the ones who stole.
We didn’t steal, it was open so we took.
You buggers!
That is called stealing.
So sad!
What happen when you entered the ATM?
Two guys walked out.
Who are those two guys?
They were wearing black
shirt and black pants.
In which vehicle did you come?
Bank cash vehicle.
Head constable sir,
they didn’t mean to steal the money.
It was those two guys who
broke into the ATM.
Black shirt and black pants.
Because they came in a bank vehicle.
They must have thought they
were bank officers and fled.
When did you come into this?
I came when the yellow shirt and
green shirt guys were removing the money.
What is the bank vehicle there?
Yes it was.
Then it was them.
Yeah.
Then what did you do?
I came back within 10 to 15 minutes.
Then was the vehicle there?
No!
Then it was I us.
Then how did you have money with you?
I came to deposit her
money Head constable sir!
Everywhere it was this
yellow and green shirts,
I got confused!
None of us have done anything wrong.
Just answer my questions,
I will rescue you.
Who are you and where
are you coming from?
"Yellow shirt, Green Shirt..."
Head constable sir,
This is completely set
up by the ministers PA.
If they are coming to kill all of us,
it means they are all afraid of us.
If we take that fear away,
We can all be safe.
We have unknowingly
kidnapped an innocent girl.
Go and bring her here.
I will be back.
Carefully, slowly come here.
Please come and stand here.
She is here head constable sir.
I heard everything you were saying.
My husband is not like what you think.
He’s an honest man.
I am the one who keeps
nagging and torturing him.
I will speak to him on behalf of you.
That was till yesterday.
Once she should keep Rs.40,000 aside,
Your husband has changed.
As long as none of us are
in danger by your husband,
No harm will come to your husband by us.
Shall we do one thing?!
Shall all of us go and meet
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian.
Let him come here,
we will take care.
Sir,
Where is the bag?
Sir...
Where is the bag?!
They were the ones who stole it sir.
Go and tell your long tails to
those scared fools who ran away.
Did I come here to solve the ATM case
and get a medal from the government?
Where is Paagambariya’s bag?
Where is the bag?
We have put it in the
air compressor vehicle.
It is parked outside,
and now I am surrendered!
Thannoli...
Th...!
Is she your darling?
Sweet spot...?
A villain shouldn’t have a
sweet spot Mr. mastermind!
Sir,
Where is the bag?!
Sir we went to deposit cash and got
caught up in all of this please believe us.
Sir,
Thannoli...
Sir...
I have completed my enquiry about
this case before coming here.
They both are mentally handicapped.
They were getting treated
in the psychiatric ward.
The two who ran away are fools.
You are looking to get them caught in
the ATM cash and escape with the bag.
I figured it out when the ATM camera
switched off only when you were near it.
I know who you are I know
who I should talk to.
Sir, this is Ekambaram’s planning.
Shit!
First go and arrest him sir.
I doubted him once he offered to
give me more than I asked him for.
I know he wants the bag for
himself and not Paagambariya.
I enquired what is in the bag,
now I even know that.
I know that Paagambariya doesn’t
want that bag and Ekambaram does.
That is when I decided.
I am going to take the bag.
Shouldn’t I settle down in life.
As soon as Ekambaram gets the bag,
if I put the gun to his head.
he will hand it over himself.
Sir, then go and arrest him.
You are right.
I was waiting for the
bag to come into play.
When he called the old marriage hall
‘the policy marriage hall’ I realised,
That the bag won’t come into play.
That is why I came here myself.
If as a mastermind you want to play games?
I have made a Plan-B to
kill you all and take the bag.
He has also given me permission for it.
I am a dullard to let
you take away 22 crores!
Shit!
Kneel you...
Get over there.
Sir, shall we go inside?
Sir, there definitely inside.
Shall we go in?
Mujeeb, it must be a clean sheet.
There must be 10 to 15 people inside.
We will take care of it
when they come out.
Your time seems to be auspicious
my brothers are here for a hunt.
Let them finish and go,
we will talk after that.
"A growing lust is within me, please come."
"When you hug my mature
body it shivers with joy."
"Don’t touch me, I am highly poisonous."
"Don’t get caught I am
the lips that will bite you."
"In this very late hour,"
"let us play hide and seek."
"Let water flow in a dry riverbed."
"Which is part that the
wind never touches?"
"Men really loved it
and it is women’s heart."
"Which pitch is never sung in a song?"
"As soon as you open a
bottle you will learn it."
"Scarcity..."
"I have none of it."
"Regret..."
"is all you will have."
"You keep looking at me,
shall I return every day?"
"You take aim and strike me,
shall I give you a kiss?"
"A growing lust is within me, please come."
"When you hug my mature
body it shivers with joy."
"There in auto that doesn’t use a meter?"
"If you just show your hand
it will stop by itself?"
"Is there a house without a door?"
"Turn that into a fort of love."
"Butterflies..."
"flutter in my heart."
"Take a coconut shell..."
"Tap a nice rhythm on it."
"You have to walk this hand cart,
come and practice how to do so."
"This crop filled truck is out of control,
come and steal all that you can."
Hey, time is running out!
Now you have only two options.
One,
Handover the bag to me and
I will let everybody live.
Or else I will kill everybody,
take the bag and go
There is also a third option
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian.
I can kill you and get out of here.
What Prabha, have you set us up?
What Mujeeb sir,
you said get me the video
recorded in the watch
I will negotiate with Judhani,
Now you have jumped ship?!
What Mujeeb, are you playing a double game.
Sir, he is playing sir.
Hey, it is that girl Kajali!
Come
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian is on to us sir!
When will all of this end?
As long as Judhani is alive we cannot be.
Go out!
Dear!
My dear...!
I don’t have time to fight with you.
I will save myself.
If you can, save yourself.
Come let’s go.
Look here.
You know I can kill the both
of you and escape from here.
Because we both are
not registered anywhere.
But there is a way
where we can all escape.
If that’s okay with
you just raise your hand.
Don’t do anything to him.
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian,
Tell the media exactly what I say now.
Those three police officers used these
two crazies to rob the ATM,
After you discovered this you came here,
they shot at you and so you shot back.
Nobody can arrest them,
because they are mentally handicapped.
You too will be safe.
I will immediately called for an ambulance.
Hey, get out of here as soon as
you can and call for an ambulance. Go.
How can I leave without you?
Banu,
three police officers are dead
and one is fighting for his life.
It is best that you are not here, so leave.
I said just leave!
Bro, let us also runaway.
Hey, what are you saying
the bank you still here.
Hey, what will you do with those documents?
Hey, those are not just documents.
Come I will show you.
Hey, Jackpot!
Just a little while police, ambulance
and everybody else will be here.
It’s not safe for us here.
Let us hide the bag somewhere
in the factory and leave.
Once everything settles down, we will come
back tomorrow morning, get the money and live
Come
Move it a bit more.
Come let's go.
What, you seem to have escaped from
a huge case I saw it in the news.
Okay, two strong teas
and a pack of cigarettes.
No way, I don’t have change here!
I don’t want the change, you can keep it.
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian,
was severely injured...
...in a shootout where he
killed 3 police men!
There is no big problem sir.
It’s a ricocheted bullet injury.
Mandible was fractured.
We have done a minor surgery.
He will recover soon.
Can I talk to him?
You won’t be able to speak
but you can talk to him.
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian is okay now.
He will soon return to duty.
The three men he shot,
Have been identified as
Criminals pretending to be police.
Karimel Thunjiya Pandian who
was an inspector till now,
has now been promoted to DSP.
To compensate for his injury,
4 lakhs from the internal ministry and
4 lakhs from the chief
minister’s relief fund,
...a total of 8 lakhs be
presented to his family.
The video of the murder of Arabian dancer
Chaya, who was missing has come to light.
A special team is about to arrest
the suspect Dilip Judhani.
Rowdy Prabha and his accomplice
have surrendered the evidence.
Ekabaram, arrange to bail them both out.
Both of them are violent criminals,
an they are stuck in a complicated case.
They went in for us right, bail them out.
Okay sis.
Sir, the police is here
with an arrest warrant.
Now, you should learn to eat by yourself.
Go
Hey!
Where is the bag?
Hey don’t burn it.
Hey!
Hey,
Sir!
Why did you do this?
He is deaf.
Why!
I burnt it.
I burnt it all
So much money can only be wrong.
Only wrong money can come here like this.
That is why I burnt it, money wrong.
In Lanka,
When we fought for our rights.
One bullet...
just one bullet!
Took away my eyes and ears.
Having lost two of my senses...
I was living in a prison of my own body.
You middle of the ocean
in the island...
all alone.
in lap of this blind and deaf man.
She lay there on my lap.
She had a disease.
The great disease of hunger and thirst.
The medicine for that,
was food and water
Money should surely by that, right?!
I too thought
it surely would.
But there was no food to buy,
No water to drink.
In the middle of the ocean.
In the middle of the island.
I screamed to let others know,
and I bought both of them to be shore
The courts of my wife...
and a lot of money.
I burnt them both!
Money...
It is the cruelest weapon that man invented.
Cave man had very little needs.
Food to eat, water and a place to shelter.
Once people start to occupy these shelters,
his greed surfaces!
Money...
Money...What is it?
It is nothing.
I promise to pay the
bearer the sum of Rs.500.
Money is an abstract.
It is an inclusion.
It is just a promise.
If one day that promises is broken,
They will say it is worthless.
Because that money remains
as a belief.
As his riches
and as all his needs
Money...
The cruelest weapon man invented
Money can you break a man.
Money is everything.
Money is a dictator.
Money is Almighty!
It becomes the creator of all misery
As long is they were goods
riches were equally distributed among all.
Once it became money...
it accumulates with one person,
and the rest become slaves.
Riches,
must be shared!
Only a society without money.
The starting of the
next level of civilization.
If mankind needs to be respected
A society without money should be created.
We need a society without money
and to create that,
an understanding of the truth
is what man needs.
Our king Thannoli, made it his job
to teach everyone ancient way of life
where he ghost of money never existed.
and so this story comes to an end.