As we enter the next room,
this is the main observatory, the old observation room.
Where the inventor looked at
the planets and stars.
His name was Pehr Wilhelm Wargentin...
and he was known throughout the world.
Why are you staying up here?
I left the door open for you.
So we built and publicized
it. Now we'll enter the next room.
Radio Echo. The time is 5:45.
Miloslav Dragan still at large.
Poor business growth
in Stockholm.
No progress in lease negotiations.
The fugitive Miloslav Dragan is still
at large after escaping a week ago.
Police said he could
have made his way to Stockholm.
The guard at Anstalten Hall Prison
who was shot in the escape
is being treated
at the Karolinska Hospital.
His condition is serious
but stable.
According C.I.D. Commissioner Stig Åke Malm,
Dragan is heavily armed.
Larsson here. Hi.
No, not at all. How so?
Yes, it was a week ago.
Here are some addresses to begin with:
Slavo Slav Mística, Andrei Korda...
Dragan won't be hiding at the first place we'd check.
We have to start somewhere.
Can't the fucking Yugoslavs be content
to kill each other at home?
Slavo Slav...
Hi. The situation isn't good at all with Dragan.
A telephone call, Gunvald. The Chief.
- Malm? Stig-Åke? What fun.
- It'll be nice to talk to the big cheese.
- I'll go now.
Putte?
Dad?
What do you want?
- A Magnum ice cream bar.
When I was little I thought
that all the guys were like you.
A little boring, but okay.
Hopeless in a sense,
but at least reliable.
Kalle isn't at all like that.
He's good looking...
Sorry, Dad.
You're also pretty gorgeous in your way.
He's completely unreliable, damn it.
It doesn't make any sense, like...
we were at a party on Walpurgis Night.
It was there that he met Anne.
Anne, the bitch.
He didn't say anything to me,
and I don't give a shit.
He saw her for a full month
without telling me a thing.
He was certainly never
going to say anything.
Why does it have to happen like this?
We had stopped smoking and everything.
- Yes, but that's good, that's good.
I might as well start again now.
- But please Putte...
Well then.
I'll smoke myself to death.
- But what is this nonsense? Putte...
No! Let go!
Stop it!
No! Please, no...
God, I'm so late!
Do you mind if I shower before you?
Yes, it's Beck. Vanadislunden Park?
How can this kind of thing happen?
How can you let that happen?!
We have to able to go home!
My grandmother won't go out
because she's afraid. I'm at the day care centre
and responsible for 30 children!
People steal from anywhere! Someone stole
the children's clothes from the laundry room.
How can such a thing happen?!
The rain has probably ruined everything.
- Strangled, perhaps some form of rape.
Panties missing.
It happened sometime last night.
- Check out what she ate and when.
Is it a sex murder?
- It can't be ruled out in any case.
Did it happen here? -Forensics say
that everything points in that direction.
How are things going?
- The rain...
If you find a few footsteps,
they're probably mine.
I was here last night at nine o'clock.
There was a robbery here. The lady at the kiosk
was attacked 50 feet away.
She had all the takings in her bag.
- The girl must have been there then.
Probably. A patrol came by
a half an hour before the robbery.
Of course they saw nothing.
Could it be the same guy?
No, she was raped
It's probably not the same person.
In any case, the doctor hasn't ruled out the possibility.
- Damn...
Two crazy people in the same place at the same time,
one worse than the other.
What a fucking job!
What happened to the woman from the kiosk?
- Cerebral haemorrhage, broken cheekbone...
and a broken nose.
Granlund identified the girl from
a photo the mother filed yesterday.
Karin Svensson. Kollberg has gone
to visit her parents in Frejgatan.
Lennart Kollberg, CID.
- Have you found her?
Can we go in?
Can we sit down?
- Yes.
What happened? Have you found her?
We...
Would you please sit down?
Where's your husband?
- I don't have a husband. We're separated.
I... I'm terribly sorry
to have to tell you this...
Your daughter is dead.
But we're going to the country.
It isn't Karin. You're wrong!
It isn't Karin! It isn't Karin!
It isn't Karin!
How did it go?
- Life's a bitch.
Having to try to comfort and calm...
and at the same time...
If this had happened to you,
you'd have committed suicide.
Say something, damn it.
- What can I say?
Anway, it changes nothing.
- What should I do then?
You have to get used to it.
You... Let's walk.
Let's begin with the next of kin.
We can rule out the father.
He's out of reach. A sailor.
- Where the hell is Kracke?
Did any other people know the girl?
- No, we don't know yet.
Hello. Gunvald's looking for you.
It's about Dragan.
- Gunvald wants more coffee, Skacke.
Good that you came. Karin Svensson's mother
reported a flasher to the police last year.
Karl Erik Einar Ingmarsson. Here's an
interview we conducted with the girl then.
Assistant Detective Bergström.
- Karin, what did the man do?
He smelled nasty,
but somehow he seemed nice.
He asked us to go home with him.
- Why do you think he wanted that?
I don't know. He seemed strange.
- In what way?
He had weird clothes
and talked a little weird.
Did you agree to go with him?
- No.
What did he do?
- He talked to us several times.
What happened then?
- He left and we slipped away.
Did you tell your mother?
- No. I don't really know why.
Did you tell her what happened yesterday?
- Yes.
Was it the same man?
He said he'd give us money if we went with him.
But you didn't follow him?
- No. Mama had warned me about this kind of thing.
That's good.
What else do we have?
- We're working on tips from the public.
We've interrogated the guys we already know.
Do you want to talk to Ingmarsson?
- No thanks.
This report is the preliminary autopsy.
Strangulation, finger marks on her neck,
no skin scrapings under her nails.
A few bruises on the arms and hands,
more around the genitals
caused first by heavy blows and then by punches.
No outright rape.
Panties are believed missing.
They were white knit,
size 1.40, a common brand.
The mugger that Gunvald interviewed,
that skinhead. He could be a witness.
Perhaps he cased the location before the robbery.
The lady at the kiosk could also be a witness.
Unless the mugger and the murderer
are the same person.
That's unlikely.
The kiosk lady saw the mugger.
The mugger saw the killer...
Coffee?
- No thanks.
I was sitting at the Pelican
until they closed.
You can ask the guys.
I'd never kill a human being.
I've told you.
I was at the Pelican all evening.
Okay, Ingmarsson. Go home.
I fell asleep.
- Hi.
Soon.
He's kicking.
How's it going?
Annika?
Stop! Wait!
Yes, that's about all.
The time now is 13:45
How long ago did it happen?
-20 minutes. The body temperature is 35º.
Less than an hour ago then.
One of the dogs followed a track to
Gyllenstiernsgatan. But it lost the scent.
Has anyone talked to the parents?
- Yes, we don't have it.
I want to meet the boys who found her.
Lennart...
He's going to do it again.
According to the boys who found Annika,
she had been playing with your daughter Lena
earlier today.
She knows what's happened?
- Yes. How can anyone...
I'll get her.
Toot, toot! Hello. I've got a car.
I've got a taxi.
Can you drive it then?
- Toot, toot.
Is there a button?
- Are you sick too? Toot.
Brmm, brmm.
I think that Lena and I should talk alone.
Shall we sit down?
My name is Martin. I know that you've
been through something terrible today,
but I'd like to ask you
a few things anyway.
You were with Annika today.
After school we picked up Bosse
from kindergarten, and then we played outside.
- Bosse? Who's that?
That's my little brother.
Do you know what time it was?
- About four.
Did you see anybody else in the park
or did Annika talk to an adult?
No. She got angry at us and ran away.
She ran away?
- Yes.
She ran away alone?
- Bosse followed her behind the church.
Then did she come back?
- Just Bosse.
Not... Annika.
If he kills again it will be in the inner city,
so I've marked out all the parks.
I've noted down the telephone number.
We'll let you know if there's anything more.
Thank you.
How did it go?
- Well we've got two witnesses now.
Both the mugger and Bosse Oskarsson.
He's three years old.
A known mugger and a three year old...
Brilliant.
What the hell is Gunvald doing?
The getaway car was a Peugeot, white, '79 model.
A mugger. In Vanadislunden.
- Wait a minute. What is it?
Get him!
- I'll call you back.
What do you think I've been doing?
We have to find Dragan. He's dangerous.
He's already shot someone.
Your amateur kiosk mugger can fucking well wait.
- Not any more.
Now you've got to get him.
- Fine. Give me 3,000 kronor for extra staff.
- When was the Vanadislunden robbery committed?
- Between 7:45 and 8:00.
- And a killing between 7:00 and 8:00?
- Yes. But we already knew that.
I'm trying to convince myself
that the mugger might have seen the girl...
and perhaps also her killer.
Are you with us?
- Get him.
Use your stool pigeon.
Either he's in the Canary Islands
or in a crack house somewhere in Söderby.
Use all your underworld contacts.
Use television, radio, whatever the hell you want.
But get that guy.
Do you think I don't understand?
- Bravo, Gunvald.
Martin... I was at the university
and saw this course catalogue.
I recognized the name Susanne Grassman.
I've read some of her articles.
It might be something.
What the hell are we doing?
I don't know. But we'd better damn well hurry up.
Grassman...
All this is due to the ridiculous sentences.
There should be public lynchings.
Murdering and raping little girls...
There's got to be a limit. There should be
public executions... shown on TV.
It's a bitch. You can't help wonder
what the police are doing.
When were you planning to be chief of police?
- I borrowed it.
Could we have a coffee or something?
- Is this where you learn about life?
At the library... or on Surbrunnsgatan?
You don't normally read the newspaper.
- There's nothing in it.
Give it to me, then.
- Let me just browse a bit.
Take the supplement.
You're cops, huh?
I recognize you.
Yeah. And to what do owe the honour?
Dragan.
You're looking for him, the fucking asshole.
I know where he is.
There's no reward.
I don't care about money.
I probably earn more than you.
Yes, in the pussy.
- One more word like that and I'm going.
Sit down.
- It's a free country isn't it?
Please, sit down.
Do you know where Dragan is?
- Yes. Next door.
69 Luntmakargatan
- Is he there now?
Yes.
What does it say on the door?
- My name. Simonsson.
- How many stairs?
- One. There's a second one to the kitchenette.
How many windows?
- Three.
Do they look on to the park?
- No, it's a lake view.
Is he alone?
- No.
We're on the rise in park.
- Roger. Notify me when you're on site.
Come in Wiktorin.
What about the stair well?
Soon. Give us five minutes.
Two helicopters will be here soon.
How fucking good is that to pull
the helicopters in? It's pure Gulf War.
You mean that I shouldn't have called?
I know it's difficult, but we'll try
again. Try to remember what he looked like.
Dragan? Was it him?
- Attention. Three minutes to go.
- Wiktorin here. Understood.
Johansson here. Understood.
- Bergelin. Understood.
Yes, it's blocked.
Is Malm somewhere here?
- Up on the roof.
Wait!
I have to talk to him!
- He's taken a woman hostage!
He's probably our only witness
to the Vanadislunden murder!
Unthinkable! No suicide operations!
- Listen to me!
Dragan is a witness.
He's probably our only chance
to identify the girl's killer.
Look at that.
Get it? Let us handle it.
Stig-Åke, we need him alive.
Not shot to pieces by a whole army of police.
Let me try!
We'll wait.
We're waiting.
We're calling it off.
I repeat. We're calling it off.
What the hell are we doing to do now?
- Give me ten minutes.
I'll go in and talk to him.
What are you going to do? Ring the doorbell?
No. We have the key.
We're going in now.
You had the key?
- Yes. But it's my house key.
Put on your clothes … if you have any.
- And you.
Who are you?
- Lisbeth Karlström.
We're from the police. How long
have you known this man?
Two hours and twenty minutes.
I met him in the park.
Not much to show for the ladies.
What's he done?
- Sex maniac.
- What's happening?
- Don't ask me.
Call Beck.
Martin Beck, come in.
Beck, come in.
He doesn't answer.
Actually they have two more minutes.
We're going in now.
Wiktorin. Come in.
Malm, dammit!
Attention! Drop your weapon!
Attention!
Come out with your hands over your head!
Stop Malm or there'll be a bloodbath.
We'll storm the apartment!
I repeat. We're going to storm the apartment!
Stop!
Yes, shall we talk a little then?
Not you and me.
- What?
Not with you.
I don't want to talk to you.
Well then. Who do you want to talk to?
With the guy who took me. The tall one.
Fetch Gunvald.
Gunvald!
He wants to talk to you.
Dragan wants to talk to you.
Yeah?
You were the one who took me.
- So what?
It's nothing I'm proud of.
Arresting you was my job.
In a week I'll have forgotten all about you.
There are some details we want to go over
before we deal with your offence.
We know you were in Vanadislunden
Friday evening last week.
Yeah.
- Where you violently assaulted a woman at 8:00,
the kiosk owner, Hildur Magnusson.
What time did you get to the park?
- Shut up!
Be bloody careful how you speak.
Hildur Magnusson is in a coma.
Cerebral haemorrhage, broken jaw,
four teeth broken, broken nose.
How much money you bring in?
1,500? Or even 2,000?
Why didn't she let go of her bag, huh?
A murder was committed
while you were in the park.
Heard of it?
- I read about it.
- And?
- It wasn't me. I swear!
Did you see that girl?
Did you see her?!
I think so.
- Where?
In the playground beneath the water tower.
In any case a kid was there.
What was she doing?
- Swinging.
Alone?
- Yes, alone.
I've been thinking about this.
It must have been 7:30.
She left the playground at 7:30
but she wasn't there at 8:00
when you hit Hildur Magnusson?
No.
What did you do
during that half hour?
I was watching to see the people
who were coming from both directions.
Did you see any?
- People were coming and going.
Five or six.
A police car cruised by.
A man went by with a dog.
I followed him for a while.
That was between 7:30 and 7:45.
Was that all?
Now try to remember, dammit.
- Yes... Aah...
- Yes?
I did see another one.
Someone who came from the other direction.
When you did you see him?
Shortly after the...
When the lady was lying on the ground.
Why didn't she let go of her bag?
When you assaulted Hildur Magnusson
you also saw a man coming
from Sveavägen?
And could you see him clearly?
Yes.
He was balding with his hair brushed straight back,
and a not very long nose. Approximately.
That's too big I think.
Was he blonde?
- Yes.
How old would he have have been?
- Between 30 and 35.
Maybe 35.
Hi, Dad. You're late.
We got a pizza for you.
I ate out.
- Then Kalle came here.
He's sleeping here tonight.
That's okay, isn't it?
I thought you had quit smoking.
- That's Kalle. He started again.
This is Dr. Susanne Grassman
from Berlin
Psychiatrist and behavioural scientist
and guest lecturer at the university.
Dr. Grassman has had access
to FBI research reports.
We can benefit from her help
in our continuing reconnaissance work.
When you're back at school again
- It's time to start studying.
There might be two different types of
serial killer, but what good is that?
If he strikes again tomorrow, does it
matter what category he belongs to?
You know how to look for him.
- How? Check out all single men?
Damned bullshit.
- Everything new isn't crap.
No, but a hell of a lot of it is.
Have we completely ruled out Dragan?
It might be him.
He was on the spot.
He's not the chaotic type.
How do you know?
Have you gone camping with him?
Is it meat or fish?
Shouldn't we check out the girl
who was with Dragan?
Hello?
What the hell are you doing here?!
Do you always break into people's houses?
The door was open. I rang the bell.
- Yeah. What do you want?
I'm 25 years old. I'm studying art.
I'm unmarried, free as the air...
On Tuesday, I happened to pick up the
guy. I didn't know who he was.
I didn't know he was Dragan.
- Miloslav Dragan.
I don't suspect you of anything.
I just want to ask some questions.
Sorry. Would you like coffee?
- Yes please.
Actually, I want to ask you about
something I think you know quite a lot about.
How was he, Dragan .. sexually?
I usually don't give reviews
about the guys I sleep with.
Dragan probably isn't a violent man.
A week ago on Friday
he was in Vanadislunden...
when a ten year girl
was raped and murdered.
I didn't know that.
As far as I can judge, he was
completely normal. Almost too normal.
What do you mean?
When you do it so rarely, you want
a little more than... the routine stuff.
Did he approach you?
- No. Quite the opposite.
I had taken my text books
down to the park. I do that sometimes.
And I saw him there...
nice, really nice.
He wasn't at all abnormal.
At the beginning, he showed no interest.
But I made ​​sure that he did.
You certainly take some risks.
- I know.
Stylish.
Goodbye.
We'll begin by knocking on doors
in all three directions.
Claesson and Winzell will take Hagagatan
and Dalagatan as far as Sveavägen,
while Gunartz and Persson will take Rogestam.
The rest of you follow me down to
Roslagsgatan. Let's get started. Quick!
What the hell is this all about?
- Police.
Then we apologize.
You were standing in the bushes
and spying on the children.
We're parents and we know
the parents of the girl who...
- We've formed a voluntary defence service.
- A what? What the hell are you saying?!
Don't use that that tone. We're not drunks.
We intend to protect our children.
Do you have a license for this?
- No.
I bought it in Seville.
Normally, I keep it locked up.
Fucking bone-heads.
Beck.
- I went to Gustavus Adolphus Park.
I got attacked by a couple of fathers.
They've formed a vigilante band.
Hello?
Is it serious?
- No, my neck's just a bit sore.
A pensioner was attacked in
Haga Park while he was peeing.
What should we do?
3802 to 70. Come in.
- 3802.
Understood. Out.
- Claesson! They've found him.
In all probability, we've found the
killer. The description fits.
We've been able to link the dead
person to the crimes in the parks.
None of our efforts have been wasted.
We've been put to the test.
That's the reason for our success.
I think the public can relax now.
Martin Beck. I want Dragan brought
here for an identification. Now!
- Lennart? Is that you?
- Yes.
Shall we read the book?
Well? Is that him?
Is he the man you saw on the evening
of June 2 in Vanadislunden?
- I can't say.
- Why not?
Stop messing around. Was he the one
or not? Answer now, damn it!
Was that a threat?
We just want to know if you
recognize the dead guy or not.
As I said, I can't say.
Right now anyway. I'm stuck in an isolation cell
in the Special Section.
It's fucking unpleasant.
I want to be with the others.
Really? And what should we do about that?
Talk to the superintendent.
Refer to Section 20 of the Penal Code.
So if you didn't have to sit in isolation,
perhaps you'd recognize this man?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Bloody rat!
I'll do what I can.
But I can't promise anything.
He rapes little girls
...and murders them.
It isn't him.
What was she hit with?
- The shaft of a hammer.
Stig-Åke Malm, what's this about?
You drew some hasty conclusions.
You take over now, Einar.
Concentrate on Tegnérlunden,
Tegnérgatan, Västmannagatan,
Upplandsgatan to Drottninggatan.
I'm looking for Inspector Beck.
- He's busy.
How do I get to see Inspector Beck?
- Do you have an appointment?
If you don't have one, it will be difficult.
I'm sorry.
Beck told me to come here.
Good morning.
This is about Bosse, my little boy.
I remember Bosse in the pedal car, yes.
He kept on about the tick
he had got from the man in the park.
I didn't understand what a "tick" was.
I thought it might be some Chiclet gum
but then I found this subway ticket
in his jacket pocket.
You said I should come here
if I thought of something.
It was stamped June 2 at 16:30.
No fingerprints. The paper is too rough.
It was stamped at the Rådmansgatan Station.
...The Handelshögskolan exit.
The subway station nearest Vanadislunden?
- Yes.
So you were on duty on June 2
in Vanadislunden?
I thought I recognized you.
A young woman had a fight with you.
Yes, a woman in her 30s.
Didn't she say something about missing clothes?
- Clothing? No, she was angry about everything.
Did she give her name
or tell you where she was working?
It was a day care centre in Frejgatan.
- A day care centre in Frejgatan?
Yes, I remember. In May some children's
clothing disappeared from the dryer.
Underwear, panties?
- Yes, that's it precisely.
Does anyone living in the building
look like this?
I don't know.
- Even approximately?
Fransson.
Thank you.
Hello.
Yes, it's absolutely crystal clear.
There's no doubt.
Send out an APB for Olof Fransson.
Olof with an "f".
Fransson with a... If you'd just shut up,
maybe it would work better.
132 Sveavägen. Nothing personal.
The observatory on Observatoriekullen?
- He works at the Stockholm Observatory.
Thank you. Can you connect me to Forensics?
There's a telescope up there.
You can look at the sky. Do you want to see it?
Only one staircase.
Do you see anything?
Eva!
Eva?
You should go home now.
Your mother's calling you. Come now.
Yes. Come on then.
Hurry now.