MARIE AND THE CASTAWAYS
Sorry.
Excuse me.
Thanks.
- What will it be?
- A beer, please.
Thank you.
It's my shout.
Okay.
Well... thank you.
You're welcome.
My name's Wim.
Simeon.
Come here often?
No, it's my first time.
I'm not from Paris.
I ended up here accidently.
You're from...?
Anvers, in Belgium.
I came here for a job interview.
Did it go well?
No.
They thought I lacked motivation.
I'm sorry.
Don't be.
I'm relieved actually.
I'm celebrating my failure.
Here's to you.
To your failure.
To our failures.
Shall we do the next song together?
No, I...
- I can't sing.
- Me neither.
So? Pass me the song list.
This one. This one's perfect.
I'm off.
I've had way too much to drink.
It was great to meet you, Wim.
Likewise.
Likewise, my friend.
Will we meet again...
definitely not,
but I'll never forget our duet.
Never.
Me neither.
Have a good trip to Anvers.
In actual fact,
I came here for medical tests.
And...
it's no picnic.
If you know what I mean.
No.
Go on home.
Off you go.
Go on, scram!
I was born in Paris,
in the early 80s.
I'm the youngest of 2 children.
After 12 years in
the army, my father
decided to escape his father's grip
and qualified as a gym teacher.
He met Mathilde
at the school he taught at.
It was love at first sight.
My brother was interested
physical labour,
whereas I, led by an
emotionally liberal mother,
chose the mind.
Mathilde and Jacques,
without ever saying so,
liked the divergent
directions our education took.
I began high school,
the time of first loves.
Above all, I liked being in love.
I dated with Laure
for almost two years.
Then Clarisse, but that didn't last.
And finally, Patricia.
I met my future best
friend at a concert,
Oscar.
I've seen them 3 times
and they keep getting worse.
That's known as a loss of innocence.
It's sad, but that's that.
What did he say?
It's the 3rd time he's seen them
and it's a loss of innocence.
They get worse.
Are you a couple?
Really? A shame.
And are you a couple?
That's a shame.
After graduating high school,
I studied journalism.
Patricia came too.
You don't want to?
Overnight, she wanted a baby.
I don't know.
Then you don't really love me.
She left me.
And I realised
I was in love with her.
I fell into a depression that
was brutally disrupted
by my Dad's death.
That tragic event
was a kind of wake-up call.
Suddenly, I had an urge to
shoulder my responsibilities.
I decided to keep dodging exercise,
to reduce my alcohol intake
and enter the workforce.
After some anecdotal experiences,
I was appointed editor
of Modoi's cultural section,
a publication boasting a daring
and discerning editorial policy.
My colleagues were
young, ambitious,
clean cut and moderately left-wing.
I tried to emulate them,
no second guessing.
I conformed.
In my second year at Modoi,
I met Beatrice.
I frequently summon up
the exact moment I first saw her
and what crossed my mind.
Hey!
Don't be shy now.
I'm curious to know
who you're texting.
Super crap opening line.
It's private.
Forget I asked.
I'll tell you.
He's called Sylvain.
I'm breaking up with him by text.
There.
As of now, I'm single...
open to the unknown.
That's how it began.
Alright.
My first two years with Beatrice
were like a romantic
adventure novel.
A fast-paced one.
Keeping it?
Yes.
At 26, I became a father.
Years went by,
time slowed down.
Sarah grew up.
Without Beatrice or I
articulating it,
the ties holding us together
gradually came undone.
Happiness doesn't last.
We decided to separate
before our love died out.
An astronaut
manages to live in a little
space shuttle for a month.
Seeing the Earth so small
through a port-hole
is enough for him.
I don't always get
what you say, Oscar,
but it helps.
Cool.
The crisis hit.
The crisis and
increasingly chaotic
financial management
saw Modoi fold.
The final issue
My only source of income
became the employment benefit.
And Oscar happened
to leave his girlfriend.
At the age of 30, we went flatting.
Now that I'm here,
I've got a vision.
I can see my turntables
right here, like this.
Two days ago, when we did the plans,
we said by the wall.
Brace yourself for change.
No, nothing's changing.
I have a vision.
It's great here. Like this...
Life resumed its course.
I tried to fall in love.
You might find this odd...
I'd rather ask you outright.
Here goes.
How about we try to spend
the rest of our lives together?
You're serious?
- Hi.
Have a good evening?
No.
Martha and I called it quits.
I made a desperate plea,
she's not interested.
Neither am I.
Who's this?
Her name is Marie.
I found her wallet
outside last night.
She looks familiar.
Don't you think?
She looks like the girl
in that commercial...
The commercial where they have...
but short and... I don't know.
Doesn't ring a bell.
I found her number
in the white pages.
You call a pretty girl like that.
Leave you to it.
Hello?
Not picking up?
You called, it cut off.
Yes... yes. That's right.
I've got connection problems.
Who are you with?
Sorry?
Which company?
Do you work in telecommunications?
No.
I was just wondering.
I've had similar problems.
You tried to call me?
Actually, I found Marie
Andrieu's wallet last night.
I found her phone number
in the white pages...
She moved out.
Have you got her mobile number?
What for?
Um... to return her wallet.
Hello? Are you still there?
06 03 53...
...21 79.
Thank you.
Be wary of Marie.
Sorry?
She's dangerous.
Thanks.
Haven't we met before?
I don't think so.
When I saw your photo,
it felt like...
Now, it's the same.
Maybe I look like someone you know.
I've got quite a common face.
It's funny looking
like many people.
I don't think you do.
Really?
Truly.
I have to go.
Already?
I'm expecting a very important call.
So, thanks for coming
all this way. It was very...
Oh sorry! I'm so sorry.
I'll get the bill.
No, it's fine.
I insist.
There you go, too late.
- And thanks.
- Thanks.
Bye.
- Have you been there long?
- I just got here.
That's really good.
Not too esoteric?
No.
No, it's entrancing.
Dark and entrancing.
Would people dance to it?
Oh yeah.
It rings every 10 minutes.
They hang up on me.
I'll get it.
Hello?
By Simeon Forest
Modoi
Hello?
It's you.
I recognise your breathing.
Sorry?
We spoke earlier,
about Marie.
So?
So what?
Did you see her?
Yes.
Seeing her again?
Why do you ask?
I'm advising you
not to see her again.
If you try to see her,
there'll be trouble.
I was born near Marseille.
Let's skip the first years.
I don't remember them.
And go straight to two
major childhood events.
When I was 6, my Dad took
me fishing for the 1st time.
He was a fisherman.
Hauling in a net,
he forgot about me momentarily.
I fell in.
The 2nd event
happened when I was 11.
I fell hopelessly in love
with my French teacher.
At the end of the year,
I decided to declare my love.
"What is there for me
in the world?"
"Other men strive for riches,
"celebrity and power!
"But I have no profession.
"You are my exclusive occupation.
"Do you not feel the aspiration
of my soul ascending toward yours,
"that they must intermingle,
that I am dying on your account?"
- That's...?
- Sentimental Education.
Now that it's the holidays,
I was wondering if...
we could go somewhere
far away, just the two of us.
She rejected my advances.
That episode left me with
a fierce desire to become
a writer and prove
to my teacher that indeed I could.
At the age of 30,
after many years of study,
I decided to leave Marseille.
I came to Paris and
began my 1st novel,
entitled The Seabed.
A kind of unstructured,
epic, chronicle of a family.
10 years on,
I abandoned The Seabed
? I was drowning in it ?,
to begin my new 1st novel,
At the Surface.
In At the Surface,
I found a style,
a way of telling a story
unique to me,
using material from my life
to generate emotion.
I received much encouragement.
The manuscript spoke.
But publishers wouldn't
touch At the Surface.
Its narrative was too experimental
and it didn't address
readers' concerns.
It was at this difficult time,
confronting serious doubts,
that I met Marie.
It was as if she came from
another planet: my planet.
That's how it felt
the first time I saw her.
A few weeks later,
Marie moved in with me.
I'd never shared
my life with anyone,
least of all a girl
who was 20 years my junior.
That's how it happened,
when I least expected it.
It's what we call
electro-hypersensitivity.
Electromagnetic fields
can deafen people.
In France, several hundred people
have been identified
as victims of this.
One day in April,
I heard a report on
electro-hypersensitivity.
...are hypersensitive to
electromagnetic fields,
around 2 million people.
I'd found the subject
of my next novel,
my last shot at becoming a writer.
I travelled to a white zone,
where victims of electro-sensitivity
syndrome had assembled.
Going there, I had no idea
just how much
it would change my life.
I expected to meet eccentrics.
I discovered deep,
complex individuals.
I went for few days.
I stayed for 2 months,
sharing their daily life,
living in a cave
with no electricity.
Returning wasn't easy.
I'd completed a
manuscript in record time.
Marie's interest was lukewarm.
I sent White Zone
off to publishers.
After a month of waiting,
I began to get migraines.
After eliminating various theories,
I faced facts:
I had electro-sensitivity syndrome.
I'd become electro-sensitive.
I renounced my
mobile phone and stereo.
I lined my apartment
with wave-shielding film.
We spent long weeks like this.
I didn't notice Marie
slipping away from me.
Then, one morning...
Hello?
Okay, I'll pass you over.
He's right...
Yes.
Just a moment.
Antoine?
It's for you.
It's important.
It was Marcel Messager,
an editor at
Des Foudres publishers.
He'd read White Zone
and was eager to meet me.
The novel came out in
September, writers' month.
It was a genuine success.
Oddly,
my hypersensitivity dropped
and then ceased to exist.
I had a phase of drunkenness.
At last, I was recognised.
"As my health began to
decline, he went crazy.
"He saw it as a bogus illness.
"I'd investigated it, as had we all.
"I knew I was electro-sensitive.
"But it was nonsense to him.
"He forced me to continue training.
So I fled,
"like a criminal. See?
"I took refuge in the forest.
Imagine it.
"I was damn well homeless.
"Living in Bois de Vincennes."
I fell on tough times.
I realised that I'd ruined
the one great love affair
of my life.
The wave of success subsided,
I sank back into oblivion,
and writing my next novel
felt completely out of my reach.
A whiskey.
Japanese.
There you go. No ice.
Can't sleep either?
Oscar?
It's not my fault.
Is that you puss-cat?
- Morning.
What's got into you?
- Don't you remember?
- No.
What should I remember?
Daddy.
Hi. Sorry.
- Cooee.
You look great.
- And how are you?
- I'm alright.
Got a job?
Um... no.
Nothing special. Stringers.
Oscar's a sleepwalker.
See you later.
- 3 pm, okay?
- On the dot.
- Can we see a movie?
- You want to?
What's a sleepwalker?
Someone who rises in the night...
- You've seen it before?
- No.
What film shall we see?
- I don't know.
- Oh! I know a cool one!
What are you doing?
Let me see.
Hold on a second.
- Was she having sex?
- What?
Was the girl having sex?
Look.
That's a famous artist.
Wonderful self-portraits.
- Do you know what they are?
- No.
It's like drawing yourself,
like drawing your own face.
Hello, I can't talk much.
Then I'll keep it, okay?
I'm working.
Right now I'm working.
Oh, shit!
I completely forgot.
I'm coming.
Tell him I'll be there soon.
I'm sorry.
I won't be long.
She leaves him, unceremoniously.
So he hits a rough patch
and starts drinking again,
not to the point of addiction.
He drinks moderately,
but frequently.
He's bored.
He thinks he's ruined
his one true love,
that he should have fought for.
That's when he decides
to reach out to her again
via an intermediary character:
Simeon,
who I'm fleshing out.
This guy comes out of
nowhere and meets Marie.
It's love at first sight.
Fireworks,
which saddens Victor.
More sad than jealous.
Sad and angry, to be precise.
He stalks him.
It's an obsession.
The guy has a little girl.
A little mastermind who understands
everything about everything,
without being nauseating.
She has a heightened sensitivity.
I'm not eloquent.
On the contrary.
I don't want you thinking
it's going to be
cliché or provocative,
a kind of sick love triangle.
That's not the direction
I want to go in.
I get it.
You sound quite far advanced.
Yes.
Well, I think I am.
I'm just untying quite a few knots.
I mean, untangling lots of threads.
I'm breaking out of a deadlock.
That's great, that's great...
I'm sorry, Antoine,
but our time's up.
I have a meeting...
Of course.
Sorry for being so late.
My head's in the clouds.
I wanted to know whether...
you think it'd be
possible to have...
a small advance.
I'll let you know.
In the bedroom,
kitchen and lounge,
like in Paranormal Activity.
I'll start with the bedroom one.
Fast forward.
There won't be much on it.
Handsome dude, no?
I'll fast forward it.
Oh fuck!
Check another camera.
- Did you see what you did there?
- No.
No...
I'm not going to jump?
No, of course not.
You wouldn't be here now.
This is serious, man.
I'm going to jump.
"Sleepwalking can be safe,
"like sitting on a bed
or cleaning objects,
"or dangerous, like cooking,
driving, raping or causing death.
"In 2004, Australian
experts treated a woman
"who had sex with
strangers while asleep."
Oh fuck!
"In 2008, reports say
"a woman sent ridiculous
emails in her sleep."
See you later.
Oh fuck!
Sarah loved walking home
via Pere-Lachaise cemetery
with her father.
He enjoyed it too.
He found it a playful
and intelligent way
of introducing great men and women.
He thought of them there,
six feet under,
the community they made,
despite themselves.
The girl's mother
strongly opposed it.
"You don't take a
6 year old into a cemetery",
she'd scolded one day
after he'd had a
foolish urge to confess.
Lying
was Simeon's main flaw.
His second greatest flaw,
which some of his friends
saw as a strength,
was his determination.
Simeon was a profoundly
determined being.
"Stubborn"
was how his mother put it.
Are you a detective?
Yeah.
I thought so.
You're tailing someone?
Yes.
Cool.
What kind of case is it?
A missing person.
A murder?
Cool.
- Shit!
- What?
She's leaving.
- Are you parked nearby?
- Just over there.
I need to seize your vehicle.
- Quick.
- I'll drive, extra helmet.
Is she escaping?
Here.
- Thanks for cooperating.
- No problem.
Good luck.
Be careful.
TGV 621 is now departing.
Please climb aboard
and do not block the doors...
What do you want?
Hasn't she gone?
Who?
The girl.
What girl?
I took your colleague
to the station by scooter.
What colleague?
You're not a detective?
I am.
How'd you know?
What's this colleague stuff?
You mean he wasn't a cop?
Right...
Tell me everything
from the beginning.
I came in before and saw
a guy sitting like you...
At Lorient, Marie took a taxi.
She got out at the wharf
for Groix Island.
"Whoever sees Groix, sees their joy."
I'd travelled a long way
and I deserved a little joy.
So I boarded too,
not knowing where it would take me.
Hello.
Is there a room free?
You want to sleep here?
It is a hotel.
Yes, of course.
Room 8.
Upstairs.
- Thanks.
- The stairs are there.
- Oscar?
- What are you doing? I'm waiting.
You won't believe me.
You found a job?
No, no.
I'm not in Paris.
I'm on Groix Island.
What island?
I followed the wallet girl.
What?
I followed Marie.
I'll take it.
This is your lovely house.
There's some local produce
to welcome you here.
You should have
everything you need.
Tonight's dinner
and tomorrow's breakfast.
I'm not seeing Cosmo?
No one told you?
Told me what?
Cosmo would rather see
you tomorrow morning.
He wants to save the
magic for tomorrow.
So, I'll leave you to it.
You've got my mobile number?
If you need anything, just call me.
We're just down a bit,
in the manor.
I'll pick you up at 5.30 am.
"5.30 in the morning"?
Early, to capture
the magic moment.
Have a great evening.
Good evening.
I was an early-winter baby.
My parents live in a village
in Bearn, in the Pyrenees.
They cultivate
our ancestors' land.
At least, my father
cultivates my mother's
ancestors' land.
Days after my birth,
the priest begged my parents
to let me be baby Jesus
in the nativity scene
he was making.
It would be great.
You couldn't find a boy?
That's how I changed sex
and got my first big role
before an emotive crowd.
At 7, I was devastated
by the death of Gedeon,
a white duck I'd won at
a fair in a nearby village.
I declared that all my life
I'd be strongly opposed
to the concept of death.
At 10,
I began to wonder if I was
really related to my family.
At 17, I decided to
leave the family nest
to avoid, despite my
expressed opposition to death,
strangling my father.
I went to Bordeaux with
Leonard, my current boyfriend.
Still as cute as ever.
And you're a spaniel?
A smiley spaniel.
Little mouse, cooee.
Mouse, the mouse.
In Bordeaux, I discovered
the joys of urban life.
I loved dancing, drinking,
physical love and chemical drugs.
- Okay?
- Yeah, I'm okay.
Yeah, okay, okay.
Sorry.
Great evening.
Yeah, it's brilliant, so good.
Happy birthday, Marie.
How do you know my name?
Have we met before?
Here.
Open it.
This is my present to you.
A little pill.
You're leaving?
From that moment on,
I became the odd ball
that I am today.
After that night,
it started to sometimes feel like
life stopped abruptly
for a few seconds,
or that at least I was gone.
I decided to change
my life and town,
abandon my law studies,
leave Bordeaux, Leonard,
and move to Paris.
The rents were sky high
so I replied to an ad.
Suzanne entered my life.
You're very pretty.
You must get that a lot.
Not so much.
The world is cruel,
people are blind.
You know,
I hardly ever go out.
I have everything I need, here.
I have my memories,
my books, my paintings.
What would I do outside?
You can move in when you want.
That is, if you like the room.
Really?
Live how you choose,
do what you have to do.
I just need to know
that you're not far from me.
She was a former actress,
shepherdess, teacher,
photographer, hotel maid,
American artist's model.
Married 3 times,
didn't want children.
He was still young...
She talked about the
departed she'd loved,
about weariness
and a sense of having lived enough.
After a while,
it's like an injustice,
still being in the world.
Don't you think?
Yes, maybe.
I lied.
I don't know how you can
think about your own death.
You know, Suzanne?
You're my 1st female friend.
My 1st real girlfriend.
Suzanne introduced me to Balthazar,
a top fashion photographer.
I compiled a portfolio and
joined a modelling agency.
Offers kept coming in,
until the day I agreed to appear
in a perfume commercial.
I found myself half naked,
kissing some guy
who looked like a cyborg.
Cut.
I decided to stop
making a living that way.
I started babysitting.
Babies are strange creatures to me.
They seem to suffer constantly.
You didn't ask to be born.
Feel resentful?
Then one night...
Okay Suzanne?
Suzanne?
Suzanne was cremated
at Pere-Lachaise cemetery.
Why's she sad?
I left the funeral alone.
I didn't know anyone.
It felt like...
Suzanne had been a mystery.
She'd passed like a shadow.
I think...
my purpose was
to be there when she died
and she planned it that way.
I was angry at her.
Then I forgave her.
I lived in a hotel,
waiting for a break.
I needed money,
so I decided to return to modelling.
While I waited for offers,
I slept all day
and walked all night,
brainstorming about my future.
This was when I met Antoine,
a beautiful person.
Beautiful and sad.
It's written on his face.
- Good evening.
It's late, you don't know me,
but can I come in?
You need to tell me more.
I don't let strangers
in after midnight.
It's 11.45 pm.
It doesn't matter.
I'll tell you more.
It's about your friend.
It's important.
Do you have any liquor?
Whiskey?
- Japanese.
- "Japanese"?
Japanese.
- I've got Irish whiskey.
- That'll do just fine.
Have a seat.
Make yourself at home.
What's the camera for?
For filming me at night.
I sleepwalk.
It's quite new. I tape it.
- Can I see?
- What?
The footage.
No, it's personal.
That's a pity.
Sorry, there's no ice.
I don't mind.
Are you the one who's been calling?
I thought so.
What was that about Simeon?
- Tell me where he is.
- Why?
- We need to talk.
- About what?
It's personal.
- Why would I tell you?
- You know where he is?
Maybe.
Where is he?
Help yourself.
Wow, those are big.
Right...
I'll level with you.
Marie was my girlfriend,
the girl whose wallet Simeon found.
We split up recently.
I'm pretty sure he's following her.
I know she took a train,
but I don't know where to.
So, I want to know:
1) where they've gone,
2) Simeon's intentions,
and 3) if I can see your
sleepwalking footage.
You're a guy...
who's very...
You're really weird.
You don't seem very nice at first,
but you have a kind of
perseverance that makes you...
likable.
There's something
else I have to tell you.
The reason I'm here
is because your friend...
is in danger.
In what way?
Marie is dangerous.
"Dangerous"? But...
How is she dangerous?
Just dangerous.
What are you doing?
I've decided to
show you the footage.
That was last night.
Now I'm scared to fall asleep.
I've been drinking
coffee to stay awake.
It's fascinating.
You think so?
When I was a teenager,
I wrote a short story called
Sleepwalker Love.
What was it about?
The story of a guy and a girl,
both sleepwalkers.
They only love
each other at night.
- And how does it end?
- Badly.
Very badly.
One night,
they leave town
to live their love far away.
They walk along the train track,
a symbol of their freedom.
They walk together, hand in hand.
A train approaches,
but they don't hear it coming.
They keep walking.
The train gets closer,
closer...
and bam!
The train hits them
and they die in their sleep.
Right...
I'll tell you where Simeon is.
On one condition.
I'm listening.
I come with you.
It's a deal.
Don't tell Simeon we're coming.
Why not?
It'd be dangerous.
Promise?
Promise.
Until tomorrow.
8 am, Montparnasse Station.
Going to Sandy Bay?
Do you recommend it?
If you come here, you have to.
It's convex.
"Convex"?
Europe's only convex beach.
Instead of being like this,
it's like this.
And it's moving.
10 years ago, it was by the village.
Now it's on the other
side of the lighthouse.
So the holiday village has
rocks instead of a beach.
- That's funny.
- Is it true?
There's the Hell Hole.
- "Hell Hole"?
- Yeah.
Okay.
I'll go tomorrow.
My great grandfather was a member
of the first lifesaving service.
- Have you heard about it?
- No.
Back then, in Groix,
there were lots of rescue boats.
- It was Rescue Island.
- "Rescue Island"?
Why did you come?
- I followed a girl.
- You followed a girl?
Hoping what?
What's she doing in Lorient?
It's not Lorient.
Where is it then?
It's Groix.
Fuck, that's an island.
We have to take a boat.
Yes, that happens
a lot with islands.
Last time, I was 6.
Just the idea of getting
on a boat terrifies me.
I'm going to have a nap.
I didn't sleep a wink.
When my wife left,
I almost got into trouble.
Sorry?
I looked at my son.
He smiled.
I wondered: "What will
he think if you leave him?"
Do you have kids?
No.
Never wanted any.
What would they do
with a father like me ?
They're not missing much.
The next boat leaves in 15 minutes.
Do you think about death much?
No.
I mean...
not your own death,
the idea of causing it,
killing someone.
How many did you take?
Cut. Great.
We got what we want.
Have a seat there.
You know,
this video clip portrays
my primordial scene,
my founding moment.
It happened here on this beach,
Europe's only convex beach.
It's like this. You see?
It's strange, isn't it?
Yes.
What happened to you?
Wait, I'm going there.
It was the summer of 2013.
I'd just finished filming.
I'd decided to take a break.
I never take holidays.
To me, holidays are like dying.
But my body was telling me to.
I have a rule:
when your body speaks,
you must listen.
So I came to this island.
Nowell, my partner,
have a family home here.
I'd never been.
I didn't even know it existed.
We'd arrived the previous
day, eaten and drunk.
It was a lovely day.
Nowell brought me to
the beach and immediately
I felt odd vibrations.
I felt good.
There weren't many people.
We got out our towels
and lay down on the sand...
I'd never done that before.
My body started to go numb.
It was strange.
Strange, but not unpleasant.
Quite the opposite.
That was the moment I left it.
Left what?
Left my body.
There were two of us.
I saw it lying there on
the beach, next to Nowell.
I had left that bodily form.
I looked at myself like a stranger.
That's when I turned
towards the sea and saw you.
How did you see me?
I saw the sea maiden
in a dreamlike light.
When I started to make the video,
I searched actresses' faces
for one that looked like her.
And when I discovered
your perfume ad,
I couldn't believe my eyes.
- You know, the one that...
- Yeah, yeah, I know the one.
Even now, I feel troubled
when I look at you.
You have to lose the girlfriend.
She doesn't love you.
She loves your fame.
You don't love her either.
Not truly.
You just like sleeping with her.
- What are you doing?
- Shut up, I'm concentrating.
Where did she go?
Now, I'm going to dress you,
to make you look
a little less hillbilly.
"Hillbilly"?
What's this madness?
That's better!
Right... come on, do like me.
Come on, do like me.
So I did what the sea maiden asked.
I raised my arms
and it was like being reborn.
Like becoming someone else.
That was the reality.
I became someone else.
From now on,
your name is Cosmo.
"Cosmo"?
Yes, Cosmo.
Like the cosmos,
without the second 's'.
Next,
you'll stop making
such cynical music,
which doesn't suit you at all.
You'll move into electronic music.
But I know nothing about it.
You'll learn.
You're no dumber than anyone.
And you're a true musician.
You need to be braver.
Get keyboards.
- "Keyboards"?
- Yes.
Keyboards, drum
machines and a good beat.
And start writing abstract lyrics
that only you understand.
They'll evoke images
that belong to you alone
and are deeply moving.
You'll come here to film
the video to your first single,
from your first album,
from your new career.
It will be about today.
Then you disappeared
and I found myself alone,
planted there like an idiot.
So that's what happened.
What are you...?
But... I don't understand.
How...?
You followed me.
- You know each other?
- No.
- You are...
- Cosmo.
Didn't recognise you.
Simeon.
- Cosmo?
- Yeah?
Let's find shelter.
The rain's coming.
Come on.
This is good.
Go on, have a seat.
Tequila, rum...
vodka...
Serve yourselves.
Never forget your roots,
who you were before.
I look at that every day.
Now, a little vodka for me.
- One for you too?
- Yes, thanks.
That's good.
Go on, speak.
You must have so much to say.
Pretend we're not here.
I'll try to explain.
I went back to the
bar where we met.
I waited for you.
I wanted to talk to you.
What are you doing?
Where are you?
Oh, that...
The taxi arrived
and stole my thunder.
I know what you mean.
Go on, I'm listening.
Then, I followed you to the station,
I hopped on the train,
then on the boat.
It's all very factual.
Tell her how you're
feeling right now, deep down.
You only live once.
Mustn't miss these moments.
For example,
if I hadn't taken a chance
on the beach that day,
with Marie,
I mean the sea maiden,
I would have ended up miserable
and phony, a soulless musician
obsessed with his own image.
There's a Chinese proverb:
"You can't look at the stars
while you are walking
"with a stone in your shoe."
Well, I had a big stone
in my shoe before I met
the sea maiden.
Cosmo, I think you had heat stroke,
intense heat stroke
that made you hallucinate.
You don't mean that.
The rain's stopped.
I'll go get changed.
Want us to remove your makeup?
No, I can do it.
- Coming with me?
- Yes.
Hang on.
The big wrap party's tonight.
Did you distribute the flyers?
I did it during the break.
Coming? I'm counting on you.
Yeah.
See you later.
It's me.
I've got something weird
to tell you. A bit late now.
It all happened so fast.
Please don't be mad at me.
So.
I'm on a boat
heading for the island with
that girl's ex-boyfriend.
I'll explain later.
According to him, she's dangerous,
and he...
I've got to go.
- Oh, shit!
- Are you okay?
- It's all moving.
- Come get some air.
I feel so bad.
Don't resist the sea.
Go with the wave,
like a floating bottle.
Look.
There's the island.
We've made it.
What Cosmo said wasn't so dumb.
What did he say?
He said...
you only live once.
He talked about stars and
having a stone in your shoe.
The metaphor didn't inspire me.
Marie?
Yes?
I remember now.
- What?
- The first time I saw you.
I was with my daughter
at Pere-Lachaise.
She asked me why you were sad.
Thanks for returning my wallet.
No problem.
Can you help me with...?
Look.
Look how beautiful it is.
It's beautiful.
I got anxious.
I was ridiculous. Sorry.
Look.
This hotel's not bad.
We have to sleep here.
The next ferry's tomorrow.
Let's go then.
The Jetty Hotel
- Hello.
Hello.
Two rooms please.
- What?
- Two rooms.
Thank you.
It's upstairs.
The stairs are there.
Right, thanks.
We'll meet here once
I've collected myself.
Don't do anything without me.
Can I trust you?
- Promise?
- Promise.
- A party ?
- Yes.
The crossing was gruelling.
Victor had to fight his demons
in order to reach the island.
Simeon and Marie
arrived the day before,
separately.
Victor didn't know
whether they'd met up.
Neither did he know
Simeon's intentions.
He wasn't even sure of his own.
Why had he come to this island?
How would it all end?
He felt capable of anything.
Unsettling urges
were rising from within.
He rested in his room
at the Jetty Hotel,
fighting off the images
infecting his mind.
He thought about The Jetty, a film
that he'd seen with Marie.
Victor remembered
the voice-over:
"This is the story of a man, marked
by an image from his childhood."
But soon the parasitic images
returned to haunt him.
Today, at 3.53 pm.
Yes, it's me.
I've got something weird to tell you.
A bit late now.
It all happened so fast.
Please don't be mad at me.
Today, at 5.04 pm.
Why don't you pick up?
We just got to the island.
We're staying at the hotel...
- What's the name again?
- The Jetty Hotel.
The Jetty Hotel.
It's really nice.
Call me back when you get this.
I don't know what to do.
The guy I came with
is a bit unstable.
So, call me back. Oscar.
End of new messages.
To listen to your...
- You're not going to answer?
- No.
- Are you writing?
- Yes.
Right...
What do we do now?
I have to find Marie.
They told me Simeon got here
last night and has a room here.
There's a party tonight.
The wrap party for a music video.
I feel like a walk.
You're a genius.
Wait for me.
- Is it that way?
- Yes, straight ahead.
Why are we going to the manor?
Marie must be there.
What makes you say that?
She shot adverts
when we were together.
I thought I'd seen her before.
That's Simeon!
- Shit!
- Oscar?
- What are you doing?
- You're not going to shoot me?
- Put your hands up.
Don't you want to talk?
I wanted to talk to you.
About what?
Quite frankly, I don't
think we have much to say.
The location and
scenery are interesting.
The light, the wind...
The 3 of us are here.
Marie's around somewhere...
Why did you follow her?
You said she's dangerous.
So?
You court danger,
head down, no questions asked.
Yes. I thought:
"What is a dangerous girl?"
It made me curious to see her.
A sound argument.
Oscar.
- What's all this?
- I'll explain.
The bathroom's upstairs.
Antoine?
I can't believe it.
- Who's that?
- That's Oscar.
My flatmate.
A pepper spray gun.
How stupid is that?
What a dumb idea to tackle me.
As if I'd kill your best friend.
Antoine?
You're such a weirdo.
You never said.
- Are you in love with Marie?
- Oh please...
I fell for you the moment
I saw you at the bus stop.
Have you slept together?
Maybe...
you two should talk one-to-one.
Let's go have a smoke, Oscar.
But I quit smoking, Simeon.
Come.
Oscar.
I was a jerk:
my electro-hypersensitivity
and my book launch.
There's something
I wanted to say to you.
I understand why you left me.
I would have done the same.
I'd leave me.
I'd have left me sooner.
Don't you think the main thing
is that we knew each other?
We could have passed each
other by without ever meeting.
Like if I hadn't been
at the bus stop.
Are you okay?
Are you crying?
I think it's the pepper spray.
You've changed, Marie.
You're calmer.
Is it because of this guy?
Maybe.
Do you know he takes his daughter,
who's very young,
to cemeteries?
Yes, I know.
And to erotic films.
I mean Korean films.
Are you writing again?
Yes.
And? What's it about?
I'd rather keep it secret for now.
There's a moving convex beach.
What's that nonsense?
It's not nonsense.
Speaking of strange movements,
are you still sleepwalking?
I haven't slept since yesterday.
So, I don't know.
But I did have a
conversation with myself.
Really?
When I was talking
to myself, I said:
"Oscar, it's funny how
"this sleepwalking business happens
"right after you finish a piece."
That gave me a boost to finish
and it gave me an idea.
Look.
I put it on YouTube.
5 000 views already.
That's awesome!
Bravo, Oscar.
You managed to make a hit
that's both sad and a dance tune.
What's this?
He's a cross between
that strange singer and Rael.
- Good evening, Cosmo.
- So, my friend Simeon?
Do I have to fetch you?
This is my best friend, Oscar,
who's also a musician.
Nice to meet you, Oscar.
Likewise, Cosmo.
Amazing.
Brilliantly mad.
Go on.
Play it for them.
- Go on.
- Really?
No.
I can't play my music.
Be daring!
Alright then!
Over to you.
Marie? Simeon?
Join us.
Come on.
Marie.
Simeon.
Antoine.
Marie.
What?
I'm going to stay here
to finish my book.
Are you sure?
Yes.
I have the title.
What is it called?
It's called Marie and the Castaways.
The next morning,
they walked along
Sandy Bay beach together,
towards the Hell Hole.
An evil thought
crossed Victor's mind.
Marie and Simeon left the island
without Victor,
alone, with his story.
What happens next?
Subtitles: Eclair Media