FILMEXPORT HOME VIDEO
Presents
MARIJKA THE UNFAITHFUL
Story by
Screenplay by
Directed by
Music by
National Theatre Orchestra Conducted by
Director of Photography / Assistant
Art Director / Film Editor
Produced by
Sound Editor
The film was shot in Subcarpathian
Ruthenia, in Kolochava and Chorna Ritsa
The actors are highlanders and fellow
countrymen of outlaw Nikola Suhaj
Cast
Fire, fire!
- Water! Bring water!
Good day, Petro.
- What do you want from me?
Don´t be so stubborn
and sell the land to me, Petro.
No! I won´t sell it!
If you don´t sell it,
I´ll have to take it myself.
You still owe me money
and I´ll write something off.
Don´t be so hard headed!
Khust - Kolochava Bus Terminal
How much is it?
- Twenty crowns.
How much?
All right, here you are.
Look at the man.
Quiet. Wait.
I want to take a photograph of you.
Quiet. Stop...
Wait, wait...
Never mind.
Is there a pub somewhere?
Beer. Bier...
You should´ve built one right here,
if you were smart
and knew the ropes...
Goodbye!
What do you want this time?
- Have you made up your mind yet?
Will you sell or not?
- No! Never!
Don´t be so hasty and think it over.
Happy Shabbat!
He doesn´t want to sell but he will.
Go on.
Why do I have to work so hard?
- You have to, Marijka.
That´s why we were born.
Hurry up.
Why aren´t you working?
Look at my hands.
It´s no good working with you women!
We have a cottage to build!
Hang it!
She doesn´t want to work.
You can´t go on like this, Marijka,
or we´ll never finish the cottage.
I don´t have time for this,
I have to go to the forest to work.
I´d hire someone if had the money.
But everyone´s going to the forest.
- If only she were willing to work!
All of us can´t go
and only Danilo will stay here.
It´s no use...
Good Lord,
why is our life so hard!
Good day.
- Danilo.
Let´s go home.
Praise the Lord.
- Forever and ever.
I need a helper.
- To build your cottage?
I could help you out.
- Let´s go.
Why don´t you hire me then?
- I could.
Let´s talk about it inside.
- Very well.
I´ll pay you properly.
And there´s not much work.
I need you to work for me
until we float timber.
Until then you could work for me
for a reasonable wage.
L´ve got enough work of my own
and I don´t want to skin you.
I´ll do it for a cheap price.
- That´s settled then.
L´m getting married in three weeks
and nothing is ready yet.
Let me tell you something.
Shabbat is almost over,
so I can tell you now.
- What is it?
- L´ve found a nice place for you.
A fine place indeed.
I could build an inn there.
The Lord summoned
Princess Sabbath to his throne.
I recorded Petro´s debt
on his land in the books.
It is a fine place.
Ester and Hershkowitz will have an inn
and a tobacconist´s shop there.
Praise the Lord!
Praise the Lord,
Jesus Christ!
Brother, don´t let Mother work
on her own at home.
Not to worry, brother.
- I know.
Come and have a look at my fine goods.
For five crowns only.
It´s beautiful!
Do you like the scarf?
- It´s very nice.
Petro Birchak!
Have you made up your mind?
Will you sell?
- I won´t!
Play us a tune, band!
Keron, come here.
You´ll dismiss Petro in a week.
- Who?
Petro Birchak.
- Why would I do that?!
Do it for me. Dismiss him.
And I´ll write something off
from your debt.
He´d kill me if I do that.
He won´t kill you.
Do it for me.
What´s in it for me?
- I´ll settle with you later.
Very well, I´ll see what I can do.
Let´s get going, fellas!
Follow me!
Let´s sing the Red Rose.
You´ll be all alone now.
- Olena will be with me.
How are you?
You´re so pretty.
May the Lord bless you with good health.
How are you?
- Very well.
I know, you old fox.
Give me some nuts.
How is our young lady?
How about a kiss, huh?
Leave me alone!
- What do you want from her?!
Keep your hands off!
Or do you want to kill me?
You ought to show some respect
to your employer!
Don´t be angry at him, Mr. Keron,
he´s still a hot-headed youth.
Shut up! Hush!
Is your corn ground?
- Yes, it is. - Very well.
Are you still afraid of me?
Come on, don´t be afraid...
- Please, don´t...
It´s finely ground.
Give it to Khava.
- Take it...
Take it before I buy it...
Have you seen Keron Herzan?
- No.
I don´t believe you!
You´ve paid us less!
Me?
- Show me!
I can show you.
You keep ripping us off.
Let´s go.
- That´s not true.
Marijka, get some hay.
- Yes.
Why aren´t you doing anything!
L´m forced to do everything myself.
Don´t stare at her like that
and do your work!
Go to hell!
May the Devil take you!
- Good Lord!
A plague on you!
And misfortune!
Marijka!
Adam, you´ll go over there
and Petro will chop the bark off.
Why are you giving him such work?
- He´s a lazy and unreliable fellow.
I want to get rid of him.
Meet me at Rosenthal´s in an hour.
Give me a discount, the bacon stinks.
Smell it.
- But you knew about it.
You didn´t have to buy it.
Cut it out!
To hell with you!
How are you, Margita?
Where´s Khava?
Are you still angry at me?
L´ve brought you something.
Why can´t you leave me alone?!
- You´re always like that...
Go to hell!
What do you think of the bacon?
Nothing.
- It´s good bacon.
If you say so...
- It´s good and cheap.
Do you have some home brew?
I have and it´s good and cheap.
And strong. Everything I sell is good.
- How much do you want for a litre?
A few crowns.
- A few crowns? All right.
I may buy more. I´ll leave some money
as an advance.
Very well.
I´ll leave the bacon here, too.
Petro Birchak will pick it up.
All right.
Khava!
Keron... Keron! Keron!
Itska! Keron... Itska!
What do you want?!
Here´s some...
- Go to hell!
Remember what you have done, Itska!
You´ll never see me here again!
- That´s all we needed.
You´re such a fool!
Why did you fall out with him?!
That´s all we needed!
Good day, Rosenthal.
- Good day to you.
L´ve come for bacon. Where is it?
- Over there. Take it.
Tell him not to bring it
to my house ever again.
L´ve got enough troubles of my own.
- L´ve got troubles of my own, too.
L´ve got more troubles than you. Go.
- Goodbye.
Let´s move out
and leave this place.
Let´s leave this place.
Move out.
Six...
Seven...
Here´s bacon for lunch.
It stinks.
- What stinks?
Are we supposed to eat it?
This is what Keron buys for us!
If we work hard,
we need to be fed properly.
It´s Keron´s work! To hell with him!
We can´t eat this. Look.
Feed it to the Devil! Let´s go!
Look, fellas, if l´m not right...
Let´s find Keron!
Keron, your men earn too much.
The price of timber has dropped.
We´ll cut their wages by 20 percent.
We can´t do that!
We must. Some cigarettes, enough to eat,
and home brew should fix it.
Only if the men accept it.
Give it to them.
- Twenty percent off?
Three percent are for you.
I´ll see what I can do.
- Go.
And talk to them.
- I will.
I´ll count it up.
That´s much better now.
- Goodbye.
I bring you money, fellas.
You´re going and you too
to make sure that everything goes well.
You´ll help them too, Kovacz.
Petro!
Don´t you hear?
You´ll fetch some home brew!
We´ve bought tickets to Jaffa, Father.
- What?
It´s one of Herzan´s men.
Thank God.
He could buy something.
May the Lord keep you, Rosenthal.
- Likewise.
I need some home brew.
- It´s over there.
It´s good and strong. Here.
Making good home brew
isn´t easy, is it? - Take it.
Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
What´s the matter?
- Nothing.
Come, let´s have a drink, Petro.
- All right.
It looks like the price of timber
has dropped.
They´re cutting our wages by 30 percent.
It´s too much for us.
I bargained with them
to cut your wages by 20 percent.
It´s up to you, fellas.
It makes no difference to me.
As long as we get something in turn.
It´s better than nothing.
We have to accept it.
We have no choice.
- Very well.
Have you heard the news?
- What news?
Keron wants to cut our pay.
- Our pay?
They can´t do that!
We won´t let them do it!
Get fire from the neighbour.
- Right away.
May the Lord bless you with a young,
pretty, hardworking and pious woman.
May the Lord bless you with glory,
new life and keep you.
What will she get?
- A fine new inn.
Petro Birchak built it.
Birchak would be a fool
to build it for you.
He won´t give it away for nothing.
- He owes me money.
You can see for yourself.
Here´s my book of debts.
I have a house, an inn,
and all is good.
May you have ten thousand
sheep in your pound
and two or three lambs from each ewe.
May your wife be happy
and may you lead a happy family life.
What will we call our inn?
It has to have a name.
- Turistaheim.
No.
L´ve got it. Touristhouse.
May the Lord keep you.
Give me paper and sugar for the eggs.
Here you are.
Goodbye.
STATE ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
Write a letter for me.
- I can write it for you.
There´s no need.
Dear Petro, Marijka is cheating
on you with Danilo. Olena.
Listen, it´s meal time.
You ought to let them go.
Look at what time it is.
Break.
Is this supposed to be bacon?
And I am to eat it?! Look!
He´s ripping us off! Thief!
We won´t let them cut our wages!
Who is ripping you off? Me?
Who bought you the ram?
Who bought you home brew?
L´m not ripping you off, Rosenthal is!
Let´s teach him a lesson!
Run! Pogrom!
Talk sensibly, fellow.
Who are the people?
The loggers from the forest.
- I though so!
Who is he talking to about it?
- Maybe he doesn´t want to wait.
Is Keron with them?
- He is. - Be careful.
Line up!
The rabbi told me:
´´lf you leave, you´ll make God angry. ´´
Run, Rosenthal, pogrom.
The loggers are coming!
Pogrom! Pogrom!
Nothing´s the matter,
the men just had too much to drink.
Let me take care of it.
I´ll put things in order.
By hook or by crook.
It´s our right.
Let´s go!
Follow me, let´s put things in order.
Petro Birchak!
- That´s me!
L´ve got a letter for you.
Where is it from? - From Kolochava.
- Any news?
Petro Suhaj!
- That´s me.
I´ll read it for you.
- No, thanks.
He´s a strange man.
- Who?
Petro, help them carry the log.
A 20 percent reduction.
How do you expect to achieve it?
I managed to cut production
costs by 20 percent.
How did you manage that?
I reduced the workers´ wages
by a quarter.
It wasn´t an easy thing to do.
The workers went on strike.
And if it weren´t for Keron Herzan...
You´re a true businessman, Hugo.
A genuine talent
when it comes to national economy.
How dare you come here!
Go to my father.
Rosenthal, would you read
this letter for me?
Give it to me, I´ll read it for you.
Dear Petro, Marijka is cheating
on you with Danilo. Olena.
Nothing else?
- Nothing.
Give me some home brew.
If you pay for it.
On the slate.
- I can´t.
Give it to me on the slate.
What a bargain!
What did you read to him, Father?
What was it?
His wife is cheating on him.
He´ll kill her when he comes home.
Kill her!
- It happens.
Out of my way!
- What do you want?
What are you doing?!
It´s Danilo´s oar.
What do you want?!
What do you want!
You´ll get a hundred crowns and leave!
You´re fired!
Fired or not, the logs are ready.
Danilo will come.
Let me go on the raft with him.
I´ll settle with fifty crowns.
Very well.
They´ve been waiting for you
for quite a while! - L´m coming.
What are you doing? Help him out!
Praise the Lord.
- Praise the Lord.
You´ve come just in time,
the logs are ready.
I´ll start working right away.
Praise the Lord.
- Praise the Lord.
How´s Mother?
- She´s well, thank God.
Praise the Lord.
- And what did Marijka say?
Nothing.
Wait! Wait!
You´ve come just in time.
Go now! Hurry up!
Be off!
Do you know
what happened to Danilo?
What´s the matter with you?
- Nothing.
You don´t know
anything, Adam, do you?
I know what happened.
- You only think you do.
You´ll never get anything out of them.
One´s like a stranger here.
Petro Birchak killed my brother Danilo!
In that case, tell me something else.
How did you find out?
- I know.
I mean whether you have any evidence.
Anything that would prove you right.
I don´t, I only know he killed him.
You know nothing at all,
no matter what you think.
I can´t prove it before the court
but I...
That´s just it. And where
will you go now? - Home.
Open the door.
I can hardly breathe in here.
It can´t be that bad.
You´re drinking too much, dear.
I can´t stand this damned country
any more.
Do you know Petr Birchak?
- I see him now and then.
He killed someone today.
- Why?
Why? Because he´s an animal.
Because this wolf country.
Because this country
is still in the middle ages.
It´s horrible.
He´ll end in jail.
And who would report him to the police?
Besides, it´s hard to prove.
Maybe it was an accident after all.
You always pick the worst,
don´t you?
They eat one another.
Animals, Jews, men and their masters...
...and we´ll all end up dead.
What blasphemy!
I´d be happy here.
Where are you going?
Never mind.
Goodbye, Father.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye, my child.
You´ll come in a year, Father.
You will see.
Let´s go. It´s high time to leave.
They´re waiting for us.
Where are they going, Mr. Rosenthal?
To Jaffa.
Pour me a glass, Rosenthal.
I don´t have time.
I have to bid them farewell.
What for? They are lucky
they can leave
this damned country.
- You´re right.
It such a nice house.
- It costs money.
We need an oven.
- Make one yourself then.
May the Lord bless you with good health.
- The same to you.
What brings you here?
- There´s no help here.
This cottage belongs to me.
- Good Lord, how can that be?
How come?
- Your son owes me a lot of money.
It´s my house now.
I want to live here
so pack your things and go.
Very nice.
It´s a nice house.
It´s Petro´s cottage.
It´s mine now!
Good day.
Do you have cigarettes and beer?
Our first customer!
- At last.
Don´t laugh. It´s a nice sign.
Here´s your beer and cigarettes.
- Open it.
Open it.
A fine business you have. Mazel tov!
It was the Czech man who told
us to open our Touristhouse.
Pack your things and leave.
It serves you right. You can go.
He should have left long ago.
Good luck and may the Lord keep you.
Petro killed Danilo!
Petro owes me more
than his cottage and land are worth.
He´s here! Petro Birchak!
Did you think I wouldn´t come back?
Do you want my cottage?
In that case, you have to pay me.
More! More!
You have to pay me more!
My God, you´ll ruin me.
Here´s a thousand crowns.
You´ve ruined me.
It´s good money.
Take it a leave.
Praise the Lord.
- Forever.
Are you hungry?
Do you hear, Marijka?
And Petro is building a new cottage.