* Hup, hup
* Hup, two, three
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* Hit the deck, leatherneck
* Fall in line, double time
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* We're going to make some
history along the battle line *
* Hup, two, three, four
* Hup, two, three, go!
* From sunny California
to the beach at Anzio *
* From beautiful Manila
to the gates of Tokyo *
* He fought in every battle
from the start to the end *
* And he was always out
in front, calling to his men *
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* Hit the deck, leatherneck
* Fall in line, double time
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* We're going to make some
history along the battle line *
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* Hit the deck, leatherneck
* Fall in line, double time
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* We're going to make some
history along the battle line *
* We're going to make
some history *
* Along the battle line
* We're going to make some
history along the battle line *
* We're going to make
some history *
* Along the battle line.
HANK: Here is Korea,
where the 1st Marine Division
is holding the line
against the North Koreans
and the Chinese hordes.
My name is Hank Dyer.
And like most
war correspondents,
I'm writing a book
between dispatches,
not on the grand scale
of Caesar's Commentaries,
nor about master strategies in
the triumph of giant machines,
but about the smallest
commodity of modern war: men.
Particularly about the men
of Gunnery Sergeant Hawkins'
platoon.
Gunny's got both fools
and wise men here,
but none who lacks
guts and strength.
Pete Kono,
the veteran campaigner;
Russ Waller, the quiet one;
Newt Levells, the naive,
likeable galoot from Texas.
Quite a contrast to Skip Roth,
with his glossy shrewdness,
known to his confidents as
The Brain.
Or David Chatfield,
the Back Bay aristocrat.
It took some doing to trim him
to the Marine pattern,
and there's still some doubt
that the operation
was a success.
And then there's that born
leader, Let's Go McCaffrey,
busted from
sergeant to private,
but don't let that fool you.
It happened on furlough,
not out here.
The fields of war
are the only circuit
that can take
that big fuse-blower.
And for better or for worse,
he's the guy these men follow.
(jet engines roaring)
Let's go!
We'll hole up here. Dig in.
-McCaffrey.
-Yo.
Work your fire team down
to that bunker; check it out.
Hey, let's go!
Let's go!
You guys cover me and Skip.
We'll get them out of there.
Don't knock them off.
We'll bring them in.
Hey, Sarge, you want to take
these guys along with yours?
Sure, Mac.
Gunny.
Yeah? Who is he?
Harper.
-How many didn't make it,
Hawkins? -Six missing.
-Charley Harper?
-Harper will be back.
I hear Harper got it.
-Tough break, Mac.
-How would you know?
He wasn't a buddy of yours;
he was a buddy of mine.
Why don't you speak plain,
McCaffrey?
Spare me that customary delicacy
of yours for a change.
Don't give me that college
crapola, you pedigree pup!
Come on, Dave,
don't think anything of it.
It's that kind of a day.
No, it's routine.
I get born in a bed
with silk sheets,
and he's dedicated
to the principle
of never letting me forget it!
I don't care how you was born,
just get that snoot of yours
down out of the air, Chatfield!
"Were born," Mac,
not "was born."
-Who you talking to?
-"Whom," not "who,"
and a verb after it would
further improve the syntax.
Don't bug me, Skip.
I don't feel like
slugging you today.
Come on.
McCaffrey, such an act
of physical violence
-will soon be
beneath your dignity. -What?
I hear you're gonna be promoted
for meritorious service,
skipping the rank of corporal
right up to sergeant.
-Huh?
-Oh, no.
What, you're not happy about it?
Promotions can lose a guy
a lot of old buddies.
Now, don't you worry, McCaffrey,
you'll get busted again,
just as you always do.
(laughter)
Yeah, it's kind of confusing
to remember what my rank is.
Well, anyhow,
here's the rest of the news.
This outfit's going
into regimental reserve.
Should mean a leave for
the Let's Go McCaffrey Club.
And that'll mean Japan!
Yahoo!
I'll bet you'll be glad
to get the furlough.
My wife's coming down
to Yokosuka from Tokyo.
She works there in
the Department
of Army Civilian Employees.
And you know something?
This will be our first chance
for a honeymoon.
We were called back into action
five minutes after
I said, "I do."
Sounds like quite a change
from this out here.
Yeah, but there's a catch to it.
Some of the men
are going to Yokosuka
for rest and rehabilitation.
Lieutenant asked me unofficially
to keep an eye on them.
-McCaffrey? -McCaffrey and
some of the other guys.
He's up for decoration.
We want him in top shape
for the big brass.
That's a large order
for McCaffrey.
Right.
A headache to the enemy,
but a real migraine to the MPs.
(people speaking Japanese)
Hi.
(sighs)
My prayers are answered.
My brave one comes back.
Not so brave, Song Do.
McCaffrey's been having
severe doubts about me lately.
-The one you call
Let's Hurry Up Go? -Uh-huh.
Maybe it's his way to hide
that he's not brave himself.
Oh, no, you can't
take that away from him.
He's a wild bull, and that
also goes for his mentality.
For three days and three nights,
I listen to the guns.
I watch the sky red with fire.
I felt the ground tremble,
and I trembled too with terror
for your safety.
And when sleep tried
to close my eyes,
your face was always before me.
And I would awake my grandfather
with cries in the night.
Is your grandfather well?
Yes, but so old.
This war has grieved him.
He will not wake up someday.
And then you'd be alone.
You won't be alone, Song Do.
I'll pull through alive.
And no matter
where else they send me,
I'll get back to you somehow.
(laughs)
Lee-san.
Sit down, my good friend.
And, uh, don't think you must
bear gifts each time we see you.
It is you yourself whom we love.
I heard a rumor that I might
get a leave before long.
And I thought you might need
a few things while I'm away--
some canned fruit, chocolate,
rice and tea.
You will not pass this way again
before you go?
No, I'm afraid not.
Then my letter will find you,
care of postmaster.
Your family would never
accept Song Do.
No, but I accept her.
I love her, and that's that.
I've broken with the past.
It all happened
when I wanted to be a Marine
with my father holding out for
desk commission in Washington.
I wanted to be a Marine.
Why do you not go to McCaffrey
and tell him these things?
Try and talk to McCaffrey?
Never.
And yet, a little while ago,
you talked of him
as though you admired him.
You know, it's strange, Lee-san,
but I do admire him.
I think it would be one of
the happiest days of my life
if he ever walked up to me,
shook my hand and said,
"Chatfield,
you'll be all right."
(playing melody)
*
* Hup, hup, hup, two, three
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* Hit the deck, leatherneck
* Fall in line, double time
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* We're going to make some
history along the battle line. *
So every officer and man
in our services
should appoint himself
an ambassador of good will.
Both in manners and speech,
he should impress our allies
and even our enemies with
our sincerity and cordiality.
Man, this whole thing's
beginning to undermine
your character.
You just worry about
your own character.
I don't want my buddies
horsing around on leave
like a bunch of Navajo Indians.
And you talk about Chatfield.
Look at him moping.
Probably over some
flat-chested society dame
who's cheating on him.
I can read the mind of that punk
like a skull with window glass.
I can hear you.
Yeah, you're brilliant, you are.
Well, maybe you can tell me
what we're gonna do for money.
I um, guess you guys heard that
I ran into a little bad luck
against a pair of loaded dice
down at the airstrip,
and we are, as they say,
flat on our honkers.
But I'm thinking all the time.
(chuckles)
Yeah, that's it--
when old Skip starts thinking,
we got nothing to worry about.
So let's get down
to the real tactical stuff.
Levells, as usual,
you'll do scout patrol.
Only you got a tougher problem
this time:
finding a couple
of kimono cuties
who likes a guy for himself
and not his dough.
Deal me out.
I got a gal, and she lives
right there in Yokosuka
where we're going.
Your duty to your buddies
comes first.
Nah, come on, Newt,
you can't let us down.
Why, you got a knack for
meeting more girls accidentally
than most guys do on purpose.
Maybe so,
but them days are over.
That's what you think.
I'm not asking you;
I'm telling you.
Well, listen, you don't
have to find a broad for me.
I got my own.
Well, I'll be happy to act
as an interpreter for you guys.
The language of love
is universal,
especially when the cherry
blossoms are in bloom.
And according to my calendar,
the, uh, cherries should be ripe
while we're in Japan.
I cut this out of
the, uh, Yokosuka American.
Says, "Hotel Okamoto,
"catering to the best,
family trade,
"has own bathhouse on premises,
refined scrub girls,
expert manipulators
and certified masseuses."
(laughs) I'd buy that!
What with?
You just keep thinking.
You'll figure an angle, Skip.
See that cigar?
That's the same kind
that Winston smokes.
I remember I was coming back
in a convoy with him,
and I said, uh, "Winnie,
how'd you like the trip?"
And he said... (clears throat)
"Well, jolly good, jolly good,
except for one thing.
(clears throat) "There were
11 of your American Marines
"chasing three
of our British nurses
"up and down the deck
of the ship.
"And never (coughs)
have so many chased so few,
so far, and received so little."
(laughter)
Glad to see you chose
a fine, respectable place.
Are you sure
your finances can handle it?
Thrift will be necessary.
Take it easy; tomorrow's
a big day for Mac's decoration.
Yeah, thanks for helping us
with the transportation, Gunny.
That's all right. I'll be using
your driver once in a while.
This looks like
a pretty classy joint.
What are we gonna use for money?
Relax, Mac.
I got a little gadget in here
that'll take care of
the room rent in nothing flat.
What is it, a bomb?
Nope. It's a much more modern
work of science.
Pete, you stay here
and do like I told you.
Ten-hut!
(speaks Japanese)
Greetings and salutations
from my distinguished commander.
He will require
a private room and bath,
plus two others for his staff.
Who is he?
(shushes)
Military secret.
His code name is Red Fox.
Family hotel, catering only to
respectable, married families.
My good man, we are here on
a mission of the utmost delicacy
which can only be accomplished
in a hotel
of the most peerless
respectability,
and yet you refuse to aid us.
Very sorry, very sorry.
"Very sorry, very sorry."
Well, Captain Sampson
and the chief of staff
will be keenly disappointed
to hear this.
Red Fox calling Blue Boy.
Blue Boy. Blue Boy.
Blue Boy, Blue Boy.
Come in, Red Fox. Over.
Red Fox, sir, there are
no accommodations available
in the hotel that
General McArthur selected. Over.
Who say so, the manager?
Put him on.
If the honorable
Japanese manager won't cooperate
with the honorable
American intelligence units
on a secret mission,
then he's put his country
in a very dishonorable mess.
Over.
No, no, no, no.
Japanese people always cooperate
with great hospitality.
Japan very much love
occupying American.
-How nice.
-Yes, yes.
Commander?
(clears throat)
Red Fox. No more?
(shushes)
Ah.
(bell dings)
-Where are the phones?
-You got phones?
-There, sir.
-Crazy.
(over radio):
Red Fox, Red Fox,
don't forget a double bed
for Blue Boy.
Oh, Blue Boy's quite a joker.
You'd be crazy about him.
(chuckles)
-(typing)
-"Don't forget a double bed
for Blue Boy"?
Well, what is it? What is it?
Captain Sampson, sir, I just
picked this out of the air,
and I'm a little confused
by the code names.
"Honorable hotel, Red Fox,
Blue Boy, General MacArthur."
I swear, Captain,
I took it down verbatim.
"Intelligence unit
on secret mission,
a double bed for Blue Boy."
Intelligence's coding system
must be all fouled up.
Tell them to run this down and
call it Operation Gainesboro.
Aye-aye, sir.
We have very finest bath
in Japan on roof.
Very strong and pretty girls
for scrubbing, you know.
Big room with fine exposure.
Great American-family-sized beds
for supreme comfort.
Get very happy sleep.
Well, boys, I can be
chummy up to a point,
but this is ridiculous.
But for Mr. Red Fox,
a private room,
fitting for commander
of expedition.
Nice joint you got here,
Yoshida.
When I get back to Washington,
I'll tell the president
all about it.
No, no, no, no, please.
This room is booked for
soon coming honeymoon couple.
Yes, I see
by the vase of flowers.
Cherry blossoms, aren't they?
Artificial, but nice sentiment.
Yes, it is.
Uh, Hotel Okamoto
wishes your mission success.
If you need help with secret
spy work, call on Yoshida.
Just consider yourself
one of us, Yoshida-san.
Bountiful thanks.
And you will not be
disappointed.
I was once house detective.
(speaks Japanese)
Grab a mattress and sleep
on the floor, Chatfield.
You won't catch cold.
How could I?
I brought my silk sheets
with me.
(whistling tune)
Well, I got a phone call through
and struck gold.
You did? Where?
No place you could cut it.
This is a hideout deal.
And you leave big footprints.
You know, there's something
crummy about you, Waller.
Look who's talking.
You ain't no angel, McCaffrey.
No, I'm not,
but I don't hide nothing.
My hands are always on the table
in plain sight.
But not yours.
I get the feeling
they're kind of dirty.
You know, if you wasn't apt to
be my sergeant, I'd flatten you.
Well, come on, chicken,
I'm still a private.
Now, come on, fellas,
cut it out!
The matter with you?
We're gonna have some fun, huh?
What's the matter?
Thanks, Skip. I-I got to be
careful and get that promotion.
Yeah, that promotion.
But you're not very happy
about it, are you?
(chuckles) No, it just won't be
the same old happy life.
Well, I wish I could help you,
but who am I
to challenge destiny?
Hey, Newt, what's the score
with you? When's the wedding?
I gave the clerk her address and
we looked up the phone number,
but she's moved.
My nerves are jumpy, Skip.
I think I'll get me
one of them baths,
let one of them cuties
give me a massage.
Why don't you fellas go up,
keep an eye on him.
He's liable to start
massaging those cuties himself.
I think you got
something there, Skip.
Well, this mattress is no good
without a pillow.
Poor old McCaffrey.
What do you mean?
Uh, I should've let him
put Waller in the hospital
and lose his promotion.
He'd be happier,
I'd be happier.
We'd all be happier.
Maybe he'd even
take it easier on you.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
I guess the man wasn't born for
responsibilities and restraints.
Only when the guns are firing.
When McCaffrey's on furlough,
he just doesn't fit in.
You know, I'd almost be willing
to see him wreck this joint
just to save him the misery
of that promotion.
Well, I'll see you
at the baths, huh?
Yeah, I'll be right up.
I, uh, just want to catch up
on my correspondence
with Mother.
Private McCaffrey,
Hotel Okamoto.
-(child giggles)
-Hello there.
Hey, what am I offered here?!
(speaking Japanese)
Yeah, I'll take
anything you got.
(laughs)
Letter for Private McCaffrey,
requesting quick delivery.
Red Fox McCaffrey, that's me.
Who'd know I'm here, Skip?
Well, we had to leave
a temporary address
at the air station.
Yeah, maybe it's something
about my promotion.
Uh, my hands are wet, honey.
Read it to me,
if you savvy the lingo.
Um, "Dear Desmond."
-Desmond!
-(excited chatter, laughter)
Well, I think that'll sound
rather dashing,
Sergeant Desmond McCaffrey.
-(laughter)
-Nobody ever calls me that name.
Somebody must have been
looking in the files.
Desmond! (whooping)
"Dear Desmond, for a long time,
I have wished to express
"my secret admiration for you.
"I withheld the impulse,
"fearing that the deep emotion
you inspire in me might be
"misunderstood by a person
less sensitive than you and I.
-(men whooping, laughing)
-"At last, however,
"when I saw you here,
revealed in all your masculine
Greek god magnificence..."
(laughter, whistling)
Where'd that letter come from?
I found it
on the reception desk.
Perhaps a lady in the women's
bath took an admiring peek.
No, some crumb-bum in here
wrote it.
I got a notion
to wreck this joint!
You got the right idea, Mac.
I'd make a United Nations case
out of this.
Wait, read some more, honey.
I'll get a clue
to who I'm gonna murder.
"I fled to the retiring room
and penned this missive,
"which I hope you will
never discuss
with your coarse
and vulgar associates."
-Whoops. -All right, Skip,
who's been out of here?
Who's been out of here
long enough to write that junk?
Gee, I don't know, Desmond.
I guess I was too relaxed.
You keep reading, honey;
we'll look for a clue.
"But for the present,
I must remain anonymous,
"dreading that
you may think ill of me,
"languishing for some
future moment when I can look
"into your great, blue eyes and
know the true poetic tenderness
that you conceal beneath your
gruff exterior." -(laughter)
Poetic, huh?
Tender, huh?
How's it signed?
"Lonesome."
(laughter, whooping, whistling)
All right, I'll find that joker!
-I'll knock that lollypop
off his stick! -Attaboy.
What kind of a joint
are you running here?
I'll rip this place wide open.
It'll take all the plumbers in
Japan to put it together again!
Now you're talking, buddy!
(laughs)
Wait a minute.
Why didn't I
think of this before?
Think of what before?
I got it now.
It was one of these cuties
in here wrote it.
Did you girlies go to school
and learn your English
real good, huh?
Or maybe you were right, honey.
Maybe some dame
did take a peek in here
and remembers me
from my last trip to this burg.
(laughs)
Sure, I'm always blowing my
stack without analyzing things.
(chuckles)
Hey, honey, you've been
scrubbing me real nice.
-Let me scrub you.
-(woman shrieks)
(laughter)
(playful shouting)
Uh, miss, bring me
a bottle of cognac.
I'm expecting a lady friend.
-Cognac. Cognac.
-Fine. Cognac.
Okay? Yeah.
-Thank you very much.
-That's all.
Hi, lover boy.
Hi-ya, kid. You've been
on my mind ever since Honolulu.
(chuckles)
Oh.
Mm.
I managed to get away
for a little while,
but I got to be back
pretty soon.
What is this, always having
to get back to somebody?
The same way in Honolulu.
I've been wondering about you.
You just keep on wondering,
big boy.
Maybe that'll
keep you interested.
Stop bugging me.
What's with you, anyhow?
Why don't you have me
up to your place?
My place is
anywhere we get together.
You know what I mean--
your home.
(laughs)
Social climber, huh?
Mm-hmm.
Okay, you got an invitation
for tonight.
I'll leave
the back door unlocked.
You big ape.
Why do I take
these chances for you?
You know why.
Yep, I guess I do.
Oh, uh, no, miss.
(speaking Japanese)
Come on, baby.
Uh-huh.
Let's go.
*
What is the soldier's pleasure?
Well, I ain't feeling
much pleasure, miss,
but I'd be obliged to learn
where Grace Blake has moved to.
I used to write her
at this number.
Grace, did you say?
Are you by any chance
her brother?
Uh, no, ma'am, I'm her feller.
We're gonna get married.
I believe Grace did
mention something,
that she had some sort
of a misalliance
with an American Marine.
Well, no, ma'am,
we didn't mess around none.
Oh, she was one girl
I sure respected.
Come into the parlor.
I'll see what information
I have about her.
Here we are.
Blake, Grace.
Brunette, age 28.
Height: five-foot-six.
Excellent figure,
lady-like manners.
Yeah, and to think
a lady like Grace
had to live in
a Japanese prison camp.
We won't discuss that.
I'm sorry, she didn't leave
a forwarding address.
Well, this is
a terrible disappointment to me.
See, ever since I left Texas,
I've been dreaming about
somehow getting to Japan,
and-and instead I landed
straight into Busan, Korea.
Well, I have a wide social
acquaintance in this city.
There are any number
of nice girls
to whom I could introduce you.
Sit down, won't you?
No, ma'am.
Thanking you all the same,
but I ain't feeling so hot.
Ah, youth-- its broken hearts
can be quickly mended.
Sit down and tell me about
your exciting young life.
You're a Marine I see.
Your pay amounts to a great deal
in Japanese yen.
You are a lucky boy, really.
Money is only
a little material thing,
and yet it compensates
for many sorrows.
I spent my last pay
two months before I got it.
How naughty of you.
You are a prodigal,
perhaps because your pay
is only a trifle to you.
I believe you mentioned
being from Texas,
that great, rich American state
of oil, cattle and millionaires.
Yes'm, but my folks are only
poor cotton sharecroppers.
Really?
That is most unfortunate.
Well, I hope I haven't
detained you too long.
And life ticks away so fast,
doesn't it?
Not a precious moment
should be wasted.
-(phone ringing)
-Good-bye.
Yes?
Oh, doggone,
my bad luck's got me so loco,
I don't even know
where I'm going.
Maybe your luck change now,
solider boy.
Me, Su Me Sagita.
Me, Sio Sagita.
Me, Toyo Sagita.
We all three sisters.
He pretty nice.
Nice for Marine.
Big dreamy-eyed boy.
Sagita sisters share everything
with each other.
Yeah, where we going?
To Yokosuka Gaiety Club.
No, no, I wouldn't do you
no good there.
-I got bad troubles.
-Aw.
But there's some buddies of mine
who are raring to go.
They've been counting on me
for something like this.
If you're all gonna be
at the Gaiety tonight,
I'll bring them on over.
-Happy times!
-(giggling)
We keep honorable get-together.
-Sayonara.
Sayonara.
(chuckles)
That dumb little cookie
that wrote this, Gus--
why didn't she tell me to
my face she's nuts about me?
I ain't hard to talk to.
Yeah, I wonder
if she's got a girlfriend.
What if she has? What do we do?
Invite them up here
for a dinner of sea rations?
Wouldn't that make
a swell impression.
More dames out there in the
Ginza than snowballs in Alaska,
all just itching
to make my acquaintance,
if I had a little scratch
in my pocket.
And with all due respect to that
Greek god physique of yours,
let's not underestimate
the power of a little money.
Ah, why'd I bother
to take a bath anyway?
From the look on your kisser,
I guess you didn't catch up
with that broad of yours.
She's a lady, and don't you be
calling her a broad.
You never seen a lady till
you've seen that broad of mine.
I've seen the place
where she used to live.
It's a real nice boarding house
run by a real lady.
The last thing I'm looking for
is room and board.
What else you got to report?
Su Me, Toyo, Sio.
Cut the Japanese lingo.
Don't try to cover up
you blew your mission, Levells.
But I didn't;
that's their names.
Three of the cutest
little bunnies you ever seen.
Yeah?
Family type, not gold diggers?
Well, I'm afraid
this ain't exactly Lin Leese.
They seem to know
their way around.
They said to meet them
at the Gaiety Club tonight.
The Gaiety Club?
Why, coffee's a buck
a cup there,
and we're so broke,
we're eating kettle rations.
And now, gentlemen,
I am going down to the lobby,
and I'm gonna hit old "Ahso" for
about 200 bucks worth of yen.
Oh, come on, you'll have this
whole hotel down on our heads.
That's what they said to the guy
who built
the Leaning Tower of Pisa.
Just take it easy, Skip.
We got to remember tomorrow.
Mac, will you relax?
I have just gotten a scheme
that is so brilliant
that it took me five minutes
to think of it.
Look...
Boy, that Marine is a genius.
You give him
a Rock Island timetable
and an Ingersoll watch,
and I bet
he'd be president of the road
in 20 minutes.
(speaking Japanese)
That is honeymoon couple
I mentioned.
Ah, so.
-Fine, young people.
-Oh, yes, sirree.
But cannot rent a room
in respectable hotel
to show marriage certificate.
Well, naturally.
It certainly is a comfort,
Yoshida-san, to know
that we're in such
incorruptible surroundings.
It, uh, sort of lightens
my other cares.
What's the matter?
Is Red Fox operation
not proceeding as planned?
No, no, not quite.
Has headquarters phoned us?
-No call from Blue Boy.
-No call from Blue Boy?
Well, there's just
too much red tape.
They're all tangled up in it.
When I get back to my desk
in Washington,
there'll be some fur flying,
I can tell you.
Blue Boy, Blue Boy, Blue Boy.
Red Fox calling Blue Boy.
Come in.
This is Blue Boy.
Come in, Red Fox. Over.
Uh, Captain Sampson said,
uh-uh-uh, Blue Boy, sir,
uh, we left you in such a hurry
that, uh, we forgot to pick up
our expense money. Over.
A very understandable oversight,
Red Fox,
but we have no messenger
available at the moment.
Tell you what you do.
Have the management of the hotel
advance you the equivalent
of $200 in yen.
$200-- that is very much yen!
I heard that.
Who was it, the manager?
Put him on.
Uh, since you're one of us,
Yoshida-san,
I feel free to divulge that,
uh, Blue Boy is none other than
Chester Sampson,
the captain in charge
of our military police
here in Yokosuka.
And I can assure you that,
uh, Chet will reimburse you
for any money advance,
no matter the amount.
(speaking Japanese) Over.
(speaking Japanese over radio)
Uh, don't be alarmed.
That's merely
the, uh, staff interpreter.
(speaking Japanese)
Very well, very well.
Extremely proud to help.
Oh.
Everything all over.
(laughs)
Oh, thank you, Yoshida-san.
(speaking Japanese)
Uh, just for, uh,
incidental expenses, huh?
Say, by the way, what was it
the, uh, captain's interpreter
said to you?
He say,
"Cooperate or Uncle Sammy will
cut off reconstruction funds."
My hotel would lose
thousands of dollars.
(over radio): Now, don't you
worry Yoshida-san.
Captain Sampson's heart
is as big as Mount Fujiyama.
He'll back you win or lose.
Perkins!
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Now, that's better.
I'm heartened by your response.
You do know your name.
I was about convinced
that everybody around here
belonged in a psycho ward.
Yes, sir,
I'm-I'm afraid you're right.
Here's the latest
I picked up on Red Fox.
And Blue Boy?
Yes, sir.
Blue Boy is supposed to be
a captain.
They're still chattering
all over the place,
and now a couple of Japanese
are getting into the act.
Blue Boy says to Red Fox,
"Have your hotel manager
loan you $200,
and he'll guarantee payment."
Very generous fellow
this Blue Boy.
Oh, very, sir.
The 200 was only a starter.
Pretty soon,
it got up to thousands.
Did you gather who this
philanthropist might be?
Speak plainly, Perkins.
Who is Blue Boy supposed to be?
You, sir.
Get me Intelligence.
The place we planned
to spend our honeymoon
when you were called away.
It's just as lovely
as I imagined it would be.
Not a care in the world
this time, darling.
Just you and me
and the little cooing doves.
Welcome.
Wait a minute.
This looks like
a old Army game again.
Don't tell me
we're not going to get in.
Well, young woman can get in
and you can get in,
but not together.
Now, see here,
we're a perfectly decent
married couple.
Well, wedding ring is
very applicable
for present situation,
but a marriage certificate
is more convincing.
Now, look here, Charlie,
we been married two years.
I don't carry
a marriage certificate around
in my duffle bag.
Well, here, this is who I am--
Marine Gunnery Sergeant
Howard Hawkins.
What else do you want to see,
my good behavior medal?
I tell you, I'm his wife.
His wife.
(horn honks)
(speaking Japanese excitedly)
Honey, you understand Japanese.
What is he saying?
Your men have acquired
a lot of money
and are going on a bender
at the Gaiety Club.
What I'd like to know is:
what's that got to do with us?
It's just one of
those things, honey,
I've got to straighten out.
Two years a bride,
but never a wife.
Ah, so, now truth come out
in the wash.
Baby, I just got to
look after them.
Talk to the man in Japanese
and get us a nice room,
and I'll be right back.
*
Two bottles bourbon,
two bottles gin,
one bottle of rum
and a case of beer for chasers.
And some scotch.
And some scotch for my buddy.
They all look good to me.
They all look alike to me.
Which three
did you pick out, Newt?
I don't know. I can't spot them.
(applause)
There they are; that's them.
*
Good scouting, buddy boy.
You could get rich
running a lonesome heart's club.
*
(applause)
(whistling)
*
(whooping, cheering)
(music ends)
Levells, get backstage
on the double
and get them
out here for a drink,
along with any other
little knick-knacks
you might run into.
Skip, order us some champagne.
Champagne? You never used to
go for that fancy stuff.
Yes, I did,
every time I got promoted.
Well, you're not promoted yet
this time,
and I've been hoping
it won't happen.
Boy, you're getting
a hopelessly split personality.
That's jealousy talking, buddy.
No, it isn't jealously.
Just wouldn't appreciate
my type of genius.
That's why I've been
avoiding promotion.
Believe me, you'd be a lot
happier if you avoided it, too.
(speaking Japanese)
Uh, me friend of, uh,
three sisters.
Uh, sisters.
(speaking Japanese)
Grace?
Grace? Grace?
(car drives off)
What's the matter, jughead?!
Haven't you got any manners?!
Oh, begging your pardon,
but you don't look like
any etiquette expert to me.
Looks like we'll have to run
a red Chinese through this dump
to fumigate it
after this sea crab
gets through smelling it up.
Well, I guess that's gonna
call for a little lashing.
-Who's first?
-Go get him.
Take your best shot, Marine.
Come on, what are you gonna do?
We got to be careful, Skip.
I got to remember tomorrow.
On your way, sailor,
on your way.
Our dear Desmond
abhors violence.
Navy's landing, boys.
Situation well in hand.
How do you like that?
They're even
stealing our slogan.
Yeah, but we got to be careful.
We got to remember tomorrow.
But, Skip, I know it was
a tough pill to swallow,
-but I can't go...
-But, but, but, but what?
Boy, you've hit a new low.
I'm telling you, you keep
this up, you can go to Demark
and get one of those
operations they do,
and when you come back,
we'll call you Peaches.
Pardon me while I wash my hands
of you, cutie.
Well, boys, have fun.
I got a man's job to do tonight.
Never trust a guy that keeps
his lip buttoned like that one.
Yeah, he's an oddball,
all right.
Give him a couple of whiffs
of cheap perfume
on some chesty broad, and
he'll go right over the hill.
Hey, baby, wait a minute.
(whistles)
That gentleman there...
...with the bottle...
(chugging)
you take.
I go. You come, right?
Wonder what happened to Levells
with those, uh, three chicks?
Ah, who cares?
I'm too ashamed
to even face it.
They might have went back there
and got the birdie
from that sailor.
Just consider the source.
"Just consider
the source."
What's that?
How should I know?
(laughs)
-Hmm?
-It's another load of mush
from that Miss Peekaboo
at the bathhouse.
Listen.
"My Desmond, I have counted
the lonely hours
"since my last missive to you.
(laughs)
"Your gorgeous image continues
to float before my eyes,
"that tawny ripple of muscles
"like the waves which
softly kiss the golden sands.
-(laughs) -Got a real
seafaring flavor to it.
Yeah, she's pretty salty, huh?
"A short while ago,
I passed close by you
and was tempted to touch you."
She's here somewhere!
Hey. I got a hunch that note's a
rib from that sailor over there.
Hey, bellhops, have fun.
Nah, only a broad
could get this poetical.
Listen.
"So perhaps the time draws near
"when we shall meet
in breathless rendezvous,
"alone in some exotic bower
beside the sea.
(laughs)
Yours forever to be."
How's it signed this time?
"S-Sea Nymph."
(laughs)
Sea Nymph,
all that nautical talk.
Let me see that thing.
This is undeniably
a man's handwriting.
Look at it.
Yeah, well, it does look like
maybe some guy wrote it.
Yeah, yeah, now I get the
picture.
The locker room, the baths--
I saw that same sailor
in the locker room.
-That guy?
-Yeah.
Why, that crumb.
Yeah, crumb.
Well, wait a minute, how did
he know my name was Desmond
until you just mentioned it
a couple of minutes ago?
Well, he-he could've been
on some transport
with you somewhere.
-Go get him.
-Yeah, he remembers me.
He's trying to get even, huh?
Well, sure. Are you gonna let
him get away with this thing?
Go get him! Break up the joint!
Ah, wait a minute.
I can get him anytime.
I want to have
some fun tonight, Skip.
What happened to Levells
with those three chicks?
-(applause, fanfare plays)
-Nothing ever gets done
around here
unless I do it myself.
(upbeat jazz music playing)
I give up. I give up!
Ought to retire
and become a scoutmaster.
Listen, Skip,
I hope he becomes a general.
The further it takes him away
from me, the better I like it.
(speaking Japanese)
...uh, three little pussycats.
Ah? Pussycats, three.
(speaking Japanese)
(women giggling)
On your feet, Sea Nymph.
I've got a love letter here
for you.
Get lost, Desmond.
You don't want to make me mad.
Oh, you're a tough guy, huh?
Yeah.
Well, you don't fool me, buddy,
using these three girlies
to cover up.
Buster, what have you
been smoking?
I don't read you.
-Oh, you don't, huh?
-No.
Well, don't you like
my gorgeous image?
Are you still counting
the lonely hours,
or are your waves too busy
kissing the golden sands?
(grunts)
I don't take that kind of talk
from nobody.
Oh, come on, sailor boy.
Don't play foxy with me.
We read each other now,
don't we, huh?
You tipped yourself off when
you waved nighty-night at me
with your limp wrist, daffodil!
-Daffodil?
-Daffodil!
-Limp wrist?!
-Limp wrist!
I've killed guys
for less than that.
(women gasping)
Come on, cowpoke,
get up and fight.
Yeah, put it right here,
right here.
See what you can do, come on.
Right there, come on. Right...
Come on, get up, will you?
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
(women shrieking)
MAN:
Go on, baby, hit him!
(cheering)
(clamoring)
(women shrieking)
-We send you in there!
-Oh!
Look, you hide me, and if I get
out of this, I'll marry you.
-(women giggle)
-Get under the table!
(women clamoring)
Hide him!
Looks like he gave us the slip.
(chuckles)
All right, McCaffrey, let's go.
(groans)
Well, I guess it's just as well
you found me here.
I can show you more hospitality
than I could've
in our old hometown.
So many of these little luxuries
were frowned on there.
What's yours, Newt?
Bourbon?
Or I have some sake if you want
to go the Oriental route.
I don't want anything.
Well, here's to
the age of innocence, Newt.
The old days back home.
That-that man I seen you with
tonight-- who was he?
Who knows? Who cares?
Yeah, but what about
all the letters you wrote me?
They sounded just like
you used to be.
I was preserving you, Newt,
as a hope of last resort.
A dream of a day
when I might kick this all off
and come home to the poor
but pious respectability
-of being Mrs. Newton Level.
-(phone ringing)
But you had to find me
like this, didn't you?
That was a pretty shoddy
trick of fate.
But what does it matter?
I probably never would have
gone home anyway.
Yes?
Yes, I remember.
Where are you?
All right.
It'll take me about 15 minutes.
I have to change.
Bye.
See you.
Newt, you better
pour yourself a drink.
I'm going to tell you
a few facts about life
in a Japanese prison camp.
It was nothing at all
like I wrote you.
A bit rough at first,
especially when mother died.
But after that, the commanding
officer took a fancy to me
and moved me to better quarters.
And then... there were
other officers, of course.
And finally, that quaint
little country girl named Grace
was only a far-gone memory.
Oh, yes, it seems
that nature so favored me,
there wasn't even
any more prison camp for me.
I was moved to a higher echelon
of comforts in Tokyo.
And then, when our
American conquerors arrived,
I suffered no obvious hardships.
That, of course,
is why I moved to Yokosuka,
to be near the larger base
of operations.
For as you know, their...
generosity and their affection
is legendary.
And you know
something else, Newt?
I'm with it.
You'll get a good, long stretch
in the brig, McCaffrey.
I'm preparing my report
to your commanding officer.
Gunnery Sergeant Hawkins will be
the chief witness against you.
Right, sir.
He was up for promotion, but of
course that's a dead issue now.
I've been watching you
ever since Guadalcanal,
through Iwo Jima and Okinawa
to the landings of Inchon.
And I've never seen
a better fighting man
or a more troublesome citizen.
I'm sorry, sir,
but like I always say,
furloughs is my worst enemy.
There's such a thing
as battle fatigue.
Doesn't that bother you?
No, sir, just furlough fatigue.
For a long time,
I've shared the delusion
with Gunny Hawkins and others
that there might be
noncommissioned officer material
in you.
Although, you never were quite
my idea of the all-American boy.
In the well-rounded Marine,
the guts to storm
an enemy position is essential,
but that isn't
the only requirement.
He must reflect credit
on the service
in the public walks of life.
I realize that, sir.
However, you won't be deprived
of your medal.
You won that
before your trip to Japan.
I understand your commanding
officer has requested
these decorations
be presented here.
Yes, sir, Captain.
And it will soon be time
for the formation.
Well, then you'd better be
on your way.
And get that hangdog look
off your face, McCaffrey.
At least you've earned
this chance to be proud.
March out, McCaffrey!
*
Thank you, sir.
Gunny, you don't figure
they'll carry this
-as far as a court-martial?
-How should I know?
You've been in trouble before;
you ought to be an expert
on these things by this time.
Yeah, well, my intentions
are always good.
There's an old saw that says
the road to hell
is paved with good intentions.
Meanwhile, the provost marshal
is allowing you
to remain on technical liberty.
So be careful, Let's Go,
and don't dig yourself
in any deeper.
Or let me put it this way.
I've never had a real honeymoon,
so do me the personal favor
of allowing me to spend
a few hours with my wife.
Hey, come on, buddy,
let's shove off.
Time's a-wasting.
Well, that's all over, Ellen.
Let's shove out of here
and have a real honeymoon.
Our marriage certificate.
Why'd you dig that up?
Just to jam it down the throat
of that stuffy proprietor
at the White Dove.
I'm going to make him let us in,
even without our suitcase.
Attagirl, Ellen,
you tell him off.
All right, where's the driver
for this heap?
-Let's go!
-(horn blaring)
Sorry to hear it, Mac.
Looks like
you lost your promotion.
Yeah, it's a load off my mind
even if does mean the brig.
Well, it's made him
a real buddy again.
Frankly, I haven't been
so delighted
since that widow in Manila
named the twins McCaffrey.
Well, that's the motto of
the McCaffrey club, isn't it?
All for one and one for all?
Don't be a wise guy, Chatfield.
All right, you guys,
come on now, ante up.
We got to pay that hotel bill
while we still got some dough.
Speaking of dough, where
I'm going, I don't need it.
-So long, boys.
-Okay, yeah.
Boy, he's still talking
like a gyrene
that's about
to go over the hill.
Pete, you better bird-dog him.
-Okay.
-Yeah, Pete.
I promised Gunny
no more foul-ups.
Now we're gonna leave this truck
at the hotel.
I'd appreciate it if you'd do
a little cruising tonight
-and keep an eye on the guys.
-I'll have a guy
on the Red Fox shortwave
in case you need us.
Right-o.
Where you going,
you Plymouth Rock capon?
Why, just so I shan't disappoint
you, McCaffrey, I thought I'd go
to the blood bank
to see if mine's still blue.
Very funny.
Snap out of it, Levells.
Keep looking for that broad;
you'll find her yet.
I found her.
What a bunch I got here--
busted Romeos, free lovers,
financials wizards,
and that cutie Chatfield
who come over on the Mayflower.
To say nothing
of the big balloon brain
who keeps us all in a jam.
Come on, give me some dough.
Yeah, well, no more.
I've had it, boy.
-No more pub-crawling
for your uncle Mac. -Oh?
Just a nice quiet evening
at home with a nice family.
You mean those,
uh, Sagita sisters
from the, uh, Gaiety Club?
(laughs) You guess good.
Oh, I can see it all now.
Just them and you and me
sitting around with
our shoes off, drinking tea.
Not you, buster.
Go shoot your own quail.
You'll miss me;
I'm the life of every party.
Like you were in Honolulu?
Telling every ugly broad on
Waikiki Beach that you were me?
(laughs)
My phone never stopped ringing.
Oh.
But seeing what a fall guy
you made out of me,
-I'll let you get yourself
on the hook. -Hmm?
-I'll give you a buildup.
-Hmm?
They want to get married.
Oh, no, thanks.
I'll do my own selling.
Okay, write them a note,
and I'll deliver it
and tell them how great you are.
And if they want you aboard,
I'll give you a buzz
at the hotel.
But right now, buddy, I'm gonna
make a date for yours truly.
Ahso. Ha, ha.
Hey, Boy-san, psst, come here.
You got the writer paper?
Write-oh?
(speaks Japanese)
(speaking Japanese)
Hello.
Uh, which one is this?
Oh, Su Me.
Hello, baby. This is big,
handsome Marine boy, remember?
Oh, big, handsome
under table boy?
No show tonight.
You come here, our house.
Okay, baby, will do.
Start cooking up the tea
and the sake,
and I'll be right over as soon
as I can change my socks.
Sayonara, baby. (kisses)
(whistling tune)
Give this
to those three dollies.
That note will
get me in anywhere.
-(laughs)
-(engine starts)
Go.
SONG DO: "My dear one, I'm happy
that you are away from danger,
"though my heart
cries out for you.
"Each day, I stand
looking across the torn land
"where I first saw you,
"and I try to dream
that you are there.
"But it is strangely empty now,
"and there is a great
and frightening stillness,
"as though the world
were catching its breath
"to make again
the fire and thunder
"more terrible than before.
"And so I fall
at the Lotus throne
"and pray that my visions
of terror are false,
"that there will be
life and peace
"and the nirvana
of our love forever.
(playing melody)
"Then suddenly again,
I'm filled with the faith
that sings in my heart to the
happy music of the komungo."
(melody continues)
*
(speaking Japanese)
(laughter)
Marine boy very good
with Japanese custom.
(laughs)
You can say that again, baby.
We're gonna have quite a night
tonight, huh? (laughs)
(speaking Japanese)
(laughs)
Our bother, Fuji.
-Brother?
-Yes.
We're proud of him.
He's a wrestler,
champion of all Japan.
(speaking Japanese)
(conversation continues
in Japanese)
Did I? Yeah, that's...
Oh, yeah, I did. (chuckles)
Uh, uh, Su Me, Su Me! Yeah.
(speaking Japanese)
Sake? Yeah, I could use one.
You got one?
(women giggling)
Trophies of brother Fuji,
all for victory
in many festivals.
Gold samurai sword
presented by the government
for breaking neck
of Chinese champion.
(both laugh)
(speaking Japanese)
(women speaking Japanese)
(women giggling)
Have a nice, big home
in America?
Yeah, yeah, Camp Pendleton.
(women giggling)
Well, this is quite a setup
you got here, Fuji.
Uh, wrestling racket
must be pretty good here.
(laughter)
Here, have a cigar, Fuji.
Old man Churchill sends me
a box of those every Christmas.
We're buddies. (laughs)
(sighs)
Fuji, how would you like to have
another American
for a brother-in-law?
He's not as good-looking as I
am, but he's got a lot of money.
He's got a big estate
called Fort Knox.
(speaking Japanese)
But, you see, he's a little shy.
He likes to send in
his references first, see,
so he don't get his feelings
hurt if he ain't welcome.
Uh, dig this.
"Most lovely and illustrious
flowers of Nippon,
you are the blinding beauty in
the secret garden of my heart."
(speaking Japanese)
Yeah, he really hates himself,
doesn't he?
Uh, dig this.
"I pine to make
your acquaintance
"and hope the following
qualifications
"may strike a note
of-of response in you.
I have often been referred to
as the Greek god type."
"Greek god type."
I've heard that one before.
He make nice word music.
Yeah, honey, but I got a hunch
this guy's only got one tune.
"However, if it is the higher
ideal of manhood which you seek,
"gentile of manners,
profound of mind,
"and with the rippling muscles
like the waves which kiss
the golden sands..."
"Rippling muscles."
"Golden sands."
"...then I shall feed
your heart's desire
"in some breathless rendezvous
with only the pale moon
to spy upon us."
Rippling muscles, huh?
Golden sands.
That's it.
He's the Sea Nymph.
Where's the telephone?
In trophy room.
When I go to America,
I bring whole family.
Hotel Okamoto.
R-Red Fox headquarters.
Skip, this you?
Hey, listen, buddy, I don't know
what you wrote in that letter,
but you sure hit the jackpot.
Get over here on the double.
It's 318, just around the corner
from the hotel.
And, listen, the door's open.
Walk right in. Okay?
See you, buddy.
(whistling quietly)
Yeah.
Well, folks,
I got bad news for you.
-The wedding's all off.
-(speaking Japanese)
My buddy just tipped me off
on the phone
that the provost marshal's on
his way over here to arrest me.
For fighting in club last night?
Yeah, that's right.
Just when I thought I had it
all squared away, too.
And then this copper,
he frames me just because
we had an argument
about the wrestling racket.
(speaking Japanese)
That's what I told him, Fuji.
Naturally, your name came up,
and that's when I chewed him out
for calling you a big phony.
(speaking Japanese)
(grunts)
That's right, Fuji.
Give him the full treatment!
Rip, bam, wham!
(speaking Japanese)
SKIP:
Hey, McCaffrey!
(grunts)
What's he doing?
Getting ready
to break neck of your enemy.
Hey, McCaffrey!
Hey, Mac!
Ahso.
Uh, hi there.
(laughs)
Uh, uh...
Roth! Uh, Roth, my name.
Uh, U.S. Marine Corps.
Glad to meet you.
I seemed to have,
uh, stumbled into
the little old
wrong doorway here.
I guess I'll be going now.
Uh, uh...
Good night.
Um, so sorry.
(yells)
-Hey, now, look, you got
the wrong idea, buddy! -(grunts)
Hey, now,
let's talk this over, bud.
Let's get to know each other.
I mean...
-(grunts)
-(screams)
Now, wait a minute, buster!
I don't want to lose my temper.
-I don't want to have to
hurt you. -(yells)
Hey, McCaffrey,
this guy is gonna kill me!
(laughter, shouting)
Get him, Fuji!
(laughter, shouting continue)
Don't forget your shoes, Roth!
(laughter)
No more trouble.
We have wedding soon.
Yeah, yeah, uh... (chuckles)
I think I'll go get
the license, honey.
(laughter)
(laughs)
*
Frisk him.
Come on, honey, let's dance.
I don't want to dance.
Come on.
(laughing)
Poor Skip.
Give me the pass key.
I lost mine.
-Yes, sir.
-(laughing)
Ah, Mr. Red Fox employee
create system.
Very good.
Yeah, I'm using
my old noodle tonight, Yoshida.
(laughs)
Mr. Red Fox very clever.
Smart as famous
Japanese detective, Mr. Moto.
Have nose like
bloodhound dog, huh?
(burps)
(shouts in Japanese)
(shrieking)
(shouting in Japanese)
You demented baboon!
What are you, nuts,
trying to get me killed?!
Oh, that'd be a big loss
to the art world,
wouldn't it, you privy poet?
What are you talking about?
"Greek god."
(laughs)
"Kissing the golden sands."
"With only the pale moon
to spy on you."
-(laughs)
-You dirty,
double-dealing, Sea Nymph!
(laughs)
Okay, okay.
You can't even take a joke.
You had to set a hired
bone-crusher on me, huh?
Well, let me tell you this,
buster, I finally caught up with
that Oriental tub of lard,
and I laid him out flat.
Ha!
Tell me another fairy tale.
Okay, come on, that does it!
Hey, McCaffrey,
Blue Boy's calling Red Fox,
and it sounds like an S.O.S.
Hello, Blue Boy.
This is Red Fox. Over.
(over radio):
I hear you, Red Fox. Listen.
Newt's been nicked and
they're all at the All Nations.
We've been trying
to get his money back,
but we met heavy
enemy resistance. Over.
The All Nations, you say?
Griff Plummer's joint?
Yes. We need reinforcements
on the double.
Reinforcements on the way. Out.
-All right, get your gear.
Let's go. -Right.
So the keeper of the White Dove
wouldn't go for
our wedding certificate.
Well, this is my idea
of a honeymoon heaven.
The chief didn't even
ask us to register.
Well, you talk like you've had
experience in such matters.
Always glad to have
Marine boy back again.
He don't know
what he's talking about.
I've never been here before.
So sorry, so sorry.
Much apology. Have room key.
Boy, these guys, I don't know.
They see one guy in uniform,
and then every guy they see
is the same guy.
On my word of honor,
I've never been here before.
(speaking Japanese)
What's he saying?
They're in trouble again.
They've left the hotel
with a walkie-talkie.
Where are they?
(speaking Japanese)
Right off Takari Street
on the Ginza.
Tell him to go find them and
then call me at headquarters.
I'm sorry, Ellen,
I'll be right back.
(speaking Japanese)
(sighs)
*
Hold it.
This place is out of bounds
for you fellas. Beat it.
How do you like that, Pete?
(women shrieking)
Go to sleep, you bum.
Hey, McCaffrey!
Take it easy, Mac.
Long time, no see, Plummer.
Not since New Zealand
when I knocked your brains out.
Oh, you got lucky.
Get out of here
before I call the MPs.
You'll call the MPs?
Why, you big, cheap,
jugheaded louse.
Headquarters, headquarters,
Blue Boy, Blue Boy.
Red Fox calling Blue Boy.
(over radio): This is
Blue Boy at headquarters.
Proceed, Red Fox.
Say, Captain, we're in
a clip joint down here.
The place looks like
a nest of red female spies.
They knocked down one of our men
with cheap liquor
and rolled him. Over.
Select some good samples, and
I'll run them through the lab.
And pick up the suspects.
Bring them in, and I'll
interrogate them personally.
Over.
Will do, Captain. Out.
L-Look, you guys,
I-I got real 90-proof here.
-Yeah. -Leave me alone,
I'll give you some.
Okay, we'll take
a couple of cases of scotch,
a couple of cases of bourbon
and some gin.
And if it checks up all right,
we won't put you off-limits,
Plummer!
Pete, go with him!
All right, you in the gold
dress, and you, and you, Red!
Come on, all of you!
You're all under arrest.
That's good intelligence,
McCaffrey; they all look guilty.
And we'll take
that jukebox, too.
That looks like it might have
a few hidden documents in it.
-Come on, out!
-All right, ladies.
Come on. Let's move along now.
-Out, out, out!
-Come on, here we go.
Captain, sir.
Red Fox again?
Yes, sir, Blue Boy, sir--
I mean, Captain Sampson, sir.
Self-control, Perkins,
self-control.
Don't break down.
Look at me. I'm doing fine!
Yes, sir.
But wait till you hear
the latest.
They've just raided
a nest of spies.
What's that?
Someone going over my head?
Oh, no, sir.
They say you're gonna
test the liquor
and personally inspect
some females.
You don't believe that,
do you, Perkins?
Oh, no, sir.
Oh, yes, you do.
How long has it been
since you've had a good rest?
Captain, my last leave was over
a year ago, but I'm all right.
I-I'm all right.
That is, I think I'm all right.
Captain Sampson, sir.
I just received
a telephone call,
and I believe it's the answer
to the problem he's discussing.
(men murmuring)
-You okay?
-* Oh, when the saints
* Go marching in
-No, no, no.
-* Oh, when the...
Extreme purities,
motto of Hotel Okamoto.
Woman characters very
shady-looking. Cannot permit.
Oh, now don't blow your cork,
Yoshida,
till you hear the good news.
Tonight's a night that'll
go down in the history of Japan.
We wrapped up the spy ring.
-Spies, woman species?
-(speaks Japanese)
Yeah, they're the most
dangerous kind.
All right, Skip,
take them upstairs
and interrogate them
and search them.
Come on.
Go.
Congratulations!
Congratulation to me?
You're an honorary member
of our successful mission.
Ah, delightful honor
to be member
of intelligence secret service.
Yeah, and it's an all-American
custom to throw a victory ball.
Now, bring all
your friends, okay?
Our party is your party, okay?
-Yes.
-Okay?
-Okay.
(bottles clinking)
(siren wailing)
(laughter, excited chatter)
Hey, hold it, hey!
Pipe down! Quiet it down!
Hey, hey, everybody!
Hey, hold it!
-Pipe down, Skip.
-What?
-(chatter quiets)
-Hmm.
I want to give a toast.
Here's to the wonderful...
wonderful, uh...
Wonderful friendship
between America and Japan.
Yeah, yeah, that's it, yeah.
And also to Yoshida,
who made our wonderful stay
so wonderful
in his family hotel.
-Yoshida.
-(cheering)
That boy, Yoshida...
Hey, al-also, also,
to this wonderful
honeymoon couple,
who-who I'm sorry hadn't
much chance to get acquainted!
(laughter)
Mac, that was wonderful.
-(laughs): Yeah.
-Now, can all this noise
and let's get down
to some serious drinking here.
Yeah, drink up! Drink up!
(laughter, excited chatter)
(whooping)
I tear up remainder
of hotel bill,
in name of
international goodwill.
(cheering)
Yoshida! Mr. Moto!
-Wonderful!
-A very gentlemanly thing to do!
-Hey! -I want you to know
that we appreciate it.
Let's have some music.
-Yeah, play... -Pete, put
some more yen in the jukebox.
Play "My Melancholy Geisha."
(laughter)
-(upbeat music playing)
-(excited chatter continues)
-Here we go, here we go!
-(rhythmic clapping)
Do-si-do!
Hey! Come on.
Yee-haw!
Come on!
(whooping, laughter)
(music continues inside)
(excited chatter continues)
Swing it, baby! Yeah!
Come on, McCaffrey.
-(music stops)
-(shrieks)
So it's Red Fox McCaffrey
and Blue Boy Roth.
I should have known.
(laughs)
Look, Captain,
I'm sure I can explain...
You can do your explaining
at a court-martial.
Well, in a very few words...
Shut up, you barracks Confucius.
-Uh...
-And you needn't even bother
to bring your gear along,
McCaffrey.
By the time you get
out of the brig,
your uniform will be
out of style.
You make serious mistake.
Mr. Red Fox capture
these Mata Hari spy girls.
Mata Hari hookers.
Lock these men up,
and let's get some sleep.
Report to headquarters.
Tell them to secure
the rest of the patrols
that are out on this operation.
Yes, sir.
Diamond, Diamond,
this is Diamond Six. Over.
(over radio):
Get off the air.
This is a priority message.
All leaves of the U.S.
Armed Services are canceled.
All officers and men report
immediately to your base.
This is an alert
from the supreme command.
It looks as though these men
may be shipped out,
and that's a break for
the peace and quiet of Yokosuka.
Take your men with you, Gunny.
My report will follow them
-back to the division.
-Aye-aye, sir.
-Okay, let's go!
-(clamoring)
Let's go!
(speaking Japanese)
All right, come on,
you guys, move!
Let's go, on the double!
Let's go, come on!
Where's Waller?
I got him spotted
and he's close by.
Okay, let's go get him.
All very confusing!
Please come back again,
solider boy!
-Going over the hill, Waller?
-Don't let them stop us, Russ.
What do you mean, don't let him?
He's got the gang with him,
-and there's only one of me.
-That would save you
from making your own decision,
wouldn't it?
But you're gonna have to
make it by yourself.
I'm not a cop;
neither is any of those men.
The provost will
put out a tracer on you,
but still you might get away.
Come on, Russ, let's go.
Sure, who else but you would
want a bilge rat?
Take his decorations
in the morning,
then go over the side at night.
Well, not me, not my platoon.
You've got him,
and he's right for you.
Well, that's all
I stopped by for, Waller,
just to give you a load
on how I feel about you.
Wait a minute, Sarge.
Don't be an imbecile, Russ.
Can't you see
what he's trying to do?
He's trying to get you to
swallow the bait, hook and all.
You keep out of this.
Well, so long, Waller.
Remember what I told you,
and live with it.
-Hold it, Gunny!
-Russ!
Sayonara, tramp!
*
Okay, McCaffrey,
you and your men
make that patrol to the right
front like I briefed you.
Let's go!
If you guys can find
a better hole, get to it.
Missed us again, Navy!
That's better, sailor boy!
Keep trying, you'll hit us yet,
you dummy!
Who you calling dummy?
Who was it that kept hollering,
"Let's go,"
when we got lost from Gunny
and the rest of the squad, huh?
What do you expect
on recon patrol, tourist maps?
That joker on the guns
thinks he's ranging in
on a nest of red goons.
Well, we're about a mile
inside the Chinese lines.
I suppose that's a big laugh,
huh, genius?
Well, that's real tough.
Looks like we're still gonna
have to go before the mass
to face the C.O.
That's means five years
in the brig for me.
That's what a furlough
does to a man.
(laughs)
Those guys will burn them out!
Come on, let's go!
-Skip?
-Huh?
-See that hill?
-Yeah.
Take your men and circle around.
Pete and me
will go straight ahead.
We'll take Chatfield with us
so he won't get lost.
Right.
*
That'll drive the red buzzards
back into the hills.
Chatfield, stay undercover
of those woods.
Work your way down
to that valley of Koynam
or whatever they call it.
You spot any red goons,
get back here on the double.
I've been wanting to look at it.
Be careful;
don't get your pants blown off.
Pete, cover him.
He'd walk right in
to a Chinese patrol
and ask for a bowl of chop suey.
Don't forget this position.
We'll meet back here.
*
(explosions continue
in distance)
(man groaning)
Anything I can do?
(weakly):
No.
No, I've had it.
Where are the people
who lived here?
Most got away, in the wood.
Are there many Chinese patrols?
Yes.
Yes. Watch out, Yank.
McCaffrey sent me to cover you.
He wouldn't trust me
with anything, would he?
Well, I got information for him.
(explosions continue
in distance)
*
(groans)
(gunfire continues)
(quietly): Pete, there must be
more of them around.
Our best chance of getting back
is to separate.
-Yeah, but how's your shoulder?
-It's okay.
Now, look, you go that way,
and I'll go through the woods
this side.
Now get back to McCaffrey.
Okay.
(explosions continue
in distance)
My dear one? My dear one?
Song Do.
Lee-san.
My friend.
Just as I thought.
What'd softy boy do,
stop somewhere for tea?
No, you had him all wrong.
This guy is tougher
than a 50-cent steak.
We were dropped by a red patrol.
When they busted his shoulder,
he still blazed away at them.
Yeah? Where's he at?
He made it into the woods.
Well, he's on his own.
I ain't gonna risk a detail
to save his hide.
Just to find you alive,
it's better than any medicine.
I've got to get back
to my squad now.
You stay hidden here.
Our forces are moving up;
you'll be safe then.
You stay here, too.
The wound is bad. You must rest.
No, there's no time for that.
(sighs)
(woman shouting in Japanese)
The Chinese soldiers come.
All right,
get your people out of here.
Come on, get them out of here.
You'll all be shot for this.
-And what happens to you?
-I'll just give them
the McCaffrey treatment.
Song Do, go!
Go, Song Do!
My love, remember,
our lives will be
joined together
by what these fools call death.
(gunfire)
McCaffrey!
So you found yourself a chick
out here and got yourself
all shot up so you can go back
and set up light housekeeping.
I'm not going back anywhere.
Shut up, punk!
When our guys come through here,
you get yourself back
to an aide station
and take all these people
out with you!
All right, Pete,
knock that red gook off.
Go ahead!
Hold it!
We'll take him back with us.
Maybe he'll do some talking.
All right, all you people, out!
Come on, out!
(explosions continue
in distance)
What the hell
are you doing here?
Don't hand me any more orders,
you broken-down private.
The only one I'll take
from you is, "Let's go."
*
(quietly):
Psst, hey, Mac.
Look what I found.
All right, Pete, ask him again
where the lookout post is,
how many men they got,
and where the charges are.
(speaking Chinese)
He says the whole valley over
there's loaded with explosives.
The control men are
in a bunker up there
on the other side that hill.
And our guys
are walking right into it.
Where you going, Chatfield?!
They can't walk into it.
You stay here. This is my job.
All right, Pete,
get him out of here.
Cover him, you guys!
*
(speaking Chinese)
(groans)
Mac?
Chatfield?
Yeah, Mac?
You're okay.
Skip.
Yeah, old buddy?
I...
(exhales)
(sniffles)
Well, come on, can't you hear
what he's saying?
He ain't saying nothing;
he's dead.
Not to me he isn't.
I'll always hear him yelling,
"Marines, let's go."
*
* Hup, two, three
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* Hit the deck, leatherneck
* Fall in line, double time
* Hear him call, "Let's go"
* Come on, Marines, let's go
* We're going to make some
history along the battle line *
* Hup, two, three, four
* Hup, two, three, go!
* We're going to make some
history along the battle line *
* We're going to make
some history *
* Along the battle line
* We're going to make some
history along the battle line. *