Evening, Victorine.
- At last!
Wipe your feet.
Arriving at this time.
That's all you can say after 15 years?
- You haven't changed. It's like
I saw you yesterday. - Really?
You've always looked older
When I think of what happened here...
What a spectacle!
"Spectacle"?
Murder, shootings, and all the rest?
It could've been worse.
You're lucky you weren't
arrested straightaway.
You were clearly involved.
Did everybody show up?
Yes,and on time!
There?
You know the way.
Don't ruin my carpets
with your cigarettes.
What a memory!
I hope you didn't marry some poor woman.
Married, divorced and remarried!
No! Not Maruval...
My name's "Marinval"
Castille, my brother, our friend,
leader.
You deserved a minute of silence.
Fifteen years ago, on this day,
in this house
a few days before the Liberation,
you were shot down by the German police.
All of us witnessed that tragic event,
Which is why we are
gathered tonight in this house.
In our former HQ.
It's long overdue.
War and defeat brought us together.
Peace tore us apart.
The Vaillance network, your network.
Has become a cherished part of our
lives.
Like a memorable vacation.
We're alumni of sorts.
But although we haven't always kept in
touch, we've remained true to your
values.
Castille, you're everywhere we go.
We've never
stopped thinking about you...
and the freedom that cost you your life.
That freedom for which too many died,
is a symbol of eternal hope
And because I know
you want us to do this.
I raise my glass
to our flower, our good luck charm,
and, dare I say it, our heroine,
though you abhorred the term.
To Marie-Octobre,
who organized this gathering.
And for that, we are very grateful.
Castille, I'm proud
and honored to have known you.
To Castille.
- To Marie-Octobre
- To good heath.
Marinval, still punctual.
Sorry, I was pulled over by the police.
I couldn't find a cab,so I walked.
I told Renaud Picart
I'd be in a meeting.
He chairs the butchers' association.
Aren't you embarrassed?
Au poteau!
Il y a longtemps?
We're like family. Shall we kiss?
Of course.
Here.
For me?
A little something for old times' sake.
There were good days and bad days...
Oh!
A led of lamb!
And a bread card. How sweet!
He kept it frozen for 15 years.
The lamb was killed yesterday.
Merci, Victorine.
Recognize me?
Counselor Simoneau.
I saw your photo in the paper.
You've lost your hair and gained weight.
So now you defend murderers?
At your service.
I'm an SPCA member.
Self-defense.
Idiot!
No!
Yes.
Le Gueven!
That's right.
You had a bright future.
All your conquests...
When did you...?
Ten years ago.
To think you were a real ladies' man!
Bernardi,I heard you gave up wrestling.
True.
- Did you have dinner?
- I'm starving. What'd you eat?
A delicious duck a I'orange
And fish that tasted like chicken.
- The appetizer...
I want it all!
Serve Mr. Marinval. We'll have coffee
here.
I set the service in the living room.
Then I'll eat in the living room.
I want to sample everything. Victorine.
My poor carpets.
C'est pas marrant.
How old is your son?
Fifteen.
I can't diagnose him at a distance.
Medicine has its limits.
I'm not trying to cheat you out of a
consultation fee.
With our programs,we can afford any
disease.
Yes, cancer is no longer a luxury.
You didn't invite me.
It was a small wedding.
Et puis?
You tell your friends just good news,no?
You're not happy?
I didn't marry the true love of my life.
Oh, mais j'aime!
But I love my job,good books and music.
And I really love coffee.
If you want coffee,raise your hand.
- I asked for herbal tea. -Here it is.
It's my liver.
People look at me and say:"It's your
liver".
- You don't say.
That's the sugar.
- Coffee?
No,never at night.
Piano
Merci.
Thibaud doesn't belive you own the
Marie-Octobre couture house.
- Really?
I didn't make the connection.
For a Parisian doctor...
I figured you married an explorer,
someone like Paul-Emile Victor.
No,I never married.
Why not?
Who knows?
The couture house...
- It's a major player,no?
Indeed..
Thanks to this gentleman. Meet my
silent partner.
I made a wise investment. With
honorable intentions.
He's defensive.
I didn't say "With honorable
intentions."
I said,"With honorable intentions".
Marie has a flawless heart of gold.
And closed.
Love was grand before the war.
How would you know?You were 14.
I knew quite a bit.
Simoneau!
Tell me the truth.
- The defendant,yesterday...
The one I acquitted?
He was guilty.
- He fired the shot.
They couldn't prove it.
You can't believe he was innocent!
My feelings don't come into play.
He didn't fool me. He who kills must be
killed.
Simplistic reasoning.
Strange profession.
Not yours?
My clients thank me,yours curse you.
- You're fearsome.
- Thanks. But I'm respected.
The guilty get jailed. I'm proud of my
profession.
You are...?
Civil servant.
A super civil servant!Tell him what you
do.
Fine.
Then spit it out.
I will!
Well?
I'm a tax inspector.
Oh! Dur!
The lowlife!
Let's watch TV.
There's a great wrestling match tonight.
- Interested?- At my age...
I'm a rabid wrestling fan.
So you stopped wrestling?
I quit when I seriously injured my back.
It's a young man's sport.
Shall I call you "Father"?
Are you kidding?Call me Yves,
You haven't lost your touch.
I play saxophone too.
Really?
Piano
I'm not particularly fond of that.
I'm into the Romantic
composers:Berlioz,but especially Wagner.
Tristan,Tannhauser,The Ride of the
Valkyries!
Scientists predict that this device...
...will one day replace the
refrigerator.
Right!Sounds like science fiction to me.
It's a cultural program. What time is
it?
Wrestling is on later.
You don't have a TV?
No,for drama i have my wife.
Thanks,Victorine.
Married?
Common-law. You know Linda Bell?
The singer?
"Come to my place On the sixth floor
"Then you'll..."My Panorama. I've heard
her records.
At home,I get to sample...
... the live version!
What else?
I run a nightclub,Sexy Pigalle.
Really?
How interesting!
A first class joint. Authetic
stripteases.
You musn't get bored.
I'm never bored at work.
I'd love to take a tour!
You're welcome to come.
I bought the place in '45.It cost me
two million F.
But we feature great artists.
Anyone can put up a sign that
says,"Striptease"
- But running a striptease...
That's right!
That's swell,no?
You feel it. Unlike...
Say...
Remember the song we used to sing in
'42 or '43?
Euh...
No,it was a little silly,yet charming.
You know...
The Bonaparte St. song. You used to
sing it.
That's it.
You'd play your mandolin.
Oh!
Keep playing.
Thank you.
My hospital was thriving.
I was making a name for myself
But then I lost my wife.
No children. I wanted to pack it in.
But I cared about my patients.
If I lost my wife,I'd be devastated.
I get along with my son. He helps out
at the forge.
I'm worried about my daughter. She's 14
and in love with me.
And she's so pretty!Men shouldn't have
daughters.
Shall we do this?Go first,then I'll
take over.
Can I count on you?
Sure you won't regret it?
You know me better than that.
Marie,you owe me this dance. You
promised me,remember?
In that case...
That melody...
- Bonaparte St.
The small boutique
Where we sent our letters.
- What times!
- Wonderful.
- I'd see you every day.
Go on!
May I cut in?
Not always the same.
I need to talk to her too.
You were decorated?
- Clients are impressed.
My fees can go up.
And I'm single.
- Really?
- Yes.
Like you.
Meaning?
Just thought I'd mention it.
What's wrong?
Are you worried?
No?
You're up to something.
Yes,actually...
Four-man tag team match!
Best of three falls.
The European championship belt is on
the line.
The team of Delaporte and Villar...
Yes,the infamous Delaporte,along with
Villar,
will try to defeat Zick 400
and King Kong Tavern.
Plenty of action on tap.
The ref's got his work cut out.
- We can't hear anything.
- Just listen up...
Later,Victorine. Now's not the time.
What's going on?
At the fourth stroke...
Shut up!
Haven't you been wondering why.
after 15 years,
Marie-Octobre felt the need to see you
again?
Aren't you curious to know?
She missed us.
I'll tell you.
Fifteen years ago,the Gestapo stormed
into this house.
By some miracle,we all escaped unharmed.
Except for Castille.
Castille was killed by a German
policeman
right where I'm standing.
Our network was dispersed.
- Then came the Liberation.
- Whew!
We didn't keep in touch.
Sure,sometimes we'd run into each other.
But with indifference.
Don't exaggerate.
I've often wondered how the Gestapo had
been tipped off.
How could it know where and when our
meeting was being held?
That question has remained unanswered
for 15 years.
But there is no God for traitors.
What are you saying?
What information do you have?
The network was rattled out.
We suspected as much.
By one of its own members.
By one of us.
What?
"By one of us"?
- Is this a joke?
How outrageous!
What nonsense!I'd rather watch TV.
It's true:One of us ratted out the
network to the Gestapo.
- Are you...?
- I mean,really!
A traitor?I doubt it.
Can you name him?Who is it?
You.
Everyone and no one.
So what if there's an extra Judas,right?
Marie-Octobre's accusation must be
taken seriously.
Two weeks ago,I released my winter
collection.
During the show,a man kept staring at
me so intently
that after the show,I asked him what he
wanted.
And?
"The name Marie-Octobre",he said.
"The name you gave your shop..."
"Wasn't it a secret code name during
the Occupation?"
"Why do you ask?"
"Because Marie-Octobre's network gave
me a hard time."
He was a German buyer.
His name is Wilfrid Muller.
He was a German officer who worked with
the Gestapo.
Designers meet interesting people.
What else?
Then he made a staggering assertion:
"We uncovered your network thanks
solely to a traitor.
"You were rattled out by one of your
own members."
"One of your own members."
Then he added sincerely,I'm sure,
"Too bad,you didn't deserve it.
"I admired your courage."
That's it.
No name?He didn't give a name?
He couldn't remember it.
Sounds like malarkey to me!
He waited 15 years to...?No,I don't buy
it.
We're victims of a fabrication,
an anonymous denunciation or an act of
revenge.
But that you,that he,that I... No, my
friend.
We're upstanding citizens. In my heart
I know...
Savingthe closing arguments for later.
Supposing...
some bastard did talk to the buyer
to rat out the network.
He could've pretended to be Marinval or
me.
Can I say something?
Isn't there a statute of limitations?
Then I'll confess...
I rattled out the network.
In a moment of madness.
Happy?
Then let's move on to more serious
things.
Et voyons ou en
sont ces messieurs!
Delaporte managed to break the hold.
He's out for blood!The ref tries to
step in.
Delaporte sends him flying.
He's determined to wreak
mayhem in the ring and to...
What's the big idea?
I disagree.
Either too much was said or not enough.
We keep complimenting each other:
"Your're a great guy."Not as great as
you."
- So?
- Let's prove we're great guys.
Let's take inventory.
Yes. If we were to end the evening now,
our good-byes would ring hollow.
That seed of doubt has been planted.
Doubt is a cancer without equal,isn't
it,doctor?
You insist on doing this,huh?
Great.
And the traitor will receive a prize.
We're all gonna have a good time!
You're being flippant.
- I have a right to my opinion.
- You have every right.
Sure,horse around at inopportune
moments.
He who laughs last...
You insinuating...?
Nothing.
You assume...?
I assume nothing.
I've always shied away from showdowns.
You're twisting yourselves a know over
a faraway event.
I leave the past behind me.
But I'm at your service.
Just like your auditors.
Here are my books:
Marinval plays by the rules. Yes,tax
inspector.
Glad to hear it.
At least you are.
I had to fork over an extra 25% in
taxes.
not to mention the fines
because of a minor accounting error...
But you play by the rules?
I have a clear conscience.
Are you quite sure?
That's not the point.
He's horsing around again.
You can be so witty!
All of us,then,get to be the judge and
the accused.
Yes,but then what?
What'll we do with the culprit?
Good point.
What if I were to confess?
What then?
Would I grab my hat and say,"Good
night,everyone"?
- Life goes on?
Traitors were executed in '42.
This isn't 1942.
So it's too late for justice?
We're past that point. It's too late to
punish anyone.
No,not the culprit.
And he's right here.
He dined with us. He must be punished.
It happened 15 years ago. He's changed.
Maybe he can't understand what the past
means.
Are you pleading your case?
I'm not pleading.
I'm praying for everyone.
Le Gueven is right.
We have no right to execute anyone.
I wouldn't have the guts.
And I certainly wouldn't.
A condemned man who was pardoned wrote,
"To kill with a clear conscience,you
need faith.
"Or you kill out of fear or
revenge,which is repugnant."
I must admit I don't have much faith
tonight.
Besides,before the courts,
perhaps a sentence would be given,
but surely not enforced.
I see...
You sure have changed!
A snitch is a snitch. Show him no mercy!
Bravo. Spoken like a real man.
Let's kill the culprit.
You'll be the hangman.
The "hangman"?
You judge,you sentence,so you execute.
Certainly,if the accused confesses.
Actually,maybe. It depends on the
circumstances.
So we wipe the state clean?
The network,Castille... Let's write
everything off!
We'll never be able to look at each
other again,my friends.
We'll no longer be friends.
We'll be suspects.
You sentenced Simon to death in '43,and
I did the dirty work.
If you let the traitor walk,
Simon becomes a victim of injustice.
And I become a complete and utter
bastard!
You Pontius Pilates!
You wash your hands because they're
dirty.
We can't allow the situation to persist.
We may not be 13,but there's a Judas
among us.
Maybe your brother did it.
Very funny.
- I don't know what to do.
- I do. I have a solution.
Suicide.
Do you agree?
OK.If I disagree,you'll assume I'm
guilty,so...
I agree as well.
After all,a traitor won't rat himself
out.
You never know.
I agree.
But I don't.
It's a hypocritical solution.
We can't take justice into our own
hands.
If you want something done...
Please listen to me!
- Let God...
- We've heard it all before.
Your God can't save an innocent life.
Where was He during the Crucifixion?
- God Almighty! -Sacrilege.
Idiot.
What if the culprit won't kill himself?
I'll know exactly what to do.
You'll find me in your way.
Fine.
Have you thought about the
consequences,Renaud?
What will you tell the police?
There'll a corpse in your home.
The traitor's confession and suicide
will be on paper.
- The corpse's discharge!
- The corpse... Whose?
It's as though we're all innocent!
Yes,all of us are innocent.
- Except for one man.
Or woman!I'm sorry,but...
In short,
it's crystal clear:
One of us won't walkk out of here alive.
- Right?
- Dr. Thibaud,you have a call.
Dr. Thibaud?
Thibaud...
Let's sit down. We keep walking
around...
Victorine,fetch the liqueurs.
No,Marinval!
Before I die,I wanna know who wins!
Didja see that hold?Incredible.
Take a look.
That's a waste of time. Come along.
My patients are getting antsy. I should
be with them.
Perhaps.
Whisky,raspberry liqueur?
- The last glass.
- The last cigarette?
Thanks.
So how shall we proceed?
You're the jurist.
Yes,but this is illegal.
Like in '43.
Let's focus on those who had contacts
with the Germans:no?
Dealings with the enemy.
Not necessarily.
During the Occupation,Frenchmen had
contacts with the enemy.
I defended them at German trials.
What about you?
What about me?
During the Occupation,you had dealings
with the Krauts,no?
That's news to me!
Black market dealings.
I made sure we had food.
What about the crap?
What?
Where was it from?You had to grease
their palms.
Now that's rich!
Hear that?
Who gave you fresh food?Who sent
parcels to Fresnes?
The butter tasted great,didn't it?
You want a statue for your achievements?
Honor and fat content!
My goal was to dupe them.
- But you obeyed them.
"Obeyed"?
You were a civil servant!
I was loyal to my superiors.
You skipped a scheduled meeting.
We were friends and I didn't know what
he was planning.
Remeber?In February or March 1942.
February 1942?
- Yes.
- Saint-Denis subway station.
It's possible.
You never showed. Why?
I have no idea.
You'd been arrested.
Yes,that one time.
The Germans had raided my apartment
building.
- But they arrested you?
- And every single tenant.
- They kept you in custody?
- For 48 hours. ID check.
- Then they released you?
- Yes.
Just like that?
Yes,"just like that."
What about Costa,Daumont and Verger?
They were arrested,but never seen again.
So what?
So there!
I'm afraid we're starting to stray.
And didn't you used to print German
weeklies?
The publishing house where I worked
printed them.
It meant I could make fake IDs.
And leaflets and passports. Remember?
- You'd give me sketches.
- Yes.
The first time I met him,he was
speaking German
- with a propaganda officer.
- My foreign language.
When you asked about the network,
I was convinced you were a spy.
Then I trusted you...
...but I was mostly drawn to you.
We're going nowhere fast.
Let's try to remember
what happened the night the Gestapo
raided the place.
I must've beaten the world record for
the 100-meter dash.
That night's dinner...
What about it?
It didn't go down well.
You overeat and don't chew properly.
Dinner was...?
- Coq au vin.
You're still digesting it.
You're not exactly a gourmet!
- Still enjoy coq au vin?
- I still do.
Your culinary tastes haven't changed.
But I'm rather taken aback by...
How you lusted after young women's
thighs!
I'll never forget that.
It's not true.
But you're still a handsome young man.
When you run into your ex-girlfriends,
what do you tell them?
Leave us the hell alone!
Don't talk to me like that.
Or they'll think I raised you wrong.
We had all gathered here that night
with Castille.
No.
No,not all of us. Some of us weren't
present.
Are you sure?
Quite.
Then they'll get blamed. If we need a
suspect...
If I had denounced the network,I
would've avoided the meeting.
To avoid a shootout. But I was present!
So was I.
But I wasn't.
Where were you?
Don't worry,I have an alibi.
Four days earliers,Castille had sent me
to Saint-Malo.
It took four days to come back?
Yes.
Rouen was being bombarded.
Really?
I don't recall that at all.
But Rouen's citizens haven't forgotten.
Blanchet.
You weren't there that night either.
That's right.
- Why not say so?
- I'm telling you!
I had a very high fever.
My wife insisted I should'nt go,so I
stayed in bed.
Why didn't you warn us?
I called.
- You didn't have a phone.
- From the next-door bistro!
- So you went out anyway?
- No,my wife phoned.
Who took the call?
I don't know. Castille,probably.
- He's dead,he won't deny it.
- Stop pissing me off!
My wife called!Got it?
It happened 15 years ago,so...
But tragic events are never easily
forgotten.
True.
You had an altercation...
with Castille shortly before he died.
What was behind it?
An "altercation"?
Castille and I often quarreled.
We didn't share the same vision for the
network.
Castille was a remarkable man,
yet profoundly inhuman.
An intransigent doctrinarian.
On the contrary,he exhibited great
sensitivity.
I admit I was hotheaded and
temperamental.
A loose cannon.
Some squabbles,nothing serious.
"Nothing serious"?
I jumped in before someone got hurt.
A punch can be a philosophical argument.
Or Christian charity?
What were you fighting over?
Wasn't there a rivalry between you?Well?
None that I know of.
I'm sorry,but...
Don't you think
you had something to do with it?
Le Gueven?
My feelings for Marie-Octobre
were strictly fraternal.
Either you forgot what you were like.
or you have a peculiar notion of the
term "fraternal."
I remember the night we were alone at
your place.
And that night,you were most eloquent.
What would've become of us
if the air raid warning hadn't sounded?
Women led you to God.
Le Gueven.
why were you and Castille ready to come
to blows?
It's best to come clean.
Spit it out. What are you worried about?
I'm concerned about you,not me.
Aren't you miserable?
The unjustly accused can't help but be
miserable.
I can't tell you that.
Castille claimed you stole three
million F.
Is that true?
Yes,it is.
Three million,back then...
We had received large sums of money
from London
to support various network activities.
That's why I went to Saint-Malo.
But the three million F Castille kept
with him had disappered.
What was his motive for accusing you?
I led,in those days,aside from our
activities,
a rather turbulent and expensive
lifestyle.
Spendthrift!
- I was debt-ridden.
But that doesn't mean...
When Castille confronted me...
I was belligerent,so I didn't react
well.
Luckily,you broke it up.
Makes sense.
What?
The devil tempted him,but God beckoned
him.
- If Castille accused you...
- I didn't steal!Believe me?
Not for a second.
You should.
Le Gueven didn't do it. Castille said
so the next day.
The thief was never caught?
A matter of minutes.
Castille was going to unmask him during
the last meeting.
He never got the chance.
"During the last meeting"?
Castille walked in through that door
and told me,
"The thief is here."
It was a close call for one of us.
Saved by the Gestapo.
Exactly.
It's all water under the bridge.
You don't care,you're alive.
But through no fault of my own.
They missed me three times. Maybe
you're sorry!
I'm "alive"!
What if being alive suits me just fine?
But not me!Not until Castille's death
is avenged.
I don't know what Castille meant to you,
but I've never met anybody like him.
We served in the Corps Francs in 1940.
I survived thanks to him.
I owe him everything!
Before I met him,I was a lout,a crook.
But he made me a man. I walk with my
head held high!
If he could hear me,
I'd tell him, "Mr Castille,you'll be
avenged tonight!
"It's an honor to salute you."
I was very fond of Castille too.
You never wanted to disappoint him.
Yes,you wanted him to think highly of
you.
Then let's see this through,to remain
true to him.
Whoever ratted us out didn't only
betray Castille,
he also betrayed all of those we never
saw again.
- Those who never came back.
- Hold on.
Is the theft and betrayal a cause and
effect relationship?
Possibly.
The money was spent somehow!He hid it
initially,and then...
You...
It seems you have a large practice.
Practices are costly.
You were broke then. You worked in a
garage.
Yes,at night. To pay for my education.
I wanted to lend you some money.
I didn't want to owe anyone.
Your practice opened in '46.
Yes,and it cost over three million.
An inheritance?
Dr. Carelli's practice. I married his
daughter.
When he retired,I took over his
patients.
Your methods aren't tinged with
subtlely.
He thinks he's performing again.
Defending blows!
Like a wrestler.
Stick to slaughter,butcher!
Bravo!How classy!
Mind you,he knows plenty about the meat
market.
By the way,
did you also inherit your fine arts
shop from your grandmother?
We all know what you were up to in
Puteaux!
Bernadi!
I'm sorry,I was way out of line.
Marinval!
I'd like you to do something.
Go back in time and tell me
if you've ever questioned a network
member's loyalty.
Simoneau?
- Never.
External betrayals,yes.
Blanchet?
I had doubts at time,but never any
proof.
It's all so long ago.
- But I have!
I suspected someone,and I still do.
You all suspected him too.
- His name's on the tip of...
- Who is it?
No,that'd be too easy.
- Have the courage to speak.
- I'm keeping the name secret.
- So you won't answer?
- Yes.
My way.
Vandamme has voted. Your turn.
Come on!Let's see if we agree.
This is rather...
But in case anyone...
Now maybe the truth will finally come
out.
You believe in Santa Claus?
Le Gueven.
I mean...
- You refuse to vote?
- Yes.
The vote will foster hatred. Count me
out.
- I don't hate anyone.
- Hatred!
And here comes King Kong,
who's intent on teaching Villar a
lession he'll never forget.
The blows are raining down...
Simoneau's got my vote.
That'll teach him to have murderers
pardoned.
- So?
- No volunteers?
"Simoneau."
A blank vote.
Simoneau.
So I'm a traitor?
You think I'm a traitor,don't you?
It was a secret vote.
True enough. And one blank vote.
I'll never know whose. Happy?
It was mine.
I see.
I had no choice.
- Regardless of my conviction.
- Your "conviction"?
You vote white,but think black. The
Last Judgment awaits.
You think I'm a bastard too?
I can't be sure.
- Still,you voted yes.
Like Thibaud.
A wrong diagnosis is serious.
We all agree it's you.
You were all thinking the same thing.
Yet you said nothing.
You were braver back then.
We didn't consult each other. The
result...
It wasn't premeditated,right?
A combination of circumstances.
But you need evidence.
Or certain presumptions.
What "presumptions"?
You know your origins.
My "origins"?
Yes. In 1934...
En 1934,I was a fascist. That's a fact.
- In the Spanish Civil War...
- I supported Franco.
The France-Germany Committee?
De Brinon!
Great!
And after the Armistice,you started,at
Sorbonne...
The France-Germany University
Association.
A very busy agenda of politically
charged activities.
In 1942,when Germany violated the
agreements,
I wanted nothing more to do with them.
The Gestapo arrested me!
Fresnes,a transfer to Drancy... That
counts for something!
You know how I escaped from Drancy.
I never hid anything from Castille.
He introduced me to the network. He
shielded me.
Would you question his vigilance?
If Castille trusted him...
You suspect me.
But, I have some questions too
We drew a correlation between...
...the theft and the betrayal.
A hypothesis.
Castille told you Le Gueven wasn't the
thief,right?
Yes.
He was going to unmask the thief,right?
He said the thief was present?
- Yes.
But I was in Rouen!... One of you is
the thief.
I wasn't there either.
I was sick remember?
He didn't have time.
The Germans came in...
10 minutes after the meeting started.
But during those 10 minutes...
Let's try to reconstruct that
evening,shall we?
We were sitting at that table.
Castille was right here.
I can still see him...
I was sitting here.
And me,right here.
During those 10 minutes...?
First,I read a communication from London
about sabotage we were to carry out.
We talked.
Castille needed a map that was in his
car.
He ordered me to retrieve it.
That's when it all started.
On the grounds,
I saw parked cars and Germans with
machine guns.
So I rushed back here and warned
everyone.
Castille ordered us to split
- I went to the kitchen to
protect Victorine
Le Gueven and I ran out through that
door.
The three of us hid together.
In a thicket.
And you?
Who? Her?
She wanted to stay by Castille's side.
Imagine that!
But Castille had left important
documents in that desk.
The London correspondence.
- We both ran back inside.
Disaster ensued.
Castille was taking his files. I was
helping him.
The Germans stormed in.
Castille fired two shots,
but they fired back and Castille went
down.
Five minutes.
If I'd been armed I'd be dead too.
Then what?
Then they searched the place
And they took me away.
When they slowed down on Suresnes
Bridge,
I bolted from the car and plunged into
the Seine.
And come what may.
Shots rang out. I got hit in the
shoulder.
They figured I had drowned.
He showed up at my place,soaking
wet,covered in blood...
He told me off!
I was busy packing.
I removed the bullet,
then we hid in Limousin.
When was Castille killed?
When the Germans barged in.
How long did it take?
I don't know...
Five or six seconds.
Two shots,machine-gun fire...
Are you sure?
I almost paid the ultimate price.
Something's not right.
Why?
Sorry to say,but... Something's not
right.
Your story is flawed.
How?
From the time the Germans raided this
room
and left with you,no shots were fired.
"No shots were fired"?
No gunshots,no machine-gun fire.
How would you know?You weren't there.
I was there.
What?
No,you weren't!You were sick.
- Your wife called.
- From the bistro.
That's all true.
But that afternoon.
I felt better,and since my wife was
running errands...
That's interesting. No one saw you.
Naturally.
The Gestapo showed up seconds after I
did.
I hid in the rhododendrons. I witnessed
everything.
I was scared stiff!
Why didn't you tell us that earlier?
So you wouldn't suspect me,
given the circumstances surrounding my
arrival.
Why do you feel the need to open up now?
Some things you can't keep to yourself.
Castille may be dead,but I can't let
him down.
Don't you believe me?
How can we?
You swore you weren't there,and now...
My word isn't good enough?
The first one or the second?
Do you have proof?
"Proof"...
That night,you didn't come by bike,as
usual.
Yes.
No. You came by tandern.
It was next to the front door.
True.
I borrowed it from my brother-in-law.
See?
But how did Castille die?Try to focus!
I don't know what Blanchet is trying to
prove,
but I maintain what I said.
Castille fired, the Germans fired back,
and Castille went down.
Under a hail of machine-gun fire?
That's right.
No. Shots rang out before the Germans
stormed in.
They were shooting at you while you
scattered.
But when they went in there,there was
total silence.
Total!
But...
Machine-gun fire causes damage.
Did you see any bullet holes?
None.
It must've been a replica machine gun.
A toy machine gun.
Say something.
Now I'm not so sure...
It happened so long ago!
Try to remember.
Let's see...
I was right there.
Castille...
Let me think.
You have nightmares,you wake up,you
can't remember them.
It's the same thing.
So Castille...
The desk...
Yes...
Yes,now I remember.
You were right,there was no machine-gun
fire.
Men armed with machine guns came in
here,but fired no shots.
I made a mistake.
Two plainclothes policemen with
handguns...
...came in through that door.
One of them shot Castille in the back.
There you have it.
It's strange that I thought I heard
machine-gun fire...
We make up stuff we think is true.
- Through that very door.
- No one came in...
...through that door,sir.
- How would you know?
I was behind it.
"Behind it"?
Yes,behind the door.
When the Germans were spotted,he fetch
me in the kitchen.
You wouldn't budge.
On account of my rheumatism. They
wanted to hide in the tank.
A woman my age!
So my cat and I stayed put.
Poor little creature. I kept caressing
it.
I heard shots in the grounds.
"In the grounds."
I headed here to see what was going on.
From behind the door,I heard quite a
commolition...
I just stood there while my cat purred.
But then I got scared and I headed to
the tank too.
Were any shots fired in the room?
No,but I heard the stomping of feet.
And shouting. In Germans. They made
quite a racket!
What do you say to that?
I don't know...
But I witnessed Castille's death.
I wasn't taking notes,so whether they
came in through...
He's right. We'll come back to that.
Focus on the order of events. First,the
thief.
We forgot about him.
When we unmask him...
And he's among us.
You were broke back in '44.
I was working.
For a pittance.
I had regular employment!
You tried scrounging off me a few times
to no avail.
You'd need to get up pretty early!
I lent you money several times. Small
sums,but...
We'll get to the bottom of this.
So...
Let me,I'm used to it.
Fiscal inquisition...
When did you buy your printing house?
1946.
It's quite a sizable one.
Yes.
How much'd you pay for it?
None of your business.
Any partners?
No.
You bought it cash?
None of your business!
It is!You don't become an owner
overnight.
And don't say you won the lottery.
Where'd you find the money?
- I don't have to tell you!
You know very well I'm innocent.
Then why not answer?
But what...?
Well?
Where'd you get the money?
A friend lent it to me.
A friend "lent" you money?
Sometimes friends do lend money to
their friends.
What friends?
You didn't know him.
Did you commit it to paper?
Not between friends!
And where can we question this model
friend?
- Where does he live?
At the cemetary,he's dead.
Before getting reimbursed!You think
we're idiots?
I'm an honest man.
I'm an honest man!
If you were us,Rougier,
you'd find your answer suspicious too.
In 1943,you were in dire straits.
In 1946,you bought a printing house
worth millions,
and when asked where you got the money,
you conjure up the ghost of an
anonymous creditor.
But why suspect me instead of...
...Vandamme or Bernadi?
Is it our fault if you gave two
versions of Castille's death?
And if those versions contradict
Blanchet and Victorine's?
My word is just as good as theirs!
Blanchet retracted himself too,but no
one suspects him.
Yet he got here just a few seconds
before the Gestapo.
- "This way,please"!
What?
Bastard!
Let's not get worked up.
Blanchet,
didn't you say there were no gunshots
between the time the Germans entered
the house
and they left with Rougier?
Yes.
- You stand by that?
- Absolutely.
It's quite simple,then.
If the Germans didn't murder Castille
then he was murdered before their
arrival.
A few seconds before.
During the short time he was alone with
someone.
What are you implying?
Admit it.
Admit that you'd figured it out.
You stole the money.
You'd been found out.
Castille was going to unmask you.
But then,a miracle.
You're mad!
The Gestapo arrived.
- Call that a "miracle"?
The arrival of the Gestapo?
You could pin the murder on them.
You heard him,he called me a murderer!
Let it go!
He's got no proof,no witness!
Thibaud...
I came back with a bullet in my
shoulder.
Tell them what state I was in
when I told you Castille was dead.
Did I look like a murderer?
Say something,Le Gueven!
I'm the one who gave the alert the
night of the meeting!
You escaped thanks to me!
If you're all alive today...
OK,since I've got no choice...
Tell them,Marie-Octobre.
Tell them they're wrong.
- How can I...?
- Tell them the truth.
What "truth"?
Brace yourself and tell them.
Tell them... what kind of man Castille
was.
I don't understand.
Marie-Octobre...
I'm defending my honor,maybe even my
life!
Remember...
...when you'd bring your sketches to
the printing house.
Every Tuesday. Remember?
Yes,so?
We hit it off right away,no?
Yes.
I lived alone. I was withdrawn,
yet you found a way to...
We'd chat away confide in each other.
Then one day I invited you to lunch.
Just a modest lunch.
Then I started thinking about you.
And waiting for Tuesday.
"Marie-Octobre" had become a habit.
You called me "Little Messenger Boy."
"Little Messenger Boy"...
Go on.
Continue.
Then you resigned.
You didn't want to work for your
magazine anymore.
With good reason!
I wouldn't see you anymore.
No more Tuesdays for me.
So I asked you to marry me.
You knew it was impossible.
"Lack of money."
But that wasn't the real reason.
The real reason was that...
...you were in love with someone
else,right?
Tell them.
Fine...
Marie-Octobre was in love with Castille.
Impossible!
Marie-Octobre?
I realized it right away.
As soon as she had me join the network.
That's news to me!
Women are amazing. Castille?
It's true.
I was in love with Castille.
It was love at first sight.
I was his mistress.
I never replaced him.
I'd never have guessed!Life is full of
surprises!
Castille knew how to keep a secret!
All this is irrelevant.
On the contrary.
Your turn now.
You can't keep this quiet any longer.
What do you want me to tell them?
Tell them who Castille was.
A remarkable man.
A great leader,yes,we already know that.
The embodiment of courage and
selflessness.
But he was something else too!
He had faults,like all men.
In his private life,he was a selfish
brute.
- Cynical,capricious.
You're lying.
He's lying,don't listen to him.
How dare you speak of him that way?
Who are we to judge his private life?
I'm telling the truth!
I'm defending my hide!
Castille despised women.
How would you know?He never confided in
you!
No,but you did.
You'd come to me when he made you
miserable.
How many times did I see you cry?
It was one humilation after another.
"Humilation"?
We quarreled sometimes,of course,but...
The morning of that meeting that went
awry...
Didn't you pay me a visit?
You were panic-stricken!
You spoke of suicide
You'd found out he had another lover,
that he wanted to marry her.
You wanted to have one last...
... discussion with him.
And I did,on that very afternoon.
He asked me to forgive him.
- He promised me...
He promised you nothing.
You have to tell them exactly what
happened,
after the alert,
when Castille ordered us to flee.
But... I refused.
I didn't want to leave him.
So you stayed alone with him?
Yes,I lied earlier. I wanted to avoid
this.
Truth is,I left right behind you.
You were alone with Castille.
He was putting away papers in his
briefcase.
Then I remembered the documents in the
desk.
I came back here,in this room.
And then...
No!That's not how it happened!
Castille was dead.
There was a gun beside her,on the
pedestal table.
Forgive me,Marie-Octobre.
An awkward silence?
There's orange squash for the thirsty,
and whisky for the drunks.
Look me in the eye.
You stand by what you said?
It's the truth.
Your word of honor?
Do you swear to it?
I do.
I must be the traitor,then!
Me,who summoned you here today.
It's absurd!
Why?
Why would I have taken such an
initiative?
A long-forgotten affair that happened
15 years ago!
Out of recklessness?Out of defiance?
When you put it that way...
Murderers don't investigate their own
crimes!
Excuse me,but aren't you mistaken about
something?
"Mistaken"?
Was this meeting really your idea?
You said so yourself.
Oui. Enfin, je vous I'ai dit.
- Yes,but I meant...
Actually,wasn't this my idea?
When that German
buyer,Muller,recognized you,I was there.
Yes,you arrived at that very moment.
You were so pale,I thought you'd faint.
You asked Muller to repeat what he'd
said before leaving us.
Then I told you,
"We owe it to Castille's memory to find
this traitor."
What did you answer?
That it'd be impossible to find the
members of our network,
that it was too late.
My secretary found everyone's address
easily enough.
At which point I insisted we call this
meeting,right?
Yes
Afterward.
I've seen you every day these last 15
years.
And after all this time,I still don't
understand you.
Nor have I ever heard about this great
love for Castille,
this love that explains so many things.
Since we're stirring up old memories,
I'll ask you just one question.
I know you'll answer truthfully.
Marie,
did you kill Castille because he was
going to leave you?
I love Castille more than life itself.
And he loved me,he wasn't going to
leave me.
Did you kill him?
No.
I believe you.
We do too,Marie-Octobre.
We believe you.
Friends,I don't know what happened 15
years ago,
but I can't take all these accusations
seriously.
We're playing a dangerous game,it's
beneath us.
It's a losing game... Let's tread
carefully.
Well,my mind's made up.
That's right.
I've been watching you,listening to you,
and here's my conclusion:
We're all amazing,but we're acting like
idiots.
We're all accusing each other of the
worst crimes.
We want a culprit,but how absurd is
that?
I don't like big speeches,but...
...we were all part of a great
adventure,right?
We liked beautiful women,fancy
dinners,the easy life.
Yet we threw ourselves into a crazy
ventures.
We became terrorists,forgers,saboteurs..
We learned how to use transmitters,
parachutes,plastic explosives...
And for what?
For nothing!For honor.
And honor doesn't pay.
Honestly!Have you all forgotten?
And Marie-Octobre?
Remember your escape on Des Saussales
St.?
And you,the printer?
We were glad to go to him for false
papers,and the test...
As for you,Simoneau,
If I voted for you earlier,I was wrong
and I apologize.
You took great risks,we all did!
So...
let's lay off each other.
There are no traitors here.
Life wasn't a picnic for me either.
I know,you had lots of guts,
- Didn't I?
- Lots.
When you'd hide on Chardon-Lagache St.,
and I'd bring Mr. Marinval's supplies
to you...
And I'd bribe the inspector. What cheek!
Sometimes my courage flagged.
Sixth floor and no elevator!
They'd call you Aramis.
"Aramis",with that mug?Great cover!
Luckily you were never
arrested,Victorine.
Yes,once.
You never mentioned it.
'Cause I was at fault.
I had a roast beef for Mr. Aramis.
I decided to give it to my
sister-in-law,
but I came across some policemen on the
way,in civvies!
Did they question you?
- Naturally.
I thought they were German officers,but
on the contrary.
"On the contrary"?
They said they were Resistance fighters
too.
"Too"?
I'd intimated that I had contacts with
the Resistance.
- Which led to...
- You mentioned the network?
- Why wouldn't I?
When did it happen?
It's simple.
The roast beef was for my
sister-in-law's birthday.
Jeanne's birthday is on August 20.
On August 21,the Gestapo barged in
here...
...and killed Castille.
And we've been racking out brains for a
decade!
What'd I say?
You betrayed us,you dumbbell.
Never.
You screwed up big time!
They were patriots,I say!I'm not that
stupid!
Just a few minutes until
the European champions are crowned,
for,as you can see,
there are still four of them left...
Marinval!
I know how to hold my tongue!
You don't open up to just anyone!
You would've done the same thing.
I knew I could trust them.
Why?'Cause they "looked" trustworthy?
"Why"?
While we were talking,
one of their friends came in and said,
I remember it clearly,
that the Canadian landing in Normandy
had failed.
He'd received a dispatch.
If you'd seen them!They were all
shattered.
What a sorry sight!
That's when they said I could leave.
They were completely distraught!
See?
"Canadian landing"?
Yes.
That took place in August '42.
Yes,August '42.
The Gestapo came here in August '44,two
years later.
True enough.
Victorine is therefore exonerated.
See?That's what I was saying.
Accusing poor old me,with my
rheumatism...
Anyone can make a mistake,Victorine.
So we're back at square one.
Just great!
For breakfast tommorow,I'd like two
fried eggs and white wine.
What time is it,anyway?
Excuse me,but I have to drop by the
hospital.
Victorine,be nice and get my overcoat.
But,Thibaud...
It's late,old man.
I gotta be at the office by 8 tomorrow.
Once a pencil pusher...!
Please,Vandamme!
Sorry,Marie,but my paper comes off the
press at 7...
- Gimme a lift?
- Sure,it's on the way.
Wait,don't leave just yet.
Gimme five more minutes.
We can settle this in five minutes.
I doubt it,but I wouldn't want Marinval
to accuse me of putting a wrench in the
works...
I wish we could've settle this among
ourselves,
and avoid calling in a third party.
But too bad,you asked for it.
An old enemy will therefore judge us.
Only one man saw the face of the person
who betrayed us.
Only one man knows him.
His name is Wilfrid Muller,
a former Wehrmacht intelligence officer.
Wilfrid Muller is here.
He's waiting upstairs.
Damn!
There's still time to forgo his
involvement.
No?
So be it.
Mr. Muller,please!
So it was you, bastard!
Admit it!Admit it!
No,leave me alone!
It was a trick,our last resort.
Fess up!
How much did you sell us out for?
- It wasn't for the money.
- No,it was for honor!
But you'll talk,I guarantee that!
You piece of shit!
Why'd you betray us?Why?
For Marie-Octobre.
- What?
- I killed Castille for her.
Out of love,I bet!
- Yes.
You think we're fools?
And you accused her out of love,too?
- Talk or you're dead!
Stop!
You've got nothing to lose now,so tell
the truth.
I'll help you,I think I've figured it
out.
"Help" him?With a swift kick in the ass!
You weren't lying about loving
Marie-Octobre.
But between that love and Castille's
murder,
there was more than betrayal.
There was also the theft of three
million.
You're not the first idiot to steal for
love,
thinking that money will win over a
woman,
but it doesn't always work. The proof...
Who cares why or how?
There are no extenuating circumstances!
Let's finish off this scum right now!
He's half dead anyway.
Have some dignity,Rougier. Be a man.
You didn't kill Castille because of
me,did you?
He knew I'd stolen money from the
network.
When I realized he'd accuse me in front
of you...
You panicked.
So I went to the others.
Those Gestapo swine!
So they'd get rid of Castille?
Is that it?
I'd lost my mind.
It's only when I saw them arrive that
night,
machine guns in hand,
that I realized what I'd done...
So...
I tried to make amends.
At least...
minimize the damages.
i gave the alert.
And took advantage of the situation to
murder Castille?
You had nothing to lose,you were
hedging your bets.
The Germans thought you'd killed a
terrorist,
and we blamed the Gestapo.
But they still arrested me!
No,Rougier,they only pretended to.
And you pretended to escape,right?
Thibaud removed the bullet you shot in
your own shoulder.
You're a thief,a traitor
...and a murderer.
Let me go now.
Step aside.
Gimme the car keys,Marinval.
But...
Move!
Step aside.
Farther back!
Move over,OK?
No,Rougier,you won't get past me.
Please don't make me shoot you.
I beg of you.
Stand back,it'll be your fault if I
shoot her.
No!
What'll you do with him?
We all agreed beforehand.
He'll sign the confession,the reason
for his sucide.
No.
You have no right!
You don't...
Start writing.
- No.
No,I don't want to.
You can't make me.
Start writing.
Go on,Rougier. Your situation is
hopeless.
It'll be over in a flash.
"I admit..."
Go on.
"I admit that I,in August 1944,
"denounced to the Gestapo,
"the Vaillance network.
"I also admit
"that I killed,by my own hand,
"Comm.Castille.
"leader of the network."
Just one more sentence. You can do it.
"Confounded by my former comrades,
"I've resolved...
to take'
'... my own life."
Sign it.
Sign it!
In the name of what justice do you
condemn him?
In the name of our own justice.
A justice without pardon,leniecy or
mercy?
Did he show Castille mercy?
- For your own salvation...
No sermons,please!
Thibaud,tell them to let me live.
I'm a bastard,but I promise to make
amends.
Get up,I can't do anything to help you.
Blanchet...
You have a wife and kids like me.
What'll happen to them?
- I'm not dog!
Get away from me!
Listen to me!
If you murder this man,
...and it is murder.
Don't count on me to back up your
suicide story.
I'll go to the police and testify
against you.
Murder and accessory to murder. You
know what that entails.
You already know that,Simoneau.
We'll accept the consequences.
All of them.
You'll accept them together,but
individually?
Alone with your conscience,no.
You're not monsters.
You don't execute a man after 15
years,it's appaling!
Deep down inside,you know this isn't
right.
You know it isn't right,but you're
afraid to say so.
Isn't that true,Thibaud?
Blanchet?
Isn't that true?
Vandamme?
And you too, Simoneau.
You know I'm right, just admit it.
You don't like killing Rougier at all!
"Jacques Castel,of the Vaillance
network,
"18, died in the camps.
"Pierre Brunet, Vaillance network,
"33, shot to death.
"Robert Fleuret, Vaillance network,
"54, tortured and shot to death.
"Etienne Godot, Vaillance network,
"... 32, tortured
and shot to death.
"Jacqueline Riviere,
Valillance network...
"... 26 ans: Deported and hanged.
"Pierre Castille, leader of the
Vaillance network: Assassinated by a
member..."
Marie-Octobre!
He's dead.
Hello?
This is 248
Give me the police, please.
Hello, police?
This is the Chesnay estate.
Can you come right away?
I just killed a man.