What are you doing, Mousy?
I'm just walking around
the lamp post.
- Around the lamp post?
- Yes, so as not to break my leg.
- That's no good.
- How do you know?
I don't understand how anyone
can be that superstitious.
- Don't you understand everything?
- Most things, but not you.
I'm not easy to understand.
You shouldn't say you're afraid
to break your leg.
Why not?
- Because that's when it happens.
Hardly anyone who breaks their leg
thinks about it in advance.
Those who don't think about it
break their legs.
What are you frightened of?
- Wait.
What if that bloke is colour blind?
He's probably learnt to drive
when he thinks it looks red.
But what if his vision
suddenly becomes normal again?
Then we're finished!
- We will be if you don't hurry up!
I'm trying to avoid
stepping on the stripes.
It's better not being run over.
- But the best is to avoid both.
It's dangerous
to be that scared, Mousy.
Do you have to call me Mousy?
- Everybody calls you Mousy.
But you could call me Markus.
I'm your friend, right?
- Yes...
That's why I call you Mousy.
Then you get used to it.
No, I don't.
- Just wait and see.
Mona is looking at you.
- No, she's looking at you.
That's just what I was afraid of.
- Just look back, then they'll stop.
That's easy for you to say.
- No, it was actually quite hard.
May we have your autograph?
That was Jostein Gaarder!
- I can see that.
Don't you want his autograph?
- Don't you?
I don't collect autographs.
Hurry up.
- I don't want to.
Sometimes I wonder if you are
the world's biggest coward.
Dear Jostein Gaarder.
I'm an 84-year-old widow,
unfortunately, nearly blind, -
- so I can't read your books
myself, but my grandson, -
- little Markus Simonsen,
reads them to me.
I'm sitting here in my wheelchair,
blinded by tears, writing to you.
I used to prefer "Superman",
but now you're my favourite.
Little Markus
collects autographs, -
- so would you please
be so kind and send him yours?
That would make both
a young and an old heart...
...mighty joyful.
Is something wrong, Markus?
No...
It's so quiet here.
As if you were crying,
if you know what I mean.
No, everything is okay, daddy.
I just got a bit worried, after...
So everything is okay then?
- Yes.
Nothing is wrong?
No.
Well, it's time to go to bed then.
Tomorrow's the big day.
The big class trip
to the mountains.
I bet you're looking forward to it.
Yes, I'm sure it will be fun.
Are you going high up?
- Yes, I suppose so.
Above the tree line?
- Yes, quite a lot higher.
Poor those with acrophobia.
- Oh yes, poor them!
Maybe I should come and help carry?
- Some other time, daddy.
We can go in the mountains
together some other time.
Just the two of us?
- Yes, all the way to the top.
Viggo, pull yourself together.
I don't know.
Leave the girls alone.
Is all the luggage loaded?
Stop running around.
Let's take a photo.
We're going to take a photo.
We need to have a little memory
for the parents.
Yes, that's good.
I'll help you with the rucksack.
I don't think that's very smart.
- No? I wanted to help...
I think you'd better leave now.
See you, dad.
- Yes, bye...
Have a nice trip.
- Thank you, Simonsen.
Be careful, my boy.
- Relax. We'll look after him.
World record in weightlifting!
- Calm down a bit now.
Are you moving
to the mountains, Mousy?
We'll take one more.
Markus, you decide now.
Markus, it's your turn.
A tiny mouse a tiny mouse
is never wanted in my house
Come on, Markus.
An autograph an autograph
that is a...
That's good, Markus.
What rhymes with autograph?
An autograph an autograph
that is a...
No, this is no good. What...
- Nothing, teacher.
Nothing rhymes with autograph.
- Well, never mind.
My phone is ringing.
Hello, this is Kåre.
Yes, we're having a great time.
You heard it. That's good.
I'll tell him. That's all right.
That was Markus' daddy
wishing us a nice trip.
Let's sing another song.
Hurry up. Don't just stand there.
Come on!
Can you see that star?
Where?
There.
That's Sirius.
But what we see
isn't Sirius now.
The light has taken many years
to reach Earth.
What we see
is Sirius eight years ago.
My mum was alive then.
Dad won't sleep tonight.
Markus and Sigmund,
come on!
Who's the sexiest?
Sharon Stone has tits
like mountains.
Melanie Griffith is much nicer.
- I'd like her in the sack.
She's married to Don Johnson.
I wouldn't have him in the sack!
I think she's divorced now.
- They're all divorced.
They remarry, have a fuck
and get divorced again.
Diana Mortensen isn't married.
- No, Diana Mortensen is very choosy.
She's been with Michael Douglas.
- Everybody has been with him.
Not Melanie Griffith,
because she's with Don Johnson.
Paul Newman hasn't been divorced.
- Has he always been married?
What do you mean with always?
- All the time.
Since the Big Bang?
- What bang?
Ten points to Sharon Stone
and nine points to Diana Mortensen.
Sigmund, who is Diana Mortensen?
Don't you know?
- No.
She lives in Hollywood,
but comes from Horten.
She acts in
"Money and Power" on TV.
I have a photo of her.
Oh...
What are you doing?
Hey, Mousy!
Who's that guy
on the other side of the pool?
That's her bodyguard.
He tried to smash the camera,
but the photographer got away.
Diana Mortensen
has no private life.
Poor her.
Let's get into bed
and sleep now, boys.
Shush, I can't hear what he's saying.
What did you say, Reidar?
Julia Roberts gets three points.
- That's nice for her.
But let's sleep now.
Diana Mortensen... ten points.
What's happening here?
- Mousy is sleepwalking.
Shush! Don't wake him.
You can give him a shock.
Help, a ghost!
- Shush!
He's probably dreaming something.
- Dreams may be as real as reality.
You bet they can.
Come on now. Stay on the path.
It's not that far now.
Come on, Markus.
You're not superstitious,
are you, Mousy?
You're crossing as number 13.
Come on!
You can do it, Mousy.
Come on, Markus!
Has he gone bonkers or what?
Hey, Markus...
Mousy!
Mousy...
Forget about them, Mousy.
- Please don't call me Mousy!
Never again, Markus.
I ran up here all alone.
Did you see it?
Even though I have acrophobia!
- Don't look down.
Let's have a rest here. Relax.
Can we walk on the glacier?
We've walked far enough today.
But I can make a nature trail...
- They're for kindergartens.
Walking on glaciers is much cooler.
- And much more dangerous.
I've walked on glaciers.
- Have you, Markus?
That's really something.
You're lying!
- I'm not.
Me and my dad walk
on glaciers every summer.
That's great, Markus.
Maybe you can give us
a lecture about it?
A lecture?
Yes, about walking on glaciers.
When?
Here he comes!
Walking on glaciers
is like walking on ice.
When you walk on glaciers,
you need warm clothes...
...if the sun doesn't shine.
Then it's not so important.
What about wellingtons?
With spikes.
Wellingtons with spikes.
Last year when dad and I walked
on the glacier, it was very cold.
The wind was so bad
it was a hurricane.
Yes, a great big hurricane.
- A big hurricane!
Good advice...
- Was hard to come by!
The fog came...
- Where did the fog come?
It came... drifting.
- I knew it...
The ski tracks became covered
in snow. Should we turn around?
No, we didn't turn.
We just continued walking.
On the other side of the glacier
was the warm cottage.
We walked on. The glacier
was slippery like a skating rink.
We folded out our jackets
and slid joyfully along the glacier.
It was a fantastic experience!
We knew walking on a glacier
could be dangerous, -
and the most dangerous thing
is the cracks in the glacier.
They were our worst enemy.
And what did we see in the distance?
A crack in the glacier?
- Yes, a crack as deep as...
Really deep! Daddy and I
slid straight towards it.
The speed was incredible!
It was really incredible!
And then?
Then... Then we went home.
And afterwards we both agreed
it had been a nice trip.
That's me.
Yes, this is Kåre. Oh, it's you.
One moment, and I'll ask.
Markus, it's your dad.
He wants to know how you are.
I'm fine...
So this is where you are.
Do you think dreaming
is the same as lying?
That depends on
what you're dreaming.
I dream
that everything is different.
That's not lying, that's hoping.
I wish I was there now.
Where?
On Sirius eight years ago.
Dear Diana Mortensen.
I'm a Norwegian mountain climber
and millionaire.
Here I am, all alone
in a cottage in the mountains, -
- after having climbed out of
a crack in the glacier, -
- which I was unfortunate enough
to have fallen in.
Many Norwegian mountain climbers
think about you, -
- feel sorry for you
and wish you all the best.
I have to tell you
that I have a special hobby:
I collect autographs.
It's an interesting hobby
for a lonely millionaire.
I'm unmarried. The mountains
and the business take all my time.
As you understand,
I'm a lonely millionaire.
Just like you're a lonely film
star. I can see it in your eyes.
But don't worry, Diana Mortensen.
One day we'll both
meet the right person.
Best regards
from the Norwegian mountains -
- and Markus Simonsen,
millionaire.
There's the mountain wanderer.
Did you have a nice trip?
- Yes.
Was there any snow up there?
- No, there was a glacier.
Glaciers are eerie things!
You didn't walk on it?
- No.
Do you know
what they call me at work?
They call me "The Owl".
I shouldn't have phoned, should I?
- It doesn't matter.
Did they tease you
because I phoned?
No, you phoned
because they tease me.
You have to go to bed now, Markus.
Markus...
A cheque for ten million dollars
for your daughter, Mr. Smith.
That should give life a chance.
I've brought your breakfast
and a letter.
Letter?
- Yes, from USA.
Do you know anyone
in America, Markus?
"Yes, I'm lonely.
Most people think I'm cold, -
but deep inside I'm still
the little girl with burning cheeks -
who left her friends
to conquer Hollywood and the world.
Yes, dear Markus Simonsen. I'm
Cinderella, but where is the prince?"
Has Diana Mortensen
written that to you?
She sent me a photo
with her autograph as well.
What did you write to her?
- That I was a millionaire.
Have you won the lottery?
- No, it's from...
Diana Mortensen.
Do you know Diana Mortensen?
He's just mocking you, Per Espen.
- Watch the cracks in the asphalt!
You watch the cracks in your brain.
They're much deeper!
Practicing psychology.
We never learn that at school.
What if he had taken the letter?
I would have punched him
in the face.
I swear...
- I swear...
To dedicate my life
to helping Diana Mortensen.
And never let her down.
- And never let her down.
But to help, comfort and support her
in her deep loneliness.
To respect, obey and never betray
the secret laws of the Diana Club.
Help Diana!
- Help Diana!
Dear Diana.
I recognized my own feelings
in your letter.
I experienced a deep melancholy,
as well as pleasure.
A pleasure because you exist,
live and breathe.
Personally I appreciate
the little things in life.
I often get my inspiration
from nature.
A small cone
with its rugged beauty, -
- an evening sun which gilds
our hearts with its magic lustre.
Yes, dear Diana, this was a little
something about my inspiration.
With greetings from one heart
to another. Markus.
Hello, Mousy.
- Hi.
Do you want a punch in the face?
- No, thank you.
Oh, did you fall, Mousy?
- Straight down the glacier crack.
Who do you think you are?
What are you doing, boys?
- Nothing, teacher.
I'm just teaching them judo.
Do you know judo, Markus?
- Yes, I have a black belt.
Well, be careful then.
Yeah, that's just it.
We were just fooling around, Mousy.
- Yeah, just fooling around.
Do you want to come see the girls?
- See the girls?
They have PE.
Per Espen and I watch them change.
Lots of tits and thighs.
- You'll get dead horny.
I'm not interested in girls.
- Are you gay or what?
Gay?
- Maybe he's frightened he'll come.
When you're nearly coming,
then think of someone dead.
That's what I do.
- Per Espen gets really horny.
The girls don't want you
to come straight away.
I know that.
- Do you want to or not?
Look at Ellen Christine's tits.
- Look at that arse.
Move over, Per Espen.
I guess he came!
But listen, Sigmund!
She writes she's coming to Horten.
She wants to meet me.
She wants to drink champagne with me!
What shall I do?
Meet her, of course!
- But, Sigmund...
She thinks I'm a millionaire!
I've got it!
You have to pretend to be your son.
- I don't have a son.
No, but the millionaire
Markus Simonsen has one.
Markus Simonsen Junior.
- Junior?
Millionaire sons are called Junior.
- But I'm no millionaire son.
You have to pretend to be.
- But she wants to meet Senior!
But Junior is like his dad:
He understands and comforts her.
Why should I comfort her?
- She writes that she's lonely.
I don't want to.
- Are you a coward?
Do you want her to be alone
with her loneliness?
Everything for Diana, Markus.
- Yes, I know, but...
May we sit here?
- Yes, just sit down.
Where are you going?
"The little curlyhead is curious as
a squirrel and fast as a stoat, -
but also a thoughtful little thing.
I can talk to Markus Junior
about everything.
He's a comfort and pleasure
to his father during sad times.
Yes, dear Diana, this was
a little something about my son."
How did that sound?
- Where do you get it from?
Maybe we should drop "curlyhead"?
- Why? It sounds perfect.
Yes, but I don't have any curls!
Have you got any books about
behaviour and manners?
We want to learn
how to behave correctly.
Are you sure you don't prefer
something a bit more exciting?
Good behaviour can be exciting.
- Yes, that's right.
Not many kids your age
understand that.
No, we're a bit special.
- Yes, you can say that again.
Let me see.
"Behaviour and manners
in the nineties". How about that?
I'm sure that excellent, madam.
"Today, more than ever,
it's important to market yourself.
The first impression is crucial,
so look happy and friendly -
and repeat your name
so others remember it.
Either use a business card
or say it loud and clearly."
Lots to learn here.
- What do you mean?
How long is it since you
looked happy and friendly?
How often do you repeat your name?
- Everybody calls me Mousy anyway.
Yes, and here's the explanation.
- For what?
For why you're being teased.
You look so unhappy.
I thought
it was the other way round.
How?
That I was looking unhappy
because I was being teased.
"Rules for kissing on the cheek."
- I don't give a damn!
What if you don't know
how to kiss Diana?
I don't want to kiss her!
- All millionaire sons do so.
Which cheek do you kiss first?
- Isn't one enough?
"Watch how the royals do it.
First the right, then the left."
Do you understand?
- What are you two up to?
Nothing, we're just
marketing ourselves.
You have to kiss her!
"Today, more than ever, it's very
important to look happy and friendly.
Watch the royals..."
Markus, is that you?
I had a bad dream and...
I thought you were a murderer.
I dreamt too.
What did you dream?
You smiled very pleasantly.
- I dreamt I was being friendly.
How heavy is a tennis ball?
- It weighs at least 56.70 grams.
And how long is it?
- It's not long! It's round.
What's the diameter?
Why do I have to know all this?
Diana knows about tennis.
- I can't take anymore of this!
Come on, Markus.
You're really getting it now.
Mousy, do you play tennis?
I think she's following me.
Hi, Sigmund.
You want to play double?
- No!
No, we're finished.
But would you like
to have dinner with us?
Dinner? Where?
- At The Star restaurant.
When?
- Friday at 7 pm.
It will be a good dress rehearsal.
- For what?
Your meeting with Diana.
Has anything special
happened lately?
No, dad, what should that be?
Dad?
- Yes...
Does one have to wear gloves
to be correctly dressed today?
No, that isn't necessary
to be correctly dressed today.
Unless you want some nice accessories
for your spring suit.
Have a nice day, dad.
But, dad...
- Yes?
What does one do if one doesn't
want the guests to arrive in jeans?
Come on! Who leads the way to
the table? The man or the woman?
What?
- The man or the woman?
When the waiter shows you
to the table, -
the woman shall follow him,
and the man go after her.
Who shall sit where in a restaurant
if two seats are mounted on the wall?
You're burning me!
- With one chair across from them?
The woman shall have
the view of the room. Be careful!
We've invited guests to a restaurant.
What can we expect from the waiters?
A polite and in no way
condescending attention.
Get finished. Daddy's coming soon.
- I know. Let's receive him well.
Hello!
Hello...
Hi, Sigmund, are you here?
Good day, Mr. Simonsen. Did you
have a hard day at the office?
A bit. Where is Markus?
I brought a small...
Would you like a glass of water?
You look like
Little Lord Fauntleroy!
Maybe you're not thirsty?
- You look like a "snuffle"!
What's a "snuffle"?
- You... shut up!
You look like a...
Straighten out those curls,
you curly mouse!
Please don't call me
a mouse, daddy!
What?
- I thought you would like it.
Yes, you look nice. Very nice.
- Why did you call me a mouse?
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to...
- That wasn't very nice of you.
Especially not when we've
invited the girls out for dinner!
You have?
I'm no mouse!
- No, you're not a mouse.
I'm a mouse. I'm a...
"Snuffle"!
- Yes, I'm a "snuffle".
Look, Markus, here's 100 kroner.
You can treat...
100 kroner... the girls.
You can give the girls...
Good evening, ladies.
Where is Markus?
Here.
You look so grown up.
- Handsome. I didn't recognize you.
A simple dress
can be made prettier -
with the help of an elegant handbag
and a pair of nice shoes.
I got them for my birthday.
- Was your photo in the newspaper?
If so, people will take it as a sign
that she's accepting visitors.
Let's go in.
So, the House of Lords
are out enjoying themselves?
My name is Markus.
- Is it really?
Yes, I would like to stress that.
Markus.
I'll never forget it.
Do you have a room
where we may plan the meal?
No, we don't.
We'll have to discuss the menu
with the head waiter then.
This way, ladies.
Markus, that's my name.
Have you booked a table?
- Yes, for Simonsen Junior.
Oh, yes. Please...
My name is Markus!
- My name is Dahl.
Have you decided yet?
- What shall we choose, Markus?
I don't know.
What would you like?
You decide.
- We're not used to restaurant food.
Choose something
you know is nice.
Guests can't choose the food at home,
so why should they in a restaurant?
That's right.
So, Junior, what do you want?
Four Anchois Vinaigrette,
four Boeuf Bourgogne -
and four Soufflé d'Orange.
Would you repeat that?
Four Anchois Vinaigrette,
four Boeuf Bourgogne -
and four Soufflé d'Orange.
What's "boeuf"?
It's pronounced "buff".
It's a French meat stew.
I know that.
But I usually say boeuf.
Boeuf!
- My name is Markus!
Here's four Anchois Vinaigrette.
Is that what it is?
- Yes.
Lovely!
- You may have mine, too.
Yes, mine, too.
We want to save our appetite.
- Yes, for the boeuf.
Thank you.
- You lucky devil!
Boeuf Bourgogne.
May I have a glass of water?
Soufflé d'Orange, steaming hot.
The restaurant's pride and joy.
Excuse me...
Your name is Markus?
Your soufflé is getting cold.
- It doesn't matter. I don't want it.
Don't you like our soufflé?
I've invited guests to a restaurant.
What can I expect from the waiters?
I can expect to get polite and in
no way condescending attention.
The waiters' main task is
to make the guests comfortable!
The biggest mistake is to ignore the
guests or make them feel inferior.
And now I would like the bill,
if that's not too much trouble.
Yes, of course.
That was cool!
- He deserved it.
There are limits to
what I will put up with.
Here you are.
Excuse us for a moment.
You like the toilet!
1,950 kroner. I only have 500.
- I only have 100.
We have to call your dad.
No, I think it best
you call yours.
Yes, I thought as much.
Would you like to pay now?
- My dad will come and pay.
Would you like anything?
- No, thank you.
We'll just relax and dance.
What's that dance called?
- Markuska!
Thank you for the dance.
- Don't you want to dance any more?
I can't dance like you.
Nobody can.
The youngsters
have their own style.
Oh...
So, you're out enjoying yourselves?
- Thanks for the food, Mr. Simonsen.
It was really nice.
- I'm glad. They only just let me in.
Yes, your outfit isn't quite...
What have you done
to your nice curls?
I'm sorry.
I can't afford
another dinner like that.
We aren't millionaires.
- Yes, we are.
What?
- No. I mean no.
"I have dropped out of
"Money and Power".
I jump out a window and die
in episode number 78.
I quarrelled with the producer.
He treats me like an animal.
I've broken up with
Robert de Niro.
Right now I'm making
a commercial for mouthwash.
First I'm sad, then I gargle with
the mouthwash and get happy.
It's a fun part to play. I'll be
coming to Horten on the 12th..."
She's coming next week!
I refuse to meet her.
Dad and I are going to Copenhagen.
Make him go to Horten instead.
- I don't want to go to Horten.
You can't let her down now.
At least I won't have curls.
Do you play golf, Mr. Simonsen?
- Golf?
No, but it might be fun to try.
You should take a holiday
at Hotel Grand Ocean.
The best golf hotel in Norway.
- Oh, yes?
They have a green on the roof,
where you can practice your put.
Well, Markus and I are going
to Denmark to Tivoli.
I bet he would much rather
go to the Grand Ocean.
Would he?
Yes, if Sigmund can come.
- My parents said I could.
Where is this hotel?
- In Horten.
In Horten?
She's going to jump.
- No, Markus.
Things like that don't happen
in films. Only in real life.
Do you want to bet, Mr. Simonsen?
- Bet?
If she jumps, we go to Horten.
If not, you go to Denmark. Okay?
Okay.
Now I'm Diana, you're yourself.
What do you say?
Hello.
- Oh, hello. Who are you?
And...
I can't do this, Sigmund.
- Rubbish. Who are you?
Hello.
- Stop saying hello. Who are you?
Markus Simonsen Junior.
Hello, boys.
Do you know who is in Horten?
Diana Mortensen!
And she's having dinner
at this hotel.
I've booked a table for us, too.
What do you say to that?
If you're lucky, maybe you'll
get her autograph, Markus.
That would really be something.
It was this big!
I think fly-fishing is great.
I'm no specialist.
I don't know -
how many times the fly has
got stuck in a tree behind me, -
but it's a lot of fun.
Yes, I can see that.
- We'll try it one day, Markus.
What?
- Fly-fishing.
Does that taste good?
Fly-fishing doesn't mean
we'll fish flies. It means...
It's so nice to be back.
That's Diana Mortensen!
- Yes, we know.
Give us a nice smile, Diana!
Hello, baby.
Haven't you had enough now?
- No, give us a bit more.
Okay, boys. That's enough.
Yes, it's quite a lot of fun,
isn't it?
To bother those who can't defend
themselves. I bet you enjoy that.
But the party is over now!
Can't you see
that she's a human being?
But I don't suppose
you know what that means.
You all think she's a doll
you can treat as you like.
What a fantastic PR stunt, Diana.
Just shoot. We're not afraid of you.
You haven't caught us.
We don't give a shit about you.
You're just some lousy...
Mice!
You're so cute.
What's your name?
- My name is Markus!
Markus Simonsen,
that's my name.
Are you Markus? Markus Junior.
I know how long a tennis ball is.
Hello, everybody,
come and say hello to Markus!
Would you like to sit with us?
No, I have to go to my dad.
- Is your dad here?
Yes, he's sitting over there.
What on earth did you do?
I said hello to Diana Mortensen.
- Do you know her?
A little.
She wants to raise her glass
to you, Mr. Simonsen.
Why does she want to do that?
She probably thinks you look nice.
You have to raise your glass,
otherwise you're rude.
What shall I do?
- I'll fix this.
Thanks. Put it on room 312.
- I'll do that.
Thank you for coming...
Yes.
I'm Markus' father.
- I'm so glad we finally meet.
Yes... sure.
He's the silent type.
I'm also a bit silent.
What did you say?
Markus would like to meet you.
- It didn't seem like it.
He just doesn't like publicity.
He's a bit eccentric.
Where does he want to meet me?
- In room 314.
Tell him I'd like to come.
I was wondering...
May I... please... have...
...your autograph?
But why didn't you just write
who you were?
Because...
Because I'm much better
at not being me.
I hope you are, too, Mr. Simonsen.
- What do you mean?
And don't call me Mr. Simonsen!
She's coming here in half an hour.
- What?
She wants to see you, Markus.
- But I'm not Markus, I'm Mons!
Are you a coward?
- Yes!
Just go out and enjoy yourself!
I'm not going to enjoy myself.
I'm going to play golf in my room!
One... two...
...three...
Markus?
- Yes?
I just wanted to wish you luck.
- I thought so.
Was it you who...
- Yes, I fixed a meeting.
Get lost!
What?
I want to be alone.
Don't you want me to stay
and support you?
No, sometimes a boy's got to do
what a boy's got to do.
Hi. Isn't your dad here?
No, it's just me.
Oh, but I thought...
- I have a letter for you.
From Markus?
I'll read it to you.
"I'm Markus. Markus Simonsen.
I've written all those letters.
Everything is a lie.
My dad is no millionaire,
and I'm no millionaire son.
Everybody calls me Mousy,
because I'm so scared.
I'm scared of everything.
The only thing I'm not scared of,
is not being myself.
That's really easy, but I'm not sure
everything should be so easy.
I'd like to try something
a bit difficult, too.
The most difficult thing I know,
is to be Markus.
I'm sorry I lied to you,
but I'm not completely sorry.
Because if I hadn't done it, -
I wouldn't have discovered
that I didn't really want to lie.
Best regards from
Markus Simonsen... myself."
Look, there's Sirius.
What?
- Sirius eight years ago.
That's how long it takes
the light to reach Earth.
I wish I was there now.
- Where?
On Sirius... eight years ago.
How was I?
- What?
Did my tears seem real?
I had to practice crying a lot.
You wish you were there, too,
don't you?
But that's not Sirius we see.
It's just something
that doesn't exist any longer.
My name isn't even Diana.
My name is Mette.
Yes, I thought so.
Do they really call you Mousy?
- Yes...
Do you know what they called me?
- No.
They called me Mette Mouse.
- Mette Mouse!
And I'm a really bad actress.
- Me too.
I didn't leave "Money and Power".
They sacked me.
The only job I could get was
the commercial for mouthwash.
Mouthwash can be useful, if you
have a foul breath. But you don't!
They had to withdraw the commercial.
Sales went down 30%.
And I never met Robert de Niro.
- Not me neither.
When are you going back?
- I'm not.
I'm staying here in Horten.
I'll say that I'm retiring because
I'm fed up with the jet set life.
Will they believe that?
- They believe I'm a star here.
You are a star.
- No, I'm not.
Yes, you are.
You are Sirius!
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
E N J O Y   this   SRT   SUBTITLE   R e l e a s e
http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0129225
Markus Og Diana - Markus And Diana (1996) Norsk.srt
FPS: 25.000
With special thanks to: "Finn & Mikkel"
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
We want more subtitles right NOW!
1) ALL DVD's to be subtitled.
2) ALL VIDEO GAMES to be subtitled.
3) ALL videos/DVD's used in lessons at school to be subtitled.
4) More pre-recorded & live subtitles on TV.
____           __            ___   __              ___        __               __
/     /   _   /    )  _   _ (_     /  _)        _  (_      _   /  _)        _   / _   _
(     /)  (-   /(_ /  (-  ( /  /     /(_)  () (/ _)   /   () /    /(_)  () (/ _)   (__)  /  () (/  /)
- Bringing you free subtitles       /                  Online  /  Since 1993    - /
-
Africa
Asia
Australia
Europe
North America
South America
-  /
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+
+                          A big Thank You to EVERYBODY                            +
+        involved in making [closed capture] srt files and supporting us       +
+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+-+