A MIKA KAURISMÄKI FILM
SIRKKA'S DINER
MASTER CHENG
TODAY IS SAUSAGE DAY!
Hi! Come on in.
You want something? Coffee?
I look Fongtron.
Fong what?
- Fongtron.
Fongtron? I don't know Fongtron.
Coffee? Tea?
- Yes.
A Coke for the boy?
- Yes. - No!
Two tea.
Just a moment.
Thank you.
- Fongtron?
Yes, Mister Fongtron.
Sorry, no Chinese people here.
Levi.
- Levi?
There are Chinese people...
Japanese and Chinese are there.
But no Fongtron?
- I don't know.
You know Mister Fongtron?
- Fon...
Fongtron.
No.
You know Mister Fongtron?
Drink it.
Hi.
- Jello!
Why don't you fix me a plate?
Is there room at your table?
- As always.
Here you go.
- Thank you.
I look Fongtron.
Do you know Fongtron?
Fong?
- ...tron.
Fongtron.
What does he want?
- I don't know.
He asked me the same thing.
Sirkka!
I think this guy wants to know
something.
He's looking for somebody. I think.
Mister Fongtron.
- Fongtron...
Pohopoki.
- Pohopoki?
That's Levi, right?
- Yes.
What's that?
Pohjanjoki.
- That's right.
It's Pohjanjoki!
Pojopoki?
- Pohjanjoki. Pohjanjoki.
Pohjanjoki. Fongtron?
- No, no.
No here live. No live here.
- No, we don't know.
No, no.
- But Pohjanjoki...
I thank you.
Pohjanjoki.
- Pojopoki.
- Pohjanjoki?
Pohjanjoki.
- Hongajoki?
You're finished?
I'll take the buffet away.
You want something?
Food? You're hungry?
- Oh.
You hungry, Niu Niu?
Yeah? Mashed potatoes.
Sausage sauce.
- Okay.
Two?
- Yes.
Vegetable?
Here you go.
Finnish vegetable: sausage.
Eat.
Enjoy your meal.
Good appetite.
Good day. Good day.
- Yes.
Okay, don't eat it then.
I'll lock now. Closed. Closed.
Oh.
Poyopoki any hotel?
- No, only in Levi.
Forty kilometers.
- Okay.
Let's go. Take your bag.
I know a room.
Not a hotel. Room. Okay?
Okay. Okay.
Let's go.
You take this bed,
and I take that bed.
Let's unpack our suitcase.
Niu Niu?
Can you stop playing a moment?
Come here.
Make your bed.
Here you go.
- Thank you.
Wow, that's big.
Take this.
I'll eat at the diner.
Niu Niu.
Can you stop playing
with your phone?
What else is there to do here?
It was gravel,
and it was an island.
Every hole we drilled,
we got salt water.
That's right.
You won't find water in gravel.
Howdy.
- Hi.
I drilled seven holes
before they said it's enough.
They won't find drinking water there.
- No, not in the gravel.
The deepest hole I've drilled
is over 200 meters.
Then I found water. A lot of it.
I'm sorry. Can you help?
Ask Fongtron.
Guys.
There's this foreigner
who's asking me to ask you -
if you know
a person named Fongtron.
Never heard.
- Fong what?
Fongtron? Isn't it that company?
They make pressure vessels
in Tampere.
Pressure vessels?
- Yeah, the company is in Tampere.
It makes pressure vessels
in Tampere.
Makes pressure things in Tampere.
I'm sorry.
Your CRP level is 600,
so the infection is severe.
Your hemoglobin is low.
Your sed rate is high.
I have to up your dosage.
Right. Goodbye.
Did the alternator belt snap?
- No, the cooler. The light is on.
Is it leaking?
- Yeah.
I have to call the repair shop.
Hi.
- Hello.
Are they hungry? We have food.
Tourists are usually picky.
But you can go ask them.
Where are they from?
- China.
So how is the food here?
- It's good.
So, I have this nakki. Sausage.
And potatoes. Soft potatoes.
Mashed potatoes.
And then raastepöytä.
You have no sushi? Sushi?
It seems they don't like it.
You just have this?
No, I don't have sushi.
I only have
this potato and sausage -
and that raaste...
I'm sorry.
They only have sausages and
mashed potatoes. - I can help.
Hello everyone. I'm Cheng.
Nice to meet you.
I'm their tourist guide.
Basically,
they only have this food here,
but if you want to have
Chinese food,
I can cook you noodles.
How about chicken noodles?
Please take a seat.
And noodles.
You take ten. Ten packs.
Noodles? Noodles.
You have chicken?
- Yes, here.
We take all.
What did he say?
- He'll take it all.
Put everything on my account.
- Sure.
I'll pay you as soon as I can.
- I know you will.
That looks slimy and awful.
- It could be delicious.
I doubt it.
A white heterosexual man
won't eat that.
Are you a white heterosexual man?
- Don't you start with me.
Oh shit.
- What?
The amount of pills
just keeps growing.
I'll stay young and healthy.
- Right.
Well, well.
Look who's talking.
The food's delicious.
I'll tell my colleagues
about your place. - Thank you.
80, 90.
310.
320, 330, 340.
350.
Today was the best day ever.
Best day ever.
Good business.
Hey, thanks a lot. Thank you.
Oh. Thank you very much.
No need. No need.
- You work hard. This is yours.
No. I cook, you happy.
The Chinese people happy.
Everybody happy.
You're a cook?
- Yes, professional.
Restaurant in Shanghai.
A good one.
- Must be.
I'm Cheng.
- Sirkka.
Srikka?
Sirkka. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you.
We clean?
I do it. I do it.
- We can. We can.
Everything okay with your son?
Yes.
- He looks lonely.
Hey, come. Come.
You need to do something.
- I'm not a sportsman.
Go and play with your son.
No.
I'm paying back part of my debt.
750.
- Wow.
Come on. What's going on?
You're not kicking.
Again, harder.
Come on.
Not bad. Again.
Niu Niu.
Turn the lights off.
You turn them off.
Turn the volume down.
- Okay.
I'm looking for the number
of a company called Fongtron.
In Tampere.
Yeah.
No, Fongtron.
Oh, okay.
That's okay. Thanks.
Today I cook.
You? Why?
- The tourists come back.
Really? How do you know?
- I asked them.
You're a good businessman.
- Just a cook.
But I need some more materials.
Salad, vegetables, chicken.
You have in shop?
- No, nothing left from yesterday.
They only come once a week.
Only in Levi. Thirty minutes.
Let's go.
Look.
Reindeer.
Look. Niu Niu, take a photo.
They're delicious.
You eat them?
- Yeah, of course.
Look, there's a Chinese restaurant.
- Yes.
Do you want to eat?
I can check it out for you if you want?
- Er...
Look.
Dad, come here.
Take it.
Me?
- Yes, your turn.
Okay.
Just cut it this way,
this way and then this.
- Okay.
People happy important.
Good food make happy.
Important.
- Yeah.
Happy.
That's important.
All the customers are gone?
- Yeah.
You're welcome back anytime.
Spread the word.
- I will. "Wooord."
Looks like you had a full house.
You have anything left for us?
- Sure.
Here you are.
- This looks exotic.
Sometimes
you have to try new things.
Tell me, does the name Fongtron
ring a bell?
A friend is looking for him.
- Sounds like a drug dealer.
Or a human smuggler.
- Who is this Fongtron?
Forget about it.
It just crossed my mind.
Fongtron. - Let's check
if there's an APB out on him.
All right.
Delicious.
- It sure is.
First you spit on the worm.
And then you throw it
in the water.
The water clean?
That's good.
I can cook a very delicious soup.
It can heal people.
Heal?
- Yes.
Chinese food can, sometimes.
Okay.
You wanna try?
Cheng.
- Yes?
You don't smuggle human?
I cook. Professional cook.
I guess you are.
Sorry?
- Nothing.
Cheng, if you cannot find Fongtron,
what do you do?
I will find him.
Fongtron is important.
Your room.
You can stay as long
as you want to.
Thank you.
Hey, it's eating!
It's biting!
- Niu Niu!
We're getting bites!
Come here.
It's coming up. Good!
It's a big one.
Jello.
- Hi.
According to the Shit Shoveling
Workers' Union, it's lunchtime.
What? Where's the grub?
Today we have perch soup
Chinese style.
Are you seriously suggesting -
that a handsome
heterosexual Finnish man like me -
would voluntarily eat Chinese food?
I can warm mashed potatoes
and sausages for you.
Is that real perch?
Finnish perch?
- From our lake.
Because my motto is
"Live dangerously,"
give me a portion of
that Chinese perch soup.
So, that's it, huh?
- It's hot.
The chef said the soup can heal.
Heal what?
You'll become
more and more hetero each day.
Be quiet.
This is delicious.
Really delicious.
Huh?
- Yes, this is really delicious.
Niu Niu.
Stop playing and come help me.
Get up and get in there.
I want my phone back.
Everything okay?
Something to eat?
- No. Go home.
Sirkka's Diner, Sirkka speaking.
Yes.
Listen. Can you write me a menu?
We can get more tourists coming.
The tourist guide has spoken
to his boss.
Menu?
- Lunch.
Everything Chinese?
We make a deal.
You help me cook,
and I help you find Fongtron.
Okay.
We'll find Fongtron
in a haystack if we have to.
Fongtron in a hashtag?
Sirkka. Where is Niu Niu?
Went home.
Niu Niu.
Niu Niu!
We have to call the police.
It's him.
I found him in the hills.
I was looking for blueberries,
and he was there.
What's wrong with you?
Where have you been?
He was in the woods.
It's great that
Romppainen found him.
Does it hurt?
Come.
I wonder what he's all about.
And who is Fongtron?
I have no clue.
I wonder if he even exists.
And is the boy his son?
Where's the boy's mother?
I haven't asked.
Shouldn't you?
I'm sorry. I've been selfish.
I wanna go home.
Mom must be waiting for us.
Mom isn't waiting at home.
You have to believe me.
Mom is here with us, here.
We have to stay strong.
Okay, let's sleep.
Where are we going?
- This way.
I didn't know
there was so much space.
Yes. We look so tiny
in this huge space.
What are you doing?
What's that?
Your mom and I bought these
when we got engaged.
Good.
Now we've given them
to Mom.
Mom's not here.
Don't cry.
True.
Mom's not there,
but Mom stays inside your heart.
Okay?
Cheng.
Ni hao.
- Ni hao.
A hockey player named Jani.
- A hockey player named Jani?
Nine letters for a hockey player
named Jani. - Forsström.
Forsström? Nailed it.
Yes! Fongtron. Fongtron.
Fongtron.
Listen.
Could Forsström be Fongtron?
Fongzon.
- Forsström.
Yes! Pohopoki, Fongtron.
Cheng.
I have bad news for you.
I have some bad news for you.
He like my food.
He come to my restaurant
every day and order the fish soup.
I can believe that.
And he help me when I'm in trouble.
What kind of trouble?
Very big trouble.
I just know he live in Finland.
Po... Po...
- Pohjanjoki.
Now I have all my money.
I want to pay Fongtron back,
and I want to cook for him.
And he can feel happy again.
But now he's dead.
Cheng must be a man of honor.
Damn, he was looking
for Pekka Forsström,
and we didn't realize it.
I guess Cheng doesn't know
what he's going to do now.
I guess not.
He sure knows how to make soup.
- He sure does.
Romppainen looks
like he's come back from the dead.
Romppainen?
- Yeah.
What?
- And he's not the only one.
Dad, let's go inside!
It's great news
you're coming back home.
Dad is already packing the suitcases,
and we'll leave soon.
I can't wait to see you.
Somebody's coming,
I'll call you later.
Yes?
- Cheng.
You can't leave.
- Why?
We need your Chinese kitchen.
What?
- You can stay here and work here.
People like your food.
Romppainen likes really much,
and he's sick.
Yes, I know.
I can see it.
And I learn, yes.
You must teach me
how to make your Chinese soup.
No work paper.
- Your boy will like it here.
He doesn't like it.
That's because
he doesn't have any friends yet.
Only a stubborn man.
Goodbye.
Thank you. I'm sorry.
Crazy?
Maybe.
Sirkka.
Yeah?
We decided to stay a little longer.
CHAINASE WEEK
1. FRIED PLANTS 2. HERB RAIN DEAR
So this is what you have today?
Dim sum, herb reindeer
and fried vegetables.
Are there vegetables in the reindeer?
- Some.
Mashed potatoes and sausages then.
- We only have this.
Jello!
Do you have soup?
Cheng said the reindeer has
the same effect as the soup.
I'll have the herb rain, dear.
- There's pizza at the gas station.
That's a 16-kilometer drive.
I'll live dangerously
and risk it to eat foreign food.
If I die, I'm leaving my reindeers to you.
- You don't have reindeers.
I do have rain, dear.
I'll also have the herb rain, dear.
Goddammit.
This is the best "rain dear" ever.
This is pretty much
what rabbits eat.
C'mon, grown man.
All right.
We're here as I promised.
Cheng. It's the local school.
We heard that you serve Asian food.
- Yes.
But my pupils are not familiar
with Asian food.
Okay. Noodle soup very quick.
Is it okay?
- Yes.
Of course.
Excuse me, I have a question.
- Yes.
Some of my students have
special diets, you see.
Some are allergic to milk.
Some to gluten.
Some come from vegetarian families.
Okay. Understand.
Rice noodles, no gluten.
Chinese cooking, no milk.
And there are
many, many vegetables.
I think they will like it.
- Oh. Thank you.
Come.
- Children, follow me.
Don't touch anything.
Behave. No horseplay.
Tommi, don't touch anything!
Sirkka.
- Yes?
Can you help me cut
the Chinese cabbage?
Make it fine. It can help cook faster.
- Okay.
Okay.
Chinese cooking is based on
very old tradition.
Balance everywhere.
In color, taste, when serving.
And in the effect.
Effect?
- Yes.
For example, in winter,
we make more warming food.
And in the summer,
we make more cooling food.
For the active person,
we make more calming food.
And for the lazy person,
we make more active food.
And even for man and woman,
we can make different food -
for different effect. Just depends
what effect you want.
I know. It's like yin and yang.
Like love and sorrow.
Like sweet and sour.
Exactly. Now you know everything
about Chinese cooking.
How do you like it?
- It's delicious.
Good.
Well, what do you think?
- This is really good.
You still have the Asian chef?
Is he working here?
Er... I didn't actually hire him.
He's a trainee.
So he's not getting paid.
Judging by the taste,
he's no trainee.
He has potential.
His name is Fongtron?
- No. It was a misunderstanding.
A misunderstanding?
- Yeah.
I smell something.
- Yeah, smells delicious.
You wanna go with them?
I can give you a bike.
- No.
You're sure?
- Yeah.
Why?
Dad won't let me.
- I don't know. Ask him.
Cheng.
- Yes?
Why don't you let Niu Niu
ride a bicycle?
What?
- You heard me.
None of your business.
- None of my business?
No.
Okay. No need to get offended.
You okay?
Yes...
Every month.
You have child?
- No.
Many blood come out?
- Yes.
Better not.
Cold thing not good for you.
Warm thing better. I make.
Eat slow. Chewing makes
your stomach like it.
Food good medicine.
This sugar, cold thing
make pain for you.
CHINESE WEEK
Hello!
Finally! I didn't think
I'd be getting any customers today.
You're getting customers.
They're from
the assisted living facility.
I told them to come in.
They serve rubbery potatoes
at the facility.
What would you like?
- I hear the "rain dear" is good.
Herb reindeer for everybody?
Come on in. Welcome.
Sirkka, wait.
I know this sounds crazy,
but I think his food is healing.
I don't think it sounds crazy.
I'll only eat Chinese from now on.
That's for sure.
Me too.
Thanks.
It looks good. Thank you.
This is bah-kut-teh.
Bah-kut-teh?
- Bah-kut-teh.
Reindeer ribs tea.
Reindeer.
- Leindeel.
- Leindeel ribs soup.
We steam the leindeel and herbs.
- Herbs?
This is the best tea I've ever had.
Chew well.
Your stomach feel good.
Chew hard.
Chew well.
Chew hald.
- Chew hard.
Chew hard.
- Yes, chew hard.
- Hard, hard.
Chew well, everybody!
And tomorrow:
sweet and sour mandarin fish.
Is it good fish?
- Like fish.
This is one heck of a guy.
First he makes herb "rain dear"
and then "like fish".
Let's give a big hand to our chef.
Master Cheng!
This is damn good.
- This is the best.
Niu Niu!
Niu Niu.
Who gave you the bike?
You mustn't take anybody's bike.
This is mine.
She bought you the bike?
Why you buy him a bicycle?
He wanted a bicycle.
You don't let me pay anything.
- It's too much.
No, it's nothing.
You work here all the time.
The house is more full every day.
Niu Niu does not want a bicycle.
Well, yes, he does.
His mother die with bicycle.
Cheng, I...
I'm sorry.
Wait.
You don't want a bicycle.
He wants a bicycle.
Oh my God.
- What happened?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
- I'm so sorry.
Does it hurt?
- A little bit.
Okay.
Painful?
That's it. We're done.
Okay. No worries.
Okay, now...
Okay. Just press it.
I think he needs a little rest now.
Lay down and rest.
If he doesn't vomit for a while,
he's okay.
Okay. You're a good doctor.
No, I'm not. I just pretend.
You want some tea?
- Yes, please.
Still hurts?
Oh, no, no, no.
What?
- No boiling water.
Eighty degrees is good.
Do you want me to do it again?
You Chinese people.
You're crazy.
Drink it.
I think he's okay.
Do you use it?
I'm trying to learn.
May I ask...
...personal?
Yeah.
Do you have a man?
I had.
In south.
A marriage.
We tried to have a child, but...
...it didn't happen.
I couldn't get pregnant.
Eight long years.
Maybe I didn't eat enough Chinese.
- Yes.
Then what happened?
You still married?
- No.
He found another woman.
And left and...
...had a child.
It was a...
I was very depressed,
and then my aunt died.
She didn't have any children,
so I inherited this place
and the restaurant.
I remembered how happy I was -
when I used to visit
this place as a child.
Even though I knew
it wouldn't be a great business,
I thought, "What the hell?"
Why not give it a try, maybe.
Maybe I will be happy here.
So here I am.
Couldn't do no better.
Just don't look down to yourself.
It does not do any good.
That's true.
In China...
...women not usually live alone.
In Finland we do.
And there's a reason.
What is it?
Men are so stupid.
It was a joke. You can laugh.
And how can I find a man
here anyway?
Everybody's over sixty
or married or drunk or both.
Is it a joke?
No, that's the truth.
Sirkka!
- Yeah? Good morning.
Do you have...
I'm having stomach pain.
Who told you?
- Romppainen told me.
He gossips so much. A grown man.
Do you have the soup for me?
- Here it is.
Chew.
Chew? This is soup.
Believe me. Chew.
Cheng is a miracle man.
Vilppula's blood pressure is down.
Eki Raskavaara has
regular bowel movements,
and believe me,
he's never had that.
Tauno Teriö said his kidney stones
dissolved and came out with pee.
He said he saw crumbs in his pee.
How can food have that effect?
- It can.
Hope does wonders.
Stop.
Something I can help you with?
I heard you have medicine
for stomach pain.
Thanks.
This "like fish" is damn good.
- Yeah, it's damn good.
Good?
- Excellent. - Very good.
Listen.
Now we want you to do
something very Finnish.
Very Finnish.
Me?
- You.
Feels good.
You know, these are all made
by him, Vilppula. - Oh.
He's very famous in Helsinki.
Well, maybe not in Helsinki,
but in Rovaniemi anyway.
Maybe not in Rovaniemi,
but Pojopoki. - Pohopoki.
Pojopoki. He's very famous
in Pojopoki. Yes.
I'm not fish.
And I cannot swim also.
Pass here.
What?
- Go to the ball.
I'm the goalie.
- Good.
Good job! Good.
Do you have a wife?
Yes, but she's dead.
Oh.
Accident.
She ride a bicycle,
and then a big car come.
Bang.
- Oh.
She's dead.
- I'm sorry. So sorry.
After she die,
I work day and night.
And I have no time
to spend with my son.
Then -
I start to drink.
- Drink?
Yes. Very, very much.
And borrow money
from the bad people -
to run my restaurant.
And then Fongtron saved me.
He give me money -
so that I can pay back
the bad people.
And he always said that -
Finland is a good place.
"It's good for your boy."
So afterwards,
I sell my restaurant,
and then I come here
with my son.
And I want to pay Fongtron back
so badly.
But he's dead.
Fongtron was right.
Finland is good place
to you and your son.
But now we must go to sauna.
More?
Let's get down to business!
Karsk.
- Karsk.
Is the singer any good?
She can even get people
with two left feet dancing.
Niu Niu. Put the music on.
Okay. And then the position.
Yeah. Okay.
And then you start
with the left.
Okay? You remember?
One, two, three, four.
Slow, slow, quick, quick.
Slow. No. You need to hold me,
like, here, like, close.
Argh, you stubborn man.
Okay, now.
One, two, three, four.
Slow, slow, quick, quick.
Are you nervous?
- It is interesting.
No, no, no.
In Finland, we say what we think.
Don't be polite.
It just makes things complicated.
Okay? So...
You're nervous?
Yes or no?
- No.
I think you are too nervous.
And shy.
Close it.
Okay.
Good?
- Yes.
Good. That's how you do it.
You say what you think.
Look.
Okay, let's go.
- No, no, no! Not yet.
Hi. Two donuts
and a mineral water for him.
Sirkka.
- Yeah, sugar is bad for you.
Don't say anything.
Hi.
- Hi.
Thanks.
Let's go.
- Don't eat it all.
Quick, quick, slow, slow, slow.
Quick, quick...
- And?
What?
- Are you ready to go?
Let's go.
C'mon.
When the flaming sun goes down
And the woods fall into a trance
In the wind the treetops bow
Making the shadows
of the night dance
From the shadows of the earth
into space, flying free
Like a particle that blends
I'd fade into eternity
A particle that never ends
I hear something calling me
at night
A call so quiet and bittersweet
And the sigh
of the wind whispers oh so light
The longing is complete
If the wind gave me wings to fly
I'd leave
this darkening earth behind
I'd soar into the evening sky
Into the brightening starshine
Eighty degrees.
- Thank you.
Do you notice
that he's not sad anymore?
This is really a good place to be.
Near to paradise.
Well, we have our problems
like everybody else.
But you have everything.
Everything what?
Where are we going?
What do you hear?
Nothing.
- Exactly.
I live in Shanghai.
A big city.
You can hear
how quiet sounds here.
Sirkka. One thing.
Yeah?
It is easy for you to find
a handsome guy if you want.
Handsome men can be stupid.
Yes, I know.
- Do you?
Do you have a phone in your pocket?
- No. Why?
Help, help... I can't swim!
Oh my God. Wait! Wait!
Very clever! Very clever!
I didn't tell you I was a swimming
champion when I was young!
It's warm.
Think about it.
Four billion men in the world.
You can have many choice.
I can choose anyone I want.
- Sure.
I'll think about it.
I'm hungry.
Give me herb rain, dear.
We know that his visa expired.
These days,
we can see it digitally.
They're so strict about these things today.
- Very strict.
We're actually being flexible here.
Very flexible.
- I understand.
But the food was delicious,
as always. Thanks.
The law is the law.
There's nothing we can do.
I should have seen this coming
a long time ago.
It would be a big loss for you
if he had to leave.
A big loss for all of us.
I'm alive thanks to his food.
Seriously?
- Oh yes, indeed.
Maybe I'll throw in the towel
and close up.
This place won't be profitable
without Cheng. - You can cook.
I can't.
I'll just end up chopping
my fingers off into the soup.
What? What's going on?
Nothing.
- Yes, there is.
Papers.
Your papers.
I knew it.
So I must go.
So you're gonna go?
I'm sorry, Sirkka.
I thought you knew
I cannot stay forever.
So you're just gonna go?
I wanna pay you.
What? - I wanna pay for your work.
It's all here.
I told you. No need to pay.
Why are you doing this?
- Why I cook?
- I'm a cook.
You know what I'm talking about.
Did you think you can just come
here and cook and cook and -
walk away?
Sirkka.
Hi. Why don't you keep an eye
on the boy for a couple of hours?
She'll take care of him
for a few hours.
What?
- No questions.
We have some guy business here.
Get in, please. Ciao ciao!
Hi!
Good. Just go.
You want to kidnap me?
- Maybe, maybe.
Ni hao.
- Weigh the anchor!
"He raised his glass with a grin,
'Brothers, let the drinking begin.'"
Cheers.
- Cheers.
There's only one answer
Summer in Lapland
Please, have a small.
Cheng.
Your food.
- Yes?
Sometimes it can heal a person.
I mean if you are ill,
you can do better with the food.
Yes, but not always.
- I know.
I have this cancer.
And I know it will follow me
till the last day of my life.
But what your food gave to me
was hope.
You gave hope to me.
You gave hope to all of us.
You gave hope to Sirkka.
And I want to thank you for that.
Yeah.
Sometimes hope and health
are the same thing.
Exact... Exactly.
Now Sirkka is very sad.
She has no hope.
Oh, learn from the swans
They leave in the fall
and come back in spring
Our shores are
so peaceful and calm
And safe are the Lapland hills,
so nurturing
Rustling your wings
Soar through the air
Do important things
Bring the joy for which we yearn
When you see
winter has gone from here
I beg you
I ask you
Please return
So there's Vega.
In the south.
And then there's Milky Way.
And then there's Big Bear.
And Arcturus.
The brightest of all.
And Capella.
Her pink cheeks
Look just like the red sun
Her beautiful eyes
Just like the pure moon at night
I would leave everything I own
And follow her, my shepherd
To see her lovely smile
and pretty dress
I would love to be a lamb
And follow her
I wish she could hold a little lash
And whip me lightly
Morning.
- Good morning. Mama's birthday.
Niu Niu!
I'm sorry, Dad. I slept in.
No rush. Come here, Niu Niu.
I'm watching the clouds.
Look. Beautiful, isn't it?
When I was a little boy,
I dreamed -
there's another world
beyond those clouds.
Is Mom there?
Maybe.
Can Mom see us?
I think so.
Niu Niu, let's make some noise
so that she can hear us.
IN MEMORY
OF MY LOVING MOTHER
Look. It's Mom.
I can eat with sticks.
This is delicious.
This is better.
- Better than the rubbery potatoes.
You're having soup.
This is a fat man's soup.
Where is he?
- Fongtron?
No, the Chinese guy.
Never heard of him.
Outward.
You can flex your muscles a bit.
Bring your arms down.
He's so tai chi'd,
he can't stand up.
One more time. Here we go.
Turn your palms out.
Bring your arms down.
Good job. That's it.
Hi. We are in China now.
My dad and Sirkka
decided to get married.
We hope to see you soon.
Oh, dang!
Oh, Sirkka looks so pretty.
Will you marry me?
- Of course.
Happy wedding day to you
Happy wedding day,
dear Sirkka and Cheng
Happy wedding day to you
Hey! Hey!
Sirkka! Good wedding! Wedding!
Hi!
- We'll be back.
"We will be back," I said.
We will be back.
Willow bee...
- ...back. We'll be back.
Willow bee... hack.
- We'll be back.
We'll bee...
DIRECTED BY
MIKA KAURISMÄKI
WRITTEN BY
HANNU ORAVISTO
Translation from Finnish
by Aretta Vähälä
Proofread by Rich Lyons