Damn!
Shooting coal
Danny
- what in God's name are you doing?
- I got a shot set up back there.
Word's come down from Turley.
The tonnage rate?
They've brought it
down to 90 cent a ton.
Down!
Those dagos
are holding fast in No. 3.
He says, "Take it or leave it."
Sephus, what we going to do?
It was 1920 in the Southwest Field
and things were tough.
The miners were trying to
bring the union to West Virginia
and the coal operators and their
gun thugs were set on keeping them out.
They were hand-loading days.
They paid you by the ton
and they didn't care any more
for a man than they did for a draft mule.
They were hard people,
your coal miners then.
They weren't
anybody you wanted to cross.
So push come to shove, and pretty soon
we had us a war down there in Mingo County
which in those days
was known as "bloody Mingo".
And that's where it all
came to a head: there on Tug Fork
in the town of Matewan.
We did it. mama.
We're going to have the union.
I've just got to stop for a little
repairs. Sorry for the inconvenience.
They shifted
Italians in, right off the boat
so they're still
bringing coal out of there.
I'd sure hate to
get a whiff of that mine!
What the hell
are we stopping for?
Step down gentleman.
This here will be your new home.
How come,
we aren't getting off in town?
Just get in line.
I'm going to kill him!
Get on the train. Get on.
Come on, Bill.
Give me your hand, man.
Get out of here.
When do we get to Matewan?
You don't want to go there, mister.
It's nothing but crazy people.
Hi.
Everybody was here.
Then they got word and
they went on up the line a ways:
some kind of union business.
Yeah. I saw.
You'd best steer clear of it.
My name's Bridey Mae Tolliver.
uh  Joe Kenehan.
uh  Do you know
Radnor's Boarding House?
The big white house
right on, past the coal dock.
She's a real sourpuss, though
Elma Radnor.
Thank you.
Are you going to
be in town long?
That depends.
I'll see you around.
I hope so.
These picks and shovels
are to be considered a loan
from the
Stone Mountain Coal Company.
Their costs will be deducted
from your first month's pay.
Tool-sharpeners provided
by the Company are 25 cents a month.
Use of the wash house
is 75 cents a month.
The medical doctor provided
by the Company is 2 dollars a month
special procedures: extra.
Your train ride here provided
by the Company will be deducted
from your first month's pay.
Your pay will be
issued as Company script
redeemable for all goods
and services at the Stone Mountain
Company Store.
Purchases of any items
available at the Company Store
from outside merchants
will result in
firing without pay.
What's to keep you from
jacking up them prices at your store?
Name?
Johnson.
They call me 'Few Clothes'.
Powder, fuses, lamps, head gear
all appropriate clothing will be
available at the Company Store
and Stone Mountain
will generously advance you
a month's supply of these items
payment to be deducted.
I'm going to take you
over to camp now, where you'll be living.
There are some Italian gentlemen
that are very eager to meet you.
Rentals will be
for one room: $2.50 a month.
The Company rule:
no more than two people
to 1 room, children included.
Electricity,
where that is feasible
will be 1 dollar a month.
Mrs. Radnor?
Yes.
My name is Joe Kenehan.
I'm going to be in town for a bit
and your place here was recommended.
What do you do?
uh
I guess I'm looking for work.
Are you with the Company?
The Company?
If you aren't with the Company
there isn't any work.
Look mister.
Don't act the lamb with me.
- What's your business here?
- Mama
Mama, it's Hillard.
Those scabs did it,
up the line a mile.
They were all colored this time.
They busted his nose.
Have you got any ice?
There's some in the back.
Go and fetch me two chunks
about this big and a piece of rag.
Are you a doctor?
No but I've seen
my share of broken noses.
Just put it up in the air, buddy,
just like you're watching the clouds.
We'll get that bleeding stopped.
I ga my liggid
Say what?
He said, he's got his licks in.
It seems to be all
the men around here care about.
Wives and kids are starving, so
as long as they've got their licks in...
It's just frustration. That's all.
When you can't
take care of those you care about
I know. It isn't their fault.
Here you go.
This freezes up
all those little veins inside.
It's just so that they close up
and they don't let any more blood out.
Are you a doctor?
No.
I'm just a guy
looking for a place to stay.
5 dollars a week cash.
That includes
dinner and clean sheets.
I hope
I'm not making a mistake.
The name is Joe Kenehan.
Well, mostly I work for
the railroads, laying track.
Kansas, Missouri...
I went out west for a bit
and worked in a lumber camp
a little of whatever
pays an honest dollar.
I'm a coal miner.
At least
until we came out I was.
I had me over in Section 3...
I was a trapper boy.
Aren't you a little young?
I'm almost 15.
There are some in there
younger than me.
Of course with the strike now
I mostly work on running this place.
I help a little, don't I?
It's going to be a long one.
That superintendent
at Stone Mountain said
he'd go broke before
he let one union son of a bitch
so much as
step into his coal-mine.
- Danny
- Sorry, madam
but that's what he said.
Daniel is a preacher.
Is that so?
You ought to hear him testify.
What church are you with?
Well, around here
there's the missionary folks.
They're Hardshell Baptists.
And then there's the Free-Will folks
which is your Softshell Baptists.
Right now I preach for both.
I'll get it.
Daniel is going to preach
tonight over at the missionary.
I never was religious myself.
It's Sephus, mama.
Hello, Elma.
Mrs. Knightes...
Hello, Sephus.
I've come to have
a word with your new boarder
if he doesn't mind.
Excuse me.
He claims, he's
the fellow the union sent us.
Can you prove it?
It doesn't take anything
to have a card printed up.
I guess
you'll just have to trust me.
Who wrote The Iron Hill?
Jack London.
Where's Joe Hill buried?
All over the world.
They scattered his ashes.
Which eye
is Big Bill Hayward missing?
His right one.
How did Frank Little die?
Butte, Montana: they
hanged him from a railroad trestle.
You know your stuff!
- I was with the Wobbley's.
- Me too
back when it meant something.
One big union!
Not around here buddy.
C.E. Lively...
This is my restaurant.
Fellows are waiting.
They don't give a damn
whether we live or die
just as long as they
get the coal out of the ground.
They had us pulling pillars
and the roof was working
you know, like it does
before it's going to fall down.
If I say I'm not
dying in here, and walk away
they'll put me
down in some damn puddle
in a two foot seam
and no air to breathe.
A man can't mine coal that way.
They're just pushing us
further than we can go.
The check wayman, he'll take
50 pound off your load for slate
when there isn't a pebble in it.
It's down in the bottom, he'll say,
where there isn't any looking for it.
Then they raise the prices
at the Company store
the same God damned week
that they lower the tonnage rate
and they still haven't
rock-dusted that damned hole.
- Who am I talking about?
- Jesus!
- I can't hear you!
I still can't hear you!
Jesus Christ our Lord!
Do you know His name?
Hallelujah! Say, "Yes, Glory"!
Have you felt the warming
comfort of His precious love?
Praise Jesus!
Praise His holy name!
Praise His blessed spirit!
Praise His everlasting love!
Jesus Christ our Lord!
Listen to me now.
The Prince of Darkness
is upon the land.
Amen.
Now, in the Bible
his name is Beelzebub
Lord of the Flies.
Right now on earth today
his name is bolshevist!
socialist!, communist!, union man!
Lord of Untruth, Sower of Evil Seed!
Enemy of all
that is good and pure!
And this creature
walks among us.
Now, what are we
going to do about it?
The first thing
we've got to have
is all of these niggers
and all these dagos
that came in here
to take our jobs
thrown out of the mines.
Mines, hell!
They've got them in our houses!
They're sitting
at our tables right now
and they're sleeping in our beds
while we're out
living under a piece of canvas
at the back of the hollar.
I've been
a union man my whole life.
I know the story with these
coal operators and their gun thugs.
The only thing they understand
is the bad end of a bullet
and if we show them
we'd just as soon
blow up their damn mines
as see them
worked by a bunch of scabs
then they're going to listen.
Someone is coming.
It's Alex.  He's got someone.
Where did you find him?
He came
right up on the steps.
They told me that C.E. Lively's
is where the union men meet.
So?
I've got
business with the union.
Is that so?
What's your name, son?
They call me "Few Clothes".
I didn't come here
looking for any trouble.
A man's got to eat.
So why don't you go and eat
back where you came from?
They told me
that there were jobs here.
- Go home, nigger.
- God damned scab!
You watch
your mouth, Peckerwood.
I've been called, "nigger"
and I can't help it that
that's the way white folks are
but I've not ever
been called a scab
and I'm not
fixing to start up now.
I'll go ton for ton,
loading coal with any man here
and when I do, I expect
the same dollar for the same work.
You get out of this hollar alive son,
and you be doing good for yourself.
"Union men", my ass!
Do you want to
be treated like men?
be treated fairly?
Well, you aren't men
to that coal company.
You're equipment
like a shovel, a gondola car
and a hunk of wood brace.
They'll use you till you
wear out or you break down
or you're buried under a slate fall
and then they'll get a new one
and they don't care
what color it is or where it comes from.
It doesn't matter
how much coal you can load
or how long your family
has lived on this land.
If you stand alone
you're just so much
shit to those people.
Do you think
this man is your enemy?
huh?
This is a worker.
Any union that
keeps this man out isn't a union.
It's a God damned club!
Now they've got you
fighting white against colored
native against foreign,
hollar against hollar
when you know, there aren't
but two sides to this world:
those that work
and those that don't.
You work.
They don't.
That's all you've got to
know about the enemy.
You say, you've got guns.
Well I know that
you all are brave men
and I know you could shoot it out
with the company if you had to
but the coal company
don't want this union
and the state government
don't want it.
The federal government
And they're all of them just
waiting for an excuse to come down
and crush us to nothing.
Fellows, we're in
a hole full of coal gas here.
The tiniest spark at the wrong time
is going to be the end of us.
So we've got to pick away
at this situation, slow and careful.
We've got to
organize and build support.
We've got to work together.
Together!
Till they can't get their coal
out of the ground without us!
Because we're a union!
Because we're the workers damn it!
And we take care of each other!
How can we shut the mines down
if we don't dynamite them?
The men walk out
all of them...
Fat chance!
And every man that
walks out on his own steam
we take into the union.
All the dagos
and all the coloreds?
That's
what a union is, fellows.
You'd better get used to it.
So this fellow owns a vineyard.
He goes out first thing one morning
and he hires some workers.
He says he'll give them
a dollar for the day
which was decent
wages in biblical times.
Well, then
he's at the marketplace
and he sees some
other fellows and he hires them
and some more at noon
and some at 2 and some at 5
and every time, it's
the same deal: a dollar for the day.
And he's hiring all day long,
right up till 1 hour before quitting time.
Look. We're really
sorry to barge in on you like this
but it's come to a point
where we've got to talk to you.
Now I know you people have
got it hard, coming to a new country.
You don't know the rules.
You don't know how things work.
They don't know shit
about mining coal. That's for sure!
They've been dying
like flies in that No. 3 hole.
But how it is:
you don't have
a whole lot of choice in this thing.
Do you know
what a union is?
- Sindacato.
- "Sindacato"?
What the situation is
- we need every
- If we join the union
they'll shoot us.
If we don't join the union,
you'll shoot us.
Well, that's
one way of looking at it.
That dago's
just driving me crazy.
- Now what's he playing  - sh
Now who's that?
Peckerwood's gone past.
A union man
will be up in a few minutes.
What are we
talking to him for?
Do you want to
walk back to Alabama?
The sun goes down and he
sends for his foreman and he says to
go and pay off the workers
starting with the ones
he picked up just an hour ago
and to pay every one of them
the same dollar a day.
And of course
the fellows that went out first
are roped off about this
so they get to agitating
complaining so loud that
the owner comes up
and he says, "Look."
"We dealt for a dollar
and that's what you get"
"and what I pay anybody else
is none of your look-out. So there!"
Now that's
all the gospel story says
except for the moral
Jesus drew out of it.
And so Jesus says
"Thus it will be
in the kingdom of heaven."
"The first will be last
and the last will be first."
Now it's clear
from this parable
that Jesus hadn't
heard anything about the union.
If he was walking the earth today
and had seen the situation we've got
with these coal operators,
he would have changed his tune.
"A man deserveth
an hourly wage," he'd say
"for though the pit be gassy
and the face full of slate"
"a man still toileth
by the sweat of his brow"
"and wants
a better deal here on earth"
"no matter what I've got
in store for him in the hereafter."
Praise Jesus!
Kenehan
out kind of late, aren't you?
I met some people
and we got to talking.
Talking?
Yeah.
Who are you?
The name is Sid Hatfield.
I'm chief of police around here.
It isn't against the law
to talk, is it?
It depends.
I take care of my people.
You bring them trouble,
and you're a dead man.
Sleep tight, Kenehan.
Hi.
Well, look at this, Griggsy.
They've got up a little
reception committee for us.
What is your name, honey?
Bridey Mae Tolliver.
Do you like to watch
the trains come and go, Bridey Mae?
Yeah.
And the people
that come into town.
Have there been a lot of
new people coming here lately?
A few.
Did a fellow
named Joe Kenehan show up?
Maybe.
Are you married, Bridey Mae?
I was.
He got killed in the mine.
That's too bad.
Did you hear that, Griggsy?
He got killed in the mine.
It's a shame.
Was your husband
a union man while he was living?
No. He said, it wouldn't
ever take hold down here.
He sounds like a smart fellow.
I think that you are really pretty.
Do you know that, Bridey Mae?
Thank you.
Don't you think
she's pretty, Griggsy?
You are
the best looking mountain trash
I've seen in a long while.
We'll see you around.
Let's roll, Griggsy.
The sooner we get out of
this shit hole the better.
I was putting up blackberries
when Tremel Blankenship come
shouting up the hollar
that the No. 5 had blown.
I remember I took
the pot off the stovetop
and washed up my hands
before I went down.
It took 2 days
to dig through.
Then when they brought them up,
you couldn't tell which was which.
They found blood on the walls from
fellows trying to claw their way out.
Mrs. Elkins,
Mrs. Mounts, Bridey Mae, me
we all lost our men in that fire.
Danny was seven then.
Now he's
back in that same hole.
How did it start?
Coal dust gets hanging in the air
down there and there's a spark.
They could
spray the walls down
but the company says
that'd cost too much.
Hey. Was
was Sid Hatfield
ever a miner?
Not for long.  He doesn't
like to be closed in, Sid.
He's always
really friendly, smiling Sid.
Then the war came.
Cabell Testerman
got to be the mayor.
He made Sid, chief of police
and then the girl that Cabell married
Well
I don't want you using Danny
on any crazy union business.
A man has to stand up for
what he believes in.
Danny isn't any man.
Look, mister.
You're going to be moving on.
Win or lose, you're going to
walk on out of this hollar
and we've got to stay here.
I intend to
leave a union when I go.
My husband
used to talk union.
I saw where it got him.
Mama!  People out the front, mama.
Sorry, mister. We're full up.
Not any more,
you're not, sonny.
Stone Mountain
sent us down here.
We're still full up.
Can I help you gentleman?
These two are trying to
push their way in here.
I told them
there wasn't any use.
I don't see where you've got
any say in the matter.
If my mama says you can't stay here
then you can't, that's all.
Danny
Keep out of this.
Look. I've only got
one room left.
Well then, somebody is
going to have to move, aren't they?
Let me see your register.
You aren't seeing anything.
Lady, we're here as guests of
the Stone Mountain Coal Company.
They own this house.
Good morning.
Are you fellows moving in?
- Yeah.  - No.
Well, you won't find a better
night's sleep anywhere else in town.
It's a shame I've got to move
over to the hotel. It's business, you know.
So would you mind if
I settle my bill, madam?
Danny, you sign
these two gentleman in.
Don't think the Company
isn't going to hear about this!
Boy, sometimes you've got to
bend so that you don't break.
The food's awful at the hotel.
The mattresses have got lumps
probably cooties, too.
I'll be all right.
I'll get my things.
Thank you.
Now, if you want to
stay alive down here
you've got to listen up,
get a hold of something solid
and give the top
a little poke.
Now, if you get a nice
ringing sound, you're all set.
You've got a nice
solid top over your head.
You get
a kind of hollow sound
like a drum:
that's slate sagging a bit
and you've
got to put in another post.
Have you dug coal a long time?
Since I was 10. And you?
We make a shoe. Everybody
in the same fabricca  in Milano
make a shoe.
Shoes.
You make-a shoes.
As soon as they get that union
they'll send us back.
It could be
but you try and
head out of here now
and you'll be owing
all that money. Like they say
The company will
shoot you for a thief.
We're just some slaves up here.
They own our black asses.
Gentleman...
Hey, Few.
I've got a question for you.
Yes?
Now suppose they let us
in this union, like they say.
Are we going to have to
work with those Italian people?
Come on, babies.
Come on and get it now. Come on.
Come on now.
Oh, boy.
All right.
Taking a walk?
Hi.
I'm going up to the coal camp
to meet those new fellows
when they come off their shift.
You're doing
union business, aren't you?
How do you like Mrs. Radnor's?
Well there wasn't room.
I'm at the hotel now.
Isn't she a sourpuss though?
Mr. Kenehan
They're evicting
in town, Mr. Kenehan.
It's Baldwin.
It's those Baldwin thugs.
This is town property.
Who are you?
I'm the mayor.
Well, pleased to meet you!
My name is Bill Hickey.
This is Tom Griggs.
We're carrying out
an eviction for Stone Mountain.
You can do what you want
up at the coal camp
but this is town property.
Stone Mountain holds
the deeds on these houses, Cabell.
You need a writ for an eviction.
Are you the law around here?
Well, good!
Then you can help us.
Now these people are
trespassing on Company property.
They all signed a contract
that they wouldn't join any union.
Are you...
are you
Baldwin-Felts Agency?
That's right
presently employed by
the Stone Mountain Coal Company.
This is from Mr. Turley here
and this is from our boss
Mr. Thomas Felts.
I've met Mr. Felts.
Well, good!
We won't have any problem.
I wouldn't pee on him
if his heart was on fire.
Neither of these
will do for a writ.
You'll have to
see a judge in Charleston.
What if we haven't
got time to go to Charleston?
Then you'd better find some.
Now I can't do anything about
what you pull outside town limits
but you bother these people
under my jurisdiction
and I'll put you under arrest.
Yeah?
You and whose army?
All you men who own a gun
go home and get it.
You're deputies as of now.
The rest of you people,
stick close.
We'll need witnesses.
I'm giving you 10 minutes
to get those people's belongings
back in the house.
If the rest of the boys were here
you wouldn't be so cocky.
If the rest of the boys were here,
I'd give you 5 minutes.
Now move it.
You can't win, you know.
This is going to
happen with you or without you.
You can't stop it.
All right boys.
Let's put it back in.
This isn't our day!
That a boy, Sid!
I've never seen a law man
buck a company gun before.
He's mostly
a really nice fellow, is Sid.
I may be mayor of the town
but I'm going to be mayor of a cemetery.
Contention
makes him nervous, though.
We've got
a motion on the floor here
and this is coal miners only.
All those in favor of
keeping those scabs out of the mines
tomorrow morning, using whatever
force it looks like is necessary
raise your hands.
It's settled then.
Pass those peas, boy.
Pass the peas, Danny.
Is your boy
deaf or dumb or what?
Daniel isn't dumb.
Daniel's a preacher.
Is that right, boy?
Are you a preacher?
What do you
preach to, boy? Squirrels?
Daniel preached
at the meeting last night.
It was
a good number of souls there.
Are you a soul-saver, boy?
You want to have a go at me and Griggsy here.
We ought to be be a real challenge.
He's a squirrel preacher, is what
stands up
on a stump out in the woods and
testifies to the holy rodent.
Danny
are you in a hurry to
meet your maker, boy?
There aren't
any guns allowed at table.
You sit down, Danny.
You do what
your pretty mama says, preacher.
You put that away now, mister.
Pack it away, Griggsy.
Look.
We're going to be
here a while, little lady.
You can have it
the easy way or the hard way.
Now, how about those peas?
The boy's getting on my nerves.
Oh Lord.
They told me
they would talk to the fellows.
I saw
their faces last night, Joe.
They weren't buying it.
We're playing
right into the company's plans.
The men voted, Joe.
What more do you want?
I've seen
the lights on the hill.
They're sneaking them in
for a night shift.
Let's go, fellows.
Keller told me,
you're sent from the union.
uh-huh
I bet you've seen
hundreds of strikes.
Yeah.
I got thrown clear out of
the missionary the other night
talking the union
from the pulpit.
Are we getting close?
Up there...
They're down the hill.
Over here...
When our fellows
put their lanterns out
you just hit the dirt.
I think, this belongs to you.
I'm with him.
All of you union men
let's welcome our new brothers.
From now on
Stone Mountain doesn't
move one piece of coal
unless it's
a union man that moves it.
Let's get out of here.
Glad you could join us!
In those days the coal company
owned your camp houses.
They owned your land.
They owned most of the town
and the people who ran it.
If you weren't for the company
there weren't too many places
you could go that were still on the map.
The union didn't have too much
they could
give to the people back then.
"All we've got
in common is our misery"
Joe Kenehan used to say
"and the least
we can do is, share it."
She's got
the evil eye, that one.
Oh, mama.
Don't you let me
catch you peeking over there.
She's got the evil eye
if I've ever seen it.
Well, what have we got here?
We've brought you some food.
Mama stole it from the company.
Quiet, Danny.
Well, we can use
everything you've got.
You people are crazy! You aren't
ever going to win this thing.
Then what are you helping us for?
I've got work to do.
We appreciate your help.
I've not ever seen
everybody all together like this.
The company doesn't stand a chance.
Jessie
what's the pitch?
Well I was just
saying to the mayor here how
we're all trying to do our jobs
you, and me and him
and nobody is paying us enough
to be dodging any bullets for it.
um  Now
Mr. Felts
has authorized me to
make it more attractive
for you gentleman to cooperate.
The town isn't for sale, mister.
What about you?
Now, I figured that
little show you were putting on
out there the other day was
just for bargaining power.
Or are you
going to be stupid, too?
If either of you shit hogs
lift a finger in town limits
I'll put you away.
Damn hillbillies! They've
always got to do it the hard way.
You boys
are going up against some
pretty big people.
Don't push your luck.
How's Jessie these days?
Oh she's OK, Sid.
Do you think, they're bluffing?
No.
Neither am I.
Now, the way the relief fund works
is kind of tricky
because with all the different situations
we've got going around the country
we're stretched really thin.
There's a lot of strategy
to who gets what and when.
I report to the strike committee.
They evaluate
the progress we're making here
and the political situation
and then they release
the strike fund to us.
Do you mean, they'd cut us off?
No. The amount we get is based on
What if they
think we're going to lose?
Look. The strike committee
considers what's best
for the union as a whole
but that doesn't mean
Politics, boys!
If you're going to play union,
you've got to play politics.
I'm sure Joe doesn't like that
any more than you do.
I don't like it one damn bit.
Me either. I didn't
get into this thing so that I could have
one more boss
to tell me what to do.
The union isn't your boss. It's you.
Then why have we got to wait
for some hunkies up in Pittsburgh
to give us the word to move?
Because it's a democracy.
It's like the United States:
a democracy.
That's a joke.
Quiet.
Get down. They're shooting.
Just keep your head down, son.
They're going to make a night of it.
Sarah, you come over here.
I think you've just got
a little piece of bullet left in there.
The company doctor
said he wouldn't come out
but there's a fellow
in Pikeville on the Kentucky side
that'll treat union men on the sly.
He'll be here by noon.
Will he treat colored?
If he treats union,
he'll treat colored.
- More water, Danny.
- Yes, madam.
You just hold this up there
against that, really gently.
- Don't press hard.
- Hey, Elma.
Have you seen any of the men?
Only those that are wounded.
How's she doing?
Not bad.
At least nobody got killed.
No thanks to you!
Take it easy, buddy.
Good morning, Joe.
Hey, Bridey.
Have you seen any of the fellows?
Not a one.
He's really nice looking.
He likes me. I can tell.
How?
I just know men. That's all.
That'd make a cat laugh.
If you want to
make that kind of slop
for dinner,
you go back home and make it.
This is the United States here
and we do things differently.
Listen to me.
You can learn something here.
Come on ladies.
What's the problem here?
I thought she was going to
make up some cornbread with it.
Well, you should see
the slop she came up with!
Miss Elkins
these people have got
their own way of doing things.
Well, that is a waste of
good corn meal, if you ask me.
She makes up
this porridgy kind of mess...
I wouldn't feed it to the pigs!
Ascoltate
where have all the men gone to?
That changes the whole picture.
What I'm saying is,
unions are fine for some things
but for other things
a man's got to go on his own.
Of course that's up to you.
Roscoe
you make sindacato
you do what the sindacato  say.
I listen to Joe.
Few Clothes?
We're going to be
shooting white folks, right?
That's the idea.
If people hear about
black folks shooting white folks
no matter what it's for
there's going to be hell to pay.
You've got a point.
Well then
if you gentleman will excuse us
andiamo.
You people
have been put out of
Stone Mountain Mine housing
and some of you have seen fit to
take along certain items
of food, furniture and clothing
that don't belong to you
but belong to the Company.
As of the day of the strike
your script ceased to
be legal tender, meaning
that any item of
food, clothing, and furniture
not paid for in cash money
must be turned over to me
and my deputies
and I suggest that
you all cooperate.
You see... my boys
they didn't
get much sleep last night
so they're kind of jumpy.
Besides
we've got the law on our side.
You aren't any law!
You've got to slip around the real law.
You've just got guns. That's all.
You're just thugs.
Yeah. Maybe your right, sonny.
We've just got guns
and you've still
got to hand in those goods.
You yellow scab-herder, you!
Hillard, you get up from there.
Have you got a list of goods?
I don't need one.
How you going to know what belongs
to the company and what doesn't?
He's the red, Hickey.
He's the agitator.
Everybody, you see.
I haven't got a gun on me.
What good do you think
that's going to do you, red?
You shoot me, and
folks will know, it was murder.
Well, that's some cold comfort.
Now you listen to me, red.
We were hunting.
You folks are making
an awful lot of commotion.
You scared all the game away.
Is this your machine?
I heard it last night, too.
It's an offense to the ear.
Hold it pops.
You're talking to the law here.
Did he ask you anything?
Where did you get that thing, pal?
The Spanish war?
No.
The war between the states.
You all, get in this machine and
get back into town where you belong.
There isn't but one law out here
and that's the law of nature.
Let's get the hell out of here.
You folks try and keep
the noise down and you'll do fine.
Help yourself to
the bird and the rabbit.
If you see any hogs,
they're probably ours.
We'd appreciate it
if you'd leave them be.
Good day to you.
Are you OK, Joe?
Yeah. I'd be all right
if it weren't for my ribs.
Who were those people?
Rossums, mostly
and a Shuttleworth.
- Are they miners  - No.
You'll never find those folks near a hole.
They've had most of their land
stolen by the company.
- They're hill people.
- Foothill people, really.
Your genuine hill people
can be dangerous.
Now the thing
you've got to remember, son
is, your fuse
burns one foot per minute.
Make it too long,
and they might see it.
Make it too short
and we'll all be
meeting you on the other side.
Damn it!
Air shaft No. 4.
Go out the back way.
Where are all our
other friends tonight, Miss Elma?
Did they get
tired of the chuck, or what?
I think
that old bitty went on strike
and laid down her teeth in protest.
They're just
particular about who they eat with.
What about you, Miss Elma?
Are you particular?
If Stone Mountain didn't
hold the lease here, you two
if Stone Mountain didn't hold the
lease here, you'd be peddling puntang
down in Cinder Bottom,
so just shut your mouth about it.
Where's your
little preacher tonight?
The bitch has got no table manners.
Elma
do you know where Danny is?
No. I don't know where anybody is
and nobody wants to tell me either.
Are you OK?
Yeah, just tired. That's all.
I've been working all day.
This place
I've been working
the day they burned my husband,
I started and I've been working and
it doesn't ever stop.
I get so tired
and
- there isn't anybody.
- Look. It's hard.
It's hard being on your own.
You don't know anything about it.
We're in business, buddy.
Let's get going.
What is it?
It sounds like
dynamite up at the mine.
It might be that No. 5 shaft.
It might be some shooting.
Hillard!
Have you seen my boy?
Has anybody seen my boy: Hillard?
That'll be the Baldwins.
Hillard!
Has anybody seen my Hillard?
It's the Baldwins up the hill
Shoot low, boys! Cut them down.
You fellows get on
out of here. I'll hold them back.
Reese! Reese, get up.
Sephus, come on.
OK, boys. Let's
spread out. He's here somewhere.
- I've got him. He's over here.
- Hold it boys. It's me.
Hold your fire, boys. It's C.E.
Are you all right?
You'd better get back to camp.
Judas
hold his leg.
Hold it.
Hold.
Now I'm just going to
pull this back from your leg, boy.
Give me back
that knife, Hillard.
Hey. What happened?
We were sold.
Those Baldwins
came up from behind.
They knew right
where we were laying out.
They knew when the men
were out of camp today too.
How's she feeling, buddy?
You made it.
We thought
we'd lost you back there.
Well, I got off a couple of rounds
and buried myself in the leaves.
I saw Reese Hadley go down, though.
Did Sephus get back?
I don't think so.
You see what happens
when you pick up a gun!
All I see is, those niggers
and dagos weren't there tonight
and we were sold
and somebody's going to pay.
Something bad
is happening out there:
those guns.
A hunting party. That's all.
Now, where was I?
"Time to put all shyness"
"time to put all shyness aside"
"and admit"
"to our heartfelt"
"attraction."
I'm not sure
how you spell "attraction".
How about
"heartfelt"
"desires"?
Are you sure
you want to do this?
"heartfelt desires"
"dearest"
"Joseph"
Look at that:
just covered with gore.
Dogs didn't do all that.
Are you drawing breath, son?
The Baldwins!
We were sold.
What's your name?
Bosephus
Sephus Purcell.
Kin to Nimrod Purcell?
That's daddy's uncle.
You say,
some Baldwin agents took you?
From behind.
None of those Purcells
ever was too bright.
Grab his ankles, missus,
and mind your dress.
He's bleeding like a stuck pig.
I've found him boys. He's here.
It's Reese.
You've got yourself a martyr.
I tried to stop this.
See any sign of Sephus?
We'll maybe
smell him before we see him.
Have they found somebody?
Just stay right here, honey.
You don't want to look at that mess.
But I've got
something for Mr. Kenehan.
I don't think he's in any mood
to be bothered right now.
I'll see he gets it.
Who is it?
Oh, just some poor miner
whose troubles are finally over.
Don't look, honey.
I talked to Ellix.
He says
your phonograph machine is
going to be fixed
in a couple of days now.
It's awfully
nice of you to do, Everett.
Well, we've got to take care of
our favorite lady now, haven't we?
You've been so generous
thinking about me
when that Mr. Kenehan
had got you all
so busy with the union.
That Mr. Kenehan is what I've
come to talk to you about, Bridey.
I've got a suspicion, he
might not be what he says he is.
What do you mean?
Bridey
did you send Kenehan
some sort of letter?
What do you want?
No.
He wouldn't.
There was a whole
crowd of fellows standing around him.
I saw Kenehan
laughing and waving that letter.
So I
came over to see what was so funny.
A lot of fellows?
Do you mind if
I have another drink, honey?
It isn't pretty,
what I've got to say.
He said some things, Bridey,
"She's been following me around
ever since I got here"
"trailing after me
like a dog in heat"
"sniffing around my legs
like a brood bitch."
"She doesn't
wear any drawers", he says
"so she can
be ready for whatever"
"stumbles down the pathway."
He didn't
he didn't
he said you did it
with one of the coloreds.
The lying bastard!
Bridey
I think
it might be worse than that.
I think, he might be a spy
in with the coal operators.
Well, he's got the fellows
so turned around with all his talk!
I need for
you to help me, Bridey
and sometimes you've got to
tell a little bit of a lie
just to get the truth across.
If we fight them with guns
we lose.
That's the whole damn story.
I'm not going to
bullshit you fellows
and tell you
there won't ever come a time
when the people that own this state
send the word down
to have us all murdered
but if we don't stand together now
as workers
we've got no hope at all.
Help me up.
Are you going somewhere?
This is miner's business
and you aren't any miner.
You two come along.
So
last night he came up here and
he was all drunk and everything
and I said how
I didn't want to
have anything to do with him
and I would
call some of you fellows
for help and
he said that all of you were
taken care of.
"Taken care of", huh?
When I saw that
there wasn't any help
he kind of
forced me
he forced me
Si...
That's OK.
You'd better
hear this first hand.
Go ahead, honey,
What happened then?
And afterwards he
he threw money on the bed
like I was some kind of a whore.
You did just fine, honey.
Now why don't you
go and sit outside for a minute
while we figure out
what we're going to do about this.
So he doesn't
have any sense with women...
So what?
You know
how Bridey builds things up!
Take a look at this
that our friend left
lying on the floor last night.
"Baldwin Felts Agency."
What's it say?
It's a death warrant. That's what.
For Mr. Joseph Kenehan.
So it's,
"Goodbye Mr. Kenehan", tonight.
Miners?
How'd you manage that?
That tramp that
goes to meet the passenger train
it seems
she's got the eye for Kenehan.
So he put it in her head
that Kenehan has been
bad mouthing her all around town.
He's got her down there
right now, crying to the miners
and he's got
these papers from Bluefield.
I didn't leave my Colt like this.
You spying little bastard!
What did you hear?
- What did you hear?
- Nothing.
Horseshit! Hit him, Bill.
See this medal?
Do you know how
I won this, preacher boy?
I was sitting alone
in a ditch in France
and this kraut
jumps in right next to me
and I took my bayonet
and I stuck him right in the face
and then another jumps in
and I stick him too
and another and another
and another... They just kept coming
one at a time, all night long
and a little bit
I got worried
that they weren't all dead, so
I stuck them all again
a couple of times, just to make sure
and in the morning
they said that I was a war hero!
Well, I'm going to stay
close to you tonight, preacher boy
and you let one wrong word fly
and I'm going to
put one in your skull
and I'll do
the same for your pretty mama.
You know
I'm not lying, don't you, boy?
Yes, sir.
The man who draws the short straw
gets to do the job
and word doesn't travel
beyond this room about who it is.
The rest of us
will want a good alibi.
I figure on
that prayer meeting tonight
right under the preacher's nose.
Welcome to the union, son.
What's the story?
Ludie heard that the Baldwins
were coming after you tonight
and I'm supposed to
stick by you.
You got
the shit detail again, huh?
Are you all right, Danny?
have you got your sermon memorized?
I'll bet he doesn't know
any more scripture than I do.
And that isn't a whole
hell of a lot, is it, Griggsy?
Do you know any?
I never got any further than
"In the beginning was the Word..."
I guess we're
both doomed to the hot place.
If the Lord relies on little shits
like this one to spread His word
I don't want any truck with heaven
and as for hell
well, we've been to West Virginia.
Ah
What in god's name
are you doing, son?
I'd just got
your leaks all stopped up
and here you're trying to
bust them open again.
I've got to get down there.
They've got to know.
You aren't going anywhere
unless it's in a pine box.
Where's your sense?
I've got to.
I wish
those fellows would get here.
Huh?
If they're coming
I wish they'd hurry up.
I don't want
any more shooting in the woods.
Did you ever use one of those?
The 10th Cavalry
in Cuba, back in '98:
San Juan Hill.
Pretty rough down there?
I did what I had to.
Is it true, you're a red?
Yeah. I suppose it is.
Then how come, you don't carry a gun?
Well, we carry little round bombs.
Don't you read the papers?
I want to tell you tonight
about the blackness
in the heart of man.
I'm going to warn you
about the many and devious ways
in which Satan
will hide from you the truth
of who your real friends are.
I'm going to do it
with a story from the Patriarchs.
Now, we all know about Joseph
and how out of
all Jacob's 12 children
he was the
smartest and the smoothest
and how
his brothers got so jealous
they pulled off
his coat of many colors and
whooped on him and left him
out to be sold into slavery.
But Joseph was not your
ordinary fellow, even for biblical times.
He had a special way with him
a way of looking at
the grand scheme of things.
So when this fellow,
Potiphar bought him for a slave
Joseph just smiled and
vowed he was going to be a good one.
Making the best of
a bad situation
he put his heart to his work
and was honest
and friendly in his dealings
and before you knew it,
he was just about running Potiphar's
households and fields
and all his businesses for him.
The only trouble
was Potiphar's wife.
Now she was what
you might call, a loose woman.
When I was in Leavenworth
there was a bunch of Mennonites
mainly because
they wouldn't fight in the war.
It's against their religion.
It's also against their religion
to shave their beards or
wear buttons on their clothes and
they were being forced to
do both by the prison guards.
So they refused to work
and they went on a strike
right there in Hell's Half Acre.
They were handcuffed to
the bars of a cell house
8 hours a day, for 2 full weeks.
They were put
with their arms up, like this
so that they had to
stand on their toes
or those cuffs
would cut into their wrists.
There can't be anybody
who'd stay on their toes eight hours.
So pretty soon
their fingers would start to swell up.
They turned blue and then they'd
crack open.
Blood would run down their arms
8 hours a day
day after day
but still they wouldn't work.
Still they tore
the buttons off their uniforms
every time they were sewn back on.
They tore them with their teeth
because their hands
wouldn't close any more.
So now I don't
claim a thing for myself
but those fellows
haven't ever
lifted a gun in their lives
and you couldn't
find any braver, in my book.
I wish
those fellows would get here.
Also in Potiphar's employ
at this time
were a couple of
spies from one of his enemies
fellows that wanted to
bring him down in the world
and get their hands on
his fields and houses.
They'd seen
the want and lust in Mrs. Potiphar
and seen, it would
be good for their purposes
to get shed of the young Joseph.
So they came to Potiphar's wife.
She called Joseph in
and she asked him one more time
"Joseph will you lie with me?"
and he said, "No madam. I won't."
And she set up a ruckus and grabbed
hold of the garment he was wearing
and rent it in two
before he could get clear.
Potiphar runs in with his guards
and she's bawling her eyes out
and shaking like a leaf.
"Your servant Joseph", she says
"he come in here and
tried to make me lie with him."
"Only when I called out, he fled"
"leaving
this here garment as evidence."
"And not only that", she says
"he's been spying and plotting
against you with your enemies."
"He means to take over here
and have you killed."
Potiphar had no reason to
misbelieve his wife.
Joseph was
a slave and a foreigner.
So he gathered up his servants
and household workers
and they went and slew Joseph dead
cut him from gut to gizzard
and left him bleeding in the street.
And lo! They never
learned of Mrs. Potiphar's lies and
went to their maker, unrepentant,
with innocent blood on their hands.
Draw your own conclusions.
- It's getting awful late.
- shh
Did you hear something?
No. You?
Yeah. I think I did
like somebody moaning.
Maybe it's the fellows.
I think we should
go out there and have a look.
Who's that?
That's Hillard.
The meeting's been called off.
Well, we'd better
get back to camp, huh?
Wait a minute.
Well, at least
we didn't waste a trip.
- Shouldn't we do something?
- No way. It won't spread.
Is C.E. inside?
No such luck.
Find that son of a bitch.
How come, they waste
more food in one day
than a poor worker's family
has on their table in a week?
Now let me ask you!
Who's sweat was it that
went into building those mansions?
Once they'd seen how
they'd almost done an innocent man
it was like
Joe couldn't say any wrong.
We moved out
into the Mango County then
spreading the word about the union
spreading like wildfire
over to Red Jacket
to Ragland and Delbarton
all up and down the Tug Fork river
bringing the union out
to all the folks that needed help
putting the spirit into them
and trying to shut down
the whole southwest field
helping themselves to our land
and our labor for too damn long.
Joe Kenehan said
how there was a new day coming
and sometimes
I could just about see it
but it was
a dangerous living for a union man
and you didn't
dare turn your back.
It was hard times
and it was hungry times too.
The union relief was spread thin
and with the hope of a new day
can feed your soul
but leave your belly rumbling.
Scoot.
Lady...
since there are
just me and Hillard
and you've got
all these little ones
well
do you know what to do with this?
Hillard brought it in.
It's for you.
I'm not going to
watch no babies go hungry.
Now here...
You go on. You take it.
Here are some navy beans
and these here are ramps.
Now, you can cook with these.
They put a taste in your stew.
Anyhow
well, I
figure, we're all in this together.
You've sure got some pretty babies!
- Who's your favorite pitcher?
- Hod Eller.
He's from Logan county.
Did you get to play ball much?
When the mines were open.
Joe...
Yeah?
Did you ever kill anybody?
What brought that up?
I'll bet Sid has.
He were in the war.
All I saw was
workers killing workers
and there wasn't any point in it.
They thrown you in jail
because you wouldn't go?
Those 2 years kept me from
killing some poor stiff that got
pushed out on a battlefield
by rich folks and politicians
and they were worth it.
It's getting dark, Danny.
You'd better go and get that coal.
Do you see there,
right there by the railroad trestle?
That's where Cap Hatfield
and his boy Joe Glenn killed 3 men.
Th boy wasn't but 13.
He used a Winchester.
Do you think
it hurts much, a bullet?
It beats dying in a damn coal mine!
The boy wasn't but
13 years old, Joe Glenn.
He must be in there.
He always
sleeps with the lights on.
We've just
got to be quiet. That's all.
Let's get
the little bastards.
Over here...
Grab him. Cut him off.
Well, well...
What have we got here?
Smarts a little,
doesn't it boy?
"Hillard", right?
Now
how about, you give us the names of
your ring leaders up in Logan...
Give us 5 names boy. That's all:
5 names and we'll let you go.
That's fair isn't it?
Never!
Griggsy
talk to us boy.
Talk to us.
I'll rot in hell first.
Have it your way.
Mr. Lively
Boy
I sentence you to death for
the crime of stealing Company property
and being a dirty
bolshevist union man.
You've got 10 seconds to talk.
Talk.
What a smell!
The boy dirtied his diapers.
We want names, son.
I can't. I swore on a Bible.
Then we're going to
have to get down to it son.
Use the razor.
Hold him boys.
Just a little nick, boy.
Get it off your chest, son.
Plyant Mount, Bill Mahan,
Asa Radnor, J.T. Keadle
5!
Give us 5, boy.
And Harley Shilton.
- Kill him.
- No.
So where do
those fellows he named live?
Clay Hill.
Where's that?
It's a cemetery.
They are all fellows
that were killed in a gas fire
5, 6 year ago.
There's nothing like
a young boy dying
to stir things up!
Baldwin's coming
into town tomorrow, Kenehan.
Do you fellows have
any idea what's waiting for us?
You mean, they didn't tell you?
No. I just saw
a line in the papers about
"opportunity
for red-blooded American men"
"immediate openings"
"high pay,
travel, chance for advancement."
"Apply Baldwin Felts
and write your own ticket."
When the natives get restless
someplace they put that out
and hook some more cannon fodder.
Ever hear of
the Hatfields and McCoys, son?
Yeah. Of course, I have.
This Matewan
is their stomping grounds.
They'll put a bullet in your brain
as soon as they look at you.
Sid
we have authorization
to put these miners
off Company property here in town.
Not from me, you don't.
And we've also got
a warrant for your arrest
if you give us any trouble.
This isn't worth shit
and you know it.
One way or another we're
going to carry out these evictions
tomorrow morning.
Gentleman
they came to kill me.
Hillard was my friend.
When I first came
down to the mines, it was Hillard
who'd show me what to do.
He was a good coal miner,
a good union man
and he always
took care of his mama.
I don't know how they
could have done him like they did.
All he wanted to do
was live decently. That's all.
Sometimes people say
how God willed it
how everything is His plan.
Well
I don't think He planned on
Hillard lying here
amongst all these Elkinses.
Not this young in his life!
I think
all God plans is, we get born
and we've got to
take it from there.
So you rest in peace, Hillard.
You rest easy because we're
going to take up where you left off.
Amen.
Are you going to tell us to
turn the other cheek, still?
Shooting is what they want now.
Maybe it's what we want, too.
You expect
too much of people, Joe.
You're still after that
one big union, but most of us
we can't see past this hollar.
I need to talk to the men.
It wouldn't be decent now.
I'll call
a meeting in the morning
first thing.
Pass the word
to stay out from town tomorrow.
Is something up?
I've got a feeling.
You know how white folks are
when they get all excited...
Nothing's going to
bring Hillard back, you know.
Danny, I came here to help.
Sure you did.
First people come here
to help us with some money.
Next we know we've got no land.
Then they say
they're going to help us with a job
and a place to live
and they stick us in
some damn coal camp
and let us dig out their mines.
Now you come here
to help us bring in the "new day".
Well, Hillard isn't
going to see any new day.
We had about
as much help as we can stand.
We've got to take care of ourselves.
We've got to
take care of each other.
Joe!
The men go to town.
See it?
There's no need
for you to be in on this.
It's my town too.
They're my people.
You have no right to
come to this here town
with all these people and
drawing guns and terrorizing them.
The writs you have
are not valid for this town.
- You can't get one
- No.
No. Wait.
Jesus! Don't shoot me.
I just wanted to talk.
I can't feel my legs.
There was a trial
but there wasn't
anybody going to pass guilty
on Sid Hatfield in Mingo County.
Sid got married to
Mayor Testerman's widow
and then the Baldwins
caught him unarmed
walking up the steps of
the McDowell county court house.
They shot 15 bullets into him
right in broad daylight
and C.E. Lively stepped in
and put one right through his skull.
There wasn't even
a trial on that one.
That was the start of
the great Coalfield War and
us miners took the worst of it,
like Joe said we would.
"It's just one big union
the whole world over"
Joe Kenehan used to say
and from the day of
the Matewan massacre
that's what I preached.
That was my religion.
We buried
Joe Kenehan with our own.
My mama thought
he wouldn't ever stay
but now he's with us for always
lying up here
in these West Virginia hills.