A NETFLIX ORIGINAL FILM
Please come in.
How about upstairs?
It's clean and spacious.
Come.
That's just the cellar.
This will do.
Did you bring what I asked for?
Shit!
Superstitious nonsense!
I believe now.
I'm your servant.
Remember, Lesmana.
He has accepted your oath.
Go home!
There's more wealth waiting for you.
LESMANA WIJAYA
PORTRAIT OF AN OVERNIGHT SUCCESS
LESMANA PURCHASES MULTIPLE PROPERTIES
LESMANA WIJAYA
THE NEWEST PROPERTY ENTREPRENEUR
YOUNG ENTERPRENEUR LESMANA:
KEY TO INVESTMENT SUCCESS
LESMANA: OVERNIGHT SUCCESS,
PLANNING EARLY ON
FIRST WIFE OF BUSINESSMAN LESMANA
FOUND DEAD
A WIFE'S DEATH
INTAN, WIFE OF BUSINESSMAN LESMANA,
COMMITS SUICIDE
FORMER ACTRESS LAKSMI SURYA
MARRIES SUCCESSFUL BUSINESSMAN
LESMANA MARRIES A FORMER ACTRESS,
MARRIAGE BLESSED WITH A DAUGHTER
SORRY
LESMANA'S BUSINESS STARTS TO DECLINE
HITTING SUDDEN BANKRUPTCY,
LESMANA CORPORATION TO SELL ASSETS
Excuse me.
Yes, it's Alfie.
Hospital?
24 HOURS
Alfie?
Alfie.
They called you, too?
-He's there, isn't he?
-Alfie.
Don't be emotional.
We need to fix things eventually, right?
After everything that has happened,
I never thought of you as an enemy.
Relationship with patient?
We are his children.
She's his biological daughter.
Mr. Lesmana is unresponsive,
but you may speak to him.
Being around familiar people
might help his motoric response.
What's wrong with him?
We have no clue yet.
He's showing stroke symptoms,
skin disease,
and failing organs.
Mrs. Laksmi isn't with you?
Yes. Our mom's not coming.
How come?
She just doesn't want to.
Very well, miss. Excuse me.
It's been ten years, right?
Since you last saw Dad?
A year ago, he started visiting his villa.
Back and forth.
Isolating himself.
Not long after his bankruptcy, right?
Alfie, this isn't easy for us.
Your issues with Dad
has nothing to do with me or Ruben.
No one wants to be alone
in this condition.
Ruben. Take Lily out.
We don't need her to start puking.
Mom plans to find any remaining assets
over at the villa.
Assets?
Have you visited that place?
The villa's ownership is under your name.
It's up to you, guys.
All right.
I'm going to call my mom.
I thought I'd feel satisfied
seeing you suffer like this.
You left us both.
Meanwhile, you were successful
and married that damn woman.
I should be really hating you right now.
But look at you now.
What is there to hate?
What is there left to hate, Dad?
Alfie!
Alfie?
Ruben!
Lily.
Lily!
-Lily!
-Let me go!
Alfie.
It's been a while.
Be strong, child.
Goodness, what a mess.
How are we going to sell this
with a high price?
How long are we staying here, Mom?
Nara.
Ruben dear, where's your little sister?
Find her. Don't let her wander alone.
Nara.
-If there's nothing valuable here,
-Nara.
we'll head back to Jakarta tonight.
Okay, dear?
Yes, Mom.
Nara?
Better sell fast before this dump
becomes a dead asset.
Who will buy this old dump, Mom?
It's very antique.
Besides, you should be asking Alfie.
Nara.
Sit down.
Don't be naughty.
Alfie.
What an unusual visit.
I'm just looking around.
Well, you know,
your father is really sick.
Obviously, the medical bills...
Are not cheap.
I know.
Has the hospital explained his condition?
Whatever it is,
let's just pray that God will protect him
and enlighten his path.
So you're selling this house, yeah?
Don't you guys have savings?
Alfie, you seem tired.
Why don't you rest a bit?
It must be hard for him.
Rich, but still not enough
to provide for an actress.
I meant a former actress.
Watch your mouth.
Who do you think you're talking to?
Who?
Her?
She's not my mother.
My mom was with Lesmana
even when he had nothing.
-My mom was faithful.
-Alfie.
Funny, isn't it?
All that, and she was still betrayed.
For who? For...
For you!
-Mom!
-You little demon!
What's wrong with you?
Can you just chill?
I'm going nuts here.
Sit down, Ruben.
Sit!
All of you, get ready
to find any documents,
anything we can take back with us.
It's me, Ruben.
Come in.
Eat, Alfie.
You haven't eaten, right?
I didn't poison it.
Isn't that your sister's snack?
Yes, I made Nara's snack.
I'm the only cook in the family.
See? Your stomach can't lie.
Well, let me dig in.
I'm starving.
You're kind of dorky, aren't you?
Is it my hair?
I haven't showered all day.
I was the one who drove here, too.
That's not what I meant.
Your personality.
You act like a dork.
I see.
You meant funny, right?
Funny stepbrothers do exist.
Actually, they are funny.
Have you heard of evil stepbrothers?
So lame.
I'm always wrong.
You're better than them, though.
Well, that's my mom.
Maya isn't usually cynical like that.
But...
since we've had money troubles,
she has become...
insecure and fearful.
That's how she is.
Please cut her some slack.
Maya is right, though.
I really want us to get along.
Have a good relationship.
Ruben.
Eat up.
Go on.
What's up?
What is she up to?
Crying?
Oh, please.
Take this.
What's this for?
That door there is closed shut.
Try pulling out those nails.
Why me?
You’re the strongest here.
Here, go straight to it.
Maya?
All good now?
24 HOURS
What is this?
Ruben, go check it out.
Go on.
I think we should check it tomorrow.
Ruben, we're going home tonight.
Go check downstairs.
There may be a safe-deposit box
or other valuables.
Now.
Go on, Ruben.
-Go on.
-Okay.
Ruben, don't do it!
Something's wrong with this place.
There's something upstairs!
You again.
-If you don't want to help, then--
-Listen!
There's something upstairs,
pictures we need to investigate.
-Mom.
-Something?
What pictures? You're still lying.
-You damn orphan!
-Mom!
What did you say?
Ruben, don't stick your nose
where it doesn't belong!
-Mom.
-Even your father abandoned you.
-You're all alone now!
Ungrateful brat!
Mom, enough.
-Mom.
-I really am tired with this brat.
-Mom!
-You should defend your mom.
What?
-Mom!
Mom!
-Ruben!
-Help!
Ruben!
Give me a hand!
Help me!
Mom!
-Mom!
-Maya!
-Maya, don't!
-Fuck off!
-Maya!
-Ruben, Mom...
We don't know what's down there!
Ruben! It's Mom!
Mom!
Ruben, what should we do?
Ruben.
Mom...
Ruben, step back.
Mom?
Fortune shall be paid with souls.
Mom!
Maya!
This will have to do for now.
What is that, Nara?
It was outside--
Throw it away, Nara!
It's filthy!
Give me the doll.
Alfie.
Come with me.
We're stuck here.
What is wrong with my mom?
Ruben!
Your phone's dead, right?
Try calling the police, local district,
or anyone who could help us.
You sure about this?
Your sister's not well.
That wound could be infected.
There's a village down the path.
She can be treated there.
In this situation,
it's safer for all of us to go.
What about Nara?
Ruben.
Remember who's lurking out there.
Just in case.
You're the tough one.
But please, don't act rashly.
Alfie.
What is it?
You hate me, don't you?
I don't hate you, Maya.
I don’t want you to hate me.
My life isn't exactly a joyride.
I'm not even close to your father.
And my mom...
Yeah, she isn't exactly a good mother.
Now, she's possessed.
Maya, we have to keep on moving. Come on.
Maya!
What's that?
Mom!
What is this?
Maya, that's...
Maya.
Alfie, have you been stalking us?
No, Maya, not at all!
Why did you bring me here?
Maya, you need to be treated.
Why, Alfie?
Please hear me out, Maya!
Maya!
Maya.
Police...
Police hotline...
Honey, where are you?
Why didn't you tell me?
You promised to be with me.
I'm still upset
-your father puked on me.
-Honey, I...
What? If you really want to be with me,
-you should be more mature.
-Honey, please listen to me.
Your mother hates me, Ben.
So does Maya.
-You really are--
-My mom's possessed!
What? How come?
-No, I mean...
-What?
-My head hurts.
-Honey, be serious!
-I really want you here.
-Don't talk like that!
Please come here. I'm really tired.
Let's leave together.
I'll send you my location, okay?
Where are you now? I'm going there.
Send your loc--
Brother.
I saw the person who took Mom.
Where?
In that scary room.
We're safe in this room.
Ruben.
How did you turn into this?
I needed to hold on to something.
Even if it reminded me
of everything I hate.
But that's all I have, Ruben.
That's it.
So you hate me?
Maya?
Nara?
The person I hate the most is myself.
In this world, I hate myself the most.
Then how about Maya?
Do we just leave her out there?
Ruben, look at me.
As soon the sun rises,
we'll look for Maya.
We will not leave her.
Trust me.
Now what?
There's something
you need to see downstairs.
SORRY
Turns out Lesmana is not a good person.
I saw this woman at the hospital, Ruben.
He stuck these symbols on that door
leading to downstairs.
Is it possible...
he was trying to keep something there?
Ruben.
"Dark priestesses.
Usually, these women
have dedicated themselves
to be the concubines of the Devil...
until doomsday comes.
Therefore, they are given the power
to do supernatural things."
Why would Lesmana mess around
with this stuff?
Think of it.
Lesmana.
All of a sudden, he became rich.
Then he went bankrupt a few years later.
Then he started coming back here.
What does it have to do with your mom?
And now my mom's also in deep shit.
Alfie, what if that woman is still lurking
in the basement?
Alfie. Alfie?
Alfie.
Mom!
Mom?
Nara.
Are you sleeping?
Please accompany me, Nara.
I really love you.
I'm lonely, Nara.
It's dark in here.
I'm scared.
You damned demon!
Come here, Nara. You should wake up.
Wake up and stay with me!
Wake up!
I'm alone here! Accompany me!
Come on!
You're not my mom!
Nara!
Ruben!
Alfie.
Sweetheart.
Hold on, dear.
Mom will be right back.
Mom!
Let go!
Hi, it's Ruben.
I can't talk right now. Leave a message.
Maya?
What happened to you?
What are you doing here?
Just helping out.
You want to meet Ruben, right?
Yes, he told me to come.
What did he say?
Open the door.
You can go first, Maya.
I'll be behind you.
Let's go together. It's not that far.
Maya.
Why are you holding a hammer?
I'll just stay here.
What did you say?
Unlock the door, Lily.
If you don't believe me,
talk to Ruben.
Here.
Nara.
Maya.
Who are you?
I'm your mother.
Mom?
Mom, forgive me.
My child.
I'm inside her now.
I didn't mean to.
This is not my fault, Mom.
-Your brother and sister chose me, Maya.
-Maya.
-You're scared, aren't you?
It's all her fault.
It's your fault!
You're tearing my family apart on purpose.
It's all your fucking fault!
Maya.
-Would you like to be my follower?
Be my lambkin.
Kneel before me.
I know this isn't real.
But you need to know, Mom...
I want to be with you again.
Stay with me, Alfie.
It's so dark in here.
I'm so alone and scared.
It should've been you.
You should've been taken, Alfie.
Are you letting me go again, Alfie?
You want to be like your daddy?
Don't you get it?
I'm lonely!
You're not my mom!
Alfie.
Alfie, what's wrong?
Calm down.
Why?
I like this dress.
I found it upstairs. It suits me, right?
Maya, why are you... When did you--
Soon, Alfie.
Alfie?
Alfie, what's wrong?
Ruben.
-Ruben!
-What?
We have to leave now.
I called Lily. She's coming, all right?
We can't go
because Mom is still out there.
Look at my arm. Look!
Look at Nara's!
Remember what your mom said last night.
"Fortune shall be paid with souls."
That woman we saw last night,
she came and took my mom.
Now she's in your mom!
She'll never let go of me and Nara.
And I don't know
what will happen to you all.
We should go, Ruben.
Let's just fucking leave!
It's time!
He will never let you leave.
What do you mean?
Who are you talking about, Maya?
Who is he?
Say his name!
-Say it.
-Who?
-Say it!
-Who, Maya?
-Say his name! Say it!
Say it!
Maya?
What are you doing there?
He will never let us leave.
Maya!
Alfie! I got to find Maya.
No, Ruben, don't!
-Don't!
-Watch over Nara.
Ruben!
Maya!
Maya, we need to leave.
Maya, what are you doing here?
Maya.
He wants Alfie and Nara, Ruben.
Maya?
Please tell me you're Maya.
Who do you think this is?
Wake up, Maya.
I told you.
We will never leave this house.
I've killed Mom.
Lily, too.
In the woods.
What did you say?
Ruben, calm down.
Calm down.
Mom is already beneath his feet.
Look.
He's there.
My daughter.
He's waiting for me, for you,
to be back in his embrace.
Who is he?
Now, let's take Alfie and Nara to him.
You and I...
we will never need to ask
for anything else.
Are you crazy?
This is our chance
to repay Lesmana's debts.
Alfie and Nara.
-And still, you reject him.
-Maya! Wake up!
You're blind to his greatness.
You're blind to--
Sorry.
Maya!
Ruben!
Ruben.
-Ruben!
-No!
Don't come here.
Go!
Go now!
Maya!
Brother!
Nara!
I have been waiting for you.
Did you bring what is needed?
I can't.
Alfie's my daughter.
But you could do it to your first wife.
Lesmana, you didn't make a promise to me.
Until now, you have not been able
to pay your dues.
You take me for a fool, Lesmana?
Lesmana!
Not now, not later,
but when you least expect it,
you will lose everything!
Along with your own flesh and blood!
Be ready to be taken, Lesmana!
Maya.
Maya is one with me.
She's laughing at you, my child.
Your defiance is useless.
Nara is your sister, Maya!
Ruben was your brother!
Please come to your senses, Maya.
It's me, Alfie!
It's all useless now, my child.
Maya has already accepted who she is.
After I have taken her.
I know you still love Nara, Maya!
I know it!
Alfie.
Honestly,
I never really liked you.
What's so funny?
You're funny.
Even now, you're still acting.
What do you mean?
"What do you mean?"
You know what Ruben said about you?
What?
He told me
that you are insecure and fearful.
"Please cut her some slack."
It seems like you won't need your legs
in the place where you're going.
You go first.
Nara!
Alfie.
Mom...
Mom.
Subtitle translation by Anggie S. Sidharta