That is our Planet.
From distance it is like the usual school globe.
Let's look through clouds.
But let's not ask earthmen about this city's name
and the title of this scientific centre --
on the shore of warm blue sea.
Fishermen and poets, schoolboys and academicians,
astronomers and cosmonauts live here.
It's Sunday today,
and everyone is spending it in his own way.
This is the operator of the computer centre - Paul.
He is a joker and chess player.
Never failed in playing chess to his friend Andrey.
Andrey - specialises in sky mechanics.
Writes songs and dreams of remote stars.
He believes stars are populated.
Ivan Batalov. Engineer and amateur painter.
He draws cartoons of friends in his album.
This restrained man of few words
is nicknamed Commander by his friends.
Academician Krylov. Head astronomer,
compiler of star atlas.
He meets today his foreign colleague -
Dr. Laungton
They have an old dispute - what kind of event will be
probable upon the meeting of Earth and space aliens.
I. S. Shklovsky
The Universe. The Life. The Mind.
Tanya. Radio-astronomer.
She listens to mysterious voices of far stars.
Today she's recorded strange,
unusual signals from space.
What if these ones are exactly those signals
which The Earth been waiting for many years?
Hurry up to Andrey.
- Give me your hand.
- Stop laughing, Andrey, I'm serious.
What if it's really the signals
coming from another world?
Look out, Tanya.
Have you really never thought about it?
Never thought about it.
Never thought?
And what is that device
which you demonstrated to Paul?
Device? It's a typical crystalphone.
Show me?
Nothing interesting.
Just dreams in spare time.
Well.
I will not ask you anymore.
Are you serious?
OK, here you are, listen to it.
Living and believing is wonderful.
We have unprecedented voyages in the future.
Cosmonauts and dreamers say
that apple trees will be in flower on Mars.
That's good when your friends are with you.
It's easier to come across the whole Universe.
Stars will meet the Earth in flower,
And apple trees will be in flower on Mars.
Overcoming endless space distances,
the Earth song has reached the planet Centuria,
and the greatest and most beautiful event
in the Universe happened --
people of one planet have heard
a voice of another planet.
I became a friend of far stars,
don't worry about me and don't be sad.
While leaving the Earth we promised
that apple trees would be in flower on Mars.
But what kind of feeling the Earth song
has evoked in their hearts?
Fear or joy?
And what if they are to give the Earth a challenge?
That's what Dr. Laungton thinks of.
Hostile challenge.
No. Such a way of thinking is only for a man
who doesn't believe in the power of mind.
Scientists of the planet Centuria have known
that the Earth is populated
And they decided to fly, only fly.
But people of Earth didn't expect
guests from the Universe.
- I flew to the Moon, and you will fly to Mars
- There's lack of water on Mars. No cocktails at all.
Especially for you, gourmet, pikes
will be bred in Mars puddles.
You're completely right.
- Only in the case if crucian carps will be there.
- Crucian carps? What are you talking about?
Attention! All the cosmonauts except those who are
under observation in thermo chambers and isolation chambers,
please get together on the Gagarin Square.
Attention! All the cosmonauts except those who are
under observation in thermo chambers and isolation chambers,
please get together on the Gagarin Square.
- So Ivan, we will fly?
- Possibly, but our routes could be different.
Come along.
Like in the song: The order is given -
he should move to Phobos,
she should move in the opposite direction.
Sergey Petrovich arrived,
They will send together only newly
married couple. Think about it.
My friends, I am glad to inform you about an alarming and
at the same time, remarkable piece of news.
We've just received structured signals from space.
This means that the hypothesis of progressive scientists are confirmed.
Sergey Petrovich, it is probably an accidental coincidence?
No, my friends, the signals are being progressively increased.
As for now, decoding machines are
unsuccessfully trying to decipher this
enigmatic symphony of radiation,
The Eyes and Ears of the Earth
are focused on the supposed source of the signal.
This is information from the International Cosmo Centre.
At 17:18 MSK, satellite observatories have noticed again --
an unidentified spaceship. It's crossed the Moon's
orbit and is moving towards the Earth.
Our electronic machines are calculating
the possible landing place.
But why are the signals interrupted now?
This really is a puzzle...
We just should solve it.
Incomprehensible.
It all looks like some fantastic fiction...
So the excited Earth was awaiting the
crossing of its orbit with the orbit of aliens.
What will happen?
A giant explosion which will burn all life on Earth, --
- - or the Earth with the addition of the aliens' mind
will be in blossom, become more beautiful, --
will become the planet of
the Companionship of Suns?
But to the earthmen's astonishment, only a little star
has fallen to the sea, leaving there a strange object.
So what has this amazing delegate
from space brought to the Earth?
Pyotr Timofeyevich, what happened?
It's their ship's video log-book.
The Starship's cabin is clearly seen.
Call Krylov to me.
Play it.
They were flying to us.
But why?
I suppose that a civilisation capable of overcoming
interstellar distances could have only one purpose -
thirst for knowledge.
- Are you sure?
Thirst for knowledge pushed civilised Europeans on
to an unknown Asia and Africa.
This all brought to us a sea of tears and blood.
This was done by people living under one sky.
What we can expect from meeting with another world?
This could be a wonderful meeting.
This meeting could be unpleasant.
Sergey Petrovich, we are receiving
a lot of requests from different countries.
I suppose, Sergey Petrovich, we should call the Congress.
Yes, a lot of difficulties,
almost unresolvable tasks --
So, should we publish a report about our inability
to solve this, and break up with disgrace?
No, ladies and gentlemen.
Now, when we've faced real opportunities of
establishing friendship between different worlds, --
when residents of other planets
have taken the first step in doing this --
we ought to make a step in answer.
Even if they didn't ask our help.
I don't believe in the risk of this meeting,
the risk is hidden in another thing --
the risk that we are too late to help.
Mr. Laungton, you're welcome.
Dear colleagues, ladies and gentlemen.
I have listened with astonishment to
this very interesting --
but absolutely fantastic
speech from president Krylov.
What the respected president said is
romantic and beautiful, but impossible.
Our mechanical spies have
reached Mars and Venera.
It is obviously that neighbouring
planets civilisations --
interpret this as an attempt
to conquer circumsolar space.
I accentuate, dear colleagues,
that I would be happy if I'm wrong.
These are thoughts of not a scientist
but a politician from the past.
Not a scientist?
Perhaps, but a human who wish to
defend his home --
which also appears as your home too.
And at least, whom will you send
to meet suspense, to the foreign planet?
People who love their planet.
And these are thoughts of
a dreamer, not a scientist.
For doing this we need to make a jump over
centuries of technological progress.
Why not try? We could unite
the intelligence and science of our planet,
gather all the needed things together.
And money, Mr. Laungton... Who can
believe that our powerful planet --
which recently spent billions
for militarization, can not...
- Fly. We should fly.
- Right
He's right, Mr. Laungton,
we cosmonauts are ready to fly to Mars.
Crashed in the area of Mars,
cosmonauts of Centuria --
transmitted SOS signals not to
Russians or Americans, Frenchmen or Arabians.
They addressed it to the
whole our planet, its collective mind.
Comrades, friends, ladies and gentlemen
Spaceship OCEAN made by
the nations of our country --
was to be launched
in half a year --
when an advantageous
arrangement of planets will occur.
But the situation is now changed, --
and we ought to fly immediately
and with maximum speed.
But this is impossible without
the express delivering of --
a huge amount of energetic
resources to the Moon.
And despite difference of opinions,
people of Earth decided to fly.
Tens of shuttles flew to the Moon to deliver
energy for supporting spaceship OCEAN -
which is ready to fly to Mars.
We are leaving our home planet
to spread our Earth truth.
Through stars and planets,
Flying faster than light.
For making it possible for Earth to sound
everywhere with a long-expected signal.
I am Earth, I will never forget my children,
sons and daughters
Fly to the Sun
and hurry to come back home.
We will fly to the Sun
and will hurry to come back home.
Our purposes are high and distant
Our ancestors who helped the Earth to be beautiful
are with us on our star way.
So let the commander's order and mother's
instructions sound for us and them.
I am Earth, I will never forget my children,
sons and daughters
Fly to the Sun
and hurry to come back home.
We will fly to the Sun
and will hurry to come back home.
So what about Mars' behaviour?
- Silent, no life signs.
- So we should be looking for?
No life signs.
Nothing.
Attention! The Earth calls for
commander of cargo spaceship RDU-12.
- Lusya, when?
- The Earth channel is busy.
- My orders?
- Later.
Lusenka, Lake of Dreams please.
Don't waste your time.
My apologies, I am new here on the Moon.
Santos Rem, journalist.
I ask you, please.
Unfortunately, all channels
are busy right now, Mr. Rem.
Predictable.
I'll wait.
The weather on Earth
was beautiful yesterday.
You like it?
That's for you.
How beautiful.
That's all very well, but what
is the result of flight Mars-3?
Are your suppositions confirmed?
Yes, they are confirmed.
But lots of aspects are still unclear,
and surprises are possible at every step.
But we can't wait anymore.
Even during minutes of great events,
there's always a cluster of people --
for whom a loud report of an event
is more important than the event itself.
They are always ready to
rush to the middle of event, --
and nobody knows
the question they'll ask again.
Why are you flying to Mars?
It's worth it to fly to.
Ivan, what happened?
By the way, it's Commander,
he could help your newspaper.
I am at your service.
Excuse me, I have...
Mr. Commander, that's for my newspaper.
What are you flying to Mars for?
What for? To return to the Earth.
- And bring smiles from a different world.
Yes, but only two of you, and we
know that three of you should fly.
So, who's the third one?
Like a drummer friend said:
"One more beat and the music is over".
Tanyusha, come in.
If you're interested
in orbital flights...
I want... I want to say
happy birthday to you.
Because... You know... I...
I know. Because "the order is given -
he should move to Phobos... "
Report about readiness.
"We have passed 75 million km. Mars in sizes is
like a dish from here. What if we... "
Is it lunch already?
Even far away from the Earth, people
will still have their usual earth habits.
They will miss home lunch,
green fields,
will joke and argue.
The temperament of the people in the
spaceship will obviously weigh the same
value as on the Earth.
Let's play?
I am finishing reading
Moon Diaries by Krylov.
Mars...
How will it meet us?
- Tanyusha.
- Paul, how will we understand each other?
There's a language which
should be understandable.
I am speaking of them.
When will you be serious?
When I will die of
hunger, mademoiselle.
- Don't upset Martian girls,
they are waiting impatiently for you.
But before dying of hunger,
I will write a book.
A story?
A novel?
I will write a book about
cooking tasty and healthy... space food.
What's that?
"Food for gods and cosmonauts. "
A gift by a French company. Every pill's
nutritional value is like lamb chop.
Let me see.
I know this company, they sell pills
only for those who leave the Earth.
Try it.
- What happened to devices of the 2nd block?
- Look.
Sun!
Put your pressure helmets on.
An unexpected solar burst
has detuned some important units.
Close your face guards.
I'm switching on units
of the 3rd and 7th blocks.
Maximum protection.
All blocks are working.
To the limit.
Calculating stars energy.
To the limit!
In only five Minutes, radio-waves have
delivered Tanya's words to the Moon.
We are trying to stick to Mars' orbit.
Only emergency block are working.
Tanya, Tanyusha, move something.
Ringing in the ears?
Weakness...
Connections.
Paul. Cotton with
ammonia spirit.
Am I alive?
Some symphony in my ears...
- The emergency one has done its job.
Switch off the blocks of
UV protection.
Now two tasks: Paul, monitor it,
and I will inspect our energy sources.
- You see?
I swear it is it.
Let's check it out.
Starship.
OCEAN crossed the Mars orbit.
Intellect wins.
During a 19th lap around the Mars,
OCEAN crew detected a starship.
Starship discovered.
What will Krylov state?
OCEAN lost too much
energy due to a damage.
So landing on Mars is impossible?
Landing is possible, but
taking-off is impossible.
So we should speed up
the launching of OCEAN-2.
And what do they suggest?
Mars. A lifeless desert.
Did Mars expect, that here spaceships
of different planets would meet?
Shall we go?
Spaceship OCEAN transmits.
Watch and listen.
We are broadcasting right from
the place of starship landing.
- I will go.
- Wait.
Paul, stay here.
No response.
Some more steps, and Commander
will enter the Starship.
The Starship from
a far unknown planet,
You've overcome long long
distances, for what?
What have you brought to us?
What mysteries do you
hide in your modules?
We believe in good, so we
meet you with trustfulness.
But Dr. Laungton...
what if he was right?
OCEAN transmits for Earth and Moon:
we've found the Starship, there's
one Centuria cosmonaut - he is dead.
I repeat - only one dead cosmonaut.
"One dead cosmonaut was
found in the Starship. "
"Where's the rest of
the cosmonauts?"
How are things?
I'm trying to find out
where the other two could go.
OCEAN crew supposes
that 2 other cosmonauts of Centuria
escaped the Starship on
an emergency ship during the crash.
We need to launch the satellites
around Mars as fast as possible.
It is the only way to find them,
but OCEAN-2 is not yet ready for launching.
But my METEOR is ready. I will take
video satellites and throw them over Mars.
And what next?
You know that METEOR should
move fast, all the energy will be out fast.
You will not be able to come back
to Earth nor to land on Mars.
Lack of energy.
And I am not going to land
on Mars in METEOR.
Have a look. After the launching
of satellites around Mars, --
I will land on Phobos, leave METEOR -
and will land in
an emergency ship on Mars.
I thought about it.
It's a huge risk -
a minor mistake and...
Sergey Petrovich,
risk will be in any case.
Me and Andrey have made
all the necessary calculations.
Well, call for Andrey.
So the second spaceship leaves the Moon
and moves forward to Mars, --
to launch satellites into the Mars orbit,
they will search for the lost cosmonauts of Centuria.
OCEAN crew was waiting.
Video satellites are working.
Good.
Tanya, it's sharp visibility.
Now we will find them, Paul.
After launching the devices for observation,
having not enough energy to land on Mars,
cosmonauts have approached Phobos - Mars satellite,
where the gravitation is far smaller,
and have succeeded in landing.
Communicate with OCEAN
How's Phobos?
It's splendid. Now we are
going to observe it.
It's not necessary. Let's do it later.
Because you could be late for launching,
and thus could stay there for a week.
Remember, only 32 minutes left to launch.
We will contact you every 5 minutes.
- In two hours we will be on Mars.
- Hoping for a warm meeting.
Hurry up, we have a wind here,
very strong wind.
Be careful.
I repeat, we contact
you every 5 minutes.
Ivan, what's that shadow?
It's Centuria cosmonauts.
We are looking for them on Mars,
but they've landed here on Phobos.
Why do you not respond?
17 minutes left to launch, answer.
OCEAN listens to you, why no response?
What happened?
Tanya, give me Vassily, please
It's me.
Listen, they are on Phobos.
Who are "they"?
Cosmonauts from Centuria.
One of them is alive. Here are three
of us now, and the ship takes only two.
You understand?
Someone must stay on Phobos.
- Is there any possibility?
- Only to wait.
To wait?
How long to wait?
Why can't you decide, Ivan?
I must stay here.
You know it, I've never controlled
an emergency ship with so much loading.
We have no choice
It's not just the cosmonaut.
Think what you're risking.
A human from another planet.
Don't persist, Ivan.
If we'll be late for launching,
we all die.
Don't persist, Vanya.
Emergency ship,
where are you?
We can't see you.
Keep in mind - there's a storm,
dust-storm the whole way up to the equator.
Yes. To the equator.
Emergency ship.
I am emergency ship,
I'm going to land.
Your coordinates please, repeat.
Once again, repeat.
I am landing in the area of Starship.
Emergency ship, I am OCEAN,
please answer.
Contact with Emergency ship
could be not resumed.
We can't waste time.
I am Batalov, we've
landed in the area of the Starship.
The emergency ship has exploded.
Turn on radio beacon.
Turning on radio beacon.
Space maps, navigator is defining the
further route more exactly for the last time.
Guys, let's sing a song before launching,
We have 14 minutes.
My friends, I believe caravans of spaceships
will deliver us from a star to another star.
Our footprints will be left on
dusty paths of distant planets.
OCEAN, I'm Batalov, have
landed in the area of the Starship.
Andrey, answer. What happened?
Living and believing is wonderful.
We have unprecedented voyages in the future.
Cosmonauts and dreamers say
that apple trees will be in flower on Mars.
I became a friend of far stars,
Don't worry about me and don't be sad.
Tanyusha, I hear you.
Andrey, so why did you not answer?
Why?
I thought about the Earth,
about you.
I wrote that song for you.
Do you remember it?
All that I have done on the Earth, Tanya,
and what I planned to do...
No, don't say that. I don't want those last wills.
Don't you dare say that.
You will live, you must live.
Attention. People of the Earth. Turn on your Televisions.
That's Mars speaking. Now you will see...
... a daughter of the far star,
saved by your kindness and bravery.
She is with us, and breathes the Earth air,
though was born under a different Sun.
Do you hear us, Mr. Laungton?
They've come to us with an open heart.
You said that you'll be happy
if your expectations were wrong
You were wrong, Mr. Laungton.
Be happy.
Yes, you shouldn't die.
Only one hour we spent
in the dreams of Andrey.
But his companions, not in dreams but in reality,
are singing songs for the Universe.
Are singing and will sing
new and more new songs.
Where are you?
Come here.
You know what happened?
Hurry up.
Moscow speaks.
All the radio stations of
the Soviet Union are working.
This is information from
the Telegraph Agency of the Soviet Union.
According to the program of the
circumsolar space research --
spaceship OCEAN has been
launched to Mars.