MEMORIES OF MY MELANCHOLY WHORES
- Hello?
- Today is the day.
What day?
Tomorrow I'll be 90 years old,
and I want to give myself
a crazy love night with a virgin.
Oh, it's you, my sad sage.
Disappear for 20 years and now
you demand the impossible.
Is anything impossible for you,
dear Rosa Cabarcas.
SOMEWHERE IN THE CARIBBEAN
I'm ugly, shy, and
old-fashioned.
But using the power of
not wanting to be it,
I've managed to
play the opposite.
Until this sunrise
I've been able to show,
how I am through my
own free will,
although it serves only
to lighten my conscience.
A gentleman
should not spy.
And certainly not
on his own mother.
But she is so beautiful.
SUNDAY OF THE SAGE -Selective Memory-
- Can we trust our brain?-
GLORIFICATION OF THE OLD AGE
When did I realize that I'm old?
I was less than half as old
as I am today...
when one day...
Say one!
One!
How old are you?
44.
Nothing's wrong
with your lungs.
But what's that pain
when I'm breathing?
It's normal for your age.
Then is something
wrong with my age?
I see, you're a philosopher.
Philosopher.
God day.
No! Leave me!
Let me go!
The day has come.
Which day?
Tomorrow I'll be 90 years.
And I want to give myself
a crazy love night with a virgin.
Oh, it's you,
my sad sage.
Disappear for 20 years and now
you demand the impossible.
Is anything impossible for you,
dear Rosa Cabarcas.
Give me some time,
I'll see what I can do.
Listen, Rosa Cabarcas.
In my age an hour counts
like a whole year.
I just want a virgin,
and I want her tonight.
But why a virgin?
They say, it's rarely enjoyable.
It's not about having fun.
It's a question of life or death.
Virgins are out of fashion. What
do you want to prove to yourself?
Nothing!
I know very well,
what I'm able to.
I call back.
The moment she sensed
the sting,
she fell into a deep sleep.
That sleep overcame all
inhabitants of the castle.
The King and the Queen,
who had just entered
the vestibule,
fell asleep, and with them
all their servants.
Also the horses.
When the prince came
into the vestibule,
all inhabitants of the castle
had fallen asleep.
Good day.
Damiana?
Are you coming on a Friday?
Shouldn't the apartment
look nice for tomorrow?
Is it important?
Listen, my girl!
There's nothing to be afraid of.
An old man.
How should he harm you?
In one night you can earn more
than in four weeks in the factory.
Doesn't it sound good?
Alright!
Only one thing:
Think more of your sick mother
and less of yourself!
Yes?
You're a lucky fool.
I've found a lovelier goose
than you asked for.
That sounds good.
- But there's a problem.
- What?
As I told you, virgins are rare,
especially beautiful ones.
- And?
- I have doubts about her age.
I was just a kid when I
lost my chastity.
You don't risk anything, but who will
pay me for three years in prison?
No one goes to prison,
and last of all you.
The ones who could accuse you
are all your customers.
They wouldn't dare.
But you must pay me
2 pesos more.
No problem.
Well, come at 10pm.
Any problems?
None!
Senor! It is not an entrance.
It's an exit.
You're dressing like a bishop
for a ritual.
Maybe.
What do I know about
bishops' dressing habits?
When did you last
wear that suit?
Many years ago.
For a wedding.
Why?
It looks as if it's not yours.
Pardon.
Congratulations, my girl!
An exceptional choice.
Young man!
Can you come to the library
in ten minutes?
My love.
If you knew...
If only you knew,
how long I have longed for,
that you
should come through this door.
You smell like a perfumery.
Aqua de Florida. Only for men.
But I doubt you
just meet men?
That's true.
Will you be late?
One never knows.
Be careful. In a couple of hours
you won't be 89 anymore!
I know that myself.
Prominent wedding in
the Palomar de Castro family.
Well my love,
now there's no way back!
Young man, you shall know,
that we are honoured
to include
in our family
such a respectable journalist.
Do you have a cigarette?
33 years, 2 months and 17 days ago
I quit smoking.
I didn't think you were so old.
You're very kind, my girl.
I wish, I had a cigarette for you.
And then one over.
And one under.
And then one over again.
I have to go.
Ximena! A lady should
always wear underwear.
Some ladies are just
always ready for action.
But you don't belong to
that kind of ladies. Or do you?
I don't know.
Try it out!
I will, in a few days.
Couldn't you stay
a little longer?
I told you I have to work
for the Diario De La Paz tonight.
And I must prepare myself
for the wedding.
With you I would even
do it for free.
Over my dead body.
Why?
My principles. I always pay
if I want something.
In other words...
If I had asked you to lie
with me,
then I had to pay you?
No!
That's unrighteous.
Who said life is righteous,
Casilda?
Be careful, Maestro.
Rosa Cabarcas' house is not
the same anymore.
Thank you. Thank you.
God bless you, doctor.
Enjoy your fuck!
Thank you, my friend!
Until death parts us.
Will you honour these women?
Love them?
Take care for them?
Be faithful to them?
Till death do us part.
Only one at a time!
One... One at a time!
You can pay me next week.
You don't so old.
You do. But it suits you.
Really?
The years have even shined up
your dead horse-face.
Cause the horse changed stable.
You had a cock
like a galley slave.
How are you?
The only change since
we met last
is that my ass itches sometimes.
Always at full moon.
Lack of use.
I only use it for
chastely purposes.
Oh Maestro,
I didn't imply anything.
The girl! She has been
waiting since 10pm.
She is beautiful, clean
and has good manners.
But she's dying of fear,
because a girlfriend,
who ran away with a sailor,
bled to death within two hours.
Poor girl... lets go.
In addition to all that
she sews buttons in a shirt factory.
It doesn't sound so hard?
- That's what men think.
It's worse than woodcutting.
Help me!
The Bolero is life itself.
For whom are you mourning?
For my husband and my son.
They both left this world recently.
I'm sorry to hear that.
I gave her a mixture of valerian
and bromine. She sleeps now.
Wait here!
Yes, she sleeps.
Let her sleep as long
as possible.
Your night is longer than hers.
What do you think, I should do?
- You'll find out.
It's you who's called
the sage.
A tender bull before
the fight.
Shit!
What shall I do,
if you don't like me?
Take it easy, my girl.
Nobody will hurt you.
Delgadina, Delgadina...
The bed of Delgadina...
...is watched by angels.
Don't be afraid, my friend...
Very soon you won't
feel pain anymore.
The bell tolls anyway.
In the end...
of this crazy love night...
we'll be united
in the sleep.
You must know I love you all,
but one at a time.
Goodbye forever.
May God protect you.
Never again!
Tell me, Damiana.
What do you remember?
I didn't remember anything,
but your question makes me think.
I've never been in love.
I have.
I cried because of you for 22 years.
We would have been
a beautiful couple.
It's not a good idea
to say that now!
It doesn't please or
comfort me anymore.
For 22 years you fucked me,
once a month,
always the same way.
You won't believe me,
but thanks God
I'm still a virgin.
I wish you that you get
100 years old. Damiana
You have an appointment
in the cathedral!
We know, you're up there!
Come out!
If you can't behave like a gentleman,
show at least you're a man!
She trusts you, and is waiting.
You'll pay for this!
Ximena cries in the cathedral!
With this column...
I add a happy end...
to a long and straight life.
Who's there?
What happened to the girl?
Nothing.
You didn't even wake her up?
A woman will never forgive the man,
who doesn't honour her début.
Maybe she just played sleeping
out of fear?
She rather thinks
that you're unable.
I wouldn't like it leaks out.
I don't care. She is in such
a pathetic condition,
that no one will believe her,
neither sleeping nor awake.
I could make her
return the money.
Forget it!
No harm is done.
It helped me realize that I'm
not up for these things anymore.
Anyway, the girl is right.
I'm finished!
Thank you for the 90 years.
Reception of visitors
in the printing hall.
My dear Don Jerónimo,
You shouldn't...
I know. It is only
a little compensation
for all the words I have censored out.
from your columns over the years.
A censor does only
what his work is.
With Gods help!
You are a man
in his prime.
Thank you, Don Tulio. Almost. Almost.
Where's your column?
- This time there's none.
- Are you kidding?
I'm sorry, señor.
Impossible!
Think of it
as an exception, please.
I had a difficult night
and woke up numb.
Then you should have
written about it.
The readers would enjoy
to learn how life is with 90.
Perhaps it's
a delightful mystery.
Apparently she marked you
immediately.
How beautiful!
You still blush so elegantly.
It has certainly been
a phenomenal night. I envy her.
What I said before, was a joke.
- Here you are.
- I knew it!
I knew you wouldn't
abandon me!
Bravo, young man!
It would be wonderful with you,
because I need it.
Promise me that you
marry a white woman.
And that you'll have
at least three children.
The girl you call Florina,
just like me,
like my mother and
my grandmother.
Will you do that for me?
I'm happy about
the newspaper today,
because I thought
you were 100 and not 90.
Do you see me so weak?
But no!
I was surprised how young
you still look.
So good that you aren't
one of these dirty old men,
who play older so people think
they are still in good shape.
I have a gift for you.
What is it?
The girl.
Thanks, that's over.
I'll send her to your home,
wrapped in silk paper,
warmed in a lukewarm
herbal bath with sandalwood.
All for free!
Don't you dare.
You're right.
The girl was in a
poor condition yesterday,
because she had sewn on 200 buttons
with needle and thimble before.
And she was actually afraid that
it might become a bloody rape.
But now she's prepared
for the sacrifice.
Better for her.
You may be interested,
that the girl got up at night,
to go to the bathroom,
but you slept so deep that
she didn't want to wake you up.
Why are you wasting both yours
and my time with silly lies?
The truth is,
that she woke up in the morning
and you were gone.
The girl regrets.
Poor her, she's at my place.
I don't believe you.
Shall I sent her to you?
Damn, no!
No!
Typical censor Ortega.
This is absurd.
And what can I say?
You speak of justice?
After so many years, please.
Then I'm glad that
you listened to my protest.
Goodbye.
The crosses are not added by me.
I find them tasteless.
Allow me to say,
that you're the most indispensable
man I know.
I'm talking about
your termination.
Finished is finished.
No Maestro.
Didn't you read the newspapers?
So you ignore that your column
didn't appear?
It wasn't published?
No!
Don Jeronimo used his red pencil
all the way through it.
But in private,
I can tell you
that I am grateful for the
censor's mercilessness.
As long as you can hold
a feather
and use your typewriter,
we want you to go on.
You are a star among
our columnists and critics,
since you were almost a child,
We don't want that this star
burns out too early.
I urge you,
Don't leave the ship at sea.
The Archduke Franz Ferdinand
of Austria-Hungary
and his wife, the Archduchess,
were killed yesterday by gunfire,
while they visited Sarajevo.
Good evening. How are you?
What's new, Maestro?
The heir apparent
of Austria-Hungary is no more.
- What do you mean?
- They were murdered yesterday.
What does that mean for us?
Regardless of who you are,
death can get you anywhere.
That's not new.
No, but it's good to know.
Casilda!
I'm busy!
My brother is not joking.
He's attacking us.
I tell you, girl, I know
the governor very good.
If I want I can move people.
I can get them killed.
We're planning to let
someone disappear.
Don't you like your Casilda?
You'll see...
Of course I like my Casilda!
But I forgot that tonight...
I'll come back tomorrow.
I must go now.
Another time.
Ximena!
I've been dreaming
of this moment.
Funny you should say that.
And who are you?
I think she recognizes you,
but she doesn't remember.
What do you have in the basket?
- A cat.
May I see it?
Little Tiger.
How old is she?
Dont know.
She was just given me.
Because she looks very old.
Like ten years or so.
I think she was exposed
and has experienced a lot.
What is your work?
I'm a journalist.
- For how long already?
- For a century.
Take care of yourself.
You aren't 18 anymore.
Thank you for reminding me.
I had forgotten it.
Girl! Your bracelet!
Delgadina...
It's good, wife.
It's good, wife!
Sorry for the rage recently.
Don't worry.
I knew you'd call.
I want that the girl awaits me
like God created her.
As you wish.
But you'll miss the pleasure...
to undress her
piece by piece,
like old men love to do,
for whatever reason.
But I know it.
- Why?
Because every time
they get a little older.
Then tonight at 10 clock.
Before the little fish gets cold.
The virgin in her head...
carried her along on a litter,
the bells of joy...
tolled for Delgadina.
Delgadina,
my girl
that you are for me.
THE TIGER
EATS NOT FAR FROM HERE
Is anyone here?
I'm not talking to you.
Why are you so old already?
How old you are has nothing to do with
how long you have lived,
but how long you intend
to continue living.
Now I know
that it wasn't a hallucination,
but another miracle...
the first love of my life...
at the age of 90.
I don't understand how you can spend
two nights with this child,
without touching her.
Sex is just the consolation,
if you can't experience love.
It's your right not
to like her,
but damn behave
like an adult.
The case isn't that simple.
I'd have another one for you,
a little older,
also a virgin, good looking.
Her father wants to swap her
for a house.
But we will certainly
get a discount.
Shut up!
I want that girl again
and I want her always.
Without fail, without dispute
nor bad memories.
Good.
That must be what the doctors call
... senile dementia.
Senile dementia.
My mother owned them,
and before her my grandmother,
and long before that
my great-grandmother.
I want you to wear them.
There's a picture on the wall.
It's painted by Figurita.
A man we really liked.
The best brothel dancer
that ever existed.
And so good-hearted,
that he pitied the devil.
The woman in the picture
is a nun.
Figurita abducted her from
a monastery and married her.
I leave it here,
so it is the first thing
you see when you wake up.
I tell my readers,
I float between
wandering clouds,
carried by the love,
I feel for you,
with an extraordinary intensity,
I haven't known in my
life previously.
We've never published
hand-written texts. You know that.
The idea is absurd!
This isn't a conventional column.
These are love letters.
Love letters that everybody
can relate to.
Make no mistake, Marco Tulio.
The gentle savages own the future.
I think it was Delgadina, who...
Delgadina?
That isn't the girl's name...
- Don't tell me.
Well, finally she's yours.
I've never seen her face
and I don't know her real name.
For me she's Delgadina.
It sounds like anorexia.
I think it was Delgadina,
who wrote that verse about the tiger
on the bathroom mirror.
What verse?
"The tiger doesn't eat
far from here. "
No, she can't have done it.
She can neither read nor write.
Who then?
Maybe...
someone who died
in that room.
I don't need a full moon,
to set my bum on fire tonight...
Don't complain now!
Be happy that you still
have a butt that can burn!
Why don't you marry her?
You live already together
practically.
It will be cheaper
for you.
To be good or not
is the question at your age,
but you said it's too late
for you.
I've never been married.
Your beautiful eyes
didn't give me time for it.
I have a funny feeling that Delgadina
will grow up before her time.
That is normal.
A flower must blossom.
Sooner or later.
In one week is her birthday.
I never thought about
that angels have a birthday.
Delgadina,
we are alone in this world.
The elderly know best
how to love, my Delgadina,
because they have
nothing else to do.
The young ones on the other hand
at the beginning of their life,
care about their work,
about success and money.
For the elderly all that
isn't important anymore.
The past is forgotten.
What remains is nostalgia,
which is as pointless as sorrow
and love,
if it appears by chance.
Never again, I will wake up
with a bitter taste.
Never again, I will say I have
missed an experience.
And as long as my lips
can say "Thank you",
I will always honour,
what you have taught me.
Me, who has written and spoken
about everything in the world.
But misunderstood
the essence.
- What is it, Mary?
- Who is this Delgadina in reality?
I don't believe she exists.
Sure she exists,
but she lives in another town.
You have no right to speak,
if no one asks you.
Why do you think
she is from another city?
Because he wouldn't dare to publish
love letters in the newspaper,
if we could meet her in
the street.
- Where were you with the cat?
- At the vet.
- For what?
- The cat is ill.
And?
They want to euthanize her,
but they need you must agree.
- Why do they want to kill her?
- Because she is very old.
Well, do you agree?
I ask you, whether you agree,
that they euthanize her?
No!
You can kill her she is
threatening public health.
But not because she is old.
For a long time I slept early,
and when I woke up in middle of
the night, I didn't know where I was,
and for a moment
not even who I was.
Unfortunately, after eating,
I saw myself obliged,
immediately to leave my mother,
who tattled with the others in the
garden if it was a balmy night,
or in a small room, where they gathered
when the weather was bad.
My only consolation was,
when I went upstairs to sleep,
that mom would come
to give me a kiss,
when I lay in bed.
It was Isabel, who made
the snails cry.
Whose were they?
My poor son.
Get dressed and come with me.
I have a serious problem.
Isn't that J. M. B?
Help me dress him.
Nothing is more difficult
than to dressing corpse.
This isn't the first time I do it.
Someone must hold him.
Who could be convinced by
a body stabbed to death
in the suit of an
English gentleman?
- You are trembling.
- Because of her, Delgadina.
- Best you take her with you.
- You know I can't.
Then tell her to disappear
before someone comes.
I will.
Nothing will happen a journalist.
Not you either.
You're the only liberal, who has
influence on the government.
Delgadina!
Be quiet, sage!
The girl isn't there,
She's gone.
Better that way.
Best you disappear also...
Silence!
Do you know what time it is?
You're right.
She don't suit you.
- Is everything made up?
- According to my sources, yes.
Good.
If your sources are
really trustworthy,
Well...
This is the truth:
The young banker
wasn't murdered by rebels,
as they believed erroneously,
but by someone who knew him well.
THE TRUTH ABOUT
THE KILLING OF THE BANKER
Life is sad,
if we live without an illusion.
Have you seen the señora? - No.
Sorry,
have you seen the señora?
No, señor. We haven't heard
from her for a long time.
Have you seen the señora?
No. Really.
Sage, why don't you moderate
your letters a little?
While we think about how we comfort
all those readers who are in love.
Are you ill, maestro?
- No.
But I'm sick.
Sick with love.
Two unidentified corpses
of young girls are found
in the Amphitheatre.
- How old?
They are very young.
Maybe refugees
be from the inland,
hunted by the butchers
of the regime.
The condition invades us
silently to us stain with blood.
Not with blood, maestro.
With shit!
What do you want?
You wouldn't have done
that to me, Delgadina.
Damiana!
Take off your clothes
and roll around with me.
What do you do
if I say yes?
Your eyes have the same colour
as Delgadina's when she's angry.
Maybe you can help me
to find her.
Take it easy.
Come, come, come.
One, two...
Who's there?
A friend.
- I'm looking for the owner.
- There's no owner.
Open the door at least,
so I can get my cat.
There's no cat.
- Who are you?
- No one.
- How old was the girl?
- Maximum 16.
- No, 15 at most.
- And how did she look like?
- Why do you ask?
- I'm a journalist.
- She was tall and thin.
- Short, curly hair.
Is there a young girl here
who had a bicycle accident?
Yes, half an hour ago.
Can you identify her?
- Maybe.
- Follow me.
I... I'm not the one
you are looking for.
What would I've done,
if she had been there?
Excuse me, señor.
Is it you who writes the love letters
in the newspaper?
Are you back?
- Yes, I'm back.
- Where were you?
Take it easy!
I gave myself a break,
in Cartagena de Indias.
- And she?
- You shall take it easy.
- You have to wait.
- How long?
- No idea. I'll let you know.
- Wait! Give me a hint.
I have no hint.
- Damn it!
- Be careful!
You could harm yourself,
but worse you could harm her.
Give me at least an idea
of what's going on.
After all, we are accomplices.
Or not?
Calm down.
She's fine, she's waiting
for my call.
Right now that's all.
I won't say more!
Shit!
Today is the day.
Whore!
My God!
Let's go!
Now behave yourself like an adult.
What's wrong with you?
Everything has become clear for me,
Señora Cabarcas.
You have sold Delgadina's virginity
to one of your influential customers,
so that you go free
for the crime.
And then, a honeymoon threesome.
The other two in bed,
and you on the luxurious patio,
happy about your impunity.
Marvelous!
Jealousy always knows
more than the truth.
But the truth is different.
I was alone in
Cartagena de Indias,
while the scandal cooled down.
I came back yesterday.
The girl came at once to me,
in such a poor condition,
I bathed her for you, dressed her
and sent her to the beauty salon.
Her jewelry and clothes
are just cheap imitations!
Bawd and whore!
That's what you are!
Damn it!
Sage, go and look for the girl,
beg her pardon
and take care of her,
for now and forever.
No one deserves more
to be happy.
Fucking bitches!
I don't want to know
you anymore,
or any other whore
and least of all her!
Farewell forever!
God be with you.
Sage!
I'll send the bill
for the mess in the room.
It'll cost you dearly!
I inherited them
from my mother.
I've had them for
more than 60 years.
They have been purchased here
more than 100 years ago,
Please wait.
Don't tell your father,
that we've been here.
In this business it's important that
each purchase is recorded.
On February 7th 1882 has your mother,
Florina de Dios Cargamantos,
exchanged the mounted stones
in her earrings for imitations,
and sold the originals
to us for 20 pesos.
At least gold is gold
platinum and platinum.
We can offer you...
- No thanks.
I'll keep them,
in memory of an other
Florina de Dios,
whom I never met.
Mom!
Now I'm an old man.
Mother,
I always believed
that dying of love
happened only in poetry.
But today I found out
that it's not only possible,
but that I myself,
old and lonely,
am dying of love.
And I would have told you,
mother,
that I wouldn't exchange
the pleasure of my pain
for anything in the world.
Are you still doing it?
I've had trouble to remember names
and faces for years now.
But yours, Casilda Armenta,
I will never forget.
Not even after 40 years?
Not even after 40 years.
What are you doing here?
I escape from myself.
You look sad.
I am.
Come home with me.
Whenever you are mentioned
on the radio,
they pay tribute to you, because
people admire you so much.
They call you "Master of Love".
Imagine.
I think no one knew your charm
and your quirks as well as I do.
Seriously,
no one could have
tolerated more.
The truth is that I'm getting old.
Yes.
Your body.
But from what you tell me,
you're still a young man inside.
Do what you want.
But do not lose
that spirit.
There is no bigger misfortune
than to die alone,
Isn't it so?
It's enough.
It's enough, woman.
Woman!
Today is the day.
I haven't seen the girl
for more than a month.
But she must have recovered
from the shock that night,
because she has
found a new job
More pleasant and better paid
than sewing on buttons.
That can only mean
as a whore.
As a whore?
Then she'd be here.
How should I know
she's not here?
In this case it's better
if you don't know.
Or is it?
It would have been best
for the sage,
if he had never met
madam Rosa Cabarcas!
I'll look for her, I promise.
It's difficult but it
will not kill me.
Wait and you'll see.
My poor son.
I bless you.
This is the wrong moment,
mother!
Have you found her?
Not yet.
But I think I will
before the day ends.
If you find her...
Remember:
If you find her, forget all
grandfatherly sentimentality.
Wake her up,
and fuck her good and proper
with your donkey dick
that the devil rewarded you with
for your cowardice and pettiness.
Honestly. Don't die before
you've experienced the miracle,
to fuck out of love.
We'll see.
Bring me my girl tonight!
That's impossible.
Tonight,
for the Holy Father's sake.
Impossible.
Well, here you have her.
She wants to me?
You has to meet you,
- Does she agree?
- She must agree.
What do you mean?
Don't they call you the sage?
Don't be so stupid.
I'm not.
Then you're blind.
Don't you see the girl's
quite crazy with love for you?
Let's make a deal,
notarized.
The one who survives,
inherits everything from the other.
No.
Because when I die,
everything should go to the girl.
The girl doesn't count.
I take care of the girl and bequeath
her everything, yours and mine.
I have no one else
in this world.
I'm crazy out of love!
Not crazy, demented!
Maybe!
But today
the world is much better!
Do you hear me?