Quick… Run!
Get him in!
Come in, quick!
Boss, we can’t run away.
Ask the police for a car.
You’ll never get away, surrender at once!
I want a car, $20 million cash.
Hurry up, or I’m gonna kill her!
Let me go!
Calm down, I’m going to contact my superiors.
Okay, you have 20 minutes.
Stay calm.
20 minutes isn’t enough to prepare $20 million.
We can talk if you guarantee the safety of the hostages.
You have 30 minutes.
If I don’t see the car and
money in 30 minutes,
I’ll kill the hostages and
throw down on the street.
I’m going to kill one every 5 minutes.
We’ve blocked the scene.
No cars are allowed to drive past.
No casualties at the moment, report.
– Here.
– Thanks.
Yachi, the three criminals are
holding hostages on the roof,
we can’t get close.
Did you get their identities?
They should be from mainland China.
They won’t surrender, prepare for a raid.
It’s dangerous here, they have hostages.
Call for SDU.
Have you found Mumble yet?
Officer Chi, Mumble cannot be contacted.
Keep on looking for him.
Yes, Sir!
Mumble, you bastard!
Yeah, how is it now?
Sell 200,000 share of HK Bank, yes.
Good, thanks.
What perfume is it?
Coniba, good taste.
London stock market is bull,
Wall Street is soon down, I want—
I don’t care about London,
I care only about screwing.
I come here just to try to get a man.
Let’s go to toilet for a screw.
Directly and waste no time.
He’s coming too?
He’s into toilets.
Listen carefully.
We are to deal with three criminals.
They have one AK-47 and two pistols.
We must rescue four hostages, too.
We must guarantee safety of the hostages.
The criminals injured three of our men.
They have four girls as hostages.
It’s hard to get close to them.
Let me take over.
One lay $3000, overnight $5000.
The three criminals are scattered at the moment.
We have only three positions.
Get three snipers, and shoot at the same time.
I repeat, the three snipers must
shoot at the same time, understand?
Yes, Sir!
Remember, you mustn’t harm the hostages.
Go! Go!
How come Mumble is not here?
I want to see him too.
Damn, how come I have no luck at all?
Miss, your “Blow job.”
Sir, Mumble hasn’t arrived yet,
we’re missing one sniper.
Siu Ming, Siu Ming!
Yes, Sir.
You take the place of Mumble.
– Get changed!
– Yes, sir.
Siu Ming is only a driver, can he manage?
Of course, he arrested the
fleeing prisoner last week.
Hallo, it’s Yachi. Get him.
Ten.
Ten, ten! Drink!
What do you want?
Smoking.
I was asking him. What do you want?
Can you make it? Well, I can’t.
Cut me some slack.
– Crap, he’s gone.
– Hey!
Be quiet! Don’t move!
I said don’t move!
Locked on target.
Don’t move, or I’m gonna kill you.
Siu Ming on target.
If I succeed with this task, there’ll be promotion,
I won’t be just a driver anymore.
OK, men, let’s get ready to save the hostages!
I think we should wait for Mumble.
Look here, stop trying to fuck around.
In five minutes, the criminals
will start killing people.
Hallo? Mumble, where have you been?
I’ve just located the fleeing prisoner
so I wasn’t able to call you back.
I know his address already.
Go check tomorrow, I’m coming now.
That prisoner was arrested by our driver last week.
He’s being detained in custody.
We need one sniper.
Ask Officer Chi to wait for me.
He asked the driver Siu Ming to take your place.
Driver Siu Ming? He won’t make it.
He keeps drinking coffee, he has numb hands.
You’ll fire on my count of three.
I’ve found Mumble, he says—
I don’t give a damn.
Boys, watch out, we have only one chance.
We’ve got no time for another shot.
Get our men to rescue the hostages.
Ready, 1, 2…
Wait, Officer Chi, wait…
Are we shooting after 1, 2, 3 or after 1, 2, 3, Fire?
Come on, ready, 1, 2, 3…
Idiot!
Let go.
When I count three, you fire.
I didn’t say fire, stupid shit!
Thanks, Officer.
All ready.
1, 2, 3!
Oh, shit!
My God! Shit!
I’ve said we must wait for Mumble…
Well done, the criminals are dead, so are the hostages.
Siu Ming, why didn’t you fire?
Siu Ming, why did you
take a gun, you are a driver.
You drink too much coffee
and your hands are trembling.
I’ll drink less coffee.
Dare you talk back?
Thanks for teaching my men.
You’re welcome, Officer Chi.
We’re in the same team. Right, Siu Ming?
Bastard! I’ve been tolerate.
Did you enjoy it, touching my dead body?
I’ll kill you! I’ll cut your head!
– Molester! Damn!
– Come on, it’s all right.
Is it just a drill? But it’s so realistic.
Two vodkas, one dozen of beer.
Go on drinking.
You’re fired.
Can you smooth things over for me?
Why are they taking a drill so seriously?
They didn’t have to fire me, did they?
I’m a sniper, anyway.
Look, I’ve been champion for three years.
You’ll be taught a lesson without me.
Don’t call me back.
We don’t want to see you again.
Call you back? They’re celebrating your leaving.
Most of the policewomen complained
of you for sexual harassment.
There’re are so many works outside.
I’ll help you to find a job.
I’m fired, I’ve lost my pension.
How can I stand a chance?
There is a chance, my dream girl.
Why is the red light on?
How many guests?
Let’s go, that guy is scary.
Welcome.
This is my restaurant, come in.
Great, big bust!
I think this job suits you.
You didn’t have to cut it, it’s no newspaper.
This is the same like SDU.
It’s USD, driving garbage car.
You’re a good driver, it suits you.
What? It requires a graduation
and ten years experience?
I’m not up to it, man.
Sorry, I’ve cut more.
It’s an add for a bank director.
How many… guests?
Miss, what can bring you?
Orange juice, please.
Wow, so quick!
Miss, have you come alone in this rain?
I’ll drink the juice with you.
You must be upset.
Your eyes tell me you need a man for the night.
But your body tells me you
can’t accompany for tonight.
I don’t understand.
I understand now.
Bye-bye.
How many guests?
Hey, help me, please, smartie.
Hey, can you see them?
The guys over there.
They want to kill me.
If you help me, I’ll give you a kiss, OK?
Kiss me? OK, why didn’t you say it earlier?
Go away, this girl doesn’t like you. Shoo!
Excuse me, it’s none of your business.
I know, but this is his business.
What do you want?
Want to take advantage?
Don’t panic.
What did you promise me just then?
Did you help me just then?
You helped me, come on.
I’ll leave now, thanks.
I haven’t paid yet.
Here.
No need for so much.
It’s OK, sorry to bother you. Bye-bye.
Master, we need to pay too.
Wait, drink some more.
Drink, he knocked out the four guys
because they didn’t want to drink.
OK.
Monster, you took my girl!
How can you make it up? Look at me!
You’re wet, mind you’ll catch cold.
Why are you following me? I’ve paid already.
Have you paid for the taxi, too?
Let me walk you home.
No, thanks.
Those four guys haven’t left yet.
I’m afraid you’ll run into danger.
You are afraid? Go away if you fear, I fear nothing.
What about coming to my place?
Take shelter.
OK.
But you mustn’t regret.
Where do you live?
Upstairs of the pub.
Come on…
Let me think over.
Welcome.
Make yourself at home.
Hey, where are you going?
You ask me to make myself at home.
But no one asks me where
I’m going when I’m at home.
Want to go to bedroom? That is not my room.
I see, want a bath?
Do you have 100% feel?
Does it hurt? You regret now?
Do I look regretful?
I’m going to sleep now.
OK.
What a nice toy!
What are you doing here?
Mickey Mouse?
What? Don’t you like Mickey Mouse?
Hey, don’t play a fool since you came here.
Don’t scream!
Get off!
Don’t scream so loudly.
Go away, you pervert!
This is my home.
OK, I’ll go… don’t throw away my things.
I said you’d regret.
Did you crawled home from the back again?
No, I’m hungry after sleeping.
Give me some chicken wings.
Nothing!
You don’t have to shout at me.
Miss, what for you?
I’d like “Blow Job.”
Miss, it’s not drunk like this.
Thanks.
Terrific.
Give me “Sex on the Beach.”
Me too.
Hi.
My name is Lau Tang.
My name is Chow, Ben Chow.
Oh, Ben Chow.
You can call me, umm, Mumble.
You drink a lot.
Can’t I? What about you?
Depends who drinks with me.
Then… drink at my place, OK?
Think it over.
I don’t have to think it over.
Don’t think I’m a casual man,
I just want a chat tonight.
My secret drink, “Flaming Blow Job.”
It’s a big glass, how do I drink it.
Ready, 1, 2, 3.
Very tasty.
Got drunk with just one glass? What’s inside?
I put some gasoline in.
Don’t say I can’t bring here to senses, uncle Yee.
How do you raise your daughter?
You’ve spoilt Cher.
And you, you’re just a stupid uncle.
So many of you can’t talk to a girl, how come?
What’s going on? Did you ask
me to drink with your family?
You’re Mumble?
Listen, the girl at your place, that beauty.
Don’t touch her.
She’s daughter of Mr. Chiu
here, and also my cousin.
Mr. Chiu Sai Pak, I’ve seen you in the paper.
You look like father of Chow Wah Kien.
But sure you have lots of money.
The girl who snatched my place is your daughter?
She’s… quite good.
But she’s my fiancée!
You were an SDU member for two years.
You got fired! You’re useless indeed.
You must be up to something to enter SDU!
I was champion boxer in Harvard University last year.
Harvard University?
I was sweeping snow Harvard last year too.
All the guys who practised
kung-fu there couldn’t beat me.
Then let’s fight.
Do you want to fight or dance?
Small size clothes?
Took them from kids?
Mind your business.
Mr. Mumble, this boy is always talkative.
The reason why I ask Tang to take you here
is because I want you take Cher back here.
You’ve got lots of men, why don’t you find her yourself?
We sent some men.
They were kicked by some idiots out of the pub.
They should have ordered a drink.
You’ve got my birthday wrong.
Hey, you’ll get paid.
I’ll pay you $300,000 to bring her back.
But you mustn’t bully her.
Got it? It’s troublesome to chop you into pieces, you’re too big.
So little money? I must think it over.
No need to think.
You’ve just been fired from SDU.
The money is enough for living.
Oh!
I’m sorry.
Can I have another fork?
What are you sorry for?
I’ll pay you three million dollars if you make him hurt. It’s peg-leg.
Come on, take $300,000 deposit first.
Remember to shut the door.
Got it, I will.
Hallo. Wait a second.
Mr. Chan, your cousin wants you.
Fighting is interesting.
Cher, I knew you’d call me.
Why don’t you come home? It’s just a quarrel.
It’s bad, you know this makes me lose face.
Everyone knows we’re getting married soon.
Hey, will you stop it a while?
First thing, I’ve never promised to marry you.
You can’t just turn me down.
Your dad is my boss.
He’s for our marriage, just do as he wishes.
OK, after our wedding, I promise
I’ll let you do whatever you want.
Don’t think I’ll go and beg you.
You know I’ve been busy.
OK, I have an interview with a journalist at Taiwo Restaurant today.
You can come and make it clear,
I’ll wait for you.
We’ll have good days after marrying that bitch.
We can make a fortune when we’ll take up the shares of those two geezers.
Right, you have a point, Mr. Chan.
Who taught you such lousy words?
Good morning.
What are you doing? That’s horrible.
Some exercising.
It looks more like a pervert exercising.
Let me take you for breakfast.
Thanks, but I’d lose my appetite
if I’ll eat with you.
Bye.
Mind your steps. Catch you later.
This is restricted area,
no cars stop here at this hour.
Let me drive you.
Please.
When the journalist arrives,
wait for me in the next room.
Don’t scare him.
Yes, Sir.
Mr. Chan, what would you like?
I eat anything.
What are you doing here?
I’m the journalist, I’ve come to make the interview with Mr. Chan.
Hands up, turn around.
Why? Why did you take the negatives out?
Get new one! Mr. Chan is over there.
Thanks.
Mr. Chan, I’m the journalist of What Magazine.
I’ve seen many reporters,
but you’re the most clumsy one.
You’d be an editor if you were smart.
But you’ll become one after the dinner. Sit down.
Thank you, Mr. Chan.
Why are you following me?
I’ve come to meet my cousin.
Meet your cousin? Good.
He’s a boss of Mafia.
Mafia is fine.
You must have seen too many Mafia films.
Money at hand after this task.
No, I must let her cousin know
I’ve brought her back.
Frankly speaking, I didn’t exaggerate in that.
Didn’t I say… I’m like a hero.
There are no heroes,
what we count on is power.
Right.
I can tell you didn’t get pointed
at the head with two guns.
You only think what will happen in films?
I was really once got pointed at with two guns.
Where did that happen?
Holland.
Luckily, I reacted quickly enough.
I pointed at him with four guns,
and he wetted his trousers.
That’s why I’m never scared when
others point at me with guns.
What did he point at me with,
I must point at him, but not massage.
Shall I take you a photo?
I’ll leave now, thank you.
You’re not going to force me into marriage.
If you’ll marry me against my will, I’ll kill you.
Why don’t you say something?
You’ve killed Mr. Chan!
I didn’t do it.
My, my. This is no way for four
men to pick up a girl.
Still want to shoot? Put it down.
Let me! Help, Mumble!
You can do it now?
You couldn’t do that in the morning.
Well, fighting doesn’t need exercise.
Now cousin is dead, what shall I do?
Go have a tea, police will handle it.
My cousin died horribly.
Talk to me, so I don’t have
to keep thinking about him.
You kept saying you knew nothing on the police station.
How come you know nothing?
I really know nothing. You won’t understand.
Your cousin was killed in a public place, surrounded by his men.
That assassin must have been skilled.
Nerves of steel, so he wouldn’t give himself away.
Have you knocked on the door?
What are you doing here?
Do you know each other?
I’ve come to see how you are.
It’s going to happen you sooner or later.
Cousin was like you, a Mafia
member, now he was killed.
Do you want to end up like him?
You mustn’t talk to me like this, I’m your dad.
Are you talking back?
OK, I’ll be quiet, if you don’t like it.
You’re a boss of Mafia, you’re the boss.
You’re my daughter, you must obey me.
What manner is this? I’m talking to you.
Are you hot? Go inside, it’s air-conditioned.
OK…
Mumble, sorry for arguing at your place.
It’s OK, just make yourself at home.
Make yourself at home!
Oh, right.
Here’s a cheque of $300,000.
Cher’s cousin paid me to
take Cher home, but I failed.
He’s dead now, and it can’t be cashed. So I’ll give it to you.
Don’t worry, all cheques signed by me can be cashed.
That bastard gave you $300,000?
Take this money.
Don’t take my daughter home for the moment.
Why?
Sit down first.
She can’t come home now.
I want you to protect her,
I must check Simon’s case.
You have lots of men, why do you want me to protect her?
You’re a good bodyguard,
even though you’re perverted.
Don’t try to touch her,
or I’ll have you castrated.
Don’t panic. Be gentleman and you’ll make it.
What do you think? Is it a deal?
Mumble, don’t disappoint me.
You’ve really made yourself at home.
Let’s go.
Get me an apple. Cher, I’m leaving.
You haven’t closed door.
I invited you to my place
before but you refused.
Now you’ve come here yourself?
Mind your fingers.
What did Chiu Sai Pak talk to you just then?
Oh, so you’re investigating Chiu Sai Pak.
OK, what is about him?
He belongs to a Mafia.
I’m investigating him for a long time.
Simon was killed today.
Those men you beat at Taiwo
Restaurant were killed too.
Are you suspecting me?
No.
Would you keep an eye on him for me?
I will owe you one shot.
Hey, you owe me five shots,
you haven’t paid yet.
Don’t worry, I’ll pay you all at one time.
OK, I didn’t see anything, go on.
Hi.
Hey, you can’t just go out to disco, can you?
Listen, you’re so persistent, but you won’t get me.
Do you think I want to follow you?
It’s only my job. Your dad hired me as your bodyguard.
I hate father’s bodyguards.
One person.
Thank you. Bye.
Sir, you can’t go in.
Why?
This is not YY, this is QQ.
Oh, Ladies only, for $150?
I’ll pay you $100 extra.
So many girls? Great!
Hi.
I haven’t seen you here before.
It’s my first time here.
No wonder! What will you drink?
Anything except “Flaming Blow Job.”
You’re charming.
You too, let me kiss you.
It’s OK, I love both ways.
You’re open minded, I like it.
Oh, you are…
Yeah, I am like you.
No, I don’t like men.
Hey!
You look familiar.
Your coughing is familiar too.
Ten.
No, you know nothing but ten!
Ten…
Hey, no men are allowed here? Don’t you know?
I know, but I own this place.
You can’t run away, it’s my place.
OK, I’m gonna leave.
Stop smoking, you keep coughing.
Suit yourself.
What do you want? Leave me alone.
Wanna fight our boss?
Listen, get out of here at once!
What did you say?
If my dad learns this, he won’t let you off.
Everyone knows you’re in bad terms with your father.
Are you threatening me?
Do you know who I am?
You’re an octopus!
Bitch, dare you swear at me? I’m Little Chong.
So what? I’m Supergirl,
never heard about me?
Help!
Will you try to pick on a tall woman?
Mumble, kill them!
Who is this woman?
I have never seen her, boss.
Faggot, I’ll sodomite you
if you won’t go away!
Do as you please.
You like this, too?
Kill him!
You think we’re some tribesmen?
Throw all at once!
Take them.
Good, we can return them in supermarket.
Nothing more?
It’s our turn now.
Let me take a look, it’s all right, no bleeding.
It’s OK, stop crying.
Why did you take me here
first thing in the morning?
We didn’t come here to drink anyway.
Come on.
Why did you come here?
Well, I came to see the kids.
When will your boss arrive?
Very soon.
Boss, Cher is here.
No!
Principal, go get ready.
Yes.
I run this orphanage.
It’s a surprise from me.
You all lie to me?
Yachi, what are you doing here?
What’s going on here so early in the morning?
I’m your assistant.
Why don’t you talk to your father? Speak to him.
Dad, why won’t you tell me anything?
I didn’t have a chance to talk to you.
You’re right, I should retire now.
Will you retire?
Yeah, boss does listen to you.
But you’re alike, you are both stubborn.
I’ve set up a charity fund.
I’ll announce it in a banquet next week.
I won’t be in this business anymore.
Will you smile finally?
You never smile at me.
Dad, I’m sorry.
I keep losing temper to you.
It’s good you know,
let’s not lose temper again.
My dream girl!
You two look alike, are you twins?
Kid, how old are you?
Fire!
Stay calm.
After him!
Wait!
Let him be.
I know who was that man, he killed cousin.
I’ve found out that Dragon Club
sent an assassin to kill Simon.
I’ll send our men to handle them.
No, let police to do it.
Father is right, we mustn’t
get involved in this anymore.
Right.
Why don’t you chase him?
What about you? You’re police.
That assassin failed to kill them both.
He won’t just let it be.
He’ll be after me now, too.
Wake up, jog with me.
It’s safer at home.
Killers don’t get up so early.
Hey! Faster! Are you awake? Poor you.
Be sharp! Come on, run, faster!
I can run as fast as you can.
Let’s contest.
One, two…
You’re so slow, run faster.
Not bad.
You’re fooling around.
Mumble, help! Mumble!
Just in time. Go.
Open the door! Let me go, open the door!
Mumble can’t protect you anymore, we’ll protect you.
I hate you!
Faster.
It’s fine.
Hey, can you drive?
I’m used to sitting on the other side.
This door won’t open, what should I do?
This door won’t open either.
Don’t press on me.
Don’t move.
What can I say?
Did you have to kidnap this?
Mumble!
What’s going on?
Why are you after me?
Leave the girl and get out.
Don’t shoot!
I didn’t see anything.
I didn’t see you killing.
What do you want?
I’m waiting for someone.
I’ll kill you when he comes.
He’s waiting for me.
Mumble!
Now you’re going to die.
This is dead end, you have nowhere to run.
Yes, I’m waiting for you.
I want to have a duel with you
without anyone disturbing us.
Why do you want to fight?
You’re going to lose.
If you hadn’t run away last time,
you’d have been killed.
I wonder if someone sent you to kill Cher.
Last time, you weren’t alone,
that’s why I ran away.
She’s just unlucky that I have to kill her.
Because she saw me killing Simon.
OK, let go of Cher, and I won’t tell others you’re that lousy.
You won’t tell anyone if I kill you.
What? Then I’d better stay away from you.
To be precise, is this position OK?
You’re asking for it.
This way.
My turn now.
I said you would die.
A sniper needs only one shot.
A master needs only one bullet.
Don’t be scared, he can’t kill anymore.
Really? I want you to hug me.
Bastard!
What happened?
Show yourself!
I know you want to kill me.
I didn’t want him to kill you, because you’re mine.
Why do you want to kill me?
Because you killed Shek Chung.
You’re Shek Chung’s daughter?
Why did you kill my father?
Mumble didn’t kill him.
His death had nothing to do with Mumble.
Mumble just wanted to help him.
Monster!
Speak.
Years ago, Shek Chung used
to be a sniper in police force.
It was him who taught
Mumble shooting skills.
In order to get money for your brain operation,
he got bribed by Fook Ying Gang.
At last, are you coming to arrest me?
I was wrong.
Just as Mumble and Shek Chung were talking,
Shek Chung decided to commit
suicide — he cut his wrist.
When Mumble saw that
Shek Chung was bleeding badly…
What are you doing?
If a good sniper can’t use a gun a again,
then he might as well be dead.
Why do you want to kill yourself?
Have you thought of your daughter?
It’s for the sake of my daughter.
If I commit suicide, insurance company won’t pay.
Please, hold this gun.
And tell them I resisted to be arrested.
Why?!
He was just corrupted, you didn’t have to kill him.
He was your teacher.
His blood stained Mumble’s clothes.
That’s why Mumble always wears the red shirt, in memory of Shek Chung.
And the blue jacket to cheer
himself up, like the blue sky.
What about the black trousers?
Black trousers won’t get dirty easily.
Monster, you’re bastard!
You should believe Mumble.
I do, I’ve tried to kill him six times, and he’s wearing this every time.
Please, mind the door.
Wai Heung.
Mumble, you’re great.
The killer is dead, you don’t need my company. I’ll see you home.
No way. You must go to the
banquet with me tonight.
Sir.
Thanks.
How do you do?
This is Mr. Leung.
Nice to meet you.
Sorry, Mr. Leung.
Dad, Mumble has arrived.
You mustn’t behave like a pervert.
You’re beautiful.
Do you wear something different today?
What’s wrong? Does it suit me?
$380 for a day.
Put it away.
I’ve rented it from Jordan Road.
It’s reasonable.
Cheaper than orange juice.
You don’t need to pay tips.
Excuse me.
Cher, do you remember my son?
No, I don’t.
It’s John.
You used to play together.
Did we?
He’s just graduated from UCLA,
medical college.
He’s smart.
John, talk with Cher.
How are you?
Dear guests.
Shake hands.
Welcome to the ceremony of setting up Cher’s Charity Fund.
Please, be seated.
Cher, we…
Please, take a seat.
Excuse me, I have to go to my Dad.
All right.
Wait for me.
First, I must explain you the reason of setting up this fund.
We aim to help the poor orphans and children without care.
We must thank Mr. Chiu Sai Pak
who donated $750,000,000.
Please applaud.
Ladies and gentlemen, please help yourself to dinner.
I don’t need you.
What are you looking for?
Nothing.
Thank you very much for coming.
What are you laughing.
Nothing, eat on.
Cheers.
Well done!
Well I never! I could be your mother, and you’re still so perverted?
Sir, you look strong. Can you help me open it?
No problem.
Mum, are you all right?
Dad, I’ll go over, help yourself.
Don’t scare me, help her to take a rest inside.
You didn’t have to beat my mum,
just because she turned you down.
Is the girl coming for me?
Can I have the first dance with you?
I’ve just hurt someone, it’s not too good.
No worries, her son is a doctor.
You’re right.
Oh, lucky man.
Cher, you are really beautiful tonight.
You should have the first dance with your dad.
It’s OK, he’ll understand.
I don’t know why, but I’m starting to have feelings for you.
It’s all right.
Do you love me, too?
Yeah.
Are you serious?
Miss, Mr. Chiu asked for you to cut the cake.
All right, go inside.
Yes.
Go cut the cake. I’ll come in a while.
Let me think it over.
Hurry up.
Sure.
If you want, just tell…
Cher, I’ve retired, just as you asked me.
Why are you still upset?
No, I’m very happy today.
It’s because of Mumble.
No.
You can’t lie to me.
Really? You’re so clever.
Go back!
Protect my daughter.
Yes, sir.
Who are they?
I don’t know.
Take my daughter away.
We don’t stand a chance against them, sorry.
Don’t shoot, we surrender.
Fire.
Run if there’s an opening.
No, we must run together.
Cher, get off and run!
Dad, run!
Dad…
I’ll protect you.
Fall back.
Your dad got shot, and is bleeding.
I’m not going to stop his bleeding.
With his weight, he’ll die in three hours.
Don’t try to call police.
He’ll die in ten minutes if I’ll shoot him again.
So you’re the boss behind the scene?
Don’t try to harm him anymore!
OK, where do you want me to go?
You just want money.
You didn’t need to send so many guys just for us.
Why are you doing this?
Just for revenge.
I’ve fought so hard for you.
My legs are crippled, but I never blamed you.
Your nephew was getting married with your daughter.
Did you think that bastard loved her?
He just wanted your shares.
So I sent the assassin to kill him.
I’m doing all of this for your good sake.
Did you kill him?
Then you tried to kill Cher for my good sake too?
No, I never wanted to kill her.
She happened to see the assassin,
so he had to kill her.
You’ve done so many evil things,
and you’re still making excuses?
You’re mad!
I’ve done evil things?
You’ve been the one who was smuggling, remember that please.
You can never become a charitable person.
You’re mad.
Well, I can be mad.
But why did you bring me here?
I don’t want to see you throwing money out.
I want you to give all your properties to me.
OK, I’ll give them all to you, but you have to give me a pen!
Are you satisfied now?
Mr. Chiu, even though you’ve signed,
all your properties are jointly owned by you and your daughter.
Now, we need your daughter.
You bastard!
You don’t have to call for Cher.
My signature is valid on everything.
I’ve called Cher.
But she’s with Mumble now.
I’m afraid he’ll come with her.
He was once my man.
I have nine others here.
I can handle him easily.
All right then.
I’m just asking you to deal only with him.
It’s dangerous for them to deal with Mumble, too.
But they might disappear after this incident.
So we must get reasonable money.
Do you want to raise your reward?
You’ll get too much money.
You’ll get $5 billion, I just want 10%.
Pay me now if you agree.
Money is not important, we must cooperate.
OK, boys.
I’m repeating, this is not a drill. Come on.
I’m repeating, this is not a drill.
You know your positions, you know what to do.
Kill that pervert, kill him on sight. Understand?
Yes, sir!
Go!
Number 1, the girl has just arrived.
Number 2, what do you see?
Number 2, that girl has just walked past.
Number 3, lock the door.
Dad!
Dad, does it hurt?
No, but why did you come here?
They dare not harm me.
You’re cruel!
Sign it and you can go home with your father.
Don’t do it.
Dad, money is not important.
I just want to live a peaceful life with you.
Go away.
I hope you let Cher go after she’ll have signed it.
Dad, bear it, we will go home soon.
I’ve spotted Mumble.
Kill him! Now!
I’ve thought it over.
I wanted to split up our ways in a peace.
But I think it’s not a good idea.
Are you turning against me?
Mr. Chiu, sorry.
Driver Siu Ming?
Mumble, where are you?
Mumble wants to play with us.
Don’t disappoint him. Move!
Kill Mumble when you’ll see him.
Yes, sir!
It hurts…
Dad, bear it. It will be all right.
We’ll get home soon.
No, I can’t walk anymore.
Shoot if you see anyone.
Mumble, go ahead.
I’ll stay here and shoot whoever I see.
Dad, let us kill that bastard.
Are you still fooling around
at this critical moment?
If you want to live, you should help me.
What is it?
Mumble!
They have escaped from the black hole.
We’ll be right there, they can’t get away.
Why do you wear the sunglasses
in such darkness?
Watch out!
Run, quick!
Eddie, we’re moving to the position 2!
What’s that thing on your arm?
It’s a .44 Magnum, modified.
Without the metal support,
the recoil can break your arm.
Watch out!
– Hide yourself.
– Dad, quickly get down.
You’ve got still one more gun.
Eddie, why?
Dad, calm down, you’ll hit Mumble.
Have you fooled around long enough?
Call Officer Chi.
Yes. Reporting, we’ve caught Mumble.
Kill him now!
Eddie, are you all right?
Come, this is the exit.
Fuck!
Get in the position 1 to block Mumble. Quickly!
It’s locked, what should we do?
Mumble, stay away.
Doesn’t work.
Do you think we’re in a film?
Do you think this is a TV show?
OK, doesn’t work.
Let’s kill them.
What’s the matter?
What’s going on there?
Even a bullet-proof vest is useless.
What?
Our Father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on earth as it is in 1997.
Giving up so soon?
Oh my God!
Jesus Christ!
Holy shit!
Damn you, Mumble! I’m gonna kill you!
Monster, take them away first.
Mumble!
Officer Chi, you have disgraced your family,
the Royal Hong Kong Police and the special unit.
Shut up!
No, you shut up.
Officer Chi, the gig is over.
Where do you think you can run away?
I can go everywhere.
I must remember to thank you for killing them.
The money belongs only to me now.
If you want, I can give you a share.
Fine, let’s get the money from an ATM now.
Fuck it! You’re just talking bullshits!
Your .44 Magnum is modified.
You can’t shoot without the metal support attached to your arm.
Maybe not.
Just be careful not to shoot the other two by mistake.
Mumble, another special mission again?
Got it, it’s another drill again.
I know what to do.
Hi.
That really hurts.
I’ve found out they’re Yee’s accomplices,
but wouldn’t expect to be kidnapped here.
Mumble.
Why did you come back?
I took Mr. Chiu away,
but Cher has disappeared.
Cher is over there.
Dad, Mumble.
Don’t come over.
Let Cher go now!
Since you’re all here, I can
get rid of all of you at once.
Mumble, put the gun down.
If you’ll keep making problems,
I’m going to kill her.
Hey, it’s fun to make threats,
I’d like to play the criminal part, too.
Monster.
Huh, you’re using a human instead of gun support.
Aim, one, two, three.
Well deserved.
Mum… Mumble.
What are you doing?
Don’t move, or I’ll kill her.
Let her go now, and I won’t chase you.
Let her go!
Nonsense!
Cher, I hope you remember…
we had a “good time” at the Peak.
Don’t move.
Don’t come over, or I’ll kill him.
Still don’t have enough?
Is the drill over?
Yes, it’s over.
It was like a real thing.
You’ll get promoted by three ranks,
no need to quit drinking coffee.
I have already quit drinking coffee.
I’ll treat you to coffee
if you get promoted.
Mumble, I want to thank you.
Your skills with gun are amazing.
You are always day-dreaming.
I don’t know if you can be serious.
but I really don’t mind it.
Think it over carefully, don’t act impulsively.
Just pay me back for rescuing you and your father.
I’ve already thought it over, I won’t regret it.
Today, you appear grown-up…
No, you are really grown-up and mature.
You’re not the girl I met in the café.
I didn’t like that girl.
But now, I…
I’m over 18, you don’t need to worry.
I have to think about it.
I really have to think about it some more.
Dear Mumble.
You’ve done so much for me,
but all I can do is just thank you.
I will cherish this relation with my father.
I might never meet you again,
but I will miss the happy days we spent together.
You have decided to live without me.
I respect your decision.
I’m studying music with Dad at Harvard.
He studies music seriously.
I hope you get whatever you wish for.
Mumble Private Detective Agency is open, come.
10% discount for adultery cases.
Is that a joke?
Wow, did you dress so sexy
for taking the subway?
If I’m not dressed sexy,
how can I catch perverts?
Mission Possible?
Yeah, Mission Possible. I caught some
on the way from Central to Tsun Wan.
Come on.
Go, go.
Hurry up!
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, J, Q, King.
Great, exactly the same number
of times you owe me.
You’re not catching perverts,
you’re seducing them.
Hey, is it really you?
I almost couldn’t recognise
you with those glasses.
I couldn’t get another pair like that type,
so I’m wearing my mum’s.
New car?
No, I crashed your car last time,
so this one is to repay you back.
Good friend.
I’ve paid only $5,000 for the first instalment,
you’ll have to pay $4,500
a month for the next 4 years.
Old Chiu paid me $300,000 to open my agency.
It’s like a bad dream.
You can economize.
There is… my dream girl!
Wait for me, beautiful girl.
Hi.
Fucking gay, don’t follow me, or I’ll kill you!
Oh, Wai Heung.
Mumble!
What is it?
Hey, still trying to run away?
Damn you, pervert. Come!