(gentle music)
(dramatic music)
(speaking in foreign language)
- You have done well.
Merlin's spell is weakening.
I can feel the bonds on my cage breaking.
- Your suggestions were useful,
the theories all check out.
Now it's just a matter of practical work
setting up the machines.
A few days, a week at
most, and we'll be ready.
- Excellent, hmm.
Good.
There had better not be any mistakes.
- We have a deal.
As long as you stick to it,
there won't be any mistakes.
- Of course.
(woman gasping)
(man gasping)
(man groaning)
- What's happened? How is it going?
Is Maxwell ready for us?
- Don't grief, Mother.
Why don't you give me a
chance to catch my breath?
This isn't easy, you know.
- Wine, bring wine, quickly.
You, Guinevere, revere
us and pass that wine.
- Yes, wine, yes, yes, yes.
(Merlin gasps)
Merlin.
- Merlin.
- Stop him!
- [Guinevere] Run, Merlin!
- [Mordred] Help me up.
Get him.
(men screaming)
- Are you all right?
Would you like something to drink?
- Oh, no, thank you.
Did I get through to
the spirits this time?
- I'm afraid not, mother's
being a little stubborn.
- I'm sorry, Ms. Maxwell,
I don't understand,
normally I get through
without any trouble.
- Don't worry yourself,
Megan, we'll try again.
Hi, Kate, how are you?
- Fine, thank you.
- Kate!
- It's all right.
- Kate, that was not very polite.
- Well, I don't like her and I
don't like her upsetting you.
- That is no excuse for bad manners.
- I am too old for this.
Oh, no!
- [Lancelot] Guinevere.
- Lancelot.
- What's going on?
- [Guinevere] Merlin's here.
- Merlin?
- Yes.
- You're joking?
- No.
Maybe he's come to free us.
- Free us after all this
time, what's changed?
- Maxwell.
- Maxwell?
Come on.
- Hello, Merlin.
Caught you like a rat in a trap.
- Merlin!
Merlin, come on, Merlin!
- After them.
(tires screeching)
- Well, Richie, what do
you think of our mountains?
Bet you got nothing like them in Iowa,
you'll just love it here,
there's never a dull moment.
Pity your father isn't here.
- Everlyn, Hank's dead,
he didn't decide to go to Hawaii.
Oh, no!
(vehicle honking)
- Stupid woman.
(water splashing)
- Merlin.
- [Merlin] Guinevere.
- Come on, we've all got jobs to do.
(car rumbling)
- Everlyn, look.
(woman groaning)
- Come on, Merlin, stop being so pompous.
- Pull it, Merlin, we need to start,
we don't have much time.
- Thank you.
- You are welcome.
- Wow.
- What are you doing?
- Keeping an eye on Mordred.
- What, after all this time,
don't you ever give up?
- How can I, my spell is
breaking, dark forces stir,
the world balance is on
the brink of disaster.
- What, again?
- Yes, again.
- Just because you've
given up fighting Mordred
doesn't mean we all have.
(man screaming)
- What, come on, quick, we must go now.
- [Merlin] This way, Guinevere, come on.
- Well, that's taken care of them,
but I don't know how
to get you out of here.
- That's all right, I
can take care of myself,
now that I have a few
moments to concentrate.
- Can't you take me with you?
- I'm sorry.
So far the spell's only weakened,
it still holds you all here.
- But I so want to see the sky again.
- Oh, I think you might.
In fact, if I can't
stop Mordred and Maxwell
from completely wrecking my spell
everyone here will see the sky.
Now, I must go.
- [Guinevere] No, wait.
- What, what is it?
- How's Arthur?
- Well, asleep, I hope.
Though, the spell holding him
is weaker than the spell holding Mordred.
To tell you the truth, I don't know.
I must check.
Thank you.
- Give him my...
Love.
(people screaming)
(Everlyn laughing)
- Mary, dear, you remember Merlin?
- Oh, yeah, hi.
- I'm too old for this.
- [Everlyn] See, dear,
nothing's changed, welcome home.
- How are you feeling now?
- Better.
What's going on outside?
- Everlyn nearly run down Merlin.
He was out jogging in his underwear.
See you later, mum.
- Bye.
(drumming)
- What do you think, Gawain?
The young beast is large.
- Aye, sire, and stronger.
- Strong, but slow.
And my muscles ache for action.
- Had we better just lie low
until we know where we are?
- Get the others ready.
Come on, get him, get him.
(truck wheezing)
(truck honking)
No.
No, Gawain, stop.
(men screaming)
- The beast didn't feel a
thing, it just kept going.
Sire, look.
- [Arthur] What is it?
- What's going on there?
- I don't know.
- You don't think that...
- What?
- They will attack us.
- You don't think it could
be the big beast's cub.
- Aye, maybe.
- I think we'd better go.
- Okay.
- Well, go on, hurry up.
- All right.
- Hurry up.
- I'm doing my best.
- Pump it, they're coming down here now.
Why don't you put it in gear?
- Merlin.
- Arthur.
(somber music)
- Everything okay, honey?
- Yeah, great.
- I know it's hard, Richie,
but give things a go,
you'll like it here, I promise.
- I'm hungry.
- [Merlin] Everything's wrong
and if you're awake,
Mordred's almost free,
and the whole village thinks
I'm some crazy old man.
- [Arthur] Hurry up, Merlin.
- [Merlin] I'll be with you in a minute.
I'll be with you in a minute.
Dammit.
It's Maxwell I blame,
meddling in things she doesn't understand,
her damn experiments
messing up all my spells,
then look at my robes, no one knows which-
- Stop dithering, Merlin, and pick one,
they're all the same.
- You and your damn fool
knights could've killed me.
- I still might if you don't
tell me what's going on.
- What do you remember?
- Camelot.
Lancelot.
Guinevere.
Mordred.
Stonehenge.
I was dying.
- So you were.
Mordred had all but won.
Our army was routed,
it's remnants dispersed.
We were trapped.
(people shouting)
Only the power of the stones
was keeping Mordred at bay.
(lightning crackling)
Mordred's magic was too strong.
- Can you hold, Merlin?
- No.
They come.
- Why do they wait?
- They wait for their lord.
Death.
Mordred.
(horse whinnying)
- Ah, Arthur.
You look surprised, Merlin.
Did you really think your pathetic efforts
could keep me out?
- Leave, Mordred, you'll destroy us all.
(Mordred chuckling)
- [Merlin] I thought I
learned to control the spell
but what cared he if
he destroyed the world.
- Looks like we were just in time.
- In time to die, witch.
- You fool.
Haven't you learned anything yet?
Your day is over, you're finished.
- Guinevere.
- Yes, that's right, Arthur, Guinevere,
and she's mine now, she's all mine.
- No.
- [Merlin] The powers I hold in my staff,
I released at Mordred,
but in vain.
- Bravo, Merlin, bravo.
Just a few days ago, that
blast would've killed me,
but not now.
Not now.
I have this.
- Excalibur.
How did you?
- Never trust a lady,
Arthur, least of all a queen.
- What?
- Arthur.
What's a queen to do on long cold nights
when her husband is away playing king?
- Lancelot.
- [Mordred] Explain to
your king, Sir Knight.
- [Merlin] All seemed lost.
Again, I released the energies
I had gathered at Mordred,
but Mordred had Excalibur.
- Merlin, hold.
Hold.
- [Merlin] No, I can't.
- You'll never defeat Excalibur, Merlin.
No!
- No!
- For the dragon!
- Stonehenge was broken.
(thunder cracking)
It's been broken for 1500 years.
- 15?
- Just be grateful that
Lancelot did what he did.
- Lancelot.
I'll kill him.
- I trusted him with
my wife and Excalibur.
- He saved your life.
I couldn't destroy Mordred.
He's too powerful, but
thanks to Lancelot's little diversion,
I managed to banish Mordred
to another dimension.
- And Guinevere?
- She's with Mordred.
I'm afraid he's using
his magic and a medium
to make contact with a
scientist from this world.
- Scientist?
- Oh, alchemist.
She's been experimenting
with the magnetic flows of the earth
which is where I get my power.
It's bad enough that she's already broken
the spell holding you,
if we don't stop her,
she'll break the spell
holding Mordred, too.
- 1500 years and nothing's changed.
If we couldn't defeat them then,
how are we going to defeat them now?
- I wish I knew.
- We need Excalibur.
What happened to Excalibur?
- Mordred has it.
(electronic whirring)
- So, how are we doing?
Yes, that's good, good.
Oh, Roz, I've got a meeting,
make sure we stay on schedule.
- [Roz] Yeah, sure.
(Game Boy beeping)
- Your mum seems happy to be
back home, don't you think?
It's not easy for her, Richie.
She misses your dad, she needs her family.
You can't blame her for
wanting to come home.
- Not easy for her, what about me?
I didn't ask to come here.
This place is a dump, I've got no friends.
- You'll soon make new friends, Richard.
- Oh, sure, where?
- [Kate] Hi.
- Hi.
- Mom asked if you could
post these for her.
- No problem.
- [Kate] It should come
to three pounds 87.
I think that's the right money.
- Thank you.
Kate, meet my nephew, Richie.
- Hi.
- Dungeon Keeper, I've got
Breakup on my PlayStation.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, you fancy a game?
- [Richie] Sure, there's
nothing else to do around here.
- Everlyn, you're a genius.
- How long are you staying for?
- For good, I guess, my mom was born here.
Aunt Everlyn's the only family we've got.
- [Kate] Rats.
- What's wrong
- Mum's working.
- What does she do?
- Oh, she's a medium.
- Cool.
(Kate gasping)
What's wrong?
- Shh, something's not right.
- Do you think that's a good idea?
What is it, what?
- [Kate] Look.
- I don't believe it, what is it?
- Shh, can't you be quiet?
- [Maxwell] I hope you
have good reason for this,
I'm needed at the lab.
- Quiet, wench.
How ready are you, can
you complete it tonight?
- No, I don't know, why the rush?
- There are other forces at work.
If I am to move my army
through the gate unopposed,
it has to be now.
- I'll try, it won't be
easy, there's a lot to do.
- If you want the power that you crave,
you will do more than try.
- We have to stop them.
Come on.
- What are you doing?
- I told you we have to stop Maxwell.
Are you coming or not?
- All right, my pet, you'll
soon be at your room,
just think how good it'll be
when you switch places with
Arthur leaving him to rot.
- Put a sock in it.
- What, sweetheart?
Will Maxwell open the gate tonight?
- Yes.
- Don't you get touchy with me?
- Just shut up.
- Those two deserve each other.
- We must warn Merlin and Arthur.
- I don't think Arthur will believe
anything we have to say, do you?
- Maybe.
Maybe not.
We've got to try.
There's too much at stake not to.
- Believe me, when that
gate opens tonight,
we're going through.
On that you have my word.
Come.
- Will the lady of the
lake come if you call her?
- No, I can't reach her.
I have no idea whether Lancelot destroyed,
all I know he destroyed Stonehenge.
- So, what do we do?
- Trust in luck, jump.
- And hope she catches me?
- The sword is in Mordred's throne room
embedded in the lodestone,
just where Lancelot left it.
Neither he nor Mordred can pull it free,
only you can do that.
You are the chosen one for Excalibur.
- Gawain.
I leave you in charge whilst I'm gone.
- Is this necessary?
- I can't stop Mordred without Excalibur.
It's our only defense against him.
And don't do anything rash.
Are you sure there's no other way?
- Fairly sure.
(heartbeat thumping)
- She didn't catch him.
- No.
But she let him in.
- [Gawain] Merlin.
(car honking)
- Morning, Ms. Maxwell.
- Where are we?
- Maxwell's lab.
- Well, it should be
happening next week sometime.
- Yeah, can we talk about it then?
Get the rotors sorted out.
- Right.
- What's he doing here?
- Don't know,
but he sure has a habit of popping up
in the strangest of places.
- I knew we couldn't trust him.
- [Richie] You don't know that.
- Anyway, if he wasn't
working for Maxwell,
why would he be here?
- Shh!
Come on.
(sneaky music)
This way.
- [Kate] There's Maxwell.
- [Richie] What is that?
- [Kate] Shh!
- Okay, Sherri, now.
(eerie whirring)
Oh my god, it's working.
- What's happening?
- You.
Stop him.
Get him.
Get him, someone.
- We have to help him, come on.
This will stop them.
Turn it.
- Get them.
- You can't stop me.
My strength has grown tenfold
since my imprisonment.
No!
You little runt.
- Now.
- Stop them.
Protect the gate.
- Go.
- Merlin.
- [Lancelot] Guinevere.
Good luck.
(alarm blaring)
- No!
Stop them.
Stop them, you idiots.
- Come on, come on.
- Someone.
- Let's go.
- They're ruining everything.
Stop them.
- Throw it at them.
Come on.
- Oh, you'll pay for that.
- Really, how?
Guinevere's gone.
Hello, mother.
- Look at that.
(eerie sounds)
- Yes.
Yes.
The old man is weakened.
He cannot close the rift.
Mother, dear, I will
take every spell maker
and witch here now.
(water babbling)
- God, it's good to be
free, to drink fresh water,
to feel the wind, to see the trees.
So green.
Look at the stars.
They're beautiful.
- If Mordred gets out, the
trees won't stay green for long.
- Well, we'll just have to make sure
that he won't get out.
- How?
- I don't know.
Maybe Arthur will.
- I'm afraid Arthur isn't here.
- He's not?
- No, he went to go get Excalibur.
- You mean I've come here
to warn him about Mordred
and he's gone in to get the sword.
- Yes.
- We sure gave Mordred a shock
when we hit him with the water.
- [Merlin] First bath he's
had in a thousand years.
- [Kate] Listen, Merlin.
- [Merlin] Yes?
- I owe you an apology.
I thought you were on Maxwell's side.
- Oh, that's all right, Kate.
I've always been misunderstood.
There's no harm done.
Well, it's been a long day.
I suggest we all get some sleep.
And decide what to do tomorrow.
(dog barking)
- Cheer up, at least your
mom will be all right now.
Maxwell won't come near her.
- Yeah, guess you're
right, see you tomorrow.
- See ya.
Hey, aunt.
- Richie, are you all right?
- Fine, just great.
You were right, aunt,
it ain't so bad here.
Goodnight.
- What's got into him?
- Who cares, as long as it lasts.
- [Kate] Mom.
(eerie chanting)
- You know what to do.
Do not fail me.
(woman shrieking)
- Hey.
- Hi.
- [Man] Drink this.
- Thank you.
- Get warm, I won't be long.
(dogs barking and howling)
Edmund?
(howling)
(eerie ominous sounds)
(man humming)
(television crackling)
(man screaming)
- Mom.
Mom.
- [Mom] Let me go.
- [Man] Quit stalling, woman.
- Hold it right there.
- Kate!
Let me go, take whatever
you want, but let me go.
(Kate screaming)
(Richie groaning)
- Kate!
What?
- Get off me, get off me.
- Oh, no, Kate.
What are you doing?
Let go of me.
Help, stop it.
What do you want?
- I want you to help me.
- Never.
- Never?
Never?
My young friend, you
have absolutely no idea
how long never can be.
- Why, why should we help you?
- Well, that's a very good
question, very good question.
How about because you have misunderstood
shall we say my point of view?
No?
Well, then what about out
of respect for your betters?
Well, then I guess that leaves
us with the obvious choice,
blackmail, imprisonment.
Torture.
I see I'm getting closer
to what motivates you.
- You'll never make us do anything.
- There's that never again.
I would love to teach you about never,
but I haven't the time.
That's a joke, Richie, my
god, don't you get anything?
Time, never.
(Mordred clapping)
Have a look at this, Richie.
- Mom!
Look at your face now.
Shall I have her killed?
- No, let her go, please.
- Help me, please, Richie.
- Richie, help me, please.
- Let her go.
- Your mother's life belongs to me now.
- What do you want us to do?
- It's very simple really.
I just want you to kill Merlin.
- Here.
- What is it?
- Well, for what it's worth,
it's an irregular magnetic pulse switcher.
You push this button here as you point it
and it releases a frequency
that causes waves in the
earth's magnetic field.
I'm rather proud of it.
(gadget beeping)
Careful, you could cause
a small earthquake.
- So, what's it for?
- Well, you wait until
Merlin's casting spell,
preferably a big one, then
you point this at him.
As it's the earth's magnetic
field that powers his spells,
this little gadget will disrupt the flow,
the spell will turn back on itself,
poof, Merlin goes up in smoke.
- Well, if it's that simple,
why haven't you used it?
- I'm not a murderer.
- Of course, he could always
turn it on Mordred instead.
- I'm sure his dear mother
would thank him for that.
- I knew you'd come.
- So, traitor.
You didn't have the nerve
to stab me in the back.
- I betrayed no one.
I fell in love.
- I trusted you.
You were my friend.
- I'm sorry.
- Sorry?
- [Lancelot] Yes.
- Yes, I'm sorry.
(swords clanking)
Arthur.
- I'm gonna kill you, piece by piece.
- If you do, you won't
reach Excalibur, will you?
Listen to me.
I was right.
- Not only to me, but
the whole round table.
- You need my help.
You need me.
- Never.
- Arthur, listen to me.
- Stop it.
Does she still love you?
- No.
- [Arthur] Oh, all right, then.
- Missed.
Shh!
- All right.
You had to tell them.
- You didn't want it easy, did you?
Arthur!
(men yelling and screaming)
- We're trapped.
- We can jump it.
- [Arthur] We'd never make it.
- Do you wanna live forever?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- When the flame drops.
You first.
- I'm your king.
- [Mother] Mordred!
Mordred.
King Arthur's here.
- What?
- Arthur's here.
- I know, mother.
- You don't seem to be
too bothered about it.
- Look around you.
Do you really think a couple
of tired old has-beens
can make their way through my whole army?
- What if he gets the sword?
- Don't you listen to anything I say?
Arthur's no threat to us
and if he's here, he
can damn well stay here.
But let's not fall out.
Get out!
Get out now.
My plan is going well.
We will soon be free.
- Force the rat to kill Merlin.
- Precisely.
- Ye gods, Merlin,
can't I even eat without you badgering me?
- I didn't say anything.
- The sleep has addled his brain.
- How many times do I have to say this?
Arthur left me in charge not you.
- I am queen.
- In name.
- [Merlin] Will you two stop wasting time?
We have to find Mordred.
- What are we going to do?
- I don't know, but we mustn't
let on about this, not yet.
We need time to think.
Come on.
- Mordred is not going to wait
for Arthur to get Excalibur,
we have to stop Maxwell ourselves now.
- [Kate] Merlin!
- Now, what?
- Mordred's attacked the village,
he's taken everyone prisoner.
- I know, I was just
explaining that to Gawain.
- Well, are you going to help
or leave it to me,
Merlin, and two children?
- All right, all right.
Do you know where they've taken them?
- Stonehenge.
(indistinct shouting)
- Stop this.
It's all right, you'll be okay.
- Are you all right?
I've been a fool, Merlin.
Mordred's power may corrupt,
but it will never again
cloak my mind, I'm with you.
Can you save her?
Oh, I think she'll live.
- Bury these men with full honors,
t'was Mordred's demons we fought
not the men they possessed.
Rouse the camp.
We know our enemy and
he awaits our swords.
- [Knights] Yeah!
(indistinct whispering)
- You look pleased with yourself.
- Of course, why shouldn't I be?
Things are going well.
Mordred's plans will soon
see him free and Merlin dead.
- Really?
And how do you think
you're going to fit in
with Mordred's plans
once he's free that is?
- We have a deal.
I'm a scientist.
Mordred will give me free
reign with my research
and all the help I'll
need for my experiments,
soon I'll be free of all
the small-minded fools
who think science should
controlled by rules.
- Of course you can trust
Mordred to keep his word.
It wouldn't worry him that your science
might one day become a threat to him.
- I think I'm needed.
- [Mom] Just something to think about.
- Where are you, where
are you, where are you?
Oh, come on, come on,
come on, come on, come on.
Oh, it's always the same.
You can never find
something when you want it.
- What?
- I said you can't-
- Oh, yeah, sorry, I
heard, is it important?
- Is it important?
Interesting question.
Is anything important?
It depends on the circumstances
and to what it relates, I suppose.
To a man who's drowning, air is important,
to a fish that's watching, the water.
Good question.
- Well, can I help you?
- Help what?
- Tell me what you're looking for
and I can help you find it.
- No, no, no, no, no, that's
all right, I'll find it.
(stone scraping)
- Penny for them.
- I was thinking how strange life can be.
And how short.
- What do you mean short?
- Well, I was thinking
of all the friends I had
when Arthur was king,
their hopes, their children, their dreams,
all crammed into a few short
years of furious living.
- You didn't have that with Lancelot,
you had all the time you could ever need.
- Yes, perhaps too long.
- Have you seen Richie?
- Yes, he left with Merlin
to collect a few things
from Merlin's house before we leave.
- He's been acting quite strange,
think I'd better go and fetch him.
- Kate.
Think about what I said, life is short,
you make the most of it.
(birds crowing)
- [Merlin] Well, if it's not
in there, it's gotta be in here
and of course it's not.
- Is that magic?
- What?
- Your staff, have you
cast a spell to make shine?
- Yes.
- Is it a large spell, does
it take a lot of power?
- All spells take a lot of power,
but how much depends on
the person casting them.
It can't be in there,
so it has to be there,
and it can't be in here
because it's never in here.
Come on, come on, no, no, no, no.
Found it.
- That's it?
A pipe?
Is that what all the fuss was about?
- I keep a pipe, but I never smoke it.
It's my little test to
myself, so far I've passed,
but tomorrow is a new day, a new test.
Like you, Richie, I will
have a choice to make.
Now.
I think we will both make the right one.
- [Kate] Merlin, Richie, are you there?
- Shall we go?
- [Kate] Are you in there?
- [Richie] Oh, he knows.
- [Merlin] Come in, Kate.
- God, he knows.
- He knows what?
- About this?
- How can he?
- I don't know.
- Shall we go?
(metal jingling)
- There's Maxwell.
- [Scientist] Carbon
dating results are ready.
- This is gonna be a
great day for science.
- [Scientist] Yeah, as
soon as you can, please.
- Yes, this is a big night.
- Make the most of your
next hour, Maxwell,
when Mordred arrives he might
see to it being your last.
- Oh, I don't know,
I may have an ace or two up my own sleeve.
How are the levels?
Are we close?
- [Scientist] Radio online.
- [Scientist] All right,
everyone, here we go.
(electricity crackling)
(machine thundering)
(high-pitched whirring)
- Mordred.
Look.
It's working.
Your magic's working.
- Everyone in place.
- We're free.
(speaking in foreign language)
- Not this time, Merlin.
You're getting old, Merlin.
- [Mother] And tired.
- Not so fast.
- We have the machine, Merlin.
- Good.
Good.
- Lancelot.
Look, they're through, gotta
cut 'em off from the gate.
- Sire, forgive me, but that's a bad idea.
- Trust me.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, wanna live forever?
- Yes! I got ya.
Boy, your time's up.
I'll take care of Mordred,
you, don't let anyone through that gate.
- Ready, now.
Cover me.
(swords clanging)
- We have to do something.
- I know.
(Mordred groaning)
- Do it now.
- What about you?
- Come on.
- Richie, wait.
- No, Richie, it's too dangerous.
- Richie!
- Come back.
- Quiet!
- No, stop that, no.
Rat, I knew you couldn't be trusted.
- Richie, do it, quick.
- Your mother dies.
Off with her head.
- [Mother] Richie, help me.
- [Richie] Let her go now.
- Kill Merlin now or she dies.
- [Mother] Oh, no.
(Richie's mom crying)
- Arthur, just do it.
(triumphant music)
- Arthur.
- Guinevere.
- [Kate] Richie.
- Give me the sword or the woman dies.
- Take it.
(Mordred groaning)
- I'm sorry.
- Everything is ready.
- Are you sure about taking
your knights through to there?
- We are men out of our time,
Richie, where else can we go?
And besides, there's a whole new dimension
out there for us to conquer.
Kneel.
Arise, Sir Richard,
the youngest and last
knight of the round table.
- Bravo, young man.
- [Knights] Aye!
- [Knight] Well done.
(people clapping)
- Kate.
This was, is my wedding ring.
You be careful who you give it to.
- [Kate] Thank you.
Will you be okay?
- I think so, it won't be
easy, but I am a queen.
I belong with the king.
- You always have.
You are my queen.
Sire.
- Are you still adamant about staying?
- Yes.
Well, I've had 1500
years to think about it.
That's long enough for any man.
Hope you can look after
yourself without me around.
Good luck to you, sire.
- Good luck.
- It is time, clear the stone.
- Don't worry.
We're going to have lots of fun.
- For the dragon.
(triumphant heroic music)
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
(bright music)