[music playing]
NARRATOR: Strained...
The monstrous assurance
of this race of puny bipeds with
overblown egos, the creature
who calls himself man.
He believes he owns the Earth
and every living thing on it
exists only for his benefit.
Yet how foolish he is.
Consider, even the lowly
insect that man trods underfoot
outweighs humanity several
times and outnumbers
by countless billions.
In the continuing war
for survival between man
and the hexapods,
only an utter fool
would bet against the insect.
Let a man or woman
venture from the well
beaten path of civilization.
Let him cross the threshold
of the limited intellect,
and he encounters
amazing, wondrous things...
The unknown and terrible.
If he escapes these weird
adventures with his life,
he will usually find he
left his reason behind him.
Perhaps that is what happened
to these two souls, lost
in the great Mexican desert.
But then ask yourself, why would
anyone trod from the usually
well traveled roads
of this modern age,
from the luxury of an air
conditioned automobile?
It's difficult for our modern
world of statistics and
electronics to accept miracles.
But you could almost call this
a miracle... a genuine miracle.
Out of hundreds and thousands of
square miles of heat and seared
wasteland, where the vultures
wait for the other vultures
to die, an American
oil surveyor has chosen
to explore this particular
terrible corner of the earth,
the Muerto Desert...
The Desert of Death.
This surveyor can
hardly credit his eyes.
Perhaps they're only
illusive images produced
by roasting the optic nerves.
But if they do
exist... If they are
living things from somewhere...
One fact is certain.
Miracle or not, they will not
be living things for long.
The Muerto Desert,
true to its name,
will soon convert
them into dead things.
[man panting]
Maybe he's coming
out of it, then.
I've got it, Doc.
Even if they got across
that desert alive,
the sun's bound to have
cooked their brains.
It's a miracle to me old
Pepe and Frank found them.
Now I'd be getting
back to work.
Beats me how they got there
or what they were doing.
That's the most
god-forsaken spot on earth.
Maybe they're from that
missing plane we read about.
That plane was headed
for Mexico City.
It'd have to be 100 degrees off
to land in the Muerto Desert.
100 degrees or not, they
had to come from somewhere.
Where did you say you
picked them up, Pepe?
On the road to Zarpa
Mesa, Senor Medico.
[woman moans]
DOC: Pretty girl under
all that sunburn.
She was almost
completely dehydrated.
I don't know what
kept them alive.
You're all right.
You're safe.
You're in an oil company office.
You sure?
She's in about the
same shape you are.
She hasn't come out of it
yet, but I think you're
both going to be all right.
Here, try to take this.
[coughing]
Who did you think you
were anyway, Superman?
Super...
Nobody's ever been able
to walk across that desert
and come out alive.
And you try it with a girl.
You said this was
an oil company.
Can you load a truck
with full drums
and bring all the
men you can spare?
If we get there in
time, maybe we can...
Can what?
Burn them out
before they scatter.
That's the only thing
that scares them... fire.
But if we're too late, we're...
Now just a minute, young fella.
Take it easy.
You've been out in
the sun too long.
That sedative will quiet
him down in a minute.
I tell you, you don't know.
You haven't seen them.
But if you had, you'd realize...
Seen them?
Look, you said Superman.
Well these are super monsters
or bugs as big as we are.
They can... the can... they
can kill you with one bite.
DAN: What can?
MAN: These... these...
These things.
I... if they scatter before
we get there, we're...
Where do they come from?
He's got a... an underground
lab up on Zarpa Mesa.
He does something
to their glands.
Who does?
Doctor Aranya.
Aranya?
Ay, caramba!
I told you the sun had
cooked their brains.
Pepe doesn't think so.
And besides, nobody's ever
been able to climb Zarpa Mesa.
But you can reach it by plane.
Let's listen to
his story anyway.
What do we got to lose?
It all started on the
border a few days back.
I pilot for Jan van
Croft, the big financier.
Well, we had engine
trouble, and I...
I made a forced landing
in the... the field
outside this little
Mexican town.
After we landed, I stayed
with the... with the ship to...
NARRATOR: Quite a sorry he's
telling, isn't it, Pepe?
You heard from your
people about Zarpa Mesa,
and the mysterious
Doctor Aranya, even
though your bosses haven't.
So why tell them?
They would only laugh at
you and say, poor Pepe,
you're getting old.
But you heard for years about
the grotesque and misshapen
people, about the women...
Strange women who do not die.
No, Grant Philip doesn't
know the whole story.
You see, he came into it late.
It actually began, oh, almost a
year ago, the night Dr. Leland
Masterson, the world famous
specialist and researcher,
found himself in the
middle of the Muerto
Desert, the Desert of Death.
He came in answer to a rather
mysterious summons from a man
he admired but
knew only as a name
signed to a series of brilliant
scientific treatises... Aranya.
Well, we've arrived.
NARRATOR: Your eyes must
be playing tricks on you
in this light.
Is that what you
think, Masterson?
What was it you thought you saw?
Apparently, they've
come correctly.
But, uh, to Masterson
it seems strange... a man
with the genius of Aranya
building his laboratory
on an inaccessible
mountain top in the middle
of an uninhabited desert.
Why Zarpa Mesa?
Why Zarpa Mesa, indeed!
A natural question, doctor.
And one that was soon to be
answered, though in a way so
fantastic and horrible as
to make a man of science
doubt his senses.
How do you do?
My name is Masterson...
Dr. Leland Masterson.
I believe Dr. Aranya
is expecting me.
Nervous systems of insects.
Dr. Masterson?
Dr. Aranya?
I trust your
journey was pleasant.
Well, moderately.
I must confess,
though, that I was
a trifle uneasy when your driver
headed into the Muerto Desert.
But everything seems
to have worked out.
The sentimental human
mind being what it is,
this is the only
sort of a place I
could find to carry on my work.
But I can understand
your feelings.
These papers on the anterior
lobe of the pituitary
and the effects of the specific
hormones on other living
things... quite the most
remarkable endocrine
theories that I've ever read.
Well thank you, doctor...
Coming from the world's
foremost organo-therapist,
a fine complement.
That's why I
jumped at the chance
to come here, work with
you, examine your theories.
Oh, let us understand
one thing, Doctor.
These are not theories.
Not theories?
I have successfully proved
every point over and over again
in my laboratory.
MASTERSON: Wait a minute.
You want me to believe that
you have produce these things
by experimentation?
And many more.
Then my eyes weren't
playing tricks.
So you can see why
such work as this
must be completed
inside a mountaintop
amidst this desolation.
Oh, I'm completing a
most unusual experiment
in my laboratory, Doctor.
Would you care to observe?
Oh, certainly!
Then come along.
[machinery humming]
Only a matter of minutes now.
What is the na...
Nature of this... this...
Well, I require some
clarification, Doctor.
As you know, I have isolated the
growth hormone of the anterior
pituitary, the
specific substance
which controls the growth
pattern of human beings.
Yes, it was the subject
of one of your papers.
Yes, and with
this accomplished,
I said to myself what would
the effect be of this hormone,
or a complete human pituitary
being transferred in the body
of another creature?
I began a series
of experiments...
Moderate success among
the lesser animals,
a complete failure among birds.
And then, experimenting
one day upon the hexapods,
I came upon the
Theraphosidae family.
MASTERSON: A tarantula?
Exactly.
The tarantulas began to
yield amazing results.
They grew as large
as human beings,
began developing new
reasoning powers.
And I found I had the telepathic
power to communicate with them.
And then I reversed the
process, transplanted
the controlled
substance of the insect
back into the human body.
Doctor, observe this girl.
I call her Tarantella.
She has human beauty
and intelligence,
but still possesses the
capacities and instincts
of the giant spider.
How do you mean?
She has the indestructibility
of the insect.
If her body became
damaged, if she
were to lose an arm or a leg,
she could grow a new one.
I expect Tarantella may
survive for hundreds
and hundreds of years.
And what about males?
Well unfortunately,
in the insect world,
the male is a puny,
unimportant thing.
You saw a few of the examples.
The dwarfs.
I think we're beginning
to get some results.
What is it?
If we are successful, I shall
have a super female spider
with a thinking and
reasoning brain,
a creature that
someday may control
the world subject to my will.
Are you convinced now, Doctor?
I hope you appreciate this
opportunity I'm giving you
to become a colleague of mine.
No... no!
You can't do these things!
You're tampering with
the work of the Creator!
Gibberish.
You're evil!
This place is like...
You must be destroyed,
you and all the foul
things that you've made!
Your choice, Doctor.
A very poor choice.
Of course you know I cannot
let you leave this place.
Someway, somehow I'll find
a way to put an end to you
and your ghastly experiments!
[sinister music]
Regrettable.
I was hoping for a colleague,
but... well at least we have
another experimental subject.
Mr. Masterson, here's
your orange juice.
Mr. Masterson!
[music playing]
[music stops]
[applause]
Thank you, sir.
Thank you very much.
[music playing]
What a dump.
Well, it isn't exactly
the Star Club, I'll admit.
But...
Senora, Senor... the
best people in the house.
Something to drink...
Anything tall and cool.
Si, senor.
We had to come down in this
flea-bitten border town.
And you would drag me to this
dive... this upholstered sewer.
Oh, I find this
place rather amusing.
Your great southwest has
a certain, uh, flare, no?
No.
I don't happen to be in
the mood for a cook's
tour of our great southwest.
If it wasn't for
that forced landing,
we'd be in Mexico
getting married by now.
But my dear, you can't blame
me for the motor trouble.
Those things will happen
to the best of planes.
Well it didn't have to
happen on my wedding day.
Now you're acting childish,
and that's not you.
After all, being able to
adapt oneself to any situation
is the mark of the
true sophisticate.
I'm sorry.
And you're not angry with me?
Of course not, darling.
William J Masterson
is the name.
May I?
I beg your pardon?
May I say you are
beautiful, my dear?
Very beautiful and good.
That's very kind of you.
Yes, Wu?
The plane is ready, huh?
Not for some time.
The pilot is having
considerable trouble.
Spend a small
fortune for a plane,
hire the best pilot I can
get, and what happens?
Well, Wu?
What are you waiting for?
Get back to the plane.
Yes, master.
[guitar]
[music playing]
Masterson, it's
certainly good to see you.
I've been looking
for you for two days.
I'm sorry, but I felt
like a little trip.
We missed you, sir.
Dr. Harrison wishes
to see you, you know?
[awkward chuckle]
I know, George.
But I don't want to see him.
I don't get this.
Who are you, and
what's this all about?
I'm his nurse, miss.
His nurse?
Yes.
You see, Mr. Masterson is...
MASTERSON: No, George.
I wouldn't do that.
See, I like this lady.
You like her?
Very much.
She's fascinating... as
a dancer, of course.
I don't like her.
That woman is evil.
Tell me... tell me what's wrong.
Not now, Anne.
Don't talk.
And they threw
her down, and blood
was sprinkled on the wall.
And he trod her underfoot.
[gun shot]
Give me that gun,
Mr. Masterson.
Please, give me that gun!
Come on, let's get out of here.
Stop, everybody!
Listen, this man's
an insane killer.
He's loco.
He'll kill all of us
before you can reach him.
Thank you, George.
Well spoken.
I only did what had to be done.
George...
Don't take another step.
This lady is my friend,
and nobody shall hurt her.
I will kill her first.
[cacophonous music ]
[sound stops]
George... let's go home.
Don't be afraid.
I won't let them hurt you.
Oh, you brought
the cars, George.
Excellent.
You'll sit with me.
But Mr. Masterson,
she's not going with us.
Not going with us?
You must, my dear.
You're in danger.
But we've got to get
to the landing field.
Landing field?
Very well, I shall
take you there.
Let me talk to the Sheriff.
Doreen dear, you
sit up here in front.
Miss Doreen is going to
sit with me, aren't you?
Yes.
Yes, of course.
[car starts]
There's a dead woman lying
right here on the floor.
That's right, Sheriff.
He shot her dead.
No, she's right where she fell.
Nobody touched a thing.
We...
[music playing]
Sheriff, the body just got
up and walked out of here.
Here we are, my dear.
At last.
And Philip seems to
ready for the take-off.
All set to go, Philips?
Sorry sir, but one of the
engine's still acting up.
Whatever it is, I
can't find the butt.
It's probably nothing serious.
Can't we take off anyway?
No sir, I can't
take that chance.
You're the captain.
How much longer do you think...
My dear young man.
I want to fly.
You... you want to...
I've always wanted to fly.
And now I will.
Sorry, sir.
But I'm the one who decides
whether we fly or not.
I command, and thou shalt obey.
Is he kidding?
He ain't kidding, mister.
You'd better do as he says.
We fly... now.
You'll go first.
[sirens]
Listen, the police!
At last!
Don't be afraid.
I won't let them harm you.
Get in, quick.
Come along, George.
Now we will all fly.
Well, she's on course.
How long do you think
it will take us, Philips?
If everything goes all right,
about an hour and a half.
It's wonderful up here
so close to heaven.
Wait a minute,
there's something
wrong with this gyrocompass.
Somebody's fooled
with the setting.
We've been flying 100
degrees off course.
I knew it.
The left engine's
acting up already.
Is it bad, Jan?
Do we have to go down again?
How should I know?
Just stay calm, please.
Nothing seriously wrong so far.
It's getting worse... much
worse' I'll have to go down,
and fast.
I can't see a place to land.
It don't look too good, Miss.
We keep on flying.
I like it.
This is my order.
Fasten your safety belts.
This can't last much longer.
And please, remain calm.
Can't you find the
landing spoke, Philips?
Not yet, but I am trying
for that Mesa dead ahead.
You think we'll make it?
I don't know, sir.
Keep your fingers crossed.
Miss Culbertson, no smoking!
OK, captain.
But may I ask where we are?
Somewhere over Mexico
at an altitude of 1,500,
and with a dying engine.
The other one's OK.
It doesn't do us any
good, not in this ship.
Birds fly without
motors, and so will we.
Mister, I don't know
who you or what you are,
but this bird won't fly.
When a bird is
sick, he has to land.
And our bird is
sick... very sick.
The sick I shall heal.
The good I shall protect.
We've got a chance.
I'm going down.
Well hold tight!
It's going to be rough.
Hold on, everybody!
It looks too short.
I'll have to break the run.
Is everything all right?
Yes.
Yes, I'm all right.
Good.
Stick close, I
want to talk to you.
Right.
I never thought we'd
make it, Philips.
But we did, sir.
Good girl, Miss Culbertson.
Oh, thank you, captain.
I like it here.
Our voices sound
strange up here.
Do you hear that?
It must be the echo of
our voices, my dear, thrown
back at us from the forest.
Two days ago he
got away from us.
I been hunting him ever since.
I caught up with him
in that border dive
just before he
killed that dancer.
I tried, but I
couldn't stop him.
Why did he kill her?
How did he get that gun?
Nobody knows why he kills.
He just wants to, and he does.
How he got that gun?
Probably bought it.
He has lots of
money all the time.
Doesn't mean a thing to him.
Can't we get that
gun away from him?
I'll try, captain.
You can bet on that.
But for the sake of all of us,
don't try to rush or force him.
Leave it to me.
All right.
May I smoke now, captain?
No, not yet.
I have to look at
a gas tanks first.
Now, Miss Culbertson,
you may smoke.
Thank you, captain.
Any idea where we are, Philips?
I think so, sir.
We're in Mexico about 120
miles below the border
on top of a mesa rising
600 feet above the desert.
600 feet!
That's right... stuck
up in the air like a...
Like an island in the sky.
I suppose we can't
walk down from here.
Not unless you're a human fly.
DOREEN: I'm sorry, captain.
Haven't been with
the circus for years.
It's wonderful!
So close to heaven.
I'd better get that
flare and the flash light.
We'll need some light.
Something moves in there.
I don't like it here a bit.
Well, if they had a
nightmare, this is it.
Who could be out there?
I don't know, Culbertson.
Well it could be a
very natural cause...
An old dead branch breaking
off, or a falling tree.
I wouldn't worry too much.
Well here comes Wu.
Now we will have a fire.
Did you hear that
noise out there, Wu?
Yes, master.
You heard?
Did you see anything?
The curtain of darkness
veils the sharpest eyes.
Wu saw nothing.
Well let's get that fire going.
I'll be back in a minute.
Well, that's better!
We have a fire, flare and...
A drink... oh, I
certainly can use it.
That's what occurred to
me when I saw the bottle.
But first, let's get
this into the air.
[loud whistle]
Our only flare, and it worked.
How do we know it was seen?
Well we don't, sir.
All we can do is hope.
Sorry, Miss
Culbertson... no glass.
Oh that's all right, Wu.
It's a relief to be
informal once in a while.
I think I'll eat something.
I feel hungry.
Shut up, you fool!
You are the fool, Jan!
Remember his gun?
A hungry animal knows no fear.
No, thank you... not
brandy just before dinner.
Sorry, sir, to disillusion you.
But there's no food on this
ship, not even a K-ration.
Thank you, sir.
That helped.
I'm going to look around.
What for?
You can't see anything.
We need this flash lighter.
I have this.
Does that give
out enough light?
Sure, I use it at the
sanitarium all the time.
It's passed my
dinnertime, dear.
Aren't you hungry?
But Mr. Masterson, we
have no food with us.
George will bring it.
He always does.
If our fire wasn't
seen by anyone,
how will be get off this mesa?
To be honest,
sir, I don't know.
We can't do anything
decisive until daylight.
[music playing]
Thank you, captain.
You're so attentive.
But even I can do some
things for myself.
So I noticed.
And, uh, no offense meant.
You scare easily,
don't you, captain?
[scream]
It's George!
He needs help.
I'll go see what happened.
Wu's right.
He does need help.
I'm going with you, Grant.
Anything's better than to
have to sit here and wait.
May I suggest that we
wait here until Philips
find out what happened.
You'll be safer here.
Are you concerned
about my safety?
George is out there
and in trouble.
I'll go.
Anyone who wants to come
along can do so now.
I'd like a stroll
before dinner.
Since you insist, we all go.
You come too.
Yes, master.
I'll have to put some
more wood on the fire.
Let's stay close together.
The, uh, best way is to
hold each other's hand
and form a line.
If you don't mind...
I believe it's better,
Mr. van Croft, if you hold
onto Mr. Masterson's coat.
And Wu, you bring up the rear.
DOREEN: Can you see anything?
I can't.
[rustling]
Is that you, George?
The is the end of the trail.
Can you see
anything down there?
Only a black, gaping hole.
Light won't reach bottom.
Well you wait here.
I'll try this alone.
It looks too narrow.
One wrong step, and
we may all go over.
Is it George?
Yeah.
Who could have shot him?
Nobody shot him.
Look.
Those aren't bullet wounds?
How horrible!
What could have killed him?
I don't know.
I hope we won't
have to find out.
George is beyond help.
We should all go back and
tend the fire for the living.
Poor George.
Well there's not a
thing we can do for him.
Now stand close
to the underbrush.
I'll have to get by.
I can't see a thing.
That noise is not
falling branches.
Something's moving in there!
Help, it's got me!
Something got me!
Where?
Here on my arm... my left arm.
That's a nasty scratch, all
right, but nothing serious.
I'll dress it as soon as
we get back to the plane.
I'd suggest we all stay
away from these thorns.
Oh look, this skirt's ruined.
And so is this heel.
But you weren't
hurt, Miss Culbertson.
No, not a bit.
Thank you.
May we go on now, Philips?
Uh, yes sir.
Let's go.
Where's that bottle
of yours, captain?
I sure could use another drink.
I think we all could
stand a little drink
after this experience.
How about you?
There must be something
we can do to get help.
We've done the
only thing we can
do... that's send up a flare.
If help doesn't come by morning,
we'll make a signal fire.
But meanwhile, I'd
suggest we get some sleep.
We got a long night ahead of us.
Do you expect any of
us to sleep after...
After what happened tonight?
Well, I... maybe not sleep, but
at least you'll get some rest.
But we are all in danger.
Whatever killed
George may attack us.
Take it easy, sir.
I'll stand guard and keep the
fire going... my eyes open.
Well, we all could
use a little rest.
But remember now, we are
putting our lives in your hands.
I realize that, sir.
Doreen, dear, why
don't you try to make
yourself a little comfortable?
Try to get some rest.
I'll try.
The doctor said it was
a good night to melt
away with the morning sun.
Mr. Masterson, don't you think
you better get some sleep?
Is it bedtime?
Yeah.
Yeah, it's bedtime.
I'll awake you
when morning comes.
[rustling]
Very good, my dear... very good.
Soon their nerves will break.
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to wake you.
I wasn't asleep.
Are you nervous?
No.
I was just thinking.
Philips, why do you ignore me?
That what you were
thinking about?
Yes.
And I resent it.
You're not used to it, huh?
Do you really
dislike me that much?
I don't dislike
you, Miss Culbertson.
But you don't approve
of me, is that it?
You think I'm marrying
him for his money.
Well, aren't you?
I'm very fond of him.
But you don't love him.
Well I'm not exactly mad about
him, if that's what you mean.
But I am fond of him.
And he can give
you nice things.
Well, yes.
Why not?
He can give me
security, for one thing.
And that's important.
Don't you think?
Why should you
care what I think?
I don't exactly.
It's just that I'd like
you to understand me.
What is it?
I thought I heard something.
No, I guess it wasn't anything.
Now, uh, what were you saying?
I was saying that I'd
like you to understand me.
I think I do understand you.
Oh, no you don't.
You can't.
Oh yes I can.
I've had my hard knocks, too.
I've had to work ever
since I was a kid.
Some of it wasn't very much fun.
Well, I guess it boils down
to what you want out of life.
What is it for you, Grant?
Well, I want a girl who's
sincere, real... someone who...
Who'd stick by me
when the chips are
down... one who wants
me only for what I am,
and not for what I have.
It's a big order, huh?
Wait a minute!
This was to be your
wedding night, remember?
Yes.
Yes, of course.
That was a foolish thing to do.
Grant look!
Take it easy,
Mrs. Culverson.
Your imagination
is getting the best of you.
This was no imagination.
It was there, I saw it!
What did you see, dear?
Well, I couldn't sleep.
Philips and I were sitting here
talking, and there was a noise.
I looked up, and I... I saw
some women and a little man.
He seemed unreal.
No offense intended,
Miss Culbertson,
but I know what strange tricks
our minds can play on us.
Yes I know, Philips.
But I'm sure I saw it.
Where's your comb, my dear?
Comb?
Oh, I guess I lost it
out there somewhere.
But I gave it to you.
We must find it.
That comb is a valuable
heirloom of my family.
What do you mean by we?
If you think I'm going out
there once more, you're crazy.
I didn't intend you to go.
Wu will go and look for it.
May I have the light?
Oh, don't be a fool!
He who serves well will
also serve in danger.
Wu?
The wanderer in the
valley of darkness
shall have my guidance
and protection.
OK, Wu.
If you feel that way
about, I won't stop you.
But don't hesitate
to use that gun.
I hope you know how.
There is a day to be
born and a day to die.
I want you to realize that
if Wu doesn't come back
you will be responsible.
I'll never touch that comb
again even if he finds it.
I still have my heirloom.
You make me sick!
And you are a coward, sir.
What?
Why you...
You're very brave, aren't
you, since Masterson
no longer has a gun?
Let go of me if you don't
want to lose your job.
I haven't had the
opportunity to tell you yet,
but I quit when Wu went
out there on your orders.
Have you brought Masterson?
Yes, he's here.
Good, we've found him at last.
What about the others?
Well I have something in mind
for the girl and the pilot.
The other I'm going
to dispose of.
What's the matter, Wu?
There's your
priceless heirloom.
Wu is dead?
Yeah.
You murdered him!
They're coming for us!
They're coming!
Throw more wood on
that fire, quick!
Just keep it moving, Doreen.
Well, remember, we
haven't seen them yet.
Aren't you afraid, Grant?
I'm scared stiff.
If you're frightened,
what do you call him?
I can't stand it.
I'm getting out of here.
GRANT: Don't be a fool!
The only thing keeping
them back is our fire!
Oh, no!
[scream]
Grant, look!
He'll recover
consciousness in a moment
or so... be perfectly sane again.
Unfortunately, he left us
in such a state before.
I understand that he was
committed to an asylum,
and attempted to
kill Tarantella.
Grant, look!
It's the dancer from the cafe.
I saw him kill her.
Amazing, the durability
of my creations.
Dr. Aranya!
Aranya... that's
Spanish for spider.
We meet again, doctor.
Again?
Did I leave here?
Yes, I seem to
remember vaguely that...
Yes, you escaped
us before, doctor.
And well, you led us a
merry chase recovering you.
Why... why not just kill me?
Why bring me back?
Unfortunately, I
still need your help.
If I give you one more
chance to change your mind.
No, never!
Nothing you can do will ever
make me a party to this.
Tarantella...
No, you're not going
to torture him anymore!
Stop it!
Don't, you fool!
Fool?
I don't think so.
In just a few moments, this
will explode and destroy you,
and me, and all of your
terrible creations.
Doctor, you're
a man of science!
You wouldn't
destroy the greatest
achievement of science.
Scientist, yes... but
I'm a human being, too.
And that's where we differ.
You two have got a chance.
Through that door and down the
corridor on the right... hurry!
Who is he?
What is this place?
He's a brilliant madman.
Hurry, there are
only seconds left!
- What about you?
- Don't argue... go!
No, don't!
Take it, Aranya.
Your creations can grow
a new arm or a leg,
but nothing can survive fire.
[explosion]
I don't know how
long we stumbled
and staggered across that
desert before they found us.
Well, that's about the story.
Believe it or not.
Grant!
How do you feel, honey?
All right, I guess.
I've just been
telling them our story.
They... they don't buy it.
I think he did.
Es verdad.
That's the truth.
Now don't worry about it.
You're going to be all
right in a couple of days.
Just a little too much
sun on the bare head.
Anybody thinks I'm going to
load one of my trucks with oil
and send it up on top
of a mountain to burn
a bunch of imaginary spiders...
NARRATOR: Yes,
you're right, Dan.
Common sense tells you there
isn't anything to his story,
doesn't it?
Giant spiders on a
desert mesa... fantastic!
Pepe is just a
superstitious native.
True, no one has ever
been on Zapa Mesa.
But it's just like any
other bit of table land...
Not a thing different about it.
Or, uh, is there?