Well intentioned. He spoke.
We are laughting too much!
We don't need dress on black tie.
What is this?
Why this is a problem?
The weeding is here, here.
Weeding is here.
You are lovely as a bride,
honey.
And you look lovely
as a waiter...
Look, as soon as I get to Italy,
I'm going to the church
of Saint Anthony
to fulfill my promise!
I finally met the
man of my life!
Saint Anthony, just to
let you know,
hat guy there is me, okay?
Look at the size of this line!
Don't you think we're
marrying too fast, do you?
Fast? Look at the size
of this line!
We've been here for six months.
Did you bring everything?
Let's see, ID, birth
certificate.
Oh, my God, this is you?
Your name is Fabio Clovis?
Your name is Mia then,
so don't push it, okay?
Man, you're thirty-two?
Hey, you told me thirty. That's
so cute, you lied about your age.
Stop, focus, Fabio. Focus.
Next...
And 120 reais in cash.
Youbrought it?
I did. And another 200 dollars
to spend on the ship
because I'm going to splurge
I'm daring, I'm going
to get the money,
throw it all out and
then get it back,
because I'm not crazy.
Wait, wait!
Did you bring a witness?
I'll give this guy
behind us thirty bucks
and he'll swear he knows
us since childhood.
Fifty!
Huh?
Next.
We got married, happiness, rise.
Hi, Judge, how are you?
The thing is, you have
to marry us quick,
our honeymoon will be
in Europe...
First time you're
going to Europe, right?
Yeah, how do you know?
Because people who've
never been to Europe
love telling to any stranger
that they're going go Europe.
Let's roll, guys...
I, Mia, accept you, Fabio,
in sickness and in health,
in poverty... it's important
for you to understand
the poverty part...
There's twenty bucks missing.
Hey, but wasn't it
120,00 reais!?
Mia, you told me
that it was o...
You've paid me,
I'm not giving it back!
Next!
Take it easy, Mr. Justice,
you're of the peace,
aren't you?
The name says everything.
Isn't there a discount
for cash payment?
Next!
I promised Saint Anthony
that I would personally,
thank him for the day
that I met a handsome
intelligent, kind,
successful man...
Forgive me, miss,
but where is this man?
Oh, you're so funny,
you're a real riot.
We married! Come on, husband!
Quickly!
Calm down beloved wife!
I'm practically carrying
all the bags!
All of your bags, right?
Man, what is all this for?
Look at me,
I'm the bride... one bag!
When it starts getting cold
and you ask to borrow a coat,
I'm not giving you one!
You know that we are going
to go through all these.
Different temperatures
during the crossing
of that endless ocean, you know?
Why do people throw rice, huh?
What a stupid tradition.
Not to mention
that rice is fattening.
You wanted them to throw
brown rice, Mia?
Shouldn't we catch a cab, Fabio?
Look at him there.
Hi, Mr. Péricles!
You took your time!
Thank God you got here!
Everything will
be fine. Trust me!
Go!
- Come on baby!
- Whait, Mia.
- Whait, hold on the ship.
- Lets go, get out here.
- Stop!
- To Italy!
Italy. Speed up!
Oh, that's lovely!
Look at the size!
Why doesn't it sink?
Put aside the passport
and the ticket.
We're going to Europe!
On a plane at least
I can at least take a pill
and induce a semi-vegetative
state and just wake up
at the destination.
My mother warned me that I would
get dizzy and feel sick on the ship.
But we haven't even
gone aboard yet!
I didn't know you were
so afraid of ships!
I'm not a man to be afraid.
It's dread!
Relax, it'll go away soon,
it's too much emotion
for one day, right?
I'm impressed!
Have you ever felt this
sometime in your life?
There was this time that
I helped my father
to carry a sack of cement for
construction at the house.
It was very similar.
Take a deep breath,
feel the salty sea smell,
let's embrace this ocean.
I can't take a deep breath now,
because there is something
crushing my lungs.
Things are kind of heavy for me.
And to embrace he sea,
I have to drop you to the floor,
so you choose.
Let's turn around, love!
What?
Wheel around, like in those
romantic movies you know?
The couple kisses
and twirls around and around.
Loved the idea.
But how about this that
romantic movies have too;
Let's go to our room,
get naked and have sex?
I love that about romantic
movies.
Okay, let's go to the room then.
Hey, hey, hey!
In your arms.
Or it'll be bad luck.
Oh, so this that I'm trying
to do is luck for you?
Good of you to tell me.
My love I want to enjoy
every second with you!
I can't wait to get to
Our master suite plus.
Our room, pleased to meet you,
Mia, room? The best cost benefit.
Cost benefit in this
case is like
"you pay cheaper and gets
a real bargain staying
in a room that looks
really cheap!”
Mia, many things in
the room cause anguish,
you want to do a lot
of things and stuff
when actually the
point is to what?
To have sex and spoon
I doubt that a balcony
with a view
to the ocean
can make you anguished.
I'm going to tell you that
this view is making me feel
very anguished... come here,
because you can fall out.
Be very still...
Hey, Mia, what can I do?
It's the room.
Look, the room is simple,
but our trip
will be incredible.
Just let me make a call...
Yeah, me too.
Hey, Mommy, how's everything?
Hi, Pri, how are things
At the newsroom?
You're going to love Mia!
Italy, yeah!
In installments!
Okay. But what about the
story On renegade Brazilian
exports in Asia?
Say it again, boldus tea
and lemon balm tea.
But if I can mix
Paracetamol with
acetylsalicylic acid
and clonazepam,
do you think there'll be
some bad side effects?
Okay, when I get
back from the honeymoon,
we can have a meeting
with the team.
No, Grandma,
I haven't had a fever yet.
Let's hope.
Hi, Aunt Santinha!
If you need anything,
try my personal email, okay?
I ate it, yes, I did I made it,
I made that yogurt
loosens everything,
Mom, I have to hang up
because something is going on.
I'll call you back, Mom.
If I survive.
Okay, big
kiss. What is happening?
Attention,
attention all passengers
are called to perform
the emergency drill.
Dress your jacket life preserver
and go to metting place.
It hasn't even left
and it's already sinking?
- What is going on?
- Calm down, calm down.
It's a routine procedure, love.
Is it routine to sink?
What is this?
Come to the middle of the bed,
we have to keep to the middle.
What is going on,
for the love of God?
I don't understand why
we're wearing a life vest!
When I travel by plane I
don't have to wear a parachute.
Fabio, can you stay close to me, please.
If I hold you, both will be falling.
I'm sic.
Lady and gentleman,
welcome on board.
In case you listen the
emergency alarm,
Is ♪ short beeps after one long beep.
You have to dress the savety jackets.
And go to metting point.
- Can I ask you a question?
- Sure! Why not?
Is there a boat for everyone or
just for the rich,
like on the Titanic?
Fabio...
Hey, guys, it wasn't a joke,
it was a sincere question.
Hmm, this food is wonderful.
Excellent whistle.
Love, are you afraid
of sinking from your chair?
Take that off, please.
Just let me keep it
on today until I get used to
this idea of being on
the high seas.
It makes me feel so safe.
Look around you,
everyone is happy,
excited, taking pictures.
Hmm, look.
Could there someone
famous out there?
Oh, I think this is so chic.
Every chic place has a
tragic event happen there.
And if there is
someone famous here
then it's even worse.
Because the newspapers
are only going to
talk about the celebrity and
I'll be buried as an indigent!
Hi, how are you?
Thank you very much.
You can leave the bottle
on the table, please.
Wait. It's all
included in the package?
Oh, then you can take
it away! Thank you.
Come back only with water.
Be back only with wather.
Please, drink only a little.
Stop!
You gave me something to me, right.
Stop! Look at! What?
We get food at this time.
You are so lovely, you know?
Let's take off this life vest?
No!
Haven't you heard
about safe sex?
What is it? Are you crazy?
Cruise minibars are even
even more expensive
than hotel minibars, Mia.
You're an economist
and should know that.
Okay, so I die of thirst,
is that it?
What do you want? Water?
I brought water, so we
wouldn't have to spend money.
Hey, the room is occupied.
Who are you?
Good morning, darlings.
I am Suzana, cabin chief and I.
Oh, and also to warn you to
hurry up because your
time is almost over.
What is it?
The boat is sinking and
there aren't enough boats.
What boat, kid, you're going
to miss breakfast!
It's only served until
10 o'clock!
Man, we slept really
well, right?
We've already missed
a lot of things, Mia.
Have a look, we lost
a lecture on the importance
of arnica, a relaxing
walk with Uncle Ruy,
a Jacuzzi for pregnant women
Mia, we're paying we have
to enjoy everything!
He's just kidding.
Well, if you want it,
I can bring your breakfast
to your bed, no problems.
That way you can relax,
wake up on your own time,
acuddle a bit.
That's great!
God, what a mess!
Let me take care of that.
I'll put everything in
the closet for you.
The service here is
super VIP, huh?
Honey, for just 40 extra
dollars, I wash, iron, sex...
Look, that's one of their
tactics, I know!
We don't want it.
What's included in the package.
Do you want me to warn
reception that they mixed up
his bags with those
of a teenager?
Mia, this tobogan is a monster.
Man, this tobogan is awesome!
Fabio, don't you think
that now that you're
a married man you
should try to speak
less slang, read some
adult books
Mia, seriously, now that
you're a married woman,
couldn't you relax
and let your man be happy
with the entire range of
his tastes and hobbies?
You're right, I'm sorry,
I love you!
Wonderful little fuck
we had earlier today.
WONDERFUL.
The five minute one because
you wanted to come quickly
to enjoy the day?
My love, here the days
are wasted in dollars!
We have to enjoy them!
And all that phobia,
all that fear?
It was terror, we know
that, and it was replaced
by the fear of being here
on the ship, spending
a fortune and not enjoying and
not making the most of everything!
Excuse me, lovely couple!
My name is Wilson and
came to tell you that in a
few minutes we'll have
the forro class with me
and the lambaerética class
with Guilherme Malhagao.
It's not right that they're
both at the same time.
Because if those two
Classes are in the package,
the right thing would be for
me to be able to do both...
But you have that right!
You're the one who chooses!
Then I'll do the forré class
and you the lambaerébica!
That way we enjoy to the max
the advantages of the ship.
He's joking...
Come on, forward and backwards.
To one side, go...
You're great.
Now make your bodies sexy, everyone.
Very sexy.
That's great, now each
of you choose a partner!
Oh, lovely creature,
what's your name?
Fabio.
Fabio, I'm going to take
you out of solitude you'll
be my assistant!
Mia, don't drink that,
drinks are included
in the package, right?
Not at all, you have
to pay for everything.
I get it, your wife
likes to spend a lot?
Actually, I don't know, we've
only known each other a month.
It was a love at
first site thing.
I'm finding out here.
Really?
Then enjoy this moment
all you can.
After that it's all down hill.
First there's the "you're
the love of my life" phase,
then it's "come on, man,
don't talk like that to me"
and at the end the
"you fucking bastard,
"I should have never
met you" phase.
Just to remind you that
I'm on my honeymoon and
you're an employee paid
to entertain, give hope.
That's right, but you
can't have joy and hope
in the life I lead, kid,
especially with a bitch
for an ex-wife over there.
This woman invaded my room
today without even asking
for permission.
She did the same with my life.
Which is much worse.
Hey, Wilson, you could really
have a good thing here, you know?
All these hot chicks...
And you think the chicks
are the ones who hit
on the entertainers?
My turn to dance
with the big boy!
Of course! It's an honor!
What is your name, ma'am?
Ma'am is in heaven
just like the three
husbands I buried.
My name is Mirtes.
You are very elegant, Mirtes.
I imagine these husbands
left behind much more
than just good memories for you.
Let's dance.
Let's dance...
Come your face close, please!
That scented that you are today!
Let's start?
What's the name of
her best friend?
Correct. And couple 3?
Who is Lu?
What is his favorite movie?
Dead Poets Society.
My God, they're Jamaicans,
they're cold, what more
do you want from a movie?
Purple.
That's a color?
He said color.
Clarice Lispector.
The blogger?
Crotch.
Fabio...
Oh, unfortunately couple
number 3 is disqualified.
I can't qualify you, you
haven't made any points.
It's much better!
Because it means that
we'll get to know each other
much better during our life.
It's much better to be
surprised ten years from now,
like: Carolzinha, who is she?
Oh, your best friend...
Couple 1 has won.
Congratulations!
They won a super fanny pack.
Congratulations, a fanny pack!
And inside the fanny pack,
there is a stay at a five
star hotel in Italy!
Couldn't you even remember that
my favorite director is Truffaut?
Truffaut? Isn't that
a kind of chocolate?
Fabio, I showed you one
of his movies, remember?
All I remember is that when I
woke up some documentary was on TV.
I'm tired, Fabio.
You won't stop for a second.
You won't even stop talking!
Do me a solid.
You know all the old ladies
fall for me,
you have access to the
ballroom key
I take the old ladies there
and in half an hour of dancing,
I get some money from them.
You keep an eye out to make
sure no one comes.
Forget it, Wilson,
I'm not going to be a pimp
for my bankrupt ex-husband
who takes advantage
of dancing grannies.
We have to find another
way to make some extra money
and get out of here.
I can't stand looking
at your face every day!
And you think I can stand it?
Second day and they're
already at it.
You know what that's called?
Marriage.
Poor guy, he got
married too fast.
I think this marriage
isn't going to last,
it won't last even until Europe.
I want 50%.
You want? What?
Give me 50% of what
you make with the old ladies
that I'll help you with
the illegal ball.
I hate doing business with you.
If on the second day of
marriage you're already tired,
I don't know how it's going
to be when we get to Italy.
Let's choose together, love.
Gym opening.
The most modern in America.
Bridge ten.
You don't even like exercising.
But it could be fun,
they'll have some hotties.
Fabio!
I mean, some hot activities
some nice bikes...
Let's go? I need to
work on my glutes!
I've surfed, did rock climbing,
and participated in marathons!
But I had never seen sport
as an extension of my work.
Today I know that the
courage necessary to jump
from a mountain at a height
of 300 meters is the same
for new investments!
Without will and passion,
we wouldn't have become the
largest fitness enterprise
in Latin America!
Wonderfull!
He? He get atletic power.
Let's go further up ahead.
No, I'm fine here.
Don't you want to go
back to our room, love?
I need to take one of
your anxiety meds.
Suddenly I feel so
afraid of ships...
It's written there that the
guy's biography is for free.
Why not get a copy?
We already missed out
on the quiz prize.
Sailing is necessary.
And so is working out!
We wish you all a good trip!
Hello, fine? My name is Fabio,
can I have another one?
I'm here with my wife
over there, Mia!
It's our honeymoon!
Oh, that's your wife?
She is shy?
Not at all, she's jealous
of me, poor thing.
Lots of hot chicks here, right?
It's just a passing thing!
Can you autograph
it for me, please.
Write "For Fabio and Mia,
with love"...
Man, what a chic guy.
He completed a master's
degree In Massachussets.
degree in sports marketing
management in llli-fucking-nois!
I'm not feeling very well!
Hi, how are the lovebirds?
Everything is fine.
Actually I already cleaned
up the room, you can give me
tip next time, okay?
But you just got married
and you're already so pale,
not knowing how to tell your
husband that it was a mistake?
That love doesn't exist and
that living with any other human
being is unbearable?
It's not because Wilson kicked
you to the curb that we are going
to be unhappy, right?
Honey, I don't know what that
lowly employee told you,
but I was the one who
let him go.
Take it, I just came to
give you this VIP invitation
for dinner tonight.
VIP invitation?
Enjoy! Considering how
cheap you are,
it's not always that you
have this chance, right?
Is it an actual invitation in
the sense that it's free
or one of those trap invitations
and you have to pay at the end?
Looks like it's an actual
invitation,
but we can forget about this.
Let's just stay in our room
tonight, just you and me?
"Fabio and Mia, who are already
on a honeymoon, I will have great
pleasure to receive you for
a special dinner at the
ship's best restaurant.
I'll expect you at nine.
"A big hug, Beto Assunc¢ao!"
Ah, it's from him, is it?
That's nice.
Rich people love making
friends with ordinary people.
It brings credibility.
And I have charisma right,
so I bring people together.
But we didn't bring clothes
for this VIP restaurant.
You didn't even bring
a basic blazer.
Basic or not basic
blazer my ass!
You know what, love?
I would rather we have
dinner just the two of
us something more simple.
Honey, you're going to have
dinner just with me for
the rest of your life.
And it's always going to be
beans rice potatoes.
But tonight I want to enjoy
with the love of my life a little
free glamour.
Can you do that for me?
Great!
Is that one?
Is good!
- And now?
- Is Ok!
-For what?
Good, you nor looked at!
Oh, Sir!
And now did you like this one?
That's great.
By the way, you
cancelled the dinner.
Now we're going to the Oscars!
You're not going dresses
like that, are you, Fabio?
You can't go to dinner
with that shirt!
Why not? I've had dinner
with it since I was 15
and I've never had any problems!
Let's focus here, Fabio:
This one or this one?
They're just the same
so it doesn't matter.
Of course not this one is
white and this one is eggshell.
Oh, I get it. Give me
the eggshell one then.
Oh, my God, have you seen
the price of this white shirt
trying to be eggshell?
Forget it, put it back.
Eh! Is very chic! What is this?
Honey, I have to tell
you something.
I didn't want to come to
this dinner because Beto, he...
Look him there,
can you talk later.
How are you?
This is Mia, my wife.
Who would have imagined!
This is Fabio, my husband.
I know, very nice we spoke
at the opening!
But let's sit down.
My wife should be coming soon.
You know how it is they
take ages to get ready.
I do.
I got ready really fast.
I took two seconds.
Per favore puo portare
che il vino italiano rosato?
You still like rosé wine, right?
Yes, a lot, my favorite.
Fabio?
- Could be.
- We studied together...
How are Dona Ruth,
Mr. Luiz Carlos!?
Great. My parents...
And your uncles, they still
have that house in Ibiuna?
You still like French movies?
Truffaut, right?
Wow, some good times
at that house!
Taking a bath in the
river and then a movie.
I used to invite my
class from college...
Look, make yourselves at home.
But I warn your chef, Nicola,
is offering a tasting menu...
Wow, awesome,
congratulations to Nicola!
Listen, don't these chic dinners always
have those bullshit shrimp dishes?
Where's the shrimp?
Fancy restaurants always
have them.
He's joking.
This is my wife,
Laura. Mia and Flavio.
Fabio.
Hi honey.
Hello, good night. Good night.
Wow, you...
L... Laura?
Ih, it's Titty! Titty! Titty!
Come, Laura, this
kid is strange!
you seem familiar
to me, you know?
I have an ordinary
face, that's all.
I'm sorry I'm late.
I was on the phone
with an old patient.
Laura, and it's not
just because she's my wife,
but I'd say she's one
of the best doctors
in the country.
Don't exaggerate...
That's great. What's
your specialty?
She's a pediatrician,
but she is really in love
with alternative treatments.
Chinese, Indian medicine!
A great woman!
Stop, Beto. I really
love children and...
She loves studying!
Helping people!
Wow, pediatrician is
really cool. I love kids.
You really wore me down tonight!
Stud! Sexy! I want more!
Later, Dona Mirtes. Later.
You have to take a medicine.
Dona Mirtes wipe out
she dance very well.
So? How much did we make?
They came with this talk that
seniors pay half price, Wilson.
I got 100 dollars.
Fifty for me and fifty for you.
Old crows! And I'm sweaty all over,
giving my all in the
electronic meringue!
For nothing!
I make more money
cleaning toilets.
Since we split up, you've been
going down hill, honey.
Fuck!
And now in Salvador we're
going to open the first
six units in Bahia.
So you see, the company
is really growing.
Wow...
And, Mia, what do you do?
I'm a economics journalist...
Save a little is good, but you don't!
And how did you meet?
Yeah, how?
Let go of me so we
can sing Happy Birthday.
Are you nuts?
Look at what you did.
You got my hair all wet,
my new dress.
In Paris, right, love?
Hi, would you have something
that's less "sea"?
A cheeseburger, an omelet?
He's joking!
And Fabio? What does
we work with?
And speaking of work!
Sorry, it must be one
of my companies!
- Hello, mr. Rubens.
- Binho, how is everything on the ship?
Yes, Mr. Rubens, everything
is as expected.
I'm sorry to bother you,
son, but what is the costume
we have to send to fix?
Batman or Spiderman?
The orphan man's, who lost
his parent's too early.
What, son?
The one who lost his parents
in a robbery, so sad.
He finally get revenge and
turn out a milionnare!
We are almost close the deal.
We have to grow up!
Hello, Fabio?
I didn't understand anything.
Police captain? Judge?
Criminal lawyer?
I work with big events.
Imagine that, another
business man at the table!
Large parties, very sought after,
thematic, with great impact, crazy...
What kind of audience?
Child audience.
Education?
Yeah, you could say that.
His family has a child's buffet.
Oh, that's so cute.
Gee, I've always people who
manage to stay forever
in their childhood.
Actually, how many
memories today.
Laura, I forgot to tell you, but
Mia and I used to be sweethearts!
Really?
What a coincidence.
I am very happy to have
met you at this,
very important for me.
And for you, of course!
A toast to your honeymoon!
Dessert?
Look, I can't stay any longer.
Remember, love, that we
were going to see
the rerun of that Sunday show?
It's almost
time. So I have to go!
Success!, pediatrician,
very happy.
I'm taking the rose because
she loves it... You see?
I didn't even want to
come to this dinner!
But you couldn't give
lose a free meal
for anything in the world.
If you weren't so cheap,
we would have had
a romantic dinner just
the two of us.
Lying is ten times
worse than enjoying
toasts and VIP invitations, Mia!
I didn't lie.
I tried to tell you.
Why are you so irritated?
Because I'm a childish,
fearful man who never
left my childhood,
isn't that right?
Enough, this argument
makes no sense!
Forget it, Beto!
You called me Beto?
No, I said Fabio, Fabio.
I said Fabio.
Don't be silly, honey.
Beto is part of another
part of my life.
A time when everything
was fun, partying, adventure.
Really?
Of course! Now I want
to have kids, stay at home
and watch TV by your side!
Oh, with him its fun and with
me its washing the dishes!
Fabio, there is no reason for you to
idealize my relationship with Beto.
We had many problems.
Tell me one them.
And it better be good.
"Oh, he didn't cut
his toe nails".
I want something serious!
Okay... Well we had a
serious sexual problem.
Ah-ha! I knew it!
These guys can't get it up,
they have their blood
stuck in their heads.
It was just like that...
but it was the opposite.
This hyperactivity thing
was the worse.
Beto wanted to have sex all the
time, morning, noon and night.
It was a terrible problem!
I'm going to take a walk
and figure out what is
the best way to kill myself and
we'll see each other later, okay?
Meanwhile, you can have
your favorite rosé, okay?
I'm very tired!
What a surprise finding
your ex-girlfriend here...
So much time lost with intense, crazy,
jealous, scandalous, aggressive women.
Where were you that you
didn't show up sooner?
Are you sure that my meeting
my ex didn't bother you?
Of course not! You had a
love life before you met me!
And since I enjoyed it,
it was great, I really had fun.
But you're not bothered,
are you?
No, love. It's all fine.
Give me a whiskey, please.
Did someone die or your
problem is just marriage?
I've just found out that the
super millionaire on the ship
is my wife's ex-boyfriend.
And the worse thing is that
she never told me about him.
She thought you would be bothered
because you're poor or she never
forgot this guy and thought
you would be bothered
because you're poor.
Hum?
It's that the poor guy complex
is the right answer.
And the guy is married with the
most beautiful from my school.
I was crazy about her during all
my teenage years.
Wait a minute!
Your wife is much more hot because
I'm a red blooded man and
I saw her in a bikini today and
she's here with you on a honeymoon.
She's not with him.
You're really going to waste a
night of make up sex because
of some shitty millionaire with
whom she did not marry?
Why are we here?
- On the ship?
- Yeah.
Because we got married and...
And we love each other...
Okay, it's getting good...
We love each other
and I'm crazy about you...
It's getting better, I like it...
And I'm crazy for you and
I'm really getting horny
I love you very much!
I love you too!
Let's go, baby.
Fabio?
That tasting menu didn't
agree with me!
What didn't agree with you
was stuffing yourself like a refugee.
Go on, get dressed already,
we're already in Salvador.
Does the HMO helicopter
come out here?
Come on! My godmother is dying to
meet you, get rid of that sick face!
Honey, look at me,
I'm in no shape to go.
But she said she would
make a vatapa, acarajé, that
shrimp with garlic and
olive oil that you love.
Honey? You're not okay, are you?
You go, honey. I'll be fine.
Are you sure?
Of course, this here is
nothing! I'll be fine.
Hi, Beto.
Where are you going?
I can give you a lift.
Forget it, Beto, there's no
need. I'll wait for the next one.
Don't be silly, Mia.
I'm in a car,
I'm heading downtown, come on.
Yeah... ok.
Just drop me off anywhere
and I'll catch a cab.
Calm down, we're getting
to the infirmary!
You had to have taken some
medicine against seasickness,
this happens very frequently.
I not only took twenty of those pills
as I took all the other medicines
there are in the universe.
I think there is no point in going to
the infirmary to deliver my life
into the hands of some
incompetent resident,
I need an experienced doctor.
So you're going to have a witch doctor
look you over, take a bath with coarse
salt, a more
alternative medicine.
Fabio? Are you all right?
Oh, I miss my godchild so much,
you are the one I love the most!
Hi, godmother, let me
introduce you, this is...
What an elegant man
you married, my dear!
No, godmother, this isn't...
Huh? What a catch.
But look at this car.
It's like a spaceship.
And your mother was so worried
thinking that your husband
was just some ordinary man, but
look what a lovely man what a catch!
To protect you and protect your
love. Welcome to the family!
Gee, thanks! It's an honor!
Godmother, no, that's not it...
We have to take a picture to preserve
this lovely moment, come on.
Sorry, this is the liver.
I vomited so much it
ended up in my foot, right?
This is the heart!
God, my heart sometimes
beats in strange places...
Calm down, everything
will be fine.
You always wanted to be a
doctor, right? Since school
yeah. When I turned 18, I
went off to do some work as a
model abroad and I became
interested in oriental medicine.
You lived in Japan. Tokyo.
Exactly. Then I came back,
applied for medical school...
He get on federal exam
in third place.
Wow, you were guessing this as
I was placing the needles on you?
This connection with the patient is
very rare and very magical.
You are very sensitive, Fabio!
Yeah, that's how I am.
But it also helped that we studied
in the same class at school.
What?
I want you to tell me everything.
How was the wedding?
She probably was very
beautiful, right, Mr. Fabio?
Godmother, I want to make clear
once and for all...
Look when your godchild walked into
the church in the white dress and veil,
I started trembling, truly, I was
frozen because I was so nervous.
She was the most beautiful bride
I have ever seen in my life.
You are beatifull.
Can I do an ayurvedic massage?
Breathe and relax.
Relax everything. Relax.
I'm getting tenser.
It's pulling...
Relax. Release the
air in five times.
I think I'll relax better on my back.
It makes it easier for me.
You have wide shoulders, they're great
for exercising. Don't you like that?
Of course I do. I kind of let go because
I ate too much at the wedding party,
but tomorrow I'll be in the gym!
It's so weird that we studied at
the same school, right?
Funny I don't remember any
Fabio in my class.
It's okay. I wouldn't
remember me if I were you.
According to Ayurveda, when
any of the five elements are in
unbalance, a disease
process begins.
That is why you were sick...
Ah, sorry to bore you
with all this talk.
Beto is always saying this no one
is interested in this stuff.
No, perish the thought!
I'm loving this story of the
elements, earth, water, rock,
paper, scissors! Really!
You didn't have to say that to please
me, I saw you were nearly sleeping.
Laura, I'm sleepy
because for the first time
on this ship I'm feeling
100% calm and relaxed.
Oh, no, get off of me,
senior citizens!
Excuse!
Dona Mirtes! Were
you looking for me?
No, honey, I'm sorry, not
I only dance with Danilinho.
He is younger, dances
better and new flesh
is always more
interesting, isn't it?
Wow, do you remember that you had
to convince your father that I wasn't
going to drink and also had
to take your friends home.
God, my friends turned
out to be so boring.
And you turned out so
beautiful. What is it?
I feel guilty for lying for leaving
Fabio in the room
I loved being your
husband for a few minutes.
Beto, please.
I mean it. What can I
do, Mia? You move me.
What part of "this is my
honeymoon" you didn't understand?
You want me to really ignore this
crazy coincidence? And look, it's
obvious that Fabio
isn't the man for you!
You're crazy to say something like
that. You're being overbearing.
You don't even know Fabio!
But I know you very well.
You broke up with me because
you were a girl and I was the
older, more experienced man.
You couldn't handle that.
Okay. But now you're an incredible
woman, are you going to be scared?
Goodbye.
Incredible how
you still smell the same.
- Mia? Z?
- Hi, love!
Hi, love, how are you?
Wow, are you better?
I am... yeah (coughs) a little.
Kind of... Well, now that
you mentioned it. I'm not.
My godmother said these are to
protect you and protect our love.
You explained that I was sick.
I explained,
she understood completely.
I'll call her later to thank her.
No! There's no need. She doesn't
care about these formalities.
Of course I'm calling.
Give me her phone number.
- Her phone doesn't work very well.
- You sure?
- She lives in a distant area.
- I'll send the e-mail.
There is no cell phone
service or internet.
What a crazie!
I would like she love me justa little.
Than after, she will love me,
than we will be back!
- You will be there, and metting!
- I like!
You look so flushed, love,
it doesn't look like you
were in the room all day.
Yeah, well, it's
I think the fever is coming back!
It could be malaria, dengue
fever, stagnant water.
God, what karma. I can't get away
from this looser even in the kitchen.
Hey, Suzana, don't
butt into my life, okay?
Okay, okay. Listen, did you or
didn't you find a way for us
to get some money
from the passengers?
Mirtes isn't
yielding me any money.
I haven't thought of anything because
I was present at the birth of adultery!
Do you know where I left
the silly blonde kid?
At the SPA!
Doing what? Buddhist badinage with
that trophy wife of Beto Assuncao!
Come on, you think the
worst about everybody.
They were there, lying down talking each
others ears off, laughing like crazy!
And where are the spouses?
On land. This isn't going to
have a good ending.
Wilson. I can see it!
Wait a minute...
If there is something that these
lazy women on cruises love is
a little tarot, some astrology.
Sounds good.
If I give you privileged
information, can I keep 50%?
Deal!
Then pay attention.
Fabio was crazy for this
Laura woman when she was a
teenager! He studied with her!
Beto Assuncao is Mia's ex.
They, that is, the couples are
doing the crossing.
Are you all right, girl?
Sure, why?
I think you look a little worn,
your skin a little muddled,
I feel some confused feelings.
Don't you want me to
read you the tarot cards?
There's no need, thanks.
The first one is free. Look,
I know you don't want it, but
I can do a quick reading,
I can see a situation from the
past that hasn't been put to rest,
but which is coming back now
with full force.
Really?
I see betrayal now
I see an ex-boyfriend,
a stolen hug... Death!
Take it easy, it can be the end
f the rebirth of a love affair!
That's it. Sorry, to see more, I
really have to do a proper reading.
How much is that?
200 dollars.
Hey, this gym isn't modern at all,
there are bicycles in all.
This treadmill is modern,
there's a computer.
Eh, boy... there is a computer.
I'm very hi. Today, very hi!
This boy, Great!
Let's go. Move on, is good?
Fabio! What a surprise finding you
here. I didn't know you jogged!
Oh, I love it. And today I'm really very
excited to run. I should run all day.
Look, if you allow
me to give you a tip.
The tip.
The tip is permited. What is a tip?
Set it to this speed here.
On this inclination here.
For you who is just starting,
it is important to maintain some
constancy, this speed is okay?
This is the speed at which you run?
No, but I've been running
for 17 years, see?
But I've always been very
active, I have a good structure.
I'm always on the run. Bam, bam,
running here and there.
I have a good frame, big thighs,
I run pretty good. You can
adjust it to the same as yours.
- Ok.
- 13.
Go straited!
Everything's fine.
I'm going to market, get some DVD.
I went on some dancing place.
I caught a lulling.
I'm going to home, to put some
letters on mail box.
Good. That's good!
So, how are things with Mia?
That's good!
Yesterday I was talking
that never being so happy.
Fine? But a marriage
is a marriage.
Not even a discussion,
a drag out fight?
If you'll allow me a tip.
Another one!? Go on.
Wow lots of tips.
You are the tip guy.
If one day she gets angry buy
her a jewel with diamonds.
It can be simple, like a
pendant or a solitaire.
That's all?
And traveling, of course.
Bed and breakfasts from the
Charm Route, resorts yachts.
Mia is just like a child, isn't she?
She is easily distracted.
When you least expect it,
she's already forgotten the fight.
Do you have some other tip, something
under the 15 thousand dollars limit?
Of course I do, but you'll have
to find them alone.
Easy, easy, are you all right?
I'm fine. Has the Sao
Silvestre race started?
Look who's here. My helper.
What are you doing
here all alone?
Are you trying to run away from your
big spending wife? We're starting a
relaxing walk in a moment, coming?
I don't think so, right now I'm feeling
kind of shitty, I'm going to stay here.
It's being hard to
bear the presence
of my wife's big dick,
athletic, millionaire
stud ex-boyfriend, right here
in my honeymoon. It's hard.
Come on, kid. But feeling kind of
shitty is just a basic prerequisite
for being a married man. You'll
just have to learn how to live
with it. So the guy is...
Huge. It's actually a little scary.
It's immense a ship, a vessel.
And you and Mia, how are you? And
the other one, your crush from school?
You won't tell anyone?
Don't talk about it out loud.
Who would I tell? My only friend here is
you. I don't know anyone in this place.
Tell me everything,
get it all off your chest, man!
Let's go, guys.
Concentration!
Any news?
Fabio didn't tell Mia that he got
a relaxing massage at
the spa and by her turn, Mia
did not tell Fabio that she
came back from Salvador
very friendly with her ex.
This is going to end badly,
Suzana, because not only Beto has
a big dick but he's addicted to sex.
And you tell me this without
any preparation.
My God, this is wonderful.
I'm even all sweaty.
You're so shameless,
Suzana! Get away from me!
Go find a toilet to clean yourself.
Mia!
I'm just taking a walk...
It's lovely. Come in, there's room!
It's water from the Dead Sea.
They say it's good for the skin.
My mother always
says, the skin first.
You never came here?
No, you come here often?
Every day, get in already,
you'll feel the difference.
Can the Dead Sea be really here?
I loved our dinner.
You're such a fun couple.
I loved the
invitation, too. Thanks.
Beto speaks of you
with great tenderness.
I'm glad that's not
an issue for you.
Of course not, we're both mature and
balanced. That's how it is for you?
No! Truly, Fabio was a bit
bothered when he found out
about Beto, because
he is crazy about me.
Really? It didn't look like it.
It didn't look like
he is crazy about me?
No! He didn't seem
to be bothered!
And yesterday, at the spa, I
also found him very sweet, calm.
Spa?
Yeah, he wasn't feeling too
good because of his liver and
I did some detoxifying work
with him using my hands.
He didn't tell you about it?
Oh, yeah, he did. Of
course, now I remember.
Thanks! With your
hands, huh? To detoxify?
And how is he, is he better?
He's fine. He's really great!
I'm glad, Fabio is such fun.
Yeah, great fun.
You're lucky, marrying a
man with a sense of humor.
All these coincidences are funny.
All? There are a lot
of them? There are more?
We used to study
at the same school,
but I didn't realize it,
Fabio is so different.
And married with
my husband's ex.
It's a small world!
You studied together?
Look at this things. Excuse me!
Only ugly women here!
What is this shit?
I think you owe
me an explanation!
Oh, yeah? Then you owe me too!
What? Have you checked the
Internet today?
What is this I hear about
you and Laura at the spa?
Laura is a doctor and I was feeling
very sick when you left me behind
to die, remember?
The ship has its own
doctors, remember?
But you'd rather look up you
little friend to get a massage.
Meanwhile, my wife was introducing
her husband to the family!
To an aunt that didn't
even have a phone,
and she now has a
Facebook account!
The only reason why I don't go
and bash his face in
is because... because...
Because he didn't do anything.
He just gave me a ride.
My godmother never let me
explain. If you look carefully,
you'll see I look awful in
the picture, very unhappy.
You are laughing, Mia.
I'm laughing because
I'm so nervous.
My godmother is a nut job,
but I know who my husband is!
And I love him!
From now on we'll have a pact
to only say the truth. Deal?
You have cellulite.
I once faked an orgasm with you.
You shore.
You have bad breath
in the morning.
You have this fold under
your arm that is kind of fat.
Look at your stomach.
You look beautiful when
you're angry.
I get so angry that I can't
get angry at you.
Attention! Lady and gentleman!
Be prepair to crossing
the atlantic sea.
In 3 days we will be on Marrocos.
Honey, take it easy. We'll
arrive in Casablanca tomorrow.
I'm calm, Mia.
Calmer now because it's been
two days seven hours and five
minutes since we've had a fight!
Promise that nothing more
is going to get in our way?
I promise!
Couldn't you have told me
that you were going to meet
this friend of yours?
I wanted to surprise you, Mia,
you're going to love him.
Titty! Fatso!
Give it to me, Head!
Ask me if I have candy?
You have candy?
Titty.
Stop. Let me introduce
you, this is Mia,
the woman of my life.
This here is Head.
Hey, Mia, how's tricks?
But tell me!
Have you seen anyone
from the old gang?
And Bolado, have you seen him?
And Peida? Mario Maconha?
Rodrigueira? Big Joe?
Fart, pum, fart men.
What is this? What a Casablanca?
Let's applaud the most
beautiful woman in the world.
What are you doing now, Head?
Currently nothing.
Okay, and when you are
doing something?
The thing is that with this
busy life as a traveler,
I don't have a lot
of time to work.
So I'm making due with
my unemployment checks.
Wow cool!
Cool? The unemployment
benefits are sinking Europe.
No boss can compete because
the government pays.
People better to
not do anything.
Great! The dream is becoming
reality. Master, master...
Hey, Fabio, you know
what I remembered now?
All of us classifying women in
school by the size of their boobs.
Whait... 12!
Easy to win!
Remember, I was the fourth!
I Was the fourth!
- I won of Gabi and Paulinha.
- Paulinha, she is breast less.
What is this?
Take, take...
Loved meeting you Head.
It was great you came here
to say hello to your friend.
Bye now.
Fabio didn't tell you?
I'm going to travel with you guys.
- On the ship!
- Let's go, she is very on time people.
I told you he was afraid of
being alone in the cabin,
he's kind of tense with
this high sea thing.
But it's just for tonight.
All right, you want me to sleep in
the extra bed so you can
spoon with your friend Head?
Come on, Mia, it wasn't on purpose
but I can't leave my friend alone.
First it was just to
remember old times,
then he comes to
torment us on the ship?
Pretty soon I'll find out that his name
is Rubia and you have a son together.
Look, lady, let's make one thing clear.
This kid who is before us called Fatso,
had a very difficult
adolescence,
many problems and who
was with him to help him?
Who?
You better believe it!
So now you see how
he's much better?
Look, Mia, pay attention!
I won't let you take my man
away from me you hear me?
Oh, My man.
- His joke!
- Did you see the girl?
God! Look at her face!
Eh, the breast of my man.
Get around!
Whait Mia, just a joke.
She don't get you humor.
I-Oh, Mia! Is refined!
Alone at last!
Listen, I had the impression that
I saw muse of your
self-abuse, from fifth to eighth
grade on the ship.
SHHHH, not so loud!
I don't want Mia to know.
By the way, try to be nice.
Mia and I have just made up,
things are much better.
Come on, she is a wonderful
woman, a woman who is...
A pain in the ass!
She couldn't even receive
your best friend properly!
Actually, for everything.
You married and we didn't
even get drunk!
Come with me, my man.
Let's get drunk!
Look, I'm sorry to intrude, but I can
see you like to know about the future.
I work with the
future too. Tarot,
divination, coffee
grinds, palm readings
I get it, look, thanks,
I don't believe in this stuff.
It's not everyone who
has this talent.
I've been perfecting my
gifts for years.
Looking at you, I see a
"woman from the past."
What?
Sir, I know women
from a distance.
No way, I'm a married man.
My wife can come
in at any moment.
Ok, since you don't want
to know how your ex feels.
No, wait!
Do I have a chance with her?
You know, I'm not
feeling anything anymore?
Being sensitive
requires some incentive.
Excuse.
Look, I see that you
are on the same path.
You are going to
reach a destination
and are going to
arrive at the same time.
Really?
For just a little more,
I can guide you better and...
Shure. Right here!
This is good!
Is very good. Excuse me!
Yeah, she misses something that
is very grandiose about you.
Something she doesn't have
with the current spouse.
I can't see here is if it's
character or goodness,
but really seems
something palpable.
- Are you sure, Suzana?
- Absolutely!
The tarot isn't giving
us anything.
It's far from freeing us from
this enforced togetherness,
this prison called a cruise
ship. We have to go big.
You see that security guard
over there? Stall him with some
story cause I'm going to gamble
a bit. Or do you want to go?
You have more luck than me, Suzana,
you married me. I married you,
I have terrible luck.
- Get out here!
- Will be a winner..
Look the man, looking us!
Everything goes wrong with you!
You're nothing but
a washed up old man,
like that grandfather
of yours who used
to extort money from
the alcoholic sister!
You know I can't handle it
when you badmouth my family!
They're better than you cousins,
those whores from Valinhos!
The only slut cousin was yours, the
one who hung out at the overpass.
The Ema who lived with the
bad bladeer.
- Oh right!
- Ok!
After discharge, the
things going to were?
To the gap.
Gap? Must be stunk.
My God, look at your wifey...
Stop! That's rightt.
Look at, is everyhing that we wanted.
To this very special day: To
Esteban's bachelor party!
Eh, esteban, congratulations!
Today is to extrapolate!
We lost more than one warrior.
We lost two warriors.
Right, Anderson?
Stop, stop... I'm jealous.
That's why I don't want
anyone touching my man.
But everything is included here.
But I'm "The Inclusive"
Only one way.
French kiss, French Kiss...
Hey, I'm not fucking gay!
What is it, bro?
Is a lie!
We're kidding!
French kiss, French Kiss...
Thanks.
I tried...
No.
Listen, I just wanted...
Shut up!
Sorry, honey, are we late?
No, not at all!
Hey there, Mimia. Were
you waiting for us?
Gee, that's so creative!
Actually, no, I was waiting for
my husband for a romantic
dinner for two. Oh, do you
want an extra chair for you?
Ih, so tense.
I thought you had cooled off.
I'll take a walk, see you.
Gee, honey you went too far.
Oh, really! There is
a limit for everything.
Love, enough, you can trust me.
Head isn't going to
bother us, I swear.
Tomorrow he's going
to his own room, okay?
Take easy!
We are getting a competition
on contest of belly!
Falling! Get out!
Get out here.
Don't scrull my jump!
Hi, who are you again?
I'm Head.
I'm sharing a room with
Mia and Fabio, Fatso.
Poor guys, come on, they're
on their honeymoon!
Poor Fabio, who married
this unbearable woman.
Because, I mean, come on,
she could be more easygoing.
Hi, hi, hi, remember me?
You're Fabio's friend, right?
He's a doll!
Now, is me!
Judge, be prepair!
Go Fabio, is you!
Champ!
Corageos!
Fabio, I can understand why
you work with children!
I have their mental age.
I was going to say their purity!
Yeah?
Ok.
Hey there, wifey!
There's going to be a
super couples competition.
Unfortunately, my husband
traded me for his asshole
friend and the Zen ass
of his school crush.
I'm going to give you a tip,
pay attention, dear.
When a man marries a woman,
they also marry the family.
When the woman marries the man,
she also married his friends.
So there's no point
fighting against it.
I would rather
have a manipulating
mother-in-law that
this brainless friend...
You can be sure that you'll
also have the manipulating
mother-in-law or your husband
wouldn't act like
a 14-year-old beast
in a 9-year-old body.
I get it, you had sex
with my chambermaid, became
confused and decided to take
it out on me, who have no
participation in any of this.
Go, leave, get out, entertainer,
because I'm trying to see dolphins
and you're in my way!
Thurday only on Costa Fabulosda.
The big bale with mask.
I wanted to take
the opportunity that
we're alone to talk
about our relationship.
Sure, honey! A very
propitious moment!
I actually think Head is nice, and
I also want to meet Ass, Ear, Neck...
But I think we should
do more romantic things.
We should try a little cooler
hotel tomorrow when we get to Italy,
this one with a community
bathroom that you reserved,
frankly... and going back
to Brazil, I would like to
change your TV room into a closet
because my clothes and your clothes...
Gorgeus! What a romantic!
I'm very festive..
Honey, can you get a drink for us?
With ambrella, strawberry.
- Let's talk more!
- Yes, talk about everything.
I want the carpet on the room.
Let's put the sofa and green cushion
you are crazzy?
Let's go there, come on!
Yeah, Mia will take a drink to me.
The best fantasy of the ship.
Won the prize!
Look at the commander!
Where you get the fantasy
do convincent.
Weren't you in that gay group
that was partying with Esteban?
Looks like a washing machine.
Look, we're really in shit.
Look, Captain Giuseppe,
we really didn't get it see?
We thought it was a costume.
Eh Freitas?
The bous had a inappropriate behavior
and need
stay by here.
- Have to stay here.
- Just a little.
Amateur. Now learn from someone
who knows. Zorro is going to play.
It's all or nothing now,
Wilson, you go take a long walk,
take that bad luck away from me!
You're completely wrong. We either
play together or we don't play.
- Dona Suzana, did you understood?
- Ok!
- So, you go!
- Do you believe?
- I'm talking!
- 0k, nothing!
- But!
- Oh, god!
Lie!
I told you, you bastard,
that I was lucky!
I told you, you depraved woman,
that I'm your lucky charm!
The man who leaves alone the most
beautiful woman on the ship
has no concept of danger.
You're talking about
yourself, aren't you?
Where did you leave your wife?
She is resting, will wake up
early tomorrow to meditate.
My marriage is over, Mia.
It was already at an end.
It was borring!
But then I found you again.
Look what the pirate here stole
for you at a jewelry store today.
Are you crazy?
I'm kidding. I didn't steal it.
I just bought it.
Come back to me, Mia?
You're a handsome, wealthy,
nice smelling, wealthy guy...
Wealthy...
But I love my husband.
And where is he? Or do you think
it's right to be alone like this
during your honeymoon?
I don't know where that
bastard is and neither
that blockhead friend of his.
You know what? Let's dance!
Suzana, look at this!
I can't believe we won all this
money, you crazy, wonderful woman!
We can finally leave this ship, get on
with our lives, be rid of each other.
None of that, let's not confuse
things. I was the one who won!
- You won!
- Yeah, was me!
Suzana, don't be crazy now. The money
will be shared between both of us.
Hmm, are you nervous now?
You sound like your uncle Cleber,
unemployed, living off his wife.
Don't start,
you know I can't take it!
How about your mother, who never
worked, that useless ignorant woman!
- Talk about her.
- She is better than
your ignorant, classless brother
who says "nucular” and " dolphins”.
"Pei" as peru, brother.
Came here right now, I will cath you!
And your cousin Rose,
that pig with the nasty nails.
Your father is a beggar.
This is a hot!
Oh, Wilson, I'm so horny!
Take me, my stud. Come.
My God, Mia has been alone all
this time... She's going to kill me!
They'll not let us in
go back to the party...
This party is included in
the package I'm paying!
You can not do this!
Lets's talk something!
Can't be enter, is not that way.
We talk, we just went..
I don't know.
How are you, we can enter here?
Eh, my dear, did you remember me?
Soi we are free, everything is right.
Our relationship with the
captain is like family. Huh?
- He don't talk our idiom.
- Don't talk?
His is strawed.
For God, I need metting Mia.
Stop, stop, I'm feel bad.
And I'm crazy to kiss you.
No, Beto, you're crazy?
- Mia, do you traveled?
- Shut up, litte head.
Fabio...
Fabio!
Mia, I forgot!
- Fabio!
- Wy did you?
You don't know what happened.
Fabio, wait. Wait.
Listen to me.
Let me explain me.
Fabio!
Fabio
I didn't do anything,
he was the one who...
Oh, sure, Beto drank alone,
danced alone, laughed alone!
He is so "self-sufficiently"
badass, isn't he?
You disappeared from the party,
left me alone once more to party
with you little friend,
as though you were a
reckless single teenager!
I am a woman! Treat
me like a woman!
Take it easy, Mia. It's over!
You can go back to your
millionaire perfect lover boyfriend.
Go back to your "approved" Beto.
You ruined everything!
Great! Because you were the one
who ruined this honeymoon!
Go on, you can go back to admiring
you Zen little high school friend
with the perfect ass!
I didn't break up with you because
I was a silly and insecure girl!
But because you think
you own the world,
the guy who can have
everything he wants!
But you're just an arrogant prick who
only knows how to talk about himself!
You see! But that's why I love you!
You tell me the truth!
And the truth is that I
want nothing to do with you!
Because I was betrayed
by my wife during my own
honeymoon, get it?
Mia is her name.
Tis woman is a slut. SLU...
Right. Yeah. She's a slut.
She kissed another man,
during our honey fucking moon.
I'm the cuckold of the world!
Look, Wilson.
Isn't that Fabio?
- Eh, folks!
- Look at!
Stoked! Poor!
We caused this, Wilson.
We were so bitter and wanted to
destroy other people's love...
We who, Suzana?
You were the one who read that
Taiwan tarot cards to those poor guys
and ruined everyone's marriage.
And all for what?
A thousand dollars?
What do you mean a thousand?
You only paid me 100!
Weren't we splitting it 50/50?
I can't believe it.
Can you focus on the problem
here: We need to help this boy!
You owe me 400 dollars.
Pipe down... Come on... Fabio
Laura, I need to
tell you something.
Sure, love!
Mia... she... moves me...
That's normal, she's your ex!
Listen: I think I still like her.
That's normal. Liking
is a good feeling...
Enough! Can you tell the
truth for once in your life?
You're a selfish, individualistic,
sexist bastard, but I enjoy the life
you afford me and I think you enjoy
making me into your happy, stupid wife.
They say those are the
marriages that really last!
Wow!
If you'd let me speak more, you'd
remember that I can be smart as well.
And there's more: You'll
never be naive, fun,
tender and candid like Fabio!
I think he and Mia
deserve each other.
And I think we deserve
each other as well...
Can you forgive me?
Try to cheer up, Fatso,
pretty soon we’ll be in Italy,
full of women...
No joke, Head, leave me alone.
I need to talk with you.
Are you crazy, man?
Don't you have any shame?
You come here with that
bastard millionaire face
I want to hear
what he has to say.
Did you come to show your
compassion with the cuckold?
Did you come to give me
shopping tips to improve my mood?
Did you come to offer me a
VIP dinner, but it's not quite
a tasting menu you're
hungry for, is it?
Look, Fabio, I really did want Mia
back, I kept after her, declared
myself to her...
but she loves you.
Oh, all right, Beto, bla bla bla. Mia
fucked up and now she sent you here...
See? Could you react to that?
No, right?
That is what I did to Mia.
And she didn't feel a thing because
she loves your silly adolescent,
stupid, clueless, upbeat way!
Fuck, millionaires
are all bisexual!
Mia!
Hi, Laura...
My, I've never seen a
man so sad to see me.
I'm sorry, I just thought that
I came to say
good-bye to you, Titty.
You remembered me?
I did! But I had
to make an effort!
You became an
interesting, sexy man,
almost unlike that
boy at school.
Almost?
Almost because
you managed to keep the spark
in your eyes from that boy.
Few guys manager that.
You're the best catch
on this ship, Fabio.
You can have any woman you want.
Fabio, look at this.
Fabio, what are you doing?!
Me? Nothing much, just
some calculations.
Calculations?
Yeah. Come with me. This
ship is 60 meters tall, right?
I think it's 63.
Perfect. I weigh 80 kilos.
That means that with the
impact on the water... force
equals mass over distance, 80 divided
by 63... you can do some good damage.
Come on son, are you going to
kill yourself because of a woman?
Actually, it's not even worth
living because of a woman
imagine killing yourself.
There's no other way.
How can I trust Mia again?
Honey, you don't have a choice.
You have to place
emotion above reason.
Love above the facts.
Feelings above intelligence.
Love demands a certain stupidity
honey, but one thing I can tell you:
It's better to have a woman
who makes you suffer once in
a while than an ex-wife that
makes you suffer every
single day. If you need it,
you can count on us!
Is this? Not be that way.
Suzana, is bad we metting
Mia by here?
We have to find out this girl!
Wy is your fault?
Oh, shut up! It is your fault.
It is your.
Seen questa donna?
You know dove is la donna?
Hai visto questa donna?
This is my wife. Dark skin,
kind of thin, you haven't?
So, the boy let her go away
alone can you believe it?
No, wait, nobody told her to
kiss the other guy, Suzana!
Wilson, do you want to go against
me in front of the Europeans, do you?
If you're angry,
that's your problem!
She is happy...
No no.
- Mia! Mia!
- Folks, look at here!
Mia!
Mia, is brasilian,
she is losting by here.
Do you know?
- Yes!
- Where, on TV?
- This woman?
- Yes.
No. No in TV.
Prego, no.
We have to separate.
Each one go mto one place.
I'm go to find out Mia.
- Let's go!
- Let's go to here.
Whait!
Mia!
Excuse me, did you see a girl...
No, I didn't see.
- Marry me, I love you.
- No!
And...
Nothing.
The city is small but
it's not a neighborhood.
Let's stop a moment, Titty,
pretty soon will distribute more.
Fabio? Whait!
She is there!
Where are you going, you nut?
- Let's go fastly.
- Fabio!
Wait me!
Saint Anthony, how are you?
I'm Fabio, husband of Mia.
She disappeared and
I need to bring her back.
I swear I'll never leave her
alone because of any friend,
I'll never say "cost-benefit"...
Mia!? I had this hope that you
would still have some reason
to thank Saint Anthony!
Thank? I came to demand why the
man of my life had to be precisely
an idiot, clueless, ham fisted,
irresponsible and even so...
You love me!
I do!
Will you marry me, Mia? Now,
with no hurry, no idealizations,
and forever?
Mia, do you accept his young
man without a cent in his
pocket, who is afraid of being
away from his mother and
hasn't learned how to dress
as a man till this day?
I do!
Fabio, do you take this hard
ass, spoiled, complaining,
compulsive consumer, pseudo
intellectual like your wife?
I do!
Then I declare you two fools
are going to be tied
together in a boring marriage
for the rest of your lives
while I'm going go continue having
sex with woman all over Europe.
Sorry. You can kiss the bride!
Never more I will be
gone from your life.
For God, don't do that.
Because I'm taking clonazepam,
and I'm almost a zumbi.
- What about our honey moon?
- What about?
We get a married again.
We will talk about, later.
Now I will tell you.
Beto is a bad Kisser.
How?
The Cabecga, is better kisser.
Did you kissed the Cabeca?
Was not as kiss, was only a stamp.
- Who wells did you kissed on this ship?
- I kissed you, Mia..
And 3 older on first class,
and suddenly had kissed
may be a money that we can pay some
better hotel than the
hostel that will be stay.
- Hostel?
- I'm joking
we will stay on any hostel?
Can you imagine, if I will put my
love on the hostel?
- Idiot!
- We are going to stay on Maneba house.
Friend's mine living in Otaly.
You will love him.
Mia, came back, here.
I no support any more,
looking you on italy.
Somebody, please have
a clonazepam, folks?