(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
AIR TRAFFIC CONTROL OPERATOR:
Air traffic control to police 2-5-1.
Divert to new coordinates, 5-1-7-7-7-9-4.
POLICE OFFICER: Roger that, ATC.
(CAR HORNS BLARING)
I spy with my little eye
something beginning with R.
If you can't get it, you do a forfeit.
Rain?
(SIGHS)
(YAWNING)
Can I get you a pillow?
CIA OPERATOR: London Control, the package
was supposed to be
in CIA custody 19 minutes ago.
Our aircraft is waiting.
AGENT: Understood. Waiting for an update
from Traffic Control.
Good job our guest's not in a hurry.
Traffic tower says
they'll be moving within eight minutes.
The Home Office cupboards are bare.
We're going to have to be a little bit
more imaginative with our funding.
- Perhaps we can put on a telethon.
- Claws away.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
Where the bloody hell is Oliver?
Where's the air cover feed?
The helicopter's been requisitioned.
A police emergency.
You can overrule, but you'll need to issue
an executive countermand.
Do it. How soon before we get it back?
Under 10 minutes.
Something's got to be done.
At the moment it's just not viable,
and the Americans know it, too.
- Director General.
- Harry.
I know you don't like hearing this
from a politician, but reform is coming.
You do know
that lift is for emergencies only?
If I come in the front,
people want to talk to me.
I call that an emergency.
(HORNS BLARING)
Escort Two, what's your status?
LANSBURY: You got ants in your pants,
Juney?
You know, you would be a lot less uptight
if you'd just let yourself be
my London girlfriend.
The position's not gonna be open
much longer.
I spy with my little eye
something beginning with...
REED: Bikes, traveling at speed.
Put them up.
Transport team, we have
multiple motorbikes approaching.
Threat unconfirmed.
(MOTORBIKE ENGINES REVVING)
Calum, nearest police units?
They're two miles out.
The traffic units are unarmed.
Control, Lead Two.
Pillion passengers on both.
No visible weapon.
Scramble everything we've got, now.
- Code One! Code One!
- Jesus, they're everywhere.
LANSBURY: Attack in progress!
Oh, my good God.
June, for Christ's sake, don't.
Get out, now!
Ops Command to Transport.
This is Harry Pearce.
Convoy is under attack.
Lethal force is authorized.
- (JUNE STRUGGLING)
- MAN: Don't move! Don't say a word!
MAN: Open the van or everyone dies.
- I can't. I don't even...
- I'm not talking to you.
Open the van now!
- Pearce.
- Now!
There are civilians everywhere.
If they start shooting...
He's a Tier One CIA target.
We cannot let him go.
- MALTBY: Pearce.
- WARRENDER: The Americans will crucify us.
Your operation, Harry.
Transport team. Belay last order.
Surrender the prisoner.
- LANSBURY: Say again, Control?
- Harry.
PEARCE: Lay down your weapons
and release Qasim. That's an order.
What the bloody hell are you doing, Harry?
There's a significant
threat to civilian life.
I have no choice.
MAN: Open the gates! Open the gates!
Go, go, go!
LANSBURY: Control, prisoner escaped!
Heading north!
- No, no, no! June, no.
- Rob, let me go.
Keaton!
LANSBURY: Control, Lead Two
pursuing on foot.
Any more feeds? Follow her.
Nearest armed unit's eight minutes away.
Helicopter's 20 miles out.
- Road blocks?
- In place.
Other side of that tunnel
and the last junction.
There's nowhere for them to go.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
SCO19 is seven minutes away.
(MUMBLING INDISTINCTLY)
Go.
Lead Two, report.
PEARCE; Lead TWO?
Respond.
Ed, wait.
PEARCE: Lead Two, report.
Lansbury's down, sir.
I repeat, the CIA Liaison Officer
has been shot.
Lead Two, do you have eyes on Qasim?
(ENGINE RUMBLING)
Control, I hear a vehicle.
(ENGINE ROARING)
(SIGHS) He's gone, sir.
Anything on CCTV?
REED: They've knocked everything out.
We're blind.
There's no air cover, nothing.
It's over.
REPORTER 1: The BBC can confirm that
the American terrorist leader Adem Qasim
has escaped from Ml5 custody
in one of the most serious failures
in the organization's history.
It's understood that
the secure convoy transporting Qasim
came under armed attack
en route to RAF Northolt.
REPORTER 2: You say it's not war but murder
because it happens on Western streets.
Because you didn't ask for it
in New York, in Washington, in London.
But the children of Pakistan,
they didn't ask for it either.
When they're bombed by drones,
they call it murder, too.
REPORTER 3: Qasim presents
a new kind of threat.
He's articulate, charismatic, persuasive.
And in the Middle East,
he learns how to kill.
So far, he hasn't targeted civilians.
REPORTER 4: Our models show a 90%
chance of attack within 48 hours.
The more pressure he's put under,
the smaller that window becomes.
MALE INTERVIEWER: Why the hell is
he even here? Why us?
FEMALE INTERVIEWEE: That's classified.
I can't tell you while the tape's...
AGENT 1: The Secretary of State
flies in tomorrow.
If we lose CIA support, we're finished.
GCHQ, Ml5, MI6. Everything.
AGENT 2: We serve the British people,
not Washington.
If that's no longer true,
then we're already finished.
AGENT 3: The Americans feel
we're no longer fit for purpose.
We need a scalp.
It's over. I'm out.
They're letting you take the fall?
I had command, Erin.
I'm to be decommissioned in the morning.
You heard nothing about Qasim's escape?
Nothing. They recently closed ranks.
Are you blown?
I don't think so.
Harry, if you're out, what happens to me?
You get out, too.
No one else knows
you're inside Qasim's network.
Just walk away.
But what if I can find him?
It's too dangerous.
Suddenly now it's too dangerous?
Why?
Because I won't be able to protect you.
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTING)
(HORN BLARES)
(TYRES SCREECHING)
Will Holloway? Get in.
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
(HORNS BLARING)
SANTO: Go.
(TYRES SCREECHING)
So, how is life after Ml5?
You're not from the Moscow section.
SANTO: You're needed back in London.
What for? To pay my respects?
No, I don't work for you any more.
I don't owe you anything. Drop me here.
Anyone you need to say goodbye to?
SANTO: Thank you.
Okay. They're ready for us.
We know about Harry's connection
to your family,
so we understand
this may not be easy for you.
It'd be fine, even if he was dead.
It'd be an admission of failure. Harry's
too bloody arrogant to kill himself.
He was certainly acting
like someone who was about to.
He went to visit this woman's grave.
Ruth Evershed.
Ml5 analyst killed in action 2011.
How would you describe their relationship?
Love of his life.
Harry's team has noticed changes
in his behaviour since her death.
He's become emotionally distant, cold,
been drinking heavily.
- Changes?
- So, what? He swam?
The water would have been
below nine degrees.
He'd have developed hypothermia
before reaching the bank.
This is a picture before
he walked into shot,
and this is a picture
after you say that he jumped.
Top left corner. Identical bird.
Different time stamp, same image.
CCTV's been tampered with.
As you already know.
So let's stop wasting time.
This is about Harry losing Qasim, isn't it?
Before he disappeared,
Harry made three encrypted phone calls.
The first two we can't trace.
The third was to you.
Your ex-service emergency voice-mail.
I haven't checked that in months.
You must know that.
- Why call you?
- I have no idea.
Last time I spoke to him
was the night he decommissioned me
from Ml5 three years ago.
MACE: Well, he wants to chat now.
That makes you useful.
Will you help us find him?
No, thanks.
You and Harry ever talk much about Berlin?
The night your father died?
Yeah, he told me what happened.
Did he?
If there's something else, Mace,
I have a right to know.
Oh, I don't think it's up to me...
(STRUGGLING)
If you're not going to actually murder him,
I think you've made your point.
(MACE CLEARING THROAT)
Find Harry
and you can ask him about Berlin yourself.
(SIZZLING)
(SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
(SHOUTING IN ARABIC)
QASIM: Who are you?
Who...
Are you?
Sir Harry Pearce. Although I doubt
I'll take that title to the grave.
Until recently, Head of Counter-Terrorism
for Her Majesty's Security Service.
(SCOFFS)
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Funny, but who are you really?
Someone who knows
what these two words mean to you.
Asma Shishani.
(SPEAKING ARABIC) Go.
How did you find me?
Alone?
I still have a trick or two.
So what do you want?
I want to know who helped you escape.
- (CHUCKLES)
- I know it was someone on my side.
They never told me who they were.
Of course they didn't,
but you must have had a contact.
A phone number, that's all.
A phone number will do nicely.
And in return, I'll give you what you want.
(SIGHS DEEPLY)
There is no way you could get that.
It'll take a few days, but as I said,
I still have a trick or two.
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
She said she was a human rights lawyer.
Helped two of my brothers after they
were imprisoned by your government.
But after I was freed,
she became too curious.
She's how you found me. She's your agent.
I don't know this woman.
If she's a spy, she's not one of ours.
Now, do we have a deal or not?
If this woman is no one,
she's still a witness.
She has to die.
Just so I'm clear again,
tell me she's nothing to you.
(GUN COCKING)
All right. She's my agent.
You keep her alive, she's your guarantee
that I'll keep my word.
(WATTS WHIMPERING)
QASIM: I don't need guarantees.
PEARCE: Get her to a hospital now,
or the deal's off!
She doesn't need a hospital. It's too late.
What she needs is mercy.
(WATTS BREATHING HEAVILY)
Her death will take so
much longer, otherwise.
So much pain.
No!
She has a daughter.
And still, you sent her after me?
You put her in danger
and then you refuse to spare her the pain?
What sort of a man are you?
(WHIMPERING)
Spare her family from the video.
Harry...
I don't want her to see me die.
I'm sorry, Erin. I can't.
(PANTING)
QASIM: You've got a deal.
REPORTER 1: The BBC understands
there has been no breakthrough
in the hunt for escaped
terrorist Adem Qasim.
The national threat level
has been raised to critical,
indicating an attack is imminent.
Ml5, already under intense scrutiny,
today suffered further embarrassment
as a leaked memo from the American embassy
claimed that the US
is demanding greater control
over joint intelligence
initiatives with the UK
due to an increasing lack of faith
in British security capabilities.
REPORTER 2: In business news,
the F TSE 100 fell again this morning
and sterling continued to slide
against the dollar,
the euro and other major
trading currencies.
(MOBILE VIBRATING)
MALTBY: Anything on those files
we sent you?
Not yet.
We have fresh intel on Harry.
He bought a pay-as-you-go phone
that we tracked to the Kent Coast.
Holloway, this is classified.
Qasim had been there, too.
Smuggling in weapons from North Africa.
Harry found him.
- He didn't call it in?
- No.
We found traces of explosive there, too.
Qasim's planning an attack.
London, we think.
(SIGHS) You've known him
longer than any of us.
Do you think it's at all possible
Qasim might have got to Harry somehow?
Turned him?
I don't know.
Regardless, find Harry, we find Qasim.
(RUSTLING)
Anything for Holloway?
There you are.
PEARCE'. Glad you remembered
the umbrella drop.
We have to meet.
Tomorrow, 12 pm. Heathrow, Terminal Five.
Park in short stay one, row A, bay one.
Then, keep your eyes open.
I hope you'll come alone.
SANTO: Wait.
Look in the glove compartment.
For protection only.
If you can't bring in one loopy
Cold War relic without shooting him,
we really are in trouble.
No promises.
- Got an envelope.
- Open it.
It says not to yet.
HOLLOWAY'. We play this Harry's way
until we've got eyes on him.
SANTO: Alpha Team, be advised,
Alpha One is wearing a white hooded top.
It's a spotlight. Our target's watching.
"MAN: Roger that.
LIFT RECORDING: Doors opening.
Level three.
Go.
LIFT RECORDING: Level zero.
Doors opening.
Open sightlines, multiple exits.
"SANTO: Say again, Holloway.
They're Harry's requirements
for running a meet.
Morning. Are there any messages
for Will Holloway?
Uh, let me see.
Yes, Mr Holloway, your uncle said
he'd meet you at the coffee shop.
He left his mobile at home.
Thanks. That's so Uncle Harry.
Guy in the car park, get rid of him.
He might as well be wearing an Ml5 T-shirt.
Listen to me. Stop underestimating Harry.
You do that, we lose him. Don't think
he won't put your people in danger.
All right. What now?
- We wait for him to make his...
- (BEEPING)
"SANTO: What is it, Alpha One?
Holloway? What is it?
Holloway? Holloway, where are you going?
He's Terminal 5B. The shuttle's leaving.
Wait. No, we're not set up there.
Stand down. Holloway, stand down!
Alpha Team, get after him.
SANTO: Go, go! Wrong building. Move! Now!
Terminal 5B.
(ENGINE STARTING)
SHUTTLE RECORDING: Doors closing.
He's booked me on a flight.
PA309 to Glasgow. Gate B34.
Will, do not get on that plane.
We have to clear this.
You do.
I'm going to Glasgow.
SANTO: Call the Glasgow office.
Get me the airport police ops command.
Priority code Sigma Nine. Police request
a clearer path to the terminal.
And get us cleared by Heathrow security.
WOMAN ON TANNOY: All remaining
passengers for flight PA309 to Glasgow...
I have to go dark or I won't get through.
He's dry-cleaning me.
SANTO: Holloway, do not go airside.
Do not go dark. Do you hear me...
WOMAN ON PA: PA309 to Glasgow.
The departure gate is now closing.
(PANTING)
HOLLOWAY: What am I doing here, Harry?
PEARCE: I need to find someone
outside the service that I can trust.
It's a short list when you take off
the drunk, the mad and the dead.
It's quite telling, the fact that
the closest thing I have to a friend
is someone who thinks I ruined his life.
You're finished. You're coming in.
Qasim's escape was sanctioned by someone
at the very top of the service.
By one of the people who asked you
to track me down.
That's why I had to disappear.
You had Qasim.
- You let him go.
- I had no choice.
He's our only connection to the traitor.
Once he's in the system, he'll be silenced.
He's planning an attack.
If they can't stop him, it'll be on you.
This is bigger than Qasim, Will.
Someone wants to destroy
the service itself.
You've lost it. (CHUCKLES)
- Ruth's death...
- Don't!
I don't expect you to trust me.
Look at it yourself, that's all I'm asking.
What do you expect, Harry?
Loyalty? Gratitude because you helped
my mum with the rent
and dropped by twice a year
to give me a fucking lecture?
Ml5 was all I had
and you took it from me, for nothing.
Hate me all you like,
but I think you believe in the service.
What it stands for. Just
like your father did.
What happened in Berlin?
So that's how they got to you?
(POLICE RADIO CHATTER)
PEARCE: This may not pan out
as you'd hoped.
I'm afraid I had to tip them off that there's
something in the lining of your jacket.
Nothing there of course,
but they'll have to check.
I'm going to send you a number.
Call me in 24 hours, please.
Sir, please stay there. I'm afraid
we're going to have to search you.
Listen to me. I am Security Services.
That man there is the target of an Ml5
operation. Just let me make a call.
Hands up! Lie down! Now! Now, now!
Hands behind your back!
Move! Out my way, out my way!
(DOOR OPENING AND CLOSING)
So you just let him walk away.
MACE: Calm down, Francis.
We wouldn't want you to have a stroke.
Not a fatal one, anyway.
Ml5 is looking like
a complete liability right now
and I'm just about the last friend
left in government it has.
So you should really be nice to me.
Ignore them. What did Harry say to you?
He, er... He wanted to bring Qasim
in by himself, make amends.
In other words, he's lost the plot?
That wouldn't contradict
his last three psych evaluations.
He refused to attend them.
WARRENDER: Well, he hasn't stopped
being Harry Pearce.
Even completely gaga,
I'd still take him over...
Well, this chap, for example.
- MALTBY: Why contact you?
- He thinks we still have a bond.
Asked me to help him disappear.
It didn't occur to you to agree
and then turn him over to us?
He's known me my whole life.
He'd see through that.
Just because your life hasn't been
worth a damn since Harry booted you,
don't think we can't very easily
make it even less satisfactory.
Since we're all threatening each other,
you three should be under no illusions
that you're not teetering on the edge.
Your whole organization is looking
pretty bloody disposable right now.
Find Qasim. Find Harry. Today.
WORKER 1: Fully loaded.
WORKER 2: Bring the container to the side.
They are ready, brother.
Mmm-hmm.
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
(GRUNTS)
I got burgled twice last year.
They got in the same way.
Qasim's escape. What really happened?
Who are you?
I've seen that name in a case study.
I thought they decommissioned you.
They did. Now, what really happened?
(GRUNTS)
The escape may have been
set up by someone in the service.
Do you know anything about that?
- What are you looking for?
- Cigarette.
I only gave up six weeks ago.
There must be one here.
- Why did you join Ml5?
- What?
Just tell me, why did you apply?
I didn't apply-
When I was 17, I went out with a guy
who did money transfers.
Had one of those dodgy shops.
You know, families sending cash back home.
K section were interested in some of
the people using it, so they approached me.
- So you started as an agent?
- Yeah. And I was good.
And when I was done,
they asked me to train as an officer.
My family laughed when I told them that.
So when I got through vetting,
I wasn't gonna let it go.
And I haven't.
I made my choice.
So the job means a lot.
And if someone you worked for
had helped Qasim to escape,
that would matter, right?
Okay.
Something did feel wrong that day.
Rob Vass, my team leader,
he was in the lead car with me.
He told me not to open
the weapons compartment.
He ordered me not to pursue.
Where does he live?
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
(CAT MEOWS)
I think we got our man.
You take the bedroom.
Loaded.
Chinese made. Unauthorized.
Doesn't make him guilty, though.
This might. He's a neat freak.
Keeps all his statements nicely filed,
apart from this one, which he'd binned.
Check out March 17th.
WILL: W78 account prefix.
Panama City.
Service slush fund.
(DOOR OPENING)
June, what the hell are...
Who are you?
- You told me not to pursue Qasim.
- What?
That's what you said to me
when I went for my weapon.
This is a wind-up, right?
An agent gave it to me. It's a souvenir.
June, whatever you're up to, it's over.
We swore an oath, Rob.
You sat in your car while Lansbury
was killed. For 65 grand?
I'm not saying anything
until we get to Thames House.
We're not going to Thames House.
(MOBILE PHONE RINGING)
Will, what have you found?
Qasim's escort was deliberately weakened.
The team leader was in on it.
He's just the errand boy.
Find out who gave the order.
No. If you want my help,
first tell me what you know.
The Americans think Ml5 is a weak link
and I think somebody here agrees with them.
Qasim escapes, we're disgraced.
The CIA quietly take over.
- (CRASHING)
- (JUNE SHOUTS)
(GRUNTING)
(GUNSHOT FIRES)
(GUN SHOT FIRES)
He was...
He was going to fire.
Who paid you? Who set up the escape?
(GASPING)
We could...
We could check his pulse. He might...
He's dead, he's dead. He's dead.
Listen. You have to go home.
You were never here.
Don't let anyone see you.
Don't take public transport.
Do you understand?
June! I'll deal with this,
but you have to go, now.
(CELLO SOLO PLAYING)
(AUDIENCE APPLAUDS)
I've never heard a piece
murdered with such glee.
Who's Warrender batting his eyelashes at?
Landon Miller. Agency hawk.
He's trying to secure
their continued support,
hopefully without handing over
the keys to the kingdom.
(CHATTERING)
Every time I see you, Francis, you seem
to be buried another inch or two deeper
in the recesses of some swivel-eyed
wonk from Langley or the Pentagon.
It's all for you, Oliver.
You lost their number one most wanted.
For goodness' sake.
If the Americans withdraw their support,
our entire intelligence apparatus
will completely collapse.
You don't have to tell me.
I just think, in times like these,
we all need to remember
which flag flies over our heads.
MALTBY: Francis.
Relax. It's Oliver. He sees someone
under pressure, he can't resist a push.
I'm trying to help and he practically
accuses me of moonlighting for the CIA.
Huh. Careful, Geraldine.
You almost got off the fence there.
CONCIERGE: Francis.
Do I know you?
(SCREAMING)
Tonight, your generals,
your politicians, your spies,
met for a celebration.
Tonight, we struck back
at the heart of their power.
But to the British people,
I say you are not our enemy.
Our enemies are the politicians
who send your sons and
your daughters to die in illegal wars.
The spies who spy on you,
like you are the criminals.
This fight goes beyond
religious differences.
Stand with us. Cast off your rulers.
The video was posted
just moments after the explosion
ripped through the lobby of
the Albery Theatre in central London,
killing six people, including the Chair
of the Joint Intelligence Committee,
Francis Warrender,
and the suspected suicide bomber.
All flights out of the UK...
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
(GRUNTS)
You had him. One call.
One call and those people would be alive.
Warrender would be alive.
HARRY: This is the traitor's fault.
They set Qasim free.
Spy game's over. If you have a way
to get to Qasim, give it up, right now.
There's another way.
Qasim's wife.
Asma Shishani.
The FSB have her.
If I can work out where they're
holding her, he'll give up the traitor.
- You made a deal with him.
- Yes.
And if we see it through,
it'll lead us to him.
Come in now and we'll set it up.
If I come in now, the traitor will have
me killed. It has to be just you and me.
How do you know
the Russians have his wife?
We gave her to them. In exchange
for a blown CIA officer stuck in Moscow.
Oh, that's why he hates us.
That's why he's come here.
Her location is in a file on a
low-security GCHQ archive server.
I can remotely access it,
but I need you to open the back door.
This is an IP address.
You are joking.
It's the only way, Will.
If you're working another angle...
If you're lying to me...
Harry's getting help from somewhere.
I've ruled out old contacts,
but I need access to
personnel files to do it properly.
I'll bump you up to Restricted Strap One.
Still won't get you anywhere exciting.
And every file you open will be logged.
So don't go nosing.
WILL: (OVER PHONE) In place.
And away we go. Better stay on the
line, Will, until we're done,
in case of any hiccups.
Seems like I'm going to have
to steal a lot of extra bandwidth.
- How much?
- The borough's.
Malcolm?
WYNN-JONES: Okay, I'm in.
Trawling the servers now.
Harry, we need to get moving.
Can we do this any quicker?
I could, yes. Unfortunately,
this machine is pre-millennial.
(DOOR OPENS)
G Branch already pulled these.
Erin Watts. Served under Pearce.
Current whereabouts unknown.
Might be worth a closer look.
So, come on, then.
What is it between you and Harry?
SANTO: Fill in the blacked-out bits for me.
I was running a pretty heavy op
that went south. We had to burn it.
But I had an agent left exposed.
Harry's order was to cut him loose.
I chose to ignore that order.
I almost got him out.
I only just got out myself, and Harry...
Decommissioned me on the spot.
I'd been in that job less than a year.
I was here just long enough to realise
you can do good or you can do well.
Sooner or later they make you choose.
Well, I'll let you get on.
Are we nearly there?
Once I press enter, there's no going back.
Are you sure about this?
WILL: Sure about what?
I'm sorry, Will.
The archive's downloading.
We'll have it in 11 seconds.
Harry.
(ALL COMPUTERS BEEPING)
Harry!
- He's disconnected us.
- Did we get it?
WILL: Harry, what did you do?
Stand away from the computer.
I've never had to say this to you before,
but I hope you know what you're doing.
Is Harry working with Qasim?
He stole an entire GCHQ data archive.
Everything we have
on friendly Western agents in Russia.
Why is Harry going to Berlin?
He popped up on Schonefeld Airport's CCTV.
I don't know.
Mace wants to enhance this interrogation.
Put you on a plane to Morocco.
I can't stop it.
Not unless you give us something.
Harry didn't run that cyber attack himself.
So who's helping him?
Besides you.
MALTBY:
Harry kicked you out of the service.
Now he's used you to steal state secrets.
And still you're protecting him.
- Why?
- I'm not.
Let me go to Berlin and I can find him.
(DOOR OPENING)
Keaton, sir. The file you wanted.
And chatter's spiking.
Analysis indicates a large-scale
attack in the next 48 hours,
suggesting multiple targets.
MACE: An officer present
at Qasim's escape is missing.
Signs of a struggle in his home.
Know anything about that?
(CHUCKLES)
How's your mother, Holloway?
Doesn't keep too well, I hear.
Never has, since your father died.
Understandable, really.
All those years of trying for a baby.
The joy at it finally happening.
And then comes that knock at the door.
I know, I know.
Harry was right about one thing.
You're not good enough.
NEWS REPORTER:... primarily
attacked military and political targets.
Home Secretary, can we really hope
to stop Qasim striking again?
HOME SECRETARY: I say to Adem Qasim, we
will not be cowed-We will not be bullied.
We have faced down threats to our
freedom and way of life time and again.
Your ability to wound us
may be significant, but it is finite.
You will find our resolve
to be without limit.
They're not listening.
Have they never killed our women?
Our children?
If we kill a hundred of theirs,
we won't have repaid
one thousandth of the debt.
We're making a better world, brother.
WOMAN: (OVER RAND)
Transfer team in position at City Airport.
We have ATC authorization
to hold the runway
for prisoner transport when necessary.
DRIVER: Roger that.
We'll be there in 20 minutes.
- (TYRES SQUEALING)
- (HORN BLARING)
(ALARM WAILING)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
- JUNE: Keaton.
- I think I owe you one.
You kept quiet about Vass.
Least I could do.
Danke.
(MOBILE PHONE DIALING)
- Colonel.
- WOMAN: Hello, Harry.
Alexanderplatz. Northeast corner
by the subway, 11:00 am.
Why there? We have a safe house.
Call it nostalgia.
- WOMAN: Did you receive your gift?
- HARRY: Yes. Very thoughtful.
"WOMAN: Don't forget to bring the archive.
HARRY: Don't forget to bring his wife.
How did you find me?
There's only one place
to run a meet in Berlin.
You used to tell me.
Northeast corner of Alexanderplatz.
Open sightlines. Multiple exits.
Undone by sentimentality.
That's the price of Qasim's wife.
Once she's out of FSB custody,
he gives me a phone number.
That gets me to the traitor.
WILL: Qasim's gonna attack in the next
48 hours. You're gonna help me find him.
HARRY: I don't have a way to Qasim.
I never did have.
- Then this is over.
- They'll tear it down, Will.
They'll destabilize the service to the point
where it's justifiable to take it over.
- Get in the car, Harry.
- There's an old hotel 10 minutes away.
My contact can meet us there with
clean passports for all three of us.
You're going home.
JUNE: Sorry about this.
He's a bit paranoid. Through here.
- Why are you here, Miss Keaton?
- Keep moving, Harry.
I killed someone because of you.
Rob Vass. He was a mate.
I want to know why.
PEARCE: You're C2, aren't you?
A C2-ranked junior field officer
who can source clean passports
in a foreign city. That's impressive.
- What are you doing, Harry?
- Talent spotting.
Remind me, what was
the smoking gun on Vass?
- HOLLOWAY: A bank statement.
- And which one of you found it?
I did. Will, he's trying to mess with us.
My contact's waiting.
For God's sake, Will.
PEARCE: Preparation is everything.
- It was an order. It was necessary.
- And what about Vass?
What about Vass?
When you came to my house, I called it in.
Said someone was asking
about Qasim's escape.
I was put through to Command
and they told me what to do.
They got to Vass's apartment
ahead of us and planted the evidence.
I tricked Vass into running.
He's going to kill you. Go, now. Run!
(SHOUTS)
- What did they promise you?
- They didn't promise me anything.
It was an order.
You think I wanted to do it?
I feel sick about Rob, okay?
But we have to follow orders.
- We don't have to like them.
- Old-fashioned blind obedience.
I know my duty.
I'm the only one here who does.
You were played.
- Who gave the order?
- Come on. You don't have it in you.
She's right, Will.
But I wonder if Miss Keaton
is so sure about me.
(GUN COCKING)
it was an order. They
said you were traitors.
That's all I know, I swear.
It was a secure command line.
What was I supposed to do?
Do you believe her?
Yeah.
PEARCE: I'm sure your people
will come and find you,
if you haven't outlived your usefulness.
After all this was over, what did
you think they were gonna do with you?
All I've done is what they asked of me.
We're changing the deal.
We take Qasim's wife back to London.
Tell him he comes to the handover
in person or he never sees her again.
Let's go get her.
- What happened to Alexanderplatz?
- Sudden attack of agoraphobia.
I'm afraid there was a
problem with Qasim's wife.
- I needed her alive.
- She was pregnant.
She miscarried, blamed us.
There was an accident.
At least be good enough
to put her in my car.
HOLLOWAY: Harry.
Colonel.
I hate to be ungentlemanly,
but we're going to need your clothes.
RADIO ANNOUNCER: As the manhunt
for Adem Qasim intensifies,
all passengers traveling
on the UK's national rail network
will have to show valid ID
and face on-board bag checks.
(MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
The Home Secretary
has authorized police checkpoints...
PEARCE: I have your wife.
- So let me speak to her, then.
- The Russians have sedated her and...
- Bullshit.
- Do not interrupt. The deal's changed.
I'm bringing her to London.
You name the time and the place,
and if you attack before the exchange,
I'll cut your baby out of her
and drown it in a toilet.
No.
I'll tell your whore you said goodbye.
(PHONE BEEPS)
(SHOUTS)
- PEARCE: Was the baby thing too much?
- No, it was very you.
I trusted June.
You were right to decommission me.
Despite everything I've done,
you're still here trying to do some good.
- You're your father's son, all right.
- Careful, Harry.
Why do all this? Why not just walk away?
Why? Erin Watts.
Ruth Evershed. Your father.
They gave their lives for the service.
I won't let it be destroyed.
I won't let their sacrifice be in vain.
It was down there.
- What was?
- Where your father died.
Don't fucking play me. I'm warning you.
I'm not working you. Not this time.
Was it quick?
Two to the heart.
He could have given me up,
but he chose not to.
(MOBILE RINGS)
Yes?
Tomorrow at 12:00,
you're gonna be standing in the middle of
Waterloo Bridge facing south with my wife.
You try anything, anything at all,
I can't guarantee anyone's safety.
Anyone's.
You bring my wife,
I give you your phone number.
We're on.
Hello?
Holloway.
- That message came from H Branch.
- Sorry.
- You'd have brought backup, otherwise.
- Who says I didn't?
I do.
HOLLOWAY: We can get to Qasim,
but we need help.
Call it in and we disappear.
One clean choice, Hannah.
Trust me and help me.
Or walk away.
Do good or do well, eh?
Shit.
- I thought you'd gone to kill him.
- One thing at a time, Miss Santo.
They're nearing position.
- Anything?
- WYNN-JONES: Not a sausage.
The self-perpetuating algorithm I wrote
last night is constantly updating,
revising all potential vantage points.
- Sudoku not cutting it, then?
- Please.
PEARCE: Okay, we're here.
- PEARCE: How long do we have?
- Thirty seconds. We need a lead.
WYNN-JONES: I'm covering
over 300 cameras.
Give me something. As soon as he
realizes we're playing him, he's gone.
Wait.
National Theatre. Dead feed.
- It was working 30 seconds ago.
- Are you sure?
Yes, confirmed.
Camera's gone down in the last minute.
Third level roof, east corner.
Harry, we need to stall.
(MOBILE RINGS)
- Don't pick up. He'll ring again.
- I have to take it.
We have to assume
he's looking directly at us.
Yes?
"MAN: You were told to be facing south.
- I have his wife.
- You were meant to face south.
"PEARCE: Give me the number.
MAN: Turn around.
Give me the number now or we walk.
Turn around now
or I put you down.
HARRY: There. MAN: Her, too.
I haven't gotten him yet.
You've got five seconds
to turn around. Turn.
- HOLLOWAY: I need time. Do something.
- Wait.
- What?
- Well, maybe this guy's never seen her.
I'm almost there.
(MOBILE RINGS)
Is it her?
MAN: No, brother.
I'm sorry.
QASIM: Kill her.
Give me the number.
WILL: Don't!
Stop!
Where's Qasim? What's the target?
No!
It's okay. You're only winded.
Okay?
Will, she's all right.
- Sniper's dead.
- Then it's over.
"PEARCE: Malcolm, make yourself scarce.
(MOBILE RINGS)
Yes?
QASIM: My wife's dead, isn't she?
"HOLLOWAY: Harry, listen.
Let Hannah call us in.
Harry?
Hannah, why is Harry off comms?
- He's on the phone.
- Who's he talking to?
No idea.
Call us in.
Get SCO19 here now.
Four vans loaded with RDX leaving
from Limehouse North Industrial Park
within the next 15 minutes.
- How do you know that?
- Qasim just told me.
SANTO: Vans loaded with bombs leaving
in 15 minutes. You need to move now.
Mr Emerson. Sir.
I think we got him.
Let's get going!
- Armed police! Stay where you are!
- (SHOUTING)
- Don't do it. Don't!
- Clear!
- Eyes on principal.
- Negative!
Negative!
- Negative, sir.
- Command, we are clear.
Principal is not on site.
I repeat, Qasim is not here.
Harry.
What did you say to him?
He told you his plan.
He gave up his own men.
Why would he do that?
What have you done?
Armed police! Don't move!
Put it down. Slowly.
Go!
(BEEPING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(CHATTERING)
You need to tell them everything, Harry.
Harry. I'd say we're due a catch-up.
Indeed we are. Might be a little
over this one's head, though.
Oh. Finally outlived his
usefulness, has he?
Ever since the southwest corner
of Alexanderplatz.
Keep Holloway close by.
Make sure he's secure.
Perhaps we won't be so hasty.
Have you found Qasim?
Harry will talk.
You still don't know him.
Qasim gave up his entire operation.
What did you say to him?
I'd have thought
they'd cut you loose after Berlin.
They want to offer you a deal.
Pin everything on Harry and walk away.
They've prepared a statement.
All you have to do is sign.
I told them I'd do this, then I'm out.
There is no "out".
The door behind you
leads to an access tunnel. Open it.
I can't.
You have an emergency backup key
on a chain around your neck.
PRICE: What did you give him?
MALTBY: Harry.
Whatever you're up to...
What would Ruth think of it?
What did you give him?
(SPEAKING ARABIC)
Check the back.
- Southwest corner.
- What?
I found Harry on the northeast corner
of Alexanderplatz.
Open sightlines. Ideal place for a meet.
Just now he said southwest corner.
The opposite.
Where you trap someone.
- What did you give him?
- Oliver, control yourself.
- (BEEPING)
- That... That's a perimeter breach.
Harry?
I gave him you.
Stay down!
Stay down! Stay down!
Lock us down.
(SHOUTING)
Stay down!
- Shut up! Stay down!
- You're a psychopath.
Stay down! We're not here for you!
We're here for them.
You stay down!
Think about your families.
- Is the glass rated for assault rifles?
- It'll hold.
Hamza.
Why?
REED: There's 50 armed men
the other side of those doors.
You should give yourselves up.
Get here. Open it!
If you think we're going to negotiate...
- Open the door.
- But he'll kill us.
(DOOR BEEPING)
- There's so much evil in one room.
- (DOOR BEEPING)
(sum COCKS)
Your only chance of getting out
of here alive is to surrender...
Do you think I want to get out?
How many people's lives
began to end in this room?
- My people's lives.
- MALTBY: Your people?
Nobody asked you to speak for them,
to kill for them.
If you want a hostage...
I think he's made it clear
he's not interested in hostages.
I'm the Director General of Ml5.
Kill me and then put down your gun.
Show mercy.
It will resonate around the world.
Otherwise you're just
one more dead terrorist.
- To your half of the world.
- Oh, you don't understand.
No one's going to see you as a hero.
By the time we've finished,
you'll be a drunken, wife-beating,
impotent kafir.
We'll wheel out
a couple of Marrakech rent boys,
give them free tickets to Disneyland
in return for saying
you begged them to piss on you.
Can't have you being remembered well,
can we, Adem?
Wait, wait, stop. This is my fault.
I set up his escape.
Called off the helicopter. But I...
I didn't know... I shouldn't
be the one who...
You bloody coward.
I thought you fought to a higher standard.
I'm sorry, Adem, about
the loss of your wife.
I know what that can do to you.
Is that supposed to stop me?
(MUFFLED SHOUTING)
It's okay.
Stop!
Why did you bring him here?
I made a choice. To stop the attack
on London. To expose the traitor.
- With no backup plan.
- I had a backup plan. You.
Why do you think
I kept you out of that room?
People are still dead, Harry.
Far fewer than would have died
in the bombings.
How do you make a choice like that?
It's my job.
(KNOCKING) Auntie G,
can you come outside to play?
I'm still feeling a bit poorly.
Maybe I'll come out later.
- Okay.
- Come on, sweetheart!
PEARCE: Hello, Geraldine.
In the end, it comes down
to who can tell the best lie longest.
Don't you think?
If we'd had cover that morning,
Qasim would never have got away.
You sent a secret directive
to the Met's Air Unit
ordering them to decline
all Ml5 requests, didn't you?
Emerson was trying to protect you.
When he confessed, you looked...
Relieved.
You're a lone maniac.
Even if you had something,
you could never make it stick.
That's the advantage of
being a lone maniac.
I don't need to make it stick.
Sacrificing your own service so
it could be absorbed by a foreign power.
The Americans would have made you
Director General, no doubt.
How many more lives
was that promotion worth?
What was it you think
you accomplished, Harry?
The service is dying.
All you did was buy it a little more time.
Oh, I know.
But if I'd given up the fight the moment
I realised I was on the losing side,
my career would have been a short one.
So what's your plan? Blow my brains out
for my 10-year-old niece to find?
No. I simply want to offer you...
A way out.
This came from you, I take it.
What is it?
It's new. Perforates the small bowel
over six hours or so,
causing irreversible haemorrhaging.
Leaves no trace.
How clever.
You're madder than you look.
Shoot me or get out. I'm not taking that.
I was afraid that would be your answer.
That's why I've taken the decision
out of your hands.
It's not your pub lunch
that's making you queasy.
I had the rib of beef, too.
Tell me you're lying, Harry.
Please.
Tell me you didn't betray your country.
It's been four hours already, Geraldine.
You can spend the last
two in a hospital bed,
but if I were you, I'd go and play
with that beautiful niece of yours.
PEARCE: I hear Mace offered you a job.
Are you taking it?
HOLLOWAY: Thinking about it.
Your message said
you had something to tell me.
They've put surveillance on Ruth's grave.
You can't go there any more.
I have something which, by rights,
should be yours.
Your father was wearing
it the night he died.
The Stasi stripped his body
of everything that could be useful
and it found its way
into an FSB archive somewhere.
He was wearing a wedding ring
on the night of his op?
Ordinarily, he wouldn't have.
But he'd just found out
he was to have a son.
I didn't decommission you
because you weren't good enough.
After your father, I couldn't...
I had to protect you.
The good ones tend not to last, Will.
Then who does?
The ones like me.