You alive in there?
Yeah.
You're 15 minutes late, Lefty.
Dale's looking for you,
and he's more pissed than usual.
- You hear what I said?
- Yeah. I'm coming.
- Hey.
- What?
Thanks for making me late.
Gee, I'm sorry.
My boss, who pays me,
wanted me to do something.
Next time I'll tell him I work for Lefty.
Hey, princess.
When you're done putting your makeup on,
get your royal behind in my office.
Say, Dale, I'm gonna need
an extended lunch today,
seeing as I got a meeting
with my wife's lawyers.
You must be joking.
No, Dale, I'm not.
Now, I know that you're...
Come on, Lefty.
What's wrong with you?
Am I nuts, or did we have
a conversation yesterday?
What wasn't clear about what I said, Lefty?
Didn't I warn you
that was the last time?
We talked about it.
What else can I do for you?
I got you the promotion.
Nobody else thought it was a good idea,
but I pushed it,
and you thank me
by being late every day since.
Every day. How is that possible?
You think this is funny?
I can't believe I wasted my time on you.
Look, Dale...
I appreciate the promotion.
I do.
But you gotta understand.
Now that I'm making more money,
I'll admit I've been partying a little bit more.
But that will not...
affect my work.
Please tell me you're not that stupid.
I gave you a promotion.
You didn't get a raise.
Assistant Production Line
Supervisor?
It doesn't mean a thing.
It's just a name.
I did it for your custody case
because I knew it'd look good
for the judge and your kids.
But you... you take that...
that... that charity,
and you blow it up in my face.
I'm not blind. I know you're drinking again.
You're hopeless, Lefty.
Sucks to hear it, I know,
but somebody needs to tell you.
I'm sorry, man.
I gotta do it.
Now, Dale, before you go
and do something stupid,
you really ought to think about it.
I mean, this place would
shut down without me.
Who else is gonna go out there
and change all those belts on the line?
Anyone with opposable thumbs.
Playtime's over.
Clear out your locker and go home.
You're fired.
An escort will walk you to your car.
Now, Dale...
Go home, Lefty.
Hi, Jacob.
How you doing, buddy?
Hi, Mary.
- You doing okay?
- Fine, thanks.
- You?
- Seriously.
You doing all right?
As good as can be expected.
Seriously.
I love you, Jacob. You be good.
Love you.
His juice box is in his backpack.
He'll try to tell you
I forgot to give him one...
Got it.
Hey, you know
these seats are adjustable.
Oh, yeah.
This is the way Rick liked it, though,
so... I just, um...
you know.
Yeah.
Okay.
- See you at 3.
- I'll see you at 3. Bye.
Pump one.
This plus 20 bucks on 2.
21.05.
Problem?
No, it's really good, actually.
Where's Security?
The least they could do
is have Security take me out.
Security's got sensitivity training today.
Yeah, well, this isn't very sensitive.
Yes.
Go home, Lefty.
It's kinda hard when you're standing
in the middle of my living room.
Yes. Good luck, buddy.
Hey!
Got a fiver?
Just till payday?
I'll show you playtime, Dale.
...to consider the feelings of the violator,
at least on par with
those of the violated.
We mustn't forget,
before they were perpetrators,
they were victims themselves.
So they are hurting individuals,
deserving of our empathy, concern,
and, yes, our love and compassion.
Perhaps you can ask, them, brother...
or sister...
if... if they're comfortable with that,
"Why is it that you felt compelled
to take what did not belong to you?"
It's prepay only.
I don't care what day it is.
I guess that would explain the sign
right in front of my eyes
that says "Prepay only," huh?
It kind of sucks working today, huh?
Christmas Eve and all?
Working Christmas Eve. No fun.
Oh. Yeah. I guess.
Boss gave you the raw deal.
You're looking at him.
Then why the heck
are you working today?
Kid didn't show up today.
Called in sick this morning.
What else am I going to do?
Kids aren't the most
dependable creatures.
20 bucks on 2.
So you even have
to be open today?
Chug-a-Lug and Neighbor Mart
are closed.
It would be stupid to pass up
the Christmas Eve rush.
Oh. Yeah.
27.01.
Thank you.
Merry Christmas.
Yep.
Hello?
Uh, is, uh... I was...
Is this the walk-in clinic?
Oh, good.
I was afraid I had the wrong number
for a minute.
Um, um, l... I saw Dr. Lyndel yesterday,
and I'm... I'm a little confused
about some of the medications he gave me.
I think I need a little help w...
Uh, yeah, I can wait, okay.
Uh, hi. This is Eva Boyle.
Yeah, I saw Dr. Lyndel last week,
and I was wanting to...
I wasn't expecting you, Dr. Lyndel.
What...
No. Uh...
I know it was yesterday.
I told that woman that.
Anyway, I know you told me
to take some medications
in the morning
and some in the afternoon...
I did?
I did. I wrote it down right here.
Oh. Now I do feel silly.
Well, uh, which...
Uh-huh.
Yeah, the... Oh.
The red with the red
and the yellow with the yellow.
Thank you so much.
L... I know I wasted your time,
but I just remember
your telling me
that I need to be careful
which ones I took
with which and when.
Thank you.
Merry Christmas to you, too, Doctor.
Ah, Mitch. Putting the music together.
Hey, Pastor Mark.
Yeah, I'm almost done.
I put these packets together
for you to give out.
There's a card, a Christmas CD,
and 20 bucks in each one.
Isn't this kind of insulting?
No. I don't think so.
I want to give them
something they need
rather than some kind of tree ornament
or a candy cane or something.
I'm just not sure
how they're going to take it.
L... I gather you're not,
uh, excited about tonight?
Not tremendously, no.
I mean, we're talking about
high school students here.
The last thing they want to do
is go caroling for old people.
I mean, it's not 1948 anymore.
Fair enough, Mitch,
but maybe I'm not too concerned
about what they and you want to do.
Not every act of service is a joyride.
Is this about, uh, what day it is?
I know the accident
was a year ago tonight.
Maybe, I guess.
You know, this can be good for you.
Most of the people
you're visiting tonight are shut-ins.
You're the only person
they're going to see over the holidays.
Others, they haven't
been here for a while.
They're not sure if the church
still cares about them.
Yeah. We've been through this.
Well, let me put it in another way.
Not everything with the kids
has to be cool or hip.
It's good for them to just do
some ministry once in a while.
I don't... I don't know.
Man, I'm just feeling...
I feel like I'm up against a wall
with some of these kids.
I mean, they're all great. It's just...
They haven't decided
if I'm worth listening to,
and I'm afraid this sort of thing
is gonna push them over the line,
and... and once they're on the other side,
just bury me and hire
a new seminary grad.
At least you're overly dramatic.
I'm sure they can identify with that.
Okay.
You want them to decide
you're worth listening to?
Be worth listening to.
Show them a faith
that makes you want
to do stuff like this.
See you at the services later.
All right. Later.
Oh, and, Mitch...
technically, old people are still people.
I'm not sure that's true,
but I'll look it up on the Internet later.
Yeah, do that.
Lucio Boyle?
Don't get up.
I'm Gordon Macintosh.
I'll be working with Samantha
representing your ex-wife
from here on out.
I know you two have met,
and this is Greg, our file clerk.
Lefty.
Excuse me?
His nickname. Cute as it is,
we won't be using it today.
I'm sure you'll understand.
I'll call you back.
Everyone calls me Lefty.
Of course they do.
If my parents
had named me Lu...
I'm a lefty, too. Born that way.
Oh, in my case, it's a little weird
'cause I'm not even left-handed.
Uh, where is your representation?
My lawyer and I,
we don't see eye to eye
on a few things, so...
You don't have a lawyer.
Right.
Anyways, when I was growing up as a kid,
we didn't have a whole lot of money,
so every time I wanted to play ball,
I had to borrow my brother's
left-handed baseball glove,
and because of that
I really wasn't any good,
and all the kids that I played with,
they didn't know I was right-handed,
so they just thought that, uh...
well, they just thought
that I wasn't any good.
All rightie.
Greg, we need mochas.
Mr. Boyle,
you realize you have a right
to have representation with you,
and since you've chosen
not to have counsel at this hearing,
you waive all rights to such protection
as would be provided by state statutes
regarding said representation.
You're okay with not
having a lawyer here.
Right.
Good.
Then I'll speak my mind.
I advised the court against this.
I think you're a terrible father,
and I don't think...
I think what Miss Lewis is getting at
is that this agreement
is tenuous at best.
We know this,
your ex-wife knows this.
It's important that you know it, too.
So I strongly suggest you do
everything in your power
to retain your newly-acquired
visitation privileges.
I just got a promotion.
I'm going to be getting
a much nicer place very soon.
I still think...
Maybe we should just
fill out this paperwork
and be done.
We just need to verify a few things
and get some signatures.
Are you still at 4742 Alcott Avenue?
No.
What's your current address?
It's a little complicated.
Um, see, while I'm waiting
on the promotion money,
which is going to take a minute,
I got a landlord... he's like...
like a real Nazi landlord.
He, uh, he's just not willing
to let me slide
for a couple of weeks, so...
Are you saying you don't
have an apartment or a home
or any sort of shelter, Mr. Boyle?
No, I got shelter.
I just don't have
an address at the moment.
What are you, living in your car?
I don't believe this.
Mr. Boyle, no court in the world
is going to grant visitation privileges
to someone who's homeless.
We... We can't go through
with this today.
Uh, the court says
that I can have visitation.
I mean, that's a done deal.
Greg, call civils courtroom
and ask for a new hearing,
whatever it takes.
Unbelievable.
Please.
My kids should see me.
I'm going to get a new place
as soon as I get a new job.
A new job?
I thought you said
you just got a raise.
It's complicated.
I did get a promotion,
and I got fired right after that, so...
I'm sorry, Mr. Boyle,
but we're going to have to report
the information
you gave us to the court.
We'll be in touch with you
as soon as a new
hearing date is set.
But I'll get to see
my kids up until then?
I'm afraid that can't happen.
I'm sorry.
Try to have a good day.
This will make things easier.
Oh, you are getting so big.
I can barely hold you.
Hey, guy.
Hey.
How'd it go?
Good.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Hey, we're going to go visit Daddy.
I know.
So you ready?
Yeah.
Okay.
Hello. This is Eva Boyle.
Uh, I've got my checking account there,
and I'd like to close it, please.
My mother's name...
maiden name is, uh...
Slade. That's what it is.
Slade.
How much?
$9.52?
No, no. Don't send it back to me.
Uh, just, uh... uh...
send it to the Salvation Army.
I bet they'd be able to use it, don't you think?
I understand.
It's... yeah. Same address.
Merry Christmas to you, too.
Thank you.
Yes, sir. We got that on back order.
We'll get it right out to you.
Abso... Hello?
Dang it! Stupid cell phone.
Excuse me, sir? Buddy?
I just lost a very important
phone call.
Could I borrow a cell phone
just for one minute?
Thanks.
Absolutely, sir.
We'll get it right out to you.
We have it on back order right now.
Hello? Stupid...
Sir, I just lost a very
important business call.
You don't have a cell phone
I can borrow for a minute, do you?
Well, what happened
to your phone?
It just hasn't been the same
since I dropped it on my boat.
Your boat?
What is this thing?
You were just on this?
- Right.
- Just now?
Yes, sir.
It's a very important business call.
All right. Well, just for a minute.
I have a 2:00.
Great. Me, too. Thanks.
Heather? It's me, Lefty.
I know it's you, Lefty.
- What's this number?
- A friend.
Whatever.
How'd the meeting go today?
Oh, you ought to know.
Everything was fine until those stupid
pit bull attack dogs lawyers of yours
screwed me over again.
I knew this was going to happen.
What are you talking about, Lefty?
All you had to do
was sign the papers.
Yeah, I know.
That's what the court said.
And then your freaking lawyer said
I've got to come back into the court
and have another meeting
with the judge.
I'm getting sick and tired, Heather.
Lefty, I honestly have no idea
what you're talking about.
Why wouldn't they let
you sign the papers?
Because you
and your new boyfriend
don't want me to see my kids.
You know that's not true.
As long as you're sober.
We've been through this.
Besides, it doesn't matter what I want.
The judge said you can see them,
so you can see them.
Tell that to your freaking lawyers!
Lefty, would you please calm down
and tell me what happened?
Look, all's I know is they told me
if I don't have an apartment,
I can't see the kids.
Listen, I really need my cell phone...
Just give me
one more second, buddy.
This is very important.
I'll be there in one minute.
Hello? What happened
to your apartment?
I don't want to talk
about it right now, okay?
So why don't we lay off it!
Whatever.
What else did they say?
They said I couldn't see the kids.
How many freaking times
do I have to tell you that?
Listen, I really,
I got to...
Buddy, just back off, fella!
Please.
I told you this is
a very important business... call.
I'm telling you right now, Heather,
this whole thing ain't right.
And if it don't get fixed,
I'm going off on somebody.
Where are you, Lefty?
All I know is I'm in the office
with your pit bulls.
One minute I slip
and tell them I got fired,
and they're out of there
like bats out of hell
with their cappuccinos
spilling all over themselves.
You got fired.
Hey!
Is that this gentleman's phone?
One second, please. I got to go.
Buddy, you got to go.
- What's the matter with you?
- Get out of here.
What's the matter with you?
Are you across the street again?
Knock it off. Okay?
You... You got problems.
All right, guys.
Listen up. Here's the deal.
Are you listening?
Now, there's a rumor going around
that caroling is a dorky thing to do.
I just want you all to know
that unfortunately it's not a rumor.
Caroling is a dorky thing to do.
So don't sweat it.
We're in this thing together,
so let's make this fun.
- Got it?
- Yeah.
You with me?
- Yes.
I said are you with me?
You're all very hip.
Come on. Let's go.
- Hi, Mary.
- Hi.
I'm glad you came in today.
Hey, little man. How's it going?
Merry Christmas.
We've been working on that one.
Can we go see him?
Of course you can, honey.
I'll call down and make sure
he's in the TV room.
Oh. And, Mary, he had kind of
an angry spell this morning.
He had to be chemically
restrained again.
He's not going to be
very lucid tonight.
Okay.
O Christmas Tree
Thy leaves are so unchanging
Not only green
when summer's here
But also when 'tis cold and drear
O Christmas Tree
Thy leaves are so unchanging
Hi, baby.
How are you?
It's Christmas Eve.
I don't know if...
Jacob is here with me.
I knew that would mean a lot to you.
Say hi to Daddy, honey.
Hi, Daddy.
Why does he have a beard?
Well, I don't know. You like it?
Yeah. I like it.
Merry Christmas.
Honey, you don't have to get that close.
Daddy can hear you. He just...
He can't show you right now
because of the medicine.
Hey, why don't you give Daddy a kiss?
You tell him that you love him,
and then you can go over there
and play with those toys
for a few minutes.
I love you, Daddy.
His beard's tickly.
I'll come get you
in a couple minutes, okay?
Okay.
He's doing really well, Rick.
He's still quiet, holds it all in.
But he is so polite
and courteous and thoughtful.
So much like you,
it freaks me out sometimes.
Oh, he advanced another round
in the spelling bee this week.
He and Sammy Jarvis both get to go
to the district competition
right after New Year's.
I'm going to take work off
and go see it.
It's hard, Rick.
So hard.
There is no one I can
really talk to about this.
No one knows quite what to say,
and then I feel weird
because I know they're uncomfortable.
For the first time
in my life, I feel alone.
I need help, Rick.
I wish they wouldn't
dope you up so much.
This just isn't you.
Oh, we've got to get going.
Making the drive
to my parents' house tonight,
but we'll be back
tomorrow night, okay?
Please come back.
I love you so much.
Merry Christmas.
Two more minutes.
Mary!
Hey. I thought
I might see you here.
Yeah, well, he needs me
here, I think.
Have you seen him lately?
Uh, no, no, no, not exactly.
Uh, my schedule's pretty full now
with the high-schoolers and all.
I do need to find time...
He needs to see people, Mitch,
people who love him.
I know that sometimes it's awkward,
but it's so good for him.
I know, Mary. You're right.
Hey. Tough guy.
Merry Christmas.
Hey, you know what?
I'm going to stop by your house
sometime soon, okay?
And go to the swings park?
Yeah. Yeah, that's right.
- We love the swings, don't we?
- Yeah.
I'm sorry I haven't been a good friend,
to Rick or to you.
I still don't know
what to do with all this.
It's not an excuse.
I'm just saying I'm really sorry.
Not that I should
feel sorry for myself.
I was back on my feet
a month after the accident.
You're the one who got the bad deal.
You got a bad deal, too, Mitch.
I know how close you were.
Yeah, but I'm not...
You know what? I'm going to stop talking now.
It's okay. You're right.
I really did get screwed
on this deal, huh?
Hey, why don't you
come to church tonight?
We haven't seen you there
since it happened.
Tonight might be
the right night for it.
I can't, Mitch.
Come on.
I'll make sure no one...
I can't. Okay? I just can't.
Well, we all love you
there, Mary, right?
Yeah.
Right? Mary?
Yeah. Right. I know.
Does everybody still love Rick?
I'm sorry, Mitch.
I really am glad I saw you.
Let's keep in touch, okay?
And I know that tonight
might be too tough,
but please see him.
I know.
Okay.
Merry Christmas.
Come on, honey.
Oh, and Rick has a beard now,
so if you kiss him,
his beard might be tickly.
Got it.
You shouldn't be here, Lefty.
Oh, hey, Gary. It's me, Lefty.
I know it's you.
Why do you think I just called you Lefty?
You got to get out of here.
Can I just get the rest
of my stuff, please...
Gary...
You mean the rest of those paint cans?
Well, all right, then.
I'm going now...
Gary.
Lefty?
Hey! Lefty, get back here!
Lefty!
What do you want to do?
Fix the thing, I guess.
Want me to call the cops?
No. Forget it.
I just want to be rid of him.
What?
What do you mean, what?
I got the stuff.
Get out here and give me a hand.
Just stop that honking.
It's Christmas Eve.
There's neighbors all around.
Back that piece of junk in here.
I'm coming out.
Come on, hurry up!
The whole neighborhood's watching.
Come on! Let's do this quickly.
Just open it up. We'll do it out here.
Move it, Lefty!
What you got?
Stuff.
Let's see it.
Okay. Fine.
Get it into the garage.
Come on.
All right. That'll work.
This sucker is hot, Lefty.
That right?
Scorching.
I'm surprised you ain't blistering
just touching it.
What's with all the dramatics?
What, are we on TV?
The folks it belongs to
won't be happy they see you with it.
Those folks,
they wear badges.
You know what I'm saying?
Where the heck did you get this?
Well, why don't you tell me
about these tools?
Then I'll see if I can remember
where I got the gun.
Well, this is just a little more
than what I was looking for.
What are you looking for?
It's a gun.
It goes bang-bang.
You want to be picky,
just get out of here.
I could care less.
Got any bullets?
Yeah.
Now get out of here.
One more thing.
What's that?
I'm real thirsty.
Geez.
Now go on!
Merry Christmas.
Yeah.
I seen that!
Merry Christmas.
Yep.
Son of a...
Can I help you find something?
I'm hungry.
You've come to the right place, then.
You like cranberries?
Cranberries?
It's Christmas Eve.
They taste different
on Christmas Eve?
I guess not.
You like turkey?
Yeah, sure, if it's not made up
to look like bacon and stuff.
Yeah. That'll do fine.
How much?
2.99.
Got a bag?
Merry Christmas.
Yep.
Genius.
Excuse me. Do you know
anything about cars?
Uh, I know a bit, yes.
Well, it keeps stalling out on me.
I got to drive another three hours
to my parents' tonight.
I don't think I'm gonna make it.
This isn't really a garage.
Do you know of any
that are open around here?
- I mean, it's Christmas Eve.
- I know.
And that's a problem.
Everything's closed.
Nothing?
I really doubt it.
Right.
Hi, Mom.
No, we're still here.
No, not home, just...
It doesn't look
like we'll be there tonight.
Well, the car's shot,
and I can't get anybody
to look at it right now.
Yeah, it's... I know. It's lousy.
I know.
What am I supposed
to do about it?
Mom, everything is closed.
I can't just rent a car tonight.
I'm going to have to see
if anybody can drive
in the middle of nowhere
on Christmas Eve
and give us a ride back home.
Honey, come here.
Stay by me right now, okay?
Mommy's on the phone
with Grandma.
Okay. You know what?
I'm going to call you later.
Mom...
Yeah, I wish Rick was here, too.
Thanks for sharing.
Right. Bye.
I guess I could look at it, but l... l...
What?
Uh, I was just saying
that I could take a look at it, I guess.
I mean, I don't know
a whole lot, but...
Really? That would be great.
Anything you could
do would be great.
All right.
And a Happy New Year
Merry Christmas!
Thank you. Thank you so much.
Can we offer you a ride
to church tonight?
That's very nice,
but we need to get our sleep.
Understood completely.
Oh, uh, can we offer you
this small gift
from the youth group?
Two gifts: One for each of you.
Well, we really don't need...
We'd like for you to have them.
Just a reminder you, uh, haven't been, uh,
forgotten.
Thank you again.
Merry Christmas.
Moving right along.
Is that bad?
Yeah. I think it's pretty bad.
Can you fix it?
If I had an air filter,
but I don't carry
that sort of thing here.
It's a convenience store.
Well, that's not very
convenient, now is it?
I've heard that one a few times.
Sorry.
Oh, wow.
This is another problem.
When was the last time
you had a tune-up?
A what?
Oh, uh, that would be last Christmas.
Probably the fall before...
before that, actually.
Rick, my husband,
thought that a fall tune-up
would be just fine
for Christmas travel.
You're lucky it's running at all.
The points are trashed.
The filter's disgusting.
I can't imagine what
the oil must look like.
Last fall?
Why didn't you bring it in after that?
Rick always handled
things like that.
Why did he let it go so long?
Well, that's a loaded question.
Rick was in a car
accident last year.
He lives in a home now.
Sorry.
No, it's okay.
But it... it left him
brain damaged,
and they're not sure what kind
of recovery he could have,
if at all, so...
Anyway, he hasn't been in the mood
to take the car in for a tune-up this year.
I can tell you that.
I suppose you'd like to make it
to your folks' place tonight, huh?
You know what? I appreciate
you even trying. I do.
If you help me, we could jerry-rig
the points and plugs,
clean up the cap a bit.
Um, we could change the oil.
I do have oil here.
How convenient is that?
Take the air hose. I'll blow out this filter.
Maybe we can get by
without a new one.
If all goes well, and that's a huge if,
we'll have you on the road
in a couple of hours.
I don't have to have a clue
what you said, right?
Not if I don't.
I'll show you what to do.
Oh, uh, Kirk?
Yeah.
I'm Mary, and this is Jacob.
Jacob. Hey, Jacob.
Why don't you go in
and read your book?
Yes.
Mrs. Boyle?
I'm Mrs. Boyle. And you are?
My name is Margaret,
and I'm with Meals On Wheels.
Oh, I can't afford
to give anything this year.
Oh, no. We're not here
to collect money.
We're here with your Christmas dinner.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, well, why would you do that?
Well, because it's Christmas Eve.
Well, I understand,
but I didn't ask for anything.
Oh, no. Um, someone
gave us your name,
and we bring meals to people
who may need a little extra...
assistance.
There must be some mistake
because I don't need a meal,
and I don't need assistance.
So please, just give it to somebody
who really needs it.
Are you saying that you
already prepared a meal?
No. I'm saying
that I don't need a meal.
How'd you get my name?
Well, we're not supposed to say, but...
I think it was from Dr. Lyndel
at the Jefferson County Walk-in Clinic.
He's your sponsor.
Uh, my notes say that you told him
you had a family of six coming
for Christmas dinner.
- Is that true?
- Oh...
I did talk to Dr. Lyndel about my family.
Yes, I did.
So they are coming over for dinner?
Uh, yes, they are.
Oh, well, I guess Dr. Lyndel
was just trying to help out.
I mean, six people.
Uh, well, uh, come on in
and bring it into the kitchen.
Here.
I was starting to think we'd
have to take Dr. Lyndel in for a checkup.
Oh, I don't think he needs that.
Okay. Now, this turkey is warm,
so it'll be good for the next couple of hours,
you know, if the dinner's tonight.
Otherwise, in the morning,
you can heat it up
for an hour on 275.
Thank you so much.
Oh, and when you're done,
just toss the containers.
Oh, that's fine.
Thank you so much
for all this lovely food.
My family's going to be delighted.
They'll think I'm a wonderful cook.
Well, I hope so.
Oh, and, Mrs. Boyle,
you have nothing to be ashamed of.
What do you mean?
You have cooked enough
meals in your life.
You can take a break now.
Well, I think I will
take a break tonight.
Well, I'm glad.
Merry Christmas.
Oh. Merry Christmas.
You all right in there, buddy?
You alone in there?
Just me.
What are you, some kind of pervert?
What?
You get your thrills doing this?
What do you mean, thrills?
I'm going to have to ask
you to get out of here.
Is there a problem, Officer?
You got about ten seconds,
or we go for a ride in my car.
It's up to you.
Yes, sir.
I didn't do anything.
Mom?
Ouch! Kirk, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I have to go to the bathroom.
It's, uh, not exactly homey.
I don't think Jacob
would mind, if you don't.
Uh... okay.
It's inside in the back.
You can use it, but it's really not...
Uh, okay.
What do you say?
Merry Christmas.
That, too, but what else?
Oh. Thank you.
Sure.
Hark, the herald angels sing
Glory to the newborn king
Merry Christmas!
Oh, Merry Christmas to you.
Thank you kids so much.
Can we offer you a ride
to the service tonight?
No, thank you. It's...
I'm feeling a little sick tonight.
We'd like to offer you this small gift
from the youth group.
Thank you.
I wish I had something to give you.
Nice to see you.
You have yourself a good night.
And Merry Christmas, you hear?
Okay, then. Bye-bye.
Can I help you find something?
Some gas.
How much?
Whatever.
20 bucks.
Merry Christmas.
I said "Merry Christmas" to the man.
You did? Well, that was nice.
Hello.
Hey. Look what I got for you.
Merry Christmas.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Sir, do you have another...
Anyway.
We've got more work to do.
Yes. We do. Come on.
Any of you boys hungry?
You're a godsend.
No one's ever accused me
of that before.
But let's see if I can fix your car first.
So, what about you?
Why are you open today
instead of being with your family?
Pretty pitiful, huh?
The short answer is I've got
nothing better to do.
Oh, come on.
A nice, good-looking...
Sorry.
It's fine.
Look, um... I'm not
implying anything here,
but I do want to be upfront with you.
I have a husband.
Yeah.
You told me that already.
- Remember?
- Yeah.
That was awkward, wasn't it?
I'm sorry.
No. Of course not. I understand.
I haven't been hitting on you, by the way.
Oh, I know.
Of course.
And I'm sorry.
Don't sweat it. I just wanted you to know
that I'm not hitting on you.
Silent night
Holy night
All is calm
All is bright
I'll be there in a minute!
Round yon Virgin
Mother and Child
Holy Infant
So tender and mild
Sleep in heavenly peace
Merry Christmas!
Oh... thank you all so much.
L... I would have
some cookies for you,
but my grandchildren
ate them all.
Oh, stop it. We just wanted to stop by,
tell you we've missed you at church.
I've been traveling.
Uh, my family's all spread out.
Really?
Well...
Will we see you
at the service tonight?
10:45 sharp. Well, give or take.
Service will last till midnight. We can stop by,
- pick you up.
- I'm afraid not.
Um, I have, um, my family's
all coming tomorrow.
Maybe next week, then.
Well... you take care of yourself.
- Merry Christmas.
"O" for 7.
But the singing is getting better.
Really?
No.
But... they probably
can't hear it anyway,
so...
The packet.
You forgot to give her the packet.
Packet.
You know what?
I really don't think that she...
- Oh, come on.
- Wants to...
She might need it.
It's what it's for.
Crap. Hold on.
I nearly forgot.
A gift... from the youth group.
L... I don't need anything.
Just a small something.
Let you know
how much you're loved...
and missed at the church.
Oh, thank you very much.
You okay?
I'm fine.
You sure?
- Is there anything I can do to...
- No.
Please. I'm fine.
All right.
Merry Christmas.
Are you okay, Mitch?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Hey, guys.
I think we're gonna call it a night.
So... tell me more about your husband.
What's he do?
Well, nothing.
Yeah.
Right. What did he do?
Oh, wow. What didn't Rick do?
When we were first married,
he was an engineer.
He always joked he'd never stop
until he'd built
the perfect mousetrap.
Then one day, he comes home
and tells me he's quitting.
Just like that?
Yeah, just like that. And he did!
The next thing I know,
he's working at a ranch for at-risk kids.
Wow.
Talk about a pay cut.
He also volunteered
at our church.
Mostly with the youth group.
He'd help anybody who needed it.
He sounds like a real jerk.
Uh... um, that was supposed to be a joke.
I'm sorry.
Uh, it... it's okay.
It's just that he can't
help anyone now.
It's like his purpose has been...
taken away.
You know, my mom had a stroke
towards the end of her life.
What's that?
My mom.
She had a stroke.
She couldn't take care
of herself anymore.
I'm sorry.
So you know.
Well, it's not the same
as you and your husband... but,
uh, my sister and I did have to take care of her.
My dad... he just couldn't deal with it, I guess.
Yeah. A lot of people can't.
It's funny, though.
It...
I'm grateful for that time.
I mean... it's easy
to take care of someone
who gives back or says "Thank you."
But taking care of someone
who doesn't even know
what you're doing...
it... it makes you figure out
what kind of a person you really are.
You know?
Yeah.
I mean... uh...
I'm not saying that's
why... why this happens.
It's... just that's what I got out of it, anyway.
Huh. I wish other people
saw it that way.
Other than the pastor of my old church,
no one visits him regularly.
They... They all just feel too awkward.
They don't know how to talk to him.
I'm embarrassed for him.
You'll be giving those out
all the way to the new year.
It is 9:32 on the night before Christmas.
Not a lot of traffic out there,
but we do want you to drive careful
and be safe.
Please don't stay out too late tonight.
Well, this was unexpected.
How's that?
Nothing. I just wasn't planning on...
Didn't think you'd have a meaningful
conversation
- with the gas station guy, huh?
- No. Not that.
- L...
- It's okay.
I understand.
I know what this place is.
I'm not proud of it.
So then what are you doing here?
When I bought it, I was a genius.
It's... out in the middle of nowhere,
but the city limits
were headed this way.
I was... I was gonna sell it.
Reinvest.
Make a fortune.
But the city just never made it,
and I got stuck here.
Uh, so l... I figured, uh,
maybe I'd have a chance if I made it
a different kind of a gas station...
a destination-type place, you know?
Uh, gourmet coffee?
Good food? Great service?
Clean as I could get it?
Problem was I did all that,
and no one gave a rip.
So it's never gonna be
a destination for anyone.
It's just a stop along the way.
I don't know.
You know...
you think about that one thing
that you can contribute.
What's my thing?
That I make a good pot of coffee?
Most of my customers don't care
about gourmet coffee anyway.
They want gas
and a Styrofoam cup of pennies
by the register.
That's about it.
Tonight's the anniversary.
Of the accident?
Yeah.
Oh, wow.
He was a good man.
He is...
a good man,
but he was a good man.
I still love him so much.
I meant what I said.
You know, in my vows...
"For better or for worse."
All of it.
Yeah.
Are...
you okay?
Yeah.
I just... I haven't had a chance
to breathe about this for a while...
between fighting for him and...
dealing with his friends
and staying strong for Jacob.
I just...
I haven't even cried in months, so...
Hey, guys. Welcome back.
Brett. Gretchen.
Hey, good to see you. How'd it go.
Not bad.
- Yeah?
- It was cool.
Hey, everybody, head upstairs.
Bathroom break,
and then free time until the service.
So?
What's to say?
We did our duty.
We sang for some folks,
invited them to church.
But they shut their doors
and went back to their lonely lives.
You... handed out the packets?
We did.
That's good.
You know...
I'm still not sure
what value all this had.
Maybe you never will.
So, what's the point, then?
None of them are gonna be coming
to church tonight because of our visit.
They... They didn't care.
And the kids sure aren't gonna
get anything out of it.
- I mean... I just...
- You know something, Mitch?
You go out and serve God
with that attitude,
there's a good chance
that nothing will come of it.
Maybe this is a test for you. I don't know.
Sometimes you do the right thing
because it's the right thing?
Geez, you sound like
a pastor or something.
And, look, you don't know
what's gonna come of tonight.
I got it. I got it.
It's just tonight...
of all nights.
You know?
I mean...
before, a year ago,
when Rick was here,
he mattered.
He was important.
He had good ideas.
The kids thought he was exciting.
And now it's a year later,
and we've got him
tooling around, singing on porches.
Badly, I might add.
I hear you, Mitch.
I do.
I want to talk to you about this, okay?
Can we talk after the service?
Yeah.
Great. Thank you.
You know...
there was something tonight...
kinda odd.
Um...
Eva Boyle.
Is she a little off?
Something didn't seem quite right,
and... and I don't know what it was.
Yeah, Eva Boyle.
I, uh...
She's kept a lot of our church ladies
on their knees for a long time now.
Her husband's been dead ten years.
He was terrible.
Her family's scattered all over.
Some of them she hasn't seen for years,
and from what I hear,
that isn't necessarily a bad thing.
You sure about that?
She said they were all
coming to see her tomorrow.
No. Not likely.
That's great.
I'm glad I followed my instincts.
Listen.
Why don't you follow up
with her sometime?
I can go with you.
Mitch, I know you didn't want to,
but you did the right thing tonight.
It was good for the kids, too.
Yeah.
Long lay the world
In sin and error pining
Till he appeared
And the soul felt its worth
A thrill of hope
The weary world rejoices
Hello?
What are you doing here?
- It's me.
- I know who it is.
Why didn't you answer the door?
Because I didn't want
to be bothered.
Right. I'll just, uh...
No. What... What
are you doing here?
I came by to, um, just get something.
Well...
Give me your jacket.
I'll keep it on. I'm not staying.
How's Heather?
She ran out on me two years ago, Ma.
Well, how would I know that?
Right.
Life doesn't always turn out
as we hoped, does it?
You have no idea.
The hell I don't.
The kids. They okay?
Heather won't let me see 'em.
Now what have you done?
Ma.
All right.
What do you want?
Lucio, l... You... You scared me half to death.
Lefty, Ma.
Lefty.
Oh, for heaven's sakes.
You're not even left-handed.
All right, Lefty.
You came here...
to this house...
on this night...
- for no reason?
- I got a reason.
Well, what is it?
I came to wish you a Merry Christmas.
Actually, that ain't right.
I came here...
so you could...
wish me a Merry Christmas.
You... You need me to wish you
a Merry Christmas?
Well, why would you...
Why...
'Cause you're my ma.
That's all.
Well, Merry Christmas.
Okay.
I'll just be going.
No. No, no. Wait.
Please. L... I'm sorry.
Um... it's just...
all so unexpected.
Yeah, I know.
Uh, let me make you some tea.
Uh, are you hungry at all?
L... I've got leftovers.
- Ma...
- No, please.
Come on. It'll just take a minute.
I gotta say...
you're the best thing
that's happened to me all evening.
That right?
You ever hear a group of teenagers
sing "Silent Night"?
Not silent enough, huh?
Definitely not.
- Lucio, no! Oh!
- What? Ma.
Oh, you didn't drink
any of that, did you?
No, Ma.
Oh... I'm sorry.
I've got a cold.
I just don't want you to get sick.
I'm so sorry. I'm sorry.
Ma...
you all right?
I'm fine.
It's Christmas Eve.
Are you going to church?
Oh, those Christmas carolers
asked me that this evening.
I told 'em I didn't think
I was gonna make it there this year.
How come?
Well... I don't have a car anymore.
What about the bus?
They changed the route last year,
and now the closest stop
is all the way
on the other side of the four-lane.
Oh. Here. Sit down!
Come on. It's just gonna be ready in a minute.
Get you a napkin. Get all ready.
It's just gonna be a minute.
- Hey.
- Hi.
So, tell me.
What were you gonna do
with your fortune?
I don't know.
I didn't get that far.
Does it really matter?
That's the second time
you've said that.
I, for one, am glad
you didn't sell this place and move on,
'cause I'd be stuck out here
in the middle of nowhere tonight
trying to get a new AAA account.
Yeah, that's true.
See?
It was all worth it.
Thanks.
That changes everything.
Oh, anyway,
it was... it was good
to talk about it.
So thanks.
Yeah.
Why don't you hang
out with Jacob, okay?
I should be able to knock
the rest out myself, okay?
Your brother just won't have anything
to do with me anymore.
Think he blames me for your father.
Kevin's too good for all of us now.
I wouldn't waste my time waiting on him.
You hear anything from your sister?
Nope.
Me, neither.
Three years.
Last I heard,
she was still... dancing.
The kids used to write me,
but now I don't know what's going on.
Is that right?
That girl's had a death wish since junior high.
I don't know how she made it as far as she did.
Well, it wasn't really that far.
I'm sorry about you and Heather.
I wasn't exactly Man of the Year.
Well, just don't you lose touch with those kids.
It's no fun when your kids stop talking to you.
Okay, Ma. I get it.
I'm just saying.
I get it.
All right.
Your cousin Jeff just had another baby.
What's that, two now?
That makes four.
I don't know how he affords it.
I don't know.
I haven't seen it, but I hear it's a beautiful baby.
You know, Ma, I got a car.
Okay...
If you wanted to go to church, I can take you.
You'd do that for me?
Right.
If you needed me to.
Well, that would be wonderful.
I would like it.
I really would.
Would you really do that?
If you needed me to.
Would you go inside with me?
I don't know.
Oh, please. Go inside with me.
If I walk in there, Ma,
the place might burst into flames.
I'm gonna go get dressed.
You look great.
Here. Sorry for the spill.
Thanks.
- Your father called those his...
- Church shoes.
Thank you for this, Lucio.
You're welcome.
You'll... You'll take
some of this food, won't you?
Oh, I don't have
any room for it right now.
Oh, it's way too much for me. Please take it.
Maybe you could bring it to church.
Oh, that's a good idea.
I'm sure they'll know
somebody who needs it.
Well...
we should...
we should get going.
Ma, we got a problem.
I don't have any money.
If we're gonna go to church,
we'll need gas money.
I don't have any.
...the snowman
Was a jolly, happy soul
With a corncob pipe and a button...
Well... that should do it.
I don't know how to thank you.
How much do I owe you?
Come on.
Kirk, you've gotta let me
give you something.
Are we leaving?
Well, it looks that way, honey.
Why don't you go turn off the TV.
Just hold on. Hey.
Look, by law, I can't
give you that card back.
It's okay. I got cash.
All right.
Oh, you two are back, huh?
Yeah. Car broke down.
You've been stuck here
this whole time?
Yeah.
But, actually, Kirk here just fixed it.
No charge.
Free.
On Christmas Eve.
Well, not your regular,
uh, gas station, huh?
Uh... look, if you're gonna make it
to your parents' place,
you should...
Oh! My parents.
Oh, we... we were going
up north to my parents'
for a late dinner, but now...
Excuse me.
I have to call them.
- I'm hungry.
- Look, if he's hungry,
there's plenty in the freezer.
No, it's fine. We need to get outta your way.
Excuse me.
- Candy.
- No.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, of course.
Pump two.
Sorry about before.
Merry Christmas.
Yep.
It came upon
The midnight clear
That glorious song of old
From angels bend...
Thanks, Mom.
You... I'll be all right.
You two talk about it
and call me back, okay?
Yes. I will tell him.
He loves you both, too. Okay.
Bye.
We're gonna stay here
for Christmas and be together.
Our little family, as it should be.
Good. I'm glad. I'm sure Rick will love that.
Hey, do me a favor, will you?
Close up the store and go home.
It's Christmas Eve.
Will do.
Let's go, honey.
Oh, hey, let... let me walk you out.
I need to clean up. Okay?
Merry Christmas, Kirk.
Merry Christmas, Mary.
Ready?
"From my mom and me.
It's really good."
It came upon
The midnight clear
That glorious song of old
From angels bending
Near the earth
To touch their harps of gold
Peace on the earth
Good will to men
From heaven's all-gracious King
The world
In solemn stillness lay
To hear the angels sing
Yet with the woes
Of sin and strife
The world
Has suffered long
Beneath
The angel-strain have rolled
Two thousand years of wrong
And man at war with man
Hears not
The love song
Which they bring
O hush the noise
Ye men of strife
And hear the angels sing
And ye
Beneath life's crushing load
Whose forms are bending low
Who toil along
The climbing way
With painful steps
And slow
Look now
For glad and golden hours
Come swiftly
On the wing
O rest beside
The weary road
And hear the angels sing
O rest beside
The weary road
And hear the angels sing
Subtitled By J.R. Media Services, Inc.
Burbank, CA