MIKADO
- Happy birthday.
- Happy birthday!
The one I saw on TV?
Happy?
Yes. Hold this.
Get your hair out of the way, I'll help.
Do we go out tonight or leave it
for the weekend and stay out longer?
- Up to her.
- I'm going out with the girls tonight.
Let's do it on Saturday.
- Where are you going out?
- I don't know yet.
Just you girls?
Yes.
What time are you coming back?
- 11?
- Alright, but not later than 11:30.
- Will you drive her to school?
- I'm skipping the first classes.
Who needs school anyway, right?
Ha-ha.
Go get dressed.
There's an event at the hospital,
I already told the teachers
I'm skipping classes.
We had an agreement.
- Not nice.
- Serves me right for telling you.
Magda.
Cut her some slack today.
Bye.
Make sure she's not late.
- Want to do a magic trick?
- Yes!
So faint!
Haven't you eaten?
Don't they feed you here?
No?
- Why, Madam, are they naughty?
- They're the best!
- Have you been good and eaten?
- Yes!
Then answer this:
Why are elephants' eyes red?
So they can hide in cherry trees.
Never seen an elephant
up a cherry tree?
Well hidden, aren't they?
The next question may be
too tough for you.
- Not for me!
- You think?
No one figured it out
in the adults section.
Another reason why
elephants have red eyes
is so they can hide from
the little red lights in the air.
Can you see them? Where?
You show me where.
You see one here?
I think I can see it too, a little.
Another one! They're everywhere!
Here's one!
It got in my tummy!
Pick a card and show it to everyone.
Now put it anywhere in the pack,
even if I've seen it.
- It's in there, right?
- Yes.
Now pick one of your friends
to be the magician.
- Her!
- What's your name?
- Luiza.
- How old are you?
- Six.
- Why?
Now make a magician gesture, like this.
Well done!
Now show everyone the first card.
Excellent!
- Ready for the surprise we prepared?
- Yes!
Happy birthday to you,
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday, dear
Magda and Luiza,
Happy birthday to you!
Bravo!
You were loud again.
Want a drink?
I swear,
you're addicted to Instagram.
I'll go shoe shopping with her,
want to come along?
If you're going during the weekend
or in the evening.
Her birthday party is this weekend.
We can go around noon.
It's less crowded, too.
How sweet, they went
to Herăstrău Park.
Let me see.
I'm talking to you!
I told you where it is.
You'll be late, you know.
Have it your way.
Go get dressed.
I said go get dressed!
- You'll be late, leave her be.
- Stay out of this!
Make yourself a coffee
or just do your stuff.
Where is it?
Why are you being like that?
Are we back to this?
- We agreed on something.
- You agreed on your own.
After the last parent-teacher meeting,
you promised you'd change.
Are we back to lying?
- I said I gave it away!
- To a pawn shop or what?
- None of your business.
- Really?
- Can't you move it forward?
- Where, on top of the bus?
- Just two metres!
- There are bollards.
You can squeeze past.
Right, sorry.
Are you at the hospital, can I stop by?
Yes, I'm here.
Just try passing.
You'll fit.
We're leaving in a moment.
- Please, can I just leave these?
- No, Madam.
- Excuse me, Sir -
- Dr. Avram is expecting me.
- I can't let you in, Madam.
- You just let him!
He's not visiting a patient.
- But you let him in!
- Please, go home.
- I let her come, I thought you knew.
- Does she ever talk to me?
I'm sorry. She and a boy
hold a monthly event for the children.
Since she's going for Medicine,
I thought it would be good for her.
Come in!
Your delivery is downstairs.
If you don't want her to,
I'll tell her to stop coming.
- Bring back the receipt.
- Yes.
Sugar?
No, thank you.
I spoke with my friend,
he'll do the fundraiser here again.
- Campaign or event?
- Campaign.
- A Text-to-Give, ads and so on.
- Great.
You could build another ward.
Remember the media scandal
about that other hospital?
This is private money,
it's all checked by the Ministry.
What's your target?
One million for a fully-equipped storey.
Or 200.000 for two equipped rooms.
- Can do.
- Great.
What's with Magda?
I bought her a necklace for her birthday.
She claims she gave it to a girl here.
- A nurse?
- No, a patient.
A little girl, Luiza.
- Here?
- That's what she says.
It looks like silver, but it's white gold.
The value doesn't matter.
- I just want to know.
- I'll find out in a minute.
Don't tell her I checked.
- Luiza, right?
- So she said.
- See you tomorrow.
- Bye.
Can I use someone in the audience?
I'll bring my own
magic tricks equipment.
I can do three, if you want.
Alright then, just two tricks.
Of course.
I'll come sign the contract, then.
Shoot!
- How was the test?
- So-so.
- Did the TV guys call back?
- They did, you're a star!
- As of today!
Way to go!
- How about the one you showed me?
- Which one?
Where you swallow a chocolate
and pretend to pull it back out.
You need special makeup,
and everyone's seen it.
Have you?
- What do you want?
- My birthday, my treat.
- No way.
- Come on, it's on me.
What will it be?
A fishburger and a salad.
A cheeseburger and a cola.
- Large, regular?
- Regular. You could get a job here.
No, your mum makes me fishburgers.
It's much cooler to have
your own YouTube channel.
I'll make one and tell the audience
to follow me online.
Hello, Dad.
What do you mean, not there?
I'm not lying, I gave it to her!
Where are you now?
Stay there, I'm on my way.
- Can you drive me to the hospital?
- Anything wrong? Let me get Mihai.
- Do I drop you off here?
- Yes.
- I'll call you when I'm done.
- Let me know.
- Take care.
- Bye.
- You'd think you want to marry her.
- Shut up, idiot.
All that lovey-dovey...
Are you right in the head?
Watching her all puppy-eyed.
- Can I touch you?
- Go ahead.
You're for real, you fuck!
There's no necklace.
I embarrassed myself in front of them.
- I gave it to her!
- Stop lying.
It was mine, do I need
your permission to give it away?
- Is that all you understood?
- And that you're checking on me.
Because you've been playing me
for an idiot, here and at school.
That's why.
You control me to show you care?
Like you did with mum?
- Aren't you embarrassed to -
- No!
I never left her side
the three years until she died.
Someone give the man a medal.
- Meaning?
- Nothing.
Don't change the subject,
that's so like your mother.
Did you sell the necklace?
Do you ever listen to me?
Do you need money?
Are you taking drugs?
- Where is it?
- I gave it to Luiza!
Take your hands off me
and leave me alone!
Doesn't matter if you lost it or broke it.
I broke things when I was little too.
So tell me, did Magda
give you a necklace at the party?
Don't look at her,
she won't mind you telling.
I promise I'll give you one if she didn't.
Did Magda give you
a necklace at the party?
And I suppose you haven't seen
a necklace on any of the children
They would have said something.
I see.
Thank you.
I'm sorry. See you.
- Dad, please wait.
- No.
- There will be consequences.
- I just asked you to listen to me
If you mock me, two can play this game.
At least wait.
Luiza, I know I said
this will be our magic secret,
but let's make that necklace reappear.
I'll cover my eyes and count to three.
1, 2, 3!
- Magda, that's enough.
- Luiza!
- Where is it, Luiza?
- Magda, stop it!
- Where did you put the necklace?
- Magda, just go!
- Dad, wait!
- Geta!
Change her catheter.
We have the same birthday,
so I gave it to her!
- Was it gold or silver?
- White gold.
Geta, if you now something,
tell me right now.
- This is theft!
- Theft?
- Didn't you say you took it?
- Yes, but -
Don't "but" me!
Typical thief behaviour.
If you had come out and said
"I needed the money" -
I didn't do it!
Who gave me this, not two minutes ago?
- Me, but I didn't steal it!
- "But" again?
- I'm losing patience.
- Wait.
Rodica's been with us for 12 years.
Let's hear her side of the story.
I did my night round
to check on Andrei, Alesia, and her.
When I checked her IV,
I saw it on the bed, she was asleep.
It had slipped off her head,
it was on the pillow!
I thought it might get lost or broken.
- I wanted to ask someone about it.
- Did you?
There was no one to ask at 5 a.m.
I left it in my locker,
I didn't even take it home!
I bet you did. But I say
you wanted to steal it.
I swear not!
Doctor, you know me!
- Just admit to it!
- May God strike me if I stole it!
I wish He did.
- I swear on the Holy Cross!
- Keep God out of this, it won't help.
I want her fired now.
I've known Rodica so long,
I don't think -
You will fire her now!
Or I go to the police
and get your hospital in big trouble.
It will be all over the news:
"Nurse Steals from Child with Cancer".
- Stop staring and get out!
- Wait, Magda and Iulian were there too.
I don't care!
Keep Magda out of this!
She told the truth,
you all tried to hide it!
I don't care if you're my friend,
you can forget that new ward!
Fire her!
Or bear the consequences.
I'm sorry.
Here.
Give it back to her.
I'm sorry.
You give it back to her.
Want to touch a celebrity, bro?
I wanted it to be a surprise,
but I couldn't wait.
I'll be on their morning show!
Mondays from 9 to 10,
I'll be there every week.
You bet we'll drink to that!
Catch you later, bye.
Your lunch order.
Thanks, please send Rodica over.
- Congratulations, dear!
- The doctor wants you.
When do you start?
On the morning show?
On a contract?
Well done!
Alright then.
No, I -
We'll talk when I get home.
Bye, dear.
Come in.
- Give him two miligrams.
- I did, half an hour ago.
Have a seat.
How are you?
Alright.
I'm sorry.
It's out of my hands.
At least until the dust settles.
I didn't steal it, Madam.
It doesn't even matter now.
Think of the children.
A whole new ward, fully equipped.
Isn't it a pity not to be done?
Do you believe me, though?
I do.
Listen, take three days of leave.
File the request today.
By next week, I'll have you
transferred to another ward.
It will be alright,
I'll take care of it.
I can't help it, it is what it is.
When the new ward is built,
you'll be so proud you contributed.
I don't want to leave the children.
We'll see.
I'll try talking to him
once he calms down.
We'll sort this out somehow.
Your pizza.
That will be 54 lei.
Just a moment.
- Hello.
- Mum, how are you?
- Good.
- Are you OK?
- Yes.
Something wrong?
The lift's broken.
- Want pizza?
- Yes.
Are you working on Monday morning?
No.
If he gets 10.000 online views
from the TV appearance,
he'll have 100.000 in a week.
He'll earn money from
subscriptions to his YouTube channel.
Only if the views are monetised
and he has ads.
Love, let's eat.
- He'll get ads too.
- From whom?
- Advertisers?
- Yes, he needs something targeted.
Companies that sell things
related to his kind of content.
Let's say he does a trick with cats,
since pets are hot on YouTube,
then he can try with cat food brands.
- Ads for cat food or litter.
- Or cat collars.
I can give you a hand if you want.
- Are you downstairs?
- Problems?
The usual stuff at work.
What hospital?
Her ID is expired,
didn't the ambulance personnel tell you?
You can't get
the paperwork done with this.
We need something valid,
like her birth certificate.
You need that one
for the morgue anyway.
You need to pick her up
from the morgue, Entrance F.
Can you have someone
bring it from home?
Not really...
We can't release the body without
the form. Can you ask a neighbour?
Neighbours...
I left with the ambulance,
I didn't think...
She won't be released until tomorrow,
with the documents we issue.
With the papers from the morgue,
you go file for a death certificate
at the City Hall.
But they close at 2 pm and -
Excuse me.
How is she doing?
She's gone.
Nothing more will happen here,
just bring the certificate.
- Can I see her?
- Of course.
You'll have to identify her
at the morgue in a few minutes.
Ask them to give you some time.
Please get the papers tonight, yes?
Doctor.
How's the situation?
They need her birth certificate.
- Need a lift?
- I can take a taxi.
I had a drink, I can't drive.
You want to go?
- Or give me the keys.
- No, I -
It's alright.
Do you know where she kept it?
- A brown box on a side table by the TV.
- In the livingroom.
- You know where he lives?
- I'm his neighbour.
- Dad can go on his own.
- I still need the address.
- Should I come along?
- Just give me the address.
Right, 37.
Yes.
Yes, I will.
In the livingroom, right?
I see two boxes by the TV.
Yes, found it.
Need anything else from here?
Alright, I'm coming.
Alright.
- Hello.
- How are you?
I've been meaning to call you.
- About today -
- She's dead.
Who?
Rodica, the nurse with the necklace.
How so?
I'm at the hospital with her son.
I brought Magda
so she could be with him.
- The Forensic Institute or the hospital?
- The hospital.
- Why didn't you tell me who she was?
- You didn't let me.
I thought you knew and did it
so Magda would break up with him.
Now what?
I don't know.
Let's sleep on it.
She had medical issues,
but she was under treatment.
I'll ask in Cardiology,
I remember she was taking some pills.
Can you check tomorrow?
It's weird if I ask to see the papers.
Sure, I'll ask around.
Can you call the morgue too?
Yes.
May she rest in peace.
Talk to you in the morning.
Sure, thanks.
If they pick her up at 11,
they'll be at your place just after 12.
The funeral home guys.
- Sure you don't want me to come now?
- Let him rest.
It's all taken care of here.
Don't tip the morgue guys,
I took care of it.
- Want a lift?
- Where to?
- Home, aren't you tired?
- No, I...
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Let's go, bro.
Call me when you wake up.
Get some sleep.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
Get some rest, we'll talk tomorrow.
Let's go.
Will you set your alarm?
Yes.
- Can I have a glass of water?
- Sure.
Goodnight.
- Make me some coffee, please.
- How about tea?
No, coffee.
I thought you might
catch two hours of sleep.
So?
I didn't know she was his mother.
I lost my temper a little.
But I really don't remember...
Don't.
Don't go there.
I know what you're thinking, but still...
If we argue now and I die later,
in my sleep or something,
you may feel guilty but,
rationally and medically, you're not.
- People don't die from an argument.
- How about the other way around?
Say you told me harsh words
and I die in my sleep.
- Wouldn't you feel guilty?
- No.
- Well, I would.
- Me too, I'm just saying.
But there's a long way
from an argument to someone dying.
Magda!
It's not like we can help.
A crowd won't do him any good.
- Do you want to go?
- If she wants me to.
Wait.
- Magda, wait!
- What?
If you insist, I'll come along.
But it's better this way.
Suit yourself. I'll call you later.
- She could have taken the tram home.
- It's a long way, why did she walk?
I don't know.
She was on the phone with Iulian.
- Prolonged effort didn't help.
- Think of all her troubles!
Can I have the ashtray?
Sit here, I need to go to the hospital.
I'll walk you out, then.
- Any more sandwiches?
- In a bit.
- Where's dad?
- He'll be here soon.
May she rest in peace.
- I'll talk to you later.
- Sure.
- I need to go, are you alright?
- Yes, thank you.
Give me a call if you need anything.
See you tomorrow.
- Did word get out?
- Of course it did.
- Did you ask at the morgue?
- Yes. Heart attack.
So it was her heart?
You want to know if it was your fault?
Medically, it could have
happened any time.
Her work, her eating habits,
her sleeping patterns,
her age of 60, her genes.
But putting all that into context
You understand, right?
If you want, you can help
the boy with some money.
Everyone at the hospital pitched in.
- Are you staying?
- I need to get Magda.
- See you tomorrow.
- Alright.
- Buy a two-litre Fanta.
- Got it.
Maria!
Should we get going?
I'll have a smoke first.
I couldn't believe it at first.
At first I didn't realise it was her.
Put it there.
No one ever stole anything
in our hospital.
I spoke with a priest too.
It doesn't matter now.
This is from all of us.
Don't refuse, there's a lot of expenses.
Just to get you over this tough time.
The Doctor contributed too.
We'll manage.
Maria, will you tell her to come?
Yes, let me finish this.
Pass me the papers.
This is from the funeral home.
- Did they get the paperwork done?
- They spoke with Mihai and Iulian.
- Can we get some more coffee?
- In a minute.
Hello?
This is Cristi, about the funeral.
Did you file the papers at City Hall?
When will they make the payment?
I see.
You'll be talking to Iulian.
The deceased's son.
Alright then.
I won't be here tomorrow,
but I'll leave the receipt.
You'll need it at the cemetery.
He was horrible.
He was yelling,
threatening to have her fired.
If I hadn't told them
about the necklace...
I don't want you to think it was my fault.
You can ask the other nurses.
When did that happen?
They came to the hospital
and asked the girl first.
Were they both there?
Yes, your girlfriend and her father,
but only he went into the office.
Then he went berserk.
What are you doing here?
Get out!
You threatened to have her fired!
- Fucking piece of shit!
- Calm down!
Get the fuck out, you murderer!
- Iulian, what happened?
- You killed her!
Let go!
- I'll kill you, fuckers!
- Iulian, enough!
Where's that necklace now, huh?
- Hands off her!
- Get out!
Let go of him!
- I hate you!
- I didn't know!
I don't give a fuck!
I hate you!
You threaten people!
You never trust me!
- Stop yelling!
- I'll yell if I want, you animal!
Go straight to hell!
Magda didn't know.
That asshole father of hers
didn't know, either?
Maybe the broad who fired her
didn't know, either.
Actually, no one knew.
Your mother fired herself.
Why did they come to the wake?
With that doctor leading the parade?
Why does her father want
to pay for the funeral?
And how the fuck did a few nurses
put together 10.000 lei?
They want to play you.
Geta told me
he threatened to go to the press.
Let's talk to an attorney,
listen to your bro.
The one who got me off the hook
with the car trial, we can talk to her.
I did not know.
- Is Iulian with you?
- Hi. No, he isn't.
Hi. How is he?
- See you in Bikers?
- No.
I'll text you.
He's not good.
Please tell him I didn't know,
he's not answering my calls!
He's really upset.
Is he home?
I'm coming with you.
Better wait until after the funeral.
Give him time to clear his head.
- I just want to see him.
- You will, at the cemetery.
The thing is...
You have to reach an agreement,
tell your dad.
We need to find a way
that's fair to everyone.
Sure, we need to talk.
With all that's happened...
Pass me your dad's number
so we can talk.
No point in taking this to court.
The main thing is
we need to be by his side.
- What court?
- Just give me his number.
- We'll be at the funeral.
- Just in case you can't find us.
Even if Dad won't be there, I will.
Very good, at the cemetery
Iulian can't lose his grip again.
So, the number?
0744 52 00...
300, right?
I'll take care of it.
- Will you settle things with her?
- Yes, I'll let you know.
Don't let her sucker you.
Don't be a fool.
Iulian!
- Iulian, wait!
- Get lost.
- Magda!
- Leave him alone.
Murderers!
God will make you pay in kind!
- I didn't know!
- I just can't look at you now.
- Do you believe me?
- Yes, just leave me alone!
- I swear I didn't know!
- Leave me alone!
- Do you believe me?
- Yes, just let go of that door.
- Are you angry with me?
- Ask your father.
Please, let go of the door.
Please.
- Why did you try to hide it?
- Let's talk in my office.
- Tell me why!
- In my office.
Were you afraid?
- You fired her!
- I didn't.
- You sent her home!
- For a few days.
Tell me the truth!
I know you're upset.
Tell me!
Her heart attack was unrelated
to what happened.
- Then why didn't you tell me?
- It was a bad time.
No, because you were afraid!
I'm afraid of very few things
and you're not one of them.
I'm sorry, but with her health issues,
it was a matter of time.
But it happened
right after you fired her!
And after she walked in the sun
for four hours.
- She had done it before.
- And she got fired before.
And I put in a word for her,
so stop it.
I just sent her home
for a few days, until things calm down!
- She was very calm!
- Until "things" calm down.
Don't fight me, I'm on your side.
So is Cristi.
How much did you put in that envelope?
Everyone contributed.
Geta said the nurses each gave 50 lei.
How did it get to 10.000?
- It doesn't matter.
- It does! It means you had a reason!
- Isn't caring about you reason enough?
- About me?
Funerals are very expensive.
It's not all tears and feelings.
- We'll see about that.
- Iulian!
She's not at his place.
I rang, I knocked, there's no one here!
How am I supposed to know?
OK, bye.
It's not easy, but you can ask
for financial damages.
- I don't want money.
- Stop it!
- But I don't!
- That's not the point.
Burn the money if you want,
but they must pay.
- But not with money.
- You have to hit them where it hurts.
Then you can -
be Santa Claus to some poor people.
It takes a long time and
you don't get the amount you ask for.
It depends on the deceased's income
and the degree of trauma.
You can get more for moral damages.
He should fucking pay for it!
- How long will it be?
- 2-3 hours.
Leave the old tyres in the back.
If we file criminal charges,
it goes to a prosecutor.
He asks for a counter-expertise
on the cause of death,
to contradict the official expertise.
- Geta can testify.
- Did he threaten her?
- Who, Geta?
- No, his mother.
He said if she wasn't fired,
he'd tell the media
nurses steal from children.
That gets him 3 to 12 months.
If we prove direct causation,
it's 3 to 7 years.
Are you fine with that?
Where were you?
Why don't you answer my calls?
I asked you something.
- How is Iulian?
- Fine, he's just buried his mum.
- Don't shut the door in my face.
- Leave my room, please.
I will, but don't shut
the door in my face.
- Cristi!
- I don't care what -
Cristi!
All I want is to know you're alright.
I am, leave me alone.
That's why I called you!
- Hello?
- You can at least pick up!
He's unavailable, who is this?
Hi, it's me, Maria.
He'll call you back.
Actually, wait.
It's Mihai, Iulian's friend.
Want to talk to him?
Hello? How is he?
I understand.
I'm listening.
What do you mean?
Why do we need to meet?
I don't know, let me check my schedule.
I'll call you back.
On this number?
Right.
Yes, I got it.
What?
He wants me to meet Iulian's attorney.
I keep telling you, it wasn't like that!
Still, I don't think you should meet him.
- People were talking at the funeral.
- I don't care!
Fine.
- What were they saying?
- You weren't even there to hear.
You'd be feeding the rumours
by meeting that attorney.
I'll strike the iron while it's hot.
Sticking my head in the sand
won't solve things.
They have nothing on us
because there is nothing!
- Let them take the first step.
- They did, they called an attorney.
It doesn't mean we have to react!
I'm sorry, but it looks like
this is more about yourself than them.
You're reliving your own loss.
What are you doing?
Don't call him now.
Wait until you calm down.
Cristi.
Hi, are you busy tonight?
How about meeting?
As her son,
he can file for a second autopsy.
Rodica had no other close relatives,
not that it would matter in court.
I see.
I doubt you do.
Things have degenerated.
It didn't have to be this way,
but with the threats
and the nurses who can testify,
it's getting complicated.
People say many things
when they're angry.
But I think we can find
a mutually convenient solution.
No point in going to court.
We could get more money that way,
but the boy needs help now.
I advise an amiable agreement
with you and the doctor.
I see.
In whose name are you speaking?
In their name.
- Who are "they"?
- Iulian.
Let me see your power of attorney.
- I'm here to extend a hand.
- You still need a power of attorney.
Trust me, courts are nasty.
Damages, legal expenses...
Plus the criminal record.
You would get at least 3-4 years.
- Easy with the accusations.
- Just stating the facts.
But have it your way.
Threat is a crime too.
The sentence is lighter, though.
One year at most.
But with aggravating circumstances,
it can go up to 7 years.
Get out right now.
Cristi...
- Stop staring and get out!
- Cristi.
- You too.
- Let's calm down and talk.
I say you just get out
and calmly meet in court.
Suit yourselves.
I said get out!
- Hands off, man, or -
- Or what?
I'm warning you,
you'll lose on both counts.
- Got it, now scram.
- Cristi, let's...
Out!
Boss, you're playing with fire.
Say what, you fucking scum?
- You might get burned.
- Get the fuck out!
- Get out of here!
- This will turn ugly!
Cristi, that's enough!
- What did I tell you?
- If they're like that...
Wait a moment!
- He's just hot-headed.
- Prison will cool him off!
- Give us a minute.
- But he -
Wait in the car, please.
- That was not OK.
- Neither were you.
You don't understand your situation.
He risks ending up in a very tight spot.
We're willing to end this for 50.000 euro.
Him and the doctor, half-half.
Wouldn't it be easier?
She has some rubbish power
of attorney.
Understood.
- Please text me that.
- What are my options?
- And practically?
- Thanks, bye.
Right.
Thanks a lot, I'll call you later.
It's possible,
but it would be very hard for them to
prove connection to the cause of death.
- So they can prosecute.
- They can ask for a re-examination,
if the forensic expert
and the prosecutor agree.
For now, they can only sue for threat.
"Threatening a person with a crime
or an act liable to cause them fear"
"is punishable by 3 to 12 months
in prison or by a fine."
Who cares about a fine?
And you didn't threaten her.
They have nothing!
I said I'd go
to the police and the media.
- That's not a crime!
- According to you.
I said I'd do that
unless she was fired.
At most, you threatened the doctor.
And she's not complaining.
It was just
the three of you in the office.
Then how did Iulian find out?
Maybe someone in the hospital told him.
At the end of the day
it's your word against theirs.
And you want to pay them 25.000 euro?
- Wasn't it 50?
- From both, you and the doctor.
All that money,
and it wasn't even a real threat.
"Determining or facilitating
suicide or acts causing death"
"is punished by 3 to 7 years in prison."
If they prove it! You want to give them
money by default?
Iulian...
Iulian!
Slow down!
Stop!
Iulian, stop!
Iulian!
I see.
No, I don't have a problem.
A friend of mine wanted to check
on this lawyer, that's why I'm asking...
Right.
Thanks a lot.
Maybe we'll find some time for a coffee.
Ok, bye.
So what if her dad was a prosecutor?
You'll see, things will calm down in time.
In a month, they will see it differently.
But let's say they file charges now.
Protracted procedures,
no evidence, judicial vacations...
Even well-grounded lawsuits take years.
You think this will be done in two days?
You can choose to
give them money in a few months.
They'll take any amount, any time.
They'll drop the complaint
even for 10.000.
Do what you want, I'm not paying.
Let them sue me.
Want anything else
or do we ask for the bill?
- I'm in a hurry.
- I got this.
Excuse me!
A cappuccino to go and the bill, please.
You can pay at the bar.
We can pay at the bar.
What if you pay him
and he still files charges?
Or you make the settlement
and let the trial go on?
I wouldn't be paying him
for his mother's death.
I don't know to what extent
it was my fault.
Is it guilt or fear of prison?
- I don't feel completely guilty.
- To what extent, then?
This doesn't let me sleep at night.
- So it's about you, not the boy.
- It's about him too.
And about my peace of mind.
Suit yourself.
I say you should reconsider.
You didn't kill anyone.
We all die, whose fault is that?
- Do you have the boy's number?
- Yes, I'll pass it to you.
You think you understand?
You have someone to go home to!
- I lost my mum too.
- You have your father! That murderer!
- I'll leave home, move in with you.
- Spare me, both of you!
But you still want money from us!
- Who said that?
- Mihai and that attorney!
They came and asked Dad
for money as compensation!
I told the attorney I don't want money!
- So you did see her!
- So what?
They asked Dad for money.
Fuck your money!
Will money bring my mother back?
Iulian.
Iulian, where are you going?
Are you listening? Iulian!
- Wait, talk to me!
- Let go!
Iulian!
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
I couldn't answer your call
with my wife there!
- Say you'll call back.
- Can I call you back in five?
I'm not at the beach, things come up!
That's why I don't answer your calls!
Shit.
I need 15.000 euro.
- Are you OK?
- Yes, I just need it.
I can't, I swear.
You know my money
gets split two ways.
And the company account?
- Today?
- Yes.
- What is it for?
- A personal issue.
I don't want to.
I have nothing to talk to you about!
I understand, I'm still not interested!
This shit is your fault!
- I did it for you.
- Did you even ask?
No, I just did my thing.
Sunny side up?
- Ana? Sunny side up?
- Whatever.
Pour us some soda.
It's Magda, want to talk to her?
I LOVE YOU
- Did she let you do her in the ass?
- Fuck off!
You swearing at your bro?
Her dad sent her to get him off the hook!
- No, he wants to meet me!
- To fool you into not asking for money.
- You asked for it, in my name!
- To help you!
- Why, am I handicapped?
- No, just a retarded sucker!
I love you like my brother,
she loves her daddy best!
- Why do you think she came to you?
- To talk, idiot.
To keep her dad out of prison,
that's why!
He sent her because
he knows you're an idiot.
She'll fuck you for a month or two
and go back to her daddy.
Who will you go back to?
Who, you piece of shit,
after you fought me for that cunt?
Won't you come back to me then?
I'm sorry.
Good evening.
Good eve -
- Hello.
- Sorry I'm late.
- Don't worry. Coffee?
- No, thank you.
- Water?
- I'm fine.
I won't keep you.
How do we do this?
With our cards on the table or in court?
Aren't you here to discuss things?
- Will you take a seat?
- Thank you, I sat enough in the car.
First, sorry for my outburst.
I don't deal well with threats.
Don't worry, you're not the first.
Second,
the lawsuit would drag on and on.
And you might not win.
Technically, it's possible,
but still a long shot.
An amiable settlement
would be best for you.
If you say so.
I'll give him the money.
But not all of it, and not out of guilt.
To help him.
I'm a father, I empathise.
But it wasn't my fault.
If you want the full amount,
try in court.
It's 15.000 or nothing.
Are you sure you don't want to sit down?
No, I'm in a hurry.
Bring Iulian to this address tomorrow.
It's my company.
He won't talk to me.
Come together and I'll explain why
I'm only offering this amount.
I'll talk to him, we'll find a way.
Please do.
I want to do what's right.
What's best for everyone.
- Have a good evening.
- You too.
- We did it, bro!
- I told you not to knock like that.
Answer when I call,
don't throw pussy tantrums.
Fucking mask.
God sent her to you, mate!
She told her dad you're a sucker
who faints at the sight of cunt
and then he changed his mind!
Want to eat?
Mrs. Sweet Tits Attorney called.
He's giving you the money.
- 15.000, 5.000, who cares?
- What money?
- Can't turn down 5.000 euro.
- What?
At least it's something.
Do you have a bank account?
Or maybe he brings the money
in a fucking shopping bag.
Hey!
What got into you?
What?
Please leave me alone.
There, there.
It will be alright, you'll see.
This will pass too.
And you know
what bothers me the most?
What hurts the most, actually.
He can't see it.
As a father, he's not thinking about
myself or what he's done.
It's always someone else's fault.
Even with this whole madness,
I don't think he considers himself guilty.
It's not quite like that.
You could say I started it all.
I showed him those photos
of you in the Herastrau Park.
Agent Corbeanu, traffic police.
Your documents, please.
Your insurance?
- Do you know why I stopped you?
- No.
- Oh, my seatbelt.
- Why is it off?
I'm sorry.
Please wait in the car.
It's fine, I'll give it to him.
Not all of it, 15.000.
And not as settlement, just to help.
I just want to do it.
Yes, they'll come to my office,
our legal counsel will be there.
No, this is for him,
the attorney is another matter.
1.000? She wishes!
2-300 at most.
Didn't I tell you it would work out?
Fuck...
You said it would take months.
It's not about money, the main thing
is this is right for everyone.
Fair is fair.
Subject closed,
let's talk about something else.
Call an ambulance!
for my father