Excellent,
my wife has given birth to a son.
Very good...
This is joyful news.
We will call him Thopaga (joyful news) .
She is so lucky.
A rich husband and now a son.
Come!
Zesay, come!
Peta, come!
What are you two talking about?
Thopaga and Zesay's future.
That's all you talk about these days.
Here, have some meat.
lt'll make you strong.
Peta, wake your father.
He has to go to Dingri.
Thopaga, that's making too much dust.
Mother! Father won't get up.
Call my brother and sister.
Yungdrung Gyaltsen.
Yungdrung Gyaltsen and Peydon,
please take care of my children.
Give them the love
l won't be here to give.
Don't worry, your children
are my children.
lt's all in writing.
l entrust my children to you,
their uncle and aunt.
When my son comes of age
to marry Zesay,
let him receive all my wealth
without exception.
Kargyen,
please forgive me.
l didn't expect to go so soon.
lt makes me sad.
This is something we can't change.
lt's karma.
Be strong.
Don't worry about us.
We will be fine.
Don't look back.
Take this.
This too.
These are our most precious jewels.
A rich widow is an easy target.
These will be safer with us.
We'll look after you.
Don't worry.
Peta!
You're still taking lice
out of your blouse?
l really need a new one.
How can you talk like that?
We don't even have enough to eat.
You still haven't finished.
You're so lazy.
What do you do all day?
Your husband really spoiled you.
lf you don't work,
why should we feed you?
Mila's not coming back...
and that son of yours,
where is he?
Hurry and finish!
Hurry up.
We didn't have to take you in.
Don't touch that.
lt's for Senge.
One man's pleasure
is another man's pain.
You should rest. l'll finish.
Why do l always lose at dice?
Zesay, what a nice surprise.
What are you doing here?
l was hoping l might find you here.
Should we walk back together?
Oh, wait...
This is for you.
Dried cheese.
Thank you.
These are for you.
They smell nice.
l wish l had more to give you.
Thinking of me is enough.
Don't you have enough?
What about you? Don't you have enough?
Such a greedy woman,
too bad she's my sister.
How dare you sing
while we are so miserable!
Mother, l'm sorry.
l wish your father was here.
lf he was still here,
things would be different.
What's going on down there?
Tidy yourself up.
Today's an important day.
Right here is fine.
Yungdrung Gyaltsen.
Kargyen would like to invite you both
to a rice wine party.
She's having a party?
What's going on here?
Just a small gathering
with friends and family.
Please have a seat.
Kargyen, it's time.
l'm grateful you have...
joined us today
for this humble celebration.
As you all know,
ever since my husband Mila died
many years ago,
we have suffered a lot.
Today is a new beginning
and a happy occasion.
Yungdrung Gyaltsen and Peydon,
l want to thank you
for taking care of us.
l've invited you here
to request the return
of my son's inheritance
left to him by his father.
lnheritance? What inheritance?
Mila had no estate!
lt was always mine, on loan to him!
Mine! He just returned it to me!
Please don't say this.
Even if there's not much left,
give us what little there is.
Didn't you hear?
There's nothing!
ls this what we get
after all these years?
Even this house belongs to me.
You greedy woman.
Don't touch my mother.
Leave her alone.
Stop! Stop!
We don't need this.
Don't be so naive.
lt's yours.
lt's your birthright.
Foolish cow.
Where is your loyalty?
Someone say something.
Mila was good to you.
l called you all here
thinking you would honor
Mila's dying wish!
Why doesn't anyone speak up?
Let's go.
You will regret this!
One day you'll suffer like we have.
lf you are many, make war.
lf you are few, cast spells.
These people are following
the scent of money.
l'll get some tea.
Some blouses for Peta.
Thank you.
ln these difficult times,
you two and my brother
are the only ones...
who have stuck by us.
For this l am very grateful.
lt means a lot to me.
You should send Thopaga
to learn a skill.
Can l help you?
l need a place for the night.
l'll come down.
Enough.
l'll bring another butter lamp.
Be careful,
the consequences can be terrible.
My mother gave me this field
when l married Mila.
lt's all l have left...
The soil is no good.
But barley grows well here.
lt's all we've had to live on.
Please, l really need the money.
Your husband was always good to us,
so l'll buy the field as a favor.
Thank you.
Son.
l sold the field.
What...
Why?
We have suffered so much.
l can't bear it any longer.
l want revenge...
against those who harmed us.
What can we do?
Your aunt is going to get
what she asked for.
l want you to master the art of sorcery.
Destroy your aunt and uncle
and all the villagers
who treated us badly.
Zesay, l have to go away.
How long will you be gone?
l don't know.
Maybe a few months.
l'll try to come back soon.
Do you have to go?
Hurry...
The sun's almost up.
You must leave
before the village awakes.
Son,
let the memory of your father
and the cruelty of your uncle
inspire you in your studies.
lf vengeance does not come soon,
l will kill myself
in your very presence.
Mother, l will do my best.
Offer this turquoise to your teacher.
l'll return as soon as
l fulfill your wish.
Take care.
Zesay! What are you doing here?
l wanted to see you off.
Don't open it now.
lt's a surprise.
l'll miss you.
l must hurry.
Come back soon.
He can never do it.
l swear.
Kargyen sent Thopaga to study sorcery.
Are you sure?
Yes, l just heard.
Can l camp here for the night?
Okay.
The nights get pretty lonely
in these parts.
Where are you from?
Kya Ngatsa.
lt's near Gunthang.
What brings you to these parts?
Whatever it is, we have the whole night.
l'll get my saddle.
Amazing!
l'm going to hang prayer flags
for our safe journey.
Protectors dwell in places like this.
Hurry!
My uncle's coming!
Let's go!
Dharma!
What are you doing? Hurry!
Hurry! Let's go!
They can't be too far away.
Let's go!
Don't look back.
l'm worried about my family.
They may be in danger.
Don't let your emotions take over.
Let's go!
What happened?
We crossed this bridge before.
Maybe it's Thopaga's magic?
lt's not Thopaga!
We just got lost in the fog.
Curse this fog!
Can you see the trail?
Are you still worried?
Yes.
They could be here any moment.
Trust me, they won't be coming.
How do you know?
They got a little confused on the trail.
Confused?
Why were they confused?
l played with their minds.
What?
How?
How do you do that?
l study with a great master.
Who?
Yungton Trogyel of Yarlung.
Ah, this is wonderful!
He's the one l've been searching for.
That's the fortress of Yungton Trogyel.
Your father has been waiting for you.
He's your father?
You were supposed to be back yesterday
but you're here today.
l met someone on the way.
He needed my help.
There must be a good reason
why you've shown him compassion.
So, what's your story?
l make this offering.
l request you accept me
as your student.
Yesterday l spoke about death charts
that are used to determine
a person's time of death,
and when their life force is vulnerable.
Each day of the week,
everyone has white days
when their power
and life force are high.
And black days, when their power
and life force are vulnerable.
lf you want to help someone,
you should do so when
your white days overlap.
But to harm someone
you must determine when your white day
overlaps with your enemy's black day.
lf you can determine that day,
you'll be empowered
to perform spells effectively.
You're no good.
Just wait.
Any other challengers?
- You go.
- No, you go!
Hey, Thopaga!
l'll kill myself...
You have been given
all necessary instructions,
incantations, and secret methods.
lt's time for you to go back
to your villages.
There is nothing more to teach you.
Guard the teachings and...
practice well.
Thopaga is still here.
He's outside.
Poor boy.
He thinks sorcery
is a poor man's weapon
against injustice.
Shall l bring him in?
Yes.
Why are you still here?
The practices l've learned
are not effective enough.
lf l leave now,
my mother will kill herself.
Precious Master,
l request
the innermost secret teachings.
l will send Dharma to your village
to verify your story.
That will take days.
lt's very far.
lt won't take long.
Dharma has mastered kang gyok.
He will return in one day.
Master, Thopaga's story is true.
Really?
As your story is true,
you have no choice.
Your cruel and corrupt relatives
have no regard for right and wrong.
They must suffer
the consequences of their actions.
Dharma will take you to the master,
Yonten Gyatso.
Can he really help me?
Of course.
He is the descendant of Sangye Yeshe.
There is no one more powerful than him.
Bring yourself in front of me.
This old man never looks back.
We are students of Yungton Trogyel.
l was expecting you.
Construct a chamber where
people will not see it.
This particular method
is a secret teaching...
from the lineage of the great master,
Sangye Yeshe.
Transmitted only once in a master's lifetime,
in this lifetime, you are
the one to receive it from me.
lf you practice it diligently,
a result should manifest in seven days.
Thopaga, it's the seventh day.
Any signs?
Lama, l ask to continue for seven more days.
You have been distracted.
ln the dark,
the mind has no leash.
Thoughts become strong and reckless
and visions emerge from chaos.
lf you are trapped by these illusions,
you will accomplish nothing.
You little monsters,
watch where you're going!
Young man, is that a storm approaching?
Yes. A very big storm.
We should take shelter.
At last!
This must be Thopaga's doing!
l warned you,
my revenge would come.
You deserve this for causing us pain.
Do you hear me?
l can't believe this day
has finally arrived.
What a wonderful spectacle to behold!
l'll kill you, witch!
Look! Smoke!
Come on.
Hey! Stop where you are.
Come closer and l'll kill you all.
Murderer!
We'll kill you first!
You deserve to die.
You destroyed my family!
What do you want?
A safe place for the night.
Old monk, thank you.
What can l do for you?
Old monk, we're looking for a friend.
Did he come here?
Rarely does anyone come this way.
The old monk wouldn't lie.
Come on, let's go.
Enemies are never ending.
Your enemies arise from your mind.
lt's just a matter
of learning how to control your mind.
You better finish your soup
while it's still hot.
What are you reading?
The words of the Buddha.
What does the Buddha say?
Cease negative actions,
cultivate positive actions,
and tame your mind.
What?
Why don't you help me with these?
What's the problem?
You should rejoice
in your accomplishments.
Rejoice? l've accomplished nothing.
Don't let the memories
of the dead haunt you.
They deserved it.
Sit.
What troubles you these days?
What is it? Tell me?
l don't know what to do...
l'm so tormented.
Revenge doesn't solve
any problem.
lt only creates more.
ls there any other way?
Yesterday, my benefactor died.
l couldn't save him.
lt's ironic, that l, Yungton Trogyel,
who can...
kill thousands,
can do nothing...
to save a single man from death.
Everybody dies, don't they?
When death comes,
only your life's actions accompany you.
Your future will come from your past,
as the Udumbara flower comes
from its seed.
Then the future for my mother and me
is nothing but suffering.
lf l could take on my mother's part
in all of this, l would.
You can't change your karma...
like you change your horse.
lt's not that easy.
But there is a way to help your mother.
What is this way?
By following the path
of the enlightened ones
you are destined to arrive
at the place beyond all suffering.
This is the way to really
help your mother,
and all living beings.
Precious Master,
can you teach me this way?
This old fool can only tell you
who to go to.
This is as far as l go.
Come with me.
No, but l wish you luck.
l hope you find what you're looking for.
Stay well.
H-M