MILLENNIUM GENERATION
Alright...
Then, fair, I want to do differently.
You will get out of the fair out, shoot the first two frames.
For the second shot, we want to do something
it is risky for the child.
Well then record it
running down the road with her big belly,
in the seventh month, and she run, run, run.
You will save in slow move around.
and then probably go without sound. Something.
Send ... When ready, send it to me and I read it.
OK, see you! Bye.
Bye.
Just imagine this is your mother, and this is the little baby in it.
This is her stomach, and this is your smaller sibling.
AND...
And Mom was a little sad the last few days.
And I want to know why.
And you also want to know
why she's sad all the time.
The way we play you the ...
wonder if something is wrong.
And we'll see how it will be.
- Alright? - Yes.
Try to find out what's wrong with Mom.
What hurts?
Inside there's a baby, right?
And baby ...
Something is wrong with him.
Did you kill her?
Honey, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Listen, Emily.
Much needs to be angered.
You know? Because you love the baby.
Stoma're ready ...
You have to run.
- you understand me? - No, not morality.
He wants to get out to see the world.
Look, I am the mother
and I have to bear a baby and keep it.
- Hello. - Hello.
What brings you here?
Will you stay with Anne, right?
Come here and give me a hug again?
Srcence?
Mom goes to work, but will be back very soon, okay?
- Okay. - Yes, ah ...
Thank you, thank you.
Bye, Tony.
Bye!
- Purple! - Purple.
That ...
And here, what season is it?
- What is this?? - Is it autumn or spring?
Spring.
And this?
Essen.
See the leaves on the ground.
Here the stem.
The leaves fall in autumn.
What is that?
Castle.
In the castle lived a witch.
- Witch? - Witch
- Witch? - Yes.
It witchcraft.
Whether you're a witch?
Witch are you?
Maybe, sometimes.
And this and this?
No I did not recognize. I've never been there.
Nor I have been to.
Arise!
Good?
What's up?
Do you want children?
Yes.
Certainly.
But not yet.
Cheers!
What are you doing?
Au, baby!
You pushed his nose?
So kid, joints?
Excuse!
No, but only briefly,
A friend of mine makes it very often.
Go to the supermarket
if saw strong fish, simply run it.
I think I fucked up.
It does the trick.
You know? While people like us think the psychological work ...
he just does.
No, I can not imagine.
Not something handsome, he just ...
Easy does it. That ...
So I do not know anything as extreme as your friend does.
- However, Leo wants to love with. - Does not work.
- Wow, what is this, dude? - Lump.
- We have grass? - Hey Leo, your birthday, dude.
Do not you old to 30 years.
You have to stop to think about it.
But somehow it is easier for us.
We're potent.
So?
I say we are potent, but women ...
- Women ... - does the same.
No, but older men how, beautiful flowers
and women zbrchkani.
- That's it. - Depends.
Saying that Ann is wrinkled?
I have 34 years.
Well, things will start happening soon ...
Lele, pistons.
Wow, I'm all for it.
- I want to be alone tonight. - What number?
... like a roller coaster with us.
And what is your solution?
Since you have many expectations of me that I have to fulfill.
And instead we ...
We accept the situation as such.
And besides, now I ...
you provide.
In fact I can not even for me to acquire now.
No time for anything.
And you could do well much attention.
AHA.
I think it works with us in stages.
Yes, but that would be the ideal situation?
Not an ideal situation!
Yes, but only because ...
And strive more for it!
We accept things as they are, but not:
to get married. It simply is not true.
Finally I do not think so ..
It's a huge pressure.
Because I think I can give ... what you expect.
Whatever you say, I can not udovolam ...
Leo, I want to sleep.
I can not sleep.
Then go to the kitchen.
... This is a bit different from what we do.
We focus on people,
And I ... really do not see where is the link.
What I now to give you
edition is
that we have an amateur photographer.
I researched and I know the material.
The thing is, ah ...
that this moral section, which can be downloaded,
we can use spontaneous material that we sent.
And if you send us something like this
We will look. Maybe you use.
It is almost empty.
I'm not used to these little houses in general.
No? I grew up in such.
When you have problems, you can not break out.
Yes, but I could not in the city center.
But you will still know people who make exhibitions?
Yes, I know a few.
But...
I think...
a little publicity in a magazine or so
perhaps before doing The exhibition or whatever.
If you just show up with your portfolio, you have no chance.
- No? - No, I do not think so.
But I can not import.
The most important thing is that you meet people.
If you are interested in you, and you love your job.
This is Anne.
You still see?
Yes ... now and then.
- But now somehow difficult. - Why?
Unable to bear it to be close
and says I'm too intrusive
and on the other hand, it always ...
We must discuss and constantly looking for me,
no speak only for myself and ...
And I think some questions and thoughts that I have
I can cope with it, and instead ...
I talk to you or my mother, or ...
Yes.
And all this ...
stress begins to annoy me.
How do you email?
I think in relationships?
I've never been in a relationship.
Seriously ??
Well, never a fit.
Whatever that means. "Guess."
But as with men in terms of relationship?
I get the picture ...
I imagine that it is simpler.
No, actually the same shit.
Sit down.
One foot throttle, the other on the brake.
Well, Miss Marshus, well you see the screen?
- Oh, is Ladny. - Yes.
What you see here is your bladder
and there goes the colon.
Here's your uterus. I'll show you in more detail.
Will pause the image. Here is the uterus.
Here is set
between the two notebooks that did.
Just like it would expect in the middle of the cycle.
I save the image.
Now let's look at the ovaries from the right.
I'll show you how I closer.
And then you look and lev side.
It's here.
Watch here. This ovarian follicles.
And here there are many smaller follicles.
It is proof that your fertility is excellent.
On the other hand.
So it all follicles that are ready for fertilization.
This means that the initial trials
until this point your fertility is intact.
Just to make sure that I have missed something
It may make our problem.
But there is nothing that would cause a problem.
How many years were you the first period?
14 years.
And now, it is too painful to do is to download something?
- Yes. - Are you taking pills? What are you doing?
Sometimes I drink pills, if you bet wrong,
and usually put hot water bottle on the abdomen.
Have you ever been pregnant?
You pometnale, abortion bad pregnancy?
I once aborted, yes.
When either of the occasion?
I was 21.
You taking any medications? Any?
No, nothing.
What is your schedule of work and daily routine?
- More regular or irregular? - Very, very irregular.
It's certainly a lot of stress.
Usually I'm very stressful
and often stay up late and get up early.
OK it's background. Just for a moment ..
I want to explain the diagnosis as to your not understanding.
It's important for me to know how much percentage'm still fertile.
- Yes. - Can you tell me?
I'll tell you a percentage.
The question is how to help.
Will it help me ... why I'm here.
There is no percentage in conception.
Either you conceive or not.
If you want good advice,
The earlier you get pregnant the better.
Waiting reduces fertility.
It can actually be darker.
I'm missing a little pigment here and mask.
You have something darker?
Simply anyone no longer telling him about my love life.
This is not a love story.
So I tell you, I saw the material,
the end of the week will call parents
to tell them clearly that we love Emilia and Avid,
and we want to see them again.
Yes, this might.
It's cool.
I think they're cool.
one
two,
three,
four five.
This is not like you at all?
Not.
But there is something about it.
It is different from others.
It's kind of childish.
- You like it? - Yes.
And me.
It's kind of an unusual way of exposing things.
But here often I watched photographic work.
But here in the corridor, for example, several pieces in a large format.
You think?
For example, there may be a series with the dog.
- Yes, why not? - I like it.
What are my chances?
We will meet with him and see.
I'm sure I will like your work.
This is very out.
Watch!
Radically.
That is good.
Alright.
Seriously.
And you put the plastic cover.
Head up a little, eyes ...
See here left behind.
Cheers.
This will be funny.
- Hey! - What's up? Where are you?
Sorry. I will be able to.
Show me!
You like?
That is good.
What?
No, it's fine.
As long as I you like me ...
Let the day float past.
Be here now, in this moment.
Weightlessness,
security.
Go back
in your mother's womb,
where it is warm
and beautiful.
Feel Your Presence here and now.
Do not do anything.
Just to get here
and to be enjoyed.
And feel safety
here at this point in your shell.
- Hello! - Hello.
- Come on in! Everything is okay? - Yeah, thanks.
This is important if you want to increase the lips,
it is really very nice and shaped shading.
You can watch me.
to see it increase, embellishment from here to there.
And zasenchuvanjeto really nice and shaped.
Complete oral look bigger and fuller. Yes?
That means you can look completely natural.
- That's right. - I do not want to stand out a lot.
Completely natural.
Well, soon we are ready.
Well kept. It does not hurt. Bravely.
Once again little by the parties.
Then you add some makeup, you raise.
And tonight you can go out.
- So how does it look? - Beautiful.
- Not yet seen! - Really nice.
- To put a little powder. - True.
Ready? Yes.
.
- Oh my God. - Yes, more lip.
- Now is the flow can be understood. - Oh no.
- you will need only 10 minutes. And then ... - 10 minutes?
- Oh, it's really swollen. - It is normal.
Just shaped course. Like that?
Like that. It is best not to touch more.
- Only 10 minutes far! I have important Nastan tomorrow.
10 minutes. Then everything will be settled.
And wait 3 to 5 days.
You need a little patience and confidence.
It will be much milder than with us. Like that?
- Does the swelling is gone tomorrow? - Yes.
- Up to 11 in the morning? - Will it run for 10 minutes.
Oh God.
But as you can see have a perfect shape now.
Srcevidnata form out great.
- Looks great. - You look great!
Swollen, but this is normal. Just be patient, have a little faith.
Hour swelling is gone, and tomorrow will look great.
Just in time for the event. Do not worry.
- we promise. - Alright.
Then you have an appointment next treatment.
When suits you most? Morning or poslepladne?
- At noon, the better. After noon, okay.
As late as possible. - Alright.
It must not, understand?
You know? - No, no.
But why did not you understand?
It wants to get out and see the world.
Light. Can we get some light?
Guys ...
Cheers! The ex?
Not bad, but ??
... just tits ... not just tits.
Please, it's my face.
Hello! Leo's.
Hey. You OK??
You may kacham above ??
Hmm ... I do not know.
Maybe tomorrow to see?
Alright.
I will call you.
Otherwise, I am very close to art photography,
and Jan Sibenhan us presents a series of photographs
depicting naked male body.
These are scenes that reveal a certain intimacy.
Very subtle scenes are presented here.
Some scenes even have philosophical effect
as this picture from behind, for example.
And here we see the imaginary Leonard
sit in front of a mirror with a lot of desperation in itself.
In order to implement this Jan Sibenhar.
Yes, first of all to thank Richard
I allow organisms to my first photo exhibition here.
It's uncharted territory for me,
and I think there is not much to say.
If there is a question, of course, is free to ask me.
It is great that you have gathered here in such numbers,
and I hope you enjoy "I'm excited."
Thank you very much, thank you.
I was terribly nervous!
Everything out at the last minute.
Just email me soap.
Hello! I'm glad you came!
Why did not you tell me?
I tell you?
Do you like it?
It is uncommon.
You will come back?
This woman collects photos?
Well, we'll see. I will not decide.
Sure, but it might be a good chance.
Today we celebrate.
- Hello. Hello, ŞEKERCİ.
- Want some fun? - Yes.
Stop, stop, stop!
Thank you.
I took another pat.
- You want a cigarette? - Yes of course.
How long you been here?
... about two months.
- Two months? - Yes, I'm new here.
And you?
Not long. Several months.
Here it is cold.
Yes...
I came here because my girlfriend ...
and I wanted to start a career here, but ...
nothing happened.
I have to go now.
Alright. Need a lift?
No, just ... I'm going there.
Someone will pick me up.
Alright.
Well, we see!
Healthy?
Yes, hello, too.
And I wanted to tell me?
Hmm, I do not know.
Sam there?
Where are you?
No, I'm in the car.
Ah! Where are you going?
I do not know myself.
Whats wrong? Nervous are you?
So why?
What happens there?
I'll call you later, okay?
Yes ... calm down first.
Somehow, all that work seemed strange,
muss ich dir ehrlich sagen. Moram da kazham you.
You must have control over their lives
and find a solution.
It can not continue like this.
That's right. We will be in touch, right?
- Yes. - Bye.
Come here. See. Sit back here.
You can again briefly. Sit here.
- We'll try again? - Yes!
- Hello. - Hello.
- Alright? - Ok?
- How are you? - I'm good.
- Finished allowed. - Hi, Tony.
- Hello. - Guided my hands.
I have to go, but ...
We can see the coffee and talk a little?
Yes, great.
Great!
Well, go then, you Tony?
You go home? Yes?
Hey? Honey?
We'll go to see Julia.
And Annie. With all ... Come.
- And Dad! - Yes, you see Dad. Come!
All right. Clothing, blanket.
We have everything? - Yes?
- Say bye! - Bye!
- Bye! - We'll see each other!
- Take my jacket ... - jacket.
All this we will do. I see.
We will discuss the actors re briefly
but today I have a great feeling. Yesterday I was ...
Ah ... Bev very tired.
Not. Not!
There's another.
Then extract it.
- Yes? - Yes.
Others were much better.
What do you say you?
- Wow, it's too ugly. - No.
Perfectly.
Yes, but it is very cool, too.
This photo you can look at it from all sides.
Cheers, dude.
She looks as deer!
Yes, a little scared. Because the hunter is close.
- That the hunter. - Comes hunter.
And then there are the gates of hell.
All come, all just looking, looking and seeking.
All always seek. Everyone wants to take a stand.
You also need to take a stand, Leo.
Let me say it, dude.
From another perspective.
Why?
If we take embryos will not take just one,
We will take more if we can.
We will do it with provocation of your own hormone.
- Yes. - It is not complicated.
All right. Should I take this every day ....
And what if it is wrong?
What if you want to start over?
I do not think will make a difference.
No, not really ...
I never wanted to be someone else.
But maybe ...
Well, you always want more, right? As ... never satisfied.
I think if we start over again ...
I will start more comfortable with more feeling.
I did everything with more feeling.
Yes, but it may not have been so successful.
Maybe it was not so bad.
I have to Mock.
Well, now you can come here
and sit on the chair.
Carefully.
Come forward with your hips,
put your feet here. That's lev and right.
Another forward. A little bit more!
All right. Great!
Good other side.
Yes, that's better.
Okay, all are placed. Great.
What is the meaning of life?
Life: what distinguishes animals and plants from inorganic matter,
including the possibility of growth, reproduction, activity,
changes and eventually death.
I do not want to die.
I do not understand, "I do not want to die."
If you will check the internet.