"Hey Bikaneri chick, you are so slick."
"Lost my house because of you,"
"And now I'm about to lose my job too."
"Hey Romeos!"
"Roadside Romeos!"
"Innocent looking deceptive..."
"liars!"
[Background vocal]
"Hey Romeos, worthless boyos!"
"Stop bothering me,
you good for nothing fellows."
"You have already stolen our hearts,"
"Don't leave us behind."
"This isn't right, my love."
"You sometimes look like Mona Lisa."
"And sometimes like a mesmerising Lolita."
"Oh."
"And sometimes like a mystery."
"You are a super-super-super
supreme beauty."
"From head to toe, an absolute beauty."
"You are a super-super-super
supreme beauty."
"Hey supreme beauty..."
[Background vocal]
"I can't be tied down."
"I am like the wild wind."
"I have a long way ahead of me."
"I am not interested in gems or jewels,"
"I am interested in chasing my dreams."
"I am used to my dreams coming true."
"I don't want men chasing me."
"I am made for the big screen."
"You have already stolen our hearts,"
"Don't leave us behind."
"This isn't right, my love."
"You sometimes look like Mona Lisa."
"Buzz off."
"And sometimes like a mesmerising Lolita."
"And sometimes like a mystery."
"You are a super-super-super
supreme beauty."
"From head to toe, an absolute beauty."
"You are a super-super-super
supreme beauty."
"Don't touch me."
"I don't want be yours."
"I don't care even
if you beg for my company."
"No, no, no..."
"Hey Bikaneri chick, you are so slick."
"Lost my house because of you,"
"And now I'm about to lose my job too."
"Looking at your curves,"
"My heart starts to race."
"Like the hands of a clock
going hickory, dickory, dockery."