* Decide to hold my dreams
- Good morning, sunshine.
- Good morning.
- Hey, David, how's it going?
- Craptacular.
Paper and a
large dark roast to go?
Yep.
Nothing
to eat this morning?
Nah, just the coffee.
- Ah, you're killing
me, never a bagel
or dare you try a latte?
- I like my coffee one way,
dark and bitter just like Mamet.
See you tomorrow.
- Dude, wake up.
Robert.
- What?
Get up, man!
- What time is it?
8:25.
What day is it?
It's Friday.
Jesus dude.
Shit.
- Ah, glad you could
join us, Mr. Montgomery.
I have a place
reserved just for you.
- Rough night?
- You should know.
You have
one hour, starting now.
- Hey John, what's up?
First Sergeant Solomon,
this is Captain Brighton,
prepare to copy.
- Ready to copy, sir.
Our unit
has been activated.
You will report to the Army
at 0700 on Friday, 12, August.
Bring all of your gear, we'll
have a shake-down inspection.
You will receive more information at morning formation.
The uniform of the
day will be ACU's.
It is your responsibility
to notify anyone else
under you of the information
I have just disseminated.
Do you have any questions?
- Do we know where we're going?
No, you
know as much as I do.
- Roger that, sir.
Do you have any
other questions, David?
- No, sir.
Out.
James Whitmore.
- Sergeant Whitmore, this
is First Sergeant Solomon,
prepare to copy.
So dude,
did Jenny stay all night?
Nah, she must
have left after I passed out.
Dude, you're
such a lightweight.
- Yeah?
PFC Montgomery?
- Yeah.
PFC Montgomery, this
is First Sergeant Solomon,
prepare to copy.
- Ready to copy.
Our unit's
been activated.
You'll report to the Armory
at 0700, Friday, 12, August.
You need to bring
all of your gear.
There's gonna be a
shake-down inspection.
Uniform of the day
is gonna be ACU's.
Do you have any questions?
What if, um, you
know, what if I'm over there--
James, we can't even
start to think like that.
Look at me.
I can't have you
thinking that way.
- The last time,
it was different, you know,
it was just policing and
that's all we ever did.
The only time I saw action
was when someone got
too drunk on base
and there was one night
where some asshole was
playing with a grenade and
I didn't see it, I
mean, I heard it.
I didn't even see it and it
this time,
this time is,
- Hello?
Hey mom.
Who is it?
- It's Robert.
He's not
getting anymore money
until the first of the month.
Tell him he can eat that Army
food if he needs to get by.
- Ray.
Sorry sweetheart.
So, what's going on, my son?
How are classes?
- Uh, they're fine.
It would have been nice
if you could have
been home for more
than just a couple of weeks.
I'm sorry you had to take
those summer courses.
- Yeah, me too.
- Did you need
anything, sweetie?
Food, money?
You know your father's
just being
well, your father.
- No, no, I'm fine.
I actually wasn't calling
about anything like that.
Well what is it, Robert?
- I got a call today.
From?
- I got the call today.
My units being activated.
We're being deployed.
Mom?
Mom.
- Baby no, no, no, not
my baby, not my baby.
- Linda, what's going on?
- Okay, this can't be
happening, you're in school.
They can't, they can't take you
outta school in the middle--
They can.
- They can't.
- Mom, they can.
And they did.
What's going on, Linda?
- They're sending
our baby off to war.
They haven't told
us where we're going yet.
- They haven't told him where
they're sending him yet.
Military intelligence.
- Ray.
Mom, I'll let
you know when I do, okay?
What about school?
- I have to go talk
to my advisor tomorrow
and I'm pretty sure I can
pick up where I leave off.
You know, they've probably
done this before, right?
My God, my boy,
my boy.
Mom, stop
with the my boys, okay?
Well you
can have a child
and you go through
this and then you can
tell me to stop my
boys, all right?
- Okay, sorry.
Well mom, I have
some stuff to do.
I have to get some
stuff together,
but um, there's gonna
be a thing on the 12th
for friends and family and--
- That's two weeks.
I know.
- They're leaving the 12th.
There's gonna be a
small ceremony there.
Do you think
you guys can make it?
Okay, oh my God.
- Okay mom,
I gotta go, but I'll call you
in a couple days, all right?
Oh, my boy.
My God.
Mom,
it's gonna be okay.
I love you.
- I love you too, sweetie.
I gotta go, but
I'll call you in a couple days.
- Bye.
Hi, this
is Jeanie and Rachel.
We can't get to the phone,
please leave a message.
- Fuck it.
- Yeah, you were so
quiet that night.
I remember telling myself
that if I kept talking,
you wouldn't have a chance
to say it's getting late.
Oh, no.
I was so afraid I'd
say something stupid.
- We just sat there.
We didn't make it to the movie.
We didn't make it to dinner,
we just sat at that
bar, that bar.
What was the name of that bar?
- Oh.
Thurman's.
- Yeah, yeah,
Thurman's that's right.
We just sat there.
I didn't mind
that we never made
it to Davinci's.
- Neither did I.
- And then we just sat out
front after they closed.
- Yeah, I was an
exciting guy, wasn't I?
- It was perfect.
- It turned out well, didn't it?
- It turned out perfect.
- La la la la la la la la--
- I got a feeling
about this one.
Yeah?
Oh, how about that?
Drink up boys.
- Cheers.
- Meh.
- You know what,
fuck that, all right?
Cheers to my man, Bobby,
kicking ass and taking names
in the fuckin' sandpit.
- Yeah, take care of Bin Ladin
and make mommy and daddy proud.
- Hi.
- Is Rachel home?
- David, you can't
just stop by like this.
We agreed.
I know.
- No, we both agreed.
- Jesus, I know.
- She's at her piano
lesson, it's Tuesday.
- When's her recital?
- It's three weeks from today.
- Fine, I'll just--
- You'll just what?
- When did the swing do that?
- I don't know.
I don't know, David.
There's a lot of shit around
here that needs to be fixed.
Would you like me
to make you a list
that you only do
half the things on?
Look, I have a lot of
things I have to do
before I pick her up.
- I got the call.
Our unit's being deployed.
- Oh my God.
- Yeah.
I uh,
I just finished calling my guys.
- Is uh, is John still your CO?
- Yeah.
I was just heading over
to meet him at the Armory
to get everything together.
- What about Jennifer
and the baby--
- No, no, Mosley
switched out of the unit
a couple months ago.
- That's good.
Yeah.
- David, I'm sorry.
Is there anything that I can do?
- No, no.
Just tell Rachel I was here.
- Do you want to go
with me to pick her up?
- I can't, I gotta meet John.
But, thanks.
- God.
Yeah.
- Where are you gonna be?
Can't say.
- Right.
- You need to go.
Yeah,
yeah, so do you.
- Yeah.
- Hey Dean.
- Hey David.
- Buy you a drink?
- Sure, I'll have another beer.
- I was thinking something
a little stronger.
I'm in kind of a mood.
- Mm, sorry no.
Liquor makes me
mean and irrational.
- Beer it is then.
Get
anything for you, Dave?
- Yeah, take a beer and
another one for Dean here.
- Thank you.
- So, shipping out in
a couple days, huh.
- Yeah.
- You know everyone here's gonna
be thinking about you guys.
- And you know how much it
hurts for Dean here to think,
so hurry up and get your
ass back home, would ya?
- I'll do my best, Frankie.
- Preferably in one piece too.
I don't want you
taking up anymore room.
I got customers to serve.
Hey,
watch your six man,
boogie's on your tail.
- Got 'em man, chill out.
If it took you that
long to
those fuckers in real life,
you'd be dead, asshole.
- Yeah, well hopefully for you,
we won't be saying
the same, soldier boy.
Go fuck yourself.
You know what?
After I get done
kicking your ass--
Uh huh?
- You can show your patriotism
towards this country
and its great citizens
and go fetch us some beer.
How about if
Johnny Little Walker over here
goes and gets some fuckin' beer?
- What are you trying to say?
The all mighty Striker
Six, the God of War,
can't even complete
a simple mission
like going to get us some beer?
- I went through a grueling
nine weeks of bootcamp
and NIT after that, so I was
gonna cut you some slack,
but now I think I'm just
gonna have to smoke your ass
and make you run off haji mart
and get us some fuckin' beer.
- Boom!
- Oh.
Oh, guess who's hoofin' it
to the haji mart now, bitch?
Biatch.
- If you guys don't remember,
I'm not even old enough
to buy the beer anyway.
- Oh, so take my I.D., man.
They never look at it
that closely anyway.
Fuck they can barely speak the
language, let alone read it.
- You kidding?
- Don't be such a pussy, man.
- Honestly.
Fuck.
- Oh, and Striker?
- What?
Watch your six.
- I'd like to update
my earlier comment.
Both of you go fuck yourselves.
Oh, ow!
Fuckin' dick.
Bitch.
Game on?
- I'm in.
Fuck me.
- Come here a second.
Hey, hold up.
What's your name?
- Why, what'd I do?
I'm not
gonna ask you again, kid,
tell me your name.
- William Rogers.
- Mind showing me some I.D.?
Just made things a whole
hell of a lot worse
for yourself, kid.
Hands against the wall.
- God, hey, I'm shipping
out in two days, man,
cut me a break.
- Got any weapons or sharp
objects I should know about?
- No, did you fucking hear me?
I'm going to Iraq
in two fucking days
and I can't buy a fucking beer?
- Hey, watch the language.
Tell me your name.
- Robert Montgomery,
Private First Class,
United States Army Reserve--
- Cut the patriot crap.
You just purchased
alcohol using a false I.D.
and attempted to flee from
an officer of the law.
- Fucking kidding me.
- Hey, I said
watch the language.
You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and
will be used against you
in a court of law.
You have the right
to an attorney.
If you cannot afford an
attorney
Never figured
you for a smoking man.
- Yeah, I'm not usually,
but given the circumstances.
- You should try flossing.
- What?
- Flossing.
It's cheaper, better
for your teeth.
You're a strange man.
- If I had a nickel.
Thanks for
bringing the stuff.
- Not a problem.
- I was hoping my order would
get here before we left,
but I'm guessing they'll
put it back though.
- Yeah, I can only imagine.
- Be nice if they would
just give us the stuff
as standard issue.
- Oh, I feel compelled
to remind you
that you did, in fact, enlist
in the United States Army.
- What?
You're kidding me.
I thought I joined an highly
efficient forward thinking
group of individuals acting
towards the common goal
of global security.
Hi David.
- Hey Allison.
- How's it going?
- Well you know, can't complain.
Wouldn't make any
difference anyway.
- Can I get you anything?
Are you hungry?
- No, thanks, I just ate.
- All right.
Well, beer's in the fridge,
help yourself if
you need anything.
- Thank you.
- I'll get the other one.
Thanks.
- Someday you're
gonna have to tell me
how you managed that one 'cause
buddy, you married way up.
Throw that butt out.
So how you feeling?
Good, good.
- Jackson finally get
his shit squared away?
- Yeah, he actually passed
the PT test last week.
Yeah, I nearly had
a coronary when I saw that.
- Yeah, Jackson nearly
had a coronary doing it.
I bet.
- Man, I really shouldn't
make this stuff.
- So what about Montgomery?
How's he doing with all this?
- I haven't talked to him one
on one since the phone call.
I swear that kid
thinks he's rolling in
like Stormin' Norman.
- Yeah, I remember those days.
- Yeah, he's a good kid.
He just hasn't had his
eyes opened for him.
- Dunlap.
Dunlap!
God damn, Dunlap!
- Yeah?
- Did I hear you
right that the kid
that you got out there
is from the 951st
and he's due to get
shipped out in two days?
That's what he says.
- Shit.
Bring him in here.
- The kids I work with,
it's kinda like that.
You know, they're hard to reach.
They act like they
don't wanna be reached,
but when it comes down to it,
they just want to
know that they matter.
- So how do you show
'em that they matter?
- I don't know.
If I could tell you
that, I wouldn't have
a stack of cases on
my desk.
Each one's different.
Some of them are air tight.
It's a matter of trust and
you build a repore with 'em
and when no one else is
there for 'em, you are.
Not all of 'em.
I wish that I could be,
but when you get that one,
when you reach that one,
it's,
yeah,
yeah.
- Yeah.
Well I should get going.
It's about time you think about
reaching out to
your wife, you know?
Right.
I heard that.
Thanks.
It was
that kind of thinking
that got me into my
current situation.
- On that note, think you
can get yourself squared away
in the next 48 hours?
- Yeah, I guess.
- Great, your confidence
is overwhelming.
- Yeah, I'll see you in Canada.
Take care
of yourself, David.
- I'll do my best.
I mean if I can find
the time between
taking care of your husband
and the rest of my soldiers.
I know
what you mean.
I can't get this one to remember
to pick up his ring
from the jeweler's.
- Call me if you need anything.
- Yeah, will do.
Goodnight.
Mr. Solomon?
- Yeah?
This is the
Springfield Police Department,
please hold for
Officer Daugherty.
Hey, what's up?
- We have a little situation.
I'm telling
you, I didn't do anything.
That cop just had it out for me.
God,
just stop talking.
What kind of a moron gives a
fake I.D. to a police officer?
You're lucky they called
David instead of me.
I would have left you here.
- Now am I right in
assuming that you're not
looking for a big
chicken dinner tonight?
No.
- No, I'm not right?
- No, I mean, yes.
Wait, what's
a big chicken dinner?
- Bad conduct discharge.
Oh no, no,
no big chicken dinner.
I am stuffed.
I'm just looking
for some dessert.
- Well, after you.
You are, after all,
our man of the evening.
- Oh, okay, um, well, I can
tell you guys are a little rusty
so I'll show you
how it's done, okay?
* And I made a choice
* To use my voice
and tell them-- *
Watch and learn, boys.
- Come on, let me square
things away with Frankie.
- My pleasure.
- You back already?
- Frankie.
Yeah, I want you to
meet a friend of mine,
this is James Whitmore.
- James, good to meet ya.
Nice to
meet you, Frank.
- Please, call me Frankie
like this guy does.
Just like he's my
best regular customer.
Not even my mother is allowed
to call me Frankie anymore.
How is it you have
the misfortune
of knowing our
mutual friend here?
- I'm in the 951st.
- Yeah, we're dropping his
rank of Staff Sergeant tonight.
What brings
you guys back around here?
- Had a little situation
with the kid over there.
And that would be?
PFC Robert Montgomery.
- Oh, do tell.
- Well sparing you the details,
Ben Daugherty let him
go with a warning.
He was trying to
purchase with a fake I.D.
He also had a choice
a clash of ideals
with a certain police officer.
Dunlap?
- Uh huh.
- Why am I not surprised?
Yeah.
Listen, kid's gonna
find one way or another
to get his hands on something.
I'd just rather it be
with a little supervision.
- You gonna keep an
eye on him, right?
- An eye and a
foot, if necessary.
I appreciate it, Frankie.
- It's the least I
can do for you guys.
- Montgomery.
Private.
Montgomery, this
is Mr. Townsend.
He's gonna be taking
care of us tonight.
Say thank you.
Thank
you, Mr. Townsend.
- Tell him how well
behaved we're going to be.
- School boys, sir.
- Well just make sure
it's not the boys who
always end up in detention.
- Thanks, Frankie.
- Thanks, Frank--
- That's uh, Mr.
Townsend to you.
- Thank you, Mr. Townsend.
- May the road rise to meet you.
May the wind be
always at your back.
May the sun shine
warm upon your face
and may the rains fall
softly upon your fields
and until we meet again,
may you always feel
the love of this place.
How about a couple
of beers to wash that back?
- Sounds good.
- I've got some unfinished
business to attend to.
Thanks.
- Hey, I almost forgot,
Marilyn's at it again.
On a Wednesday?
- She's starting to rival you
for best regular customer.
- Be back in a minute, I
gotta say hello to someone.
- Take your time, I'll keep
an eye on Casanova over there.
Hi Marilyn.
- David.
Sit your wise little
ass down, honey,
and have a drink with me.
- So, what are you into tonight?
- Just a little date
with my old friend, Jack.
- Been seeing a lot of
him lately, have you?
- More than I might like,
but he's always there for me.
- Fuckin' A.
- Don't mock me,
you little shit.
- So how you really
doing, Marilyn?
- You know how it goes, David.
Pretty much a class
A cluster fuck.
But me, soldiering through.
- Huh.
Fuckin' right, huh.
- Not spending too many
nights at home, huh?
- Why would I?
I don't have a dog
at home to feed.
Do you
want one for a while?
Jesus, David.
First you can't keep a
wife and a kid around,
is your dog sick of
your shit now too?
No, actually
nothing like that.
I'm going on a little vacation.
I thought you might
like the company.
- Where are you going?
- Somewhere sunny and warm.
- Really?
- Oh yeah.
Best sand storms
you'll ever see.
- Gotta love that free airfare.
- So many perks.
- Too many to mention.
You got everything squared away?
- Stopped by the house.
Jeannie was there,
but Rachel wasn't.
So what the
hell are you doing here?
- It's a long story.
But uh,
ended up here with a couple
of guys from the unit.
- That's great.
That's your bonding.
It's not like you're gonna be
spending any time together.
How's Jeannie?
- Well you know how it goes.
It's more confusing
than the sandpit.
- You looking forward to
things being simple again?
- You need another drink.
- You're goddamn right I do.
- Well,
I'll see you when I see you.
- You know where to find me.
David.
- Yeah?
I'm not the
one you should be asking
to watch your dog.
- Send her another
one, would you Frankie?
You sure, Dave?
- Yeah, make it a double.
Got it.
Two days,
can you believe it?
Two more days and we're
loading up in that C47.
- Yeah, two more days.
You think that'll be
enough time for your balls
to have finally dropped?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- You need to get
your head straight.
And we're not leaving on a C47.
We're taking a civilian
flight to Germany.
- I know, I'm just saying.
- Yeah, you were just saying.
You were just talking.
That's what you do, you
just talk, you don't think.
Army doesn't
pay me to think.
- Is there an original
fuckin' thought
in that head of yours
or is this what you do?
You just quote
lines from movies?
- Forgive me for believing
in what we're doing.
- Tell me, what exactly
is it that we do?
- We go, we secure, we
mow down the first fucking
camel jockey we see with
a cellphone in his hand--
- Oh that's what we're doing?
That's what we're
gonna be doing, huh?
- Keep it simple, stupid.
KISS, you've heard of
that, haven't you, Sarg?
- All right, guys.
- Haven't you, Sarg?
- All right.
All right, just relax,
all right, take it easy.
Let's just drink our
beers, all right?
After all the trouble I went
through to get it for ya?
These last two days are
gonna go by like two minutes.
So just sit back and enjoy it.
- All right.
So where's the
nearest strip club?
Are you serious?
- Thought maybe you could go
for some of that right now.
This place is dead.
And uh, I appreciate it and all,
but honestly, only ass
I'm gonna see here tonight
is your two guys and uh,
quite frankly, I don't
subscribe to the whole
don't ask, don't
tell side of things.
- Yeah well, for the last time,
we're not going to a strip club.
- I'm not gonna spend my
last two days here, okay?
I can't buy beer
at the haji mart
and I'm with two guys who
have some strange phobia
about making brats.
- You can't buy beer where?
- Haji mart.
- Mm, do you know
what a haji mart is?
- Fuckin' 7-Eleven.
- No, you dumb shit.
You have no fuckin'
clue what it is, do you?
- Why don't you enlighten me?
- Now why would I wanna do that?
- Because you're my sergeant.
- Well when we get there,
you can find out for yourself
and until we get there,
stop talking about shit
you know nothing about.
- What if when we get there--
- What if, that has got to
be the most useless question
on the face of this planet.
What if I want you to
shut your fuckin' mouth
and try to learn from
someone else for a change?
- All right, man, take it easy!
Save some of that angry
shit for haji, okay?
How about you save it
for when you come back
and you find out that Jodie's
been giving it to your wife.
What did you just say?
- All right, all right,
that's enough, Private.
- You have been so hell bent
on telling me how it's
gonna be, but you know what?
Let me enlighten
you for a minute.
Do you want
your ass beat inside
or do you want it out?
- All right, guys, why
don't we just step outside
and get a breath of
fresh air, all right?
All right?
- After you.
- That's right, after me.
That's where you're gonna be
when all the action
takes place, right?
Behind me?
You know what your
fuckin' problem--
- Don't you ever
disrespect my wife!
If you ever talk about
her like that again,
I will break you,
do you understand?
You think you're so fuckin' bad.
You're not a mystery,
you little shit.
I know you.
You're mommy's boy.
You joined little league
so daddy could come to
see how tough you were,
but only he couldn't
make it to the game.
- Get him outta my
fuckin' face, man.
- James--
- No, no, no,
this is exactly what he needs.
Poor little Robert, never
good enough for daddy.
- All right, come on, guys.
- I am fucking sick
and tired of you
talking shit about my family.
What the fuck do you do?
Work your fuckin' yuppy job.
You got your shiny shoes
and you walk around
and spit shit in people's faces
just to see how they'll react.
You know what, you keep a
family together for 20 years
and then you find me
and we'll fucking talk
about little league then, okay?
Because as of now, you
don't know a fucking thing!
Okay?
- Let's go get in the truck.
- Hey, I don't need your help,
but thanks.
- All right.
- Lover's quarrel.
- Just keep on walking.
- What'd you say to me?
- Just keep walking.
- Fuck you, asshole.
Yeah, you'd probably
like that, wouldn't you?
- This is Dunlop, I'm
near that location.
Brighton?
- Yes.
Last
door on your right.
- Thank you.
I'll deal with you in a minute.
Good evening, Sergeant.
- Evening.
What is it now?
Major General?
Right, I
should be so unlucky.
- It's good to see you, John.
How long's it been?
How's Lori?
Oh you know Lori,
keeping me in line, still.
- Yeah, well somebody has to.
Sit down.
- So, give me an idea
of exactly what it is
I'm walking in to here.
- Oh, my fearless
deputy, Barney Fife,
he's making his rounds,
keeping the streets safe.
He goes past Frank's and
sees a fight going on
in the back entrance.
He steps in to break
it up and somehow,
catches one in the eye.
- Oh shit.
Was it from one of mine?
- Funny thing, no one's
really owned up to that.
- And this is the guy that
brought Montgomery in earlier?
Yeah.
It's funny, huh?
- Yeah, it's funny.
Has anyone pressed charges?
- Nah, best I can figure,
Solomon and his men
are trying to resolve some
differences amongst themselves.
Some civilians heading
out of Frank's,
they see it going on and--
And you
know how that goes.
- Yeah, that's how it went.
Could have been a lot worse.
But thank God Barney was
there to save the day
and since everyone is saying
someone else hit the officer,
nobody wants to
press any charges,
but my guy still got popped, so.
- So, here we are.
- Here we are.
You know, John, nobody
wants this to get messy.
I took care of everything.
If you ask me,
this is just what
those boys needed.
- Thank you, Ben.
- No problem, John.
You just bring those
guys back home safe.
I'll do my best.
I know you will.
Just don't bring 'em
back here tonight.
- Fair enough.
- Dunlap!
Dunlap!
- On your feet, let's go.
Montgomery, Whitmore,
wait outside.
Thank you.
'Cause I was way too
comfortable sleeping
in my living room with the
game droning in the background.
And Ben tells me this
isn't the first time
he's seen you guys tonight.
- Yeah, about--
- Do I even want to know?
- Well actually,
it's pretty funny.
No sir, you do not wanna know.
- Well you three are
pretty goddam lucky.
Now I gotta let Ben win
next time we play golf.
- Gives a whole new meaning
to support the troops.
- They at least hold their own?
- Yeah, yeah, I mean,
I knew Montgomery
was full of piss and vinegar,
but even Whitmore was
a little impressive.
Could have been
just what they needed.
- Yeah.
Too bad though.
- What?
- Shoulda called me earlier.
Would have loved
to have seen it.
I hear Marilyn
was there tonight.
Maybe you should go
by and see Marcus.
Might be a good thing
for all three of you.
- Yes sir.
- I'll talk to you tomorrow.
- Tomorrow, yes sir.
- Who's this?
- Remember that
woman at the bar?
This is her husband, Marcus.
He's my friend.
- What happened?
- Marcus and I,
we were attached to the
First Infantry Division.
You know, round up any POW's,
assist in transfers,
and uh, we were making
the push up to Um Kasar.
Tuesday morning.
Some of the most
amazing sunrises
and sunsets you'll ever see.
Nighttime is just stars from
one end of the sky to the other.
What a fuckin' waste.
So Marcus and I were called
up to the front of the line
and there's these two fuckers
sitting right in the
middle of the road.
I take one, he takes the other,
you don't think
about it beforehand,
you know, which one
you're gonna take,
you don't think about it before.
So Marcus is making his way up
and he's got a shotgun
and I got my sidearm.
There they are,
just sitting in the
middle of the road,
on their knees, they
got their arms up
and they're just
waiting for out.
So Marcus takes the
one on the right first
and he shoulders his weapon.
Just as he's leaning down,
this fucker reaches
up and grabs him
and Marcus is yelling and then
this fucker's yelling at him.
This other fucker,
he takes off, right,
so I'm yelling at him
to get on the ground
and then I look back at Marcus
and then I see it.
You know, this
asshole's got a grenade
and he does not plan
on being a detainee.
So Marcus, he's trying
to get a hold of him
and he sees the grenade
and he's got this
weird look on his face,
it's like he knows.
This is it.
And then,
limbs flying, blood,
there's lots of blood.
He hung on for about a
year and then I guess
he'd just had enough.
He died during
his 9th operation.
So every time I see
Marilyn, she gets a drink.
- What happened
to the other POW?
- I took him out.
There's two things they
never prepare you for,
everything else you
learn pretty quick
'cause if you don't,
you end up dead
or you end up like Marcus.
They never prepare
you for leaving
or coming home
or how to deal with feeling
guilty about coming home
and missing it.
Come on.
Thank you.
- Well, enjoy tomorrow.
We are officially
at D-Day, minus one.
You let me know if
you need anything.
Okay.
Well I'll see you
guys at formation.
- We got one more stop to make.
- What's up?
You know, I think
we've pretty much
used up all our
favors for tonight.
- Relax.
Come on.
Shit.
- You ever use one of
those for this before?
No, I can't
say that I have.
- It's pretty easy,
I don't think I gotta
give you any instructions.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- What the hell's going on?
- I didn't really think
you were gonna do it.
- You just told me to.
- And I was just checking.
Jesus Christ, okay.
- All right, all right.
I actually need your help.
You have used a
flashlight before, right?
- Is that right?
- All right, all right,
shine it right there.
All right, let's go.
- What?
Jesus, you really love
your coffee, don't you?
- Let's go!
* Even if you
don't remember us *
* You're everything I wanted
Hey.
- Hey.
- Hey David, you're in early.
- Wouldn't wanna miss the
favorite part of my day.
- Oh, how sweet.
- Yeah, isn't it?
- It's a tough one today.
- Who comes up with
these questions?
- Stumped?
- Everything's squared away,
so I can pick up right
where I left off.
- So where would you
like to eat tonight?
There's a nice little Mexican
place next to the hotel.
- Actually, I was planning
on doing something
with my friends tonight.
So we can eat early,
if that's okay?
You know, it's like
a surprise party,
but not really a surprise.
- Whatever you want.
- Is dad,
- Well he,
work has been very
busy with him lately.
I don't know, Robert.
- It's okay, mom.
- No, it isn't.
- I know.
- You know, you can
invite your friend, Jenny,
with us tonight.
I've never met her.
This Mexican place
oughta be pretty good.
They say that their Jalapenos
will make you sweat
in three seconds.
Daddy!
Hey kiddo,
how was your piano lesson?
- I got a dinosaur sticker.
- You did?
That's great!
- Honey, why don't you go
put your piano books away.
Okay.
- So what, you want me
to give you that list?
- I had that one coming.
- Well since you're here, there
are a couple other things.
There's a couple boards on
the deck that keep coming up.
- I can do that.
Are you sure?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
- Okay, I'm just gonna go
inside and check on Rachel.
- Okay, I'll finish up out here
and I'll get started
on those boards.
Okay, do you
want something to drink?
- No, no, I got coffee
in the truck, but thanks.
- Okay.
Or, you know, you
could stay for dinner.
I'm sure Rachel would love it.
- Yeah, yeah, it'd be nice
to have dinner with her.
Okay, I mean, it's just
lasagna, of course.
Her favorite.
- Sounds great.
Great.
* I can't remember
how I got here *
* I've got a hazy memory
* I need to rest
my aching head *
* On your pillow and blankets
* Maybe if I could fall asleep
* My love will come back to me
* This cannot be happening
* I'm losing you, losing
all our memories *
The same questions
that I get from my mother
every time I go home, oh man.
My mother's upset over the
fact that I am divorced.
Every time I go
home, same question,
when are you gonna
get married again?
When are you gonna
When ma, when?
When the pope has a
saint at the Ponderosa
on a Good Friday,
back off, all right?
* I need someone to comfort me
* The tears are
rolling off my cheeks *
* Maybe if I could
fall *
- Hey you, where you going?
- I have an exam tomorrow.
- Okay, I thought you would,
- Goodbye, Robert.
- Bye.
- Okay.
It is time for bed.
I mean it this time.
- Can't we watch one more?
- Rachel.
- Please?
- No, it's bedtime, come on.
- Yeah, listen to
your mom, kiddo, okay?
- But I wanna stay
down here with you.
- I know you do, but
it's time for bed
and plus, I'll see
you tomorrow, right?
- I guess.
- Well I don't guess.
I will see you tomorrow.
- Okay, love you, Daddy.
- Love you too, sweetheart.
- Are you leaving?
- Well yeah, I mean,
I just thought that,
Oh.
Yeah, okay.
David, what are
you so scared of?
Don't you think that I'm scared?
I am so scared for you.
I'm scared for her,
I'm scared for me.
I mean, what if you don't
come back this time?
You know what?
Just go.
God, how dare you.
God, how can you
go there and fight?
And we're right here.
David, I am right here
and you can't face this.
- I don't know how to--
Just leave.
- Look, I just--
- Just leave.
* I waited for our
house, our house *
* I've made it my, mine
* No speak, no sound, sound
* I've waited for hours
* But I'm not awake, I'm
not awake, I'm not awake *
* I must be dreaming
* I'm not awake, I'm not
awake, I'm not awake *
Major, we have
our troop movement orders
ready and available.
- All right, gentlemen,
let's have them
do their final goodbyes and
we'll do a final headcount
as we get on the bus to
head to the flight line.
- Roger that, sir.
Sir, the
vans are ready.
- Excellent, let's make
this happen, gentlemen.
- I picked up your
ring from the jewelers.
- You know what?
Keep it, I'll get
it when I come back.
- Take care of him.
- I'll do my best.
Call Jeannie if
you need anything.
See you in the van.
Private.
Robert.
- First Sergeant.
- Could be stuck in traffic.
- Yeah, probably.
- Listen,
- Mom.
Oh my boy.
- Oh mom, this is
First Sergeant Solomon.
First Sergeant, this is my mom.
- Please, David.
Pleasure to meet you, ma'am.
- Nice to meet you too, David.
You're gonna watch out
for my boy, aren't you?
- Yes ma'am, I'll do my best.
And you must be Mr. Montgomery?
- Yes.
- You should both be
very proud of your son.
- Yes, we are.
- I'll leave you to
say your goodbyes.
See you on the van.
- You let us know where we
can send you some real food.
I imagine you'll be sick
of those Army meals.
- Well I want to introduce
you to my sergeant.
- Daddy!
- Oh.
Oh hey kiddo.
I like your outfit.
Oh.
Thank you.
So when are
you coming back home?
- I don't know.
- I brought you this just
in case you get homesick.
- Did you make this?
It's the best thing I'm
gonna be taking with me.
- Are you scared, daddy?
- Yeah, a little bit.
I was when
I went to summer camp.
I wish you didn't have to go.
- Me too.
I love you, daddy.
- I love you too.
Thank you.
- You have to go.
- Mm, yeah.
I'm coming back.
We'll be here.
- Captain, first squad's
secured, ready to move out.
- Excellent job.
You ready?
- Let's do it.
- Let's go then.
- I gotta ask you something.
- What?
- What in the hell were we doing
at the coffee shop
the other night?
- Well, after they close,
they put the trivia up on the
board for the next morning.
They don't know how, but I
get it right every morning.
- And you're just leaving
without clearing your conscious?
- I'll tell her when I get back.
* Today I got the call
* That changes it all
* I need you to understand
* That I made a choice
to use my voice *
* And get up and take a stand
* For you
* If something happened to you
* I wouldn't be the
man who said I do *
* So I'll go for now
* Save my place until I return
* Inside I know, I
know it burns always *
* Know I'll be standing guard
* And watching from afar
* I'll keep you safe from harm
* Brothers in arms
* You were always there for me
* And if I come to call
* Your hero will fall, but I'll
leave you the memory always *
* If something happened to you
* I wouldn't be the
brother that you knew *
* So I must go for now
* Save my place until I return
* Inside I know, I
know it burns brother *
* Know I'll be standing guard
* And watching from afar