They see him? Even the humble mail train
at 6:45 a.m. he goes through this town without stopping.
Of course, this did not happen 50 years ago.
At that time, for an express
could be called luxury,
it necessarily had to stop at Fontecilla.
What has happened since then?
Why, as in so many towns in Spain,
the big expresses only stop when passing by here
a brief shaking in the pots in the cupboards?
And yet there are things that have not changed,
for example, the people of Fontecilla.
They are still waiting for the council to install the new sewer system.
The men still till the same piece of land.
And the women continue as always with their simple faith
asking for simple things from heaven.
Rain, for example.
What has changed then?
What could have happened to make the trains pass by?
The famous Fontecilla spa is simply no longer fashionable.
Nobody buys their postcards anymore,
nor drink its calcium-nitrogen waters
that cured everything.
Hear? The good people of Fontecilla are going to rejoice.
That rain they asked for has not been long in coming.
The harvest will be better.
Congratulations.
But it never rains to everyone's liking.
And clean water doesn't suit the old spa
that falls from the sky.
Yes, the spa is nothing more than a ruin.
And to restore the old prosperity, its owner,
Don Ramón, he's ready for anything.
Maybe to cheat with the law
and even worse. Much worse still.
Carmela! What is 11:00!
¡Carmela!
What is 11:00!
-How much force? Half or all? -Half.
Half! For four cats that are ...
Good Morning.
Luisito! Don't touch the palm tree, you can prick yourself!
-Good. -Remember that it causes tetanus.
-How shall I tell you? -How's the world going, Don Ramón?
Have you already reached the debut of Josefina Baker?
I'm still in October 17th. This European war is so long ...
How are those of the source of Health?
-A 1.50. -Child, don't touch!
What prices! How is your life!
Come on, write.
And without staining your fingers!
Dear parents...
But woman! Write now! How the best places take us
-Well, you'll see. -Do not worry!
They were still calling the waitress.
-Look at these! They are there! Didn't I say it? -We can still reach them.
- Down the hall! -Yeah, come on, come on.
Child, don't drag your feet!
Eugene! Eugenio, come on!
-Come on, I've taken a place for you. - Hurry.
-Its busy. -Oh yeah? Excuse me
-I put a signal! -Not that this was the train.
Postcards, postcards. And my bronchial tubes to get bored.
Silly stuff.
Good...
What do we do? Are we waiting for Dona Paquita?
Get started! Get started now!
Luisito, don't go near the waterfall!
Remember that the Romans made it.
Do you want to separate a little, not letting me breathe?
-Why don't you turn the horn away? -Come on, Carmela! Gymnastics!
One two.
One two. One two.
-Has it started long ago? -Do not worry.
-It's still on time. -Good...
One two. One,
two. One two.
One, two and three.
-One two. -(SHOUTS)
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
-Coming soon! To the doctor! -Not!
Not the doctor! Don Fidel.
To the priest, I'm dying.
-How? -So,
-Run! -Luisito!
The waterfalls do not touch!
Doña Paquita!
-Doña Paquita! -What's wrong with him?
That he is dying again.
He has made him dizzy and asks for a confession.
This lady! Dying every day!
-It will end up scaring the water users away. -The poor!
How she is so old and she never wants to admit it!
With that of spas to die at ease ...
Come here to make me Easter!
¿Central?
Central? Get me Don Evaristo right away.
Say it?
Great! You run to church
and notify Don Fidel. I take care of the rest. Right away.
What's up?
Yes Yes.
See you later!
Pedrito has a total of 24 apples.
Writes!
If he gives 12 to his mother and six to his little brother,
How many apples will Pedrito have left?
Stay in silence. Quiet!
(Horn)
Pay me the coffee!
That lady is a bore!
When something hurts, you already think you are dying.
-I'm just letting you know ... -Yes, I know.
At least last year he died in good weather.
With an archangel no one would be surprised.
They have appeared so many times ...
And the sword of fire, what? Do you think it is very easy to do it?
It doesn't have to be. Feeling is enough.
A little glitter and ... Leave me the technical details.
I already have it!
Let the archangel Don Ramón, who has studied fencing, do.
Don't you realize that it's outrageous?
What? Appear with a gun in hand.
People will be scared, man!
¡Oh, miren!
San Roque. What do you think?
Whoops! Great! Great!
It is done! Don Antonio and Sultan!
Neither Don Antonio nor Sultan. But...
You don't play with my dog! (MUG)
These must be the five martyrs of Prague.
Tortured in 112 under Diocletian.
Clear! Five, like you!
They appear in a group and that's it.
That, and halfway through the apparition,
we sing along for you to have fun. Very pretty.
So then...
so...
Man! San Isidro!
He looks like Don Salvador.
In addition, they say that he is a very miraculous saint.
A nephew of mine fell out of a tree and nothing happened to him.
Yeah, so what? Well that.
Nothing happened to him. Don Antonio can put the springs.
This of San Isidro seems to me a great nonsense.
They would believe that a farmer or someone from the town appeared.
So do you think that to be a saint you don't have to know anything?
If he is a farmer, because he is a farmer.
And if he is a warrior, because he is a warrior.
So there is no way to make appearances!
Don Antonio calls us.
Come on. What? What happens?
Look, I already found it. Oh yeah? Where?
In the choir. If there is nothing there.
Miren, miren. Miren.
See, who does this face remind you of?
Without the beard, huh?
Hey? Check it out, huh?
Is it him or is it not him? It is done!
It is true! Well of course!
Not! I do not! I do not want! No no no!
There was a man named Dimas.
And another called Gestas.
The two had committed theft
and they were crucified with Christ.
And it said Gestas, the bad thief ... Hey.
Aren't we getting into something too serious?
Look, I am Spanish. Catholic like the most!
Would it be calm if we were offending
to things of the ...?
Well, from the church? We dig too deep.
The consequences are interesting. Do you know what happened in Lourdes?
The miracle water killed the atheists.
And here who is going to know that it is a lie?
Only U.S. If we are careful ...
-Don't make that noise, man! -It's all rusty!
Also, he put that wire where it shouldn't.
Since when did two poles of the same sign join
is doing the wrong thing? Take a look.
(SHOUTING) We're lost!
They've already caught us!
- (SILENCE) - (WHISPER) They hide, they hide!
-Half strength or full strength? -Half! Half!
Be careful with Dona Paquita, don't go near the waterfall!
Well, we don't win for scares.
Fortunately, tourists will soon come to give us their money.
And what tourists! Tourists with scapular
willing to pay whatever it takes to see Don José appear.
Thousands and thousands! They will have to stay somewhere, eh, Don Ramón?
Cut your hair and shave.
You can sell that batch of rancid oil
that he has not been able to place anyone.
To Don José, as will San Dimas,
they will surely give you alms. How much?
Wasn't there a gold rush in California? This will be the fever of ...
of the miracle. Well I have fun
But I do not believe it. Why?
Because people will not return here even if we invent a movie miracle.
That is what I say. Don Evaristo is right.
The miracles in the cinema.
And what a favor we are going to do to religion with the birria de santo.
And so bad! I, at least, would not convert.
With this birria de santo, whoever I want converts.
If you are not interested, you go home in peace.
If I say it is for the impression at first sight,
but I think with the help of the azure blue,
we will be able to achieve top quality effects
And these records will help a lot.
Do I have the right to choose music?
By showing up, I think so.
Which do you prefer? I do not care!
It was to know.
Very good. There are other more important points.
For example...
For example, where will we do it?
Do I have the right to choose a site? Well, say where and we'll see.
Around the apple trees there is a very sheltered area.
Protest! That land is yours. And that?
He wants to take advantage to do the miracle.
Well, we don't go anywhere like that.
Let us form a commission to study the issue of the land.
It could be you two
and chaired by Don Ramón. Agree.
What is the second point? The most important.
The peseta has disappeared!
It has flown through the air! It has flown!
You believe me? I play a peseta and poof! It disappears.
But you are a very good boy.
The best in school. If you want, the peseta will return.
You have to ask the little angels. You want to?
So we do like this ...
(BLOWS)
(LAUGHS) Look! He's back!
Here I have the peseta, the peseta has returned!
- (LAUGHING) -Yes sir. Great!
Do you want me to disappear again?
Look. Look. Look.
¡Uy!
I rub against my elbow ...
The peseta is gone!
Look! Flying!
Oops, how it flies. I see her.
He's with the little angels!
Be careful, it falls from your neck, Don Salvador.
And this is the unhappiest kid in school?
Anyone make you believe that Don José ...
We will strengthen your trust in the supernatural
through chemistry. This will make a great impression on you.
Hala, you can go. No, no, no, kid.
You stay You and I are going to do a very good thing.
You will like it.
You see, when children are good, miracles can happen
and you have the face of being very good.
Take a good look and pay close attention. This is water
pure water.
Do you want it to become wine?
Me? No sir.
Not worth. You have to say yes.
(NODES) Yes.
So, say an Our Father.
If you pray an Our Father, God will do the miracle.
You, Reza.
Do as Don Evaristo says, Pepito. Come on
- (PRAY QUICKLY) -Amen.
Now I mix the water in the two glasses, take a good look,
and that's it, here is the wine.
But yes...
The point is that...
As it is not that the bisulfite is of national manufacture ...
I don't know what the hell ...
You haven't prayed devoutly enough, stupid!
Tomorrow you will write to me 200 times "I don't know how to pray the Lord's Prayer."
I can't pray the Lord's Prayer! Go away!
My terrain is better because it is higher.
But it does not pay contribution.
Very well, I will not pay a contribution, but on my farm there is no relevant.
When we enter mine
start to get cool? Clear!
Come on! As if the clouds when they pass over them say:
"Watch out! We are at Don José's farm!
We're going to hail elsewhere! "What nonsense!
It is not about hail, but about relente.
And the cold gives me a cough.
What would people say of a saint who cannot cure a cold
with so many years in heaven? What would be said of a saint
who appears in a farm that does not pay the contribution?
That is also true.
Look, behind the spa there is ... Man, very nice.
Now you want to take advantage of yourself. Don Salvador is there.
-What, Don Ramón? Was there an agreement? -No way!
Well, we can't find anyone. So, we are ready!
Anyway, it was a shame.
Where are you going? Wait. Still.
We could be one of us.
If I say that I saw San Dimas, they will believe me by force.
I am the official chronicler of the town.
Man, that takes an innocent soul and you ...
It seems to me that I have the solution!
Down at the halt, don't you see a man by the tracks?
We had all forgotten Mauro.
-Everybody! -Ah! It is true!
Mauro, from the station? But it is silly!
Yes, silly, silly, but maybe he recognizes me
Yes, poor Mauro.
Always expect a miracle.
And finally it will.
Does not wake up. Insist.
Yes I go.
Plus.
The brake is already released. Let's push.
Come on, come on.
It is done. Come on.
Yes.
We are already here.
Courage, don't worry. Everything will be fine.
Without leaving the tracks.
Come on, Don José.
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
Be careful not to drop it.
Hey, those cables can't go there.
Why? Because there is induction.
The electric field suffers.
To suffer. I have to hold them.
My electric field sabotages me.
If you fail me later, take the consequences.
Without leaving their grounds. Don't leave without this.
It's very important. Not the palm tree.
Pricking.
No palm tree, but go now.
Come on.
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
Nerd. You are going out.
I'm not the mayor for a reason. What if I get stung by a wound?
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
Still!
Without leaving the track.
Music.
Dammit. Right to the balcony.
(Music)
What do you think? Evil.
If we do everything this way, we will fail.
He's stepping on my cabbages.
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
And the others to annoy her.
You bastard!
Music.
(Music)
I am San Dimas.
The ancients called the good thief.
Oh, listen to you. Oh
Hear the word of blessed Dimas.
Since you were the chosen one
by divine mercy.
(SHOUTS)
By divine mercy ...
You have forgotten everything.
I will help you. Well, well.
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
That ... this ...
Listen you. Listen you. Listen you.
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
But who has done that savagery?
Don José does not know a word.
Listen to me, Mauro, I'm Dimas.
It is that nothing is seen.
But I tell you that man is not alone in this uncertain hour
and dark. My will ... my will ... I don't hear.
What does it say? In this day.
In this day. Yes Yes.
Oh, on this day.
You and those who receive my testimony
fulfill the mandate of San Dimas.
First of all, you should go ... I'll agree to appear.
Yes, come, brother, everyone.
How does it end, man?
Spaniards and foreigners, come and trust.
Consuming the miracle water
of the Fontecilla hot springs will be cured
all your ills and alleviated all your misfortunes.
This has been my mandate. Bear witness to him.
(SCREAMS) Miracle, miracle!
All wake up, listen to me!
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
- (THEY TALK AT THE TIME) -Me, me!
Wake up all of you and hear me. It will come every Thursday.
He wears a crown and stars are falling. Don't you want to believe me?
We have to go pray there. I'm going to tell everyone.
(Bells)
-You've gone mad? -San Dimas.
I have seen San Dimas. You have to make a sanctuary.
He has told me to tell everyone so they can see him too.
That's silly! Get out of here!
It will come every Thursday. She wears a cloak and a talking palm tree.
-And the music plays. -On the street.
So what do priests believe in?
-San Dimas will punish him! -On the street!
I don't want drunk people here.
It was true, it was true. I have seen him.
I was San Dimas and I have seen him.
-He will punish them all. -You're drunk.
-Yes to everyone. -Go to sleep.
He has told me, he has told me that he is coming back.
Hear me Come with me to pray.
-Idiot! -He will punish them all.
They ignore him.
Never mind. We will insist.
Otherwise he saw this San Dimas and got drunk,
-But if you don't drink. -It could have been something.
-Anything but a miracle. -Why don't you take it out?
It is not good to have him in this corner.
It is true. We had forgotten it.
Look, here, next to Saint Nicholas.
No, no, it takes away your sight.
We can leave you by the door. It is where it has always been.
And now with what happened to Mauro, maybe he got bad votes.
Don't talk to me about Mauro. Here, which is seen from the entire church.
As he is the good thief, perhaps he turns the one who always steals.
Then we cover the table with some curtains
and a bedspread and we have the base ready.
At least with this we remember San Dimas.
And to me that this is a familiar face.
Why am I going out if Mauro already knows the message?
Today he will perform for Mauro and for someone else. Take a look.
Here is the poor man. Here it is, here it is.
Let's sit.
Give me your chair.
Your halo, Don José.
Total, for two old women.
Couldn't we just skip this Thursday? You promised to show up today
and it appears or I break it ... But, man, today I have a phlegm.
That's nothing, if you saw me in the morning as I wake up.
Okay, I'm going out, but not talking, huh?
That then we start with the sanctuary ...
Don't be silly, man. Don't you see that something needs to be said?
But can't we mail it?
Be careful, someone is coming.
Ah, he's a drunkard.
Matías. Matías the bailiff.
Ah, now, there are four. Sorry, five.
Counting me? No, telling me.
and as I am the chronicler of the town, no one will be surprised
behold the miracle.
Clear. See you later, gentlemen.
By order of the mayor,
it is made known that San Dimas is going to appear.
Praise the Lord.
His holy will always be done.
I don't want to die now after seeing you
and understand how much we have left to do as good Christians
here in the earth.
Yes, of course, of course, but you don't die,
you will bury us all, dona Paquita.
I wish that way I would have time to organize
the most holy arch-brotherhood of San Dimas
and the miracle water, as he personally requested.
-Yes, sure, sure. -You know, Don Fidel?
There is the turn of the pharmacy.
They are almost 15 hard.
Take them for the cult of San Dimas.
I take them for the poor.
For the record, accepting them does not mean that I approve
what you call a miracle.
Oh, Don Fidel, how do you know that you were not up there last night?
Ask Carmela.
Carmela saw the end nothing more.
-Well, yes, he would learn a lot. -The poor.
What country do we live in? If this water were miraculous,
Wouldn't we know? That we have been drinking it since the Romans.
It will be necessary to drink it entrusting to San Dimas, I say.
Well, entrust yourself to San Dimas, drink it, and see what happens.
But I'm just saying ...
Come on, this water is carbonated, calcicalnitrogenated,
And now also miraculous, do you see?
In my spa and miraculous.
What, Carmela? How about?
Yes, sir, and if you now put a golden ornament on it ...
Oh, a little gold ornament.
Come on, how good. Did I say put it on, Don Ramón?
But in a provincial capital,
Who is in the same printers as in Madrid?
A little golden ornament, what nonsense.
Here, take it away.
And remember that they only change the "mineromedicinal de Fontecilla"
by "miraculous of San Dimas". When do you want them?
On Thursday I plan to put a place where the miracle, so calculate.
What do I ask, 250 or do you think 500 is better?
Don't bother, at least 3000. Sounds like a lot to me.
Well, order them, and if there is any excess, for next Thursday and in peace.
-Do you understand? -That's also true.
A truth that I have seen with these eyes,
with the same eyes that see Silvestre now,
put your finger in the inkwell and paint the neck of the one in front.
Boys, Fontecilla was chosen by good San Dimas,
who loves them so much,
to bear witness to a true miracle.
A very beautiful and very great miracle.
As big as your children's hearts.
Vizcaíno, give you a slap.
So tell your families that on Thursday you should bring candles.
Izarbe, what should you bring on Thursday?
Candles, many candles.
15 or 20 packages.
You send them to me by the first mail.
Hey? But still don't know there?
Wait, wait a minute.
Concha, explain to this man about the miracle, I'm going to the town hall.
But, Antonio, for God's sake, by conference.
Two pesetas every three minutes.
But do you want to stop thinking about money?
You see, they say San Dimas showed up.
Several people have seen it last time.
Some ladies who take the waters in the spa.
-The teacher has also seen it. -I've seen it.
And do you believe me or do you not believe me?
If you believe me, well, but if you don't believe me, damn it,
I mark the nut to my father.
But he calculates that it was the invention of the priests
to get us the rooms. Well, I don't know them.
But have I not told you a hundred times that it appeared in the air?
Here in Spain you are so stupid that until you break your nose,
do not create a firewood.
Hey, Matías, who are you calling for?
It's very important.
Read it right away. All right, Don Antonio, to send.
By order of the mayor,
It is made known that by making sure with neighbors of this village
has agreed with Don Antonio Guajardo
the rental of your van, which will leave every half hour,
Who is the city council to get where they are not called?
Well, you tell him that while the Church does not recognize the miracle,
who wants to see San Dimas, go by bicycle.
I'll tell Don Antonio, you'll see how he suspends the truck.
Hey, hey, wait.
We have to talk you and me. I cannot consent to what they do.
Don Fidel, calm down, don't you see that everyone wants to go?
Look, don't fool me.
They are pushing people onto dangerous ground.
Very comfortable, to say that it is not very comfortable.
And what do you want me to do?
What does the canonization of Mauro and doña Paquita ask for?
No, sir, but at least you go.
Have the curiosity of the National Magisterium,
that he is also catholic.
It is very easy to close your eyes and say that nothing has been seen.
Well, we will see that of San Dimas, of course we will.
You have to see the game that the scoundrel Don Antonio gets out of him.
Instead you, stunned, you prefer your little games
instead of coming to thank him for showing up on your grounds.
For the last time, are you coming or not? Do not force me.
I don't want to know anything about a miracle
which does not yet have ecclesiastical approval.
Okay, then I'll go alone, like always.
Don José, it's us, come down.
Nothing, no answer. What does not answer?
Will something happen to him? I dont know.
Hello, Dona Margarita, at your feet.
Your husband ... My husband is not up for games.
It is not for miracles, then it is not for little games.
Yes, sure, good night, ma'am.
Let's go? Let's go.
Ay, ay.
So bad. Come on, Don José.
Nerd!
No, no, I'm not going, ay.
Ok, I'm going the same. So bad...
Give me a glass.
Thank you.
The same, the same.
Yes, the same, but two pesetas more expensive.
-A fraud. -Amazing.
Luisito, the needles of the stations do not touch!
Remember the Titanic.
-Goodnight. -Goodnight.
What a few hours to come.
You're late, huh?
Don Eugenio, tell them to put you a glass.
-This water looks like another. -And total, for two more pesetas.
You, baby, baby.
-What a difference. -Yeah sure.
Hey, why don't you hang on for a bit? Now it is OK.
I am the coach.
Do you hear? That sounds like San Dimas is coming.
What goes, is the goods, which brings delay.
The gramophone, but who has left it on the road?
I don't show up without music.
But if the band is there ... But also Don Fidel,
What can you ask me about things from heaven?
and say what San Nicasio does.
And what do I know who San Nicasio is? Well, I didn't answer him.
It comes from heaven, it doesn't have to.
But a poor fool can be fooled.
Now, I don't know if 300 people ... 300 people and a priest.
And who has given you permission to come here with that candle? Come on
Get out.
Well, it seems that this Don Dimas
Railroad customs have caught on a bit.
You don't know what punctuality is.
Three minutes past 00:00 and three minutes are nothing.
As much as nothing, haven't you ever put on a lecture?
Very funny, very funny joke.
We'll see who laughs at the end.
Come on, get out of here. Come here, boy.
I don't go out, huh? What do you mean not?
If you want there to be a miracle, you do it.
You dress as any saint and say:
"San Dimas cannot come, he has a lot to do."
That is an informality. Whatever I want, but I don't go out.
Are you sure that cable goes there?
Do I get into the fuse that you put on your rockets?
Don't you understand that there will be a short circuit when you plug in?
If you keep nagging me, I put down the projector.
Ah, very good, there you, but that cable is bad.
Please...
Wow, a very timely blackout.
Timely.
He has melted down the entire village facility.
Let's see what we do now. Sure, you have maddened me.
Let me give you a sign so you don't get nervous.
What do we do if the light doesn't come? They will give it right away.
In the transformer there is a guard.
Do you hear it? They are impatient.
The best thing is to get out, Don José.
Why do you turn off the flashlight? It must be from the stack.
With the rockets there will be plenty of lighting.
Mr Jose. Mr Jose!
Does not hear me? Mr Jose!
Hey, Don José.
Where has he been? I think it's gone.
Wait, it looks like I caught it. And I also.
Good evening, Don Salvador. Goodnight.
Come on, kids.
Gee, how soon you got tired of waiting.
Children, poor children, have to sleep.
Of course, of course.
Luisito.
A well-behaved child should not play with insects.
Remember that they transmit diseases.
How will this child be told to be still where he is sent?
When I was a child, I would keep quiet if they gave me a book.
How many times have I read "Corazón" by di Amicis?
Arturo, if you don't take care of your grandson, misfortune may happen.
I'm going, I'm going right away.
He dies in the Battle of Jutland, I'm sure.
He is going to tell me that I have read the story of Blasco Ibáñez.
It was the year the Austro-Hungarian Empire was lost.
-Arthur! -I go.
If you had made the connections right.
You are getting heavy.
It wasn't me who took advantage of the blackout to defect.
Well said, very well said.
If I had held the guy
we would not play now perrachica la bean.
What if we tried again today? Is Thursday.
Your aunt will show up, not me.
Auction it because it doesn't have a nickel left there.
Is there no one who will leave me a couple of dollars?
I'll give them back to you right away. Yeah huh
With the work that it has cost me to earn them.
With the money he owes Don Manuel and all of us.
You owe me $ 50 in penicillin alone.
Those are old debts.
The game is the game
and what is gained by playing should not be given to anyone.
The descending one at 3:40 p.m.
What informality. Why?
Because it's exactly 3:40 p.m.
¡Eh, corran!
Fuck him, he's in the wagon!
Stop it, it's my house!
Hey, stop it, it's my house!
Stop it!
Sorry, friend, but the houses should not be on the road.
You will have to find it for me.
You have released the brake.
It's many miles downhill.
and the great station, and many tracks.
It will be lost, they will never find it.
I don't have a home either.
You have escaped from the guards. They were taking him to jail, I know.
Hey, listen ...! Shut up, shut up.
Don't yell like that, no one can hear you.
Nobody, do you think nobody.
I have a friend who listens to us because he works miracles.
Are you a friend of God?
We are all friends of God. You less, of course, but no.
It is not God.
Do you want to know my friend's name?
It is called San Dimas. San Dimas?
Hey, San Dimas, I'm Mauro! Don't shout so much, it's not necessary
the saints have good ears.
I have seen many people praying and they could not be heard within two steps.
Santo San Dimas santo, hear me.
Here I am with the man, my house is gone. And the guards.
Santo San Dimas, listen to me, there is a man ...
there is a man who lived in jail.
Get him back there.
I'm Mauro, Mauro.
Surely San Dimas will be mad at you if you ask him to pursue me.
Don't forget that before he was a saint, he was a thief.
If instead of denouncing me, you would lend me your help, he would be happy.
Do you understand And it is even probable that one day he will return to Fontecilla.
Who told you that it was already? Where I was, everything is known.
But tell me, what did San Dimas look like?
Very old man, he coughed many times.
One night I was about to give him my cimarra.
Oh yeah?
You know? I like Fontecilla, yes,
but not his living forces.
(Reception bell)
So much fun, huh?
There was no one. What do you do when no one is there?
The bell is rung. What the hell do you want?
A room,
but I do not like.
What? Everything, everything smells dirty.
Yes, we will have to clean a little, air it, let the sun come in,
the papers are damp.
The paintings look like national awards for Fine Arts.
Plants do not have the slightest dose of chlorophyll.
And the furniture?
The furniture is very uncomfortable. And the pension 80 pesetas per person
entitled to water from the source of health. It's convenient?
It suits me if the right to contemplate the miracle is included.
How do you say? Is there no miracle? What a pity.
Thus there is no way for the spa to increase its clientele.
Please tell me your name?
Ah yes, put Martino.
I can't enroll you like this.
Yes you can.
Don't you know that there are provisions that ...?
Forget them. Firm.
Okay, I can hardly move my hand.
Whoever never wore them cannot imagine the damage
that make tight-fitting handcuffs
You? But you...
I am a good thief who has been attracted by the miracle.
Take. Well.
I'll go upstairs to clean up a bit. I've been on a long journey
and it shows.
See you later.
Well done.
And now I'll give you a cinchona friction and served.
But very badly served. Hey?
Do you think this is a haircut?
Look, these curls are unmatched, and what sideburns.
This cannot be left like that, I will protest.
I will have the government take action on this matter immediately.
Luckily, everything in life has an arrangement.
Where did you find that wig? Nerd,
If you guess, I'll give it back to you. But if it's not mine
if I have never needed ...
As you will see, nothing favors me.
And maybe you know a saint who needs it.
Goodbye.
Look, take a good look at this hat and what's underneath.
We mean the price tag.
For these models, we hope they will shine during the summer,
even if husbands have to work overtime in winter.
Elche, the beautiful Levantine city, surrounded by palm trees,
performs a representation of its wonderful mystery.
Between the first and second act of the sacroliric drama.
The image of the Virgin ... He has dropped something.
This.
Be careful with tunnels, things are lost and not found.
Let's see, open your mouth wide.
I don't see anything, my tonsils are normal.
I do not explain those inconveniences.
What annoyances? What annoyances?
Didn't you say your ears were ringing and your throat hurt?
Something must be said when you go to the doctor.
You are an artist handling light.
You should teach me.
What is this? A joke?
No, doctor, a miracle, a miracle of science.
Ah, the electricity.
However, care must be taken with the connections
because if you are not careful with the connections, goodbye miracle.
Hey? Who's there?
Who is the idiot who scares me rabbits?
Does not answer?
Who the hell scares me hunting? Come in, have a seat.
The lands are mine, and the rabbit was also mine.
So I guess being inside your property,
I must also belong to him, right?
Want to see how I still shoot you?
I prefer to teach him to kill rabbits. You have no idea.
What does? Damn, the shotgun is mine.
He takes the shotgun
leans on the shoulder, like this.
It points anywhere
and hours and hours are expected
until something comes into focus.
An abandoned wagon
a poor madman
or maybe better, a tunnel.
It aims well and ...
A gluttonous man would say it is a donut.
A folkloric, a Cordovan hat seen from above.
A geometrician would simply see two concentric circles.
And a fearful ...
What would a fearful person say, Don José?
Do not come to me with stories, that guy knows everything.
That guy doesn't know anything.
It has been shown that appearance is one thing and reality is another.
And the reality is that nobody can be aware
of our activities.
Unless...
Unless there has been a betrayal,
Dare you suggest that I may be a traitor?
I did not say you.
I have said any one. It is true,
one of you has told him everything.
How one of you? It can be you
or it could be you, or it could be ... no, not me.
I was at the movies, I had never seen it.
Why don't they ask Don Ramón?
Who spoke to him first. Oh yeah?
I am as honored as the first and more than you.
On top of that he insults me, I really can't stand it.
Be careful, I'm going to lose patience.
And why didn't Don Antonio do it? Because it is enough to be mayor.
Enough, silence!
Silence!
Arguing like this for nonsense.
Do you call it nonsense that they come to blackmail us?
I call it foolish to be afraid of that man.
If he knew anything about our matter, he would have talked to me too.
He has been in Fontecilla for three days
and he still hasn't done anything to see me. Sorry.
He came to see if there are night classes in this school.
I would like to learn the life of the saints well.
Dammit.
Shut up, demon.
Let's see, let's see.
Most Illustrious Lord, the quail ban will be lifted.
Don Antonio, how timely.
Don't yell so loud, the sergeant will wake up.
Watch out, I've put a sleeping pill in the seals you take for rheumatism.
Hold on, the neighbors ...
and Mr. Antonio Guajardo Fontana will pay 500 pesetas of fine
for violation of the Water Law.
Damn it, let them do this job to me, the mayor.
It is that in Spain you cannot live. There is nothing here.
It has to be on the table or in one of the drawers.
Yes, but they sure are closed.
Well, let's see, let's see.
Didn't I say it? These guards don't trust anyone.
But Don Antonio, don't be foolish, this can cost us dearly.
Lost to the river.
Leave me, and if I break it, the better.
Let them bother.
Here it is.
Alum.
He is wanted for alleged perpetrator of robbery with fractured drawers
at the Civil Guard Command.
Atiza, like ours.
Yes, go on.
The Chilean.
Here's one without a photo.
Rafael Villena alias El Señorito, habitual offender
against property ... What else?
84 years. No, this is not it. No no no.
Zamora, Zamorano ... There is a piece of paper.
Let's see.
Recipe to polish patent leather.
This must be something unique to Sgt.
There should be something earlier. Ramos told us he had the mark
of handcuffs. Let's search calmly.
Maybe there is another file here.
Hi.
You again. What does she want?
Here is the tab.
Give it to me. I'm sorry, but it's mine.
Give it to me. No, let's leave these things
in the hands of the Civil Guard. Token borrowed, token forgotten.
But man, that's just to check it out.
Nerd. You see, I am going to propose you a very interesting riddle.
You must speak first. Say, what am I?
Well, I don't know ... Don't be afraid.
Say, for example, murderer. Nerd.
Come on, say it without fear, tell me.
Nerd. Say: "Murderer".
Assassin. Fatal error
that it can cost you dearly to call me a murderer.
Don Antonio, what comes to mind? I cannot consent to this.
You will have to consent, it amuses me. It's me?
Currency counterfeiter, drug dealer?
Blackmailer?
Pass, pass.
Now we go up, let's show you this.
C'mon C'mon.
Hurry up
Hurry up.
-Come, come. -Come on.
Wait a minute. What do you think?
I like it, but don't think you have bought my silence.
Is living in the royal suite not enough for you?
A place for princes, for dancers.
Or for thieves.
At this table I always want a bottle of Fontecilla water.
Why? I am interested in its healing virtues.
Well okay. I could make a few changes
in this room.
It would be much more comfortable.
Look. What happens?
I would like this mirror more tilted forward.
What difference does it make? Is to see them
while playing cards.
It is convenient for them to feel observed. You get better when you know they are looking at you.
Should we also entertain him? I want joy, some music.
Is there a piano in this hotel? Yes there is: that one.
Magnificent! We are going to organize a party.
How about a play with the guests of the spa?
Before they represented one between months, but now they are so few and old ...
That they will no longer remember anything.
I already have it!
We will rehearse the life of San Dimas. Doña Paquita will come out on her knees.
But who will play the saint? That's the problem.
I will be in charge of presenting the show.
As an aperitif, little magic numbers.
And, as the end of the party, something serious as they like it. Look, have this.
Nothing in this hand, nothing in the other.
And now ... One, two.
One two.
Attention! The great Martino is going to surprise them and perhaps himself
with the appearance of an unexpected object.
Man! A tablet of soap.
That means it's bath time.
Half force or full force? All, 70 degrees at least.
-Did you not want comfort? Take comfort. -Blackmail me, I'm the mayor!
-Almost reached the top. -Well, hold on for a little while.
You cannot hear him protest. What if we really cooked it?
No, the human body resists to incredible lengths.
I remember the case of a tax inspector who once ...
Hey? What?
Are you comfortable?
That the water is ice cold?
Wait I'm going to give you a candle!
What? Are we getting warm?
We are entering unknown seas and you are my boatman.
What funny things he comes up with ...
This...
It was a joke. It was indeed.
I like jokes, happy people.
Impossible. Impossible. But it is.
The cabin has no other exit and we have seen him enter.
They saw me get into that one
But I made them believe I was coming in here
Answer quickly: who killed Cain? Abel. What nonsense, it is the opposite.
Sees it? I can make them think backwards for a while.
Hypnotism? Who knows.
Whatever it is, I don't believe in those things.
Raise your left hand. There, what's up?
-The left has told him. -And what am I doing?
-That's the right one. -Do you take me for a fool?
-It's the right. -The left, a lifetime.
No, you are confused. It has hypnotized you.
What is going to hypnotize me? It's the left!
While they come to an agreement, I'm going to get dressed.
Come in half an hour to the royal suite.
We will discuss literature, music
and even miracles if you like.
Ah, Dona Paquita!
At a hundred degrees it will start to burn, take it out as soon as possible.
Doña Paquita!
A wonderful bathroom, I am like new.
Left ... I'm already crazy.
Come on, come on! Shoot, dare.
Well!
Bravo! That awful.
It is inconceivable.
This trick always excites you.
I have seen the best specialists do it,
some were killed by the bullet.
But in full action?
Sure, in rehearsals it always works out.
Do you want to know another trick? Which one?
Get a public official
creates, for example, silkworm, tape measure
or storm over a forest.
Make me believe that I have the left hand
where right, still.
But to feel what one is not ... It is a bit strong.
Now we will see, but for the record, I did not come to amuse you.
Is there no one who wishes to feel like an ice skater, Viscount
or academic of Fine Arts?
This...
(LAUGHS) None?
There is only one thing to convince us. What is it?
May Don José return the money he owes us.
That, that. I will do more:
I'll make you the first philanthropist
of Fontecilla. What is a philanthropist?
Philanthropist is to be generous, charitable ...
Don't care about money. Nerd!
I don't want to be a philanthropist! Let go of me!
Let go of me! I don't want to be a philanthropist!
I'd rather be an ice skater or one of those fine arts!
Never! My money! You have to please your friends.
We're aiming.
Come.
Look at me No I can not. I can not.
Don't you want to look at this beautiful bright
200 carats?
It can be up to you.
Very pretty. It's not pretty, it's repulsive.
It's gross. Money is also disgusting.
The money, what crap.
He is now giving away ten thousand pesetas for parish works.
The church needs a new bell.
The casino, a pool table. Mauro, some pants.
And Don Manuel, the 20 duros that I owe him.
And to me the 50 of the penicillin. Yes bye.
I'm going to get more money from my wife.
(LAUGHS) This is easy.
Much more than the appearance of a saint
in an abandoned station.
We are simple amateurs, you do ...
Listen, we're going to do something important.
You put faith in San Dimas and I put everything else.
When I saw you in the tunnel I understood that if I joined you
We could overcome their flaws and mine, of course.
You saw us, that explains everything.
Yes, I saw them.
Other people saw them too, but no one was interested
both the matter and me.
You talked about joining us.
That means a lot. It means that it's okay
of playing blackmail and that San Dimas returns to Fontecilla.
Don't count on me. I count on your amazement
you will be surprised by everything that happens.
You will write chronicles, you will contribute the miraculous water,
you land and you will listen to all the look for the miracle.
There will be very serious lung problems, heart problems,
An Our Father to Saint Dimas can do wonders.
Oh great. San Dimas returns.
Now no one will last from him, but ...
Who will dress up as a saint?
Don José does not want to. And matters?
The apparitions must be authentic.
Actually San Dimas is not going back to Fontecilla.
The miracles return. Or they start. But how?
Very easy. With the mystery of a single word.
Some call it faith.
Don Evaristo, recreational physicist. And me...
Someday I'll tell you who is right.
So what is the first prodigy going to be?
It can be for example ...
Ah! Carmela's ear. This may be the symbol of your deafness.
Can you hear me now, Carmela? Naturally, sir.
Let's pray.
(SPEAKS IN ANOTHER LANGUAGE)
Well, well.
-Wait. -Let me.
Hey, Don Manuel! How did it go? Were there faints?
Was any sinner converted? Are you going to organize the processions?
It was awesome. As it did?
Playing my head at a height of more than 40 meters.
And the light was a projector? No, a simple mirror.
That? Yes. Look at the people.
It's true, she's upset.
Although rabie Don Evaristo, you got some effects
that he already wanted.
We are both amateurs. There are those who do it even better.
Look what a beautiful morning! Everything is perfect.
With details that are very difficult to achieve like this breeze from the southwest.
Tell me, don't you feel a sense of well-being?
What I notice is that I am getting a cold.
Your town is beautiful from above.
But it is getting too late.
Remember that they are waiting for us at the spa.
Did you know that there are 32 acacias in the municipality?
You said miracles started at 11:45.
I'm not in a rush yet. Look down there in the river.
There is a nice backwater. Some bathe, others fish,
others walk.
Sometimes I think that the greatest miracle is that everything works this way.
With such simplicity. Yes, yes, check it out.
Everything is in place.
Sounds easy to you?
Well come on, try yourself.
(LAUGHS) Try.
But it's almost 12 o'clock! You have nothing prepared yet.
It is the same, I am an artist
and artists we like improvisation.
I am a priest and we do not like to be miracle workers because if we were
calculate the skids we would hit.
But if everyone saw it. It was something supernatural.
A window that opens suddenly, a ray of sunlight, natural things.
Doña Paquita is dying and I have given her only half strength!
Gentlemen, this time, it really is.
Don Ramón, I'm sorry to tell you that room 18
-He will also be free. -Stop the stupid jokes.
They are not joking, he is dying. And nothing can be done?
Any American medicine? I would pay whatever it was.
Not America, nothing. If you want to spend the money on Doña Paquita,
-Buy her a flower crown. -Poor woman!
Fortunately it is already 00:00, the time to start the prodigies.
Do you want to try it with Dona Paquita?
-Very good. -In the case of a heart attack
nothing less, all you do is waste time.
Don't believe it. I listened.
You don't hear anything, do you? Not.
And yet you see, I am fully alive.
My medicine, and everyone's, is light.
Give me a tape, Don Evaristo. Yes.
What are you going to do? San Dimas is already illuminated,
now it only remains to illuminate the water.
We will direct a beam of direct suggestion on the source
from which all must drink to produce a reflection.
From this moment the waters of Fontecilla are miraculous.
That is, they can already cure diseases.
But what diseases? If apart from Dona Paquita ...
How is it that there are no sick people?
You cannot consent.
You, to bed right now with a colic in the gallbladder.
Me? If I...
But if the gallbladder was removed for two years
Before the war.
Don Salvador is prone. Hey?
Take care of the symptoms tonight: numbness and pain.
Don't worry, the colic will be a hit. Well.
I would like a patient with appendicitis. Let's see...
You? No I do not.
Don Manuel is indeed pale. Look, look!
It doesn't matter who it is as long as it is healed by spirit.
The spirit is thirsty and there is its water.
Look out!
But don't cover the beam. And let's see what happens with Dona Eva.
Luisito, don't go near the lake where you've had a banana!
Well, you can get closer.
But without putting your hand in the water!
(LAUGHS) How funny. Get in the water!
A well-mannered child does whatever he wants.
Don Fidel! Hey, Don Fidel!
Don Fidel! Come up, Don Fidel!
This water is miraculous, it has saved my life! Drink a little!
Don Joaquín Sapena. Me?
Acérquese.
Here.
Children,
by allowing you to attend
to my last moments, I'm giving you the best lesson
theoretical-practical on the transience of life.
Rodriguez, don't put your finger up your nose! I give you a slap ...!
(TIRITA)
Children,
you are going to witness
the death of a man who gave everything for teaching.
And in the absence of manuals on the matter,
transforms into waxed
his funeral bed.
(TIRITA)
You are the first of the class, touch my forehead. Do not be afraid.
Touch and calculate my fever in degrees centigrade.
Calculate!
I don't notice any heat.
Sapena, you are the first of the class.
I slap you like that!
You must know that my fever is very high!
What temperature do I have?
I dont know. (BAND AID)
39'5.
-This is getting alarming! -Yes?
Yes, very alarming!
Do not be scared that he had it prepared.
Anyway, the symptoms are obvious.
I have never come across a case as clear cut as this.
- Do you think it's something serious? - It could be.
For now, do not move. Absolute immobility.
And don't forget to put ice packs on your abdominal region.
"Let's see, Don Manuel!" -Yes, my back hurts.
-I think I have pneumonia. -You have appendicitis.
-Appendicitis. -Not.
What I have is pneumonia, I'm sure.
But man, remember: Don Salvador, typhoid fever
and you, appendicitis.
509, 510, 511, 512, 513...
Listen! Don't you think a lot of bottles?
In the last ten years he had not sold even half.
You must have a liter of water ready for each man in this world.
A cursory estimate gives us about two billion.
Couldn't we just leave the Chinese? No, no, the Chinese
they also have a right to the wonderful.
Will it not be necessary to encourage people with prizes on the cap?
A floor, a sewing machine, something like that.
It's not a bad idea.
This water tastes so bad that no one will drink it
If we only promise miracles Does it taste so bad?
But haven't you tried it? Me? In my life, what for?
Try it, it's only fair. She has to suffer like everyone else.
Yuck! What crap!
We have redressed a reprehensible lack of professional ethics. What time is it?
2:45 p.m., the Maldonados have just arrived at the pavilion.
And our first bottles are reaching their goal.
Above all with devotion, with a lot of devotion
and slowly, in small sips.
An Our Father to Saint Dimas.
Our father who art in Heaven.
Yes, go on, pray to San Dimas.
In this of miracles we have jinx.
Now he goes back and forth with double pneumonia.
If you need to buy something ... I've put camphor oil in it.
Doña Paquita was cured yesterday with the water.
Listen, for pneumococcus there is nothing but penicillin.
Hail Mary, you are full of grace.
The Lord is with you.
Blessed you are.
I signal him to finish drinking the water.
I can not think of anything else. And what good is that?
If I knew anything about medicine, I wouldn't say such nonsense.
Now and at the hour of our death.
Glory to the Father, glory to the Son.
Glory to the Holy Spirit.
What are you doing here?
But ... is it possible?
Is that I...
Perhaps...?
What happened? Why are they looking at me like that?
-This is inexplicable. -Water!
It was the water! The water of San Dimas!
Miracle! Miracle!
San Dimas wanted me to be the one to bring water to those who suffer.
Where are there sick people?
All must be cured!
Don Salvador who is dying! You have typhoid fever.
This is called a fever.
It usually accompanies all infectious processes.
(TIRITA)
And when it reaches, as in my case,
figures above 40 degrees
means danger of death.
José Rodríguez Lapuente! Please repeat me
everything you just heard about fever.
Fever
it is a heat that enters
when one is dying.
All on your knees!
Don Salvador.
Will there be a glass around here?
Oh yeah.
Drink you, drink slowly
and pray to each sip with me.
It is the water of San Dimas! Give me!
I feel very bad!
But I think.
I think! And I entrust myself with all the powers of my soul
to the sweet and pious Saint Dimas.
Very well, and now we are going to pray the litanies of Saint Dimas.
-Glorious Saint Dimas. -Glorious Saint Dimas.
Glorious Saint Dimas.
All that we entrust to you.
-Let's regain health. -Let's regain health.
-So from the soul. -So from the soul.
-Like the body. -Like the body.
And bring peace to hearts ...
So of the body, as of the soul.
Miracle!
This water does not belong to you. It's from San Dimas!
-And nobody does business with him. -But if half goes to taxes,
also you can take the one you want.
No, he charges me what he charges others.
Here, mine and the children, I invite them.
But by God, Dona Paquita!
Hey, hey!
-Hey, you, the peseta. -I don't have.
Well, you'll give it to me, you owe it to me.
What's wrong with you, you don't believe in San Dimas?
Yes we believe, sir, we believe. What happens is that ...
Don't be ashamed to say it. What happens is that we have no money.
You neither? No sir.
We have none. Wait.
Do you know that water goes under the ground?
Like a river that cannot be seen? That's.
I am like an engineer, a water engineer
and I'll tell you where that spring comes from.
San Dimas appeared at the station.
And there is a chute on the platform for the locomotives.
¡San Dimas¡ ¡San Dimas! San Dimas!
-I have seen San Dimas. -Drink this water,
-It's for the miracle. -Well, he would have told me.
-I heard the engineer say it. -Well, ask.
Ask for it, come on!
Help me, San Dimas!
Pipo! Pipo, come here! Don't go, it's me!
Pipo! Come! Come, Pipo!
I asked San Dimas and he brought it to me.
Pipo! Where have you been, Pipo?
Handsome, come! Come with me!
(LLORIQUEA) ¡Pipo!
Miraculous water, a peseta the glass!
Drink the miraculous water to peseta the glass!
-Miraculous water! -Come on, give it to me!
Mother, mother! I got it!
Thanks to! Your son brings you the water!
It was cured! It was cured!
It was a miracle!
It was a miracle, Pablo!
Emilio, my Emilio who has been cured! I had the fevers and that's good!
Miracle!
It was a miracle!
Don Salvador! But where is that man going?
Stop him, Don Ramón!
Don Salvador.
¡Salvador!
What happens? Where is it going?
I don't know, to the church.
I think I felt like praying.
Still don't understand?
That man suggested that he feel devoted.
A very practical joke, come on. Don't talk to me about jokes!
The one we did was the worst of all.
¡Mire! ¡Mire!
And that? That we could not imagine.
Come on, come with us.
-Now it is too late. -What's going on?
How what is it? Bah, come on.
We go and argue inside, we are puzzled.
But what scandal is this? Listen to me!
I can't have you go wild here!
Can't you hear me? Silence!
Leave the saint, or I'll call the Civil Guard!
Doña Paquita, know that inside the church I do not tolerate other water
other than holy water!
I do not care! Whatever you have to tell me, in the confessional!
On the street! Out all! The church is not a chicken coop!
Here you come on Sundays at 8:00, so yes!
Ale Ale! To make a ruckus, to the soccer field!
Out all! Out all!
Why not, my God?
825 sick.
4200 pilgrims in total.
I use round numbers.
I've called you to talk about the benefits.
That is, so that I can talk about them if they don't mind.
Section A: economic benefits.
Let's calculate a profit of three pesetas per pilgrim,
which means 10,200,000 pesetas a month.
That is 122 million in a year, 212,000 in a century
and one trillion two hundred billion in a millennium.
Well, this is my offer.
I buy them the monopoly of the miracle
and I pay them all their cash value. Look.
Money, bills.
Money, more money! How much they have not been able to dream!
Gold! An eternity of gold! We are not interested.
Not? Neither you, Don Evaristo?
I do not know! And don't play magic games anymore, we're not in the circus.
Of course not. Not yet.
You have to laugh, joy! You buy miracles!
I pay more than anyone! Gold!
Gold to cover the mountains, the rivers, to satisfy
your least wishes.
Here is seriousness, guarantee! I pay more than anyone!
Look how gold flies! Catch it!
Check it out! It's legit!
Used to fake miracles, buy rockets, lights, wigs!
It works for everything!
You spoke of a section A: economic benefits.
What is section B?
Section B? Spiritual benefits.
Hey, friends?
Hear? An illustrious visitor has arrived.
Do we have the right to play with them? What do you think?
I'm not afraid.
No fear, you know. I'm going to say it all.
It's okay.
Whoops.
It has to be done, it is necessary.
I am left wondering who you are. Will you tell me?
Any day.
I don't know where it will be. That is my secret.
Listen to me!
Hear me! Listen to me all!
We try to deceive you!
To all! To all!
There was no miracle water!
I'll tell you who San Dimas was!
Look at it! We disguised it, it looked like!
But we get scared!
We thought it would be easy to fool you!
And this was San Dimas, this!
You, San Dimas?
I, I have seen it! Carried light
and a palm tree, it looked nothing like that.
It is true! What she says is true!
-We wanted to get rich! -We did it for Fontecilla!
Not! Don't believe him! Don't believe him!
I don't care to whom this is due, whether the apparition is true or a lie!
Look, what I want is to take care of my daughter!
I've come a long way, I sold it all!
And whoever does the miracle must cure her!
-Everything was false! -Invented by us!
-Lie! Don't you see how I walk? -I asked him and he gave it back to me.
And these hands, who has cured me?
And I am cured. I had the fevers and look at me.
I am already cured. I'm healthy.
She is my daughter, heal her. She is sick.
-Don't leave her. -I have healed
with this miraculous San Dimas water.
And it will heal your daughter too. Come with me, come all.
(THEY SPEAK AT THE TIME)
You are miserable fooling everyone.
Martino, come down, help us! Do you hear me
Martino! ¡Martino!
It has to be here. Martino!
Let's see, where is it?
I want to see it. Where is?
There is no one here, nor has there been in many years.
-When have you seen it? -I was just a moment ago.
Where is that Martino?
-It was here. -Yes, just now.
Miserables.
-They are miserable. -There, look.
"For Don Ramón, José, Evaristo, Antonio,
Salvador and Don Manuel.
One day I came to Fontecilla to clarify the mystery for them
of a word that can do everything. His name is faith.
They wanted to do business with her, not knowing that when they woke her up
among the people, they woke me up.
If this faith also awakens them, my trip will have served for something.
Tell Don Fidel that the San Dimas of his church
it looks nothing like the original.
Just in case you want to remember the image, I attach a photo
and personal details of the authentic San Dimas.
That! That's Martino!