There are some fairytale
characters I'm jealous of.
Cinderella.
She lived on easy street
thanks to a prince.
And Juliet.
She had a man to love for life.
Oh, and Snow White.
Sleeping Beauty met a prince
while sleeping.
Wait, SHIN Mi-su.
You'll beat them all.
There's always a man
behind a woman's happiness.
I'm not too picky
when it comes to men.
My right guy's 100 things.
No, I'm not picky at all.
There are only 100 things
I want from a man.
Just watch.
I'll fiind Mr. Right,
no matter what!
Directed by Park Yong Jip
Miss Gold Digger
Aren't they pretty?
'Oh, my beautiful princess,
open your eyes.'
Look at her.
She's like an angel.
She's so good with children.
I'd love her to be
my daughter-in-law.
- If I had a son!
- I told you.
Father?
Good?
Name's LEE Jun-seo.
He's loaded.
Not so cute.
In fact, cheesy and ugly.
But he's rich.
That's what counts.
This is my room.
Let me be frank with you.
I don't see myself
getting married.
If it weren't for my parents,
I would've become a nun.
I wanted to become a Father, too.
I'm sure you would've made
a fine Father.
If so, I wouldn't be here
with you today.
Right?
It looks shabby, doesn't it?
I'll have this place remodeled
once I get married.
It's weird.
When I first saw you,
I felt like I'd known you.
Never felt this way
about anybody.
You're the first, Mi-su.
I'm sorry.
I can wait.
All he needs is some style.
KIM Yoon-cheol...
Just pass the Bar,
and I'll grant you your wish.
Yoon-cheol!
You okay?
Why follow me around?
You can't win my heart
by doing so!
Mi-su.
Even death can't stop me
from loving you.
Your feet will hurt
if shoe strings are loose.
This is it.
If you fail the Bar again,
we're done.
Tired of waiting, Mi-su?
I'm not your girl...
...until you become a D.A.
Okay?
I love you, Mi-su.
Fine.
It'll be like growing
vegetables for myself.
God...
Hold it, hold it...
Mom? Mom?
Where is she?
Coming!
What can I do for you?
You think I did this?
Oh my...
Look at my fragile arms.
I'm not strong enough
to break it.
Why would you think
it was me?
Look at me.
I'm not the lying type.
Can you say that
to the police?
Are you threatening me?
You have no proof!
He's my witness.
There's nothing worse
than lying.
Stop lying to your dad.
Or you'll end up in hell.
I'm not his dad.
Mom...
Why are you crying?
I didn't say anything bad.
Help me here!
I will.
But I've lived here
for 20 years.
You have?
Okay.
We have a girl here
with an announcement.
I'm SHIN Mi-su
living at 103-805.
Today, I broke a flowerpot
and ran.
And I got caught.
Many residents have fallen
victims to vandalism lately.
Perpetrators out there,
turn yourselves in.
Happy?
All of his friends are doctors.
Hook up with them
at my wedding.
- Really?
- Mi-su, okay?
Congratulations, Young-mi.
I hope
you never get divorced.
Hey!
Think about it.
She's rushing into it.
Once you get hitched,
that's it.
Few people consider themselves
happy in marriage.
On top of that,
some doctors are psychos.
And a lot of them do drugs.
Right?
Let's go have fun!
Ready, girls?
OK!
Thanks for saving my spot.
Guys still dig you, Mi-su.
OK!
God, they're so cheap.
It's a deal.
Working through lunch?
You scared me.
I'm on a diet.
You should be the last
to be on a diet.
Any idea what it feels like
to have a killer body?
Isn't it too negative
toward the competitors?
It's kill or be killed.
What if it gets us in trouble?
If it does,
we'll find a way to fix it.
That's the spirit, Mi-su.
Hi, Jun-seo.
I'm in a meeting.
I'll call you back.
Show me
what they don't like.
I can't take it.
It's nothing.
I know.
It may be nothing to you,
but not to me.
I just want to make you happy.
Jun-seo...
This is it?
You're a blessing
from the Virgin Mary.
And that is a blessing
for a couple.
It will connect our love.
Thanks so much.
Hello?
Yes?
Who?
You're wasting your time.
I'm spoken for.
By only two!
You know what?
I like you.
So let's go steady.
You do your thing.
I'll do mine.
Okay?
This is no joke.
I like all three of them.
Mi-su, thanks for drinks.
You're cool.
Be careful.
- You're good!
- Bye.
So sexy!
Buy us drinks again!
Champagne will be good!
I'm not your bank!
Don't bring them
next time.
It's tiring to keep a puppy.
Let me go.
I apologized, didn't I?
Here's what you ate
yesterday.
Kimchi, chicken, eel,
beer, whiskey.
You don't chew well,
do you?
I'll pay for the laundry.
How much is it?
Feel like going
on the air again?
Wash them well like new.
He's such a jerk.
God, this is embarrassing!
Mi-su is Watching
How could you?
I wish to live with you
in a place like this.
I wouldn't survive a day.
Happiness comes from
petty things.
It's what the rich say.
To keep the wretched
from killing themselves!
Tell me.
If I fail the Bar again,
you'll leave me?
Yes.
That was quick.
You know what will happen
if you give up now?
You'll be a bum...
...with nothing but debt
and despair.
You'll be a loser
without any friends.
Should I go on?
Meat will help you focus.
I don't want much.
All you need to do is
pass the Bar, okay?
Don't make me leave you.
You're not allowed
to eat meat at a temple.
This guy did
and got kicked out.
Really?
Hurry finish eating.
Please, forgive him.
Please!
It's not his fault.
It's all me.
Punish me instead.
Please...
Kook Nyung Temple
1,000 bow ceremony
Mi-su!
I'll study really hard.
I promise.
I love you, Mi-su!
Love?
Will this accomplish love?
Sorry I'm late.
Traffic was horrible.
I bet it was.
Say hi.
She's the manager
you were talking about?
Yes, she's a treasure
of our company.
Every project she worked on
was successful.
She isn't called
Midas's Mother for nothing.
I see.
You'll find out how...
You know what?
- I'll have to reconsider.
- What?
See you around, Ms. SHIN.
You know him?
Not really.
Just a little.
Wait.
Don't get personal.
This is business.
I'm quick on the uptake.
You don't know
what I can do.
I have no time to waste.
Hey!
He stands unchallenged
in his company.
And he has a good rep
in the IT business.
I can't believe
he's still single.
Did you see his eyes?
They were sparkling!
He's a freaking meanie!
Why are you looking at me
like that?
It's time you got promoted.
So I could...
Words travel fast
in our business.
Once you get a bad name...
...you go down
into a bottomless pit.
Whatever it takes,
make him change his mind.
A Young Entrepreneur
Helping the Needy
He'll do wonders for me.
Stop it, okay?
Stop it before I lose it.
I warned you!
You need some beatings!
You're dead
if I get my hands on you!
I grew up like an orphan.
My parents were never around.
They never held my hands.
I was so scared
when they were home.
I was constantly afraid
to mess up...
...and disappoint them.
Mi-su.
Yes?
What's the most important thing
for you in life?
Money and strings to pull.
I think it's love.
I feel the same.
He canceled the contract
for personal reasons.
How could he do that?
He should put the company
before himself.
It's a great ad agency.
Okay, thanks.
Everything will be fine.
Don't tell me
you pulled stings for me.
Don't do that.
We're friends,
but business is business.
Let's stop talking shop.
Jun-seo...
I like it when you smile.
Restricted Area
What the...
What's going on?
Insulting me is like
challenging authorities.
Isn't it, Mr. DA?
- Put your arms around her.
- So pretty.
Come on, smile.
Yeah, smile.
One, two...
Smile.
Looks hot.
Like this?
He's so smooth about it.
Is it his second marriage?
- What are you talking about?
- What's wrong?
Look at him.
He looks like a crook.
Come on, he's a doctor.
You never know.
Are you jealous?
Look at him.
How can I be?
You have no idea.
I'm having so much fun
shopping around.
Hi, I'm Mi-su's boyfriend.
I sing and rap.
You're not my boyfriend.
- He's just a friend.
- I see.
I'll be right back.
He's so hot.
Way to go, Mi-su.
Let's drink.
Cheers!
What's up, sisters?
Hi!
They're his friends.
- Introduce yourselves.
- Hi, I'm Isaac.
Enjoy the last night
of your single life!
Thanks!
Poor thing.
Leaving all this behind...
Staying for my show?
What show?
You'll see.
He's a kick-ass rapper!
Really?
Yeah, that's right!
Jump, jump!
Just once!
Go!
Is she slepping?
She's sleeping.
You can't sleep there, lady.
I must be dreaming.
My cell phone...
Mom, why didn't you
wake me up?
Where were you?
I called you like crazy.
How cold you miss
a presentation?
The client was so mad.
Why aren't you
at the hospital?
You were too sick to call.
I'm so sorry.
Some miss the meeting
from a hangover.
But I know
you're not like that.
But you know what?
If it was a hangover,
I'd be very upset.
But I would understand.
I don't wanna be
nagging a sick person.
If you're too sick to work,
take a break.
Forever.
You're strange lately.
Anything wrong?
I just have a lot
on my mind.
Can we reschedule
the meeting?
I wouldn't agree to that
if I were the client.
Hi, Jun-seo.
I'm at a church.
Got a few things to pray for.
You're in Hong Kong?
I hope
I didn't put you in trouble.
Please, don't do that
for me again.
Yeah, I'm at a church.
They're rehearsing a play.
Nosy, isn't it?
Can you hear me?
I'll call the client
and apologize.
You're at the airport?
Have a safe trip.
They're waiting for me.
I'll be home soon.
Sweetie, let me shower.
What the...
Honey?
Thanks.
Hi.
Asshole!
I don't buy water anymore.
There's this spring
in the mountain at the back.
It's good for your system.
Check it out.
Or we can go together.
I have some ideas
for your ad.
Should we discuss it
over drinks?
Hey!
Who do you think you are?
Be a freaking man!
Come on, bring it on!
You'll be called
to the resident's meeting.
If you miss it,
I'll go to the police.
Can you give me a break?
Resident's Meeting
It's a beautiful day.
You said you'd do
anything for me, right?
What?
Of course.
Just say it.
A restaurant?
He's buying me lunch?
Act like a couple.
We're getting married soon.
What?
Let me get it straight.
Your younger sister can't
get married before you.
So you lied to your parents
that you have a girl?
Her fiance will be
transferred to China.
If not now,
she has to wait for 3 years.
It's none of my business.
You tricked me into this.
I thought
you wouldn't mind.
What if I say no?
If I give you the job?
I heard you were good.
3 years is too long
for her to wait.
Where are your parents?
Dong-hui!
Think about it.
I have a career and life here.
I can't throw away
everything for a man.
You shouldn't.
Why don't you talk to him?
That'll change nothing.
Why'd you wanna marry him?
Marriage is about
supporting each other.
You didn't think that?
What a fairytale.
Stay out of this.
What you're saying
doesn't make any sense.
Why should a girl
sacrifice for a man?
I'm not saying that.
Let's turn the table here.
Can you give up your life
for a girl?
I can.
What?
If I love her,
I can and will.
Food is good here.
Almost as good as yours.
- How do you like it?
- It's good.
Enjoy it.
Oh, sure.
Do you remember?
You cried about this fat girl
in the elementary school.
Do you know
what his nickname was?
It was a crybaby.
Was it?
You were a crybaby.
Try it.
Go ahead.
Here.
- Chew it well.
- It's very good.
How long have you dated her?
Not long.
Why don't you marry her
soon after your sister?
What?
She seemed very mature.
I liked her.
She's not sleazy, is she?
What are you talking about?
She seemed fine.
I'm just asking.
You never know.
Why twist my words?
I liked her.
Give me some more pear.
Pretty good.
Did Daddy ever
bone a fish for you?
Bone a fish my butt.
He never did anything for me.
Would you like a DA
for a son-in-law?
Why on earth
would a DA marry you?
You'd like that, huh?
Fine, I'll make you
a DA's mother-in-law.
Stop that.
The sacrifice day for your father
is next week.
I changed my religion.
If you miss it again,
I'll kick you out.
Put this in your underwear
and chant like this.
Okay?
Repeat it 3 times.
With it in your underwear.
Don't be nervous.
Good luck.
Go.
If you pass it,
I'll sleep with you.
Good luck!
Really?
Wish me luck!
WCDMA will be the next
generation mobile service.
As SHOW, the new brand,
has been launched...
...a high-speed data service
is available now.
It will help KTF enhance
its position in the business...
...and venture out
to the world.
That's all in the brochure
we provided.
Tell us in detail
how you'll set our image.
Of course.
I was about to.
Using USIM cards,
it'll offer various services...
...that will change
the mobile life dramatically.
We'll show people happily
using SHOW...
...saving up to 30%% %
of their phone bills.
The public will see
the new image of KTF...
...as an innovative
and leading telecom company.
- What do you think?
- I like it.
When can you do it by?
Wait.
Got more to show me?
No, it's not that.
Bye.
Thank you.
If you're free,
I can buy you...
What a nice picture!
You guys are going out?
- No way!
- This is business.
Yes?
No.
Now?
Wait!
Mi-su, stop sending me
to both heaven and hell.
Sure.
Hey.
Why do you smile all the time?
God, this guy is so romantic.
But, no.
It's too early to fall for him.
What if I do?
No, it's too early.
I need more time.
Be patient, Mi-su.
What am I gonna do?
No, I should be in control.
Mi-su?
It's a beautiful night.
Yes.
This is so romantic.
Fine, I'll let you kiss me
for trying.
Why does he
wanna work out at night?
What are you doing?
No...
I was looking for you.
Let's go.
Yes, that's right.
That's right.
Hold it tight. Good.
Hold it tight.
Good. Good.
Come on,
give me one more.
I'm so tired.
- Tired?
- I might drop dead.
Need a ride?
No, I can walk.
You must be tired.
Working and dating...
Don't get fresh.
Night.
Bye.
He's quite all right.
Yeah, I'm tired.
My life is tiring.
Here you go.
Enjoy it.
Come here.
Give me some more.
I like sausages.
You have to share.
I'll give you more later.
Give me more, Mrs.
I'm not Mrs.
Get out of here
before I eat them all.
Next.
With money,
it's easy to be an angel.
Should I dump others
and be a rich angel?
Daddy!
Shoot.
I'm sorry.
You should've been careful.
So sorry.
- It's okay.
- You should've been careful.
That's okay.
Yeah, there's a poor angel
as well.
It's okay. Go play.
Bye.
Look at your shirt.
It'll dry soon.
You're almost too good.
Here.
He'll forgive me
for whatever I do.
What?
I'd be so happy
if you pass the Bar.
I guess
You haven't checked it.
What?
What is it?
The result is out?
Give it here.
Did you pass it?
Feels so awkward.
I like the buttons.
This is it.
Now you look like a DA.
Sir, you're due at court.
- Stop it.
- This is fun.
Let's get this, Mr. DA.
I'm so proud of you.
What do you feel like eating?
Mi-su.
I won't be able to come home
for a few days.
Take care of the kids.
I'll call you.
Ji-gum is only 1,
and he speaks English.
Teach him Korean first.
Thank God
he's smart after me.
I'll be lonely.
I won't be shackled
to the kids, will I?
Hi, Honey.
I'm serving food
for the homeless tomorrow.
I'm so grateful to have you.
Just pretend you're happy
out there, okay?
Thanks, Honey.
Yeah, it'll be tiring.
Sorry.
My buddy got fired.
So I took him to a bar.
Why don't they
recognize my talents?
Can you help me
put out an album?
I'll be good.
Just one album.
What if I lose
all my savings?
What's wrong?
Can't sleep?
Let me hold you.
I must be tired lately.
I'm seeing things.
No way.
You would look good
driving it.
You can't buy my heart.
I couldn't be happier
with you.
Just...
Please, take it.
You don't have to decide now.
What I want is you,
not your money.
Mi-su...
Hey, it's me.
It's a beautiful day.
Does your mom like fruit?
She's out of town.
When will she be back?
You passed the Bar,
but you're not a DA yet.
Go and study.
I get a lot of calls lately
from matchmakers.
Threatening me?
No way.
You're the only girl for me.
Go study then.
Hi.
You can't have
all the girls on earth.
Listen.
She has a great body
with a tight ass.
You slept with her?
Of course, I did.
No shit.
You really screwed her?
She moved her ass like...
It was awesome.
What?
Mi-su?
Listen to me.
You asshole!
When'd I sleep with you?
I just wanted to show off.
We're a couple anyway.
What?
Don't ever call me again.
Mi-su...
Can you hear me?
Please come outside.
Mi-su!
Can you hear me?
I was wrong!
I'm in love with you!
I was wrong.
I love you.
- I'll never do that again!
- What are you doing?
I'm sorry.
I won't do it again!
I love you!
Mi-su, I'm sorry!
I'm sorry!
Why can't you just
let it go?
I thought you were cool.
It's cool to give up
a woman I love?
Is that it?
I told you I had a man.
What do they have
that I don't?
Money, future, power.
You have nothing.
What about moments
we had together?
What about love we shared?
We're through.
There's no way to go back.
Check, please!
Fine.
You gave me no option.
I'll send out your pictures.
That I took.
What do you have?
My naked body?
Yes.
I took them for my eyes.
What's going on?
He seems serious.
We can talk about it
over drinks.
Go ahead.
What pictures are they?
- Don't know.
- Go ahead.
I was just concerned.
There was time...
... when I thought
love was everything.
Pictures are not only
to look at but to erase.
I'll let you go now.
Go back to your world.
How many guys
are you seeing?
What?
Mind your own business.
Are you a stalker?
Why keep bumping into me?
You're sick.
Keep talking.
You love them all?
Do you know what love is?
Of course.
What do you think it is?
Why should I answer it?
You should love yourself
to love others.
What?
You should be honest
with yourself...
...to give anybody love.
Who are you to judge me?
Do you even know
what your type is?
I'll rent a car
until it's fixed.
And if I feel sick,
I'll go to the hospital.
Why so angry with me?
Why live like that?
Who made you this way?
What the...
Is it the accident?
Are you hurt?
It's nothing.
Got any news for me?
You know the KTF project
we're working on?
What about it?
We're invited to the party
they're hosting.
At Hotel Paradise.
Why should we care?
We should!
Think of all the clients
we can fish for.
Mr. CHOI told me to dress up.
He said I was the mascot
of our company.
Nice.
That's 100%% % cashmere.
Pick anything you like.
It's on me.
You don't wanna show up
looking shabby at the party.
Still, this is...
If you refuse to take it,
I'll be mad.
Let me help you pick.
It's leather,
and ladies love it.
You look fantastic.
Especially, your arms
and black silk gloves.
So beautiful.
Why couldn't I see
this side of you earlier?
Isn't it small for you?
It's the only size we have.
- Try something else on.
- No!
It fits.
I'll take it.
Please, do so.
This...
Perfect.
I'll sign with other companies
and dump thatjerk.
Don't worry.
I'm the mascot, remember?
- Glad you made it.
- Dong-min.
Hi.
This is a great party.
- You think so?
- Sure, it's all great.
Hi.
I'm counting on you.
I'll call you next week.
Thanks.
Can you breathe in that?
What do you care?
Oh!
I'm here as a guest.
Show me some respect.
I must've gained weight.
Hello?
Going to Daegu?
Anything happened?
You're no help.
Okay, have a safe trip.
Mi-su, listen to me.
I'm sorry I messed up.
I love you!
Mi-su, I messed up!
Mi-su!
- Busan Station, please.
- Don't do this!
I love you!
Mi-su!
I love you, Mi-su!
Mi-su! Mi-su!
Your father is so patriotic.
He dedicated his life
to bring justice to...
Yoon-cheol?
You have a good taste.
What's going on?
Is this Daegu?
Who's this chick?
What a nice surprise.
How are you?
Been a while.
What's going on here?
She's got a temper.
Say hi.
We went to school together.
This is Yu-jin.
She's my girlfriend.
Fucking high?
Why don't you watch
your language?
- She's been always...
- Look.
I'm SHIN Mi-su.
One that you love for life!
Stop it.
It's not funny.
She's justjoking.
Joking or not,
I don't like it.
I have black and silver on.
We're like a couple,
aren't we?
Yeah.
Excuse me.
- Where's Mi-su?
- No idea.
I'm sorry about this.
Wait here.
How could you do this to me?
We'll talk outside.
I took care of you
when you were struggling.
Fine then.
Let's go.
How long has it been?
Get off!
She was just my junior
in University.
What the hell!
You...
Let me go.
Asshole!
- Who are you?
- You don't need to know.
You are the ones
who stole my Mi-su?
Who are you?
I want my Mi-su back!
You win. You win.
What are you?
Who are you guys?
Get out of here!
Who are you?
Don't worry.
I'll take care of it.
This place isn't for you.
Go home.
Let's go.
I'm counting on you.
Why releasing them?
We fought together!
Without their kindness,
you would be detained.
Let's go.
He's a soon-to-be DA.
And she's the daughter
of the Attorney General.
The client wants you
off the project.
I don't think
it was Dong-min's idea.
At the meeting this afternoon...
they'll decide
what to do with you.
You might as well resign
to save face.
Hi, Jun-seo.
Try them all.
They all taste different.
You're all I have left?
Why not eating?
Not good?
Is it the smell?
No, it's good.
That's right.
I heard there was a fight
at the party.
I don't know.
I wasn't there.
Mi-su, it tastes better
when eaten with hands.
Good?
This is my favorite restaurant.
You know what?
I got dumped here
five times.
Pity me, huh?
Guess you aren't as naive
as I thought.
After the third time,
I took pills.
I wanted to die.
I'm glad I survived so
that I met you.
Will you feed me now?
What?
Come on.
Go ahead.
Mix it well.
Your hand tastes so good.
It's something
I've never tasted before.
Mi-su.
Frankly speaking...
Please, accept my love.
I know
you'll understand.
God damn it!
You're so disgusting!
Go home and lick the doll,
you sick pervert!
Mi-su?
Yes.
He was perverted
with a fetish for hands.
I'll explain later.
Sorry, Daddy.
Can I have some egg rolls?
Okay.
I know I ruined it
for you.
I'll make it up to you.
Drinks are on me.
One more bottle, please!
There are things
you can never control.
You know what?
Love is one of them.
I loved him so much,
but he left me.
It hurt me so much...
...I didn't want to get hurt
ever again.
Is that bad?
Why?
Why are you doing this?
Why should we break up?
I did everything for you.
I did everything
that made you happy.
Don't do this.
Be cool about it.
But why?
You don't know?
You've never been
honest with me.
Yeah, I've never been
honest with you.
Whose fault is that?
What?
That's my fault?
What the fuck.
You wanna go there?
You've never used
the F word before.
Yeah, I have a dirty mouth.
3 bottles of these won't
get me drunk.
And I hate shirts like this.
If I had told you
I had dated over 100...
You wouldn't have liked me.
Su-han...
This isn't you.
You're innocent and naive.
Damn it.
Because ofjerks like you,
girls have to play innocent.
It's so hard to live
as a girl.
I ended up like this
because of assholes like you!
Why did my father
name me Mi-su?
It means 'lncomplete'.
Whatever I do...
It never works out
the way I want it to.
Even love I wish for.
It's always incomplete.
Everything is incomplete for me.
Right?
Daddy!
Daddy, am I heavy?
I grew up
while you were gone.
I'm a grown-up now.
I just didn't wanna wind up
with a man like you.
But I miss you so much.
You would've beaten up
those bastards for me.
Daddy...
I'm sorry.
You jerk!
Get your hands off my ass!
Stop wigging!
When you beat up
Yoon-cheol for me...
I was grateful.
You looked awesome.
Not much of a fighter,
but you did well.
What if we didn't get off
on the wrong foot?
Would I have given you
a hug?
Maybe a kiss?
How would your lips feel
on mine?
Stop talking
right to my face.
Bone the fish for me.
I'm closing the account.
You sure?
I need the money
for something.
Getting married?
Nothing's perfect.
Men, love and life.
None is perfect.
Life is
about satisfying yourself.
So you have to choose.
Yes, life is about taking
chances and making choices.
You don't have to do this.
I've always wanted
to go to France.
You can take my position.
I still have a lot to learn
from you.
You'll do well.
What do you mean
you're going to France?
Is this to attract attention?
Is that it?
I guess so.
Is it the party?
You can make up for it.
Don't do this.
Take me back when I come back.
Though I might come in late
with a hangover.
SHIN Mi-su!
Tell them
that we broke up.
That I'm sleazy
with drinking issues.
Who would like such a girl?
If I tell them you're smart,
hard-working, and flexible...
They'll like you.
Thank you
for telling them that.
Why do you have to go?
You can study here.
Begging me to stay?
Should I get on my knees?
Like you once told me,
I don't know what I want.
All I cared about was
how to look to other people.
I want to find myself
before it's too late.
How long should I wait?
I've shopped a lot.
I'll give you a year.
If you're not back by then,
I'll remarry.
That's why I'm leaving.
Thanks, Mom.
For listening to me.
Like father, like daughter.
I might have thought
someone could change my life.
No, I did.
If one of them had,
would I have been happy?
The plane is going to
departure at 11 am.
Enjoy your trip.
Do you have to go?
Yes.
Fine.
I'll be waiting.
The dice has been rolled.
I'm still a single woman,
Ms. SHIN.
Bonjour!
Han Ye-seul
Lee Jong-hyuk
Gwon Oh-joong
Kim In-gwon
Son Ho-young