♪♪
♪ Walkin' through
these dirty halls ♪
♪ With them &quot;so cool&quot; kids
around ♪
♪ Walkin' with my head
held down ♪
♪ Just trying
to avoid the crowd ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ One hand on the glass bottle,
and the others would follow ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ All this smoke
strikin' my face ♪
♪ I don't feel
nothin' but sorrow ♪
♪ Now I'm seeing, now I'm
seeing, now I'm seeing ♪
♪ That y'all nowhere ♪
♪ It's been a few years now ♪
♪ Now I'm feeling, now I'm
feeling, now I'm feeling ♪
♪ Like your glory days
have now gone ♪
♪ And I know it,
and I know it, and I know it ♪
♪ Y'all hurtin' ♪
♪ For a while, you been lost ♪
♪ For all those times y'all
thought you ran the world ♪
♪ Your glory days
are now gone ♪
♪ Gone ♪
♪ Your glory days are now gone ♪
♪ Walking through
these old memories ♪
♪ Where I'd feel so apart ♪
♪ I never fit the normal crowd ♪
♪ Never drank or smoked at all ♪
♪ Oh ♪
♪ They always talked to me ♪
♪ Couldn't understand
why I never followed ♪
♪ Too much pride
in my damn self ♪
♪ Don't need to feed no ego ♪
♪ Now I'm seeing, now I'm
seeing, now I'm seeing ♪
♪ That y'all nowhere ♪
♪ It's been a few years now ♪
♪ Now I'm feeling, now I'm
feeling, now I'm feeling ♪
♪ Like your glory days
have now gone ♪
♪ And I know it, and I know
it, and I know it ♪
♪ Y'all hurting ♪
♪ For a while you been lost ♪
♪ For all those times y'all
thought you ran the world ♪
♪ Your glory days
are now gone ♪
Thank you
for seeing me today.
Ms. Walden, your son's situation
is very serious.
He cuts class constantly,
and when he does show up,
he doesn't even try.
♪♪
[ Scoffs ]
Well, that's...
inventive.
[ Chuckles ]
That's a math test.
Are you aware
that your son
is running with --
with corner boys?
Thugs?
No, my son --
He is not like that.
Why don't we just
call him in here,
lay down the law
right now.
James isn't
in school today.
Yes, he is.
I dropped him off myself
this morning.
Well, he didn't make it
into the building.
He keeps this up,
he'll have to repeat the year.
He's a good kid.
He can still
get back on track.
There are 1,200 students
in this school.
I have to focus on the ones
who want to be here.
♪ Oh ♪
♪♪
[ Dog barks in distance ]
[ Siren wails in distance ]
How was school today?
Fine.
Learn anything new?
Nah, not really.
[ Barking continues ]
Well, I learned
something new today.
Hmm?
Yeah, I learned
that my son...
is a liar.
I hope
you had fun today,
'cause you're gonna
pay for it tonight.
Whoa, what's this?
These are textbooks.
And you would know that
if you went to school.
Hey, you don't
know nothing.
Look, what I know, James,
is that the only thing
you have learned
is how to cut class.
And it's &quot;anything.&quot;
Huh?
&quot;I don't know anything.&quot;
And you said it,
not me.
[ Barking continues ]
♪♪
For many years, she's a mothe,
a mover, and a shaker.
Please welcome Congresswoman
Lorraine Townsend.
[ Cheers and applause ]
So, Lorraine, children
are your priority.
Yes, Sally Ray,
that is why educatin
is the centerpiee
of my agenda.
Our kids are the futur,
and if we want that futue
to be bright,
we have to start investig
in our kids now,
and that starts
with our schools.
Right on, sister.
Right?
If we want our kis
to have the educatin
that they deserve,
we have to give our schools
the resources that they nee.
Amen to that.
So, a vote
for Lorraine Townsend
is a vote
for your children's future?
Absolutely.
[ Horn honks ]
[ Engine shuts off ]
Uh, hold on, hold on,
hold on, hold on.
That's your homeroom,
right?
I'm gonna wait here until you
wave to me from that window.
Ma, come on!
I am not leaving this
to chance.
Come on, Ma.
Do not make me go
in there with you.
[ Groans ]
[ Sighs ]
[ School bell rings ]
[ Indistinct conversations,
announcement over P.A. ]
[ Laughs ]
That your mom?
Huh?
Don't cry, Superfly.
You'll be back
with your mom tonight.
She'll tuck you in real good
and tight.
You miss your mama,
don't you, boy?
[ Laughs ]
Now we're going to move on
to germination.
What is it?
[ Sniffs ]
Mr. Turner,
perhaps you can enlighten us?
[ Music playing on headphones ]
Mr. Turner.
[ Music continues ]
Mr. Turner!
[ Students murmuring,
laughing ]
You killin' my groove, lady.
What's up?
Can you define germination?
Germination --
a nation of Germans.
I don't know. Uh, germs --
I don't know.
A long word for germs?
Go ahead, Mr. Smith.
Germination is how a seed
turns into a plant.
It has angiosperms
and gymnosperms.
[ Laughs mockingly ]
Bonz: Anyone catch that?
Boy, did you
just say &quot;sperm&quot;?
[ Laughter ]
You could all stand to be
more like Mr. Smith here.
You won't be laughing
when you flunk out
and end up working at McDonald's
for the rest of your life.
[ Students &quot;Ooh&quot; ]
[ School bell rings ]
I ain't gonna be working
at McDonald's.
There will be a quiz tomorrow.
[ Music playing on headphones ]
[ Door opens ]
What's going on?
[ Door closes ]
What up, James?
Jerome, come here.
Come here.
What was that shit you were
talking in class earlier?
Huh?
W-What are you
talking about?
What am I talking about?
You trying to show me up?
Hmm?
Think you so smart?
No.
Huh?
Man!
[ Chuckles ]
You fucked up now.
You stepped on my Ones.
[ All grunting ]
[ Bone snaps ]
Aah!
What up, James?
You need a lesson, too?
Huh?
Aah!
Come here.
Get in on this.
Come on. Come on!
[ Clears throat ]
Go!
[ Door opens ]
Oh, shit!
Come on!
I'm sorry, man.
I'm sorry.
Principal Chapman:
Give me one reason I don't
have him arrested.
Please. He is 15.
He can't have a record.
James, tell me
the others involved,
and I might
go easier on you.
He's suspended,
effective immediately.
Next time,
he goes to jail.
I will personally see to it.
There will not
be a next time.
Come on, James.
[ Car doors shut ]
You want to tell me
what happened?
I defended you
back there.
Tell me I was right
to do so.
You better answer me.
You think
you know everything.
I can't hear you.
They made me do it, Ma.
You can't keep blaming others
for making bad choices.
What are you talking about?
You weren't even there!
James Walden!
You want to know
why they beat on Jerome?
The teacher asked
&quot;What is germination?&quot;
Jerome told him,
and the teacher
told the other kids
to be more like him.
And Bonz --
Bonz just got so --
Whoa. Bonz?
Bonz -- he's skinny.
Bonz just got so mad, Ma.
So, he hit another boy in class
for answering a --
Yes.
And there are three of them
coming for me next, Ma.
♪♪
Baby, I'm sorry.
People around.
♪♪
[ Engine starts ]
[ Seatbelt clicks ]
♪♪
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Now, that's what your school
should be like.
What?
[ Scoffs ] In your dreams.
May I help you?
Yes.
I need to enroll my son.
We don't enroll students
mid-semester.
But if you'd like to apply,
we can consider him
for the winter term.
No, no, please.
My son needs
a new school now.
I'm sorry.
[ Papers rustling ]
[ Scoffs ]
[ Papers fall ]
James.
I'm sorry.
Do you draw a lot?
Sometimes.
May I?
♪♪
Wow,
these are very good.
Thank you.
You see that?
That was done by a young man
about your age.
He's at Georgetown now
studying graphic design.
Why don't you go out
into the hall?
You'll see
our Fall Arts Exhibit.
Lots of great
student work.
Okay.
♪♪
We did have one student
withdraw last week.
So there's one
open space.
Yes.
My son needs this.
$3,500 pro-rated.
That's $3,000.
$200 for books
and $100 for uniforms.
So $3,300.
A year?
For the semester.
Tuition alone
is $7,000 a year.
Any chance
for a scholarship?
Not with the grades
you mentioned. I'm sorry.
[ Chuckles ]
It's fine, it's fine.
♪♪
I forgot my checkbook.
When would you need it?
The board meets next month.
The books have to balance.
That's not a problem.
Welcome to
Harriet Jacobs Academy.
In a Jiffy Tax Services.
How can I help you?
Uh, let me transfer you
to a tax specialist.
Just one second.
♪♪
♪ I'm playing games
like I've been for a while ♪
♪ You're dropping names,
but that suits your style ♪
You'll empty trash,
sweep, clean --
all the stuff we can't
make the interns do.
That's fine.
Wait, is that
the Congresswoman?
Yes.
I am a huge fan.
I think the education plan
that she's come up with
is so important.
This is her private office.
She's extremely busy.
Don't speak to her
unless she speaks to you first.
Don't even look at her.
You're invisible.
One more thing.
Can you scrub toilets?
I've had experience with this,
yes.
Good.
You're hired.
♪ Hangin' on a line ♪
♪ It's got you, too ♪
♪ Sayin' it's fine
when it's not up to you ♪
♪ And in due time,
we'll see this through ♪
♪ And follow all the maps
we drew ♪
♪ In my life, I wanna be ♪
Wait, hold -- hold on, hold on,
hold on, hold on.
What?
Please say you're not gonna make
me wave to you at my new school.
I'm scrubbing toilets, James,
for you to go to this school.
Am I wasting my time?
Ma.
No, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no.
You have got to choose.
If you want to be a delinquent,
ruin your life,
I will drive you to juvy
right now myself
to help prep you for the life
you will be living in prison.
School or juvenile hall?
School.
What?
Just a little louder
so I can really hear --
School!
And with, like,
that feeling.
I want to go to school!
There we go.
That's the answer.
Can I go?
I'm gonna be late.
Boy, let me look you over
before we do anything.
Come on.
[ Laughs ]
Sharp. Oh, wait,
you still got a tag on.
Hold on one second.
Oh, don't. Don't -- don't.
Why not?
You know,
I just want to --
Just in case
we have to return it.
This uniform is not
going to be returned.
You're gonna
get to stay here.
Yeah, but can you
just leave it there?
Okay.
♪♪
I love you.
Later, Mom.
I love you, too.
♪♪
Congresswoman Townsend:
Great.
Well, a contribution like that
is a game changer, and I'm --
I'm -- I'm thrilled
to have your support.
All right. Well, thank you.
We'll be in touch.
[ Receiver clicks ]
That was a six-figure
phone call.
I love it.
[ Laughs ]
It's Virginia, right?
That's right.
Those your kids?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's Whitney.
She's 14.
And that's Henry.
He's 10.
My James is 15.
Oh!
Want to --
You know you
want me to see him.
Okay.
I'll show you.
[ Laughs ]
Let me see.
That's my James.
Aww, look at
that face.
He's handsome.
Thank you.
It's a great age.
Phew!
It's a crazy age.
[ Chuckles ]
Tell me about it.
[ Laughs ]
I cannot keep up with all the
lessons and recitals and games.
Hmm.
Tell me about your son --
What's he do?
Um, yeah, no.
His school didn't offer
anything like that.
They learned more like
how to cut class
and how to trick
the metal detector.
That has to change.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
But, um, I put him
in the Harriet Jacobs Academy
because I wanted to give him
some more opportunities
like...
your daughter has.
You're a good mom,
Virginia.
But it shouldn't
be that way.
Our schools have simply
got to do better.
You know that that is a big
part of my agenda, right?
I definitely know.
That's why I really
like working here.
I feel like I'm part
of the team.
[ Both chuckle ]
The cleaning part, anyway --
but the team nonetheless.
There are no small parts
in this fight.
You have a good evening,
Virginia.
And you tell that dimple-y boy
I said --
I said hi.
[ Laughing ] Okay.
[ Footsteps departing ]
♪♪
Mr. Walden,
enlighten us.
Why can't plants
eat bugs?
'Cause plants
aren't animals.
Ah, the metaphysical
approach.
Animals eat.
Plants are not animals.
Ergo, plants do not eat.
But what if I tell you
some plants do eat?
This is Edith.
As you can see, Edith is
a plant - a Venus flytrap.
She didn't have much growing up.
The soil was very poor.
So...Mr. Walden,
will you do the honors?
Just pick up a bug...
and drop it in when I say...
now.
And that is evolution
in action.
Edith's ancestors
couldn't live in poor soil,
so they adapted.
And now Edith eats bugs.
Nature is resilient.
Living things find a way
to survive.
U-Unless they're bugs.
[ Laughing ] Uh, yeah,
unless they're bugs.
Uh, if you remember what we were
talking about yesterday,
we were talking
about evolution.
Can anyone tell me how this
relates to our conversation
yesterday?
Now, remember, we were talking
about &quot;Jurassic Park&quot;...
Hey, no Hot Pockets?
Oh, you can have Hot Pockets,
or you can have tuition.
Which is it gonna be?
Well?
I'm thinking.
[ Laughs ]
[ Scoffs ]
[ Dog barking in distance ]
♪♪
[ Knock on door ]
Yes?
I'm sorry to bother you.
Hey.
Can I ask you
a quick question?
Yeah, sure.
Oh, thank you.
I'm very, very interested
in your work.
And I've been doing
a lot of reading.
And -- here we go --
I found this.
This looks like D.C. spends
$14,000 per child per year?
Yeah, that's right.
I mean, I'm sorry, I'm probably
not understanding,
but isn't that a lot?
Do you mind if I see that?
Oh, no. Sure.
So, it's right there,
District of Columbia.
[ Laughs ]
There's your problem
right there.
Do you have any idea
who Cliff Williams is?
No, not really.
Let's just say
he's not someone
who wants to see people
lift themselves up.
He's someone
who stands opposed
to the kind of work
that you and I are doing
for our kids.
Huh.
But thank you, Virginia.
Thank you for bringing this
to my attention.
I appreciate it.
Oh.
[ Glass breaks ]
♪♪
[ Sighs ]
♪ Beware the false motives
of others ♪
♪ Be careful of those
who pretend to be brothers ♪
♪ And you never suppose
it's those ♪
♪ Who are closest to you ♪
♪ To you ♪
Oh. Hi, Virginia.
Hello, Ms. Townsend.
So, are you coming
to the town hall on Friday?
Yes, ma'am.
Good.
The mayor will be there,
plus our biggest supporter.
So it's
all hands on deck.
♪♪
[ Sighs ]
All right.
Well, see you then.
♪ Forgive them, Father ♪
♪ For they know
not what they do ♪
It says here you want to
borrow $7,000 for school?
For my son.
For one year.
Right.
Well, that is
a significant percentage
of your annual income,
ma'am.
I know.
But I'm good for it.
I have never been late
on a payment in my life.
Uh, okay. Do you --
Uh, do you own your home?
[ Clears throat ]
I rent.
♪ They say all the right things
to gain their position ♪
♪ They'll use your kindness
as their ammunition ♪
Assets? Land?
Businesses? Boats?
[ Scoffs ] Uh,
I just sold my yacht.
[ Chuckles ]
♪ And I found to be true ♪
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa. $600?
♪ That everyday people,
they lie to God, too ♪
Fine! Fine!
♪ So what makes you think
that they won't lie to you? ♪
♪ Forgive them, Father ♪
♪ For they know
not what they do ♪
[ Sighs ] I-I really wish
I could help, Ms. Walden.
But, um,
you just don't qualify.
Please?
Please.
I promise
I will pay you back.
On time
and with interest.
[ Sighs ] Um,
what about the father?
Can he help?
[ Sighs ]
♪♪
Principal Martinez.
[ Crying ]
♪♪
Goddamn it.
[ Crying ]
♪♪
Hey, Ma.
Hey, Ma, what are --
What are you doing here?
Whatever it is,
I-I-I didn't do it.
Like, I've been real good.
I-I even got a pass
to come out here.
Um...
I am so sorry,
James.
I am so sorry.
♪♪
[ Silverware clanks ]
[ Door slams ]
[ Rap music plays ]
♪♪
James Walden!
What is this doing in the trash?
Because that's
what it is.
This --
♪ And we about to
make a killin' ♪
[ Music stops ]
I spent good money
on this.
And you're gonna need it
for when you go back there.
How am I goin' back, Ma?
You gonna rob a bank?
You gonna do that for me?
Please?
[ Rap music plays ]
♪♪
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Shoe clasp breaks ]
[ Scoffs ]
[ Sighs ]
Annette: There you are.
I've got your question
all written out for you.
Oh, wait. I'm sorry.
What?
Your question.
Just in case.
You've never
done this before.
So, in theory, people will ask
great questions
so the Congresswoman
can show off her strengths.
But sometimes we have to help.
Sit here.
If I touch my ear like so,
you go up to the mic...
Whoa.
...and you ask your question.
No, I'm sorry.
I'm terrified
of public speaking.
This is reading, not speaking.
You'll be great.
[ Clears throat ]
He's not here.
Let's start.
You sure?
Yeah.
All right.
[ Light feedback ]
Good evening.
Welcome to the School Matters
town hall meeting.
[ Applause ]
We're a tight community,
and we look out for each other.
But we couldn't do it without
strong, righteous leaders.
And we have one of the best.
For 20 years, she has done
battle for you in Congress,
and she has won.
So, folks, let's welcome
our very own Lorraine Townsend.
[ Applause ]
Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
Thank you so much.
And thank you all for coming
to discuss
what is the most pressing issue
facing us today --
education.
And I am so excited to see
what we can accomplish together.
All right,
who's up first?
Yes, sir?
My daughter is scared
to go to school.
There's fights,
knives, guns.
How's she
supposed to learn?
I am a mother of two.
And that's why my plan
calls for tighter security
and stricter
disciplinary rules.
Come on, now. They have guards,
they have metal detectors.
That ain't no school.
It's a damn jail.
I hear you.
But these things take time,
right?
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
Um, my -- my kids, they --
they make all A's.
But the test scores say
that they're reading
below grade level --
Well, we have to end
social promotion.
And we have to end
grade inflation.
So, your solution
is to flunk my kid?
No, ma'am. I-I am not
suggesting that at all.
But what I am suggesting is
we have to start thinking big.
That's why my plan
calls for
rebuilding
our crumbling schools,
giving more funding
to our teachers.
So that eventual--
[ Audience murmuring ]
Yes, ma'am.
Did you have a question?
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
Hello--
[ Feedback ]
I'm Virginia Walden,
and I have a question
for the Congresswoman.
[ Inhales deeply ]
[ Exhales deeply ]
&quot;D.C. schools are chron&quot;--
Oh, God.
Sorry.
Very nervous.
Take your time.
You're among friends
here.
[ Laughs ]
&quot;D.C. schools
are chronically&quot;...
[ Scoffs ]
It's been a long day.
I had to pull my son
out of school.
It was a really good one.
But I couldn't afford it.
So, tomorrow, my son
has to come back here.
And he can't learn here.
Nobody can.
And Lorraine Townsend is
telling us that we need to wait,
be patient,
and, &quot;eventually,&quot;
change will come.
Well, I don't know about you,
but my son can't wait.
He needs change today.
Not tomorrow, not next week,
and definitely
not &quot;eventually.&quot;
'Cause we've been waiting...
for decades.
And...
I'm done.
And -- and -- and you know
what else I'm done with?
I am done with this lie
about money.
Now, they tell us, they say
to us that the schools are bad
because they're poor, and --
and we believe them because --
because we know
what poor looks like, right?
This place does look poor.
But you know what?
The school I took my son
out from?
Now, that school
cost $7,000 a year.
Now, I know --
I know that is a lot.
It's a lot.
Ms. Walden --
But did you know
that this public school
gets twice as much money...
Ms. Walden!
...per child per year.
Woman:
Are you kidding me?
What if your kids
could just go to school
and sit down and study?
Yes!
Just get out of this
hopeless cycle that we live in?
Yes.
They could go to college,
become a doctor,
a scientist.
They could become a teacher.
Anything!
Just imagine it.
Because I know I have.
And losing that hope today,
losing that hope --
Man: Yeah.
Let her finish!
[ Voice breaking ]
Losing that hope for my son,
that was the saddest thing
in the world.
Amen.
[ Audience murmuring ]
You're fired.
I'm fired. I know.
I quit.
And you can clean
your own damn toilets.
[ Murmuring continues ]
[ Siren wails in distance ]
Hey. What's up, y'all?
I want some candy.
I want some candy, too.
All right.
Candy! Candy!
One for you.
Can I have some candy?
Want some candy?
And a Ring Pop for you.
What -- What --
What are you doing?
I'm passing out
after-school snacks.
What's wrong with you?
Wha--
Does your mother know
you're out here recruiting kids?
Nah, just helping out
the community --
offering career options,
is all.
Get off my street,
Garnett.
And if I ever see you here again
with these kids,
I swear, I'm gonna make --
What?
What you gonna --
You gonna put me in the corner?
Give me a time-out?
I'm gonna give you a good
old-fashioned ass whuppin'.
That's what I'm gonna do.
[ Laughs ]
All right, uh-huh.
Be careful.
'Cause your boy
already missing a daddy.
There you go.
All right.
That's for you.
Ring pops.
Hey, stay in school.
All right?
Okay.
[ Scoffs ]
&quot;Stay in school.&quot;
[ Sighs ]
[ Scoffs ]
[ Siren wails in distance ]
♪♪
I'll make you a deal,
okay?
You go to school,
you study hard.
I will move heaven and Earth
for you to go back to
Harriet Jacobs Academy.
Which bank you gonna rob?
[ Both laugh ]
I will not tell.
♪ I'm looking around,
and I see more of the same ♪
♪ Yeah, more of the same ♪
♪ People looking for purpose,
someone to blame ♪
♪ As I'm on my quest for fame ♪
♪ Every day the place
is changed ♪
♪ I stay humble
trying to play the game ♪
♪ Trying to play the game ♪
♪ I'm trying to play the game,
yeah ♪
♪ I figured it out,
my dreams are bigger than me ♪
Do you really need
this that bad?
We hurt you that bad?
You can't walk?
You need a wheelchair
or something, too,
while you're at it?
♪ I'm so glad that I believe ♪
♪ I believe ♪
♪ That God has plans for me ♪
♪ Got plans ♪
♪ Mama told me it will happen,
you'll see ♪
♪ It'll happen,
you'll see, you'll see ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah,
time for you to raise up ♪
♪ Time for you to get right,
time for you to get up ♪
♪ Time for you to be loud,
time for you to raise up ♪
♪ Get up, stand up, raise up ♪
♪ You gotta know who you are ♪
♪ You are meant for a purpose ♪
♪ Who you was meant to be ♪
♪ You are meant to be ♪
♪ Mm-hmm ♪
♪ I can't move forward
till I let go of the past ♪
♪ Got to let it go, yes ♪
[ Door creaking ]
Hi.
I would like to see
Congressman Williams.
The Congressman
isn't here right now.
Then let's make
an appointment.
[ Pages rustling ]
His first available
is December 3rd at 8:00 A.M.
He can give you 10 minutes.
[ Scoffs ]
You've got to
be kidding.
Sorry. He's very --
Yes, yes.
He's very, very busy.
Got it.
[ Sighs ]
♪♪
I mean, he's got to come through
the door at some point, right?
[ Scoffs ]
♪♪
We'll take care of that.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Yes. Yes. Okay.
Cliff: Yeah.
See you tomorrow, Cliff.
Congressman?
Sir? Hey!
Cliff?
Um...
Yes?
I read your report.
Um, when you said
that young people,
they shouldn't have to wait
while we take the long,
slow walk to lift up
our public schools.
Yes, yes. I say a lot of things.
I'm a politician.
Sure, but, um, what you did
in Milwaukee and Cleveland,
um, so that low-income students
could go to private schools,
well, I want to do that here
in Washington D.C.
Uh-huh.
I see.
Um...
You've done your homework.
I-I did.
Yeah.
And you get an F in history.
We tried it here.
No one wanted it.
Did you know that?
Uh, no. No.
Yeah. Parents in poverty
with kids in terrible schools,
who will, therefore,
remain in poverty.
The parents
just didn't want it.
No.
I-I don't believe you.
Well, it doesn't matter
what you believe.
No one wanted it.
No, but we do!
I do.
Take it up with your local
representative.
Lorraine Townsend doesn't --
Lorraine Townsend
is not my problem.
Now, if you'll be so kind
and step aside,
I have a date
with my 9-iron.
Yes, sir.
Thank you.
♪♪
&quot;No one wanted it.&quot;
Tryin' to tell me
what people want.
How's he know?
Burnt-out old fart.
♪ She turn fire into rain ♪
♪ Heal your pain
like novocaine ♪
♪ If you was blind,
I guarantee ♪
♪ She touch your eyes
so you can see ♪
♪ Ohh, I lo-o-o-ove ♪
♪ Livin' in a woman's world ♪
Hi.
I was hoping you might be
interested --
I ain't got no money.
♪ A woman's world ♪
Afternoon, sir.
Hi.
I was wondering
if you'd be open --
♪ Pick her pills
and give you life ♪
Ma'am, hi. Hi.
I'm Miss Virginia.
I have a petition --
Oh, can I help you
with that?
Stop! Thief.
Thief!
No! No.
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Livin' in a woman's world ♪
Get a scholarship to go
to a better school.
♪ It's a woman's world ♪
Thank you.
You won't regret it.
♪ It's a woman's world ♪
Hi, there.
How are you?
♪ It's a woman's world ♪
Would you be interested
in signing a petition?
♪ And you're just a man
in a woman's world ♪
♪♪
[ Car alarm blaring ]
Virginia:
Young lady, why are you sitting
out here all by yourself?
[ Man shouting ]
Where's your mother?
[ Blaring stops ]
You live here?
[ Shouting continues ]
[ Bang ]
Come on.
Delilah!
Get inside! What'd I tell you
about talking to strangers?
She was out here all alone,
and it was dangerous.
Are you judging me?
No, ma'am,
I am not judging you.
I know you're judging me.
Get off my block.
Mom! Mom!
Mom, Mom, Mom.
It's -- It's all right.
Telling me how to be
a mother to my baby.
I get it, I get it,
I get it.
It's all right, it's all right,
it's all right.
Just go inside.
Go inside.
Hell no.
Damn...
My bad. I had to work.
You had to work?
Aren't you like 15?
So who's watching her?
I am.
And who's watching you?
You should
get out of here.
Would you like to
sign a petition?
Okay.
Just write your name
and then sign it.
♪♪
Great. We're gonna
have some meetings,
and I'll give you a call.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
♪♪
Well, Well, Well.
I see you prancing all over the
hood acting all civic and shit.
Let me by, Garnett.
Not till you pay
what you owe.
Owe?
I don't owe you anything.
No?
Get out of my way.
Why you think
nobody been hassling you?
Why you still
got your purse?
I didn't ask
for your help.
What you getting names
for anyway?
It's just for
a scholarship program.
Hmm.
For career options.
Mm.
No, no! Don't!
Please! No!
[ Clipboard thuds ]
I'm the career optin
around here.
Got that?
[ Engine starts,
car door closes ]
♪♪
[ Vehicle departs ]
Man: Several weeks later...
♪ I've been in love
with perfect strangers ♪
Let's check the first flower.
♪ That had me caught up
in my dreams ♪
♪ Always dressed
like heaven's angels ♪
♪ But they don't know me ♪
♪ They don't comfort me ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ God knows
I'm tired of crying ♪
♪ When love's
cutting me so raw ♪
♪ I don't wanna hurt no more ♪
♪ No more ♪
♪ Breaking the chains
out of this tragedy ♪
What's up, man?
You good?
All right?
Man, you doin' something
with this corner.
You turnin' shit to gold.
Yeah, you know, I'm grinding,
working hard.
A token of appreciation.
Oh, nah, man.
All right, all right,
all right.
Yeah!
Damn!
See what happen when
you put in that work?
All right, all right.
Shit!
You like the kicks?
Yeah.
Come work for me.
I'll hook you up.
Think on it.
♪♪
[ Dogs barking ]
[ Indistinct yelling ]
[ Baby cries ]
[ Yelling continues ]
[ Knock on door ]
[ Lock unlocks ]
Hey!
You're the lady
from the other night.
Yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
Um...
Whatcha --
What are you doing here?
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
[ Sighs ] I dropped out of
that school 15 years ago.
And it was terrible
even then.
Hmm.
Nothing changes.
Oh, it changes.
It gets worse.
[ Clicks tongue ]
How many names you got?
Oh...
Oh.
Oh, well, I had more,
but Garnett Brown burned them.
Mm.
Oh.
That sounds about right.
Mm-hmm.
Whatcha gonna do
with the names?
I was thinking about taking them
to the D.C. Council meeting
tomorrow night.
Mm.
But now...
[ Scoffs ]
I got so few names,
I don't even know.
You thinking
what I'm thinking?
What?
[ Both laugh ]
Say no more.
That's it.
Mm-hmm.
Excuse me.
No, it's cool.
[ Knock on door ]
Shondae.
Hey, go ahead, have a seat.
It's all good.
Okay.
Yeah.
[ Pounding on door ]
Shondae!
Damn it, Robert!
What the hell you doing
waking me up?
Uh...
Maybe I should --
No, no, no, no, no.
No, no.
Sit tight.
It's all right.
She testy when she tired,
but she can get you them names.
I'm taking names right now.
Shondae, honey, I --
Unh-unh.
Don't call me honey.
Look, I'm sorry I woke you up.
I really am.
But I think you will
want to hear this.
When do you
need these by?
Um, tomorrow night
for the D.C. Council meeting.
All right.
[ Slaps clipboard ]
She said &quot;all right.&quot;
Okay.
Okay. [ Chuckles ]
I mean,
is there a problem?
No. No. Nothing at all.
No.
We'll see you
tomorrow night.
Okay.
Um --
I'll grab your stuff
for you.
[ Siren wailing ]
Hey.
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa!
No!
C-Chill, chill, chill!
It's me.
[ Sighs ]
If you get enough names,
can you change things
around here for my sister?
This is complicated.
But, yes.
Yes, the more names
the better.
Okay?
Okay.
I can get more names,
then.
Okay.
[ Chuckles ]
I didn't mean to scare you
like that.
I know.
[ Chuckles ] I know.
♪♪
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Chairman Randall: Uh, I hereby
call this meeting to order.
Unbelievable.
Um, excuse me.
Sorry, Your Honor.
Yes, sir.
Please, have a seat.
♪♪
Oh, my God.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Who are they?
Let's just say Shondae
has a way with people.
Looks like we're gonna have
an interesting meeting.
Woman: Lots are so broken,
I almost fell the other day.
Ma'am, ma'am,
thank you, uh...
I mean, what are you
gonna do about --
...but your four minutes
are up.
[ Scoffs ]
Uh, next?
Next?
[ Clears throat ]
Um...
Ma'am?
I-I'm here to present,
uh, a-a petition.
Now, I have --
Uh, your --
your name, ma'am?
It's Virginia Walden.
Virginia Walden?
And, uh, on behalf of the
parents of Washington, D.C.,
for a scholarship program
so that low-income students
can go to a private school.
Uh, ma'am, ma'am,
excuse me for second.
Uh, um, uh,
did you register to speak?
We -- we don't have
your name on record.
Uh...
I'm sorry, I thought
this was an open meeting.
Well, the --
the rules are clear.
If you want the floor,
you have to register
48 hours before the meeting.
But I thought t-this
was an open --
I know what you thought,
but the rules are clear.
No, but I-I-I --
No, no, no.
Ma'am, ma'am, ma'am,
the rules are clear.
Sir, to whom?
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
If I knew the rules,
I would have followed them.
Now, I am here.
Can't you just take
the petition?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
We can't.
Um, we've gathered
many names here.
Why don't you register
for the next meeting?
Okay?
Please, take your seat.
[ Audience murmuring ]
[ Scoffs ]
Uh, all right.
Uh, anyone else?
Okay, I move--
Hold on.
[ Audience murmurs ]
Ma'am, your name?
Shondae Smith.
Okay. Uh, I don't have your name
here, either.
Yeah, I'm sure you don't.
But I'mma speak anyway
because I took off work.
All these folks
took off work.
Woman #2: That's right.
My boy, Jerome --
he right over there.
Say hi, baby.
My son -- He real bright,
and he work hard.
And the bullies at his school
beat him up for it.
They hurt his leg
and broke a bunch of ribs.
I shouldn't have to put him
back in that school.
But I got no choice.
That's wrong.
♪♪
[ Sighs ]
My -- my name
is Tasha White.
White.
My name's not on your list,
either.
[ Sighs ]
My kids, they --
they falling behind,
but the school won't help.
And they act like
I'm the problem.
They say that my son
has no potential.
My daughter should have
a choice, but she doesn't.
That's wrong.
[ Audience murmuring ]
Can we have order
in the chamber?
♪♪
[ Gavel banging ]
Folks...
♪ Yeah ♪
Please, respect the Council.
Please have a seat.
Virginia: ...And present
this petition
on behalf of the parents
of Washington, D.C.
[ Sighs ]
[ Camera shutters click ]
♪♪
[ Golf club swings ]
Okay.
♪♪
Hey!
[ Groans ]
Congressman Williams!
Hey! Hey.
What are you
doing here?
Uh...did you see this?
This is a private club.
I know.
Members only.
That's why I had to tell
the people at the gate
that I was the maid.
Did you see this?
Don't make me
call security.
Oh. Look at you,
Mr. tough guy.
Well, I guess you got
a lot to prove, what
with those pants and all.
You said the people of D.C.
don't want change, and they do.
Now, I took a petition
with hundreds of names
to the Council last night.
Shouldn't we at least
have a conversation?
That last shot
doesn't count.
You have no idea
how difficult this would be.
If we lived anywhere else,
you could go
to your local government and
set up a scholarship program.
That's what we did
in Milwaukee and Cleveland.
But in D.C.,
you need an act of Congress.
That means you need to
get the attention
of a bunch of politicians
who don't care about you,
because you didn't
elect them.
And then you've got to get them
all to agree,
which happens...
never.
And then you need the President
to sign it into law.
You have a better chance
of winning the lottery
than getting all of that done.
Well, no wonder why nothing
changes around here.
Exactly.
Until now.
[ Silverware clanks ]
I've been in this game
for a long time.
There's a way things are done --
or not done.
And that doesn't change
because you want it to.
Disagree.
Disagree all you want.
It doesn't change things.
Dis...a...gree.
[ Swallows ]
[ Breathes deeply ]
You might
just be formidable.
Agree.
Why don't we have a real drink
and seal the deal?
No.
I like to stay sharp.
Prevents bad choices...
like those pants.
These pants are tactical.
They blind the opposition.
Ha! What, so folks don't see
how bad your game is?
I like golf.
But what I'm really good at?
Legislation.
You better be.
You have no idea.
Congressman Williams: Education
is the civil rights issue
of our time.
We, the people, have failed in
our moral and legal obligation
to provide quality education
to every American child.
Right now, thousands of children
right here
in our nation's capital
are bearing the burden
of our failure.
These children are caught up
in a cycle of poverty,
dependency, and crime.
We have abandoned
the most vulnerable members
of our society.
And we must do better.
I'm thrilled to introduce the
D.C. Education Incentive Act.
This bill will create
a scholarship fund
so that low-income parents
like Virginia
can send their kids to schools
where they will break free
from the shackles of poverty.
It's my pleasure to introduce
you to Virginia Walden,
a single mother from one of
D.C.'s toughest neighborhoods.
Please put your hands together
and welcome Ms. Virginia Walden.
[ Applause ]
Man: First you let her run over
you at the town hall meeting,
now this.
Honestly, Lorraine, it's like
you want us to pull our funding.
No, no, no.
I-It's nothing to worry about.
It's not going anywhere.
Look, I am 100% confident
in our plan.
Then prove it.
[ Receiver clicks, dial tone ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Siren wailing ]
Shit.
[ Dogs barking ]
Yo, that was --
That was close.
[ Chuckles ]
You got some weak-ass
shoes, man.
The damn sole's
coming apart.
[ Chuckles ]
I wish I had some kicks
like yours.
Come to work.
You know where to find me.
Yeah, yeah.
I got you.
All right.
[ Barking continues ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
♪♪
[ Cheers and applause ]
This is the &quot;Sally Ray Show.&quot;
Please join me in welcoming
our special guest.
She is a mother,
a trailblazer --
Virginia Walden.
[ Cheers and applause ]
♪♪
[ Cheers and applause
continues ]
So, Virginia,
you're a single mom.
Yes, I am.
Tell us about your son.
Um...
James is kind
and smart.
He's also a teenage.
Speak!
[ Laughs ] Teenagers!
I have two myself.
[ Laughter ]
James is, um,
susceptible.
The streets
just pull him in.
Yeah.
And school --
He was just falling
between the cracks there.
And I just...
[ Clears throat ]
Sorry.
I just thought I was
gonna lose him.
So I put him
in a private school.
Wow.
How did you afford that?
[ Laughs ]
I didn't.
[ Laughter ]
Overnight, James --
He just changed.
You know, my son was excitd
for school.
It was just incredibl.
But then I had to pull him ot
because I couldn't pay for i.
And that led you
to partner with
Congressman
Clifford Williams
on the D.C. Education
Incentive Act.
Yes. No child should be
cut off from education.
Poor kids have just as much of
a right to learn as rich ones.
[ Applause ]
Well, that's, uh,
inspirational.
And Congressman Williams -
He had tried this
before in Milwaukee..
and so I thought
this is somebody
who's passionate about it,
and I feel lucky
to have his support.
I'm sure he feels lucky
to have your support
and your information.
I don't know
what you mean.
Congresswoman
Lorraine Townsend,
who's served our community
for over 20 years,
uh, she said
that your plan, uh,
actually harms
low-income residents.
Yeah, that's not true.
It's not true that
Townsend said that
or not true that your plan
helps poor people?
Neither. I --
I mean, b--
[ Breathes deeply ]
I mean --
My source says that you
went through the trash
looking for
campaign secrets.
What? Campaign secrets?
What?
So, you admit
you insinuated yourself
in the inner circles
of the Townsend campaign.
You're not serious.
Donna! Get me
the &quot;Sally Ray Show.&quot;
Now.
Oh, no,
I am serious, Virginia.
Admit it.
Admit what?
This is all
about the money.
Yes. Yes, it is.
That - That is what
I am saying.
Right.
So, how much is Cliff Williams
paying you to do his dirty work?
Hmm?
Now, I-I have a statement here,
uh,
from the Townsend campaign
that I'd like to read.
&quot;For generations,
black people were kept out
of America's public schools.
Now Virginia Walden
and her reactionary allies
want to set us back
50 years.&quot;
What do you say to that?
[ Audience murmuring ]
♪♪
All right!
Yeah!
[ Dogs barking ]
[ Vehicle approaching ]
[ Rap music playing on radio ]
[ Music stops ]
What's up, man?
Hey, yo, I got a petition
I need you to sign, too.
[ Barking continues ]
What?
You ain't gonna sign it?
[ Engine starts ]
It's for the kids, man!
[ Door opens ]
Rise and shine.
Mm!
Girl, it's been a week.
Get your ass
out of this damn bed.
Listen, I just worked
a 12-hour shift.
My feet hurt. My back hurts.
My soul hurts.
But I'm here.
I'm here.
So get your ass
outta this damn bed.
Okay.
But Cliff Williams
is gonna be here
with about a million parents
in exactly --
hmm --
15 minutes.
Wait, what?
Mm-hmm.
This is a movement,
honey.
It don't stop just 'cause
you caught the vapors.
[ Crying ]
Aw, hell no.
Okay.
All right, all right.
Here, baby.
I can't go out there.
Either you go out there,
or they come in here.
But you doing this.
I got my ass handed to me
on that show, Shondae.
There's still plenty left.
Mm-hmm!
[ Laughs ]
You're too much.
Shondae, I got to tell you
something.
Sure, anything.
Come on.
I can't even
look at you.
James, my son...
he --
He was the one
who stomped my Jerome's glasses.
I know all about that.
Then why are you here?
'Cause this is bigger
than all of that.
Plus, James ever come
near my Jerome again,
he got me to deal with.
[ Both laugh ]
I can work with that.
Then we good.
Shondae, what am I gonna
tell all these people?
The right thing.
You're gonna say
the right thing.
[ Scoffs ]
[ Clock ticking ]
Okay, good lord, family.
He don't bite.
Excuse me, baby.
Not my friends, at least.
Where's Virginia?
Mm.
She was delayed.
We should just get started.
I'm out.
No, Tash. Come --
Come on. No, no, no!
Unh-unh!
Listen, y'all, y'all can't
just walk out like that.
Virginia: Sit...
Why not?
...down.
[ Women groan ]
Well, you heard her.
Get back in there and sit down.
Please.
Go this way.
Now, I know what you all
are thinking.
And I know because
I thought the same thing
when I first met
the Congressman.
No offense.
And I thought he can't be
bothered with us.
He doesn't care
about us.
But he does.
Is she right?
Do you care?
Look, I understand why
you might doubt me.
I'm a white man
with a Harvard degree,
two homes,
a chauffeur --
A fat head.
[ Laughs ]
[ Clears throat ]
And a fat head.
But this isn't about me.
It's about your children.
Can you get my son into a school
where they don't beat him up
because he's bright?
There's no telling what we can
accomplish if we work together.
Man, why should we
trust you?
Ha ha.
You shouldn't trust me.
I'm a politician.
[ Light laughter ]
But what you can trust is that
I'm a hell of a legislator.
And I'm never better than
when the stakes are high
and the odds are long.
So I'm confused. Are we talking
about politics or poker?
[ Laughter ]
I never fold.
I can't.
So, where do we go from here?
♪♪
♪ Some souls are born
in the shadow ♪
Lorraine Townsend
is going to fight you -- hard.
And I'm sorry to say
that Congress just
doesn't care about you.
Well, we gonna have
to make them care.
That's what we gonna do.
Well, now, how are
we gonna do that?
♪ Out of the womb
in shackles ♪
If you want people
in Congress to care,
you need to find someone
with clout to endorse you.
Wha-- The mayor.
Exactly.
That is gonna
take a miracle.
The mayor is on Townsend's side,
a-a-and has been for years.
Well, luckily
I specialize in miracles.
And now, so do you.
♪ Well, sometimes
you got to rise ♪
♪ Rise ♪
♪ Sometimes you got to rise ♪
♪ Above your ♪
Okay, can someone
please tell me
where the hell
the Congressman is?
He is coming.
He's gonna be here.
This is crazy.
Oh, you made it!
You made it!
What's going on?
Anything for my baby sister.
So happy to see you.
Hey! Ah!
[ Cellphone ringing ]
Oh, wait. Hold on.
Hey.
Oh.
Hello, Congressman.
Congressman Williams:
I can't make it.
Wait, what?
I've got another vote --
the Water Reclamation
and Storage Act.
The what?
The point is that
when I vote &quot;yes&quot; for them,
we'll pick up six votes &quot;yes&quot;
for us.
So how many do you need?
218.
Ugh.
What's he saying?
He's saying that
he's not coming.
What?
Okay, I'm gonna
kill that man.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Hey.
You want to help me
give a speech?
♪♪
Come on.
[ Indistinct conversations ]
♪♪
Hello, everybody!
I'm Delilah.
All: Hi, Delilah.
This is Miss Virginia!
She's nervous,
so I'm helping her.
Hi, Miss Virginia.
Uh, thank you, Delilah.
[ Chuckles ]
Uh, Delilah is right.
I am so nervous.
Um...
But, you know, I start
to feel less nervous
when I look out at this crowd.
In fact, I start
to feel fantastic.
Yes!
[ Laughs ]
I feel fantastic because
there's just so much power
standing here.
There's so much purpose.
There is so much strength
right here.
Can you feel it?
Yes!
Now -- now,
those up on the Hill,
they said we would fail.
They say that we all don't care
about our kids.
But they could not be
more wrong.
[ Cheers and applause ]
Hi.
Yeah, you will not believe
what's going on down here.
We have started a petition.
And more than 7,000 people
have signed it.
That's right -- 7,000.
And we are going to march it
over to the mayor's office.
We are going to put it
in his hand.
And we are going
to get his support.
Do you hear me?
That's right!
I need you
to fix this.
I'm not shutting down
a peaceful protest, Lorraine.
This is America.
Now, do you see these?
You see these bags?
These backpacks,
every single one of them
is filled with signatures --
yours, mine,
our neighbors,
our friends.
Whoo!
We need your help to
get them over there.
Who wants to carry one?
Come on.
Come on up here.
Help us with a bag.
Because we have to let them know
that kids come first.
Kids come first!
All: [ Chanting ]
My entire legacy
going down the drain.
All because of this
ridiculous woman.
Are you listening to me?
Kids come first!
[ Vehicle approaches ]
[ Music playing on radio ]
♪♪
[ Music stops ]
Superfly.
Everything cool?
Hey, yo, speak up.
You finding your way?
Yeah.
Yeah, you --
you been working real hard.
Maybe I put you
on your own corner.
Yo, come here, man.
I want to ask you something.
Make sure you tell me the truth.
The count's off.
Know anything about that?
Nah.
Yo, just playin' with you,
man.
Hey, almost forgot.
This right here...
for services rendered.
Yeah!
Jays is fine, right?
Yeah.
Thanks.
Yo, uh, where Bonz at?
Uh...
[ Sighs ]
...poverty,
communities torn by crime.
[ Scoffs ] Windbag.
Today, I stand before you
with my friend and colleague
from across the aisle,
Congressman Clifford William.
And I hereby endorse the
D.C. Education Incentive Act.
I call upon Congress
to move forward and to act.
Ahh!
Ma! Ma!
Yes, yes!
Do not kill this bill...
I thought you was dying.
...a bill which provides
great opportunities --
No, no, no.
Mnh-mnh.
I am very much alive!
Oh, my goodness!
[ Telephone rings ]
Oh, wait, hold on
while I get the phone.
[ Laughs ]
Hello?
Oh! Hi!
We are watching you right now
on the TV.
Congressman Williams:
You're going to need a speech
for when you testify
before Congress.
Wait, no.
No, I-I -- I-I-I really --
♪♪
Sit.
Oh, my goodness.
Yes!
[ Dog barking ]
What's up?
Before I give you this, can you
sign this for my little sister?
[ Dog barks ]
All right.
A little token
of appreciation.
It's on the house.
[ Dog barking, telephone rings ]
Virginia: Hello?
Woman: I was calling you about
the scholarship program.
Abs-- Yes.
You want to do something
with the scholarship program.
I will --
Uh, let me just grab a pen,
and then I can get
all of your information.
Okay.
Hello?
♪♪
Ma! When's dinner?
I'm starving.
I'm not even gonna ask you
to explain this.
[ Bangs desk ]
You are not even
going to school.
Did Garnett Brown
give you these? Huh?
Are you selling your soul
for clown shoes?
[ Stove clicking ]
Ma. Ma, what are you --
What are you doing?
Mom -- Mom --
Please don't do that, Ma.
That's my money. Please.
It is not yours.
You did not
earn this honestly,
and you will never
spend it.
Stop, Mom! Please! Stop!
Mom, what are you doing?!
Stop! Please!
Please!
Stop it!
[ Groans ]
I hate you!
I hate you, Ma!
I hate you.
♪♪
[ Door closes ]
[ Spray can hissing ]
♪♪
Damn.
How you do that?
Just do.
&quot;Just do&quot;?
Yeah.
Lucky as hell, man.
Look at this.
You got talent.
I'd try to make some money
off this shit.
My mom found my money,
man.
Oh, shit.
She hates me.
Your mom don't hate you.
She's --
I wish I had a mom
like would stay
on me like that.
Then you can have her.
You don't get it, man.
Just think about this,
though --
Some kids
don't even have a mom
or a pops out here, man.
Alright.
Everything your mom do, man,
she do for you.
I wish my moms would get it
together like that.
Yeah, you right.
Be safe, man.
♪♪
[ Exhales deeply ]
[ Gunshots ]
[ Dog barking, alarm blaring ]
[ Tires squeal ]
Jesus. James!
James! Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Bonz?
Oh, Jesus.
Jesus.
[ Sobbing ]
♪♪
Somebody help me!
[ Sobbing continues ]
♪♪
[ Sirens wailing in distance ]
[ Police radio chatter ]
♪♪
[ Engine starts ]
I run a high school
with 1,200 students.
The building is falling down.
We can't afford chalk.
And she wants to steal
what little we do have for her
so-called
&quot;scholarship&quot; program.
This woman delivered
7,000 signatures,
but the D.C. Education
Incentive Act
would only provide scholarships
for 1,700 kids.
It's an affront
on equal opportunity.
We cannot allow it.
Next up, we will have, um,
Virginia Walden.
♪♪
[ Clears throat ]
I wrote a speech.
Um, I was gonna come here
and beg you all
to not
abandon our children.
Again.
But then, um,
then after this &quot;testimony,&quot;
I-I just can't
be polite anymore.
This misinformation.
The bad faith --
Ms. Walden.
Let me just start
with Principal Chapman.
You said that this bill
takes money away
from the public schools
and makes them worse.
But, sir, have you even read it?
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
Didn't think so.
Because if he had read it,
he would have known
that it provides the same
funding for the public schools
as it does for
the scholarship program.
That's what we call compromise.
And we wrote it like that
so that people would not be able
to argue that we're somehow
undermining the public schools.
But, yet, sir, somehow,
here you are arguing
exactly that.
And you, Mr. Patterson,
or should I really just call you
&quot;Mr. Lobbyist&quot;?
Because, and I do think it is
important for this room
to know this,
this is not a neutral party.
This is one
of Lorraine Townsend's
biggest donors.
She is bought and paid for --
Ms. Walden.
Now, now, Ms. Townsend,
I have the floor.
I'm so tired of this --
so tired of trying to persuade
you all to do the right thing.
So now, I am just going
to flat out tell you
what you are going to do.
You are going to do right
by my son.
You are going
to do right by him
and the thousands of kids
in Washington, D.C.
just like him.
♪♪
This is America.
This is the land of opportunity.
There is no opportunity
if there is no education,
and you all know that is true.
So you cannot --
You must not --
♪♪
You will not deny our children
their right to learn.
♪♪
One last point.
[ Groans ]
[ Zipper unzips ]
♪♪
Way more than 7,000 people
signed up for this.
People want this.
And it is life or death
for them.
And -- and in fact,
the boy who collected
these signatures --
he got shot last night
trying to deliver them to me.
He was a dropout.
A drug dealer who just wanted
better for his little sister.
♪♪
Don't let his death
be in vain.
♪♪
[ Gavel bangs ]
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Mama?
Oh, baby.
Thanks, Ma.
♪♪
Thanks
Okay, guys, this is it.
The House votes
on our bill today.
And we are here at the Capitol
to make sure that every
one of those 435 representatives
understands what's at stake.
What's at stake for us.
The people of the District
of Columbia.
And we will be heard.
Voices.
Crowd: Choices!
Second chances.
Second chances!
Kids come first.
You got a permit?
Officer, please.
Our vote is today.
Hey, lady, lady, I got kids
of my own, okay?
I wish I could just turn my back
on all of this,
but we're getting
complaints.
Who is complaining?
Move or I'll have
to remove you myself.
Then you do
what you got to do.
[ Chanting &quot;Kids come first!&quot; ]
Put the megaphone down.
Kids come first!
[ Indistinct shouting ]
♪♪
[ &quot;The Price is Right&quot;
playing on television ]
♪♪
Barker: Mary, your bid.
[ Indistinct shouting ]
Mary: $850, Bob.
Her bid is --
Hi. Officer.
Officer.
Officer, please.
This is an emergency.
Man: $1,450, Bob.
What?
Could you please
put the TV on C-SPAN
so we can all watch
the House vote?
The actual retail price
is $868 --
[ Cheers and applause ]
You got kids?
Narrator:
Sprinkled with pollen --
the stigma is the green objet
on the right.
Almost all the pollen tubes
now grow toward the stigma.
So, that's government.
Yep.
What are they doing?
I'm not sure.
[ Gavel bangs ]
Madam Speaker:
The House is in the Committee
of the Whole House
of the State of the Union
for the further consideration
of H.R. 1956,
the D.C. Education
Incentive Act.
Narrator: This seed grew inside
a ripening apple.
If the seed is planted,
it will grow into a mature
plant that will flower.
If the stigma
of the flower --
What do you think
you're doing?
Madam Speaker: To provide
private school scholarships
to low-income District
of Columbia families.
Question is on
passage of the bill.
Those in favor, say &quot;aye.&quot;
Those opposed say &quot;no.&quot;
[ Gavel bangs ]
The no's have it.
[ People groan ]
Officer: That's it?
That's it.
Good.
&quot;Family Feud&quot; is
about to come on.
Wait.
Wait. Wait, wait, wait.
Wait, Virginia.
Virginia, come back.
♪♪
Madam Speaker, I'd like
to ask for a recorded vote
on the final passage.
Those favoring a recorded voe
will rise.
♪♪
Those in favor having risen,
a recorded vote is ordered.
Members will record their voe
by electronic device.
This is a 15-minute vote.
[ Gavel bangs ]
♪♪
[ Clears throat ]
Excuse me.
A little last-minute
whisper campaigning, Lorraine?
I bet you wish
you could vote today.
[ Button beeps ]
♪♪
It's not fair that the member
who doesn't get to vote
is the representative
from D.C.
I feel you.
I do.
No, you don't.
You're enjoying this.
On the contrary.
I find it tragic.
Almost as tragic as
the thousands that elected you
not actually
being represented by you.
How dare you?
Those are my people.
I know them.
Maybe.
But you don't listen
to them.
They want this bill,
and you want to block it.
If that's not failure to
represent, I don't know what is.
♪♪
-[ Laughs ]
-Yes!
♪♪
Dang, man.
[ Scoffs ] It's all good,
it's all good.
We still in this,
we still in this.
Okay, I can't take it,
I can't take it.
I can't take it,
It's okay.
♪♪
[ Indistinct conversations ]
[ Light applause ]
♪♪
What happens now?
Do they go to sudden death
or something?
[ People shushing ]
And that's that.
On a tie vote,
the motion loses.
&quot;Robert's Rules of Order,&quot;
Article 8, number 46.
Mm-hmm.
You got me there, Lorraine.
Oh! But...
♪♪
Madam Speaker:
And the &quot;ayes&quot; have it.
[ Cheering ]
♪♪
God, I love politics.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
Oh.
Mm!
♪♪
[ Indistinct conversations ]
Hi, Miss Virginia!
Oh, my goodness!
Delilah!
How are you, baby girl?
Oh!
I'm good.
Yes.
I believe it.
Hi.
Hey.
Sorry for your loss.
Thank you.
♪♪
If you fill out this form,
we can get
Delilah all signed up.
[ Chuckles ]
I don't write too good.
Okay.
I'll help.
I-I just want to do good
for Delilah.
I don't want her
to end up like me.
♪♪
I got you.
[ Chuckles ] Yeah.
Just sign this.
♪♪
Okay, great.
[ Indistinct conversation ]
♪♪
Great.
Thank you.
No problem.
♪♪
♪ If you hear this message ♪
♪ Wherever you stand ♪
♪ I'm calling every woman ♪
♪ Calling every man ♪
♪ We're the generation ♪
♪ Can't afford to wait ♪
♪ The future started
yesterday ♪
♪ And we're already late ♪
♪ And we ♪
♪ We've been looking
for a song to sing ♪
♪ Searched for the melody ♪
♪ Searched for someone
to lead ♪
♪ We've been looking
for the world to change ♪
♪ If you feel the same,
then go on say ♪
♪ If you're out there ♪
♪ Sing along with me ♪
♪ I'm going to believe ♪
♪ That you're out there ♪
♪ Stand up and say it loud ♪
♪ If you're out there ♪
♪ Tomorrow's starting now ♪
♪ Now, now ♪
♪ Oh, now ♪
♪♪
♪ If you're ready,
we can shake the world ♪
♪ Believe again ♪
♪ It starts within ♪
♪ We don't have to wait
for destiny ♪
♪ We should be the change
that we want to see ♪
♪ If you're out there ♪
♪ Ooooh ♪
♪ Ooh, if you're out there ♪
♪ And you're ready now ♪
♪ Say it loud ♪
♪ Scream it out ♪
♪ If you're out there ♪
♪ Sing along with me ♪
♪ I'm dying to believe ♪
♪ That you're out there ♪
♪ Stand up and say it loud ♪
♪ If you're out there ♪
♪ Tomorrow's starting now ♪
♪ Sing along with me ♪
♪ If you're out there ♪
♪ I'm dying to believe ♪
♪ That you're out there ♪
♪ Stand up and say it loud ♪
♪ If you're out there ♪
♪ Tomorrow's starting now ♪
♪ Now, now ♪
♪ If you're out there ♪
♪ If you hear this message ♪
♪ Wherever you stand ♪
♪ I'm calling every woman ♪
♪ Calling every man ♪
♪ We're the generation ♪
♪ We can't afford to wait ♪
♪ The future started
yesterday ♪
♪ And we're already late ♪