Around the Earth float hundreds
of gigantic space colonies.
Half of humanity now lives in space.
It is the year 0079
of the Universal Century.
The colonies of Side 3 declared themselves
the Principality of Zeon
and launched a war of independence
against the Earth Federation.
One month after the war broke out,
it reached a stalemate.
Eight months later,
a Zeon cruiser under the command
of Lieutenant Commander Char Aznable
entered the vicinity of Side 7.
If the Federation's new battleship
has come to Side 7,
they must be conducting the final tests
on their mobile suits.
Orders, sir?
We need to make sure.
Send in three Zakus to reconnoiter.
Due to the use of Minovsky particles
which render radar and other tools
of electronic warfare useless,
wars have come to be fought
at close range even in space.
The humanoid weapons developed
for this close-quarters warfare
were called mobile suits.
The Federation
had been slow to develop them.
However, a mobile suit that could stand up
to the Zeons' Zaku was nearly complete.
The power's on…
Amuro Ray, the son
of an immigrant weapons technician,
found himself sitting in the cockpit
of the new mobile suit Gundam.
Gate sensor, 360 degrees. All clear.
Your shoulders are too tense.
Relax. Let the computer handle this.
Yes, sir.
Run a system check!
Now exiting docking bay.
Now, with half the total population dead,
the ranks of both the Federation
and Zeon armies have been decimated.
Inexperienced young men
and women are sent into battle.
Newtype? A Newtype, you say?
From what I've heard,
Zeon has been looking into them.
They say they're like espers.
People with good intuition.
If we had men like that, the Zeon soldiers
in these parts would be wiped out by now.
I'll ram the Gaw into the Trojan Horse!
Perhaps this wait
for the appearance of Newtypes,
the next stage in human evolution,
was just the wishful thinking
of those who had grown war-weary.
Garma Zabi, youngest son of the Sovereign
of Zeon, attacked White Base.
The only reason its crew survived
was because they wanted to survive.
Glory to the Principality of Zeon!
During that battle, Amuro Ray's skill
as a soldier grew rapidly.
Amuro! Wait!
Amuro!
SOLDIERS OF SORROW
It has a fine ring, doesn't it?
Yes, sir. Is it a special piece?
It's a Hokuso, I believe.
What do you want?
A division under Revil's command
has crossed the Straits of Dover.
-Commander M'Quve!
-What?
We have news on the Trojan Horse!
It seems to have changed course
to south-southwest.
This isn't good.
It's shadowing Revil's division.
Uragan! Ramba Ral's unit
came down to avenge Garma.
Inform him of this.
If he can destroy the Trojan Horse,
I won't have to split my own forces.
We're under Kycilia Zabi's command.
Ral's unit is under Dozle's command!
We don't have to help them!
We can let them help us, though.
Sir!
-Give me the data.
-Sir!
The Federation Forces are advancing
on our defense line along eight routes.
M'Quve is giving us the location
of the Trojan Horse?
What's he up to?
He wants us gone.
This unit,
under Admiral Dozle's direct command,
is poking around
in Admiral Kycilia's jurisdiction.
A shooting star!
I didn't see anything.
You can still see them on Earth.
-That's because the air is still clean.
-True.
Darling?
Why did you accept this mission?
-You think I shouldn't have?
-No.
Like you said, this mission
is part of the Zabi family's vendetta.
If I destroy the Trojan Horse
and avenge Lord Garma's death.
I'll get a special two-rank promotion.
My men's prospects
are tied to my own success.
So this is for your men?
And for you. Through the Zabis,
we can live closer together.
Just watch.
I believe in you.
You're attacking the Trojan Horse
first thing tomorrow, right?
Let's turn in.
The 136th regiment's Matilda Unit
has made contact with White Base.
Now we just have to deploy two fleets
southwards to drive them from the rear.
That would seem to be
the most prudent course.
Is something bothering you,
Lieutenant General Elran?
Yes, sir. White Base will be the only ship
attacking from the right rear flank.
Do you really think they're Newtypes, sir?
You read the battle reports, didn't you?
It certainly leads me to believe
in the abilities of the Gundam's pilot.
But isn't it dangerous to assume
that White Base is a ship of Newtypes
based on less than two weeks' data?
Yes, but I can't spare any more units
from the front.
That Zeon soldier, Char, the Red Comet…
Rumor among the men
is that he's a Newtype.
Zeon Deikun used to say that Newtypes
are the next step in human reformation.
If he's right, it's only natural
for some of them to be in our army.
The Red Comet is an anomaly.
No one can destroy that many ships
with a single Zaku.
Then what about that boy, Amuro?
He was able to pilot our Gundam
without any training.
Surely that isn't normal either.
Good work.
Oh, Lieutenant Matilda!
What are those?
Parts for the Gundam.
I have to repair it myself anyway,
so I thought I'd sort them out.
That's very diligent of you.
-Where are you headed?
-Up to the bridge.
-I'll walk you there.
-That won't be necessary.
I have a system for that too.
I know a shortcut.
Good morning.
Morning.
Amuro!
What?
You said you'd fix the AC in my room
once you were done eating!
I did?
Jeez!
It's true! Up close,
that Lieutenant Matilda's a real babe!
She's my type.
She's a sharp dresser and she's sweet.
I wish I had a girlfriend like her.
I see some idle hands here.
Good morning, Lieutenant!
Find yourself a good girlfriend, okay?
I'm already humiliated, Lieutenant,
so I might as well ask…
If you don't mind,
can I get a picture with you?
Sure. How about now?
Sure! I'd be honored!
Cut it out! I can only make 12 copies!
-What's the holdup?
-Just take it already!
Okay, here goes…
Damn it!
Lieutenant Bright,
I've brought Lieutenant Matilda.
Thank you.
Sorry, I'm late.
-Is the ship ready to depart?
-Yes, in 30 minutes.
We'll cut through the desert and head
for the Black Sea via the Caspian Sea.
Excuse me.
Something's approaching.
It's one unit, but there's too much
Minovsky interference to get a read on it.
What do you think it is?
Probably a ground combat type. It's fast.
It's at one o'clock.
Sayla, can you see it?
No, sir!
-You're sure there's only one?
-Yes, sir!
Just one unit…
The pilot might know my brother…
I admire your courage.
But you don't look like
a soldier or guerrilla fighter.
Take off the helmet and turn around!
A Zeon soldier might've heard
something about my brother Casval…
Sayla!
You don't know what model it is?
It looks like a ground combat model,
but that's all we know.
That puts us at a disadvantage.
How do we fight something we don't know?
Starboard machine gunners!
Level 1 battle stations!
I want the Gundam, Guncannon,
and Guntank standing by!
Don't send them out yet.
Clamp, are the mobile suits in position?
Yes, ma'am. Watch this.
We'll attack the enemy's flank
in the Gallop
while Lieutenant Ral takes it out
with his three Zakus.
Very good.
The Gundam!
Job! Who's in the Gundam?
It's Sayla!
She said she had special orders!
You mean she lied?
I don't believe it… Sayla!
Catapult secure! Launch!
I thought I'd mastered this
in the simulator…
I didn't expect the G-force
to be this bad!
-Take us in closer!
-Yes, ma'am!
I have to make contact
with the Zeon soldiers…
Enemy units?
From the right?
Sayla! Get up!
Go!
Sayla!
What about the pilot?
Too bad the sand acted as a cushion…
Here he comes!
Where is he?
I have to force it into close combat…
Cozun! Don't be stupid! Pull back!
Watch this, Lieutenant Ral!
I'll capture this Mobile Suit!
The main camera!
He's destroying my cameras…
If we let that new model get close
to the Gundam,
we won't be able to save it!
That thing's just too fast!
Damn! The Zakus are too far apart.
Cozun! Are you okay?
I think so, sir.
I'll try to disable it myself.
Acous! Can you get past the red one
to get close to Cozun?
Yes, sir!
Damn! I'm out of ammo!
The red one!
Cozun! Get out of there now!
They just took out Acous!
They got Acous, sir?
What's going on?
Lieutenant Ral!
You'll pay for that!
Cozun!
Cozun, come in! Are you hit?
Hamon, do you read me?
Send in the Gallop! I'll meet you!
You'll obey the Antarctic Treaty's
POW provisions, I assume?
Of course.
I want three square meals a day.
I'm an officer, you know.
Well, well. Our Valkyrie returns.
Sayla.
Sayla!
I read you, Captain.
-Report to the bridge immediately.
-Yes, sir.
You wanted to prove that a woman
can fight as well as a man?
Is that the only reason?
Yes, sir.
Why did you do it? It's not like you.
We have to discipline you
to maintain order on this ship.
Three days of solitary. Understand?
I don't mind.
Take care of it, Ryu.
-Food for the prisoner?
-That's right.
You need more guards with you.
I'll do it, Fraw.
What a babe…
Who is the Red Comet?
The Red Comet? Why do you want to know?
Why wouldn't I? He's a legend.
His real name is Char Aznable.
They say he was a wanderer
who drifted to Zeon from Earth.
I heard he fell out of favor with Zeon
after he failed to protect Garma Zabi
from you guys.
He fell out of favor?
And is he really from Earth?
Yes.
That's why some people think
he may have a grudge against the Zabis.
It makes sense.
So he's no longer welcome
in the Zeon military?
Sayla!
Far from it.
I hear Kycilia has taken him in.
-Thanks.
-You shouldn't be talking to him.
Keep your chin up. It's only three days.
Don't worry about me, Ryu.
If you need anything, just let me know.
Thanks, Fraw.
He's my brother, all right…
Thank God…
Casval!
Why are you leaving?
How is it coming along?
Thanks to that Zaku we captured,
I know exactly what it can do now.
But how are you going to simulate
the Gouf suit the prisoner mentioned?
I use the Zaku's data,
and increase everything by 20%,
That's our Amuro, nothing ever stumps him.
Want me to take over?
Sure, thanks.
-You should get some sleep too, Amuro.
-Yes, ma'am.
Any progress, Bright?
Are all your female soldiers this young?
He refuses to believe
that I'm in command of this vessel.
Where is your Gallop's base,
Ensign Cozun Graham?
There are rules regarding
the treatment of enemy officers, you know.
I'm familiar
with the Antarctic Treaty, Ensign.
What can you tell me
about M'Quve's mining operation?
It's going to take more than this
to make me talk.
This Zaku's seen a lot of use.
Has it been checked out, Clamp?
It's been overhauled. It's fine.
The joints have been replaced
with new ones.
Good. Send back the Fat Uncle!
Okay! Get going!
Water!
Amuro, fix it! Fix the faucet!
The faucet?
Kikka!
Mirai's still in there, right? Go ask her.
Mirai, the faucet!
What's the matter?
Amuro, are you still there?
Check the faucet, will you?
Sure. Pardon me.
All right, let me see.
Kikka, where's the faucet handle?
It's in the sink.
It's fixed!
You're a lifesaver, Amuro.
Is it fixed now?
Yes, ma'am. Well, I'll be going now.
You won't be getting out anytime soon!
Amateurs! They don't even know
how to do a proper body search.
You're from Zeon, aren't you?
You can come with me if you want.
You misunderstood me.
If you're trying to escape,
I'll call the guards!
-What?
-The prisoner's escaping! Come quickly!
You bitch!
Missiles, sir!
Missiles! Horizontal launch!
M'Quve has a mining base this far east?
Sorry I took so long!
Infrared scope! Maximum magnification!
Amuro, get ready to launch the Gundam.
We'll attack their base!
Roger! Amuro, launching!
Amuro! Are you sure about this?
We're disobeying orders!
Relax, I don't need
the Gundam to destroy a mine.
The tank can do the job.
It's the Guntank! It's Amuro and Hayato!
What? Ryu's not in there?
-Number one hatch!
-Bright!
Ryu! Where are you?
Sayla says the prisoner has escaped!
What?
I'll have her look for him.
I'll go out in the Guntank!
The Guntank already launched.
-What?
-Too late to do anything about it now.
Hurry up and find the prisoner!
If need be, shoot to kill!
-Take care of it.
-Okay.
Thank you, Bright.
I'll find him, no matter what it takes.
Don't mention it.
Run a system check! Move it!
Why is this thing so hard to tune?
Got it!
Mustang 2, this is Cozun!
I'm calling from the Trojan Horse.
There you are, sir.
-Incoming transmission from Cozun!
-What? From Cozun?
There are three types:
Gundam, Guntank, and Guncannon.
There is only one of each
aboard the Trojan Horse.
I haven't seen any fighters, but…
Is someone in Comm Room 2?
What? Why would there be?
A comm channel is being used!
Put it on the monitor!
The TV line's been cut!
Kill the master comm circuit!
Yes, sir!
Damn it!
Bright, how much do you think
he's told them?
I don't know.
We already have those enemy guns
up there to worry about,
and now Ramba Ral's Gallop
is probably headed our way.
Right flank!
What did Commander M'Quve say?
That he can't send a single unit!
The EFF main force is attacking
from the European front!
Why are they attacking a mine
that has no strategic value?
-Lieutenant!
-What is it?
Ramba Ral's Gallop will back us up!
Ramba Ral?
Cozun, make it back in one piece…
Here he comes!
Defensive attack! Go get him, Haro!
Attack!
There he is…
The Trojan Horse and a tank?
That's strange…
The white one's not here,
but I'll cover you!
The Gouf!
Hayato, fall back! The Guntank's
no good against moving targets!
Kai, do you read me? Cover us!
Get serious, White Base!
One Guncannon can't handle this!
Understood! Mirai! Take us in!
Yes, sir!
Right flank!
Don't let that Gallop get any closer!
This should do the trick…
Sayla! Where's the prisoner?
In the airlock!
We have to stop him from escaping!
On it!
They won't be able to get through
with just a pistol.
Sayla! Get back!
Here goes…
Sayla…
Don't worry about it.
We may end up like that someday.
Right…
The suit's going to blow!
Guncannon retrieved! Retreat, Bright!
So the Zaku and the Gouf move differently
because of their pilots
and their environment…
Maybe I should rethink my approach.
I really don't think it's a good idea.
I've had Job and Omur run simulations.
Still…
The Guncannon isn't repaired yet?
They're making a replacement arm
in the machine shop.
You think Amuro's a Newtype, Mirai?
How else would you explain
everything he's accomplished so far?
I'll give you that, but there's no proof.
The question now
is how we're going to survive.
They say that Newtypes
are the next stage in human evolution.
If Amuro's showing signs of being one…
We don't have time
to wait for it to happen.
We should give the Gundam to someone else.
Bright!
He needs to be disciplined
before he develops a superiority complex.
Mirai, please. Back me up on this.
Amuro!
Were you listening?
-Amuro!
-Let him go!
This saves us the trouble
of explaining ourselves.
You think so?
Okay, next!
Amuro! Where are you going?
I'm leaving White Base.
Take care of yourself.
What?
I'm leaving the ship.
What happened?
Bright and Mirai say I'm not needed here,
so I'm leaving the ship.
-Wait!
-Don't try to stop me!
Amuro!
Lieutenant Bright! The Gundam's launching!
Gundam, come in! Who's the pilot?
The Gundam?
Come in!
Marker! Can't you close the hatch?
Too late! The catapult's firing!
It's Amuro! Amuro's in there!
Amuro!
Damn you, Amuro.
A tent?
Do you have any water?
I can't spare any.
There's a town nearby. Buy some there.
I see. Thanks.
Do you have anything to eat?
Newtypes aren't real.
It's all just wishful thinking.
-You think so?
-You don't?
How do you explain
Amuro's piloting skills?
I don't care if he's a Newtype.
He violated military regulations.
They're just on-the-spot draftees
and you keep talking about regulations!
This isn't fun anymore…
Look, Commander! A restaurant!
Let's take a break!
Innkeeper, we're taking a break here!
There's 13 of us.
I'll be right with you.
This way, Ms. Hamon!
Sorry, Sagred, Mile. You're on watch.
I'll send replacements soon.
-Yes, sir, Lieutenant Ramba Ral!
Ramba Ral?
Innkeeper, bring us some delicious water!
Sit down and eat whatever you want.
It's our last meal before the operation.
-Yes, sir!
-What will you have, darling?
-I'll let you decide.
If I may, Sodon is a neutral zone.
If you engage the enemy here--
We won't be fighting here. Relax.
There's not much on the menu.
Cook whatever you can for 14 people.
Yes, ma'am.
-There's only 13 of us, Hamon.
-It's for the young man over there.
Kind of young for you, isn't he?
Don't be silly.
Why didn't I think of it?
He has to get something to eat!
What's going on?
I do appreciate the gesture,
but I'm afraid I have to decline.
Why?
There's no reason for me
to accept a handout from you.
The boy has you there, Hamon!
How about because I like you?
Is that reason enough?
Well, that's…
It's rare for Hamon
to take a liking to someone, boy.
That's right.
If you turn her down, you'll regret it.
I envy you, kid.
Not every man is as lucky as you are!
I'm no beggar.
I like you, boy.
You don't mince your words.
It's not just Hamon's treat.
I'm paying too.
That makes it okay, right?
That's not the point…
Commander! We caught someone suspicious!
A spy?
A woman who was acting strange, sir!
What? She's just a child!
Fraw Bow!
A friend of yours?
Yes.
But she's wearing a Federation uniform!
-You think so? It's not quite the same.
-It's one of theirs, all right.
Is that true, Hamon?
So it would seem…
This boy says she's his girlfriend.
Amuro!
-Let her go.
-But--
Just do it.
I like that look in your eyes.
And you're brave.
You've earned my respect.
"Amuro," was it?
Yes, sir.
Don't expect me to let you go
when we meet on the battlefield.
Good luck, Amuro.
Thank you, Mr. Ral. You too, Ms. Hamon.
I appreciate it.
Amuro…
Let's go.
-Hey!
-Sir?
Follow them, Zeygan.
If there are Federation troops around,
the Trojan Horse must be here.
What's the matter with you?
I told you to leave me alone!
If you think we can't survive without you,
think again.
Look who's talking!
You got caught by Zeon soldiers!
And what about you?
Amuro!
Get in.
I bet you let go of my hand
because that woman was watching.
You're distancing yourself
further and further from me…
Bye.
-You're not going to White Base?
-No.
You better get back
before you get sunstroke.
You'll regret this!
-I'm free to live my life when I'm alone.
-You're so stubborn!
And I'm not going to regret it!
You saw the Gouf? The enemy mobile suit?
Yes. They must've been loaded
onto those two large trailers.
Did you run into Amuro?
Yes. He was also in Sodon.
I bet that bum Amuro told Zeon
about White Base!
Watch it, Kai!
We should stop the repairs
and prepare to intercept an attack.
There we go!
I can't believe he sent Fraw…
Bright should've come himself.
Because I like you.
Hamon likes you, you lucky dog!
Are they really the people
we're fighting against?
Fraw was followed!
A tank?
Hayato! Looks like two enemy units!
-Don't let them near White Base!
-Roger!
Stetch, I'm going airborne.
Take out that tank!
Yes sir, Lieutenant Ral!
Ryu! The caterpillar's hit!
Damn it!
Damn Zaku!
Ryu! I'm going to eject
the Guntank's upper half!
But what about you, Hayato?
You won't be able to move!
I'll keep the enemy at bay! Go find Amuro!
Roger that, Hayato!
Perfect, I can take them from behind!
A Zaku's approaching us from behind!
What? What about the aft missiles?
No one's manning them!
Full speed ahead!
That careless idiot!
Bastard!
Hayato! Kai! Listen!
Can you take out the Gouf from there?
Bright! I'll shake the Gouf loose!
What? Can you do it, Mirai?
I'm going to invert the ship!
Fasten your seatbelts!
-But what about you?
-I'll be fine.
Is that him?
If I use the beam rifle now, I won't be
able to use it against the Gouf!
Amuro! Do you read me? I'll keep him busy!
Head for White Base!
Ryu! You came for me?
I'm dead!
This must be the Gundam!
Where was it hiding?
Amuro! What took you so long?
Damn Gouf!
What precise shooting…
That makes it easy
for my computer to predict his moves.
To hell with this!
I only have one shot left anyway!
That's one determined pilot.
But that won't save him!
What?
Nice move, Gundam,
but my controls are still operational!
Here he comes!
I knew it!
You! The boy from town!
You only helped us
so you could follow us to White Base!
I can't believe it…
Times really have changed.
The boy's a pilot!
Well?
Well done! But you didn't win
because you were the better pilot, boy!
You only won because of the Gundam!
Never forget that!
What a sore loser!
Wait!
Not much choice. I'll wait until nightfall
and meet up with Hamon.
Going rogue is a serious offense!
No exceptions!
-The Gundam is no longer yours to pilot.
-Please listen to me!
I didn't leave White Base
because I wanted to!
I have an excuse!
But I don't have to listen to it.
Bright! You know you'll need me again
if Ral comes back!
Amuro!
Ryu…
Sayla and I can pilot the Gundam now.
Think about what that means, Amuro.
Ryu! Kai!
Ryu! Bright!
We'll have to work all night on repairs.
That Gallop may have been damaged,
but it'll be back.
Yes. Look, are you sure about Amuro?
You didn't have to put me in solitary!
Bright! Lieutenant Bright!
Or Mirai, if you're there…
Just listen to me!
There's something I want to say!
You blew it, Amuro…
I know you can hear me on the monitors!
I can use…
the Gundam better than anyone.
Better than anyone!
Don't get cocky! You didn't win
because you were the better pilot,
you only won because of the Gundam!
You've got guts.
Maybe that's why Hamon likes you.
It's my treat, Amuro.
I want to…
fight him again and win.
He's having trouble
with Revil's forces at Odessa?
Yes, sir. Commander M'Quve says
that's why he can't send reinforcements.
He asks that you capture
the Trojan Horse on your own, sir.
And he wants us to capture it undamaged?
Yes, sir.
How selfish.
I understand.
Tell him I'll complete the mission
with my bare hands if necessary.
-Yes, sir!
-Dismissed.
Excuse me, sir.
What are you going to do?
It's a chance to avenge
Garma's death. I have to do it.
We don't have much, but we can
hit them using guerrilla tactics.
-What do you say, Clamp?
-The troops will be glad to hear it, sir.
White Base will be our only support ship
on the right rear flank.
We don't have
any other land battleships to spare.
Is it wise
to rely so heavily on them, sir?
If they can't survive a risk
as small as this,
they can't be called a Newtype unit,
Lieutenant General Elran.
All that's left now
is to see how fast your team
can repair White Base's engines.
We'll do our best.
And there's something
I'd like you to deliver to White Base.
They'll probably be angry with us
for using them as guinea pigs again.
I want them to test the Core Booster.
"Booster," sir?
-Here's the inventory.
-Very well, sir.
These are our three Doms for land battle!
You can count on us, Commander M'Quve.
The Gaia Unit's strength
will equal that of a full division.
First, we attack Revil's front.
Then the Trojan Horse.
Isn't that a little naive?
They're Newtypes, aren't they?
I don't believe
in the existence of Newtypes.
That's because you don't fight
on the frontline, sir.
The Trojan Horse is a formidable enemy.
We mustn't underestimate it.
They win because you only think
in terms of brute force.
Zaku! Ghien! Launch! Next, the Cui!
All right, young man.
How will you make your entrance, I wonder?
All hands, wake up! Oscar! Marker!
Sayla! What's the count?
Unknown!
-Start the engines!
-Yes, sir!
I'll go out in the Gundam!
Roger! Now opening
forward surveillance camera!
Hurry up with a firing solution!
Open the main cannons!
It's the Gallop!
Lieutenant Bright!
The Gundam is ready to launch!
Thanks, Sayla.
Here I go!
-Two tanks closing in from behind!
-What?
-Cancel mobile suit launch!
All hands, prepare for close combat!
What?
-Prepare for close combat!
-Close combat?
Hurry! They're coming in from behind!
Fraw, let Amuro out of solitary.
The door will open
with a type 6E key. Got that?
Amuro! You have orders to fight!
-Where's the Gundam?
-Sayla launched it.
They want you
to man a starboard machine gun.
Understood.
Sorry I'm late!
A backwards jump!
I see it!
Charge!
Here they come!
Where is he? Where's Ramba Ral?
It's no use! The Gundam's weapons
are just too powerful!
I don't want to damage the ship!
You jerk! Go away! Get off the ship!
What? What's this kid doing here?
Get back! You'll get hurt!
Get away from there!
Oscar and Marker,
guard the entrance to the bridge!
-Job John, take the front!
-Yes, ma'am!
I can make it!
There's one!
Hatch 78's been breached!
What?
Bastard!
I can fight without the Gundam!
Go get the Gundam from Sayla!
Use it to drive the enemy
out of the secondary bridge!
But how?
-Destroy the bridge if you have to!
-Yes, sir!
Sayla!
-It's all yours, Amuro!
-Thanks!
-The enemy?
-Secondary bridge!
Got it!
Don't you think it's weird?
These soldiers are all kids…
They must be short on men too.
It's opening!
Enemy soldiers!
-Straight ahead!
-Not on my watch!
Cut the circuits to the main bridge.
Yes, sir!
You! You're Lady Artesia!
I'd recognize you anywhere.
Don't you remember me?
I'm Ramba Ral, the son of Jimba Ral!
He was in the revolution
with your father, Zeon Deikun!
Why are you pointing a gun
at me if you know I'm Artesia?
But why are you on this warship?
Sayla! Move back!
Ryu!
Ramba Ral! Go!
Amuro, do you read me?
They've taken the secondary bridge!
Destroy it!
Roger!
-Have you made contact with Hamon?
-Yes, sir! I've set the frequency!
I want all of you to withdraw!
The mission's a failure!
Darling?
I'm sorry, Hamon…
Destroy the Trojan Horse with the Gallop.
It's my fault.
I lowered my defenses and forgot to fight…
What happened?
That boy in the Gundam again?
Pay close attention.
This is what it means…
to be defeated in battle!
Ral…
Ms. Hamon! Mr. Ral's dead!
Stop!
Eject the bridge!
Was it that boy?
Ramba Ral… Hamon…
Plane 4 to Plane 1! We can't go on!
Go on without us!
Roger!
Can we fly at a lower altitude?
Yes, ma'am.
How many enemy units are there?
Two, I think.
Looks like they won't overlook
even a small group like ours.
-Can we make it?
-Yes, ma'am!
Using this battle as a signal,
the Federation Forces launched an attack
against the special mining base
protected by M'Quve's forces.
This was the commencement
of Operation Odessa.
If the Federation won here,
they would avoid a protracted war,
even out in space.
I can't do it!
You have the aptitude for it.
You can do it.
-Bring in the Core Booster set!
-Yes, ma'am.
Do you really think Amuro
and Sayla have Newtype abilities?
They'll decide that at Jaburo.
Personally, I don't know.
All I can say is that
their records indicate it.
So we'll test them.
They'll be our guinea pigs.
I can't believe you're treating us
like guinea pigs…
According to Zeon Deikun,
the founder of the Principality of Zeon,
mankind will evolve to meet the needs
of the space age.
I find that entirely possible.
So you're saying that our powers
of perception will expand,
-and we'll understand each other better?
-That's right.
Is increased perception linked
to an increase in piloting ability?
We're running these tests to find out.
Don't you find this inhuman?
No, I don't.
We have a sample by the name
of Chief Petty Officer Amuro.
Amuro?
Check over the Core Booster
once it's loaded into position!
So they built the Core Booster
and long-range weaponry, Lieutenant?
Right. And this keeps the costs down.
White Base's engines need to be tuned too.
Will there be enough time?
-I'll get them both done.
-But…
If we don't want to die,
it has to be done.
My crew will help.
Something's approaching security line 1!
-An enemy unit?
-Unknown!
-Mirai, can you start the engines?
-Yes, sir!
I want that unit identified.
Engines 1, 3, 4, 7…
It's an attack!
All clear!
Get Medea 3 out of White Base's way!
Tell Sayla that she may be sent out.
Sayla?
Forget about the engines that aren't
fixed! Just give me the usable ones!
They could send out Kai
or Hayato, or even Amuro…
Damn this body…
Just put electromagnetic coil tuners 38-52
into the blue zone!
This is just a scratch…
I don't mind having the control system
up top, but will it work okay?
Hayato, you going to be okay
flying solo from now on?
If you can do it, so can I!
They're all pretty much the same!
You could pilot the Gundam, right, Sayla?
-Are you being sarcastic?
-Hurry!
No! You're a Newtype too, aren't you?
Launch the Gundam immediately!
Tell the bridge to launch the Core Booster
if the situation warrants it!
Yes, ma'am! We'll hold off
on launching the Core Booster!
The power system gain
is 1.5 higher than the simulator.
Understood.
Do you really think I can do it?
If this isn't a Newtype experiment,
you'll be in serious trouble
for commandeering the Gundam.
General Revil is just trying to help you.
For a supply unit commander, you're…
Gundam, launch!
…surprisingly well-informed.
There's nothing organized
about military organizations.
People who can do everything
are worth their weight in gold.
Zeon Deikun's Newtypes
aren't just a bunch of handymen.
I know that.
-Should I have an expert look at that?
-Yes, ma'am!
Fraw Bow! Have Lieutenant Matilda
and Captain Seki
report to the bridge at once!
What's the matter with White Base?
Why haven't we lifted off?
Main engine output isn't rising.
What?
-Just follow Amuro!
-Yes, sir!
-How many enemy units are there?
-Three, sir!
To the left?
What?
This just isn't going to work…
Okay! Go!
Where's that white bastard hiding?
The sync motor's fine?
That doesn't make sense.
Everything's fine here, too.
Recheck everything!
The other engines
can't reach criticality either?
That can't be right!
We might be a little late.
Why do you think that?
No reason. I just think so.
Why, Mirai?
What?
It's nothing.
You're a worrywart, aren't you?
I suppose. Everyone says so.
Amuro, Sayla… Kai, Hayato…
What's wrong with me?
I can't even slow this guy down!
-Captain Seki!
-Is it fixed?
Watch the left flank!
Pressure's come up on engines 2 and 3.
The rest are hopeless.
Their pressure's falling!
We've figured out the problem.
Give me three minutes.
Finish it in two!
A mobile suit?
Damn! Now they're attacking White Base!
This Federation suit isn't all that tough!
I won't let them damage White Base!
Not on my watch!
-Launch! Hurry!
-Yes, ma'am!
That damn suit!
Is it trying to destroy White Base first?
That damn pilot's a Newtype, all right!
Ortega! Mash! We're going to hit that suit
with a Jet Stream Attack!
Damn it! What's he up to?
It'll work!
Use the Jet Stream Attack again!
The Medea? Who's in it?
Damn!
He used me as a springboard!
Bastard!
He took out Mash's Dom!
He slipped out of the Jet Stream Attack!
I can't believe it!
Here come reinforcements!
You're not getting away!
Course clear!
Core Booster, launch when ready!
-I missed!
-Is that Sayla's Core Booster?
Mash… Ortega…
Destroyed by a single mobile suit…
And so, M'Quve's forces
were forced to retreat
in the face of the Federation's
overwhelming material superiority.
Towards the end of that fight,
a small unit found itself near White Base.
I only have one Zaku,
a Samson with four machine guns,
and my Magella Tops' three main cannons.
But the strength of 18 devoted men
will be enough.
Ramba Ral, I'll avenge your death,
and that of Lord Garma.
It's my way of thanking you
for the affection you showed me.
Allow me to do this for you.
And if that boy should try to interfere…
Darling, please watch over us.
It's not working. The Minovsky Craft
output isn't powerful enough.
Check the output of the main engine again!
Gundam! Go forward by 10km
and set up a perimeter!
What? Oh, right.
What's wrong?
Understood.
-Send out the Guncannon too!
-Yes, sir.
Where's Sayla?
What's the Core Booster's status?
Calm down, Bright.
You can replace the tread
on the Guntank, right?
That shouldn't be hard to fix.
I'm calm!
Operation Odessa is underway.
What's wrong with doing everything I can
to carry out our duties?
I get that, but still…
I could've sworn I saw Matilda…
-I know I did…
-We're under attack?
-The Guntank's finally fixed!
-Amuro, what are you doing?
What? It's not just a Zaku?
Damn it, they didn't fix the engine!
Just as I expected, Trojan Horse.
You've been damaged.
What kind of unit is this?
Why? What am I fighting for?
The Guntank's malfunctioning?
Mirai! Can't we move White Base?
Damn it!
Ryu! You shouldn't be up!
I'm not going to call in sick
when White Base is being destroyed!
I guess you're right, but…
What are you fighting for, Matilda?
Good question.
I joined a supply unit
hoping I would be able to build something
among all the death and destruction.
Zeon bastards!
Where's the boy?
It's her!
You won't let me kill myself, boy?
You'll never stop us all
with just your Gundam.
If I ram the Trojan Horse,
the explosives inside it…
Tachi! Finish off the Gundam from behind!
Lady Hamon!
From above? Will this work?
I expected nothing less from you.
But you can't stop us.
Damn!
No matter how much armor it has,
it can't withstand a shot at this range.
The blast from the Gundam and my cargo
will destroy the Trojan Horse!
Ms. Hamon?
I really liked you, boy.
Don't worry.
-Ryu!
-What?
A Core Fighter? Who was in there?
There, unheeding of the life
and death of the soldiers in the rear,
both sides struggled
on the main battlefield.
The outcome of the war
won't be decided by this battle.
Just think, the resources
we sent Her Highness Kycilia
will allow Zeon
to fight for another ten years.
What? What did I do?
Why didn't you stop him? Ryu was injured!
He ejected the top half
of the Guntank from outside
and got into the Core Fighter!
You could've stopped him!
With all those enemy units around?
-You're a soldier too, Hayato!
-Enough!
Stop it! Stop it, you two!
What good will this do?
You can't bring back the dead.
For all of the soldiers
we lost in Operation Odessa…
As an expression of our sorrow…
All hands! Salute!
I'm sorry I couldn't do better, Matilda…
Matilda…
Matilda!
Unknown warship sighted.
Will begin reconnaissance.
Message from 107.
A large warship has docked in Belfast.
The photo's no good.
Too much noise from the jammers.
Let me see.
I can't tell from this.
Boone's unit is in that area, right?
-Yes, sir!
-Ready the Sealance!
Surface the Mad Angler
once you're sure it's clear.
Surely Boone can handle this, sir?
If it's the Trojan Horse,
I want to verify it myself.
Lady Kycilia finds it amusing,
but I can be stubborn about some things.
Very well, sir. The Mad Angler
will be waiting here for you.
Thanks, Mulligan.
I come across the Trojan Horse
right after I'm sent to the Mad Angler…
I can't believe my luck.
According to their report,
external repairs will be done in a day.
I'd prefer to give them a week off,
but we all know that's not possible..
What a pain…
Hey, soldier!
Would you like to buy something?
Really?
You're trying to sell me that crap?
They're all local goods.
They're delicious!
You're cute. Looks like you're down
on your luck, though.
-Then buy something!
-Bye!
Tightwad!
-Buy something?
-No, thanks.
What do you want to do for fun this time?
Fraw? What's wrong?
It's nothing.
-Keep up the good work!
-At ease!
If you say so.
Hey!
-Where are they?
-They've been assembled, sir!
Stop that, you little--
Excuse me, sir!
Attention!
Salute General Revil!
-Yes, sir!
Just you wait!
Salute!
Thank you. Please, have a seat.
At ease!
No words can express our gratitude
for your actions since you left Side 7.
-Excuse me.
You will leave here for Jaburo
to undergo Newtype testing.
I have a question, sir.
Could you explain what a Newtype is?
I think of them as people
with excellent intuition and insight.
But I don't know
if the military agrees with me.
The military?
It's complicated.
Even if human perception expands
due to a change in environment,
we don't know how many people
are capable of evolving this way.
Anything else?
-I feel sick. May I be excused?
-Go ahead.
General?
Yes?
About the children on board, sir…
Jaburo has facilities to take them in.
There's nothing to worry about.
This ain't funny…
They're planning on staying on this ship
for the rest of their lives.
The Gogg will reach the Trojan Horse
in 40 minutes.
Good. After it launches,
we'll wait here for Captain Char.
I bet it's true.
I think so, too.
-Hurry up with the repairs.
-Yes, sir!
-You too, Captain.
Kai!
Kai! Where are you going?
Sorry, pal,
but being a soldier just isn't my thing.
-Kai?
-What?
I'll admit that you grate
on my nerves sometimes.
But we've been through so much together.
You're one of us!
That's nice of you, Amuro.
Take care of yourself.
Kai!
I've authorized his departure
under the pretext of shore leave.
Let him go.
Kai!
That's the Captain, all right!
That guy's amazing!
I've lost the signal from Area 22!
Go to alert status!
I knew it!
That's my Gogg! Shook it right off!
Freeze Gel, launch!
Maybe I should offer my services
as an electrician.
Hey, Mr. Soldier.
You again?
Why are you dressed like that?
Did they fire you?
Something like that.
You don't have a place to stay, right?
Come over to my place.
Are you sure?
So? What's your angle?
Don't be silly. I'm just saying
you're welcome to stay for a few days.
I'm Miharu.
My brother and sister live with me.
I hope you don't mind.
How long will you be in port?
Worried about White Base?
No, I like ships, that's all.
Well, White Base may be a ship,
but it's a spaceship.
I see.
Yes?
Nothing. Never mind.
You must be tired.
I'll bring you a blanket.
-What?
-Just make yourself at home.
They taught her well.
If he goes outside,
tell me right away, okay?
Okay.
I knew it.
-Sorry for the trouble.
-Don't worry about it.
White Base is leaving port tonight.
The right engine's
still giving them some trouble.
If the engine goes,
it'll have to stay here.
Kai…
Hey, don't sweat it.
I know what it's like having to worry
about your younger siblings.
These images were taken
by a Gogg on patrol.
That's the Trojan Horse, all right.
107 reports that she has made contact
with one of its crew members.
Reports say it's in Belfast, right?
Have her sneak aboard the Trojan Horse
and find out where it's going.
The civilian spy, sir?
Yes. According to the rumors,
this is piloted by a Newtype.
We need to know where it's headed,
the African front
or Jaburo in South America.
Yes, sir!
I want to find out for sure
and destroy it.
Looks like I'll be able to sneak in.
Captain Boone, I'd like some support fire.
Make sure we're ready
to go to South America if necessary.
It's time. Launch missiles!
Missiles detected!
In Area 22?
No, Area 54!
Launch Sayla's Core Booster!
The Guncannon should be good to go too!
Yes, sir! Open the dock!
Prepare to launch Core Booster!
-We need a few more minutes!
-Get real, this thing won't move!
They had to attack now?
Damn it!
Send out Connolly's boat!
Hey! Where did your sister go?
-She'll be right back.
-She went shopping.
Really?
It's true!
Okay, I'll believe you.
Are they attacking from the sea?
He stole my bike!
The army needs it! You'll get it back!
Hello. Are you in a hurry?
It's you?
No, I'm in no real hurry.
Why did you ask to meet here,
of all places?
I'm new at this. I didn't think
someone like you would be our spy.
Here's your payment in gold.
You're to sneak aboard the Trojan Horse
and find out where it's headed.
How?
That's up to you. Just sneak aboard.
This is a lot.
You'll do it, right? If you succeed,
there's more to where that came from.
Here.
There's a Federation uniform in there.
Papers from the ship's captain too.
Okay, I'll do it.
I have my younger siblings to feed.
How noble. Well, I'd better go.
Here it comes. Looks like a bomber,
judging from the silhouette.
Have the Gogg out there attack it.
Prepare for ground-to-air combat!
-You weren't scared, were you?
-Of course not!
-Where is he?
-He left with his bags a while ago.
Did he say anything?
He said, "Hang in there."
"Hang in there"?
Kai…
Listen… I have a job to do.
I might be gone for a while this time.
Use the money a little at a time.
Don't tell anyone where it is, okay?
We'll be fine.
Once I'm done, the three of us
will go where there isn't any fighting.
Stay strong. I know you two can do it.
We'll be okay.
Miharu?
You smell like Mom.
Sorry, I didn't mean
to bring up old memories…
Four o'clock aft!
A mobile suit just appeared!
Hayato! What's the matter?
Go out in the Guncannon!
I'm heading out now!
The beam rifle's ready, right?
I just…
Damn it!
Why am I worried about White Base now?
Isn't there something you should be doing?
Coward!
You call yourself a man?
Yes… Maybe I am a coward.
There!
Can you fix it?
-I'll try!
-I'm counting on you!
Stop! I'm with the military! Stop!
Come pick it up at the base, okay?
Where's the Gundam?
And where's the Guntank?
It's right here! Why is it sitting here?
Kai! Can you give me a hand?
The shaft repairs are finally complete!
Hayato already launched in the Guncannon!
Well, since you asked…
It's hopeless! I've taken too many hits!
I'm losing power!
The tank?
You've had fun long enough, pal!
What the--
Bastard!
I've sunk the Jukon!
No sign of the other ship.
Back off!
You're mine!
First, find the wardroom.
Find out where they're headed.
Then find out whatever you can
about the Trojan Horse.
Find the above information.
Make contact at 05:00 hours.
Captain Bright!
They need you on the bridge!
Is he up there already?
What was that?
Did I tear something?
Kai!
Don't scare me like that!
Who's down there?
Sorry, I didn't mean to scare you.
What the heck? Miharu?
Jeez!
Come on!
-I missed you.
-Liar.
It's true!
Really? You missed me?
This is my room.
Who was that?
None of your business, so don't ask.
Your girlfriend?
Something like that.
I'm dropping her off at Jaburo,
so keep this under your hat, okay?
Jaburo?
Don't worry. I didn't see anything.
Thanks!
Don't leave the room.
Don't snoop around,
not until we get there.
-All right.
-Good.
Civilian plane at four o'clock.
It's sending out an SOS.
An SOS? Is it really a civilian plane?
Well, Fraw?
Yes, sir. I have verification.
I checked the registration number.
It's registered
to the Verde Islands Fishing Union.
Okay. Tell them to come aboard
through the aft hatch.
Yes, sir.
We're probably the first Zeons
to sneak aboard the Trojan Horse.
Probably.
Keep your mouth shut.
Your Zeon accent's too strong.
Yes, sir.
Thanks!
Hurry up! It's going to ignite!
We were out looking for fish,
and a Zeon plane
started taking pot shots at us for fun.
-When was this?
-About 20 minutes ago.
A dud 20mm slug did this, I bet.
We'll patch you up
and give you enough fuel to make it home.
I appreciate it.
But you have to stay in that room.
Everything else is off-limits.
I understand. Hey, Carioca!
I'll send the repair bill to your union.
Keep it cheap, okay?
I wonder if there's actually
someone around to take that bill?
Good question.
Well, then…
Where's the toilet?
-Down the hall, on the right.
-Thanks.
There, on the right!
That's as far as you go.
I see it, thanks.
Can't blame him for being curious.
There's the signal!
107! Answer if it's safe to talk.
-What's the Trojan Horse's destination?
-The spaceport at Jaburo.
-Excellent. What else?
-I'm still working on it.
Well done. Keep up the good work.
That's better!
What have you been up to?
Have you made contact?
Don't you think it's strange
you can contact them from out here?
I guess. But it doesn't matter,
I have to do this to feed my family.
I get that. But still…
I'm making trouble for you, aren't I?
Me being a spy and all…
Well, yeah. Hey, wait a minute!
There's a civilian plane on board!
It's them!
You're talking to them by radio!
Damn it! Hold it!
They're spies! Shoot them down!
What are you talking about? They're just--
You idiot!
Looks like you were successful, Boone.
So they're not going to the African front?
No. They're heading for the spaceport
at Jaburo. No doubt about it, sir.
This is our chance.
While we're tailing the Trojan Horse,
I can send our forces at California Base
and the African front to Jaburo.
Please Captain.
Let me borrow a mobile armor.
A Grublo? It's been prepped, but…
I don't want to say I'm out for revenge,
but I've lost three suits.
Let me do it.
With a mobile armor, I can
catch the Trojan Horse, even from here.
There are children here?
How does it look?
Bad! You've been using
the Gundam too much!
Where did the shells hit?
Deck 2!
Give me a damage report!
That was a direct hit!
Put on this survival gear!
Dying won't do anybody any good!
What about you?
We're being attacked!
Let me help!
There's nothing you can do to help!
-This is all my fault!
-Hey…
I just leaked that information,
and now your ship is under attack!
That information wouldn't
make them hit us like this.
I'm sorry, Kai! I've set you up!
What?
Launch the Core Fighter ASAP!
There!
All decks, damage report!
What's keeping the Guncannon?
The catapult's been hit!
The Gunperry can make it out!
Kai, go to deck 3!
We'll launch the Gunperry!
-Kai, get to deck 3!
-Don't follow me!
You're not getting away, you bastard!
He's mine!
Godard's Z'gok!
Bastard!
I have you!
Activate fire extinguishers!
Damn!
Are you okay?
I'm okay! It'll take more than that!
Don't cry over something like that!
Kai, let me fight!
I can't let these children die
to save my brother and sister!
Get it together! The fire isn't out yet!
I have to break free from Zeon.
I'm done being their puppet!
I can't just stand by and watch anymore!
But you can't--
Kai! Launch!
Roger! Hey, what happened to Job?
He can't leave the machine guns!
Come with me! I need a gunner!
You can at least fire
a missile, can't you?
Sure! Just tell me how!
Fire when the scope crosshairs
overlap with the enemy blip, okay?
-Got it.
-Over there!
I'm out of rounds and missiles!
He's all yours, Kai!
Roger!
Push the levers one at a time. Steady now!
Got it.
-Missed! Next!
-Okay.
Miharu! Shoot!
I pushed the lever, but it's not firing!
What? Why now?
It's useless! That blast just now
took out the power circuits!
How can we destroy it?
We could pull the levers
beside the catapult.
Miharu! Where are you going?
The levers are by the catapult, right?
Miharu! It's too dangerous!
This must be it…
Miharu! You have to do it just right,
or it won't work! Understand?
Kai! Keep it steady so I can aim!
Ready? Here he comes! Five! Four!
Kai! He's coming to us!
You did it! Miharu, you did it!
Miharu? What's wrong?
Get up here! Miharu!
Kai, be careful! Come back aboard!
Roger!
Miharu's gone?
Yes. Kai says she went out with him
in the Gunperry.
Who is she? Do you know her?
No, sir. I've never heard of her.
-How about you?
-No.
She was a stowaway.
A stowaway?
You knew about her?
Not really.
I saw a woman enter Kai's quarters,
but we were attacked right after, so…
Miharu… I lost you…
Miharu…
Hey, don't cry. I'm glad I met you.
Gil and Milly? Those two will be fine.
They're my kid brother
and sister, after all.
They'll be fine.
The world won't stay this way forever.
Right, Kai?
What, you don't mind that you died?
Nothing good ever comes out of dying!
I just wasn't lucky.
I wanted to be with you, Kai.
Nothing good ever comes of dying…
No doubt about it.
The Trojan Horse is headed for Jaburo.
Just as our spy has reported.
Don't let it get away.
Butterflies!
Aren't they beautiful?
They're amazing…
This is Jaburo? I don't see anything!
Look!
Landing completed.
I've lost the Trojan Horse!
Which means we've discovered
Jaburo's largest entrance.
I want a thorough search of the area
where we lost the signal!
Tell California Base
to prepare to scramble!
They're hurt pretty bad.
It's worse than they reported.
White Base has seen
one battle after another.
Okay! Begin inspection!
Begin inspection!
Teams 1 and 2, begin inspection!
Captain Woody? I'm Bright Noa,
the man in charge of White Base.
Well done.
Is there a young man named Amuro Ray?
-Yes, sir. Amuro!
-Sir!
-That's Amuro?
-Yes, sir.
He's just a boy!
Sir?
-I see, so you pilot the Gundam?
-Yes, sir.
Matilda told me about you.
Lieutenant Matilda?
Thank you.
Man, these physicals are a pain.
No kidding.
Yours sure took a long time, Amuro.
I wonder if you have Newtype potential.
No, these guys have never
subscribed to the Newtype theory.
Kai!
They said I'm perfectly healthy
in every possible way.
It's not like there are any
established Newtype standards.
Come back here!
Katz! Letz! Be quiet!
-There's nothing wrong with us!
-We're totally fine!
You don't seem to have cavities.
-Excuse me, sir.
-Take care of it.
Captain Woody.
Oh, Amuro.
Aren't you going to sleep?
Being a supervisor has its drawbacks.
Is there anything I can do to help?
While you're here at Jaburo,
let us take care of things.
Thank you.
About you and Lieutenant Matilda…
We had planned to get married
after Operation Odessa.
-Married?
-Yes.
Matilda said she wanted to invite
the White Base crew to the ceremony
since you'd all be here at Jaburo.
Oh, I see. I didn't know.
I'm sorry, Captain Woody.
If I had been a better pilot,
Lieutenant Matilda would still be alive.
I'm sorry.
You think too highly of yourself.
Don't try to tell me that the actions
of a single Gundam
could have saved Matilda or ended the war.
But…
A pilot should give it
everything he's got during battle
and make sure he doesn't
regret his actions later.
Yes, sir.
I love this White Base
that Matilda worked on.
So I'm doing everything I can
to repair it.
Yes, sir.
That's all a man can do.
I found it! It's the entrance to Jaburo!
I would've missed it if it weren't
for that metallic signature.
Do we attack, sir?
No, that would give away our location.
Hold your fire!
Two are underwater combat Goggs.
The one other isn't in the computer.
A new mobile suit model?
The routine flight should be coming soon.
How's the south block look?
Regular Zeon bombing of south block
commencing on schedule.
Roger!
What's the point in regular reports
from a remote outpost like ours?
Don't complain. They're flying patrols
to earn their pay, too.
What is it?
A scheduled enemy bombardment?
There's no need to worry.
White Base's crew will remain as-is.
You are now the 13th Independent Unit
of the Tianem Fleet.
I will now hand out written orders
to each crewman.
-Lieutenant Bright Noa.
-Yes, sir!
Ensign Mirai Yashima.
Yes, sir!
-Warrant Officer Sayla Mass.
-Yes, sir!
What's the point
of these empty formalities?
Ensign Amuro Ray.
Yes, sir!
-Ensign Kai Shiden.
-Yes, sir!
Master Chief Petty Officer
Hayato Kobayashi.
The last time I got something like this
was when I graduated from grade school.
Seaman Fraw Bow. Is she here?
No! I don't want to!
Come back here!
Excuse me.
No! We're not going anywhere!
Yeah!
We're not going to leave!
What was that all about?
Those kids refuse
to go to the childcare center.
What willful children!
That's my specialty.
I'll try to talk them into it.
Come with me.
Yes, ma'am.
-Take your written orders!
-Yes, sir.
Furthermore, Ryu Jose,
who died valiantly in battle,
shall receive a special
three-rank promotion to lieutenant.
Three ranks?
A three-rank promotion? That's it?
Is that all, sir?
You can write off our dead
with just a three-rank promotion?
What? What are you saying?
You didn't do anything for us
when we were fighting.
This promotion thing is stupid.
The least you could do
is thank Ryu and the others!
Drop it, Amuro!
Why, you little…
Why did you dodge, you little shit?
Do it again and I'll throw you in a cell!
You talk too much. Getting smacked
once in a while will do you some good.
All right already…
How are Kikka and the others doing?
The lady from the the childcare center
is looking for them.
But I wonder if those kids
will ever be happy here…
We have to leave them here.
Why?
Little kids shouldn't
see people killing each other.
Maybe you're right.
The routine flights
have increased in frequency.
Are you used to them yet, Mirai?
Yes, sir.
If your father were still alive,
this war would probably be over soon.
I'd rather you didn't talk
about my father, sir.
We're trying to do right by your father.
We don't know what to do with White Base,
not with someone like you on board.
But that's…
To get to the point,
because of your achievements,
we made White Base the Newtype Unit
of the 13th Autonomous Corps
under the Tianem Fleet.
Your primary duties will be
to provide a show of force.
And so, once White Base's repairs
are completed, it will leave for space.
The Tianem Fleet
will go directly to Luna II,
so you will take a retrograde orbit
on a path to capture Solomon.
These orders aren't final.
You'll probably receive new orders later.
Be careful, Ensign Mirai.
Thank you, Admiral.
Don't worry.
Once Solomon falls,
Zeon will come to us with a peace treaty.
That would be the end of the war.
I hope you'll let me
find you a husband then.
Of course.
Oh, right. You have a fiancé.
Sorry about that.
No, it's…
He may be my fiancé,
but it was arranged by our parents.
Where is he?
I heard that he fled to Side 6
to avoid the war.
Things worked out for the best.
Right.
Sir, they moved up our departure time.
Will the ship be ready?
Don't worry about it.
Our orders are always changing.
Welcome back!
We're finally going back into space.
Make sure every block is airtight!
Hey, where's the captain of White Base?
What do you want with him?
Where is he?
Lieutenant Bright! You have a visitor!
Who is it?
I'm Lieutenant Sleggar Law.
I was transferred here today.
Mirai, can you confirm this?
Here it is!
Man, am I lucky to be on the same ship
as a pretty lady like you!
I'm Ensign Mirai. Pleased to meet you.
Pleasure's all mine.
Hello, miss.
I'm Sayla Mass.
You look like
you're having trouble with a man.
Where's my bunk?
Come back! Can't you hear me?
Answer me! Kikka! Katz! Letz!
Someone's coming!
Hold it! It sounds like kids.
Come on, Kikka!
Katz, you're going to slip! Be careful!
Katz!
I'm coming.
That was close.
Captain Char…
The Federation's come this far?
Those are probably just part of it.
Impressive as ever, Captain.
No, the Federation Forces are.
-Team Ramsey will plant the bombs here.
-Yes, sir!
Team Akahana and I will head
for the Trojan Horse's dock.
Yes, sir!
I can't go any farther!
-Hang in there, Kikka!
-I want to rest!
-Well, if you have to…
-Hey, this door is open!
Really?
Kikka, we'll rest in there for a while.
Then we'll go back to the ship.
How much longer?
Five minutes should do it.
Hold it! Hide!
-It smells in here!
-It's deserted.
Look! Gundam!
-Wow!
-Wow! There are lots of them!
It's a little different from the Gundam.
Now that you mention it,
they're a lot different.
-Down by its foot!
-What?
Something moved!
You're imagining things.
I can't see anything.
But it's true! I saw something move!
It might've been a person!
A person? If it is, it's bad news!
Let's hide!
This way!
The center should've called by now.
They haven't returned to White Base.
They're wandering around somewhere…
That woman's from the center!
Just the people I wanted to see!
I still can't find Kikka and the others!
I've set them to blow in 30 minutes.
Good. Let's go.
Bombs!
I'll go look for Katz, Letz, and Kikka.
-Roger.
-Is there a car?
Yeah!
-Mirai! Sayla!
-Captain?
They might be nearby.
I'd like you to go find them.
-Can you do that, Sayla?
-Yes, ma'am.
Mirai out.
Got it! Katz! Hurry!
You're a lifesaver…
We've got to find the bombs!
-You and Kikka look underneath these!
-Okay!
See any?
No!
What do we do?
I found one! This is a bomb, right?
Hurry up, Kikka!
How many went up?
It's hard to tell.
There were at least four, so…
One must have been real
while the others are just decoys…
Here they come!
Go to level 1 battle stations!
How do you know they're out here?
It's just a hunch.
Amuro's a Newtype! A Newtype!
Stop making fun of me, okay?
Yes, sir!
Okay, it started! What next?
Right, I'll pull this!
Wrong way!
Katz, Letz, and Kikka were in that car!
-What the heck are they doing down here?
-After them!
Stop the car!
Can't you stop?
Zeon planted some bombs!
We're going to throw them away!
Bombs?
Those are…
Hey, Amuro! They're telling the truth!
They're time bombs!
Where were they?
Inside the Gundam factory!
Okay, Letz, I'll take it from here.
Get into the other car. Hurry!
Kai! Get the kids into the other car!
I'm on it! Okay, Letz! You first! Come on!
See? You're okay!
Your turn, Kikka! Come on!
Okay, next! There we go!
Hey, you did great! I got them, Amuro!
Thanks, Kai!
Amuro!
-Jump!
-We did it!
White Base is in danger!
The people who planted those
are probably heading for the space dock!
We failed to get to the Trojan Horse.
Ivanov, do you read me?
I read you, Captain!
Escape in the Acguy! We'll catch up later.
-Roger!
-Let's go!
Launch all our units
once the pilots return!
Yes, sir!
Decks one and two!
Katz! Kikka! Letz!
Katz! Letz! Kikka!
Artesia!
Hello.
I can't believe you joined the Zeon army.
Not my sweet brother, Casval…
Leave the Federation Forces, Artesia.
Sayla! Are you there? Answer me!
-Think about it!
-Casval!
Sayla!
Where are you? Kikka!
Was that a gunshot?
Is there a Zeon soldier around?
What do you mean?
The Zeon commander was right there!
You didn't see him?
No, sorry. Maybe we shouldn't go that way.
-See you!
-Good luck!
Akahana!
Can we make it down there?
-They dropped 28 mobile suits.
-That's a fairly large group.
Perhaps, but it's too small
to attack Jaburo.
They're only after A-Block
of the space dock.
Did they follow White Base here?
Probably.
White Base is nothing but trouble.
Just one tank will do! Send one over here!
We're practically defenseless!
Sorry I took so long!
-Activate the main engine!
-Yes, sir!
All right!
Guntank, launching!
Guncannon, stand by for launch on deck 2!
I won't be sad anymore, Miharu.
I'll destroy Zeon
so there won't be any more girls like you.
I'll wipe them out!
Amuro, Gundam! Here I go!
How many enemy units got through?
They're here!
Here they come!
Zeon made it past our defenses?
Have the workers
take up defensive positions too!
Yes, sir!
I won't let them scratch White Base now
that I've run the pressure checks.
Don't mess with me!
You won't lay a finger
on the ship Matilda protected!
Fall back!
You can't do anything in a hovercraft!
Fall back, Captain Woody!
Captain!
A red mobile suit!
Is that Char?
It's fast!
It's him, all right. He's here.
Is that you, Char?
You've gotten better, Gundam!
Nice!
If I hit him with a missile
at point-blank…
Captain Woody! It won't work!
You must be joking.
Char!
Was my balance off?
You're not getting away!
This pilot, the source of this pressure…
Who is he?
An underground river!
Damn you, Char!
That's just like him.
He ran away while I was pinned.
I understand how you feel.
But are you sure?
You'll be safe if you stay here.
They'll be at the mercy of bureaucrats.
Don't the children get a say in this?
These kids are survivors.
They've fought with us in every battle.
They've been through hell and back.
They've seen things you can't imagine.
Don't you get it?
They don't want to leave.
You want to stay with us, right?
-Yeah!
-But…
Maybe you're right.
I'll make the necessary arrangements.
-That's great!
-I'm so happy for you!
-We can stay with you!
-I'm glad it worked out.
Isn't that great?
Soon afterwards,
the Earth Federation Chiefs of Staff
determined that Zeon was overestimating
the real potential of White Base.
Therefore, they entrusted the duties
of the 13th Autonomous Corps
to White Base alone.
This was presented as a privilege
given only to the esteemed Newtype Unit.
You're saying that White Base
is to specialize in being a decoy?
Skies are clear!
White Base, lift off!
-Wow! Birds!
-Pretty!
Anyone who's not busy,
look out the portside windows.
-There's a flock of flamingos.
-I'll get it on video!
You have my permission.
Char's mobile suit?
Yes. It was him, all right.
Char? The Red Comet?
Is he really that good?
Casval…