(winding)
(metallic tapping)
(slow music)
(light music)
(ding!)
(music)
(whinnying)
(ding!)
(music fading)
- Hands above the covers!
- Oh!
- Was I...? It wasn't you.
It was the dreaming you.
Keep your "yous" separate
and you'll never have anything
to apologize for, possum.
So what shall we girls
tackle today?
- I wanna make muffins.
- Well, wash up and we'll see.
- Oh!
(sighing in contentment)
(soft music)
(birdsong)
Oh... We don't have any vanilla,
do we?
- No. Make them without.
- Uh... but...
the book says we need it.
They won't turn out
the way they're supposed to.
- Most things in life don't turn
out the way they're supposed to.
In fact, that will be today's
lesson:
Anticipointment.
- Oh! Fun!
- When we expect too much
out of life,
we get smacked
by disappointment.
- Oh.
- Words to live by.
(soft music)
(ding!)
(sighing)
Why can't you leave them at
the back of the church on Sunday
and people can grab them
when they leave?
- Because they're warm now.
People have been so kind to us.
It's time we repay them.
- But so many of them haven't.
- But so many of them have.
I won't be long.
- Fine.
But head down at all times,
and whatever words
come out of their mouths
are not to be listened to.
- Yes, Mum.
I'm 24.
- Well, if you want to see 25,
you'll come back as soon
as they snatch that last muffin.
(young woman sighing)
- Deal.
There and back.
Mwah!
(giggling)
(winding)
(ticking)
(soft music)
(birdsong)
(light, upbeat music)
- Oh, Claire!
What a treat seeing you.
I'm surprised you're out.
- I couldn't keep these
to myself.
- Oh.
They smell amazing!
Thank you, Claire.
- Anytime!
- Oh, so she's okay,
your mother?
- Better than ever.
- Oh, she's very lucky
to have you, you know.
- I'd do anything for her.
- I wish my children were here
to take care of me.
Too busy complicating
their own lives
to realize where they're needed.
When my husband died,
I was at his bedside,
holding a picture
of our children.
Oh, well,
she's just lucky, is all.
Thank you for the muffin,
Claire.
- My pleasure!
- Oh!
Have a great day.
- You, too.
(giggling)
- Off I go!
(chuckling)
- Yes?
- Hi.
Are your parents home?
(woman): Who is it, baby?
- It's that girl
from down the street.
- Shhh.
Stay quiet and she'll leave.
- I don't like her.
How could you? She's crazy.
Now shhh.
- Mom?
(muffled screaming)
(crying)
- Stay off my damn porch!!
(brakes screeching)
(exclaiming)
- Stay home, freak show!
(Claire crying)
- Are you okay?
Oh, my... give me your arm.
- Oh...
(grunting)
Oh...
- Come on, let's get you inside.
- Hey...
it's 14108 Pinewood.
- Well, yeah.
- I have a muffin for here.
- I'm sure you do.
Oh, crap.
Here.
Hold your nose like this.
- Oh.
- Go sit inside.
- Okay.
- Well, it looks like you've got
everything under control here.
- Who's that?
She's gorgeous.
- No one.
You should still
probably ice that.
- Okay. May I see your room?
- Uh... I guess.
Just don't bleed on shit.
- I have a tampon up my nose.
- Yeah, I can see that.
(funky music)
(woman moaning)
(moaning)
Oh...
Churn me like butter.
You're my favourite cousin!
Ah!! Ah!!
(exclaiming)
- Wow!
I love this.
I'm only allowed
to put up things that I create.
- That's cool.
That's really cool.
- I want a map like that.
Have you been
to all those places?
- My uncle's been
to all the pins that are red.
All the blue pins are the places
I'm gonna get to someday.
- Do you have anymore ice?
- Yeah, sure, one second.
(door opening)
(man): I'm home!
- In the kitchen.
I have someone over.
- Oh?
Oh, it's you. Hello, Claire.
- Hello, Pastor Paul.
- You... you okay there?
- Oh, I... I ran into a tree.
- Well, I hope
you taught it a lesson.
(laughing)
You know, Claire, your mom's
probably worried sick.
Let me drive you home.
- That would be swell.
- Danielle, I'm gonna
give your friend a ride home!
You wanna come with?!
- Nah.
- We can stop and get
some chicken on the way home!
- No, Paul.
- Oh...
(chuckling)
Let's go Claire.
- Okay. Ah...
What's your favourite bird?
- My favourite bird?
I've, uh...
...never really given it
much thought.
(chuckling)
Ugh, pigeon.
No.
Seagull.
- Why?
- I don't know. You?
- I don't have one.
Birds scare me.
- Birds scare your mom, Claire.
Listen, um...
Okay - ahem - how would you...
like to represent the parish
at the annual...
Pump Up the Jamboree
Youth Ministry Conference?
- Why me?
= Because you'd be perfect.
And - ahem - it would be a sin
to turn something like this
down.
- Oh, wow.
I... I... couldn't.
- Yes, you could. And you will.
Even if your mother
doesn't agree.
- Can she come?
- No, Claire, she can't.
- Oh.
Will you be there?
- Definitely.
- Then yes.
Yes, I'm going to come.
- Excellent.
Well, then it's settled.
You still live
at your grandparents' house?
- It's ours now.
- Oh?
- They signed everything over.
- You ever go visit them?
- It's too far.
- Fifty miles is not far,
Claire.
- That's a world away.
- Well...
here... we... are.
- Thank you, Pastor Paul.
- You're welcome, Claire.
And, um...
would you do me a favour?
Would you...
say hello to your mom for me?
- I always do.
- Thanks.
- Okay, bye-bye.
- Bye-bye.
(knocking)
Jesus Christ!
Yes?
- I forgot to offer you
my muffin.
I made it nice and moist
for you.
I even got
the neighbour's zucchini in it.
- Thank you, Claire. That's...
Thank you.
- Okay.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye-bye. Oh, uh, Claire?
I think, uh, the bleeding has...
stopped.
- Thanks.
Bye-bye.
- Bye-bye.
(soft music)
(sniffling)
(sighing)
- Oh...
Oh! They loved them!
They loved them!
(soft music)
Oh! Hey!!
(honking)
(screaming)
(gasping)
- No! No!!
No! Look what you did,
you idiot!
- Uh, is it okay?
- No, it's not okay! You're
gonna have to replace this!
It's a fucking vintage camera!
- I have glue.
- Go. Just go!
- Uh...
I feel bad.
- You should.
- Well, I... I do.
- Good.
- It was a mistake.
- Just like you!
(crying)
(sobbing)
(birdsong)
- ...and with that...
comes a huge degree
of responsibility.
Now, we often think of ourselves
are scions of free will,
of...
choice, of...
personal desire.
Now, that simply isn't the case.
Every moment we experience
contains not only a series
of consequences,
but is also the product
of a predetermined blueprint
set out for us by our Good Lord.
Now, as much
as we want to fight the notion,
nothing in this life is random.
Each situation we encounter
brings us closer to the truth
of our existence.
And it is our responsibility
to suffer the consequences
of our actions.
Now thank you.
Thank you for coming
and God bless.
(doorbell ringing)
- So how do I get you
a new one?
- What, my camera?
It's no use.
- No.
I have a responsibility to you,
and to fixing your camera.
- Yeah, yeah, you do.
- So what do I do?
- The store's closed today.
I'll meet you at your place
tomorrow.
You can hook me up then.
- What time?
- Say 10:00?
- And how much money do I need?
- Fifty bucks,
but bring more to be safe.
- Deal.
And hey. Your muffin
was freakin' delicious.
- That was for your dad.
- I'll see ya tomorrow.
- I said hello, Mum! Mum?
- Not now, Claire.
This is pointless.
- Do you need a hand?
Mum?
- Do you call this clean?
- It looks clean.
- Well, it isn't.
- Mum...
tomorrow I have to fix
something I broke.
- What did you break, honey?
- Someone's camera.
It's my responsibility.
- Your responsibility...
is to our family and this home.
Anything else is self-serving...
...and I won't allow it
under this roof.
- Are you okay, Mum?
- It's disgusting.
It's filthy.
- The sermon was great, Mum.
- Not now, Claire.
(celestial music)
- It is our responsibility
to suffer the consequences
of our actions.
(engine stalling)
(sighing)
- When was the last time
you used this thing?
(engine stalling)
Did you hear that?
- No.
(engine stalling, then starting)
I don't know about this.
- This was your idea.
I thought you wanted
to do the right thing.
- I do. I do.
I just... I've... I've...
never taken her car before.
- We'll be back in no time.
- Okay.
I have to be back
before the timer goes off.
- Uh...
alright.
(radio): Residents are asked
to keep an eye out
for the alleged sex offender
whom,
as a result of last Wednesday,
some are now calling
the Diddler on the Roof.
The man is described as--
- Gross.
- So how long
is this gonna take?
- Not long.
- Stop.
Stop!
- What?
(seatbelt clicking)
- Okay. Drive...
Jeeves!
- Okay, freak.
- Gas levels acceptable,
Captain?
- Assuming the gauge works,
we're at a quarter of a tank.
- Attagirl! Eyes on the road.
(radio): Another casualty
of the power outages
from last month
was the local sperm bank.
Due to their freezers not being
able to run at full efficiency,
there was an estimated loss
of four-quadrillion sperm.
We were able to find...
- This is weird.
Can we listen to something else?
- What do you wanna listen to?
- Sound of the wind.
- He's asking all male locals
to donate today.
- Yay!
(light music)
Ah...!
Ah...
(music)
(ticking)
(ding!)
(knocking)
- Hey, I gotta step out
for a moment
to finalize
some Jamboree planning.
Um... Tsk.
Look... Danielle, uh...
I would really like to sit down
and talk with you tonight.
I... I found another bottle.
Okay, well,
if you're ignoring me,
then you probably won't hear
that I left some money for food
on the fridge.
- O...kay.
Uh...
- What's wrong?
- I don't like this.
- We're almost there.
- Pull over.
Pull over!
Pull over. Pull... pull over.
Pull over.
- Okay.
Pull over. Pull over.
Pull over.
(Claire panting)
- Oh, my God, what?!
(exclaiming)
(groaning)
(Claire taking deep breaths)
Are you okay?
- Oh...
Oh... I don't know.
- Well... are you hungry?
Did you eat anything today?
- I'm always hungry.
Mmm... good sandwich.
Thanks. It's lettuce.
- It's really good.
- Good.
- Mmm.
- Hey, so, like...
what's the deal with your mom?
You know, like,
what's her thing?
- What do you mean?
She's... wonderful.
- Dude, she keeps you locked up.
- No, she doesn't.
I chose to be home-schooled.
- Let me at least
sit on your face
if you're gonna go
all Pinocchio on me.
(laughing)
- Gross.
- I'm not judging.
I'm just observing
with intense criticism.
Like...
like, what do you think
she's feeling right now,
the fact
that you just took her car?
Seriously?
- I'm sure she's fine.
- Claire.
- She is.
- If you haven't noticed,
I'm not a fan of lying.
- Okay, okay.
She's probably
balling her face off.
(sighing)
- Claire, that's insane.
You are just taking your friend
to the next town over
to buy her a new camera
from the one that you broke.
What?
- You said friend!
(Danielle snorting)
- Okay, okay,
we're not going all that.
Let's go.
We're almost to Deersmith.
- Deersmith?
That's where
my grandparents live.
- No shit. Your mom won't be
mad at us for visiting them.
Let's go.
- Oh!
We can visit them?!
- Yeah! Let's go!
- Oh, my goodness,
that would be swell!
- Were you dropped on your head
as a child?
- No. Why?
- Just saying,
the way you talk is so--
- Refined?
- Annoying.
- Oh.
- Hey, we're gonna make
a grandparent pit stop, okay?
- Okay.
- But first the camera.
- Claire...!
(sobbing)
Claire, don't do this to me!
Please...
I'm sorry!!
I'm sorry!
- Okay, now just follow my lead.
- Roger that.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
- Hey. Huh...
- Hey, I called this morning,
and they said that they had
a Canon 310 XL on hold for me.
- Oh, yeah, perfect.
Huh, you're perfect.
That's perfect, that's perfect.
Perfect.
- So can I get it?
- Get what?
- The camera.
- Oh, yeah, we have
a large variety of cameras.
Do you know the brand?
- Canon.
- Okay, Canon. And the model?
- She told you, weirdo.
The 310 XL.
- Oh, yeah, yeah, of course,
of course. One sex.
Second, uh... Sex,
I don't... Wah, if... if only.
I mean, uh...
- Oh, oh... He's bizarro.
- I know. He likes me.
- Well, he shouldn't ignore you,
then.
- Remind me to get you
a personal massager.
- Mom has one of those.
(chuckling)
- No doubt.
- Oh, that's so nice of you.
(sighing)
- Nope.
Uh, sorry.
- What? Uh, she said
they had it this morning.
- Well, sorry, we don't.
- Shit.
- We do have this Beaulieu R8.
- Yeah, how much is that?
- Um, I can give it to you
for 65.
- Fifty.
- I can't. My mom won't let me.
- Aw.
Look, pumpkin,
another home-schooler.
- Okay, fine. Fifty. Cash.
- Great. Fork it over, sister.
And a roll of film. Both: 50.
- I can't. I can't.
Okay. You know, okay, here.
Uh...
(laughing)
- Great. Have a nice day.
- Okay. Two?
I... No?
- Oh! No...
(laughter)
Aren't you gonna ask
for his number?
- Pfft. Man,
I have so much to teach you.
- No, you don't.
Mum's done a great job.
- Yeah.
Let's hit the Raisin Ranch.
- Okay.
Hi.
Uh... hello?
- Greetings,
and welcome to Grasswinds.
- When are your visiting hours?
- 5 to 7.
- Uh, a.m. or p.m.?
- Either way, you're either
too late or too early.
- Uh... we can wait.
- Wait, what?
- You'll wait. We all wait.
- Thank you.
- Hmm.
- We can't wait here that long.
- We're here now.
- Exactly.
Excuse me?
Yo!
- Yes, my darling.
- Do you have a restroom?
- Grasswinds is a place of rest.
We don't isolate it
to one room.
But if you need
to filter your kidneys or...
expunge your bowels,
down the hall, first left.
(sighing contentedly)
- I don't have to go.
- Neither do I.
(music playing)
Look.
- Oh!!
I've never taken
a dance class before.
- Do you see your grandparents?
- No.
I haven't seen them
since I was 12.
- But you'd recognize them,
right?
- Of course.
I send them a picture of me
every birthday
to keep me fresh in their minds.
- Claire? Claire!
- Nana!
- Oh...
Oh!
- Come here, Claire bear!
Come here!
- Pop-Pop!
- Ah...!!
Ah! Oh, look at you!
(laughing)
- But...
Mum said you had dementia
and that you could barely move.
- Really?
- Catherine.
- She has some nerve.
- Remember your exercises.
- Mmm...
Ah!
- What?
- Your mother and I
have entirely different ways
of moving through our journey
of existence.
- Why would she say that
about you?
- It's... complicated.
But... look! Look at you!
I am so glad to see you!
We have so much to talk about.
Honey, there is a beautiful
garden in the back.
Let's talk!
- Oh, that's a great idea.
- Okay, okay!
(laughing)
Oh!
This is my friend,
Danielle.
- Hey.
Listen, I'll let you guys
do your thing.
It sounds like you have a lot
to catch up on.
Plus I need to take footage
of this place.
- Well, thank you, dear,
but be careful.
They don't allow cameras here.
- Oh. Shhh.
(giggling)
- Come on.
- That's my friend.
- She's very nice.
- Danielle, I'm home! Finally.
Sorry, it took longer
than I thought.
(knocking)
Danielle?
(soft music)
(sighing)
(phone chiming)
(soft music)
(birdsong)
- You get this
when you get older.
(sniffling)
Oh, gosh.
Ah...
(sniffling)
Oh...
- Hey.
- You ready to go?
(soft music)
Everything okay?
- She's gonna be just fine.
- You can visit us anytime.
- Anytime.
- I will.
(grandmother chuckling)
(sighing)
- Love to your mother.
- Can we not talk about her,
please?
- Oh, dinner... is on us.
(Claire giggling)
- Thanks, Pop-Pop.
I don't wanna go.
- Oh...
- Honey, we have to go.
They're gonna wonder
where we are at karaoke class.
- Awesome.
- Oh, sunshine...
everything will be just fine.
You keep an eye on her.
- I will.
- Okay.
- Uh, what she said.
- You ready?
(sighing)
So what'd you guys talk about?
- Can we just get out of here,
please?
- Yeah, totally.
Um... where?
- I don't care.
I just can't go home right now.
- Okay.
(sighing)
- Give me strength.
- Yes?
- It's me.
It's Paul.
Is, uh, is Claire home?
- No.
Someone stole my Claire
and my car.
- What are you talking about?
Open the door!
- Ah...
You've aged.
- We both have.
Can I come in?
- I've lost her, haven't I?
- No.
- Then why would she just leave
like that?
- I think that you know
the answer to that.
What did she say when she left?
- She didn't tell me anything.
She just said that she had
a responsibility
to fix some broken camera.
- Danielle.
Look, I am sure
that they'll be back tonight.
And I'll wait with you
until they are.
(kettle whistling)
Let me get that.
- All... all... all we have
is English Breakfast.
- It's... it's good to see you
and I am not here for the tea,
Henrietta.
- Ah...
we have a splash of milk,
thank God.
Claire used all the milk
when she made her muffins--
- Henrietta.
- And, um, sugar.
You still take sugar, right?
- Henrietta. Henrietta.
Everything is gonna be okay.
(soft music)
- So, uh, what'd
your grandparents tell you?
- Enough to make this feel
like this is the best decision
I've ever made.
- Amen, sister.
Anywhere in particular?
- Like I said...
I don't care.
(laughing)
- We'll just go to the next gas
station and take it from there.
- Sounds like a plan.
(crickets chirring)
(bell tinkling)
- Restroom?
- Back there.
- Hey, hey, will you get me
chips, beef jerky and water?
And coffee.
Two creams, no sugar.
- Okay. Oh!
- I might be a while.
Hi.
- Hi.
- You know where you are?
- Now I do.
- Well, that makes one of us.
(laughing)
- There isn't anyone in there,
by the way.
- Oh. Thanks.
- Oh, hey.
- Hey.
- Do you have
any white "Zenvendel"?
- Are you old enough?
- I sure am.
I bought some earlier this week.
- Oh, good for you.
It's in the back left.
- Neato!
(laughing)
- Hey, um...
I'll throw in a couple
of free jerkies
if you eat one real slow.
- Oh, that's so sweet of you.
- How far back can you put it?
(gagging)
Okay, that's enough.
Um, that'll be... 15.75.
- Okay.
One, two,
three, four, five, 15.
Fifty...
Sixty... 85.
You owe me a dime.
Oh.
(giggling)
- Here ya go.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Have a good day.
- You, too.
- Hello.
- Hi.
I'm just waiting for my friend,
but I should probably pee too.
(laughing)
- Yes, you probably should.
- I like your guitar.
- Thank you.
It's a ukulele, actually.
- Oh, it's so cute.
Are you in a band?
- No.
Nah, I'm just doing my thing.
- Me too. Just doing my thing.
(laughing)
Are you lost?
- Sometimes.
- Where you going?
We're going
to the Pump Up the Jamboree.
- No way.
That's where I'm going.
Wh-where is it exactly?
- Ah.
Oh...
It's right here.
- Yeah.
- Do you need a lift?
- That would be great, yeah.
- Ours is the station wagon
out front.
Here, make yourself comfy.
- This is amazing. Thank you.
- I think she's pooing,
but I'll be real quick.
- Excellent news.
(toilet flushing)
- Where'd that guy go?
- Outside. He's coming with us.
- What?
- I gave him the keys.
He's heading to the Jamboree!
- My dad's thing?
- Yeah. He asked me to go
the other day.
- And so now we're going?
- Yep.
- Okay, FYI, it's kinda lame.
- FYI, it's kinda perfect.
- Do you even know
what FYI means?
- Yes. Forgive your intentions.
- Wow. Yeah, let's go with that.
So where is he?
- In the car.
- You gave him the keys?!
- Why not?
He's heading to the Jamboree!
- Who does that?
(phone ringing)
- Claire!
Oh...
I don't need to explain anything
to you, Mother.
Where?
Is she safe?
Is she safe?!
Is she still there?!
I do not need
to get into this with you!
Ah!
(sighing)
Ah.
- You know any lyrics?
- Of course I do.
* And then the ship *
* Came sailing to *
* The course of long begotten **
- Whoa, you're ridiculous.
- Uh, I think you mean fabulous.
(Claire giggling)
- You know,
I never got your names.
- I'm Danielle.
And she's Claire.
- Trevor.
I really appreciate this.
- Oh, it's no problem at all.
We're all going
to the same place, apparently.
- Lucky me.
- Lucky us!
(laughing)
- I'll drive.
- There ya go.
- Oh, thank you.
- Don't be ridiculous.
You'd be saving her.
- From what?
- From everything
that could harm her.
(Paul sighing)
- I can't go collect her
by myself, okay?
She's 24 years old,
for godssake!
- What are you saying?
- You know exactly
what I'm saying.
- Uh, uh. I can't. I can't.
- Fine. Fine. Then you'll just
have to wait this out, then.
- We'll call the cops.
- Call the cops?! And say what?
- I don't know.
Whatever it takes.
You're the pastor,
you know what to tell the...
- How about looking you
right in the eye
and telling you
that the only thing
that makes a cat an indoor cat,
is a lazy, self- centered,
obstinate owner.
An owner who doesn't wanna deal
with the responsibility
that that innocent cat
might just find out
that the backyard
is not all that scary after all,
but, instead,
is filled with beautiful,
wonderful moments
that are ripe for exploration.
If they're not back tonight.
I will be in your driveway
at 9 a.m. sharp.
Meet me there. Or don't.
Good night.
- Use the back door.
* Amazing grace *
* How sweet the sound *
* That saved a wretch *
* Like me... *
(laughter)
* I once was lost *
* But now am found *
* Was blind *
* But now I see... *
- And now from the front seat!
* A... grace... *
* Was... *
* Born... **
(turning engine off)
Okay, guys, seriously,
what is the plan?
Where are we sleeping tonight?
- I'm good with pitching a tent.
- Ah!
- I bet you are.
- I'm good with outside!
Let's sleep under the stars!
- Well, I'm not.
How much money do we have
between the three of us?
- I've got, like, 30 bucks.
- Oh, it's okay.
We can cover you.
- Claire?
Can I have a word with you
outside, please?
- You know what?
I gotta find a tree anyway,
so I'll just leave you two
to talk.
- Oh, you should take this
in case you get more
than you bargained for.
- I'm good. Really.
(chuckling)
- Okay.
(door closing)
- What are you doing?
- Helping out.
- I don't know about this.
- Are you okay?
(Danielle sighing)
- What are we doing here?
- Having an adventure!
- Seriously, how much money
do we have?
- Hmm...
Well, with what I took from home
and what's left
of what Pop-Pop gave me,
70 bucks, around?
- That's not gonna be enough
for two rooms.
- Why do you want to be
in another room?
- For you.
He clearly wants to be with me.
- But we know songs.
- Well, I know
how to make music.
- But you were way off-key.
- I can hum.
- I...
Oh, do you like him?
- Obviously.
- Oh!
- Why? Do you?
- No.
(knocking)
- Good.
(whispering): Great. Fantastic.
(music playing)
- Hello.
- I don't want watermelon.
Oh, hey, sorry.
Must've dozed off.
How can I help you?
- We'd like a room
for the night.
- Uh-huh. You guys going
to the full-moon party
down in the woods?
- What? Full-moon party?
- Oh, no, sir, we're here
for the Pump Up the Jamboree.
- Oh, the Jesus thing?
So three rooms, I'm guessing?
- Two rooms. How much are they?
- Sixty. Each.
- Really? 'Cause the sign
outside says from 35.
- Yeah, well,
those are all taken.
- Shit. I mean, can't you just,
like, move the books around?
The owner will never know.
- Hmm.
Yeah, well, I'm the owner,
so the owner will know.
Sorry, can't go under 60.
I got horrible, unspeakable
vices that need fuelling.
- It's a Monday.
Are you really expecting
a crowd?
- Full-moon party. Sorry.
Can I go back to sleep now?
- Well, if we say no
to one room,
you'll have lost 60.
I know you offer two for 120,
but say you gave us two for 70,
that's 35 each,
then you're only 50 dollars shy
of what you're asking for,
and losing 50 is way easier
to process than losing 60.
Think of your horrible vices.
- Okay, that just hurt my brain,
but... you do have a point.
I'm pretty sure
I could get a BJ for 70 bucks.
Fine, 70 bucks, two rooms.
- Sixty!
- Don't push it.
- Guys, this is kind of you,
but I can't justify staying
in a room all by myself.
- No, you'll be with me.
- Sir, let's just take
the one room, please.
- Huh?
- I-I'll sleep on the floor.
- You guys are confusing
the shit out of me.
What do you want?
- One room, two beds, 50 bucks.
Deal?
- Yeah. Fine. Whatever.
Room 3. No smoking.
- Oh, we're clean-living.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
That's what they all say.
Then I find a condom
lodged in my neighbour's cat.
It was so deep in there...
- Oh!
Oh, wow, what a big bed!
- Uh,
I'll get to the bottom of this.
- Has anyone ever told you
how pretty you are?
- My mum.
- Well...
has a man ever told you
how pretty you are?
- Yes.
Just before he was convicted.
- You're not gonna make this
easy for me.
- Sorry...?
- You're very pretty.
- Thanks.
So are you.
- Well... apparently
this is the last room, so...
- Oh!
- Don't worry,
you're not sleeping
on the floor, mister.
- As long as it's hands
above covers, folks!
- That's what my mum says
when I touch my no-no garden.
(Claire laughing)
- So, girl, boy, girl?
- Works for me.
- Oh!
We don't have any jammies.
- No, no, we don't.
- How about a couple of these?
Huh?
- Cool. Oh!
(snorting)
(slow rock music)
(muffled screaming)
(screaming)
(Danielle screaming)
(slow instrumental rock version
of Amazing Grace)
(music fading)
(light music)
Ow.
Dear Lord,
this adventure is confusing,
but I know it's part
of your plan for me.
(yipping in distance)
Please help Mum.
I love her...
but I'm frustrated.
I do know I have to go
to the jamboree.
Also, thank you so much
for Danielle.
I had asked for a friend
for so long and she's perfect.
Oh, and aren't we supposed
to celebrate your creations?
I mean, if families traveled
thousands of miles
to see Mount Rushmore,
then certainly it's okay
to show my jelly jams.
I'll take that as a yes.
It's hot in here.
Thanks, God.
Good night, Mum.
(honking)
(nervous breathing)
- Oh. Oh, no. Oh, no.
No... No, that's...
No, that's... No, that's...
(knocking)
No, that's different. No.
(insistent knocking)
No...
- Argh! Enough! Henrietta?
Henrietta!
Fine! But if you don't get out
here right now and join me,
I'm taking that car back
immediately.
- I-I... I have a condition.
- Argh!
Keep telling yourself that.
And you find me one doctor
in town to support that myth.
- Why are you being so mean
to me?
- Mean?
Oh, you want me to be mean?
I can be mean. Let's have
a little mean, shall we?
Ahem. No one cares anymore,
Henrietta.
People's lives have moved on.
Alright?
Now you're just that weird lady
who stopped living
to ensure that her daughter
doesn't live.
Best you stay locked up
in your parents' house!
That'll teach them a lesson!
(Henrietta moaning)
- How dare you?! No!!!
- Come on.
No, just... We're good.
You're fine.
- No!! No!
- Here we go.
- Ah...!!! No!!
- Prove me wrong.
- Ah!!
- Prove me wrong! Here we go.
(groaning)
Prove me wrong. Prove me wrong.
- Trevor?
Hello?
Hey, what the hell happened?!
- What? Wh-what happened?
- What happened last night?!
- Where's Trevor?
- Yeah, where's Trevor?!
Your fucking tits come out
and he bolts!
- Don't call them that.
- What did you do?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?!
God, that's bullshit. You know,
he really liked me, okay?
- Oh, wouldn't he have paid you
more attention, then?
(scoffing)
- And I saw him first.
I can't believe that you would
box-block me like that!
- What does that even mean?
Danielle, why are you so mad?
- Why are you
so fucking clueless?!
- I'm not, though.
He was really different
around you.
And you weren't you around him.
It was weird.
- He liked me, okay?!
- Bu...
(door slamming)
(radio): ...by the association
of men with women's names,
and it hopes to draw attention
to these difficulties.
- Do you want to listen
to anything in particular?
- Uh, anything
to calm my nerves.
(laughing)
- Okay, Blanche.
(scanning stations)
(soft music playing)
- Better.
(soft guitar music)
* You might be desperate *
* And on your last legs *
* But you're not falling out *
* I don't know how *
* You always manage *
* To fight another round *
* You always ride it out *
* You always
ride it out somehow *
* You always ride it out *
* You always
ride it out somehow *
(siren wailing)
* I come to see you *
* And all
that you've been through *
* Never shows up on your face *
* You go on and on
and you smile so warm *
* Though the world *
* Can be such a cold place *
* You always ride it out *
* You always
ride it out somehow *
* You always ride it out *
* You always
ride it out somehow **
(soft guitar music)
(woman moaning)
(crying out)
(moaning)
- Ugh, I'm really sorry
for being such a dick.
(moaning)
I really thought he liked me.
- I don't even know what I did.
You're, like, my best friend.
- Oh, Claire.
- Oh, Hal, spread me like jelly!
- What are you watching?
- Oh... this is amazing.
(woman moaning)
- Gross.
- Yeah, yeah, yeah...
- What?
- This is vintage.
Look at her nails.
- Oh, ho, ho, ho, ho!
- Look at his back.
- He loves her, doesn't he?
(woman crying out)
- Uh, no.
No, he doesn't.
- But...
(indistinct dialogue)
But...
look what she's letting him do.
(woman crying out)
Especially there.
(woman): Ouch!
Ah! Oh!
Are you going to...
Ah! ...the reunion?!
Ah! Ooh!
- Have... you ever done that?
- Totally.
(man): Oh, yeah.
* Row row row your boat... **
- You know, we should probably
think of a plan.
We're running low on funds.
Do you have an ATM card?
- Is that like
a pregnancy thing?
- No, a bank card.
- No, we're cash only at home.
Mum doesn't believe
in electronic--
- Unless they're inside her?
- What?
- Never mind.
Seriously, though,
we need a plan.
- Well... I think
I need to go to Jamboree.
I mean, I really wanna go
to the Jamboree.
- Really?
- Yeah!
- We'll barely make it there,
though,
and we'll be skimping for food.
- Well, if the Jews
spent 40 years in a desert,
I think we'll be fine.
- Okay, well, what about me?
- What about you?
- I just get the pleasure
of dropping you off at Jamboree?
- You can come!
- Uh...
- Besides, look how many pins
you'll get to put on your map.
- That was the map of the world.
We're on Highway 6.
- But we're more along Highway 6
than we were yesterday.
- That's a good point. Okay.
Shit, I gotta pay.
- Oh, suck on a beef jerky
real slow
and they'll give you a free one.
- We're at a different station.
- Oh, I'm pretty sure
it's a universal truth.
- I'm pretty sure it's not.
- Well, you...
You should just try it anyway!
- Okay, alright.
(Claire laughing)
Yeah, you're doing it right.
Look through the viewfinder.
And then focus on your feet.
And then you'll notice
that the focus
on the horizon softens.
- Cool...!
So what's all this filming for?
- Oh, nothing.
- It's not nothing.
- It's nothing.
-= My mum says that when truth
is replaced by silence,
the silence is a lie.
- Okay, it's for my mom.
- Oh, that's so nice.
Where does she live?
Oh...
- No, it's okay. I mean,
she died when I was six, y'know?
She was
in a really bad accident.
You know, she never...
got to finish the film
she was making, so...
I don't know, it's stupid.
- It's not stupid.
- I have no idea what I'm doing.
- Makes two of us.
- Thanks.
You wanna check that out?
- Oh! Uh... yes!
- Yeah?
- Hey, Henrietta, don't
your folks live around here?
- Uh... yes.
- Quick pop-in?
- Uh... no, thank you.
- Okay.
- Hello?
- Hello?!
Hello?!
- Can I help you girls?
- Oh. I'm here for the contest.
- Are you now?
- Sure am, sir.
- Well, we don't have karaoke
contest this early on a weekday,
but that's unfortunate,
'cause, girls,
I'd love to hear you sing.
- We should go.
- The stage is all yours.
I could hum for ya.
Hmmmmmmm...
Heeeeh....
Mm-hmm...
Hmm-hmm-hmm...
(door closing)
Hmm... hmm...
Heeeh...
- Could you roll the window down
for me, please?
- Uh, could...
could we keep it up, please?
- Window down!
License and registration.
Everything okay there, ma'am?
- Oh, yes, she's, uh...
agoraphobic.
- I won't pretend to know
what that means.
- I have a great fear
of being in--
- And I won't pretend to care.
- Okay...
- You rolled through that stop,
mister.
- I did, didn't I?
- You certainly did.
Bad boy.
- Well, I'm...
I'm very sorry, Officer.
I'm a man of the cloth and--
- So why the rolling stop,
Paul?
- Well, we...
we were preoccupied.
Our daughters just up and left
this morning and so--
- Your daughters?
- Uh, well... daughters.
He has a daughter,
I have a daughter.
They're separate daughters.
And... and I have a sense
of where they're heading, uh,
but, you know,
they could be anywhere.
- Whose vehicle are they in?
- They are in mine, Officer.
- Yeah, this is a rental.
- Oh, there goes my crush.
Look, give me the license plate
number and I'll put out a call.
I know some of the motel owners
around here.
- Oh, okay it's, uh, S4326...
(engine stalling)
- Shit.
Shit. Shit, shit, shit, shit!
- What?
- Car's dead.
- Uh... everything will be okay.
What?
- I skip town and my dad
only calls me three times?
I bet your mom's going berserk.
- Yeah...
Let her.
- Okay, according to my phone,
there's a gas station...
that way a little ways.
- Should we walk?
- I'm not going back in there.
- Okay!
Wait here one second.
- Well, it looks
like a Danielle Logan
checked into the Shady Pines
on Highway 8 last night.
- That's my girl.
- So let's go check it out.
Follow me.
- Thank you, thank you.
Thank you very much.
You see?
- Oh, cool!
Look at these!
(Danielle laughing)
- Henrietta!
Oh!
- Oh.
(giggling)
- What?
- Here.
As a thanks.
Did I do something wrong?
- No.
No.
That was really, really sweet.
Thank you.
- That's your favourite, right?
- My mom used to drink it.
The smell of the cork
reminds me of her.
- Well...
We're finishing her film,
we should drink it
in her honour.
- I'm not gonna argue with that.
This looks good on you.
- Thanks! I like yours, too.
(music)
(indistinct chatter)
- Yeah, the boy left
around 6 a.m. this morning.
He seemed kind of stressed.
Also,
someone owes me some money.
There's an outstanding charge
for, uh, a "blue" movie.
- Blue?
- Pfft. Good girls, I see.
- Yeah.
- The best. Well, mine is.
- Which flick?
- Oh, it's a good one.
Uh, Second Cousin
Twice Removed.
Classic.
- What? What?
There was definitely something
in that look.
(music)
(indistinct chatter)
- Best friends!
(laughter)
(...music...)
- Whoo!
(music fading)
(howling)
This is...
(gasping)
This is so...
cool!
- Are you little girls out here
in the forest all by yourselves?
- Oh, we sure are.
- Welcome
to the full-moon party.
(phone ringing)
Hello?
So sorry.
Yeah?
No, no.
It's like my one big night.
We can get whatever's
in the basement out tomorrow.
Yeah, look, I gotta go.
So sorry.
(chuckling)
You guys tripping?
You have to try
my super-spicy space cakes.
(music playing)
What's the matter?
- We're lost
and our car broke down.
- Claire!
- That is such a bummer. Where?
- On our way here, yeah.
- Look...
here's what needs to happen.
You need to eat some cake,
you need to get silly,
and you need to dance.
You're totally safe with me.
Trust me. Seriously,
you girls are in for a treat.
- Ah... ah...
Whoa...
(speaking with mouth full)
That's great.
- Let's go.
- It is so good.
- Yeah.
(laughter)
(beat-heavy music)
(demonic voice)
(techno music)
- Now don't freak out.
Don't fall.
- Ah.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- But imagine that wall gone.
- Oh.
- Mm-hmm.
Bedroom - bang.
Upstairs fireplace,
second bedroom.
Oh, my fuck,
his croissants are to die for.
Must have one now.
Oh, you're up.
- 'Morning.
- Hi.
- Hello. You're handsome.
(chuckling)
- I'm Hal.
- I'm Danielle. This is Claire.
- We're girls.
- I can tell. Hungry?
- Starved.
- Follow me.
- Mmm...
- We have more if you want.
- Only if you have more
of this insane jam.
- Jelly jams!
These are my jelly jams.
(laughter)
- Yes! Those are
your little jelly jams.
- These are my jelly--
- I really like your jelly jams.
- You like my jelly jams?
- They're really nice ones.
- I really like your jelly jams.
- Thanks. You do?
- Mm-hmm.
- Aw...!
(laughter)
- The car's been spotted.
- Oh, wonderful.
- Uh, so we'll follow you, then?
- No, no, no, we'll take my car.
Leave yours here.
- Oh, that's very kind of you.
- It is. But I'm not going
to drive you anywhere
until you tell me
what's really going on here.
- Here?
(water running)
(groaning softly)
(man): Ahem.
(Claire giggling)
- Where's Artemis?
- He's gone
to get your car fixed.
- Oh, that's wonderful.
Can I help with anything?
- Well, uh, you can crack
some eggs over there.
- Oh, I don't know
how to do that.
- Seriously?
- We buy the yolks
in the carton.
(laughing)
- That is so suburban.
Uh, come here, let me show you.
Here we go.
Okay, grab an egg.
Okay, bump it just hard enough
to crack the shell,
but gentle enough
not to damage the egg inside.
Ready? Okay, now...
(Claire exclaiming)
There you go. Look at that,
look at that, look at that!
There we go.
- Oh!
- Not bad, babe.
- Wow...
Our house used to get egged.
- That's awful.
- Yeah.
- There you go.
- How am I doing?
- I'd hire ya.
When you drop a little shell,
you just scrape it out
like that.
There ya go.
Nothing to it. Keep going.
- Uh... that's my car!
- The wagon?
- Uh-huh.
- Who's the long-haired guy
under the hood?
- Did you see my Claire?!
(siren wailing)
(brakes squealing)
(humming happily)
- Oh! Mmm!
Ah, they smell amazing!
- It's all that vanilla
you added.
- Uh, we have guests.
- More guests.
- Smells great in here.
- Thanks.
- Should we get the coffee
flowing here?
- Hal?
- Henrietta?
- Hello, Hal.
- Mum? You know each other?
How do you know each other?
- Oh, Jesus. Screw the coffee.
You have anything stronger?
- How do you know each other?
- Officer Lori,
Danielle, I think
we should leave them alone.
Oh, dear God.
(Danielle groaning)
- Oh, Jesus. Here.
- I'm sorry.
- Danielle, let's... let's...
let's... let's go.
- Um, okay.
Hal... Claire's your daughter.
- What?!
(child giggling)
- Excuse me?
I'm really sorry, Claire.
I had no idea.
- Oh!
- Artemis, grab a towel,
grab a towel. I got her hair.
- Sweetheart?
- Oh, baby. Towel. Oh, baby.
Oof. I'm really sorry
about this, people.
- Hal, would you like
to tell your daughter
what line of work you're in?
- Um, was in.
And you're being inappropriate.
- And-and I'm very sorry,
who are you exactly?
- Hal's lover.
- What? Tell me.
- Tell her, Hal.
- You're Hal Spreadum!
That's an impressive
body of work.
- Oh... he was in that movie
we saw, Claire.
(soft music)
- That woman didn't love you.
- I know.
(soft piano music)
- Great jam.
(...soft piano music...)
- Alright, you've had enough.
You're done.
(soft piano music)
So here's what's gonna
go down next, okay?
Your car needs attention,
so I can take the both of you
in the cruiser.
Paul and Danielle
can take the rental car.
- No.
I'm sorry, but no.
Mum...I love you
with every core of my being.
I do.
But I'm going
to Pump Up the Jamboree,
with Danielle.
You guys can do
whatever you wanna do.
But that's what I'm doing,
Okay?
- You don't need that.
(Danielle sighing)
- You... you just don't get it,
do you, Paul?
- I hate it
when you call me that.
Why can't you call me Dad?
Hey...
I'm trying to love you here,
Danielle.
- Well,
then that makes two of us.
- You okay?
- Define okay.
- Okay, look...
I am very worried
about your drinking.
I find bottles all the time.
- Oh, she doesn't drink them.
The smell of the cork
reminds her of her mom.
I think it's nice.
How is it in there?
- Oh, it's weird
and heavy and awkward.
Kind of like how I was
in high school.
They're having
a long-overdue chat.
It's a good thing.
- Man, you guys are awesome.
- Ah, tell me something
I don't already know.
(laughter)
- Thank you for everything.
- It's my pleasure.
You know what?
We could kind of use a hand
around here
until things get up and running.
Just putting it out there.
- Awesome.
(Claire): Ah...
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Uh, girls? We, uh...
- Behave yourselves!
- Okay.
(laughter)
- That's your dad.
(soft music)
- We could help.
- I wanna go.
- We'll get you home
soon enough.
- No, I wanna go
to the jamboree.
I wanna support my baby.
- Wait, I want to support
my baby, too.
- To the jamboree, then.
(chuckling)
- Here we go, doll.
- Okay.
Okay.
- So glad you could come.
Okay, it's almost speech time.
(woman): ...our saviour!
(Claire giggling)
I felt good about the way
I looked in my bathing suit,
and I found the courage
to go down the water slide.
I found the courage
through his love.
I love you, Christ Jesus!
I love you with every pore!
(crowd cheering)
- Thank you so much, so much,
Maxine. How bout that, huh?
That was some beautiful,
beautiful, heartfelt testimony.
Thank you, thank you.
He's everywhere, isn't he?
(laughing)
Alright, now this is...
this is very exciting.
Please, ladies and gentlemen,
welcome for the very first time,
representing Penderson County,
our very own Claire Woods.
Let's pump it up for Claire!
Huh?
Ha-ha-ha!
Yeah.
Watch your step.
- Thank you... Pastor Paul...
for inviting me...
to speak here.
I've...
been asked to speak...
about how my... spirituality
has lead me to where I am now.
Or... something.
All I know is that...
you have to treat spirituality
like a breakfast buffet.
Only eat what you crave.
There's a reason you crave it.
And I have a new friend.
(laughing)
And she's making
all the difference.
And I just found out
that my dad's gay.
And we made amazing croissants
this morning.
And...
and he and his boyfriend are...
creating a home away from home
for lost travellers.
Isn't that all of us?
We need to step away...
...run away...
(laughing)
...knowing that...
along the way...
there will be amazing...
and terrifying surprises
at every turn.
And guys that make you suck
on beef jerky for a discount.
But all of that doesn't matter,
because we're all just trying
to do the best we can
with what we're given.
And, Pastor Paul,
you have it wrong.
It's not our responsibility
to suffer the consequences
of our actions...
but...
rather celebrate them!
(whistling)
- Whoo-hoo!!
(music)
* We're all traveling
down this lonely road *
* We're all tumbling
in the tides *
* But I am here
to simply let you know *
* I'll be right by your side *
* We all hear
that voice inside our souls *
* A wind that whispers
in the night *
* Whatever lies
down this old winding road *
* I'll be right by your side *
* Oh oh oh oh *
* Don't have to face
this world alone *
* Oh oh oh *
* I'll be the place
that you call home *
* Oh oh oh *
* The pages turn
and years go by *
* And I'll be
right by your side *
* A hundred books
can't tell you what to do *
* A thousand songs
that still don't rhyme *
* Be yourself
and keep your heart true *
* I'll be right by your side *
* Oh oh oh oh *
* Don't have to face
this world alone *
* Oh oh oh *
* I'll be the place
that you call home *
* Oh oh oh *
* The pages turn
and years go by *
* And I'll be
right by your side *
* It doesn't matter where
we choose to plant our roots *
* We'll always blossom
in each other's light *
* And from the shelter
of your open arms *
* You look into my eyes *
* And say oh oh oh oh *
* Don't have to face
this world alone *
* Oh oh oh *
* I'll be the place
that you call home *
* Oh oh oh *
* The pages turn
and years go by *
* And I'll be
right by your side *
(music fading)
(funky music)
Subtitling: CNST, Montreal