We ask whoever took our Emily..
...please remember
she's someone's child.
We come to you with an exclusive
this morning as new breaks
that a three-year old girl
was abducted from her home
in Copeland County
late last night.
Investigators say that the young
girl was asleep in her room
when an assailant
forcefully entered her home
and abducted her.
An amber alert
was issued this morning
as the unidentified suspect
is still at large
and potentially dangerous.
If you have any information..
Any little girl
dreaming of being a ballerina
loves our dresses made of tulle.
But...satin dresses
are pretty popular
with the budding princesses,
but my personal favorite
is the tulle dress
paired with sneakers.
And, um, these just,
pull the look altogether.
Makes you wish
you were five again, right?
Um, I'll go
wrap this up for you.
I think I even have a hair bow
to match. Be right back.
- Hi.
- I'm working.
- So am I.
- No, you're distracting.
- Okay, I was working.
- Well, go, continue.
But I need your approval
before I can keep going.
Excuse me?
I'm just gonna
wrap this up in the back
where I have
the tissue paper, okay?
- What do you think?
- Ryan..
Yeah?
I mean,
whoever we sell this to is--
Maybe we don't sell it.
We have a store
for selling things.
Maybe just put it
in the store window
but don't sell it.
You stop right there.
Or maybe I don't
and then you'll be so glad that
I had this thing ready to go.
We're not ready.
- We're ready.
- We're almost ready.
How much longer?
When it's time.
But right now I have a customer.
She's fine.
We cannot behave this way
at work.
- Says who?
- Your boss.
And then he calculated
what each of us owed on the tab
down to the cent.
- Boy.
- Yeah.
And then I had one spring roll
and he divided a quarter
of the price of the rolls
and added it
to my part of the tab.
I mean, no wonder
he's still single.
I-I threw down my cash
and I wished him luck.
I mean, can you imagine
traveling with this man?
- I feel sorry for him.
- I-I-I know.
I mean,
he's completely clueless.
Well, get back out there.
You're gonna find someone.
Between work and school,
I-I'm literally exhausted.
Well, a couple of more tests
and you're gonna be a nurse.
Yeah, it's that easy.
Of course not,
but then we can get back
to brunches and game nights.
So you can slaughter me
at trivia?
I'll take you anywhere
I can get you.
'Cause I'm your favorite.
- Thank you.
- Thanks, honey.
But, um, Karina, you do need
to find another brunch buddy.
- Don't say that.
- Seriously.
I mean, you came out here
to get the shop going
and to start a family.
Shop is doing great
and the family thing is
well, well, as you say,
in the works.
So it's time, right?
I-it's time to find
a local lady-friend
to have some fun with
between our visits.
- Are you breaking up with me?
- Well..
I am actually seeing someone.
He looks an awful lot
like a text book.
- Stop.
- Babe, I love you.
I don't mind sharing you.
You put so much of yourself
into that shop
I-I just want you to enjoy
this life that you have here.
I just don't know anyone
out here.
You know, it's not
as easy to meet people
as it was in college.
It's not like I work
in an office. So what do I do?
Well, next time a nice
customer comes into the shop
ask her to lunch. Start there.
Okay.
But if she brings out
a spreadsheet
to calculate the tab?
- Run!
- Yeah.
As fast as you can, okay?
- I'll drink to that.
- A drink to that.
Hello there.
Hey, sorry,
I kinda got in the zone.
You have been for hours.
Here's your half of the snack
you were supposed
to join me for.
Whoops.
- You want some company?
- Sure.
So, I thought
we closed the shop on Sundays
so you could have a day off.
When inspiration strikes..
How is Cam?
She's good, you know
she's very close to making
all her dreams come true.
She just never comes up
for air, you know?
I know someone else
we could say that about.
- The business is doing great.
- I know.
You can start enjoying the life
that we've built here.
I know.
And I'm not trying
to pressure you.
I know.
I wanna build a family, too.
But I just had this idea
that when we raise a family,
we'll be in a community.
And every time I see Cam,
it becomes very apparent.
- That's not what we have here.
- Yet.
That's what we need
to start building.
Not more stuff.
Ooh.
You're right.
I'm right.
Just let me finish the hem.
Please.
Thanks.
Alright, Master Hemster
show me how this is done.
Well, watch
'cause I'm really good at this.
In this week on special report
we begin in Copeland County,
California.
Sleeping safely in her bed
was a normal and curious
three-year old girl.
Then an unidentified assailant
kidnapped the child.
Now, five years later
investigators officially
put an end to their search
declaring her dead in absentia.
Tonight, we bring you
this story and others like it
in CBN-7's special report
on child abduction cases
that have run cold
in California.
Are the dresses for people, too?
- The dresses?
- Or just for fairies?
Let's see, shall we?
Excuse me, Mr. Hippo.
- This little girl--
- 'Mallie.'
Mallie would like to know
if she can borrow
the fairies' dresses.
The Hippo said
the fairies would be honored
to share their dresses with you.
- I read the most books--
- 'Mallie!'
You can't take off like that.
Mallie, what did I just say?
Mom, look.
Honey..
...you are
my most precious thing, okay?
I don't know
what I would do without you.
Sometimes I'm just so fast,
I can't control myself.
I understand, honey.
I bet, and you're fast
at reading, too.
I get a medal
in front of everyone!
So this dress
is for a celebration?
Honey, remember,
we-we're not doing the ceremony.
- Just the dress.
- I've never gotten a medal.
You're going to get the medal,
okay?
Her school is honoring the most
avid readers in each grade, so..
How exciting!
I mean, I don't,
I don't love the idea
of my daughter being paraded in
front of a bunch of strangers.
But, you know,
you hear all of these things
that go on these days and it's..
- 'Yes, of course.'
- Yes.
Well, how about..
...you try it on?
Okay.
- She's so cute.
- Thank you.
I'm sure I-I sound crazy.
It's just you hear
these stories these days.
And I, I mean, I don't mean
to be over-protective
but she's, she's literally
all I have, so it's..
Of course, you know,
I can't even imagine
what it's like to parent these
days with all the technology--
It's crazy, they're exposed
to the world like that. It's..
Well, good for you for keeping
such a close eye on her.
Thanks, I try.
How about you?
Do you have any kids?
Not yet.
- Not yet.
- Yeah.
But you-you work here?
I own here, actually.
- Well, good for you.
- Yeah.
Little bit of advice
for when you do have kids.
What they say is true,
it takes a village
which is something
I do not have.
- It doesn't fit.
- Aw, honey.
We'll find you something else.
How about I make you a dress?
But who made this dress?
Fairies or you?
Well, I make the dresses
for the fairies
and I can make a special one
for you.
'You don't have to do that.'
Nonsense.
Come on, let's go
get you measured.
So I'll see you
for dinner, instead.
This is more beautiful than
my mind could ever think of.
We,
we can't thank you enough.
You're nice people.
It was my pleasure.
Sweetie, go get dressed
'cause I've to get
to the post office
before it closes, okay?
But I never wanna take this off.
I can watch her
while you head over.
- Are you sure?
- It's no problem at all.
Okay, I'll be real quick.
Be dressed and ready
when I get back, okay, honey?
Thank you.
Mallie, I have to help
this customer
right here for just a sec.
But over there
there's a book shelf.
You can read any book
that you want to.
Okay? I'll be right with you.
- Hi, how are you?
- Hi, how are you doing?
Great. Um, are you interested
in this crib?
'Yes, I am. I'm very interested
in this crib.'
'Well, my husband designs
all the cribs.'
'He does all the woodwork
himself'
'and it's kinda supposed
to be reminiscent of'
what you would have played with
at your grandparents' house
when you were young.
'Awesome.'
Um, and he also designed
the dresser to match
so it's kind of a set..
It's trending
with all the hipster parents.
Mallie, stop!
Hey! Hey!
Honey, sit down,
just read a book right there.
Okay. Yeah. Yeah.
Hey.
- What's going on?
- We need to call the police.
Why?
A man,
he-he tried to take Mallie.
I think, I'm-I'm assuming
that it wasn't her father.
'No, her father's
not in the picture.'
Okay. If I hadn't stopped him,
he just, he would've taken her.
You did, okay?
You came to the rescue,
so don't, don't call the police.
A man tried to kidnap
your daughter
and you don't wanna
call the police?
I don't wanna alarm her.
Can you imagine a little girl,
her age, talking to the cops?
They're not exactly good
with kids.
How can you be so calm?
It's just, children pick up
on a lot more than they let on
and I just..
Please, I-I, I don't wanna
make her feel unsafe.
You understand?
Please, I-I..
I'm so sorry,
it happened so quick and I--
Honey, you did, you did great.
Really, you're a..
You're a godsend,
I mean, I don't..
My God. How am I ever
going to repay you.
Actually, I could start
by-by paying you, I mean..
- Here. Please take, take extra.
- No, no, no.
It's okay, it's okay. Um..
I don't know, maybe we could
go out for a-a bite sometime
you know, I don't know
very many people around here.
Honey,
a bite would be great.
- Okay.
- On me, okay?
- Okay?
- We'll see.
- On me!
- Okay.
Thank you.
Just keep thinking I should've
reported the incident today.
I mean,
what, what if it happens again?
Well, you definitely should
let people know
but you got to respect
her privacy.
Yeah, but what happens if he
succeeds next time? Then what?
That's why we all
have to exercise caution.
How, when she won't report it?
Maybe she doesn't wanna
scare her daughter.
Yeah, but what about
other people's children?
I bet you spooked him.
- He won't be back.
- I hope you're right.
Turn that brain off.
- Go to sleep.
- Okay.
- Goodnight.
- I am so glad that we did this.
- Yeah.
I just, I don't tend
to get out on my own.
Well, the life of a single
mother must not be easy.
I know that I'm not
the only one in town
but it really feels like it
sometimes.
- You know?
- Yeah.
Does your ex help out at all?
He..
I prefer to keep anything
involving him in the past.
I mean,
Mallie and I moving here
was really about a fresh start
you know,
so it's important for me to--
Yeah, I--
Lena! Congrats are in order.
Dylan told me that Mallie won
the Eager Reader Award.
- Hey. Thank you.
- I'm not surprised.
Hi. I don't know you, I'm Emma.
Hi, I'm Karina.
Nice to meet you.
Our kids share a teacher.
And thank goodness
it's Mallie, too.
I mean, Dylan could never.
I mean, he's way too shy.
'But your little Miss Thing
is gonna steal the show!'
Yeah, I'm, I'm not sure Mallie
wants to be part of a show.
But she has to,
we're gonna have all the winners
read a passage
from their favorite book
you know, to inspire
the other kids to read.
I'm head
of the parents' association.
We're always looking
for volunteers. Are you local?
I am, I own
a children's store on 3rd.
Get out! What's it called?
Juvenile Shop
Children's Boutique.
I know it.
I'm gonna peek by for myself.
Mallie got a dress
from my shop that I made.
- She wanted--
- Actually, about the--
No kidding!
We should have you
present an award to the kids.
You know, we need to show..
...our community
supports each other
and it would be great exposure
for your shop.
- I would love it.
- Lena, always good to see you.
And, Karina, nice to meet you.
I've got to run.
Always a million things.
I'll be in touch.
She's a ball of energy?
She sure is.
- Are you okay?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- Will Mallie be excited?
Yeah, I guess I am.
Have to take back all of that.
My God, I-I..
I'm so sorry, I thought that
you, you changed your mind
I assumed that--
- It's fine. It's fine.
- I..
Did Mallie say anything
about the other day?
She, she thought the man
knew where the fairies lived
and was about to go
right along with him.
See why I have to keep
such a tight leash on her?
I mean, she's amazing,
but she's a handful.
Well, I can help keep eyes
on her if you'd like me to.
That's.. I don't wanna
burden you with that.
It's not a burden.
It's what you do.
- Cheers.
Sounds like you made that
new friend you were hoping for.
Is it strange
that I feel more connected
to Lena's kid than to her?
You want one just like her?
I do.
Careful, Lena's gonna think
maybe you're trying
to swipe her for yourself.
Poor Lena.
You know, she was
so unnecessarily worried
about the worst thing happening,
and then it almost did.
This is the world
that we're living in
and this is why
I have such hesitation.
What if I can't protect--
Don't start thinking like that.
We live in the kind of world
that we make for ourselves
and you and I
are working towards
the life we've always wanted.
We are.
- Speaking of work..
- Karina..
You have everything it takes
to be a great mother.
- I'm glad you're so sure.
- I am.
I wanna be sure, too.
I just hope that one day..
...I can be everything
that a child needs.
More sugar, anyone?
Mine is perfect. Thank you.
Mine needs more flavor.
What kind of tea
are we having today, my love?
''- Ooh.
I thought I detected, um
fresh notes of the garden
in my tea.
Delicious, like always.
Honey, mommy really needs
some caffeine.
Are you okay if I go inside and
make Karina and I some coffee?
Sure, and then you can
get rid of the yucky taste
with my world-famous
delicious tea!
Okay, my love.
I'll be right back.
So, Mallie, did you come up
with this recipe yourself?
Yeah. I just maked it up.
Well, it's delicious.
Well, I've been having tea
parties for a very long time.
I used to have tea parties
with my dolls.
Brings back very good memories.
Yeah, me, too.
I miss my dolls sometimes.
- Well, where are they?
- I-I don't know.
I had different dolls and toys
when I was called Emily.
Well, is Mallie
your middle name?
No. At my other house
my name was Emily.
Right.
You moved here right before
you started school.
Yup.
Well, did you change your name
when you started school?
Mallie?
Mom, can we have those treats
you were saving
for a special day?
Well, you're gonna break me down
anyway, so, yes.
- 'But only one, okay, love?'
- Okay.
The coffee will just be
another minute.
This is nice.
Yeah, it is.
You gotta, you gotta watch her.
She'll take two
and tell you otherwise.
- Yeah, she's quite a character.
- Yeah, she is.
She, um..
She told me
her name used to be Emily.
Really?
Last week she was telling people
that her mom was famous.
Can you imagine
their disappointment
when they meet me? I mean..
What am I gonna do with her?
It's odd, isn't it?
'It is, but she's a kid.'
'Kids say things and don't
analyze them the way adults do.'
Yeah, but what if she was trying
to tell me something?
- What do you think's going on?
- I don't know.
But what if something is?
Well, you asked Lena
and she gave you an answer
but you weren't satisfied
with it.
I think
she was dodging my question.
Well, she left her husband
or something along those lines.
Maybe she needs to protect
their identity.
But what if it's not that
and it's something worse?
Hold that thought.
Emma? Hi.
What a little treasure trove.
I can't believe
I've not been here before.
I brought you a flyer
for the assembly.
Thanks.
Gosh, really, just too cute.
It was so great
meeting you the other day
and thanks so much
for stopping by.
I'm sorry I interrupted.
But Lena would've kept you all
to herself now, wouldn't she?
She keeps a lot of things
to herself.
I mean, you know, in contrast to
Mallie because she's just such--
A little spitfire? I know it.
Dylan had kindergarten
with her, too.
So you must know them
really well.
No one does. Lena keeps
her head down and to herself.
Which is why I was so happy
to see her with you.
Well, yeah.
Why do you think that is?
Well, she's a pinch older.
And, well, despite our efforts
to rope her in
she doesn't strike me
as much of a joiner.
Yeah, well, you know, it must be
hard being all on her own.
But, I mean, let your kid take
a school picture, am I right?
What do you mean?
Mallie doesn't do a picture day.
Lena is afraid
of child predators
and how stressful
to be wired that way.
But enough about Lena.
'I don't want you thinking
I'm all gossipy'
when we're just
getting to know each other.
- No, that's not--
- I'm kidding.
I'm kidding.
But I'm telling you,
get ready for a rush
because I'm gonna tell everyone
about this place.
That's so nice of you.
Do you hike? I have a group.
We, hit the trail and then
we gorge ourselves over lunch.
Sounds like my kind of group.
I know where to find you.
The books I ordered came in
so I thought I'd swing by
Lena's and drop 'em off
to save her a trip.
I should be home
within the hour.
'No rush.'
- Okay, bye.
- 'Bye.'
'Hi, it's Lena. Sorry I missed
your call. Leave a message.'
'911. What's your emergency?'
Yeah, hi, I'm at
1-1-0-3-0 Woodland Avenue.
There's an incident,
an altercation, maybe.
I think my friend's in trouble.
- 'Are you inside the home now?'
- No, I'm-I'm in the car.
I just saw a man
go into the house.
I, I think
I hear them struggling.
'Officers
are on their way, ma'am.'
'Please stay
inside your vehicle.'
Thank you.
- 'Right now!'
- 'Lena, Lena..'
'Lena, put that down.'
'Lena, put that down!'
'It is none of your business.
Keep her out of this.'
'Okay. You have to stop.
Lena, no, put that down.'
'Put that.. Lena, no, no! No.'
'Get out!'
'Get out! I said get out!'
Sorry.
Karina?
Wh-what are you doing here?
Lena, I called the police,
they're on their way.
Lena! Lena, are you okay?
Lena! God! Are you alright?
I-I heard you scream
and there was glass breaking--
It-it was just an unsuccessful
burglary, that's all.
Well, you did the right thing.
Is she okay?
She can sleep
through an air raid.
Lena, why don't I
take the couch tonight?
No, we're... We're fine.
I mean,
the police were thorough.
There's no reason for you
to trouble yourself, really.
It's no trouble.
It's just,
then I'd have to explain
why you're here and, you know
right now she doesn't know
anything's amiss.
I would, I would just
rather keep everything
status quo for now.
Understood.
What did you tell the police?
Exactly what I told you.
The same story.
I'm surprised
they didn't wanna question me.
I'm sure they have
bigger emergencies
to tend to than this.
I mean, I didn't wanna
keep them when we're fine.
So what's your analysis?
- What?
- Well, is it edible?
Thank you.
I'm sorry, babe.
I don't mind you
being out to lunch
but we're currently
out to dinner.
I know.
I just have this bad feeling
I can't shake.
Can you please try?
What if Mallie is in danger?
What if she needs our help?
Look, we can only be
so involved.
I mean, I understand that Mallie
has an over-active imagination
but I don't buy that
as an excuse
to hide what's going on
around her.
Would you do that?
No, but we're not her parents.
Just if something else
happens to her and we're--
Your empathy for her is a sign
you're gonna be a great mother
but we have to let
Mallie's mother
take care of her daughter
her way.
I get it.
You want me to drop
this whole thing.
Maybe I am misreading it.
But if I'm not
do you promise
that if Mallie's in danger
'we will help her?'
Of course.
I've always got your back.
You know that, right?
I know.
Thanks.
- Eat before it gets cold.
- Yeah.
'Luckily, they're gonna keep
the incident under wraps, so..'
'I'm so surprised you think
they want to alert the public.'
Well, I, I shared with them
that I've spent years
trying to conceal our
whereabouts from my ex-husband
and if they ran a story on me
all of those efforts
would go to waste, so..
So your ex-husband,
do you think that he's the one
that tried to take Mallie?
It was almost successful
when she was a little baby
but I'll never let that
happen again.
So it wasn't him.
When's the last time you've..
I've spent so many years
off the radar for Mallie's sake
it's-it's not natural for me to
you know,
settle into a community.
But you have been
just a wonderful gift for us.
- You guys, too.
- Don't get me wrong.
I mean, the parents here
are, are welcoming.
It's just
they're so involved
in everybody's lives, you know
it's just, it's nice to have
a friendship that isn't forced
because, you know,
a play date went well.
Yeah.
So when are you and Ryan
getting
in the baby-making business?
Technically, we already are.
What did I tell you?
Isn't this the cutest ever?
Karina, this is Jenn.
We were just talking
baby shower registry
and I brought her
straight over here
because you have all this stuff.
I mean, all this great stuff.
I wouldn't know what to call it.
I could've really used
this place when I had Dylan.
Great to meet you, Jenn.
Congratulations.
Thanks. And you, too.
Emma said you're new here.
You know, it's been about
a year, but it's taken a million
to get settled and to get
this place up and running.
Well, you've done a great job
and now you need
to get acquainted here.
Do you hike?
Yes, I do, but I am
more inclined to do so
if it's followed by a brunch.
- What did I tell you?
- She's gonna fit right in.
So her husband does
all the wood stuff
and she does all the dresses.
You're kidding.. Wow!
So talented.
Idea. So I'm hosting
Jenn's baby shower.
What do you think
if we have it here?
I mean, we can move
all the middle stuff out
and have the food over there.
I mean, it would be
great exposure for you
and you get to meet everyone.
I love it.
You know, that sounds like fun.
Just let me know
what I need to do to help.
She said yes.
- You don't mind?
- I love the idea.
- That is amazing.
- Unique, right?
I'm tired
of the same old shindig.
Since we're here,
um, we could actually
do these things as parents,
you know?
We could. Is it weird
that we don't have a kid?
We're going through the motions.
It's so easy, we just..
Speaking of that,
wait, wait. I have to go.
I told Lena that I would go
check on Mallie's dress
before the ceremony started.
Okay?
Sounds good. Do you want me
to save you a seat?
Yes, please. I'll be right back.
Mallie, you look so beautiful!
Are you excited
to read your book to everyone?
'Can I read Karina
my favorite part now?'
Honey, you, you h-had
the book. You had it in the car.
I had to carry my bag
with both hands.
'And my dress is too tight.'
N-no problem. I saw a couple
of copies at the front desk.
I can watch Mallie
if you wanna go get it.
- Okay. Are you sure?
- Of course.
Okay, hon, remember,
you're my most precious thing
in the world, okay?
Turn around. Let me see.
I know what the problem is.
You've been doing some growing.
I just knew what was happening.
I'm just gonna stick
my hand right underneath here.
- Okay?
- Okay.
What's this? What happened?
That's just my ugly spot.
Honey, no part of you is ugly.
The ugly goes away
when I keep the Band-Aid on it.
I see.
Band-Aids help things heal.
Does it hurt?
No. It's been there
as long as I can remember
that I forget.
Like a birthmark or a freckle?
No. Just a spot
that no one is supposed to see.
That's why my mom puts
a Band-Aid on it.
Hey.
Every part of you is perfect,
okay?
I don't want you hiding
any part of yourself.
I think
what you're saying is true.
Unless you're playing
hide and seek.
Mallie,
I think that you're right.
Let's see
if we can fix this dress.
And that's one of the things
I love about this book
which I recommend to everyone
and even their dogs.
'And that is our last recipient'
of Willow Elementary's
Eager Reader Award.
Let's give them all a hand.
Okay, it's picture time.
Hey. Hey, hey, hey,
where are you goin'?
Don't you wanna get your picture
taken with the group?
Where do you think
the picture will be?
Maybe in the newspaper.
For everyone to see? Even people
that don't live here?
- Probably.
- Will our names be in there?
Maybe.
You know, I've always wanted
to be in the newspaper.
Mom's not gonna like it, though.
Why not?
She doesn't like us
taking pictures.
Well, we better not, then.
Hey, how about I see
if I can still get your name in?
- Would you like that?
- Yeah.
We're gonna take off.
They're just gonna do a picture.
But..
But let your kid take
a school picture, am I right?
'What do you mean?'
Mallie doesn't do a picture day.
'I called the police
they're on their way.'
She, um, told me
her name used to be Emily.
Really?
What's this? What happened?
Just a spot
that no one is supposed to see.
- Hi.
- Um..
W-well, since you guys left
so quickly the other day
Mallie didn't get
her book.
- And I, I brought you this.
- Thanks.
- Come on in.
- Thank you.
Emma came by my shop
the other day
and, she brought Jenn.
She was just glowing,
it was really great, um..
And they invited me on a hike
on Sunday.
Have you ever went hiking
with them?
No. Actually, I haven't.
Just some things don't
make sense to get a sitter for.
- So.. Thanks.
- There you go.
Um, Ryan and I are happy
to watch Mallie for you
any evening
that you wanna go out.
We're, we're okay.
Lena, about the group photo
yesterday..
Are we okay?
Sure. I just, I mean..
Sorry, I was..
What?
You know, I..
Mallie wouldn't take
her medal off.
You must be so proud.
She's a good kid. I'm lucky.
Do you...ever wish
that her dad
was still in the picture?
No, we're..
We're fine on our own.
Do you mind me asking
what happened?
Well, there's really
nothing to share.
We..
We just moved forward.
Why don't you let her
take a picture, Lena?
Why don't you stay out of this?
I'm just concerned.
You know, if you are hiding
from something
you can let me know. I--
Excuse me?
How dare you suggest
I'm hiding something?
- I didn't say that.
- No?
You're not a parent.
You could do me a favor.
Stop trying to parent my child.
Okay?
That's not what I'm doing.
- No?
- No, I am concerned.
- Mallie has told me something--
- Mallie is a child.
You have, you don't have any
business talking to a child
without their parent there.
I mean, she is a kid.
Kids say things..
I mean, come on.
Especially kids
who read a lot of books.
- I mean..
- I know.
And I am not a parent
and I have no idea
what you've been through.
But I want you to know
that I am here if you need me.
What I need right now..
...is for you to leave.
Are you Karina Harlow?
I am.
Come in.
We were visited
by a Lena Colbert.
- Do you know her?
- I do.
Well, Ms. Colbert's requested
to file a restraining order
against you.
Why? What did I do?
'According to Ms. Colbert,
there's been'
some inappropriate behavior
regarding her daughter.
Like what? That's crazy.
Did you tell her that
her daughter was taken by a man
while the child
was in your care?
Well, yes.
'Were you outside of her home'
'when you thought
you saw a man enter'
'and you took it upon yourself'
to call the police?
'Did you gift her daughter
with several items'
'including a custom-made dress'
'that you later
made alterations to'
while it was on the child,
with no other adults present?
That's not how it happened.
That's not
how it happened at all.
This is not right.
Ms. Colbert
is feeling very uncomfortable
with the multiple
false scenarios
that you've created
and embellished on
with no actual evidence
that they've occurred.
I didn't make any of this up.
Well, you've attempted
to involve the authorities
on more than one occasion,
all of which Ms. Colbert feels
'are the product
of delusional paranoia.'
'Now her daughter has expressed
discomfort as well.'
Did you even talk to Mallie?
If we do go through
with serving you
you'd have to appear in court.
I know that might not be
the best thing
for a business
that caters to minors
so she has agreed
to a polite warning.
She's not right.
You have to talk to her
about her daughter.
- She is hiding something.
- Ms. Harlow.
If I have
to speak with you again
it'll be in regard
to a court-ordered appearance.
Respect her wishes.
Have a good day.
Is everything alright?
No.
Should I be worried?
Lena's trying
to cast suspicion on me
so they don't suspect her.
'I know I have a tendency
to keep to myself'
and I hope it doesn't insult you
or your efforts to include me.
It's just,
being a single parent is..
...it's hard.
Of course. We're here
if you ever need a hand.
Actually, that's why I wanted
to, um, talk with you guys and..
I don't wanna start
any problems or..
But Mallie has, has said
some things to me
and I just,
I can't, I can't ignore it.
Mallie has shared
that there have been some things
that have made her
uncomfortable.
And again, I don't, I don't
want to jump to any conclusions
or cast anyone in a bad light
but, you know,
she's, she's my kid.
Of course. What happened?
It's Karina.
I would
really appreciate your help
in ensuring Karina
keeps her distance from Mallie.
Did she do something to Mallie?
She can be a little aggressive
in her urges to parent my child.
And I just..
I feel a line has been crossed.
T-thank you.
I-I'm sure this wasn't easy.
I just, I felt as a parent..
...you had a right to know.
You have our support.
It's Karina.
- That's uncomfortable.
- Right?
It's so sad.
This couple that has a business
that caters to children..
...they can't have a child
of their own.
Just breaks my heart.
Hey, so I don't want
to alarm you or anything
but there's been a man
hanging around here.
He was in a blue Jeep and..
Just keep a close eye on her.
Are you kidding?
I had Maya the same month
that little Emily went missing.
We flew out of Copeland County
as soon as I recovered
from my C-section.
I'll never shake that.
Emily?
That little girl
that was kidnapped.
About five years ago.
What a nightmare.
Have a good one.
'Please, we beg you.'
'Return our little girl.'
If anyone has seen anything
or knows any information..
'...please..'
She has a birthmark.
Right here.
Tragedy strikes
in Copeland County this morning
as a married couple
was killed in a car crash
just south of the I-45 bridge.
Lacy and Tom Worthington
were on their way to the airport
at around 6.30 a.m.
says the Copeland County
sheriff's office
when their vehicle lost control
and flipped upside down.
'The couple was killed
instantly.'
'This news comes
almost two years after'
'the late couple's daughter
was abducted from their home.'
Tom and Lacy leave
no surviving family.
'But friends mourning
at the crash site say'
'they were inspired by
the couple's tireless search..'
Ryan, you have to see this.
This Emily Worthington
would be nearly eight
and Mallie
is nearly eight as well.
And they're both
blonde-haired, blue-eyed.
I hate to say it, but so are
most of the other little girls
that go missing, and Emily
is a pretty common name.
And what about the car crash?
But this girl was taken right
out from under her mom's nose.
Right from her bedroom
in Copeland County.
And she has a birthmark.
- Who? Mallie or Emily?
- Both.
Mallie has a spot
on her shoulder
that Lena makes her cover
with a Band-Aid
and Emily had one
on the back of her shoulder
in the same area.
Well, could Mallie have
heard this story somewhere
and just kinda made it her own?
I don't think so. She was three
when this happened.
Wow, I don't know.
You're gonna have
to talk to Lena about this.
Well, if I ask
too many questions
she just might pick up
and disappear with Mallie
somewhere untraceable.
Well, once you make
an accusation like this
you can't come back from it.
Start with Lena before you do
or say anything to anyone.
I just have to do right
by Mallie, you know
and she doesn't want me
anywhere near them.
And now I know why.
Hey, Jenn, what's going on?
Hey there, so I really
appreciate you offering
to host the shower, it's just,
the more I think about it
I'm starting to feel like
a hot-air balloon
and I think I just wanna
keep it intimate and easy.
Yeah, of course.
Yeah, We're just gonna do it
at my house with family
and a few close friends.
I don't want a fuss.
I totally understand.
Let me know if there's anything
I can do to help.
'Thanks. You take care.'
You, too.
Lena's already going
after, my new friends.
What do you mean?
The friends that I just made,
they're pulling away.
I'm not backing down.
Okay, I support that
but she's actively going ahead
of you to discredit you.
Are you really up
for that kind of a fight?
I have to do right by Mallie
even if it costs me
my reputation.
Maybe go around Lena.
You know, enlist the help of
someone who isn't in the circle.
You're right.
Hey, Cam, can you meet me?
It's urgent.
'I'm just trying to figure out
why she would wanna'
keep this burglary quiet.
I mean, I would wanna
get this guy, right?
Well, by the sound of the
bleeding, I mean, she got him.
Maybe that's the reason why.
Maybe.
And I went to the local library
to find out what I could
on Emily Worthington case.
There wasn't much,
she's from a small town
there wasn't
a lot of coverage on it, but..
...I found this picture of her.
This is her, this is Mallie.
That's quite
a striking resemblance.
You know what, can you send that
to me for reference?
Of course, of course.
And would you mind presenting
this to the authorities?
I just don't think
that they would take me
seriously right now.
Absolutely.
Karina?
Sorry to interrupt.
I just wanted to say
thanks again
for your offer
for Jenn's shower, but..
I know. Jenn called me.
Well, I'll see you around.
'Karina was having lunch
with some woman'
'showing her a picture
of Mallie.'
'It was so strange, when I came
over, she hid the picture.'
'I was sure
she was up to something'
so I waited and got her
friend's license plate number.
I have a friend at the DMV
who gave me her address.
I think you should go
and talk to her and figure out
what's really going on.
'9-1-1. What's the emergency?'
'Hello?'
I'm sorry, I-I just felt like
I took too much of a break today
and I need to catch up.
I left you some food
on the counter.
Aw, thanks.
I'll be home in a bit.
'Well, I'll try
to wait up for you.'
No, that's okay. I'll
snuggle into bed next to you.
Alright. Love you.
You, too.
'Paging Dr. Roth, please report
to Emergency immediately.'
Hey.
- Hey.
Um..
Help me get this out.
- No, sweetie.
- We have to go.
No, no, the doctor said
if you hadn't turned your head
when you did,
this could have been fatal.
I'm fine, I promise.
We have to go.
Honey, no.
The police think
that this was a robbery.
It was not a robbery,
Ryan, please.
Honey, Look at me. Look at me.
This was a really close call.
You've been in some really
dangerous situations lately.
Okay, it's time
to take a step back.
Please.
That's weird.
Hello?
Yes, this is she.
My gosh.
Is she okay?
'Will the orderly on duty
please come to reception?'
Hey.
Love ya.
I couldn't ask
for a better friend.
I'm so sorry.
Karina.
I couldn't protect her.
I can't even protect myself.
Hey, you couldn't
even if you wanted to.
How am I gonna protect Mallie?
Okay, these incidents
they are unfortunate,
but they are unrelated.
Do you honestly believe that?
Because I'm not gonna
be able to forgive myself
if I don't do something.
Okay, that may be,
but you shouldn't do anything
without the help
of the authorities.
They're not going
to listen to me or you.
We have to push forward.
We can't handle this, we're not
equipped, we need their help.
The police think
that I'm a danger to Mallie.
They've already threatened
to slapped me
with a restraining order.
Why would we waste our energy
trying to convince them
that they're wrong when
we can use that to help Mallie?
Sweetie, you're upset.
Okay, I know this is very
difficult to see Cam like this
but, sweetie, please,
I need you to think clearly.
Is that really, really
the best choice of action?
Lena's not well. I know it.
And if she's mentally unstable,
then she needs to get help.
We have to think about Mallie
here, someone has to
because if Mallie is Emily
then we have to be sure,
you know?
I mean, one day
we might have a Mallie
and if she's in trouble,
wouldn't we want someone
to do everything that they can
to help her?
Okay, okay, I just think
we're entering territory here
neither of us
know how to navigate.
I know that you're scared,
I'm too, but we have--
Do what, exactly?
The man that tried
to take Mallie
or the person that was
at their house that night
they may have been involved
in the Emily kidnapping
or they can know
something about Lena.
Okay, I don't want you
doing that alone.
I can start by reviewing
the security-cam footage
from the day
that Mallie was almost taken.
Maybe I can ID him or his car--
Karina.
And I won't do anything else
without you.
Now can we please
get me cleared to leave here?
'One minute please, ma'am.'
That's why I'm so surprised
he didn't report it. I..
My son said that he scraped
the side of the car pretty bad.
The poor man's probably worried
about how much
this is gonna cost him.
That's exactly why
I wish he had left a note and..
I'm just trying to teach my son
responsibility for his actions
that's why I want him
to call the man
and properly report the damage
and apologize.
Can you get me a number?
'I found a similar Jeep
under an Ivan Serling.'
Ivan Serling.
I know she's dangerous.
I was trying to get Mallie
away from her.
I thought you were trying
to kidnap her.
No, I understand that
in retrospect
but you don't know my wife
like I do.
- I had to take the chance.
- Lena's your wife?
Technically, yeah,
but I haven't seen her in years.
For the last week, like I said,
I've been tracking her
to try to save Mallie from her.
How long have you been
tracking her?
Her real name
is Isabelle Redder.
I searched every county court
in the state for her name change
and a few weeks ago
I finally got lucky.
And it was here.
One day I saw her,
but she was with a little girl.
For a brief second,
I lost it, I thought
"What if
that little girl was mine?"
You know, m-maybe she didn't
wanna raise a child with me
and so she tried to kill me..
Then I came to my senses and I-I
realized w-what's bothering me
is that she looks so familiar
and not because
she may be my daughter.
A few days before she left me
we went by this park and..
...she was fixed
on this little blonde girl
about three years old.
Said it reminded her
of her littler Abby, you know
the one who was taken from her.
Where were you living
at the time?
Copeland County.
I think that toddler
might be Mallie.
I knew she was violent.
But kidnapping?
I never thought that she'd be
capable of such a thing.
But I-I..
I don't know anymore.
You should try to understand
that Lena wasn't always
this way.
It's because of what happened
to her when she was a child.
Isabelle, or Lena
gave birth at 16
but Lena's doctor diagnosed her
as having a mental illness
and that meant
she was incapable
of safely raising a child.
She refused to give
that baby up for adoption.
She ran away with the baby.
Her doctor told the Department
Of Children And Family Services
who came and took the child
from Lena.
This was your child as well?
No, no, this was years before
I met Isabelle.
Her daughter
is in her twenties by now
raised by a, a loving family,
we're told.
You need to tell the police
what really happened.
What's the point?
They won't believe me.
She's too dangerous.
'Who knows what could happen?'
'And think about
what she can do to Mallie.'
You made a terrible mistake.
I will do anything
for my daughter.
And if you all don't mind,
I would love for you guys
to try my newest recipe.
It only takes a few moments
for the magic powers to mix it.
Abracadabra.
'Mallie, come on,
it's time to go.'
- But I have guests.
- Don't argue with me.
- Five more minutes?
- Say goodbye to your friends.
- Now.
- Okay.
Psst. Mallie.
- Karina.
- Shh, shh, shh, shh.
You came just in time for tea.
- I'm so lucky.
- Come in the yard.
Actually, I was wondering
if, you wanna come with me.
If I come with you,
can I at least have a tea party?
Of course, sweetie,
of course, you can
but you can only come
if you feel comfortable.
I think maybe I would like
to go to your house.
Okay, great. Come on, let's go.
'Are you going on a trip?'
No, actually, we-we're
kind of on a trip right now.
This is my best friend's house
and she's not here,
so we're watching it for her.
So it's kinda like
having two houses.
Fun?
Yeah. Karina,
I need to use the restroom.
Okay, go ahead,
it's right in there.
What if Lena goes to the cops?
She wouldn't risk it
a second time.
How can you be sure?
How can she report
her child missing
if her child
is actually a missing child?
Okay, the way we're going
about this, it looks really bad.
Like, we're taking
a child as well.
What? We didn't have a choice.
She was gonna leave with Mallie.
We were never gonna
see her again.
Mallie is Emily.
No one's gonna care
how we prove it.
And how are we gonna prove that?
Well, Lena attacked me
at the store.
I can go and get
the video surveillance of it.
Wait, Lena attacked you
at the sore?
Ryan!
You promised me
that you would do this.
Please.
- Right, I'm going with you.
- No.
Mallie, hey,
can you do me a huge favor
and, take care of Ryan?
'Cause I gotta leave
for a little bit.
Sure.
I think he might need
a hair cut.
I think you're right.
Sit right down here, sir.
Okay.
So where did you learn
how to do this?
Some things people
just have a natural talent for.
Well, you are very talented
at it.
I miss my daddy.
Yeah?
Thank you for bringing me here.
I really like having you here.
No, Lena.
'...to an automatic
voice message.'
Ryan!
Damn it!
Ryan! Mallie!
My God, Ryan! Ryan!
Ryan!
Mallie's gone. Call the cops.
He's stable, but it's best
we keep him overnight.
The doctors would wanna
run some tests.
We've notified the police,
so expect a call.
Get some sleep and you can
visit him in the morning.
Okay, let me know
if anything changes
and I'll come right over.
We will.
- Any change.
- We will.
My purse.
'My sister and my niece
are staying with you.'
I was wondering
if you could tell me
if they've checked in yet.
My sister is staying with you
and I was wondering if you could
tell me if she's checked in yet.
My niece, she's seven,
she's got blonde hair and..
Yes, I understand that
information is private, but..
I understand, I understand,
I was just wondering if I could
give you the make and model
of their car
and you can tell me
if you've seen it?
Can you tell me
if our car is still there?
I-I, I just don't know if she's
left to come pick me up yet..
The license plate number
is 3-D-H, that's all I know.
It's California plates,
though. It..
Yeah, yeah, I can wait.
It is?
Well, um, th-thanks so much, um.
Actually, my mom just texted me
and she was, like, in the shower
when I called.
Okay, thanks a ton. Bye.
'Mallie, are-are you ready?
Do you have all your stuff?'
- 'Think so.'
- 'Mallie.'
'Gather up your things, okay?
- 'Mom, you said--'
- 'Come on, honey, let's go.'
- 'What's wrong?'
- 'Sweetie, grab your..'
'Grab your bag. The car's here.'
Mallie, let's go!
Mallie.
Honey, hurry, come on.
Seatbelt.
No, no, no!
'Mom, where are we going?'
Mom, why are we moving again?
'Honey, please stop asking
so many questions.'
'Mom, why are we moving again?'
'I'll tell you what, let me
find somewhere to pull over'
'and I'll tuck you in
so you could get some sleep.'
'Is that okay?'
Ivan.
I need your help.
Isabelle Redder?
I'm sorry,
you have the wrong number.
'I know it's you, Isabelle.'
'I'm sorry about Abby.'
I'm sorry they took her
from you. And I want to help.
- Please let me help.
- Stay out of this, Karina.
You took Abby to the overlook
to see the city
'and that's the last time
you saw her.'
That.. That's not what happened.
You wanted her
to see the lights.
I bet you can't go there
without thinking about her.
Lena?
Hey there.
Hardly any cars
have passed through.
Well, we only need one.
This was the spot.
I took her here more than once
and she would just sit here
staring at over the city
whispering to herself.
Thanks again for doing this.
Listen, I'm gonna park my car
up there, out of sight.
All I need for you to do is
to distract her long enough
for me to grab Mallie. Okay?
Anything?
Not yet. Wait, wait..
I do.
It's a gray sedan.
'That will be her.'
What if she sees me
and bolts?
Lay low
until she gets out of the car
and then you approach her.
'Can you see a little girl
with her?'
No. Not from here.
Keep me on speaker, okay?
Don't hang up.
You got it.
You always loved to come up here
and look at the city lights.
Don't think
I didn't expect to see you here.
Isa, I have missed you.
I know
you have missed her, but..
...you have to stop running.
Ivan.
Don't make this harder
than it has to be.
I agree.
- Look, let's just start fresh.
- She's not yours.
- And I'm not giving her up.
- Who?
I'm not stupid, Ivan.
Is there someone in the car
with you?
If there were, do you really
think I would let you near her?
We can be a family.
I'm not falling for this, Ivan.
What, you, you surprised?
- Look, you are not gonna--
- I am.
- Because I have to.
- Put the gun down.
You know why? Because you will
never stop looking.
Please put the gun down.
- She will never stop looking.
- Please.
It's over, Ivan.
Lena! No!
God..
Help! Help!
- Karina!
- Help!
Ivan! Ivan?
- Can you hear me? Are you okay?
- 'No.'
'No, I'm not. I'm not.
I'm shot.'
Karina?
You're something else.
I trusted you.
I let you into our home
'into our lives.'
This is about
what's right for Mallie.
This is what's best for Mallie.
It is not what's best
for Mallie.
You don't know
what's best for her.
- I'm her mother!
- It's not! You're dangerous!
- She's not safe!
- She is safe with me!
I'm her mother!
What?
You didn't uncover that
in your research?
Yeah,
that's 'cause I'm good.
And I'm an even better mother
'and I will do anything
for my Mallie.'
- '911. What's your emergency?'
- 'Hello. I need help.'
'She has a gun.'
'Track my phone. I..'
Ivan. Ivan, are you okay?
It's okay, help is on the way.
- Okay?
- Karina!
Lena, you have to stop running.
You have to stop hiding.
You have to give Emily up.
You still have a chance
for a relationship with Abby.
Don't you want a relationship
with her?
It's too late for that.
That's not what she told me.
- W-what?
- We found her.
It's time to stop hiding.
Please put down the gun.
Police. Put the gun down!
Slowly put the gun down
and step back.
Please put down the gun.
'...gun down, ma'am.'
'Ma'am, put the gun down.'
It's okay.
Do you want a cracker?
Who else needs a cracker?
Yum-yum yum-yum.
- Emily.
- Yeah?
Come on out front,
Ryan and I wanna talk to you.
Okay. Bye.
Whoa!
Emily, we have something
very important to tell you.
Well, what is it?
Well, we just found out
this morning..
That you're getting
a baby sister.
My own baby sister?
I love you.
We love you, too.
Thank you for everything.
Thank you.