You sure everything's okay?
Of course.
Who's there?
Sorry, Pops, it's just me.
Mikey...
what are you doing here?
There was a problem
with the plane
and it was overbooked
and they said that, you know,
to wait around
for a little while,
'cause they're probably
gonna bump some people, but
it's probably
gonna be hours, so...
Anyway, I just figured
I'd leave tomorrow instead.
Hey, Flo, look who's here.
Flo.
Hey, Ma. Hi.
Hi.
What are you doing?
There were problems
with the plane, and...
they were gonna wait around
for other people
to get bumped.
Anyway, just go back to sleep.
- Everything's okay, yeah?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay. I'm glad we're gonna
see you one more day.
You know what?
I'm just gonna put you down
for one second, okay?
I'll be right back,
just gonna grab that.
Stay right there, okay?
Mikey.
Where are you?
Yeah, yeah,
that airline's awful.
When will you be back?
What was that?
I missed the last part.
Oh yeah, hmm, fine.
Can't you hear?
Those are tears of joy.
Okay. Good night, Michael.
See you tomorrow.
Love you too.
Okay, up we go.
That's over.
Ma?
Yeah, I just...
I was on hold with them
for, like, an hour.
I don't know,
they kept transferrin' me
like, ten times, and finally,
they put me on
with their headquarters in
Georgia or India,
I have no idea,
where it's very far away.
Yeah.
Um... no, they said that...
they said that I could
call back tomorrow morning
or buy a new ticket.
Yeah, tomorrow morning.
I don't either.
Um...
No... yeah, I'm gonna come back
as soon as I can.
Yes.
Yeah.
No, I...
Just will you give Ana
a kiss for me, please?
I love you.
Mom, that smells good.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
- Great, thanks.
- You're welcome, Mom.
Okay.
Could you try the dressing?
Yeah.
How is it?
Mmm...
Okay, come on.
Oh my God, it's good. +Okay.
- Yeah.
- Okay, good.
Okay, would you get the dishes?
Yes.
Okay, and the forks
and the napkins.
And when's your flight?
I don't know, the whole thing
has been so annoying.
I just explained
the whole thing to Laura.
They canceled my flight,
I was on hold forever,
they kept switching me
to all the different places,
and I don't know.
So I'm probably gonna go
tonight or tomorrow, or...
it's gonna be fine.
And I talked to Laura,
it's fine,
and they're both good,
they had a great day
at the park today,
- so it's good.
- Okay.
Yeah. +All right. I hope...
Okay. Yeah.
Did you put vinegar in this?
Yes.
Vinegar is my enemy.
Well, he likes it.
And anyway,
don't have it, it's okay.
It's... you don't need the oil.
I'm making these things happen
with projected light.
Um... with the same...
You think you're seeing
the same things are happening
in terms of, uh,
making things appear,
not appear,
on the picture plane.
Wow.
I's... anyway, this is
really, really beautiful.
It's amazing.
The space is 50, so good.
This is a painting.
I don't know about a paint...
I wouldn't call this a painting.
Why not?
Doesn't use pigment?
No, it isn't that.
Robert.
- What?
Hey, man.
Yeah, it's... fuckin' airplane.
Dude, I wanna get back,
it's freezing here.
No, I can... I can
take care of everything
when I get back there,
be back on Tuesday,
or even if I'm back Wednesday,
I'm sure I won't be, but...
even if I...
Probably be there Tuesday.
But, um...
Um...
Do me a favor.
If anyone asks, you just kinda...
Will you cover for me?
Thanks, man.
I appreciate it.
Mad Mike!
Mad Mike.
Honey, did you call me? No, Ma.
What?
Brigitte.
"What the fuck is your problem?"
"Fine, so I said
pretty fucked-up things.
You know I didn't mean them.
I hear all the shit
you say, like..."
"I didn't do that shit to you.
You want me to hate you?
Well, I do.
I fuckin' hate you 50 much..."
“...right now for what
you're putting me through,
and I'm sure you're just
totally getting off
"on watching me suffer,
aren't you?"
I hate you for we've never met.
"Why don't you fucking give up
on trying to make me
so jealous?"
I love you so much.
"You treat me like...
you treat me like shit.""
You just won't get, get over it.
Brigitte.
"You never gave a shit...
No, obviously not."
"The problem is,
I'm getting sick
of trying to figure out
what I did that was so wrong.”
'Cause I knew [ loved you.
You stupid whore.
You stu... you stupid whore.
Always asking for more
Mikey?
- Sorry, Dad.
Is that the radio?
No, I just found a...
some old songs from high school.
Please play quieter, okay?
- Yeah, okay.
Well, at first, it wasn't true.
Fuck, fuck... fuck, fuck you,
I hope you die too.
You were my first,
I'll be your last.
You'll never forget
our early past.
You'll never forget,
never forget
all the lies and deceit.
You call me after school,
you say you're not well.
When I ask what's wrong,
you say you can't tell, tell.
Well, fuck, fuck, fuck you,
I hope you die too.
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck you,
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck you.
Better find someone new
Laura, will you stop yelling?
Just stop yelling.
No, I don't understand
what you're saying.
Yeah, well,
I'm coming home, right?
Laura?
No, I'm just gonna stay
a little bit longer, okay?
I'm... just a little bit longer.
Because do you know
what it's like
to watch your parents get...
Oh my God.
Laura, do you know
what it's like
to watch your parents get old?
I'm sor... I'm sorry.
Please don't cry.
Listen, I'm gonna hang...
I'm gonna call them
right now, I'm gonna book...
I'm gonna book
their first flight, all right?
I-I'm just gonna...
Welcome to your first choice
in airline travel,
a customer satisfaction leader.
We will gladly assist
with getting a representative
to help you,
but first we need
to ask a few questions
to make sure you are transferred
to the right department.
Are you traveling within the US?
- Say yes.
- Yes.
I'm sorry, I wasn't
able to understand.
- Was that yes?
- Yes! Fuck.
I'm sorry, I was still
not able to understand.
Yes, fucker!
Please be patient
as we transfer your call
to a representative
who can assist you.
Thank you for flying
with All-American Sky.
My name is Jonathan,
how can [ help you?
Thank you for flying
with All-American Sky.
This is Jonathan.
Can you hear me?
Hello?
Customer, can you hear me?
Okay, we seem to have
trouble with the line,
so, customer,
if you can hear me,
I'm going to have to ask you
to place your call again,
I'm sor...
Hey, Ma.
Hi.
You startled me.
What are you doing?
Nothin'. Sorry.
Everything's okay?
Yeah, everything's fine now.
I talked to Laura, and actually,
we sorted everything out.
She... she suggested
at the end of the conversation,
she said, "You should just
stay an extra night," so...
And I'm gonna do that,
and I can be with you guys
a little bit longer.
So probably leave, like,
Wednesday or something.
And things are okay
with your job?
It's fine, they emailed me
everything a little bit ago
and I've already started on it,
so everything's good.
How is it out there?
It's freezing.
I just came back
from the Food Emporium.
I just ran into Maggie.
She said Dante is back,
he's got his own job
and he seems to be doing well.
Wow.
Yeah.
I'd love to see...
Maybe I'll do a little bit
more work up here
and then go over and see him.
- Great. Okay. Good.
- All right.
I'm gonna go start some lunch,
Bye, Ma.
Where you going?
I'm going over to Dante's.
Why now?
Because I just finished
some work.
I'm gonna go over and say hi.
You need more clothes,
-you need a hat and scarf.
<I'm fine, it's two blocks away.
Put on something...
-it's really, really cold.
+I love you.
Bye, Ma!
It's cold.
I'm fine.
Come on, I'll give you a scarf!
You need gloves!
It's not California!
Fuck.
Oh, yo! What's up, bro?
Hey.
Okay, dude!
What's going on, brother?
I'm good, how are you?
Good, man, how you been?
I'm good, I just...
I'm in town for a business trip
and I was gonna leave
a couple days ago,
but I ended up staying, so
I'm here for a little bit.
Businessman, what's going on?
Come on back, come on.
Hey, Mom, look who's here.
Hi, Nan.
I, uh, saw
the Blimpies out there.
I know, man,
that's some kind of fuckin'
ritzy-titsy, you know,
coffee shop now.
It's a new New York,
and I just...
I been here the whole time,
I can't even get adjusted to it.
You must be, like,
in total shock over this shit.
So what was it like in there?
Ugh, man, the fuckin' worst.
I'm never goin' back.
18 months.
But you know what?
I'm not sorry I went.
Yeah, 'cause it built me up.
- Yeah?
- Yeah, it made me see
a whole different
aspect of life,
a whole different way
of running my life.
At first, I was just
a lethargic, you know,
had no direction.
But I started running
and I started, you know,
thinking there was
a way out of all this mess.
And after the running,
I started lifting weights
and I started...
My mind got right
and everything kinda just
fell into place, you know?
Good.
Hi, Mikey. How are you?
I'm good, how are you?
I heard that
you're in California.
Yeah.
How is it there? +It's good.
It's good, it's really good.
- Are you married yet?
- Married... have a kid.
Yeah, Mom,
Mikey's not a virgin anymore.
- Well, nice to see you.
- You too.
Yo, man, you're not gonna
believe what I found.
Got it.
Close your eyes.
You remember this?
Yes.
Watch... watch, here it comes,
here comes the knockout.
Hearns is smiling
but he's taking shots.
Watch this... pow, bitch!
Hearns turns his back,
takes another right.
Watch this, one more time,
you gotta see this.
Watch this,
watch the right hand.
Here it comes, here it comes...
Hearns is smiling
but he's taking shots.
Bam!
Another right hand!
Hearns turns his back,
takes another right.
Look, he's going down,
he's going down! He's out.
Hearns is down in the third row
and on his back.
And he's not gonna get up.
.I don't believe.
Tommy Hearns tries to get up
and he's...
One more time, come on,
we gotta see this again.
Hello? Hello, hello, hello?
Long distance, please.
Paris stock exchange.
6572,
Here!
Hello?
Baton and Company?
This is Monsieur Verdoux.
I'm wiring 50,000 francs
this morning, is that enough?
No, I won't be in Paris
for some time.
I have one or two matters
to clean up here first.
Robert?
Hey, it's-it's me.
Listen, I'm... I'm, uh,
I'm still in New York,
I'm actually
at my parents' house.
Yeah, listen, I didn't wanna
say anything to you before,
but, um... my mom...
And she's fine,
and they say
she's gonna be fine, but, uh...
she's, uh...
she's been in the hospital,
and...
Thanks.
No, I just... I'd like
to stay until they know every...
The results and what's going on.
Yeah... will tell her.
You... you too.
Thanks.
NPR's Jamie Taraday reports.
There's been widespread
sectarian cleansing
by both Sunni
and Shi'ite militias
since civil war erupted...
You never make me pay, man,
you know what I mean, bro?
Hey, uh... hi, sorry.
I was wondering if maybe...
I have some friends over here,
I was hoping maybe you could
possibly buy us some beer?
I don't know if that's...
It's these guys over here.
Hey.
- Thank you.
- Sure. I, uh...
I got some paper bags
in there, so...
Okay, cool, dude. Thanks.
Thanks.
All right,
Mikey?
Hey!
I tried phoning you before
but your phone wasn't working.
I know, I turned it off
by accident.
We just finished dinner.
Would you like some food?
I could bring you in some food.
No, I'm good,
I had some falafel, and...
Are you okay?
Good.
Could you come and sit with us?
I think I'm just...
I should go lie down.
Come.
I've been waiting
to see you all day.
Come and sit down.
No, no, no, it's okay,
I'm gonna... my stomach...
the falafel...
Please come and sit down.
I could make you some tea.
Come on, please?
I... okay.
Okay. I'll be right back.
Mikey.
Dad.
Your tea is ready.
Wow.
And just have
a little bit of brownie.
New York, New York.
The number for Brigitte Sidell.
S-I-D-E-L-L.
Okay, how 'bout a Sidell on...
Jane Street?
I don't know, Mr. and Mrs...
Okay, thanks.
Hello?
Miss... Miss Sidell?
I don't understand
what happened.
-Probably...
-Things were working okay
and then it just stopped.
Let's try another Ethernet cord.
That's probably the problem.
Good morning, Mikey.
Good morning.
Would you like some breakfast?
I can make some hot cereal?
No, no, no, I gotta go,
I have a huge conference call
for work,
it's this really big,
big, big deal that we've been...
I'm gonna close on, so.
I'm gonna...
How about some coffee, some tea?
No, no, no, I'm gonna just...
I gotta do all this work, so,
so much work stuff.
Mikey?
Yeah?
- Is everything okay?
- Yes, Ma.
Are you sure? Mm-hm,
Can I get you something?
No.
How 'bout some coffee, some tea,
something?
N-no, Ma, I'm just...
I'm in here.
Please. Ma!
- Are you really okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine, I'm just in...
I'm in here.
You don't sound okay.
Ma?
I'm worried about you.
Okay, gimme two minutes, Mom.
I have some cold cereal?
Raisin bran, granola?
Okay.
Mikey?
What time is
your conference call?
It's been canceled.
I'm back!
What's up?
What's the matter?
Mikey?
- Yeah?
Could you come down, please?
We wanna talk with you.
I'm doing work for my job, Dad.
Please come down.
We really need to talk with you.
All right,
I'll be down in a minute.
Mikey.
Okay. What's up?
Is there anything I can get you?
Some coffee, tea?
No... what is it, what is this?
Is this an intervention?
No.
Some soup?
We're concerned, Mikey.
We like having you here,
you know we like
having you visit,
we enjoy it.
So what's the problem?
You're supposed to be here for a
few days, and it's much longer.
Something's wrong, and, uh,
we'd like you to tell us
what it is.
Please, Mikey.
Nothing.
Something's happening.
Don't you need to return home
to your family, to your work?
Are you asking me to leave?
No, it's okay,
'cause if you are,
you just have to ask,
and I'll go.
No, no, sit down, sit down.
We just want you
to speak with us.
Did something happen at home?
With Laura?
Is there somebody else?
I knew it.
How could she, with a newborn?
It's not all her fault.
There's other factors...
involved.
There always are.
What happened?
You don't have to speak,
it's okay.
It's all right.
You can stay here
as long as you want.
I think I'm gonna go outside,
get some air, "cause I feel..."
Oh, shit.
Fuck.
Listen, whatever you do,
please just don't get involved.
I need to handle this my way.
I'm... I'm gonna go out
for a minute.
- Do you know where you're going?
- No, I don't.
I'm just gonna go take a walk
and probably get a coffee.
- Do you have money?
- I'm fine.
Okay, take some money, please.
All right, I'll see you soon.
Here, okay.
I changed my mind.
Mikey?
Mikey.
- Hey, Tom.
- Hey, Laura.
What's up?
Oh, you know, I just wondered
if Mikey's back
from New York yet?
- Not yet.
- Oh, okay.
'Cause I'm dying to play
some backgammon and...
Hey, look, I was just going
to the supermarket.
I was just wondering if, uh,
you need anything,
because I could...
Oh, that's so sweet of you, Tom.
How nice.
No, we're fine, no.
- Thank you.
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
- Oh, all right.
What about something
for the baby, you know,
some of that mashed stuff,
I don't know,
mashed carrots and bananas
or, I don't know,
broccoli, whatever.
Whatever they like.
No, we're okay.
Thank you though.
Well, look, if, uh,
if you need anything,
don't be afraid to ask,
you know where I am,
just around the corner.
- Okay, I will.
- Okay, cool.
Um, okay.
- All right.
- Bye.
By him?
I don't know,
they don't mention...
I have a book here.
Conversations with, uh,
abstra... abstra...
Abstract expressionis...
Expressionists.
But I think it includes him.
Yeah, and it also says
this is gonna be, like,
the last of the abstract...
You know, they now...
They'll now have
the last work of...
Of the abstract expressionists,
in terms of what they consider
to be the first...
That's bull.
There's people,
they-they never got,
like, Max, for instance.
No, but they mean
of that generation.
That generation is, you know,
there's hidden people
we don't know. «No.
And maybe
they don't know either.
And there... and now there's
these art conservators.
-Who's building it?
+I don't really know who,
but there is gonna be
a museum in Denver.
You know, they can show from
the "20s, the '30s, the '40s."
- Yeah.
- They can show, you know...
That doesn't bother me.
- Think that's good.
- Yeah.
Yeah, yeah,
Well...
- He's been working.
I mean, he had been working
and he produced
an enormous amount.
He's not really up hiding it.
The museum will...
This museum will show,
but they're not gonna show
thousands of works.
No, they say, um...
He said we can clear the whole
museum and just do drawings.
He said, the challenging
question is whether people
will come for repeat visits
to see stills art.
Mikey, we're going to Chinatown.
You wanna join us?
Can't.
Shall we bring you back
something?
No, thanks, I'm gonna make
something here.
Okay.
We'll see you in a little while.
Bye.
Bye, Mike.
Yeah, I know, it's crazy.
I, um...
I just came here
for work, and...
I thought it would be
really nice to reconnect.
Okay.
S... so, 10 a.m. tomorrow.
All right,
Can you hang on one second?
Uh, Brigitte,
that's actually my other line.
Um, so, I'll see you then,
Okay, thanks.
Bye.
Um, it's Laura,
Hi, I was...
I was hoping to speak
to you both.
I'm not sure
what Mikey's been telling you,
but we've expected him home
a while ago now.
I don't really understand
where he is or what he's doing.
His phone's off,
and it seems like
he won't speak to me,
and I'm here faking care
of... of Ana and everything.
So please, I would appreciate
if you could, um,
give me some insight
to why he's not coming home.
So please call me back.
Thanks.
Bye.
Message deleted.
Looks very good.
Okay.
I'm just gonna go check
on the pie.
What's going on?
Laura started...
Started seeing someone...
Stop, stop.
Do you recall us
once lying to you?
Is everything okay?
Everything's very good.
Thank you very much,
It's beautiful.
Thank you.
It's fine.
Mikey?
Brigitte.
- Hi.
...“Wow, that's...
I can't believe it.
- I know.
- It's crazy.
It's been a long time.
Yeah.
Hi.
Um, sit down, please.
I see you brought
your little baby.
Julie, that's little Julie.
Say hi.
So, how... how long has it been?
It's been since...
...high school,
our sophomore year...
of high school.
Can I get you something?
Oh, no, no, I'm fine,
I have to...
Okay. Yeah.
So...
- Yeah.
- 80... what's... what's up?
It's very weird.
Um...
I found a... just a letter
that you wrote,
um, from high school.
I found it
in my parents' place, and...
I just-just wanted to...
say that I was sorry.
What?
For what?
For whatever happened back then,
Wow.
Well, um...
whatever you're sorry for,
apology accepted.
It's...
Um...
Now that we have that
out of the way...
So, what have...
What have you been up to
since you, um, you know,
were into fireworks
and skateboards?
- Got one of these?
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
And a wife.
Oh, really? Let me see.
That's Laura.
- She's pretty.
- Thanks.
- And Ana.
- Oh my God.
Aw, what a darling.
Give me your other hand.
Okay.
All right,
I know.
Thank you so much, Tom.
It's my pleasure.
All right,
Hey, Laura, let me, uh,
let me... let me take
the baby inside.
Come on...
I haven't had a baby in my hands
in a long time.
Uh, okay.
Just be really careful.
Hey, baby.
(
Hey.
Back here.
Hey, man, what's up?
What's goin' on?
I fucked up last night, man.
I got a piss test tomorrow too.
What happened?
Oh, man, I got high last night,
but don't worry,
I went to the gym,
and I spent two hours
on the elliptical.
I was working out like
a mad man, like a beast.
I'm not goin' back, don't worry.
Get fuckin' shit
outta my system.
Sweatin' that shit
right outta my system, man.
What are you listening to?
Indigo Girls, man.
Every time I heard them
when I was locked up,
it made me feel like I was free.
There's more than one answer
to these questions.
Pointing me in a crooked line.
And the less I seek my source
for some definitive.
- Hey, listen to it, man.
- I don't need to hear it.
- Indigo Girls.
- Ah, yeah.
Closer I am to fine, yeah
I went to see
the doctor of philosophy.
With a poster of Rasputin
and a beard down to his knee.
He never did marry
or see a B-grade movie.
He graded my performance.
He said he could see through me
I spent four years prostrate
to the higher mind.
Got my paper and I was free
I went to the doctor
I went to the mountains
1 looked to the children
1 drank from the fountains.
There's more than one answer
to these questions.
Pointing me in a crooked line.
And the less I seek my source.
Closer ( am to fine.
Closer I am to fine, yeah.
Mikey.
Hi, Dad.
Mikey?
Hi, Ma.
Come here, please.
Can it wait?
No.
All right, give me a minute.
I'm just gonna put my coat down.
Come here.
What?
Yes.
Ma.
Ma, I'm gonna crush you.
Ma...
Sorry, your mailbox is full,
This number cannot fake
new messages
until you erase some
of your existing messages.
Twenty-two new messages...
First new message.
Mikey, uh,
I'm trying to figure out
where you are,
I don't really under...
Next message.
Mike, I'm wondering
if you have gotten
any of my messages,
and if you have, why-
Next message.
Mikey, this is your wife,
Laura, remember?
Where are you?
Why won't you call me back?
And why won't you answer
my calls?
Next message.
I'm trying to find you and...
figure out what's going on.
Call me back.
You have one new message.
Hey, it's me.
Um...
I am coming home,
and, um, and...
know I've said that a lot.
And...
I, uh...
And I'm, uh...
And I really do understand
if you don't even want
to look at me.
I hope that you do,
but if you don't...
Okay, well, I'll see you
in a little bit.
All right, bye.
Got something for you.
- Bye, Dad.
- See ya, Mikey.
- Remember that?
- Yes.
I have something else.
This is for you.
She's gonna melt quick
with these.
What about that? «It's great.
- Thanks.
- Yes.
Carry it carefully
all the way to, uh, Los Angeles.
I will.
All right,
Bye.
- Bye.
I hate you for never met.
I love you so much.
You just won't get, get over it.
Well, you lie first,
and it wasn't true.
Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck you
I hope you die too.
You were my first,
I'll be your last.
You'll never forget
our early past.
You'll never forget,
never forget.
All the lies and deceit.
To your... to your grave
it will follow, whoa, whoa.
The smiles and shade.
So fuck you, fuck you,
fuck you, fuck you.
Sorry, Dad.
No, I just found, uh...
some old songs from high school.
Yeah, okay.