Wakey-wakey, count Dracula.
It's time to rise and shine!
Hot! Hot! Hot!
How dare you break
into my castle?
Hi, everyone. I'm Max.
Hey, bat-breath,
you've got the camera
- the wrong way round!
- Huh?
Point it at me!
No! Not at my tummy!
And definitely not at my butt!
Today we are
experimenting with...
With this!
The magical amulet of baba yaga.
It bestows magical powers
to whoever holds it.
I am totally not supposed
to have this.
I snagged it
when she wasn't looking,
but it's ok.
She's a good witch now.
We all hang out together.
Ok, so there was that time
that she did turn us
into monsters.
And we fought count Dracula.
Don't worry, he's not
coming back any time soon.
We trapped him in his castle
so he can't escape.
And, to be honest,
it was actually pretty cool
being a super-strong werewolf!
Ilovedil
but the curse only works
when my family is unhappy.
And we're all happy again now.
Apparently.
So, back to the magical amulet.
Imagine if you will...
The marriage
of magic and science!
I can make the world
a better place,
just like my heroes, the starrs!
We '/I make the world
a better place!
This is outrageous! Who are you?
My name is Mila. Mila starr.
And we have some tests to do.
Tests?
- Ok, what smells gross?
- What are you doing?
Hmm. Thought so.
You've got a cavity.
Third molar, top right.
I mean left.
I knew it! It's been hurting me
for decades.
When was the last time
you flossed?
Er... thirteen hundred and...
Dental hygiene, inadequate.
You dare to insult
count Dracula,
the prince of darkness?
You shall pay dearly for this!
I don't think so, your highness.
Just sit back...
And relax.
Hmm, that one was still ok.
Ok, experiment number one.
What is that smell?
That can't be me.
I just showered three days ago!
Change of plan.
New experiment number one.
Magical everlasting deodorant!
By night, by day,
send foul odours away!
Yes, yes, yes!
No, no, no!
Mum, dad. I've caught Dracula!
Of course you have!
You are the best daughter
in the world, Mila.
You're the very best.
So, what's my next mission?
Capture this witch.
Experiment number 27.
I will transform a bat
into a handsome prince!
By day, by night,
create regal might!
It's working!
Yes, it's working!
It's...
Whoops.
Sorry.
Oh, a message.
School group chat.
Someone's hacked my account
and uploaded my dance video!
It's ok.
Maybe no one will see...
It.
Dancing? At school?
You've got to stop
being such an easy target.
- I was practising!
- For what? Dancing with dorks?
I can't believe
you've embarrassed me like this.
How am I supposed to show
my face in school tomorrow?
What do you care?
I thought you were
dropping out of school.
That was supposed to be
a secret!
And I haven't decided yet.
Well, I think you should.
They'd have to invent
a whole new alphabet
for your grades
to get any lower.
I got a c in home ec!
Guys, I'm sorry to interrupt
your argument,
but we do have a wedding
to go to.
Tell that to Max!
He isn't even ready yet!
The wedding is today?
I'll be two minutes.
Remember the time we nearly died
fighting that evil vampire?
- Er, yeah.
- Sometimes I miss that.
What is taking them so long?
Don't weddings
make you feel romantic?
Not when we're late for them.
Don't hug me in public.
Ah, freak out!
Le freak, c'est chic
freak out
ah, freak out!
Le freak, c'est chic
freak out
have you heard
about the new dance craze?
Listen to us
I'm sure you'll be amazed
big fun to be had by everyone
it surely can be done
ah, freak out!
Le freak
freak out!
Come on, Max.
Max wishbone,
get into this car right...
Come on, dig it!
Come on, dad, we're late.
What are we waiting for?
I love a wedding, don't you?
Fay, you hardly say two words
these days. Are you ok?
Of course.
Oh, apart from the fact
that I have absolutely
no future!
Why would you say that,
sweetheart?
You really don't know, do you?
- Fay's dropping out of school.
- What?
- Oh, Max!
- Fay?
I'm not. At least I don't...
I don't think I am.
You are not quitting school!
Out of the way!
I'm driving here!
Ok, let's go.
I'm no good at anything!
I'm flunking everything
and you'd know that
if you paid any attention to me!
But we do pay attention to...
Everyone in my class
is good at something.
Ashley is a runner, Jenny won
young journalist of the year.
This is Taylor.
She's 16 and she's going
to medical school.
And do you know why that is?
She's really good
at science stuff?
Her parents support her!
All of my friends' parents
support them.
- We do support you.
- Oh, really?
I was in a play last week
and none of you came to see it.
- I got held up at the book shop.
- I had a meeting.
Well, you were playing a sheep.
And not even the main one.
We're always here, fay.
We just don't feel the need
to be like those parents
who watch
their kids' every move.
We trust you to make
your own decisions.
And there is something
you're really good at.
Really? What?
Staring at your phone.
Did you know that smartphones
are covered in 18 times
more germs than a toilet seat?
Eat this, then!
What's this
you're sending me, fay?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
You just look so funny.
No one laughed at me
when I was a werewolf.
I told you we'd make it on time.
Come on, disco king.
Erm...
Didn't you use to be a frog?
- What's up?
- Those are girls from my school.
80? Go and say hi.
I don't want them to see me.
What's the problem?
You look great.
I do, dontl?
- Is that Max?
- Wow.
And shared.
Can't you get through one day
without embarrassing yourself?
This is bullying.
I'm gonna talk to their parents,
and their teachers
and their teachers' parents.
Please, let it go, mum.
- But they're making fun of you.
- You'll just make it worse.
Max, it'll be ok.
Oh, you two look so sweet!
This is the happiest day
of my life.
Sorry we're late.
No late, on time you are.
Hey, fay. Put your phone away.
Don't shout, frank.
We're in church!
- That was my foot.
- My wedding, this is.
You are now being happy.
Pronto.
Or else I will be
turning you into...
Sorry, reverend.
This isn't the time for cursing,
this is the time for loving.
Emma, frank,
you being witnesses.
- Fay, you be taking photos.
- Fine.
Max, please try not
to trip over your trousers.
Now, who wants
to married getting? We do!
Will you, renfield,
take this woman, baba yaga...
To be your wedded wife,
to love her,
comfort her,
honour and keep her...
In sickness and in health...
Ok, I guess I'm no good
at photography either.
Wait? What is that?
Until death do you part?
What is it you are wanting
at our wedding?
You.
I think you are not knowing
what it is you are facing.
My amulet!
Uh-oh.
I know I've got it
right... right here.
Somewhere.
Leave baba alone!
Cool trousers. Do they make them
in your size?
Who are you any...
Way?
Why would I want
to tell you that?
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I've got a job to do.
Not my baba!
Baba!
Stop the drones!
We need to get the controller
from whoever she is!
I'll get her!
Ok, maybe I won't.
Baba!
Baba! My snookie-pooks!
Just hand it over.
You don't stand a chance
against me.
I've got skills.
What? Ordering pizza?
Neverjoke about pizza.
Let go, pizza boy!
Don't call me pizza boy!
- Ew!
- Yuck, yuck, yuck.
Give it back!
Yeah, never.
Er, guys? I don't think
you should be throwing it
around like that.
- Why not?
- Because of that.
Baba, hold on!
Trying!
Baba!
I'm right here, pizza boy.
Baba, my snookie-pooks!
I'll save you!
Going somewhere?
Huh?
What are you doing?
We'll crash! You're too heavy!
Ok, so I could lose
a few pounds.
No need to get personal.
Now, let go of my friends!
Baba!
After them!
Max?
Let go! I'll catch you!
No, no, no! Not again!
What am I doing?
- Watch out!
- I can't see anything!
Right! Go right!
No, that's left! The other way!
- Why didn't you turn right?
- That was right!
Phew, that was close, pizza boy.
Are you crazy?
We almost got killed!
You can't even tell
left from right!
Bye-bye, pizza boy!
Oh, and give us back
baba and renfield!
Why are you all
spinning around like that?
The end is near!
She can't even tell
her left from her right.
Stupid girl.
If I was still a werewolf,
I'd have shown her
what's left and right!
I couldn't save them.
You did the best
you could, sweetheart.
- But it wasn't good enough.
- Welcome to my world.
I haven't got a chance
against that girl, but...
Werewolf Max does!
Max, no!
Just one tiny spell.
Mum! He's gonna turn us all
into monsters again!
Max, what did we say
about cursing the family?
But I won't change all of us.
Just me!
Max...
Magic is best left in
the hands of the professionals.
Look, I've been practising.
I'm practically a witch myself.
By fire, by light,
by all things bright...
Frank, do something!
Prepare me for the fight...
Ok! What, exactly?
On this magical monster night!
I told you!
Stop him!
Yes! Were-Max is back!
Great job, Max.
Come on, old flicker box!
Live from
the starr headquarters,
join our favourite inventors,
Marlene and Maddox starr
unveiling
their mind-boggling tech
to make the world
a better place!
Welcome, folks!
Let's take a look
at our new starr rocket cruiser.
Blazing-fast ignition,
three supersonic boosters.
Carries a load of 50 tons,
no biggy. Let's stay focused.
Because on top of it all,
it's remote controlled.
Simply press this field
and the burning chambers
are preheated in five seconds.
After that, everything
is ready for take-off.
Welcome back, my darling.
Hi, mum.
Why have you brought me
three creatures?
The husband
was a bit too clingy.
And did anything else happen?
Well, there was some resistance
among the wedding guests,
but I was able
to deal with it quickly.
Oh. Can't have been that quick.
You're 14 minutes
behind schedule.
Mila will make up for it
next time. Right?
Of course I will.
- Ok! Let's take a look at this.
- Already?
Can't we hang out
for a little while
before I have to leave again?
Mila, our project
is to save mankind.
There's nothing more important.
You're right. I'm sorry.
Right! Your new targets are
Nessie, the Loch Ness monster,
and yeti, the snow monster
of the himalayas.
Ok. There's no way
those two monsters
are going to fit inside
the starr-copter.
Then it's a good thing
we invented this.
What is it?
A shrinking-ray gun.
One day,
all the world's plastic waste
will be shrunk to the size
of a single atom.
Wow. Nice going, mum and dad.
I'm going to make you
regret the day
you messed
with wilberforce renfield!
Excuse me, we're the good guys.
It won't hurt him, will it?
The process
is completely painless.
I must warn you,
I've got a white coat in karate!
You guys are geniuses!
When I grow up,
I want to be just like you!
Of course you do.
You're a starr.
And we starrs...
We'll make the world
a better place!
I won't be long!
This was supposed to be
the happiest day of my life.
So, now I look like
3,000-year-old meat loaf again.
I'm putting all your
embarrassing photos online.
I told you not to play
with baba's amulet.
You are absolutely impossible.
Turn us back, right now!
I'm sorry. I... I can't.
What do you mean, you can't?
Huh?
Don't you remember?
The first time
baba used a spell,
she only wanted to change mum
into a monster.
But the spell changed us all
because...
Because we were unhappy.
And we only changed back
when we were happy again.
Great, so we're gonna be
monsters forever.
So, I guess it's true.
We're an unhappy family again.
Did you really need magic
to tell you that?
I'm sorry. It's all my fault.
No, mum. It's not yourfault.
It's dad's fault too.
What?
Ok, so I guess we're down
to one responsible parent again.
Hey! Look on the bright side.
Now that we've monstered up,
our odds of saving
baba and renfield
have risen exponentially.
I hate it when you speak nerd.
Look at us!
We're faster and stronger.
Mum's a vampire,
you've got mummy magic.
We can totally get them back!
Ok, you've got a point, I guess.
But how can we save them
if we don't know where they are?
- With this.
- Sweetheart, no offence,
but you haven't exactly
got the hang of that thing.
Frank! No!
Sorry!
Trust me. I can find anyone.
All I have to do
is think really hard about them.
By day, by night,
bring me second sight!
You are supposed to be finding
baba and renfield,
not your new girl crush.
She's not my crush.
She's just a girl
who I totally can't stop
thinking about.
She can't even tell
left from right.
Where's she flying to?
Scotland, Loch Ness.
That girl is our only lead.
Can you get us there?
Sure. I know
baba's teleportation spell.
Couldn't we just book a flight?
There's no time!
Disappear, pronto!
There are now claims
that the former president
is in fact a martian.
- Who are you?
- Just fans.
Disappear, pronto!
So, we're back where we started.
I think that's enough magic,
don't you?
Ok. But how will we get
to Loch Ness now?
Er... mat-met.
Mat-met.
Is it just me or is dad making
less sense than usual?
Mat-met.
- Oh, he means bat-jet.
- Mat-met.
- Dracula's bat-jet?
- It's in Cheyenne's barn.
Your dad thought it might
come in handy one day.
Uff da!
Do we even know how to fly it?
- Well, how hard can it be?
- Er, very.
Come on! We're wasting time.
- Ooh, I feel strange.
- Mat-met.
Mum, what's the matter?
I feel... ooh, I'm hungry.
Cheyenne's still in India,
so let's head
straight for the barn.
Blood! Put me down!
Mum, I can't believe you had
Dracula's bat-jet all this time
and didn't tell us!
- Yeah, I don't think...
- Hungry!
Mum and dad are really up for
answering questions right now.
Uff da.
- The bat-jet!
- Ha, I knew it.
That's no lawn mower.
You need a pilot's licence
for that.
Ah, you must be
Cheyenne's annoying neighbour.
He won't be annoying
once I've drained his blood!
That's it!
I'm calling the police!
Look deep into my eyes.
You're a beautiful dancer.
And now you dance
the dying swan.
I'd forgotten
how much fun this is.
Oh! Put me down!
Hungry! Let me go!
Not like that!
Er, why are you looking at me
like that?
- Hungry!
- Ok, that's not good.
Er... I've got an idea.
Keep her busy!
I don't think that's gonna be
a problem.
Blood! Hungry!
Mum, I know
what you're thinking,
but trust me, I taste like
a mouldy sandwich right now.
Dracula had a stash of
plasma pills in his food locker.
- Fay, I'm so sorry!
- You tried to drain me of blood.
Great parenting, mum.
Er, does anyone actually know
how to fly this thing?
Renfield does,
but he's kind of captured
right now.
Maybe there's a manual
in the glove compartment.
I don't think there's a manual
or a glove compartment.
It's just a matter of
discovering the user interface.
It's probably intuitive,
so, if I'm the pilot
and I want to start the engine,
I just press, er, this!
Uh-uh.
Oh, just make it start already!
Your wish is my command.
I am your voice-activated
autopilot.
And, yes.
I really do look this good.
- Dracula?
- My mife!
It's ok, it's just a hologram.
The bat-jet is voice controlled.
For those times when you've got
more important things to do
than press buttons.
So, we just tell it
where we want to go?
I... I guess so.
Er, Dracula?
Take us to Loch Ness.
I've found three entries
Loch Ness in the local area.
Loch Ness fish restaurant
is 2.3 kilometres away.
Loch Ness tartan manufacturers
on the other hand
is 3.1 kilometres away.
Loch Ness, Scotland!
As fast as you can!
Dad, I'm in position.
That's great, Mila.
The Loch Ness monster
is your next target
for project save mankind.
It has been hiding
at the bottom of the lake
for thousands of years.
She looks kind of friendly.
No! It's a monster, Mia,
and definitely not friendly!
Of course, sorry, mum. I...
- I'll have to call you back.
- Don't you...
Dare disconnect us.
She's getting more wilful
every day!
Don't worry, we only need her to
fetch the remaining specimens.
Then our collection
will be complete,
and her mission will be over.
What is that girl doing here?
Judging by the way
she grabbed baba,
I'd say she's some sort
of hunter.
I bet she's here
for the Loch Ness monster.
That's ridiculous.
Nessie doesn't exist.
Said the vampire
to the werewolf.
- I'm sure I'm right.
- Who are these weirdos?
Well, maybe it does exist.
Nessie sightings
have been reported
for more than a thousand years.
And, fun fact, since 1934,
Nessie has been
a protected species.
There is nothing fun
about those facts.
There's her 'copter,
but I can't see her.
Hey! Don't touch that!
Who are you?
Where are our friends?
- Pizza boy?
- Yeah!
I mean, no! I'm were-Max.
So, you're a werewolf now?
Exactly!
At least you're not wearing
those ridiculous trousers
anymore!
Exactly!
Cos you're not wearing trousers
at all!
Exactly.
That's enough!
Now, listen here, young lady.
Sorry, I don't really have time
to listen, old lady!
Uff da!
Which do you like better?
Basketball
or football?
Huh?
Frank, wake up. Wake up!
Hey, Supergirl.
Time for a little hypnosis.
Look deep into my eyes.
You are going to dance
like mc hammer.
Look in my eyes, man,
you can't touch this
yo, let me bust the funky lyrics
fresh new kicks and pants
you got it like that,
now you know you wanna dance
so, move, outta your...
You gotta...
Look in my eyes,
man, you can't touch this
ready for round two?
Sorry, pizza boy!
I've got work to do.
Stop calling me pizza boy!
Mila? Are you all right?
Hi, dad, sorry for
the little interruption earlier.
Let's get to work.
Uh, ok, right. Where was I?
Ah, yes! We've added
a little update to your suit
to help you find the monster.
The last attempt to find it
was in 2003
using 600 sonars,
which we hacked.
We altered their results so
they couldn't find the monster.
But you'll manage in no time!
Just follow the drone.
Wow, beautiful plants.
What is it?
You? Again?
Come on, come on!
What... what happened?
That was pretty brave.
Brave? Me?
And also really stupid.
I won't let you take Nessie.
You've got to stop trying
to beat me.
You're only going to get hurt.
You saved me.
Of course I did.
I'm one of the good guys.
Oh, great.
Because of you, I'm totally
behind schedule again.
Thanks, pizza boy.
My name is Max. What's yours?
Erm...
Come on.
If we're going to be nemeses,
we should at least know
each other's names.
- Mila. Mila starr.
- Starr?
As in Marlene and Maddox starr?
The tech wizards?
Well, I just call them
mum and dad.
Whoa!
Yep, they're pretty "whoa",
all right!
Those guys are geniuses!
They've made billions
with their inventions,
and they give it all to charity.
They have financed
1,111 orphanages
all over the world.
How come I know everything
about the starrs
but I didn't know
they had a daughter?
Well, they're keeping it secret.
- Why?
- They're geniuses.
If they told me,
I probably wouldn't understand.
Are you sure it's not because
you're flying around the world
trapping innocent witches
and sea creatures?
That's a beast.
She's no beast!
Just look at her!
She just doesn't want
to be called names.
Or be made fun of
because she's different.
And you definitely shouldn't
take photos or videos of her
when she's dancing.
And put them on... ow!
Oh! And put them online
for everyone to laugh at.
You've stopped talking
about the monster, haven't you?
Good guys don't do what you do.
It's... it's all for a reason.
And what reason is that?
I'm not supposed to say.
Wait!
- Frank, wake up!
- Can't touch this
wake up!
Look in my eyes,
man, you can't touch this
mum, dad, fay!
We've got to stop her!
Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
Wake up!
Come on.
Oh! Finally!
We've got to get to the jet!
Can't touch this
We have to follow that monster!
She isn't a monster.
She's just made
some bad decisions.
You were talking about Nessie,
weren't you?
So, you've got a thing
for the weird girl
who catches monsters.
No! There's just something
not quite right about her.
Yeah, she's a kidnapper.
No, there's...
There's something else.
- What?
- I don't know,
but I'm going to find out.
Dracula, do not let
that starr-copter get away!
Your wish is my command.
Thank you for choosing
Dracula airlines.
We hope you have
a pleasant flight.
Please stow your luggage
out of sight
and prepare
to surrender your soul
to the prince of darkness.
That's me.
Please remain seated
throughout the flight,
with your seat belt
tightly fastened at all times.
In the unlikely event
of cabin depressurisation,
an oxygen mask will fall
from an overhead panel.
Ah! So that's where
I put my bowling ball.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Jet, touch down, gently.
Welcome to the himalayas.
As you disembark,
please remember your luggage
and to tell your pilot just
how devilishly handsome he is.
You won't give up,
will you, pizza boy?
I'm not wearing enough bandages
for snow!
Look!
Tracks! These feet
are as big as yours, dad!
Uff da.
These might lead us to Mila!
Oh, so now she's "Mila".
Uff da.
Huh!
Yeti!
And he doesn't look happy.
I'm sure if we just explain
nicely why we're here,
he won't eat us.
Ok, you first.
Greetings, we come...
In peace.
Uff da?
Love is in the air
uff da.
- Uff da.
- Every sight and every sound
- uff da.
- Uff da.
Love is in the air
in the thunder of the sea
and I don't know
if I'm just dreaming
- don't know if I feel sane
- uff da!
But it's something
that I must believe in
and it's there
when you call out my name
Love is in the air
love is in the air
I'm so glad
no one knows me out here.
Uff da. Uff da. Uff da.
Thanks for distracting him
for me!
- Uff da! Uff da!
- Mila!
Sorry, pizza boy.
Gotta fly!
I've got this, dad.
As a human,
I might not be good at anything,
but as a mummy,
I can do everything!
Fay! Stop spinning!
You're causing an avalanche!
Mila, look out!
We've got to help her!
It's all my fault!
Watch out, kids!
Don't worry, I've got you!
But who's got you?
Uff da!
W... where's Mila?
Mila?
Hello?
- Heho?
- Huh?
- I'm here!
- Mila!
- Pizza boy!
- Hold on!
I wasn't planning on letting go!
Can you see my backpack?
There's a rope in it.
I'll get it. Don't go anywhere!
Here it is, pizza boy!
I can't find it!
Left pocket!
Red rope!
You meant the right pocket!
I don't need a lesson!
I just need a rope!
Stop!
Can't have you fall down too.
Frank, help us!
Frank!
Maybe we should get up?
We should.
- Now?
- Now.
Max? Are you ok?
No problem.
So, we just saved your life.
I think you owe us some answers.
What happened to our friends?
They... they're with my parents.
What are they doing to them?
I don't know. I just know
that they need them.
- For what?
- To save humankind!
But, how?
I don't know.
They only tell me what I need
to know to do my job.
So, you kidnap our friends,
drag creatures
out of their homes
and you don't even know why?
My parents have their reasons.
They can't be good reasons
if it means taking everyone
against their will.
My parents are the starrs,
the best and most noble people
on earth.
My parents would never ask me
to do something like that,
and they're not noble at all.
Uff da.
Mila, think about it.
Something isn't right.
I've got to go.
Stay! We'll talk!
Sorry, I've got a job to do.
- Mila!
- What?
Ask your parents
what their plan is!
Could someone
turn on the heating?
Mila! You are 73 minutes
behind schedule!
And you haven't even caught
the final monster.
- No. And I'm not going to.
- What?
At least not until you tell me
exactly what you need them for.
- Hmm.
- You don't need to know that.
Why? Why is there so much
you don't tell me?
Why can't people know
I'm your daughter?
Mila starr,
you are on very thin ice.
I think we should show her
what happens to the monsters.
As a reward? For her insolence?
Marlene, it's time.
She's proved herself.
Come with us.
Finally.
At last I get to see
what's on level x!
You certainly do.
This is an exciting time
for us, Mila.
Your mother and I have finally
found a way to save mankind.
- How?
- We have developed a machine
which will allow us
to live forever.
You mean, no one will ever die?
No more sickness,
no more disease.
We will eradicate it all.
That's incredible!
But what do you need
the monsters for?
We'll show you, Mila,
but no one else must ever know.
Wow, we are really high!
High enough
not to be observed by anyone.
Why are they in there?
What do Dracula, baba yaga,
Nessie and the yeti
all have in common?
Definitely bad breath,
but I'm guessing
that's not the answer.
They've been alive
for centuries,
and we have found a way to tap
into that immortal energy.
So no one will ever get ill
or die.
But what happens to them?
Why does that matter?
I'm pretty sure
it matters to them.
They are abominations.
No, they're not!
Mila, it's ok.
Nothing bad happens to them.
Really?
Have we ever lied to you?
We're the starrs!
All three of us.
And we starrs...
We'll make the world
a better place?
Did she say it? I couldn't hear.
We'll make the world
a better place.
One more time.
We will make the world
a better place!
So, what do you say?
Are you gonna get
our last monster?
Consider it done!
Why did you show her all this?
To stop her asking questions.
- Is the test subject ready?
- Of course.
Ok, so, now we're here,
where do we go next?
I could find out
where baba and renfield are,
if mum would let me have
the amulet back.
I don't know if magic
is a good idea, Max.
It's just a location spell.
I've already turned us
into monsters.
What else
could possibly go wrong?
Oh, you did not just say that!
Mum?
Ok, but be careful.
By day, by night,
give me second sight!
Oh, wow!
The unmistakable twin peaks
of the legendary island
of tora-tora.
You've found Mila again.
Could you stop thinking
about her for just ten seconds?
I'm trying.
You like her, don't you?
No! She's a know-it-all
and a show-off.
And she can't even tell
left from right.
Wow, he really likes her.
Uff da.
I'm a starr.
I am a starr.
Pizza boy!
According to the amulet,
she's not too far away!
You just can't stay away,
can you?
Did you ask your parents
what their plan is?
Yes, I know exactly what it is.
But it's top secret, I'm afraid,
so I won't be telling you.
Will they let our friends go?
No. I'm sorry.
They're too important.
- For what?
- I can't tell you!
At least tell us where they are.
But they're our friends.
I'm sorry, I can't.
Well, I'm sorry too.
Well, if that's the way
you want it.
Whoa.
Oh, no.
Mila, it's not too late
to change your mind.
Huh?
Uh-oh!
Out of my way!
I'll shrink it.
Are you looking for this?
- Give it to me!
- No.
Oh, really?
You'd rather get squished?
Actually, when you put it
like that, er...
- I'll handle this.
- You?
Sure. He's just a big, friendly,
misunderstood guy.
Look deep into my eyes.
Oh, darn it.
You are powerless
against my words.
You will submit to my...
Oh, dear.
So, you like music?
What? You don't like my moves?
Your sister's crazy.
Sometimes I think I'm the only
normal one in my family.
Sorry, hairball.
It's the rhythm of the island
I like the sugarcane so sweet
if you want to do the monster
you've got to listen to the beat
I guess that's why
he's called king conga.
Uff da?
You're not enjoying yourself,
are you?
Maybe.
Hey, we've found something
you're not good at!
And you could do it better,
pizza boy?
- You tell me.
- You are all crazy!
Everybody gather round now
let your body feel the heat
don't you worry
if you can't dance
let the music move your feet
it's the rhythm of the island
I like the sugarcane so sweet
monster beat.
- Fay.
- Yes?
You were great back there.
I danced, mum.
Anyone can do that.
You knew how to connect
with a gorilla.
Not everyone can do that.
Yeah.
I guess I just knew
what he was feeling.
And you didn't need me
or dad to tell you what to do.
That's why we don't watch
your every move.
We trust you
to find your own way.
You know, I think I might enjoy
working with animals.
Maybe I could become a vet
or even a scientist
and discover unknown species,
like king conga!
Sounds sort of sciencey though.
You might have to stay
in school for that.
You know what?
Maybe I will.
What's wrong?
I have never had so much fun.
You know fun is supposed
to make you happy, right?
Do other families
have fun together?
Sure, that's what family is.
A group of people who annoy you
and make you laugh equally.
I'm pretty sure my parents
have never made me laugh.
So, what do they do?
They educate me in chemistry,
physics, athletics,
music, arts, computers,
Chinese, arabic, klingon.
Klingon?
Well, just in case.
And do you want to learn
all that stuff?
I have to be perfect,
so they're proud of me.
Don't you want your parents
to be proud of you?
But they are,
even when I mess up.
Ok, maybe not so much
when I lose my trousers.
But mostly, yes.
My parents want my performance
to be absolutely perfect.
And even then, I'm not sure
it's enough to make them proud.
You're ok, pizza boy.
You know that?
You're not so bad yourself.
She's already five hours,
23 minutes and 46 seconds
behind schedule!
- Forty-nine, 50, 51...
- Let's see where she is.
Drone, locate Mila.
She's holding hands
with a monster?
I'd say that was just
an exceptionally hairy boy.
How many times have I told her
not to waste time
on other children?
I'm sure it's nothing.
How can it be nothing?
She's with a boy! A hairy one!
Who knows what ideas
he'll put into her head!
Don't worry. I'll deal with it.
Mila! Finally.
You're mad at me for being late,
aren't you?
I'm sorry, I can explain.
No, something has happened.
Something terrible.
What? Where's mum?
Mum is sick, Mila. Very sick.
- I'm on my way.
- Wait.
You're the only one
who can save her.
What do you mean?
The machine is our only hope
to save your mother,
but we need all five monsters
to make it work.
You have to bring back
the giant ape immediately.
Hurry, Mila.
Every second counts.
Mum, please be ok.
Dad, I've got him!
Excellent, Mila.
Put him over there.
I'm sorry.
Mum?
I just hope
you weren't too late.
We're the starrs.
We're the starrs!
We're the...
Starrs?
We make the world
a better place.
Uff da, uff da, uff da.
Uff da, uff da, uff da!
King conga's gone.
So has your girlfriend.
I thought I knew her.
I thought I could trust her.
I... I thought...
She really liked you?
Welcome to your teens, kid.
We have to stop her, for good.
Mum! You're ok.
Of course I am.
Then, who is that.
That's Mila.
- But I'm Mila.
- You are Mila 1.0.
This is your replacement,
Mila 2.0.
I don't understand.
You've been made obsolete.
Obsolete?
We haven't been completely
honest with you, Mila.
Our research failed.
The life energy
of immortal beings
can't make humans live longer.
We found that out
a long time ago.
We had hoped we'd be able
to make ourselves immortal.
After all, it wouldn't be fair
to deprive the world
of our genius.
So, our next plan
was for our brilliance
to live on
through our offspring.
Offspring? You mean me?
In you, we wanted to create
the perfect child.
Unfortunately, you proved
to be less than satisfactory.
But we starrs never give up.
We discovered
that immortal energy can be used
to bring life to the inanimate.
You made a robot
and brought it to life?
Don't call your sister a robot.
She is everything we wished for.
She is perfect.
But what about me?
What about you?
I'm your daughter.
Ok, that's another
teeny white lie.
You're not actually
our daughter.
You're an orphan, selected
for your neural capacity.
We acquired you.
You're not my real parents?
We are the starrs.
And you are not.
Get rid of her.
Yes, mother. With pleasure.
Sorry, but I can
only see clouds.
- Come on, Max. Concentrate.
- I am.
So, the one time
you have to find Mila,
you can't actually
think about her?
I can think about her.
I'm thinking
about how she lied to me
and got me to feel sorry
for her,
and made me feel feelings
just so she could trick me.
Believe me, fay,
she is all I'm thinking about.
So, do you think you could do
the teleport spell?
- Mum!
- Uff da.
It's our only chance
to find Mila.
But the last time I did it,
I nearly drowned us all.
So, we'll just call that
a practice run.
Max, you can do this!
You have to.
Where are we?
Exactly where we need to be.
You have got to help me.
Forget it, Mila.
I'm not falling for that again.
The starrs are insane.
You're just working
that out now?
Your family is crazy!
They're not my family.
We were never a family.
They bought me to turn me
into something... perfect.
What?
But I couldn't be
perfect enough.
And now they don't want me
anymore.
I've got no one.
That's not true. You've got me.
You've got all of us.
Uff da.
So, we're back to believing
the crazy girl?
Am I the only one
who has a problem with that?
I know I don't deserve it,
but you have to believe me.
And we've got to get away
from here right now.
Or what?
Or that.
There are two of you now?
She is nothing like me.
- Who was that?
- An artificial life form.
My parents... the people
I thought were my parents
used monster energy
to bring her to life.
I thought I was helping
the world.
Turns out I was...
Making my own replacement.
Sorry to interrupt.
I just couldn't wait.
I will not let you
hurt my friends.
Now we'll see
who's the better one.
What's happened? Where are you?
I'm on your left.
Watch out,
I'm coming from the right.
Just kidding this time.
Max!
Stop that lift!
Max? What are you doing?
Saving you!
Got you.
Not to sound ungrateful,
but I think
we're still going to die.
- Listen.
- I am so, so sorry!
I shouldn't have taken
your friends.
- I should have listened to you!
- Mila!
I'll never, ever call you
pizza boy again,
and not just because
we're about to be squished.
- Mila!
- Yes?
We are not going to die.
Disappear, pronto!
Ok, that didn't quite go
according to plan!
- You can do magic?
- Not as well as I'd hoped!
You again?
Disappear, pronto!
Huh?
Oh, no!
Disappear, pronto!
The amulet's losing power!
- Max, close your eyes.
- Huh?
Please, just do it.
Think of your family.
Think of what you have to lose
and imagine
being back with them.
Disappear, pronto.
Mila! It worked!
Oh, Max! Thank goodness!
We're finally together again.
Uff da.
The curse is lifting!
Er, is anyone else
still a monster?
I don't understand.
Why didn't it work?
Maybe one of us isn't happy.
Max? What is it?
I'm sorry. How can I be happy
when Mila doesn't have anyone?
Don't be sorry. It shows
what a caring person you are.
Uff da.
There they are. The lovebirds.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
You're just a machine.
You're obsolete, Mila 1.0.
Her name is Mila!
You're coming to live with us.
After all I've done to you?
Look into my eyes.
That doesn't work on me.
I am perfect.
And I can't feel pain.
I'm to bring the monsters
to my creators.
I am stronger than he is.
Uff da.
That means he forgives you.
We all do.
Uff da.
So, you crashed a wedding
and kidnapped
the bride and groom.
It's ok.
Everyone makes mistakes.
Except our little starr.
You cannot beat me.
I am perfect.
Fay! Stop!
Ah! More monsters.
What a thoughtful present.
I'm so sorry.
I can't believe
I got it so wrong.
It's ok to make mistakes.
Even mistakes as big as mine?
Nobody's perfect.
You really are the best family
in the world.
Not now! I need the werewolf!
This is not a good time
to be happy!
I'm unhappy. I'm unhappy.
I'm, er...
Who am I kidding?
Best family in the world!
Ridiculous!
Look at these sorry excuses
for human beings.
How can you stand people
like that?
You're right! Max isn't perfect,
and that's exactly why
I like him.
Incredible!
I bet none of them even have
a basic grasp
of quantum mechanics.
They've got the shrink ray.
This could be our chance.
Mila 2.0, get rid of them.
Time to go.
Er, wait!
Nobody's perfect,
and the sooner we realise that,
the happier we'll all be.
We don't need to dress
like someone else
to impress people.
We're all ok
just the way we are.
And that's what makes
life interesting.
Perfect... is boring.
What nonsense!
Only those who are perfect
will be liked by others.
I am perfect.
I don't want to be perfect
at all.
Correct. And you never will be.
You're full of flaws.
And that's what makes me human.
I... I need more time.
I'm only human
of flesh and blood I'm made
ooh!
I'm only human
of flesh and blood I'm made
born to make mistakes
I'm only human
of flesh and blood I'm made
what are you doing?
Finally having fun!
- That is awful.
- No, it's beyond awful.
Having fun? It is so, so...
Born to make mistakes
- ordinary.
- Human.
I'm only human
of flesh and blood I'm made
born to make mistakes
you finally made it!
- I'm only human
- quickly! Over here!
Of flesh and blood I'm made
I'm only human
darling!
Let our friends go!
Never.
Get off me!
Stop! What are you doing?
I am going to shrink all of you!
You shrunk my parents!
And now it's your turn!
Keep still!
- We have to free the monsters.
- Quickly!
- What about Max?
- We believe in him.
He'll do it, somehow.
You cannot hit me. I am perfect!
- We have to open the tanks!
- Yes! But how?
Just push all the buttons!
But what if we push a wrong one?
Oh, they only have
self-destruct buttons in movies.
I hope those are not
famous last words!
Open, you silly thing!
It worked!
It's me, fay. Your friend.
Uff da!
H urry,
let's take the starr-copter!
I have to stop them!
Not so fast, miss obsolete.
- Give me your hand!
- No, me first!
We have to hurry!
Renfield! Snookie-pooks.
My darling.
Baba? Renfield? Are you ok?
I think Dracula's
in very good hands here.
Where am I?
Stop!
- Shoot her.
Which one?
Her! I'm the real Mila!
She's lying!
No, she's lying!
Shrink her!
- Come on, Max!
- Come on, pizza boy!
Max, no! It's me. Mila!
Your Mila!
Looks like you're the one
who's obsolete.
You wouldn't call me pizza boy.
You will...
Do nothing!
Finally.
Finally what?
Finally, I will have my revenge
on you all!
Sorry I asked.
All you puny humans shall bow
to the prince of darkness!
The count of bats!
The nightmare of nightmares!
The most beautiful...
- Beautiful?
- Hmm?
Really?
Yes, beautiful.
I guess beauty lies
in the eye of the beholder.
Whatever, sister.
The most beautiful creature
of the night!
The ruler of transylvania!
The king of the world!
The master of the universe!
What the...?
What's happened to you?
Why are you so big now?
Listen to me. Obey your ruler.
That's enough!
My big hero!
- You're safe now.
- Uff da!
Yes! I was about to say
the same thing!
Give me that!
Torture! I hate disco!
King conga, no!
The lab's falling apart!
We have to run!
Everyone, get to the lift!
Max, come in!
Mila, we have to...
Mila?
- You go ahead!
- Not without you!
- I need to save her!
- I know!
Come on!
I'll help you out of here.
Humans.
Mila!
Pizza boy
is not going to make it.
I won't let him die!
Uh-oh. No, no, no!
Max, take my hand!
I've got you!
What's going on?
I will end your imperfect life.
Max, you need to guide us
out of here.
Ok. Straight ahead.
Accelerate!
Which way now?
You know how sometimes you have
a problem with left and right?
Max, I can do it. Left or right?
Left. Or the other left.
- To the right?
- To the left!
Right! Left!
Right!
And again, to the right!
Those crazy, imperfect children
are going to crash into us!
Duck!
Yay! Yes, yes, yes!
I guess I know my left
from right after all.
How did you know that
I would get it right this time?
The starrs never believed
in you,
so you doubted yourself.
That's why you always
got it wrong.
But you believe in me.
With my life, completely.
Well, it's about time.
Will you,
wilberforce renfield,
take this woman,
baba yaga,
to be your wedded wife,
to love her,
comfort her,
honour and keep her...
In sickness and in health?
I do.
Will you, baba yaga,
take this man
to be your wedded husband,
to love him, comfort him
in sickness and in health?
Doing, I am!
Oh, I want something
just like this
I want something just like this
I've been reading books of old
the legends and the myths
the testaments they told
the moon and its eclipse
and Superman unrolls
a suit before he lifts
but I'm not the kind of person
that it fits
she said where'd you wanna go?
How much do you wanna risk?
I'm not looking for somebody
with some superhuman gifts
some superhero,
some fairy-tale bliss
just something I can turn to,
somebody I can miss
I want something just like this
mortal fools.
They're no match for my cunning.
I will bide my time and then,
when they least expect it,
the prince of darkness
will rise again!
Rennie, my bubla.
Have you remembered
to be feeding Dracula?
Making the weird noises,
he is again.
Sorry, my little snookie-pooks.
I almost forgot.
Mm, black pudding.
My favourite! Hmm.
Sapex scripts