♪ Sometimes I'm james bond ♪
♪ sometimes I'm billy the kid ♪
♪ sometimes I feel
like sherlock holmes ♪
♪ sometimes I feel like
jack the ripper ♪
♪ 'cause I got an image
out of control ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ I've drawn in a face ♪
♪ 'cause mine's been erased ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ sometimes I'm on a case ♪
♪ sometimes I'm shooting
bad dudes ♪
♪ sometimes I'm
slashing the face ♪
♪ sometimes I'm looking
for clues ♪
♪ sometimes I'm
breaking the law ♪
♪ sometimes I'm solving
the crime ♪
♪ I'm always fast on the draw ♪
♪ I get the girls all the time ♪
♪ 'cause I got an image
out of control ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ I've drawn in a face ♪
♪ 'cause mine's been erased ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ Sometimes I'm james bond ♪
♪ sometimes I'm billy the kid ♪
♪ sometimes I feel
like sherlock holmes ♪
♪ sometimes I feel like
jack the ripper ♪
♪ 'cause I got an image
out of control ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ I've drawn in a face ♪
♪ 'cause mine's been erased ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ now I got an image
out of control ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ I've drawn in a face
'cause mine's been erased ♪
♪ identity crisises.
So what do you say, vince?
Not bad, huh?
Not bad?
It stinks.
The next one we do has
got to have more punch.
Is that why the record company
sent us back here to shoot it?
To give you some
hometown inspiration?
Sure.
Once we get there
we can take it,
experiment, play around
till we come up
with something original.
What's going on back there?
Very funny.
How many years is it since
you last went back home, vince?
Nearly 20.
Old joss is the only one
left now.
He's the caretaker. He's been
alone in the house all these years.
Joss...
I can hardly remember his face.
He was already old when I left.
We kids used to rib him about
the way he shook all the time.
We were always asking him
to make us malts.
Lousy weather.
It sure is.
Goddamn fog.
Oh, jeez, another roadblock.
We only just left one.
Looks like all the cops in
this county are out tonight.
They're making a whole big deal
about those mad dogs.
The camper's mine.
It's registered.
I used to live up here.
We're coming to shoot
a rock video.
Vince roberts.
Ain't you lou and
martha roberts's boy?
Well, I'll be.
Vince raven...
The guy who sings
"my mother's gone"?
Uh-huh.
Holy shit.
Imagine meeting you.
I can't tell one of these
newfangled songs from another,
but if you really are
lou and martha's boy,
you sure as hell
should remember me.
Sheriff morrison.
Yeah, I remember.
I used to sit on your lap
and piss all over
your pants, right?
That's right, boy.
You was more full of water than hoover dam.
And now he's a rock singer, huh?
Just sounds like
a big pisser to me.
Flesh and blood,
as I live and breathe.
It's been a long time
since I last saw you, boy.
Since your father had...
Oh, yes, I remember.
Well, if it's okay with you,
guys, we'd like to go now.
The caretaker's waiting up for us
and it's really
getting cold out here.
Okay,
but you know about the dogs,
don't you?
Yeah, we'll watch out.
There already have been
five deaths in the area.
Five?
At the other roadblocks
they only mentioned two deaths.
Well, now there's three more
to chalk up to the damn dogs.
The samples family...
Bill, Jennifer
and peter samples...
Butchered like hogs.
It was difficult to tell
which bit came from where,
just like last time.
Why, what was left
you could put in a plastic bag this big.
Okay, kids,
you can go now,
but be careful.
Vince knows what
these dogs can do.
Barricade yourselves in
when you get to the house.
Back the car up.
You sure picked a fine time
to come back home, vince.
Folks around here ain't forgot
that story about your daddy,
you know.
Well, take care, boy.
Make sure there are weapons in the house
and don't let nobody in.
Slow down, vince.
I'm crawling as it is.
Vince,
what was all that
about your father?
Okay.
If you don't want
to talk about it,
it's all the same to me.
I'd rather not talk about it.
- I thought...
- I said I don't want to talk about it.
All right.
I'm sorry.
Vince, how are you going
to find the way to the house?
With my nose.
What are you laughing about?
I'm not kidding.
When I was a kid
I could find my way home
- just by the smell.
- What smell?
The bullshit.
It's unmistakable.
Hey.
What's gotten into you?
I saw something move over there.
I don't see nothing.
Maybe it was one of them things,
one of them dogs.
Well, I guess we'd better
go take a look.
What do we do if they attack?
Bleed, I guess.
♪ Whoopee-ti-yi-yo
♪ come along,
little doggie... ♪
- Sheriff.
- I'm right here, dan.
Got a pack of doggy cookies with you?
Might come in handy.
Come on out.
Show yourselves, you damn dogs.
I'll pop lead into
every last one of you.
Yes, sirree.
Hey, sheriff.
Sheriff, where are you?
Sheriff, answer me.
Don't get too far away.
Sheriff, for christ sakes,
answer me.
Sheriff?
Vince, look out!
God.
Easy, vince.
It wasn't your fault.
Oh, that poor dog.
What if we killed it?
Jordan, frank, I found it.
He's alive, but not for long.
At this rate, we may not be
either. Those dogs could be everywhere.
She's right.
Let's beat it.
In a second.
Jordan, switch on the emergency lights
before someone rams the camper.
And frank, let's move the
dog over to the side of the road.
Okay.
- Vince, don't.
- He has to.
Come on, let's get back
to the camper.
Who are you?
Now you've done it.
Can you feel the wind?
The wind is lifting the fog
and blowing away the clouds
that cover the moon.
Now he's back at last.
He will command the house.
And all of you...
All of you will die.
- It was an accident.
- All of you will die.
Can't you see he's crazy?
Make him go away!
You are already dead.
All of you are already dead.
His dogs will not spare you.
He'll find you wherever you go.
And when the moon shines again,
you will all die.
Wait. Let's get you
to a hospital.
Hold it, vince.
If there's something out there,
we'd better all stick together.
He was covered with blood.
He needs help.
My god, what's that?
The dogs must have attacked him.
Let's go away, please.
Let's get back
into the camper
before it's too late.
Yeah, vince,
let's get out of here.
I'm going.
I can't just drive off
and leave him.
Okay, so I'll drive.
Hey, wait a minute, vince.
You're crazy to go
out there on your own.
You're all chicken.
Wait, vince.
I'm coming with you.
Here, put this on.
Vince, we've got to find him.
Sure we do.
He'd be great for our video.
I don't think
that's at all funny.
Lighten up.
What's eating you?
I don't know,
but I have a feeling,
something would like to.
Vince, what's that?
In the camper, quick, everyone.
Come on, vince.
I want to know what went on in the woods.
Nothing, man.
I didn't touch her.
- What about the old man?
- Didn't touch him either.
Joss.
I haven't had a welcome like
this since I came back from camp.
And they used
the same banner then.
They don't throw their
money around, these country folk.
Local boy comes home a star.
"welcome, vincent"...
- How about that?
- Hey, joss, we're here.
Joss.
Hey, joss, where are you?
The welcome seemed warmer out there
- than it does in here.
- You can say that again.
Joss?
Quit hiding out on me, will you?
I wonder where
the old guy's got to.
Let's try the kitchen.
Sandra, come on.
How are we supposed
to shoot a video in here?
There's not enough light
to take a pee.
Vince said we needed something new.
- How about 10 minutes of total black?
- Revolutionary.
He's got to be here somewhere.
Joss.
Hey, joss.
Well,
at least he put in some good work
before he disappeared.
Mm, right on.
You guys wait here, okay?
Okay.
- I'll just be a minute.
- Sure thing.
- Jordan, want a beer?
- Sure. Thanks.
- Wowee.
- What have you found?
Another tray.
Good old joss.
Mm, I'm starving.
- Leave a few for vince.
- He's too busy looking for joss.
These look even
better than the others.
Angela, why don't you
eat something?
I'm not hungry.
You don't know
what you're missing.
We're not safe here.
I've got a strange
feeling about it.
Angela, for god's sake.
There are some things I feel.
I sense them.
We're in danger here.
The old man was right.
We should never have come.
Horrible things
are going to happen here.
Can you feel the wind?
The wind is lifting the fog.
He will command the house
and all of you will die.
You are all going to die.
You are all dead.
They have come for you.
They're his.
Go away!
No, leave me alone!
You're horrible!
I warned you.
You should never
have come to this house.
You will all die.
You're going to die too.
It's no use trying to resist.
You are all doomed.
Help me.
Your singer...
He is the killer.
You will see.
Only he will escape the dogs.
If you come out now,
perhaps he will spare you
because you're
so young and pretty.
You're trying
to trick me, old man.
I know you're lying.
Vince is our friend.
I know he is.
He's our friend.
And now it's you
that's gonna die.
Vince.
Can you hear me?
Watch out for the old man.
He's trying to kill us,
but we'll kill him first.
We'll kill him before he gets the chance.
Right, vince?
Vince, where are you?
So you think I'm lying, do you?
You'll soon find out
who your singer is.
Vince! I knew
you were still alive.
Do you hear me?
Hey, vince,
it's me, angela.
No!
I don't want to die!
- Leave me alone!
- Angela, what are you talking about?
It's okay.
Wake up.
- Go away!
- What's going on? What happened?
Wake up, angela.
- What the hell's going on?
- What's the problem?
It's all over, honey.
It's all over.
You're all right now.
- What's wrong with her?
- She's had a nightmare.
It was a signal.
You changed into a...
And you killed everybody...
Everybody except me.
I call that discrimination.
- Right on.
- Yeah.
Vince, you can't play
favors with friends.
Either you wipe out everybody or no one.
But then he almost killed me.
There was the old man too,
the one we met on the road.
Before, you said
I'd changed into something.
What was it?
You changed into a... a werewolf.
Can you see vince
transformed into a werewolf?
Just think of vince
covered with hair,
howling at the moon.
She's sleeping now.
And the others have gone
back to bed too.
Only now I can't get back to sleep.
Neither can you,
from what I see.
What are you reading?
Oh, vince,
you're not letting angela get to you?
Forget her nightmares.
We're grown-up people,
vince, rational and...
That thing we saw in the
woods wasn't normal or rational.
"Werewolves:
Myths, legends
and scientific
realities."
Just what exactly are
the scientific realities?
There's a disease...
A heart disease
that transforms the patient
into some kind of madman,
a beast that goes howling
at the moon like a wolf.
What?
That's crazy.
That thing we saw out there
was an animal of some kind,
not a man.
Listen, werewolves do exist.
Oh, bullshit, vince.
The year 2000 is
just around the corner.
I am a recognized expert
in electronic videos.
And you are the hottest
rock 'n' roll star in the world.
You're making records,
videos, movies
on high-tech
electronic equipment
of fantastic sophistication.
You can get on a plane tonight
and be in australia tomorrow.
And you're scared of werewolves?
20 years ago something terrible
happened here.
And it's happening again.
Entire families were wiped out
by a pack of killer dogs.
They weren't normal dogs.
These dogs were
more unpredictable
and more intelligent.
The people went crazy.
They needed a scapegoat
so they accused my father.
Oh...
your father?
Yes, my father.
He was afflicted with that
disease I was telling you about.
Sometimes when the moon
was full he'd leave the house
and go wandering through
the fields like an animal.
One time my mother found
him underneath a bush.
His hands and his mouth
were covered with blood
and next to him on the ground
were the remains of a baby calf.
He'd ripped the guts out
and eaten them.
- Oh my god.
- The neighbors were convinced
that he was the cause
of all the atrocities.
They came to the house
and dragged him out.
My mother and I
tried to stop them,
but it was useless.
They slaughtered him.
They stabbed him to death
with pitchforks.
They doused him with
gasoline and set him on fire.
Oh, vince, forgive me.
How was I to know?
But you must try to understand
that this has nothing
to do with werewolves,
just a pack of
ordinary stray dogs.
And that creature
we saw out there?
That was a dog too.
He was a bit bigger than normal,
that's all.
Maybe he was sick.
After all,
we only saw it for a second.
You sure are something,
you know that, sandra?
Do you know something, vince?
As soon as we deliver
this video job,
we're heading
straight for moorea...
One of the 130
polynesian islands...
Floating in crystal clear water,
two weeks of nude sunbathing
coconut drinks
and making love.
I love you, vince.
I can't stand
seeing you like this.
You go to bed now.
I'll be up in a minute.
Okay.
Don't be long.
I won't.
Oh, no.
♪ The clock struck midnight ♪
♪ and through my sleeping ♪
♪ I heard a tapping ♪
♪ at my door
♪ I looked but nothing ♪
♪ lay in the darkness
♪ and so I turned inside ♪
♪ once more
♪ to my amazement
♪ there stood a raven
♪ whose shadow hung
♪ above my door
♪ then through the silence ♪
♪ it spoke that one word ♪
♪ that I shall hear
♪ for evermore
♪ Nevermore.
♪ See me in the mirror
if you want to ♪
♪ see me in the mirror
if you really want to ♪
♪ maybe not too clear,
but the face you'll see ♪
♪ is mine
♪ do you feel my eyes
burning through you? ♪
♪ Do you feel the burn ♪
♪ when my eyes see
through you? ♪
♪ Do you see my eyes ♪
♪ when they burn
into your mind? ♪
♪ I can feel the teardrops ♪
♪ hit the ground
where I'm laid ♪
♪ I can feel you breathing ♪
♪ while I sleep
through the day ♪
♪ see you in a vision ♪
♪ in the dark with no light ♪
♪ your soul may go to heaven ♪
♪ but your heart's
mine tonight ♪
♪ do you feel my skin
when you touch me? ♪
♪ Do you feel my skin
♪ when you reach
and touch me? ♪
♪ Cold and blue and thin ♪
♪ but it's still somehow alive ♪
♪ and you can feel my blood ♪
♪ running through you
♪ you can feel the rush
of my blood ♪
♪ run through you
♪ you can feel the gush
of my blood ♪
♪ run up your spine
♪ and I can feel the teardrops ♪
♪ hit the ground
where I'm laid ♪
♪ I can feel you breathing ♪
♪ while I sleep
through the day ♪
♪ see you in a vision ♪
♪ in the dark with no light ♪
♪ your soul may go to heaven ♪
♪ but your heart's
mine tonight ♪
♪ see me in the mirror
if you want to ♪
if you really want to ♪
♪ maybe not too clear ♪
♪ but the face
you'll see is mine ♪
♪ see me in the mirror ♪
♪ mirror, mirror
♪ mirror
♪ see me in the mirror, mirror ♪
♪ see me in the mirror ♪
♪ mirror
♪ mirror, mirror.
Look out.
Give me a hand.
Turn him over.
Oh, god, it's joss.
Joss?
Why would anyone want
to kill an old caretaker?
I don't know.
Take it easy, angela.
Take it easy.
Come on, up you get.
Here, let me give you a hand.
It's okay.
You'll be all right now.
Here, blow your nose.
That's the way.
Come and lie down.
No, I don't want to lie down!
I want to get away
from this house.
I told you we should never have come here.
Angie, you've got to calm down.
Okay, guys,
I want to check out what went on up there.
Does anyone want to come along?
Looks like there's been
one hell of a struggle here.
Hey, guys,
maybe whoever it was dropped this before.
What do you think?
I don't get it.
Why would anyone
want to kill joss?
But if the dogs did it,
they could still be
in the house.
Hey, guys, where is angela?
She must still be
in the living room.
Come on, we mustn't
leave her alone.
Thank god you've got
guns in this house.
Looks like we may need them.
We've looked everywhere.
She's not in the house.
I'm going outside to look for her.
You stay here
- and barricade yourselves in.
- What if you don't find her?
If I'm not back by sundown,
leave without me.
- Are you crazy?
- No, I mean it.
Are we all agreed then?
Well, only if you swear
not to take any risks, okay?
Sure.
And don't open up to anybody.
I'm going to call the police.
I'll go with you.
The line's dead.
This is all getting
like a nightmare, marilou.
Yeah, just like angela's
nightmare, right?
That's done.
Ed's finished his little job.
This here is a bullet
that will pierce
vince roberts's heart.
Hey, we've got company.
Was vince expecting anyone?
Not that he told me.
Here, take this.
Keep your guns up.
Howdy, folks.
Is vince roberts with you all?
No,
but he should be back soon.
We're after them damn dogs.
We ain't seen no sign of them
around here.
How about you?
Not yet.
But if they do show up,
we're ready for them.
Good, sonny.
That sure is good to know.
Angela.
Angela!
You know, I'm sort of
like family to vince.
We knew his daddy real well.
I can't wait to see him again.
If you invite me in,
maybe we can
wait for him together...
real friendly-like,
over a couple of beers.
What do you say?
Shall we let them in?
Vince said we shouldn't
open up to anybody.
But these people are
in the same boat as us.
And it seems to me the more
guns we have around the better.
Well, I don't like
the looks of them.
Oh, come on now.
Don't you try and tell me
you ain't got
no beer in the fridge.
That wouldn't be friendly.
Well, I guess since they said
they knew vince's daddy...
okay, come on in.
That's more like it.
Do you hear that, guys?
What do you say
we accept these people's
kind hospitality?
Ed, you stay out here
just in case anything
unpleasant comes around,
know what I mean?
Angela!
Hey, ed, take care
of the camper.
Stay where you are.
Who's this?
Joss, the caretaker.
What do you know?
His heart's been torn clear out.
Another victim
of your boyfriend?
What the hell
are you talking about?
I think you know, missy.
And if you don't,
you'll soon find out
when vince roberts gets back.
What are you going
to do with him?
What I'm going to do with him,
I'm going to shoot
this here silver bullet
right through his heart.
But why would anyone
want to kill vince?
I think I understand.
You are the same band
that killed vince's father,
aren't you?
We made a mistake back then.
We should have known that his
son was cursed by the evil too.
We should have
killed him off then.
You're just a bunch
of stupid animals.
What the hell do you think
that killing vince
is going to solve?
Don't you understand
that werewolves are
just an idiotic superstition?
Listen, I was here
that night when
we killed roberts
and I'm telling you,
he wasn't a man anymore.
You understand me, girl?
He was something horrible.
It was a night like this,
a night when there was
a full moon.
It is then that they
transform themselves.
When vince gets back,
I'm going to shoot him
right through the heart
with this silver bullet.
That's how you kill werewolves.
But they're mad, completely mad.
And the dogs... have you seen the dogs too?
It's him who commands them,
controls them.
Those are the powers
of werewolves.
If you try to kill him,
we'll turn you in.
We'll go to the sheriff.
The sheriff's dead,
and so is the deputy...
Torn to pieces by the dogs.
Ed and me seen vince roberts
while he turned
from a man to a monster.
What monster?
What's he talking about?
I saw it too.
- What? What did you see?
- The monster,
the thing you call the werewolf.
When?
Last night,
when I was with vince.
So it can't possibly be him.
Did you see it too?
Well, I guess you must be
the werewolf's sweetheart.
Ain't that right?
- Angela.
- Vince.
Come on, let's get back
to the house.
- I have this vision...
- forget the vision.
Let's get out of here.
He's coming.
It's vince roberts with a girl.
Jerome, greg, watch these kids.
If they move so much as a hair,
shoot.
Ed, you be ready
to open the door
when I tell you.
Right.
Frank, sandra, open the door.
Come on, quick.
Whose car is that?
Are you guys all right?
Answer me, someone.
Jordan, frank, come on.
Wait here a minute.
Now!
The bastard's escaping.
He's getting away.
Jerome, greg, after him.
Kill them.
Okay, boys, I'm coming.
- Let's get her onto the couch.
- Right.
He's going up on the roof.
Up, both of you.
I don't like you.
Well, you're not exactly
my type either.
You look like a couple
of queers to me.
Queers make my stomach turn!
Move.
Go on.
Do you know I got to kill you?
You're not serious.
Say goodbye to your boyfriend.
- Vince roberts!
- Don't shoot!
I'm going to treat this bastard
like he wanted to treat you.
- Well?
- No, sandra.
We're not murderers.
Listen, sandra, think of vince.
We've got to help him.
Okay.
I'm going out to find vince.
Okay, but be careful.
Shut the door!
Frank!
Hey, you!
All right, vince roberts.
Shoot them!
I can't.
I'd kill him.
No!
Frank! Frank!
Fight them off so I can shoot.
Frank, fight them off.
I can't.
He may be hurt.
- They've quieted down.
- Yeah.
- Why?
- I don't know.
Something is trying to get in!
That's not a dog
trying to get in.
I can't hold it back.
Your jacket.
- Don't jordan, don't.
- Let me go.
Come on, let's go.
Sandra, my hair, my hair!
He's pulling my hair.
My hair.
Help me, sandra.
Help me.
Okay, where is it?
I'll kill it!
Vince. Oh, vince,
where have you been?
Come on, marilou, let's go.
That's good.
It's all over.
We are going to die too.
We haven't got a chance.
It's all over.
Calm down, marilou.
You'll see, everything
will be all right.
It's him.
He is to blame
for what has happened
to angela, frank and jordan.
What are you talking about?
Have you gone crazy?
Where was he
when that monster dog
crashed through
the living room door
and when jordan was eaten alive?
And before that,
in the bathroom?
And now?
Why don't the dogs attack us?
Tell me the truth, vince.
Your neighbors were right.
You are the monster dog.
You are the murdering animal.
God damn you!
Damn you!
You are a werewolf.
I know you are.
I know it!
What can we do, vince?
Vince.
It's amazing, isn't it?
They suddenly all calm down,
just like that.
But how?
Why?
Go wake up marilou.
Make it quick.
Okay.
- Shit.
- What's happened?
The keys aren't here.
I guess one of those four
had them on him.
- I'm gonna have to go back.
- I'll come with you.
Are you going to
leave me here alone?
You'll be safe enough
locked in here.
But what if you don't come back?
Well, you'd better pray
that we do.
He doesn't have them.
- Check that one.
- Okay.
Vince, I found them!
Here, catch.
Vince!
I'll catch you yet,
vince roberts.
Sandra, grab the gun!
Help!
Oh, vince, vince.
It's not over.
We've still got to get out of here.
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
Come on, hurry up.
I can hardly believe
that this nightmare
is finally over.
What do you say, marilou?
Marilou?
You haven't
fallen asleep, have you?
Marilou?
Open the door.
Sandra, open the door.
- Jump!
- No.
Jump!
Vince?
I tell you now,
he's taken my place
and his blood is
as tainted as mine.
Vince was just a baby.
Horrible things happened.
His father sank his teeth
into my neck.
And now vince
has come back to help me.
Now, for better or worse,
we have a new king
who will live in the house
of the dead forever.
Vince.
Vince!
- Vince.
- Stay away from me!
Why?
Stay away from me!
Use it.
Shoot me.
Do it before it's too late.
Come on, shoot me.
Come on.
God help me.
You were right, angela.
You weren't crazy.
You knew.
You knew all along.
♪ Sometimes I'm james bond ♪
♪ sometimes I'm billy the kid ♪
♪ sometimes I feel
like sherlock holmes ♪
♪ sometimes I feel like
jack the ripper ♪
♪ 'cause I got an image
out of control ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ I've drawn in a face ♪
♪ 'cause mine's been erased ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ sometimes I'm on a case ♪
♪ sometimes I'm shooting
bad dudes ♪
♪ sometimes I'm
slashing the face ♪
♪ sometimes I'm looking
for clues ♪
♪ sometimes I'm
breaking the law ♪
♪ sometimes I'm solving
the crime ♪
♪ I'm always fast on the draw ♪
♪ I get the girls all the time ♪
♪ 'cause I got an image
out of control ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ I've drawn in a face ♪
♪ 'cause mine's been erased ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ Sometimes I'm james bond ♪
♪ sometimes I'm billy the kid ♪
♪ sometimes I feel
like sherlock holmes ♪
♪ sometimes I feel like
jack the ripper ♪
♪ 'cause I got an image
out of control ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ I've drawn in a face ♪
♪ 'cause mine's been erased ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ now I got an image
out of control ♪
♪ identity crisises
♪ I've drawn in a face
'cause mine's been erased ♪
♪ identity crisises.