"The sheep were grazing..."
"The sheep..."
What then?
-"Were grazing."
- OK.
"The sheep were grazing."
"The butcher was making pate."
Not so fast.
After "the butcher"?
"Was making pate."
After pate?
"The shoemaker was tanning leather."
"Leather."
Then...?
-"The little town lay stretched out
as time went by."
Come on, Laurent, sit up straight!
You'll ruin your spine.
When I'm like this,
it makes the letters big...
Especially the O's.
The what?
The letter "O".
Come on, sit up straight!
So, where were we up to?
"The little town..."
An "O"?
Where did the "O" come from?
That's not right, is it?
Laurent...
Of course it's not.
In this case the "O" sound,
is written "AU"...
and not "O".
I thought it was
"O thread of time".
Like "O time!
Suspend your flight".
It's wrong.
Don't argue.
Anyway, this dictation is stupid.
What?
"The butcher makes pate..."
They're really shitty sentences.
Please, Laurent...
I don't need your opinions...
And I don't like you
saying bad words.
- Alright?
- Alright.
We'll go over it.
"The butcher was making pate."
You spelled pate with an extra E.
- Sure I did.
- But that's wrong!
You told me before
that it has an E.
Me? I told you there was
an extra E in pate?
Yes, last Thursday.
You're just being cheeky now.
You're forcing me
to make mistakes.
That was "LA patée du chien".
La patée du chien...
Dog mince!
In that case,
there's an E on the end!
So, when the butcher is making pate,
there is no "e".
But if the dog eats it,
it gets another E. Crazy.
That's how it is!
And now to finish...
the cultural outing.
We have Abel Gance's film, "Napoleon".
A masterpiece, that shows us
a very fiery Bonaparte.
6 francs, with metro ride.
Or, more classic,
a visit to Malmaison...
12 francs...
Coach and sandwiches included.
So all we need do now,
is to vote.
For the film to discuss,
raise your hand.
1, 2, 3, 4,
5, 6,
7, 8.
8.
We'll discuss the film
in the Trocadero gardens.
The film is shorter
than the visit would be.
It's cheaper because
of the distance.
Any questions?
So, Malmaison?
3,
4, 5, 6,
7, 8, 9, 10,
11, 12.
12...
Well, I see classicism
has won out.
Good evening.
Mr Lanier, I wanted
to congratulate you, about Laurent.
Congratulate me+
Despite your family situation,
I understand...
...you've been able to
keep him balanced, and mentally sound.
My wife and I have split up
without animosity.
I know what I'm talking about.
You're a fantastic father.
- "Fantastic"...?
- Yes.
To bring up a child on your own,
is rare.
Well, it's just a matter
of being organised.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Leave me the dry-cleaning ticket.
You'll forget tomorrow.
3, 4...
5 faults... well done!
I bought your cigarettes.
There's cold chicken
in the kitchen.
Unbelievable!
What's going on...?
Damnation!
The lights don't work.
I put the stool there to fix the fuses.
Thanks.
I hear buzzing.
I hate that.
Capital 'A'...
"Brumaire the 18th."
...m, a, i, r, e.
Small 'a'...
"The origin of the coup."
Small 'b' - The event.
Small 'c' - The consequences
of the coup.
Small 'a' - "The origin..."
Pellegrin, can't you restrain
your artistic impulses?
- I didn't do it, Ma'am.
- So did I do it?
- I'd never draw that, Ma'am.
- Go outside.
- It wasn't him, Ma'am.
- What are you on about Lanier?
About the truth, Ma'am.
- Did Berthier call?
- No.
I called all morning.
It was busy.
He doesn't give a damn
about anyone.
- Does he know the form-work was frozen?
- Obviously.
He'll call back.
Well, I'll go up and help them.
Hey!
Well...
So?
It'll all need to be re-done.
What do you mean, "all re-done"?
It has to be checked out.
It needs to be assessed.
Can you hear me?
You're wanted on the phone.
- What did she say?
- You're wanted on the phone.
I think it's Berthier.
Who is it?
It's your son.
That's why you brought me down?
He said it was important.
- Laurent?
- Hello... Dad?
You forgot the dry-cleaning ticket.
What?
You forgot to leave me
the dry-cleaning ticket.
I was to go and pick up
your suit after school.
Listen, Laurent...
But I can't.
Can't what?
I won't be able to.
Too bad for you.
Listen, Laurent, be a good boy..
You won't yell at me
about your waistcoat?
Miss Turp is much better
than Carpentier.
You've never had her.
Yeah, but you're
still on Napoleon.
We do him in more detail.
Takes more time.
Carpentier's a bitch.
Tassard says she's hopeless.
You're kidding...
He made 100 mistakes in his dictation.
- That true, Tassard?
- Tassard, he says you're crap.
If there's no answer,
we'll go round the side.
Come on.
Hello, ma'am.
Hello, children.
It's soil from the country.
We got it last weekend.
If you have pot-plants,
you should change the soil.
- It's 5 francs.
- Yes, but...
How often have you changed it?
- I don't know.
- That's bad.
You'll be infected by bugs.
Plants like fresh soil
that breathes.
It's only 5 francs.
We won't make a mess.
- Finished?
- Yes.
- Thank you, Ma'am.
- Goodbye, boys.
- Hello, Ma'am.
It's soil from the country.
We got it last weekend.
If you have pot-plants...
...you should change the soil.
It's only 5 francs.
How long is it
since you changed it?
That's bad.
You'll get bugs.
Plants love fresh soil that breathes.
- It's only 5 francs.
- We won't make a mess.
Good evening.
Hotel Westminster.
Hello. Possible to speak
with Miss Garcin?
Just a minute.
I'm afraid Miss Garcin
is not here.
She don't left a message
for Mr Lanier?
No message. Sorry.
Thank you.
You're welcome, Sir.
-"You're welcome, Sir."
Something wrong?
Everything's fine.
Fancy a movie?
Now?
I've already been this afternoon.
So what?
I won't get to bed till late.
I start at 8.30 in the morning.
You act like an old man.
Well, if it will make you happy...
Yes... yes.
No... that can take 2 days.
We can't start the plumbing during...
April 17?
Catching up in winter
is difficult, you realise.
Yes, I realise how upsetting
it must be.
Very well then...
I'll report back in a fortnight.
That OK?
Fine, that's what we'll do.
[Ingredients for rabbit dish]
Call me on the 15th.
I'm going to the supermarket.
You got the good plates out?
A special dinner.
- The rabbit fricassee?
- Yes.
Done your homework?
- Yeah, yeah.
-"Yeah, yeah."
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I've done it.
This is how you
mop up the sauce.
I'm still hungry.
"Still hungry!"
It was really yummy.
Rabbit's my specialty.
That's all you can do,
but you do it well.
Thank you Sir.
Well...
Now then...
You want Liege coffee
or Vanoise?
- Vanoise.
- Alright.
That's good.
Then I get what I like.
Have you really finished
your homework?
Yeah.
"Yeah"...
I only say "yeah".
Where's your exercise book?
On the table
in my room.
4 remains...
carry 3....
7 and 3 is 10.
Take away 3... point...
2 x 5 is 10.
3...
2 x 5...
5... 9.
9 x 5 is 45.
46, 47, 48, 49, 50...
0, and I carry 4...
9 x 5...
9, 10, 11, 12, 13...
There we are.
Divisions are hard
with the decimals.
You haven't made any mistakes.
That's good..
You don't have
a very clear conscience.
- Me?
- Yes.
Laurent, don't laugh.
Where is it?
I understand.
Go and get it.
What?
Go and get it...!
You think I don't know?
And do you think
you're making progress?
You also use it.
But you know that
I can do divisions.
I use it to save time.
Me too... to save time.
Mine's just as valuable.
Go to bed!
- You're in my room.
- So what? Go to bed!
Confiscated.
Aren't you saying goodnight, Dad?
What's this thing?
It's memory
for polar coordinates.
Why don't I have it on mine?
I don't like when you yell at me.
You're nuts...
I'm not yelling at you.
I'm just a bit tired.
But all the same, we can
have a little match if you like.
- Now? - OK? - Sure!
Come on...
we'll set up.
Be careful of the TV.
Let's go!
A professional match
of 15 rounds...
...competing for the world
mosquito-weight title.
Between the title-holder,
Franck Lanier...
and his challenger...
the little Laurent Lanier.
Laurent Lanier,
26,850 kg,
Franck Lanier, 71,500 kg.
Allow me to present...
Laurent Lanier!
And Franck Lanier!
Dong!
Go to your corner.
Already?
- Yes. 5 minutes rest.
- It didn't last long.
3 minutes...
with head-butts...
You know...
It's not fair
that you're the referee.
We only resume
when it suits you.
When you're in trouble,
you make the round shorter!
Dong!
1, 2, 3,
4, 5,
6...
Hello?
No, I'm not leaving.
Oh, it's you?
You're in Paris?
You'll be there
in half an hour?
Dad?
Who was that?
On the phone.
No one special.
Just about work.
Brushed your teeth?
We had a super evening, eh?
Sure, yeah.
You hurt me.
Sleep tight, world champ.
We both had a great time.
Of course we did.
Come on... off to sleep.
Hey, the door!
What about it?
Leave it open.
Sorry.
- Like this?
- Yes. Thanks.
Have you missed me?
- Finished with your travels?
- Yes.
Look...
It's cute.
Terrific, eh?
I found them in Glasgow.
Quiet!
Miss Carpentier is here.
Tassard, you watch the class.
No noise!
I'll be listening.
Hey, you haven't paid.
5 francs.
Here.
Are we practicing, Tassard?
- Dad!
- Here.
Look at this.
- What?
- You have to buy another pair.
- With what money?
- Yours.
It's not a scooter.
It says age 10.
Go try them on.
Hey, how are they?
Pardon me.
Hurry up, Laurent.
We could've fixed the others.
It would've cost less.
Considering my talents
as a seamstress...
Laurent, are you coming?
We're going to be late.
I'm coming!
- What's this?
- It's for Grandma's turtles.
For the turtles?
You sure have a lot there!
They're not going
to eat all that.
There are 2 of them.
Oh, there's 2, yes.
I was thinking of leaving you
with Grandma today.
And then...
You'll do what?
I'll pick you up this evening.
I wanted the chance to take a walk
in the countryside with a lady friend.
Who is she?
Oh, you'll see.
She's a very old friend.
A girl I knew at university.
Funny I should run into her
as I was leaving the work site.
Pure chance.
We decided...
You don't mind, do you?
That's OK.
- There's a cop over there.
- Where?
There.
If he shows up,
tell him I'm coming.
Okay.
Liar!
"Funny I should run into her..."
- Is the driver your father?
- Yeah.
Go and tell him
he can't park here.
He's with a woman.
What?
He doesn't care
about parking tickets.
He tears them up anyway.
He's alright about
staying on his own.
We'll drop him off
with his grandmother.
You're not worried
he'll make a fuss about it?
Not at all.
- Here you are?
- For me?
Why?
I don't want to go to Grandma's.
What did you say?
A little while ago you said
you wanted to go.
I've changed my mind.
You said you were going to Grandma's.
You're going to Grandma's.
Mum said you were dressed
like an old man.
I need to pee.
Can't you hang on?
He's decided to screw up our day.
He can have a pee.
My intrusion isn't going so well.
Let him come with us...
for my sake.
No... I mustn't give in.
Franck, I'm getting to know him.
I want this day
to be a success.
Let's go to the seaside.
The sea? You're joking.
It's 200 km.
Well...
We'll have to fill up...
You like the seaside?
Yeah, it's not bad.
You'd better, because we're going.
Yeah!
My first is a first-name.
My second is a name.
Making an actor.
Who is it?
- Jean-Paul Belmondo.
- Wrong.
Humphrey Bogart.
Do you have many others
like that?
Thousands.
Want to hear another one?
No thanks, I'd rather
get some fresh air.
This is not the Olympics,
for heaven's sake!
It's stupid we don't have a ball.
We could've played a game.
- You just have to buy one.
- You've got 10 balls at home.
Go on!
Buy one!
We buy one
every time we go out.
Go on, Dad!
Alright, but it counts
towards your birthday.
Which one?
10th or 11th?
- Which do you prefer?
- 10th.
He's not stupid, you know.
He's 10½ now.
Really...
How do you feel
about eating oysters?
My first is numeral "Un".
My second is... "frais".
My third is...
..."beau".
My fourth is a "gare".
All making a film actor.
A...lain Delon.
No!
Has the cat got your tongue?
Yeah..
Humphrey Bogart.
Un, frais, Beau, gare.
It's the iodine...
It increases his brain activity tenfold.
Doesn't stop her laughing madly.
"Come along."
"Quietly, this time."
"Pass me the suitcase.
We'll stash the dough in it."
"The dough!"
I could do with a short nap.
On the beach
or in the car?
On the beach.
The sand, the sun,
your toes spread out.
You know there are bedrooms
with central heating.
The sea tends to give me ideas.
Really?
What sort of ideas?
Wonderful.
It's the iodine.
It increases your
brain activity tenfold.
Like me to show you my idea?
Don't want me
to show you my idea?
Yes.
Laurent?
Can't he stay playing
on the beach?
Shouldn't be a problem.
It feels nice,
taking you to the seaside.
Did you see that, Dad?
The horses?
Yeah.
Do you think we could have a ride?
Sure!
Janine is a bit tired.
You could have 2, 3 rides.
Laurent wants to go horse-riding
on the beach.
He wants to do it on his own.
The horses down there?
Yes. Do you want to come?
Why not?
Well, let's get going!
Good... let's go.
It'll be fun, eh?
You know what
he said to me just now?
"You wouldn't think so,
but she's very nice."
You don't put on airs...
but you're very pretty.
Have you thought about Bangkok?
Are you going to be able
to get away?
I'm sick of being the sucker!
I'm always the one who cops it.
You're all going on a trip,
and I have to stay.
You don't like going on trips.
Bangkok is more than a trip.
The lady from Bangkok.
Are you going to tell him
you're going with me?
I don't know...
We'll see later.
- Is he your gangster?
- What?
Doesn't look like one.
The garage is a hideout.
You want to spend your life
carrying bags of soil around?
With his trick, you can make
at least 30 francs.
Don't let me down...
I have the tokens.
OK. But we need to make
at least 30 francs each.
- I'll go and get it.
- Alright.
What are you doing here?
Laurent wants 30 francs each.
I've told you 100 times
already not to come here.
He's not the boss.
A 5.58pm, you go
to the record section.
You casually collect
a bunch of records.
Each of you a separate bunch.
- In the pop section?
- Yeah... pop that's in English.
- All clear?
- Yeah.
At 6pm I come in
and attract attention.
You grab the discs
and scram.
We'll meet up
at the garage.
- How will you attract attention?
- Never mind.
Let's set our watches.
Are you looking for something?
No... nothing...
You going to work in jeans?
I'm meeting your mother.
She's always telling me
how I dress like an old man...
Shit, I forgot my exercise book.
- See you this evening.
- See you!
2 return tickets to Bangkok
Cut the noise!
I found two tickets.
He wanted to surprise me.
He's going to say to me...
"Pack your bag, we're
going to Bangkok."
I know what he's like.
Two sets are equal if,
and only if...
Where's Bangkok?
I don't know.
To the right, in Asia...
You just have to look
in the dictionary.
Pass me the dictionary.
The dictionary.
The rule is as follows...
When more than one set
is involved...
A or B...
A equals B...
or B equals   A
signifying that...
A and B...
...designate one
and the same set.
"Bangkok, capital of Thailand."
It's on the right,
down the bottom.
"Cement works, shipyards,
food factories..."
Sounds like Bangkok
is like Aubervilliers.
There are no shipyards
in Aubervilliers.
What are you
talking about?
That there are no shipyards
in Aubervilliers.
We don't give brochures
to schoolchildren
What a nice surprise.
What's her name? Corinne?
No... Janine.
Oh yeah.
When are you leaving?
- You haven't told anyone?
- No.
- It's not true.
- No, I swear.
You'll never change, eh?
What do you mean?
It's true you're secretive.
Now my son gets into it!
Give me a break, you two!
The other day you
shook hands with Janine,
as if I didn't know
you kiss each other.
Modesty...
You won't even tell me
where we're going on holiday.
You going to Courchevel
with your mother.
You'll see... He'll keep it
right till the end.
I found the tickets
for Bangkok, you see.
-1, 2, 3, 4.
1, 2, 3, 4.
We open up the lungs.
Tassard doesn't have his outfit?
Come and see me at
the end of the session, Tassard.
3, 4...
On tire. 3, 4... 1, 2...
There's Dede who wants to see us
in the garage at 6 o'clock.
He wants to talk about
a great new hit.
- Not interested.
- What's up?
I'm just not interested.
...has its source
on Mt Gerbier-de-Jonc...
1,307 metres high.
Do you have photos
of Bangkok?
Shit.
I investigated.
There are elephants.
- You're lucky.
- You're pissing me off.
Who was using bad language?
I'm waiting.
It was me, Ma'am.
What was it about?
- Good evening.
- Miss.
Sorry to disturb you.
It's about Laurent.
Really?
Come in.
I'm worried,
Mr Lanier.
Laurent is not interested anymore.
He's regressing day by day.
Well... give me your coat.
Certainly.
He's becoming downright
insufferable.
Isn't that wonderful!
You have wonderful taste.
So I did a little investigating.
May I sit down?
Of course...
I put some questions
to Laurent.
It turns out that he's traumatized
by your trip to Bangkok.
Really?
With Janine.
Because...
It started the day you
received the call from the airport
and when you kissed Janine.
Children feel rejected.
They are also
quite talkative.
Aren't you going to
offer me a drink?
Yes, what would you
like to drink?
A whisky with lots of water.
I wouldn't want to get drunk.
This morning,
I'm making breakfast.
- Cocoa and French toast.
- You're burning the toast.
Not serious.
There we go.
About Bangkok,
if I'm not taking you...
...it's really not my fault.
You want to be alone
with Janine.
Don't be silly...
You don't understand...
It's all about money.
4,000 francs. I don't have enough
to take you to Bangkok.
You must realise that.
- Otherwise you'd take me?
- Yes, of course.
Who's paying for Janine?
You?
What? For her ticket?
Yeah.
She is, of course.
Not me.
There's cement in Bangkok.
How much will it make?
Lots.
At least 4,350?
5 times that.
The tote takings, understand?
What is the tote?
The betting shop.
You'll pinch the takings?
The one at the Cafe Goulart,
on Michelet St.
- You're talking about a heist?
- So what?
It's not serious.
Your mum's gonna make you rinse.
I like cordial better.
We can buy some.
Were you in time
for the doctor?
So what did he say?
Angina?
What do you mean, angina?
Hold the line.
So is it serious or not?
Where did he get hold of it?
Hold the line...
It's Janine.
Alright... please...
Can you stay
to make him his dinner?
I'm sorry to have to ask you.
Very kind of you.
Well, you take care of it.
Love you. Goodbye.
I'll put him on.
You OK?
He has angina.
- Is this what you're reading?
- Yeah.
But that'll give you nightmares.
I swapped it with Gilles,
for 2 "Asterix" comics.
- Who's Gilles?
- My best friend.
- "Your best friend"?
- Yes.
I had an even better one,
before we moved.
Laurent! See who's at the door?
Hello.
Who was it?
She's a bum.
She sells potatoes door-to-door.
I told her to get lost.
Open the door!
Ignore her, Mum.
You sell potatoes?
Sorry?
I find it hard to believe.
"A bum"?
You called her a bum?
- Yes, I was very cool about it.
- Cheeky, you mean.
If you call that
being cool.
How long, for
the potato gratin?
95 minutes.
Set the thermostat at 4.
Hello? Who do you want?
It's Janine.
She's calling from work.
I think she's crying.
Hi, Franck.
How are things?
Fine thanks.
Well, I'll leave you to it.
See you.
Everything must be wrapped up
by Christmas. It's hell.
So tell me, what's wrong, eh?
Nothing.
Is it the potato story,
that's brought this on?
I don't give a stuff about that.
It's all about your ego.
My ego?
I'm sick of you hiding me.
It's gone on too long.
I'd come to spend the afternoon
with Laurent.
And I find myself
in a clownish situation.
It's because of the divorce.
My lawyer says
I have to be sensible.
Stop it! Anyone would think
you were at war with Sylviane.
Your kid's not going
to get stolen from you.
This is for Laurent.
It's a Meccano set.
Can I come up for 5 minutes?
On Sunday.
Pick me up around 3pm
at the printery.
What's the matter?
Dracula comes out
from under the bed.
Look.
So?
You can see no one's there.
You're hot.
Go back to sleep.
Who's told you about Dracula?
Nobody.
He's in the lounge-room.
You'll see.
He's behind the books.
There's no one.
Behind the German dictionary.
Mum put him there.
What are these horrors?
Can I sleep in your bed?
Who gave you this?
I swapped it with Gilles
for 2 "Asterix" comics.
Come on.
Dad...?
What now?
Did you hear a noise?
Go to sleep, Laurent.
I can't sleep.
Count sheep.
That's dumb.
We could play poker?
Don't be silly...
We're going to sleep.
Give me two.
Plus 2.
Pair of queens.
Three kings!
Good... you've won.
-6, 8, 10.
Cut.
Tell me, Dad...
...if I had those 4,300 francs,
will you take me to Bangkok?
- 2.
- I'm in.
- How many cards?
- 3.
2 to me.
We're going to do a heist.
Yeah?
The tote.
You'd be justified.
It's dirty money.
Either way, there are people
who ruin themselves on the trifecta.
Don't you feel sorry for them?
Not at all.
It's your turn.
Your call.
I'm all in.
- What have you got?
- Nothing at all.
I'm sorry, pal,
full house, kings and tens.
You win.
- Yes?
- Marlboro.
If it starts like this,
let's stop here and now.
Second window on the right
with the flowers.
See it?
- Of course.
- You can do it?
We already smashed the windshield
of Carpentier's car.
It's not an Olympics time.
Show me.
1 minute 40.
We need to cut at least 10 seconds off.
- Shall we do the voice shot?
- I'm out of breath.
Will you be out of breath
on the day of the heist?
I will have practiced.
How do you do that?
Show me again.
Show you what again?
What do you want?
It's for tomorrow.
"National Defense Committee
against tuberculosis."
Good morning.
Good morning, Marie.
Here's another trifecta
that's difficult to decipher.
But with these handicaps,
it's became the norm.
These handicaps are given
to young horses...
or today, with the price of 'Plaisance',
to the elderly.
There will be 22 starters,
2,200 metres to cover.
Hello, Gilles?
- It's starting badly.
Why?
- It's stamps of '56.
- What year?
1956.
We can't go back now.
Will we be finished
with the heist by noon?
I have to be at my mother's
by 12.30.
Good morning, Ma'am.
It's for the anti-tuberculosis campaign.
Do you want stamps?
-Shit!
They were talking about it on TV.
I've seen nothing about it.
On the TV... for research...
It's for doing good.
It's for saunas.
- For what?
- Saunas.
"Saunas"?!
You mean sanatoriums don't you?
Show me your stamps.
- They're not for this year.
- What?
Look!
Mrs Goulart!
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
The same thing happened to me.
You still here?
Where are my stamps?
What stamps?
Yes, here you are.
I sell stamps for a living.
I don't buy them.
- Here.
- Thank you.
What have you broken?
- Nothing.
- What's that then?
It broke all on its own.
- What can I do about it?
- What can I?
It's not my fault.
It's nothing to yell at me about.
I'm fed up.
I told you I wasn't OK about it!
He just had to work,
to get started.
He tells me he can't find a job.
So I said "Spend less time at the cafe
and more at the job centre."
He said to me... "If I'm at the cafe,
it's because I'm unemployed."
I said... "The hospitals
are full of unemployed."
I tell you!
- Marcel...!
- Yes?
- Shall I put the roast on?
- Yes, that'd be the right time.
Got to run..
Got to feed him.
Talk to you Sunday.
I'll get it.
Mr Goulart?
Owner of the Cafe des Coteaux?
Someone's messing
with your security shutter.
Sounds like burglars.
Shit!
What's going on now?
What is it?
Seems someone was messing
with the shutter.
Got a phone call...
Hi, folks!
Cottage pie...
do you like it?
Sit up.
You don't look
very happy about it.
It's true...
You look sad.
I'm tired.
I've had a hard week.
Well, in 10 days
it'll be holidays.
- It'll be fun in Courchevel.
- Yeah.
Hi... how are you?
Could you call Janine?
- She didn't come in.
- What?
Did you have
a date with her?
Can I use your phone?
Hello, Mr Lanier.
Miss Janine isn't here.
She didn't leave a message?
She left a note?
Could you do me a big favour.
Could you please
read it to me?
I can't. It's private.
I'd be terribly embarrassed.
You could do it for me,
Mrs Ferral.
It's just to tell me
where she is.
Do me a favour.
Thank you.
I really don't know
if I should.
I give you full authorisation.
I have no secrets from you.
Alright, I'll read it.
"Darling..."
"Darling!"
I've gone to the country, to reflect.
"Partly to clear my mind,
and partly to be alone."
"Don't read too much
into my departure."
"I'm not only happy
with sex..."
"I also want a life with you."
Shall I go on?
No, thank you, Mrs Ferral.
Goodbye.
Sorry to have bothered you.
- What's Dede doing?
- I don't know.
What if he doesn't come?
It's your fault, after all.
You're the one
who called Dede.
Think you're smart,
do you?!
So, guys?
Arguing are we?
No, it's OK.
We were just talking.
Here, a stick each.
Almost.
What's a stick?
You just have to count, man.
See you guys next time.
Do you know what time it is?
Yes.
What are you up to?
Here.
- What is it?
- A stick.
So it's a stick.
You want me to open it?
Where did this money
come from?
- Answer me, Laurent.
- The tote robbery.
What are you saying?
Are you kidding?
- No, I'm not kidding.
- Come on, there's a good boy.
Tell me about it.
Just between you and me.
Calm down now.
Come on, old chap,
tell me about it.
Tell me about it.
You think it's normal?
A heist at 10 years old
is normal?
You grumble because
we're too hard on you!
If you watched less TV,
it wouldn't happen.
I told you about the heist,
and you didn't believe me.
Rubbish!
Your story is a load of nonsense.
It could have been
that Goulart had a safe...
or that his wife closed the door.
Or they weren't downstairs
at his cafe, eh?
Completely crazy.
9 out of 10 chances for it to fail.
It's crazy.
Perhaps. But we succeeded.
Laurent, forget
that kind of reasoning.
You want me to go in?
Where does Dede live?
This is it?
Yes?
- You're Dede?
- Yes. Why?
The tote?
You want Gilles' address?
Good idea.
I have to warn you
about his father, though.
There's your father.
Come here.
What are you doing
still with that boy?
You're not to see him again.
He's a bad influence on you.
A what?
The less you see of each other,
the less you'll get into trouble.
Hurry up.
We have to pack
your suitcase.
Your mother's coming at 5.
You little devil!
- I don't care, I won't go.
- What?
Bangkok?
What next?
I won't be rewarding you
for what you did.
Consider yourself lucky
to go to winter sports.
I don't know if I'll be going
to Bangkok, now.
I've heard nothing from Janine.
Laurent.
Laurent!
Dear Dad...
I only did this to be able
to go with you,
but you didn't understand.
I'll take care of myself,
because I don't want to go
to the snow.
You'll be able to walk quietly
with Janine in Bangkok. Goodbye.
Shit.
I'm so happy to see you!
But what's up, Franck?
Laurent...
"Laurent"?
He's run away.
"Run away"?
It's so sad him saying
"You can walk quietly."
He's misspelled it.
Excuse me, Madam.
Is Janine here?
No, she's gone out.
There, there, little one...
She won't be late.
Come inside.
No, inspector.
1 metre 39.
Yes, Inspector.
I'll wait to hear from you.
Thank you.
- Is that you there?
- Yes.
I was a singer.
Drink it while it's hot.
I'm sure you've never
heard "Carmen" sung.
- Like it?
- Not bad.
Pardon?
How come he's at your place?
What's he doing there?
Janine, he's at your place.
Attention. Departure of
Thaï International flight 905...
destination Frankfurt
and Bangkok....
...boarding now.
Please present your boarding card
to the hostess.
Thaï International
wishes you a pleasant journey.
Passport, vaccines.
The dough...
Mr Dad had a trivial life...
A sweet little girlfriend,
just a bit of a bother
Because Mr Dad
had but one desire,
to be as one with his kid.
Mr Dad had his little boy
who ran the house,
taught him a lesson.
because Mr Dad, in his desires
was even smaller than his son.
Mr Dad said to his wife
"It's okay, now that
I keep the apartment"
because Mr Dad
for once, knew how to do it
Conducting his business
in an upside down way
Mr Dad had a certain charm
When at thirty-one
he got it together,
only Mr Dad felt torn.
A shared love is only half...
Mr Dad wanted a mum
to take care kindly
of his little child
Only Mr Dad had a rascal
who politely said
"Go to blazes"
Mr Dad wanted to live his life
and leave his little one
at least a lifetime
So Mr Dad began to say
that he was going to work