Funny kid. She's on the right path.
And don't go daydreaming
when I need your eyes.
We can never be quiet in this house.
-Stop! It's a private property!
-But we're guests at the house.
-Stop goddamnit!
-Let us go.
I'm telling you to stop!
-What?
-Who are they?
-How could I know?
-Probably Laurent's friends.
-He has strange friends.
-I don't care.
We can never be quiet in this house.
-Stop goddamnit!
-Stop the car.
We're sorry. We didn't hear you.
We're coming to see Laurent.
Laurent Lorrain. It's here?
Yes it's here.
We're Laurent's friends.
From the Art school.
The fine arts...
Why not? Laurent seems to
be very fond of them.
I've got nothing against that. It's a high-class
fad inherited from his mother.
Look at Elsa and you'll
have an idea of her painting.
Superb and academic even if she
never went to the fine arts.
I mean academic but transfigured by
something that no school can learn.
A strenght, a passion!
The only paintings I've seen from
Laurent were Ingres pastiches.
My God! Ingres...I'm exagerating.
I don't know where that languor comes from.
You're exagerating. There's one
thing or two not so bad in Laurent's work.
Remember that big thing
with china ink
that the Parturier's hung above their
sideboard. -Evidently. Three accents...
a black wash and suddenly we have
the sea tortured by the wind spirit.
And I don't mention his ironworks.
Or art metalwork as he says.
The truth is that he loses himself.
Don't worry. This is Laurent in a nutshell.
Family dinners you know.
And after all it's only...
nine o'clock.
Please don't reproach me
again about Milos' slipshod shirt.
Or I will tell you again that I don't
want anyone to go through my jewels.
Walerian!
I already told you to stop nosing in Elsa's jewels.
You know very well how she hates that.
John...
To the chapel.
You don't take off your clothes?
What's the matter with you?
How can you say that?
What I like with you is your worriness.
I should worry about what?
It's what I say.
You never see anything.
You're self-satisfied.
You're at ease here like...
you were at your aunt's
in Villers-Cotteret.
And in ten minutes you will
snooze like a locomotive.
And Laurent? You don't find
his absence a bit odd?
He wrote you.
He invited you here, didn't he?
Nobody said he wasn't here.
-He's probably in Aix.
-In Aix? It's nonsense.
Did you get a good
look at them at least?
You're incredible. He's still
his son and her brother.
I was wrong to take you to that
Terence Fisher retrospective!
You're an hopeless romantic...
a dark romantic girl.
Which makes it worse for you.
Turn off the light.
It's a strange room.
I'll never be able to sleep.
Ungrateful high-class girl!
You're lodged in a modern art
museum and you still complain.
Smart guy.
If you cough tomorrow
don't count on me...
What now?
What's happening?
Helene?
It's ridiculous.
Come back.
Helene.
Leave me alone!
Oh shit!
What have you done with that lovely girlfriend of yours?
She's not feeling very well this morning.
She wants to sleep a bit longer.
Or maybe it's our oil cooking that
didn't sit well with her?
We're leaving.
-Already?
-We must be at Antibes before 3 PM.
You're not going to leave without
seeing Laurent first?
You like my sister?
Sadic, sadic! It's you
the sadic of the garrigue.
Take the girl with you and
bring back some tea.
You're a nice boy. It must
put you in a bad spot sometimes.
I already told you a hundred times
not to leave the newspaper within her sight.
She already has bad role models with us.
Oh la la, that boring sadic of
the year story again!
And those endless articles written by Benedetti. The
poor guy must drown himself in his own words.
It's still funnier than the
sum-up of the church celebration.
You can't go like this?
What would Laurent think of you?
Daddy, tell them to stay.
Laureeeennt!
-I'm coming.
Hey Laurent!
You were here? I was taking my time.
I didn't mean to make you wait.
You're all alone?
Helene is here, isn't she? Where is
she? You're hiding her from me.
Helene, Helene?
-In the chapel.
His mad dog number.
Sit down and have some tea. So our oil
cooking does not agree with you?
-You're going to Aix this morning?
-I will be back for lunch.
You can give an envelope to Milos?
Be reassured, it's precisely to disengage him.
I had completely forgotten our party tonight.
Even if all things considered Milos
won't look so odd amongst our guests.
Your friend Bezin will
probably bring his whore.
-Bring the envelope to the office.
-Again!
I already spent my life bringing your messages to
the gas station. I prefer leaving the message there
while getting some gas. Between you and
your friends my tank is always full.
My dear father, he has to be
taken like he is.
I tease him, he fiddles with me but in the end we
always agree. Drink your tea, it's going to be cold.
You knew this spot? No you didn't.
Nobody knows it fortunately.
Sun and loneliness. They will soon
become very rare in this damn country.
You know I was raised
here almost entirely.
When I was a child running
with shepherds in the garrigue.
My tomboy side.
Even now I often roll
myself in the thyme fields.
You don't believe me, do you?
It's my Garbo side deceiving you.
I'm a simple and healthy girl.
I think we could understand
very well each other.
So...I was talking about my
healthy and sportive side.
You're a sportsman too, aren't you?
Wait a minute, let me guess.
Football?
Basketball?
Swimming maybe?
Nothing. I used to run a little in college.
You still have some good rests.
I'm sure you could be
my Vanquished Paganism.
One of the central figures of my
big project for the Malemort Chapel.
It's a bit ridiculous to ask a
painter to be a model, don't you think?
You'll see, it won't be too exhausting.
My workroom is very cool.
I paint almost naked.
Then I said to Jacques. "Listen old pal
Helene is something else compared to Françoise.
She won't be so easy to live with."
You know what Jacques said?
But...what are you thinking about?
You look like a lady patroness this morning.
Is it because of my family?
You're so open-minded usually.
Come on, I don't believe in
your morning nausea.
-Laurent?
-What?
I don't know. Sorry.
-I don't know how to say it.
-Say it!
You here...
It's not my business in the end.
-You don't want to come with us?
-What are you driving at?
Nothing.
I think you're pale.
"Atmoshère, atmosphère"
One never knows when you're
serious or you're bullshitting.
Look how under-fed I am.
A real martyr.
But say...
it's you who don't look so well.
What's wrong with you?
-You look afraid.
-Don't be stupid.
So stop your false manners.
Come. They must worry about us.
Look! I bring you a very sick girl!
-So we stay?
-We stay.
Wait for me.
Not there!
Why?
There's a corpse.
In shreds. It's horrible.
Oh yes, the sadic.
Here.
Go on. I'm staying here.
There's no-one.
We stay or what?
We stay.
We stay but you stop snooping
around Laurent like Sherlock Holmes.
I'm telling you. Either you're
crazy or he made a joke at your expense.
Or maybe both.
-That's rude of you.
And you didn't see him like I did.
Yes, I know.
Chained and imploring,
Mutilated and bleeding
-Let me laugh.
-Laugh then.
We stay but give me a break
with your imagination.
Sorry, you came at the wrong time my sweet friends.
My father receives the country gentry once a year
and it just falls tonight. The tuxedo is okay?
This year the evening dress
is beating all the length records.
The train must be worn behind,
in front and on all sides.
Walk barefoot.
You're looking like the queen Ravanalona.
And if you put some bistre
even Mrs Lug will be
jealous of your exotic beauty.
Robert! Robert! I was looking
for you everywhere!
It's wonderful! Extraordinary!
You always amaze us!
Did I introduce you to our poet?
Jean-Loup. Robert Lorrain.
He's a Marquis. You don't
see that in Paris.
I introduce you to Mr and Mrs Lug.
-The bearded man is very attractive.
-Beware he's an ogre. The local Gilles de Rais.
-He's coming to invite me.
-Refuse, refuse!
-So you stopped the singing lessons?
-Who's the dark handsome man?
-You don't know?
-Helene...
Don't turn your back. Look there.
The Bezin woman is behind you.
-He's talented? -Well you know,
lyrical abstraction but ten years late.
Good evening Mr canon.
-May I? -Good evening, you're
beautiful. -Please.
This is Jacques and Helene. The Popelin
canon. A great  admirer of my painting.
Good evening Miss.
So...
dear Mr Benedetti
is this sadic
still running?
-Your magus looks great. Krishna-Murti,
the Beatles...And he crushed my hand.
Who's the dark handsome man?
One of Laurent's old flirts. The viscountess
Elfie de Liancourt now married to her cook.
She would be a nice woman if she did not
think of herself as the new Michel-Angelo.
Her painting isn't worth anything.
In the end and to talk
frankly it's just shit.
-You saw Laurent?
-No. And you?
Helene, you're really crazy.
So?
Nothing.
You see.
Lucien. Allow me
to introduce you to
Mr and Mrs Klerk. Walerian Kostros.
-Pleased to meet you.
Thank you.
-What do you think of our little party?
-It's superb.
Really?
-Elsa, did you see Elsa?
-So it's your turn to get suspicious.
Stay here. I'm going to take a look.
Milos my heart, don't
you have enough now?
Jacques?
-You're looking for someone Miss?
-Where's Laurent?
Mr Laurent left.
I saw Miss Elsa get inside her car.
Mr Marquis left with some friends.
And these friends
also hit the road. I'm afraid
there's nobody left Miss.
And Jacques? Where is Jacques?
Mr Jacques? He's not in his room?
He probably went for a walk.
It's such a beautiful night.
One wants to walk, don't you think?
Bastard!
May I?
I'm so sorry.
It was Walerian's idea you know.
Me I didn't agree
but your friend was so
receptive to the idea.
It must be said that Walerian
do a bit of alchemy.
Well, his own alchemy. By the way...
always hid your meds when he's around.
He's crazy about them.
You know, the other day he gobbed the dog's
suppositories. He ate them as if it they were candy.
But what was I saying? Oh yes,
yesterday evening Walerian told us...
"You're not going to end the evening
like this. It's so gloomy."
We searched for you everywhere
but we couldn't find you. We thought you left with
the Parturier to see their paintings collection.
Since Jacques was alone he accompanied us.
I have a cabin in the hills.
We get together there
between friends.
Walerian had promised us a surprise.
He had prepared an extraordinary mix
much more powerful than LSD.
It was terribly exciting
but no dangerous at all.
He took out his flask of sugar.
Me I didn't take anything.
I hate that stuff.
Then he asked for a voluntary.
Of course
he already had swallowed
some but without effect.
But of course nobody voluntereed.
So we balloted for a "voluntary".
And Jacques was the winner.
Just after that I felt
a terrible remorse.
A boy so kind and so simple.
At first it just makes the
effect of an aphrodisiac.
It's not that bad.
-You poisoned him? -No, don't worry. He
only vomited a lot when we brought him back.
I think that with some sleep,
a bath and some rest...
I was furious
but Walerian found the
situation very funny.
-What was so funny?
-Nothing.
But Jacques was speaking
and acting like crazy.
-What a nice picture!
-Not bad...
not bad at all.
Wait for me.
I think I know who's the culprit.
That's his signature.
Your tea is served my queen and may the honey of
the morning forecast the softness of your day.
You seem to be in a superb
condition this morning.
It's clear that you're the most reasonable person in this house.
-The only one who went to sleep early.
-And Jacques, he is where?
You can't say "he is where?".
You must say "where is he?".
But it's true, where is Jacques?
Helene? Jacques is still in bed?
Excess of the night my dear.
Our "Bonaparte" is not used to party.
Nothing serious by the way.
Isn't it Sir?
A small indigestion like the one
I had yesterday.
We're not used to your oil cooking.
To the same evil...
the same remedy. A cold bath.
John!
When you have some free time make
my sister say her lesson.
Did the sadic of the garrigue
strike again?
A tourist has disappeared. But it's the
dark handsome man of yesterday evening.
Hurry up. We're going now.
Get dressed. We run away.
Laurent isn't coming to take us?
Yeah right. Laurent comes and tomorrow
our picture will make the frontline.
Laurent will have to sort it
out himself. Me I'm leaving.
But Laurent can't...
Listen Jacko, you were right.
I'm stupid.
The Lorrain are very nice people,
they only want the best for us.
They hold Laurent prisoner. Fine.
Elsa is a complete nympho.
Her classification : the praying mantis.
You heard about them?
The climax, the knuckleduster and death.
The daddy is a darling.
He likes young people.
Some real sugar-daddy.
You tasted his sweets
yesterday, right?
Listen. They're all very nice.
I even begin to feel
comfortable here.
But if I don't want to become completely
crazy I have to flee right away.
Do you understand love of my life?
So Laurent...
You know Laurent...
John.
You have your rifle?
What happened?
A flat tire I guess.
You've got a flat?
Laurent is not with you?
So you were leaving?
It's a scandal!
What's wrong? Did daddy do
something naughty?
You're going to tell me everything.
Come on, Helene, Jacques, explain yourselves!
In the end I'd rather not know. It's probably
Laurent commiting some foolishness again.
Where is he by the way? Come on,
get inside, don't stay here.
Now you're my prisoners.
Hello? Number 5, Miss.
Garage Delgado?
Give me Mr Baille.
No, the elder.
Hello Mickey?
Elsa Lorrain. I'm fine.
You can come up?
I have friends here with
a Deux-Chevaux.
They have a flat.
What? Not ready yet? You're crazy
to dress like that for a walk in the sun.
-You wanted to leave?
-I packed our clothes.
-The room looked like we were
here for 6 months. -And why not?
Come on, get up, we're going
to swim.
-Go both of you. I don't feel well.
-What do you mean?
-I thought Jacques was not feeling well.
-He feels fine.
-Come on I tell you to go. -Just a quick
swim. I don't want to be in the sun at noon.
No regret then? So it's a boys date
and we'll have a drink at Julia's bar.
-Who's on the phone?
-It's Helene.
You want to speak to Mr Marquis?
Come in my dear.
We played at Ivan the terrible.
I hope it doesn't make
you uncomfortable.
No, it's rather interesting.
You probably want to talk
to me dear Helene.
-I wanted to talk to you
in private. -In private?
-I must confess that I'm a bit worried.
-Worried about what good heavens?
I'm sorry Sir but I m not joking.
And me when I'm playing I'm not joking.
You can talk now my dear.
-So I will speak.
-Good for you!
Be aware you who lay here that my
soul is anxious and my body in stress.
Really?
Really. My nights are filled with
ferocious dreams and fearful screams.
I see everywhere monsters on the
sly in the white shadows.
-Monsters?
-Monsters.
The clawed one who devours.
The smiling one who poisons.
-They hold a prince charming
in their grip. -Charming?
Charming.
Each night they put him in chains.
Why?
-He suffers and I love him.
-You love him.
I love him. I don't
care about the monsters.
If need be I will tame them and go
in their lair to see the prince again.
-If necessary I'll offer myself to the dragon to save him.
-Nobody asks this from you.
Right but something pushed me to do this.
-And what is it beautiful fanatic?
-I don't know.
I'd like to pierce the darkness
and light the fire
in the darkness of the souls.
-Swell!
Oh, you tried to kiss me!
I'm the eternal temptress.
The woman. I'm yours
against your secret.
I will display on you
all my perverse weapons.
Let's stop the play a moment.
What do you want exactly?
Nothing.
I was just playing.
-I was wrong?
-No...
but you must warn me when the
play becomes very serious.
I know the mystery
of the dark temples.
Is that so?
The temple of the forbidden scents.
The temple of inhuman passion.
The temple of sacrifices.
-Of sacrifices?
-You know him too.
-Me?
Didn't the oracle of the day
acknowledge the last sacrifice?
The oracle made a blunder.
Can you shed some light on me, you
who know this mystery's deepest arcanes?
Listen.
O you who come dressed with
white linen and ingenuous probity.
Listen to my word.
The prince is no prisonner
of the infernal forces.
The prince is free.
Only a spell gives you the impression
that he's chained to the monster. He's pure.
And he's yours if you want him.
But will you be strong enough to lead him out
of the bloody places where he's prowling?
I'll be strong.
Take his hand and leave.
-Really?
Yes. I give you my blessing.
What's wrong with you my dear
Helene? You seem really excited.
-I'm happy.
-For what reason?
Because of your blessing.
I stop playing.
You're really lovely Helene.
I mean it.
So you love Laurent?
It's not so astonishing.
But will Laurent love you?
I'm afraid not.
I'm going to be frank with you.
Laurent makes me worry.
Laurent is not simple.
Laurent is hiding everything from us.
I fear the worst.
I know what you think.
What's bred in the bone will
come out in the flesh.
But you're mistaken dear Helene.
Laurent is not of our kin.
Laurent doesn't play.
There's a certain
darkness inside of him.
Don't laugh. In the end
I'm happy to see
you interested in him.
I'd like to make a pact with you.
A pact to save his soul.
It's a good thing that Laurent is
interested in a girl like you.
You must admit that I'm not
the most conventional father but yet
for once
I'd like to speak like father
Duval but in reverse.
Since all is in reverse in this house.
Take my son
and transform it to your
exquisite image.
You believe me, don't you?
He needs a kind person like you.
We're not kind people.
You're curious my dear
and I like that.
You must find me a bit strange,
odd,
peculiar as people say.
This is beautiful.
-What is it?
-One of my magical sculptures.
Did you notice that bottle
containing nun's blood?
And hee is the denture
of Count Hugo d'Alesy.
Would you be tempted
by a more advanced experiment?
The thrill of the kill.
Only words dear Helene.
You talk like a girl of your time.
For you thought is limitless.
But I'm getting old.
I have principles.
You're not tempted?
A little boy by the moonlight?
His throat sliced up and down.
Go little girl.
Leave me in my silence.
I loathe these kind of vulgarities.
Knife stabbing,
scalped hair, and blood spurting out.
On your way out please
call back my "Opritchniki".
Thank you for everything Sir.
By the way...
I'm sorry to ask but...
where is Walerian?
After all...
it's his fault if
I had such an awful night.
-This laborious morning wake.
-Walerian?
I killed Walerian.
There was something rotten inside him.
I cannot tolerate anyone that
isn't pure around me.
Pure as the night.
Good day Mr Lorrain.
Only banquets and feasts are allowed
while the noble foreigners are amongst us.
Chamber music obligatory.
No formal dress.
A piece of mink will do.
That's for you old girl.
So?
-So what?
-"So what?"
So you didn't grilled him?
So you surely had a good swim.
And you surely had some
good time at the inn.
And you surely told him nothing
about your escapade last night.
In sum...
it was a delicious morning
for two well-behaved healthy boys.
Really very emotional.
Helene...
There're certain places where the horrible noises
of modern music should be prohibited.
They broke my ears.
I don't hate it. What's
your opinion Jacques?
It seemed that when you didn't
sleep your teeth were creaking.
The day you don't try to
humiliate me you'll be dead.
-Who made you listen to Boulez
for the first time? -It's true.
You're unfair Helene.
Jacques resisted all he could.
And he has some merit.
If that first violin was not
so good-looking
I think I would have left
after the first time.
Do you come for a last
drink at my place?
I think Jacques is falling asleep.
The poor boy. We give him
such a rough time.
-What's that noise?
-A bird or a beast...
Cover me, I'm cold.
The water was almost lukewarm.
Even the wind is hot.
And to say I damned myself for
forgetting my towel rail in Paris.
I didn't tell you but I had a
long talk with your father yesterday.
In the end you were right.
He's very funny, very nice.
Don't you think?
Yes, yes.
You should be happy.
-I wasn't scared by his museum
-So he gave you a visit?
Yes.
It's very funny.
Funny? You think it's funny?
Why did you scream yesterday night?
How could I not scream?
-I saw you.
-What?
I saw you yesterday night.
As I saw you that first night.
-What?
I'm sorry.
I should not have.
I was stupid.
I was afraid you know.
Forget it.
Let's not talk again.
How can I help you Miss?
Laurent...
Milos!
She's conscious now?
What is she mumbling about?
-I don't know.
Go and see in her car.
-In her car? -I tell you to go.
-It's the car of Mr Lorrain's son.
-There's no-one?
No-one.
Someone was accompanying you?
You were alone?
Someone with you?
What happened to him?
It's not Mr Laurent's
type to make jokes.
He was pretty bad
when I came in your bar.
That's the reason I stopped
in front of you.
He was shaky and delirious.
The sun probably.
-You know them well the Lorrain?
-A little.
I don't know how to say this.
Don't you find them...peculiar?
Peculiar? That's the
least you could say. Look.
I still bear her mark.
-It's you the other night...
-who was corrected by her. Yes.
It's one of her guilty pleasures.
-Pleasures?
You don't know her. She's
crazy. She knows how to concoct a plan.
And she doesn't like when it's fake.
But I'm not the kind of man you push like
that. So the other night she asked for me.
While she was having sex
with the other guy.
It gets her excited, you know.
That's the beautiful Elsa.
That rotten Lady.
But you?
You love her?
Maybe.
-And her?
-Oh, her...
She needs all the guys
and then she sacks them.
I'm not that kind.
So we had a brawl.
I saw that.
You saw?
I was there. Not on purpose.
You have some nerves!
-And the other?
-The other?
Your rival from the other night.
Is he dead?
He's much better now.
When you pass in front of
the antics shop sound your horn.
You will see him at the window.
The newspaper article, it was to
ridiculise Benedetti.
He's easily fooled.
You made us afraid.
You'll go up there again?
And to the gas station?
-You will go there again?
-It's still my job.
Don't you like being here?
And your husband?
Does he bother you?
Stay.
Stay with your nurse.
-I made a good job on you, right?
-And me?
You have a very special way
of revealing well-known people.
You reveal a lot about yourself at the same time.
Without a doubt.
It is characteristic of the artist,
isn't it? We always do a self-portrait.
Even painting a still life
or...
a muscle.
And Laurent?
You have terminated him?
It's rare to see you alone.
-You noticed that?
-It wasn't a nasty remark.
I know.
No, I didn't "terminate" him.
But maybe it's worse.
What do you mean?
I don't know.
-He's teribly sick.
-Sick?
And terribly lucid.
-In the car earlier he had a syncope.
-A syncope, you're sure?
Or a sunstroke.
Something like that.
-Laurent is solid as a rock.
My dear Helene let me tell you
that you're much too impressionable.
For instance...
You mustn't let people see
and hear your emotions by the moolight.
Jacques! The pose! You're terrible!
I'm sorry.
He's not as docile as that you know.
Beware! You moved again.
-It's Milos?
-You know him?
I've seen him here.
Yes, I remember.
Not bad.
Yes he's an handsome guy.
A complete moron but some deltoides...
You roughed him good.
-How do you know that?
-I saw him earlier at the Inn.
By chance.
-I hope so.
And then?
-Then nothing.
-Nothing?
It's hard to imagine from Milos.
I had no heart to it.
But he has the heart
to it all the time.
He's so sticky, so smoochy...
I don't know any attendant
more sentimental in the area.
There's a temptation of sublime...
and then...
lots of flesh..
in its most bestial aspect.
-If you say so...
And the suffering of others...
driving you.
Where does it come from?
Well, I mean...
Is it only in your imagination?
Or does it have its origin in reality?
It's not so simple my dear Helene.
-Helene has left?
-A minute ago.
Where are you?
I'm changing clothes.
Stay where you are.
-You have a nice touch.
-Don't say anything.
You don't give a damn about my touch
and you're right.
Show me your talent instead.
I love you.
But admit that you're a
little bit afraid.
Afraid? No. It's Helene who see
monsters everywhere. She's naive.
You, a monster? That's a joke.
You so beautiful and so sweet.
I would never have thought
that a man like me...
You hurted me.
Daddy, you'll be caught one of these days.
Walerian is the fifth one this year.
Well, at least now my rings
won't disappear anymore.
Unless one of your mechanic
is also a goldsmith.
Beside...
where is the handsome Milos?
We haven't seen him for a while.
I'm better, Helene.
I'm much better.
It's unbelievable. He has no
right over that. No right at all.
It's intolerable to be disturbed
during the diner. I'm coming John.
No Walerian! You won't come back here and
you won't take back these art pieces.
You know perfectly how much I
have given you to own them. Go away!
A name is a sacred thing.
Never forget it.
I was crazy and you abused me.
What did I look like? No!
You're not my faithful servant anymore.
Guard!
Throw him away!
-I'll tell everything.
-I guess it's already done.
You're a great cunt.
You don't amuse me anymore...
you and your pharmacian smell.
Just go.
And keep your injuries for better occasions.
They will not fail I guess.
Who's there?
It's you Milos?
It's Walerian.
What do you want?
-I'm working.
-I want to see you.
-Come back tomorrow.
-I have things to tell you.
-I already know them.
-Open.
Go away now dirty little fetus!
You will regret it.
Walerian. You know him.
One of daddy's damned soul.
I hate to be involved in
their sordid business.
You know the rumours about him?
His guilty pleasure is to drug the
poor guys drifting in the area and then...
And then?
Don't play the choirboy.
Laurent, your father is chasing me.
I'd like to see you.
Open. Remember how I helped you.
My small services.
-Where are you going?
-Somewhere else.
I forbid you!
Listen. I need a change.
I need to drive.
At this hour the Casanovas
like you are sleeping.
Silly boy.
I'm hurt.
Yeah, I heard.
-Where you going?
-Salon.
Jump behind.
Now get out.
-But Elsa...
-I told you to get out.
Get out. There's an Inn nearby. Go
there and get drunk if it can help you.
-Let me stay with you...-Sir could you please
oblige me and kick this man out of my car.
It's your car? What do you want me to do?
Dump him.
-Like that? On the edge of the road?
-Where you want.
Come on, come on...
You said you were going to...
Salon.
Salon or any other place.
Hey Julia, your bar looks like
the urgency ward.
-Accident?
-An alcohol please.
-So they dumped you too?
-I don't know you Mister.
Don't talk to me.
Don't take your high-class
tone with me duchess.
You saw the mash
she made out of your face?
Between renegades...
we can still have a talk. -Leave me
alone. I don't need your support.
Can I sleep here tonight?
-Yes, of course.
So it's more serious than I thought.
-Much more serious.
-I told you to stay away from me.
Is it Laurent scaring you?
-Laurent...why Laurent?
-Maybe you're jealous.
Maybe boys are still
jealous in Paris.
Jealous for what reason?
You don't know?
Your girlfriend and Laurent...
I didn't fly yet. We just
finished training.
Can I go and play now?
It's not funny this morning.
Here are our two love birds.
Don't you think they make
a nice couple Elsa?
You must be very discret you and Jacques.
You will pack and leave.
Leave us and forget.
You can't help me.
Go.
Sorry.
I will pay you later.
-Thank you for your kindness.
-Please. This is quite normal.
Beware the sun. It's strong at this hour.
Who's this guy?
-Nothing.
A guest at the Marquis.
Calm down, it's not the sadic.
You can never know.
With his ugly mug...
he fits well in the crowd up there.
Where are you going Helene?
You're not staying with us?
We will loot every house in town!
Burn everything!
Rape women and children!
Behead the bodied men!
Skin the old ones!
Me I'm going to rest
in the royal tent.
So it was you!  Well you've got
your car now. Why didn't you leave?
-What does it mean?
-Stupid fool!
-You're crazy! You became crazy!
-Yes.
And you think I'll let you quiet and easy?
That I will let you
play with your "toys"?
Give me this. I'll bring
it to the police.
They'll be interested. You heard about the sadic of the garrigue, right?
You don't know what you say.
You don't know what you do.
I know both very well.
You don't know nothing.
I know enough to catch the
cops attention.
-You won't do it.
-It won't embarass me.
You will do nothing.
Prince Jacques, what a surprise. You're looking
for Elsa? She's napping. Come play with us.
You're looking for Prince Jacques?
He's my prisoner.
-John.
-Miss?
The adress book please?
It's here Miss.
No, give it to me.
I can find alone.
Number 15 in Sannes please.
What a surprise.
Yes.
Something to put someone to sleep.
You're insomniac?
For Jacques.
Alright I'll keep it for myself.
You're quite deceptive with your
wise little girl looks.
Strong?
Powerful? Not lethal at least?
Yes I'm coming.
Don't mention it.
The pleasure is mine.
We swim into anarchy.
Can you tell me Sir what my daughter is doing
now? I guess you don' know about the rest.
Miss Elsa is resting I think. She told me to go to diner
alone and I said I was embarassed to do that...
It's unbelievable! If it keeps on like
this I will have my meals in my office!
Nice family life, don't you think?
Sir will have another
plate of cold soup?
It's not anarchy anymore. It's
a complete organized mess!
John didn't even put the kid to sleep!
That's unheard of!
Interesting...
Sir! Sir!
I'm terribly sorry.
I had such a busy day.
-The groceries, the washing, I didn't think
the little Miss...-It doesn't matter.
Can you keep her for the night?
I need her bedroom.
Of course Sir.
She'll be there like in her room.
There's somebody at your place?
Who could be there?
See you tomorrow at noon.
No. Don't say anything.
I call to our past friendship.
To a tradition of hospitality that you
prided yourself on yesterday evening.
I admit that this art pieces business
was ridiculous.
But admit yourself that your
reproachs were hypocrital.
Come on, Bob...
Admit that you get bored without me.
Same is true for me.
That's where you're wrong my sweet Walerian. We've
no time to get bored anymore in this house.
I found something unbelievable and you know
where of all places ? In the kid's room.
I found a sublime stigma on Jacques body.
You remember the leopard-men in Congo?
You remember these splendid
claws they used?
-Don't you read the newspapers?
-You had better reading tastes in the past.
I had guessed from reading Benedetti's
wordy articles that the sadic
used a special tool. And it
striked me when I saw Jacques body.
-You mean that...
-The sadic is amongst us my dear.
He's here. Isn't it wondeful?
You're not suspecting me at least?
-What's that noise?
-You repeat yourself.
I'm telling you there's nobody.
You're afraid?
Tell me...
-You're afraid?
-You're kidding me?
I was left alone in the dining room.
What shall I do?
I'd like to go home unless you
let me sleep here another night.
-I don't like him.
-Beat him up.
-You're too excited, Bob.
-Admit that I have my reasons!
They come out of the woods
at the meridian hour, noon or midnight.
Dressed with animal skins
and their face covered by hoods.
They wear at their fingers artificials
nails made of horn or iron
which they use to shred their preys.
It's almost midnight.
And the moon is full.
If you're right your sadic
will make some delicatessen soon.
Maybe he'll finish what
he started on Jacques.
-Poor Jacques.
-What are we doing now?
-We wait. -What do we wait?
-Midnight -And then?
Listen.
Sleep little bitch!
Where are you going?
Another victim of your sadic?
-Please, don't ask me again who he is.
-I know him. It's Elsa's last find.
Here we are. No need to search for marks
on his body. You're sure to find them.
Your daughter has good taste.
He's good looking this victim of love.
Tell me by the way...
-Jacques and Elsa? -Yes he was at her
side in the dining room yesterday evening.
Don't search further.
You saw your daughter's nails?
-I swear they're as tough as
the lepoard-men's. -You hate her.
Not as much as you think. And don't
make me say what I didn't say.
Look. It's right in front of you.
You panic for nothing.
-You have to much imagination and you don't see
the evidence. -You always try to belittle my family.
You know how I appreciate Laurent.
Don't make me believe you don't
have an agenda of your own?
Come on, between us...
I like you Walerian but why turning into
a vaudeville a story which could be wonderful?
You're unfair Bob.
Very unfair.
To prove you wrong
we're going to scheme
something much more delicious
than a sordid news item.
Look...
Wait, wait...I'm going to
wear my big chasuble.
Again? You're too nervous big guy!
You can't throw me away
each time a bird lands on the roof.
A bird...It's a man.
I tell you I don't expect anyone.
You can't see through the
dark. Light the lamp.
No need for a lamp.
The moonlight is gorgeous.
Look carefully.
-I'm looking.
-Nothing?
Nothing.
You're sure?
Sure. There's only the other guy.
The little flying-man.
-He didn't leave.
No. He seems to sleep.
Maybe you killed him.
That's bullshit.
Why not?
You're so strong.
Hello Helene. You're happy?
-I'm happy.
-Jacques is not with you?
He left last night.
-You stay?
-I'd like to.
So we'll see each other again.
Without a doubt.
It's good to take a little walk at dawn.
I'm sorry but I have to take this
soldier back to his barrack.
I'm delighted to be able to help you.
-See you soon.
-Good day Helene.
-Miss, your lessons!
-Not on a marriage day.
They're wonderful.
-It's the word.
-Mr Lorrain, what a splendid marriage.
We'll have superb photos.
It'll help me to fill my Sunday column.
That and the calcined car
accident at the Pernes gulch.
ty
rarelust