Hard to describe that feeling,
it makes you feel so at ease.
By the way, do you know
a Western restaurant called "Little Puppet"?
"Little Puppet" refers to a traditional
toy from the Tohoku region in Japan.
Y記
Even though it has "Little Puppet" in its name
the restaurant doesn't
have any puppets displayed.
Their omelette rice is especially delicious.
Hey, are you even listening?
You spaced out!
I'm starting. Forgot about it.
Oh, by the way...
Recently, I watched a DVD called
"Blade Runner." Have you heard of it?
Oh, the one you mentioned before.
Oh, did I mention it?
You did,
you did.
Yes, yes.
Did you watch it?
I did.
It's a sci-fi film from 20 years ago.
I'm not really into sci-fi movies.
It's different.
You have to consider it was made 20 years ago.
Let's go watch it together next time.
Watch it twice.
Watch it as many times as you want,
it's still not enough.
Really?
"Blade Runner," huh?
I'm not great at borrowing DVDs myself.
Long time no see. Happy birthday!
Oh, by the way,
I'm getting married.
What?
Marriage?
You're getting married?
Yeah, next year,
I'm planning to get married.
Who is with whom?
I am with my girlfriend.
Who?
Who is your girlfriend?
It's the one from
the Sales Department, Murata.
Do you want to come to
my place tonight for some activity?
Next,
What should we do?
We are still open.
Welcome, please come in.
The boss is quite troubled.
It's a common thing.
Without setting proper prices, it won't work.
This time, we got some good books in.
I'm constantly annoyed,
and the troubles keep coming.
By the way, we also got the books
Mr. Sabu requested. Take a look.
Found it!
Thank you so much.
But, if Mr. Sabu buys too many books,
won't his wife get angry?
No problem. She lost one before,
so now it's fine even if i buys a lot.
So, how many bookmarks do you want?
I'll take five.
Five bookmarks,
here you go.
I still want to make pork cutlet curry.
If you have spare time,
can you teach me?
You really say things like Li.
-Really?
-Yes.
Why does it break again?
We just fixed it a few days ago.
It's not working.
Now it's completely broken.
Mr. Takeuchi, sorry to bother you,
but can you take a look at it? -No, no need.
Sorry, let me move aside.
Mr. Takeuchi is good at repairing machines.
Hello, Mom.
Takako.
Yes?
Are you okay?
Yes.
You finally got into a company after so much effort.
This can't go on like this.
Yes, I know.
Hello, this is Morisaki Bookstore.
Satoru?
Oh, it's my sister.
Long time no see.
How have you been?
Me? I'm doing well.
Why did you suddenly call?
Playing back the message.
Takako, are you okay?
It's me, Uncle Satoru.
I'm at the bookstore.
Remember to call me back.
A customer has come in.
So, bye for now.
Satoru.
Satoru?
Satoru..
Hello, this is Morisaki Bookstore.
Is this Uncle Satoru?
It's Takako.
Oh, long time no see.
Are you doing okay?
Yes, I'm fine.
Really? I knew you came to Tokyo a while ago.
Why didn't you come to see me?
I'm sorry, I've been busy with work.
But you quit your job, right?
I've been thinking about it.
If you don't want to find a job right away,
why not come over to my place?
Huh?
Water and electricity bills
can be quite a burden, right?
If you come here, it's all free.
Of course, if you can help out at the store,
it would be a huge favor for me.
You suddenly say this...
You see, right now, I'm the only one taking
care of the store, and my back isn't in great shape.
When I go to the hospital,
it would be great to have someone look after the store.
There's a room on the second floor of
the store with a bathroom and shower.
You can use it freely.
Outside of business hours,
I go back to my nearby home. How about it?
What do you mean, how about it?
You're asking me to come...
Satoru.
Here's a map of
the area around Morisaki Bookstore.
Here, take it.
Not bad, huh?
Let's see what it says.
- Ah, so it's a map.
- Oh, I see.
Shoes, stairs, one's own home, fireworks, keys, table,
textbooks, treasure chest,
and then it's red envelopes.
A treasure map, huh?
Exactly.
Seems quite interesting.
Really? Good luck with your search.
Takako.
Long time no see.
It's been about eight years, right?
That long?
You've grown up.
Is that so?
Yes.
come in.
Alright.
Come in quickly.
Sorry.
No worries.
There's a musty smell.
Like the morning after rain.
I like this dampness.
Excuse me.
How many books are here?
Um... about five... six thousand, I think.
Six thousand?
That's a lot.
That's actually not much.
My shop is small.
Takako, why don't you go upstairs?
Alright.
Put your luggage up there.
Thank you.
Don't mention it, please.
What's going on here?
I twisted my back three days ago.
Don't worry;
I've already cleaned up most of it.
Really?
Takako sorry for the trouble.
Just move some books and you can stay.
Move some books?
Where to?
There's always a way.
What do you mean by "always"?
Let's get to work.
Oh no!
Welcome.
Thank you for your patronage.
welcome.
Where's Mr. Satoru?
On another note, who are you?
Are you working here?
But this place can't afford to hire anyone.
No, I mean, I work...
Uncle will be back at 1 o'clock in the afternoon.
Seriously, Mr. Satoru is unexpectedly
adorable with such a lovely niece.
Today, I want to read some
Shiga Nagoya after a long time.
The ones I bought before were
misplaced by my wife.
Is that so?
Which of Shiga Nagoya's
works do you like?
I haven't read any.
You don't read books?
It's not like I don't read at all.
Then why don't you read?
I'm sorry.
Let me tell you, if you continue like this,
you'll only see the surface of the world.
If you don't want to be shallow,
read some of these wonderful books here.
Alright.
I must say, Shiga Naoya..
Yes?
He wrote many excellent novels
during the Taisho and Showa eras.
They didn't mention that in the textbooks, did they?
Naoya Shiga?
He was a member of a literary school
called the "White Birch School"...
Good morning.
It's Uncle.
Takako, you look quite relaxed there.
I'm just sitting here, that's all.
Is everything going smoothly?
Yes.
Mostly fine, e
xcept that a talkative old man came by.
Ah, Mr. Sabu,
a regular customer for 20 years.
What did he talk to you about?
It was related to Shiga Naoya.
Really? He genuinely loves
Japan's literary giants.
But he talks too much,
and sometimes, it gets annoying.
Oh, by the way, pour him some tea,
nod a few times, and he'll leave on his own.
Mmm... Mmm.
Alright, let's change shifts.
You've worked hard.
It's no problem.
Uncle, I wanted to tell you...
Yes?
Is the store doing okay? There are no
Visitors at all, and people only buy cheap books.
Nowadays, old books don't sell well.
Did they sell well before?
In my father's generation,
there was a market for old books.
During that time, publishing companies
weren't as active, and there was no television to watch.
But nowadays, I also sell books online. Occasionally,
I sell some rare books for tens of thousands of dollars.
Yes, there are books that
cost tens of thousands of yuan.
Yes, don't you like to
visit secondhand bookstores?
Don't you visit secondhand bookstores?
Not really.
I go to BookOff sometimes; they have manga there.
(BookOff is a large chain of secondhand bookstores in Japan.)
I see, I get it now.
But, you see,
many people love the old books here.
There is a lack of affection for old books
But, you see, many people
love the old books here.
Even adults like you, Takako.
Feel free to pick any book you like from here.
Alright.
People who know about these things understand,
but there are also many who don't.
In that case...
Takako, , I brought some snacks.
Would you like some?
I'm coming up.
Takako, are you up?
I'm sleeping.
People who are asleep don't answer, you know.
I want to go somewhere now.
Do you want to come with me?
Huh?
I won't do anything bad, okay?
Let's go then.
This place...
Smells so good.
Good evening, sorry to disturb you.
Hello, welcome.
boss.
Let me introduce you.
This is my niece, Takako.
Good evening.
Please have a seat.
This shop is really good
This shop has been owned
by the boss for about 30 years.
Really?
Good evening, Mr. Morisaki.
This is my niece, Takako.
Good evening.
Tomoko is also a regular visitor at our shop.
She's the type who looks but doesn't buy.
That's not true.
Please give me a mixed coffee.
Sure.
I'll have the same.
Boss, where's Tanako?
Tanako?
Takano, this is my niece, Takako.
Good evening.
By the way, Tanako, you should
go out with Takako next time.
Uncle, what are you talking about?
When you go back to college, you might visit as a working adult, and the feeling may be different...
Why do you say that? Because I'm also growing up, and though I look forward to it, I feel a bit anxious too.
Let me ask you, Uncle.
Yes?
What was Uncle doing when he was my age?
Me? I was always reading books and traveling.
Traveling?
Yes
backpacked through many countries.
Thailand, Laos, India, Nepal, I even went around
Europe while working and saving money.
I have no idea.
It's quite surprising, isn't it?
Yes.
But is it reasonable?
Why do you keep traveling?
What do you mean?
I want to use my own
eyes to see different worlds,
and also to explore my own possibilities.
Possibilities?
It's a time when you stop imitating others
and start searching for your own direction in life.
Impressive.
Is it?
But I often make my dad angry.
I ask him, "Have you found anything on your journey?"
You can say I found something,
or maybe, probably, possibly, I haven't found anything.
What kind of words are those?
During my journey, my dad fell ill and
passed away. Then, I inherited the family shop.
Is that so?
Do you have any regrets?
No, I feel like I'm most
suited for this profession.
That's great.
Hmm?
Living life the way you like.
It's not exactly like that.
Even now, it's full of worries.
Your mixed coffee.
Alright,
thank you.
I'm starting.
It tastes good.
The boss's coffee is truly unique.
Special service, please.
Can I do it?
No problem.
Thank you.
Takako, is it your first time here today?
Yes, I haven't visited until now.
That's good.
Please enjoy your life in Jimbocho.
What's wrong?
Uncle said the same thing to you.
Of course,
no one loves this place more than he does.
Although he has experienced
so much, he has never left.
Ah.
What's wrong?
I feel like I'm wasting time.
Huh?
I haven't done anything recently.
That's not true.
You need some rest now.
The boat you sailed is
anchored on this street now.
Take your time to rest and
then set sail again, isn't that good?
Hmm.
But Uncle also complains
about me sleeping too much.
Alright, let's stop talking about it. Let's go.
Takako, are you coming?
Let's go.
Dream Memory, Kazuo Oizumi.
No matter what appears before our eyes, a part or all of our souls will be infused into it.
This quote is from "A Scene in the Heart" by Motojiro Kajii.
This is the first time I've seen this book.
I never knew this city had such a place.
There are over 170 bookstores here alone.
The world's number one old book street.
Number one in the world?
Yes, there are really many bookstores.
Each store has its own unique charm,
and they are all different and colorful.
It's wonderful.
Uncle, can I borrow this book for a moment?
Oh that's fine
Oh, okay then.
I'm heading out now.
Hello.
Are you on the morning shift today?
No, I have classes today.
I only come when I have free time.
I see.
If you don't mind...
thanks.
What's your major?
Japanese literature.
Wow, that's impressive.
why?
Because I still don't understand
anything about literature.
Are you in college?
No, I've already graduated.
I studied design and worked
at a design company, but I quit now.
Oh, but design is great,
and many people admire it.
Why?
Because I really don't understand it at all.
Occasionally, I'll look at some
paintings and think they're nice,
but I have no professional knowledge in this area.
We were just thinking the same thing.
Really?
May I take your order?
Oh right, I'll have the same as well.
Good morning.
Hello.
Sorry, I'll be back again.
That's fine.
This is delicious.
Right?
This is super delicious.
Oh, by the way,
Takano came to our shop earlier.
Is Takano also interested in books?
It seems like he wasn't looking for books.
Do you talk to him when he's at the shop?
We both have work to do,
and we don't see each other during breaks.
Oh, right, the date.
A date?
Yeah, didn't Mr. Satoru mention it before?
I see, he's obedient, isn't he?
Doesn't he look obedient?
Good morning.
Hello.
Sorry.
Um...
Excuse me.
Oh, by the way...
Do you often come here, Aihara?
Huh?
Aihara, the one you mentioned earlier, Tomoko?
Yes.
Well, she comes here often,
for various reasons.
What do you talk to her about?
Huh?
Does she have a boyfriend?
I don't know, she never mentioned it.
Can you ask her casually next time?
Huh, why don't you ask her yourself?
If you could help me with this, and besides
I've never initiated
a conversation with a girl before.
If you can help me with this
I'll treat you to coffee at the shop every time.
Really?
Then I'll go every day.
Going every day might be a bit...
Deal's done.
No, still...
What should I do?
Thank you for your help.
But please never tell her about it
I see
Thank you for your help.
Hello.
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
This is the book you ordered.
Thank you so much.
Can I have three bookmarks, please?
Bookmarks?
Wait, over there, in the second drawer.
Found them.
Here are three, choose.
This one, this one, and this one.
Thank you for visiting.
Bidding in progress,
coming right back, shopkeeper.
Excuse me.
Is it heavy?
Are you okay?
uncle..
What's with the books placed here?
Um, those are books we received
but couldn't set a price for yet,
so they're just there for now.
It seems like an interesting book.
that book?
Hmm.
Really? I see.
Then you decide the price of this book.
Huh?
After you read it, set the price.
But, is that allowed?
It's allowed.
Then, excuse me. Let me through.
Most shop owners will participate, right?
Yes, bookstores are all
taking part enthusiastically.
can't imagine it.
It's truly incredible.
What's that?
I've only started reading old books recently.
I used to have no interest in them,
but now I can't stop.
What's wrong with that?
Any place can be the starting point of one's life.
That's true.
The Kanda Used Book Fair.
Here it is!
Hello, Mr. Satoru.
Hello.
It was tough to find you.
This is my wife.
Oh, it's Madam.
This is Takako.
- Nice to meet you.
Sales are going well, aren't they?
Mr. Sabu you've gone crazy buying books again.
Yes, if I keep buying like this,
my house will be filled with books.
If you don't mind, can we collect
all the books from our house?
Leave me alone. It's terrifying.
Don't you often lose something?
Your way of walking is strange.
Sorry, I forgot how to walk.
There are many books over there too. Let's go.
What did you say?
Participating in the used book fair makes
you feel like Jimbocho is just like a book.
Like a book?
On the surface, it seems calm, but when
you open a book, you find a noisy world inside.
After finishing reading and closing the book,
it returns to tranquility.
I, I like this street.
You do?
Yes.
Takako, feel free to come whenever you want.
Why are you so kind to me?
Didn't I tell you before?
We haven't met many times,
Because I like Takako
and to you, I might just be an unfamiliar uncle.
it's different.
You are my angel.
Angel?
Yes,
You are the book god.
Book god? Have I done something?
When you were born...
Didn't I tell you about the trip before?
I traveled to many countries,
and it was because of you.
How could that be?
After graduating from university,
I worked at a publishing house,
But it didn't go well.
I quit after the third year.
The things I wanted to do
didn't seem to work in society.
I wasn't suitable for commercial books.
I couldn't handle it.
After resigning, I couldn't find anything to do,
and it felt like everything was collapsing.
Are you okay?
I was also confused. I wondered if
I didn't have a place in this world.
Just live in depression.
like being trapped in a cocoon.
At that time, Meihui gave birth to you
When I saw you for the first time,
I almost cried for some reason.
Seeing your tiny body wrapped in
a blanket, sleeping so soundly,
I felt like I should try harder.
Although I'm not confident now,
I believe that one day
I'll find a place where I truly belong.
I want to work towards that goal.
Starting to travel, starting to read books,
all of these have influenced me.
So, have you found your place?
I have found it now?
Although it took a long time to find it.
Is it here?
right here
After setting off into the world,
I ended up back where I grew up.
It's funny, isn't it?
But at that moment, I finally understood
Place is not a problem,
What mattered most was my state of mind.
Good night.
Seriously, you can come here anytime.
Thank you.
Boss,
I wonder why
people continue living while
searching for what they have lost.
While reading, I recalled past events.
Like about Takako.
Yeah.
The things about Momoko
and when the store just opened.
It's so nostalgic.
If I had tried to keep Momoko,
would she have stayed?
Only the heavens know.
Yeah.
Where are you going?
I'm going to Hama-daima.
Hama-daima... Where is that?
-We're done. Thanks for your hard work.
-Okay, thank you.
Good morning Takako.
It's getting colder and colder, isn't it? But if it keeps getting colder, it will eventually become warm.
I feel like I didn't get enough sleep.
Really? Well, that means you
must be leading a leisurely life.
What happened?
Did something happen?
Hmm?
I have this feeling that you...
Encountered someone unpleasant, is that it?
Takako
Before you came here,
what happened exactly?
Uncle, how much do you know?
I know nothing,
except that you resigned from your job.
It's better to talk about
your feelings if you're in pain.
What happened?
Want to sit? Sit?
Come on, have a seat. What's wrong?
Be a good boy. What's wrong?
A senior colleague from
the same company told me he's getting married.
Not with me.
No, I've been dating him for a year and a half.
So that's how it is.
Yes
So
I slept for a long time.
Slept for a long time
I woke up thinking,
"Can I pretend it didn't happen?"
But I can't.
Okay,
be a good girl and ask that guy to apologize.
Really?
Ask him to apologize in person.
Say sorry for hurting you.
No need.
It's just that I'm so foolish
that I wanted someone to talk to.
Takako, aren't you unwilling to accept this?"
Of course, I'm really unwilling. But...
Unless you don't talk to him honestly,
you'll be burden by the past forever.
Come on, let's go.
Okay, I got it.
What...
I'm Takako's uncle, Morisaki Satoru.
Hmm.
what's the matter?
Are we looking like newspaper peddlers to you?
what?
We came here because
you did something really unforgivable to her.
Can't you feel anything at all?
what?
She's been so upset that she even quit her job.
She's been depressed ever since.
Don't you have any emotions?
You hurt her deeply.
Are you heartless?
Wait, wait.
Did she say I hurt her?
Yes, that's right.
I don't know where you came from, uncle.
Why do you believe what this woman says?
What benefit does she gain from lying?
Because of you, she quit her job
and is now in great pain.
She quit on her own accord.
Takako this guy is out of line.
Why should I listen to you say such things?
What's going on?
What happened?
Suddenly, he came here to insult me.
I'm saying,
what are you trying to do?
Speak up,
Takako.
I don't know what you're thinking.
I used to like you.
I'm not an object,
I'm a person, I also have feelings.
I also think, and when things happen...
I used to be in great pain.
I told you, she has poured her heart out.
You should respond as well.
If you don't want me to call the police, go back.
Let's go back.
Okay, fine.
Sorry.
It's okay.
That was the first time
I honestly expressed my feelings.
It feels like a weight has been lifted.
uncle
Have you made a decision?
Yes.
Then, put it on the third shelf over there.
Huh?
It's okay. I just felt relieved, that's all.
Hmm.
What's wrong?
It's nothing.
uncle.
Hmm?
I'm leaving this place.
Why?
To find a job and leave this place.
Leave this place?
Yes.
Really?
It's a big decision.
It seems so sudden.
It's not sudden.
I've been considering it for a while now.
I finally made up my mind.
I see.
That's how it is.
But I will stay a little longer
until I can stand on my own.
Really? Then you have to work hard.
I know. I'll do my best.
Alright, I understand.
Yes.
Thank you for visiting.
I'll feel very lonely.
It's not easy to find a job.
I'll still be here for a while.
No need to move either.
But it's easy to become spoiled here.
I should learn to be independent.
But I really like this street.
It's a pity to leave.
I like this street too.
What do you like about it?
Every time I come here, I think
I used to be someone who could create value.
The owner of a bookstore once said that
instead of relying on buying
valuable things to gain value,
one should create value on their own.
That's what makes a person strong.
I want to become that kind of person.
Someone who creates value on their own.
Yes, but the future is uncertain.
Still, it's not bad.
The weather is really nice.
Yes, it is.
Do you want to go to the café?
Again?
Their drinks are delicious.
Then, you treat me.
Sure, why not? It's nice.
Wait a moment.
Movie Title: " Days of Morisaki Bookstore"