FACES OF CHILDREN
Saint-Luc,
a village in the Upper Valais.
The mayor's house.
On this spring morning, all those
not kept away by toil have come..
Because there is sorrow in the house.
The mayor, Pierre Amsler.
His son, Jean.
His daughter, Pierrette.
A neighbor.
The mother of the two children.
Where is Mama?
"She's away on a trip."
"She’s had a shock,
nothing life-threatening.
A few days’ rest and she’ll be
herself again."
Canon Taillier, the priest
of Vissoy, was Jean’s godfather.
And for Amsler,
life returned to normal
and he managed
as well as could be expected.
It hurt him to see his children
left on their own,
his home poorly cared for.
"And this torn sleeve!"
Every night, Jean whispered
a prayer to his mother.
Staring at the portrait as he did,
he thought it came to life and
smiled at him.
Like every Sunday.
Saint Martin’s day, when the tenant
farmers pay their rent.
Her daughter, Arlette.
"I can’t pay."
"The accident that cost
my husband his life
was blamed
on his carelessness."
"So the insurance company, invoking
the regulations,
didn’t pay anything."
And spring returned.
Amsler often cut
through Jeanne Dutois’ fields.
The first Sunday in June.
"Jean, I have business to see to.
You go alone."
"If you agree, we could be married
before Saint John’s Day."
"I’m going to spend a few days
with my old friend, Father Porchet.
How are the children?"
"I’m going to remarry."
"The house is empty
and there’s no one
to take care of little Pierrette.
It would be the best thing
for the children."
“What about Jean...
Did you tell him?”
“No, not yet.”
“He’s such a sensitive child.
I think you’d better
prepare him gently.”
The next day.
“You have things to talk about.
I’ll get out of your way.”
“Well?”
“Would you speak to Jean?
I think you’d explain it
better than me.
He’s a good boy,
but he’s so sensitive.”
“I have an idea! I’ll take Jean
with me to Vissoy for a few weeks.
Then I can gently
break the news to him there.”
“And when he comes home,
things will have returned to normal,
and he’ll adapt without too much
trouble to the new situation.”
The next day, at dawn,
the priest set off with his godson.
Having got through the pass,
they went down into the next valley.
By nightfall, they could see
the belltower of Vissoy.
At the end of the hay harvesting,
Saint-Luc celebrated
the marriage of its mayor.
“When you get home,
you’ll find some changes, Jean.
Your father is going to remarry."
“Your duty, my child, is to also
think of your loved ones.”
“Do you want your sister
Pierrette to be brought up badly,
and your papa living sad
and alone for the rest of his life?”
“Do I have to call her Mama, too?”
“Well then... call her mother.”
At the end of the month...
His heart heavy,
but full of good intentions,
Jean set out on the road home.
He saw things again
as if he’d been away for years.
Before he even crossed the threshold,
the house already seemed different.
“What do I want?
I want to get into my own house,
that’s what!”
“Mama said I wasn’t
to let anyone in.”
“Sure, but I’m Jean. I live here.”
“Who said you could use
my crayons?”
“Mama did.”
“Pierrette and I sleep in here.
You sleep in the small room
in the back.”
“You have to listen to me,
because I’m your mama now.
Then I’ll love you
and you’ll be my little boy.”
“I want you to be cheerful.
I don’t like children who mope
or daydream.
They’re just lazy.”
“Yes, ma’am.”
The snack.
“and you’re not to fight,
or envy one another,
but love and help one another.”
The following Sunday.
Jean had just noticed
his mother’s brooch.
“What’s the matter?”
From the first weeks, the animosity
between the children was evident.
Pierrette and Jean
always played on “their island”,
far from Arlette,
who could not play with them.
“Where is your hat?”
One day, they cleaned out the attic.
“The material is good. I could make
a dress for each of you out of it.”
“It’s not yours. It’s my mama’s.”
“Why did you do that?”
“Answer me!”
“Will you answer?”
“I hate her! I hate her!
I hate her!”
"A few months later,
Arlette and Jean
had come to hate each other.”
“My doll!"
“It’s too late to go get it now."
That evening, at home.
“It’s silly to cry over a lost doll
at your age.”
“Go upstairs.
I’ll be up in a moment.”
“I’m sure your doll
fell near the bridge.”
“It’s not far. Go on.
I’ll open the door for you.”
Jean had merely hoped that Arlette
would get a scolding.
He began to understand
the seriousness of what he had done.
Lost.
“Did you hear the avalanche?”
The only solution: to admit
everything right away.
"What's wrong?"
“I only want to speak to Papa.”
"Go and pray.”
Full of shame and anxiousness,
he turned to his mother’s portrait...
but the image seemed distant and faded.
Even the portrait had abandoned him.
The next morning.
His father hadn’t made
the slightest reproach.
Jean thought he had become
an object of horror to his family.
He felt like a criminal.
Dear Papa,
Goodbye. I’m a wretch.
I hope you will forgive me.
Love, Jean.
“I’m going away forever.
“Since you forgive me Arlette,
will you give me a kiss?”
"I leave this letter to father."
"then he left for the torrent."
"Mama."
THE END