DAI DIEN - SOUTHERN VIETNAM
1950s
This story is passed down in Dai Dien,
an ancient land of prosperity,
about the legend of the women
in Councilor Huynh Van Linh's family.
The one in the picture is Mrs. Hai Xuan,
also known as Councilor Hai Linh.
She spent almost her whole life
obeying and enforcing
the harsh rules of tradition.
Her obligation to the Huynh family
would only be fulfilled
when she could find somebody to pass on
the key to the family heirloom.
This is Ms. Ba Tran,
who will follow Mrs. Hai Linh
and take care of the Huynh family.
Seeing as her father is
an oriental medicine practitioner,
she developed a passion for herbs.
Ms. Ba Tran is a beautiful
and graceful woman.
After getting married to Mr. Hai Nhut,
the only son of Councilor Huynh Van Linh,
she became their eldest daughter-in-law.
Ba Tran!
Mrs. Hai Linh longs for a grandchild
to be the heir of the Huynh family.
How dare you disobey me!
Nonetheless,
Ba Tran antagonized her mother-in-law
by losing her first child.
Her life has been tumultuous ever since...
On a spring day of the 18th year
of the Dai Dien’s calendar,
Mr. Hai Nhut married his second wife,
Ms. Bay Loan,
only two years after his first wedding.
This was arranged by Mrs. Hai Linh
to satisfy her wish for an heir.
Today is a blissful day.
We are delighted
to open our hearts and to open our doors
to welcome the groom and the bride.
Bride, groom,
please serve wine to your mother.
Grapefruit flowers drive away evil.
Grapefruit leaves keep ghosts far away.
May the newlyweds be blessed
with many children.
&lrm;The bride is so beautiful.
Ms. Ba, Councilor Hai Linh calls for you.
Something was broken!
Breaking things during a wedding
is a taboo,
and you did it in purpose.
I’m sorry, I didn’t mean to.
You didn’t?
"Of the three ways of being unfilial,
not bearing a son is the worst."
Among the three sins of being unfilial,
not having a son is the worst one.
You’re well educated.
You should’ve understood that.
During the two years as the
daughter-in-law of the Huynh,
you have never been asked to do anything.
You can't even fulfill your
only obligation of producing an offspring.
Mother-in-Law,
procreation is a natural process.
It isn’t something
I can make happen on my own.
You’re kind. I hope you can understand.
Our family's blessing is
not yet that depleted.
Don't lecture me on this.
Mother-in-Law, I don’t dare to.
Such a toxic tree that bears no fruit.
Mother-in-Law...
It’s you who lost the first child
of the Huynh family.
What do you have to say now?
You're an evil woman who can bear no son.
Take a good look at this.
Tell me what it is!
Don't assume that if you keep silent,
I won't know about your wicked weed.
Mother-in-Law,
please forgive me.
It's just because of my ambition.
-You want Hai Nhut to be crazy about you.
-Mother-in-Law.
You don’t deserve to be
the Huynh’s daughter-in-law.
-Chin Ti!
-Yes, ma’am.
Take her to the annex.
-Forbid everyone to go nearby.
-Mother-in-Law, please.
-Mother-in-Law...
-Get off of me.
-Didn't you hear what she said? Go.
Mother-in-Law.
-Mother-in-Law...
-Go!
Mother-in-Law.
SUMMER
ONE YEAR LATER
To brew the magic black rosemary,
you must find the blood of a virgin.
No man
can resist the allure of black rosemary.
Even the most toxic snake will be charmed.
I’m sorry.
It has been one year that you
have been forsaken because of me.
Mother has probably calmed down by now.
I will bring you back to where you belong.
I just need you to keep thinking of me
and impregnate me soon.
Ms. Hai, something has gone wrong.
-Ms. Hai!
-What happened, nanny?
The ferry Mr. Hai Nhut took this morning
has crashed.
Mr. Hai Nhut's condition is not yet known.
Hai Dia just came back to inform us.
Councilor Hai Linh has fainted.
I pay respects
to the Huynh family's ancestors.
Please protect and save Hai Nhut.
Please help Bay Loan have a safe delivery.
-Ms. Ba Tran.
-What?
Mr. Hai Nhut is dead.
Mother-in-Law.
It’s you again.
Why don’t you try to have some manners?
I have something urgent to tell you.
What is it now?
Hai Dia just came back to inform us.
They found Mr. Hai Nhut's body.
You're lying.
I don't dare lie to you.
It's impossible.
Mr. Hai Nhut is dead.
No, I don’t believe you.
-I’m telling the truth.
-I don’t believe it.
Mr. Hai Nhut is dead.
-Mother-in-Law.
-Go away!
You're a poisonous snake.
You have brought misfortune
to your husband.
Do you hear me?
Hai Nhut!
No!
The Huynh lineage cannot be cut off.
Mother-in-Law!
When you see someone having a seizure
with rolling eyes, a twitching mouth,
convulsion and jerking limbs
press firmly on the acupuncture point
called the Man's Middle...
and prick the fingertips to prevent
that person from being paralyzed.
Such a toxic tree that bears no fruit.
You're such a poisonous snake.
You have brought misfortune
to your husband.
Councilor, Ms. Bay Loan
has given birth to a boy.
Ms. Bay Loan has given birth to a boy.
-It's a boy.
-Ms. Bay Loan has given birth to a boy.
Get her a towel.
That year, Ms. Ba Tran gave birth
to a boy named Phuoc.
She officially claimed back her title
as the eldest daughter-in-law
and took over the power.
Yet, she still wasn’t given the key
to the heirloom to replace Mrs. Hai Linh.
AUTUMN
16 YEARS LATER
&lrm;They sang beautifully.
Attention, people of Dai Dien!
Let's welcome Ms. Ba Tran.
Ms. Ba Tran has come.
Ms. Ba Tran
Ms. Ba Tran,
please make your announcement.
Hello, everyone.
As you may know, after the annual harvest,
the Huynh family often holds a competition
for everyone to compete and have fun.
I’d like to announce that...
this year’s prize
will be three tons of Nang Thom rice.
I want to play.
-I want to win the prize.
-Mr. Hai Phuoc...
Hai Phuoc.
Mother, I want to play.
Hai Phuoc, be a good boy
and return the drumstick to Hai Dia.
Come here and sit with me.
Tu Thi, lead Mr. Hai to his seat.
No, I want to play.
I don’t want to sit there.
Be a good boy and listen to your mother.
This competition isn’t as easy
as playing with your locust.
It’s really dangerous.
You’re too slow for it.
Who said he couldn’t play?
I mean...
this competition
is for the servants only...
No, I want to play.
It’s just for fun.
If he really wants to play,
then let him play the drum.
Bring the drum here.
Come on!
I will allow you to play
but only with the drum.
I can do it.
Remember, you are Ba Tran's son
and heir to the Huynh family.
So do your best.
I will try my best.
Go, go!
Whoever puts the bag of rice
into their goal first
shall win the competition.
Both teams, get ready. And start.
Faster!
-Faster!
-This way!
Faster!
Give it to me!
Over here!
Faster! Faster!
Mr. Hai, run! Run!
What are you waiting for? Run!
Hai Phuoc.
Run!
Mr. Hai!
Go, Mr. Hai!
What are you waiting for?
Hurry up!
Go!
Mr. Hai, faster!
Come on, Mr. Hai, faster!
Up, up you go!
It's in!
We won!
Mr. Hai Phuoc's team has won!
Mr. Hai is brilliant!
Mother, I won.
I won!
Congratulations!
Goodnight, ma'am.
-Mr. Hai.
-No.
No, I don’t want to.
Mr. Hai.
-Mr. Hai.
-I’m playing with my locust.
Stand still so I can measure your body.
Then you can go play.
Come here.
Forty-six.
I don’t want to.
Mother.
I don’t want to!
Be a good boy and stand still
so he can make nice clothes for you.
I already have nice clothes.
I just want to go out and play.
I know. But these will be better.
Do you remember what I told you?
Who are you? Answer me,
and I will let you go.
I’m the son of Ms. Ba Tran,
heir to the Huynh family.
Excellent. Now stand up.
Good boy.
Mother said I’m a good boy.
Next.
These rice grains are low grade,
so 10 sheaves will be increased to 15.
-Move.
-The rice is fine. He's acting strangely.
They are really
pushing the price down.
How was this rice milled?
This doesn't look good.
Your 20 sheaves are increased
to 25 sheaves.
You're so harsh on us farmers.
If you think so,
then don't rent the field.
See who will end up starving.
This has always been the rule!
Next!
No one can stand this!
Auntie, Uncle.
Tu Thi.
-Hey.
-Don't just call her by her name.
You will offend the councilor.
It's all right, Uncle.
Why do you want to see me?
This year's harvest is bad.
We...
We'd like to ask you a favor.
Please ask your mother-in-law
to see whether...
we can pay her half of our rent later on.
We will pay after the next harvest.
-Auntie, Uncle, I...
-What's going on, Ba Tung?
Well, Chin...
Faster!
You're asking for a payment extension,
aren't you?
Well, this has been a bad harvest...
Remember, Mrs. Hai Linh
is still in charge here.
No one can speak for her.
I don't dare to think so.
I think only you can handle this.
Anyway, Ba Tung,
you did contribute to the mill.
All right.
Let me try to talk to Mrs. Hai Linh.
-I owe you big time.
-Thank you.
-Hurry up!
-Yes, sir.
Please understand.
My opinions don't matter here.
We understand the difficult position
you're in.
Get back there, or you will be scolded.
Goodbye then.
Mr. Hai.
Mr. Hai. Please get inside.
I'm playing with my locust.
Mr. Hai.
Your mother will scold me
if she sees you here.
Mr. Hai.
You stalker.
I don't want to play with you.
Mr. Hai.
I'm your wife.
Why do you keep calling me sister?
Mr. Hai, you've been playing all morning.
Now let's go inside so I can bathe you.
I'd rather play with my locust.
-Mr. Hai.
-I don't like playing with you.
I'm playing with my locust.
It's so fun.
The lotus looks sad
at the end of the season.
Let's pick a few then go home.
Ms. Ba Tran will yell at us if we're late.
I have to admit that
Ms. Ba Tran is not only pretty
but also very smart.
Watch your mouth.
I'm just saying the truth.
Don't do that.
We're only servants.
We should keep our mouths shut,
keep our eyes closed,
and listen only to what we're told to do.
Do you understand?
"Of the three ways of being unfilial,
not bearing a son is the worst."
"Having no son is the worst
of the three sins."
You used to teach me that.
I intend to get another wife
for Hai Phuoc.
I hope to soon fulfill my responsibility.
You had better give me the key
so I can take over from you
and serve this family.
Please treat this cup of tea
as my announcement.
Drink up.
Drink.
It's mid-autumn,
and the lotus season is about to end.
You should cherish the moments
when you can still enjoy
a cup of tea which I have prepared.
Don't worry.
Hai Phuoc will soon have a son.
And you...
had better give me the key.
You're so wrong.
Don't get so angry.
It's not good for your health.
You have to stay healthy.
Open your eyes and see
how I will serve the Huynh family.
Give me the key!
Do you hear me? Do you?
Open your eyes and look at my son
and at Bay Loan's son.
See who is better than who.
Mr. Hai.
Mr. Hai, where are you?
Mother-in-Law, I'm looking for Mr. Hai.
Yes, Mother-in-Law.
My mother-in-law is tired.
You can talk to me instead.
Then I will wait for her to get better.
I will see her later.
Mrs. Hai Linh is merely a living corpse.
How long do you want to wait?
Do you want to isolate her?
We'll see how long
you can abuse your power.
Damn it!
Ba Tran cannot cover the sky
with the palm of her hand.
Don't celebrate too soon.
To be honest,
we are only servants.
Whatever we do
will only benefit our masters.
Guys, rob the mill.
Let's rob!
-What are you doing?
-Rob it!
Stop it!
Chin Ti, you're drunk!
This is so wrong!
Do you want to stop me?
You'd better keep your mouth shut.
Take them all.
Stop it.
Put it down. Stop it.
Drop it.
Mistress!
Mistress, there is chaos in the mill.
They're raiding the mill.
Put it down.
Stop it!
Who organized all of this?
I did!
Who organized this?
Mistress!
Do you want to rebel?
-Who told you to rob the mill?
-Well, well...
Chin.
Didn't I tell you to share
the rice with the farmers?
Why didn't you do as I told you?
Now you've caused a riot.
I will share the rice with you.
-But if you try to rob...
-Mistress,
it's all Ba Tung's fault.
That's right, Mistress.
Councilor, I'm a bit drunk.
Please forgive me.
-Everything was planned by Chin Ti.
-You...
-That's right, Mistress.
-It's all Chin Ti's fault.
I never thought it was you, Chin Ti.
Get out, everyone!
She's the most powerful person.
Is there any chance
she will have Chin Ti killed?
Who knows?
We are relatives, though.
Who's your relative?
The snake hasn’t molted yet.
As long as Mrs. Hai Linh is still alive...
you don't have any chance
to be the head of the Huynh family.
All right.
Such a vicious woman.
Don't think that
I don't know about your wrongdoings.
You don't deserve
to be a part of the Huynh family.
Shut up.
I will report you.
You're such a slutty
and vicious woman.
Mistress has come!
-What's happening in there?
-I'm afraid she will punish us all.
Chin Ti died in an accident.
-Remember his example.
-Yes, ma'am.
WINTER
At the end of the lotus season that year,
Ms. Ba Tran found another wife
for Mr. Hai Phuoc
in order to fulfill her responsibility
of providing an heir for the Huynh family.
The new wife is named Tuyet Mai.
Tuyet Mai didn't get a fancy wedding.
She was only welcomed
with a modest ceremony.
Mother-in-Law, Tuyet Mai has arrived.
Hello.
Tuyet Mai, take off your hat
and give me your suitcase.
Yes, please.
We should've had someone to send you here,
but the horoscope master
said not to make it so fancy.
Yes, ma'am.
Give your good wishes to your grandmother
and to your mother-in-law Bay Loan.
Hello, Grandmother.
Hello, Mother-in-Law Bay Loan.
Hai Phuoc.
Mother.
This is Hai Phuoc.
Hello.
Hi.
This is Tuyet Mai. She'll be your wife.
Tuyet Mai.
My wife Tuyet Mai is pretty.
From today, you are officially
a member of the Huynh family.
Take your time
and start learning your duties.
But I remind you:
you must respect your husband
and dedicate yourself to his family.
And most importantly,
you must give us a grandson soon.
Yes, ma'am.
Call me "Mother-in-Law."
Yes, "Mother-in-Law."
-Nanny!
-What?
Ms. Tuyet Mai, Mr. Hai Phuoc's wife,
has just arrived.
She looks modern.
Mr. Hai seems to like her very much.
You should watch your mouth.
Go wash the vegetables.
She was talking nonsense.
Please don't take offense.
My mother-in-law asked me to go check
on grandmother's medicine.
It's all done, ma'am.
I heard you went to a private school
in Saigon.
You also have a good family background.
Why did you decide to get married
into our family?
I'm not hiding from you.
My father killed an officer by accident.
He's in jail now.
My mom was so depressed that
she got sick and passed away.
I need some money
to hire a lawyer for my father.
Now, you have been
accepted into this family.
Try to settle down
and live in harmony with others
and to have a son
as your mother-in-law wishes.
Yes, Mother-in-Law.
Tuyet Mai. My wife Tuyet Mai is pretty.
Ouch!
-You may leave.
-Yes.
Yes, Mother-in-Law.
Mother.
Let me give you a bath.
Then you can go see your wife, all right?
Mother! You wet my locust.
Good boy.
Finish your bath,
then go see your pretty wife.
You two should give me a grandson soon.
I don't know how to have children.
I only want to play with my locust.
Please let me go out and play.
-Give me the locust.
-No.
-Here.
Fine, take it.
This locust can lay eggs, many, many eggs.
Take it! Now get out!
-Get out!
-Hai Phuoc!
Don't you understand my concern?
Don't you?
If I hadn't tried to keep you,
I would have ended up like this locust...
just a puppet in someone else's hands.
Do you understand my concern now?
Mother.
Mother, don't cry.
I don't want you to turn into a locust.
I love you. I'm finishing my bath.
It will be really quick.
Mother, don't cry.
Mother, don't cry. I will finish quickly.
Quickly.
I'm finishing my bath.
Good boy. I love you, son.
Bring it to Mr. Hai
when the ceremony is over.
Yes, ma’am!
Mattresses come in pairs
A pair of stalking mattresses
Which are brand new
Help the couple make a baby
-A lot of babies
-Don’t scare, my beautiful wife!
-Tiny little ones
-Don't scare.
Wearing jackfruit leaves
Riding toy horses
One kid after another
Keep coming to their mother
Please touch his head for good luck.
My beautiful wife, touch his head!
My wife is so pretty.
Your medicine is ready.
I’m not sick.
My pretty wife, take it.
Mother will love you.
-No!
-Take it! Take it! Take it!
May you have a good night!
Let’s go to bed, honey!
OK!
My beautiful wife, come here. Next to me.
-Ms. Tu Thi.
-Hurry up.
Did Tuyet Mai drink all the medicine?
Yes, she did.
-What about Mr. Hai?
-He took it, too.
What’s wrong?
What makes you unpleasant?
Mother-in-Law, I am not.
Then go back to your room.
Yes, Mother-in-Law.
-Tu Thi.
-Yes!
Yes, Mother-in-Law.
You may know my intention with Tuyet Mai.
What do you think?
Mother-in-Law, on what you have arranged,
I don't dare to comment.
I know your feelings,
but this is of the utmost importance.
Yes.
I tried to make it work
between you and Hai Phuoc.
I know you also care about me.
It’s all my fault.
I don’t blame you,
but you should remember
that having no sons
is the worst of the three sins
of being unfilial.
It should not happen to Hai Phuoc.
Mother-in-Law, I know.
Excuse me!
Aren't you with Mr. Hai?
He went to see his grandmother.
In the Huynh family,
a daughter-in-law has
to visit Grandmother twice a day.
It’s so complicated here.
It's too difficult to serve them.
Don’t say that.
You will make mother upset.
All right.
I’ll perform my duties starting tomorrow.
I will visit Grandmother twice a day.
I’ll go with you.
I thought I had to go with Mr. Hai.
Sister-in-Law.
Sister-in-Law...
why are you picking
our mother-in-law’s flowers?
These lotus petals are dead.
Mother-in-Law will scold me
if I leave them like this.
I thought she would destroy
a whole lake for a single dead petal.
What do you mean?
I mean...
is it true that the Huynh family
only needs a grandson,
not a daughter-in-law?
That's true.
In this house, there are many other rules.
If you want to live here comfortably,
watch your words.
I’m just telling the truth.
You can ignore them
if you don't like it.
-Tuyet Mai.
-Yes.
Mother-in-Law told me to show you around.
Come with me.
This is the main house.
The shrine is over here.
This is the reading room.
So our house is here,
and where is the rice mill?
Tell the butler to take you there.
These are all the rooms. However,
don't ever go near the wooden annex
near the lake.
Why?
It's deserted and murky.
It's where the daughters-in-law
are punished for violating
the family's rules.
Don't forget that!
Don't go there by yourself!
-Mother-in-Law will be unhappy.
-Yes.
The table is ready. Please come in to eat.
OK!
-Mistress, meal is ready.
-Yay, food's here.
Let's eat!
Yes, Mother-in-Law!
-Where is Tuyet Mai?
-She...
My beautiful wife!
-Mother-in-Law!
-Have you been permitted to sit?
It's absurd that
a daughter-in-law needs to be invited,
and the mother-in-law needs
to get approval to dine.
Don't make the same mistake!
Yes, Mother-in-Law. I’m sorry!
My beautiful wife, come here!
Sit down!
-Tu Thi, stay to eat.
-Yes, Mother-in-Law.
Next time, advise your sister-in-law
on our family’s rules.
Yes, Mother-in-Law.
Eat.
Let’s eat! Let's eat!
Mother-in-Law!
When did you come back?
I just got here!
I intended to visit Grandmother
before seeing you.
Tuyet Mai!
-Yes, Mother-in-Law.
-This is Ba Khiem,
your mother-in-law Bay Loan’s son,
your younger brother-in-law.
And this is Tuyet Mai,
your brother’s second wife.
Greet her!
It has been a long time
since our last cup of tea.
I’ve lost my taste for tea since you left.
Mother.
I came back here to...
I want you to understand that
whatever happens to me,
you're the only one
the Huynh family can rely on.
How long are you going to stay?
I don't know yet.
Mother.
How long has Tuyet Mai been here?
Thien Khiem!
You must remember
Tuyet Mai is Hai Phuoc’s wife.
She's your elder sister-in-law.
Do you understand?
Mother-in-Law.
Why is it taking so long?
Where is Tuyet Mai?
Mother-in-Law,
Tuyet Mai is resting in her room
because she does not feel well.
So disobedient!
Eat your meal! I’m not feeling well.
Mother-in-Law...
I just wanted to come
and see why you couldn’t dine with us.
I’m sorry, Mother-in-Law!
I’m feeling unwell.
If you feel sick,
stay in the room.
You don’t have to visit your grandmother.
Yes. Thank you, Mother-in-Law.
My beautiful wife.
Tuyet Mai.
Tuyet Mai, my beautiful wife.
Stop calling my name like I'm a kid!
Make me a grass locust!
I don't know how to.
You don't know how to,
but Tu Thi can do it very well.
Then ask her to do it for you.
Do it for me!
I don't know how to!
Go away! Stop annoying me!
You nag at me.
I'll tell my mother!
Mr. Hai Phuoc! Hey!
-Tuyet Mai.
-What are you doing?
I want to see you tonight.
We shouldn't.
Mother-in-Law is suspecting us.
I'll wait for you.
It's you!
Tuyet Mai.
How can you do this to me?
Tuyet Mai, do you know...
I've dropped out of school for months
to look for you.
I'm sorry. I have my own burden.
Ms. Tu Thi.
Why are you so panicked?
I saw Mr. Ba Khiem and Ms. Tuyet Mai
sneaking around out back.
Every day, I went to the library
where we first met,
wishing that you weren't gone.
Why are you here?
Why have you become Hai Phuoc’s wife?
I... think we should stop here.
I saw them with my own eyes!
Keep your mouth shut.
My mother-in-law
should not know about this. Understood?
Mother-in-Law, your tea is ready.
Mother-in-Law, are you unsatisfied?
Why is the tea mixed with jasmine?
Who brewed the tea?
Mother-in-Law, I boiled the water myself,
washed the pot, and brewed the tea.
I did not assign anyone to do it.
It may be from the jasmine
I picked for Mother-in-Law Bay Loan.
Do not ever mix lotus with jasmine.
I'm sorry, Mother-in-Law.
My beautiful wife! Let's eat.
Mistress, Ms. Tuyet Mai's meal is ready.
Tu Thi. Have someone bring it
to Tuyet Mai's room.
-Mother-in-Law.
-You don't have to dine here.
Did I do something wrong, Mother-in-Law?
Tu Thi!
Yes, ma'am.
-Hai Tho, serve the rice!
-Yes, ma'am.
The wooden annex by the lake
is where the daughters-in-law
are punished.
Don't go there by yourself!
Dai Dien still needs your help.
Do the best that you can...
and you will get well rewarded.
Tu Thi!
Where are all the servants?
Why are you doing it yourself?
Mother-in-Law is not feeling well.
I want to take care of her.
-What’s in this box?
-Tuyet Mai!
No matter how much the Huynh family
is longing for grandchildren,
you should not be so disobedient.
It’s not just me in this house, right?
I don’t understand what you’re saying.
Mother-in-Law!
I went for a walk last night
and by chance
found your handkerchief near the lake.
Seems that it was blown out there
by the wind.
How come you bother to keep
such a small handkerchief.
You are such a good daughter-in-law.
Yes, Mother-in-Law.
It turns out that you, Mistress,
are this lustful.
You misbehave!
Who allowed you to enter?
Speaking about misbehaving,
you're way beyond that level,
Mother-in-Law.
Tuyet Mai!
It’s all my fault, not hers.
You’re such a fool!
This woman will betray anyone.
You think she will spare you?
It smells good.
It must be the poisonous black rosemary
which can enchant any man
and even the deadliest snake.
You...
Ba Tran, you are even eviler
than a poisonous snake.
Go to hell!
Once you use black rosemary,
you absolutely must not bleed.
Blood will incite
the snake's aggressiveness.
Go to hell!
The storm might come to Dai Dien.
You should go as far away as possible.
Mistress!
Go anywhere else but here...
and forget everything.
Mistress!
You mean…
I’m begging you.
Please let me be your servant.
Don't make me go away.
I’ve been doing everything for you
for years...
would you just treat me like...
What are you implying?
Mistress!
It's my fault.
Please forgive me.
Mistress! I’m begging you.
Please let me be your servant.
I'm begging you.
Don't make me go away.
Mistress! I knew you would come.
Mistress...
Since you became
Councilor Linh’s daughter-in-law,
I know that...
you have never lived in happiness.
Why don't you leave
all of your unhappiness here
and leave for a place
which no one in Dai Dien knows?
Are you afraid that I'm poisoning you?
Let me.
I will drink it...
even if it’s poison.
Mistress!
I only have one desire.
May I gaze upon your face for once?
Hai Dia! Hai Dia, what happened to you?
Oh my God, Hai Dia’s dead!
Oh my God.
SPRING
Congratulations,
you are now a grandmother.
You are carrying a child belonging
to our family. Take good care of yourself.
Yes, Mother-in-Law.
Grandmother,
I have done nothing for our family.
It's time for Grandmother
to take her medicine.
Sister-in-Law.
Bay Loan is also here?
Sister-in-Law,
Thien Khiem is visiting our mother-in-law
before he leaves for school.
OK.
Grandmother!
I know this family needs a real man
to handle everything.
I promise I won’t let you down.
Mother-in-Law!
Please get well soon
so you can be a great grandmother.
I have good news for you.
Thien Khiem, leave with me.
Tu Thi!
Hai Phuoc will soon have a child.
Don’t I deserve...
the heirloom...
or you wish for more evil from me? Huh?
Thien Khiem!
I want you to go back to school tomorrow.
Mother, I want to stay here with you.
Just go.
If you love me, don't stay here.
Mother!
Why do you have to tolerate everything?
I can bring you away at worst.
Thien Khiem! Don’t ever think that.
To be honest...
In all of Councilor Linh's family,
no one is as good as you.
Ms. Bay Loan is so kind,
yet you two can’t live in comfort.
As a man...
you shouldn't let your mother
live like a servant.
Honestly, if I were you,
I would make it fair for my mother
by any means.
Run away with me.
-No, I can’t.
-I know you love me.
-If not, you wouldn’t have come here.
-Khiem.
I came here to see you for one last time.
Just want to let you know that
I’m pregnant with Mr. Hai's child.
Stop following me.
Tuyet Mai!
You’re lying, aren’t you?
You shouldn’t stay here.
We can find to a better place to live.
Trust me, Tuyet Mai.
-Come with me, Tuyet Mai.
-I don't want to talk anymore. Just go.
-Tuyet Mai!
-Khiem!
Don’t leave me.
Stay here with me, Tuyet Mai.
-Tuyet Mai.
-What are you doing?
-I’m begging you. Don’t leave me.
-Let me go!
Mistress...
Don’t leave me.
Slap me, but please don’t leave me.
Bring Bay Loan to the main house
right away!
-You called for me?
-It’s late at night,
and you yourself can guess...
-Mother-in-Law!
-...what a man and a woman do.
-Thien Khiem!
-Mother, it's all my fault.
I wanted you here to see
what your son has done...
Our mother-in-law will demand punishment.
For now, let me punish my daughter-in-law.
-Bring me a pair of scissors!
-Mother-in-Law!
-Shut up!
-Thien Khiem!
-Mother-in-Law, please. It’s my fault!
-Cutting off your hair,
applying lime on is not enough
for your sin.
Stop calling me "Mother-in-Law"!
Mother-in-Law, please. I'm begging you!
Mother-in-Law, it’s my fault.
-Please spare her.
-Mother-in-Law!
Ba Tran!
-You are way out of line.
-Insolent!
Sister-in-Law, I’m begging you.
Please forgive him.
I'll take all the punishments.
Punish me instead.
Mother, you don’t have to do it!
Let me take you away from here.
Don't stay here! Just leave this house!
Be quiet! Go away!
Sister-in-Law, I beg you.
Please spare Thien Khiem.
-I will...
-Let me go!
Grab him!
What are you doing?
-Isn't it enough for you?
-I beg you.
I'll never leave with you, never!
Go! Stay away from me!
-Tuyet Mai!
-Thien Khiem!
Shall I die here?
Go! Go!
-Mother!
-Go!
-Why, Mother?
Go!
Fight for ourselves!
Take them all!
Everyone, take as many you can
and fight for what we deserve.
Let's fight for what we deserve!
Mother, I'm back to take you away!
Mother!
Mother...
Mother! Mother! Mother! Mother...
What happened? Mother!
Mother!
Mother! I have killed you!
Mother, please wake up!
Mother!
You are OK, aren’t you?
Mother, let me brush your hair.
I’ll behave.
I'll go to school. I'll go to Saigon.
I won’t argue with you.
Mother!
Mother, please wake up!
Mother, I've killed you!
Mother-in-Law, please let me explain!
-It’s not what you think.
-Shut up!
Drink it and leave!
Give it to her!
No! Let me go!
You can't do it!
I’ll keep my child.
Why do you want to kill your grandchild?
You’ll never see him again!
See him?
Even his father doesn’t dare
to stay here for him.
He is a bastard child!
You know who his father is!
It’s a pity that I don’t need a grandson
born from a whore like you.
You disgrace him.
You think you're so pure?
Give me her medicine.
Give it to me.
Stay away from me!
Let me go.
Don’t hurt my baby.
I’m begging you, please spare him.
You can’t leave with your child!
You disgrace this family.
-Stand still! You can’t run away from me.
-Mother!
Mother!
-Mr. Hai!
Spare her! Don’t kill my beautiful wife!
Hai Phuoc!
She doesn’t deserve you.
Tell me, who are you?
I’m Ba Tran’s son,
heir to the Huynh family.
Good. Grab her!
-Stay away from me!
-Mr. Hai!
I’m Tuyet Mai’s husband
and the baby’s father!
Stay away from me! Go away!
Hai Phuoc, calm down. Listen to me.
Put the scissors down.
I’ll do whatever you want.
-Put them down!
-Mr. Hai!
Hai Phuoc, put the scissors down!
-She wants to kill our baby.
-Hai Phuoc!
-Mr. Hai!
-Put the scissors down.
Mother, I'm hurt!
-Hai Phuoc!
-It hurts.
Stop!
Mr. Hai...
Tuyet Mai, where are you going?
Tu Thi!
How come you look so exhausted?
You look so pale.
You need some medicine.
Medicine… no! What medicine?
I don’t want it!
-It’s yours, Tuyet Mai.
-No!
You can't kill our family's heir.
You know, not having a son is the worst
of the three unfilial sins.
No! What are you doing?
-You're right.
-No.
Not having a son is the worst
of the three unfilial sins...
-but incest, betraying your husband...
-No!
...and disgracing the family’s morals
are grounds for the death penalty.
Open the door!
Tu Thi, the servants are all
waiting for your command.
Tell them to follow our plan.
Fight! Fight!
Mother!
Hai Phuoc!
-Mother!
-Hai Phuoc!
It hurts.
You will be all right.
I’ll find someone to save you.
It hurts, Mother.
Mother.
I love you.
Please don’t cry, Mother.
I'll be nice.
I won’t make you angry anymore.
I'm a good boy.
I’m good. I remember,
"I’m Ba Tran’s son...
heir to the Huynh family."
Mother, don’t cry!
I love you.
Hai Phuoc!
Fight! Fight!
Mother.
Mother...
Every mother-in-law has been
a daughter-in-law once.
Just like you,
I was born and raised by my family,
then had to serve another.
I spent my entire youth to love
and serve my husband wholeheartedly.
I bitterly left everything behind
and stepped into a new house
where few can overcome the prejudice.
I don't want to pressure you
to do things that
I myself was also afraid to do.
Those things include the duty
to give birth to a son
and the obligation to share our love
with another woman.
That prejudice has never changed.
One day, daughters-in-law
will become mothers-in-law.