"Eleusis keeps always something hidden for
those that will visit her again" Seneca.
The Mourning Rock (lit. The
Rock that doens't smile)
dedicated to Dafne, Anna and Panayota.
In the age of antiquity, thousands of people
came here searching for the happiness
that was offered to them by the
participation in the Eleusinian Mysteries.
Here the adepts learned that they
can overcome the fear of death.
Today humanity without knowing anything
more about it, seek happiness elsewhere.
As for this place, those who
pass from here avert their gaze.
When I came here I knew, like everyone, the
old myth taken place in these low hills.
The myth of the abduction of Persephone, at
the hands of god of the underworld, Pluto
and the return to her mother's
side Demeter (Ceres),
made Eleusis one of
the most famous and
principally one of the
most sacred of places.
I even knew of the modern
reality taken place here.
And which destroyed even these hills.
I started to observe the city from
the point of view of a pilgrim.
Eleusis, May, 1988. Good Luck!
The first images.
Excavation in the field of
Papagiani Street, North Eleusis.
Irregular shapes, unusual
activities, unusual images.
From above, the excavation looks like
an open wound in the body of the Earth.
This site was a cemetery
in the antiquity.
Today it belongs to Mr. Tirlis and a
building is going to be built here.
As in all salvaging excavations,
here too, the images
coming out daily are unique
and unfortunately the last.
These existed for 2500 yrs
in the arms of the Earth,
however today, are being
driven to annihilation.
Seeing this image up close, a
feeling of discomfort ensues.
Little by little you get used to, as if
this had nothing to do with human destiny.
A currency, essential to
cross the lagoon of Acheron.
I encountered today, almost by chance,
him who had a secret and peculiar
relationship with all this.
His love for the ancient findings, his
figure refer us to a man from another time,
persecuted and moonstruck,
that fell into the present.
At noon, I was waiting for him on the
docks. There accross of Salamis.
Ha appeared suddenly, from the
corner of the supermarket Cronos,
And started to search among the most petty
material of this world: The rubble.
It's as he gives his own different
meaning in this summation
of incoherent things, that
we call everyday life.
A crazy, with a crazy relation with ancient
things, rejected by those around him.
In these incidental encounters that I
had with him, he constituted my guide.
Today the anthropomorphous larnax
(human-like coffin) was opened.
This type is discovered for
the first time in Αttica.
It was a custom of Asia Minor
and the Aegean islands.
So, we assume that this tall
man holding in his right hand
an iron sword, came from
these lands, from the East.
And brought with him this custom.
These days I met Stelios Theologou.
He also came from the East, in 1922,
as a refugee, along with many others.
He lives in the refugee
neighborhood, in Northern Eleusis.
With children and grandchildren, and
the photo of Plastiras in his wallet.
(second lieutenant, right-wing
politician, prime minister of Greece)
He had all the qualities
of his homeland.
Hard-working, tireless, with a tremendous
thirst for prosperity. Ionian.
I followed the milkman.
It's not the quaintness
what attracts me.
It's the modesty, the discretion, and
the kindness of his daily route.
He could be potentially comparisoned
with the goddess Demeter (Ceres).
That's how she came to
Eleusis, endpoint and limit to
her wandering to the world,
searching for Persephone.
Therefore, mr Panagiotis, is one of
those who write with their daily route
the word "The End" over
an epoch of the city.
A new excavation started
in the winter of '88.
It brought to light part
of an archaic cemetery
where mostly childern were buried.
These ancient infants, immature children
didn't grow to become handsome teenagers
like Kritios Boy, or beautiful girls
as Peploforos. (veiled one).
Their stay in this world
was desperately short.
Today we find them buried in containers,
or jar-burials in scientific terms.
Often devoid of funerary offerings and sometimes
buried with Attican or imported Corinthian pots.
From the type of tombs
and burial customs,
We surmise it to be
cemetary of common people.
A new observer was added in the
southern corner of the square,
facing the hangout of the adolescents.
The first installation
hapenned years ago.
In the ceremony of unveiling the sculpture
of Aeschylus in his birthplace,
the president of the Republic attended.
When the mayor changed,
the sculpture was
removed in order for the
square to be reformed.
Today, after he traversed
the city, he returned
back to his place, this
time without formalities.
With the minimum impact possible, like
Panagiotis Farmakis, or the milkman.
Petrola (oil company) = DEATH.
Everyone knew. Both those
participating in the manifestation,
and those who were stood
behind fences, like the
mister that received the
resolution so disreputably.
Everyone knew.
That the refinery was to be expanded.
Time, and especially envy, accelerated
the disintegration of this excavation.
Persephone Street, Spring 1988.
Here a part of a Roman
baths complex was found.
With underfloor heating,
liquid tanks and mosaic floors.
In the north, an ancient
well was discovered.
Even till this day it gushes.
It has been investigated
up to 7 meters depth.
Its constrution is exceptional, and
therefore, it was in use for many centuries.
It fell to disuse when the city was
deserted during the time of Byzantium.
However, the recordings
from the southwest corner
have kept us something
valuable today.
The image of the house next
door, with the palm tree.
Now the house has been
demolished, the palm tree sold,
and here a large building
is going to be built.
Already with the first
excavation a destruction layer
of the Roman times was found.
Today, since morning it was
snowing throughout Αttica,
You can barely see Salamis,
to the other shore.
Going up the Pangalou Str.,
opposite Saint George Str.,
we encountered this scene.
Towards the evening, it stopped snowing.
As for this work, it had
finished close to noon.
Coming back, the image
of that house whose
destruction we saw today
came vividly in mind.
In Piraeus, we were not
allowed to disembark.
And we started our way
to Eleusis, at dusk.
So, the place where we did disembark...
- Shall I point at it now?
- Yes, yes.
Exactly at this stairway, that's
what I call it, we disembarked.
And this mister, mr. Tsigkos,
who owned the factory,
illuminated with lantern,
and everyone came out.
Theodoros Tsigkos, who received
them alone with a lantern in hand,
was possibly the only one who
understood the magnitude
of the catastrophe (Asia
Minor Catastrophe)
Later, I always found
this small party
in the Eleftherios Venizelos
square, in Northern Eleusis.
They came when they
were small children,
they were to live the most tragic
part of the history of Greece.
They took many years to understand that
the land of lonia was definitely lost.
In each face the anguish of memory,
And instead of a
collective memory,
thousands memories of people
who drag their personal drama,
Into the great wound of history.
So, in this oil mill where
pomace oil was produced.
I worked ten years as a worker.
From 1925 to 1935.
And when I say that
I was a worker,
I mean the trolley was made of scantlings,
not planks and the corners were iron.
And it transported 109 kilos normally,
Or 167 when it was overloaded. You took
it from there and you sent it there,
at the stokehold and the stokers
were working with this.
They worked and produced
steam this huge, every year.
The work was very hard, because you
were carrying over your shoulder
from the drier one poke
weighing 90-100 kilos,
and there was a cobblestone staircase at
this side and you were climbing them.
And whether it was snowing, or it was cold,
you were barefoot and with a single shirt.
Among those ruins, you no longer hear
the monotonous sound of machines,
the labor, the toil, the
daily anguish of survival.
(russian )
It may well be the last
time we see this symbol,
it will soon be retired in
the dark side of history.
What prevails today are terms
like private initiative,
economy of the Free Market,
goods of Capitalism.
We will have to say many things.
I only want to say that mr. Panagiotis
has stopped distributing milk in the
neighborhoods of North Eleusis.
He told me that his horse grew old, and
it was difficult to cross the highway.
Later, he told me another version.
His children didn't let him.
Nothing is simple.
I wonder how can one prove that the city
is a bit poorer without his route.
January 16, 1991.
Much cold today.
No excavations were taken
place at the plots today.
I came across Panagiotis
Farmakis on the farmers' market.
He told me he was sick. In fact, he didn't
possess the same agility than in the past.
The students had a gathering and a protest
march today. Among them, the Kourou twins.
Later, they closed the National Highway,
at the height of the Steel Company.
In the afternoon, along with Roula, I
visited her grandfather Stelios Theologou.
The grandfather struggles
with the angel.
Entering the kitchen, I had
this sensation of abandonment.
I sensed that in the following steps I would
come up against what I could not avoid.
But the image of grandfather
was more comforting.
Him, still attractive, was sitting
in the chair, harmless as a child.
Really, how is the expectation
to be called by your own name?
Late at night, the Persian
Gulf War broke out.
Great rock concert protesting against
the expansion of Petrola! (Oil company)
Today at 19.00 at Youth sq.
In North Eleusis!
Resolution against the
expansion of Petrola!
A little time later, on the
initiative of the city council,
a referendum was held in the city on
whether or not to expand the refinery.
The results of the referundum
were: 97% against the expansion.
Afterwards, we saw with surprise those images
in the news. (mayor in cahoots with government)
And it came to my mind
that woman in Eleusis
that we saw the day
of the resolution.
The excavation in the Tirlis plot ended.
The last time it traversed the town,
it was about 410 B.C.
Today, in this anonymous
transport of March 31, 1989,
too few a glances gazed upon it.
As it walked down Demeter str.
a bit unorthodoxically,
bound to the
archaeological enclosure.
Today I went to to Eleusis
without any particular reason.
I search in this place that
which may partly balance
the daily routine, the
concerns, the fear.
Here in Aspropyrgos, I
have seen many times
these faces glued in this
melancholic background
sometimes looking right in the eyes, as
if they invited us in another world.
They know well that this world is
fictitious without reciprocation.
I would say it's a non-place.
Few days later, I have seen what
would be defined as non-faces.
In the Rentumi plot,
the excavation is over.
The few walls will be
preserved in the basement
for the archaelogists of
the fourth millennium.
NO TO THE FIRESALE OF THE SHIPYARDS.
In the square, a rally
of shipyard workers.
[the] workers through their
mass organizations should
develop their united and
cordinarted struggle...
Soon, Panagiotis Farmakis appeared.
He arrived as a hiker, as always.
As if a deity manifested itself.
I followed him to the sea.
Here! Can you carry it from the holes?
- Now I'm leaving.
- Where are you going?
Down - Is there anything there?
May I also come?
- I have not seen anything.
- Where down? Are they digging somewhere?
- Will you take a picture of this?
- It's old, isn't it?
It's beautiful, yes but they didn't
take it, and it's full of tar now.
Wait, I'll come too.
With your car?
Wait for me to bring it
because I've left it open.
- Okay, go!
- Where will I find you?
I wander by, aimlessly, like this.
The "Seven Against Thebes" Str. is
possibly the smallest road in the city.
It concerns only three houses.
However, Ms. Antonia
feels very proud to
live on this street, and
not without reason.
Right in front of her house the Western
Cemetery of Eleusis is located.
A clyster of graves are of
monumental construction.
And since the ancient times,
they were believed to belong to
the seven generals of Argos who
fought and died in Thebes.
According to Aeschylus, the seven
Argeian generals are buried here.
This is all that is left of the
"Western Cemetery of Eleusis" area.
It is a pity that the
"TITAN" cement factory.
Has not felt the same pride that Mrs.
Antonia
as far as the historical and
mythological aspect of the case.
I started as a 15,16
years old boy in '45.
Working on the first gig
called orbital sander.
I continued as air hammer operator and
after 2-3 years I obtain my license.
And since then I always filled the
ovens. I was an explosives technician.
I was here in 1946.
- How was this site then?
- All this was a sierra. A mountain.
Were you working on the
unit blowing up the hill?
Yeah, I was an air
hammer operator.
At this point, right here, there was
the tower measuring 60 meters high.
We were refugees.
My father was from Asia
Minor, my mother from Aydin,
my brother, who was
killed, born at Piraeus
and I, named Vasilis, born in Eleusis.
I had a father, a mother, a brother...
two brothers,
who they both died, one in Germany,
and the other close to 10 years ago,
And now I'm alone with my sister,
I do not have anyone else.
Mr. Giorgos in Sacred Street,
seems to welcome you
every morning upon
entering the city.
He also came, as a refugee,
with a suitcase of memories.
When I arrived today at the Thanou plot,
the clay larnax (coffin) was
already open of this child.
Let us borrow for this occasion, an epigram
of Lucian, for the young Callimachus.
"As a small child, with a carefree
soul the cruel Hades grabbed me."
"Do not cry for me."
"My life was short, but in sufferings
of life, my share was small, too."
None of his bones were preserved.
All funerary offerings are
preserved along with an egg.
Excavations have started
in a new plot, north of
the Ceremonies site in
Kougioumtzoglu street.
It was a cemetery in hellenistic times.
Today it belongs to Mr. Dalios.
What seems to be the most interesting is
what little Argyro prefers to play with.
Two identical sarcophagi lids.
I was born in 1914.
I was, I think about five years old,
when we were moved again as refugees,
they took us to the Middle
East, as they call it...
In Turkey where the
Armenians were slaughtered.
Where the troubles are
happening now once again.
It was called Aydıntepe(?), there.
As ancient history
did not mention the
craftsman who made the
big amphora of Dipulou,
or the pot with the representation
of the blindness of Polyphemus.
Likewise, modern history will
not quote Giorgos Krionas.
"They had slaughtered them".
From Thrace, from Skopos. We are
Thracians. Skopos is our village.
They arrived as persecuted in the difficult
years of the beggining of the century.
And he continued the job of his
father in the furnaces of Eleusis.
I met him in Sterna, in one of the
small houses of the neighborhood.
They went to Romania, like his
father, like my father and many more.
Today I went again to Eleusis, despite
not being any particular reason.
In the coffee shop in front
of the statue of Aeschylus,
three elders who were sitting looking
at the square spoke about death.
I do not remember the exact words,
But the content was
deeply human and sincere.
In the archaeological site a
preserver paid in hourly wages
was cleaning a small shell.
This vessel was broken
from the antiquity,
possibly after a dinner in
memory of the deceased.
This coincidence of size was a
perfect frame for the figure.
From the side I watched, I also noticed
that these two faces matched perfectly.
And something else important.
This shell, along with others were
discoveries of Panagiotis Farmakis,
from the building debris
of the Tirlis plot.
The event of these three
small coincidences,
closes a unique cycle of life.
Every man builds his life as a film.
This is what cinema is, in essence.
Big films put aside the films
that everyone has constructed
according to their own life
and reach to life itself.
This is what Christos Vakalopoulos
wrote, for Tarkovsky's films.
These days Christos died.
What big films achieve, nowadays I
feel happens mainly with death.
We seek in this city all these small
films each one has for his life.
Trying to find the cause of things.
An elementary image of the city,
an elementary image of ourselves.
It is not always easy.
So, this sad occasion today, inescapably
leads us to the Glauco column.
He lived in Eleusis 2000 years ago. He was
a priest in the mysteries of Eleusis.
As we read in the inscription.
He revealed to adepts the
sacred mysteries for 9 years.
In the tenth year he "crossed
towards the immortals".
The inscription concludes that for mortals
death is not a bad thing but a good thing.
Surely there is great
distance between our era
and this meaning of the
mysteries of Eleusis.
A few meters from the column
of Glauco Ms. Alexandra
at City Hall updates daily
the great book of the world.
And if it's a coincidence
that a woman here
preserves the memory in this
great existential problem
(BOOK OF DEATHS)
it's no coincidence at all
that women are desiganted
to preserve the memory of the
dead in the All Souls' Day.
In the All Souls' Day
of February you can see
pomegranate seeds on the wheat
of the dead (Dead-cake)
which Pluto gave to Persephone to force
her to return to the Underworld.
In antiquity and as the mysteries
of Eleusis were held here
the uninitiated reached up to here.
They wre generally slaves
waiting for their master.
Here they sat for three days spending
time playing noughts and crosses.
Our knowledge today about
the issue of the mysteries
is not in any case greater
than this of the slaves.
Perhaps the slaves heard from here
the priest's dramatic warning
"Out with the profane".
With the passing of the years
the profane increased.
And they invaded the sanctuary, as
the water in a boat about to sink.
These ruins today are haunted
by a faded ancient myth.
Thanks to the signification
of the myth,
humanity learned everything related
to the cultivation of Cereal,
which assured her survival.
But mainly learned everything related
the performance of the mysteries
that ensured the cultivation of the soul
and granted hope and
blessedness to face death.
The shrines were destroyed.
The gods worshiped here setted
(died), except for Persephone
who never stopped the
turnings of the cycle.
The new religion of Christianity gave
answers to the agonizing questions.
Today, 20 November, halfway
through grain planting,
The small church of the Virgin
of midway-sowing celebrates.
Next to the ancient site of ceremonies.
♫ Take and eat;
this is My body ♫
♫ which is broken for you
for the remission of sins ♫
♫ Thine own of Thine own, we offer
You, in behalf of all, and for all ♫
Again we offer to You this spiritual and
unbloody sacrifice, and we implore and pray,
and entreat You, send down Your Holy Spirit
upon us and upon these gifts here present.
And make this bread the
precious body of Your Christ.
And that which is in this chalice,
the precious blood of your Christ. Amen
Neither today the move of
the sarcophagus took place,
nor that of the sepulchral
column or the rest
of the sculptures from
the Liberis plot.
Today I received a card.
It was from Popi Papageli.
She accompanies the
ancient Greek sculptures
to the exhibition for the 500 years
of the discovery of America.
She wrote:
"My daughter smiled to me, with
that askew smile of hers."
"Around her uniformed guards,."
"Polish operators of lifting machines,."
"American preservers
with gum and ponytail,"
"but she smiled at me."
" Our craftsmen raised
her with white gloves,"
"wrapped her with clean sheets,"
"She was placed in the wooden box."
"And they closed the space above
with insulating material."
"Like a grave said a black guard."
"I followed her in the travel of
the dungeons of National Gallery."
"But she is not anymore a
breath of the Underworld."
"She is just the number fifteen box."
Many unrelated things
come to my mind.
(NO TO THE TRANSFER OF THE
MUSEUM SCULPTURES TO THE US)
I remember that Sunday that
some high school students
came to protest so that the
statues won't leave the city.
I also remember the image of the girl when
she finally left inside the wooden box.
A new face has been added to
the other images in the area.
The face of this handsome man.
For advertising purposes an
exotic landscape was inducted
and two women looking with awe.
If we needed to add a
word that would be: Melancholy.
I've seen those faces in the past.
In Sacred Street, in Skaramagkas,
in the Sanctuary of Aphrodite,
In the Reitans' lagoon near Fritoria.
In Aspropyrgos, I have
seen them many a times.
And if you combine them with this area
they could be faces in a tragedy.
Or the tombstones of this world.
September 1st 1992, Tuesday.
First day of autumn today.
In the morning there was a great
explosion in the Petrola refineries.
At first the news spoke
of one burn victim dead.
Few hours later, the
fire was extinguished.
I remember an advertising film for
the other refineries of Aspropyrgos.
Here a white bird tries to
convince us as a symbol of purity.
However, today in this case, some black
birds, carriers of a bad fortune
showed the way for a total of 14 people
losing their lives in this accident.
Where to go? Where we used to
eat is now scorched earth.
They cleaned the scrapyard one
day and this thing appeared.
Bread?
What?
There's a bakery here.
Do you want bread?
Somewhere here there is a base by
the sea. Can you film it from afar?
Down by there, that's where it is.
I started from this sea here and
arrived at the sea in Halkida
and all the way back because
I couldn't go on anymore..
You go from one place to another and back.
Hey! Is your family in town?
Relatives and such?
I've left years ago and I don't know.
But you go occasionally!
I go as a bystander and a passer-by.
Sit down for a second. Sit on the
bench so that we can rest a little.
Our excavational observations
for these two sarcophagus
are that both are of the same
material, marble of Penteli,
They are almost equal in size, and
today, with the excavation of the trench
that had been dugged for
the two sarcophagi,
we ascertained that the
trench was a common one.
One pit had been dugged in order for
the two sarcophagi to be put together.
They buried them at the same
time in two same sarcophagi,
in a common pit, at
the same height.
They bought them the
same funerary offerings.
When they were opened, we saw they
were left in the same position
looking each other for 24 centuries.
The eastside sarcophagus contained
within a very important finding.
A helmet of the cavalry of Thebes.
According to a very bold
version, we can presume
that these two men of Eleusis
belonged to the cavalry of Thebes.
Maybe they were killed in
the battle of Leuctra.
July 19th, 371 B.C.
The Thebans defeated the until
then invincible Spartans.
Thanks to the political and
military genius of Epaminondas.
And together they won for a brief
time the hegemony of Greece.
An old battlefield.
Nature has given it life
once again with her flowers.
This is what is left of the
dream of two myriads dead.
Towards the sunset, there was a truce,
to collect the dead from both sides.
Many Spartans, not as many Thebans.
At this hour they must have taken
the two Theban cavalrymen.
Afterwards, they were
buried in their city.
In the cemetery north of the ceremonies
area, now called Dalis plot.
History does not mention the
names of those who make it.
Let us be granted the arbitrariness
of naming the two horsemen of Eleusis
even though we do not know their
names, as the conditions in their city
24 centuries after their death,
forced them into a last exhumacion.
Ceres (Demeter) Str.
Sacred Str.
February 15th, 1992, Monday.
Cold and cloudy, and a rain always about
to start but never actually does.
Nothing was recorded today, apart from a
frame of Farmakis Panagiotis in the market.
It seems enough as a comment of
what can one expect from this city.
The excavation in the Pepa
plot continues rapidly.
Here they also find
coins of the Roman era.
In the Liberis plot a
sepulchral column was found.
Placed sideways we can not read
if there is anything written.
I passed by the refugee neighborhood.
Small houses of a stereotypical
architecture made with adobes.
From this place refugees
started again from scratch.
But they had a love for
life and prosperity.
Virtues of a superior culture of lonia.
On the other hand, shuffling
I must quote Giorgos Krionas
who spoke to me yesterday
of his wife who died
the other day, and he
is not very well since.
I have to place many
mosaic blocks to create
an elementary image of this city.
This I know.
For today, we should keep
this fleeting motion
of Panagiotis Farmakis
from the market.
A fleeting shadow.
Today I passed by Papagianni str.
I saw the Tirlis building.
By now it has been built.
The limits of this plot coincided precisely
with those of the archaic cemetery.
That woman of the sarcophagus
number nine came to my mind.
She lived in the classical era.
They consecrated to her among other
things a personal object. Her mirror.
I imagine the image of this
woman through the mirror.
I imagine the images of her world.
The things we learn
in schools today.
I remember the disappointment
that I felt when
we reached the chapter of
the Peloponnesian War.
With great surprise, I saw
today the iridescences of
the mirror while coming to
light for the first time.
It was as if it was returning the images
that it had saved all those distant years.
These signs, along with
the greatest of this city
fly over it in invisible spots.
The bridge was brought
into use in late 1994.
In January, late in the
afternoon, the trucks from way up
cast their shadow over the few
marbles of the helenistic tower
that now lies on the ground.
It was once erect, with
white marbles of Penteli
and therefore it was called
Aspropirgos (White Tower).
Otherwise, the name used by
locals is Kalyvia (Huts).
If this afternoon all this seems
to you more cheerful than ever
It is due to the fact that years ago
a girl passed through here.
She wore the traditional dress of
the area that locals call camisola.
Brunette, of medium height,
she was so beautiful that this
impeded her from marryimg.
Her coevals, even now,
when they mention her name
raise slightly the tone of his voice,
followed by an imperceptible sigh.
She could not have any
name other than Mary.
I got to know her through
descriptions and old photos
taken in the archaeological place
and in the field of Eleusis
when it existed, before the factories
ad the airport were built there.
Miss Mary now lives in her
parents' house by the sea.
We found her sitting in her
favorite place by the window.
And temporarily disturbed
her daily reverie.
The last south wind endowed us
with these magnificent colours.
The blackbird sits here, and every morning
that I leave in these early hours
he climbs here and he flies
around, and also on that stone.
In the evening, at the late
hours, he passes through
here and he goes behind
the factories and nests.
Yeah, this hare descends every
afternoon at 18.00 or 19.00.
Down from the clock,
passes through the church,
goes down these stairs here,
and eats the pasture.
And in the morning at 5 or 6am
returns along the same path
and he returns to the mountain
to settle down for the day.
The snake population has also declined.
Two of them had remained. The
female one was burnt with the Fire.
I stumbled through the
male one, one night at
the clock. It went very
far with great speed.
There are no longer many of these.
We found ourselves here
following the Hadrian aqueduct.
Nowadays some remains along the
Demeter Str. are still preserved.
A last part was demolished by the council
in 1987, to build the new city hall.
Emperor Hadrian visited
Eleusis many times
and he was intitiated in
the Eleusinian mysteries.
He contrusted many projects in the city.
Thus returning the great
gift of the initiation
that was granted upon
him by the sanctuary.
One of these projects was
the aqueduct bringing
water from the underflow
of Parnitha to Eleusis.
A huge work for its time, a
maximum act of civilization.
Here on this farm, the aqueduct
was one of the walls of the barn.
The farm also contained a big well
that for over a century watered gardens,
and quenched the thirst of men and cattle.
Today its of no use to anyone.
And since nobody
needs it, let the
archaelogists of the
next millennium find it.
We kept the last image April 5th, 1995.
At 11am.
I know that art, and especially literature
has mentioned the great gifts of the well.
Along with what happened in
the mouth of the well: Plants
were watered, men and cattle
that quenched their thirst,
greetings and glances
that were exchanged.
But more than anything the
thoughts of the monk come to mind,
When he reached the well when
the waters become cloudy.
"I stopped at one of the three wells
and reaching my hand on the wellhead,"
"I leaned over to see if
the water was abundant."
"I saw it half-full and
I said thank God."
"So sweet the freshness that the summer
deprives from the bowels of man."
"Great his works (are) and great
the ingratitude of man (is)."
"And according to the gospel,
how many are the righteous?"
"And contemplating this,
my eyes rested on
my hands, which were
place on the wellhead."
Returning we saw the
boats again levitating.
I wish I could thank you little
sparrow for the look you granted us.
Although I saw it correctly
from the camera,
you looked at us a
bit suspiciously.
However your presence gives us the
sense of measure and equilibrium.
Here on this place where
it has long lost them.
October 14th, 1995.
Today the antiquities were placed
below the Karagiannis plot.
Αngel, who we encountered here, is
working occasionaly in construction.
No doubt his figure has
potentially existed in
containers and marble
sculptures of late antiquity.
It reminds me strongly of this famous
teenager who is in the museum.
Antinoos from distant
Vitynia, favorite of Hadrian
was the last mortal accepted in
the panteon of the ancient world.
His supernatural beauty,
recorded in numerous sculptures,
shows the condensation of the
meaning of life and death.
In his sad figure of intense realism,
you can see the turn "inwards".
The decline of the ancient
world, which ended with a tear.
This noon we find ourselves almost
uninvited in Mrs. Koula's house.
In her small kitchen, with
the exemplary simplicity,
you find the archetypical
definition of hospitality.
A miniature of the world
the way we dream about it.
Where do you frequent at night?
I walk around here.
I am free, I saunter. I rotate.
Haven't you finished
(the project about) Eleusis?
Where do you live? Where is your house?
Where do you stay at during the night?
Above the earth and beneath the clouds.
How can I say it.
Is this your address?
How did you say it? Above?
Above the earth and below the clouds.
Mr. Isaac came as a refugee
from Prokopi of Cappadocia.
As one of the population
exchangees in 1924.
These few years he lived as a child
in Cappadocia marked his whole life.
Events and facts that
he narrated were often
wrapped in the fog of
the myth of the East.
He loved Venizelos and Plastiras
as most of the refugees did.
Saint John the Russian was also
from Prokopi of Cappadocia.
And as Eneas brought his old father from
Troy same with the residents of Prokopi.
The first of the few things they
brought back in their new homeland
were from the bones
of the saint.
That's what they regarded
as their fortune.
The only fortune is memory.
August 1993.
This year's summer has no shortage
of wars, disasters and tensions.
The news these days, as
always, compete to impress
a gaze that is already accustomed
to any kind of atrocities.
War in Bosnia, tension
grown by Americans.
Turkish provocativeness.
Ι already know all this.
But I prefer to talk about
this fishing couple
who have taken their boat
out for repairs these days.
I feel these simple, modest
and archetypical movements
balance the heavy and charged
"air" that hovers over our heads.
Once more I feel the things that
Chrisa preserves resemble her.
The way she holds the
idol is an assuredness
that love has not been
missed from the world.
Argyro was this small
girl we had seen playing
on the two sarcophagi
on the Dalios plot.
Today she is in the fifth
grade and she reminds me
of another small girl that lived
in Eleusis 2000 years ago.
She was called Nicostrata.
Above the image of St.
Zachary which is kissed by
believers, lies Nicostrata's
inscription, or the opposite.
The small church is built with ancient
marbles, scattered around here.
It's like that so that we remember
the loans of Christianity.
From the Dodecatheon of ancient Greece
and mainly from the worship of Demeter
and her daughter, here in Eleusis.
The vesper done in early September.
When days start to shorten, and
Persephone prepares for the new journey,
they prefer to hold it outside.
Nicostrata, St. Zachary.
Those two lived about the same
era, serving different religions.
St. Zachary, minister of
the Church of Jerusalem.
And Nicostrata, as the
inscription tells us,
since a young girl, she was
initiated from her home,
in the worship of Demeter and
her daughter, here in Eleusis.
Nicostrata: Her name doesn't come
from "nicos" which means hatred
which according to
Empedocles comes out often
and captures the world
in the opposite of love.
As for her image, which
we don't possess,
we rather must seek it in the
faces of the women today.
There must be some kind of relevance,
otherwise we cannot explain
the familiarity with which they
sit on the ancient marbles.
September 23th, day that the Elefsinian
mysteries began was a day like today.
I decided to follow the procession of
the since invisible travelling players
as it started early from Athens
to Eleusis, through Sacred Str.
In the area of Keramikos, there is the
excavation for construction of the subway.
Occasionally some gazes escape, fleeting
images that linger on the mind for a while,
while you unsuspectingly pass by
Sacred Str. on foot or by car.
We have to somehow connect
these fleeting images
with what was hapenning thousands
of years ago on a day like today.
I'm afraid that the images of the procession
of the initiates to the Elefsinian mysteries,
as they have passed down
to us faded, fragmented,
correspond roughly to the same images you
can now see in the same area of Keramikos.
On the same street, the same day.
They both are incomplete.
Sacred Str. towards Eleusis Street.
A look at some of the favorite sites.
On the hill of Egaleo, the monument
of Pythioniki harlot from Corinth.
It has not been found. It
must have been somewhere
here near the Public
Psychiatric hospital.
Every time I pass by here I am
reminded of a verse from Viziinos.
He is also buried here, without been
known where exactly his grave is.
"And since I mourn
my blonde, blue and celestial light."
"The rhythm of the world
changed inside of me."
The Sanctuary of Aphrodite
is mentioned by
Pausanias, the traveler
of second century B.C.
We found that these
"cabinets" in the rock
until today, some unknown passengers,
use them to dedicate small offerings
hoping for different things
than what ancients hoped for.
But the sanctity of the
place, and the consciousness
of the holiness of
the place remains.
And so, these "cabinets" in the
rock, are "cabinets" of memory.
Towards the afternoon, many hours after
our visit of the sanctuary of Aphrodite,
we felt for a moment,
with surprise, that the
sense of guilt and sin
has abandoned us.
As if our souls were found in a
world before the original sin.
Here desires can become reality.
even the erotic ones.
That's how it worked for centuries. For
some, that's how it works even today.
This small fenced site in a place which
has suffered. It is a kind of a zone.
At night they jump over the wired
fence and leave modern offerings
in the "cabinets" wth the conviction
that wishes will come true.
Today I received a letter
from Popi (Persephone).
It was about a new excavation.
November 8th, 1996. Archangels' day.
Philip, the central pluvial
pipe of the modern city met
the Sacred Str. Of ancient Eleusis,
and the archaelogists rushed.
The mechanical excavator of company
responsible for the work, ripped the
asphalt layer and amidst clouds of
dust brought the antiquities to light.
They are being cleaned by
Stratos, George, Hasan from.
Komotini, and Ivan, the
Russian who we call John.
The storeowners complain
because we stopped
the traffic, along with
customer traffic, too.
Elders stand still for a while.
Some schoolkids stop for a moment. They
found antiquitues, says the teacher,
while gently pushing the kids to carry
on, so as not to go out of schedule.
This Fall, it's mornings like this,
that when I arrive
before going down to the pit, I
stop for a moment and loiter.
I see the stone floor,
smoothed by thousands
of footsteps,
etched by wheelcars
which came to light after so many
centuries, only to disappear again soon,
and this time forever. Our age is
relentless. After all, life must go on.
I'm standing on the edge of the ditch.
The air smells of acacia.
And for a moment, just for a moment,
it's like invisible travelling players
passing by with exquisite music, with
voices heading to the sanctuary.
I sense my extreme fortunate to have
standed where the initiated passed by.
To have cast, in the
blink of an eye, a gaze
in the past. A rare
and bitter privilege.
I wonder, what does
rescue archaelogy rescue?
This gaze of ours?
One bronze coin that slipped
from someone careless,
and we gathered it after
so many centuries?
The pieces of a crock
from some traveler
that broke before he
quenched his thirst?
The drawing of it?
The general photos?
The brief publication in the
archaelogical bulletin?
The travelling players passed.
The air still smells of acacia.
The acacia is present.
Spring has come late this year, fifteen
days much later than other years,
So have the swallows done.
Only five days ago, they came.
There are many flowers, the
whole place is very cheerful
but I don't know all the
flowers to describe them.
Cause I know them in my language,
Arvanitika from small child.
I don't know where else
could this be written
but let me note it
here in this film.
Today, Holy Tuesday 1995, April
the18th was the last day that
the guard, John Sotiriou worked
in the antiquities of Eleusis.
I should also note his great
love for the environment,
herbs, flowers, birds
and other animals.
Love that stands very far from the
modern ecological trends, but maintains
components of balance, thrift and
wisdom like all things authentic.
When the fig leaf is as thick as
a goose foot, spring arrives.
You see it everywhere, while nature
preens herself to welcome Persephone.
Tonight I encounter
Panagiotis Farmakis,
outside the church of Saints
Apostles in the neighborhood.
He had a cosmic innocence
but mainly the
discomfort of the ancient
religion's High Priest.
That's why his figure doens't
rub shoulders with the
faces of the believers who
go to church these days.
Seeing that the sun
had hidden its rays
and the veil of the Temple had been
rent at the death of the Saviour,
Joseph did approach Pilate and did
plead with him crying and saying,
Give me this stranger, who from his
youth hath wandered like a stranger.
Give me this stranger, whom his kinsmen
killed in hatred like a stranger.
Give me this stranger at whom I wonder,
beholding him as a guest of death.
Give me this stranger who knoweth how
to take in the poor and strangers.
Give me this stranger whom the Jews
in envy estranged from the world.
Give me this stranger that
I may bury him in a tomb,
who being a stranger hath no
place whereon to lay his head.
Give me this stranger, to whom
his Mother, beholding him dead,
shouted crying, “O my Son and my God,
even though my vitals be wounded,
and my heart burns, as
I behold thee dead,
yet trusting in thy
Resurrection, I magnify thee.”
The incarnation of Son
and Word of God would
be meaningless if not
for resurrection.
Now everything is filled with light,
on heaven, on earth and in hell.
Lift up your gates, O ye princes, and
be ye lifted up, O eternal gates:
- And the King of Glory shall enter in.
- Who is this King of Glory?
Its Him the King of Glory.
Panagiotis Farmakis has died.
Women here in Kleidi, placed a
marital crown upon his head,
which until yesterday he covered
carefully not to reveal his halo.
Today this wanderer (anc. greek: planet)
goes upwards to Arctos (Ursa).
Maybe he is pulled there by the
gravity of another planet.
The Boeotian field, the field
of Thriasio, and mainly Eleusis
know the unique virtues
of this wanderer.
Aeschylus Str.
He crossed the Thriasio
field with aν incredible
mobility every season
for many years.
His only fortune, his coat
which always covered his head
and sometimes a plastic
bag he carried with him.
Of his contemporaries, I
do not know anyone
who has any assets at all
and not worry about it.
On the contrary, he sensed that all
modern and mostly all ancient things
from the Thriasio to the
Boeotian field to belong to him.
With a selfless and cosmic
relationship that God has with men.
He was born in 1930, when Greece suffered
the consequences of the Great Idea,
when TITAN had only one chimney
and Kourouniotis was digging
in the archaelogical space.
So he was born in Diramari, present-day Dafni,
one small village on the
slopes of the Boeotian field
of which the only thing worth
mentioning is its cemetery.
It was one of those figures that
appeared coming from the Thriasio field
in a cloud of dust, the morning of
the crucial naval battle of Salamis
while the outcome was still
hanging in the balance.
This same figure is found in the
texts Solomos on Mesologgi.
I feel fortunate that my humble art
saved some images of this same figure.
That appeared once again in this tried
place, at the end of the second millennium.
Where the current danger we would call
it selfishness, individual interest.
Aeschylus is not in his place.
The mayor changed, the
statue's place changed too.
Here in Tristrato, he is lost
among a thousand other things.
Sometimes you see him escaping too, as a
passenger for Athens, by Sacred Str way.
I like to observe the harmony of the lines
while the stones succeed one another.
It was constructed in the archaic period
as a protective wall against the river.
In the afternoon, the sun
makes it relief, as they
purposefully left the
external side unfinished.
Observing it with atention you
find on it the basic perceptions
that characterize a work
of contemporary art.
I spent many evenings watching the
sun chariot, while setting,
And I always think about how
the sunset looks like in Eleusis.
I know that when the
sun's orbit lowers, one
of the antefixes of the
house in Pericles Str,
the one looking towards Salamina, it grants
us with a magnificent archaic smile.
This should be the time that Ms.
Helen is preparing to light
candles in the roadside shrine
for memory and eternity.
It is also time when the adolescents
begin to gather on the beach.
While on the seaside the night comes,
bringing with her this discreet melancholy.
We don't know if the current
customers of this chain of
restaurants taste even
figuratively such experiences
as the one tasted by this unsuspecting
young man who ordered a hamburger.
Modern nymphs who are mobilized
and they dont live in sacred groves.
Thir place is the television screen.
Thus we could not find a
better way to narrate
the brief history of
this plot (as in site),
That the unsurpassed philosophy
of our times: The video-clip.
2000 years ago some ceramists earned
their bread working in this workshop.
The furnace where the pots were
baked is the one in the east corner.
We do not know their names, but some
works made by their hands were saved.
These marks is avery old greeting
imprinted on these clay plates
who may have been baked
here, in this furnace.
Spiridoula of Plataea, who lives in the
working class neighborhood of Eleusis,
and works in this restaurant
chain was kind enough
today to guide us in the
basement of the building,
where next to the boss's office
the furnace has been retained.
Thus Spiridula, Mary,
Despina, Kostas, Nikos,
Dionisis and the rest
from other shifts
worked in the same place as the
ceramists of the Roman period,
close somehow this small circle
of the history of this plot.
(MARLON BRANDO AMONG US!)
These days the journals
are full of reports
about the arrival of
Marlon Brando to Greece.
He has been invited by the
owners of the Petrola
refinery and is about to
talk about the environment.
For reasons of justice, I
only want to commemorate
with satisfaction that Mrs.
Heleni continues with
her modest way to light
every night on the roadsite
shrine this small flame
that makes things balance.
The city changes faces very
fast, at least externally.
Many times nothing comes out,
neither in mood or images.
As for the internal face I
am too ignorant to answer.
That's what I also search,
not always with success.
And if tehy ask me where and how
many times I encountered it
I wiil recall offhand, last year one
afternoon, Giorgos Krionas.
All I can say now...
The mother-in-law of my
grandson came from the USA.
She says to me:"Grandpa,
that's how life goes, now
(she) is waiting for you...
(she) is waiting".
If it is true that souls meet again...
Religion says that they do.
Do you understand? What is to be done?
Whatever we say now, we are
closer there (to the Underworld).
Here I sensed for the
first time, the anguish
of a person to spread
to whole regions.
In those he lived, in those he
worked, in those he dreamt.
His word acquires in teh
end a cosmic value.
In the field of separation
lilies will bloom again.
I often buy honey from Ms. Perdica.
You find her her here, too in
the farmers' market every Monday.
She also hails from a refugee family.
However, she was born here in Eleusis.
She knows the story of Ms.
Demeter and she passed it on to me.
The Turks came and our parents
apparently held our hands,
but there was such a panic that I slipped.
I knew how to go to the beach
where the boats were.
I get up and go alone, among so many
people " she says "I went alone" she says.
The Turks kidnapped,
killed, and wrecked havoc.
I reached the beach, I was crying
so an old man took me by the hand.
He took me by the hand," he says,
"come here small one what do you wany?"
"My mother," she says.
"I'll take you there", he said.
And he took her to the ship
where her mother was. And
she spent the whole night
with the old man till dawn.
He took her the other day and
brought her to her mother.
And when she asked "Who
brought you?" She was about
to say "The old man" but
there was no one there.
She was left puzzled.
It was Saint Nicholas.
Saint Nicholas, here in Eleusis,
he also hides an old legend.
This small church was
in that period about
100-150 m. Further away
from where it is now.
They wanted to expand the factory, so they
decided tomove it to this site.
When they gave the demolition
order, the mαchines
began to work like crazy,
topsyturvy, abnormally.
Nobody wanted to demolish it.
And then they found the
so-called Vranas, who had
the courage to demolish
the curch, and he did it.
When he took the bus
home, a passing car took
his arm that hanged
from the window bus..
They started performing litanies
and with the help of the
clergy they demolished it and
brought it to its current site.
In evening song, on December 5th, you will
always find the old workers of TITAN.
It's like a vow.
In '47, we came, as I remember and
we signed a contract on 21 March.
And now only 10 people are left.
Yeah it, of course, they all died.
Cement. They built another part
of the factory, The KAOLIN.
Yeah, yeah. All who went to
work there ended up dead.
- Their stomach.
- All Who went to work came back dead.
In the lungs. And there
was no way to get it out
(tumor). ♫ blessed,
immortal O Jesus Christ ♫
The lady from the neighbourhood
that the day before yesterday
asked for a small bone from the
sarcophagus no.10 as an talisman
came back today, and this
time she didn't ask for
anything because yesterday
they told her lightheartedly.
Wha for? These were idolaters.
But she is watching thoughtfully,
trying to understand
how Hades grew so big, and maybe
she was saying in her own words.
As Pindar said in a unique way said:
Creatures of a day! What is a man? What
is he not? Man is the dream of a shadow.
The copper boiler, a very
valuable object in its day
was also a prize in chariot races.
A satisfaction for today's
discovery, certainly smaller
than that of the chariot
winner who would claim it.
From the hill I saw the new
part of the port progressing.
I also noticed the cyclamens
in the cracks of the rocks,
a sign that Persephone is on her
journey to the underworld.
I encountered Antonis, the fisherman
from Samos in the market pass.
That's where he sells his fish.
For a monent, he told me the unexpected.
Do you remember my wife?
She is not alive anymore.
And alas, I sensed that I
had seen all this dfrom
the few images that we
have of this woman.
A person brings the oars with
which paddle his own life.
She waits at the corner,
she is lost in the city.
What exaxtly was I looking
for today first day of 1999?
Maybe remorse, because in
the year that passed I
didnt occupy myself
sufficiently with Eleusis.
On entering the city, I first
glance the statue of Aeschylus.
Lost in a thousand other things,
Although I prefer the other
corner overlooking the.
Redumi building where now
the Pisteos Bank is housed.
In the port a ship is sailing among
others anchored and mute.
No movement. Niether by
workers, nor by machines.
Only these images for today,
Insufficient sample of a daily agony
that seeks solutions in this place.
Now I contemplate I'm partly on the
territory of Panagiotis Farmakis.
Maybe his soul still roams among us,
strolling the spaces like us, aimlessly.
Panagiotis and Charikleia
Kodoliou have died long ago.
I look again at the first images
that we have of this couple.
The faces reflect the reconciliation,
the kindness, and decency
you find imprinted on the
sepulchral columns.
I also remember when we spoke with
them for the exodus (from Smyrna).
70 years have passed. How long are we here?
Since 1922?
Well, I don't know what anyone else does
but my big complaint is that
we can not unite, son.
Despite all these tortures,
all this suffering was left in the dustbin.
Giorgos Krionas has also died.
I remember that afternoon
of July 28th, 1994, when
wetook us to his cousin's home, at Mrs.
Tolina's.
She gladly spoke of the
adventures of her life.
About the familiarization of
man with sadness and death.
On the right (this) was ours, my father's.
He had built it, new, this house.
He had inside barrels, we had
an oven and we baked bread.
There was a gardenn inside with
many trees, almond trees, flowers.
It was all happiness.
Poverty can be endured.
If you do not have meat
you'll eat olives, you'll
eat bread with olives,
The fear...
"Fear" was the last word she
told us, while it began to get dark.
Nikos Kiriazelos works as an oil
painter in the city of Eleusis.
What he mainly incarnates is
the type of cynic philosopher.
He had a unique sense of humor.
I have often heard him to
come down ruthlessly and
brightly on all kinds of
powers and petty interests.
My name is Nikos Kiriazelos, I am an
ex-oil painter of the City of Eleusis,
And I now guard the cemeteries.
This is the Venetian tower on
the hill west of the sanctuary.
The gill was blasted
into pieces in 1954 and
turned into cement by
the TITAN factory.
The tower was destroyed to be
rebuilt again someday elsewhere.
The marbles are housed for40 years
now inside the archaeological site.
The human-like sarcophagus
form is in the
archaeological site, like
that of Lica and Pliny.
The helmet of the Daliou plot, is the
second of its kind found worldwide.
The other was found in Mesopotamia.
It went there along with the
armies of Alexander the Great.
Tania, or more correctly
Sultana, is that little
girl we saw that day in
1992, in the museum.
Today, eight years
after, works in her
mother's company and
will marry in November.
We saw again the Kourou twins in the same
house, in the same house ten years later.
Dora studied journalism and Despoina is a
graphic artist now, as she always wanted.
Sotiris finished his studies and continues
as a postgraduate student in England.
I first saw Mary in the
archaelogical site in the
role of Eurydice in the
play of Sofocles, Antigone.
A play performed by the
theater group of Eleusis.
She had something of the greatness that the
chthonic deities of this place possessed.
In other respects, Mary
is a person like the
rest of us, with the
same modest concerns
and who the narrow limitations of
this city prevent her developing.
We saw her 10 years later in the
same city with her two children.
Panagiotis Vasiliou
works here at the port.
As an amateur player he has played many
roles. Aegisthus in Aeschylus' Agamemnon,
Koryphaio in Antigone of Sofocles,
Agamemnon in "Iphigenie in Aulis".
I remember him telling me that he learned
his roles in the holds of the ships.
The water tube pased under the
Sacred Street. The work is finished.
The images of the ancient
Sacred Street no longer exist.
Neither the images of the excavations
we've seen all these years.
The building in the Vasiliou
plot has been built.
The wall is in the basement.
We met Ms. Andro here in the
neighborhood in the summer of 1994.
It was the typical image
of a woman from Smyrna.
Lordly height, beauty, kindness.
She told me: "I do not remember
anything of what happened yesterday."
"I remember everything
we experienced in Asia Minor."
Did you like it?
This is the tree where Panagiotis
tied his horse when delivering milk.
Papa-Kostas, was a priest in the Church
of the Holy Apostles in Eleusis
for more than 50 years.
Often he paraphrased a verse
of the hymns of David:
"I shall be unworthy if I forget
about you my dear Smyrna."
The sepulchral column of the Liberis
plot, after the cleaning, has
proved to have belonged to another
priest, famous in history.
(Kalias, priest)
In the new city hall Ms.
Alejandra continues
updating the great
book of the world.
Sorry Martha, sorry Kostas, sorry
Politimi, sorry Orsalia, sorry Αngel,
sorry Michael, sorry
Demetrius, Giorgos, sorry Mrs.
Koula, sorry girls in the
church of Saints Apostles,
And the church of St. George
that you adorn the epitaph,
sorry Peter, Helen,
Mary, Antigone,
sorry Niniun, sorry Ermias,
sorry Aminoklia, Antiphon,
sorry Nicostrata, Kleokratia,
Isidoti, sorry Evnapios.
Sorry Popi, sorry Stratos, Vaggelis, sorry
Chrysa, sorry Stela, sorry Panagioti.
I couldn't occupy as much
time as needed with you.
Sorry Eleusis, the last
time I passed by the.
National Highway, I didn't
even glance at you.