- Ever since I was a little kid,
I've been obsessed with the idea
of extraterrestrial life in outer space.
It's like it was born in me.
- To me, it's not about belief at all.
It's about the truth and
it's about being open to
all the different hypotheses,
all of the different data
and just trying to learn
as much as we can.
- I've always been interested in UFOs.
It's just sort of been
a lifelong obsession.
- When I became a MUFON field investigator
and I started investigating
the phenomena for myself,
it was like a fish to water.
It was what I was meant to do,
what I was born to do.
I view it as a mystery.
I think it's
ridiculous to think that
there's not other life out there.
I like investigating things.
It's just in my nature.
So if this is all coming out soon,
you can't even talk about this.
You know the
old saying I want to believe.
That's me.
- Here we are with Jeff Krauss
outside of the MUFON headquarters here
in Newport beach. - We made it.
- We made it.
- In one piece. - Two pieces.
- One, two.
I think that MUFON's creed says it all.
The scientific investigation of UFOs
for the benefit of humanity.
- Well, it's the mutual UFO network.
They take in reports of
sightings and experiences
and put it all together
and sort of research
the entire subject.
- MUFON started out as a
midwestern UFO network.
1969, when project blue book,
the air force's official
investigation into UFOs closed,
that's when MUFON became
the mutual UFO network
and we've been doing the
air forces job ever since.
It's a private group.
We're all volunteers.
I've got a little team of
eight people that work,
ya know, under me at MUFON.
- Specifically, I'm
interested in astrobiology,
which is the search
for life on other planets.
Now, interestingly enough, most people
who are in the field of astrobiology
would not necessarily be interviewed
on a UFO documentary.
- Mostly, we do this out
of love for the phenomenon
and just a quest for
understanding this phenomenon.
The way I will do a UFO investigation,
if it's through MUFON,
I'll have a report come in.
People will, ya know, if you see a UFO,
you don't wanna call
the air force or the police
or ya know,
I mean, you could but
usually, they'll shuffle that
under the doormat.
But if you go to MUFON. Com,
it'll say report a UFO.
Ya click on that and
it'll ask you questions.
What area of the sky you saw it in,
what time of day or evening it was,
they'll wanna know where you were at,
ya know, what your city was.
I'll first sent the witness an email
and tell them who I am
and that I'm responding
to their MUFON report
and find out a good time
when we can talk on the phone
and schedule an interview with them.
- Part of it is a bit of a hunger.
Okay, I gotta figure out what this is.
I'm gonna do my best to
research and find it out.
I'm gonna go through newspaper reports.
I'm gonna search the
Internet for sighting reports
from other organizations or from ya know,
even social media, anything like that.
I'm gonna do everything I can.
I'm gonna look at local flight paths.
I'm gonna look at
everything I possibly can find
to try to determine what it might've been.
- If more people see the same thing,
then that's good too especially
because you have more
perspectives to go off of.
And you can find it which details match
in every account.
- When I start to get that going
where I'm not sure what it is yet,
so that sort of feeds itself.
The more exciting it is,
the more work I have to do.
Then there comes that moment when
I can't say and I sit on it for a while.
It bothers me.
It eats away at me 'cause I don't want to
close that report.
I don't wanna tell that witness
and I don't wanna tell the
other people in the organization
for sure that's an unknown.
I sit on it and I worry on it for a while.
And I think, I'm like I'll
leave it and I'll come back
to it the next day.
I'm like no, I gotta know what this is.
I gotta say what it is or what it's not.
And that gets even more exciting
but it's also nerve racking.
- Okay, if somebody
has just a UFO sighting,
just, right?
I mean, it's always a huge thing
when you see a UFO.
It depends on how distant it is.
If it's something that
was really in the distance,
then it's just like a visual thing
and ya know, it's like if
you saw anything else
in the distance, but sometimes,
when somebody sees
a UFO in the distance,
a weird thing happens.
It seems like this telepathic
connection happens.
Suddenly, the UFO is right on them.
- And usually, the last thing I do is
before I close the case, I
contact the state director
and our chief state
investigator and I say hey guys,
I think I might have something here.
Will you look at what I've got?
Look at my notes, look at my report,
and tell me what you think?
- In my mind, the holy
grail of UFO investigation
would be if you could
actually get some kind of
a material fragment
from the UFO, an artifact.
That's assuming that
they are physical objects
but let's say that they are for a second.
If you could get an actual piece of one,
that would be a game changer
because then you could take it to a lab.
You could look at its isotope ratios.
You can look at what
elements it's made out of
and ya know, you could see
if it matches what we know
could come from the earth.
And that would tell you
something pretty substantial
about where these things are actually from
or what their origin is.
- It's fun, it's exciting.
A lot of the basic day
to day investigations
can easily be done by remote.
Phone, video chat, email, that kinda thing.
Depends on the type of report it is.
Your basic day to day
hey, I saw something weird,
I can do that over the phone
when I conduct an interview
and I can go through
the investigation that way.
I'll research the locations,
go through, look at
the air traffic in the area,
check news reports,
everything that corresponds
on the date of the sighting
just so I can get an idea
of what that person did
or did not see or what may
or may not have happened.
As the type of sightings level up,
those would merit an
in person investigation.
Say to investigate an actual landing sight
or a face to face interview with somebody
who's actually had a
face to face experience
with something else.
All the way up to MUFON has a division
that does underwater research
with trained scuba divers.
They have a 24 hour response team.
So, ya know, if there's
another Roswell incident,
we can have people out there
within 24 hours on the ground.
I think the public would be surprised
to find out there's quite a few scientists,
ex military, police officers,
a lot of very highly credentialed people
involved in MUFON but
there's also housewives.
Just anybody who's
interested who wants to help.
- I think it helps.
If you're a pure skeptic, that's not good.
If you're like everybody is space brothers
and everything's a UFO,
that's not good either.
Ya know, you have to
be able to look at stuff
and try to be skeptical
and try to figure out
what prosaic thing that object might be
or what the person saw
and what it might've been
that's other than a UFO.
It's almost like you check everything off
and you just keep on
but at the end of the day,
if I can't find a scientific
explanation for that ya know,
sighting, there's your UFO.
Doesn't mean that it's
from an alien planet.
I mean, it might be a
black project of our own
that I'm not aware of yet.
But it's still unidentified
and that is what a UFO is,
an unidentified flying object.
- It's pretty easy actually.
You can go to MUFON's website
and you can read up on them
and see what they're all about.
You can become a member.
There's a little membership
fee and you get a newsletter
and there's different levels of membership.
After a couple years, I decided I wanted to
get more involved and I
applied to be an investigator.
There's a whole training process to that.
You sign up, you do the training,
you take tests and eventually,
you get certified as a field investigator.
- But that's pretty much how we do it.
We have generally three months limit
to how long we can take on a case.
I had somebody ya know, put in a UFO report
that was a rocket launch from
Vandenberg the other night.
He happened to be in
a boat off Catalina island
and it looked really strange.
Ya know, the space-x
launches do look strange.
Ya know, now the whole
ya know, bottom stage
will go and land back
on the landing platform.
So you've got all kinds of activity
and you can see that all in the sky.
I can understand why this person
thought it was a UFO.
I wrote the guy a really
nice email and told him
what it was he saw.
I said if you want, you can still talk.
We can talk.
Just let me know.
Send me a email back and I'll ya know,
explain it a little better
to you but, you know,
we knew about this rocket launch
and we were expecting people to report it.
- The vast majority of
the people I've spoken to
are excited about it.
They wanna know, like what was it?
What did I see?
What is it?
Did anybody else see it?
They wanna know what did you think it was?
I've talked to a couple
people who were just thrilled
that they even had the opportunity,
that the thing happened to them,
that they saw this or
that they had this contact.
Some people do ask me
directly, what was this?
Because they feel like
when they speak to me,
they speak to someone from MUFON,
they think we're the experts.
We should know.
But we don't always know.
And that's kinda the point.
We don't know.
We want to know.
We're trying to gather the information
from all these different sources,
from all these reports,
so that we can say
it is this or it is this.
We can't always say that.
My favorite reports are the ones
that we classify as unknowns.
An unknown is basically when
you can not definitively say
what it was or was not.
You know, there's a situation
where somebody saw something,
maybe they might even have photographs.
And you can within a certain percentage
of reasonable doubt say that
was an airplane of some kind.
I can't tell you what kind it was.
I can't identify it, but it
was a man-made vehicle
of some sort or it was a
satellite or it was whatever,
a planet, a star, that's one thing.
An unknown is where you can't say for sure.
I can say I'm looking at this picture and
that could be an airplane.
That's my favorite.
Those, to me, are the
most exciting ones because
it really makes you think.
You have to really do the research.
You have to talk to the people.
You have to look into all parts of it
and you really have to be sure
you can not say what it is or is not.
They're probably the
more rare cases that we get
but for me, they're the most exciting ones.
They're the ones that keep me interested.
- Yeah, a lot of them could
be secret craft or ya know,
atmosphere plasma
phenomenon or misperceptions.
Again, most of them are.
But there are still those cases
where you have something
flying in really aerodynamically
bizarre ways, right?
It's suddenly stopping
at some insane g-force.
It's reversing direction.
- I do my best to not,
I don't wanna burst someone's bubble.
If someone really believes
hard they saw something
and they're excited about it,
I don't wanna break up that for them.
I will do my best to
explain that I can't say
for sure what that is.
I can't tell you that is an
alien or UFO or whatever.
I can only say what I think it might be
or what it wasn't.
- The answer is that in most cases,
you can't ever know
that anything is for sure.
But what ya can do is you can at least
try to rule out any
conventional explanation.
- There's times where
I absolutely have to say
man, it's balloons man, I'm sorry.
There was a birthday party down the street
and those are balloons that got away.
I try and make that as easy as possible.
For me, it's not a
matter of disappointment.
I'm there to just figure
out to my best ability
what it is or what it is not.
- Ya know, there's a lot
of different ideas out there
about what UFOs could be.
Classified technology from
this country or that country,
drones, could they be just sort of people
misperceiving things, well
yeah, they are most of the time.
Could they be some kind of
new atmospheric phenomenon?
Could it be some kind of a plasma,
like ball of lightning or something?
Could it be extraterrestrial?
I would say something
like 98% of UFO sightings
have a complete prosaic explanation
and are completely explainable as
people misperceiving
things and optical illusions.
Sift out the minority of UFO
reports that are interesting
from the majority that
are just sort of people
seeing the international space station.
What you really have to do is go in,
look for every explanation,
and rule it out one by one.
It's really all about
skepticism in a lot of ways.
If you can't debunk it,
then by definition, it's a UFO.
So it's one thing that I
would say a lot of people
kind of mistake.
A UFO isn't just an unidentif, or UAP,
it's not just an unidentified flying object
or unexplained aerial phenomenon.
It's something that's
unidentified or unexplained
after you've done everything
in your power to explain it.
Does that mean it's necessarily aliens?
- I know what I want it to be.
I want it to be contact from other planets,
from other civilizations.
That's what I really want it to be.
I think it's ridiculous to think that
there's not other life out there.
- There's this idea that
they call the fermi paradox
which is like the sort of
statement in astronomy
of like, where is everyone?
Where are all of the aliens
if there's so many
stars out there that could
host life and so forth?
Classic argument against UFOs being alien
is it's too, stars are too far away.
It takes too much energy to get here
from another star system.
So, how are they doing that?
Why are they doing that?
How could they possibly have
enough time to do that anyway
because it's just really and it is true.
Stars are really far away.
It'd take the voyager
which is the furthest thing
we've ever sent out of the solar system,
something like 50,000 years
to leave the solar system.
The other side of it is
that space is very big.
It's also very, very,
very, very, very, very old.
So if you took the age
of the universe and put it,
scaled it down to a calendar year,
all of human history happened in the last
60 seconds of January 31st.
Yes, there's the stars very far away
and it'd take a very long time.
But there has been enough time.
So, let's say an alien
civilization wanted to spread out
throughout the galaxy, right?
The way they would do it is
they would send out one craft
to a neighboring star system.
It would get there.
It would arrive in the
equivalent of the asteroid belt
or whatever, consume some matter,
and then it would maybe 3D print out
a dot or probes and send
those every which way
to different solar systems.
And keep doing that.
Now, you'd get kinda the snowball effect
where within a few million years,
you could blanket the
entire galaxy with probes
and it's possible to do it in a timescale
that is much, much less
than the age of the galaxy
which is somewhere
around 10 billion years old.
Is it kinda crazy if they're
driving their spaceship
from Zeta Reticuli every Monday
to go hover over Billy Bob's farm?
Sure it is.
But it's not ludicrous
to say that their probes
could've passed through the solar system,
ya know, waves of traffic from that kind of
colonization scenario,
could be in the solar system.
They could be hiding
somewhere in the asteroid belt
or the Kuiper belt, the edge
of the solar system, wherever,
and maybe if they are, they
periodically send their probes
to observe the earth.
And that is within
physics, within astronomy,
within astrobiology, a
completely reasonable thing
to speculate about and
it's completely possible.
- When I was five years old,
my mom did disclosure for me.
Now it wasn't a family secret.
We all knew that mom worked
as one of Howard Hughes'
two private personal secretaries
but when I was five, for whatever reason,
my mom got talkative and she just told me
about what she, about a story,
about what she'd gone through.
That when she was working for Hughes,
that they took her out to this,
to the middle of nowhere, she said it was
a great American desert.
She had a little security detail with them
and there was this bunker or this shack
is the way that she put it, a shack,
and made outta concrete and
kind of low slung to the ground
and it looked like nothing.
She said that she wondered why they were
taking her out to where
it looked like maybe
they kept tools or ya know,
machinery or something.
But they opened up the doors.
Everything's locked and secured.
There was an elevator.
So, she got into the elevator with a couple
of security guys and she
thought that it was gonna
go down a couple of floors.
But it kept going down.
And she said it just kept
going and it seemed to have
a bit of speed to it and she
felt butterflies in her stomach
but when it finally stopped moving,
she said that the doors opened up
and there was a little
city there under the desert.
She said that they had this one,
that they had little cafes and places
where you could get food and movie theaters
and bowling alley
and she talked about how it was funny,
there was this one cafe that
had these yellow umbrellas
over all the little tables,
like a French cafe.
She seemed to get a kick outta the fact
that they had umbrellas in a cave.
But it is apparently to
make people feel comfortable
with their surroundings.
My mom said that there were a lot of German
rocket scientists that work down there.
Now I tried, I would ask my mom
what were you guys working on down there?
She would never answer that question.
I still don't know.
I still have no idea.
In my investigations, there was one guy
who was a RAF pilot whose
mom was another secretary
for Hughes and she told him the same story.
I heard this from a friend of his.
She was more detailed
when she talked about the lab.
She said it was Howard Hughes' lab.
They had a little cat walk
that went over everything
so you could see what they
were working on down there.
It was a quite elaborate set up.
It was like something out
of James Bond, but real.
- I would say that I was
always really fascinated by
just the question of
other life in the universe.
I grew up very into science fiction.
Basically just my young
imagination kinda got captured
by this idea of other life
out there in the universe
and when we find it, what would happen
if we made first contact.
- The first time I really
heard her talk about it
and she would kind of say in general,
well, we're not alone.
We're not alone in the universe.
There's too many stars, too many planets,
it's impossible.
So, she didn't say that she had
learned that anywhere exotic.
There was one incident where my cousins
were out visiting and my aunt brought
a copy of look magazine and
it had the Betty and Barney hill
story on the cover.
While my aunt was very
skeptical about the Betty
and Barney hill case,
she was ya know, saying
that well how would this happen
and how wouldn't everybody
else have seen this,
ya know, a space ship coming down?
Wouldn't the air force have known about it?
Blah, blah, blah.
My mom said to her,
"from what I know, what I've learned,
"this could very well
have actually happened."
We aren't alone and the
government knows this.
My aunt, at that point
said, "oh well, this is crazy.
"It's like a bad science fiction film."
It says that they stuck
a needle into her naval.
That was the first time I
heard my mom say that,
ya know, that this was a real thing,
that UFOs were real and that the phenomena,
there was something to it.
- When I was very little,
I thought I was being
visited by monsters or devils or something
when I was a little kid.
The whole like frozen in place thing,
the bed lifting off the ground,
things in the room moving, weird sounds,
footsteps, things like that.
Being frozen in place and I
have very specific memories of
things like the bed
being lifted off the ground
and actually being tilted so to sort of
slide me off the end of
the bed, that kinda thing.
Because I'd been into
UFOs and things like that,
I started thinking that's what it was.
Little bit later on, jump
forward into the 90s a bit.
Ya know, there's a thing
called the Internet now.
I was reading on a news
group about UFO abductions
'cause I was kinda feeling
like that was what was
going on, I was pretty
convinced at the time.
And then, I found out about
a thing called sleep paralysis
where you are essentially
between sleep states.
Your body is shut down
but your mind is still moving.
Your eyes are even open
giving the sensation
of being frozen in place.
And almost hallucinating
while you're doing it.
So a lot of people will
report hearing footsteps,
seeing shadows around the room,
activity just outside of the peripheral,
just outside of your vision.
Turns out I've had it
chronically my entire life,
which isn't as common and
that's what I was experiencing.
That did feed directly
into my interest in UFOs.
I've talked to people who have had
genuine abduction situations.
That's not what I was experiencing.
A lot of people think
they're being abducted
and it turns out to be sleep paralysis.
And I think sometimes people
maybe are being abducted
and everyone tells
them it's sleep paralysis
when it's not.
It's kind of a gray area.
But that fit into my
interest, got me deep into it
'cause I wanted to research all about it
up until I figured out
what this condition was.
- So this happened back in 2017.
I was taking astronomy at
the local community college.
We had been observing the
moon for a really long time,
mapping craters and so forth.
So I was trying to get
the telescope trained
on the Orion nebula and then,
I heard this group of people behind me,
another group on a different telescope,
freaking out about some object in the sky.
They're going like holy
shit, what is that thing?
So ya know, I was like okay, ya know,
the moon and the Orion
nebula are gonna be here
for a few billion more years.
I'm gonna have plenty of
other chances to look at those.
This thing might not be
here for another second.
I better go see what it is.
I walk over to where they're all pointing
and I'm standing there and what it was,
it was this v-shaped object.
It was gunmetal black
and there were four big
circular white lights
down either arm of the V.
Sort of like what was seen in the 1997
Phoenix lights incident
if you know that one
and it was just drifting
along really, really slowly.
One of the other witnesses
said looked like it was going
something like 15 miles per hour.
Really low, really, really, really low.
It was started maybe
level with the tree tops
and never got above about
1,000 feet, I would say.
It was pretty big in the night sky.
I would say it was comparable to
if you've ever seen the full moon.
It just kept on going and kept
on going and kept on going
and then, after about 20ish seconds,
it kinda got to a point and so,
this is where my account
diverges with the other witnesses.
I remember seeing
something a little bit different
from the other people that were there.
What I distinctly remembered is
when it got to the point where it stopped,
it looked to me almost like it faded into
the rest of the sky.
The best way I could describe
it is it was like the borders,
these edges of this V
shaped craft were very sharp,
very distinct and it was
kinda like the borders
looked to me like they were getting almost
fuzzier and fuzzier until the structure
kinda faded into the rest of the sky.
That's what I remember.
Now, the only witnesses only,
the other witnesses
remember it differently.
They remember just seeing it trail off
until they couldn't see it anymore.
So they didn't see it cloaking.
What I'll say about that
is that no two people
are gonna remember an event the same way.
So if I see a car crash,
I'll say it was a red Honda
or something and you might say it was
a orange Lamborghini and
that's an extreme example
but everyone remem...
Details of any remembered
eyewitness account
are gonna differ in certain ways.
But we all agreed that it was there.
We all agreed that it happened.
There were three other people.
So I was like okay well,
I saw something weird,
didn't get a video.
I'm kind of annoyed about that, ya know?
Especially as a scientific sort of person.
I like to have evidence for things.
So, I said to myself, okay,
I want to investigate this.
I wanna figure out what I saw.
And I wanna see if I
can get to the bottom of it.
- The way that I became
a MUFON field investigator
was after my mom passed away.
I started just veraciously
reading the literature out there.
Ya know, before, when my mom was alive,
there was always that
chance she might give me
that golden ticket and finally, ya know,
just tell me outright everything.
There's no chance of that now.
I just kept on reading and watching shows
and finally realized ya
know, I'm no better off now
than I was before.
Ya know, I don't know who to believe
and what's true and what's bogus and what.
Around 2014 or 15, hangar 1 TV show came on
which was the MUFON produced UFO show
and it was a cut above everything else
that was out there.
It was ya know, from case files,
by watching that show, I finally decided
I wanna do this.
I wanna go and investigate my own cases
and that way, I'm not
reading about somebody else's
ya know, investigation they did.
I'm not questioning the
veracity of these reports.
It's feet on the ground, ya know?
And it's me doing it.
But I found my state
director who is Jeff Krauss
at that time and he told me, you know,
if you go to MUFON. Com,
it'll say become a
MUFON field investigator.
Just click on that and it'll
give you all the information.
Technically ya know, you
get the field investigator's
handbook which is excellent document.
Very professional.
Based on Dr. J. Allen
Hynek's work and Vallee,
Jacques Vallee's work.
And just these many ya know, 54 years now
that MUFON has been doing this.
So I studied the book
and then ya take a test.
They do a background check on you and stuff
because you don't want, ya
know, serial killers and stuff
doing this, yeah.
The next thing you know,
I was a field investigator.
I started getting cases.
You know, a case will
come in and the state director
will assign those cases.
That's what I do now is I'll
assign the cases to other,
my field investigator team.
Once in a while, I'll
see one that seems like
it has my name on it.
I feel an affinity for and once in a while,
I'll grab one for myself
now still 'cause ya know,
you're either a UFO
investigator or you're not, right?
So, I always have current cases going
but I share the wealth now.
- We don't have very many
confirmed cases where
I could actually take a piece of a UFO
and do a lab and study it.
But what we do have is
a lot of evidence of them
affecting the environment around them.
So we have evidence of
them bouncing radar waves
off of themselves.
We have evidence of
them having heat signatures
that can be picked up on infrared camera.
- There's definitely a great interest in
our military capabilities by our visitors.
This is why we see things like
my friend Robert Solas, for instance,
who was a commander
of an ICBM base in Montana
back in 1968.
They had a UFO that was hovering right over
the missile base.
The guy in the guard shack is calling down.
Everybody sees this thing.
Each missile went offline.
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
And then they went back online.
It's like this is what we can do.
Yeah you can build these things.
You can aim them at each other.
But you're not in control
of what finally really
actually happens to them.
We have final word on that.
I think it was a show of power.
It was also showing us, I mean,
this is a repeating thing that people hear
in alien encounters is that ya know,
nuclear weapons are evil,
that they will destroy humanity.
People are left with visions and dreams
after having a contact experience
of desolation like the
book of revelation, ya know?
But we brought it upon
ourselves is what people
are always told, that this is your future
if you're not careful.
I heard from one
interesting person recently
who told me Mars isn't
so much for colonization
as it is a learning tool for you guys.
This is what you will become
if you don't change your ways.
- We're now at an age where data is finally
being released about this stuff.
Tick tack stuff, yeah, the
USS Nimitz, all of those.
You had multiple eyewitnesses.
Honestly, that's nothing new.
That's been in the UFO
literature for decades.
The point is that now,
the only difference now
is that it's being talked about a lot more
in the mainstream.
So now, even NASA is
openly getting involved
in investigating UFOs.
That was something that was announced
just like three weeks ago.
- Well I know there's
been a string of sightings
over the years of military pilots
seeing strange objects
flying around while they're
up in the air and not just visual
but also being picked up on radar.
The pilots are picking it
up and the radar towers
and the bases are picking it up as well.
There's plenty of audio
recordings of the pilots
talking back and forth
and describing the sightings
as they're seeing them.
Seems like a lot of them are
taking place over the water,
over our coasts.
And there's a whole theory on aquatic UFOs.
I find it very interesting that
the military's finally acknowledging this
and releasing it.
- Best evidence I've heard of up till now,
I would say I would harken back to
what everyone kind of talks about which is
the tic tac incident.
- As far as the tic tac and
the way that the government,
I think that they were very, very,
very foot draggy about it.
I mean, this event happened in 2004.
It wasn't until 2017 that it
became public knowledge.
A video got out and there's
nothing that they could say
about that video.
It wasn't supposed to get out.
It went out privately on the sly
and one of the pilots,
ya know, he more or less
videoed his radar screen
or his flir video screen
of what they were seeing.
And there you see this
craft that's just doing things
that are impossible for
anything that we have to do.
- Yeah, there was no
visible means of propulsion
which is really weird.
Really, really weird.
I mean, that shouldn't be
possible with what we know.
No visible means of propulsion
and being able to do those maneuvers.
And being able to, I mean,
if you think about it right,
from a physics standpoint, if you're in a
really fast moving thing that's going at
thousands of gs and suddenly stopping,
you would be turned to
paste because ya know,
if you've ever been in a
car that suddenly stops,
you know that inertia is a thing.
You would be thrown
to the wall of the thing
really, really hard.
Somehow, that's not
happening to whatever is piloting
these things unless there is no pilot.
I think the likeliest version
of the extraterrestrial
hypothesis from what I know
is that they might be machines, probes.
- So I think that the
government was kind of forced
to acknowledge that yes, it's a thing,
and it opened up the whole can of worms.
- At one point I think the original footage
had been leaked out
and then a little while later,
the military officially released it.
That's an amazing step.
That's a huge step compared to the last
let's say 60, 70 years
where they just say no, no, it's nothing.
We don't know anything.
We don't research that stuff.
Turns out they have been
researching it all along.
They've been keeping tabs
on this stuff from day one.
- And I think that they
were afraid that if they put,
if they put stuff out to the public,
you're also putting it out to our enemies.
You're putting it out to other ya know,
other foreign nationals that might not have
our self interest in mind.
So I can see why they're
foot draggy about it.
I can see why they didn't
want that information out there,
but it's about time.
- I think these tic tac sightings
are a huge step in that direction
to getting what we call disclosure,
of the government saying
yes, here's what we know.
Here's what we've got
on file for all of this stuff.
They bleed it out a
little bit at a time to us
but I think there's a lot
more they're not saying.
I know there's a lot
- Cases where you have multiple sensors
that are all picking these things up.
So it's not just eyewitnesses
but it's all of these sort of things
that are designed to monitor the sky.
Ya know 'cause the thing is a delusion,
a hallucination can't
bounce radar waves off of it
and it can't show up on an infrared camera.
- Especially near air bases or anywhere
where they have nuclear weapons,
anything of that sort.
Sort of high security areas.
They tend to see that a lot more,
traditionally near missile
silos and things like that.
There's been plenty of
cases of anything from
just strange lights to
there's been historical cases
of having alarms and things being set off
or even triggering launch sequences.
There's even been reports of just
not military, necessarily,
but NASA test rockets,
test flights, being messed with,
seeing lights and seeing
things moving around
the launch site and having
the launch being shut down.
Oh, we didn't do it.
We'll keep shutting this off.
We'll keep ya know, breaking,
but nobody could figure out what it was
except that it lined up
with these weird lights
in these sightings at the time.
- It's very difficult, I'd say.
It's very difficult to do that with the,
at least the physics that we have,
but that's what makes
them interesting, right?
So the analogy that I would make is if,
if these are alien, they
are interstellar in origin,
then it's kind of like
the level of technology
that you would need to
do what I just described,
colonize the whole galaxy,
possible but very advanced.
Advanced enough, in fact,
that I would harken back
to Arthur C. Clarke's old quote,
"any sufficiently advanced technology
"is indistinguishable from magic."
It would be a little bit like
magic in the sense that,
ya know, if you sent a nuclear reactor
back to Victorian England,
that would really be
magic to them, ya know?
'Cause they don't understand.
That would've been before
Marie curie sort of figured out
radium and figured out ya know,
it wouldn't make any sense.
One signifier of
extraterrestrial technology
that got here from another star system
should be that it doesn't make sense to us.
It shouldn't make sense to us.
- I mean, yeah.
I mean, there's some
stuff I don't necessarily
like to say or talk about just because
I don't like to give definitive answers
and I also like, with cases
I've personally worked,
I don't like to talk too
much about it because
these are private citizens
that may or may not have said,
"hey, you can talk
about this or you can't."
When you file a report,
there is a box that says,
"do you wanna remain anonymous?"
Do you want to keep this stuff quiet
or do you care?
There's a thing for that.
I just assume, even if they don't care,
I don't like to say that,
"oh, this lady from this specific town
"on this specific day saw this thing."
Because people will
put two and two together.
They'll figure out that was Mary Jane
who lived in ya know,
Las Vegas, and she's a...
They'll figure that out
and maybe that person
doesn't want anybody to know about it.
So, I tend to shy away
from giving too much detail
on ya know, actual real
cases I've worked personally.
- Ya know, there's a few different reasons.
The subject was stigmatized
but it was more stigmatized
from the standpoint
of most of the scientists
involved in the search for life, obviously,
would tell you yeah,
there's probably life out there
or else they wouldn't be spending
their careers on it, right?
But the idea was ya
know, it's very difficult for
interstellar travel is really hard.
And why would the aliens
come here to just sort of
show up and hover over
some dude's farm in Kentucky
and abduct a few cattle.
Or you've heard the old
stereotype about UFOs.
You know about it.
So, that was a big part of it.
I think another thing is that UFOs
are very difficult thing to
study with the scientific method
because you can't predict
when a UFO is gonna show up.
So, if I wanted to
observe a star, let's say,
I could train my telescope on it
and I know that that star's
gonna be there tomorrow.
So I could train my telescope on it again.
So I can reproduce whatever I find.
UFOs, you don't know
when one's gonna show up.
You can't set up an observation station,
an experiment and
everything, because it's not,
it's completely unpredictable.
It's very difficult to sort
of get repeated tests.
- This is one case
that's just kind of a really
interesting straight ahead UFO case.
MUFON case number 95355.
Kinda blows me away and I do, ya know,
keep in touch with the main witness.
Witness and two friends
were on a weekend camping
fishing trip at lake
silverwood near big bear.
Driving in a rural area,
the witness observed
a bright Amber light that was flying
silently and low in the distance.
The object, he noticed
that the object didn't have
proper FAA lights on it,
so the witness pulled his
truck over to the shoulder
and all three witnesses
got out of the truck.
They were all leaning up
against the bumper of the truck
watching as the object slowly
approached their position.
As the object approached,
it resolved into an object
which the witness described
as a black boomerang
wedge-like shape, like a giant pair of
wraparound sunglasses.
By the way, I'll mention
that the main witness
of this case is an aerospace engineer
working for a major aerospace company.
All three witnesses could
hear a low humming sound.
We could feel it in our bones and our feet.
It was quite uncomfortable.
The witness's friend said that he made sure
the truck engine was turned off
as he had heard that UFOs can cause
car electrical problems and
cause an electrical system
to burn out.
And that's true.
We've seen that from case to case.
The witness states that
the object had four visible
decks on either side facing him
that he could actually
see backlit silhouettes of
either people or possibly beings
standing or walking on four louvered decks
which were visible behind a giant window
or what looked like a giant window,
which encased the front of the craft.
I'm guessing it was
some kind of a force field
or some material that we don't or,
don't know about.
As the object passed over the witness,
he could see four panels on the back
which had the look of electronic snow
like you see on a old television set
that's between channels.
And I've heard this in other cases too
where there's a propulsion system seen
and it looked almost like the snow
that you'll see on a television.
The witness states the
craft continued heading
on it's original trajectory
until it was finally
lost to their sight at the
visual vanishing point.
The witness who was on the
camping trip with his friends,
he worked as a lab technician doing
electroplating of circuitry boards
that were used exclusively
in aerospace work.
Guy as sharp as a tack.
No reason to make this story up.
Here's some of his interview.
He said, "I've never seen anything like
"what we witnessed that Sunday.
"We all saw it.
"My best friend who passed away last year
"was there as well.
"He didn't want to report this even though
"we did know about MUFON
when we had our sighting.
"But John recently passed
away which freed me up
"to finally put in a
sighting report about this.
"I don't know if it's
ours or if it's theirs
"but I'm hoping that you can help me
"because it looked like
a flying aircraft carrier."
I interviewed the witness.
It says here, you know, I
interviewed him thoroughly
three times over four months.
A witness never changed his story,
never embellished on what he had said.
What I'll do when I speak with somebody,
like in this case, there was
only one main witness left.
So I'll kinda cold call the person
and have them repeat so that ya know,
you know if somebody's
reading from a piece of paper
or if they're embellishing
or making something up
or if they're telling you
something from memory.
This guy had just all the
emotions that you would have
if you had seen something
amazing like that.
He said, "we were all talking to each other
"about what we were seeing.
"We were excited and scared
as well as you could imagine.
"We could see columns from deck to deck
"and on the most upper deck,
"we could see humanoid
figures moving around.
"We were saying things
like look at that guy.
"Is he driving that thing or what?
"It looked like somebody
was shining a light
"up at it like the UFO
that was seen in China."
There was a similar
sighting that was seen in
Beijing airport a few years ago.
"Everything around us
seemed to be crackling
"and I could feel my insides humming.
"Thinking of it now, I'm really glad that I
"turned off my truck.
"As we were looking
at the back of the craft,
"there were four boxes that were louvered
"and they shimmered like a
road on a hot summer day.
"The boxes looked like a TV
when there's no channels on.
"Black and gray from
top to bottom of the craft.
"When I worked in aircraft, I was once in
"the world's largest building
in Everett, Washington.
"I was aircraft hangar there
"and this would not fit in there.
"The ceiling would've
collapsed with all the structures
"having to be removed to fit it in."
The way that I closed this case was,
I said witness was to the point, lucid.
He never diverted from
his original interview
and his statements.
He recounted his experience from memory
and never stumbled around
in recounting his sighting
as if recalling a remembered incident.
Witness has worked for
many years as a technician
in the aerospace industry
having originally worked
in electroplating components
at his grandfather's company.
Considering the witnesses
background in aerospace
and the witnesses composure
and the levels of emotion
while describing his sighting to me
during the four methodical
interviews I conducted with him,
I believe the witness was describing
a remembered event
that he could not explain.
And I closed this as a
unknown aerial vehicle, a UFO.
That's one of my favorite UFO cases.
It's just no abduction,
no beings except possibly,
ya know, and I wonder
what this was, ya know?
Could it have been time travelers?
Was that us from the future, ya know?
It has kind of a human craft look to it.
Ya know, the aircraft carrier thing.
I could kinda see that, ya know?
In his illustration.
But certainly, I don't think it's something
that we have now.
Or if it is, it's quite secretive.
- Ya know, I've been
told time and time again
that ya know, the more you do this,
the more involved you
get with UFO research.
You tend to start having those experiences
like you somehow, you pop
up on their radar somehow,
whoever they are.
They realize you're interested
and you're poking around,
so they poke back eventually.
I haven't had that happen yet.
It's a little frightening.
Depending on the degree
of poking that's being done.
But I do wanna experience that for myself.
- If anybody out there,
if you've had an affinity
for the things that I've been talking about
and you'd like to do this yourself,
it's not only very possible.
It's pretty easy to do.
You just apply yourself, read the book,
take the test, and then
you start getting cases
and we mentor you at first.
You know, we have a
mentorship program that we do
that kinda gets people up
to square when they first join
and before you know it,
you're going out on cases.
90 to 95 percentage of
cases are prosaic objects
that people misidentified.
But that five to 10
percent that I can't explain,
that's what keeps me going
and keeps me doing this
day in and day out.
I don't foresee a time in my life
where I won't be doing this.
I've got the bug.
I love it and you can do it too.
- And that's kinda the
point of it too is that
MUFON's a safe place
to submit these reports.
You can absolutely do it
anonymously if you want.
You don't have to give
your personal information
if you don't want to.
You can check the box that says
keep my name out of this.
Don't contact me.
I'm just giving you this information
because someone needs it.
Absolutely free to do that.
You know the old saying,
I want to believe.
That's me.
- I think that's really what
it's all about in the end.
It seems to be working now because ya know,
I've got a team working
under me and I've got ya know,
speaking engagements
and I get to tell people
about this amazing
phenomena which is like magic
but real, ya know?
And I love it.
I love it.
There's no way I'll ever not be doing this.