Thank you very much.
So?
It's beautiful!
Quieta!
Talk to me.
Talk to me like when you read
the weather report.
Come on, come on, please.
Good evening.
...Like the synoptic chart shows,
in the...
...Antarctic territory...
extreme temperatures are expected...
Say the morning fog...
The temperature will...
10º Fahrenheit.
Morning fog...
The morning fog...
Temperatures are
between 3 and 13...
In Valdivia the humidity
surprises the southerners...
In Temuco, Concepción and Talca...
...changing to clear skies...
Cheers, my love...
Cheers...
29 grados...
to the north...
it becomes unbearable.
In the Elqui Valley...
...thanks to the Pisco Sour.
...the situation becomes unbearable.
I need a cigarette...
Do you have
the lighter somewhere?
This fucking place stinks...
UNFAITHFUL WOMEN
Come on...
Four, three, two, one.
62% of the Chilean women,
is or has been unfaithful
to their couple.
This figure was obtained
thanks to a survey...
performed by the United Nations.
This is the topic
that we will address tonight...
in Mario Guzman's report.
Good evening, Mario.
Good evening,
we are here with Eva Soler,
psychologist,
specialist in sexual disorders...
who is here to explain
these figures...
Good evening Eva,
thank you for being with us.
Welcome.
Hello, thank you.
Tell us, I understand that
around 1600 women...
were surveyed in the country.
And the results of this survey gives us
an absolute and categorical conclusion.
We are in the first place at a worldwide
level in that topic, is that so?
Yes, and for an extensive margin.
We are definitely the world
champions in female infidelity...
Men only surpass us.
It can be deduced then that
we are the world champions of the cuckolds.
This makes us appear ridiculous,
of course.
That is a very masculine
point of view.
But you must consider that...
without the active
participation of males...
these figures
would not be possible.
What do you mean by
the active participation of men?
Well, in the first place,
to cheat on a man
I have to do it with another man,
unless I am a lesbian,
which is another possibility,
in the second place,
a woman cheats for a reason,
women do not cheat
just because they are horny...
We have a strong monogamous instinct
unless we are profoundly unhappy.
Excuse me... you said
monogamous instinct...
That is women can go
against their instinct for revenge?
Revenge is one of the motives mentioned
though not the most important.
The woman does not feel loved,
in general. She doesn't feel valued,
and that inhibits her sexually
with her couple,
you see then what a woman
looks for when being unfaithful...
is really a boyfriend,
is to regain the sensation
she had with her husband...
in the beginning,
when he complimented her,
acknowledged her,
he loved the way he was. So...
it would never be about
a woman would for being fresh,
to put it in a way,
would be unfaithful?
Yes, well there are women
that are more passionate.
But there are few women
that manage to separate
affection from sex.
Thus, they tend to
build a relationship
that lasts in time.
We do not have much
time left, Eva,
Tell me, what attitude should
men have to revert this figure?
In case they care...
do you think men care about it?
I don't think men are
foolish enough
...to not realize
that choosing to be distant
can bring consequences.
Now, they could
make themselves
responsible of the following
mathematical equation:
A man in Chile works
an average of 12 hrs a day,
we are including transportation,
food, etc.
He watches TV a couple of hours,
sleeps around 6 hours
which is not a lot
...and we are not considering
the dentist,
the buddies, the ex wife,
the children... and the mother
- two hours, gives us a total of 22 hours.
- Right.
2 hours, dedicated to sex...
Don't you think it's more
than enough to satisfy
the most passionate
and demanding woman?
I want you to make
love to me.
Excuse me?
Yes there is something
that is not being understood,
what an unfaithful woman
looks for
is not exactly
sexual satisfaction,
it does not go alone,
in the woman's case.
Now, even if it
were that way
the monthly average of orgasms
of a married woman
in Chile is 1.2 orgasms.
It is worrying.
Amazing.
That demonstrates that
it is not working
- ...with those 2 hours.
- No, absolutely.
Unfortunately we ran
out of time but
before we say goodbye
I would like to invite you
to our next program.
That is all for today,
we thank you
for your being with us
and wait for you
tomorrow as usual
at the same time
in our news space.
See you tomorrow, Mario,
thank you very much
for this interesting topic.
More than interesting
I would call it polemical.
Cecilia, which group
do you belong to?
The 62% or the 38%?
Good night.
Cut!
Ready?
Ready, yes. Goodbye.
Bye.
Thank you
Thanks to you.
Cecilia, you know him well.
You know he likes
to provoke.
Don't take it like something personal.
He's an asshole.
I don't want to see Mario again.
Please calm down
and listen to me.
I cannot fire him just like that.
He has just renewed
his contract with the channel.
What language
do you want me to use?
Take him off my side,
I don't know,
send him to the streets,
let him look for UFO's,
vampires,
I don't give a shit.
He pisses me off,
he makes me nervous,
I can't make the questions.
So take him away,
as far as possible. OK?
All right, but please
lower your voice.
I'll see what I can do.
Here, your husband
has called you twice.
Just what I needed.
That... I want you
to make love to me.
But, Virginita,
we are having dinner.
Yes, but I want to
make love to you now.
Honey, could you wait
till I finish dinner
and we are in a more
appropriate place?
Ok, honey, forget it.
Wait a minute, Virginia.
Sorry, but what happens
if I'm tired of waiting?
Sorry, is this a complaint?
You should be happy
with the things you have, Virginia.
And enjoy them.
And not behave like a
spoilt and pampered girl.
Do you understand me?
Ok, honey,
from now on you won't hear
any more complaints from me.
Hello, Francisco.
What is the matter?
Late, like every Wednesday,
why?
Did you use the thermometer?
That's not much,
give her half an aspirin.
I can't, I have a
production meeting.
I'll have to let you go,
Francisco,
the meeting starts in 10 minutes.
And I have not prepared anything.
No, don't wait up.
Kiss.
Me too, bye.
Meeting?
Go to hell!
Be careful.
Be very careful, Cecilia.
Out of my way, asshole.
Out of my way!
Mario.
What's up, everything alright?
Yes. I'm leaving.
Look, be prepared because
I have a little job for you.
Today?
Yes, now.
Now?
Yes, we have to do this
for the late night news.
In a Firemen's Quarters?
What's wrong with that?
This is a joke...
Excuse me?
Is this a joke?
Of course not.
It needs to be done
and we are going to do it.
That's it. That's it.
What a kiss ass!
What do you mean
I put my ass on the line
to give you
what you deserve
once a week
...and it's not enough.
And I don't...
Yes, you too.
But why do we have
to talk about it now?
Because.
But why now? We
are going to have a good time...
Because of Mario Guzman.
Who cares about thatjerk?
What's he got to do with it?
What do you mean who cares
... that asshole knows something.
He's going to make this go public.
Would you like a scandal?
Don't be paranoid,
nothing's gonna happen.
I'm not being paranoid.
I think we have to
assume the fact
...that this is notjust
being horny.
I'm not so sure this is
not being horny
Come on, Alberto, I mean it.
We can't go on like this.
We have to assume
the truth
and say that we are together
and that's it.
OK.
Hey, come with me.
You're lovely.
Then lets go.
Lets leave this place.
What are you thinking of?
Alvaro.
Lets not talk
about him now.
- Hey, I have a present for you.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Why?
Why? Because
you are the prettiest,
the hottest woman.
The best mother...
What is this?
I know it might be
corny,
but it is what I feel for you.
Tell me...
then we take it from the top.
And then
we come back to the van.
Lets go,
it's already late.
Ok, luck to you...
Nice fire engine.
Shall we make some shots here?
Yes, it could be... but no...
wait a minute...
Check it out,
the engines are brand new -Yep.
Modern, eh.
Hello, yes, working. Yes,
but I left you a message.
I can't do anything right now,
what do you want me to do,
I'm working.
I don't like it either.
I don't like it
That's how it is...
she hang up, the bitch.
Take it easy.
Idiot, retarded.
Three.
We are beating the record...
I want to marry you. Cecilia.
As if it were that easy...
At least we have
a divorce law.
We have to do something,
they will catch us any moment
and shit's going to
hit the fan.
I need a cigarette.
Do you have
the lighter there?
Thrilling news.
You come here
looking for thrilling news...
I don't know
if I offend you
but we are in Santiago,
not in New York.
Really, there's not much
happening here.
If you want we can go in
and sit down to continue talking...
A bomb!
It was near.
Near.
18 restore, 19 attack.
Lets go! Quick.
Lets move, quick!
An explosion destroyed
part of a motel in our capital.
One of our mobile units has
just arrived at the scene
In a few moments
we will have live images.
Well, we would usually
begin with a "good evening"
but there is nothing
good about tonight,
Just a few seconds ago
a bomb damaged great part
of the motel behind me,
located in the most exclusive
neighborhood of our capital
...Firemen are...
Hey,
we are going to get burnt!
Hey.
Turn it off, turn it off.
Turn the camera off.
Don't fuck me up.
I scratch you're back
you'll scratch mine... alright?
What are you doing here!
Get out right now!
Come in, come in...
I told you we should leave,
Mario.
Don't chicken out now,
asshole.
We'll save the year
with this report.
I'll make a phone call.
Hello, hello, yes,
Mario Guzman here.
Tell him that we are
inside the motel now,
tell him we are in the motel
We need to be on air
any minute now.
Surprise.
Announce shocking images,
Tell these assholes that
I'll make the report.
I'll begin it and finish it.
I don't want any censoring.
No censoring. OK, bye.
The images that we have captured
are really overwhelming
and difficult to reproduce
for you,
that is why we have
decided to enter this room,
a random room,
in order for you to see
what is happening in this place.
In order for you to see
We can see that the
structural damages are immense.
Glass, an intense gas smell.
We want to warn you that
the images we will show
...now may be shocking.
There is a body
of a person on the carpet,
our camera man, Kike Inostrosa,
is trying to identify him,
The images are really astonishing,
we are the first ones...
Shit hit the fan, man.
It's Valdes.
It's Alberto Valdes, man.
Lets get out of here.
Yes, Yes I hear you, What?
We were cut off.
We are off the air.
What are we going to do?
Hello. I understand.
I understand, OK, OK.
What did they say?
Shit hit the fan.
Nobody wants to take
responsibility for this.
Lets get out of here, Mario.
No, we are not leaving.
No man comes to a motel alone.
Hello, Ramirez, this is Teresa Vial.
Where the hell do I look.
Hello... ok, ok.
I get it, perfect.
They don't want
any more images of Valdes.
We will be on air
in 10 seconds.
Bitch, I knew it, bitch.
We continue, live.
TV 6 to show you
what is going on this motel,
we are in the presence
of a second victim,
we don't know who it is...
we want to warn you that
what we will show
now may be highly shocking.
We will see who it is...
Go to bed, dear.
But I can't sleep.
Go to bed, I said.
Hello... Listen...
Anything else?
Sorry? Hello, hello.
We are back with this impacting news,
from the place of the scene,
our reporters are on site.
Go ahead Mario.
Hi, come on in.
Excuse me.
What happened?
Forgive me for
bothering you now.
But I tried to get you
on the phone
but it wasn't on.
I turned it off because,
you know I was on TV.
Yes... Then it started ringing
so often that I turned it of.
Yes, I saw you.
You looked great,
congratulations...
Weren't we supposed
to meet on Friday?
Yes, but I needed
to talk to you now
...I couldn't wait until Friday
Come in.
What is the problem.
Did you run out
of medication for your anxiety?
No, no, that is very much
under control.
So, then...
Then, what happens to me
is calledAlejandro.
Alejandro, who is he?
Do I know him?
The horticulturist.
Remember I told you
I was building
a hydroponic orchard
in my house?
Well, he started
working this week.
He arrived on Monday, very early.
An early bird!
Well, I saw him
and I liked him immediately,
then the morning passed
and I looked out
to see him in the garden
...and then at midday
I gave him some lunch,
because he had been
working all morning,
poor thing,
under the sun.
- OK.
- Poor thing... imagine.
And I couldn't stop looking
at him through the window,
I was like obsessed.
I was feeling things,
I was like his slave...
I saw him working and,
and it was then when
I think, I had an orgasm.
You had an orgasm?
But did you touch yourself?
A little bit.
And did you feel
pleasure?
Did you feel you got somewhere?
I don't know.
Did you like it?
Of course I did. I felt
something I had never felt...
...before.
Like electricity...
But, he's not my husband,
can you imagine that?
What's wrong with that?
I feel terribly guilty
Hey, your husband has not
touched you in months
And this man
did not touch you.
I wish he had touched you.
I can't get him off my mind.
Where from? Come on,
there's nothing wrong with that.
Your lucky,
I'm glad for you.
But, what do I do?
It doesn't feel right.
You have to be faithful...
Yes you're right.
I totally agree with you.
I have a husband...
And whether I like it or...
I'm not talking about
your husband.
I'm saying you have
to be faithful to yourself.
To your nature...
This is your life...
Your husband may be
an accident in your life
But your orgasms
are your responsibility.
You follow
the path of the orgasm.
Orgasms are a human right.
I have called you
a hundred times.
I must have had my cell phone
turned off after the meeting...
I thought you were
with Cecilia Ureta but no,
I just saw her
on the news.
In a fire in a motel.
Naked.
Can you tell me what's going on?
Who were you with?
I was in a meeting.
Look at me,
...who were you with?
I was in a meeting
...Cecilia didn't turn up.
We found out what happened,
I was going to tell you now but...
excuse me
I'm going to the toilet.
Excuse me
Sorry, I only told you
what Cecilia asked me to say.
She's my friend.
Come on!
I wander how many
guys you have slept...
...with in these
production meetings.
If you had charged for it
we would be millionaires.
Hey, please, Alvaro,
ask whomever you want.
But who am I going to ask?
The asshole that's
sleeping with you now?
Come on, say the truth.
Say the fucking
truth for once.
Here's all Cecilia's production
phone numbers.
Please ask one by one
who have I slept with.
Don't be ridiculous!
Who's going to
answer this late.
As if they were sleeping
after what happened.
You know what?
I'm going out and
when I come back
you'll have to
tell me the truth.
Good evening.
I am the husband.
Well, your wife is alright.
Her vital signs are stable
and she will recover soon.
That's good.
Can I see her?
We are waiting for her
to regain conscience.
Jaime,
another whisky, please.
Hey, come on,
calm down.
No, no, it's about me.
It's about me not about her
I don't give a shit about her.
It's my honor,
my pride
The shame that
I have to go through.
Take it easy.
They are looking
at us, man.
Hey, look,
Carola is a loyal woman.
She's helping Cecilia.
You got confused
and paranoid.
No, no, I am not
paranoid at all.
I know there's something
else. I don't know what it is.
I know there is
something else.
I have this doubt.
I want to know whether
she's fucking me or not.
If she's unfaithful or not.
Lower your voice,
lower your voice.
I can't.
Take it easy.
Somebody gave me this,
but I don't need it.
Here, this may help you.
What is this?
Lts for cuckolds.
What do you mean cuckold?
For paranoids.
How do you mean paranoid?
Well, they work in infidelities.
Hey, do you want to
find out the truth or not?
They can help you.
Vilches y Liverona
Hey,
are you going to be alright?
Don't worry about me.
I'll be fine.
Stay calm.
We have work tomorrow.
It's going to be a tough day
Just one more drink
and I leave.
So I can go now then.
Yes. Please, I mean no,
no... you can leave
You're going to be alright?
Yes, I'll be fine,
I'll be fine.
Take care. Relax.
Relax!
You don't know
the amount of money
...that I spent
in the hair stylist.
Charming, waxed,
lots of perfume
you know?
Nothing.
The champagne was there,
the glasses,
I wanted to do it all.
The school girl, the nun,
the whore,
the nurse. Nothing.
Tell me about it.
And then
he got home angry,
speaking on the cell phone,
of course.
Typical.
He throws his jacket,
then sits turns on theTV.
And then...
starts telling me a story
about a Japanese executive
that planted lettuces
in some sort of sponge.
What do I know?
What do I care about
lettuces in a sponge?
That must be Roberta's flight.
Are you carrying
something like pastrami?
No, sir.
Could you open your suitcase,
please?
Yes, sure.
You know, miss that despite
the international treaties
and the free commerce
agreements
that we have with
the rest of the foreign countries,
it is strictly forbidden
to bring to our territory
any kind of animal,
vegetables, mineral and others...
that may jeopardize
our fellow citizen's health.
Yes.
And this is for personal
or commercial use?
Personal.
Nothing at all.
An hour and a half.
I better turn the engine of.
It was about time.
Hey, do you know
how much the fuel costs?
No, How much?
What?
550 pesos.
We have to change this truck.
Why, man?
We just cannot afford it.
We'll have to make an effort.
No, I don't want to
make more efforts.
I want to change this truck.
I don't like it.
Lets buy a city car.
A what?
A city car.
What's that? Don't you
know what a city car is?
No idea.
It's a concept
the Japanese invented
which is a
car for the city, cheaper,
smaller and much
more comfortable.
What are we going to do
when we go to the beach?
I'm not going back to Llo Lleo.
What's wrong with Llo Lleo?
I don't like it.
I don't like Llo Lleo.
Smells like fish.
I don't like it. I hate it
Llo Lleo, Llo Lleo,
it reminds me of a joke.
Which one?
The one about the queers...
I hate thatjoke.
You're a pain.
You have to make fun
about everything
The thing is make fun
of everything.
What's up?
My pussycat.
What's this wonderful surprise?
We have to talk.
Come in then.
What's that look on your face?
Look, I'm not going to
wait for a fucking erotic dream
to come to my bed
to have pleasure.
No, I think it's far out
of the question.
Do you want to end
up like her?
No, dummy.
What will she be like?
Who? The Spaniard?
Charming.
She's not from Spain.
She has been in Spain
for about 8 years.
Yes, but she is Chilean.
How long does it take
a Chilean to stop being one?
She takes a plane
and that's it.
Arrives in Miami,
takes her bra off
and she wont say huevon ever again.
We're gathered here
to say goodbye
to a great man.
A man of those
that unfortunately
are very few left
His generosity,
his righteousness,
will make the ones
that met him difficult to forget.
His kind soul.
Excuse me, father.
It seems that you have
mistaken the deceased.
Excuse me?
Inside this coffin
there is no great man.
So lets get this over
and done with
and lets go to the channel.
There is a lot to do.
I, I can talk to him.
Tell him that I love you.
I will die.
He will understand,
I promise.
And after that what?
Then, even if
It sounds childish,
even if it is foolish,
we grab my bike
and we go far away.
We grab my bike
We go to Mendoza
and make love
in every corner, love.
Look at me.
We leave together.
Don't make things
more difficult.
Look at me.
Yes, look at me.
You, you love me.
You love me,
because if you don't
I'll disappear. I leave.
And you will never
see me again.
Do you love me?
I love you.
Then lets leave.
We won't see each other
for a while, ok?
For a while? Why?
Until things calm down.
Promise me you're not
going to do anything foolish.
Promise me, ok?
Be apart for a while.
What is that shit.
What the fuck means
to be apart.
Shut up.
Lets go on to another topic.
Cecilia Ureta.
Mrs. Vial,
I imagine you'll want to
cancel her contract.
Zavala,
you have very little imagination.
Allow me to remind you
that Cecilia Ureta's program
is the one that has the
most important amount
of publicity in this channel.
So whether we like it or not,
Cecilia Ureta sells.
Her eyes sell,
her legs sell,
her lips sell.
Even her infidelity sells
So as soon as
she's recovered
I want her back in this channel.
But we don't know when
she will be in condition to do so.
Thus, we will have to
find someone to replace her.
Mario Guzman.
I think he won that position.
Make sure you contract
Eva Soler,
I want her together
with Guzman.
Lets talk more about
the Spanish woman.
What was that impressed
you so much about her?
To see her happy.
She was happy.
She was feminine,
an arrogance,
a smile,
do you get me?
I mean, it makes me question
my own life. I hate that.
And then when I went to
drop her off at the hotel,
sure, we had a nice conversation
but there came a moment when
I felt like crying my heart out.
Because,
how I wish to have
the bottle of champagne
in the soul, like her.
There she is,
there she is.
Is it her or not?
She's stunning.
Show the sign...
show the sign. It's upside down.
Further up, further up...
she can't see it.
Hello, Roberta?
Yes, Cristina Mujica,
pleased to meet you.
My pleasure.
Sorry, they are two,
In Spain they are two.
She is Virginia Zaldivar,
our architect.
Pleased to meet you.
One, two.
Well, how was your trip?
Excellent. Very good.
Good.
How long have you been
away from Chile?
Since I went crazy.
Too crazy?
Very crazy, very crazy.
Really?
Pretty nice.
Are we professional
or are we not professional? We are.
Ok, Ok
For a beer
We got him.
No...
This is what we call an asshole.
No, super asshole.
Somebody that
we can use as counterpoint
to Eva Soler's comments
Somebody that thinks absolutely
the opposite to create polemic.
A psychologist.
No, not a psychologist
...I don't think so
A psychologist...
on one hand we have the theory
and I need real information,
concrete data.
Did you talk to Eva Soler?
Yes, Mario.
Go to your office,
everything is fine, go and relax.
OK.
Is she going to die, dad?
No, sweetheart.
Does it hurt her a lot?
No, it doesn't hurt
because she's sleeping.
Maybe when she wakes up.
Poor sucker.
Poor super sucker.
Imagine when he finds out
that his wife is unfaithful.
Thank God the video
does not show
the guy's face.
The only thing I want is not
to be there when that happens.
Hello, Vilches y Liverona.
I'll put you through.
Who is it?
It's for us,
from channel 6.
Why don't you answer?
Because it seems that we
have a secretary this way.
Jerk. A secretary with a
cell phone. Yes, hello.
Look, what I cannot
understand is
how somebody can sleep
with another person
to save his or her marriage.
But, do you think
there are two different things?
I think that there are things
more important than sex
in marriage, Cristina.
A lot more.
Hey, sorry,
how long has it been since
you've had an orgasm?
Come on, answer.
Tell us, tell us.
You haven't had any.
How could I have
had none, Cristina.
And the rest of the times
you pretend you have orgasms?
No, not me.
I swear.
Oh, my God.
This is getting like a real city.
Hey, where would you
put a sex shop?
Here in Santiago?
Yes.
I don't know.
We would have to
make a market research first.
Sure.
Do that first.
But is there a sex shop already?
I don't know.
I am already married.
So?
I don't use those products.
Look, and you know what's best?
They don't like football.
That's ugly!
It's disgusting!
And it vibrates.
It vibrates!
Keep it.
I assure you it will
bring something new
to your marriage.
Let me touch it.
Are you crazy?
Es blandito y pegajoso.
You will design
the store for my business
isn't that so?
I didn't know that the store
would sell sex products.
Yes, it is.
Well,
if you're going to work with me
the first thing
you have to do
is open your mind
and make it possible.
It suits you.
Things one has
to do for work.
And that goes for you too.
We have to break
the taboos in this city.
We have to
offer fantasy,
I don't know...
sex quality is life quality.
Unbelievable, right?
May I?
You're smoking again?
Yes, the first thing I decided
was to change
guilt for pleasure.
Excellent.
Hey, look,
It looks like my husband.
And what do you think
about Virginia?
Listening to her scared me.
What scared you?
I mean,
resign myselfjust like her
...no, I mean really, no.
I don't want to be unfaithful
but I don't want
to languish either,
do you get me?
I don't know...
And what will you do?
Work with Roberta
for the time being.
See if they miss me
at home.
Camila, Camila.
Camila,
Francisco is going to
take her away from me.
No, take it easy.
That will never happen.
Alberto, Alberto.
Silly, I promise
I will always be here.
Calm down now.
Shit!
This thing is running away!
Virginia!
Mother.
I hope your conscience
is not as dirty as this.
Don't be silly.
Hello,
I came to speak
to you man to man.
Look for some time now,
Carola and I have, well,
Carola and I...
I have concrete proof that
Carola is screwing somebody.
Do you want to see?
Look.
While I work!
While I work.
Well that's the reason then...
While you work
...the only thing you care
about is yourjob.
Are you on her side,
man?
No, I'm not.
What I'm saying dad is
that all your life
the only thing
you have cared
about is work,
work, work, work,
and the people who love you,
where do you leave them?
But what the fuck
is wrong with that.
Nothing bad,
nothing bad, dad.
I'm only telling you
what I think as your son.
That's it.
Do you need money?
No, no.
What I need is less important,
it doesn't matter.
I'm glad you came.
Another one?
Yeah.
Relax, man.
Broads are like buses
you get off one
and get on another one.
Broads are like buses,
you get off one
and get on another one.
Cheers for that.
To buses!
The ten commandments
of the unfaithful woman.
By Vilches y Liverona.
The ten commandments
of the unfaithful woman,
I loved it. I loved it.
I think we are
going to make it with this one.
The last ten shows.
And how much
will we get paid
for participating
in the show?
I don't manage that part.
My executive producer
sees that.
We prefer to deal with you.
We know each other,
we know our faces...
I don't know.
Two millions, is that alright?
I told you.
I told you Liber.
Don't call me Liber,
call me Liberona.
Liberona,
I told you.
Mrs. Ureta was a lot more...
Excuse me...
Cecilia? Cecilia Ureta?
Yes, sir.
She offered us double
for this.
We have to get together with her
to hand her these pictures today
...but she's not available...
And because you
invited us to your show...
Which is the best mall?
No,
you don't intend to sell
your toys in a mall...
Of course, it's a modern
and pretty place,
with unsatisfied people
and with lots of money.
Yes, but I don't know
how much you remember
this country but these
women do not kill boredom
buying silicone dicks
and specially in place
where they can be seen.
And what do they do?
They get bored.
They get bored,
or we get bored?
Yes, I understand,
they learn to live with boredom
as if it were a pet, right?
Something like that.
You know what?
That has got to
change some day.
One day women will
decide to sacrifice their pet
and won't feel
guilty and think
that God will punish
them with hell.
Furthermore, I think
each one owns their happiness
Not the husband,
the mother or the children,
not even your lover
is going to come
and solve your life. No.
Lets talk about you.
Are you married?
I am happy.
And you?
No.
I mean I'm married.
Alvaro is absolutely paranoid,
he's crazy, he's sick.
What would you do?
I'd kill her.
You wouldn't?
Well, I don't know.
If you don't know,
who does?
I think one has to have
a clear point of view in life,
about every issue, abortion,
the pill, infidelity as well.
Yes, you're right,
but Virginita is different,
she would never
be unfaithful to her husband.
She's different.
Different from Cristina?
Yes, I mean no,
I mean yes and no
Do you get me?
Virginita is a
structured person.
Timid. Look...
sex makes her suffer.
What would her have a lover for
She's not interested in sex.
Neither does Cristina.
She's not interested in sex?
No, she loves sex.
I satisfy all her needs.
She has one orgasm
after the other.
Incredible,
you should listen to her
You are lucky!
Excuse me. It's her.
Hello, love. Hi, what?
Later?
Don't worry, love,
I'll wait for you. Kiss... Bye.
What happened?
She'll get home later.
She's having dinner
with a client.
Don't get any ideas,
the client is a woman.
Cheers!
For the times to come!
To silicone.
Excellent.
Delicious.
Hey, five years of marriage.
And how does it go?
I don't know,
normal, I suppose.
Well, the truth is that we
don't see each other much.
The truth is that
I don't listen to him
and neither does he.
Can you bring me
olive oil?
And when he talks
to me I don't understand
and he does not
understand me at all.
Yes,
but I'm talking about sex.
Do you get along in bed?
I don't know,
I can't imagine after 5 years.
I don't.
Nothing, nothing.
But he doesn't know,
he thinks he's
the perfect lover.
And you know what?
He doesn't even know
where the clitoris is.
He understands nothing.
I think he doesn't
even know it exists.
And you know the worst of all?
Tell me.
When he finishes
with that cheap imitation
of an unsaciable stud,
he stares at you like,
I don't know,
as if I had to thank him,
you know?
Your husband is a real jewel.
Maybe you should
introduce him to me.
Why not...
You know what?
You may think
that I'm crazy,
lost in the world,
and that I don't give a shit
but I've never been unfaithful.
Really.
Thank you.
I haven't had the need.
I don't know,
I don't feel
I belong to anybody
and nobody
belongs to me.
When I have been
with somebody it's just that.
I have fun,
I have a good time,
I fall madly in love
and when it's over
it's over and that's it.
But don't you sufer?
Yes, I do,
but it soon goes away
and I let go.
We have to enjoy.
It doesn't hurt?
What?
Depends on the size right?
And where...
Hey! I'm learning,
I'm learning.
- Hi.
- Hi, how are you?
Better.
I was at your place
and brought you some things.
I was with Camilita.
How is she?
Missing you.
I'm not getting
out of here, Carola.
What will you do.
Stay here locked up forever?
Mario is going to do a show
that will tear you in pieces.
You must get out of here.
Good morning, Cecilia.
I see that you're much better
than what your husband told me.
I'm glad.
Sorry, Teresa but I think
this is not the best time...
Honey, lets save time.
I want to talk to her.
Leave us, Carola.
I had to assume the
management of the channel, Cecilia.
And don't worry,
I don't have
heartfeelings towards you.
I want you back at work today.
I, I can't.
Yes, you can. Even more,
you are going to excuse yourself
publicly for what happened.
We have a contract
and you'll have to stick to it.
Solve your family problems
and back to work.
We pay you amounts
of money for something.
Come on.
Hello. Yes, of course.
Unbelievable.
They are elite sportsmen.
Yes, sure.
19 miles per hour at least
Fabulous, yes. Yes,
Virginita is here, she's fine.
Of course, yes,
will they show it again? OK, OK, bye.
Honey... Virginita.
Do we have batteries somewhere?
They're going to show
the goals again.
We don't have batteries, love.
Are you OK?
Yes.
Honey,
do you have a tummy ache?
Poor thing.
Pain, sadness,
anguish is what I feel today
for our workmate.
How are you?
Fine.
What's that?
You know very well
what this is.
But why did they
bring them here?
We want our money
before the show.
What was our agreement?
We were going to pay you, right?
One thing are my problems,
another thing is the show
Alright?
OK, man.
You know what we learnt
when we started this business?
Not to trust.
Go talk to the productor
and then you go to makeup, OK?
Hey, listen,
as Tony Caluga said...
No money, no Tony.
Come in.
You must be the ones
for the check, right?
Vilches and Liberona.
Pleased to meet you.
You don't know how glad
we are to find you.
I imagine,
6 and a half millions
is a sum to make you glad.
There.
No, no.
Make another one for 2 millions.
Explain it to her.
A 2 and 6 ceros.
Liber.
Explain about the 2 millions.
Your husband hired us.
He suspects you.
Well and the worst
part of ourjob
is having to say
the truth to the client.
So, Alvaro is not
going to know
that it is his son...
Carola, listen to me...
Go away,
I know everything.
These men just told me.
These are the fuckers
You... What's
the matter with you?
No, no, no.
I paid them. Lets go.
They say Alvaro
doesn't know. Lets go.
That's how you make a living...
3 millions now, jerk. 3 millions.
Cute. Bravo, bravo,
you'll make me
and my old man separate.
For some time, yes,
but then we are going to reconcile
And we'll go after you.
No.
I feel sorry for you.
You sorry fuckers.
You faggots.
Carola, listen to me.
Listen to me.
We'll do it my way now.
No more lies.
Faggots, fuckers.
We screwed up, man.
How are you?
He broke our briefcase, man.
Is he there? Is he there?
Son of a bitch.
How can you do this?
What are you doing with her?
What are you doing with Carola?
I'm your father,
don't you get it?
Take it easy,
calm down.
I'm your father,
how can you do this to me?
Did you go crazy?
What's in your mind?
She's my woman.
This is wrong, man.
Calm down, man.
How do you mean
calm down?
Take it easy.
We did not want to hurt you...
That's what you told me.
This woman
Shameless.
How embarrassing!
Come here.
You got to have bad luck!
The whole country new.
Imagine.
Everybody. Everybody.
Know what? It finished.
Hey?
What?
It looks different from here.
The world is really
changing now
Hey?
How do you think whores do it?
Do whores feel unfaithful?
They arrive home
and feel horny again?
Well, who knows
The pussy...
The fanny.
The fanny. The cunt.
The cunt.
The twat
The poontang
The carpet.
The fox.
The ass.
The cock lover.
I'm drunk.
Blood's gone to my head.
I'm dizzy.
Do you want more wine?
Yeah.
OK, I'll get it.
Why...
Drink up,
it's good for you.
It is very...
Good.
How can somebody
be so cynical.
Such a hypocrite,
such a liar.
I know I owe you an explanation
about what happened.
An explanation? You want to
give me an explanation?
You're such a fool.
You think an explanation
will fix things?
I don't want any explanations.
I want nothing from you.
I want you to grab your things
and leave my house.
But, but, think about Camilita.
Camilita,
did you think about her
when you were
screwing with another guy?
Listen to me.
I'll manage you don't see
Camila again.
You can't do that, Francisco.
Can't I? Can't I?
Of course I can.
I could put a bullet
in your head.
You bitch.
Are you afraid?
Are you afraid of dyeing?
Would you like me to die?
Do you prefer me to die?
Do I pull the trigger?
Would you like that?
Tell me.
Tell me, tell me,
and I'll do it right here.
I never was your priority.
And you were
never there for me.
Get out of my house.
Good evening.
Pain, sadness, anguish.
That is what I fell tonight
for our workmate Cecilia Ureta.
Another human being
We are with Eva Soler,
psychologist...
to help us understand
this difficult moment
that affects us all.
This difficult moment
Good evening, Eva.
Hello, good evening.
A few days ago
you surprised us all
with the results of a survey.
62% of the married women
in our country
is or has been unfaithful
to their couples.
The question is,
would you include
Cecilia in this figure?
Well, obviously, yes.
I don't think
it is that obvious
because Cecilia Ureta
is famous, a TV star.
People feel empathy for her
and tends to idealize her,
to the extreme
of transforming her
into a goddess.
So it is very hard for people
to understand that a God may
make a mistake.
I don't consider
she made a mistake.
I don't think that is the verb.
Excuse me,
you do not consider
infidelity a mistake?
You don't consider
it something abnormal.
No. What is normal?
What's not pathological.
If 62% of the women chooses,
assumes their infidelity,
then it's normal.
Like it has been for men
since the beginning of time.
Let's see, if I'm
not mistaken, according to you,
men would be guilty
of women's infidelity, right?
I didn't say guilty
I said accomplice.
It's different.
Well,
the doctor is very sarcastic
...we are going to introduce you to
Mr, Vilches and Liberona
that are also in our studio.
They are private investigators,
experts in women's infidelity.
Good evening, thank you
for being with us.
Good evening.
You were telling me,
off camera,
that there are
the 10 commandments
of the unfaithful woman.
There are many men
now in their homes
watching this programs
...some clues about
these ten commandments?
I would like to say
something before, Mario,
about what Mrs.
Eva said here,
in relation with normality,
normality,
I, deep inside,
philosophically agree with her
Normality. What is,
what is normality?
That is the topic that
we are talking about today
...to try to discover,
but we want to know
which are
the ten commandments
of the unfaithful woman.
Well, the ten commandments
are easy.
There are attitudes
that women have
that give them away,
For example
lock themselves up
for hours in the bathroom
to talk on the phone...
Or go too many times
to the gym
as she were getting
ready for the Olympic Games.
Yes, and also have a
cell phone with a contract
and a cell with card
because the one with card
you don't get the bill
at the end of the month
stating the calls
that were made.
There is this one
which is the essence
of this expression
of the unfaithful behavior
which is the waxing
between the legs
Of course.
Everything that they say
that is like
the maximum symptoms
of an unfaithful woman
I think are symptoms
of an independent woman
that likes to look gorgeous.
That is an unfaithful woman.
Oh, so gorgeous
and independent women
are all unfaithful?
I haven't said that.
We are talking about symptoms.
Yes.
Symptoms.
I agree, but
looking good and infidelity
...I agree with the lady.
But they are associated.
Sometimes.
That is what you're saying.
No, no,
sometimes, sometimes.
We have proven,
for example that in the hairdresser
a high percentage of the
women that go every day...
it's for a reason.
It's for a reason
9 out of 10.
There is a suspicion.
There is a suspicion So then
if your wife is good looking
you have to suspect
she's unfaithful.
No, but if she locks herself
up in the bathroom
to talk for hours,
she probably is.
She can do the same
from the family room...
But locked, hours
and hours in the bathroom...
It seems the debate has started
...we are going to commercials now...
When we get back we'll...
Honey, would you be
unfaithful to me?
Sweetheart,
how can you say that?
I don't need another man.
I don't need it.
I can't hear you.
What are you telling me?
Ethics! He's talking
to me about ethics!
Who are you ethical with?
With the one that pays you.
I'm leaving. No. I don't
want to keep on talking
with these people.
I'm so sorry, Mario...
but I have nothing to do here.
Excuse me. - Eva...
Eva. We haven't finished.
Who do I give this to?
You manage...
It's yourjob, Eva.
No, it's not.
I'm only being kind I don't
get paid for coming here.
Bye.
Where's my purse?
Take it easy,
we'll start with a video
that has a lot of
shots of the motel...
Audio.
Bernardita, please.
Somebody explain
to me what's going on.
I don't understand.
What? No, I'm not
going to do that.
I can't take this.
Don't worry my love,
I'm not going
to smile today.
I don't have
a reason to do so.
I hurt many people,
specially the ones I love.
During a long time
I lied to myself and I
lied to a lot of people.
Without thinking
in anybody but myself.
What I have lived has been
painful and humiliating
but it has helped me
to face the truth
and realize
that being able
to look in the eyes...
...freely
and smile with honesty
does not have price.
And smile with honesty
What's your ideal man like?
First he has to be handsome.
Sure of himself,
hot, that pampers me,
cuddly,
one who spoils me and
asks for nothing in return.
One that looks at me,
that always knows where I am.
It's seems a gay man, I think.
Silly.
I like a man when he
comes out of the shower.
Oh, yeah.
I don't know...
with huge hands...
Yes. Big hands.
I like that too.
They make you feel slimmer,
right?
Yes...
And very kinky...
very kinky and fun.
Yes. Yes.
I need a man like that.
A big man.
Yeah, yeah... with a big one.
I brought something for you...
A present.
You're crazy!
We are going to go
look for some real ones.
And it says...