Barbara, not a word.
I know he's there.
The genius.
And I do know what you're doing.
I need to speak to him.
Now.
Immediately. Understood?
Where would you be without
the paper?
Isn't it the paper - or ME in fact -
that gave you those assignments?
Printed and published your crap.
Looking after you for five years.
And they give you a price. An honor prize.
And which one? The Daily paper prize.
Who created that prize?
The paper!
And then suddenly you're a damn
genius.
Then you loose interest in the paper.
Then you want a leave.
A leave? Do you think this is
the Danish public media. We run a paper!
You are a fist fighting, horny,
part time drinker just like the rest.
- If you think you can have a leave...
- I don't want a leave.
Only regular employees get leaves.
I am a freelance journalist.
You are a devil. You are neither
freelance nor fully employed.
You're fired, understood?
From now on.
You need to return the advance,
you picked up. And get out of my office!
We have a paper to run here.
Shit!
You are pushing him. Are you
completely broke?
- I got that prize, you know.
- 15,000.
- And then IRS payed a visit.
- And?
- There's still some left for a vacation.
- Two things I don't understand.
- Just two?
- Why do you absolutely have to go?
This city is not the same without you.
And, why are you going alone?
I need someone to come home to.
So long.
By the way...
Please get the sofa fixed.
It's a racket.
- Where are you going?
- I don't know...
- Greece, perhaps.
- Don't you need a camera?
- I already have a Nikon. Brand new.
- I would go to Lesbos.
- Obviously.
- You don't have to be gay.
Lets roll dice.
Hello.
Hi.
So the paper let you go.
- How do you know that?
- We know everything here.
- I had some insider info for you.
- Well...What was it?
They say, that something big is coming.
Something big?
What is something big?
- You know...
- Drugs? Hard drugs?
- Yes, so they say.
- Who says so?
Who has something big coming?
Unbelievable. We all know it all.
Except for the things, that are
really worth knowing.
- You owe me 110.
- Keep it in mind, Kurt.
Write it down for next time.
Be careful and you don't forget it.
- You go to the airport?
- What should I do there?
They say you are leaving.
I can give you a ride.
No. I'm just going home.
Come on, sweet children.
Yes? Oh, it's you?
Would you mind putting that out?
It's not good for me.
Thanks.
It's about the first edition. Edgar
Allan Poe. You remember, don't you?
It just left with Mr. Rosenbaum.
It was Rosenbaum. I forgot that
name.
- You promised to keep it for me.
- That was nearly four month ago.
I need to live as well.
At least for a while.
- Isn't Rosanbaum an old drug lord?
- That was long ago.
Others, much more powerful, have come.
They don't come here. Don't
even live in the neighborhood.
- The Thin man.
- They live in Gentofte, and such.
I'm so sorry about that book.
May I at least offer you a glass of port?
Rosenbaum needed a present for young
friend. I have an exquisite, old wine.
Almost as old as you.
If I let it, it could be as old as
me. But I don't.
Please sit down.
Here we go.
That's it.
You are a writer.
And a fine one if I may say so?
What are you currently working on?
- I have just been let go.
- I see... I see...
- Cheers.
- Is that wise?
- Wise? Who?
- What are you going to do now?
- I don't know...travel, perhaps.
Travel? I see.
Go away?
- Sometimes that's what you need.
- Perhaps so.
Once in a while it just gets too
much. Violence... Death.
And in addition serving it as
lunch break entertainment.
- It just gets too much sometimes.
- Well... You are still young.
- Hi... I didn't know...
- Come on inside.
- This is my niece, Hanne.
- Hi Hanne. We know each other.
- Oh yes.
- I'll be off again.
- Sorry.
- No problem.
Wanna eat something?
I'm making eggs.
I'm off again.
It wasn't important.
Say hi to Ole. Tell him I'll be
with him tonight.
She is my sisters grandchild.
They live in Vejle. I don't know
why they let her move.
They don't know the neighborhood.
She needs to be taken care of.
- I suppose Ole chef takes care of her.
- Ole chef?
Who is taking care of him, then?
Would you like another glass?
No, thank you, Bille.
Let it age.
- When are you going?
- I don't know...
I would like to go too. To Vejle.
- Vejle?
- You know, Hanne is from Vejle.
It would do her good to come home
to her family again.
There is a small bar in Vejle. It
would like to buy it.
If only I could raise the money.
Are you ready?
- God, what time is it?
- 2:30.
Shit, is it that late?
We better...
- Don't you want to listen to the tape?
- No. Tomorrow is better.
- I have to clean this place up.
- Do you have any appointments? Okay.
- Who is it?
- That's none of your business.
- Where's the Colonel.
- Sick.
Let's go. We don't have
all night.
Come on then.
And the curiosity is unhealthy for you.
Yes, of course. I just wanted...
There is quite a lot in here.
Here.
I usually get a...a sample.
- Did you get anything?
- Yes, right here.
- That's fine. Give it to me.
- Don't you want to go home first?
No, come on.
Give it to me. Come on.
- Good morning.
The new detective has arrived.
And this just came from Heegaards Gade.
Any coffee left?
- Good morning...Ehlers.
- Kaspersen.
Welcome to Copenhagen.
You arrived from Aarhus? Recently?
- Last week.
- Found a place to stay?
In Broenshoej.
At my sisters. For now.
- Sit down. Married?
- Used to be.
Thanks. What do you know about
this neighborhood?
Well, you pick up bits of
information here and there.
It's all true. We have more bars and
nightclubs than anywhere else.
More brothels, prostitutes and pushers
than any precinct.
Then, there's the regular people,
shoppers, kindergartens, the retireds.
- There is plenty to look after.
- Yes. And we are heavily understaffed.
Half of us is in bed with the flu.
And then, this came in.
The riot squad wants us on a
raid tonight.
They believe a load of
drugs just arrived.
The market has been undersupplied.
Tag along and meet the neighborhood.
- Yes please.
- You're welcome. Welcome!
That's a boy. Come on my children.
- Let me give you a hand.
- Alright, pour us a drink.
Put on a record. I'll make us
some lunch.
- Do you want to sleep with me?
- What?
- I'll sleep with you.
- Now I'm making us a little lunch.
- Ole doesn't mind.
- Please sit down and relax.
You need something to eat.
- Is it true you are leaving?
- Yes, maybe.
Perhaps we are too. Ole and me.
Ole says he's making enough money
for us to go to Vejle.
- That sounds good.
- Where are you going?
- Greece, perhaps.
- I've been there.
Lovely. Very clean and such.
- Ever been there?
- No, but it sounds good.
How long is it since you were
in Greece?
Cheers!
- Taxi!
- Take it ease, there.
- Hello?
- Is it the director?
- Who am I talking to?
- This is Rosenbaum.
- Is it the director?
- What do you want at this hour?
Oh, it's the director. I recognize
the voice.
- You can also recognize it from a tape.
- Tape? What tape?
Why are you acting like a big shot, idiot?
Have you got any more money?
- Hey! Do you have more money?
- Let's have some peace and quiet please.
It's more than 4000.
It's the worlds best.
- Has it a timer function?
- Sure.
Shit man, this is the top of the line.
- If there is no timer...
- Come on man, you'll get for 1200.
- Let's roll a die.
- You still owe me, man.
Add it, write it down, for Christ's
sake.
Don't ever forget to keep
accounts.
We have some visitors.
- Visitors!
- Shit.
You owe me damn it...
Police! Please keep quiet. Hands
above the table.
Hands above the table, please.
That's enough. Get him out.
Kaspersen...
This is too much. You can't even
go to the toilet anymore.
- This way, madam.
- Oh, please.
Ah, look what we have here?
Kaspersen, please let me introduce
one of the neighborhood attractions.
This bright, young genius, here.
Denmark's hope.
A brawler and drunk.
Journalist, prize winner.
Do you know, why he won?
A series of articles about
the police' inability at Vesterbro.
He serves naked women,
blood, violence and social misery -
- as lunch break entertainment.
No, what have we here? Nice,
a brand new camera.
Where did we buy that? Do we have
a receipt? An invoice?
No, perhaps not here. Bring it to
the station -
- we'll take care of the camera until then.
We'd hate for something to happen to it.
He's okay.
We're closing now.
What is this shit? I didn't do
anything wrong.
It's Bob. We just had visitors.
I noticed they took Hanne.
Yes, he's here. Ole chef wants
a word with you.
- He wants to know if you drop by?
- I'm too tired.
He says he's broiling a steak.
Sounds like shit!
I'm much too hammered.
Why don't we listen to that tape?
It's terrific.
- Where is the tape?
- I don't have it here.
Stop doing that! I need to tell
you something about the tape.
Okay.
I'll make crisp onions, right?
You don't appreciate the soft ones.
- I absolutely hate soft onion rings.
- You're an odd bugger.
Everyone loves soft onion rings.
I'll just fry them a bit.
You see, the other day, when we were
finished playing, and you'd gone -
- they came to pick up the goods.
Someone was here I didn't recognize.
The others said he was here, because
the regular guy had caught the flu.
He didn't say much. The others
were scared shitless.
When they were gone, I noticed,
that the tape recorder was rolling.
It had recorded everything. I didn't
know what to do.
But then Rosenbaum came by, and
he knows the business inside out.
I played the tape for him, and he
said it was the Thin man.
He was absolutely certain. He was
dying to hold on to that tape.
It was obvious to Rosenbaum. But
I kept the tape.
It has to be worth something.
No one was ever able to proof
anything against the Thin man.
It has to be worth something.
The police doesn't pay anything
for that sort of thing.
I'm afraid to call the Thin man.
Rosenbaum told me he would pay.
It's just not me. I'm simply too
scared.
I suppose there is a good story
in it, right?
Obviously they'll arrest me. But
I'll get out sooner or later.
And then we could go to Vejle.
Right?
How does that sound?
What the hell, are you sleeping?
Are you sleeping?
I must have dozed off.
- What is that?
- It's a steak with onions.
I can't stomach those soft onions.
I have to...
It's not bloody soft onions.
They are crisp.
I have to get some fresh air.
Those bloody Greeks. Mixing
various drinks.
I walking sideways. I'll be back
tomorrow.
Let's play, then.
I'm sorry about the steaks.
Don't worry about the steaks.
When he realized what was going to
happen, he got scared.
He looked at me. I'll never forget
his eyes.
That's why I'm coming. I always
see those eyes.
Frandsen, you need to listen to me.
Then, I forced his head backwards
and cut his throat.
It's best that way. That way there are
no sounds from the throat.
- In the Resistance we were taught that.
- Yes?
But there was an awful lot of blood.
An awful lot.
- Frandsen, you need to listen to me.
- Absalonsgade 15 B, 3rd floor.
- By these hands...
- And what was the name?
Rosenbaum, I got that one.
But what is your name?
That's good. We'll be there.
Please don't touch anything.
Come on, Simonsen. It's the same each month.
You come here with the same confession.
Why don't you come up with a new
story?
We have a report of a homicide
in Absalonsgade.
It's Fritz Rosenbaum.
Old drug lord.
In that sort of cases, Ehlers
wants to be woken.
- Yes?
- It's me. Can we talk about it?
Half the staff's got the flu.
There are two homicides
near your place.
- Both Borch and Georg is down.
- Well...
Alright. I accept, you're freelance.
I'm giving you double up.
This is a great story. You wouldn't
let the paper down, would you?
I already sent a photographer.
Come on...
- Good morning.
- Jesus.
That was no God damn photographer.
That was the police.
- Fuck me.
- Shit!
- It's 7.42, and you are under arrest.
- For what exactly?
We need to question you further
regarding the circumstances of a homicide.
Murder? Me?
It was committed between 1 and 2
tonight.
- On who?
- You need to follow us.
The only encouraging about this dirty
affair is making you classy acquaintance.
Fuck you and give me an explanation.
No stupid jokes.
Okay, your fingerprints were all over
the place. You forgot you saxophone.
And when we ran into you earlier at
the evening you didn't seem quite sensible.
- What are you talking about?
- Cafe Freden.
Ole Wilhelm Jensen was murdered
last night at Café Freden.
- Ole chef?
- Yes, Ole chef.
Ehlers.
I supposed that's right.
Are you realizing he's on an important
job for the paper. We can't just sit around.
- As long as you know what you're doing.
- We are interrogating the suspects.
The suspects?
Give me a break.
I've called National Court Attorney
Jan Berentsen.
If you want to waste his time, go ahead.
But right now you are wasting mine.
Bring the genius for a report.
Do it thoroughly and by the book.
I already explained that to you.
Let's take it one more time.
Perhaps you'll remember something new.
You were quite drunk.
We saw that ourselves.
Not in my wildest dream am I
able to kill Ole. He was my friend.
We were best friends. Why would
I want to kill him?
Idiot.
You also knew Ole Wilhelm Jensen's
partner.
Hanne Margrethe Jespersen.
She's an addict and a prostitute.
How intimate do you know her?
Perhaps Ole chef was dissatisfied
that you and her...
Come on, guys. You don't
understand a damn thing.
We believe that Ole Wilhelm Jensen
was pushing drugs.
- And that he had access to...
- Excuse me for a second.
This is ridiculous.
You assume. You believe...
Bullshit! You neither need assume
nor believe.
You know as well as I do.
We all know -
- who does that sort of business
around here. The thin man, right?
He has perfect conditions -
- as long as the police keeps wasting
time in this ridiculous fashion.
It's the ink color.
Excuse me for a second.
It's a vcr and a stereo.
I just need to ask. Did they
vandalize anything?
- They went down...
- Besides that?
- Goodbye.
- Yes...
"The police is lost again."
Go home and sleep. Sometimes things
get a little out of hand.
- I never realized...
- Imagine the boldness.
But he's not getting away with it.
You two find him.
He's either in the neighborhood or
at the paper.
- Attorney Jan Berentsen.
- Just let him in.
It'll be a pleasure.
- Shall we drive to his apartment?
- No. He's not that stupid.
- Who gets there first?
- I do.
- HS-HS, reporting. 010, over.
- 010, come in,
We have identified the suspect in
Istedgade just outside number 13.
We pursue him and attempt arrest.
010, over.
O10, copy, out,
HS-HS, the suspect escaped via
the backyard to Istedgade 14 -
- and we call for backup.
- 010, 011 and 012 are coming.
- Copy. 010, over.
- HS, reporting. 6501, over.
- Come in.
We have identified the suspect.
We pursue and attempt arrest.
Nah, we haven't seen him
the last couple of days.
He's probably left.
Wasn't he on vacation?
- Oh, yeah. He's left.
- Wasn't it something about Greece?
Yes, he was going to Lesbos.
- Lesbos is a terrific place.
- That's enough.
Well, if you write him don't
forget to say hi.
That's it.
Take that home.
- I hope it's fine.
- It's brand new.
- Is there a warranty?
- What do you think this is?
- I ought to have a warranty.
- It's less than half retail price.
- But what if something is broken?
- Not my problem is it?
- Jesus.
- Easy, easy.
- What do you want?
- I need a place to stay.
Not with me you are.
It's dangerous.
The whole neighborhood is looking
for you.
They say the Thin man wants you.
And also the police.
If I were you, I would go to
Greece. As fast as possible.
I'm off. See you.
- Okay. Just tell me one thing.
- What?
- Where does the Thin man live?
- What do you want him for?
- I need a word with him.
- You are not well, man.
No. We have seen nothing of the Thin man,
but a taxi just arrived.
Somebody comes out carrying
two suitcases.
It's the Colonel. His Jaguar is
in the driveway.
And here comes the Mrs. with
the child.
They enter the taxi.
The Colonel stays behind.
The taxi's leaving. The Colonel
walks back to the house.
We stay put and continue the
surveillance.
It's the same every time something
is about to happen.
Only God know how that man looks
inside.
Every time it's about murder and
violence he sends the Mrs. to the country.
Perhaps she doesn't even know
what he is doing.
Under no circumstances is this
happening in Gentofte. Just call them back.
- Hey. Got some sleep?
- Yes, thank you.
- We still haven't apprehended him.
- He's a handful.
I was thinking...I seriously doubt
that he's the killer.
I don't care. Just find the man.
Find him. Dead or alive. Find him!
Hello? Hello?
- Where were you? Where are you?
- Nowhere, really. It's tiring.
- When are you going home?
- In an hour. Is that okay?
What? A shaver?
Well, I suppose I can fix that.
Just one more thing. Can you find
out, where the Thin man lives?
He lives in Gentofte.
He's not in the phonebook.
They have to know something
in the crime department.
- Hello?
- Bille! What's going on?...
Let me help you.
What the hell were you thinking?
- I'm deeply sorry.
- You're not hurt are you?
So kind of you. It's the right
leg. It's seen better days.
- What do you do out here?
- Looking for Hanne.
She was arrested last night.
She's at the station.
I'm sorry. She was released
this morning.
Those guys, that murdered Ole chef are
tearing the town apart looking for her.
- They are looking for you too, you know.
- It dawned on me.
- Please let me take you home.
- Thank you.
- Does it hurt?
- It's wear.
The doctor says I must
live with it.
And I suppose one has to
until it kills you.
Oh, that's the cognac.
For a second I thought it was the port.
No. It's aging, remember.
Where is Hanne?
I don't know. She's hiding.
She has a friend... Gurli.
Perhaps she's with her.
- I wonder if we'd find her there.
- Yes, maybe.
I don't know where she lives.
She's hanging around the oriental bar.
- I guess you could ask them.
- Yes, maybe.
Yes, maybe.
Let me show you.
Look, take this.
I've taken good care of it and it works.
And in your current situation it
might come handy.
Do you know how to use it?
- Where's the other one?
- I keep it in my coat.
You are surprised. Of course.
I sometimes ask myself how it
all ended like this.
I could never hurt a fly.
I've lived here my entire life.
These children were never
God's finest.
But they were living here.
This was a refugee.
Unfortunately the Thin man unofficially
crowned himself king of the neighborhood -
- and he doesn't even live here.
Him and his gang fill the neighborhood
with evil, fear, violence and death.
The police are helpless.
Suddenly an old man walks about
with a loaded gun.
And there's a price tag on a
poor girl from Vejle.
This is literally killing her!
- Is Gurli around?
- Don't know her. I'm sorry.
- Gurli from Vejle.
- Oh, that Gurli.
- She's not in yet.
- Do you have her address?
Let me just check.
- What the hell?
- I just need a little word with you.
- Who were you calling?
- That's none of your business.
Let's have some music.
Now, let's talk.
What were you telling me again?
Why didn't you just say so?
What the hell...
- Vesterbrogade 60 C.
- Where have you been?
They are coming for you. Everybody.
- Have you heard about Topcat?
- Topcat?
- It's a porn club, right?
- Why are you going there?
Just an address I was given
by a man in a bar.
It's not a good place.
- It's the Colonel's place.
- The Colonel?
The Thin man's right hand.
It's not good place. Stay out
of there.
Let's see.
It should be here.
- From your country?
- Very popular.
Don't get started, now.
It should be here.
- What was her name, again?
- Gurli.
Oh, Gurli?
She lives there.
Gurli lives there.
- Who is it?
- Is it Gurli?
- Who's asking?
- I have a message for Hanne.
You're the reporter, right?
She's been out of her mind.
So I got her a fix.
She's calm now.
I have to go. I don't want them
to get mad at me.
- She's scared and wants to go home.
- Okay...Hanne?
Hanne?
Come on. You are going home.
Listen, Hanne.
I'm putting you on a train to Vejle.
- Everything is going to be fine.
- Ole said the same thing.
By the way... Here.
- What is it?
- The tape I was supposed to give you.
Ole told me it was very important.
- That was beautiful.
- You can keep it.
- Do you want me to go inside with her?
- Just wait for me, okay?
Copenhagen Central Station.
Intercity train for Aarhus
leaves at 8 pm, track 5.
The train stops at Roskilde, Korsoer,
Odense, Fredericia and Vejle.
Do you want me to call anybody
and tell them you arrive?
No. I'll do that myself.
I want to tell them myself.
Okay.
Safe journey.
- Thanks.
- So long.
Intercity train for Aarhus,
8 pm, leaves in a few minutes.
8 pm, leaves track 5 in a few minutes.
Hey! Stop!
I'm busy.
I'm waiting for a customer.
- Where was he going?
- Who?
- Your customer damn it.
- I don't know.
- Go for a ride.
- No, I'm waiting.
Just drive, you little Turk shit.
- Well...
- Exactly.
Hey you.
I don't want any trouble.
- They are looking for you.
- I just need to borrow the phone.
Not at my place.
They came here for Ahmed as well.
They beat him into a pulp in
Sydhavnen.
Please open.
- I need a drink.
- We're closed.
Asshole.
What's this?
My God, it's you.
- What are you doing here?
- I live here. What are you doing here?
- You live here?
- 1st floor to the left.
- Do you know anything about that place?
- What do you want to know?
What are they doing.
What does that Colonel do?
Don't you want to come up. You look
like you're in need of a little peace.
Well, can I borrow your phone?
I don't want to involve you in all this.
Lots of people come here
all the time.
- How about a bath?
- Thanks. Just the phone please.
It doesn't matter. I didn't expect
anything.
I just boiled some water for
some eggs.
You know just in case, right?
And I probably had one drink
too many.
But I'll survive, I guess.
Things just keep happening.
Maybe, if it's not too late.
- That's fine by me. See you.
- Bye.
- Hello?
- yes.
Where are you?
If something is seriously wrong
you'd tell me, right?
- Yes.
- You'd call me, right?
- I'll call you. I promise.
- Okay.
- See you... And thanks.
- No worries. Bye.
Hello? The Thin man.
I almost forgot.
He lives at Soevaenget 14.
It's in Gentofte.
That's all.
Bye, bye.
Yes, that's him.
I thought so.
Come and have a look.
Come, look.
He's Swedish. Quite pretty.
The car's not bad either.
He comes once in a while.
And then something's going on.
It never fails.
- So what's going on?
- What do you think?
It's every time you can't score.
They are dying, poor creatures.
They are feeling terrible.
Whenever there is a delivery
he's back again.
- The Swedish guy.
- A courier?
I don't know what's going on at
Topcat. Nothing unusual they say.
Just the regular in out.
Perhaps a little slap in the behind.
- Not my style.
- Is it the Colonel's?
I think he represents the owners.
They own the whole building.
- Soon they'll own the entire street.
- The Thin man?
I don't know anything about that.
Nothing at all.
I only know the view from my window.
And according to your view something
is going on at Topcat.
I think it's the apartment upstairs.
- Can you do me a favor?
- You want that bath after all?
Maybe later.
I'm going to se what they're doing.
Would you mind calling the police?
- No.
- No?
You can make me do anything
but call the police?
It's a principle. No matter what,
I'll never call the police.
Listen. They are dying to get me.
You don't have to tell your name.
Just tell them, you watched me
enter Topcat.
- Are you sure you're going in there?
- Positive.
It's not fair.
I wouldn't mind if the police
was here 5 minutes after I go in.
I see?
Topcat, Absalonsgade.
And you are certain about it?
What was your name again?
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
Oh, Kaj. Is it you?
No, of course not. Who else?
Could you please come over?
I could really use some moral support.
Yes, as quickly as possible.
I think you took a wrong turn.
It's down there.
Thanks.
- What the hell?
- Hands in the air.
And backwards against the wall!
Come on!
- What is all this?
- This is all right.
Don't try anything or I'll pull
the trigger.
- You murdered Ole chef, my friend.
- Never heard of the man.
I won't hesitate.
I will shoot. But if you keep calm
for a few minutes -
- the police will be here.
- Anonymous you say?
- Yes he hung up.
A lot of people are
interested in him.
Editor Otzen also keeps calling.
It can't be him. The lab
determined -
- that Ole chef was killed by
the same gun that killed Rosenbaum.
When Rosenbaum was shot he was
sitting at a bar quite hammered.
- I saw it myself.
- Ehlers wants him badly.
Still, let's wait for Ehlers to come.
If he's at a nightclub
he's not going anywhere.
- How long is this taking?
- Hands behind your neck!
What do you do now?
Wait? Why aren't you doing anything?
Will you let him get away with that?
You do have someone who fixes
this, right?
How do you run this
shit organization?
So Danish...
So fucking, typical Danish!
How weak.
You're just a pack of amateurs.
Shut up!
No, No, No. Forget it.
I'm not keeping quiet.
If the police arrives I have a lot to tell
them about you and your organization -
- and your damn boss.
- That's enough.
- Keep those hands up, and shut up!
Do it yourself!
What sort of an antique gun is
that anyway?
Is it even working?
No, that's enough!
Wake him up and wait for me.
We need him to talk.
Hey... He's a real cowboy.
Did you see his revolver?
hmm, the water is warm.
Give him a cold shower.
- Jesus. Is it you?
- Didn't you call the police?
- I called. I promise.
- Call again.
Close the door and call them
again.
You look awful. you're bleeding.
Are you hurt?
Everything is fine. Just please
call the police now.
- Well, I don't know... - What the hell
is it with you and the police?
- I'm off.
- No, Kaj. Please don't.
I'm gone.
Make that call.
Yes, hello? I just called you.
Why didn't you come?
- Hello. Let me talk to Ehlers.
- Who is this?
- Chief Ehlers is not here right now.
- Come on.
Where is he? Who's at the
station then?
Nobody? That's impossible!
Take it easy! It's me. It's just me.
Otzen? Jesus?
Oh, God... The police?
- Come on, damn it.
- Yes, yes. Hi.
Get to work. Barbara called. She
was afraid something had happened.
Are you hurt? You're bleeding.
We have to get you to a hospital.
As I told you. Nothing had
happened.
- Can I take him to the hospital?
- Of course.
- We're going there immediately.
- I'll take that.
Go home and sleep. We can discuss
this later.
Half of them are still in bed.
Barbara is cleaning your apartment.
She told me she has a key.
- She was saying hi.
- Fine, thanks.
- Just a moment, please.
- He needs to go home and sleep.
I have to take him back to the station
first. We need some more information.
- Is that really necessary?
- It's okay. Don't worry.
- Then you take him home later.
- I'll see to it.
Otzen? I want you to back
to Bent.
- And pay for the damages.
- What?
You heard me. You got some great
shots.
- That's worth a lot, right?
- True.
- Can I count on you?
- Of course. I'll take care of it.
- I'll be seeing you.
- Yes, bye.
There are no doubt about it.
Those two we got...
They killed Ole chef and Rosenbaum.
The gun matches.
I had them. I was sitting with them.
Both the Colonel and a Swedish
guy.
And a whole suitcase full of
drugs. I had them.
- If only you showed up.
- I wish you'd stay out of police business!
It completely hopeless!
It's impossible to do our jobs
when you constantly mess around.
I'm sorry.
All the drugs were gone when we
arrived. Even the dogs didn't find anything.
Radio news, this is Thursday
March 14th.
A girl was discovered dead in a
train between Fredericia and Vejle.
The girl was a junkie and was
found in the toilet -
- after injection of an instantly
lethal dose of heroin.
The police withholds the girls
identity.
Hanne.
Yes, that's right.
Hanne Margrethe Jespersen.
I'm sorry.
You knew her well, didn't you?
She was dating Ole.
It was me who put her on that train.
- She wanted to go home.
- She carried any drugs?
Quite the opposite in fact.
She was not feeling well.
- I shouldn't have left her.
- Someone gave it to her on that train.
Just a couple of things.
It doesn't take long.
- The director of the police is on the wire.
- Oh, so he's up early too.
Just a moment.
I didn't quite get that.
Would you mind repeating that?
Well, let's get this thing over
with...
- Oh, is it you?
- Bille?
I am so happy to see you.
- What happened?
- happened?
Quite simple in fact.
I shot him.
- You shot him?
- The Thin man, yes.
One shot. That was sufficient.
He lies in there. On a Persian rug.
- Jesus!
- Yes.
I am very happy to see you.
Would you mind following me home?
Not at all.
You better close the door.
The train is far. Do you want me
to call a taxi?
No. It's not necessary. I can
walk.
I can walk now. Hardly any pains
in my leg.
- That's nice.
- Isn't it odd?
It's a strange feeling killing
someone.
Taking a life.
It cleanses your body and soul.
Is that spring I feel in the air?
- Would you do me another favor?
- Of course.
Would you please deliver this
to the police?
- It's a confession.
- A confession?
- In all details.
- That's not necessary.
- Nobody will suspect you.
- Yes. That is necessary.
They must know it was me.
That one of the old ones from
the neighborhood did it.
- Maybe this place can be better.
- Well...
All your books?
The pains in my right leg once again
remind me that I'm an old man.
Soon I won't be able to mount
the ladder.
Now, let's drink our port.
Listen. I won't say a word.
Are you absolutely certain...
Let's have another port.
- And you will do me that favor?
- Okay.
First I was going to mail it. I am happy
the police will receive it sooner.
Officially I can't support this.
But between us I respect the
old man.
Which reminds me... Where were
you going with that revolver?
This is Bille's. He had a pair.
He has the other one.
And it is loaded?
I better get you home and in bed
before you escape again.
- By the way. Did you report it?
- What?
'When you receive this I will
be dead'
'I am taking my own life and
nobody must be sad.'
'I did my duty and lived long
enough.'
'Respectfully, Bille'
It's no use putting you to bed.
But we could go for a walk.
The weather is fine. I'll buy you a beer.
- How do you feel?
- Might as well go on that vacation.
- Hey.
- Ahmed!
- I drove you around.
- How much do I owe you?
You owe me 300. Only kidding.
You need to listen to that tape.
You have to listen. Come.
- Where's the Colonel?
- Sick.
Let's do it then. We don't have
all night.
Come on then.
And the curiosity is unhealthy for you.
That is the Thin man.
There are no doubts about it.
He was there in person.
I'll be damned.
So that's why Ole was crazy
about that tape.
- Would you have been able to arrest him?
- Maybe.
It always depends on the judge.
He had some demonic lawyers.
If I just hadn't been that drunk
and preoccupied with myself that night...
- If I hadn't fallen asleep...
- I said maybe.
There are no guaranties with us.
But an old book shop keeper. He did it.
- Do you need a ride?
- No I want to walk.
Somebody should write down that story.
Translated by adflictatio,
Cingemageddon, 2011