[birds chirping]
[cricket noises]
[window squeaks]
[traffic and car horns]
[man and woman talking inside]
[pouring water]
[soft classical music]
[rooster crowing]
[doorbell rings]
[washing dishes]
[chattering]
[flirtatious chatting]
[crying]
[violin music]
[upbeat shop music playing]
[cash register beeping]
[door creeks open]
[dishes slamming together]
[traffic and car horns]
[television music]
[baby noises]
[loud crash]
[guitar music]
[screams]
[machinery grinding]
[violin music]
[soft singing]
[knock on the door]
[violin music]
[arcade game sounds]
[laughing]
[giggling]
[singing]
[traffic noises]
[laughing]
[snorts]
[violin playing]
[girls makes cat noises]
[laughs]
[cash register beeping]
[television playing]
[crickets]
[dogs barking]
[arcade game music]
[door slams]
[happy chatter]
[movie character talking]
[knocking on the door]
[upbeat shop music playing]
[scooters passing]
[happy chatter]
[sniffing]
[door creeks open]
[soft crying]
[crying]
[screaming outside]
[car horn]
[movie character speaking]
[people chatting]
[truck horn]
[water running]
[heavy breathing]
[radio]
[soft guitar music]
[television playing]
[woman talking on radio]
[radio music playing]
[singing]
[rooster crowing]
[dog barking]
[violin music]
[footsteps]
[dog barking]
[rooster crowing]