Chief... My Chief, the
worst has passed, huh?
What are you doing here, hick!
I'd be damned if I didn't
greet my Chief out of jail!
See that?
Chief Çetin, how was the prison?
Anywhere with Chief Muro
is a swell place, Yýldýrým.
Stop sucking up!
Let me have it...
Chief, your bag.
Yýldýrým, the door won't close.
Damn, a revolutionist should be
an expert of all technical gizmo.
Pull the door in...
Idiot...Prick...
At your command, Chief. Tell me
the place and I'll take you there.
Take us to the terminal, Yýldýrým.
Terminal? Why Chief, the house is
available, my boss left for vacation.
They're gone for full three months.
You can rest, and we
can stay together, huh?
Chief, we can always go to the
village; it's been staying in...
... its place for five thousand
years on all its feudal roots.
Let's lay back a while, live
Istanbul, shake off our stress...
- ... then we can leave.
- What do you say, Chief?
So Chief, are we really
going get married?
Yes Çetin, I've told you a hundred
times, we'll go get married.
Gee Chief, how do we make
a revolution by marrying?
Can two broads achieve
what we couldn't?
Çetin, there isn't enough
windows in the bus...
... to blow your
stinking ignorance.
- Who can we call a revolutionist?
- Pardon me brother, but who?
Your mother, you douche...
Give me my water...
Thanks...
A revolutionist is the ideal man,
a knowing person.
We are to go get married.
Start the revolution from the bed...
... then extend to the house by means
of the kids, then to the village...
... to the city, and then
to the whole country.
Wait till the cows come home
and eat the clovers...
Stop being a cow, I'll find you
the clovers, you douche.
- Bro, this is one good cake, can
I have another one? - Okay.
Here Çetin, stuff yourself with this!
I don't get it bro, what are
you so edgy about?
What's that to you man?
Mind your own business.
I've only meant to hand you
a bag, if you are car sick!
Why, are you a bagger?
l'm no carsick, you made me sick!
Alright, alright...
Push the button if you need me.
Which one? This?
Leave the buttons now.
We are having a word.
Chief, no need to be tense, relax.
We'll see if we can find a nice
broad who suits us in the village...
... or else take the bus
and return to lstanbul!
Just as no one believed that the great
Lenin was to make the revolution...
... on his return from Germany exile;
today as my comrade Çetin...
... sawing logs beside me and l,
are beating our brains out on...
... poky bus seats over the tactics
and strategy of revolution...
... of course no one
shall believe in me.
But even if the whole
capitalist world opposes me...
... the bourgeois class says no, no
feudal man gives away his daughter...
... I swear on cosmos
that I'd still get married...
... set an example with my humble
family life and make the revolution.
Çetin, I greet you with all
my revolutionist emotions.
Yes?
Bro, do you have nescafe?
Yes. Here.
Çetin, I keep telling you to stay
away from imperialist products...
... while you insist on
shoving them to my face!
Chief, a man needs to know his
enemy; if we have waged a war...
... against imperialists, we
should get to know them.
I didn't buy it, Çetin.
I didn't.
- l'm burning! l'm burning!
- Take it out...
Take your pants off, or else
you'll get burned all over...
Leave my long john alone...
Friends, comrades, stop the bus,
my revolutionist balls are on fire!
l'm burning, Çetin, l'm burning!
Hand it to me, Chief.
- Chief, which grounds did
we lose? - Shut up Çetin!
Bro, you have found water
and started bathing in it!
Come on now,
passengers are waiting.
- Don't get me started!
- Chief, what are you up to?
There are ladies in the bus,
you must wear it first!
Çetin, l won't wear it!
Damn it! Damn it!
Chief, have a sip. Coffee is
said to take off the edge.
lt took the most off me,
Çetin! lt's still burning.
At last Çetin, we are on the
earth where history of revolution.
- Uff!
- Don't say uff!
Howdy Emin Gakko,
l've come to rescue you all.
What rescuing are
you talking about?
Bro, what happened to your voice?
Look Çetin, when a man gets old,
his voice may change like this.
Mukhtar, good for you,
you have opened the store in...
... the crack of dawn so that
no one lays his hands on it.
- Where'd you come from?
- My answer is...
Mukhtar, why don't you say your
blessings, let me kiss your hand.
Have a seat and l'll
prepare the tea.
Çetin, when will you give up
these feudal habits of yours?
- Are you hungry? Will you eat?
- Nope.
We are a little hungry, Uncle.
Why Çetin, haven't you stuffed
yourself with cakes on the bus?
They said you would not be
able to come out of prison...
... before thirty years.
We apologize for coming
out so early; if we'd known...
... we'd have stayed for a while!
So, what are you
going to do now?
What will we do? We have
come to settle in the village.
What?
Folks move from the village to city,
you will move to village, right?
- See that Chief?
- Right?
When we marry two nice
ladies and come to power...
... in the village, you won't be
able to hold the villagers back in...
... ten years, l swear this will
be a global revolution village.
What marriage?
Uncle, you've just said no one
was left in the village...
... l hope there are one or two
decent single girls left.
One, at least?
- You can't get married.
- Why, aren't we men?
You are already married!
Look Çetin, we are facing
another typical feudal joke.
Mukhtar, haven't you
recognized us?
We are the red singles
Muro and Çeto.
- Muro, l've married you off...
- With whom?
- Two Russian girls.
- What?
Where?
Are they living in village?
Mukhtar, you are worth your salt.
They are beautiful, aren't they?
Damn Çetin, zip your mouth.
Chief, they are Russians,
they must be revolutionists.
Revolutionists my ass,
they are prostitutes.
Mukhtar, do you hear
what you are saying?
Why have you married
us off to whores?
Remember l've sent you five
hundred dollars each in prison?
What, what dollars?
Remember we were
a little short in cash?
You've sold your Chief, yourself and
the revolution for five hundred dollars,
... haven't you, you crook?
What would l know, Chief?
Mukhtar sold us and
send us the money.
Damn you Çetin, if we
pull ourselves from this shit...
... l swear l will put a
bullet to your head.
Mukhtar, tell me you're joking; l
swear l'll laugh at this cruel joke...
... of yours for four days
without stopping for breath.
l don'tjoke with marriage!
Girls needed certain methods
in order to stay in Turkey.
So?
My Son Muzo said, ''Muro
is my childhood friend.''
- So l've married you off.
- ls that so?
Write it down Çetin,
one lousy cell phone...
... one Hadji Muro and one
ball-saving baggy trouser are...
... confiscated on
behalf of revolution.
Come on Çetin.
Damn Muro, you were always a bandit
and you will always be a bandit!
Put those back in the glove
box Çetin, don't piss me off.
The number you have called
is temporarily unavailable...
How long is temporary, man?
Give me some information.
l need to find this Muzo prick.
Chief, l suggest we take a
medical opinion in lstanbul.
Thank you Çetin for caring for
every single part of your Chief.
- Chief, here we are.
- Don't shout in my ear.
Welcome in lstanbul? l swear l'm
willing to sacrifice half of my life...
... to live in lstanbul. There
is no other city like it!
Pass it, pass it.
l swear Sultan Mehmet
wasn't as rejoiced as you...
... when he conquered lstanbul.
Chief, metropolises are our home.
lf we were to drown, we
should be drowned in a big city.
l'll see you when we find the girls
and have them sign divorce papers.
At most, you'll be drowning in the
shitty stream of the village. Pull off.
Why Chief?
l'll drive because l'm a
cunning metropolis chap.
l resent it, Chief. l know lstanbul
like the back of my hand.
l'll take you there
with my eyes closed.
Where do you head off to?
We forgot the photos.
Chief, shall we ask these girls?
Damn your love for
women, douchebag!
- Welcome gentlemen, welcome.
- Hi.
- Welcome, welcome.
- Hello brother. - Hello.
Bro, there's a man called Muzaffer
Gündüz. Dark, crispy guy.
He has an office around
here, do you know him?
- l swear l don't know bro.
- Okay then.
- What's the deal? - Well, actually,
we are looking for two women.
We have women inside.
Come on in bro, come on.
Thanks.
Damn Çetin, why are you
jumping inside without...
... asking the women
we are looking for?
We'll see when we get in.
- Welcome misters.
- Thanks.
What would you like?
What would you like to have?
Bro, we're looking for Muzaffer
Gündüz. We'll take him and leave.
- Who? - Muzaffer Gündüz.
Muzo, Muzo.
A sucker with a crispy dark face.
Muzaffer...
He hasn't showed up today.
- Do you know him bro?
- l know him.
He had an office,
do you know where?
Two streets from here,
Zafer Travel Agency.
Come on Çetin, we are off.
He should be in his office
in the morning, Chief.
Maybe he is in the
office right now?
We are hungry, let us have
a few bite, drink a few cup.
Damn you Çetin, l'll feed
you outside, beat it!
Chief, maybe we'll find the girls
here, so we won't need Muzo.
We will be saving tonight, you
know, save our girls from others.
OK Çetin, zip it!
Guys, fully set the table with food.
No need for that, bro!
We are only looking. Hey!
- Chief?
- Huh?
Are all these women
married to guys like us?
What do you mean by
''like us'', Çetin?
- l mean, ambushed...
- How the heck l know?
We've lived for so long in
lstanbul; not once...
... you've taken me
to a place like this.
What business would a
revolutionist have here?
l wonder why capitalists
have all the places where...
... beautiful gals flock,
and revolutionists don't!
Because Çetin, only a man of
small bourgeoisie weak spots...
... lacking a revolutionary moral,
will come here. lmagine us here!
What the hell is that? Bro, these
are too much, take them away.
Perhaps you'll have company.
What company?
We don't know anyone.
Want me to call
two to your table?
You prick, do you hear
what you are saying?
God knows to whom these
women are married... Come on.
- Chief, this one looks single.
- Which one? - The purple one.
How do you know Çetin?
No married woman
shakes it like that, Chief.
Behave yourself Çetin and
act like a revolutionist!
lt hurts Çetin, it really does.
Where does it hurt, Chief?
Nowhere dick,
it hurts in the inside.
l'm trying to get over and you
keep reminding me of my balls!
No way, am l the one to remind
you of your thing, out of these broads?
Get lost!
- Hi.
- Hi! Here, here.
- Olga.
- Çetin.
Damn you Çetin, why are
you letting the girl sit down?
Chief, the gal liked me, so what
do l do, chase here away?
- What? - Break her heart?
She has a heart, too.
Let me introduce you;
Olga, this is my Chief Muro.
- Nice to meet you.
- The same here.
- What shall l bring you?
- Champagne.
Damn Çetin, if your sweetheart
leaves the bill on us...
... l swear l'll get
even with you.
Chill out for God's sake,
let us get a kick out of it.
- Where are you from?
- Ukraine.
- Where in Ukraine?
- Kiev.
- You?
- Ýstanbul.
Bullshitter.
- Your friend, alone?
- Do you have a friend?
- Your friend likes my friend?
- Then go get her.
You hick, the girl is leaving,
chase her away.
lt's okay Chief,
she's coming back.
Her friend liked you.
So l've told her to go get her.
Friend?
Possibly, they might
know our girls, right?
Possibly...
Needs questioning.
- Hi, Anna... - Muro.
- Anna. - Çetin.
- What shall l bring?
- Bro, why are you cutting in?
We've just met; give us some
space, stop interrupting!
- What shall he bring?
- Champaign mojna?
- You won't go lower than that
of course. - You be rude.
What did you see in me to
jump into that conclusion?
You see a lady, you don't
stand up? Are you a caveman?
Yes, l'm a caveman,
do you mind?
Thank you.
l'm the one who pays for it and
you thank him? Thank me!
Çetin, what's she gibbering about?
You are very rude.
l don't want you.
l don't want someone
who doesn't want me.
Please, please. Sit down.
Chief, show a little courtesy.
l've talked to them; they
said they knew our girls.
- Really Çetin?
- l swear.
Pardon me, we're tired of the road.
That's why we're a bit tense.
Anna...
- 300 dollar for two hours.
- Okay.
- What are they saying, Çetin?
- Chief l swear l didn't get a thing.
Miss Anna, l have
questions for you.
l talk in the room,
l take cash money.
- What room, what money?
- Okay l've given Olga the money.
- lt's okay, l've got the money.
- Good.
What money Çetin?
Chief, we can't keep the
girls around anymore.
- That's why we have to take
them to the rooms. - So, Çetin?
We need to give some
money in the rooms...
... after all they belong
to the working class.
Why should they have to
give up their hard-earned wages?
l didn't buy it, Çetin. l didn't! Don't
involve revolution in your dirty works.
What the heck?
Pay the bill Çetin.
- Brother?
- What?
Bro, don't forget to see me, okay?
How can l forget you bro,
you're standing right here!
You are a strong man,
why beg?
Çetin, where are the girls?
They're gone to bring
something to wear, Chief.
- So, Çetin? - So, Chief, l
believe we can get them to talk.
You're right. They won't be
resisting our questioning methods.
How can they, Chief?
There's no women to resist
our questioning methods.
Not only women, Çetin.
Men, women, no difference.
- lt's our taxi. - No, thanks. We
have our own car, we can take it!
Chief, girls got in. lt'll
be a shame if we don't.
- Okay then l'll take the front
seat. - You know better.
Thank you bro, don't
bother yourself.
- Brother, don't forget us, huh?
- Cosmos won't forget you bro.
Come on!
Don't forget us,
don't forget us!
- ldentities please.
- Çetin, take out your lD.
- Both of you.
- What? - Both of you.
Çetin! We're in the records now.
Nesim, take care of friends.
This way.
Here, that way.
Thanks, bro.
Let me show you the
place of TV, fridge, A/C.
No need bro, are we cavemen?
We can recognize TV, and fridge.
- Don't forget to see me.
- Why the hell would l see you?
My eyes popped out for
seeing you all day.
Let Çetin see you now.
Çetin, see how cute he is.
Come on...
Sir, your room is that way.
- Honey, champagne mojna?
- Go inside honey.
- No Champagne left?
- We have!
l said what l've said,
come on dear.
What do you get from
these bourgeois channels?
- Likes music...
- Who likes music?
l don't like talking,
l like music.
Why? Are we here to listen
to the music?
What's that?
- You very rude.
- You'd be rude too...
... if you'd been crashed by the
weight of revolution like me.
- Honey, do you shower?
- What showering?
- Wait, l'll first ask you a question
or two. - Showering first!
You're obsessed
with showering!
Tell me, do you know the Russians
who are working here?
l know no one.
So, how'd you pick up
Turkish language?
Honey, l had a boy friend
in Kiev, a total dick.
l learn Turkish from him.
Stop talking about a dick.
Let's not mention a man by-gone.
You called me rude, but you
are the one who is rude.
Listen, my reason
for calling you here is...
Honey you shower first,
then do the reasoning.
Holy Mother, nothing is stinking.
Shower, shower, shower!
Rude! You curse your mother?
Shame on you!
- No! That's a phrase.
- l love mother very much. You don't?
l love my mother too.
What's it with the mothers?
What is the poor woman
doing in this room?
- Olga, you are so pretty.
- You liar.
- What do you find pretty about me?
- What do you find ugly about you?
l no like my lips!
Cupcake, how can you
not like these lips?
Let me have a kiss.
- Olga, these are full of honey.
- Çeto, you funny.
Of course you
can call me Çeto.
Honey, l want champagne.
Look they're calling.
Apparently there is none, gosh!
Hello? This is Russian?
Hello. Hi. We're sitting, where
is yours? ln the shower?
Çeto, your friend is in the
shower. You shower, too.
What shower?
Business first, shower second.
l talk to friend Anna now.
You shower?
Chief, is this the
time for showering?
Damn this faucet!
Olga, here l am!
Yeah, you know what? He's
very handsome, classy man.
- Come on now, hang up.
- No, of course not.
Yeah, l like it very much.
- Why don't you hang up?
- Just a second, honey.
- Goodness Gracious Me!
- Yeah, of course.
Wait a sec, someone's at the door.
- Chief is in the shower?
- Yeah, come in.
What is it?
Chief, you are in the shower for an
hour, the hotel has run out of water.
What's it to you?
l've paid for it, haven't l?
l can either shower, or
leave the water running.
No Chief, my girl doesn't stop
talking on the phone while...
... you stay in the shower,
they are chatting non-stop.
Damn you Çetin.
A man can't even be left alone in
the bathroom, alright l'm coming.
Are you questioning
with this attitude Çetin?
l have to, Chief.
l am following what ever
she says to get her to talk.
l may even sacrifice
myself in this cause.
No kidding; live bomb Çetin, huh?
Come on Chief, the clock
is ticking, please hurry.
Don't rush me.
l'm working on a new
questioning method.
l'm mentally wearing her down
by taking a long shower.
Chief, your loss is great,
don't tire yourself out.
l'll get mine to crack anyway!
Am l such a naive that l'll
leave revolution on your hands?
- Beat it now!
- Enjoy it, Chief.
Get out of here.
l had my shower.
- Now l take shower.
- Yes.
You've talked my head off.
What do you look at, Muro?
Don't you see the girl has been
raised with revolutionist moral?
She does everything
but she never talks.
Why, you haven't dried yourself.
You'll get cold.
Honey, you're a great massager.
l'll answer all of your questions now.
Are you sure you're not hurt?
My hands are a little hard.
No honey, l like hard.
What do you mean by hard?
ls it okay?
- Honey, it's okay, go a little lower.
- How low?
Come on, hurry up, walk!
- Let go of my arm, it hurts!
- Let me go!
- Now, what were you asking?
- Do you know a Maria Rudenko?
- l don't.
- What?
- Çetin told me you knew her?
- l don't know her.
Damn Çetin, l'll crack you now!
What? Easy man, you're breaking it.
What the heck?
Vice Squad, prostitution.
What prostitution bro, do we
look like we are prostituting?
Get dressed, we're off.
No! Please don't, please
- Chief, have you cracked the girl?
- Damn you Çetin!
Let's pull ourselves
from this situation...
... and you'll see how l'm
going to crack you!
Damn! l couldn't crack
either, l'm a mess!
- Okay okay don't push,
we're moving. - Come on!
Look bro, there must
be a misunderstanding.
We were in a
questioning session.
Nothing else but questioning.
Damn you Çetin!
Shame on you! You Muro,
the great chief of metropolis...
... and you Çeto, his assistant,
you are held for prostitution.
Yes, we're really ashamed.
We had never been in...
... such an unjust position
against sovereign powers.
But our intention was
solely to question.
ln a hotel room, while
you're stripped naked?
Why not? lt's okay when the folks
run naked around holiday villages...
... but it's a crime when we tie
a tower around our waists?
Does it befit you to tie a towel,
instead of a rifle?
We know the place to tie a towel
and the place to tie the rifle!
You are talking about working
class, oppressed people.
But when it comes to you; you
are oppressing the poor girls?
Don't spark polemics; don't
engage me into demagogy.
l haven't brought these girls to the
country, nor have l made them...
... shake in clubs and discos, have
them lie on their backs in hotels!
And l have not closed my eyes
to them, using them three-star spies!
Now what are you holding
me accountable for?
Shut the hell up!
Go tell your stories to other
losers you've been deceiving!
l am ready for struggle,
now come on, are you in?
l can put an end to
prostitution in two days!
These women will be grannies and
have granddaughters working as...
... hookers until you receive your
approval from your heads in Ankara!
- Take'em to their cells!
- Take us to our cells!
Do you think Muro will
stop talking in the cells?
l'm calling to the blind generation
of a revolutionist nation.
The imperialist system of
exploitation will turn you into...
... hookers and us into marketers.
Let's stand arm in arm
and call it a stop.
What did you do, putting
the cops into our arms?
No room left for broads!
l'm on fire Çetin.
Hold on the shoulders.
Çetin! Çetin...
Hey Çeto...
- Wasn't l right in what l said?
- You were not, Chief.
Explain to me then, in
which part was l not right?
All parts from start to finish.
Çetin, l think you are criticizing
your Chief with prejudice!
Well, we were already
caught in a weak spot.
lnspector had all the right
to say what he wanted.
lf you'd exercised your right to
silence, we would have been...
... cracking others
outside this cell.
But you saw how that
spy provoked me!
He openly provoked me!
What are you doing
here, youngsters?
l didn't catch anything from
what you were telling!
Look, if l were to tell you
about unarmed propaganda...
... you'd answer me
with ''six-pack or two-four?''
So close your eyes and sleep!
Çetin, get up and cooperate.
Get us out of here,
l don't want to deal with drunks!
Chief, you are the one
cursing their mothers...
... how am l to convince
their fathers?
What did you say?
Officer, officer!
lnspector!
Thank you, Chief Çetin.
Çetin, my sugar dropped
down in the jail.
How about eating desserts?
l've eaten in jail until full, Chief,
enjoy your meal.
You are being hurtful, Çetin.
Bro, will you get me one?
Of course bro, here.
Çetin, it is crispy crunch.
Sorbet has perfect consistency.
- Won't you eat?
- Nope.
- Mate, how much is this?
- Where are you from brother?
What's it to you? Will you give a
discount from one lira to fifty kurush?
Be L'lnternationale!
Çetin, pay for the dessert,
l don't want to deal with him.
- Why is he so tense?
- Don't you see, his sugar dropped.
Here.
- Hi.
- ls Muzo here?
- Who are you?
Tell him that two duffers are here
who want to marry Russian girls.
ls he paying us 500$ each?
Mr. Muzaffer isn't here now.
l'll note down your numbers so he
can call you when he comes back.
- When will he come back?
- l don't know.
Then we'll wait inside.
You can't wait, you don't
have an appointment.
- You hick, stop it. Çetin, take
this bastard away. - Come here.
Make us an appointment
for a minute past now!
- Sir, do you understand Turkish?
- Pardon me, l learned Turkish...
... at the age of ten and l'm
doing well for twenty years.
- lt's your turn now! - You, crazy!
l don't understand you?
Chief, you really like
to argue with women.
We should go inside and wait for
him, whether he comes or not.
Don't you see the damned
thing sparks a polemic!
- Muro?
- Muzo?
- Bro, when did you come out?
- lt's been thirty five years.
When did you come out, bastard?
Who are you to marry us off?
My father called. He said
you were in short of money.
Çetin, there are bunch of
other men in the village.
l'm doing you a favor in your hard times;
and you have come here to insult me.
Can't you give the money
without marrying us?
They were deceived.
The girls were led to believe
that here they'll be working...
... in a textile workshop.
l felt pity for them.
l've married them to you so that the
poor things could feed themselves.
Thank God, Chief they were
not whores but the working class.
They are working in
a workshop, right?
Damn Çetin, stop talking nonsense
and getting on my nerves.
Muzo, call these women, get
them here and divorce us.
And from now on, stop making
favors and decently work...
... in your own workshop.
That's piece of cake.
We'll handle it later.
Now let's go to my place. l'll have
my wife Fidan cook for you.
Don't move an arm;
l'm fed up with your lies.
We are not going anywhere.
You will take care of it today.
Then l'll take you to
dinner anywhere you like.
You are the one who demands divorce;
and still want the women coming to you.
No way, you have to go to them!
Damn Çetin, do you hear him?
He's talking like l've
begged him to marry me!
Muzo, are you sure
the women are here?
Muzo, are they here or not?
Surprise!
Sweetheart, l've made up
a dozen lies to get them here.
These villagers have
not missed you at all.
- Welcome, Mr. Murat. - lt's nice
to be here by force, Mrs. Fidan.
Come on in.
This husband of yours has
turned into a total bourgeois.
Sister Fidan, l've heard a lot
about you from my Chief.
This was the day to meet.
Nice to meet you.
Mr. Murat always has
something to say.
Thank you for the
trouble Mrs. Fidan.
What trouble Mr. Murat? Cold
yoghurt soup quenches thirst.
Chief and l were dying of thirst.
Thank you sister.
So, are you staying in
lstanbul for long?
No, Muzo and l have a short business
to take care of; then we'll leave.
What business?
l swear l'm very glad that you
gave up the organization.
We didn't give up the organization,
organization gave us up.
Thank God!
What are you talking about,
what quitting?
Muzo, stop dancing
around and call the girls.
You just have to name it, Chief.
What kind of a girl you desire?
Blond, brunette, Chinese?
What?
l'm such an idiot! Of course
you have just gotten out ofjail.
- Muzaffer, can you find
Olga and Anna? - Çetin!
Why not? Maybe they haven't left yet,
we should have our money's worth!
- What money?
- What money, what women?
Just call the girls and
learn their whereabouts.
Why are you so impatient?
What'll happen if you stay
married for one more day?
- Damn it, he's sparking a polemic.
- Don't be engaged in it.
How can l resist?
Look, stop getting on my nerves.
Call the women,
let's go to their place!
Okay, okay l am calling.
Hello, listen, reserve me two...
... most expensive luxury
rooms in the hotel, okay?
- What hotel, what room?
- Listen, l have VlP guests, okay?
Don't get me started with
the VlP or with guests!
Don't be silly, don't mention
the hotel. This is your home.
Thanks, but we should go.
Okay, l'm waiting to hear
from you. Don't let me down.
What are you going
to do in the village?
Stay here, let's do
business, trading.
- Trading?
- Another polemic has started.
Shuttle trade.
lt's still a cash cow.
l have partners in Russia, to
whom l send jeans, t-shirts, shirts.
They sell like hot cakes.
You wouldn't know how
obsessed they are with brands.
Do you hear what you say?
Muro, Muro the revolutionist, will
exploit the red Russian nation...
... by selling capitalist
bourgeois brands? ls that so?
Not the originals,
these are fake!
What? Denim-selling Muro,
market-seller Muro!
Faker-Muro, is that
how you imagine?
- Mr.Murat, care for some
stuffed eggplant? - No, l don't.
- l'll have some.
- Why don't you eat all of it Çetin?
Of course he won't eat.
This can't be eaten alone.
- Let's drink.
- l don't drink
- Come on, for me?
- Don't get me started with you!
- Chief, get out of the polemic.
- Okay, l will. l won't hit you.
Come on Muzo,
let's head up to the hotel.
The hotel you've just called!
No, wait a moment. We are
waiting to hear from the hotel.
Fidan, have a word with this villager.
He won't eat or drink anything.
He never listens to me.
Husband and wife have
cooperated to stuff me.
What am l, an eggplant?
Get up Muzo!
We should at least finish
up our drinks.
What are you up to?
Muro, are you slow in the head?
l couldn't have said that l'm calling
the women with Fidan around.
l've called the broads,
pretending to call the hotel.
Çetin, watch for Fidan.
Then why are you stalling me?
lt's closed. The phone is closed.
You don't know where
the workshop is?
lt rings.
Honey, what's up? Good.
Darling, l'm going to call you.
Bye.
Sweetheart we need to get going.
Come on, come on get up.
What the heck?
What's happening to me?
A double would
not usually affect me.
Come, come, come...
- Çetin.
- Chief.
l need to throw up.
Bro what are you doing? There's
a human, not a cat lying in it.
- Chief? - Couldn't you find
another place to lie down?
No. We couldn't.
This is our hobby, lying down
the garbage bin in our free times.
Put this thing down, will you?
Damn you Muzo,
damn you Muzo!
No one can save
you from me now!
Çetin, call Yýldýrým and
tell him to pick us up.
Chief, we don't have a phone.
We're left in this deserted place.
What kind of words are these?
Damn it, damn it!
Friends, comrades, members
of the proletariat, wait for us.
You don't know but we are
facing a great conspiracy...
... could you take us to
somewhere appropriate?
- Alright.
- Thank you very much.
So, what about your salaries?
Do you get overtime pay?
Are you in a union?
Don't get me started
with the Union!
We are driving this crap, while
they are driving a Mercedes..
- Damn it man, damn it!
- Chief, what do we do now?
We'll take the car and leave
Çetin. What else can we do?
We don't have the car keys.
Then convince it to
open the doors, Çetin.
- Pardon me?
- What a prick!
- Çetin convince the car by
hot-wiring... - l'll give it a try, Chief.
God damn you Muzo,
damn you!
You've left me in such a shit!
What are you looking at!
Damn!
Why would you lock the car Çetin,
who would want to steal it?
- Do you want to have fun?
- What do you mean by fun?
l've got very hot girls.
Where are the photos gone?
Look, we need two blondes with
blue eyes, Marsha and Daria, huh?
Do you know them?
l've got prettier, better girls!
Bro, you call yourself a pimp,
then act as a pimp as well.
l want those ones,
can you get them for me?
But you're being too much, brother.
l wanted to make you a favor.
- Would a Chief like me, ask for
the favor of a pimp? - Chief!
Alright Çetin, l'm not attacking in
a polemic, l'm attacking the guy.
- Chief, not that, look ahead!
- What's happening there?
- We don't want, we are models, not
whores! - What models? You'll do...
- exactly as l tell you! Get in. - You
have a sister. Go get her to do it!
Stop talking and get in.
Take her in, will you?
- Hey, asshole!
- What the hell?
- Leave the girls alone.
- l'll kick your ass too!
- Shut up, dumbass!
- Oh God!
- Come here sweetie.
- What an asshole!
Honey, this man is bad.
He took our passports away.
Come sweetie.
Stop hugging the girl and take
the passports. Stop crying.
Çetin hurry up man, we should
leave before they come to themselves.
Okay.
Go, go, run!
- Come on girls, move it.
- Run sweetie, run!
This is the car, red one.
- lt smells awful!
- Çeto, what is this smell?
Don't ask, it's a long story.
Çetin, don't ever start
a polemic, be quiet.
Why are we here, if the
house is dangerous?
Honey, we have clothes at home.
Do you want us naked?
Honey, what is a piece of
cloth? We'll buy from a store.
What? Sorry Mr. Çetin,
l forgot, who were you again?
Cotton trader? How are
you going to pay?
There's now a fake of everything.
We'll ask Muzo.
Okay Çetin, stop chatting.
Come on you two, hurry up.
Thank you, you go.
You in danger.
Get in fast, get out fast.
We're waiting you here!
We're afraid of no one.
Chief, l'll help the girls.
ln case anything happens.
You're scared that the girls
will run away, aren't you?
Don't move for a minute, we
need to conduct an analysis!
Why don't we go up too?
We'll wash our hands, take a shower.
Shower huh? Poser!
Chief, l swear l'm only
caring for your own good.
For your revolutionist balls.
What if they get an infection?
Speak of the good, Çetin!
Çetin, what do we do now?
How would l know? They are
stuck to us because of you!
l should've left the man to kill the
girls! Damn my love for humans!
Chief, when you say humans,
do you discriminate between genders?
Çetin, don't get on my
nerves speaking non-sense.
Call Yýldýrým, tell him to provide
us with logistic support.
- OK, l'll get Olga's phone.
- You'll get it when she comes back.
Dicks, they are coming here.
They called our friend.
Çeto, let's go quick.
Honey, will you hand over
the phone for a minute?
But we are in no
position to run away!
You'll be running very
hard with this Lada!
What? Lada is your father! Do you
always have to go wrong with me?
Don't you see,
this is the Hadji Muro.
- Hello. Yýldýrým!
- Get in the car!
Where are you? We
need logistic support, urgently.
Çetin, are you sure
this is the right way?
Chief, Yýldýrým told us to turn left.
So we have.
Chief...
- We found Yýldýrým.
- Come on Chief.
Drive straight.
Closer, closer.
Welcome Chief.
We're welcome Yýldýrým,
we're welcome.
Chief, did you pick up these
sisters from the village?
Yes, Yýldýrým they are from
the village. Liked them?
Stop talking silly and jarring on
my nerves! Prepare the tea for us!
On your order, Chief.
Çetin, get your things,
we are leaving.
Çeto, pool!
l like swimming very much.
Anna this is a great pool.
We'll swim and sunbathe.
- Do you think they own the house?
- l don't know, maybe. Who cares?
Chief, where do we head to?
l don't know Çetin,
we'll figure out some place.
Chief, let's stay tonight.
We'll find Muzo in the morning...
... get it in the open and then
we'll go where ever you show.
Damn you Çetin, l just
couldn't tame your capitalist soul.
You made a favor, so you want
to get your share at night, right?
That's not the issue, Chief.
l believe Anna has feelings for you.
And you should clean up or
else it will get an infection!
Thank you for your orders
Doctor Çetin!
- Yýldýrým! - Yes Chief?
- Show me the bathroom.
Follow me Chief. This way.
- What?
- Chief...
- What is it Yýldýrým?
- Chief, l think these will suit you.
- Yýldýrým, what's that?
- Jeans.
Have you ever seen
me wearing jeans?
Chief, you are not on the mountain;
you'll not be working on the ground.
l thought you'd be
comfortable in them?
Yýldýrým, l won't wear it.
- Chief. - What?
- l brought your tea.
- Where is Çetin?
- He's showing Olga the room.
What a dog!
Yýldýrým, keep Çetin close that he
won't step on a mine or something.
Yes Chief.
What is this?
l need to apply ice.
No, no; it's okay.
What are you looking at?
Honey, you look a lot
like Antonio Banderas!
Who is he? A red?
No, an actor, l like him very much.
He's you with long hair, without beard.
You are like twins.
A revolutionist can not compare
or be compared with another man.
Compare me to Marx, to Lenin;
but not to Hollywood yuppies.
Yýldýrým made me wear these.
- Honey, you're so tense?
- lt must be of the wind of the pool.
- Come Honey. - To where?
- Come.
You must be tired
and sleepy, right?
Hey, what do you
think you're doing?
l am expressing my gratitude.
No, no!
Don't express me your gratitude.
l'm not waiting for a return.
- l want you.
- Thank you, may cosmos bless you.
l want you too, let's accept it.
But if l go for it...
... l'll be betraying myself,
and betraying revolution.
- Why? - Because a revolutionist
would never expect...
... a favor in return of a
favor he has done.
That son of a widow,
is still an intern revolutionist!
Not a full revolutionist!
l'll go and have a look.
Çeto don't!
You've broken the bed.
lt's better than my pride being broken.
Do you want me to be Chief's joke?
You are crazy!
lt's normal due to over excitement.
You say it's normal but
how'll l explain to my Chief...
... that a revolutionist
became excited?
That's enough. Honey, l'm going
downstairs, do you need anything?
l'm good, honey.
Look, don't think of
sleeping until l get back.
Alright, honey.
Chief Çetin, l was thinking that
maybe l need a girlfriend too.
lt's early for you.
No Muro?
- Chief is gone but he's
coming back. - To where?
- To Muzo. - Why are
you telling me this now?
But you haven't asked,
Chief Çetin.
How would l know? l thought
he was sleeping with sister Anna!
Muro didn't stay in my room.
This time Chief's so stressed
that he'll definitely kill Muzo.
- ls Muzo inside?
- He waits for you.
For who? Where do you find the
chutzpah to talk to me like that?
You are a secretary,
so act like one.
Muro, what was that scene you
made last night? Does it befit you?
What are you talking about?
You've soiled my
reputation in lstanbul.
What was that number
you pulled in the hotel?
Which hotel, which scene?
Harassing women,
cursing, goosing...
What the heck?
l've put you in your rooms
with my own hands.
Why did you leave your
rooms and yell...
... ''we want women,
we want women!''?
What did you pour
into our drinks?
Muro, you can't drink
decently and you foul my name.
By the way, the women said
that they'd never get near you...
... leave alone divorcing.
Call the women and we'll ask them
whether or not l'd done such things?
l don't have the face
to call anyone!
l'll take your face and...
And...
Do you want me to kill you!
You conspirator, comprador, spy!
Help, help, police, police!
So, were you demanding tribute payment
within the knowledge of organization?
What the heck? Are we
speaking the same language?
Why can't l make my point?
No, no you do make your point.
You just get out ofjail.
Come to Aksaray...
Hot chicks...
Once you taste, you want the rest
but you don't have the money, right?
So you go and bully others.
- Bravo inspector.
- Bravo inspector, l congratulate you.
Your analysis gets as good as it
gets. Let me make an analysis.
Let's call Muzo's wife Fidan; if
she confirms her husband's story...
... then l'm willing to be hung!
What does my wife
have to do with it?
You take me to your home by force, you
fed me by force, you had me drinking.
Fidan is my only witness.
Would you take me to your home,
if l was the one threatening you?
Muro is resorting to demagogy,
to cover up his crime.
l'm not asking something
difficult to achieve...
... call her so that she can testify.
- Call her.
- Bravo inspector.
Bravo, inspector.
You take a bandit's word...
... for the word of a
reputable tax payer like me!
A state which relies on
the words of a bandit, then...
... l'm withdrawing my complaint.
Who's withdrawing what?
l have a complaint
against this tax-payer...
... who became the slave
of vulgar capitalism!
Alright, alright, stop
shouting slogans.
lf l see you in Aksaray again,
l'll commit you in prison.
This is my last warning!
ls he -the capitalist conspirator-
going to get away with this?
But, these insults are unnecessary.
- You counterfeit!
- God!
Take Muro in!
Of course,
everybody strikes Muro!
Call a cab, Çetin, right away.
- Are we going home, Chief?
- Not home, we're going to kill Muzo!
Chief, the inspector said he
didn't want to see you in Aksaray.
Do you have to kill Muzo
right at this minute?
l don't have to Çetin,
it's the order of the cosmos.
Taxi! Hey mate,
what are you doing?
What is it Yýldýrým?
Where are you?
- Who are you talking to?
- Yýldýrým is calling. - Alright.
Damn it, l'm sure
she's hiding in the house.
Chief, why would sister
Fidan be hiding?
Çetin, damn well you wouldn't show
your face with a husband like that.
Get out of the way!
Damn Muzo, damn you.
The cops will bust us,
and we'll get arrested.
- l don't care if the president
comes! Muzo! - Chief, don't!
Chief, don't you see he's gone?
We'll be in prison for another 30
years in the cause of your obsession.
l won't be sure without
checking all rooms!
Damn you Muzo, damn you!
Where the heck is this guy?
- l don't know Chief.
- The cops! Move!
Where do you think?
We're heading home to make
tactical and strategic analysis.
- What about Taksim?
- Çetin, what about Taksim?
We should analyze
among common people.
What will we do in Taksim?
Chief, the girls are bored at home,
Yýldýrým didn't show them around.
l'm talking about tactics, strategies
and you're talking about broads!
Chief, sister Anna wanted to
get you a gift of gratitude.
- Which gratitude? - You saved
her life, Chief. Don't underestimate.
We shouldn't overestimate
these issues, Çetin.
You know we walk side by side
our oppressed people all the time.
- Where were they? - Yýldýrým said,
take a turn from the doner shops.
ls there another place to turn?
You've jumbled me with the crowd.
Why, Chief?
l wanted the people of our
noble nation to see their leaders.
- That's what l've reckoned.
- Don't reckon that.
Do you think our people see
anything but bourgeois...
... imperialist, capitalist signs?
What leader?
Çetin, why don't
you call Yýldýrým?
l believe we're almost there
Chief, no need to call.
Almost where?
Where are we going?
Chief, are you hungry?
l swear l'm starving like a dog.
Çetin, at which of these capitalist
shops do you want to eat?
Why would a human being
want to eat in here?
Çetin!
Why are you grinning, Çetin?
Honey, welcome!
Honey, the bikini is
very nice, thank you!
What the heck?
Where is the other half of it?
Couldn't you find another place
to eat in the whole lstanbul?
l like potatoes here, Chief.
Really? l'm fond of
the potatoes of Niðde.
But l don't go all the
way to Niðde, do l?
- Honey, for me?
- For you? For you, l'd do any...
What are you looking at? l've
got a headache, hand me a pill.
- Olga, you got painkillers?
- Yes honey.
l'm only having fries to avoid
pill's perforating my stomach.
Chief, do you mind trying
the fries with mustard?
How do you know
about mustard, Çetin?
You're hurting my feelings.
You think poised hammer
is dropping only rifles.
Why, they drop mustards,
mayonnaise, ketchup.
Çetuþka...
Do you wonder
about poised hammer?
Let my Chief explain it to you.
Please go on, my fair Chief.
Poised hammer is the hammer
that gives with a spoon...
... but takes away
with a bucket.
Such as lMF!
Such as NATO!
Çetuþka, what have you done,
giving the wrong pill to Chief?
He'll be fine.
He will be fine? Honey,
Chief popped the X!
He needs disco, needs to
get it out of his system!
Why didn't you tell it before?
- l'm familiar with...
- Brother, how much?
Can't you read, bro?
Prices are written here.
Not those, the broads?
- Come again? - How much
do you want for these broads?
l'll take you down! Yýldýrým,
bite his ear, Yýldýrým.
l'm going to kill you!
Damn Çetin, if capitalism makes
a man a pimp in the first...
... and only try think
about the second.
Çetin, what's happening to me?
Damn Çetin, my body is on fire,
is it the fries of that damned place?
Chief, perhaps negative energy
has accumulated within our bodies.
We should discharge it. Perhaps
we should go some place?
You're right,
let's go and waste Muzo.
Where can that capitalist,
bourgeois, comprador be?
- How about the disco Chief?
- What do you mean by disco?
Reina, Sortie and a variety of
other discos by the Bosphorus.
Çetuþka, we go to Reina, l want
to see it very badly. Thank you.
My honeybunny, don't thank
me sweetie, thank the Chief.
- Chief, thank you, Reina.
- Çetin, what's she saying?
Your analysis was a success, Chief.
Muzo must certainly be in Reina.
- Honey, did you like my gift?
- Chief, a classical ltalian cut.
Yýldýrým, your father was an ltalian
but l couldn't remember your mother!
We're not going to any discos.
No one is leaving anywhere.
Don't move.
Don't drink.
- You are a bad man!
- Don't push me, l'm stressed.
Damn Çetin, what's
wrong with me?
Chief, l think we
need to jump around.
Çetin, it is as if l have
another Muro inside me...
... who wants to run
through the hills.
- l feel like l want to kiss
you all. - Disco?
Damn Çetin, people will reckon
you were born in a disco, you hick.
Has your father ever
seen a disco in his life?
You're hurting my feelings, Chief.
My dad went to ''tanz-dancing'' during
his days as a worker in Germany.
He also had first place in
twisting and a medal for it.
Why don't you carry the medal
around your neck then?
l won't step a foot in a
disco unless l'm dead.
lsn't this nice? We're introducing
the girls with our own culture.
Haven't we started halay too fast?
What if we run out of breath?
Don't cop out, Çetin. Keep halay going
and revolution running. Come on!
Come on Çetin, keep going.
Mates, l beg you,
play another song!
We are exhausted, bro!
l'm usually nothing like this,
but today l have an extra to me.
Çetin, Yýldýrým, come here.
l'm the Chief, l'm calling
you here. Girls, you too?
You're playing?
l swear l love you so much
that l'll kiss you one by one.
Come on Yýldýrým, come on!
- Chief?
- What?
The dawn is breaking,
shouldn't we head home?
You'd be jumping till the morning
if we were in Layla, Reina, right?
lf l don't discharge my
energy when we get home...
... if my head keeps turning; then
l will have you dancing the halay...
... inside the pool until morning!
Come on Çetin, come on!
Keep the pace!
Chief, l swear, l'm finished.
You're still talking Çetin,
so you can't be finished.
- Çetin, damn you, get up!
- Chief, l swear l'm worn out.
Yýldýrým, take him away.
l don't need an offbeat
comrade dancing with me!
- Good night Chief...
- Good night Olga!
Anna, come here l'll show
you our folk dance.
- l sleep, Muro. - Why do you
sleep now? Come next to me.
l am too tired.
Give me a kiss.
Come on.
Honey...
See, it's very simple.
You take two steps to the
right and one to the left.
Got it? Come on.
One two three...
Good for you! l'm showing
you the spine of halay, now.
You hit, then you jump.
Muro, l'm tired, l'm not coming.
Swimming in the morning.
Muro...
Honey, l sweated like a pig.
l don't want to smell next to you.
Should l get a shower?
No, honey l like sweat.
You used to nag at
my head for showering.
No, honey, l like your smell.
Of course you do, once you've
smelled a revolutionist...
- ... you'll never forget.
- You are bad.
Okay girl. l like the way
you smell, too.
Armani, l like very much.
Why are you putting a third
man in a double bed?
- Anna?
- Honey?
- Are you asleep?
- No.
So, why are you quiet?
What do you want?
You want me to talk?
- Talk and l'll listen. - What do
you want me to talk about?
Tell me about the revolution,
the great leader Lenin.
- Lenin?
- Yes Lenin, Vlademir llyich Lenin.
Lenin is a total dick!
Watch your language, woman!
Am l cursing at your father?
- Lenin, your father?
- Lenin is my father.
Lenin is the father of all reds.
- Lenin is not my father.
- Who's your father? Bush?
- Good night Chief.
- Good night Çetin.
- Cal-vin, Calvin Klein!
- Chief?
Keep imperialism away from the
cleavage, Çetin. Leave it alone!
Okay.
- No! We're busted!
- Yýldýrým!
- Chief! We are busted!
- Yýldýrým, why panic?
The worse that can happen
will be to get arrested!
Chief, the landlord is here!
What? But you said they were
gone for three months! Çetin!
Çetin!
Anna! Anna!
Anna wake up!
We'll do it in the morning Muro,
l'm very tired.
Do what? Get up, dress up.
We're leaving. We are busted.
Who are you? Who is there?
Where are you Yýldýrým?
Sir, what are you doing here?
Stop talking, now.
Open the door.
Sir, when you were gone, l've
sprayed insecticide the whole house.
You'll get poisoned.
Open the door.
Where have you been?
Come in Sir.
Welcome Madam.
At least go and get
our luggage from the car.
Okay sir.
Who are you?
This is rudeness!
Collaborative comprador friend
is asking you a question, Çetin.
Hillbillies! You didn't set a
scarecrow, you've set a watch...
... you should've given
the guy a heads up...
... so that we can take
our position accordingly.
lf we were to make the revolution,
then this is the time!
l swear l've had it with this
miserable proletariat life.
Çetuþka, who were
those people?
Sweetie, they are my cousins.
We were at odds with them.
The house belongs to us,
but those squatters occupied it.
We didn't make a scene
because of you.
Otherwise, l'd choked
them to death.
Çetin, do you have other
bourgeois cousins in lstanbul?
Why don't you call them
and inform that we're coming.
Lying poser!
Yýldýrým, you've tarnished
my revolutionist charisma.
Chief, why are you hitting me?
l've already lost my job.
- Where are we going?
- Where do you want to go?
l don't know.
l've got friends alright;
but it'd be rude to knock...
... at their doors at this hour.
l'd suggest going
to a hotel, but...
We have a friend, Natalie, she
is a great girl, let's go to her place.
What will we do in a stranger's
house at this hour?
- Sister, is Natalie single?
- Single.
- Hi.
- Hi. - Hi.
Good night, girl.
l'm Yýldýrým.
Chief!
- Yýldýrým!
- Coming, Chief.
Get inside, we're coming.
Where were you?
l was worried sick.
- We've been through so much.
- Who are they?
We'll tell you,
it's a long story.
She's old but in good shape.
Chief, who is this Natalie?
My second cousin.
How would l know Yýldýrým?
My eyes are picking
her up from before.
Your eyes are hungry dogs,
picking up everything on the way.
Miss Natali, forgive us
for coming at this hour.
But we'll leave
early in the morning.
No problem, honey.
l'm familiar with having guests.
- How familiar? - Yýldýrým,
don't make me tie you here.
Çeto, let's go to bed,
l'm exhausted.
Chief, we're really exhausted,
let's go to bed...
... and we'll make a sound
analysis in the morning.
Good night to you all! Miss
Natali, care to show our room?
Of course.
Goodnight Chief.
There is Muzo.
Hello, Chief?
Hi father.
What have l told you?
You'll peak Turkish, speak Turkish.
- Eat my wiener.
- What? - Eat my wiener.
Get over there, go!
Bro, come in.
- Yýldýrým, what's that?
- Chief.
- Are you sure he was him?
- Yes, Chief, it was Muzo.
Yýldýrým, then head for the
home and wait with the girls.
lt can take long. l don't
know when we'll be back.
Yes Chief.
This kid is weird in someway,
but l couldn't figure out how.
Chief, l want to tell you something.
Olga proposed to me.
- What? Do women propose
nowadays? - l've said yes.
What? Çetin, what are
you saying? Çetin?
- Hello, the beautiful person
of the cold country. - Hello.
- ls Mr. Muzaffer here?
- Yes he is, come in. - Thank you.
Does this psycho have
a problem with me?
- Well, Chief, the women love me.
- We will have our talk later, Çetin.
- Brother Muzaffer, how are you?
- Where have you been?
Kid! Put the gun down,
cosmos will load it!
Çetin, take the
bastard to his mother.
Come, dear.
You've fallen into
my hands, Muzo.
Okay Muro, l spoke with the
girls, they agreed to divorce you.
They'll come through
this door in a moment.
Alright then. l'll close my
eyes and count to three.
When l open them, l want to
see two women ready to divorce.
Otherwise you are a dead man.
- One...
- Chief!
Çetin, we'll talk about that
issue later. Two...
- Chief! - Çetin, it is not the
time to argue. Two and a half...
- But Chief! - Çetin, forget
about the marriage. Three!
- Chief, for God's sake, open
your eyes! - What the heck?
- l'll shoot you!
- Shoot!
- l swear l'll shoot you.
- You should!
Muro...
What? Muro Muro Muro.
l've had it with you for 35 years!
Brother Muzaffer, why don't
you tell where the women are?
Muro, you'll look after
my family from now on.
You bastard, if you die,
l swear l'll take care of...
... all generations of
your family. Come on.
Chief, how do we
get to divorce now?
Damn you Çetin, don't
mess with my head...
... or the next bullet
is coming to you.
- Brother Muzaffer, are you dead?
- Çetin!
Çetin, get a cab to home.
l have some business.
- Where are you going, Chief?
- l said l have business.
Cross your heart Natalie,
you have a fortune!
Fortune?
Love, money, which one?
Not only love but also blind love.
His name starts with a ''Y''.
- Yaþar?
- What Yaþar? Who is Yaþar?
- Yaþar the waiter.
- Never mind Yaþar the waiter.
- Yaþar does not have an ''l''.
- This one's got an ''l'' in it. - l...
And one other thing.
l see a wedding.
Yýldýrým, you compadan,
how did you know?
- Really?
- Çeto and l are getting married!
Getting married, how?
Honey, Cetuska got down
on his knees and said...
... ''Honey, l love you so much.
l don't want to live without you.
... Will you marry me?''
Look, here's the ring.
Why aren't you happy Yýldýrým?
But sister, Chief Çeto and
Chief Muro are already married.
- You liar! Sneaky!
- Wait. What happened?
You are a big liar, shame on you.
Take your ring.
- Give it to your wife. - l swear
it's not true. l'm not married.
- ls Yýldýrým lying?
- Damn Yýldýrým, l'll kill you.
Has Yýldýrým also told you that
this was a fake marriage?
l've never even seen those
women once in my life.
You are lying.
You don't love me.
Sweetie, l'm not lying to you.
l may have forgotten to tell
you some parts of my life.
- Go! - l won't go!
Kill me if you want.
l can't be without you.
Come on, stop being stubborn.
Give me a hug.
Come here.
Are you mad at me!
Give me a kiss, let's make it up.
Mr. Murat, what
brings you here?
Fidan, l shot Muzo.
Why didn't you shoot
him 20 years before?
What's the point? Why do
you bring back old issues?
Did you shoot him to marry me?
Fidan, don't talk nonsense. Why
did you marry Muzo if you loved me?
l wouldn't have married
him if you were into me.
You were so into the revolutionary
path, you didn't realize me.
l'm still following that path.
l'm going to the mountains.
Will you leave me in the lurch?
Fidan...
l won't let people say l
shot Muzo to get his wife.
l'm sorry.
- Priviyet.
- Priviyet yourself!
Chief, Natali and l were
looking through the album.
Drop the album. Tell Çetin
to get ready, we're leaving.
Have you been crying?
Why didn't you tell me
you were married?
- Why would l?
- l wish you did.
Never mind. lt doesn't
mean anything now.
- Why?
- l'm going back.
- Where?
- Mountains.
- ls it because Muzo died?
- Did Çetin tell you that?
Muro, let's go to Kiev.
No one will find you there.
- What will l do in Kiev?
- Come with me Muro.
lt all ends here.
- Are you ready Çetin?
- No Chief.
l've told you to pack.
Didn't you hear Çetin,
we are leaving!
Chief, forgive me.
l can't come.
What? What will you do
if you are not coming?
l'm going to stay here, Chief.
Who will keep you alive,
state or the organization?
Like we have the chance of
surviving in the mountains.
Çetin, don't spark a polemic.
Say your goodbyes, let's go
out of here as soon as possible.
Chief, l can't live without Olga.
Who will keep you
alive here with Olga?
lt doesn't matter.
l'll live even for a day.
Çetin, what about our ideals,
our people, revolution?
Chief, l don't care about the
revolution or the ideals without you.
l believed in them
because of you.
And you are abandoning your
Chief, who made you believe?
Don't get me wrong Chief
but mountains are not the...
- ... place for solution.
- You're living in a dream, Çetin.
When you wake up, Yýldýrým
won't be there, l won't be there.
Olga will be gone for long.
l don't want to wake up
from the dream, Chief.
Çetin!
Chief, stop.
- Chief!
- Yýldýrým! - Chief!
- Çetin! - Chief!
Damn it, l had taken
the bastard's gun.
- Çeto, weren't you convincing
the Chief? - l did, Olga.
Convince who?
Çeto said, ''Olga wait,
l'll talk to the Chief and...
- ... convince him not to leave.''
- When?
Chief, were you really
going to leave me?
Yýldýrým already stirred
up trouble today.
Chief Çetin, look at what
you did in my happiest day?
Why are you happy?
Chief, Natalie said...
... she was going to fix
me up with one of them.
You hick, l swear, poor woman
will bring the whole Russian...
... nation to get rid off you.
Chief, if you give your
blessings, than it is on.
- Natalie, are these your friends?
- Yes.
- Are they living in lstanbul?
- Which one of them is
for Yýldýrým? - Neither one.
Why Chief?
Because one of them is my and
the other one is Çetin's wife.
Come on, let's get going.
Chief, l'm afraid these women will
get scared and not divorce us.
Either they divorce us willingly,
or we become widowers.
Chief, violence is not the solution.
l'm telling you l'm not
setting foot in the prison again.
Let's solve our
problems by talking.
- Okay Çetin, you are in command.
- Thank you Chief.
You're welcome Çetin.
- Eat my wiener!
- What?
- Çetin?
- Chief?
Damn Muzo!
Yýldýrým, get me the rifle!
Damn you Muzo!
Yýldýrým, take the door.
Çetin, hold this.
- Muzo? - Muro?
Where have you been?
Come in, l've found your women.
l was waiting for you, come in.
You counterfeit!
You've found them five years
ago, the bastard shows his age.
- Are you still denying?
- God!
Take this Çetin.
Muzo!
Which one of you is my wife?
Aren't you ashamed of
marrying a strange man, traitors?
Muzo!
You are dead.
Çetin, give me the piece.
Get out of the way.
Chief, if l'm in command,
we are not killing anyone.
Shut it about commanding!
Girls, don't panic.
Chief has always assigned me on
door duty in these types of operations.
Damn you Muzo, damn you!
The guy has married us to his
mistresses, he is still playing with us.
Open it!
Don't call them mistresses,
they are your sisters-in-law.
My sister is actually my wife,
so she is your sister-in-law!
Who else could I rely on but you?
A man can't find a man
of honor in these days!
Shut up! Go get the
crowbar from the car!
I won't leave, you'll kill the man.
Of course I will.
What else would I do?
If you don't have mercy on me,
mercy on my two babies!
Open the damn thing.
I've had enough of you.
Muro, that's entirely your fault!
If you'd married Fidan
I would be better than this!
Shut up!
Chief, brother Muzaffer is right,
sister Çýnar could not bear children.
Çetin, stop chattering,
don't make me smash you too!
God!
Should I kill you now?
You are a lowlife,
shameless disgrace!
- Stop, leave the man!
- Leave the man. - Not you again!
For God's sake,
you are just on time.
Otherwise Chief would kill Muzaffer,
you have saved our lives.
Why are you arresting us?
Arrest the collaborator!
Didn't I tell you to
never cross me again?
Inspector, there's
been a mistake.
- Muro...
- Çeto...
Sweetie, there has been
a misunderstanding.
We'll fix it quickly.
Once again, the collaborators..
... the capitalists win!
Damn this world!
Muro, don't you worry!
I'll take care of the girls
while you're gone.
Damn my love for humans...