Twenty Four - My Beautiful Days
KIM Hyun-Sung
BYUN Eun-Jung KIM Min-Sun
- Jun!
- Huh?
BANG Eun-Jin MYUNG Kye-Nam
- Do you know today's menu?
- No.
- I hope it's something good today.
- Yeah.
Hello? Oh, yeah?
Sorry. What about dad?
Mom will be home soon.
About 30 minutes.
Your kid?
- I have a month left.
- What?
I have a month until my service is up.
Is your kid okay?
No.
He doesn't like being alone.
He's a kid, you know.
Do you want to get something to eat?
A hamburger or something?
It won't take long...
I'm late.
Why don't you go ahead...
- See you.
- Bye.
Director IM Jong-Jae
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Hey, when I first got here,
I heard this story from a senior officer.
Do you want to hear it?
What is it?
I don't know if it's true or not.
Because he heard it from his senior
officer when he started his service.
So his senior officer...
It was when my senior's senior officer
was about to get discharged.
Back then, they had a dawn shift.
Anyway, it was early dawn...
...when suddenly, he heard something.
It sounded like footsteps
or crumbling...
So he walked around the parking lot
and right where he was,
there stood a deer.
The deer stared deeply at him.
A real deer...
A deer, like the ones
you can only see at a zoo...
Jun, that's a lie, right?
I'm not really sure.
It's a story my senior officer heard.
How can a deer be in the parking lot
here? In the middle of the city,
with no zoo or mountains nearby.
That's nonsense.
'1 . Passports'
- Hi.
- Hey.
Long time no see.
Have you been well?
What brings you here?
Oh, some stuff.
- Eunji Han.
- Thank you.
- You look good in uniform.
- Really? I'm not so sure.
- Has it been long?
- Over 2 years.
- I'm almost done now.
- Oh, yeah? Good.
I didn't know you were in the service.
- What have you been up to?
- Huh?
- What have you been doing?
- Oh... just work.
Wow, you're already
part of the work force.
It's nothing.
I work here, in the parking lot.
Actually, it's not really work.
I just stand there.
I don't even do that much
now that I'm a senior officer.
Jun. I have to go.
See you.
Take care.
Who was that?
My ex-girlfriend.
' Jun's Cleaners'
- You know what?
- What?
I heard the car guy across the street
is opening a Whirlpool laundromat.
When they finish the building.
Really?
Yes.
Is something wrong?
No...
I ran into an old friend.
An old friend...
it must've been nice.
Well, just...
It's always nice to see
an old friend. Not long ago,
I ran into a friend who I hadn't seen in
ages. It was really nice. Lots to catch up.
- Service days, women, all sorts of stuff...
- Uh, it was a girl.
Oh, yeah?
We used to go out.
Not for long
but she seems to have changed.
She's working now.
Seemed busy.
Why did you break up?
Well...
I don't know.
By the way,
I'm gonna crash here tonight.
- Aren't you going to shower?
- Yes.
Come here.
'Ellen Kim: Retrospect'
It's my first time here during the day.
- Why in the afternoon?
- I have something to tell you.
What is it?
You and me...
let's, let's end it now.
It's been too long.
- Is there anything to end?
- Don't talk like that.
Can you really end it with me?
Can you really?
I won't press you.
It's just that...
I doubt a wishy-washi person
like you can really end it.
Didn't you say...
you had no direction?
Nothing you want to do,
nothing you want to be.
Never loved.
- Do you have someone else?
- No.
Then what is it?
I think this is wrong.
And... I don't like you.
Still, don't talk like that.
Don't do this. I'm going.
We need to change the bulb.
Yeah. We should.
- Jun!
- Yes!
Did you take down the poster outside?
Yes. It kept covering our sign.
I see.
Hi.
I called your house.
The number's the same.
They told me you worked here.
Say hello to the owner.
Oh, that's becoming a problem.
We should fix it.
Jun, watch the store.
- I'll go buy a bulb.
- Yeah.
I went all the way up there
looking for this place.
Not surprising.
People don't know this is a cleaners.
I want to do something about it
but I don't know
what Mister Jun's thinking.
Why? I like this better.
I like it here.
It's cozy and it suits you better.
- Is that a compliment or...
- It's a compliment.
I was always comfortable around you.
It's been a long time, right?
Yeah.
I never thought
I'd run into you like that.
And that you'd be in the service.
What are you going to do after
your discharge? Go back to school?
Well... I'm not sure yet.
Where do you work?
- At a TV station.
- TV station? Then are you on TV?
Do you think everyone
who works there is on TV?
I guess not. Still, it's great.
You're working.
It's not all good.
At first, it was something
I really wanted to do.
But now, I really can't stand it.
It was so nice seeing you at the office.
You haven't changed much.
And I like it here cause it's cozy.
This chair is quite comfy.
It's the newest chair here.
Do you know the difference between
part-time and full-time military service?
If you die serving full-time, it says 'death
of an honored soldier' on the notice.
But if you're part-time, it says 'missing.'
Oh, it's raining.
The laundry! Gotta get the laundry!
I knew this would happen.
It always rains when I hang it out.
- It's raining hard.
- Stay inside.
- It's okay. I'll help you.
- I can do it alone...
Aren't you going to bring in the laundry?
- Did you see our name?
- The name?
Are you working today?
Why are you still here?
Hey, the rain gods are here,
shall we have a drink?
Drink all night again?
No way, no way.
- Can I ask you something?
- Sure.
Why didn't you call back then?
Everything was confusing for me then.
And not anymore?
- I don't know what I'm gonna do yet.
- Same here.
Why? I envy you.
I better get going.
It's raining too much.
Do you want a ride on my bike?
To the bus stop?
Do you want to come by
the station sometime?
- When you get a chance?
- Sure.
Bye.
'Sign up book: Jun Kim'
Standby. Five minutes.
Good morning!
- Good morning, this is Park...
- Good morning, this is Jung...
- The river flows...
- Good morning, this is Park...
Eunji, you went drinking
last night, didn't you?
- No, I didn't.
- You look puffy.
- Do I look puffy?
- Now in the street...
Hello. This is Eunji Han.
Today, I am going to
introduce you to lacrosse.
It is one of the oldest sports
developed in North America...
Okay, let's go.
Hey kid, you can't smoke here.
What's this scar?
From when I gave birth.
Did it hurt a lot?
I can't remember.
I was so young when I had him.
Stop! Stop!
- Do you want to see something?
- What?
Oh, something.
But you can't laugh.
- What is it?
- One second.
Tada!
- How do I look?
- What's that?
- So what do you think? Take a look.
- I don't want to.
I was worried that it wouldn't fit.
What a relief, it still does.
What the hell is that?
I... went out f or this pageant.
- Boy, you kept that all this time?
- Of course.
- Why did you go out for that?
- Why not? Can't I?
Now. Ask me.
- What?
- The questions they ask at things.
- I don't wanna.
- Come on, ask me.
- No.
- Ask me!
When did you go out f or this?
- Before I had the kid.
- So did you win?
The presenter asked me
what I would do if I lost.
- So?
- I said I'd kill myself.
He must have been shocked.
He also asked
what my future plans were.
- What did you say?
- You ask me.
What would you
like to do first if you win?
Get married.
Ask me more.
If you're crowned Miss Cotton...
who will you first tell this happy news?
Jun.
Ugh. Enough.
I'm sorry.
- Are you okay?
- Shut up, you bastard.
Um, Mister Jun.
'Ellen Kim: Retrospective'
I... God!
- You're Jun, right?
- Yes.
I'm Eunji's sister, Hyunji.
Something came up so she sent me first.
She was worried you'd have to wait.
- Have you been waiting long?
- Not long.
I don't look much like her, do I?
Everyone says so. That we don't look
alike. I heard you're serving part-time.
Sorry, I didn't mean to...
I can be so rude sometimes.
That's okay.
It's because I'm not good with words.
I like that you're cheerful.
Really? That's good.
Let's finish this fast and catch a movie.
One with Bruce Lee.
Is something up with Eunji?
Well... she just seems busy.
You know how it is with broadcasting.
She looked very down.
Well, what do I know?
I don't know.
- Tell me about yourself.
- Me?
Yeah. This and that.
What you're doing now,
what you're gonna do...
Hobbies, what you like, stuff like that.
What I'm doing now is serving.
- Oh, sorry.
- And before, I was a college student.
- What do you like?
- What I like... is to sleep.
- Future goals?
- Future goals, I don't know yet.
What about you?
- I like to run.
- To run?
I'm a runner at my school.
I'm not that good but
my specialty is the 200 meter dash.
- Why? Is it strange?
- No. Just that runners aren't so common.
Is it strange?
Nah. It suits you, Hyunji.
I mean it.
- I have something to say. Will you listen?
- Yeah. What?
- Have you ever seen a deer?
- A deer?
- Yeah. And not at a zoo.
- No.
A few days ago, in my dreams,
a deer stared at me in the parking lot.
I f eel as if it's real...
it's not in my dreams.
This deer looked at me after eating
some grass in the parking lot.
Just looked at me...
I thought it would run away.
But it didn't.
For a long time, we looked
at each other like that.
- You don't believe me?
- You said it was a dream.
You know, a dream that f eels real.
These days, when I'm at the office, I look
at that spot all the time. Just in case.
Mister Jun...
- What are you doing right now?
- What do you think?
- How do I look?
- So-so.
Then take a look at this.
I tried it on before and it looked okay.
How come you have such little hair?
Wait a second.
Hello? Yes, it's me.
Oh, one second. Telephone.
- Huh?
- The phone.
Yes, hello?
Oh, hey, it's been ages. Yeah...
His name is Jun, too.
He works here.
We have the same name.
That's why I keep him around.
Right, right.
The cleaners is doing fine, buddy.
Oh, not too many customers.
Just enough to get by.
It's nice.
The neighborhoods quiet.
I talk to them now and then.
It's okay.
Oh, you're a manager now?
Congrats,
during these lean times.
What about the others?
Yeah, yeah.
What rumor?
Yeah, I saw the poster, too.
It was in the papers, too?
Go there, f or what?
Leave it be.
So much time's passed.
Yeah.
Hey, how is In-Gi doing?
Really?
Those enemies are partners?
Oh, right. Tell them
to quit fighting and to get along.
So they can make some money now.
Jun, it's time to work.
Jun, don't be late.
Why didn't you come?
Why didn't you?
- I had an appointment.
- Then you should have called at least!
Hyunji!
Ah, I can't run anymore.
- Hyunji Han!
- Hyunji.
Over there.
Jun!
- Do you practice like that every day?
- About 2 or 3 times a week.
The coach isn't here today
so we're just practicing on our own.
Isn't hard to run like that?
Huh? This is nothing.
Cause I'm a sprinter.
- I used to be good at running too.
- Oh, you lie.
- I used to be very quick.
- Really? Come on...
I may not look it but
I'm probably faster than you.
What?
You see the end over there?
To there.
- Will you be okay?
- Don't make me laugh.
- Go, Hyunji!
Go, Man!
What?
One... Two... Three...
I almost lose to him.
Are you okay?
- No problem.
- Yes problem. I told you.
Hey, I can catch
the wind with my hand.
- Hyunji...
- Hey, do you know what?
I like this kind of wind.
Jun, we're almost there...
Hello?
- Hello?
- Oh, Jun.
- Huh...
- It's been awhile.
Just seeing if you're okay.
I'm fine.
It's strange, you calling.
- Why, I even went to the station.
- When?
It's been some time.
- I couldn't find where you worked.
- You did?
Right, I heard it from Hyunji.
Hey, Jun.
Do you have some time tomorrow?
- Tomorrow?
- Are you busy?
Just... I'm not sure.
There's a lot on my mind.
Is something wrong?
- Eunji...
- Jun, what?
I think I have time tomorrow.
That's great.
- It's great here.
- Yeah?
I didn't realize
passing by here every day.
- You'd be discharged soon, right?
- Right. I only have a few days left.
Man, time just flies by.
Yeah, you're right.
It's just the beginning f or you.
Jun, I...
Hey, let's go somewhere else.
- What is this?
- I don't want to talk to you.
What are you doing right now?
What are you doing right now!
She looked older.
Does she like you?
- Or, do you like her?
- No, it's not like that.
A few times...
well, we slept together.
I am...
I can't figure it out.
I knew it was wrong...
I don't know why I did it.
You think it's wrong, don't you?
No.
- It must have been a mistake.
- Mistake?
Yeah. People make mistakes,
don't they?
Is there something wrong?
No, nothing.
I wanted have a nice time
with you but it got kind of weird.
Jun. I... like you.
I was going to say that before.
Are you not going to
call again, like the last time?
Does it look alright?
Yes. Looks cool.
My first painting in a long time.
- Did you draw that, over there?
- Yep.
It's a little different.
There are no trees, either.
A painting is up to the artist.
- Jun.
- Yes.
Is something bothering you?
No.
Why did you stop painting?
What can I say...
I wish I had something like that, too.
Something... I can really get into.
Do you like them?
- Yes, I do.
- I'm glad.
This isn't one of yours, I guess.
No, it isn't.
A friend gave it to me.
A long time ago.
Actually, I like this picture
better than my own paintings.
He must be a great painter.
Well, it's hard to say. We haven't
been in touch for a long time.
I just know that he
doesn't paint anymore.
- Is that him in that photo?
- Yes, it is.
This painting seems to put me at ease.
Why is that?
Just that... the two seem very close.
For a long time.
Why did he stop painting?
I'm not quite sure.
Sometimes, for no reason,
I hate painting.
Maybe it was f or him, too.
May I ask a favor?
Jun. Did something
happen with that woman?
- Who?
- You know, that public worker.
I heard she handed in her resignation.
People are talking.
I'm not sure but...
there's talk that she had a fight
with you. That's way she quit.
Jun, what if people find out
about your relationship with her?
It doesn't matter.
And there is nothing between us.
- Are you good at running?
- Huh?
- Running, are you good?
- Me? l, well, I'm alright.
- How about loser buys dinner?
- Sure.
- It's to over there.
- Okay.
- Shall I count?
- Whatever.
- Okay, one... Two...
- Wait.
- Today's menu is chicken stew!
- Three!
Hyunji.
Hyunji!
Jun.
Hyunji.
I like you.
This time, f or real.
- Eunji...
- I have to go.
- Um, hello?
- Hello?
- This is the front desk.
If you're staying the night,
you have to pay more.
Okay, I got it.
How do you like the painting?
Very good.
And that doesn't
look like my painting.
Really?
Thanks f or the invitation.
Your friend came.
He is your friend, right?
Oh, that fellow...
We owe him, both of us.
This is my last time treating you.
- Gotcha. I'll come by often.
- You promised.
It must be hard to work
in this cold weather.
What?
It's not hard in the summer?
- Are you Jun?
- Huh?
Fucking son of a bitch...
I'm gonna smash your...
- You bastard...
- Let's talk this out!
This young motherfucker!
Young bastard like you
with plenty of girls around...
- Get off! Get off, bastard!
- Calm down, Mister!
Mister, let's talk!
Who's in charge of this bastard?
Get him out here!
Take this.
And we need to take an x-ray
to see if the bone is in place.
Bring this to x-ray room four.
Is your arm alright?
They say it's broken.
What a drag!
How's the cheek?
He was your husband, right?
Why didn't you come?
I didn't want to see you.
Does it hurt much?
Why did you quit?
I guess this is the price of sin.
- Sin?
- Uh-huh.
- Isn't the price too high for the sin?
- No.
Not at all.
This is nothing.
- Jun, Jun.
- Yes, I'm coming.
How can you get up so late?
- Mom, I don't work today.
- Are you crazy? Why not?
- Mom, I get discharged.
- Discharged?
Oh dear,
what happened to your arm?
- What happened?
- It's nothing.
- Just a slight crack.
- What have you been doing?
It itches. Do you have
a long stick or something?
A week after getting discharged,
I am still sitting at the cleaners.
Mister Jun has left.
I thought he would go
with her but he went alone.
Mister Jun said that he'd leave
the cleaners to me f or the time being.
I had no way of knowing
when he'd be back.
I'm thinking of a new plan.
I don't want to go back to college yet.
I don't know what I need to study
so I'm delaying going back.
I'm thinking of making
this cleaners into a real a cool place.
I feel much calmer these days.
I hadn't before...
Eunji.
Are you opening something new?
No. I just want to change it a little.
Yeah?
It doesn't look like a little.
What's with the arm?
Oh, this... I f ell down.
I'm going to study abroad.
- When?
- My flight's tomorrow night.
I see.
What are you going to do now?
Aren't you going back to school?
I will, later.
I don't f eel like it yet.
Do you want something to drink?
- You don't look like you have anything.
- No, I have some water over there.
No thanks. That's okay.
I just came to say goodbye.
' Jun's Cleaners'
It's okay. Smoke.
A light...
- It's hard, huh?
- Yes.
- You want to hear a story?
When I first got here,
my senior officer told me this story.
I don't know if it's true
cause he heard it from his senior
when he first got here.
So that senior officer... No, wait,
his senior, senior, senior officer
was about to get discharged.
That guy was on dawn duty.
Or was it night?
Anyway, he suddenly heard something.
It sounded like footsteps. Or crumbling.
So he went over to the place
and there was a deer standing there.
A deer was staring at him
in the middle of the parking lot.
A real deer.
Like the ones you see in a zoo.
- It must be a lie.
- It's the truth!
- I can't believe it.
- No, he really saw it.
A year later,
Jun's Cleaners closed its doors.
Mister Jun started painting again.
Hyunji quit running.
Eunji is still studying abroad.
No one knows about the others.
Jun still dreams about the deer.