No.
Hey!
Where's Howard and the rest
of the apprentices?
We left them at the bottom to find
their own way up!
They got to learn
sometime.
If you want to be
a troubleshooter,
you got to know
the mine.
Is it all clear
down there?
Yeah, we won't
need these anymore,
but I wouldn't go
lighting any matches.
Damn methane.
It's going to blow
this place to shit one of these days.
We ain't that lucky.
Whoo, hey, come on, now.
Knock it off.
Howard!
Hey, Howard!
Hey! Enjoy
your walk up?
Yeah, real joke.
Why didn't you guys wait?
Look, Landers, you got
to get a lot of exercise
if you're going to
grapple with Gretchen.
Oh, yeah? Well, I got
a Valentine for her
that she's never
going to forget.
Right to the heart, huh?
It's going to be a hot time
on Saturday night!
Yee-haw!
Hey, Stavinski, you do
anything else with that
except throw it
over your shoulder and burp it?
Aw, get lost, Axel.
Oh, bunch of clowns. Things haven't
changed a bit. Same as always.
Bet you wish
you never came back.
Especially now since Sarah's
going out with Axel.
No skin off my nose.
I don't give a damn.
Come on, last one
into town gets the brew.
Let's go.
Okay.
Let's go, guys!
Whoo-ha!
Quitting time!
Casanova is here!
Yee-haw!
Gretchen, it's me.
Howard,
stay away from me.
Hi, babe.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- Good to see you.
- Nice to see you too.
Hi, sweetie.
You big brute,
I missed you.
Anything I should know?
No.
Of course not.
Gretchen, I want you
to be my date for the dance. Will you?
Dry up.
Gretchen, you know
what would look really good on you?
- What?
- Me.
Suck it in and
zip it up, will you?
Gretchen,
why fight it?
Oof.
Let the good times
roll.
All right!
Hi, fellas.
Mabel, this is the best thing
that's happened to this town in years.
Your decorating committee
has done one hell of a job.
Well, after all,
the first Valentine's
dance in 20 years
has to be
something special.
Uh, yeah, well, uh,
of course, you're right,
Mabel, but I think we'd all be better off
if you played down
the fact
that it's the first Valentine's dance
in 20 years,
if you know
what I mean.
Let's just concentrate
on having a good time Saturday night
and put all that
other business to rest.
My thoughts
exactly, Mayor.
Hi, guy.
Oh, come on,
you clowns!
Help Miss Osborne
pick those things up.
What the hell are
you kids doing in here?
You're supposed to be
decorating the room,
not each other.
Where you going,
son?
Where I always go
this time of day--
for another beer
and a real good nose pick.
Ooh!
I'm sorry, TJ.
I don't think he likes
being back in the mine very much.
Well, that's too bad.
Nobody told him to go out
to the West Coast.
It's not my fault
he couldn't make it on his own.
But now that
he's back here,
he's my son and he's
working in the mine.
You guys better put those things back
where you found them,
or I'll turn you both upside down.
Especially you.
This is my date, Chief.
Chief, that meeting
in Centerville is at 7.:00.
Maybe we should
hit the road.
Then let's go.
I'll see you kids later. Bye, Mabel.
- Keep up the good work.
- See you, Chief.
I might as well go too.
All of this will have
to be rewashed.
I'm really sorry, Mabel.
This is station QPlD,
940 on your radio dial...
Oh.
Mayor!
Mayor?
Mayor, somebody
left this for you.
For me?
Who was it?
I don't know. It was already inside
when we got here.
Maybe you got
a secret admirer, huh?
You in on this, Mabel?
I'm afraid not, Mayor.
Oh, no.
No no.
Don't look at me.
I didn't have a thing
to do with it.
Oh, well, hell,
I've been looking
for an excuse
to get off this miserable diet
Mrs. Hanniger has me on.
Thanks, Howard.
If there's one thing
I like better
than Christmas candy,
it's Valentine's candy.
Have some.
Hey...
who sent it?
"From the heart
comes a warning
filled with
bloody good cheer--
remember what happened
as the 14th draws near."
It can't be
happening again.
It can't be happening
again.
Broken-down bar...
It's a bad time,
this time of year.
Bad things coming.
My words, you hear.
Beware the 14th
- if you value your life.
- Here we go again.
How many times is he
going to tell this story?
Oh, let him tell it.
I love fairy tales.
This ain't no fairy tale,
little girl.
If you don't
take it seriously,
you're a fool.
Ohh!
Hurt yourself?
Axel, are you okay?
Oh, no.
Let me see.
I know what
I'm talking about.
I'm telling you now,
this town is a-cursed.
Now it started
20 years ago.
It was the night
of the Valentine's Day dance
at the Union Hall--
the biggest event of the year.
It had been a tradition
for over 100 years.
Everybody was there,
except for seven miners
who were out
at the Henniger Mine,
five of them
still down below.
Two supervisors
were waiting for the men to come up.
Anxious to get
to the party,
they left before
the men were safely out
failing to check
the methane gas levels
in the tunnels
down below.
The five men
were buried alive
as the town
continued its party.
For six weeks,
we dug around the clock
to try to save them.
After we broke through,
one man was found alive.
I was the one
who found him.
Harry Warden spent the next year
in the state mental hospital.
Exactly one year later,
on Valentine's Day,
he came back to town.
He killed
the two supervisors
who had left their posts
the year before.
Then he cut out
their hearts
and stuffed them into
heart-shaped candy boxes.
That night at the dance
we found the boxes,
blood dripping
out the sides.
Inside was a note--
a warning from Harry
never to hold
a Valentine's dance
ever again.
Every February 14,
Harry comes back to town,
his pickax
stained with blood,
waiting in the shadows
of the Henniger Mine...
just for someone
to kill
should they not heed
his warning.
It could be you.
I know what I'm saying.
You forget about having a party
at all on Saturday night,
or you may not live
to see daylight.
Laugh now...
but you'll be sorry
you didn't listen to me.
Uh-oh.
Come on, Hap,
lighten up.
It's a stupid legend.
It gives me
the creeps.
Hi, you guys.
Who ordered the Moosehead?
I did, you gorgeous slab
of female fleshiness.
# Oh #
## There is a young barmaid
named Harriet ##
## Who has never been robbed
of her cherry yet ##
## Oh, try as she may ##
## This girl
can't get laid ##
## A Valentine virgin
named Harriet. ##
I hate that song.
I mean,
it's, like, uh--
hey, where you going?
I just want to put on
some music, okay?
Be my guest.
Excuse me.
It's your own fault.
You know that, don't you, TJ?
Never said it wasn't.
Then why can't you
just accept things the way they are?
Maybe because I don't like
the way things are.
Excuse me.
Yes, all right.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
I have to call
in the morning.
The administration office
is closed at night.
The nurse that's on duty
doesn't know a thing.
Well, she's got to know whether
he's there or not.
I just hope this is
some kind of joke
and the kids are just trying to scare
the hell out of us.
If it is a joke, I want every one of
those kids strung up,
starting with that damn
Howard Landers!
Well, it's a human
heart, all right.
A young woman,
about 30 years old.
What the hell are you guys doing
with a loose heart?
Looks like a butcher
ripped this thing out.
What's going on over
in Valentine Bluffs?
You remember
Harry Warden?
God, of course
I remember.
Those were
terrible murders.
God, I thought
they locked him up in Eastfield
20 years ago.
They did.
Are you sure
he's still there?
We'll find out in the morning.
I'm checking on it.
Well, gentlemen,
I'd say you have
your answer.
It looks like Harry Warden's
back in town.
Well, now,
I wonder who sent this?
Jake?
Ohh.
"Roses are red,
violets are blue...
one is dead,
and so are you"?
No!
No! Get away!
Get away!
No! No!
Hey, this is getting
really good.
Don't put
your nose in it.
Hey, this is what
I really call junk food.
How much longer, Hollis?
I'm freezing.
Hey, relax.
This thing ain't no microwave.
Hey, how about
revving it up?
Man, have I got
the munchies.
Yeah, me, too.
A little protein patrol, hey, boys?
Don't go
poking my meat.
It's hardly cooked.
Don't go sticking
your nose in the food.
It's his. He can do what
he wants with it.
Is that turkey, Hollis?
I asked for roast beef.
Turkey for the turkey.
Here.
Come on, shove over.
Sure is cold tonight.
Yeah.
Well, I guess we got
ourselves a problem, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah, I guess so.
What are we going
to do about it?
Well, there ain't
nothing to do about it.
Sarah's
going with me now
and that's
all there is to it.
I ain't going to back off
for you, TJ.
Nobody asked you
to go away, TJ.
Come on, Axel, don't give me
any of that horseshit.
I mean, you're beginning
to sound like my old man.
Too bad, man.
Look, you left.
You left.
You went away, and we didn't know
where you were
or-- or when the hell
you were coming back.
I ain't going to back off
for you, TJ.
You stay the hell
away from Sarah.
All right, all right.
You want a fight,
then you got it.
Because you and l
both know who Sarah wants.
You were kind of
hard on him, Teege.
You can't exactly
blame him.
Sure, it's not his fault.
It's nobody's fault.
I don't know
what to do.
You know, I really do like
that son of a bitch.
Hey, remember--
remember how we used to tear
this place apart?
Eh? Get drunk,
race out to the bluffs?
That was great.
I guess
things change, huh?
Nothing stays the same.
W-A-R-D-E-N.
Harry Warden.
He was committed under court order
approximately
20 years ago.
Well, I'm afraid
I have no records
of a Harry Warden,
past or present.
But how can that be?
He was committed there
under court order.
I'm sorry.
I have no records on him.
Look, in 20 years, any number of things
could have happened.
Now if this Harry Warden
was committed, as you say,
then he's simply
no longer here.
And if I have
no records on him,
I have to assume that he's transferred,
he's released,
or he's on the slab.
One of three, take your pick.
One out of three?
Now look, Mrs. Raleigh, you're
going to have to do
a little bit better
than that.
Now I have to know
what happened to this man
and I have to know
what happened to him now.
Now have you
checked everything?
Everything...
except the microfilms
over in central file,
and it will take
several days to check that.
Look, I need answers
and I need them fast.
I'll be waiting
for your call.
Dr. Peyton, 3-5-3.
Jumping J--
they don't even know what the hell
happened to him.
Well, w-what
do we need to know?
It's got to be Harry.
Maybe we ought
to cancel the dance.
Just decide which one
you really want.
And now for
the big moment--
will it be number one,
or will it be number two?
Patty, will you
be serious?
This is important.
You can't have them
both, you know.
- I don't want them both.
- Oh, no?
No.
Just what I thought.
Oh, I don't know.
TJ won't talk to me.
He just sulks
all day long.
He ends up making me
feel guilty,
when he's the one
who owes me the apology.
And Axel is not
behaving any better.
Oh, Patty, I don't even want to go
to the dance on Saturday night.
Oh, but you got to go.
It'll be all right.
Just stay with Hollis and me.
Besides, you got to see
the dress I got--
cut down to here,
slit up to there.
I may not get out alive.
Mabel?
Mabel, I got
to talk to you.
We got a problem
concerning the dance.
Mabel!
Mabel, you back here?
Okay.
Little John?
I want you and Mike
to check the wall.
TJ,
take care of the sump.
You get a pump down there,
or I ain't doing it.
You do it or you get
your ass out of here for good.
I'll do it.
What's bugging
him today?
Son of a bitch
is after my ass
because of Sarah.
If he keeps it up,
I'm going to nail him.
I said move it,
Hanniger!
Oh, yeah.
Come on, man.
Anytime, loser.
Hey, that's it!
Break it up, you two!
TJ, you get your ass
up top to crew 17.
Go!
There ain't going to be no fighting
in my section, Palmer!
Understand?
What an awful smell.
This is like it was
20 years ago.
I can remember those murders
just like it was yesterday.
Jake, you got to get
help from Granville.
No, not yet.
If we call in Granville, we'll have police
crawling all over this place
and we'll have a hell
of a panic on our hands.
You just mention
that Harry's back
and this town won't
be worth the powder to blow it to hell.
Uh, just a minute.
Just a minute, boys.
Uh...
I want you to bring
the ambulance around back.
Load her up from there.
I don't want anybody
in town seeing this.
You remember--
Mabel Osborne died
of a heart attack
and that's all.
You breathe one word
of this to anybody
and you'll have
to answer to me.
Wait a minute.
What's this?
Take her away.
"lt happened once,
it happened twice.
Cancel the dance
or it'll happen thrice."
Oh, well,
th-th-that's it.
The dance is canceled.
Let's tear every poster,
every banner,
every decoration down
and-- and out of sight.
I don't want to see a single Valentine's
heart anywhere.
As long as this town is
decorated to the hilt,
Harry's going
to keep on killing.
And-- and get that damn
Union Hall locked up.
All right.
All right, Mayor.
No, I'm sorry.
There's nothing I can do about it.
Hey, what's going on?
The mayor has
canceled the dance
and that's
all there is to it.
Well, in the light of Mabel's death,
he had no choice.
There'll be
no parties, either.
We owe her
that much respect.
Mabel would've wanted us
to have the dance.
I mean, she worked
so hard on it.
Yeah, you can't
cancel it now.
He's just looking for an excuse to
cancel the dance.
That's the way it is.
They'll be no dance
tomorrow night
and no parties, either.
Do you understand me?
Hanniger!
You and me have
something to settle!
You bet we do.
Howard, you got
to chew it.
You don't
blow bubbles with it.
I'll take care
of myself.
How'd you ever get
to be so stupid?
I'm going to shower.
TJ, will you stop this?
I don't want to go with you.
Are you
listening to me?
Nope.
Remember this spot?
Of course I remember
this spot.
Why didn't you
write me, TJ?
Why didn't you call?
I wanted to, believe me,
but I couldn't.
I mean, I really fell
on my ass out there.
I made so many mistakes.
But I learned something.
Look...
give me a chance.
If you still want me
to go away, I will.
But I have to tell you that I love you
and I want you back.
How was I supposed
to know that, Jessie?
I honestly didn't think
you were ever coming back.
You just left me here.
Sarah, please.
I'm sorry.
I'm so damn sorry.
## That's all I am ##
## And, girl,
I don't expect you ##
## To understand ##
## I just play my song ##
## And right or wrong ##
## My music's
all I need ##
## To get along ##
## Women and wine
don't thrill me ##
## Like they used to... ##
Have you seen Sarah?
Ain't my turn
to watch after her.
Damn it, Sarah,
why do you do this to yourself?
How am I going
to tell Axel?
Sarah!
Chief Newby.
I'm sorry
I startled you.
It's all right.
Is something the matter?
No, I'm--
I'm just making
my nightly patrol.
Right.
Good night, Chief.
Oh, good night,
Sarah.
Give me a beer, Hap.
You hear about
Mabel Osborne?
She got it just
the way I said.
Heart attack,
my ass.
Well, if we aren't going to have
a Valentine's dance,
what are
we going to do?
Why don't we have
a Valentine party?
Yeah, a party!
Where? Newby's got this whole town
locked up, bright guy.
How about
my father's mine, huh?
- TJ, are you crazy? Come on.
- The mine!
In the mine?
That'd be great.
It would.
What a blast.
In the mine?
That's exactly what it would be.
Oh, it'd be
great!
Come on, Hollis. We've got everything
we need down there.
We got, uh, let's see,
we got a rec room.
We got a pool table.
Everything.
Yeah, in the mine...
where people get killed and eaten.
Beware of
Harry Warden.
Whooo!
Shut the fuck up.
Beware of what you make fun of,
you little asshole.
- Who?
- You.
Forget about having
a party at all tomorrow night
or you'll be sorry.
Hey, lighten up, Hap.
Piss on Harry Warden
and that damn old legend.
We're gonna have
ourselves a party.
Don't you
go telling nobody.
Don't say
I didn't warn you.
That settles it then.
We're going to the mine
and we're going to have ourselves a party.
Assholes.
Damn kids.
I'll show them.
Piss on Harry Warden,
will they?
Well, I'll give them
a scare they'll never forget.
Ah.
Hey, it's
party time.
Where are
the wieners?
Hey, Hollis,
here's the wieners!
Hi, Ben.
Anything happen?
No, it's been quiet
all evening.
Good.
That came for you
though.
Oh my God.
Go and get me
a coffee, will you, Ben?
Yeah, sure, Chief.
Mabel.
Yooo! Does anybody
want a beer?
Eat you up.
Mmm!
Whoo!
Hollis,
check this out.
You asshole!
Hey, who busted
the lock?
- I got the keys right here.
- Howard did.
- Uh-oh.
- Howard.
Harry Warden did it.
And whoever parked the red
Volkswagen out front,
I want it parked out back
with the others like I said.
I don't want Newby
snooping around here.
Let me show you.
- Hey, hold it.
- Whoa.
Hey, John,
where you going?
Sylvia's gonna
get it tonight.
Talk to you
in a minute, okay?
So you're looking
pretty good, baby face.
What's the occasion?
I figured it'll get
Newby off my back.
Besides, I want to get out
of this town pretty quick.
You know, I think
he really likes you.
I've got the munchies.
Hot dogs.
Here, Spot.
Hey, what's going on?
Who is that?
I, uh, I got a feeling
about the mine, Ben.
I'll-- I'll check back
with you, all right?
Make sure you call me on the radio
if anything comes up.
Will do.
Now what the hell
is that?
Go on!
Go on, get the hell
out of here.
"You didn't stop
the party."
Stop the party?
What damn party?
Stavinski, you couldn't
clean that table with a broom.
Hollis, you don't even
know what pool means.
Hey, guys, check this out.
Check this out.
Gretchen,
this is for you.
Oh, wow.
First time I try to snort Coke, man,
and I almost drown.
Next time,
try harder.
- Axel, please.
- Oh, come on.
- Axel, please don't.
- What's the matter, baby?
- Oh, come on!
Will you please
stop it?
Guess you better
back off there, Axel.
Back the fuck off,
man.
We were doing just fine until you decided
to come crawling home.
Well, in case you haven't noticed,
things have changed around here.
She don't want nothing
to do with you.
Do you mind?
I have my own mouth, thank you.
Then why don't you use it?
Tell him.
Tell me what?
She wants to come back
with me.
Bullshit, man.
Why don't you
both just back off?
You're acting like
a couple of jerks.
Oh, well, you just
love it, don't you?
That's it!
You son of a bitch!
Hollis, do something.
Hollis!
Let go.
Shit!
Will you guys knock it off?
TJ, are you
out of shape.
Get out of here!
Are you sure
you're okay?
Look, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean for that to happen.
TJ, please stop it.
I just don't care
anymore.
Just leave me alone.
Okay, listen. I showed
you how to do it
with the right nostril,
right?
Now you take the straw
and you put it up the neck,
the left nostril, right?
And you snort it.
Come on, loosen up.
Let's have fun.
We're at a Valentine's party,
for God's sake.
I got a little
punchy myself.
How do you
get those down?
- Pull the rope.
- Just pull it?
Yeah yeah.
Release the hook and let it go.
You know what we need?
Yeah, I got one
right here.
No, I meant
a couple of beers.
Oh. I'll go
get them.
I'll go with you.
No, you stay here
and I'll be back in a flash.
Okay?
Okay, but don't take
too long.
Back in a minute.
Okay. Bye.
Bye.
Hey, TJ.
Hey, John,
how you doing?
I'm doing great.
Is something the matter?
The same old shit.
Well, Howard really
makes me gag.
You're not kidding.
If anyone, I kinda
like Tommy.
Oh, I agree.
- Hi, John.
- Hi, girls.
Yuck, what is this?
Oh, wow. One of those idiots
really thinks he's funny.
It's probably Howard.
John, is that you?
John?
John, if you're trying to scare me,
you're doing a good job.
John?
Oh!
No! No! No!
Help! Help!
Oh no!
No!
Oh!
Sorry I took
so long, babe.
Sylvia?
Sylvia!
All right.
Hey, all right.
Sylvia, I know
you're in there.
And I'm coming in.
Sylvia.
Come in, Mobile One.
Mobile One, in.
Jake, you just
got a call from Eastfield.
A woman named Raleigh.
She said it was urgent.
All right.
Mobile One, coming in.
Hey, how about
a little trip down to the mine?
- The mine?
- Yeah, it'll be great. Come on.
It's supposed to be
like a roller coaster, isn't it?
It's 2,000 feet down.
That's okay. It'll cheer her up anyway.
Come on, Hollis.
Come on, Mike,
let's go.
What? Hey, Hollis, you
going down to the mine?
- Well--
- Yes. Yes.
Come on.
Come on, Hollis.
- Chicken.
- Chicken?
Hey, why don't we
go down to the mine?
All right. One quick ride down
and then right back up.
- Hey, what about gear?
- Yeah, get that six-pack.
It's going to be
great, baby!
Ow!
Watch your step.
Come on.
- This is ridiculous.
- This is gonna be great.
Hollis!
Where do you think
you're going?
We're just going
to go for a quick ride
and come right back up.
Believe me.
You can't take them
down there.
You know the rule.
No women in the mine.
We're gonna come right back up again.
Believe me.
- Come on.
- Watch your step.
Howard, don't be a pain
in the ass.
Pain in the ass?
What pain in the ass?
Be careful.
Down we go.
Come on, you guys, hop in the cars.
I'll be right back.
- Yeah, we made it.
- You just let me know.
Here, Sarah,
put this around you.
Michael.
Michael!
Here you go.
And a blanket.
Hey, Hollis,
you got one for me?
Here's one for you.
I'll be right back.
Do you believe we're
really doing this?
It's so dark
down there.
On second thought,
I think I'm gonna stay right up here.
Oh, no, you don't.
If I'm going down there, baby,
- you're going with me.
- Oh, great.
Hey, hold on, everybody.
Here we go.
Keep your hands inside.
And pass me that beer.
All right.
Come on, pass a couple
up this way.
- Where's the lantern?
- Right here. You just stick with me.
Whoo-hoo!
Down she goes.
Hold on.
Get ready to stop.
Hey, Hollis, pass me a beer.
Want one, Mike?
How far down
does it go?
300 miles deep.
- Come on, Sarah.
- Here you go.
You're down here
every night?
Wow.
Oh, little bit of a free ride.
There we go.
Stops all by itself.
Yeah, I hope you kids enjoyed yourself,
'cause we're going right back up.
Oh, that was great, Hollis.
- Let's do it again.
- Howard usually walks.
Oh, let's do it again, Hollis.
Come on.
Hey, where does that go?
Oh, that leads to
an abandoned part.
We don't go down
there anymore.
- Oh, take us on a tour, Hollis.
- Yeah.
Yeah, let's show
them around.
All right.
Just because we're here.
Come on.
Keep those blankets
wrapped around you.
- You're gonna get chilly.
- Okay, honey.
It's cold.
All right, boys and girls,
this is called a tipple.
So that's a tipple.
This is also called
a tipple.
- Hey, Howard, come on!
- Coming!
- I'm coming!
I just heard something.
Probably some rats.
Rats! You never told me
there were rats.
This is the old engine room.
Oh, uh-huh.
Boy, what a nice view
back here.
Howard.
Hey, Hollis.
We'll meet you in 10 minutes
over at the main shaft.
All right. No longer.
We're going straight up.
It's pretty dark.
How do you like
my pad, huh?
It's okay.
I can't believe
you work here.
Yep.
- He's in there!
- What is it?
What's the matter?
He's in there.
What's going on?
Dead.
He-- he--
- What are you talking about?
- He killed her.
What are you
talking about?
Dave is dead!
No!
TJ, it's Sylvia.
Somebody's killed her.
It's Harry Warden.
He's here!
Everybody get
the fuck out!
Go! Go! Go!
Come on, come on!
Son of a bitch must have cut
the phone lines.
Okay, now listen.
I want you to make sure
that everybody
gets out of here.
And I want you
to get the chief
and tell him to get
here and fast.
Now go!
Sarah, she's in the mine
with the others.
What?
Her, Hollis
and Patty.
They took the railcars
down there.
They're in the mine right now.
We gotta get them out.
That's where that crazy guy probably is.
Look, he'll kill them!
I'm gonna get her out.
Come on.
Come on!
Go! Go!
Come on.
If anything happens
to Sarah, it'll be your fault.
You never should have
let them go down there.
Damn it, let's just worry about
getting them out.
I'll take
the abandoned section,
you take
the level above.
We'll meet in the main shaft
by the elevator.
Hope to God
we get there before Harry does.
Good luck.
Where is he?
I don't know.
Boo!
Gotcha.
Damn you, Hollis.
Where the hell were you?
I thought you were
right behind me.
You must have gone down
the wrong tunnel.
Oh, sure we did.
You did that on purpose.
Me? Come on.
Okay.
Watch your head.
Watch your step
as well.
This is the oldest
part of the mine.
Oh, God!
These tunnels were
built in the early 1800s.
- Really?
- Yeah, it's all abandoned now.
Ooh.
We haven't worked
down here in years. Not since...
Harry Warden.
Howard, what do you
think you're trying to do, you jerk?
Easy, I've got
a hangover.
Boy, did you guys
jump!
Howard!
Oh, Howard,
you goof.
- Get down out of there.
- I'll go the other way.
- For Pete's sake.
- I know what I'm doing.
Oh, God, you guys.
Come on.
Hold it.
Oh, that feels so good.
- Okay.
- Get your light.
- All right. Okay.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
- You all right?
- Come on.
Get down!
Now stick with us and
quit clowning around.
Come on! I was just having
a little bit of fun.
Yeah yeah, sure.
Hey, you guys, where's
Mike and Harriet?
Maybe Harry Warden
got them.
Stop it.
Howard, come along
and behave yourself.
Yeah, let's go.
My blanket!
Oh, come on, you'd forget
your head
if it wasn't tied on with rope.
Let's go.
Come on, it's freezing
down here.
Hey, who's leading
this tour?
Well, go ahead if you want.
I feel so good.
So do l.
Where are we
going now, Hollis?
Oh, this leads to the main shaft.
We're going up.
How come the walls
are so white around here, Hollis?
I told you.
It's lime powder.
They put it here
to contain explosions
and they put it on the wood
so it doesn't get dry and crack.
Hey, you guys,
how come Mike and Harriet
haven't come back yet?
Uh-oh.
What's that?
I thought
I heard something.
Look, it's probably
only rats.
That ain't no rat.
Come on, let's go
find Mike and Harriet
and get out of here.
- Come on!
- Coming.
Tommy Whitcomb, what the hell's
the matter with you, anyway?
Where's your brains?
How many times have I told you--
Chief, listen to me.
You have to go to the mine.
We were having a party and Harry Warden
started killing everybody!
Harry Warden?
Harry Warden
is at the mine.
There's a bunch of kids
trapped down below.
Axel and TJ are
trying to get them out.
He killed Sylvia and Dave!
All right. Get back in that car
and get home and stay put.
Go on!
- Mobile One in.
- Go ahead, Chief.
Yeah, Ben, call
the mayor right away,
then round up
every available man.
Meet me back at the mine.
I think there's some kids
trapped down below.
Out.
Howard, would you
get up in front?
I'm trying to get
up in front!
- Ow!
- I can't even see.
- Watch your head.
- Just stay beside me.
- Okay.
- Michael!
Mike!
Why don't
they answer us?
- Stavinski!
- Mike!
We never should
have left them in the first place.
Maybe they're
down there.
- Jesus!
- TJ.
What the hell
are you trying to do?
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
Yeah, we're fine.
What's the matter with you?
We gotta get the hell
out of here.
Harry Warden is back.
He's killed Sylvia
and Dave up top.
Are you kidding?
Harry's dead.
Harry died a long time ago.
Will you shut up and listen to me,
goddamn it!
Now they're dead and
he's down here somewhere.
If you wanna get out
of here alive,
you do exactly
as I tell you.
What are we
gonna do?
This better not be
your idea of a joke, TJ.
Do I look
like I'm joking?
Come on.
Let's go.
Wait a minute.
Now what about Mike and Harriet?
Last time I saw them,
they were in the engine room.
You check the main shaft.
I'll take tunnel six
and meet you there.
Howard, you stay with the girls
and wait for Axel.
- Me?
- Stay with Howard.
- No, Hollis, please!
- Stay back!
Hollis!
Wait a minute!
Howard,
you watch the girls!
I don't even know
my way around.
Oh, shit.
Michael?
Harriet?
Michael and Harriet,
this isn't anytime to be doing anything.
Oh! Oh, Jesus!
No.
Oh, God, Hollis!
Oh, Hollis!
Oh, God, Hollis.
Oh.
Oh, it's not--
Oh, please, God.
Come on.
He's dead.
He's dead!
Come on!
- Come on!
- Patty, come on.
Come on, he's dead.
Now come on.
- Patty!
- No.
Howard, you bastard!
He's dead.
Now come on.
You can't leave us
like this!
Patty, please.
Help me.
No!
Leave him alone.
- Let go of me.
- No.
Patty, we need
the light, damn it!
Okay, come on, Patty.
Don't do this to me.
We have to
get out of here.
No!
Stop it!
Okay okay, come on.
Oh, my God.
Where are the others?
We saw him.
He was standing right there.
Harry Warden's
down here.
Come on, let's go.
- Come on.
- No!
Let's go!
Come on!
Where the hell is TJ?
He went looking
for Mike and Harriet.
He told us to stay here.
Now come on.
The cage is right up ahead.
Let's go!
Keep moving.
You're gonna be fine.
- Axel, please! No!
- Hold on.
Oh, let go of me.
I don't want to
leave him there.
- Shh. Shh.
- Let's go back and get him.
I don't want to--
oh, please,
Axel, no.
Patty, stop it!
I don't want to
leave him there.
You'll be fine.
You're gonna be just fine.
Oh, God, where
are you taking us?
Keep moving. We're almost there.
We're almost there.
Keep moving. You're doing fine.
You're doing fine.
That's it.
God, where are
we going?
I can't make it anymore.
Shut up.
Yes, you can.
Come on.
Let's go.
- I can't!
- Let's go.
Shit.
It's TJ.
Aw, shit!
What the fuck
do you think you're doing?
I'm sorry, man.
I thought you were Harry.
Do I look like Harry?
Where's Howard?
- He ran off.
- Oh, that jerk!
He's never gonna
find his way out of here alone.
Hollis is dead.
Look, we gotta get Sarah
and Patty up top,
get some help and come
back for the others.
- Come on.
- Okay, let's go.
Come on. Come on.
Let's get going.
Okay.
Mobile One, come in.
Mobile One.
Come in, Mobile One.
Watch your step.
Okay.
I can't even see.
We're almost there.
Shh! Keep your
voices down.
- Come on.
- Shh!
Please, hurry.
Shh! Keep your
voices down.
He smashed
the control panel.
There's no way we're
getting out of here.
What?
What are we gonna do?
Climb.
- Come on.
- No.
Come on.
Watch your footing now.
Axel, please slow down.
Patty, you're okay.
I'm right behind you.
Keep going.
Come on. Come on.
Don't look down.
Keep looking up.
Patty, just do as he says,
and you'll be fine.
I promise.
I don't want to
go any further.
Please, can we stop
and go another way?
There's no other way.
Now move it, damn it!
Axel, you'll
have to go slower.
I'm right behind her.
She keeps stopping.
Go slower, okay?
Oh!
I'm scared of heights,
you guys.
I'm not going
any further.
I'm stopping right here.
Sarah, Sarah.
Give her a hand.
Now I'm behind you.
I'm right behind you.
Come on.
Okay.
Okay. Stay close.
Okay,
I'm right behind you.
Attagirl.
Keep moving.
Good girl.
Come down.
Come down, quick. Down.
Don't look.
Don't look at him.
Come on.
Patty, over here.
Now he's up top.
That bastard's really
playing games with us.
We can beat him
if we can get to the rail cars.
Then, come on.
I know a shortcut through the sump.
It's over there.
Watch your step.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Nice and slow.
Let's go. Let's go.
Slowly.
TJ, take the girls over
and give me a yell
when you're across.
Okay.
Go.
Watch your head.
Watch your step.
Okay.
Okay, Axel, we're clear.
Come on over.
Axel?
Axel!
TJ, do something.
There's nothing
I can do.
It's 60-feet deep.
Gosh!
We've got to
get out of here.
We can't just
leave him here.
Move it!
It's too late
for Axel.
Come on.
Okay, you just hug along
the left side of the wall.
Now just keep going.
Go on. Continue.
- But why--
- Just do as he says.
TJ?
Answer us!
TJ!
- He's--
- Shh!
Let's go this way.
Come on. Go.
Careful.
Shh!
Okay, there's gotta be
some way out of here.
- Yeah.
- Come on, keep going.
This way.
Come on.
- They're down there?
- Yeah.
Sarah! Sarah!
Oh, TJ.
Thank God.
Shh!
Come on.
TJ?
It's okay.
I just got hit.
Come on.
We've got to hurry.
The elevator isn't working.
We're gonna have
to go in this way. Let's go.
Jump.
TJ!
All right, watch
this thing coming.
Oh my God.
Sarah, move it!
Get in.
Get in!
Watch out!
Axel.
Why?
Go.
Come on.
He's in there.
Are you two all right?
It isn't Harry Warden.
Yeah. I know, TJ.
I got a call from Eastfield
late this evening.
They said that Harry Warden
died five years ago.
But then who is it?
It's Axel.
Oh my God.
Okay.
Well, you...
My God, it was
on Valentine's Day
that Harry Warden
killed Axel's father.
- Let's get in there.
- Yeah.
Come on.
Let's get it off. Get it off.
He's alive!
- My God.
- Sarah!
Oh, my God!
Oh!
Sarah!
TJ, I have to
see him.
Axel.
Why?
Help me, please.
Hanniger, I'll be waiting
in hell for you!
Harry?
Harry, I'm coming.
This whole fucking town
is going to die!
We're coming back,
you bastards!
Sarah, be my
bloody Valentine.
## Daddy's gone away ##
## Harry Warden
made you pay. ##
## Once upon a time ##
## On a sad Valentine ##
## In a place known
as Hanniger Mine ##
## A legend began ##
## Every woman and man ##
## Would always
remember the time ##
## And those who remain ##
## Were never the same ##
## You could see
the fear in their eyes ##
## Once every year ##
## As the 14th draws near ##
## There's a hush
all over the town ##
## For the legend,
they say ##
## On a Valentine's Day ##
## Is a curse
that'll live on and on ##
## And no one will know ##
## As the years come and go ##
## Of the horror
from long time ago ##
## 20 years came and went ##
## And everyone spent ##
## The 14th in quiet regret ##
## And those still alive ##
## Know the secret survives ##
## In the darkness
that looms in the night ##
## For the legend, they say ##
## On a Valentine's Day ##
## Is a curse
that'll live on and on ##
## And no one will know ##
## As the years come and go ##
## Of the horror
from long time ago ##
## In this little town ##
## When the 14th
comes round ##
## There's a silence
and fear in the air ##
## Remember the morn ##
## That the legend was born ##
## All the shock
and the horror was there ##
## For the legend, they say ##
## On a Valentine's Day ##
## Is a curse
that'll live on and on ##
## And no one will know ##
## As the years come and go ##
## Of the horror
from long time ago ##
## And no one will know ##
## As the years come and go ##
## Of the horror ##
## From long time ago. ##