BASED ON THE NOVEL BY JOSE GIOVANNI
HAD HER HUSBAND SHOT
Paris is outraged,
Paris is shattered,
Paris is tormented,
but Paris is...
liberated!
NOVEMBER 3RD 1944
At that time,
it was difficult to be young.
But you don't choose
when you have your youth.
It happens when you're young.
I've still not forgotten anything
about my time with Georges
nor anything that he told me.
Yet, I would've liked some of the details
to have got lost.
Are you OK?
That's it.
It's OK.
- Leave me, Georges.
- Stop!
Shit, we're going to get out.
I said we're going to get out.
Friend, do you hear the dark flight
Of the crows over our plains?
Friend, do you hear the muffled clamor
Of enchained countries?
Hey, partisans, workers, and peasants
This is the signal
Tonight the enemy will know
The price of blood and tears
Whoa! What have you got in your hump?
Ingots?
Don't shout!
There's too many for me.
They won't get me.
Get off.
Go away! Go back to fishing.
Documents, please.
Get out, we need to check
with the prefecture. Stand there.
- Don't stay in this house.
- Don't worry.
Hello, darling.
Georges!
You're mad coming back.
- Swear that you weren't waiting for me.
- Every minute.
Was there a treasure hunt?
No, it put them in such a rage
not finding your brother and you.
They were also looking for money
that you might have hidden.
They're not smart enough for that.
Walk a bit so I can watch you.
They arrested me, you know?
I spent three months in prison.
Luckily my uncle managed to free me,
given his rank.
Yes, I saw him come out.
You didn't do anything.
I lived with you.
Do you regret it?
Now you'll see, we'll get out.
Really?
If they find you, they'll kill you.
I told you they weren't
smart enough for me.
You didn't even come back
for these diamonds?
No.
I knew you'd be here.
You're all I have now.
What about your brother?
François is dead.
They won't be able to question him,
that'll piss them off no end.
What do you plan on doing now?
Change your life with these diamonds?
Take me around the world
followed by the police?
The diamonds are for extras.
Champagne, caviar, anything you want.
Listen.
The cops will be disappointed.
It's a masterstroke, my darling.
Do you see what's happening?
Don't start with these pipe dreams.
Listen!
This time it's for sure. I'm getting out.
You'll see.
You come help me, we'll fuck them.
First, we have to go to Paris.
Commandant Adrien Rove,
of the Second Bureau intelligence service,
ended up seeing me thanks to my uncle.
It was my third visit to the Parisian
hotel commandeered by the army.
Is it free?
No.
How much?
You need to forget this file.
Do you know what's in this file?
The registrations of Georges Gualtieri
and his brother
with German police in Marseille.
Today, that would cost
being killed by firing squad.
That's what it's cost us.
Georges' motivations aren't simple
to understand.
- I imagine.
- No.
Now that his brother is dead,
he can be himself again.
- That wouldn't clear some of his actions.
- No, I know, of course.
I'm not excusing him, you know.
But you're not risking anything
by meeting him.
You can't ignore that he helped you save
thousands of lives.
What are you doing in this mess?
What a woman would do for love.
You're risking a lot.
I know.
And when will we see him... your friend?
In an hour if you want.
But you won't set a trap for him?
You have our word.
I suppose I should be happy?
The door is there.
Make a choice.
Fine.
How did you meet this individual?
My father is a ship-owner in Marseille.
Sometimes I worked with him.
One day, Georges came to the office
for an expense history.
That day, you would have been
better off catching the flu.
You're a real one, aren't you?
Take it.
It seems you have something
to propose to us?
It would seem, yes.
Are you interested in clearing the metro?
What do you mean by clearing the metro?
It means the Germans were going
to blow it up at the Liberation.
Everything's ready to go.
Imagine a great explosion in the metro.
Not at night, at rush hour.
When all the big shops clear out.
With the Seine just above.
There's no lifeboats in the metro.
I know a network waiting for it.
What network?
Civilian Germans who speak French
with French names,
in a completely French and legal business.
- How's someone like you useful to them?
- Someone like me?
They're no longer
the masters of Paris, agreed?
How do they get into the metro
to test their devices?
We told them we knew someone
in the metro management
that could be bought. That's it.
That's why they didn't reject
me and my brother from Germany.
Can we know this someone's name?
I don't know it,
you'll just have to make it up.
What do you want in exchange?
Something very dear to me.
Very cheap for you.
A clean past?
He's great, he understands it all.
This week alone,
you're the third little traitor
to offer their services.
Traitor?
I'm not a traitor.
What's a Frenchman
working for the Germans?
For me, France is just detention centers.
Georges, it's fine, calm down.
How much time do I have?
The time to reassure me
if you want to avoid a catastrophe.
Do you want a bit more coffee, commandant?
The two brothers only operated
in and around Marseille.
Where my wife disappeared.
I know what you're thinking,
but be cautious.
This Georges Gualtieri must be
a mythomaniac.
There's no reason for him
to invent his metro story.
Yes, I'd love some coffee, thanks.
A whole network of German civilians
camouflaged in Paris, unbelievable!
For the metro.
I already have the uniforms.
The rest will go as planned.
We can't be suspicious enough
of that bastard.
He must have loved his brother,
it sheds light on the individual.
The Gestapo caves were lacking in light.
He surely must have met a lot of guys
like Goetz, who knows?
He might lead me to him.
These are the people implicated
in the La Fente file, the de Fustanges.
I protest, this arrest is unjust.
Accusing us of working with German police!
Scandalous!
Commandant, please call
the police chief immediately.
He's a friend of ours.
We'll look at it tomorrow.
- Let us go!
- This is ridiculous.
Tomorrow Gualtieri is taking me
to his Nazi network.
Maybe we could take a breath.
Before going into the snake pit.
Your commandant wanted
to have me followed.
The fake traitor.
Talk about a jerk,
I saw his guy with a newspaper.
He wants the network, to have a good raid.
He wants the cake to himself,
and then me, bam!
But since you started it all,
no one can take you away.
Shit!
I saw the whole thing.
I drove them to every land mine.
Mine-clearing, a successful mission.
And I saw all of them, them and me,
lined up with their ground machines
for the family photo.
And the, "Thank you, Mr. Gualtieri."
"Oh, thank you, Mr. Gualtieri!"
Do you know what I mean?
"Thanks a lot, Mr. Gualtieri!"
At that moment,
I became someone else, a new man.
I started again.
We both started again.
Yes!
- But I'm a traitor!
- Come on, it's not that simple.
Listen to me.
It will be even more simple.
They want to double-cross me?
- It's going to blow.
- What?
No, don't do that!
The Germans will do it anyway,
so it will blow up.
I don't give a shit about the company!
They've always laughed
at my brother, they can die!
OK.
I have an errand to run.
I'll be back in an hour.
He's a hunchback! He's a hunchback!
Come in, commandant, please.
- You're crazy bringing him here.
- I swear, he's nothing to be scared of.
Clearly, I wasn't alone.
It wasn't the newspaper guy,
it was the girl with the kid.
We're not getting involved
in a Nazi network
without the service covering us!
- Then they'll send me packing.
- I don't trust you anymore.
Listen, Gualtieri.
Four years ago, you were in prison.
When you got out,
you took revenge on the prosecutor!
He became disabled.
New sentence of 15 years' hard labor.
You got out thanks to the German police.
And you're talking to me about trust?
Answer, say something!
He humiliated his brother.
It's none of his business.
Since it's none of my business,
why did you come to find me?
You thought I'd let you stay free
just like that?
Or that I'd beg a guy like you?
You have five seconds to decide.
You agreed, didn't you?
Georges, I've had enough. This ends now.
Make a decision.
I can still count to five.
Let's go.
Are you armed?
Always.
Remember, we're familiar now.
Don't worry, old pal,
we work together now.
You'll see.
How are you? This is my colleague.
After you, René.
These are the maps of the tunnels.
There's been work on since August.
You'll have to check the device,
there might be cut wires.
What do you think?
It's possible.
We'll be dressed like the workers,
in uniforms
provided by the head
of technical services.
I suppose he's only interested
in money too.
You know, the Führer...
He really loves France, our Führer!
We realized that, yes.
I can't understand why they involved
Frenchmen in my network.
Hey!
It's Frenchman that you got for the cash,
there are others you got...
who knows why?
Right, René?
But how will you get
into the metro without us?
Ah yes, it's true, that...
OK, warn your guy that we'll go together
to check the... mine areas.
At this time, he isn't at home.
Call him at work!
They have a phone in the metro.
Metropolitan...
Technical management, administration...
Technical services.
Babylon 32-14.
Sorry, we're not leaving
until the operations have been successful.
Hello? Technical services?
Can I speak to Mr. Robillard, please?
Yes, the maintenance manager in the south.
Yes, Robillard, yes.
Ah, hello, René.
Day or night?
I can take the night if that suits you?
I can do a stand-in.
When?
Tonight.
Is tonight OK?
CHÂTELET
PONT DE NEUILLY EXIT
It's here.
There are two loads at the base.
Nobody touch the wires here.
The loads are taken in the wall,
you see where it is lighter.
Careful of this rail.
It's electric.
There's still one or two trains that need
to go back to the depot.
OK, well...
You said under the Seine, here we are.
Halfway between the Châtelet
and St. Michel stations.
This is where the Seine has to flow.
So I placed three double loads.
One at the base, one in the arch
and one at the top.
Where's your detonator?
It's easy access.
- When will it blow up?
- Tomorrow morning.
At a very busy time.
Perfect!
Who'll press the button?
Franz will.
Thanks for your help.
It stops there.
Wait.
I only get paid if it works.
- You have to monitor it to the end.
- Yes, guys.
You need to check the detonator. No?
Franz!
OK, we have to go back
to the first station.
It's this way.
Armed police, who are you?
Drop your weapon.
DELAYED TRAINS
That would have suited you, right?
You have poor taste in pranks.
It's settled.
For the Gualtieri file...
Stay here.
I'll take care of the other one.
And I'll notify the bomb squad.
Are you a collaborator?
Are you the police?
We just had to follow the wires,
we found it hidden
in the manager's office.
See this?
It's a mercury detonator.
The Germans just had
to turn the thing like this
horizontally.
And there, the mercury will touch
the wires
and it blows up.
And thanks to who did it not blow up?
Thanks to Mr. Gualtieri.
Thank you, Mr. Gualtieri.
See, you had your hour of glory.
I'm sure Commandant Rove has a word.
As soon as you have your papers in order,
your name will be cleared,
we can start a new life.
Have you done what was needed
for Gualtieri's papers?
What papers?
Toilet paper.
I gave him my word and...
I didn't give him mine.
Don't worry about it,
he won't need papers.
He worked for us.
Thanks to him, we avoided
a massacre in the metro.
He won't have time
to sing from the rooftops.
He never lied to me.
We found his brother's body.
He could still be very useful to us
in the south, he knew people
working for the Gestapo.
torturers who infiltrate everywhere.
Wouldn't it be worth
looking at the issue again?
Your officer promises are nice.
I just have one word,
but I have superiors.
Oh yeah!
And what did your superiors tell you?
They know that you knew
a lot of people in Marseille.
If you help us, they'll hire you
in our services,
- it's better than an identity card.
- What if I don't want that?
It'll be more difficult for me.
And particularly for you.
I'm just asking you to come
with me and point them out.
That's a no.
Accept it, Georges.
What do you take me for?
I'm not a professional informant!
Stopping torturers
or those responsible for deportation,
- is a service to humanity.
- Fine.
I've already been told all about humanity.
You have three days to think about it.
CITY SERVICES
Whore!
MARSEILLE A FEW DAYS LATER...
It was the year of chances
and revenge,
which came to an end
in function rooms, town halls
schools and even stadiums.
MARRIAGE HALL
All whilst helping Commandant Rove
to discover the real collaborators.
Georges had the impression
that Rove was secretly looking
for something else, something personal.
We lived in a place chosen by the service
and I waited alone for them to come back
from their hunt every day.
George was bogged down in this mistrust,
in the midst of people being arrested
quickly and freed with indifference.
- It's wet.
- No, no.
Thank you.
I really fucked them.
I recognized harelip straight away.
And they freed him!
It's the first time he's been lucky
in his fucking life!
What are we doing with this one?
Let him tell you what he's been doing
the last few years, we'll check it out.
He's the only one that went between
Gualtieri and me without looking at us.
I wonder where Rove went.
He may have gone to see
a girl on the street corner.
That would surprise me.
Do you think he spits on it?
He seems to be above all that,
or next to it.
I might be wrong.
There was a new cleaner again
this morning.
The third one in four days.
They must work for the service.
They change them
so no one gets used to them.
We're being watched all the time.
If I wanted to go, it wouldn't be
the surveillance that stopped me.
They're not smart enough.
What do you think?
There must be men around the house.
The purge won't last 107 years.
Hopefully.
It shocks me to see Frenchmen
shaving women's heads
and painting swastikas on their heads.
Whilst the Americans are dropping
like flies in the Ardennes.
Rove says they've lost 500,000 men
since D-Day.
It's not over.
Georges, this house is too big.
They've not given me a signal.
They stopped a bit, those two jerks.
They were never smart.
If you go blind, I can grow old in peace.
You'll never be old.
You think?
Not even later?
Much later?
Later...
when is that?
Félix Ringlet, known as Little Breton,
and Robert Arregui, known as The Basque.
Does that mean anything to you?
Our services think otherwise.
And there's also Gianno Rinaldi.
You know, Harelip.
Are you proud of arresting
those three poor men?
That's why I agreed
to follow you to Marseille.
They said torturers!
They won't get them if you double-cross
me, you don't recognize anyone!
They're like me, burglar buddies.
We were in prison together,
the Germans were looking for us.
We still have 13 years left.
Do you know what a central prison is?
In my position, would you have refused
the freedom offered?
You could've agreed and run off.
Right!
With all the police on my ass,
the German and the French.
I should have met you,
you'd have offered me a place
in the Resistance.
- Would you have joined?
- Would you have taken me?
The Nazis had bigger ideas.
Do you smoke now?
Only on special occasions.
Rove!
I'm stopping.
I'm leaving you.
I suspected as much.
But you won't go far.
How much advance will I get?
One hour.
If you come with me to a school
where they're waiting for us
I'll see your escape tomorrow morning,
you'll have one night's advance.
Yes! I'm sick of your help and all that!
It's not help, I need you.
Like I need nuns,
hookers, bank managers...
- Big family!
- There you go.
- Yes.
- Which doesn't bother with pity.
I want to see my daughter.
I fought in Verdun,
you bunch of little bastards!
Screw you!
What did my daughter do wrong?
She slept with the Germans, so what?
Without her the family
would've died of hunger.
Bunch of scumbags.
She was right!
Wait for me a minute.
You don't have the right to shave her!
Trash!
Release them.
Your papers, please.
Fernand Fournier,
Knight of the Legion of Honor.
Knight my ass!
This one is worth it.
Real trash.
Come on.
A.B.C.D.E THE COUNTRY WILL BE REBORN
OVER THE GRAVES OF TRAITORS
THE COUNTRY WILL FLOURISH
It's fairer, because of the bastard.
Hello, Ibrana.
What do you want?
Do you still have your offices
on rue de Paradis in Marseille?
What offices?
The French Gestapo ones.
Are you accusing me
of being a Gestapo agent?
Me?
One day, you'll apologize to me,
I guarantee it.
With a poker.
You...
Bastard.
Do you know each other?
No need for introduction, then.
It's not me!
It's him, that's his brother!
Your brother invented the poker.
Don't put anything else on my brother.
He's had enough of that.
Where is he?
Does he work for you?
Like you?
You bastard!
I should've bumped you both off.
He is well informed, you know why?
Because I was there.
So?
- The truth is there.
- It was me.
We had to.
- Tell him!
- No!
We didn't have to.
It's not fair.
He's there, strutting like a cop,
but it's not fair.
- He's like me.
- No!
Because he has remorse.
That's the best one.
Everyone can have remorse.
I have it too, it's easy.
No, remorse can be proved.
Otherwise it's settled with 12 bullets
in the skin in the small hours.
There's one.
There's still 11 more.
Work on him here.
No helping him until he says
something important, understood?
Question him about Dr. Goetz.
You never know.
I heard you talking about Goetz.
Are you interested?
Do you know him?
Yeah, he's a German
who looks after the radio.
Yes, and?
I saw him with a guy I knew.
A crook they called The Slide.
He was a radio freak as well.
But Goetz...
didn't just come for the radio.
He loved the chubby southern girls.
And where did The Slide operate?
Ah! Most recently he directed
the Gestapo from Avignon.
My wife was arrested in Avignon.
Your wife?
- Did she work with you?
- Yes.
In the underground movement.
Have you ever seen her?
You may have seen her
in the arrested Resistance fighters.
No, not that.
She disappeared on July 25th.
By July I was already locked up in Germany
with my brother.
We need to find Goetz,
it's of utmost importance.
He knows a lot.
He sent back English agents
and communicated with London for them.
He made a big move.
Perhaps with The Slide...
He's already cleared off.
His real name is Galiettas.
Miss, do I find you in the bed of a thug?
A guy from the Gestapo
and a bourgeois girl like you?
Let me explain, there must have been
a misunderstanding.
A little traitor of the homeland,
a convict on the run?
I love him, commandant,
he is so tender, so sensitive.
I'd die if something happened to him.
Little wretch!
Before I die, I will submit to you.
But commandant...
That's not like you at all!
But you're...
Stop, you're hurting me.
Hello?
Yes, hello, Commandant Rove.
Yes, don't go, I'll put him on.
Hello, yes?
Yes...
Right now?
OK, I'm coming.
Very quickly, I'll cut through
the old Panier neighborhoods.
OK, yes.
He's with Ibrana, he wants to see me.
Where?
At the precinct where he's been
questioning since yesterday.
Oh, shit!
In any case all the cops will be there.
When he recognizes me, we'll have a laugh.
They'll stand to attention.
Don't go through the old areas,
they know you.
It's dangerous. Tell Rove to come get you.
What do you want me to do,
my angel, I'm untouchable.
What's it like living with me?
If you say so.
PELLETIER HOUSE
BUY AND SELL
Look, isn't that guy Bosco's brother?
Bosco's brother is in the area.
That fucking Gestapo.
Bosco! Trash!
Quick!
Get him!
DU CHÂTEAU PRESCHOOL
Bastard!
Stop!
Don't be jerks.
We're all going to the cops together.
That's what I came back for.
And that's just the start.
After, we'll do what you did
to the others, shall I tell you?
You'll talk now.
Stop your bullshit,
here you talk or you die.
You'll go out feet first if not.
What?
Get Vincent to take care of it.
Tomorrow, you'll be begging to talk.
Today, you're mute,
tomorrow you'll be deaf, you'll be sorry.
Here, Gualtieri. Really!
Your brother?
Where is he?
You'll never get him where he is.
We got you.
You won't get a medal for that.
I'm a double agent.
A double agent? Well then.
Can you prove it?
Do you have a telephone?
Call Commandant Rove.
Adrien Rove, central precinct.
He's there waiting for me.
I don't belong there anymore.
This is a special service.
We're purifying.
We'll look into it.
Whilst we wait, take him to the garage.
Call this Rove at the precinct.
Do you believe him, lieutenant?
We might as well get information.
- Neuvole!
- Georges!
I thought you went to Germany.
Yes, I did.
I got homesick.
- What about your brother?
- He's dead.
In a way...
It's better for him?
Yeah.
Say...
What's this special service?
The research board, I think it's called.
Say...
- The captain...
- Yes.
- The one with the beard?
Have you ever seen him anywhere?
No.
Shit!
I recognize his voice,
but I don't know anyone with a beard.
You can grow a beard.
Yes!
What do they know about you exactly?
Enough to send me down for 20 years.
Go to the bathroom if you want.
One at a time.
This captain...
I'm sure I've seen him before.
We've seen so many guys
in the last two years.
Have you seen anyone?
Yeah.
Randomly, right and left.
Jo from Nice, Mathieu the Brute.
François The Belgian.
The Slide.
- What about Litas?
- Yeah.
A real nutcase.
He thinks the Germans will return.
You know what he's like.
Gualtieri!
That's it!
I know where I saw the bearded guy.
Gualtieri.
That's it! Oh.
Don't worry about it.
I'll get you out of here.
- We're waiting for you.
- Thanks, good man.
I'll do everything I can
so you don't get harmed.
So?
They fooled you, it seems?
Exactly! And it's me who got a good catch.
A nice bearded man.
Take this.
While I think about it.
I'm sorry but the mission I'm offering you
doesn't have a beard.
Highest order.
If it's really essential.
I'm sorry.
Have you had it for a long time?
September 1939.
I vowed never to cut it
until we were victorious.
I have fewer concerns!
It's just a question of weeks.
Thank you.
War wound?
Yes.
Sedan, May 13th, 1940.
But in my unit, we held on
until the bitter end.
If all Frenchmen had fought like you,
we wouldn't have seen the Milice.
No doubt.
It seems that you escaped Germany
and formed a Maquis in Sologne.
Yes!
End of 1943.
What does this mission involve,
Commandant?
We thought you could help us uncover
someone responsible for a massacre.
You really think I'm useful to you?
Yes!
You have surprising self-control.
You'll work with this gentleman.
I think you knew his brother rather well.
Possibly, what's his name?
His name won't mean anything.
But people don't forget my brother.
He's a hunchback.
A hunchback? I don't know.
No, he must have made a mistake,
I'd remember.
It's OK.
OK, let's go.
What? Tonight?
Yes, it's...
It's a long journey.
We'll get there tomorrow morning.
It's cold up there.
Take this.
Put this on.
Why?
Does this beret bother you?
No, nothing bothers me.
If you're wrong about him,
it'll be very serious.
So what are we doing?
Nothing.
Waiting.
The militiaman!
Mommy, mommy, the militiaman!
Yes, it's me, Commandant.
I am Alexis de Boitreuil.
I was a soldier, understand?
A French officer.
I'll die under gunfire.
Like a soldier.
Who is the mayor of this village?
I am.
Commandant Rove.
Leave him with us, Commandant.
We'll take care of him, it's our right.
No, I can't.
We will interview him on the spot, but...
Then, I'll send him back
to the military authorities.
He had men from this village
hanging from trees.
He didn't have the courage to go
into the mountains and trap the Maquis,
they attacked innocent people.
- Did you arrest the hunchback?
- He's dead.
We want names, dates, all the details.
If not, I'll hand you over
to your victims' families.
Mr. Mayor, take him with my men
to a locked room.
I would've happily killed your brother.
To stop talking about it,
I can tell you one thing.
If I had wanted to, I could've stopped him
doing that bullshit.
Why didn't you?
Because my brother enjoyed
seeing other people suffer.
For me, the joy
of a handicapped person is priceless.
No one recognizes you here,
are you not surprised?
No, I stayed near the cars.
And maybe I've changed already!
I did horrible things too.
But my reasons are in the files.
I understand.
No.
You don't understand.
I'm not looking for apologies.
What's done is done.
I'm just giving you an explanation.
Happy new year!
I have a present for you.
Really?
Oh, thanks, I'm touched.
Yes, it's very kind.
And it's superb.
The painter isn't
that well known yet, but...
I trust his talent.
I think you're right.
If the countess allows me...
It's beautiful!
- Where did it come from?
- I got it in a bar.
It may be from a heist.
And is there a little present for me,
Commandant?
A small medal?
I don't know, maybe the Legion of Honor?
I'll consider you for the next promotion.
Yeah? Well I have a present for you.
A present like this.
Thanks, I don't need anything.
It doesn't have to be like this, Commandant.
I spoke about your wife.
Stop, Georges, it's not funny.
Don't joke about that.
I'm not joking.
I know where The Slide is.
If we have The Slide, we get to Goetz.
And if we have Goetz...
Explain yourself.
First...
We need to get a friend out of prison.
Has he been convicted?
Not yet.
But he risks 20 years.
OK.
That's his nickname.
It was the bearded guy that duped him.
Another reason to free him.
I don't like this party anymore.
Oh shit.
It's nothing.
I was unlucky.
It might be called something else.
But I'll put it back together.
I'm the king
of putting things back together.
If not, I'll buy a new one.
A nicer one.
I have a friend
who can forge anything.
Rembrandt...
Renoir.
And he's a real artist.
The most beautiful
Of all the tangos in the world
Is the one I danced in your arms
I have known other tangos around
But my heart will never
Forget that one
I love you.
We'll send you to Spain
if you've told the truth, we'll forget you
and... you'll forget us.
Is that OK?
And whilst we wait?
We'll still keep an eye on you.
Until we find The Slide.
You can trust him.
Look at me, I'm free.
I even have my gun.
It's not in my nature to snitch.
But The Slide wouldn't last
very long anyway.
An old asylum.
That suits him. He went mad.
And where are you in it all?
I was supposed to go back there
with a part to repair his transceiver.
Tell me what the part is,
and we'll take it to him.
It's an oscillator.
A little lamp.
It's in my things with my papers.
Perfect.
Can you find this asylum for us?
Vincent!
Don't refuse, this is your chance.
The Slide is a bastard.
Take this.
To see what's coming.
Judas's last coins.
Why? Were you seeing Christ?
Be ready to intervene however we decide.
Understood.
So, did the telephone work?
Yes.
He's very happy
that I'm bringing Oberführer Kulemann,
he's the big radio specialist.
You'll see, it's on this road,
25 kilometers from Avignon.
There's a very long wall
behind this wall is a
whole gang of crooks,
former Gestapo disguised as nurses.
It's OK, open it.
Old Georges, here you are at last!
Well, I don't see Satan.
He's dead.
God too.
Let me introduce Oberführer Kulemann.
Leave us.
Here is your...
- Oscillator.
- Thanks, Oberführer.
My name will be remembered.
I was a small-time crook.
I'm going to change the world.
I thought you were
only interested in cops?
Poor fool! How do you think
I would keep mine
if the Germans lost the war?
With that...
I'm going to fix my radio station.
And so...
I'll confuse the issue
of the Battle of the Bulge.
And so...
I'll sabotage the junction.
The Americans are waiting
for their VIII Corps.
And I'll send Germans in their place.
Panzer Division!
You were reckless with the Neuvole.
He might have met a double agent.
But I know him!
And double agents always get mixed up
at any time, right?
You should have...
Killed Neuvole!
It's done.
You won't need to thank him.
In your heyday,
he introduced Goetz to you.
A pretentious idiot
who'll come kiss my ass!
Are you waiting for Goetz?
I'm waiting for them all.
I'll be their last refuge.
We need to wait here quietly
for the Germans to come back.
Then this Goetz might come
with another chick.
And I'll... kill them both.
Because the last little minx
who was with him
was a little informant bitch.
Sir...
It's the 83rd and 84th infantry
of the VIII Corps in the Ardennes.
Read that to them.
No.
It's impossible.
I can't this time.
More tightening?
Who is it?
It's me, The Foal.
We found a poisoned dog in the park.
How many times? What does that mean?
- You're not...
- We're not.
No! Bunch of pansies.
Hands on your head.
Get the woman out.
The one downstairs, quickly.
Telephone.
Roland.
Come up with the girl.
There's ten men outside with dogs.
Bunch of crooks.
Double agent!
You're not getting out alive.
Thanks, sir.
So?
It was Goetz who sent me it, the bastard.
She made us fall into a Maquis trap
we lost two squads.
We finally got the bitch!
Where is she?
In a lake.
With some Maquis members.
Carnage.
The Germans dropped them in a lake
- above Vaison-la-
- Romaine.
When they stick you to the post,
I'll come myself
to give you the final blow.
Commandant Rove told you.
It's no use telling the truth, Commandant.
I'll tell you how she died, your brunette.
Like that, you'll remember me.
They always remember The Slide.
She was a good-looking girl.
This is what Goetz and I did to her.
Goetz was a specialist.
An expert.
We...
I did the same for myself.
Thanks.
Commandant...
I had the VIII Corps.
Everything is arranged.
I'm going.
I'll cover you.
Surrender, drop your weapons!
The service is intervening.
Everything is settled outside.
There are prisoners in the cellar
and this lady needs hospitalizing.
You!
Take this one away.
For your wife...
I was really hopeful.
Bury her with her friends.
Does she still have family, parents?
No, just me.
And I just had her.
You're emotional because of your wife.
I understand, but don't worry
about that scoundrel Gualtieri.
I'm only working on efficiency now.
He could work with Pellin.
No, I don't want him
to meet another agent.
He knows you, that's already too many.
He could work alone.
Send him on a foreign mission.
- There's work in Indochina.
- No.
There's nothing for him there.
There's something in Besançon.
A cork factory where the staff
turns over completely in six months.
It might be hiding one
of those German sabotage networks.
Get him some fake papers,
a cork sales card.
That will help him succeed.
What exactly will he have to do?
Get a feel for the place and manage
to infiltrate thanks to his past.
I'm sure he will succeed.
Thank you on his behalf, Colonel.
- Hello.
This is where we first met.
Yes.
Here are the papers.
Robert Latour!
Cork salesman.
- His real papers?
- He'll get them.
This is for the mission
I spoke to you about.
- So he's enlisted in the service?
- Absolutely.
Thanks a lot. I want to kiss you!
I knew you'd keep your word.
They are more real than life, great work.
You could almost cross a border with them.
There's no need to put ideas in his head!
It's time to make a choice.
I've decided.
CORK FACTORY
COMTÉ BROTHERS
- Hello, miss.
- Sir.
Robert Latour, cork salesman.
I'd like to speak to the director,
I called.
I know, yes.
- You can go up.
- Thanks.
Hello?
It's him, he's coming up.
Hello.
Hello, Mr. Latour. Please, have a seat.
Thank you.
So, you have a proposition for us?
Yes, I think it's very interesting.
Let me start by showing you the samples.
I hope you represent a major company.
MARSEILLE APRIL 1945
Georges got away
with three months in hospital
before being locked
in Marseille's St. Pierre prison.
The cork factory was no longer occupied
by a German network
like the Second Bureau had claimed,
but by the internal security service.
He had therefore fallen into a trap.
DETENTION CENTER
Despite all the efforts
by his lawyer Mr. Vilar,
we couldn't prove that he had worked
for the Second Bureau.
In a letter rogatory
by the examining judge,
the services in Paris refused
to recognize Georges' participation.
Obviously, since they tried
to get him killed.
Now they're charging him
with the attempted murder
of the two French agents
that he mistook for Germans.
That confusion will cost us dearly.
And Commandant Rove?
By coincidence, his colonel sent him
on a foreign mission.
I never stopped asking for his statement.
It finally happened.
All my hopes were on him.
I couldn't imagine that he made
an agreement with the service
to betray Georges.
No, I couldn't have been
that wrong about him.
No and no, these orders are definitive.
The service must wash its hands
of this story.
- Colonel, it's too easy.
- It's not about knowing if it's easy.
It's about the service.
I set the trap for him in Besançon
and I gave the orders to bring him down.
He was lucky in the end.
Imagine that you've never seen
that thug in your life.
- He can prove otherwise.
- Not at all.
I took care of that,
we removed all his traces.
He was young.
There was youth everywhere.
Resistant fighters shot dead at 16.
Think about it.
Come on.
One day, you'll understand.
Commandant Rove!
The service betrayed Georges.
I know.
Now you're here, we can sort it out.
He ran into the internal security service
in Besançon.
Surely you didn't know
that the factory was a trap?
It depends who was trapped.
The service is driven
by political imperatives.
And my duty is to obey the service.
I see.
Yes, it's true.
Millions of people dead, martyrs.
You must be thinking
about your wife too.
Guys like Georges don't carry weight.
But you have to weigh up everything.
He helped you, you made him believe
in his redemption.
Yes, I always had hope for him.
I hoped that it wouldn't be too late.
Your words can make everything better.
Listen to me.
Georges will be judged
for belonging to the German police.
In his files, there's no torture
or deportation to his name.
You have to pay but you have to plead.
If he talks about his work with me
without proof, it will go against him.
He's already talked about it.
His lawyer has called you as a witness.
It'll force the prosecution to do it too.
Don't make that mistake.
It's hard to admit,
but that's the best thing to do.
The best thing to do?
I'll tell you what will happen.
Because I know Georges well.
It will work out so that you have
to face up to the trial.
- Don't play that card.
- Why not?
In Georges' game, what was the right card?
Excuse me, sir,
wasn't this a laboratory before?
I don't know, everyone is new here.
Thanks.
BRIC-A-BRAC
...CEUTICS
OUTDOOR CENTER
FOR DEPORTED CHILDREN
FOR OUR MARTYRS
And under these trees, who do we talk to?
How do I talk about Georges
to these widows and these orphans?
HOUSE FOR SALE
Georges had found Neuvole there,
at the Research Directorate.
Now there's just
these knick-knacks, and me.
Your uncle knows Rove well.
Yes, I've thought about it.
But he refuses to get officially involved
in all of this.
I'm going to the trial.
I'll testify personally.
After all, I got mixed up
in all the events.
You'll get arrested,
accused of non-disclosure,
being an accomplice.
That won't be good for us.
You have to accept
that we're in a time of special courts,
almost revolutionary.
And Ibrana?
And the militiaman?
Both shot dead.
At the moment, there's no delay.
Listen...
Since you were kids, you and your brother,
I defended you in all your petty thefts.
So today, I won't surprise you.
Rove isn't coming to the trial.
We can't prove anything.
It will be better to change
the defense method.
You know my whole life.
And you won't talk
about the one good thing I did?
I want Commandant Rove to come and say it.
That's all.
Sir, I won't allow you
to insult this court.
I'm not insulting it,
I'm saying it's a special court
and I'm starting to doubt
that justice will be done.
Please be specific.
I called upon Commandant Rove
from the Second Bureau.
And you, the prosecution,
you also have the right to call a witness
of the same importance.
I did not fail to do so.
I think despite everything
that the defendant is a liar
who dares to invent heroic actions
to cancel out his betrayal.
Government Commissioner,
I repeat, you have to put everything
in the hands of justice.
I assure you we are, sir.
But on one side there's already the blood
and tears of martyrs.
It's very heavy, you know.
Listen, erm...
I don't want to make a speech.
But if I've done wrong to anyone here,
they just have to say.
Did I do something to you?
Sit down.
Fuck you!
Silence!
I remember that the trial
turned into confusion.
No one believed
in Georges' positive actions
and his past became all the more shameful.
And then came the moment
that I'll never forget.
Sir, the main witness of the trial
has just arrived.
Please come in, Commandant Rove.
You are Commandant Rove,
attached to an intelligence service.
You're not related to
or an associate of the defendant.
Swear to tell the truth, the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
Raise your right hand and say, "I swear".
I swear.
Commandant.
Let me remind you
that you have been called by both
the defense and the prosecution.
I just have one question to ask you.
Your answer will compromise
both your honor and the life of a man.
Do you know Georges Gualtieri?
No.
Does the defense have
a question for the witness?
No.
No questions.
The Court thanks the witness.
I still remember that late afternoon
when the judge declared
Georges' death sentence.
I really thought it was for someone else.
I wanted to shout,
to run after the commandant
but I stayed still.
We often do the opposite
of what we should.
You're wearing a light dress.
It's summer again.
What about me, Georges?
Don't worry, sweetheart.
You'll see, the guns will get stuck.
Do you still have Dr. Goetz's file?
Yes, colonel.
I can tell you, I know it by heart.
Thanks, but I'd like the file.
- Is there anything new?
- Yes.
He was brought to us yesterday from Lyon.
Where is he?
I absolutely want to see him.
It'll be hard, we have
to give him to the Americans.
The Americans? Why the Americans?
Because it's the biggest
anti-communist file in Europe.
So he'll work for the USA.
Freely?
Yes, freely.
But, does that still exist?
He has many deportations
on his conscience,
even kids, the bill is high.
It became priceless.
These papers will go to the crematorium
to join their victims.
What do you want? It's still
the famous political circumstances.
We can't escape them.
He killed my wife too.
It's only the Americans
who will look for Goetz.
Dr. Goetz.
Louise.
I have to talk to you to tell the truth.
That's fine with me.
What will happen now?
As soon as the lawyer gets the letter,
he'll do what's necessary
to suspend the execution.
In a few days,
I'll go to Marseille with you.
Georges isn't risking anything?
Absolutely nothing because he's appealing.
Will there be a new trial?
Yes.
This time, it'll take ten years maximum.
He'll get pardoned, he's young.
If he finds you when he comes out,
he'll be saved.
He's lucky he met you.
Pascal, open up.
Hey!
Your chains are coming off.
Rove went back on his statement.
I'll have his letter tomorrow,
we're going to overturn the conviction.
Is it remorse or Louise?
A bit of both.
She'll tell you herself,
she's coming here.
I can see the prosecutor's face from here.
Colonel, about Georges Gualtieri,
I committed perjury.
I wrote to the judge to tell the truth.
This isn't serious, Rove?
You realize...
If it's about the rotten political
situation, it's not worth it.
And you can leave your dogs, I don't care.
Everyone lives as they can.
Excuse me a second.
Connect me to the Ministry of Justice.
Yes, yes, urgently.
MARSEILLE
17 AUGUST 1945
Oh my God, what is it?
Mr. Vilar.
Yes.
This is for you.
You need to sign there.
In accordance with the judgment
made on June 3rd, 1945,
the action taken has been rejected...
Enforces the death sentence
against Georges Gualtieri
who will be shot on August 17th, 1945
in the court of Fort St. Nicolas.
Duty of Mr. ...
No, wait, there's been a mistake!
Are you Mr. Vilar?
- No mistake.
- We do this every day.
- At 5 am?
- No, usually in the afternoon.
- Sign it.
- My client is on appeal.
That's nothing to do with us.
Hurry, it's in an hour.
Hôtel du Vieux Port?
Room 126, quickly.
- Hello?
- Louise.
Yes, it's me.
Do you know where Rove is?
Here in Marseille, in the same hotel.
You need to go and wake him up.
What is it?
It's Georges, an execution order,
in an hour at Fort St. Nicolas.
Oh no!
Don't say that.
Do something. Rove needs to act.
I'll do the impossible.
I'll run to the president.
Aim!
Fire!
Stop! Stop everything! Stop!
Stop!
New development.
Commandant Rove has
gone back on his statement.
Read it!
Gualtieri was telling the truth!
I have last-minute orders
from Paris, from the Ministry.
I can't do anything.
Sir...
I'd like to read the letter.
The commandant is arriving
in person at any minute.
I beg you to suspend the execution.
I beg you.
- Aim.
- It's an ambush.
Warning me an hour before!
It's illegal, it's completely illegal.
My client is on appeal.
I didn't even have time to get dressed.
Don't worry.
This is illegal, it won't happen.
I still did it all.
Yes, you did it.
- You did it, yes.
- Aim.
Fire.
Georges! Georges!
Another one down.
Commandant Rove,
I have a pass from General Dupuis.
It's fine, Commandant.
You don't have a pass.
- But how...
- Wait there.
The staircase is to the right, Commandant.
No!
You have a friend down there?
The redhead?
It'll be his last go
on the merry-go-round.
She still has her hair.
It's not the fear, sir,
it's the cold.
Forgive me.
Stop, it's an order!
Government Commissioner, Commandant Rove.
There'll be another trial.
I obey a minister of justice.
Take the convict away.
It's not possible.
It's not fair.
It's completely unfair.
Lieutenant, listen to me.
Listen to a superior officer,
don't kill this man.
Lieutenant, it's an assassination.
Let me go, you idiots.
Please!
Everything is bad enough, right?
Son, do you accept
the help of religion?
God's mercy is infinite.
What are you doing with that letter?
I'm taking it with me.
Aim!
Fire!
Every day, the Germans kill our own,
even women.
It comes to us all.
Did you hear that, officer?
I lost my son.
Are you not ashamed
of defending these people?
There's no more homeland, no flag.
You don't know what it is.
Have you lost anything?
They tortured my son.
What do you say to that, the pair of you?
It's clear that we absolutely can't live
without pity.
I came back to this bridge a few times.
Commandant Rove was killed
in the Algerian war
and men continued killing each other
all over the world.
Nothing really changed
if it weren't for the bodies
of the cars and their speed.
Subtitle translation by: Chloe Stout