I felt like I'd been
under there my entire life.
Wrapped in yellow blankets,
like a baby.
Swaddled too tight.
I was sinking further...
and further.
And just when I was about
to run out of breath,
something pulled me out.
Something in the trees.
A light.
A glow.
Is someone hungry?
Huh?
Hello?
Tilly.
Hey.
Hello.
Come here.
What's your name?
Tilly.
Where are you off to?
Hey.
It's okay.
Your dog's really cute.
Don't take her.
I just wanted to make sure
you're okay.
Um.
Are you okay?
How did you know I was here?
Well...
I was there...
last night at the reservoir.
I saw what happened.
I won't tell anyone.
I pinky promise.
What are you doing
with your finger?
Haven't you heard
of a pinky promise?
Well, it means more than
a normal handshake.
So...
what's your name?
Claudia.
I'm Grace.
What color are the other fingers?
- What?
- If, if this one is pink,
what color are the others?
Well, it's not that it's pink.
It's just...
just called your pinky finger.
And the other ones
all have different names.
You know them, right?
- First, second, third-
- Mm-mm, mm-mm.
Pinky.
Ring.
Rude.
What makes it rude?
- No.
- What?
Just, don't do that.
It's like saying something
really mean,
but with your finger.
Do you wanna come
and sit with me?
Can I come visit you sometime?
No one can know I'm here.
If they find out,
they'll take me away.
I won't tell anyone.
It can be our secret.
Purple promise?
Purple promise.
It was her.
Grace.
The glow on the bank.
The pull from the trees.
She's not of this place.
You want me to have a nervous
breakdown, Grace, is that it?
No, Mom.
Why the fuck are the cops here?
I don't know.
What the hell you been up to,
young lady?
- I've not done a fucking thing.
- Hey, hey, listen. Listen, hey.
Don't talk to her like that.
We just need to ask her
a few more questions.
Okay, so...
I'm Detective Croydon.
This is my partner,
Detective Jones.
We just wanted to clarify...
what you saw
at the res last night.
- Mm.
- So, you...
you saw some thrashing
in the water...
and then you said you saw a girl
running away from the res.
And we are not sure who that is.
See...
the deceased didn't have
any kids or family.
So, we think that it...
might have been a visitor,
or someone from out of town.
Now, is there anything
you can tell us about-
Look.
So, we really need you to think,
- okay?
- It's a scorpion in a lollipop.
What'd she look like?
Light hair? Dark hair?
Yeah, look,
I don't really think I saw a girl.
No girl?
No.
It was dark.
And I was on my own
and I think I got freaked.
And saw things
that weren't actually there.
I've got a really
overactive imagination.
Mom says it all the time.
So, wait.
Let me get this straight.
There was no girl
- But, you did say-
- Yeah, I know.
I know.
I'm saying that I think
I got carried away...
when I was speaking
to the officer last night.
There was no girl.
But, I definitely saw a woman,
an older lady,
walking into the water...
and then...
the thrashing.
Right. So...
you saw an older woman
walking into the water
Yeah.
That author lady
who lives by the res.
I recognised her from the back
of one of her books.
- Veronica Fox.
- Mm.
Yeah, that's her.
She just walked
into the water and...
didn't come out.
It was fucked.
Well...
sounds about right.
Cool.
So, I'm, I'm good?
I'm not in trouble?
No.
You're not in trouble.
Like I said, we just wanted
to clarify a few things.
- It's cool.
- You've been a big help.
Thank you, Grace.
Hey.
What you saw
must be really scary.
You got someone to talk to
about it if you need to?
Yeah.
Listen, my darling.
My darling girl, what's wrong?
I don't know.
Oh, my sweet.
You're having bad thoughts again?
Oh, my darling.
It's okay.
It's okay, my darling,
it's okay.
Shh, shh, shh.
Sweetheart.
Breathing in...
and out.
Sweet love,
you're doing so well.
Just breathe in.
Stay with me, my darling.
It's all okay.
Shh, shh, shh.
Sweet love, it's okay.
It's okay.
Just stay with me.
Stay with me.
Shh, shh, shh.
My darling, it's okay.
Slow it down.
Shh, shh, shh.
It's okay.
We're nearly there, my darling.
We are nearly there.
Breathe in...
and out.
Good.
Breathe in...
and out.
- Where-
- What?
Where did my mom go?
What did I do to her?
Uh, nothing.
Hey, Claudia, it's me.
It's me, Grace.
Hey, remember?
No, no, no, please.
Claudia, please.
Come back.
Wait.
Claudia.
Claudia!
Hey.
Claudia.
I should be with her.
I should be...
with her.
You can't be seen here.
You don't want
to be found, do you?
Hey, let's go home.
Yeah?
Let me take you home
where it's safe.
Oh, you have
to look in the mirror.
Why?
Just do it.
Can I do you?
Um, I've got too much hair.
It won't work.
Get in.
You like it here?
In the tub?
No, I mean, in this house.
I guess.
Why don't you ever leave?
I've left before.
I don't think the res counts.
It's on the outside.
Yeah, but I mean
like the real outside.
Mom said there's nothing
but pain there.
She said that?
Yes. She came from there.
She said that...
it was filled with selfish people...
who didn't treat
each other very well.
So, you've really
never been past the res?
Why would I?
I don't know, to...
go to school.
See a doctor, or...
go to your grandparents' houses...
and have cups of tea
and listen to the same story...
10 times over.
I mean,
I can't believe it.
Why are you laughing?
So, no one knows you exist?
Yeah. You do.
You can look in the mirror now.
Hm.
You're quite good at this.
Yeah.
I've never read any
of your mom's books.
I hear they're really depressing.
Mom said I'm not allowed
to read them until I turn 18.
How old are you now?
Sixteen.
Same.
"Lord!
"How unutterably disgusting life is!
"What dirty tricks it plays on us!
"Here we are among...
"the breadcrumbs and
the stained napkins again.
"The knife is already...
"Congealing.
"Congealing with grease.
- "Disorder, sordidity.
- "Sordidity.
"Sordidity...
"and corruption surrounds us.
"Call the waiter,
pay the bill.
"We must pull ourselves up
out of our chairs.
"We must find our coats.
"We must go.
"Must, must, must,
detestable word.
"I who had thought
myself immune...
"find that the wave has
tumbled me over...
"head-over-heels,
"leaving me to summon my forces,
"rise and confront the enemy."
Why was that page marked?
Mom was showing it
to me in class.
Wow.
What?
I thought my mom was fucked.
Sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have said that.
Mom just felt everybody's pain.
But...
she's free now.
What's your mom like?
Uh.
Mm, she kinda sucks.
Why?
She just...
she has a lot of problems.
And her boyfriend is a dick.
It's quite nice being
away from it all actually.
I like spending time with you here.
♪ As late as the hour may be ♪
♪ Gimme your love ♪
♪ I need your love so bad ♪
Purple.
Rude.
Ring.
Pinkie.
It's a bit late.
Have a seat.
You want a beer?
Here you go.
It's all right.
It's okay.
So, where you been?
A friend's place.
What? Like a...
a boyfriend?
Hey.
Look at you.
My little girl's all grown up.
I'm not your little girl, Mike.
Okay. So...
do you have a boyfriend?
It's okay if you do.
- I mean you're using protection-
- I really need to go.
Yeah, goodnight, Mike.
- I'm just playing.
- Goodnight.
I got whatever I could
before Mom woke up.
There's a lot.
There's lollies and chewy.
These are really good.
Oh, and...
- lollies with bugs in them.
- Wait, what's that?
Mm, strawberry milk.
You want some?
- Strawberry milk?
- It's really good.
Mm.
You'll like it.
Purple promise.
Okay, no.
Don't choke, don't choke.
All right.
Hang on.
Guess what else I brought?
Blah blah blah blah blah blah.
My mother said...
the fences...
were the walls of her womb.
Said she could only protect me
if I stayed inside,
away from everyone,
from everything.
I made these.
These ones are my favourite.
Brave.
Badass.
I'm gonna sell them
at the market or something.
They're my ticket outta here.
Where do you want to go?
Somewhere.
Anywhere.
Do you like them?
They're very...
colorful.
Okay.
Tell me one thing
that you like about yourself.
Okay.
I'll tell you.
You hardly know me.
I know enough.
Smart?
Aren't you?
What else?
Am I pretty?
Now,
choose your favourite color from here.
I think I like this one.
Turquoise.
Yeah, I like turquoise.
Okay.
What you do,
thread,
hold it.
You're a natural.
You'll have to help me.
Come on!
It's 200,000 degrees.
Come on.
What's wrong?
The best way to overcome a fear
is to confront it.
I'm serious.
Right.
I heard it on the TV
and everything.
Come on.
Hey! Hey.
You can't tell me
that didn't feel good?
How, how deep is it?
Not deep.
See?
You're okay.
Come on.
I'll help you through it.
- Okay.
- You ready?
Don't.
Okay.
Three, two.
Claudia, Claudia, hey, hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Okay, breathe in.
Breathe in.
Breathe out.
Breathe with me.
Hey, breathe with me.
In.
Out.
Breathe in.
Hey.
Keep looking at me.
Okay?
Okay.
Help me, okay?
It's okay.
Three,
two,
one.
Go ah.
Ah.
Oh.
Oh, I'm so bad at this.
Oh, did you see that?
Oh.
Lucky charm.
You can have it.
Can I still eat it?
Feel lucky?
Yes.
I don't really know how
I'm supposed to be feeling.
You make me think...
that all the stuff
my mom taught me in class,
about the world being cruel,
about people being...
monsters,
is all a lie.
How do you know
I'm not a monster?
Do you think you are?
Not many people like me, though.
Because monsters...
only like other monsters.
Okay.
Welcome.
I've got that poem
here somewhere.
Okay.
"When Day is Over"
by Lesbia Harford.
"When day is over
"I climb up the stair
"Take off my dark dress
"Pull down my hair
"Open my window
"And look at the stars
"Then my heart breaks through
"These prison bars
"Of space and darkness
"And finds what is true
"Up past the stars
"Where I'm one...
"with you"
I like that image...
of a heart breaking
through prison bars.
Can I feel it?
Feel what?
Your heart.
Can you hear it?
Yeah.
Is it okay?
It should be broken,
shouldn't it?
Shock can make you numb and...
I don't feel numb.
I feel more alive
than I've ever felt.
I'm sorry.
- I shouldn't have said that.
- Maybe, I should sit down.
Your mom would have
wanted you to be happy.
Maybe, you should go.
What?
I need you to go.
- Claudia, I'm-
- I said go.
Go!
Get out!
My mother said...
there would come a time...
when we would have to leave.
We talked about it for months.
About how we would be...
light again,
without pain.
But when the time came,
I couldn't do it.
I left her...
sinking...
further and further...
and further.
♪ See you darkly down the hallway ♪
- Tilly?
- ♪ You're sleepwalking, you won't wait ♪
♪ And so what if you were right ♪
♪ And it's too late to make a change ♪
♪ Or you didn't even try ♪
♪ If you despair the morning ♪
♪ I will try to lift our spirits higher ♪
Oh.
Shut up.
♪ Dim the lights so
we can unwind in disguise ♪
♪ Play the record, make me
move backwards in time ♪
We are getting out of here.
♪ When I'm alone ♪
♪ I feel a slow ticking
wildness in my mind ♪
♪ It's late at night
and I am blinded ♪
♪ With the city lights in my eyes ♪
♪ I've got the fare in my pocket ♪
Grace.
Hey.
Hey, there's a dog here.
Oh, hey.
What's your name buddy?
Tilly, no.
Tilly.
Aren't you a beautiful girl, huh?
See?
I told you it was worth a look.
Just take her out to the car.
I'll give the place
a bit of a once over.
Okay.
Come on, come on.
"Diving into concrete".
Good girl.
What's that?
Signed copy
of one of her books.
Who's it addressed to?
Why?
'Cause why would she keep
a signed copy of her own book?
"My darling, Claudia.
"I love you more than anything.
"You are my world."
Who's Claudia?
That could be a lead.
So, it's a murder
investigation now?
We don't know.
Where are you headed?
I'm just going for a ride.
Tilly?
You know this dog?
Yeah.
Yeah, I've been looking
for her all morning.
Where'd you find her?
Up at Veronica Fox's place.
Any idea what
she'd be doing there?
No.
No, we're always finding
her in weird places.
I've never seen a dog
up at your place.
Well she's an inside dog.
And...
she's shy.
Tilly, hey, hey.
Well, she looks happy
to see you.
You should put an address
on that collar.
I will.
Thanks for finding her.
Alright, let's go.
Okay.
Be careful on the road.
- Stay away from the res.
- Yes.
Let's get you back
to your mama, okay?
She's gonna be beside herself.
Come on, Tilly.
Let's go.
Good girl!
I'm gonna race you.
♪ Do you really want
to turn me away? ♪
to tell me no? ♪
Claudia?
It's me.
Oh, Tilly.
Tilly.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I saw the cops.
They're not coming back.
Please, don't leave again.
I won't.
Coffee.
I never tried it.
Me neither, but...
I've always wanted to have...
black coffee in the morning.
You know, one day,
I'm gonna be...
one of those ladies that sits
on her back porch and...
reads the newspaper and...
has her coffee and just like...
sighs at everything with
total satisfaction.
I can see that.
You'd be wearing a long dress
and lots of jewels.
Mm.
Okay.
Cheers, darling.
That's disgusting.
That's so gross.
Mm, wait, wait, wait.
I know how to fix this.
Wait one sec, one sec, one sec.
So.
What are those?
We don't have any sugar
cubes or anything, but...
I've got these.
What do they taste...?
Mm, mm.
Mm!
Yum!
Yeah.
So fluffy, like...
- Clouds.
Like clouds, I know.
So good.
♪ Honey ♪
♪ Now, every day is sunny ♪
Mm.
♪ You put your hand in mine ♪
♪ And I know I'll be fine ♪
Thank you.
♪ I pray that this is gonna stick ♪
I've been thinking that...
um...
maybe, we could
redecorate your room.
Why?
You know, for a bit of color.
I don't know, it feels...
it feels weird changing...
our room so soon.
Our room?
Yeah. Mine and Mom's.
Oh.
I wouldn't know how to do it.
Do what?
Decorate.
Well...
lucky you got me.
Okay.
Let's start with the walls.
Are we going to paint them?
Better.
You know all these people?
I wish.
Here.
What, what do we do with them?
You stick them on your walls.
These are your new guardian angels.
The trick with collaging
is just not to overthink it.
Just put them up wherever
it feels right and it can be messy.
It's Tavi Gevinson.
What's she like?
Clever.
That's Joan Didion and Beyonce.
Okay.
I love it.
Now, the bed.
What are you doing?
You'll see.
Go on.
Take your covers off.
How many do we need?
I don't know,
I guess it depends how dark
we want the dye to be.
Not too dark.
Hope it turns out to be purple...
rather than blue.
Same.
Well...
whatever the color is,
it will be...
way better than white.
Mm.
It's like a cubby house.
Come in here.
Ow.
What?
- Ah!
- Hey, you okay?
Yeah, just got a prickle.
Let me see.
Mm, better?
Better?
Mm-mm.
♪ Oh, signs are lit ♪
♪ Down on front street ♪
♪ I see the women, they're thinking ♪
♪ On the clock how
they wanna pack it up ♪
♪ They wanna get in touch ♪
♪ They wanna leave ♪
♪ Oh oh, stop ♪
♪ Fever dreaming nights ♪
♪ Too hot to get sleep ♪
♪ But it wouldn't make any difference ♪
♪ Ooh oh oh oh oh oh oh ♪
♪ Heatwave ♪
♪ Oh oh ♪
♪ Again ♪
♪ Heatwave ♪
♪ Oh oh ♪
♪ Again ♪
♪ Outside, there's a blinding- ♪
Are you eating your necklace?
- Yeah. Try it.
It's good.
I've got bracelets too.
Mm, so yummy.
Mm.
Beautiful.
Oh.
Why did you do that?
All will be revealed
in about five minutes.
- Hey.
- Mm-mm.
Guess the flavour.
Apple.
Beginner's luck.
- All right.
- Mm-mm.
This one.
Mm.
I love this one.
Watermelon?
You'll never guess this one.
It's really hard.
This one is limited edition.
- Do you give up?
- No.
- No, no. I...
- Do you want a hint?
Yeah.
Good.
I've never tasted it before.
It's cola.
Cola.
Do you want another?
Okay.
Strawberry?
It reminds me of strawberry milk.
Do you think that someone's
going to come looking for you?
No one really cares to do
that sort of thing with me.
Which is fine.
Not even if you stay out late?
Probably not.
Not even if you stay overnight?
Why do you ask?
Do you like it?
I love it.
I think I really like you.
I think I really like you too.
I don't know what to do.
Me neither.
Maybe, we can start
by breathing together.
- Ready?
- Okay.
In.
And out.
♪ My little darlin'
knows my nature ♪
♪ Oh my little darlin'
knows my mind ♪
♪ She has sheltered me
from it all the time ♪
♪ If left alone to my own devices ♪
♪ I will tear at the carpet
I'll chew the blinds ♪
♪ A more feral specimen
you won't find ♪
♪ But every year
I am getting older ♪
♪ And I lose my good looks,
lose my charms ♪
♪ All I used to lure
you into my arms ♪
♪ Who could blame
you being cynical ♪
♪ You're right
the world it is a crypt ♪
♪ It's pitiless and cold ♪
Wait, it's hard to do it
at the same time.
I know.
Oh, Tilly!
Don't watch.
Come on, come on.
I'm so sorry,
that's so embarrassing.
Don't look at me
from over there.
Come back.
You are so beautiful.
♪ I never learned
to trust a love song ♪
♪ It was not because
the words were trite ♪
♪ But I felt
the love itself was trite ♪
♪ I will be your witness
if you be mine ♪
if you be my wife ♪
Grace?
Gracie?
Get in here.
What's this about a fucking dog?
Beautiful Claudia.
Now is the time to explore
who you really are.
Play, experiment,
be colorful and messy and free.
I'll be right here by your side.
♪ I would never leave you
broken hearted ♪
I purple promise.
♪ You'll never be alone,
no need to feel discarded ♪
Love G.
♪ As long as I'm alive ♪
♪ I'll finish what I started ♪
♪ What I started ♪
- Wait!
- She's 16, Grace.
What's your point?
Hey!
It's the law.
The law says that
if you're under 17,
- then you're a kid.
- Yeah, but I'm taking care of her.
Grace, please, listen to me.
You cannot be her guardian.
- Please, but I care for her so much.
- Okay, it's only a year or so.
- She'll be fine.
- This is bullshit.
Get back in the house,
right now!
No!
She's here.
I'll go get her.
Claudia.
No, no.
Let me out, let me out!
My mother said...
to hold on tight
and not let go.
No matter what.
Never let go.
Claudia!
Claudia, no!
That's a good one, my darling.
Stay with me.
Everything that's been hard...
and dark and heavy is gonna
go away, my darling girl.
Stay with me now.
Are you gonna stay with me?
Stay with me, my darling.
Claudia!
Claudia.
What do we do?
Hey.
Hey, Claudia, look at me.
All right?
Look at me.
Yeah?
We're gonna be okay.
Okay?
I promise you.
We're gonna be okay.
You have to believe me.
Okay?
Do you purple promise?
I purple promise.
Breathe with me.
Breathe in.
And out.
In.
♪ Oh, signs are lit ♪
♪ Down on front street ♪
♪ I see the women
they're thinking ♪
♪ On the clock how
they wanna pack it up ♪
♪ They wanna get in touch ♪
♪ They wanna leave ♪
♪ Oh oh oh oh, stop ♪
♪ I can't take no more,
this heat won't let me ♪
♪ Think straight for even a minute ♪
♪ Oh oh, stop ♪
♪ Fever dreaming nights ♪
♪ Too hot to get sleep ♪
♪ But it wouldn't
make any difference ♪
♪ Ooh oh oh oh oh oh oh ♪
♪ Heatwave ♪
♪ Oh oh ♪
♪ Again ♪
♪ Heatwave ♪
♪ Oh oh ♪
♪ Again ♪