movie info: XVID  576x384 23.976fps 700.6 MB
/SubEdit b.4040 (http://subedit.prv.pl)/
Produced by nds5317
Kim Byeong-seok
I picked up a blue notebook.
There were some funny-looking
figures drawn in
Some cool phrases, too.
There's nothing I can't see.
I'm blind.
There is nothing.
Then, what is there?
Yoo Jae-kyung
How long has it been since
you graduated?
About five years.
Never worked as an accountant?
No, after high school
I worked in an insurance company.
How long?
A little over a year.
Then you should know
about the job...
What's your father do?
You have a father, right?
Yes, he's just...
...works.
What kind of work?
Just... this and that.
We may not look it,
but since we deal with money,
we're picky about who we hire.
That's why I asked.
What kind of work is it?
Well, people who need money urgently...
we loan it to them.
Not like a loan shark or anything.
We just keep a cashbox.
And we collect some interest,
from people in an emergency.
Sorry. Hang on a second.
Okay.
If you're not busy,
I'll buy you dinner before you go.
Excuse me?
Let's have a dinner before you go.
Alright.
Who told you about us?
- In the newspaper...
- Yes, yes.
Well, you have a credit card, right?
Or a bank book... No, bring them both.
Bring whatever you have.
No, just an abstract
of your family register.
Yeah.
You told me to leave an hour early.
I'm just about there. Okay.
I told you to come on time!
I said I left early.
You could've taken a bus.
Do you know how heavy
this camera is?
Can't you live without a car?
Oh, it's gone.
Car Reclamation
How much was it?
Hey.
Should I sell the car?
You hate cleaning it anyway.
Not so much...
I just do it when I feel bored...
Can you live without it?
You who hates to walk.
There you go.
Turn it up...
The volume.
A little more.
- Huh?
- Yeah.
- Oh, it's you.
Did you move the key?
Oh, you bastard.
How did you know I was coming?
I usually buy two.
You eat both of them?
One at dawn, when I get hungry.
Then what'll you do at dawn?
I'll just go to sleep early.
Hey, still awake?
Byeong-seok.
Aren't you going to sleep?
Here.
What is it?
Acanthopanax juice.
It's good stuff.
You're hungry, right? Drink it.
You're selling this stuff nowadays?
Yeah...
It sells well.
Are these all your deductions?
Yes, that's all.
Are you really working there?
Work? I quit my job a while back.
What use is a job you've already quit?
Look at this guy.
- One of my acquaintances said...
- Miss Yoo
Don't you have
anything cold?
One of my acquaintances
got about 3 million won...
and he said you were very nice.
Am I your cashbox or something?
You need to satisfy
some basic conditions.
I came by recommendation.
It's really urgent.
All Korea is like that.
You need some credit.
Think about it.
Who'll give you money
with all these overdue credit card bills?
It's really an emergency.
What is it?
I have a dog at home.
A mutt? A dog?
She needs to get a
Caesarean section.
This guy is unbelievable.
You want 3 million won for a dog?
She's long past her delivery date,
so she's in danger.
Anyway, let's go and see.
I'm in your hands.
Aren't you cold?
I'm alright.
- Miss Yoo!
- Yes?
Do you always look so depressed?
No.
I like people who look depressed.
I'll be back in a bit.
Okay.
Hello?
Who's speaking?
No, there's no one here
by that name.
This is a shop, a store.
You called the wrong number.
Who was that?
I don't know.
He was looking for you.
What's up with your neck?
Why's it bandaged?
I got burned.
You need to change that dressing.
Do I have time to care about that?
I'm OK.
Miss Yoo. Can you speak English?
Well, just a little.
I tried reading the original,
and it's giving me a headache.
What does "mute" mean?
"Mute". M, U, T, E.
Want me to look it up
on the internet?
No, I thought if you spoke English,
I could introduce you to anotherjob.
Working here's
nothing special, is it?
Miss Yoo.
Don't bother coming in anymore.
If you teach me, I can do a good job.
It's no use. I can't stand
people who look depressed.
Write down your
bank account number before going.
I'll pay you for today's work.
- You've been here?
- Yeah, when did you arrive?
I've been looking for you
all this time.
Go stay in the car. I'm almost done.
Go on.
Did you eat anything?
A while ago.
Aren't you hungry?
Let's go inside and eat something.
- Where?
- In the store.
How'd you get the key?
I thought you were just
making charcoal fires.
Are you cold?
Eat up.
Is there someone out there?
Doesn't it taste good?
Why aren't you eating?
Do I look depressed?
Eat one first.
The big one.
You don't look depressed anymore.
I got fired.
What's up?
It's not the first time, you know.
First time I was fired
on the first day, though.
Better to stay away
from that kind of place.
But I had to go.
I'm filming...
No.
You're still angry?
You want to cry, don't you?
What a shame.
I don't want to cry.
Did you buy the camera for this?
Is filming this kind of thing fun?
Why do you only ever think
from your own perspective?
Songs of reeds...
Mommy and my sister...
let's Iive together.
One.....
two...
three...
four...
five...
What the hell are you filming?
When'll you give me the camera?
Don't ever film her again.
Don't ever hit me again.
You can't film Silbee.
But for me, it's okay.
Her name's Silbee?
That name matches her looks, huh?
Is that a compliment or not?
It's sure not an insult.
Now you're gonna hit me again.
Bro, I'm an artist.
I don't like violence.
What kind of art?
Painting.
- Painting...
- Jae-hun!
See you later.
I can't call you "bro," can I?
Is anyone there?
Anyone there?
Yes...
Are you Kim Byeong-seok?
Yes.
Why don't you answer
the damn phone?
I called your office
and nobody answered.
What do you mean, my office?
That makes no sense.
What makes no sense?
How can someone take out a loan
without telling me?
Look here. Samho Trading.
This is where you work.
I've never worked there.
Look at this.
You received money in
your bank account, from here.
Then do you know Kim Hyung-seok?
Who is he?
My elder brother.
Your brother?
Look, he co-signed this.
He signed and the loan was granted.
It says he works
for a credit association.
He has no job, either.
When was the last time
you contacted him?
Didn't he tell you about this?
Are you here to return something?
No, I was told
you're recruiting associates.
Associates? Were you waiting long?
This way, please.
Yes...
All these products are made
for the winter season.
We operate a big factory in China.
We get all our products there,
and some are exported to Japan.
We export to Southeast Asia,
Japan and Hong Kong.
Have you seen everything?
Yes.
How was it? Is everything alright?
About our shopping mall,
we don'tjust handle clothes...
We handle everything from clothes
to general merchandise.
We have loads of products,
so a lot of customers visit.
Our revenues are growing, and we're
recruiting people to start enterprises.
At first, we take half the earnings.
Half for us and the other half for you.
The more products you sell,
the more you get.
I hope you can join us...?
Why didn't you call me
before their eyes opened?
I tried, but when I came in,
they'd opened them already.
Cute, huh?
You still do
a lot of those wedding jobs?
A bit.
How can you have so much free time?
I'm not photographing because I'm free.
I just want to add them to my works.
Works? You really do have free time.
Don't do that, help me out instead.
Hey, I don't think
we'll sell anything here.
Quiet, I'm writing a diary.
I'm cold.
Shut up, shithead!
You need to learn about hardship.
You weren't sleeping?
I don't go to sleep this early.
You want me to get out?
Are you going home?
Why don't you come to my home?
Is no one there?
Let's go there and eat something
This isn't our garden.
You said you were hungry?
But what good is this?
What are you doing?
Wait. One's gonna fall down.
Are you an idiot?
Didn't you know that?
Just pick one.
No, it's gonna fall, I tell you.
Say, "pear, pear, pear..."
Pear, pear, pear
Why'd you beat him?
In jail now.
- Are you playing this game?
- Yes.
You are playing?
Why don't you answer the phone?
What if it's an emergency?
I don't care.
Byeong-seok.
Don't do anything bad.
Let's live honestly.
Do you have some money?
How did you find me here?
I followed you home last time.
You followed me? Why?
I thought it might be helpful someday.
Come in, anyway.
Silbee doesn't like her remarried father
or her divorced mother.
So she lives alone.
But why are you trying
to get money for Silbee?
Have you...
ever been dumped?
Surely. By a lot of people.
Not by a person. By money.
So many times for me.
But Silbee never has.
Bro, I need to ask a difficult favor.
Well, I really need some money.
A lot.
Yes, a lot.
I need about 3,800,000 won. Yes.
Well, I have a bank account number.
Yes, bro? Thanks. Yes.
I'll talk to you later.
Is there anything
you need to buy these days?
Any items you need to get?
Well, there's a website I know.
How about buying something there?
No, I'm not working there.
No, thanks.
I'll call you later.
He promised to
lend me some money.
But he isn't answering the phone.
I will try to call again.
Who do you keep calling?
Is it good?
Yeah, it's good.
Is there anything
you're not telling me?
Nothing?
Did your mother use the credit card?
- My mother?
- Yes, your mother.
No, why?
The credit card statement says
something was bought in installments.
It was for 1,300,000 won.
You didn't really join
what you told me about, did you?
Eat first.
Is that it?
I told you, eat first.
Hey, I told you not to sign up.
Why should you pay money
to sell other people's stuff?
I told you they're swindlers.
Did you sign up?
Hey!
Did you give them 1 ,300,000 won?
How are you going to make it up?
I can make money.
How? Selling rice bags to your friends?
Don't worry.
I can make up for my debt.
How come it's your debt?
It's our debt.
Our debt? Then why do you pay
my credit card bills?
Because...I bought
my camera with it.
Of course I should pay.
Is that all?
What about the food, drink, motel bills?
They're our debts, too.
I'm telling you,
I'll pay my share among them.
Mister!
- Mister!
- Yeah
Can I borrow some charcoal?
What do you need them for?
Or will you sell it?
Hey, how should I do this?
Who are you?
Nice to see you.
What the hell are you doing?
Drink some water.
Fucker, you've never seen
someone water the garden?
Where's your brother?
You keep filming people crying.
Hey, look.
Why are you doing this?
You feel sad if
one more Korean virgin is gone?
If you keep doing this,
it'll be really hard on me.
Just give me the money.
Just shut up about the money.
Look, you don't shoot anything useful.
How can you come
and ask for money?
You feel good when I pay you...
Feel like you're rich, huh?
What the...?
You only filmed
her mother crying this time.
And what's with your camera work?
Zigzagging like a music video.
I told you last time.
Just make an effort.
Let's work together in earnest.
You're bad off these days, huh?
You bought that camera
with your credit card?
And you still haven't paid it off?
Hello?
Why?
What are you talking about?
There were worms in that rice?
They said that they design those clothes.
What, aren't they answering the phone?
Okay, I'll return them.
They said it's no problem to return it.
How could you say that?
How much do you think I earn selling it?
Yeah, that'll make me rich.
I'll be rich selling that stuff to you.
I'll be rich and happy
all on my own.
Why do you get angry over it?
Oh, there you are.
Did you move the key again?
No key over there.
What?
Let's get inside...it's freezing.
Where did you spend the money
loaned on my name?
you loaned?
Hey.
I want to hit you just once.
Are we brothers?
Are we really?
Oh, fuck.
Hey, hit me.
Hit me now. dammit!
Hit me now.
Please hit me one time.
Please. Oh, shit!
Hey.
You know me, right? Who am I?
My brother.
How do you remember me?
I saw you once at home.
You're already grown up.
Where are you coming from?
From a study institute.
Is father home?
Is he treating you well?
Stop nodding, say something.
Yes he does.
He should. He is a good man.
Go, he should be
waiting for you at home.
Yohan!
Don't use formal speech next time.
Brothers don't need to.
I told you, say it.
OK.
Go on.
Hello?
I'm Yoo Jae-kyoung,
who used to work there briefly.
Do you remember me?
I'm right outside the office.
Where are you?
Oh, come in.
Have a candy.
Why didn't you tell me
you were here?
What are you doing nowadays?
Still doing nothing?
I told you to study English.
You still look depressed.
Did I pay you for the one day's work?
I didn't?
You should have just told me.
No need to come here, just call.
That's why you're here.
Here, take this.
I'm sorry to pay you so late.
Take it.
Actually it wasn't this,
I just need money.
Money?
How much?
About 3 million won.
3 million?
Please lend me money
with the credit card.
You're really funny...
Go on.
Keep talking.
Hey, just take this instead.
Do you think money's
like a piece of candy?
Take it.
Can't you do this for me?
No, I can't.
I have an urgent reason...
Is there anyone who doesn't
have a reason?
Everyone who needs money
has a reason.
Don't you know
this is not a good thing?
You're still young.
- I know, but you...
- You know, the...
What's your phone number?
Tell me, your home telephone.
Do your parents know about this?
I doubt it.
Excuse me, is that a camera case?
Are you the one who called me?
No.
Uh...is this expensive?
Yes.
Here you are.
Uh...can I see that camera
just for second?
Can I see it just for a second?
Where is the switch?
Wow, it's nice.
Uh...in fact today's my last day,
so I want to make a souvenir.
Could you film me?
I don't like coffee...
Can you get me a cup of cocoa?
Cocoa?
Yes, cocoa.
Oh, hello.
- You wanted to sell a camera?
- Are you the one who called me?
I had a hard time
reaching you on the phone.
I got cocoa for you...
Even just 100,000 won...
Is that okay?
If you discountjust 100,000 won,
I can afford it.
Orjust 50,000...You can't?
It's not that bad, is it?
If you can't do that for me, then.....
Lady, you called, right?
Yes.
Let's go... Who told you about us?
Mr. Ahn.
Mr. Ahn? Let's go.
How much did you tell us?
Three million.
And which card?
BC.
BC...I'm not sure
if we can do this with BC card.
Hey, did you work on BC card?
They said they would
finish it by this morning.
- Get up there.
- OK
Hold on for a second.
A Jeweler's Shop
Go and buy it...
Go up there and ask them
to give you gold with that card.
Gold?
Yeah...Just go up there and
tell them to give you gold...
and they will work on it.
Go up there and say it.
Just say "give me gold."
With a card?
It's okay...
Do you want to do it by installments?
Yes.
How many months?
Twelve.
Okay.
Did you buy it?
Yes.
Let's go.
Gold...
Give me that gold.
We don't do that kind of
illegal thing.
We do it according
to interest rates.
It's 6.8 percent today.
I get 216,000
and give you the rest.
Let's go.
Come here.
Here's a million won. Take it.
Two million...
And 760,000. Count it.
Oh, I still have 6,000 to give you...
Here you are.
- Is that correct?
- Yes.
Secure it. It's dangerous.
Go ahead. You go first.
Goodbye.
Bye.
Hey, did you go somewhere?
Why didn't you get undressed?
What are you doing? Hey!
Do you want to drive it?
Push this for a second.
Where did you get money?
What money?
I saw your
credit card bill's already paid.
I just got some.
I sold my camera.
What's this then?
A camera.
You're kidding, right?
I still have 100,000 won to be paid.
I'm only holding it for today.
Hey, is that fun?
What are you doing?
I asked you if it's fun.
You're so bad at driving.
Did you stay home today?
What did you do at home?
Just rolling about, right?
You're driving without looking?
You don't want to say?
I'll tell you
if you turn off that camera.
Casting by Kim Byeong-seok, Yoo Jae-kyung
Written and directed by Noh Dong-seok
Ripped by CrimSon66
>> Napisy pobrane z http://napisy.org <<
>>>>>>>> nowa wizja napisów <<<<<<<<