* DON'T KNOW WHY *
* THERE'S NO SUN UP IN THE SKY *
* STORMY WEATHER *
* SINCE MY MAN
AND I AIN'T TOGETHER *
* KEEPS RAININ' ALL THE TIME *
GRAPES ARE
FINISHED.
WHEN THE CROP GO,
I NO LONGER
FEEL WELCOME.
AW, TOO MUCH SUN IS FOR NOTHING.
VINEYARD IS
LIKE A WOMAN:
ONE SEASON,
SHE'S EMPTY;
THE NEXT SEASON,
SHE'S FULL AGAIN.
FOR ME, WOMAN FULL
OF NOTHING BUT TROUBLE.
FOR ME, LIKEWISE.
MUCH SAFER
TO PLAY CARDS.
CYNICAL FELLOWS.
WONDERFUL SYSTEM.
WORK, GET DOLLARS.
DOLLARS GET FUN.
WONDERFUL SYSTEM!
GRAPE SEASON FINISHED.
NEXT STOP- ASPARAGUS.
WONDERFUL SYSTEM.
PICK UP YOUR FEET.
HERE I COME!
YOU MADE IT.
ENCYCLOPEDIA.
SECONDHAND SET.
INFORMATION
AS GOOD AS NEW.
AH, WILLIE CHUNG.
LONG TIME AWAY.
STATE OF
WASHINGTON.
APPLE CROPS.
HOW 'BOUT A LITTLE GAME OF POKER?
HOW MUCH ALL
THIS PAPER COST?
OH, ALMOST NOTHING,
$75.
ALMOST NOTHING
IS WHAT YOU GOT LEFT.
AH!
A LITTLE FOR SEED.
BOOKS BIGGER
THAN A MAN-
9 FEET TALL-
MUST PAY RENT.
READ QUICK, THROW OUT, SAVE MONEY.
PEOPLE SAY YOU NOW A CITIZEN, CHU CHU.
YEAH.
3 MONTHS AGO,
I SORT OUT THE PAPERS.
PEOPLE ALSO SAY
YOU OWN BIG LETTER FROM PRESIDENT.
PRESIDENT OF
UNITED STATES.
PLEASE TO READ IT.
WE'LL BE
HONORED.
BUT NOT
TOO LONG.
RECORD IS 8 TIMES
READING IN ONE DAY.
TODAY WE HAVE
A CHANGE.
TODAY CELESTINO READS.
READ.
A LETTER FROM PRESIDENT
CANNOT BE SPOILED.
"THE WHITE HOUSE
"WASHINGTON, D.C.
"DEAR MR. RAMIREZ,
"IT WAS A PLEASURE TO
"RECEIVE YOUR LONG
COMMUNICATION
"INFORMING ME THAT
YOU HAVE BECOME
A CIT... "
CITIZEN.
"... OF THE UNITED
STATES-"
I WAS WRONG.
CELESTINO READS
THE PRESIDENT
LIKE THE PRESIDENT
IS CELESTINO.
NOBODY READS PRESIDENT AGAIN BUT ME.
I WILL NOW DEAL
THE CARDS, EH?
OFF! UP!
IT'S FOR STUDYING,
NOT FOR SITTING.
IT SHOULD GET SOME USE
IF NO RENT PAID!
UP! UP!
IT'S CLEAR I AM NO
LONGER AMONG FRIENDS.
PLAY CARDS NOW.
LATER ON, BE MAN.
I HAVE TO FIND JOB.
I MUST PAY RENT
TO MY FAT COUSIN.
NO GOOD JOB
TILL ASPARAGUS.
POOR JOB IS
BETTER THAN NONE.
IT'S NO
GOOD TO WAIT.
IT'S NO GOOD TO
GAMBLE ALL THE TIME.
IT MAKES BUMS.
MY COUSIN WORRY ME.
HE THINK TOO MUCH.
HE'LL THINK LESS
WHEN OLDER.
BE SMARTER THEN.
I'M HERE TO
PLAY CARDS.
GAME IS SPIT
IN THE OCEAN.
YIP!
NOW, WAIT A MINUTE.
WAIT A MINUTE, BOYS.
NOW, BE FRIENDLY.
LOOK, YOU SEE?
AW, I DON'T
KNOW ABOUT YOU.
OH, BE MY FRIEND,
COME ON.
OH, COME ON,
DON'T BE MAD AT ME.
COME ON, THAT'S A BOY!
THAT'S A BOY.
COME ON, BOY,
COME ON.
GOOD!
COME IN.
I'M LOOKING
FOR MR. AMES.
THAT'S ME.
NAME IS CHU CHU RAMIREZ.
SELLING BOOKS?
GOOD-BYE,
GLAD I MET YOU.
OH, BOOKS NOT FOR SALE.
RAMIREZ FOR SALE.
I COME FROM
EMPLOYMENT AGENCY
TO DRIVE TRACTOR.
WHERE'D YOU
LEARN HOW,
IN THEM BOOKS?
NO, I DROVE TRACTOR
BEFORE I COULD READ.
SO, WHAT DO YOU WANT
THE BOOKS FOR THEN?
NOW I LEARN HOW
TO OWN A TRACTOR.
YOU'RE PRETTY AMBITIOUS FOR A MEXICANO,
AIN'T YA?
I AM CITIZEN OF
UNITED STATES,
HAVE PAPERS TO SHOW.
ALSO IMPORTANT LETTER
FROM PRESIDENT.
FINALLY, SOCIAL
SECURITY NUMBER.
TATTOOED HERE-
CANNOT LOSE-
UNLESS I LOSE HAND.
THEN, NO USE FOR NUMBER.
THE PRESIDENT'S LETTER,
WHERE DO YOU GOT
THAT TATTOOED?
HEY, YOU!
COME IN HERE
A MINUTE.
THIS GUY GOT SENT
ABOUT THE JOB.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
NAME IS CHU CU RAMIREZ.
I'M THINKING OF HIRING HIM.
NOT A FOREIGNER.
I'VE GOT TO HAVE SOME
HELP AROUND HERE.
DOING WHAT?
DRINKING BEER?
LOOK WHO TALKS.
YOU NEVER DO
ANY HEAVIER WORK
THAN PETTING
THAT CAT.
HIRE HIM
IF YOU WANT.
THE TRACTOR
DON'T KNOW
WHO'S RIDING IT.
YOU SEEN
THE PLACE.
THAT LAND LEFT
OF THE GATE
WHEN YOU CAME IN HAS
GOTTA BE CLEARED.
THAT'S A BIG JOB,
TAKE LONG TIME.
WELL, FOR THE RIGHT MAN, ABOUT A MONTH.
WELL, IF TRACTOR
HOLD UP, I WILL.
NO PARTS TO FIX.
THAT'S THE SPIRIT.
ANYTHING I HATE
IS A LOAFER!
I'LL SHOW YOU
WHERE YOU BUNK.
OH, EMPLOYMENT
AGENCY SAY
90 A MONTH WITH BOARD.
IS CORRECT?
TO THE PENNY.
BUT NO EXTRA.
OH, THE THING'S
A BEAUTY.
HEY, YOU LIKE GUNS?
NICE TO BE
ON ONE END,
BAD TO BE ON
THE OTHER.
THAT WHAT THE DUCKS
ALL TELL ME.
THAT'S HIS SPECIALTY,
KILLING THINGS.
NOT ALWAYS WITH A GUN,
OF COURSE.
WHY DON'T YOU GO
MAKE A BED?
HI!
BUY YOU A BEER.
OH, THANKS.
OH, IT'S A HOT DAY.
OH, IF YOU THINK
THIS IS HOT,
YOU OUGHT TO BE OUT
HERE IN THE SUMMER.
YOU COULD FRY
IN YOUR OWN FAT.
NOT THAT THERE'S AN OUNCE
TOO MUCH OF THAT ON YOU.
OH. I'M HERE
ONLY A MONTH.
A WEEK GONE ALREADY.
YOU'RE LUCKY.
YOU ONLY HAVE TO COUNT
THE DAYS ON THIS DUMP.
I HAVE TO COUNT
THE YEARS.
PLACE NOT SO BAD.
I HOPE TO HAVE ONE
AS GOOD SOME DAY.
AT 90 A MONTH, YOU
BETTER HOPE REAL HARD.
GOING INTO
TOWN TONIGHT?
SATURDAYS, EVERYBODY
HITS THE BREWERY-
EXCEPT THE AMES
FAMILY, OF COURSE.
MIGHT MAKE THE TRIP.
NOT MUCH MONEY
TO SPEND,
BUT IT COST
NOTHING TO LOOK.
STAY THERE!
LIE DOWN.
LIE DOWN THERE.
THAT'S IT.
THE LAST MAN
THAT WAS HERE,
THOSE DOGS ALMOST
CHEWED HIS ARM OFF.
HOW COME THEY
TAKE TO YOU?
GOOD REASON.
THEY KNOW I
TAKE TO THEM.
IF I HAD MY WAY,
I'D BLOW THEIR
HEADS OFF.
THEY'RE ALWAYS
AFTER NIKKI.
AREN'T THEY, BABY?
CAT LOOKS BIG ENOUGH TO
DEFEND ITSELF IN A FIGHT.
WOULD PUT MONEY ON CAT.
WHAT ARE YOU TRYING
TO BE, COMIC?
THAT'S WHAT AMES
WOULD LOVE-
TO SEE THOSE DOGS GET
A CHANCE AT THIS CAT!
AND I SUPPOSE
YOU WOULD, TOO.
THERE'S NOTHING YOU
GUYS LIKE BETTER
THAN TO SEE
SOMETHING GET HURT.
STILL PUT MONEY ON CAT.
AND IF NIKKI FEMALE CAT,
WILL GIVE ODDS.
SAY, CHU CHU...
I'M SORRY I MADE
THAT REMARK
ABOUT HIRING
FOREIGNERS.
WHAT I MEANT WAS,
UH...
I LIKE SOMETHING
HUMAN AROUND,
NOT A DIRTY RAGHEAD
OR A CHINK... OR-
OR A GREASER
LIKE CHU CHU RAMIREZ?
NO.
I DIDN'T MEAN YOU.
YOU'RE DIFFERENT.
NO DIFFERENCE.
EXACTLY THE SAME.
EXACTLY.
THERE'S ONE THING
YOU HAVE IN COMMON
WITH ALL MEXICANS:
YOU SURE CAN
LOOK MEAN.
ONLY YOU DON'T
SCARE ME.
I KIND OF LIKE IT.
ANOTHER ONE, PLEASE.
I SAID,
I'LL HAVE ANOTHER.
YOU'VE BEEN SAYING
THAT ALL EVENING.
I'M ONLY TRYING TO
KEEP UP WITH THE SIGN.
YOU PASSED IT
LONG AGO.
$2.10.
THAT'S A LOT OF MONEY
FOR A LITTLE VINO.
THAT'S A LOT OF VINO
FOR A LITTLE DAME.
WELL, I GUESS
I OWE YOU $2.00.
YOU'RE TRYING TO BE CUTE, AIN'T YOU?
LOOK, I CAME UP
FROM SACRAMENTO
TO GET A JOB,
AND I DIDN'T GET ONE.
HOW CUTE IS THAT?
DROWN YOUR SORROWS
ON SOMEBODY ELSE-
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT,
FOR INSTANCE.
NO, PLEASE!
NO, NO POLICE.
I PAY FOR THE WINE.
THANK YOU.
THE POLICE
AND I THANK YOU.
WHATEVER YOU'RE
PRACTICING TO BE
THERE SHOULD
BE MORE OF.
FOR BEER.
ALSO 5 CENT TIP.
AND THE WINE, AMIGO?
IN REGARDS TO THE WINE...
YOU...
YOU GOT A FINE
LITTLE CAR.
IT'S MINE
TILL TOMORROW,
THEN THE FINANCE
COMPANY MOVES IN.
ENGINE IS NOW FLOOD.
TAKE SHOE OFF STARTER.
LOOK,
YOU BOUGHT $2.00 WORTH
OF NOTHING IN THERE.
EXACTLY NOTHING.
I WANT NOTHING
FROM YOU I CAN BUY.
WHERE'S THE HAT?
I PARTICULARLY
NOTICED THAT HAT.
HAT NOW ON BARTENDER.
SAME SIZE HEAD.
JUST EXACTLY WHAT
DO YOU EXPECT
FOR THAT GREAT
SACRIFICE?
TO TALK TO YOU FOR ONE
LITTLE MINUTE MAYBE.
STILL FLOOD.
PLENTY OF TIME TO
TELL YOUR NAME YET.
NANCY.
PLEASED TO MEET YOU!
I AM CHU CHU RAMIREZ!
FINE!
NOW WE KNOW EACH
OTHER WELL ENOUGH
TO SAY GOOD-BYE.
GOOD-BYE.
BAD TIME TO SAY GOOD-BYE
WHEN YOU HAVE TROUBLE.
TROUBLE?
DON'T BE FOOLISH.
I'M FORTUNE'S
DARLING.
CAR WILL START FOR ME,
BUT YOU HAVE NO MONEY.
SO, WHERE WILL
CAR TAKE YOU?
NO PLACE YOU'RE GOING.
I'M HEADING BACK TO
GOOD OLD SACRAMENTO.
IN SACRAMENTO, I COULD
GET YOU SOME MONEY.
HOW, BY HAWKING
YOUR COAT?
FRIENDS THERE.
WE'LL GET YOU $20.
$20?
YOU MUST HAVE FRIENDS.
THE KIND OF
FRIENDS I HAVE,
I DON'T NEED
ANY ENEMIES.
YOU NOW HAVE A FRIEND
THAT IS DIFFERENT.
WHO?
ME, CHU CHU RAMIREZ.
LISTEN,
FRIEND RAMIREZ,
YOU WERE A $2.00
FRIEND IN THERE,
WHAT MAKES YOU
A $20 FRIEND OUT HERE?
STRANGE THING ABOUT YOU,
MEAN WORDS COME OUT
OF FACE NOT YET MEAN.
SOME DAY MAYBE,
BUT FACE STILL NICE.
NICE.
THAT'S EXACTLY
THE RIGHT WORD FOR ME.
NOTHING ELSE WOULD DO.
LISTEN, FRIEND RAMIREZ,
DO I LOOK CRAZY
ENOUGH TO START
DRIVING TO SACRAMENTO
WITH YOU?
NOTHING TO BE AFRAID OF.
NO?
NO.
OK, THEN.
WHAT'S THE DIFFERENCE,
WINDING UP IN THE DITCH
OR IN THE GUTTER?
GO AHEAD,
FRIEND RAMIREZ,
YOU DRIVE.
IT'LL GIVE YOU SOMETHING
TO DO WITH YOUR HANDS.
NOTHING SURPRISES ME.
GO AHEAD, PASS
ANOTHER MIRACLE.
OFF! UP!
FOR READING,
NOT FOR SITTING.
WHAT HAPPENED TO
A BIG $90 TRACTOR JOB?
YOU WORK FAST.
ONE MONTH JOB
LAST ONE WEEK.
I'M HERE TO
PLAY CARDS.
POT GET COLD!
ONE MINUTE, WILLIE CHUNG,
ONE MINUTE.
PLEASE DO
COME IN.
MISS CY,
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET
VINCENTE AGUILAR,
JOE MENDACIO...
WILLIE CHUNG...
ALSO
CELESTINO GARCIA...
AND MY COUSIN,
MANUEL RAMIREZ.
HI!
HI.
UH... MANUEL,
I COME TO ASK
BIG FAVOR.
NO PAY FOR ME TILL
END OF TRACTOR JOB,
YOU KNOW, SO I
COME TO YOU.
MY FRIEND, MISS NANCY,
SHE NEEDS $20.
EH!
DO NOT JUMP ON
CONCLUSIONS, AMIGOS.
$20, PLEASE.
$25 IS ALL I GOT
TILL ASPARAGUS.
PLEASE TO SHOW
COLLATERAL.
COLLATERAL? YOU SOUND
LIKE WILLIE CHUNG.
I WILL PUT UP
THE BIG BOOKS.
BOOKS ALREADY
FOR RENT.
BOOKS IS ONLY
COLLATERAL I HAVE.
WHAT ABOUT BIG
IMPORTANT LETTER?
WILLIE CHUNG
IS RIGHT.
YOU'LL NEVER GIVE
UP THE LETTER.
YOU ALWAYS HAVE IT.
TAKE GOOD CARE
OF LETTER, MANUEL.
WE'LL COME BACK
AFTER TRACTOR JOB.
WELL,
TOOK NEARLY
A ROUND TRIP,
BUT HERE IT IS.
HERE IS WHAT?
THE DELAYED PASS.
IT'S FOOLISH
TO MAKE A PASS
UNLESS SOMEBODY
READY TO CATCH.
HERE IS WHERE I GO
BACK TO TRACTOR JOB.
I NOW SAY
GOOD NIGHT,
AND YOU GO HOME.
RAMIREZ?
YOU'RE MAKING
THIS 20
TOO HEAVY TO
CARRY AROUND.
I'VE BEEN WORKING.
I COULD HAVE PAID
FOR THE WINE MYSELF.
I STILL GOT A COUPLE
OF BUCKS LEFT.
NOW YOU GOT 22.
YOU DON'T EVEN
HAVE A HAT.
OH, BARTENDER
PRETTY GOOD FELLOW.
NEXT WEEK, I POLISH
A FEW SPITTOONS,
GET HAT BACK AGAIN.
I JUST-I SEE YOU,
BUT I STILL DON'T
BELIEVE YOU.
THIS MONEY WASN'T
EASY TO COME BY,
WAS IT?
THAT LETTER
YOU LEFT,
YOU GAVE IT UP LIKE
IT WAS SOMETHING ALIVE.
WHAT WAS IN IT?
PERSONAL LETTER
FROM PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES
WHEN I AM MADE
CITIZEN OF THIS COUNTRY.
WELL, YOU SOUND LIKE
SOMEBODY DID YOU A BIG FAVOR.
DO YOU NOT KNOW
HOW BIG, NANCY?
YOU'VE BEEN CITIZEN
ALL YOUR LIFE.
SURE, SOMETHING
I WAS BORN WITH,
LIKE THE COLOR
OF MY EYES.
BUT IT DOESN'T
DO A THING FOR ME.
NOT A THING.
MAYBE PEOPLE SHOULD
NOT BE BORN CITIZENS.
TOO EASY.
SHOULD WORK FOR IT.
STUDY TO GET PAPERS.
THEN THEY KNOW
WHAT IT MEANS.
OH, I SUPPOSE
YOU KNOW.
I KNOW THIS...
I BELONG HERE
MUCH AS ANYBODY,
BIG AS ANYBODY.
SAME LAWS FOR
ALL OF THEM.
VOTE SAME AS
MR. ABRAHAM LINCOLN
OR MR. GEORGE WASHINGTON.
ONE MAN, ONE VOTE.
LINCOLN, WASHINGTON,
RAMIREZ.
IS THAT WHAT THE PRESIDENT
WROTE YOU IN HIS LETTER?
LIKE TO KNOW
WHAT HE SAY?
IF SO, I HAVE IT
WRITTEN HERE.
GO AHEAD,
MAKE ME CRY.
IT'S FROM WHITE HOUSE.
IT'S ADDRESSED TO ME.
"DEAR MR. RAMIREZ,
"IT WAS A PLEASURE TO RECEIVE
YOUR LONG COMMUNICATION
"INFORMING ME THAT
YOU HAVE BECOME
"A CITIZEN OF
THE UNITED STATES.
"IT IS GRATIFYING TO
NOTE YOUR UNDERSTANDING
"OF AMERICAN IDEALS
"AND TO WELCOME
YOU TO OUR RANKS.
"THE MEASURE OF YOUR NEW
COUNTRY'S GREATNESS
"LIES IN ITS GUARANTEE
OF JUSTICE
"AND EQUALITY FOR ALL,
"AND IT COUNTS ON YOU
TO DO YOUR PART
"TO FURTHER
THAT PRINCIPLE.
"IF YOU DISCHARGE
YOUR OBLIGATION,
"YOU WILL BE HELPING
IN THE STRUGGLE
"THAT IS NOW TESTING
THE PEOPLES OF THE WORLD.
RESPECTFULLY YOURS... "
AND AT THE BOTTOM
OF THE PAGE IS
THE PRESIDENT'S NAME-
IN PEN AND INK.
LOOK!
I'M NOT CRYING.
I'M LAUGHING.
RAMIREZ, TODAY
YOU DRIVE A TRACTOR.
TOMORROW YOU'LL
SWEAT YOUR EARS OFF
IN SOME STINKING
FISH CANNERY,
NEXT WEEK YOU'LL BE
BREAKING YOUR BACK
IN ASPARAGUS,
SPINACH, AND GRAPES.
AND YOU THINK YOU'RE
A CITIZEN FIRST CLASS?
CITIZEN OF WHAT?!
WHAT YOU ARE
IS A SAP,
AND ALL YOU'VE GOT IS
THE PAPERS TO PROVE IT.
A SAP? WHY?
BECAUSE I WORK?
WHAT'S WRONG WITH WORK?
NOBODY ANY GOOD
WITHOUT WORK.
WHEN I WORK TO TAKE
FOOD FROM GROUND,
I'M DOING PART
IN STRUGGLE.
STRUGGLE?
WHAT STRUGGLE?!
THE STRUGGLE OF
PEOPLE ALL OVER
TO LIVE BETTER,
BE HAPPIER,
HAVE GOOD THINGS.
MAYBE YOUR STRUGGLE,
TOO, NANCY.
THE REASON YOU
DRINK MUSCATEL.
GET OUT OF HERE!
ALL OF A SUDDEN,
I CAN'T STAND YOU.
AND REMEMBER-
IT'S WORTH EVERY
CENT OF THE 20 BUCKS
I BEAT YOU OUT OF-
YOU'RE A FOOL!
THEY WON'T ONLY
HURT YOU,
THEY'LL ROLL OVER
AND CRUSH YOU-
THEIR BIG BLACK HAT
AND ALL.
GOOD-BYE, NANCY.
YOU'RE ONE PEACH
OF A FINE GIRL.
BIG BLACK HAT AND ALL!
LOOK. LOOK!
YOU SHOULD BE ASHAMED!
SHAME!
SHOULD HANG YOUR HEAD
AND PRAY FORGIVENESS.
IT'S GREAT TEMPTATION THAT
SHOULD HAVE BEEN RESISTED.
BAD DOG! YOU STAY THERE.
STAY THERE!
I REGRET.
FINE THING WHEN ALL
YOU HAVE TO BAWL ABOUT
IS A DEAD CAT.
THOSE ROTTEN DOGS!
IF I HAD ONE
OF AMES' GUNS,
I WOULD HAVE SHOT THEM!
OH, THE DOGS ARE
NOT TO BLAME.
LONG TIME YOU
BUILD UP HATE
BETWEEN
DOGS AND CATS.
HOLD CAT
IN YOUR ARMS,
MAKE DOGS THINK IT'S
SOMETHING GOOD TO CATCH.
YOU KNOW?
BOUND TO MAKE
TROUBLE.
YOU KNOW,
MY PEOPLE SAY,
"BEST WAY TO
CURE SADNESS
IS BE HAPPY."
LIVE CAT MAKE CRYING
STOP WITH THE DEAD CAT.
MAYBE I FIND
YOU ONE, HUH?
SMALL KITTEN?
YOU TEACH HIM
NOT TO BE AFRAID
AND DOGS NOT BOTHER.
LEAVE CAT ON GROUND.
THEY BELONG
ON GROUND.
I DON'T WANT
ANOTHER CAT AGAIN
AS LONG AS I LIVE.
THANKS ALL THE SAME.
THOROUGHBRED
SACRAMENTO CAT.
THINK IT OVER, EH?
I'VE BEEN WATCHING THAT
RAMIREZ GUY FOR 3 WEEKS.
I THINK I'VE FINALLY
GOT HIM PEGGED.
FOR YOU,
THAT'S REAL FAST.
YOU KNOW,
HE'S THE KIND
THAT AIN'T NEVER
GONNA GET NO PLACE.
YOU KNOW WHY?
HE LIKES WHAT'S
ALONG THE WAY
BETTER THAN HE LIKES
WHERE HE'S GOING.
LOOK AT HIM OUT THERE.
WHAT'S HE DO-
YOU DIDN'T
TELL HIM TO
DIG UP THAT CAT,
DID YOU?!
OH, KEEP YOUR SHIRT ON.
COME TO ME THIS MORNING,
HE SAID HOW WOULD IT BE
IF HE PLANTED SOME FLOWERS
OVER THAT CAT?
FLOWERS ON A CAT'S GRAVE!
HOW'S A GUY LIKE THAT
EVER GONNA GET ANYPLACE?
HOW COME YOU GAVE HIM TIME
OFF FROM DIGGING STUMPS?
SHOWS YOU HOW DUMB HE IS.
HE SAID HE
COULD DO IT
IF HE DID IT ON
HIS LUNCH HOUR.
A BORN DIGGER OF STUMPS.
WHEN'S HE GONNA BE
THROUGH WITH THIS JOB?
MR. RAMIREZ WILL
BE LEAVING US
IN A COUPLE-3 DAYS,
THAT IS, IF YOU CAN
STAY AWAY FROM HIM
WITH MY BEER!
DON'T WORRY.
HE CAN'T GET OUT
OF HERE SOON ENOUGH
TO SUIT ME.
OH, I KIND OF HATE
TO LOSE HIM, THOUGH.
HE'S DONE A PRETTY GOOD
JOB FOR A MEXICAN.
THAT IS, AS FAR AS
I'M CONCERNED.
HE'S DONE A PRETTY GOOD JOB.
ARE YOU JUST
MAKING NOISE,
OR YOU TALKING
FOR MY BENEFIT?
I'M TALKING WHAT'S
IN YOUR HEAD.
I AIN'T BLIND.
WISH I KNEW WHAT
WAS KEEPING ME HERE.
MAYBE THE SAME REASON
I DON'T THROW YOU OUT...
WHATEVER THAT IS.
HI.
I BROUGHT YOU
A BETTER LAMP
IF YOU'RE GONNA READ
YOUR EYES OUT ALL NIGHT.
THAT'S A NICE LAMP.
THANK YOU.
WHAT'S SO WONDERFUL
IN THIS?
EVERYTHING
EVERYBODY KNOWS-
IN THERE.
DID YOU COME
ACROSS A PART
THAT EXPLAINS A GUY
LIKE AMES, FOR INSTANCE?
LOTS OF VOLUMES
TO READ YET.
OR A GUY LIKE YOU?
LET ME KNOW IF YOU COME
TO A PART ABOUT YOU.
OH, THAT'S THE ONE THING
THE BOOKS LEAVE OUT.
PEOPLE ARE ALWAYS WRITING
BOOKS ABOUT PEOPLE.
IT'S A WASTE OF TIME.
NOBODY KNOWS ANYTHING
ABOUT ANYBODY.
THEY DON'T EVEN KNOW
ABOUT THEMSELVES.
IT'S BIG TROUBLE
WITH MOST PEOPLE.
THEY STUDY
THEMSELVES LIKE
IT WAS THE ONLY
SUBJECT.
WHAT OTHER SUBJECT
IS THERE?
IT'S A BIG WORLD.
THE WORLD NEVER
INTERESTED ME MUCH.
JUST THE LITTLE HUNK
I'M STANDING ON.
YOU'RE STANDING
ON IT WITH ME.
IT USED TO BE AMES.
WHY HE NOT
STAND THERE NOW?
HE SAYS
I PUSHED HIM OFF.
I THINK HE JUMPED.
NO... NO, PLEASE.
PLEASE.
PLEASE LET ME...
YOU'RE A VERY PRETTY
WOMAN, MRS. AMES.
TOO PRETTY TO HIDE
IN THE DARK.
SO WHEN YOU BLOW OUT LIGHT,
IT WAS TO HIDE ME, NO?
I NOT LIKE TO HIDE,
WITH ANYONE
OR FROM ANYONE.
OH, GO BACK TO
YOUR BOOKS.
DON'T TRY TO FIND OUT
WHAT I'M THINKING.
IT'S CLEAR WHAT
YOU'RE THINKING.
I AM SORRY, BUT WE
CAN'T HONOR THAT CHECK.
IS NOT THE NATIONAL
BANK OF SACRAMENTO?
IT IS.
CAPITAL ASSETS
$4 MILLION?
THAT'S RIGHT, BUT
VERY LITTLE OF IT
BELONGS TO MR. AMES,
AT LEAST NOT ENOUGH
TO COVER YOUR CHECK.
YOU BERER SEE
MR. AMES.
YEAH.
HA HA.
HEY, FELLA, HI.
HOW ARE YOU...?
DON'T LET THOSE DOGS
FOOL YOU.
YOU'RE NOT
WELCOME HERE.
NO GOOD,
THIS CHECK OF MR. AMES.
HEY, AMES.
WHAT?
COME ON IN HERE.
THE SUMP DIGGER IS BACK.
MAN IN BANK SAYS
THIS CHECK WILL STRETCH
FROM HERE TO SACRAMENTO.
WELL, HE'S CRAZY.
THERE MUST BE
SOME MISTAKE.
I SENT HIM
THE DEPOSIT
A COUPLE OF DAYS
AGO.
YOU KNOW, MAYBE IT
DIDN'T GET THERE.
MAYBE.
I NOT LIKE CHECK
WITH TWO-WAY STRETCH.
COME ON...
BETTER THINK UP SOMETHING
FOR WHEN
HE COMES BACK.
DON'T WORRY.
I'LL KEEP THAT GUY
RUNNING BACK AND FORTH
TILL HE FORGETS WHAT
HE'S RUNNING FOR.
IT MAY TAKE HIM 3 OR
4 TRIPS, OF COURSE,
SO YOU CAN KEEP
YOURSELF DOLLED UP.
I DON'T KNOW
WHO I DESPISE MOST:
A BORN SUMP DIGGER
OR A BORN CHISELER.
YOU KNOW WHAT MAKES
A CHISELER?
HAVING TO CHISEL.
SURE, AND HAVING
A TALENT FOR IT.
BIG PROBLEM NOW IS, WHO'S
GOING TO KILL THE BIRD?
PROBLEM IS NOT MINE.
I PROVIDE THE BIRD.
MY GIRL WILL
COOK HIM.
BUT HE MUST BE DEAD,
HOWEVER, AND WITHOUT FEATHERS.
WELL, HOW ABOUT
WILLIE CHUNG?
HE'S A MAN
WITHOUT PITY.
WE WILL CUT [INDISTINCT]
ON A [INDISTINCT] BIRD.
WITH YOUR CARDS,
IS NO CONTEST.
GET DOWN, MUCHACHOS.
OH. ONE SON OF A GUN
OF A BIRD.
HE PLAY POKER?
NOBODY PLAY POKER.
WILLIE CHUNG
WIN ALL THE MONEY.
FORTUNATELY, CELESTINO
PRODUCED THE BIRD.
WE COULD EAT
IF SOMEBODY HAD
THE SIMPLE COURAGE
OF KILLING.
WELL, WE BETTER COOK
CELESTINO. HE'S YOUNGER.
THIS FELLOW OLD ENOUGH
TO RETIRE.
NO NEED TO FEAR.
FOOD IS ON ME.
I HAVE MONEY.
IT'S NOT MONEY
YET. IT'S ONLY A CHECK.
IT WILL BE WHEN YOU
CASH IT, WILLIE CHUNG.
NAME A MAKER,
PLEASE.
A BIG FARMER BY THE
NAME OF AMES, FOR WAGES.
PRODUCE
ENDORSEMENT.
HE'S STRONG.
$90 CASH.
PRESIDENT'S LETTER,
$20.
LOSE IN POKER GAME
TO WILLIE CHUNG.
A MAN WHO WILL BET
PRESIDENT'S LETTER
WILL BET
HIS OWN MOTHER.
PRODUCE LETTER.
$20, PLEASE.
$8.00, CHU CHU.
FOR WHAT? FOR LOSE
LETTER TO WILLIE CHUNG?
NO! FOR ROOM RENT,
FOR THE BOOKS!
IT'S TOO MUCH.
IT'S WHAT MAKES
INFLATION.
STOMACH IS
NOT INFLATED.
WILL BE SOON.
I NOW GO OUT
AND BUY EVERYTHING.
CIGARS, WINE, FOOD,
EVERYTHING.
WE HAVE BIG PARTY
TO HONOR
PRESIDENT OF THE UNITED
STATES, ALL RIGHT?
I, UM,
I SEE FINANCE COMPANY
DID NOT CAPTURE CAR.
I SEE BARTENDER
DID NOT KEEP HAT.
NANCY, THIS VERY BAD
FOR YOU.
PLEASE TAKE
ADVICE, HUH?
YOU'RE
THE LITTLE BROTHER
TO ALL THE WORLD,
AREN'T YOU?
IF I AM YOUR BROTHER,
I DON'T FEEL LIKE IT.
I FEEL LIKE
SOMETHING DIFFERENT.
LOOK, MR. SAP.
WILL YOU STAY AWAY
FROM ME?
I'M POISON TO SAP.
BUT IF I WAS
YOUR BROTHER,
I WOULD NOT
USE ADVICE.
I WOULD USE THIS.
NOT TOO HARD.
MEAN WORDS
DON'T FOOL ME.
YOU'RE JUST A CRAZY
KID, NANCY.
HMM.
I CAN'T STAND
THIS CAR,
ADVICE,
AND I CAN'T STAND
YOU.
OH... I CAN'T STAND MYSELF.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO LOOK AT ME LIKE THAT,
FRIEND RAMIREZ.
IT SAYS IN
THE BIBLE,
"PLAIN IS PLAIN."
A LITTLE WINE FOR THE STOMACH TO SETTLE.
DO YOU GO BY
THE BIBLE?
WHEN IT'S ON MY SIDE, I SWEAR BY IT.
SELL YOU
A LITTLE WINE.
A LITTLE AT A TIME.
CAN I HELP IT IF A LOT
OF LITTLE MAKES A LOT?
TO YOU, LIEUTENANT
WEBSON, WHEREVER YOU ARE.
GLASS IS EMPTY.
THAT'S A PERFECT WAY
TO DRINK TO A GHOST.
OH, EXCUSE ME.
LIEUTENANT WEBSON,
CHU CHU RAMIREZ.
PLEASED TO MEET YU,
LEUTENAN@
I EXPECT TO HEAR
A LOT ABOUT YOU.
LIEUTENANT, WOULD YOU
MIND IF I TOLD CHU CHU
THE STORY OF
OUR LIVES?
THANK YOU.
I KNEW YOU WOULDN'T.
YOU KNOW WHAT'S FUNNY,
YOU BEING A CROP PICKER.
YOU PROBABLY WORKED
A LOT FOR MY FATHER.
HE OWNED
HALF THE GRAPES
IN THE SAN JOAQUIN
VALLEY.
WHAT NAME DID HE
GO BY?
LIEUTENANT,
WHAT WAS THE NAME
HE CHANGED IT TO...
MRS. WEBSON?
I'LL SAY CONGRATULATIONS,
LIEUTENANT.
I- I HAD EVERYTHING.
CLOTHES, CARS,
SCHOOLS.
EVERYTHING I WANTED,
MY FATHER GOT FOR ME.
ALL EXCEPT THE GUYS.
I GOT THEM MYSELF.
AND I REALLY
HATE IT WHEN...
EVERYTHING'S EXACTLY
2 WEEKS.
BUT I FIGURE
I SHOULDN'T CARE,
'CAUSE MOST PEOPLE
NEVER HAVE NOTHING.
YOU'RE THE ONE WHO SHOULD KISS AND TELL.
ALL YOU GOT WAS A FINE MILITARY FUNERAL.
HE WAS
A FIGHTER PILOT.
AND THEN-HE DID
SOME KIND OF TEST
IN THE
MOJAVE DESERT.
SOMETHING
WENT WRONG.
SOME LITTLE THING
THAT'S WHAT
THEY SAID TO ME.
SOME LITTLE THING
WENT WRONG.
THEN 3 YEARS AGO,
EVERYTHING GOT DARK FOR ME.
CHU CHU.
ALL THE SUNLIGHT
DISAPPEARED.
ALL EXCEPT THIS
BOTTLE OF SUNLIGHT.
THE LIEUTENANT
WANTS TO KNOW
WHAT YOU THINK OF
MY STORY.
IT SADDENED ME.
DO YOU BELIEVE IT?
EVERY OTHER WORD
OF IT, NANCY.
I THINK THAT ONE
DOES IT.
I TAKE YOU HOME
NOW, NANCY, HMM?
TpEREYOLI?
FRANKIE.
CHECK?
YEAH.
WHERE THIS GIRL LIVE?
OH, GO AHEAD. I GOT NO SECRETS,
EXCEPT
IN MYSELF.
UH-HUH.
STOP AND SLEEP MOTEL.
A CHOICE DUMP.
OUT ON THE ROAD
TO STOCKTON.
ONLY I DIDN'T KNOW
THEY USED KEYS.
WHAT I HEAR IS THE
DOORS ARE ALWAYS OPEN,
AND EVERYBODY'S NAME IS
JOHNSON ON THE REGISTER.
IT'S A HOME AWAY
FROM HOME, BOY,
ONLY BETTER.
YOU WILL SAY TO MRS. WEBSON YOU REGRET.
FRANKIE REGRETS.
WHAT'S ONE MORE REGRET?
WE'LL LEAVE NOW,
NANCY, HMM?
GOOD NIGHT,
LIEUTENANT.
I SHOULD'VE KNOWN
THE MINUTE I SAW IT.
THAT'S A HAT
YOU CAN TRUST.
SAME THING I KNOW
WHEN I SEE YOU.
DON'T YOU EVER
BELIEVEIT.
DON'T WASTE YOUR TIME
ON A WINO.
RACK ME UP,
AS THE GAMBLERS SAY.
CHU CHU...
LAST NIGHT
YOU SAID YOU BELIEVED
EVERY OTHER WORD I-
I TOLD YOU.
THAT WAS WAY TOO MUCH.
ABOUT EVERY TENTH WORD
WOULD'VE BEEN MORE LIKE IT.
MY FATHER WAS
A DRUNKEN BUM
WITH 10 ACRES
AND A STATEWIDE THIRST.
BY THE TIME I WAS 12,
ALL HE HAD LEFT
WAS THE THIRST.
THAT'S WHAT HE LEFT ME
IN HIS WILL- A THIRST.
THERE'S NO NEED
TO TELL THIS.
THERE WERE NO CARS,
THERE WERE NO SCHOOLS,
THERE WAS NOTHING.
PLENTY OF WORK.
I WANTED TO GET AWAY
FROM IT.
THAT'S WHAT I DID
WHEN I MET HERB WEBSON.
HE WASN'T A BAD GUY.
HE WASN'T A GOOD GUY.
HE WAS JUST A GUY.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT WOULD'VE
HAPPENED IF HE HAD LIVED.
BUT HE DIDN'T.
I GUESS I GOT WHAT I
WANTED WHEN I MARRIED HIM.
$10,000.
INSURANCE.
IT SHOULD'VE GONE TO HIS MOTHER
AND FATHER, BUT IT DIDN'T.
IT WENT TO ME.
I KNEW THEY NEEDED IT.
WHILE I WAS MAKING UP MY MIND
TO BE GENEROUS, I SPENT IT.
I FINALLY GOT AROUND
TO SEE THEM.
I HAD $1,000 LEFT.
YOU CAN BELIEVE THAT,
CHU CHU.
EVERY LAST WORD OF IT.
I REMEMBER.
AND NOW WE FORGET.
EVERY LAST WORD OF IT.
YOU DON'T BELONG
IN THIS CENTURY.
EXCUSE THE EXPRESSION,
BUT WHY DON'T YOU GO
BACK WHERE YOU CAME FROM?
MEXICO?
NOTHING THERE FOR ME
ANYMORE.
FATHER DIE.
MOTHER DIE.
ONLY SAD MEMORIES.
NO, THIS IS
MY COUNTRY NOW.
AMERICA THE BEAUTIFUL.
WANT TO SHOW ME IT
SOMETIME.
I NEVER BEEN THERE.
WE COULD SEE IT
TOGETHER, NANCY.
IF YOU WILL BE MY GIRL.
CHU CHU.
THE HAT, CHU CHU.
DON'T STEP ON THAT HAT. OH.
AHH.
YOU'RE
A REASONABLE FELLOW.
DON'T ASK MUCH.
ONLY NOT TO HAVE
AX ON NECK.
HAVE A LITTLE
PAIN SOMEWHERE.
COUPLE OF HANDS,
MAYBE, HUH?
HA HA HA.
HA! UP!
IT'S FOR READ,
NOT TO SIT.
FINE CELEBRATION.
FINE
A TRAITOR.
IS SOGGY.
EAT, DRINK,
BE HAPPY.
DRINK TO
PRESIDENT?
CHU CHU HASN'T
BEEN WITH PRESIDENT,
UNLESS NOW PRESIDENT
USES PERFUME.
ALSO LIPSTICK.
DRINK.
ASK NO QUESTIONS.
LIPSTICK OR PERFUME.
DRINK TO
PRESIDENT RAMIREZ.
WHY, YA THIEF!
CAREFUL OF NAMES,
WILLIE CHUNG.
THIS CHECK IS
NO GOOD.
THE BANK.
IT BOUNCE.
IT'S IMPOSSIBLE.
DEPOSIT MADE.
I COME FROM BANK.
AMES DOESN'T HAVE ENOUGH
TO COVER DATE ON CHECK.
AMES LIE.
YOU LIE.
HERE IS ALL THE...
I DO NOT CHEAT YOU,
WILLIE CHUNG.
AMES CHEAT YOU,
YOU CHEAT WILLIE,
EVERYBODY CHEAT EVERYBODY.
LIKE YOU SAY,
IS WONDERFUL SYSTEM.
ONLY $50 LEFT ON 90,
AND STILL OWE ME 40.
LETTER FROM
PRESIDENT.
LETTER FROM PRESIDENT
LIKE STOCK.
BUY FOR 20, SELL FOR 40.
WONDERFUL SYSTEM.
REMEMBER THIS.
LETTER IS NEVER SOLD.
IS ONLY SECURITY.
TEMPORARY.
WONDERFUL SYSTEM.
VERY GOOD BOY, HUH?
CHECK STILL BOUNCING,
MR. AMES.
TWICE I GO TO BANK.
ONCE MY FRIEND
WILLIE CHUNG GO.
ALL TIMES,
CHECK NO GOOD.
OH, NOW THAT OUGHT
TO PROVE SOMETHING,
EVEN TO YOU.
PROVE NOTHING,
EXCEPT CHECK STILL
EXCELLENT
GRADE 6 PLY RUBBER.
I GOT NO MONEY, BOY.
UNDERSTAND?
UNDERSTAND ONLY
I WORK HARD.
30 DAYS. IS RIGHT I
GET PAID. IS THE LAW.
THERE'S ALSO A LAW ABOUT
TRESPASSING ON
ANOTHER MAN'S PROPERTY.
TWO LAWS TO BE
OBEYED, THEN.
YOU PAY, I GO.
NOT UNTIL.
I DO NOT WISH
ANY TROUBLE, MR. AMES,
BUT IF YOU INSIST,
I WILL OBL-
YOU'RE GETTING OFF
THIS PLACE.
ONE BIG PIECE
OR A LOT OF LITTLE ONES.
TAKE YOUR PICK.
WHAT A MAN EARNS,
YOU CANNOT TAKE AWAY
WITH A GUN.
EXCEPT FOR
A LITTLE WHILE, MAYBE.
YOU'LL HEAR FROM
ME AGAIN, AND SOON.
WELL.
NO MEX IS
PUSHING ME AROUND.
OH, FOOL, THAT SHOTGUN
MAKES YOU REAL HARD TO PUSH.
YOU DON'T NEED
NO GUN WITH HIM.
THEN WHY ARE YOU STILL
POINTING IT AT HIM?
YOU KNOW, MAYBE I'M POINTING
IT IN THE WRONG DIRECTION.
COULD BE.
WHY DON'T YOU TRY
STICKING IT IN YOUR MOUTH?
YOU MISERABLE...
IT'S BEEN ESTABLISHED THAT
THE DEFENDANT, ANSEL AMES,
OWES THE COMPLAINANT
CHU CHU RAMIREZ
THE SUM OF $90.
DEFENDANT HAS
GIVEN PROOF
THAT THE RANCH AT WHICH
THE LABOR WAS PERFORMED
BELONGS TO HIS
BROTHER-IN-LAW.
THE DEFENDANT HIMSELF
IS WITHOUT FUNDS,
BUT IS WILLING TO GUARANTEE
FULL DISCHARGE OF THE DEBT
WITHIN 60 DAYS.
THAT'S RIGHT.
I DON'T WANT TO CHEAT
NO MAN, BELIEVE ME.
WILL 60 DAYS BE
SATISFACTORY, MR. RAMIREZ?
OH, IT'S FINE.
I NOT WORRY.
I GOT MONEY.
I KNOW THIS.
IS LAW OF THE LAND.
MR. AMES NO CROOK.
JUST LOOK LIKE CROOK.
YOU DAMES SURE
PUT ON A BIG ACT
WITH THAT COLD TEA.
OH, LISTEN, SIR. I COULDN'T
STAND YOU ON COLD TEA.
THAT'S THE REAL THING.
WELL, HELLO.
GOOD-BYE.
I SAID GOOD-BYE.
BUY ME A DRINK.
ALL RIGHT,
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT DO YOU HEAR
FROM THE PRESIDENT?
HE TOO BUSY TO WRITE. BIG CRISIS.
SERIOUS WINE SHORTAGE.
IF THEY NEED ANY WINE,
THEY CAN RING ME UP.
WE ARE INVITED
TO PARTY TONIGHT, NANCY.
PARTY?
SURE. WHY NOT?
CELESTINO GOT MARRIED.
WEDDING SUPPER AT GIRL'S HOUSE.
CHU CHU, I DON'T
BELONG AT A WEDDING.
IT'S ONE MORE MISTAKE
YOU MAKE.
SHE'S A PRETTY KID,
CELESTINO'S GIRL.
SHE LOOKS LIKE
SHE JUST STEPPED DOWN
OUT OF A STAINED
GLASS WINDOW.
MM-HMM.
CELESTINO IS
VERY HAPPY MAN.
BUT IT'S HARD FOR
A STRANGER TO TELL.
ALWAYS LOOKS LIKE
HIS STOMACH UPSET.
HOW I LOOK, HMM?
YOU LOOK LIKE THE
BRIDEGROOM OUGHT TO LOOK.
VERY GOOD REASON
FOR THAT.
I'D LIKE TO BE
BRIDEGROOM,
BUT WITH YOU IN WHITE DRESS AND VEIL.
CHU CHU, WHEN A GIRL
MARRIES FOR THE SECOND TIME,
SHE DOESN'T WEAR
A VEIL.
IT'S TRUE.
BUT YOU'VE NEVER BEEN
MARRIED THE FIRST TIME.
YOU DON'T BELIEVE
LIEUTENANT WEBSON IS REAL?
OH, WEBSON REAL,
ALL RIGHT.
MARRIAGE? UH-UH.
I WONDER WHAT IT WOULD
BE LIKE WITH YOU, CHU CHU.
NOT EASY TO SAY
FOR YOU,
BUT FOR ME?
WOULD HAVE TO WRITE
HAPPINESS TO PRESIDENT AGAIN.
LISTEN, I TOLD YOU I
DIDN'T BELONG AT A WEDDING.
IN CASE YOU WERE WONDERING,
THIS IS WHERE I BELONG.
THE RIGHT
KIND OF PEOPLE,
KIND OF MUSIC.
ONE THING I WOULD
KNOW, NANCY.
MY PEOPLE NOT
GOOD ENOUGH FOR YOU?
LET'S SAY I'M NOT GOOD ENOUGH FOR THEM.
IT'S PLAIN YOU NOT
LOVE ME AS I LOVE YOU.
LOVE. I NEVER USE
THE WORD.
YOU'VE SPENT A LIFE
HIDING BACK OF
WISECRACKS,
BUT I WANT NO
WISECRACKS ABOUT YOU
AND NOT EVEN
FROM YOU.
OK. HERE IT IS WITHOUT WIT OR HUMOR.
I'M GETTING OUT OF
SACRAMENTO IN THE MORNING.
I'M HEADING FOR
LOS ANGELES.
THE GAY LONDON DANCE
HALL. THIRD AND MAIN.
I NOT WANT YOU TO GO.
I WANT YOU TO STAY HERE,
BELONG WHERE I CAN
TAKE CARE OF YOU.
IF YOU DON'T HAVE
ENOUGH SENSE
TO PUT SOME MILEAGE
BETWEEN US,
I'M GOING TO DO IT
FOR YOU.
WHY?
YOU AFRAID
YOU'LL WIND UP
IN THAT WHITE DRESS
AND VEIL?
YOU AND ME
AND AMERICA.
THAT'D BE A THREESOME FOR A HONEYMOON.
YOU AFRAID, ALL RIGHT.
YOU GO TO
LOS ANGELES.
YOU GET
CHANGE OF CLIMATE.
DIFFERENT BARS
WHERE AIR IS BETTER.
TAKE LOTS OF
DEEP BREATHING
AND GET SUNTAN FROM
NEON LIGHTS.
MEET DISTINGUISHED BUMS IN
HIGH-CLASS, 20-CENT DUMPS,
BUT YOU'LL NOT
GET RID OF ME.
LATER, I COME DOWN
AND PICK YOU
OUT OF SAWDUST,
WASH YOUR FACE,
TAKE YOU HOME,
AND MARRY YOU.
GOT BIG THINGS
TO DO HERE FIRST.
FINISH THE ASPARAGUS
AND GET WAGES.
GET WAGES
AND FINISH WITH AMES.
GOING TO TAKE WAGES
AND FINISH WITH YOU.
AMES WILL ALWAYS
CHEAT YOU,
JUST LIKE I WOULD.
I NOT WORRY
ABOUT AMES.
PEOPLE MAKE THE LAW
AND PEOPLE MUST OBEY
THE LAW.
I NOT SCARED.
EVERYBODY'S SCARED.
EVERYBODY
EXCEPT YOU.
GO AHEAD, CHU CHU.
YOU FIGHT AMES.
FIGHT HIM ALWAYS, WHEREVER YOU FIND HIM.
FIGHT HIM FOR ME
AND EVERYBODY ELSE
WHO'S TOO SCARED OR
WEAK TO FIGHT HIM...
EVEN IF I'M NOT
AROUND TO SEE IT.
AND I WON'T BE.
ALL RIGHT, NANCY.
YOU GO TO L.A.
YOU THINK. YOU GET CURED
OF BEING LITTLE FOOL.
THEN YOU UNLOCK DOOR FOR ME
AND IT STAY THAT WAY.
SHUT UP!
TIME IS UP.
LABOR BOARD RULE.
YOU PAY TODAY.
I WAS BROKE
2 MONTHS AGO
AND I'M
STILL BROKE.
MAN HAVE NO MONEY,
HE DO WORK HIMSELF.
HE NOT HIRE MAN
TO DO WORK
AND THEN
CHEAT OF WAGES.
AMES DON'T WORK.
HE'S A GENTLEMAN FARMER.
I NOT WANT
SOMETHING FOR NOTHING,
BUT I NOT WANT
NOTHING FOR SOMETHING.
WHEN I WORK,
I GET PAID.
I HAVE RIGHTS.
YOU GOT NO RIGHTS AROUND HERE
UNLESS I GIVE
THEM TO YOU.
NOW, GET OUT.
IT'S BAD THING
TO DO TO A MAN.
MAKE HIM FEEL ASHAMED.
MAKE HIM FEEL SMALL.
I'M NOT MAKING YOU
FEEL SMALL, RAMIREZ.
YOU WERE SMALL
TO START WITH.
TIME COMES WHEN
A MAN MUST MAKE A STAND.
SELF-RESPECT TELLS
FEET TO STOP WALKING.
COMMON SENSE BETTER TELL
THEM TO START AGAIN.
THEY START. THIS TIME,
THEY GO THE RIGHT WAY.
THE RIGHT WAY TO GET
YOURSELF BLOWN APART!
BETTER TO GET BLOWN APART
THAN TO FALL APART.
IN CASE YOU THINK
YOU'VE GROWN ANY,
IT AIN'T LOADED.
VALUABLE GUN.
SHOOT WHEN NOT LOADED.
MY ADVICE IS,
SELL GUN AND PAY RAMIREZ.
PAY RAMIREZ TOMORROW,
OR GO TO JAIL FOR BUM CHECK.
UNH!
HOW BIG ARE YOU NOW,
AMES?
IF YOU'RE GOING TO
SHOOT HIM IN THE BACK,
HE'S GOT A WITNESS. ME!
A LOVING WIFE DON'T
TESTIFY AGAINST HER HUSBAND.
NOT THIS HUSBAND!
NOT IF SHE WANTS
TO STAY ALIVE.
QUESTION IS, SHOULD SHE
BE ALLOWED TO STAY ALIVE?
SHE CHEATS AROUND
WITH A MEXICAN,
THEN THE MEXICAN SAYS
I'M CHEATING HIM!
THE WAY I FIGURE IT,
HE OWES ME SOMETHING!
YOU'RE WRONG,
BUT I WISH YOU WERE RIGHT.
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO YOU,
AMES?
WHAT'S HAPPENED
TO THE GUY I MARRIED?
YOU HAPPENED TO ME!
IF I HAPPENED TO YOU,
AMES,
THEN YOU SURE
HAPPENED TO ME.
CHU CHU IS WORTH
10 OF YOU,
AND HE JUST PROVED IT.
I AIN'T GONNA KILL YOU.
NOT QUITE.
BUT YOU'RE GOING TO LOOK
A LITTLE DEAD FOR A WHILE.
I OUGHT TO LET YOU
BLEED TO DEATH.
MAYBE I SHOULD PAY
RAMIREZ OFF IN BLOOD.
YOU HAVEN'T GOT $90 WORTH.
I'LL PAY HIM OFF THOUGH.
HE DID THIS.
YOU'RE GONNA SAY HE DID IT.
I'M NOT GOING TO JAIL FOR ANY BUM CHECK.
HE'S GOING.
I THINK I WILL LET YOU
BLEED TO DEATH.
OH NO YOU WON'T.
YOU KNOW WHY?
BECAUSE I BLEED SLOW.
AND I'D LAST LONG ENOUGH TO SAY TO THEM
THAT BEFORE RAMIREZ SHOT ME
YOU PUT HIM UP.
NOW CALL THE SHERIFF!
THEN GET A DOCTOR.
HOME KIND OF EARLY,
AIN'T YOU?
IF YOU CALL THIS A HOME.
WHAT'S THE MATTER?
LOSE YOUR JOB?
I CAN GO BACK.
IF I CRAWL ON MY HANDS
AND KNEES AND HOLD MY NOSE.
THAT'S QUITE A TRICK IF YOU CAN DO IT.
NANCY, WHERE DO
YOUR FOLKS LIVE?
THAT'S THE CATCH.
THEY DON'T.
WELL, FRIENDS, THEN. YOU
MUST HAVE SOME FRIENDS AROUND.
JUST EL COVINO,
MY ONLY NEXT OF KIN.
KINDLY NOTIFY
IN CASE OF ACCIDENT.
SO I GET THIS PHONE CALL AT
THE BAR FROM THIS LANDLADY.
SHE GETS MY NUMBER OFF A
CARD IN NANCY'S POCKETBOOK.
SHE SAYS THE KID'S
PRETTY SICK,
DO I KNOW ANYBODY CARES
ENOUGH TO COME ON DOWN.
WELL, YOU'RE THE ONLY GUY I EVER
SEEN NANCY WITH MORE THAN ONCE,
SO I FIGURE YOU CARE.
YOU'RE RIGHT, FRANKIE.
THANKS.
WHAT ABOUT ARREST
FOR AMES, CHUCHU?
AMES WAITS. EVERYTHING WAITS FOR NANCY.
GOING FAR?
MIGHT MAKE IT SHORT. THE D.A.'S
WAITING TO SEE RAMIREZ.
FIGURE YOU GOT PLENTY TIME TO READ.
BRING BOOK D
- DEMOCRACY TO...
REMINDS ME. THAT BOOK'S BIG
ENOUGH TO HOLD A PNEUMATIC DRILL.
THE PAPERS SAY YOU
HELD FOR TRIAL, CHUCHU.
ALL OVER FRONT PAGE.
ASSAULT WITH DEADLY WEAPON.
I NO WORRY ABOUT TRIAL.
IT BE FAIR. TRUTH COME OUT.
NOW, WHEN YOU SEE NANCY.
HOW SHE LOOK AND WHAT SHE SAY?
SHE NOT LOOK GOOD.
SHE SAY NOTHING.
WE'LL TRY TO RAISE BAIL.
BUT JUDGE MAKE IT VERY HIGH.
WE TAKE TIME.
MAYBE NOT ABLE TO RAISE IT AT ALL.
WHAT YOU MEAN
SHE SAY NOTHING?
SHE PRETTY SICK.
SHE TURN ON GAS.
NOT KILL HERSELF. ONLY TRY.
THEY BUST DOWN DOOR TOO SOON.
MAYBE GAS WAS ACCIDENT.
ONLY ACCIDENT WAS SOMEBODY
STOPPING HER.
SHE LEFT NOTE MENTION YOU.
IT SAY...
"TO LANDLADY,
MY APOLOGIES. "
"TO FRIEND RAMIREZ, MY LOVE. "
"TO REST OF WORLD,
GET LOST."
PRETTY GOOD NOTE.
SAY EVERYTHING.
AFRAID YOUR TIME
IS UP.
KEEP THE D.A. WAITING,
HE GETS KIND OF ITCHY.
THERE WAS A REAL GOOD PIECE
IN THERE ABOUT DIESEL ENGINES.
MOE, SEE THIS BOY
FINDS THE DOOR.
WE'LL DO OUR BEST
ABOUT BAIL.
SORRY, RAMIREZ.
THE D.A. LIKES TO MAKE EVERYTHING
LOOK REAL DESPERATE.
I'M NOT SAYING YOU DIDN'T HAVE
WHAT THEY CALL PROVOCATION.
YOU HAD PLENTY.
AMES GIVE YOU A GOOD SHOVING
AROUND AND...
WHAT WITH THAT MRS. AMES
WAVING HERSELF AT YOU.
YOU KNOW, IF I WAS IN YOUR FIX
I'D TAKE A PLEA.
YOU'D DO BETTER WITH A JUDGE NOW
THAN A JURY LATER ON.
MIGHT EVEN GET OFF WITH
AS LITTLE AS 3 YEARS.
AND IF YOU STAND TRIAL
IT COULD EASILY BE TEN.
YOU MEAN A JUDGE WOULD TAKE OFF
7 YEARS IF I LIED?
YOU'RE AN AGGRAVATING GUY,
RAMIREZ.
HEY, HOW'S ABOUT WETTING
YOUR BACK TEETH, BOY?
THANKS.
WON'T TALK.
REMINDS ME OF YOU.
ATOM BOMB SHOULD FALL ON THE GUY
THAT INVENTED THIS THING.
SHOWS WHAT HAPPENS
WHEN YOU DON'T LOSE YOUR HEAD.
HERE! WHAT THE-
CHU CHU.
I DREAMED
YOU'D COME HERE
AND PICK ME UP
OUT OF THE SAWDUST,
TO WASH MY FACE
AND TAKE ME HOME.
AND MARRY YOU.
OH, WHY DIDN'T YOU
MAKE A BREAK FOR IT?
YOU GOT AWAY.
WHY DID YOU COME TO THE ONE
PLACE WHERE YOU HAD TO LOSE?
WHERE ELSE WOULD I GO?
YOU WALKED RIGHT
INTO THEIR ARMS.
NO. I'M NOT WORRIED
ABOUT THE TRIAL.
I ONLY WORRY ABOUT YOU.
ALSO BECAUSE YOU SAY
MAGIC WORD IN NOTE.
"TO FRIEND RAMIREZ,
MY LOVE."
WHATEVER CHOICE,
RAMIREZ...
MY LOVE.
SAY IT BACK TO ME,
QUICK.
I SAY IT TO YOU NOW
WHEN I ALWAYS SAY IT.
EVERYBODY ELSE HEAR ME, NANCY. NOT YOU?
I HEARD YOU, BUT I
WOULDN'T LET MYSELF LISTEN.
THERE'S TOO MANY MEN
AT THE DOOR.
PROMISE TO TAKE CARE
OF YOURSELF.
NO MORE OF THIS
TURN ON GAS THING.
YOU PROMISE TO
WAIT FOR ME,
THEN THERE'S NOTHING
TO BE AFRAID OF, NOWHERE,
FOR YOU, NANCY,
OR FOR ME.
I PROMISE.
ALL RISE FOR
HIS HONOR, JUDGE WELLS,
SUPERIOR COURT JUDGE FOR THE
COUNTY OF MISSION, CALIFORNIA.
ALL THOSE HAVING BUSINESS
WITH THIS COURT,
DRAW NEAR, GIVE YOUR ATTENTION,
AND YOU SHALL BE HEARD.
COURT IS NOW
IN SESSION.
I ADMIT THAT I COULDN'T
PAY HIM RIGHT OFF THE BAT.
THAT DOESN'T MEAN I WAS GONNA CHEAT HIM.
I HAD THE MONEY
WAITING FOR HIM.
WELL, FIRST THING I KNEW, I HEARD
HER HOLLERING UP AT THE HOUSE.
BY THE TIME I GOT THERE,
HE WAS BEATING ON HER.
AS SOON AS HE SAW MY HUSBAND,
HE KNOCKED HIM DOWN.
I TRIED TO FIGHT HIM OFF.
THEN HE GRABBED THE GUN
OFF THE WALL AND SHOT HIM
WHILE HE WAS LYING THERE,
HELPLESS.
MY HUSBAND DIDN'T HAVE
A CHANCE.
MY COUSIN A GOOD MAN.
WORKED HARD.
NEVER GIVE TROUBLE
TO NO ONE. NOT EVER.
NEVER SEEN HIM GET MAD,
LOSE TEMPER.
PLENTY OF THINGS
TO GET MAD ABOUT,
BUT CHU CHU NOT GET MAD.
ALWAYS PAY DEBTS.
VERY HONEST FELLA.
MAKE GOOD ON BUM CHECK
OF AMES.
HE'S NOT THE KIND THAT
GOES AROUND HURTING PEOPLE.
THEY HURT HIM.
HE WON'T EVER
HURT THEM BACK.
HE DOESN'T HAVE AN ENEMY.
'S THE BEST MAN
I EVER MET...
AND A KIND ONE.
THAT'S IT.
OH, I-I NOT THE BEST
OF MEN,
BUT I'M NOT THE WORST.
I NEVER BEAT WOMEN.
I NOT LOVE HER.
BUT WHEN I BE LIED TO,
I NOT GET SHOT BY ANYBODY,
AND I NOT SHOOT ANYBODY.
AND BEFORE ALL,
BEFORE THE JUDGE AND THE JURY,
BEFORE MY ENEMIES
AND MY FRIENDS,
I SAY THIS:
WHAT I HAVE TELL YOU
IS TRUE.
CHU CHU, THE LAWYER SAYS WE
STILL HAVE A VERY GOOD CHANCE.
I FIND OUT SOMETHING
IN THAT COURTROOM.
ONLY GOOD CHANCE
I HAVE IS TO LOSE.
THAT WOMAN WAS LYING. EVERYBODY KNEW IT.
FUNNY THING ABOUT LYING.
A LIE GET LOOSE,
CAN LOOK JUST AS GOOD
AS THE TRUTH.
HOW PEOPLE CAN KNOW
THE DIFFERENCE?
YOU GO TO DOCTOR
LIKE I SAY?
YEAH, I GO TO DOCTOR
LIKE YOU SAY.
AND, WHAT HE TELL YOU?
GAVE ME SOME
SWELL ADVICE.
DON'T WORRY. RELAX.
EAT NOURISHING FOOD.
GET PLENTY OF SLEEP.
KEEP HAPPY.
WELL, THIS MIGHT...
I GIVE SAME MEDICINE,
DIFFERENT APPEARANCE.
RELAX.
GET NOURISHMENT.
SLEEP. PLENTY SLEEP.
THINK HAPPY.
DEFENDANT WILL RISE,
FACE THE JURY.
MEN AND WOMEN OF THE JURY,
HAVE YOU REACHED A VERDICT?
WE HAVE,
YOUR HONOR.
HOW SAY YOU THEN?
IS THE DEFENDANT CHU CHU RAMIREZ
GUILTY OR NOT GUILTY AS CHARGED?
UH, CAN I SAY THIS
IN MY OWN WORDS, JUDGE?
YOU MAY.
WELL, WE FIGURE RAMIREZ
DID THE JOB ALL RIGHT,
BUT WE ALSO FIGURE THAT MAYBE
IF WE'D HAD TO TAKE WHAT HE DID
WE'D HAVE DONE
THE SAME THING.
SO OUR VERDICT IS GUILTY
OF ASSAULT WITH A DEADLY WEAPON.
BUT WE'D LIKE TO ASK,
YOUR HONOR,
TO GO LIGHT
WHEN YOU PASS SENTENCE.
WE'D TAKE THAT
AS A FAVOR.
CHU CHU RAMIREZ,
HAVE YOU ANYTHING TO SAY
BEFORE SENTENCE IS PRONOUNCED?
I NOT WISH TO
WASTE ANY TIME.
BETTER TO USE TIME
SERVING SENTENCE.
BUT A FEW WORDS
MUST BE SPOKE,
AND I WILL NOW SPEAK THEM.
IS HERE IN MY HAND A LETTER
I HAVE WRITE TO THE PRESIDENT.
THE PRESIDENT?
PRESIDENT OF
THE UNITED STATES.
YOU MAY READ IT.
THESE ARE THE WORDS.
"DEAR FRIEND,
I NOW AGAIN WRITE TO YOU
"BECAUSE I AM AFRAID YOU'D
READ ABOUT ME IN NEWSPAPERS
"AND NOT UNDERSTAND.
"BEFORE WHEN I WRITE, IT WAS A
FINE THING THAT HAPPENED TO ME.
"I AM BECOME A CITIZEN.
"THIS TIME
IS A BAD THING.
"I AM IN JAIL FOR
SOMETHING I NOT DO.
"AND IF I AM CONVICT,
I NO LONGER AM CITIZEN.
"THIS TO ME
IS WORTHY TO DIE.
"I ALWAYS REMEMBER
AND I WILL NEVER FORGET
"WHAT YOU TELL ME ABOUT
THIS COUNTRY AND ITS LAWS.
"IS NOTHING WRONG
WITH THE LAW,
"ONLY WITH HOW THE LAW IS TURNED
AROUND AND TWISTED BY SOME PEOPLES.
"FOR IF LAW IS TURNED AROUND
AND TWISTED TOO MUCH, IT BREAK,
"AND THERE'S NOTHING
FOR NOBODY.
"AND NO LONGER IS
THIS COUNTRY SOMETHING.
"MR. PRESIDENT,
THIS IS A GOOD COUNTRY,
"A BIG COUNTRY
WITH GOOD, STRONG LAW,
"AND IS MORE GOOD PEOPLE
THAN BAD.
"LIKE ALL BIG THINGS, IT
GOES SLOW, MR. PRESIDENT,
"AND IT GO VERY SURE.
FROM YOUR FRIEND,
CHU CHU RAMIREZ."
THAT IS ALL I HAVE
TO SAY, MR. YOUR HONOR.
HELLO, BOYS.
HELLO.
HI, SHERIFF.
BEERS, ALL AROUND.
YOU HONESTLY THINK CHU CHU
SHOOT THAT BIG SLOB AMES?
I NEVER ARGUE
WITH A JURY.
CHU CHU WOULDN'T NEED THAT
GUN TO TAKE CARE OF AMES.
IF THERE WAS 2 AMES, CHU
CHU NEED ONLY HIS 2 HANDS.
WE HAD A MAN OVER
IN THE JAIL ONCE,
CHARGED WITH KILLING
ANOTHER FELLA.
WOULDN'T ADMIT IT.
AND LIED FASTER THAN
A DOG COULD TROT.
FINALLY, THE D.A.
GOT AN IDEA.
HE PUT THIS FELLA
IN A ROOM,
RIGHT SPANK IN
THE MIDDLE OF IT,
AND ALL OF US JUST SAT
AROUND AND LOOKED AT HIM.
DIDN'T SAY ANYTHING.
DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
JUST SAT AND
LOOKED AT HIM.
YOU KNOW WHAT HAPPENED?
PRETTY SOON, THAT FELLA BROKE
DOWN AND CRIED LIKE A BABY.
AND TALK? WELL,
YOU COULDN'T STOP HIM.
TOLD THE TRUTH, TOO.
SOME KIND OF LESSON
IN THAT, I GUESS.
SOMETIMES THE BEST WAY
TO DRAW BLOOD ON A MAN
IS JUST STAND STILL
AND LOOK AT HIM.
IF YOU'RE RIGHT
AND HE'S WRONG,
YOU CAN BLEED 'EM
TO DEATH THAT WAY.
SO LONG, BOYS.
THANK YOU, SHERIFF.
THANK ME?
FOR WHAT?
FOR THE BEER.
SOUND LIKE POKER
GAME WITHOUT CARDS.
AND RAMIREZ WAS
SENTENCED TO A TERM OF ONE YEAR AND A DAY.
A YEAR AND A DAY.
FOR ONCE I'M EVEN GONNA ENJOY
EATING ONE OF YOUR BUM MEALS,
UNLESS YOU'VE
POISONED THE FOOD.
THAT WAY,
I'D ENJOY IT.
FROM THE LOOKS OF YOU, YOU'D
ENJOY EATING SOME OF IT YOURSELF.
THE WORLD WOULD LOSE
A FINE PAIR.
SWEETLY WOMAN,
BIG, HONEST MAN.
GET OFF THIS PLACE,
AND GET OFF FAST!
CAME TO SAY GOOD NIGHT.
SLEEP GOOD.
EAT GOOD, TOO.
WHAT DO YOU SUPPOSE
THEY'RE AFTER?
YOU OUGHT TO KNOW.
THEY'RE AFTER YOUR WIFE, LIKE RAMIREZ.
THEY'RE AFTER US.
YOU AIN'T OUT OF HERE IN AN
HOUR, I'M CALLIN' THE SHERIFF!
THAT'S WHAT THE MEXICANS HAVE
GOT A SPOT ALL PICKED OUT FOR.
RIGHT NEXT TO NIKKI.
KILL IT, AMES.
KILL IT.
JUST GO AHEAD AND
KILL THIS KITTEN.
GET OFF THE PLACE,
YOU DRUNKEN TRAMP!
SHE'S NOT DRUNK,
SHE'S SICK.
DRUNK OR SICK,
I DON'T WANT TO HEAR.
HOW DO YOU
SIT THERE EATING
AND NOT CHOKE TO DEATH?
YOU PUT AN INNOCENT MAN
IN JAIL WITH LIES.
HE'S GONNA ROT HIS LIFE
AWAY THERE,
UNLESS YOU TELL THE TRUTH.
YOU CHEATED HIM,
AND THEN YOU STALLED HIM.
THEN YOU RAN HIM
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
WHEN HE WOULDN'T TAKE IT
ANYMORE, YOU LIED AWAY HIS FREEDOM
AND HIS CITIZENSHIP.
DON'T YOU THINK YOU'RE JUST
GOING TO WALK AWAY AND FORGET IT,
'CAUSE YOU'RE NOT.
IF YOU DON'T BELIEVE THAT NOW,
YOU'RE GOING TO FIND IT OUT.
THOSE GUYS DOWN THERE, THEY'RE
GONNA QUIT ON YOU AFTER A WHILE.
SO WILL I.
WE'LL BE GONE.
BUT YOU TWO WILL
NEVER BE GONE.
WHEREVER HE STAYS,
HE LEAVES HIS MARK...
EVEN ON SOMEONE LIKE ME.
EVEN ON SOMEONE LIKE YOU.
I'D TAKE IT EASY
IF I WAS YOU.
BUT YOU'RE NOT ME.
AND BECAUSE I KNEW CHU CHU,
I'M NEVER GONNA BE LIKE YOU.
AND FOR THAT,
I GIVE THANKS.
NEAR KILLED HERSELF.
I'M NOT SO SURE
SHE DIDN'T.
WE'LL HOLD THIS
AGAINST YOU, TOO.
GET HER TO A DOCTOR,
QUICK.
NANCY NOT GET BETTER,
YOU GET A WHOLE LOT WORSE.
THERE'S SOMETHING
I'M TRYING TO REMEMBER.
WHETHER THE FIRST ROTTEN
THING WE DID WAS TO EACH OTHER
OR TO SOMEBODY ELSE.
MAYBE I SHOULDN'T WORRY WHAT
THE FIRST ROTTEN THING WAS.
MAYBE I SHOULD JUST TRY TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT OUR LAST ONE WILL BE.
ALL THE TIME
THAT GIRL WAS TALKING,
I KEPT THINKING...
I USED TO BE LIKE HER.
YOU WERE?
THAT ONCE I'D HAVE DONE
JUST WHAT SHE DID.
YOU WOULDN'T EVEN
HAVE DONE IT FOR ME.
IS IT TOO LATE
FOR US?
IS THERE ANYTHING LEFT
THAT ISN'T SPOILED?
I WORKED ALL MY LIFE.
YOU SEE WHERE
IT'S GOT US.
SURE WE WORKED,
BUT AT THE WRONG THINGS
IN THE WRONG WAY.
CAN'T GO BACK.
NOBODY CAN.
NOT ALL THE WAY,
BUT IF WE WENT IN
TO THERE TO DRURY
AND GOT THAT MEXICAN
OFF THE HOOK...
GET HIM OFF THE HOOK
AND GET OURSELVES ON.
WHAT WE DID WAS PERJURY.
THAT MEANS JAIL.
WHERE ELSE HAVE WE BEEN ALL THESE YEARS?
NOBODY CAN GO BACK,
I TELL YOU.
NOT 15 YEARS.
I'M GOING BACK.
I'M GOING IN THERE
AND FREE RAMIREZ.
AND YOU'LL HAVE TO
KILL ME TO STOP ME.
I HATE TO SEE YOU
GO, RAMIREZ.
I KNOW HOW TO TAKE
A DIESEL DOWN NOW
AND I WAS JUST FINDING
OUT HOW TO PUT IT BACK UP.
THAT'S NO WAY
TO LEAVE A MACHINE.
HERE. IS GETTING A
PRESENT, FROM ME TO YOU.
OH, THANKS. I'LL RETURN
IT AFTER I'VE READ IT.
BE A SHAME TO
BREAK UP THE SET.
COME TO THINK OF IT,
I OWE YOU ONE.
OH, IT'S BROKEN.
TO MR. AMES
AND MRS. AMES.
MRS. AMES.
YOU KNOW, RAMIREZ,
IF I STOPPED
BELIEVING IN CONSCIENCE,
I'D TURN IN MY BADGE.
TO MRS. AMES.
LONG MAY SHE WAVE.
CHU CHU!
OH, BROTHER!
FULL HOUSE!
HAVE BIG JOB
IN THE PEACH FIELDS.
3 MORE CROPS,
AND YOU'RE MINE.
LIKE INSTALLING
WASHING MACHINE.
WONDERFUL SYSTEM.
I WANT TO SAY
GOOD-BYE TO YOU.
REALLY, I DO.
I'M MUCH BETTER
THAT YOU EVER HAPPENED.
I'M NOT SO SURE
YOU EVER DID.
YOU SAY GOOD-BYE
LIKE I SAY HELLO.
BUT IT'S NOT SO EASY
AS YOU MAKE IT SEEM.
WE NEVER SAY GOOD-BYE
WHEN BOTH OF US
BREATHE IN AND OUT.
NURSE!
THIS GUY'S-
PLEASE STOP.
I CAN'T TAKE IT
ANYMORE.
TIME YOU CARED
A LITTLE.
WHAT HAVE I GOT
TO GIVE YOU?
EVERYTHING I WANT,
IS ALL.
I NEED YOU, NANCY,
'CAUSE I LOVE YOU.
TO ME, ALWAYS,
YOU'RE VERY BEAUTIFUL.
OH, BUT CHU CHU-
OH, PLEASE. YOU ASKED ME.
LET ME ANSWER.
I NEED YOU, 'CAUSE...
I'M SICK OF...
AND AFRAID.
AS THE LOST DAYS
GROW INTO YEARS TO ME,
YOU ARE ALONE.
YOU'VE GOT TO GET WELL.
YOU'VE GOT TO TRY,
NANCY.
TRY.
I WILL.
I'LL TRY.
YOU WON'T BE ALONE
ANYMORE, CHU CHU.
OH, HOW I'LL TRY.
OH, CHU CHU.
THE HAT, CHU CHU.
DON'T STEP ON THAT HAT.