There was a tremendous power of love in me, a girl.
Now my power of love is dying.
I don't want to die.
Hebrew subtitles: Ulpanei Elrom
My Michael
Based on the novel of the same name by Amos Oz.
Jerusalem, 1950
What influence did Charles Dickens have on him?
Take David Copperfield's orphan, for example.
He is like Joseph the orphan from the town of Madmena
in the story of Peretz Smolenskin:
both
have endured every possible suffering.
Here's an additional detail, interesting and important,
in the work of Peretz Smolenskin -
Are you hurt?
...Peretz Smolenskin's critique of society.
We see his attitude towards man,
for example, in his story of Joseph the orphan...
It's cold in your Jerusalem.
What makes you think I'm from Jerusalem?
I saw you as a Jerusalemite right away.
They teach that in the geology department, too?
David Copperfield is an orphan, just like Joseph the orphan,
I've met a lot of violent people
violent people from all walks of life.
Hundreds of thousands of years ago, the sea covered the area,
The Judean mountains, Jerusalem, all that territory.
There are clear signs in the geologic strata,
testifying to that.
There are fossilized fish remains, shark teeth,
even found dinosaur footprints.
But that's not what I asked you.
I asked you how you knew
that I'm a Jerusalemite.
Look, I don't know much about you.
I know geology better than you,
and I wanted to impress you.
But, uh, I don't know much about you.
I don't know anything about you other than the fact
that you stumbled on the stairs today.
Hana, we have a beautiful apartment.
You should come.
Two large rooms, in the Rehavia neighborhood,
just above the store.
What's wrong, why are you smiling?
- Nothing.
- You got some kind of secret?
What rain!
- Take my gloves.
- Thank you.
Let's go.
This is where I live.
I'm not inviting you for a cup of tea,
because my hostess is religious.
When I rented the room, I promised her
I wouldn't invite men over.
Good night.
Michael.
You forgot.
Thank you.
- Goodbye.
- Good night.
- Hana?
- Hello, Mrs. Tarnopoler.
- Is it still raining?
- Just a little, not much.
Sit down, I'll give you some tea.
It's cold.
You came home late today.
Well?
Good morning.
Have you been waiting long?
- No, not really.
- Let's go.
Let's go to the valley.
Water in the valley...
...Deep in the earth, water dissolves ...
Inside is the hot core, outside is the lithosphere, -
hard rock shell.
Am I boring you?
No, no, no. Go on.
- What are you studying?
- Hebrew literature.
In the mornings, I work at a daycare center
as a teacher's aide.
You're not a Jerusalemite?
No, I'm from Holon.
My father always wanted me to be a professor
at Jerusalem University,
because his father was a teacher in Poland.
Also a geologist?
He was a teacher of the Tanakh.
Hanale received a dress as a gift from her mom.
Therefore, it was very dear to her.
However...
Hana.
- Hey. (chuckles)
- Are you busy?
- A little.
- What are you doing?
- Preparing a play called "Hanaleh's Saturday Dress."
Kids, let's all go see Sarah's teacher.
You don't want to go to Sarah's tutor?
I'll throw you in there.
And they will light candles and eat.....
Can you help me?
You were a spoiled brat, of course.
That's right, indeed, I have been spoiled.
Even the gym teacher at school
used to call me "Ganz the slacker."
If we'd met when we were kids,
you would have beaten me, of course.
Be careful, I can beat you up now.
I want to marry you.
Please don't answer me now.
Before the war, I was playing with two Arab boys.
I am the princess, they are my bodyguards.
I commanded them, I lorded it over them.
How far away it is.
I'm not used to talking about it.
I always knew what was going on with my Michael.
And then, all of a sudden, surprise.
Wedding.
You're taking away my genius, my Michael?
I'm just kidding.
- What are you studying at university?
- Hebrew literature. - Hebrew literature.
I have a book for you.
"Klozner's History of Hebrew Literature.
I'll find it.
Uh, excuse me. Just a minute.
Hello, Jehezkiel.
They didn't. for lack of light.
Thank you.
- Michael. - Hello.
- Hello. Hello.
I'd like you to meet her. This is Hana.
- This is Aunt Zhenya. - How do you do?
- Nice to meet you.
Hello, Aunt Batia.
Please meet Hana.
Hello, Dvora.
- This is Hana. - Nice to meet you.
- Dvora.
Mr. Kadishman, a friend of the family.
He found out that you come from a good family.
Let's go in the other room.
Go sit down.
See also.
You do know that Michael's father
is a small official in the municipality.
And his financial situation is pretty dire.
He spends most of his paycheck
on Michael's education.
Obviously, there's no way the family would agree
for him to drop out of school.
I'm going to let myself ask you an intimate question.
Did something happen
that the wedding can't be postponed?
No.
Then what's the rush?
I was engaged for six years
before I married my first husband.
Can't you wait a year?
Know that financial difficulties
in the beginning of your life together can ruin it.
Right, within a month, two months,
sex supersedes all other problems.
But what happens then?
Our Michael is still in the clouds.
A genius in science and an infant in life.
- What does your mother say about it?
- We're not going to see her until tomorrow.
All right. Uh-huh.
Michael.
Sit down, please.
- Do you have a suit for the wedding?
- Uh, no.
There's Joseph's costume.
It needs a little adjustment.
There's not much difference in size.
No need to.
Hanche, why don't you say anything?
A girl is about to get married,
and a face like the Ninth of Av.
Hanele is a gentle girl.
Take care of her.
There's a lot of pain in it.
Doba, what do they want?
- They want to see the apartment...
- Is the apartment furnished?
- Part of it, left over... - Can I see it?
- It's right here, please.
- This place is quiet. - It is.
- Most of the neighbors here are religious.
A little noise from the yeshiva, but not terrible.
- It's not critical. Not critical.
- It's good.
You can see the furniture. Not much left.
No bed or table.
That's it.
My name is Glick. I live across the street here.
When you're done, please close the blinds
and bring me the key.
- All right. Uh-huh.
- And if you're interested, let me know.
Then I'll tell the master.
- All right. Uh-huh. Thank you very much.
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
Tomorrow we'll buy furniture, get a bed,
clean up the apartment.
Hedgehog.
What about this table?
It is what it is.
- You can't include the table in the price?
- Uh, no.
- But, I can't buy...
- If you can't buy it, don't buy it.
But, how much do you want for it?
I'll put the price here: 60 liras.
- 60 lire a table? - This one's 100.
- 100 lira is a lot of money....
That's a lot of money, that's what I want.
100 lire, 100 lire.
If you, Mrs. Hana, scream at night.
two days before the wedding,
it's clear that this is a sure sign
of some great misfortune. God forbid!
If I were your mother,
I wouldn't let you suddenly jump into marriage.
for some stranger
who happened to meet him on the street.
I mean, you could have accidentally met
a completely different person.
You're getting married like life
is a Purim carnival.
A girl meets a stranger,
without knowing what he's made of,
she makes arrangements with him; she sets her own wedding day,
as if there were no one else in the world but her.
I got married by matchmaking.
Congratulations!
Congratulations! Where's Hana?
- Congratulations! - Congratulations!
- Meet my mom.
Congratulations!
- Michael, let's dance. - No, we're not.
- Let's go dancing.
Hanaleh took pity on him
and offered to help him.
When Hanale finished helping the coal miner,
she suddenly realized that her entire dress
was blackened with coal dust.
The beautiful new dress her mom made her,
was covered in black spots.
Hanaleh was very unhappy,
and shed bitter tears.
And, uh, here's what happened, kids.
Suddenly a multitude of stars descended from the sky.
and, instead of dirty coal stains,
gold stars appeared on Hanaleh's dress.
Hanaleh is no longer afraid to go home.
She runs straight to her mom and shows her
what a miracle has happened to her.
Mom is very happy along with Hanaleh.
- Michael.
- What?
I'm pregnant.
- I'm pregnant.
Are you sure about this?
Hana.
When she eats, she has here.....
She doesn't swallow her pee,
she has here, inside.
under the neck, there are two small pockets.
She pecks grains and fills her pockets.
Gradually it's getting thicker and thicker.
Why? Because she's hoarding.
Do you know what "hoarding" means?
It's collecting.
Hana.
Gianni, hello.
- Hello. - I'm sorry I didn't call
Michael at work that you were coming,
we would have left you a key.
- Have you been waiting long?
- No, I haven't.
Michael hasn't gotten home from work yet.
It's a good thing he's not here. I want to talk to you.
Come on in. I'll just take the groceries to the kitchen.
We're settling in nicely.
Come on, Hana, sit down, I want to talk to you.
We can sit over there.
I heard this morning.
I left everything and came to Jerusalem.
Michael told me about your situation.
I don't understand you.
Why now?
It's so bad timing, it'll ruin everything.
Michael's exams ...
Why don't you put it off?
Like a child.
I'm sorry I came. I should have known.
It's just a 20-minute surgery,
like ripping out tonsils.
Hana.
Wait, let me finish.
I didn't mean...
Don't think I'm mean.
I think my suggestion makes sense.
If so, you can plan for it.
Michael, why don't you say anything to her?
You're standing there like a statue.
Okay, I'm leaving.
It's his silence... Silence.
I'd get up now and leave immediately,
without even changing my dress.
I'd get up and leave.
Sometimes I wonder what I see in that man.
What I know about him.
If I had met someone else,
would the same thing happen?
Michael.
We're like two strangers on the same bench
on a long train ride,
must be polite,
be courteous, be courteous, be courteous, be courteous.
I feel like something big
is about to happen. I'm waiting.
Something has to happen on this trip.
I'm waiting.
You're diligent.
You don't have to mock me.
Villain.
Hana, you know it's stupid.
- Do I look ugly to you?
- Hana.
So, why aren't you hugging me?
Hana, indeed...
Have you forgotten what you asked for this morning?
You asked me not to touch you.
I'm not touching you.
Hana, don't cry.
You know I love you.
Tell me, what annoys you?
So I don't make the same mistake again.
Have a drink.
- How's it going?
- Do you care?
Hana.
Hana, you know it's really hard for me too....
It's not easy for me either.
I didn't think it was easy for you.
Hana.
- Hana.
- What?
You don't love me anymore?
I'm sad. That's all.
I'll take her now to the hospital in Tel Aviv.
I'm the deputy chief of pediatrics,
and I have every right
to demand responsible behavior.
This is a hospital? It's a disgrace!
It's like some Asian hospital!
Maybe I'm asking too much,
but I would ask you
to name him Zalman,
in honor of your grandfather, Michael.
I propose that we put on the birth certificate
a double name--
Yair Zalman.
The decision is yours.
Remember, other than the calcium tablets,
don't agree to take anything.
Yair, Zalman...
Quiet.
I saw that you were still awake,
and I thought that maybe, uh.
I work in the bedroom.
If you need anything, let me know.
Good night.
Come on, let it be sweet.
The days are the same. Nothing happens.
Michael and I don't talk much.
Mostly silent.
An outsider might think
we're at peace.
The days are just like one another.
It's going to take some more time.
Hi.
Tzion. Can you replace me?
Come on, Hana, let's go out for a while.
I'd like you to meet me. Hana, this is Tzion,
a friend of mine from work.
- This is Hana, my wife.
- Nice to meet you, Tzion.
Keep dividing. And then cook...
- Okay? - All right.
- Let's go outside.
All sections of the doctoral dissertation ...
It's hard, but I'm making progress.
- You want part of a sandwich?
- Uh, no.
Everything for my father.
I really hope he's still honored
to write on letter envelopes:
"To Dr. Michael Gonen."
It's important to my father.
Never take anything from people
you don't know.
Was it a bad man?
Yair, maybe this man
was wounded in the war.
Maybe he's a hero.
He wasn't a hero, he was a bad man.
Stop talking.
I'll eat a cookie and die to you.
- You'll never die.
- Stop this nonsense. We're done.
- Mom, Dad. - Good morning.
- Zalman and Zalman are back.
Good morning.
- Did you sleep well?
- Yeah.
When I was a girl, we lived in Kiryat Shmuel,
on the border of the Katamon neighborhood.
Near us, at the foot of the hill, stood the house of an Arab,
Rashida Shahada.
I played with his kids--
two twin boys.
I was in love with both of them.
The war separated us.
Don't worry, Hana.
It'll all be over soon.
I think this is a military exercise.
- Where's the sweater?
- In my backpack. - Oh, good.
- Dad. - What? When are you coming back?
- In a few days.
Goodbye, Yair. Take care of mom.
It's a shame I have to leave now,
when you're not feeling well.
Goodbye.
Don't worry. I'm just a communications guy.
Not a paratrooper.
Bye.
Are they coming again?
What do they want from me?
Why? Why didn't they...
I don't want to...
Kids, what do you want me to do?
Why did they come again?
Why...
Again today... Gleek...
What, what...
Doba, come here.
- Let's go home.
- Why again?
Army forces defeated Arab terrorists,
captured Kuntila and Ras al-Naqel,
have taken up positions west of the junction of the roads
at Nahel, east of the Suez Canal.
This operation exposed the vulnerability
of the Egyptian army
"and was a retaliatory strike against the violation
of the vital peace of the citizens of Israel."
Excuse me, Mrs. Gonen, is your husband home?
No, he was drafted.
I don't know what to do.
She's been different lately.
My wife, Doba.
She's not well.
You know what I mean? She threw a candlestick at me
with a burning candle. On Saturday.
So, I thought maybe
your husband could tell me what to do.
- Hello, Mrs. Gonen. We've come to visit you.
- How do you do?
- We heard you were sick.
- No, nothing, just a little weak.
Come in, please, come in.
- Where's Yair?
- He's at my friend Hadassah's.
It's very nice of you to stop by.
We thought maybe we could help in some way.
Perhaps Mrs. Gonen will allow me
go into the kitchen and make her tea?
No, no, thank you,
I'll get up and make you something.
Have you heard from Michael?
No.
There's no need to worry, Mrs. Gonen.
In these great days, I think, although the disciples of Zeev Jabotinsky
have been pushed out of key positions,
but today his teachings are celebrating a great victory.
The State of Israel will henceforth change its image.
- How's Doba doing?
- The doctor says there's hope.
- Why are you sitting in your coat?
- We were just leaving.
We're leaving.
A speedy and speedy recovery.
Are you leaving already? Am I boring you?
When Michael comes back,
I'll come play chess with him.
Thank you very much.
Uh, hello?
Michael Gonen.
Yes.
Military Post 2801.
Yes...
Uh, excuse me.
Hello? The military commissioner?
Yes... Michael Gonen.
Yes?
But I haven't gotten anything from him since the war started.
I understand.
All right. Uh-huh.
Thank you.
- What do you want with my baby?
- What does he want from me?
What did he do to you?
Crazy...
- Leave it.
- Leave him.
You should go to jail.
- What did she do to you?
- Crazy.
Let's go.
Come on, come on.
You're gonna lie down for a while, you're gonna lie down.
Michael?
Dad.
Did you kill Arabs?
No, Yair, the Jewish army almost got me
almost got me killed.
I feel almost like a war hero
from a Soviet movie.
Such a man, for no reason, fell on the sidewalk.
What's the point of this?
And the formalities of the funeral
as if he were going abroad.
It reminds me of a game
we used to play when we were kids.
They'd line up in a long line, and the first one to throw the ball,
would run to the end of the line and be the last one out.
And so it went on and on
until the last one became the first one.
I don't remember who was considered the winner or why.
Dad's dead. I'm the father now.
Yair.
Again? What's wrong?
What's wrong?
The guys got mad. There was a fight, that's all.
Yair, pet him. Okay.
Every living creature needs affection and love.
I love his restraint.
But, I wish it would explode.
I can still summon them,
twins,
just like when we were kids,
to come and take me,
to bring back the feeling of pain, of love.
I once wanted to meet a man who was strong,
who could hardly control himself.
I'm not comparing.
What are you saying...
An egg, a tough egg.
Thought it would make a chicken.
Joram is now studying for his exams,
and private lessons could help him, no doubt.
Mr. Gonen told me that you
studied Hebrew literature at the university.
That's right, it was a long time ago.
Maybe you could
give him some of your time.
Uh, okay. I'm usually free on Tuesdays,
after lunch.
- Regarding payment...
- No, you don't.
- We can't make demands of you.
- Maybe we can work it out somehow.
Joram will be able to watch over Yair
as we leave.
- Joram?
- Of course.
- Next Tuesday, then? Would that be okay?
- It's fine.
- Thank you very much, Mrs. Gonen. Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Why do you always have your hands up?
I'm explaining it to you. You can't, but it's okay.
We'll start over, no big deal.
I don't understand, don't give in.
Hana, I'm telling you,
I received the journal of the British
of the Geological Society.
There's an article printed there by a professor from Cambridge,
laying out an exciting new theory
of erosion processes.
He refutes everything I wrote.
I'm forced to start my doctoral dissertation all over again.
Don't give in. Prove to that Englishman that you're right.
I can't. I'm explaining it to you.
Why are you like this?
Hana, not possible. He's right, I'm convinced.
You raise your hands.
The British were forced to leave Israel.
We made them.
"In the flow of the cool waves you can see
"the whole surrounding landscape.
Like a mirror, reflecting the jungle that has invaded it.
Kill. Love.
In the tangles of life
I wouldn't be tempted.
I'm enchanted by this island."
Joram, are you here?
- Yeah.
- I thought you were already on a faraway island,
like our hero.
No, I'm listening.
Focus.
"It's not foreseeable that anyone would take
"seriously
to his tropical reverie.
And there was no point in hurting his feelings.
Powerful people don't show up in places so dangerous,
where I ended up.
On the nights of the full moon..."
Everyone was wondering when the English would leave the country,
- the final release will come.
- Yeah.
And so, they left the country, thank God,
- and the Messiah hasn't come yet.
- Yes, he is.
Honey, your husband helped me solve a problem
that I couldn't solve for six months.
I really don't know how to thank you.
Okay, see you Thursday.
Goodbye.
Mom.
- What does the cat want?
- He wants to eat and sleep.
Shall I get him a blanket?
No, silly, cats don't need blankets.
Why?
Okay. Ask your dad. Dad's smarter than that.
- Dad.
- What?
Why don't cats need blankets?
Look at this.
See, he's got warm fur.
Pet him, Yair. Every living thing
needs affection and love.
Read.
A religious young man writes poems about love?
- I've got a little work left, and then.
- Hello. - Hello. (chuckles)
I'm gonna go work in the bedroom, okay?
- Was everything okay?
- Yeah, fine. He slept the whole time.
My shoes are too tight.
- Finished reading the book?
- There are still 3 more chapters to go.
I hope you finish reading before your next class.
- Good night.
Joram, hello. Where are you going?
- To the youth movement club.
- We're going to fix Yair's teeth.
Let's go.
- Take it, Joram. - No, thank you.
- Take it.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
You have beautiful eyes, you know?
Mrs. Gonen.
Do I look like an ancient old woman to you?
- Mrs. Gonen.
- Hana. You can call me Hana.
The varieties are listed
in order of decreasing concentration...
"Bastard, your boy,
standing there looking at me like a little man.
- Mom, I'm going to play.
- Okay, Yair.
Information on the topic is summarized in Table 1.
I see that I have to go through all of this myself.
We started school together. You're done, and I'm stuck
on some stupid final paper,
I'm just embarrassed.
You helped me out.
Let's go to the other room
so we can keep working.
Sweetie, you wouldn't get turned on
if I steal your man for half an hour?
He needs to explain Davis to me.
Take it. For free. As a gift. Along with your Davis.
Don't be sad.
Michael, there's two of us, we're not one.
There will always be two of us.
That's what's so awful.
Understand, Michael, nothing depends
on you or me.
It's hard for me to explain. Even the words resist me.
I think I put it here.
It's in the corner here, of course.
Just a minute.
Don't be afraid, Joram, come in.
- Mrs. Gonen.
- What?
Mrs. Gonen.
One more time to ten. And she'll be ready. Loudly.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9.
Now look and get stamps.
Careful with the teeth of the stamps, okay?
- Daddy.
- Yeah?
- I'll cut it off.
Give it to me, I'll put it in.
Michael.
Thank you.
Here you go.
Slowly, carefully, gently.
- Dad. - What? There's a row of one country,
and a row of another country.
- Stamps.
- That's right.
- Same brand, here.
- Same stamp? Okay, put it down.
See how I put it in. You want to put it in?
Go ahead, put it in here.
That's great!
- One country.
- Here, more.
- Uh, yeah.
Here, we've got a whole row. What country is this?
- What country is this?
- What? Yair.
- What did I say?
- Germany. - No.
Children. get out of here.
What do you want me to do?
Why are they again...
Where?
Where's Glick?
Doba, it's gonna be okay.
It's going to be all right, Doba. Don't worry.
Mr. Gonen, perhaps you can help me?
Step aside, Mr. Glick.
I'll help you with the questionnaire.
- You're leaving?
- I got a leave of absence to help out.
We're moving to Tel Aviv.
- What are you gonna do next?
- Probably go to university.
What of the distant island?
Joram...
I have to go. Goodbye.
I talked to him.
He said the condition is much better.
He said that maybe in a month.
you'd be coming home.
Hana, that's enough. The tea is already stirred.
You drill the hole.
Everyone's going to die.
I'm gonna die, you're gonna die,
Yoram, Glick, Kadishman, all will die.
All Jerusalem will die.
Michael.
Say something.
That's enough!
Stop being silent all day long!
Stop acting like you're on a day-to-day basis,
like a clockwork alarm clock.
Hana, calm down!
Why do you even live in the world, tell me?
Hana, people, for the most part, don't live for ANYTHING.
They live. Period.
There was a tremendous power of love in me, a girl.
Now my power of love is dying.
I don't want to die.