(siren blaring) ♪♪♪
(indistinct conversations)
That was really good.
Hey, listen. You didn't have
to pay for that. Seriously.
Oh, come on! It's the least
I could do. I invited
you guys. And besides,
now that I'm divorced,
who else am I spending
my money on but my big brother
and his family? Come on.
Yeah, but you're
not gonna be single for long.
Oh, God.
- Thank you, Uncle Michael.
- Of course.
Hey, what did I tell you?
Best food in Philly?
Mm-hm. All right.
Well, uh, I've gotta
show a property
early tomorrow,
so I'm gonna take off.
OK. Be safe, kiddo.
- OK.
- Drive safe.
- Good night, Amy.
- Night.
Sorry, guys.
Excuse me for a second.
Look, I know you need this
so just take it.
- Right here?
- Just take it.
- Come on.
- Look, just take it.
I know you need it, take it.
I don't need it,
just put it away.
Really? That's a first.
All right. (Michael sighing)
All right.
Well, I'm over this way.
Take care.
Yeah. Thanks for dinner.
Bye, Michael. Drive safe
Was that really
necessary back there?
You embarrassed him.
Michael's been borrowing
money from me my entire life.
I mean, I don't...
I can't imagine
he's just gonna get
embarrassed now.
You know, I don't think
he's doing as well
as we thought he was.
What if he starts drinking again?
- Yeah. That implies he stopped.
- Trevor!
I-I could smell it on him
when we got there.
I'm just surprised Kelsie stayed
with him for as long as she did.
Still, she didn't have to cheat on him.
It's a really crappy thing to do
to somebody, you know.
If you're not happy, leave.
You don't put them through that.
That kinda oversimplifies it,
don't you think?
I don't understand
why you always defend her.
Michael needs you
on his side right now.
Michael's a screw-up,
Kelsie isn't.
I call 'em like I see 'em.
Get behind me! Get behind me!
Oh, my God!
AH! (Woman panting)
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
(gunshot)
Oh, my God! (Gunshot)
Ah! Oh, my God!
Oh, my God!
- Argh!
- [911, what's your emergency?]
Yes! My husband's being
attacked by a man with a mask!
Yes. Uh, uh, Slawson and 135th.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah, I'm OK.
- Yeah. Listen.
He's about 5'9".
He's wearing black.
He's got a black mask.
And, uh, he ran east on Slawson.
He went that way.
- They'll be here soon.
- Yeah, yeah. Oh, my God!
You should have seen the way
your father rushed these guys.
I mean, it was incredible. It was
like his instincts just kicked in.
- So, did they catch him yet?
- No, not yet.
(cell phone ringing)
That's Mike.
You should take that.
He probably just wants
- an update.
- Yeah.
Hey, Mike. How's it going?
It's, uh, too bad neither of you
got a good look at the guy.
Yeah. He was wearing a mask.
All I remember is
seeing that gun
pointed at your father's face.
Well...
maybe they could get a serial
number or prints off of it.
I don't have much faith
in the police.
Why is that?
Why don't you have faith in the
police? You've said that before.
When you have a little bit more
life experience, you'll understand.
(sighing) (unsettling music)
Holy crap!
What happened in here? Hey, Ben!
I thought you were
gonna order the cake.
I decided it's more personal
if it's homemade.
(Ben): Ash, your mom
and mamacita are gonna love it.
- Thanks.
- Hey, look at this.
What?
Did you know about that?
You can get copies
of your birth records now,
even though they're closed.
Wait. Are... are you serious?
Yeah. They changed the law
in Pennsylvania a few years ago.
I overheard a guy in
a coffee shop talking about it.
- Are you happy?
- Uh...
I thought you would be
since you wanted more info
on your biological mom
but kept hitting walls.
Yes. I-I am. It's just, um...
It's just a lot to process,
that's all. Um... So I can
get a birth certificate
with her name on it now?
Well, I printed this one off
for you too.
You send that in with 20 bucks,
they'll give you her name.
Wow. That's just...
Uh, thank you.
You... you're amazing.
You know that, right?
(woman): So we've been
together for 24 years.
And it took
the state of Pennsylvania
a long time
to recognize our marriage
but, you know what,
they finally came through.
- Here, here.
- And I have to say,
I have never been happier.
Maricella, you're
the best thing
that's ever happened to me.
And, Ashley,
you're by far the best thing
that's ever happened to us.
So here's to another 24.
(people cheering)
- Time for cake!
- Cake, everybody!
♪♪♪
No, no, no. Listen to me.
Listen. That's just too risky
in my opinion, OK?
We've got to be more careful.
I gotta go. I'll talk
to you later, OK?
Sweetheart, what are you
doing up? You feeling OK?
Who was that?
Walter.
Some new fund he wants us
to invest in.
Hmm... Walter works late.
Yeah. I don't think
the guy ever sleeps.
And speaking of sleep,
I am exhausted.
I'm gonna go to bed.
Are you coming?
Yeah. I'll be up in a minute.
OK. I'll see you up there.
♪♪♪
(sighing)
(indistinct chatter)
It's been two weeks
since that guy
tried to rob my dad
and the police have nothing.
They're worthless,
not a single suspect!
Well, they weren't hurt,
so I doubt it's the top
of their priority list.
(ambient music playing)
It's good
to see you and your stepmom
getting along better than ever.
Yeah. I've learned to keep the peace.
My dad hates it when I call her out.
She's good to your dad.
Be appreciative of that.
She's good at
spending his money.
She's been living off him
for what, the past 10 years?
- Why do you hate her so much?
- I don't hate her.
I just don't trust her.
You can just never get
a straight answer out of her.
She's always
intentionally vague.
I can see how that would
drive someone like you nuts;
You're the complete opposite.
Thank you. I'll take that
as a compliment.
(disquieting music)
"Division of Vital Records."
(knocking)
- Come in.
- Sorry to interrupt, sweetie.
- No, don't worry about it.
Trust me, any break
from statistics is a good one.
♪♪♪
This came for you.
You know what this is,
don't you?
I have an idea.
"Dear Miss Ashley Beck Ford,
"we received your request
"for your original
non-certified birth record.
"Our records indicate
that you were born
"in Philadelphia County
to Miss Sara Ann Gilbert.
"Date of birth:
September 29th, 1978."
"No father was listed."
"And the name given
to you at birth was..."
"Emily Ann Gilbert."
♪♪♪
Emily Ann.
She wanted me to have
the same middle name as her.
I'm sorry. I-I don't know
why I'm getting so emotional.
Oh, Ashley.
(sniffling)
- Are you going somewhere?
- Yeah.
Denver for meetings.
Back Tuesday.
Oh. Why so long?
Just... I have a lot
to accomplish, that's all.
- You used to take me with you.
- Can't do it this time.
Gotta focus on work.
But I won't be
a distraction. I'll just...
lay out by the pool;
I'll get massaged.
Next time.
Gotta go. Call you tonight.
OK.
♪♪♪
(beep) (sighing)
Why did you have to have
such a common name?
(typing)
(beep)
Oh, my God!
I found you.
This is a really nice letter,
If I got this
from the daughter I gave up,
I'd wanna meet her.
Really? You think so?
Should I have
written it by hand?
No, I don't think you have to.
Like, you signed it and...
the important thing is you let her
know that you don't blame her.
(pop song playing)
Will you deliver it for me?
Me? Why don't you
just put it in the mail?
I don't know if she has
kids or something.
What if they don't know
about me? I just wanna make sure
- she gets it in person.
- OK.
I'll do it tomorrow morning.
Thank you.
♪♪♪
(beeping)
(fast beeping)
(regular beeping)
(distressing music)
(sighing)
♪♪♪
(creaking) ♪♪♪
(creaking)
♪♪♪
(sighing)
(click)
Sara, you don't need these.
♪♪♪
Just go to bed.
(doorbell ringing)
I'll get it.
Hey. I'm looking
for Sara Hillman.
Yeah. That's me.
It's private, just FYI.
Thanks.
♪♪♪
(indistinct chatter)
(cell phone ringing)
Hello?
(sighing)
- Ashley, is this you?
Yes.
Oh, my.
Ashley, it's Sara.
This is your mother.
[I-I got your letter.]
[I just want you to know how
happy it made me.]
I can't believe you found me.
I would love
to meet you in person.
When are you free?
Uh, t-today, this afternoon.
I mean, if you're available...
[Yes! Yes!]
Today, today is perfect.
Any time in the afternoon,
it's... it's good for me.
Um, you have my address?
OK. Yes, of course.
I'll... I'll see you soon!
[I'm really looking
forward to meeting you.]
[Me too.] - We have
so much to catch up on.
♪♪♪
(sighing)
(deep breath)
You've finally
come back to me...
my beautiful little girl.
♪♪♪
Wow!
(doorbell ringing)
Ashley!
Hi.
I can't believe
you're really here!
Look at you.
What a beautiful
young woman you are!
Thank you. These are for you.
Thank you.
They're, they're,
they're gorgeous.
You have no idea how long
I've waited for this moment.
- Really?
- Yeah.
It's the happiest day
of my life.
Come on.
(housekeeper):
Do you want sugar or cream?
(Ashley): No thank you.
Black is fine.
I'm so sorry you don't get to
meet my husband Trevor today.
That's all right. Next time.
Next time, yes, for sure.
- So... where do we start?
- Uh...
Maybe with why?
Yeah, why I gave you up.
I'm sure you've wondered
about that your entire life.
Well, I was, um...
I was very young
when I met your father.
I had been staying with friends
and, um, they took me
to this party, and he was there.
We spent the night together.
I never saw him
again after that.
I didn't know his last name.
My friends didn't either.
I think his first name was Roy.
(disquieting music)
He was quite tall.
He was very attractive.
And I'm guessing he never knew
you were pregnant.
You know what?
I think that the past
is really important
to talk about,
and we should talk
about it, all of it,
eventually, but...
I just really wanna know
more about you right now.
Well, uh, I'm in grad school.
I'm studying to become
a pediatrician.
I don't have any brothers
or sisters,
but I was adopted by these
two wonderful women who...
(woman): Sarah?
Oh!
I'm sorry. I didn't realize
you had company.
Oh, no, no, it's fine.
It's fine.
Hi. I'm Amy, Trevor's daughter.
Nice to meet you. Uh, Ashley.
Ashley is the daughter
of an old friend of mine.
The last time we saw each other,
she was... she was just a baby.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Wow!
Do you need something?
Um, your father's in Denver.
I, uh... I just stopped by
to get my jacket
that I left here
the other night.
OK, well, it's probably
in the closet.
OK.
I'm sorry. I didn't catch
your last name.
It's Beck Ford.
Got it.
I'm so sorry, honey.
I'm so sorry. Please don't think
that I lied about who you are
because... because I'm ashamed
or anything like that.
It's just that, um...
Trevor and Amy don't know
that I gave up a daughter.
I understand. It's fine.
I'm gonna tell Trevor tonight
when he gets home.
No, please don't feel
obligated to
just because of me.
No. I, I want to.
I-I just want Trevor
to know before Amy.
I see.
(disquieting music)
Stupid bitch!
How could you?
Damn you, Kelsie.
You were happy in Miami.
Talk about keeping secrets.
You never thought to mention
that you had a daughter? Please.
- Uh... OK. All right.
- OK, give me this.
Well, I didn't know
where she was
or if she was even still alive.
When I gave her up
from the hospital,
they said that she'd never be
able to find me
or that I'd have no way of
knowing what happened to her.
Babe, what's the big deal?
You have a daughter.
Uh, yeah, and I think I mentioned
that on our first date.
OK. I get it.
I should have said something.
Can't you just be happy for me
that we reconnected?
It's not that Ashley exists. It's that
you didn't tell me that she does.
Please. She just wants
a relationship with me, OK?
She just wants to know more
about herself, more about me.
I'm just surprised
that you trusted her so quickly.
(Sara sighing)
You're usually so skeptical
with everyone that you meet.
No, I'm not.
Babe, listen to me.
I'm really happy
that she found me.
OK. She's a part of my past
that's good
and I wanna embrace it, and her.
- I hope you're right.
- Wait until you meet her.
You're gonna see what
I'm talking about.
Mm-hmm. Um,
are there any other secrets
from your past
that I should know about?
You know, besides the one
where you went to jail when
you were 18 for forging cheques
or - haha -
the medical fraud one.
That was a good one.
OK. I was 25.
I didn't have insurance.
And now a child.
Babe, I promise,
there's no more secrets.
Yeah, that's it. Now you know
everything about me. Do I?
- I swear.
- OK.
- I love you.
Hey, Mike. I was gonna call you
later on tonight. What's up?
[Hey.]
Uh, yeah. Someone tried to break
into my apartment last night.
- What?!
- [Yeah.]
[They messed up the frame and
the lock pretty good.]
Landlord said he was gonna have
to have it rekeyed.
So what time did this happen?
Uh, did you hear them?
Yeah. I don't really know. You
know I'm a pretty heavy sleeper.
What's going on?
Someone tried to break into
Michael's apartment last night.
[Were you drunk?]
- No.
Is he OK?
I had a few drinks,
but not that many.
I don't know why anybody
would want to break in here.
There's literally
nothing to steal.
Yeah. Weird timing, right?
Someone tries to rob me
the other night and now you.
[Yeah.]
♪♪♪
Hey, you don't think
that it could've been somebody
you pissed off, do you?
No, I don't.
Listen, I gotta get going.
Um, I'm gonna
call you later tonight.
And if you need a place to stay,
feel free to come over here, OK?
Thanks, man.
I gotta wait around
for the locksmith.
All right. Talk to you soon.
What's he talking about?
What guys did you piss off?
Nothing. I guarantee
they had nothing to do with it.
Are you in some kind of trouble?
Of course not. Look,
a couple of years ago, Mike
and I did a deal with these guys
and they were being
investigated by the feds.
We didn't know that at the time.
The feds contacted us,
and we cooperated. That's it.
But if Michael thinks that
they might be retaliating...
Well, then they're not
very good at their job,
are they? Zero for two.
♪♪♪
(exhaling)
(doorbell ringing)
So what is it
that your mothers do, Ashley?
Well, Kelly works
as a physical therapist.
She actually just went back
to work as soon as I finished
high school. And Marcella's
the branch manager of a bank.
They're both successful.
You must be so proud.
I am. They're amazing women.
Sara had a business
at one point,
importing and selling jewelry.
Whatever happened to that? Ahem!
Uh, well, we were
travelling in Africa and found
some beautiful jewelry that was
made by these village women,
so I decided to open up a shop.
- Sounds like a great idea.
- Uh, well, it was
a little bit more time-consuming
of an endeavour
than I imagined,
travelling all the time.
(Amy scoffing)
Is there a problem, Amy?
No. I just always thought
you stopped because
of the incident on the plane.
Something happened on a plane?
How dare you insult me
in front of my own daughter!
You invited her
knowing she would do this.
- Told you it was gonna happen.
- Yeah, but did you have to bring it up?
It's always something!
(Amy sighing)
Good luck with all that.
I'm sure you're happy
you found your mom
but trust me,
your life is about to get
a hell of a lot
more complicated.
(Amy sighing)
(unsettling music)
Amy's always disparaging me.
The incident on the plane
was nothing.
I had a panic attack,
so they had to return
to the gate to let me off.
Why do you think
Amy doesn't like you?
Because she thinks that I am
after her father's money,
but that's not true.
I'm really sorry that you had
to witness that drama
with she and I.
- Hey, it's OK.
- Yeah?
I want to get to know you,
be a part of your life,
and not just the good parts.
I needed you to find me.
♪♪♪
I really, really did.
I feel sorry for her, you know.
I mean, it was kind of mean to
invite Amy without telling her.
True. Just be careful.
Technically,
she's still a stranger.
I know. I guess that's
something I'm gonna have
to try and figure out.
Figure out what, you or her?
Both.
Understanding her
might give me some insight.
Wait, what are you
confused about?
You're one of the most
well-adjusted people I know.
I wonder how my moms
will deal with all this.
They really didn't tell me
anything about it.
Your moms are gonna be fine.
It's not like you're abandoning
them to move in with Sara.
That's true.
I haven't even moved in
with you yet.
I'm not gonna wait forever.
Yeah, you will.
All right, I will.
(Trevor): No one's trying
to embarrass you, Sara.
Amy was and you know it.
Look, we don't know
what we're allowed to say
and what we're not allowed to
say. You have so many secrets,
not even you can keep them straight.
That's not true.
What you did was more
embarrassing than what Amy said!
I mean, why the hell
did you have to jump
out of the chair like that?
How did you want me to react?!
I don't know
how you're gonna react!
That's the problem!
I'm living with someone
who half the time is manic
and the other half is secretive,
and I don't know
what's gonna come next!
Are you gonna get angry
at nothing, uh, paranoid?
Is another skeleton gonna jump
out of your closet at me?
No, no! Don't you dare
turn this around!
You knew how important that
dinner was to me! You did this
on purpose to get back at me because
you knew I didn't tell you about her!
Yeah, that's what I did.
I'm gonna sleep
in the other room tonight.
(angrily): Good! ♪♪♪
(heavy breathing)
(crying)
(screaming)
(gasping)
(disquieting music) (sighing)
♪♪♪
(panting)
(indistinct chatter)
(cell phone ringing)
- Hi, Sara.
- Where are you right now?
I'm on campus.
I have classes today.
I need you to come to the house.
Why? What's wrong?
♪♪♪
Trevor's been murdered.
- Sara?
- Oh, Ashley!
Thank you so much for coming!
They won't let me back
inside the house.
They haven't, um,
taken his body out yet.
- What happened?
- Yeah. So...
Oh, my God! Michael!
Michael, thank you
so much for coming!
- I am so sorry.
- Tell me
this is just a bad dream,
this is a nightmare.
♪♪♪
Oh, this is my daughter Ashley.
We-we-we just
reconnected recently.
Where's Amy?
I haven't told her.
I-I-I... I couldn't do it.
I... I can't do it. I'll do it.
Hey, what happened?
I don't know. I...
I was, um, I was in the kitchen
and then I just noticed
some blood.
And then, um...
I went into the guest bedroom.
It was horrible!
We... we... we had a fight
and, and that's why
he slept alone.
- Was the security system on?
- Yeah.
Trevor always set it
and so I just assumed
that he did.
- He always does.
- You didn't
see or hear anything?
The police asked me
the same question. No.
No, no, no, no, I didn't.
I... I sometimes take
these pills to sleep and, um,
they're really strong.
But I haven't taken them
in a long time.
It's just that I was really
shaken up about the fight.
Just relax, OK?
Nobody's accusing you
of doing anything wrong.
I didn't!
I didn't do anything wrong!
I... I loved him! You know that!
I know.
I'm gonna call Amy. ♪♪♪
You don't think I had
anything to do with it, do you?
Ashley, you believe me, right?
You believe me?
I didn't have
anything to do with it.
Yes, of course I believe you.
(sniffling)
- OK. OK. Thank you.
♪♪♪
As a brother, Trevor was
always generous
and supportive and kind.
He was always there for me
in difficult times.
I was in such a funk,
I was, uh...
drinking all the time.
And if it weren't for Trevor,
I don't even know
if I'd be here today.
I don't know why anyone
would want to hurt him.
But my brother's death
will not go unpunished.
♪♪♪
I'm making it my mission
to find who did this.
- OK.
- Thank you so much for coming.
Thank you.
- Sara.
- Kelsie.
- I'm so sorry.
- Thank you, Kelsie.
Thank you. This is Ashley.
This is my daughter. Ashley,
this is Kelsie Hillman,
Michael's ex-wife.
Hello. I didn't realize
you had a daughter.
- No, we recently reconnected.
- I see.
Well, I just wanted
to tell you how sorry I am.
Trevor was
an extraordinary person.
I'm just gonna be
right over there.
Amy, I just wanted to say
I'm so sorry about your father.
It looks like he touched
a lot of people's lives.
Yeah.
Apparently, he touched at least
one person the wrong way.
Well, I'm sure
the police will be able to...
The police? They're looking
at your mother as a possible
suspect, did you know that?
I mean, the spouse is always
suspected so I assumed.
Don't believe
everything she tells you.
Why not?
You never quite get
the whole truth.
What has she lied about?
♪♪♪
Let's just say
I wouldn't be surprised if
she had something to do with it.
- Your father's murder?
- She had a lot of secrets.
(Sara): It's hard to be back
in this house.
Maybe you should stay
with some friends,
just for a little bit.
Yeah, maybe.
(Sara sighing)
(disquieting music)
Do you mind my asking...?
What do you think
happened that night?
We fought.
Trevor took Amy's side
after that horrible dinner.
She's always resented me, Amy.
Never gave me a chance.
Anyway, he decided to sleep
in the guest bedroom
and I guess,
with all the drama, he must have
forgotten to set the alarm.
But... whoever did this...
wouldn't they assume that
he'd be in the master bedroom?
♪♪♪
(mumbling)
- I'm just...
I mean that...
they probably went
in there first,
so why not
kill both of you?
Because they wanted
Trevor dead, not me.
That's probably
why Amy thinks I'm involved.
Did Trevor have
a lot of enemies?
(scoffing)
Trevor was a kind man,
if he liked you.
If he didn't,
he could be ruthless.
Was he ruthless
to a lot of people?
Yeah, more than he should
have been.
I think this has something to do
with some clients that he had
that were being investigated
by the feds.
Like what?
I don't know.
He was talking on the phone
with Michael about it.
They mentioned it.
And I think Michael thought
it was a problem,
but Trevor didn't.
(Ben): What do you think about what the
daughter said, that Sara could be behind it?
(soft jazz playing)
- Look,
Sara's a little weird, yeah,
but... I really don't think
she's capable of murder.
I mean, she just seems
so weak and fragile,
like she's on the edge
of a nervous breakdown.
And I think Sara needed Trevor
a lot more than he needed her.
Ashley, you need
to let the police handle it.
Do not get involved
in this mess.
Hey, I'm serious.
Who's ever behind this is not
afraid of committing murder.
(distant siren blaring) ♪♪♪
Hi!
Ashley? What...
what are you doing here?
Uh, I was just wondering
if you maybe wanted
to grab a bite to eat?
Or...?
Yeah. Just meet out front of
the building five minutes.
All right, uh...
Thanks.
Ahem!
So...
what did you want to discuss?
I guess what I really wanna
know is your opinion
on whether or not you think Sara
could have been involved somehow.
My brother's relationships
were all unusual,
his marriages included.
Trevor and Sara
had their problems,
but what marriage doesn't?
What kind of problems?
Well, I'm really only
getting it from his side,
but, uh...
I know he used to hate
how secretive she was,
how, uh, how she had
a checkered past.
He hated how many pills
she was on.
Found them hidden
all over the house.
(indistinct song playing)
Was she ever violent though?
One assault charge.
An ex, maybe. I don't know.
Assault?
That doesn't sound like Sara.
Sara's changed a lot
in the last 10 years.
When I first met her,
she was, uh,
hard, kind of tough.
She'd anger really easily.
You couldn't really get
through those walls, but...
Trevor brought
the best out in her.
Amy thinks Sara could have had
something to do with it.
She told me at the funeral.
Well, Amy, uh,
never really liked
or accepted Sara, so you're
gonna have to take what she says
with a grain of salt.
Sara said that you and Trevor
were involved
in an investigation.
Do you know anything about that?
(ominous music)
What makes her think that?
I don't know. Overheard Trevor
talking about it, I guess.
No. Uh...
yeah, we have clients, but
nothing ever happened with them.
What about other clients.
Sara said that Trevor
could be ruthless at times.
Well, she's right about that.
You never wanted
to get on Trevor's bad side.
You're jumping to conclusions.
Mom! OK, think about it
like this.
Someone tries to rob Trevor
after leaving a restaurant -
not successfully but still -
and then someone almost breaks
into Michael's apartment,
And then Trevor's murdered
in his own home, but they don't
do anything to Sara.
I mean, if that doesn't sound
like a hit,
I have no idea what does.
Yeah, but aren't the police
looking into all this?
- Yeah, probably.
- Look,
I think you just stay out of it.
I mean, nothing good
is gonna come
from you playing Nancy Drew.
- You sound like Ben.
- Ben's smart.
I'm not investigating,
I'm just...
I don't know what I'm doing.
Look, you're trying
to find out if Sara's involved
because you want
a relationship with her.
I get that.
Yeah.
I just really hope
she's not involved.
The biggest fear
Mamacita and I had
about you finding her
was that you'd get hurt.
♪♪♪
You know it's better
to always know the truth,
even if it's not
what you want to hear.
So what if she is involved?
What then?
(cell phone dinging and buzzing)
It's her.
She's meeting
with a probate attorney tomorrow
and wants me to go with her.
Should I?
Honey, that's...
that's up to you.
♪♪♪
(honk)
Thank you so much
for meeting me here.
I had no idea you were
gonna do that. I... I thought
we were just here to discuss
your inheritance from Trevor.
- We did.
- I know, but you're having
your lawyer write up
a whole new will and leaving
everything to me.
You're my daughter.
It's just a lot to take in.
I don't think you understand
how much it means to me
that you came looking for me,
you know. And with
everything going on right now,
I'm really, really happy
to have you back in my life.
I know Amy suspects
that I had something to do
with her father's death
and the police do too, I'm sure.
And, yeah, I'm gonna
inherit a lot of money,
but that doesn't mean
that I wanted him dead, ever.
I'd give every penny back
to have him here with me.
♪♪♪
(siren bleep)
- What's going on?
- Sara Hillman,
you're under arrest for
the murder of Trevor Hillman.
- What?! OK.
- You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say can
and will be held against you.
(gasping) What's going on?
(heavy breathing) Something's
wrong with her, call it in!
This is Unit 4-14.
I have a 10-52.
- Sara!
- Subject in custody. Appears to be having a medical emergency.
Sara! SARA!
(intercom): Paging Dr. Humphrey.
Paging Dr. Humphrey.
- Ashley!
- Hi.
She's in surgery right now.
They're performing
a coronary angioplasty.
Were you at her house
when she collapsed?
Yeah. We'd just got back
from seeing her lawyer.
It happened
while she was being arrested.
Ashley,
don't you think that maybe
you need to put some distance
between you and Sara?
Are you serious?
I can't just abandon her now!
Wait, but you said
that if she was guilty...
We don't know that she's guilty. I mean,
just because she was arrested doesn't...
Do you understand
how much evidence police need
to get an arrest warrant?
They obviously have something
substantial. It doesn't matter.
Look, I can't turn
my back on her now.
The rest of the world,
you guys can all do that,
but I'm not gonna
do that to her!
She didn't mean it like that.
I'll go talk to her.
Oh, thank you, Ben. Thank you.
That wasn't fair,
what you said to them.
What's not fair is them
asking me to bail on her.
She needs me now more than ever.
I get that.
They're just worried about you.
I'm worried about you.
I don't think she did this, Ben!
(phone ringing)
[Hello?]
- Ashley, it's me.
- [Oh, hi.]
- They finally gave me
permission to make
a couple of calls.
Uh, that's OK.
How are you doing?
(sighing)
- I feel OK.
Like, no major pain.
That's good.
I... I tried to visit you
after surgery,
but they wouldn't let me.
I know. The nurse told me.
Is there anyone you need me
to contact for you? A lawyer?
No. I did.
He's meeting me tomorrow.
I want you to know
that I'm innocent, Ashley.
(unsettling music)
The police think
that I did it but I...
[I swear I didn't.]
I think it's Michael and
Trevor, the clients of theirs.
Well, how do I find out
more about them?
- Michael.
- [I already spoke to him.]
He said they're not involved
and there's no investigation
going on.
Maybe Trevor has information
on his files,
[the ones on his computer.]
OK. Uh, how do I get
into the house without the key?
[There's a key]
On that light
on the front patio.
And how do I get
onto his computer?
(sighing)
I don't know. Maybe Amy?
[Maybe he gave it to Amy?]
♪♪♪
(sighing)
(ominous music)
That's weird.
I thought he'd have
- a password.
- That was quick!
You always go through other people's
computers? Amy, you scared me.
- What are you doing here?
- Sara told me where the spare key was.
Doesn't answer my question!
What are you doing here?
I'm just trying to find out
who killed your father.
Wow! She really has you
fooled, doesn't she?
Look, I know you think Sara
did this, but I'm not so sure.
And I'm not just saying that
because she's my mother.
(Amy): I hate to say this,
but Sara had the most to gain,
and I think she tried before.
What do you mean you think
she tried before?
A couple of weeks ago,
after we went out
to a restaurant,
a man with a gun
tried to rob him.
My dad got the gun away from him
and the guy ran off.
So you think she hired someone?
Well, from my understanding,
the guy never approached Sara,
only my dad.
What about the other night when someone tried
to break in to your uncle's apartment?
I mean, that has to have
something to do with this!
Random coincidence,
or maybe Michael imagined it
in one of his episodes.
He drinks a lot, Ashley.
Ever since his wife left him, he
goes through a bottle a night.
My dad kept trying to get him
to go to rehab, but he wouldn't.
Or...
it's part of Sara's plan to try
and get the cops off her tail.
(Sara sighing)
(doorbell ringing)
- Can I help you?
- I have a warrant
to do an additional search
of the premises.
I'm sorry. What's going on?
Could you wait
for us outside, please?
Uh...
I understand,
but we can only do that
if you maintain a balance in your
money-market account. Thank you.
Once the transfer's gone
through, it shouldn't be
a problem. Of course.
You're welcome.
(unsettling music)
Oh, my God!
Thank you so much for coming.
Of course.
What's going on?
I don't know exactly.
But I overheard and...
I think they found a knife
with dried blood on it.
Wait, in the house? How come
they didn't find that before?
Apparently, it was in
a hidden cupboard or something.
Wherever it was, they must not have
searched there the first time.
What set all this off:
The search warrant
or Sara's arrest yesterday?
I didn't catch all of it,
but it sounded
like they got an anonymous tip
from someone that Sara threw out
a bloody nightgown in the trash
in the middle of the night.
Babe, I hate to say this,
but it's really starting
to sound like she's guilty.
You hired a private investigator
to run a background check on Sara?
She did it
right after you found her.
I just wanted to make sure there is nothing
about her you needed protection from.
There's quite a bit in there:
Previous addresses, employment
history, vital records.
There's a lot
you don't know about her.
I know.
I lied about a lot of things.
You lied
about almost everything.
And what you didn't lie about,
you completely made up.
Yeah, I know.
Why? Why would you
do that to me?
I came to you wanting
to know who you were,
what your life was like...
why you gave me up.
I couldn't tell you the truth:
That when I got pregnant
with you, I was an escort,
that I don't know
who your real dad is...
that I'd been arrested six times
and I was a drug addict.
I was so happy when you found me
and I just figured...
I figured if you knew
any of that,
you would have walked away
and never contacted me again.
So you basically made up
a person that didn't exist.
No. I let you into my life
the way it is now.
I went to rehab
and I met a guy there,
and he helped me
turn my life around.
And a year later, I met Trevor.
- That is such a load of crap!
- Hey, you know what?
(menacing music)
You wanna know
the truth about me?
I'll tell you the truth.
I was not a good person, Ashley.
I used people.
I wasted every opportunity
that was given to me.
I drank a lot and I did
a lot of drugs.
But you know what?
I am not that person anymore.
I am a completely
different person.
OK.
I need you to be honest
with me, for once.
Did you kill Trevor?
No.
Then why would you throw away
a nightgown with blood on it?
I don't know! I didn't!
I didn't!
I don't even leave
the house at night!
Whoever called in that tip
must have put it there!
Somebody is trying to frame me!
Don't give up on me.
Please, I need you.
My lawyer doesn't think
I'm gonna make bail.
Why not?
Because a few years ago,
I skipped out
when I was arrested
for shoplifting.
(scoffing)
- Geez.
- My hearing is
the day after tomorrow at 2 p.m.
Will you be there?
I don't know.
Can you...?
♪♪♪
(sighing)
(car door opening)
- Amy?
- You weren't answering
my texts. I got worried.
(Ashley sighing)
It's been a rough 48 hours.
Come on in.
I wanna believe she's innocent,
but, honestly,
I'm not so sure anymore.
And just lied
about so many things.
I know this is
gonna sound crazy,
but I think Sara's right.
Someone's trying to frame her.
- Why would you say that?
- The knife they found,
it was in a hidden cupboard.
OK...
I don't think that Sara even
knows that cupboard exists.
But more importantly,
the knife was not there
two days ago.
And how do you know this?
The night that we both ended
up there at the same time,
I looked in the cupboard,
and it wasn't there.
Nothing was.
And then it magically appeared
the following day.
Why were you looking in there?
I was looking for something
that my dad would have wanted
to keep hidden from Sara:
Threatening letters,
legal papers,
I don't know.
My dad used to hide gifts
for my mom there
when she was still alive.
I didn't really expect
to find anything but I...
I figured it was worth a shot.
- And is there anyone else who knows about it?
- Not sure,
but the killer obviously knew
the layout of the house.
Amy, you have to go
to the police with this.
I don't know
how receptive they'll be.
They think they have
their person.
We need something concrete.
OK. Let's start by making
a list of everyone that went
in and out of the house.
The housekeeper, she wouldn't
have anything to do with this.
The police,
although I don't know
why they would want
to frame your mother.
Michael?
Possibly.
He did use to house sit for them
from time to time.
You...
You think I could have
killed my father?!
- No. I'm just saying you had access.
- I loved my father!
He wasn't always a good person,
but he was always good to me
and he did not deserve
what happened to him! Look,
I know it's no secret
that I don't like Sara,
but I do not wanna see
an innocent person go to prison
while the person who murdered
my father is still out there!
Whoever did this needs to pay.
I'm sorry. I-I believe you. I...
I want the exact same thing
that you do.
(sighing)
There is another possibility.
Who?
I'm pretty sure my father
was having an affair.
I don't know who it was with,
but one day we were
at a restaurant,
and he got a text from her
while he was in the restroom.
I saw it come up on his phone.
So maybe her husband found out
or Trevor broke it off with her
and she got jealous?
It's worth looking into.
How do we start?
So, basically, we're looking
for any hotel receipts
or any restaurant receipts
where two people ate.
There's probably
a million of them, but yes.
(sighing) What about your uncle?
It seemed like
they were pretty close.
Given that Kelsie
was cheating on Michael,
I doubt my dad would have
been likely to tell Michael
he was doing
the same thing to Sara.
Yeah, you're probably right
on that.
(suspenseful music)
(sinister music)
(doorbell ringing)
(tablet bleeping)
- Michael,
what are you doing here?
[I need to see you.]
- No, you don't. Go home.
- I just lost my brother.
For Christ's sake,
have some compassion.
I am sorry about Trevor,
but nothing good
is gonna come from us talking.
Please, go home!
How could you do that to me?
How?
He was my brother.
I don't know what you're
taking about. You're drunk!
[Two people I love the most,
and you betray me like that?]
[How? How?!] (bottle shattering)
I did everything for you.
What are you talking
about right now?
You know what I'm talking about. Did
you really think I wouldn't find out?
[Of all the people]
In the world, you had to choose
my brother, my own brother!
[Everything]
That has happened has happened
because of you!
It is all your fault.
What do you mean "everything"?
♪♪♪
- I shouldn't be here.
- Michael!
[Michael!]
And another one
from the same restaurant.
Again, always paid in cash.
And look, they all are
between 7 and 8 p.m.
Let me see.
Now that's interesting.
It looks like these are
all with the same person.
How do you know that?
Well, the pasta Alfredo was
ordered every single time,
along with a glass
of the same type of wine,
a Bellay Chardonnay.
Did your dad always eat
the same thing?
No, and he hated pasta Alfredo.
See, there's a scotch and water
on each of these.
That's what he ordered.
Ooh, can you pull up
the calendar? Let's see what day
of the week these all fell on.
OK.
Um... Thursday.
This one's Thursday too.
And a Tuesday,
and another Thursday.
So almost always on a Thursday.
Tomorrow's a Thursday.
I can't believe none of
the servers remember by father.
The hostess did say there were a lot of servers
off tonight. And it doesn't exactly help
that they don't keep
regular hours.
Hey, uh, excuse me. Have you
ever seen this man before?
He comes in a lot
on Thursday nights.
Yeah, of course.
Uh, drives a Jag,
always comes with a lady
with dark hair, good tipper.
And you say they come in
together every Thursday?
Yeah. Well, no.
They arrive separately,
but he always pays
for her car too.
And what type of car
does she drive?
A red SUV, leather interior.
Did he ever mention her name?
Look,
nobody's gonna know
the information came from you.
You're not gonna get in trouble.
The man in the photo,
it's my father,
and I desperately need to know
more about the woman he was...
he was dating.
I guess I'm not the only one
with a complicated father.
Mine's been married four times.
Look, I don't know her name,
but I know where she works.
- How?
- There's a sticker, like a...
like a parking pass for
employees on the windshield.
- Where from?
- Truxton Medical Centre.
♪♪♪
OK. Thank you so much.
Hey, what's wrong?
Do you know who it is?
It can't be.
So your dad was having
an affair with Michael's wife,
his own sister-in-law?
Sure seems that way.
You didn't see what kind of car
Kelsie was driving
- at the funeral, did you?
- No.
Let's go find out.
That looks like the car.
Let's go see if it has
the sticker on it, OK?
OK. ♪♪♪
Yep. That's the parking pass.
I can't believe
that she would do this,
that he would do this
to his own brother!
- I'm sorry.
- Amy?
- What do we do now?
- I guess we ask her if she was
sleeping with my father.
Your father.
We would meet up once a week
on Thursday nights when Michael
was playing racquetball.
How long had the affair
been going on?
Two, three years
before I told Michael
I wanted a divorce,
that I was in love
with someone else.
He asked me so many times who it was
but, of course, I never told him.
Were you planning
on being together?
Trevor would talk
about it at times,
that he wanted to divorce Sara
and marry me,
but I knew he wouldn't.
I was content with
the little time I had with him.
I know it's hard to comprehend.
How could he do that to Michael?
But you don't know what it was
like living with him.
♪♪♪
He'd... disappear
for days at a time,
but that was better
than when he came home drunk.
I was scared of him
when he drank. He could be
angry and violent.
It was hell.
There's no other way
to describe it,
and Trevor could
understand that.
One of the first reasons
I started seeing him alone
was to get advice
on how to deal with his brother.
How could you come
between two brothers like that?
Dad and Michael were so close.
Between them?
Michael despised Trevor.
Trevor brought him down
every chance he got,
embarrassed him all the time.
Michael gave him
plenty of reason to.
Your father constantly had
to fix Michael's screw-ups.
Did Michael ever find out
about the affair?
I didn't realize he had,
- but I think so.
- When?
I don't know.
Wait. I'm confused.
How did you know that he knew?
I'm not sure exactly.
But you are sure.
There's something
you're not telling us.
- No, I'm not!
- Please.
An innocent woman is sitting
in prison right now
for something she didn't do.
If you believe that Michael
could have anything to do
with Trevor's murder,
you need to tell us.
I miss your father.
I miss him
just as much as
anyone else does. It's my fault.
If we hadn't had the affair,
Trevor would still be alive.
What do you mean?
He didn't say it
outright, but...
I got a sense that
he's the one who did it.
OK. You need to tell us
exactly what he said.
(sighing)
(alarming music)
(inaudible speaking)
Kelsie, you need to go
to the police with this.
No. I've caused Michael
enough pain.
I just want all of this
to go away.
Kelsie, we're talking
about the man that you loved!
Don't you want to see
my father's murder solved?
Of course!
But if the police find evidence
and a reason to arrest him,
it won't be because of me.
Well, what about
doing the right thing?
Legally, I'm still married
to Michael
and I don't have to testify
against my husband!
There's nothing to say
to make me change my mind!
(Ashley):
She believes he did it.
Yeah, but you heard her.
She refuses to go to the police.
Besides, what he said
wasn't exactly a confession.
Then we need
to find proof of the affair.
It gives Michael motive.
Come on.
(car engine revving up)
(car driving by)
Yeah, we have a problem.
(blues music playing)
♪ It rained ♪
♪ So much in this town ♪
(indistinct conversations)
♪ Feels like it was meant
just for me ♪
Cheers.
What's so urgent?
I think
Sara's daughter's onto us.
What makes you think that?
She and Amy
were over at Kelsie's.
How do you know that?
Kelsie told you?
No. I, uh... I saw them there.
You were at Kelsie's?
No. Yes,
but I... I just wanted
to make sure
she was alone, OK?
She didn't know I was there.
Whatever, man.
It's not important.
The point is they were there,
both of them together,
probably asking
questions about me.
So what? Kelsie doesn't know
anything, does she?
Does she?
No. But if Ashley thinks
that Sara is innocent and if
they keep digging around...
They won't find anything.
What if they do?
What if you made a mistake?
I didn't. And if you're
thinking of bringing up
what happened
in the alley, don't.
No one would predict
that your brother
would jump me when I had a gun.
So did they find
anything or not?
Not yet.
But I've known Amy
her whole life and she is smart.
Does Kelsie know
something or not?
No.
You need to stop.
The more you drink,
the more of a liability
you are to both of us.
You're calling the shots now?
Yeah. It's my neck
that's on the line
if you get wasted
and whine to the wrong person
about that affair.
Go up to your cabin
and dry out for a few days.
Burn all those stupid photos
of Trevor with your wife
and get a... damned grip.
You hear me?
Kelsie told you that?
That she thinks
Michael hired someone
and that she and Trevor
were sleeping together?
I am so sorry
that we didn't
believe you before,
but we both believe you now.
Look, Sara,
obviously Michael is
trying to frame you.
We think that if we can
go to the police
with proof of the affair,
then maybe they can
convince Kelsie to talk.
Or at the very least,
just dig a little deeper
into his finances
and see if he could have
hired someone.
I always wondered
if Trevor was being unfaithful.
I used to call his hotel room
late at night
and he wouldn't
pick up the phone.
He always made it seem
like the pills
were making me paranoid.
Makes sense it was Kelsie.
Is there anything
you can think that could help us
prove to the cops that they were
sleeping together?
No.
I think he was quite successful
at hiding his affair.
Maybe going
through Dad's credit cards
could yield something:
Hotel stays, gifts.
Listen to me.
If Michael is capable
of hiring somebody
to murder his brother
and framing me,
he is way more dangerous
than I imagined.
I'm worried you two
are in over your heads.
If the police won't dig until
they uncover the truth,
then Amy and I will.
(sighing)
(Ashley sighing)
There's nothing here.
Kelsie said the affair
went back three years, so...
maybe we just need to check his
phone records from back then.
(cell phone ringing) ♪♪♪
Hey, babe.
Sara's just on the news.
Look at Channel 7
[on your phone.]
- What? Why?
She pled guilty to
Trevor's murder. ♪♪♪
But seriously,
why would she plead guilty?
Sara's just trying
to protect you.
It's probably the most
selfless thing she's ever done.
I'm not saying
Sara did the right thing,
but what you two are doing
is very risky.
But now she's screwed.
And that's why
we need your help.
My help?
♪♪♪
A cheque from Trevor to Michael?
Where did you get this?
We found it when we were going
through my dad's stuff.
It wasn't uncommon for him
to give Michael loans.
And if you look at the back,
it has his account number
and bank. He banks
at Western National.
Oh, no, Ashley, absolutely not.
If you were to just check
and see if there was
any transfers or withdrawals...
I am not gonna put
my career at risk for something that
probably won't yield anything useful anyway.
And, sweetie,
if Michael's smart, and it seems
like he is, I mean,
he's not gonna hire someone
to murder his brother,
then pay him
with a wire transfer.
We don't know
what you'll find.
I'm just saying
even the smallest thing
could be helpful.
- The answer is no.
- I mean, even Amy, who has
literally every reason
to side with Michael
over the stepmother
she can't stand, agrees.
I know you don't want me
involved in all of this,
but I am.
And, yes, it's
because she's my biological mom,
but I can't just sit back
and let some innocent woman
spend the rest of her life
in prison for a murder
she didn't commit.
You're asking me
to break the law.
No. I am just
asking you to look.
Please?
I know it's Michael.
I know it's him.
OK. But if I don't find
anything suspicious
in his account,
will you two just drop
this whole thing and let
Sara's attorney worry
about getting her off?
- Probably not.
- I didn't think so.
♪♪♪
(eerie music)
I can't believe I'm doing this.
Now that's interesting.
♪♪♪
So no cash withdrawals
or transfers?
No, but those are payments
he made to a mortgage company
called Super Term Loans.
I did some research.
It's for a cabin
up in Chambersburg.
- And you think this could be important somehow?
- I don't know.
But it's interesting
that Kelsie's name was never
on the loan.
Remember when she said
Michael would disappear for days
at a time. Maybe this is
where he goes.
Did your dad know about it?
I doubt it.
He would have mentioned it.
If he's hiding evidence
of the murder,
or the affair,
or even of hiring the hit,
there's a better chance
that it's there
than in his apartment
here in Philly.
What do you think?
I think it's time
for a road trip.
The address is in there.
Promise me
you'll both be careful.
♪♪♪
- This is it.
- Let's go check it out.
♪♪♪
Amy, his phone's on the table.
I think he's here.
We should really get going.
Oh, my God!
What are you doing here?
We... we were worried about you.
Kelsie thought
we should check up on you,
just with the stress
of losing your brother
and the divorce
and the drinking.
- How do you know about this place?
- Uh, we...
- How did you find this place?
- I, um... We just...
What are you really doing here?
This is all you, isn't it?
Michael, Michael...
- Michael, no!
- Yeah.
- Yeah, it is.
- Please.
Michael, put the gun down.
- Yes, Michael, please.
- You think that I killed Trevor
so you show up here trying
to find evidence. Not true.
- (Amy): Just put the gun down.
- Yeah, it is.
- It's not true.
- Michael? Michael, just put the gun down!
Not a chance! I am not
letting this little bitch
take me down. Not ever.
Just put the gun down.
Michael, please,
just give me the gun!
Michael?
(menacing music)
(Michael groaning)
(women screaming)
(Amy breathing hard)
I see him! I think
he's running away!
Oh, my God! Michael! Michael!
Call an ambulance!
(Michael hyperventilating)
- Ohhh... son of a bitch!
- [911. What's your emergency?]
(Amy): My uncle has just
been shot. We're at his cabin.
It's at, uh, 712 Waverly Lane.
About 3 miles off the highway!
[Did you see it?]
No. Just send an ambulance!
Please hurry!
- It's no use. They're never gonna be in time.
- That's not true, Michael!
Tell them
it's a sucking chest wound
about a quarter inch
in diameter! Amy, grab me
a trash bag,
a plastic bag, anything, OK?
Amy, hurry! Sucking chest sound
about a quarter inch in diameter.
- [I heard her.]
- Come on, Amy!
[I'm sending help.]
(Michael panting)
- Michael, you're gonna be OK.
- (Amy): Who shot you?
Tell us, Michael, who shot you?
Please, tell us!
(indiscernible murmur)
- What?
- James Wilson. James Wilson.
- (Amy): What?
Why? Why would he want
to kill you?
(heavy breathing)
Because he thinks I'm...
He thinks I'll talk.
Is he the one
- who murdered my father?
- Yes.
Yeah. And I'm the only one
who knows the...
the only one
who could rat him out.
How do you know
he murdered Trevor?
'Cause I hired him. I hired him.
What?
After years of your dad
talking to me
like an idiot and treating me
like I was some kind of moron.
He took the only thing
that I ever loved so...
♪♪♪
We know.
We know about the affair.
It was supposed
to happen the night
we all went out for dinner,
but James messed up
and, yeah... So I gave him
the code to the alarm system
and... and told him
to do it at the house.
(ominous music)
(beeping)
(fast beeping)
I thought that it would be
harder to frame Sara,
but...
it... it really wasn't.
(crying)
- Oh!
Go, go.
Please, just go. No, Michael.
I can save your life.
My life is over.
Please...
I won't be able to speak
in a couple of minutes.
Just let me say
what I have to say.
Trevor... Trevor was...
He was the good-looking one
and the smart one,
the one everybody liked.
When...
when we went
into business together,
I thought things
would change but...
that I could show him
that I-I could... I could do
just as well as he could.
But he kept talking to me
like I was a charity case...
(Amy crying) ...like I was
the idiot brother.
So when I found out that he was
sleeping with Kelsie...
and that she loved him,
I couldn't take it.
I knew James
from some friends years earlier,
and... and when he got
out of prison,
I gave him a call.
(sobbing) Amy...
Amy... (Amy crying)
I am so sorry.
I had... I had no right
to take your father
away from you.
And I had no right to do
what I did to Sara.
She was always good to me.
I'm so sorry.
Can you please
tell Sara that I am sorry?
And...
(Michael breathing laboriously)
tell, tell Kelsie
that I-I never stopped...
I never stopped loving her.
(crying)
♪♪♪
(Amy crying)
Ashley.
Detective? Hi.
I'm just waiting for them
to release my mom.
Good.
Um, I'm sorry.
We got this one wrong.
- I know.
- If it's
any consolation, we were able
to apprehend James Wilson
about an hour ago
trying to cross into Mexico.
Oh, thank God!
That's... that's great news!
- Ashley!
- Mom!
Mom, hi!
Thank you so much
for all you've done for me.
It wasn't just me, Mom.
Amy was there the whole time.
We just knew we had
to find out the truth.
(sniffling)
Thank you. Thank you so much.
- Thank you.
- Let's go.
(piano music)
(car doors closing)
♪♪ Let me wash ♪
♪ Your pain away ♪
Amy.
- Mom.
- ♪ So you can start ♪
♪ Walking again ♪♪
Hi. I'm Sara.
Hi.
♪♪♪
(indistinct speaking)