KM Culture production
Producer Park Moo-seung
Ahn Sung-ki
Jo Han-sun
One...
Two...
Director Kim Jong-hyun
Three...
What made you apply
for the police academy?
Corrupted officer, charged with taking a bribe
For the realization of
a just society and...
keeping my democratic country
safe and free from criminals...
I, Kang Young-jun, do solemnly and
sincerely declare and affirm that...
I'll truly serve my country with
fairness, integrity and impartiality,
Upholding fundamental human rights
and according equal respect to all people;
and that I'll preserve the peace and
prevent all offences against the people.
Minho, what do you think you are doing?
- Don't touch me!
- I know, I am sorry.
- Dad, stop this!
- Out of the way, kid!
Mom, mom...
What the hell are you doing here?
Hey, Young-jun...
You killed mom!
Oh, your father is a cop too?
No, sir, I don't have a father!
My New Partner
They are coming in.
- How about the square?
- Clear, at 9 o'clock.
- Detective Cha, come in.
- Clear at 12 o'clock.
- Chil-sun?
- No problem, sir.
Great, all units,
keep them in sight, period.
- Hey, Min-seok.
- Oh, you are here!
Oh, thanks a lot,
you did a greatjob.
But I am afraid... there'll
be trouble in the future.
No, not a chance!
I got connection in the information bureau.
- Young-jun, do you want an ice cream cone?
- No, thanks, I've got trouble with my teeth.
Oh, you are too young to be troubled with that,
take care, buddy.
I know...
Take it.
Just out of curiosity... What do you
need that confidential file for?
Why Narcotics Dept?
Who did you got this for?
Let me say hello to the big shot!
Young-jun...
You got any idea
what's in this ice cream?
Damn detergent materials!
But we are crazy about it, why?
People don't know it.
Dad...
Hey, Seok-hyun...
Let's go on the roller coaster!
It's this boy's birthday,
thanks again.
So, you got your dream come true!
Coming in at the 2nd section.
Out of sight!
We've lost him in my section too.
- Come in, Detective Kim!
- No, not in here.
I got him.
But the envelope is gone!
Get him!
Damn!
Take care, boy.
Let me keep the gun for you.
Seok-hyeon, sorry
but I want to ride first.
Could you leave us, kid?
Thanks...
Hey, what's with you?
Oh, excuse me.
Min-seok, who did you meet
on the way here?
What did you do with the stuff
I had given you?
Leave this place empty.
I am really sorry.
Spit it out,
who the hell was that bastard?
It means... you are a rat
from the interior affairs?
The ice cream tastes good
'cause we don't know what's in there?
But you knew it and
you shouldn't have eaten it.
Young-jun, you slimy informer!
Now you're proven to be a dirty cop
in front of your son, and...
How does he feel about that,
especially on his birthday?
Please, I'm begging you.
Let me off this time.
It's all for my son's operation,
you know that.
I won't forget it,
if you let me go this time.
This fucking cop gives me only a penny,
and my son is dying!
Nothing can spare you from
being punished for your crimes.
The train is leaving now.
Out of my way!
Don't let him go!
Hey, go that way!
Stop the damn thing!
No, I can't once it starts,
we can't stop it.
Min-seok, it's dangerous,
let's get down.
Fuck off, you rat!
It's over.
You are not a cop,
you're a police dog!
We put our lives on the line,
and you turn them in?
No!
Minseok, don't do this.
You know this doesn't help
anything at all.
You want this, don't you?
Young-jun,
I have thought of you as...
What a police dog he is!
I warned Young-jun,
and look,
the idiot screwed everything up.
Being this dog's partner would be
the creepiest nightmare ever.
I should be careful 24-7,
in case this dog smells something.
You shouldn't do anything fishy
in the beginning.
Don't get me wrong,
I didn't mean that I do that!
Well, I mean...
What a bunch of shitheads!
You a whole squad
lost this one bastard!
Do I have to remind you
killing this jerk doesn't help at all?
We got nothing,
not a fucking thing!
Young-jun, you worked undercover
for 6 months, and what is it you got?
Wait, I got something here.
Look at this.
He has the envelope in this photo.
But in the next photo,
he doesn't have it anymore.
This girl could be the answer.
After she's gone,
so is the thing.
It's her.
It turns out this girl is Yu-ri,
who is supposed to be in Busan.
The Public Morals Dpt., Busan
is already after her.
I will dispatch you
as a narcotics agent.
You get the girl,
and we'll get the dirty insider.
Make sure you don't
make the second mistake.
The Public Morals Dpt.
You ran away from home and
commitjuvenile delinquency?
No, I didn't do it.
Oh, please sit still,
I am doing it right.
See, it works.
Give it another try,
how many times did I tell you
how to do this, you idiot!
You know what? We're going to have a screwball
from the Seoul Agency come in!
Who do you mean?
A young kid cop from Seoul!
That punk is a lieutenant!
The kids, from the police academy,
are all 'a really know it all'
Who is that kid?
Oh, it hurts, take it easy, Ginger.
- Oh, I'm lost, how can I untie this?
- What a fool!
Hello, Lieutenant,
do you want some coffee?
No, thanks.
Oh, how embarrassing!
Sir, you are here for the Yu-ri case, right?
We got the fax, already.
Hey, Ginger,
where did you put the fax?
- Look, I told you, it's on your desk.
- Oh, now I remember.
How stupid and absent minded...
Ginger, please untie this.
Sorry, but I don't know
how to untying it yet.
I don't know how to untie this!
Oh, thank you, sir.
The Chief is coming soon.
I am Detective Bae ll-gwon.
Nice to meet you
I am Kang Young-jun.
It's been nice talking with you, please excuse me
but I have to go back to work.
I told you not to touch
anything, stupid!
Oh these fuckers are so quick!
I feel like we're not going to be
lucky this time either.
That's him, get him!
Oh, thanks.
Look at you!
Young-jun, my son.
How have you been?
Aren't you happy to see your dad?
It's been eight years!
No, it's been seven years?
Let me see, how old are you?
Are you still single?
You didn't get married, did you?
When I was at your age, my son,
you were in elementary school!
Tell me how far you are on this case.
Should we talk about work, when it's been
8 years since we saw each other last?
Yes, I believe we should.
Chief Kang.
Okay, let's go, Lieut. Kang.
It's work, right?
Let's have a meeting.
I got something for you,
about Kang, the chief of this Dpt.
Well... no, it's not suspicious yet
but for reference.
His tax payment,
and other personal data,
yes, thanks.
Have a good night.
Thank you.
It's been ages since we had a casual dinner,
how I've been missing this!
Let's have a drink.
This kid, my son, works for
the Narcotics Dpt. Of the Seoul Agency.
- You know about the Yu-ri case, right?
- Sure I do.
He works on it, too.
You guys know
what to do to make sure
he's set up.
No problem, sir, whose son is he?
I apologize for my stupid action
this afternoon.
Once we get Yu-ri,
the fist phase will be done.
Then we'll get more info
and transfer it
to the Central Police Agency.
Sure, we work for public morals, so...
We catch the small fish and send them
upstairs to the head office.
- Oh, let's have a drink.
- Sure.
- Il-gwon!
- Yes, sir.
Where does your hunch say she is?
It says, she's in 'somewhere'.
Female hot tub,
considering it's a she.
And I am a she.
Great! You search in every nook and cranny,
in the hot steaming tubs.
Wait, I assume you have a problem
with who's in charge...
As long as I'm on the case,
you will take orders from me.
Sorry, I forgot my son is officially
higher ranked than you!
Whatever your boss says...
We say, "Yes, sir"
and we do it, sir.
That reminds of a funny question.
If a son is higher ranked than
his father...
Should his father call him 'sir'?
You dumb ass, does the
president's father call his son 'sir'?
They go by first names,
they are family!
I know I'd have known something more,
but I met the girl.
That son of a bitch made me
steaming mad...
Sorry, I will call you back later.
Young-jun, forgive me
for not saying hello earlier...
I am Young-cheol, bro.
- Hello.
- You want a light?
It's a beautiful night,
isn't it, bro?
Can I call you bro, like we were brothers?
I'm younger than you.
I know what's on your mind.
I look old, don't I?
Butjust using a brother basis is
fun and easy, right?
Detective Kang does
a betterjob for me.
I see, Detective Kang.
You feel so familiar to me,
because the boss has said
so much about you...
What department do you belong to?
No, I don't belong anywhere.
I am on my own.
How can a marked man like me be a cop?
The Boss has taken care of me
since my juvenile reformatory days.
Some scumbags are even envious of me...
They screwed their lives up
and tried to screw up mine too!
They treat me as if
I am a police informant.
Here comes the fish dish!
Hey, guys, listen to me, all right?
When it comes to investigation,
the number one thing is team work.
In baseball what hitter numbers
are most important?
Four and five!
Three and four?
How many are there? I go by!!
You don't count! And you?
Idiot!
3, 4, 5 are the best hitters
in every team.
But here is the catch...
For them to do the best that they can,
2 and 6 should play their roles.
So, this case is the same.
You, number 2 and 6,
do your shit perfect, okay?
- If not...
- One more fish please!
If not, it'd be one more fish!
- Damn, where the hell was I?
- No idea!
So I was...
Have fun, guys.
Gyu-hwa, don't rush, have a seat,
and talk awhile...
No, thanks, you just keep
having a good time.
Hey, Young-jun!
This is Gyu-hwa, the woman I am hot for,
and Young-cheol's sister, say hello.
In case she could be your step mom.
Oh, was my joke too much?
I don't think it was a joke
for the son you haven't met in ages!
I feel sorry for that.
Just get yourjob done by tomorrow.
I need to know all about Yu-ri.
Hey.
Hey, Young-jun, wait!
What's with you?
I don't get it, you brought
the ex-criminal's ass into this, why?
Oh, the rule is
a rat smells rats better.
He's a Busan kid to the backbone,
without him,
we'd have nothing done.
What the hell are you talking about?
Being a cop is a joke for you?
You even have a thug,
as your man, and he helps you?
Don't brag in front of me!
I'm more experienced than you!
And what a bad attitude
in front of my men!
You mean 'bad attitude'?
You think I should've hugged
my "will-be" step mom?
- Oh, I was joking.
- What kind of a joke was that?
You caused mom to die and now what?
- Young-jun, let's get back to the dinner.
- Don't call me Young-jun any more.
Young-jun, your son,
doesn't exist in me any more.
And my dad doesn't
exist to me any more.
What made you come to Busan then?
You show up, stir shit up,
and try to screw me!
If it's not for work,
I should leave right away.
Then just go, I'm not happy being
with a brat like you anyways!
Hello, let's go and get breakfast.
No, thanks, not now.
Oh, I knew you would say that!
Let's go, it's an order!
- Did you have a good night?
- Sure.
Please keep your hands off.
The Chief told me to
make sure you get there.
I won't run away,
so please let me go on my own.
Why... it feels great.
Thanks!
It was a great meal!
Have a nice day.
Thanks.
Detective Kang,
do you have a girl friend?
I know Seoul chicks
are really hot right?
The report says you come here
looking for a pimp!
- Does it have anything to do with Yu-ri?
- Oh, do you mean Jang Byeong-sam?
He used be a big pimp...
I take it his business
includes drug dealing.
- But I heard it doesn't any more.
- Oh, really?
Chances are he could've gotten
in touch with Yu-ri.
I and Young-jun are
after Byeong-sam...
You two trying to
get Yu-ri's whereabouts.
- Yes, sir.
Sorry but I am on my own,
Chief Kang, you join them.
On your own?
Aren't you a newcomer to Busan?
You just ask anybody on the street,
"Do you know Yu-ri?"?
Like it or not, you are my new partner.
Have you ever seen this girl?
Look at the photo!
Byeon Du-su!
Du-su!
Oh, damn!
Do you wanna
go to the movies, sweetie?
You mean you didn't see her, right?
Detective Dung Fly.
When you were a kid, we went fishing.
And all I ever caught were minnows!
- Have you heard of Byeong-sam?
- Do you now this guy?
Let's take a break!
All these steep hills
are killing me!
My legs are aching,
it will rain any minute.
I mean it, the rain will come
from that direction.
I miss Young-cheol. He piggybacks me
whenever my legs are aching.
Then let the idiot be your partner.
My knees are aching to hell;
it's a weathercast for rain!
Hey, miss, can I ask you something?
To start I am not a "miss".
Oh, sorry,
Mr, do you know this guy?
Sure, I do.
He's usually around here.
No one in this area is
unaware of thatjerk.
He is the moron who walks
the mongrel every morning!
Is he wanted?
Not really.
I just want to know where he lives.
Ah...
First, look to the
11 o'clock direction.
There's a house thats roof is
much higher than the others.
I see it, the house like a pinnacle.
Right, its pinnacles protrude like that...
Yeah, right.
I want to know who lives there!
Go straight that way to the stairs.
If you take the stairs...
You will meet a girl with long hair,
sitting on the way.
Just ignore her,
she's a psycho bitch!
Just go up the stairs
and at the end,
- you will see two paths.
- Let me make it clear.
Go up the stairs
and at the end turn right?
And don't give a shit about the insane girl.
- Oh, you got it right.
- I see.
- And then the house is the second from the end.
- I see, thanks.
Ask any one there.
The town chief lives there.
Damn.
Look, his mongrel is there.
You mongrel, where is your house?
Look at me, mutt!
Show me where you live,
you dirty dog!
Or I will make you unhappy.
What are you doing with that dog?
If he feels threatened, he will run
to the bastards'house,
follow me.
Oh, hello, how have you been?
Alra mantra sutra ultra...
15!
Is this bad timing?
I'm completely clean, no gambling!
"How to be the best gambler"
No more whoring!
No more drugs.
No more cops, I hope.
Oh, I can read your mind.
But I was tipped off by Yu-ri.
Your hunch doesn't smell right this time,
Detective Dung Fly.
I don't deal drugs any more.
She said she got her shit from me?
Where is Yu-ri now?
Don't butt into this
professional conversation.
Being dumped into prison
four times gave me a huge lesson...
Buddha says...
CAY, FUE
"When Cops Ask You,
Fess Up Everything!"
It's what I told you
when I put you in prison the last time!
You have seen Yu-ri, haven't you?
You Detective are a Buddha to me...
She said she'd be at the spar.
When I get dope,
she wants me to call her.
I said don't butt in!
You see? I am completely
refreshingly fresh!
- Sure I do.
Fresh!
Four separations and four prisons;
how about 44!
Deep-rooted trees don't break easy.
44! 44!
Four times four is sixteen.
Four plus four is eight.
You should've pushed him more;
this is how you do yourjob?
He's got nothing more,
I smelt it all out.
No wonder you go by dung fly.
So I am a dung fly,
and he's the dung, shit!
What do you think, dung fly?
I am a fly, you're my son
and you're a fly too!
See? I told you it would rain!
What a forecast!
It's so cool!
Hey, Ginger!
I got here, where are you?
And the chief?
Ah, I passed it, damn.
Fuck you!
- Oh, I see.
- So you've not seen her for a long time?
Where is this bitch hiding her ass?
Where is Yu-ri?
I can't see her now.
I am working on it.
Hey, Kim, you got something
in your hands?
Signed by Chanho Park!
Baseball match tickets
It feels like they rushed
out of the place.
Byeong-sam must have informed her.
They say it's been days
since they saw her.
It's a hell of a dirty place!
Invitation to a VIPparty at Aqua World.
What a fucking mess!
Where is this?
Aqua World?
It's a new facility at the beach.
I heard it's so classy.
I will fit in there!
Let's go.
You mean to the party?
Oh, no, we don't need to!
Don't you see VIP written on it?
No need to work on the VIPs!
Okay, we will go there tomorrow night.
Lieut. Kang.
- Ginger, you work on it.
- Yes, sir.
Wow, it's an eye-popping place!
Oh, sorry.
- It's a whole different world!
- Are you serious?
I don't think I'll fit in there,
because I'm used to being with dirty scumbags.
Boss, and Young-jun,
please let me come with you,
I am begging you!
Those chicks are almost naked!
Please don't leave me out!
Young-cheol, fart blossoms,
you won't blend in there.
- Isn't Ginger here yet?
- She didn't call yet?
She sent a message to come now.
Young-jun, go.
Take care of yourself,
Whatever happens you, call...
Hey, darling.
We are a couple, all right?
It's 100% official, don't worry.
Special ID is a must here.
I made you a doctor,
from Busan hospital.
You should've told me that earlier!
And what's worse... Do you
really think I look like a doc?
Yes I do.
Please show us your ID.
I'm Dr. Kang from Busan Hospital.
Thank you sir, have a good time.
So what are you disguised as?
A beauty contest
third place winner in 2004.
Do you think that makes sense?
You could be the first place winner!
Oh, I know when to stop!
Stop drinking. In case
you don't know, we are on duty!
Don't you know this
costs more than 500,000 won?
This is a chance in a lifetime
to get some damn good booze.
And you don't make a face.
You are wearing
'I am an undercover cop' dress!
And you are holding me too tight...
Hands away from my ass!
I'll report you for sexual harassment!
I'm not doing this because
I like you, don't get it wrong.
Your real name is Ginger?
Yah, my father named me.
When I was young, I was made fun
of all the time for that.
But now it's much better,
it sounds stronger.
It's a cop's name,
it's much better than Lake, Sky...
What?
I told you, it's a once
in a life time chance, cheese!
We are a couple.
Smile.
Are you a doctor
from Busan hospital?
Oh, yes...
How is the chairman Yu,
you should have come with him!
He's stuck with an urgent operation.
He loses his temper easily,
so tough to work with.
But working for patients
is tough anyhow.
Do you know
all these people at the party?
Well, I could say,
I know most of them...
Do you know a girl,
called Yu-ri?
Yu-ri? I never heard
of that name.
How do you know each other?
I once met her at a party,
so I am expecting to see her again.
Excuse me,
nice talking with you.
You have a beautiful woman
and you're looking for another?
See you later.
Come down here, honey!
Sorry.
Oh, I am sorry.
What's going?
Stop, sir.
Can I help you sir?
Let me in.
Only the staff is allowed
to come in from this entrance.
I am a cop.
Let me in for a moment.
What's going on there?
Oh, Prosecutor Park.
He said he's a cop.
A cop?
You don't see Parliamentary men
up there, do you?
How dare you make a mess
out of nothing?
Hey, calm down,
hello, Mr Park.
Nice to meet you sir.
- Hey, Kang.
I will come after you.
Does this jerk belong to you?
Is this how your men work?
How cocky he's saying he'll
search around the private property.
- It won't take long.
- What? You bastard.
No, Detective Kang!
He's a rookie,
so he doesn't know what to do.
Get out of here.
Oh, I am sorry, sir.
What a cocky shit!
Sorry for making such a fuss here.
I will keep you updated, sir.
What are you doing here?
What are you doing?
I know you know it.
From now on
you better watch your mouth!
I don't like shitty lies.
Yu-ri knew we were coming.
What did you meet Prosecutor Park for?
What kind of underhanded shit
did you talk about?
- Don't groundlessly get suspicious of me.
- Being suspicious of everyone is what I do.
You work for
the interior affairs, right?
I got my information line.
I've been a cop for 30 years.
Do you know what the worst part
in being a cop is?
We're likely to
see the evil side of a person.
Then show me your good side,
if you have one.
Look at you;
you are suspicious of Park!
But being closer to them is
the key to getting information.
- Oh, you don't know ABC about "internal affairs"!
- Don't make up shitty excuses,
I know you bastard
more than any one else!
What? Bastard?
You crossed the line!
Okay, if you think I did
something shitty, cuff me!
Here, just do whatever you want!
Hey, what are you doing?
No, give that back to me,
don't touch it!
What a shame!
Dear my love, Gyu-hwa...
Whenever I see your bright eyes,
you're my angel from heaven.
You better watch out yourself.
When it comes to work,
there's no limit!
Here are the files on the
drug related stuff you requested.
But there are a lot
not officially reported. So...
Oh, it would take days to
look though all of these.
There's more over there.
Busan is the biggest port,
so drug crimes are very common.
Thanks anyway.
No problem. What's this?
Go home;
your family must be waiting.
But you are still here,
how can I go home before you?
But my daughters need me, badly!
What a dilemma, being a good father
makes it hard to be a good cop.
Oh, you are
good enough as a cop, so...
Sorry, but,
what I got in mind is to be
a good father rather than a good cop.
So, may I go now?
"Middle School English"
Oh, "of course".
"That's all right."
All night...
Oh, look at you, Detective Kang.
"Welcome to my... brother."
The Boss is taking a nap,
shall I tell him you're here?
- No, thanks.
- Then how about some noodles?
I know a great recipe for noodle soup!
No, some coffee would be great.
Coffee, of course!
Oh, you are here, Young-jun!
Oh, you are here, perfect timing!
Let's go.
So, someone tipped you off
that she's here?
Oh, as a cop,
we have something better, instinct!
You saw at her house,
she is a huge fan of Lotte.
Today, there's a big game,
and no doubt she'll be here.
So, what numbers are important,
did I tell you?
Two and six!
Your work has no principles or rules,
is that how you work?
No rules or principles?
But this is what it takes to get
what we want.
It's a hunch!
Do you believe it?
No.
It's too bad, my hunch says...
Lotte wins today.
- Hey, Young-cheol.
- Yes, Boss.
- Go get some beer and snacks.
- No problem, boss.
I will be back in a minute,
fighting Lotte!
My hunch says today we've come to nothing.
Let's watch the game!
Don't you like baseball?
I don't like
'wasting time without discretion'.
- You are for Lotte, right?
- No, I'm for Doosan.
Oh my, you move yourself
over there to the third base area!
If you root for Doosan here,
you could get killed.
Enough!
Oh, Detective Kang, where are you going?
Let's have fun.
Oh damn.
Here I come, what happened, Boss?
Who's winning?