A SHOCHIKU-TOKYO BROADCASTING
JOINT PRODUCTION
A SHOCHIKU PRODUCTION
OH, MY SON!
Starring
TOMISABURO WAKAYAMA
HIDEKO TAKAMINE
KEN TANAKA
SHINOBU OHTAKE
ISAO BITO
KENJI TAKAOKA
TAKAHIRO TAMURA
TAMAO NAKAMURA
MASAOMI KONDO
MAKOTO FUJITA
SAYURI YOSHINAGA
GOU KATO
Produced by TOSHIHIRO IIJIMA
SHIGEMI SUGISAKI
Based on the novel by
HIDEO SATO
Screenplay by RYOKI SUNADA
KEISUKE KINOSHITA
Cinematography by
KOZO OKAZAKI
Music by
CHUJI KINOSHITA
Production Design by
SHIGEMORI SHIGETA
Directed by
KEISUKE KINOSHITA
KEIHIN INDUSTRIAL ZONE
MAY 1966
Boss!
I thought you had to go out?
I sent my wife.
I'm no good at funerals.
That's not right!
It's bigger than this.
Watch what you're doing!
- Are you worried?
- About what?
Just leave it to him.
You don't need to worry.
You're too easy.
Watch out!
Who did this? Who put this here?
- Takeshi!
- Yes?
Tidy up around here, will you?
Right.
He's only 26. He's doing pretty good.
No, he's still immature.
It takes 20 years in a shop like this.
He's only been here five years.
But in those five years,
you've drummed everything into him.
I've even felt sorry for him
just watching.
He may be your son,
but you don't have to be so strict.
Yelling at him and slapping him...
Tsune.
It was no small feat for you and me
to make this factory what it is now.
That's no reason
to scold him all the time.
Hey, he's tired of waiting
and he's playing his harmonica now.
I haven't heard it in a long time.
He used to play it a lot.
He's sulking up there.
You should get him dinner
as soon as he gets home.
Your vegetable tempura
is too complicated.
Just some eel would've done.
You can call him down now.
But there's nothing here.
Hey, Takeshi.
Yes?
We're having tempura tonight.
Oh, that's great.
Come on down.
Dad, can you hang on?
I want to talk to you.
Right. That's it, huh?
You say that, but -
Well, I've been worried about it
for quite a while now.
But I've got you in charge now.
I figured you'd have some ideas.
That sure puts me on the spot.
What? You can't think of anything?
That's not true. I have some ideas.
Like what?
I think now's the time
to get more people.
Maybe five or six good tradesmen.
Well, that shouldn't be too hard.
Yeah, but -
Dear?
What are you doing?
Come on down. It's getting cold.
We'll be right there.
Now she's rushing us.
But who knows what'll happen later
after taking on that many workers.
Takeshi, Japan's growing
by leaps and bounds.
The whole economy is expanding,
so we've got to catch the wave.
Then I can do as I see fit?
If you think it's the right thing to do,
just go for it.
It's decided then.
I'm going to get another five guys.
Here.
What are you chuckling
to yourself about?
When I went upstairs
Takeshi said he had something
to talk to me about.
I thought I would get yelled at again.
You were praised instead.
What is this about?
I thought he was
going to bring up Kyoko.
Why?
That wasn't it?
Just a chat between men.
You were playing the harmonica before.
That was «Home on the Range»?
That's right.
The same as the record Kyoko
brought when she visited, right?
Well, anyway -
Remember when we met her
and she asked about hobbies?
I was completely stumped.
Why would you be stumped?
You've played the harmonica
since you were a kid.
But I couldn't say the harmonica
was my hobby.
We laughed so hard afterwards.
That's great. You should be proud.
You really think Kyoko wants
to come live with us in this house?
She says she can't wait.
- That's what the girlfriend said?
- Yeah.
Come, now.
Still calling her «the girlfriend»?
Maybe I'll call Yoshikawa
and go out fishing for a change.
Thanks.
What should I do?
Maybe I'll have another.
- You want me to get that?
- The burdock root tempura is tasty.
- Hey, Takeshi -
- What?
You'd better take an umbrella.
It's pretty much stopped.
It hasn't stopped.
I don't need an umbrella.
Oh, come on. It's rainy season.
It'll come down again.
I'm off, then.
- Use the umbrella.
- Right. Right.
Just be safe.
The highway can be dangerous.
You're lucky being an only son.
They found a nice girl for you.
It's not like I didn't do any of the work.
Have you decided on the wedding yet?
Yeah, they're saying
maybe September or October.
Farmers have to work it
around the seasons.
I wonder what Iida is like.
It's up the Tenryu River.
Way up in the Shinshu Mountains, then?
Come on.
She's not some country hick.
She even knows what records I like.
I know. Even though I met her briefly.
Anyway, both my parents
come from the Shinshu region.
They might like her more than I do.
Give me a break.
You're head over heels for her.
I guess.
Hey, you got one.
Another goldfish.
He's pretty good,
considering the youth of today,
that Takeshi of ours.
And Kyoko is a nice girl.
She's coming out
all the way from Iida.
Adorable girl.
Don't you think?
Are you asleep?
Women sure don't have any worries.
I'm listening.
If you're listening, you could answer.
I suppose, but what time is it?
The clock struck 10:00
a little while ago.
It's past 10:00?
So you were asleep.
Takeshi's late.
Leave him be.
It's Sunday tomorrow.
Kyoko is a lovely girl.
Oh, you were listening.
What do you want?
Why?
Who are you?
Hold it!
What's the matter?
You're badly injured!
Let's get you to the hospital!
- Please get him!
- Is there a hospital nearby?
Get that young man!
Hey! Someone help me!
Hello?
Yes?
Yukie!
Did something happen to Takeshi?
Someone stabbed him.
Stabbed? Why?
I don't know!
Let's get to the hospital!
Get yourself ready right away!
We don't need an umbrella!
Just lock up! Hurry up!
Are you all right, dear?
I'm fine! Let's hurry!
FATAL STABBING ON THE WAY HOME
TSURUMI WELDING SHOP
What a terrible thing.
Her husband's lost his strength.
He won't get out of bed.
I can't blame him.
It was his only son, after all.
He's in bed upstairs.
Auntie? Can you come?
There's a police detective
at the door.
Excuse me, Madam.
Have you found the culprit?
No. Not yet.
I'm returning this.
An umbrella left at the scene.
I think it's your son's.
Yes, it is.
And this was at the scene as well.
Yes, that's right.
He told me at the hospital
that the goldfish was for me -
Allow me to offer my respects.
Thank you.
I'll do that for you.
Auntie, you have to stay strong.
Uncle can't get out of bed.
You have to stay strong, Auntie.
That's right. I have to stay strong.
Go show this to Uncle.
Can you go show it to him?
I'll just break down again.
I suppose. I'll go for you.
Auntie, Kyoko's here with her father.
Mrs. Kawase -
Kyoko -
This is simply terrible.
I can't begin to express my grief.
Anyway, we hurried here at once.
Thank you for travelling so far.
Please come in.
This is Kyoko's mourning attire.
Let me take it.
It was made along with her
other wedding things.
Who could have known
it would be needed so soon.
Please don't say such things, Father.
What's happening?
He couldn't bear looking at it.
He said to show it to Takeshi.
I suppose.
My husband's upstairs.
He's been in bed since last night.
I'd like to see him.
Sure.
Saburo, can you go tell your uncle?
I'll go offer some incense first.
Please.
Uncle, Kyoko's just arrived.
She's coming up now.
Mr. Kawase -
Did Takeshi really die?
Kyoko -
Dad,
please avenge me!
I will! I will!
I'll definitely avenge you!
Takeshi! Takeshi!
Dear!
SUMMER, 1940
SPRING, 1941
SPRING, 1949
It's difficult to say right now.
If only we could stop the bleeding.
The wound is deeper
than we thought.
There's a major injury
to his intestinal tract.
You slept well.
That's the best thing for you.
Father.
What is it?
What we talked about yesterday.
About what?
You think we can find
five or six skilled workers
so easily in these times?
We'll find them. Don't worry.
I have some connections.
I guess.
Don't worry about that now.
Don't think of anything,
and just sleep.
Just sleep.
That's what you need to do.
- Dad.
- What is it?
We need a better way...
to haul in the steel.
The way we do it now -
You don't have to worry about it now.
Don't be silly.
You should only be thinking
about getting better.
Don't think about work, all right?
Dad!
Get the nurse!
- Oh! What is it?
- Dad!
Nurse!
Please avenge me!
I will! I will!
I'll definitely avenge you!
Takeshi! Takeshi! Takeshi?
Dear!
Hey, Takeshi!
Doctor! Takeshi!
Oh, Takeshi!
He's in the inner room. Go right in.
I'm sorry I couldn't be at the funeral.
I thought I'd offer some incense.
I want to express my deepest sympathy.
Thank you.
But I'm at a loss for words.
Mr. Matsuzaki, it's kind of you
to offer your sympathy,
but what is this?
You wrote this, right?
You covered it at the hospital.
That's right.
«According to police,
their investigation revealed
that there was no evidence of robbery,
so it might've been a random fight,
or an attack motivated by a grudge
which resulted in the stabbing».
I wrote it that way because
that was in the police report.
But we heard about it at the hospital.
A complete stranger approached him.
He himself told us that!
- But they need to have a motive -
- There is no motive!
They need a motive in order
to proceed with an investigation.
Are you saying Takeshi was lying?
- He wasn't lying -
- But that's what you're implying!
I was just -
Takeshi was not one to get into fights
or have anyone hold
a grudge against him.
Like I said, the police said -
Who cares about the police?
You're a newspaper!
Why can't you write the truth?
That's enough, Saburo.
There's no sense getting angry at him.
Takeshi wouldn't appreciate that.
Hello?
Thank you for coming the other day.
Madam, a suspect
was brought into custody.
Just a few minutes ago.
Dear!
His sister's husband
practically dragged him in.
He's a 19-year-old boy
by the name of Noboru Ishimoto.
Nineteen years old.
It was thanks to your newspaper article.
You wrote a detailed description
of his age, appearance, and clothes.
Yes.
That's what did it.
He suddenly got frightened
and apparently ran to his sister's.
They scolded him harshly.
It's hard to believe,
but he's practically a child.
In that rain, on that bridge -
You're saying you waited
almost an hour?
So why did you do it?
What was the reason?
There's no point in hiding it now.
Spit it out.
- What'll happen to me?
- What?
- Will I be executed?
- Hey, don't change the subject.
We can talk about all that later.
Just answer my questions.
It could've been anyone.
What?
It was just chance.
He just happened to come along.
What do you mean?
Hey, I want you to be straight with me.
You'll pay if you're making this up.
I'm not making it up!
I actually wanted to kill more people!
Women, old folks, and even children!
What're you saying?
Just shut up!
He was just unlucky enough
to come along!
After questioning him further,
we learned he'd tried to join a gang.
But they insulted him terribly.
We're looking into it now.
Where are you going, dear?
I'm going to bed.
Can you lay out the bed for me?
But he said that's what you told him.
He then got angry,
and that's what drove him -
To commit murder.
But that's his responsibility.
Don't make me an accessory to it.
Look. Let me be clear with you.
I was honestly
just kidding around with him.
I didn't mean anything more than that.
That's right.
It's exactly as you were told.
You see,
that guy was good for nothing.
He was raised by his stepmother.
And his dad would get drunk
and beat him up.
I'm not surprised he's all messed up.
Even with work, or anything,
he just never got along with anyone.
No wonder he goes out
and does something stupid.
How about dinner, dear?
Dear,
we'd better let Kyoko know as well.
She's been so unfortunate.
I hope she eventually finds
a good husband.
Kyoko really loved Takeshi.
Kyoko mentioned before she left
that she was worried about your eyes.
How does she know about my eyes?
Takeshi's known of it for some time,
even before I noticed.
Well, I guess it was
quite a long time ago.
When I was still working
at the Oppama car plant.
I went to see my dad
at our metal shop.
I noticed my dad stumbling a lot.
I wondered why
he was in such a rush.
I wondered then if maybe he wasn't
able to see his feet properly.
- Did you mention this to your father?
- Yeah, I told him to see a doctor.
But he'd have none of it.
And he got angry when I kept at him.
As you know, he's a stubborn man.
But I could tell from his expression
that he was aware.
Is that why you quit the car factory?
You wanted to help your father?
I wasn't feeling pity for my dad.
I don't know how to put it.
I was just impressed with him.
I'd never realized that before.
So -
maybe I just thought
I wanted to be more like him.
Takeshi said that?
He wanted to be
a good successor to you.
He was working hard for that.
No matter how much you yelled at him.
Hey, play that record for me.
What record?
You know the one.
I can't.
It'll just lead to tears.
But I need to cry.
I want to cry to soothe my heart!
You've got to eat more, dear.
For what purpose?
Takeshi was killed.
I can't believe you can just sit there
and eat so calmly.
You say things like that
and I bet Takeshi would be mad at you.
Stupid boy.
What kind of son
dies before his parents?
Stupid boy!
A proper craftsman
puts his body into it!
You got that?
Takeshi, I don't want to live anymore.
There's no point.
No point to being alive.
Tsune.
Sorry to put this on you,
but can you manage it for a while?
Manage what?
The metal shop.
I'll let you manage it.
Come on. What are you saying?
I forced myself to go back there,
but I just couldn't -
It's tough
being at the shop.
Well, I'm sure the memories
must come back.
Please.
He goes to the grave every day?
Yes.
Even on rainy days.
Uncle's going to ruin his health.
Well, he wouldn't even
leave the house before.
Maybe this is better.
Do you want me to stay for a while?
Maybe he's lonely.
Maybe you can come occasionally.
But finding a grave site so close
sure was a good thing.
It would've been tough
if he had to travel far.
Listen, Sabu.
I think he wants to die.
I can tell that very easily.
That's why he won't eat.
I guess that's what it means.
Revenge.
I just don't know how to get revenge.
Takeshi,
how am I to do it?
Tomorrow morning at 10:00,
at Yokohama District Court.
I figured you wouldn't have known.
We haven't heard from anyone,
neither the police nor the court.
Well, that's no surprise.
- Please.
- Oh, thank you.
- Please come in.
- Yes. Thank you.
- Here.
- Thank you.
Why wouldn't they tell us?
Well, its just not their custom.
Except for specific summons
to appear as witnesses,
there's no precedent
for notifying victims.
Then we're just abandoned?
Abandoned?
Well, its just the way the system works.
I see. I didn't know any of this.
You might feel you don't want
to see the assailant's face.
But if you do wish to,
you're free to attend the hearing.
Anyway, I just thought I'd let you know.
Thank you.
Hello?
They're back.
The trial's tomorrow.
At 10:00 in the morning.
- Where?
- The court in Yokohama.
Who's here?
Mr. Matsuzaki came all this way to -
You're back.
Mr. Matsuzaki,
so it finally starts tomorrow?
You've waited five months.
Oh, hello.
I thought I'd better come before
you had a reason to yell at me.
Not at all. I'm grateful to you.
Well, I came because
I've become fond of Mr. Kawase.
But it'll still be a long while
before there's a verdict, right?
Yes, there'll be several sessions.
But this one's simple.
They know exactly what happened.
That's not how trials work.
They'll let him off easy.
He's still a minor.
Well, as far as that goes -
Takeshi's dead,
and the killer keeps on living.
Dad,
please avenge me!
I will! I will!
I'll definitely avenge you!
Takeshi!
YOKOHAMA DISTRICT COURT
What a gloomy building.
Well, it is a courthouse.
A dismal place.
Not a place to come too often.
Of course not.
Maybe we should go in now.
Yes. I suppose.
Hey, isn't that the -
You're the one that killed Takeshi!
Stop it!
Uncle, stop it!
Dear!
Stop!
I'm going to kill him!
What -
What do you think
you're doing, Uncle?
You'll end up in jail, too!
And then what?
Where did you get this?
This is a courthouse.
Please remain quiet,
or you'll be found in contempt.
I'm sorry.
Who is he?
The father of Takeshi Kawase,
the murder victim.
And this is his mother.
And I'm his cousin.
The hearing is about to begin.
Then, it's all right?
What is?
Considering what just happened -
I didn't see anything.
What do you want to do, Auntie?
Maybe we should just go home.
Let's at least attend the hearing.
Are you all right?
FEBRUARY 27, 1967
SENTENCING
Is that the court-appointed attorney?
That's right.
They say he has a family -
But they didn't hire a lawyer for him.
So that's how it is.
All rise!
The court is now in session.
In the murder trial of the defendant,
Noboru Ishimoto,
the sentence shall now be given.
The defendant shall step forward.
The defendant is sentenced to a term of
at least five years but no greater than 10.
The 160 days of remand
shall apply towards the sentence.
Facts and reasons
as they pertain to the sentence.
The defendant has had a habit
of stealing since childhood.
He attended elementary school
at a Kanagawa correctional institution
from which he escaped
before graduating.
He delivered newspapers but was sent
to a reform school after committing theft.
He was released in January of 1966.
As the accused is a minor,
consideration is given to him
as one with future prospects,
and an opportunity is granted
to redeem himself in the future.
Does it make you feel better
to repeat that over and over?
I want Takeshi to hear it!
That kid was given...
a lawyer paid for by the state.
They sure are considerate of him,
to have him redeem himself.
He's in for a period
of five to 10 years,
which means he could be out
in as soon as five years!
After killing for no reason -
What about the victim?
No one's thinking of Takeshi!
Nothing for being killed!
The trial is held according to the law.
The law is wrong!
They say a guy like that has a future.
I guess they mean
Takeshi doesn't have one.
That's no punishment.
They're protecting a killer.
That's all.
TSURUMI WARD OFFICE
LAW COUNSELLING
I understand how you feel.
But the law is as I've already explained.
There's no law in Japan that considers
the family of a murder victim?
Or a man killed through
no fault of his own?
That's not so.
There are some provisions.
What would they be?
Please tell me.
There's a law concerning compensation
for those cooperating with police.
In other words,
if you were cooperating with police,
and you were injured in the course
of trying to subdue an assailant,
you can get compensation
from the state.
Maritime safety officials
are also covered in the same way.
And -
there's a law concerning compensation
for witnesses at a trial.
This is for cases in which
there is retribution against you
for appearing as a witness in court.
There's state compensation for that.
Is that all?
I think so -
So there's nothing that applies to us.
Yes. As far as compensation goes.
I didn't come because I wanted money.
What judgments do the law courts
make anyway?
They take good care of the criminal,
but they do nothing for us victims.
I'm home.
Hello.
I'm exhausted.
What is this?
- They're books.
- Books?
They sure are heavy.
They didn't seem heavy
when I bought them.
Was I wrong.
Yukie, get me some scissors.
Sure.
They're all law books?
Isn't that great?
What're you going to do with these?
I'm going to read and study them.
Study them?
Going back to college or something?
Don't be silly.
People like us don't know much
about the law.
We have to educate ourselves, right?
The goldfish look weak.
Did you feed them?
Just a while ago.
I want you guys to stay healthy.
I've got to stay healthy, too.
You never know what'll come up.
But you think you can read
all these difficult books?
I have no choice but to read them.
«Criminal Procedure Law». Right?
I'm counting on you.
Madam.
Well, it's been a while.
It's gotten warmer now.
How is your husband?
He's gotten better.
Still visiting the grave?
He is. But only about once a week.
He's gotten very busy of late.
Signs and recognition of facts
corresponding to actus reus.
Rejection of illegality.
What does this mean?
Why don't they write
it in plain Japanese?
What a surprise.
I never would have imagined.
It's a bit frightening, actually.
For such an upright, law-abiding man
to say that the law is wrong.
I came today because there's
someone he might want to meet.
And -
A doctor?
No, that's not it.
Mr. Nakazawa
runs a building products business.
His daughter was murdered
early last year.
It was a similar type of incident
to your son's.
By early last year, that means
two or three months before our son.
Yes. There have been
many similar incidents lately.
It was an enormous blow to him,
but he's recovering,
and from what I've learned,
he's hoping to draw public attention
to the predicament of crime victims.
Draw public attention?
He's in Nerima?
She was in the third year of university.
She was born late in the year,
so had just turned 20.
She was studying piano
and had gone out in the afternoon
for her lesson.
However -
Somebody!
Hold it!
Stop that man!
There were six stab wounds.
One of them proved fatal.
She passed away before
they could even call an ambulance.
And the assailant?
They said he was 26 years old.
Hate what? What do you hate?
Everything! It's not interesting to me!
Couldn't care what happens
to the world!
That's when you decided to kill?
It didn't matter who it was.
I would've done in anyone
who came along.
But you were hiding in -
Yeah.
I wanted to get a woman.
I hate women the most.
Makes me sick just seeing them!
I figured I'd do a woman
if I was going to kill.
She came wandering in like that.
It's all her fault.
It sounds like my son's case.
Exactly the same.
And the trial?
He was sentenced to 15 years.
Fifteen years.
Not the death sentence?
They said that was the «going rate».
What's a «going rate?»
Who decided that?
Well, I'd say that
people far away from our situation
made that decision.
Then I suppose the five to 10 years
in my son's case is also the «going rate?»
That may be so.
That's absurd.
I can't accept that.
There's something wrong.
I'm not going to back down
until this is straightened out!
But going after the killer now
won't bring back those that were killed.
But still, Mr. Nakazawa -
To build a world free of such
vicious crimes -
I wouldn't want my daughter's death
to be for naught.
So I'm trying to figure out what to do.
That's all I think about.
I could never feel -
It's as though you've reached
a state of enlightenment.
I'm no match for that.
Mr. Nakazawa.
Was that daughter your only child?
I have two older sons.
I see.
You're very fortunate, unlike me.
Mr. Kawase.
I had three children.
One is gone, but I have two left.
Do you think thats any consolation?
I've said such a terrible thing.
You know, Mr. Kawase,
I'm being obstinate.
I'm putting too much on others
and myself, too.
How else can I go on living?
I find I can't even work.
But there's one thing I realized
after the incident.
And it's that there's a surprising
number of people who share our fate.
I've been reading the papers, too.
I never noticed before Takeshi's case
that there are so many.
What do you think?
Maybe we can join forces
and change some things.
Join forces?
Perhaps we can raise
public awareness about this.
Oh, there's Uncle. Uncle's here!
I'll have your prints ready for you.
Yes. Thank you.
Thank you.
Hello, Uncle.
I wanted to talk to you.
Well, how unusual.
It's been a while since
I've come to this shop.
What did you want to talk about?
You once told me about
a nearby welding shop.
Yeah. A regular customer.
And he wants to expand?
Yeah. He said business is good,
and he wants to expand.
What were you thinking?
I wonder if he'd buy our place?
My shop.
What'll you do
if you sell the metal shop?
There's something I'm thinking about.
You decided this after talking
with Mr. Nakazawa?
He's not in a position
to take time off work.
He can't do the legwork,
so I said I would -
It'll cost money.
And I can't be dedicated
to the metal shop.
I'll end up burdening Tsune
and the rest of them.
That's why I think
it's best to get out.
Have you made a deal to sell?
Well, they're really interested.
They're coming to look tomorrow.
Of course they'll keep the people
who work there now.
Are you angry?
For doing this
before talking it over?
Why would I be angry?
I feel this is the only way
to avenge Takeshi's death.
I can never forgive
the man who killed him.
Obsessing over that rotten man
will make me a rotten man.
When I think that way,
I just can't stop.
I don't know what it is, but I feel
that time is passing me by.
I know it might mean
some hardship for you,
but I hope you'll support me.
Even if I were to say I'm against it,
you're not one to back down.
Fine.
If thats what you've decided.
Do as you please.
Right.
There's not much more in life
that I want to do.
I'm sorry.
You really are something.
I'm so grateful to you.
What's the matter, dear?
Why are you crying?
You've cried all the tears you wanted
whenever it suited you!
You even stayed in bed
throughout the funeral!
I've been holding it together
for so long!
I've wanted to cry, too!
Takeshi!
You were everything to me!
My dear.
Takeshi!
Oh, dear!
You silly -
Dear.
I'm so sorry.
You silly -
SPRING, 1966
Here it comes.
Come on. Don't cut in line.
Get to the back of the line.
We've all been waiting.
- What do you want?
- Stop that!
Everyone's been waiting their turn!
What're you doing?
Please.
You didn't have to -
Thank you very much.
Hey, boys. Come on over here.
I've got some sweets.
Oh, you needn't have.
- Come on. Here.
- Thank you.
My husband loved them.
He was a truly great father to them.
How could such a thing happen to him?
He was a quiet man.
I never thought he'd confront such men.
I just couldn't believe it.
Who were the assailants?
Members of a gang?
They worked for the fire department.
They'd been drinking.
Its just bad luck.
I suppose I should give up.
No. You've got that wrong.
That's why I'm here.
If you don't mind,
may I ask how you make ends meet?
I manage somehow, on welfare.
I didn't get any worker's compensation.
There was a little retirement benefit.
I could go out and work,
but I'm not in very good health.
I heard you filed a suit
for accident compensation.
I was researching that,
and I came across your case.
A lawyer suggested it.
Since they were government employees,
I was told I could get state compensation.
But it didn't work out.
What did the court have to say?
They said a lot of things
I couldn't understand.
About how my husband didn't have
any authority in that instance.
Basically, he wasn't directly affected
when they cut into the line.
There was no real need
for him to stop them.
What on earth?
They just saw it as an ordinary fight.
And if it's a fight,
my husband shares the blame, too.
That's absurd.
No wonder people feel
they're better off being apathetic.
But it encourages violence.
It's too late now.
Even I wish that he had
kept to himself.
I wish he was apathetic, too.
STABBED TO DEATH IN FIGHT
TENRYU RIVER
TENRYU GORGE
Takeshi, I've embarked
on a major quest.
To create a world
free of murder victims,
we're going to get legislation
that will help victims families.
This is my way of getting revenge.
You watch me.
I won't give up until it's done.
What debt are you collecting, Mister?
For the outboard motor?
Or the chicken coop?
Debt?
You're here to collect, right?
We have no money.
If you want anything,
go ahead and take it!
I didn't come for that.
It couldn't be anything good.
Just remember one thing.
My dad did nothing wrong,
but he still got killed!
That's right. I know all about it.
Who are you talking to, Satoru?
Hello.
ELDERLY MAN LIVING ALONE SLAIN
NOTE LEFT NEXT TO BODY
AFTER TRAFFIC ACCIDENT
SPRING, 1968
WOMAN SLAIN ON STREET
- Hello.
- Oh, come in.
Nice day today. It feels good.
I see you're busy as ever.
Oh, is Uncle out again today?
Today?
He's been doing overnight trips lately.
He's in Matsumoto today.
Matsumoto?
It's been a while since
he's been to Shinshu.
Spring in Shinshu must be nice.
He was up before sunrise,
and off he went.
- This is the list of victims?
- Yes.
You put this together?
A lot of names, aren't there?
Over 100 now.
And that's not even half.
Is the victims' association going well?
Well, he doesn't talk much
when he gets home now.
He just seems lost in thought.
Some families even turn him away...
like he was a peddler or something.
That must be tough for Uncle.
SHINSHU IIDA
Mr. Kawase!
Welcome! I've been waiting!
Since I was in Matsumoto -
- I was so happy to get your call.
- I really wanted to see you.
Thanks for coming.
Now, come this way.
Thank you.
The mountains look the same
as when I was a kid.
My family all happen to be out today.
Your mother and father, too?
They've gone off to Suwa.
Some business there.
Then I'm glad the two of us
have a chance to talk.
Yes. I prefer it that way.
I was a bit naive.
We've all shared similar experiences,
so I assumed they'd all get on board.
After all, these sorts of tragedies
can happen to anyone.
I just don't understand it.
There were some people
who thought I was there
to take advantage of them.
They were very suspicious of me.
They wouldn't even invite me in.
I can imagine.
I think thats to be expected.
You think?
No one wants to dwell
on dark feelings
from a horrible tragedy
like having a loved one killed.
Rather than face up to it,
they would rather
erase it from their lives.
To think of it as something
from another world,
and cast it away.
I've felt that way, too.
You, Kyoko?
I was Takeshi's fiancee, after all.
People are outwardly
sympathetic to me,
but behind my back
they see me as a bad omen.
I didn't realize.
That's why I work at home
making gift decorations.
Isn't it ironic?
Take a look at these.
So you're not going to marry?
I'm just not ready for that.
But you need to move on.
My wife's worried about you, too.
You have to find a good man soon.
What's the matter?
I said that my father and mother
went to Sawa.
It wasn't because of business.
They said they had no connection
to you after the tragedy.
It's all right.
I can't blame them.
That's why I said I was glad
to have you to myself.
I'm sorry.
It's nothing for you to be sorry about.
I'm determined to fight as hard as ever.
Please sign! Please sign!
Let's help the families of victims
of violent crime.
SHIBUYA STATION, TOKYO
Please read this carefully.
It's written very clearly.
Please sign if you support us!
Please read this carefully!
Please sign!
BEREAVED FAMILIES WILL
NO LONGER SUFFER SILENTLY
STATE COMPENSATION DEMANDED
FOR FAMILIES OF CRIME VICTIMS
We're gathering signatures for
a petition to present to parliament.
We want legislation that will help
the families of crime victims.
That's what this petition is for.
Please sign the petition.
Please sign. Here.
Please.
Please sign the petition.
MARCH 1969
«Opinion of the Ministry of Justice.
For the families of murder victims
we feel the utmost sympathy.
The question of state responsibility
to compensate such victims'
involves many issues
that require further study.
The government must carefully
study the need for legislation».
Is this all?
That's right. That's all.
«They must carefully study the need -»
In other words, they'll do nothing.
It seems so,
by the way they've written it.
We've basically been shown the door.
They're just saying
they'll accept our opinion.
That's right.
It's a terrible way to treat people.
It's been six months
since we presented.
They make us wait six months,
and this is their answer.
We were in the papers
during the petition drive.
Many people came up to me to say
that there are all kinds of people
facing hardships.
That's what welfare is for.
Why would only the surviving families
of murder victims get -
I've heard the same thing
from many people.
So the government is probably
thinking along the same lines.
It's not unreasonable.
We thought it over for a whole month.
There are big differences.
This petition makes it clear, too.
Take a traffic accident, say -
You could be walking down the street
and lose your life.
But there's compensation for that.
They might say it's because
the driver is insured.
But the point is there's a law for that.
You think some crazy murderer
can pay any compensation?
That's why we're appealing
to the state.
The state is the only -
I understand that.
I've thought this through as well.
But Mr. Nakazawa, I'm not giving up.
I'm not one to back down
after getting an answer like this.
Of course. I'm not giving up either.
I'll even go to Kyushu or Hokkaido.
I'll get as many people as I can
to join our association.
Like you said at the start,
theres just no other way.
We have to expand this campaign
nationwide and appeal to the public.
Mr. Nakazawa,
I know you're a busy man,
but can you do the rounds
in the Tokyo area?
Of course I can.
But Madam -
I've already prepared myself for this.
He can go where he pleases,
across the country or wherever.
HIGH SCHOOL GIRL MURDERED
ASSAULTED
ON WAY HOME FROM SCHOOL
ON THE BANKS OF THE GOHYAKU RIVER
IN OMOTEYAZAWA, MOTOMIYA
I'm amazed you quit smoking.
You used to get all irritated
and smoke at times like these.
I didn't quit.
I just forgot.
It was from that day.
You must be tired,
saying things like that.
Never mind me,
I'm worried about you.
Oh, I'm used to travelling.
I worry about you.
I'm glad I came with you.
But I wonder if it's going to stay
this packed all the way.
It's been 10 years since we took a trip,
and this is it.
FUKUSHIMA CITY
INN
Is the washroom downstairs?
Yes. At the bottom of the stairs.
Oh, are you not able to see?
No. That's not exactly right.
Please turn off the lights in the hall
when you don't need them.
It's a waste of electricity, after all.
Yes, indeed. You're right.
Would you like dinner right way?
Maybe we'll take a bath first.
Oh, that might be nice.
You must be tired.
The bathhouse is very close.
Go out onto the front street,
and back toward the station,
and around the second corner.
I'll leave the clogs out in the foyer.
The light switch for the hall is a string
hanging down at the end.
Let's not be wasteful.
Yes. We understand.
MOTOMIYA, ADACHI
Her bicycle was found
in this area.
My daughter's body was found
the following morning
in the woods.
She finished volleyball practice
and left school at the usual time.
It's dark at night,
but there are houses nearby.
I wasn't really worried.
The assailant was waiting
as though stalking his prey.
A complete stranger.
The way he tells it,
he quickly strangled her -
Anyway, you came at a good time.
The 7th day services are over.
I've finally come to accept
that my daughter is dead.
I was beginning to feel
a great emptiness within me.
If you'd come any earlier, I probably
wouldn't have wanted to talk.
Yes.
It's like that with everyone.
Yukie, is the doctor coming?
No! He said to bring him in!
In this rain?
That's why he won't come!
The doctor said that?
He was just so blunt about it.
All right. I'll go!
But it's pouring out!
Wait, dear! I'm coming, too!
Hurry up, then!
Hurry up!
Stupid boy!
A proper craftsman
puts his body into it!
You got that?
FEMALE EMPLOYEE MURDERED
ON WAY HOME
AFTER WORKING OVERTIME
NO EVIDENCE OF ROBBERY
SETO INLAND SEA
«On the 21st, at about 4:00 p.m.,
while walking along a road
in Marugame City,
Nobuyuki Inoue,
a 55-year-old fisherman
from Rikunohama, Honjima,
MAN BEATEN TO DEATH
was shoved by a young man
approaching him,
who then proceeded to assault
Inoue until he became unconscious.
Inoue was taken to a clinic
in Honjima for treatment
but he never regained
consciousness,
and he died some two hours later».
Akeo! Where are you going?
I'm going to kill him!
Who are you going after?
He was a police officer!
I'll get someone else!
Then they'll know how I feel!
You'll be arrested if you do that!
Hold it! Hold it!
I don't care anymore!
You mustn't!
That boy was never like that.
He quit working
and he drinks all day.
He keeps saying his father
was a fool for getting killed.
AUGUST 1974
KITAKYUSHU CITY
On the 28th, at about 11:00 p.m.,
near the entrance to Takatoyama Park
in Wakamatsu Ward,
a man covered in blood
and pleading for help
was spotted by a resident
of Hatsune, Tobata Ward:
Kazuo Tsurumaki,
a 28-year-old company executive.
The man was taken to a hospital,
but died shortly afterwards
due to excessive bleeding.
The victim was from Koishi,
Wakamatsu Ward:
Michio Sakuragi,
a 46-year-old taxi driver.
According to the police investigation,
Sakuragi got into a quarrel with a young
passenger he picked up in Minamae,
and he was stabbed.
Police are still looking
for the assailant.
CONDOLENCE OFFERING - KAWASE
So you don't work?
You just run around the country?
That's right.
I think of it as my work.
How many families have you seen?
Let's see. Maybe around 500.
No. Probably around 600.
You should run for office.
You printed a small article
during the petition drive,
but nothing since then.
Take a look at this.
He's visited 586 families
and we have 125 members now.
It's a growing movement.
I thought we'd see more after you got
transferred to the Tokyo head office.
A newspaper isn't a place where
I can write whatever I want
and they'll just publish it.
I know that.
But a newspaper does more than
just report what goes on in the world.
You also have a duty
to make the world a better place.
We're doing that.
My uncle's over 60 now.
And he's been at this for seven years.
That's seven years of travelling!
He'll go anywhere
to meet a suffering family.
He's not even thinking of himself.
He's pouring everything into this.
Is there no one at this paper
who's moved by such dedication?
And even though
there are 125 members,
they're scattered about and linked
only through Shuzo Kawase.
These people have never met
and don't know each other's names.
But that's to be expected.
They don't meet and
there's no published newsletter.
They can't do it.
They don't charge fees, after all.
Lots of people can't even pay
a 1000-yen annual fee.
What can such an organization do?
It'll end up being a meaningless group,
and just disappear.
That would be terrible for my uncle.
And my aunt, too.
You even once said
that you were fond of him.
I know.
Yukie! This is terrible!
Come here!
What is it?
The goldfish are dead!
They were swimming so well
until yesterday.
Takeshi's disappointed.
He's probably given up hope.
Given up hope?
Takeshi would be disappointed
if thats how you feel.
That boy may be laughing at you.
You're just exhausted.
You've been doing a lot of travelling.
You'll feel better if you rest a bit.
I'm going to Osaka.
What did you say?
There's a new case there.
I'll go home and get ready.
But you just got back yesterday.
It's all right. I don't have much time.
Then I'll go with you.
You know what can happen.
It might be like that trip
to Tohoku again.
That's all right. I don't mind.
By the way, do we have any money?
I'll borrow it from my sister.
It's the Tenryu River.
Iida is upstream from here.
I'll never forget those days.
Remember when you took me
to the graves?
That was before Takeshi was born.
You got back from work
and insisted that we should go.
Oh, there it is!
These are my parents' graves.
You mean these stones?
The little one is my dad
and the big one is my mom.
Why is your dad's smaller?
Well, he died earlier.
I wasn't even in elementary school.
My brother took me down
to the Tenryu to pick up the stone.
I said it was too heavy and
we should drag it with a rope.
My brother gave me hell for that.
He said we couldn't do that
with our dads gravestone.
Then I suddenly felt like crying.
That rock started to feel like Dad.
I wondered why he had
gotten so small.
By the time my mother died
I was finishing elementary school.
So I was able to carry
a bigger stone.
But the real sadness was to come later.
We three brothers ended up
getting adopted separately.
I was the middle one
and stayed with my uncle in Iida.
No one would tell me
where my brothers went.
I still don't know where they went.
It was rough.
I had to look after my cousins.
The food I ate and even where I ate
were different from them.
That was because my parents
died from illness.
I despised my mother then.
Why did she die and leave me?
You can only be a parent
if you're alive.
Yukie.
If we ever have kids,
let's make sure
that we live long for their sake.
I'm counting on you.
Our kids will never
have to suffer like that.
SHIN-OSAKA STATION
It was mistaken identity.
A man got into a quarrel in a bar
and went home to get a shotgun.
Then he hid and waited
as my husband, a total stranger to him,
came along.
Now come this way.
Here.
They caught the assailant
and he's being tried.
But that's all I've heard.
We're the surviving victims of murder.
Can you believe it?
Can that be right?
On top of that, a psychological
assessment was done,
and they said he had
mental abnormalities.
He might even be judged innocent.
That's crazy.
Why would someone like that
have a shotgun?
Who would've given him a permit?
Don't you think?
Come.
I'm trying to carry on my
husband's business, but it's hard.
It sounds rough.
Just raising my kids
and seeing my husband's face
every day was all I wanted.
There was nothing more I wanted.
I always felt that was enough.
But I can't let this situation stand.
I'm claiming damages from the national
and prefectural governments.
I didn't really want to at first.
No amount of money would
bring my husband back.
It would've been like bartering
my husband's life for money.
What changed your mind?
I began to think of it as a duty.
A duty?
It was like Professor Nakaya said.
A victim's family has a natural right
to compensation.
Those people who can
should demand it.
There are people everywhere
with a similar fate
who are just grieving
and doing nothing else.
We have a duty to those people.
Who is this Professor Nakaya?
- Don't you know?
- No.
He teaches at Doshisha University
in Kyoto.
Last year he set up an association for
a compensation system for crime victims.
I didn't know
there was anyone like that.
I suppose a family member of his
was a victim of crime?
Actually, no.
He teaches in the law department,
and that's his research.
He's even studied in England.
And he says the victim's families
have a right to compensation?
That's right.
He says some encouraging things.
DOSHISHA UNIVERSITY
I certainly am surprised.
To think someone had been
leading the way.
If I'd known,
I would've sought you out.
So you have 150 people.
No, it's 155.
I see.
Last fall I started a group
with just four members.
Even now, there are only 20 or 30.
I tried to recruit many more,
but they were all holed up
in their homes.
A lot of people told me
to just leave them alone.
So I can appreciate the trouble
you've gone through.
It must've been hard work.
Yes.
Indeed.
Having taken it that far
is no small task.
You have my respect.
I see.
Now, to continue -
As I mentioned,
when protecting your rights
and freedoms,
it's unfortunately more difficult
to prevent crimes.
And we'll likely see more crimes
as the world gets more complicated.
These are times when you never know
when tragedy will befall you.
In fact, taking my group
as an example,
all of the victims were
completely blameless.
According to statistics
from the year before,
this was the case
with over 30% of murders.
So one-in-three murder victims
were killed for no reason at all.
As far as that goes, I believe
such crimes are inherent in society.
In a way,
they're like endemic diseases.
Endemic diseases?
Diseases you cannot eradicate
no matter what you do.
I think you have to think of it that way.
That's why I think we should be
protected at all times
through some insurance that pays
under any circumstances.
I think thats the only way
to deal with it.
Did you say insurance?
Yes.
What do you mean?
Not something you need
to get a policy for.
I believe all citizens
are part of that contract.
The premiums take the form of taxes.
Of course, there are many obstacles.
But the state ought to pay
compensation to the victims.
That's how I see it.
I wish we had heard this earlier.
We only wanted to help people
who were suffering.
It was about asking for help.
Not at all.
You've done splendidly.
You've worked so hard for so long.
You're to be commended.
Please be confident.
In Europe and the States,
and even in Asia,
laws have already been enacted
to insure the people.
There's no reason
it can't happen in Japan.
Lets join together
and work toward our objective.
Thank you.
You've given me
the courage to continue.
SHIN-YOKOHAMA STATION
Slow down, dear.
We have to hurry and tell everyone.
Are you all right? I warned you!
Are you all right?
It's nothing serious.
This way, dear.
OPHTHALMOLOGY
Glaucoma, huh?
I'm glad he was straight with me.
A good doctor.
If theres no cure,
then that keeps it simple.
We won't be bothered
with going to the hospital.
I'm resigned to this.
But I won't give up on the campaign,
with or without my eyes.
Yukie.
We're in a critical period right now.
You'll have to take my hand
and guide me.
That's all right.
I'll go with you everywhere.
AUGUST 30, 1974
This afternoon in Marunouchi, Tokyo,
in the lobby of the headquarters
of Mitsubishi Heavy Industries,
a bomb planted
by a young man went off
Six people were killed, including
pedestrians and office workers on break.
Over 100 people suffered serious
injuries in this major disaster.
The police agency
and Marunouchi precinct
are considering it a planned assault,
on the basis of a bomb warning
phoned into the office
by a young man,
and the fact that bomb fragments found
at the scene suggest a timer device.
It is thought to be the work of radicals
as police start to pursue this case.
The explosion occurred
just at the end of the lunch break
when office workers were returning
to their offices.
Many took the brunt of the explosion
and fell to the ground,
and this street in Marunouchi was
instantly turned into a scene from hell.
Let's visit them all. Take me!
Yes. We should go.
SHUZO KAWASE
ASSOCIATION TO PROMOTE A SYSTEM
OF COMPENSATION FOR CRIME VICTIMS
DEMANDING COMPENSATION
FOR CRIME VICTIMS
BORN IN NAGANO, 1912
OWNER OF METALWORKS
IN TSURUMI, YOKOHAMA
ONLY SON MURDERED IN 1966
You don't like it?
It's only because a big company
was hit and a lot of people died.
That's what it takes
to get people to notice.
That's exactly right. So what?
It makes me angry.
You sure took your time.
Now that it's a big deal
you don't look the other way.
- Don't be so petty.
- Who's being petty?
This is how the world has always been.
He certainly knows that.
He may have his doubts,
but he doesn't show it.
He wants to use this opportunity
to make an impact. That's all.
He's doing all he can
in spite of his condition.
I know that much.
FEBRUARY 1975
CRIME VICTIM COMPENSATION
SYSTEM
Please file in from the top.
Good morning.
Please come this way.
Thank you for coming.
Watch your footing.
Be careful.
Mr. Suzuki -
Good morning.
Over this way. Please.
Are you all right?
Right here, Madam.
- Thank you.
- Please sit down.
These are the Kawases.
Please have a seat, Madam.
Mr. Kawase, this segment
will be about 12 to 13 minutes.
Only 12 to 13 minutes?
We have other segments as well.
- Yes, I understand.
- Thank you.
I have some arrangements to make.
Please make yourself comfortable.
We're not the only ones here.
I know.
I'll just keep it concise.
STATE COMPENSATION DEMANDED
FOR FAMILIES OF CRIME VICTIMS
BEREAVED FAMILIES WILL
NO LONGER SUFFER SILENTLY
KANTO KOSHINETSU ASSOCIATION
POSSIBLE LEGISLATION TO OFFER
COMPENSATION FOR CRIME VICTIMS
MINISTER OF JUSTICE ANNOUNCES
JULY 2, 1976
Are we near the Diet Building?
We're just at the back of it.
The entrance is right here.
Finally...
Pardon?
Finally, we plunge into the den of lions.
It really feels like that.
It's been a long road.
And we've finally arrived.
Careful.
HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES
COMMITTEE ON JUDICIAL AFFAIRS
With respect to this legislation,
the most difficult challenge
is how to deal with
the victims of past crimes.
If this law is only intended
to help people
that are victims of crime
committed in the future,
we will not have addressed the many
problems faced by those people.
To express his views on this point
I would like to call upon
Mr. Shuzo Kawase, who has continued
to lead this campaign.
Mr. Shuzo Kawase.
Yes.
After hearing what
the honourable members have said -
I don't really understand
some of the complicated issues.
But as the honourable member
has said,
I have continued to pursue
this campaign for eight years.
I don't know how to put this,
but it's been a worthwhile effort.
For example,
when I visited the home of a victim,
just as I offered some incense,
the young widow held a wooden
mortuary tablet
tightly to her chest
and said, «Why did you die, dear?
Why did you die
at the young age of 30?
Because you were killed,
there's no money coming in at all.
If you had died in a car accident
or a workplace accident,
I would've been able to
receive some money.
I would've been able to support
our child for two or three years.
I could've raised him properly
until he was old enough.
But because you were murdered
I get no money from anywhere.
What am I supposed to do now?»
When I heard her anguished pleas,
I became determined to push
for a compensation system
to be enacted into law
as soon as possible.
I have been working towards that aim
even as my eyesight has deteriorated.
I was practically away from home
for six years.
I visited the families of victims across the country.
In some cases,
they thought I just wanted money
and they would turn me away
at the door.
I've had many experiences,
and have met all kinds of people.
I've seen a lot of families suffering.
And so it is my desire
that a system like this
be adopted as soon as possible.
And I understand
that ordinary legislation
is not retroactive as a general rule.
But my wish is that this law apply
to cases going back 10 or 15 years,
so that long-suffering families
can get the help they need.
You must be exhausted.
Yeah.
What a nerve-racking experience.
You did great.
A simple metal shop owner
who doesn't have a way with words,
finds the words come rambling out.
Don't worry about that.
They didn't call on you to talk
about law like the professor.
Is something the matter, dear?
I'm fine.
Dear? Dear!
JANUARY 1977
«In order to consider
retroactive legislation,
various budgetary obstacles
can be expected.
But public opinion in favour of
enacting the law is mounting,
as it is clearly aimed at people
who have suffered from crimes.
A campaign started by a small
band of citizens has grown in scope,
proving significant in the continual
development of democracy».
Are you listening?
I am listening.
Anyway, there you go.
They're seriously considering
the issue of making it retroactive.
Isn't that what it says?
There's more. Shall I keep reading?
Read me all of it.
Let's see. Where was it?
It's all over the place now.
It's like everyone
wants to write about it now.
Come on. Just read it.
I'm just looking for it.
Here. Here it is.
«The Price of Life -
On the value of victim compensation»
The price of life, huh?
He's weakened considerably
since appearing before the committee.
But he still insists on attending
the meetings.
Stubborn as he is,
he's starting to take my advice.
This is the same hospital
your son was brought to.
That's right. The same hospital.
He said this is where
he wanted to be.
I guess it's been 10 years.
Where were you, Auntie?
Hurry! Hurry!
Yukie -
Yes.
What is it?
Get ready.
Get ready for what?
We're going out.
Where are you going, Uncle?
Coca Cola.
The one that died because...
there was cyanide in it.
Who would do such a thing?
Killing an innocent person.
Is there a doctor?
Yes. Right here.
I have a request.
Two more years.
Why?
For just two more years -
Why two years?
Please let me live.
You'll be all right. Not to worry.
In two years -
I think in two years...
they'll enact a law.
I can't go see my son...
until I witness that.
I'm begging you.
Two more years.
Doctor!
No!
What're we going to do,
Mr. Matsuzaki?
How can fate be so cruel
to my aunt and uncle?
I'll phone the paper.
I will do it.
I will carry on the work
that you wanted to finish.
Mr. Kawase just passed away.
Mr. Kawase of the campaign
to get compensation for crime victims.
Yes. His heart gave out
from overwork.
«A Great Citizen Passes On».
That's the story.
I'll send it in 10 minutes.
The lead for the evening edition.
I know it's tight,
but I'll make it in time. Thanks.
Mr. Matsuzaki, you must know -
What?
The murderer that killed Takeshi
is already out
and walking freely amongst us.
Probably.
Not probably.
It's certain.
At least five years
but no more than 10.
Even if he got the maximum,
he'd already be out in the world.
What's 10 years?
Does that allow him to wash away
his crime and start over?
Uncle -
I can't imagine how hard Uncle
worked over these past 10 years.
Even with his eyesight gone,
he'd be walking about.
And now he's finally dead.
What did he get for that effort?
No money left, and no one to turn to.
In the end,
my aunt just gets left behind.
How do their 10 years compare
with the murderer's 10 years?
I understand how you feel.
It's not about how I feel.
It's about how my aunt and uncle feel.
It's about how victims
across the country feel.
In June of 1979,
the government drafted a bill
to pay compensation
up to a maximum
of 8.6 million yen.
However, this draft bill
did not have provisions
for retroactivity
and has yet to be introduced
in parliament.
Starring
TOMISABURO WAKAYAMA
HIDEKO TAKAMINE
KEN TANAKA
SHINOBU OHTAKE
ISAO BITO
KENJI TAKAOKA
TOKUE HANAZAWA
SANAE TAKASUGI
KAZUYA KOSAKA
KIYOSHI NONOMURA
TAKAHIRO TAMURA
TAMAO NAKAMURA
MASAOMI KONDO
MAKOTO FUJITA
SAYURI YOSHINAGA
GOU KATO
Staff
Produced by TOSHIHIRO IIJIMA
SHIGEMI SUGISAKI
Based on the novel by
HIDEO SATO
Screenplay by RYOKI SUNADA
KEISUKE KINOSHITA
Cinematography by
KOZO OKAZAKI
Music by
CHUJI KINOSHITA
Production Design by
SHIGEMORI SHIGETA
Directed by
KEISUKE KINOSHITA