Mr. Kho.
Please tell Bossman
to buy us new saw machines.
That'll help us a lot.
We could work way faster.
The work would be done
in minutes. Am I right?
Yes, but...
Tell that guy to move his bike.
If Bossman finds out, he'll give us hell.
Nah, maybe he's just a customer.
Talk to him if you want.
Hello. Happy morning.
You can't park your motorcycle there.
Because... it's very troublesome.
Good morning.
Riding a bike to work is actually fun.
It's new, you know, Mr. Kho.
Fresh from the showroom.
Take a look at it. Huge bike.
Right? Don't get too excited though.
Take it easy.
It's cool, right?
Kamen Rider.
Hey! It's Renegade, Mr. Kho.
Not "Kamen Rider."
It's expensive, you know.
It's way more expensive than a Proton,
your national brand.
- It seems that you have a lot of money.
- Business is good so far, thank God.
Can you buy a new saw machine for Faisal?
I don't have the money.
Huh?
But you said,
"Business is good so far, thank God."
When did I say that?
Are you making that up?
I think you're getting old
and you have hearing problems.
Have you tried cotton buds?
Bunch of fools.
Hey, Faisal! Park my bike.
Let's go, guys, pick up the pace!
- Is the letter ready, Sikin?
- Hold on.
Did you wash your face with sugar?
What?
Because you look so sweet today.
Hey, Adrian, it's too early to flirt.
- You ready, Rahmat?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Other Indonesian workers ready?
Sikin, cover for me while I'm out.
- OK.
- Good morning.
Hey!
Why do you all look dumbfounded?
Take it easy.
Sikin, close your mouth.
I'm not a celebrity.
You look like you've never seen one.
Why are you still wearing your helmet
in the office?
Because this morning,
I rode my new bike to work.
A huge bike.
Whoa!
If you're curious,
you can check it out at the parking lot.
It's expensive, you know.
- Do you want to know how much?
- No.
Of course.
Even if I tell you,
it will be too expensive for you, right?
Even if I had the money,
I can't ride a bike!
- See you.
- Where are you going?
- And you, Udin, where are you going?
- It's Rahmat.
I know. Ramdan, what are you doing here?
You should be in the factory
not in the office.
Silly.
We're going to vote.
It's election day today.
Wait, are we gonna punch the card
or just check mark it?
It doesn't matter.
Who gave you permission?
Today's election day.
The ambassador instructed employers
to give permission
for all Indonesian employees
and workers to go vote.
Are they gonna pay my loss
when all of my workers gone?
I don't wanna hear bullshit about punching
or checking anymore.
It's unacceptable.
It is our right as Indonesian citizens.
And you will be sued
if you deny our rights.
I'll chose Ms. Kerani. How about you?
Me, too.
Gosh. We're so in synch.
- OK!
- Dear God!
Let me ask you something.
How many Indonesians
are working in this company?
Ten.
Or 11 if we count you, too.
OK, I want you
to call the election committee.
And tell them to build one cemetery
in this factory.
- It's called a voting booth!
- Yeah, that.
So you guys don't have to go to KL.
It will save your energy, too.
OK, Kera-ni?
Hey, call the Embassy.
I'm watching you.
Tell them to put the voting booth
on the back side of our factory.
OK?
I can't believe that stupid mustache clown
you call friend.
He didn't give me permission to vote.
So, you...
You didn't go?
I went anyway.
I don't care.
It's my right as an Indonesian citizen.
I'm proud of you, honey.
What matters is that you voted.
But still...
He's gonna cut my salary. Ugh!
That sleazy bastard!
Calm down.
You know him.
That damn dictator!
Well...
I believe he is.
Are you taking his side?
It's not like that.
But you already know, it's just who he is.
Are you going somewhere?
Why are you all dressed up?
Am I?
Excuse me.
- Bro...
- Hello, bro.
Are we still on for karaoke tonight?
- Sorry, I can't.
- What?
Are you ditching me?
This is our chance
since my wife is still in Hong Kong.
Tonight we can, you know,
entertain ourselves?
Sorry.
I don't feel good tonight.
I think I have a fever.
I don't believe it. Send me your pic.
I bet you didn't get permission
from your wife.
- No.
- Buy her Padang food on your way home.
It'll shut her mouth.
I have to go.
I need to cool down my fever.
Bye.
Bro! Hello? Hey!
Who called you?
Um...
That was... my business partner.
He wants to hang out.
But his wife is sick,
so I told him to cancel.
I feel sorry for his wife being sick
and she would be alone and lonely.
- I couldn't force him to go. You know me.
- OK.
- I'm going to bed.
I'll be there in a minute.
- Honey!
- Yes?
I just got off the phone
with your so-called business partner.
He told me to let you go
to karaoke with him.
Since when are you doing business
with that mustache clown?
I don't know who you're talking about.
"Miracle Hair Treatment."
That's awesome.
I still have hope.
I need a miracle.
What? I'm busy.
Excuse me, sir.
I'm just letting you know
that Arjun is taking sick leave.
His leg was injured
during work last night.
Have he seen a doctor?
He did. The doctor said it was
not serious, but told him to stay home.
Because he still can't work.
That's just an excuse.
Ms. Sikin,
he's the saw machine operator, right?
I've never seen a saw machine operator
walk around to do his work.
- I don't understand.
- Call Arjun.
Tell him to come to work anyway.
He could walk to see a doctor,
so how hard is it to walk to work?
Are we clear?
Can you talk to Mr. Bossman?
If he continues his behavior,
nobody will want to work here.
Please, talk to him.
He's too harsh.
Don't worry, Ms. Sikin.
If the Bossman does you wrong,
I'm gonna protect you.
Body and soul.
And how are you gonna protect me
if you're afraid of him, too?
No, I'm not.
Adrian, come to my office now.
Hey, Adrian. Answer me!
Is he ignoring me?
Dear God.
What did I do wrong this time?
Adrian? I'm praying for you, bro.
Kerani, you should talk to Faisal.
He said he can't take it.
He doesn't want to work here anymore.
Now what?
Can't we have a day without problems?
Happy morning.
How could this machine always be broken?
Ms. Kerani, our saw machine is too old.
It keeps going on and off, on and off.
And it's happening
at least ten times a day.
We should get a new one.
Please tell the boss.
OK, I understand.
I'll try to get him buy a new one.
Raj!
Hey! Where's that lazy guy?
Hey, I want to talk to you.
So, you took some leave last week?
- Did you say your father passed away?
- Please don't be mad at me.
Have mercy, I lost my father.
I'm so miserable.
- I'm fatherless now.
- Raj.
You've been watching
too many Bollywood movies.
I'm so sorry for you.
I think you have potential to be in one.
Don't waste your talent
working in a factory.
I suggest you go be an actor
and make a movie with Shah Rukh Khan.
I... I don't understand.
Five months ago, you took leave.
Two weeks leave without notice!
That time you also said your father died.
Did he die again?
Is he Superman, dying over and over again?
Here's your warning letter. Now get lost.
What?
- Faisal wants to say something.
- Are you Faisal?
- Of course not.
- Then why are you talking?
- Boss.
- Mm?
Our saw machine is too old. It's too old.
Can we get a new machine?
That one is useless.
How can we work if it keeps breaking down?
This machine will claim our lives someday.
Hey!
Repair it. A new one is too expensive.
Sir, our machine is one of the oldest
saw machines in the world.
- Are you mocking me?
- But it is true!
It's too old and inefficient. We need
five days to finish two days' work.
She's right.
Hmm...
OK!
- Hey, Faisal.
- Yes?
- If you need anything, you ask Kerani?
- Yes, boss.
- And if she does, she'll ask me, right?
- Absolutely, boss.
Then who should I ask?
Bunch of losers.
Hey! Get back to work!
Are you playing hide-and-seek?
If he won't listen to us, I give up.
You're right.
He loves cutting my salary.
Once I was late for work due to flooding.
- He cut my salary.
- Yeah. And he never trusts us.
If we take sick leave,
he doesn't trust us.
He wants the doctor to tell him
in person.
He's crazy.
He wants me to sweep
the floor. I'm a supervisor.
- Not a janitor!
- Exactly!
OK. I quit!
Yes, we quit!
- Let's go.
- I quit!
- Quit!
Faisal!
Good luck, Mr. Kho.
I'll see you later.
Please talk to Mr. Bossman, Kerani.
We're about to lose all of our workers.
It will give us headache.
We're gonna be doomed!
He might even make us do their jobs.
Like we did that day.
Don't be so down. I can see you.
Do the work. Kerani, don't be sulky.
Sulky.
Oh my God, please no!
Please talk to Mr. Bossman,
because he only listens to you.
It's for our own good.
You can do it!
God has the power to change one's heart.
- Please, Kerani...
- OK!
Kerani!
- I have no money.
- Sir.
Do you know
our workers are quitting one by one?
And this isn't the first time.
If you keep doing this to them,
you're gonna lose all of them.
Sir?
Sir, are you listening?
You should tone down your nastiness.
Nobody wants to work with you.
It's not about me!
They hate working for you!
Really?
Positive?
Are you sure?
You know what, I don't care.
But we lost some of the workers,
which means it will affect productivity.
Don't blame me if bad things happen.
And don't tell me to sand the wood again.
What you mean?
Your work time is from eight to five,
and you're being paid for it.
Stop whining.
What do you mean?
You should obey me
if I tell you to sand the wood.
I'm your boss, remember?
Subang Jaya?
Hey, what are you looking at?
Do you think my office is an aquarium?
Get back to work!
Get busy, don't just look busy.
Hey, Raj.
Stop it with your Bombay acting.
No, boss. My chest suddenly feels heavy.
Heavy?
Well...
why don't you just quit...
like your friends did?
No, boss.
Nobody wants to hire
unskilled person like me.
Good. Great. You understand.
Good.
Get back to work. Nothing to see here.
You go see a doctor.
Don't tell anyone I gave you money.
Put it in your pocket.
Boss, our suppliers are getting impatient.
They want payment
by the end of this week.
Tell them I'm on a business trip abroad.
It's that simple.
I can't. They already know your tricks.
And they're asking for your phone number.
Whose number should I give them?
Give them Kerani's.
Kerani! Mr. Kho! Adrian!
Azahari! Norahsikin!
To the meeting room right now!
Before we start the meeting this morning,
as always, let's take attendance.
One by one. OK? Kerani.
No need!
We're not school children anymore.
OK.
So, here's the thing.
This is an urgent meeting.
How many times do I have to tell you,
speak Malaysian or English.
- We don't understand.
- What's wrong?
Stop complaining like netizens.
Do you understand?
Don't be such a whiner, Mr. Kho.
OK, let's move on.
So, your amazing boss, me.
Amazing.
That word always brings tears to my eyes.
Speechless.
Can't speak.
So, I just got an invitation...
to give a speech
at a Furniture and Furnishing Association
event in Vietnam.
Wow. Isn't that amazing?
This is a proud moment.
I bet you're so proud of me now.
So! I know that...
we don't have enough workers now.
So, my plan is...
we find workers from there.
What do you mean "we"?
It's obvious! You Mr. Kho, Adrian,
and Kerani will join me to Vietnam.
Sikin and Azhari can hold the fort for us.
Thank goodness!
What?
I mean...
I thank God that you trust us
to run the office while you're away.
God willing,
Sikin and I will do our best to run it.
- If God is willing.
- He's right.
It will be a great honor for us.
How about
Sikin and I run the office for you?
No.
Do you think I don't know...
that you are chasing Sikin?
Hey. No office romance allowed.
Don't worry, Sikin.
I'll be back in a jiffy.
I won't even care if you don't come back.
OK!
Meeting's over,
and we'll leave in two days.
What?
Sir. Sir!
The business trip is such short notice.
I have to ask my husband first.
I'll talk to him.
You? Are you his wife?
Are you jealous?
Jealous of an ugly sack of potatoes?
Hey, I heard that!
But, sir...
No buts. We'll leave in two days,
or all of you can work overtime
at the factory.
How about that?
You're beginning to act like Mr. Kho,
always complaining.
Honey...
Are you trying to be naughty?
Why did you come home late?
That puffer fish made me work overtime.
Oh, honey.
I cooked you dinner.
Oh, that's so sweet. Thank you, honey.
I know. Don't mention it.
Anyway...
I need to tell you something.
I know it's short notice, but...
If you want to tell me about
your business trip to Vietnam.
Don't worry about it.
You're free to go.
Actually this dinner is to celebrate it.
And don't worry, your luggage is ready.
- Bon appetite.
- How do you know about the Vietnam trip?
That ugly sack of potatoes
called you, didn't he?
- I shouldn't know about it?
- I'm your wife.
I'm the one who supposed to tell you,
not him.
Good point. It is weird.
- Honey, I know he's your friend.
- Yeah.
But why do I feel like
I'm the third wheel here?
Honey... you're wrong.
He's not my type.
- Come on, honey. I'm serious.
- Oh, I'm dead serious.
I wouldn't date a fat balding man
with weird mustache like him.
Even if I were gay,
my taste wouldn't be that low.
- Don't worry.
- Honey, enough.
I don't want that bajaj
to ruin our marriage. Period!
Don't you worry.
I promise,
no bajaj will ruin our marriage.
I'm making this promise.
This sacred promise.
Bajaj promise!
Promise.
Ke. Ra. Ni.
I think the end is near.
Hey. I know Dika gave you
permission to go.
He always does what he's told.
We have some kind of...
bromance.
- Ah, sir?
- Mm?
Do you want to purchase airline tickets
online or through travel agent?
And you said you were smart
and up to date.
But you even thought about
ordering tickets through a travel agent?
Online, of course!
You're so old fashioned.
Even I always buy tickets online.
It's my job to present you with options.
If you want to buy them online,
I'll need your credit card.
- What for?
- To pay for the tickets.
Why do you need my credit card?
You just told me to buy them online.
They only take credit cards
or debit cards.
And you said you were familiar
with online purchases.
You don't need to mock me.
Call the airline.
I'm gonna check if they really need
my credit card for the tickets.
Remember, don't eat too much.
- Hey. I'm sorry.
- Yes?
I think, I bring your suitcase.
We have same suitcase.
Hey! You must put bad thing in my...
suitcase.
No! No! No! I'm sorry.
What are you sorry for?
Hey, there is no sorry!
Bad thing in my suitcase, no sorry.
No, no!
Don't jump to conclusions.
Shut up, Mr. Kho. Stop talking.
We're in Vietnam, not Cililitan.
They could even attack with grenades!
- During war time!
- Shut up!
If you put bad, I'll call the police.
No, no.
No... No...
Don't be harsh on me! I was polite to you!
- Don't be harsh on me!
- Run, run.
I'm not afraid of you.
Excuse me.
- Excuse me.
- Come back here! Face me!
Gosh.
My back is killing me.
Don't get us in more trouble.
This is not our country.
Shut up, Mr. Kho.
Don't you know that I'm in pain?
- Good evening.
- Yes, good evening.
Adrian, what kind of hotel did you book?
Bossman will kill you
if you booked a cheap hotel.
You know him.
He wants everything cheap.
The only cheap hotel
I could get is this one.
With his budget,
we can only afford a half star hotel.
But he wants five star service.
But I feel sorry for you.
He's gonna be really pissed off with you.
Hey! Who booked the hotel?
I did, boss. Why?
Very good.
Because it's cheap.
Come on.
At least he won't cut my salary.
Are you crazy?
You booked one room
for the three of us with him?
But Bossman ordered me to book two rooms.
One room for Kerani, and one for us.
You're gonna have to sleep beside him.
Please don't be mad at me.
I didn't have a choice.
If he told you to jump off
the building, would you do that, too?
That's not fair...
And would you eat shit if he told you to?
Hey! Mr. Kho? Adrian?
What are you two arguing about?
You fight like a couple.
Huh?
If there's a problem with your marriage,
you should discuss it calmly.
Don't yell at each other.
Do you want to ruin your marriage?
Take it easy. Be nice to each other.
Since we're going to share
the bed tonight.
This room has a very nice view.
Miss. Please button up your shirt.
You'll catch a cold.
What's wrong with Mr. Kho?
He didn't sleep last night?
How could we sleep?
The boss snored like a starving tiger.
Ugh.
What time is it?
Call him.
No way.
What if he pounces on me?
Why don't you call him, instead?
- Hello?
Why are you calling me this early?
Boss, you told us to gather in the lobby
at 7:00 a.m. It's already 9:00 a.m.
What are you doing in the lobby
this early?
Don't you have anything better to do?
Don't blame us,
we're just following your order!
I'm still sleeping,
I can't even open my eyes.
Can you even arrange a meeting properly?
You're so clueless.
It's not my fault!
Boss? Hello?
Let's go! Don't just stand there.
We have many things to do today.
For God's sake, sir!
Why did you stop so suddenly?
I forgot to bring my speech.
Huh?
How could I forget to bring it?
Can you do the speech without notes?
You seem to have no problem
rambling about everything.
But I always ramble in Javanese,
not in English.
Are you stupid or something?
Here. Mr. Kho, Adrian,
help me write down my speech.
Don't listen to
the screeching of this broken record.
We don't understand any word you said.
You. I. Write. Speech.
For me. Understand?
Speech! For me?
Yes, come on.
Do you want to order something?
No, no.
No eating. No drink, no eating. No food.
- You can...
- OK.
Yes, thank you.
Hurry.
Come on.
"How to be a successful person."
What the speech is about?
I just told you.
Are you deaf?
How to be...
a successful businessman like me.
- In English?
- No, Mr. Kho. In a hippo language.
Of course in English.
Write it down, hurry!
Any longer and Kerani might order food,
and you know she eats a lot.
Taking all of you on this trip
is costing me too much money.
- I do not eat a lot!
- Come on.
Number one.
Sir. Have a seat.
This place is very nice.
♪ Oh, oh, who is he? ♪
Look at it...
Go on, take a good look.
Go closer.
Take a close look at my picture.
You must be so proud of me.
Your boss' picture is there
with pictures of influential people
in Asia.
Isn't that awesome?
Here. Look.
I'm wearing a red suit.
Never, ever forget history.
I'm making history.
Oh my...
The proudest moment.
Hey! Are you proud of me?
I'm very proud of you, sir.
I'm gonna update my Facebook status
right after this
and show it to my family.
That's a good idea.
You're not so dumb after all.
Let's take a wefie.
Sir, excuse me.
- Can you take a picture?
- Picture?
Yes, picture.
He understands my English.
There you go.
Make sure everyone's in the picture.
Look forward, smile.
Don't block my picture.
Yes, come on.
Ready? Do the thumbs up.
Good job.
Mr. Kho. I need my speech.
What's this?
It's a newspaper. Just read it.
I can't give my speech
by reading from a newspaper.
What if they found out?
It's a Malaysian-English newspaper.
You have stayed in the USA
for a long time. You should know.
Ladies and gentlemen,
allow me to introduce to you
our honored guest,
successful businessman from Malaysia,
Mr. Hendrik Suryaman.
Also known as Bossman.
Yes.
Thank you.
Let's pray he won't be
a disgrace to our country.
Ladies and gentlemen.
It is an...
honor for me...
to speak...
in front of you all
about my...
successful business in furniture industry.
Hold on.
Development of furniture design
in South East Asia
has long been
a key issue
in each individual country.
The driver and achievement of design...
and of...
What's that?
Enormously.
Azhari!
I just talked to Mr. Chung
from our timber supplier downstairs.
He is furious, asking about Bossman
and demanding we pay our debt today.
If it not,
tomorrow he will send a debt collector.
- I'm freaking out!
- Calm down, Sikin.
God will not give you
more than you can bear.
Don't ever question God.
I think that's another supplier
demanding their money.
Answer the phone. I'll pray for you.
God will not give you
more than you can bear.
No.
It's better if you answer
the phone instead.
I will pray for you.
Why me?
So. This is it.
What? Where's the rest?
What have you done, Mr. Kho?
Where's the rest of the speech?
Hey! Psst!
I... excuse me. I'm going to the toilet.
Hey, Mr. Kho!
Adrian!
What's going on?
Hold on.
I dropped something.
So...
Thank you.
Have a great day and great lunch.
Hello. Hello?
Hello?
- Hello?
- I'm Babloo.
Mr. Sanjay from Sarawak Paint,
- asked me to collect the debt.
- Hello?
- The debt.
- When will you...
- Bad connection!
Next time, you answer the phone
and I'll do the praying.
- How much?
- 300,000 dong.
Too expensive.
You can't do that. I can get it
for 50,000 rupiah in Tanah Abang.
Are you trying to rip me off?
Sir! This is Vietnam, not Tanah Abang.
And it's real silk,
you can't get it for 50,000.
Are you stupid? I won't buy it for 50,000.
My final offer is 30,000.
Miss, I'll buy this for 30,000 dong.
Your price is too expensive
and don't rip me off.
Go! Go, go, go!
- Is she telling me to go?
- Please, you're making a scene.
Scammer!
Both our countries are still categorized
as third world countries. So smug.
I have an idea.
We'd better...
...act like locals.
Act like locals. Yeah?
That way, they'll give us local prices.
Hurry, make an order. Call the waiter.
Mr. Kho.
I want...
pho, mam chung...
Hey, Mr. Kho.
You're spending the company's money.
Don't get too excited.
Do you want me to take it
from your salary?
- Pho only.
- OK. And you?
- Same.
- OK.
- What about you?
- Yes, yes.
Fried rice with "Hamlet" egg.
Hamlet egg? We don't have Hamlet egg.
You don't have Hamlet egg?
Hamlet egg is a very simple
egg. I can cook it in your kitchen.
Look, this is egg...
you smash it, beat it,
and then you fry it.
How come you can't do it?
Sorry.
Excuse me. Do you have omelet egg?
Yeah. But your friend ordered
Hamlet egg, not omelet egg.
Oh, no. Trust me,
he wants omelet egg.
OK.
- Am I right? You want an omelet?
- Yes.
It's called "omelet" not "Hamlet".
Hamlet is from a Shakespearean play,
the Prince of Denmark.
Are you sure?
And for you?
- No, thank you. I'm fine.
- OK.
- You're not ordering anything?
- I lost my appetite.
Look how fat she is when she's not hungry.
Can you imagine when she is?
You are fat!
- I forgot.
- Yeah?
Pho not two, no, one.
Sharing.
OK...
Thank you. OK, go.
It will be more romantic
if you eat from one bowl.
Don't forget,
we'll gather again in the lobby
tomorrow morning at 7:00 a.m.
I don't want anyone to be late.
Are you sure?
That means you have to wake up
at 6:00 a.m.
Yeah, absolutely. Why?
I'm a morning person, no problem.
Are you doubting me?
Are you sure?
Sure?
- Certain?
- Hey! I'm your boss.
Respect me!
Again, 7:00 a.m., don't be late.
If you're late, I'll cut your salary.
- This time, you sleep in the middle.
- No way!
Please, Mr. Kho...
Now that's a good sign.
You two getting along nicely.
What a cute couple.
- This room has a very nice view.
- Hi.
This again?
You told us already last night.
You're a party pooper, you know that?
Are you jealous of me?
I'm warning you...
nobody snores while I'm sleeping.
It'll be a nightmare for me.
My queen's calling.
It must be important.
Hey!
Hello, Mommy, darling.
Daddy, darling.
What are doing tonight?
I'm about to go nite-nite.
You're going nite-nite this early?
I don't buy it.
Once you hang up the phone, you'll go
straight to a karaoke club, right?
Who would I take to the club? Mr. Kho?
He's over the hill.
What if his rheumatoid plays up?
You can't say bad things about people
behind their back.
I'm so sad tonight.
I feel so old,
with all the wrinkles
and sagging on my face.
I know that,
but I still love you so much.
I want to get Botoxed.
They say Botox can make me
look like Kim Kardashian.
Who are you talking about?
Is she related to Kim Jong Un?
Can I do Botox, Daddy?
Of course.
Do whatever you want.
As long as it's cheap.
Daddy, I love you more and more each day.
You're the best.
Do you miss me?
My thoughts are only of you.
I miss you so much.
Prove it.
Blow me a kiss.
I don't feel it.
Kids today call it a wet kiss.
OK, Mommy.
Oh, Daddy.
- Not sleeping again?
- How could we?
There were two lovers
flirting on the phone all night.
Hey! Good morning!
Hey! Come on, where's your spirit?
Where's your spirit? Wake up!
Look alive! What time is it?
Good morning!
Good morning, boss. We go "ow"?
- What?
- We. Go. Ow?
What is he talking about?
- We go ow?
- It's "we go out".
Oh, we go "out."
Why did you say, "We go ow"?
- OK, let's go.
- Let's go.
Yeah.
Good.
Are we lost? We've been driving for hours.
Hey, sir.
Wrong way! We go back.
- Map. Go back.
- What?
Are you listening to me?
Where did you get the driver? From Uganda?
He doesn't know where he's going
and he dares to talk back to me.
If you wrong-wrong, I can't concentrate.
Did he just yell at me?
Please, sir, he's a local.
He knows where he's going.
How do you know if he's local or not?
Did he show you his birth certificate?
Do you know Obama's nationality?
- American.
- How do you know?
Did he show you his birth certificate?
Are you laughing at me?
Hey! Do you want your salary cut?
Hey, Duong, wake up.
I've told you over and over again.
Don't go to the karaoke club every night.
Work hard! Don't get messed up.
A client's about to come.
Yeah, yeah.
Get ready! Open your eyes wide!
My eyes are like this.
They're open already.
Are they Chinese?
No, Malaysian!
Nguyen!
Konnichiwa.
Hello, Bossman. Welcome to Vietnam.
Yes.
I thought you got lost on the way,
but you're here before us.
I live here, boss.
I won't get lost.
Yeah, I forgot about that.
Guys, this is Nguyen.
He lived in Malaysia quite a long time.
He's smart, kind, and friendly.
Stupid! You embarrassed me!
You've eaten so many
noodles, your brain works like one!
"Konnichiwa" is Japanese, not Malay.
Stupid!
OK, Bossman and friends.
I'll take you to meet the workers.
They're all ready,
and all is come from North.
Good.
What's with your face? Smile!
Do you want them to think
our country is not hospitable?
Don't embarrass me! Smile!
Open your eyes! Open them wide!
They'll think you're sleeping!
Smile!
OK, let's go.
- The boat's ready.
- Yes.
Smile!
Konnichiwa.
Are you sure?
Do you need to ask?
Look at me, do I look I'm afraid
of this kind of adventure?
I'm excited.
Unlike some people I know.
You need fighting spirit.
Move.
- Lady's first.
- Lady.
Kerani, get in the boat.
All right, all right!
This is unexpectedly comfortable.
Where are we going, really?
I don't know, and even if I knew,
I wouldn't tell you.
Hey, Nguyen...
what kind of boat doesn't have
any fan or AC?
- I'm cooked!
- I can't hear you!
This is called adventure, boss.
Right, Mr. Kho? Right, Kerani?
Hey, Duong, don't sleep!
Don't you dare sleep,
or I'll give your eyes chili sauce!
Can you drive faster?
How many times
do I have to tell you to fix the machine!
Why don't you fix this?
Don't rock the boat, you'll tip it!
Hey! Calm down!
- Hey, Nguyen!
- Yes, Boss?
- Are there any anacondas in here?
- Huh?
Where are we heading to?
We've been going for hours.
Are you leading us
to the King Kong village?
- Are we there yet?
- Remember, boss.
Fighting spirit!
Sir, I don't think going to rural area
was on my contract.
Look at Mr. Kho.
I think he's turning into a zombie.
That's his normal expression.
Remember, Azhari.
God will not give you more
than you can bear.
Pick up the phone, Azhari.
Don't question God.
Hello, sorry, wrong number!
Wrong number, you said?
We're dead!
Yeah! Where's your boss?
Oh, my goodness!
Find Bossman.
If he tries to fight back, bag him.
Find him first.
If he tries to fight back,
bag him and throw him into the sea.
Don't do that!
Listen up, find him.
And don't let Inspector Vijay
find him first.
This slanted jerk!
Spread out! Bring Bossman to me
as soon as you find him.
Search every nook and cranny!
Don't let that Sun Go Kong
get his hands on him first!
You jerk!
Come, Bossman. Come.
Anybody want to carry me?
I'll raise your salary!
Fighting spirit, boss!
Shut up!
My feet are killing me. Is there any
vehicle here to drive us there?
Sir...
Bossman went abroad.
Hey! Let me tell you.
Your boss said he'd pay us last week.
Where's the money? Where?
He took many containers of our logs.
My boss is getting impatient.
If Bossman won't pay us,
let's bag them instead.
Please, be patient, gentlemen.
God is with those who are patient.
We've run out of patience!
You guys talk too much!
I came here to get my money,
not to be patient!
If you try anything funny,
I'm gonna bury you alive!
Understand?
Your boss owes my boss money.
His name is Mr. Sanjay.
He has failed to pay us since last year!
Bossman and friends,
beautiful view, isn't it?
No time to admire the view!
We're exhausted!
Ma'am.
Are all roads in this area like this?
Have you ever get tired
walking everywhere?
Hey, beautiful.
- Have mercy on us, God!
- Pay up now.
If you don't wanna pay,
I'll make you guys black and blue!
Wanna taste my fist?
Understand?
Understand.
- Understand?
- Understand.
Hurry up!
Tell the cow to move aside.
Move! Move!
Please pick up, Kerani!
We're almost there, Bossman! Fighting.
- Where are you, Kerani?
- Hey!
Where's your boss?
- I want to talk to him.
- OK, OK!
Beautiful, call your boss...
Otherwise, I'll kill him!
- Please, don't kill me.
- I'll kill him.
Wait! I'm calling the boss!
Spare me, please,
I haven't go to the Hajj.
Get ready.
Put your shirt on.
You think this is the field?
Gosh! Did you get drunk last night?
Hurry up!
Why is he always angry?
Is he talking to them or yelling at them?
Gosh.
- Bossman?
- What?
These are the workers I told you about.
OK. Mr. Kho, Adrian, go interview them.
What interview? Isn't that Kerani's job?
Because I'm telling you to do it.
If she does the interview,
she'll end up asking about chili price.
Stop questioning my decision. Go!
Wait here, boss.
- Why do you want me here then?
- Come with me.
You have more important things to do.
What are those?
Tell them to fill in bio data
and working experience.
What do you mean working experience?
Working experience.
Cannot.
I have a feeling
this isn't going to end well.
Don't make me look fat.
Can I do something more useful
than taking your stupid photos?
Can you stop complaining for once?
You're not complaining only when you eat.
Look how fat you are. Give me my phone.
Well, then, take your own picture!
My bag isn't shown in the picture.
Yes, Sikin.
Hello, Miss Kerani!
Thank goodness.
Miss, some gangsters
have taken us hostage.
They came here
to collect the boss' debt.
If we don't give them money today,
we will be killed.
Die!
OK, calm down.
Bossman is here with me.
I'm gonna give the phone to him.
Bossman?
Sir.
Sikin and Azhari are being held hostage
by some gangsters.
They want their money today.
- Do something! They're freaking out!
- Really?
Hello, Sikin.
Hello? Boss?
Uh-huh... Yes...
Are you sure, boss?
Calm down.
Take a deep breath and say hi to Azhari.
OK, OK.
Thank God!
Bossman said he'll send someone
to deliver the money to you.
But if your Bossman lies again,
I will destroy this office!
If your boss lies again, I will...
- Yeah?
- Guys.
What did Inspector Vijay say?
He'll destroy this office.
Ah. If your boss lies again,
I'll burn this office!
No!
- Well?
- Don't worry.
Just enjoy the view.
Flowers all around you...
- Boss!
- And, they destroy the view. What?
- Problem.
- What problem?
If you want to be in the picture with me,
then no. Get back to work!
Those men don't have any work experience.
No working experience.
What?
You said you didn't mind
if they had no experience.
All you want is cheap.
I give you good and cheap.
When did I say that? I didn't say that.
We have many workers
without working experience.
- Some of them are even illiterate.
- Nobody asked you.
Tell them, without experience,
the offer will be reduced to half.
But, boss, we agreed.
If you don't pay full,
you'll breach the contract.
What contract?
Mr. Kho, go back there and tell them.
- No thanks. Tell them yourself.
- OK!
Kerani, go tell them.
Why me?
- Radio.
- Yes, boss.
Let's turn on the radio.
This song makes me sick.
Hey, bro. Do you have a problem?
No, bro. Do you have a problem, bro?
No, bro. Do you have a problem, bro!
Chill, bro!
Everything will be all right, Bro!
Do you have a problem, bro?
Excuse me. It's praying time.
Nice try, bro.
He said he's a gangster.
But he listens to mellow music
from, what are they called?
- Boy band, boss.
- Ah, boy band!
It's better than your people.
Broken-hearted, crying,
sad, or even mad...
you're always dancing.
Have you ever seen a sad person dancing?
If you see a tree, you'll dance around it.
You see a clothesline,
you'll dance around it, too.
Embarrassing!
Oh, you being racist, bro?
No, bro. I'm being realistic, bro.
Fine!
Please don't fight in here.
Let's have a battle to see who's the best.
OK.
- Both of you...
- Are gonna be our witnesses.
Calm down.
The agreement
wasn't like that! We disagree!
- I know, but listen up...
- No!
- Listen up...
- Cheater!
You guys tried to trick us?
Listen up...
Mr. Kho, what are they yelling about?
I don't know.
But I can confirm
they're not saying "I love you."
- Listen up...
- Let's beat them up!
Why is everything like this?
Look what you've done!
Mr. Kho, Adrian.
What's going on?
Wait for me!
Can you even negotiate, Mr. Kho?
Hey!
DO NOT ENTER
WITHOUT PERMISSION
Peace be upon you.
Peace be upon you, too.
Smartass, who are you?
Want me to punch you?
Are you Bossman's friend?
Relax, bro.
I'm innocent.
Look at me. I'm innocent.
I couldn't be friends with Bossman.
See?
I think the horse hates him, too.
Come, look closer.
If the horse could speak,
what would it say?
Hold on. Who are you?
Hey, chicks!
I'm here to give you money.
- Where's the money?
- I got the money.
The money...?
With me.
Give it to me, quick!
Patience.
- Thank you.
- Hey, smartass.
He got the money, what about mine?
Patience.
Paid off. Now off you go.
- Geng, let's go.
- Go.
Thank God.
The car's gone!
You complained to him so much
the driver left us here!
Do you realize
you almost got us all killed?
Kerani, stop rambling,
and start looking for an ice cream vendor.
I'm thirsty.
Hey!
No, I give you money 20,000 dong,
not 10,000.
So, you give my money back 10,000 dong.
- Understand?
- No. 10,000 Dong.
Yes, give me back.
You're wrong. Give me back.
- No! No!
- Yes! Yes!
- No!
- Yes! Yes! Yes!
No! No! No!
Get out,
penniless passenger. No money, out.
Making such a fuss over a small problem.
I'm not afraid of that amount of money.
I'm rich.
That's only a little bit of money.
Why are you guys so stupid?
Why are you pointing at me?
- What do you want? Why you pointing at me?
- Sir, stop it.
Who's in the wrong?
You didn't give my money back.
Why are you hitting my bus?
- Let's beat them!
- Let me finish you!
- Come here if you can!
- Jerk!
My lungs just blew up.
Where's Mr. Kho and Adrian?
Kerani.
Please don't be mad at me.
I'm scared when you're mad.
You look scary.
I'll buy you pizza after this.
It will be delicious.
I'm gonna pay for it.
Are we good?
Hey! Nguyen?
- Psst!
- Evening, Officer.
Are they your friends?
Yes, they're my friends.
I'll explain this misunderstanding.
OK. You can meet them now.
Thank you, sir.
Nguyen.
- Nguyen.
- Are you OK?
Do I look OK?
I'm helping you for the last time.
After this. I don't want to
deal with any of you again. Understand?
What an asshole-
You want my help or not?
Thank you so much.
Ignore him.
Just help the rest of us.
Entitled bastard!
Kera.
What now? I'm about to sleep!
I bought you pizza.
I thought you were hungry,
because you're always hungry.
It has a special Vietnam grass topping.
Don't play nice with me,
it won't change a thing.
And I'm too tired to eat
after being chased by everyone in Vietnam.
Then who's gonna eat this pizza?
I can't eat this.
What if I become fat?
On the other hand, you're already fat.
If he's not come in half an hour,
let's leave him.
Where's the car? And where's the driver?
Don't just stand there.
You booked the car for two hours ago.
Obviously the driver took another guest.
What a sleazy hotel.
Wait till I file for a complaint.
Please don't create more trouble.
He's right. Let's just grab a taxi.
- What did you say?
- Grab a taxi?
Grab a taxi?
To the airport? Grab a taxi?
It's too expensive!
How convenient for you.
The airport is far from our hotel, fool.
You never learn, do you?
Psst!
Are you sure
the bus is going to the airport?
Yes, it is.
Am I smart or what?
If you're kind to people,
somehow there's always a way out.
There's always a way out!
Are you sleeping already?
Hi, everyone.
Li Hua.
Are they a tourist group?
Yeah. But they're all going
to the airport, too.
But we don't belong to their group.
Stop complaining.
It's a free ride. Be grateful!
He's coming.
- Who are you?
- Me?
Yeah.
George.
George what?
George...
George Clooney?
We don't have your name on this list.
Oh, it cannot be. There must be a mistake.
Because we're in the same group.
Same group with...
With Li Hua? Hua Liu?
Hey, yeah! My friend. See?
Friend. Good friend. Group. Same.
But we don't have your name on this list.
It's not my problem. It's your problem.
- My problem?
- Yes, your problem.
Because I'm not in your list.
You. Wrong. You can get fired. Kick out.
Understand? Complain.
- I will complain about you.
- Huh?
I'll call your big boss.
What's wrong with this guy?
Damn it! What day today?
Psst!
Li Hua!
He's grinning!
George Clooney!
Julia Robert!
Ben Affleck!
Boboho!
George Clooney!
Julia Robert!
Ben Affleck!
Boboho!
We're here now.
Let's go.
Sir.
No money! No money!
Everyone, follow me.
Put your luggage in the bus.
Why?
OK, up to you. We go together.
Please don't separate
yourself from the group.
Erm...
Excuse me. Where are we going?
We are going to see the prison museum.
No, no, no!
I went to the prison yesterday.
With the police. I was afraid.
Hey, excuse me!
Come here.
We don't go to the airport?
Yes, but before we are going
to see the prison museum.
And then go to the Pagoda National Park,
after that then, we are going
to the airport in the evening at six.
What?
Everyone, follow me.
Sick?
Our flight leaves at 3:00 p.m.
I don't want to spend another night
in this country.
- I want to go home!
- Fine, Julia. Don't worry.
I'm gonna find a way to leave this group
without anyone noticing.
Be more like Ben Affleck and Boboho.
They don't complain as much as you do.
You'd cut our salary
if we dared to complain to you.
The murderous crime of the France colonies
against the Vietnam
political prisoners in Hoa Lo Prison,
who used a guillotine
to execute them.
The guillotine
that was used in Hoa Lo prison
was imported from France
to Hanoi in 1894.
Everyone follow me.
Come.
We are going to another room.
Honey.
Thank you.
Don't waste your time thinking about it.
But, honey...
- You need to forget about it.
- I know, but...
Listen to me...
look at me, look into my eyes.
Nothing but my eyes. Only my eyes.
Not my forehead, not my eyebrows, glasses,
not my eyelashes, but my eyes.
One, two, three, you're under.
Forget about your problems in Vietnam,
it's all over now.
And forget about your company's debt,
it has been dealt with.
You're done.
One, two, three, you're back.
Debt?
How do you know about my company's debt?
You don't know?
- I don't know about what?
- That I helped him paid the debts.
But he said he told you!
Oh my God, honey!
- You paid the debts?
- Yeah.
Honey, come on.
He's always late paying my salary.
And if I show up to the office
five minutes late, he cuts my salary.
If I use the company PC to access Facebook
during lunch he cuts my salary.
And now we cover the company's debts?
Well...
he's my best friend.
Your best friend?
It was your best friend's fault that
your wife was chased around
by everybody in Vietnam!
Not to mention being jailed!
Is that what you call "best friend"?
Honey...
Don't "honey" me.
You're not sleeping with me tonight!
Go sleep with your best friend!
I can't do that. His wife won't be happy.
OK, I've decided.
I want to resign.
Me, too.
I can't stand working for him anymore.
Me, too. This place is like a hell for me.
- I want to quit, too.
- Me, too.
And I'll follow wherever you go, Sikin.
Hello?
Yes, we'll deliver your order today.
You're good?
What are you doing?
Practicing for a march?
- Get back to work.
- Yes, ma'am.
OK, here's what we'll do.
Let's finish today's work.
Then we go to his office
and tell him that we're quitting. Well?
Good. OK.
- Let's eat!
- Your food looks delicious.
- Do you want to try it?
- Delicious fish!
Wanna try my tempeh?
I cooked it this morning.
It's our pleasure.
This tempeh looks delicious!
I'm suspicious.
Just tell me what you're up to.
Suspicious about what?
We're not doing anything. Right, guys?
Yeah!
Thank goodness.
Oh my goodness!
- Isn't it delicious?
- Your tempeh is very good!
I know what you're gonna say.
About what, sir?
Raj died.
Raj died?
I told you.
Are you listening to me at all?
May he rest in peace.
Let's go to the hospital,
I'll ride with you. Come on.
Poor Raj.
I didn't know he had a heart condition.
When he had just come from India,
he couldn't even speak Malay.
He lied like a rug,
but he was loyal to Bossman.
There's a problem.
Raj didn't put his beneficiary
in his bank account details.
You're right.
I went with him
when he opened the account.
He didn't put any name on it.
That's unfortunate.
He was illiterate.
He didn't know anything about finance.
Then how did he sign the documents,
if he was illiterate?
He used thumbprint signature.
This is his will.
But if the police investigate,
you'll take the responsibility.
Boss, I got the ink.
Mr. Kho, Adrian, Kerani, follow me.
Let's go.
Kerani, go ahead. You go first.
No, I won't.
Come on!
- Kerani.
- Mm?
You go first.
No way!
I'm practically blind.
I can't see in dim light.
No, you're not.
You can spot money from across the sea.
I can?
Too many bodies. My goodness.
Raj.
Which one is you?
Excuse me, dead people.
We've only come here for Raj.
- Hey, listen.
- What?
Which one do you think is Raj?
How would I know?
- Peek under the covers one by one.
- I won't do that!
- Go open the covers!
- No!
Mr. Kho, you do it then.
You're the eldest here.
Then you do it, Adrian.
Then who's gonna do it?
Are you expecting me to do it?
Bunch of cowards.
OK.
I'm gonna lift their covers...
but you do the looking.
Excuse me.
Get ready to look.
Here, take a look at it.
It's still covered, sir!
Are you sure?
Is it him?
No, no, no...
Forgive me, sir.
How about this one?
No, no, no.
Hey!
He...
looks like me.
There's too many bodies in here.
If we have to check one by one,
we're gonna be dead soon, too.
Don't talk about death.
- No, no, no...
- Really?
Yes!
- Positive?
- Absolutely!
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure!
- Close it!
- Forgive me.
Where are you, Raj?
Even after you're dead,
you're still giving us trouble.
How about this one?
Dear God!
Did he turn into old woman?
Show a little respect to the dead.
What if she woke up?
Let's move on.
Let's try this one.
Excuse me.
Is this him?
Raj!
Poor, Raj.
Farewell, Raj.
Choose your words wisely.
What if he woke up and walked away?
Where's the ink for the fingerprint?
Take his fingerprint, quick.
Why are you stepping back? Hurry up!
You do it, I'm your boss!
Just do it quickly. Hurry!
Bunch of cowards.
Raj, it's Bossman.
I'm with Adrian.
Kerani and Mr. Kho.
If you don't mind,
we need your fingerprint
to cash out your money from the bank.
I feel sorry for your wife and children
if you left them with nothing.
You worked so hard...
- You startled me!
- Hurry up!
Give me a minute!
Sorry, Raj. You know how Kerani is.
Please forgive me, Raj.
Please don't haunt me.
Give me the ink.
Is the thumb already in the ink bottle?
Yes, sir.
Give me the paper! Don't just stare at me!
Seriously.
Forgive me, Raj. Relax your thumb a bit.
- I've got it.
- You have? Good!
Let's go.
Let go of the paper, Raj.
Wait for me!
Cowards!
Hey, wait up!
Ouch.
Will you stop that?
Why did you leave me behind?
My heart is about to explode.
- Well?
- It's settled.
Thank God!
It was like something from a horror story.
Oh my God!
What is it?
What's wrong, boss?
- What?
- It's just...
It's just what?
It's just, I left my bag in the morgue.
So...
How about our plan to quit?
I don't know.
I feel bad doing this.
It's not that I like him.
But I was surprised
to see what he did to Raj.
And he was just a factory worker.
Mm, I was surprised to see
his sympathy for Raj's family.
I know.
Even I wouldn't think that far.
God has willed.
I have to admit it,
he was so sympathetic.
So, what do we do now?
We give him one more chance?
OK.
So, we give him one more chance?
One more.
OK.
Yes, sir. I'll be right there.
I'll see you there.
Yes, sir. OK!
I'm so happy
to see you all working so hard.
By the way,
I have a last-minute meeting...
with the prime minister.
The new one. So, I'm gonna have to
leave the office early.
And I bought pizza for you.
It's free.
It's not gonna be charged on your salary.
Enjoy it.
Every one of you can have them.
I'll see you guys later.
Thank God.
Pizza!
This is delicious.
Thank God he won't charge it
against our salary.
- I know.
- This is a blessing.
If he did this every day,
nobody would want to quit.
Maybe he is enlightened.
Let's eat.
It looks good.
Hey!
Where's your Bossman?
I'm here to collect my money!
- That slimeball!
- We're dead!
Fell out.
Yes.
What you mean?
Your work time is from eight to five,
and you're being paid for it.
- No...
- Take six.
Last week, you said
your father passed away?
Or all of you can work overtime...
You're wrong, honey...
Oh, I'm dead serious.
I wouldn't date a fat balding man
with weird mustache like him.
Even if I...
Hey, who...
Sorry.
You're right.
What's wrong? Not cut yet.
Forget about your problems in Vietnam,
it's all over now.
And forget about your company's debt...
I know... but...
Mr. Kho, call...