MYSTERY OF THE WOLF
Manuscript: Heikki Vuento
Photographer: Kari Sohlberg
Art director: Risto Karhula
Costume Designer: Merja Väisänen
Sound designer: Paul Jyrälä
Composer: Sarah Class
Editor: Jukka Nykänen
Producer: Leila Lyytikäinen
Executive producer: Claes Olsson
Director: Raimo O Niemi
Let me take it.
-Sit down now!
Help!
Paulus! Paulus!
Watch.
Please Salla.
Please Salla, wait here.
Mom should get dad.
Take this.
Paulus.
Please Salla.
Did you see the wolf?
It ran over there.
Would a wolf ever come in here?
Whatever it was,
it shouldn't be here.
Where are Paulus and Laila?
The girl is all alone.
Laila!
Come on, Laila.
Laila. Laila.
Mom. Mom.
Something is wrong.
Take the girl.
I'll take Laila to the health center
and alert Törmänen.
Laila, come on.
11 years later
Thieves.
Has there been
a fence here?  -Yes.
You, are you not ...
My name is Salla and tend to go
past here on the way home.
My house is over there,
but not visible.
I've also lived here.
Salla, would you come in?
Can I offer you juice?
Maybe not, mom is waiting.
Some other time. Bye.
I could have helped
if you had waited.
Go have some soup,
you must be hungry.
I saw a wolf on the mountain, or two.
One had taken a grouse from my snare.
- There are no wolves around here.
There is enough space for huskies or something.
- Stop it, I can recognize a wolf.
Salla.
-Nobody ever believes me.
I'm not good at this. Poor you,
you take after your mother.
Hold your breath for a moment, please.
All clear, little lady, it's a boy.
-A boy, how so?
You already have me.
I wondering if Pietu knows anything.
I can teach.
Is he Pietu?
-So he said.
Someone has moved into Morgam.
A woman.
Into Morgam?  -Yes.
What kind of woman?
-Dark. Quite old, like you.
Did she say anything?
As if she knew me,
but I've never seen her.
I turned down her offer of juice.
One shouldn't disturb people unnecessarily.
I'll help Dad,
you read your lessons.
I must hunt reindeer poachers
as well as fix up the cabins.
Laila has come back.
I know, Laila is there.
People may live wherever they want.
Salla met her.
I should have been told.
Has she been here long?
-She did well during the week ...
It doesn't concern us. -Antti,
I don't care for this at all.
Do we know if she can take care of herself?
-Don't worry.
It's inconvenient as is.
We're having a baby, and it's difficult
for her. -She'll get used to it.
Forestry is hardly a godsend for us.
The slow growth...
and low productivity
are limiting factors.
Among reindeer there is a type of
mad cow disease in England
and foot and mouth disease
puts our own business in a new light.
Expectations are high,
because reindeer are so natural.
The future here in the north
should also be seen ...
Give it back.
One moment, Matias.
Put away the book, boys.
Do you want to comment?
Ellu.  -Your father has reindeer.
Ask him to give them to us, if he
neither keeps or eats them.
There are too many reindeer and
they die when the lichen disappears.
Predators and scavengers kill them.
-There are no predators around here.
Yes there are.
And tourists run them over.
What is this here?
A pure sapien, which is not concerned with
propagating itself and eats only waste.
Check this out!
Watch this!
Let go.
-Scat!
Thanks, but you didn't need to do it
for my sake. -It was for my sake.
Good that it was good enough for you.
You wouldn't have dared.
Morgam is back.
-Excuse me?
Ask yourself.
If you don't know, ask your mom.
If you dare.
Reindeer will disappear in one. And
reindeer have no tread like snowmobiles.
Don't look at me, Törmänen.
I know nothing about it.
How is Venesmaa?
Always in the woods with his dog.
We came to the village
because Simo was sick.
Talk to him, boys.
Antti's daughter is said to have
seen two wolves on the mountain.
If there are any wolves here,
Salla Köngäs would find them.
She has powers.
-She takes after her mother.
Rupi, do you happen to have a leg?
Simo is howling hungry.
Shouldn't you read the homework?
Salla, I mean it.
When do you go to the hospital?
-Listen, not for a long time.
Is it dangerous?
Can you die from it?
Childbirth is not easy,
but no one dies from it.
Why did my first mother die then?
Die?
What did you say?
Who said so?
She didn't die.
Why didn't she come after me then?
She couldn't.
She didn't come back from there
because she was so sick.
I took you and brought you here.
Was she crazy?
Salla, we've talked about this.
One may bear a heavy burden,
but do not be angry over it.
You are my girl.  That's what counts.
Sure.
This case should be clear
Laila gave up custody
There's no room for interpretation
-Does Salla know his background?
-We've explained it several times.
-She has not missed...
-But Laila is Morgam's biological mother.
No one denies that!  But she
may request to take her back.
It's never easy with people
and emotions.
Yes, I understand that, but
it feels so...
Witch.
Is she preparing magic potion for someone?
-Or poison?
Who gave you permission to come here?
What does it matter to you?
We go where we want.
Witch!
-Go now.
Salla.
What are we doing here?
I'm not coming.
Hey you.
-Hello. Hi Salla.
Hello.
Yarn saboteur.
-What did you say?
You heard enough.
I saw it.
I checked the decision on Salla,
and it's legal.
It hardly matters that Laila is here.
Very well.
Thank you very much.
See you.  -Sure.
Forcing me there was embarrassing.
-Embarrassing?  Why?
You mean the boy. Matias.
Admit that you have
something going on with him.
I guarantee not.
And I'm not speaking with you.
Should I say something about him?
-Dunce.  Stop.
Find a place for it.
I need to work.
He never gives me anything.
What is it?
So nice!
Is it yours?
What do I do with it?
I get enough of them in school.
Mom!
I took a skiing trip to the mountains,
and triggered a bear trap.
It missed my leg,
but snapped the pole
Two men were there with a reindeer calf.
They left when they saw me.
I was so frightened!
Isn't it illegal?
Ask your father.
Do you have a clear conscience?
-How clean?
You've kicked shit on other people's yarn
and were rude.  What's wrong with you?
Who said so?
She came here and lied?
Never mind who it was.
Don't you know you don't do those things?
At least not you.
And especially not against her.
Why not against her?
In order to ... -She's my mom!
And you aren't?
Who told you?
Well, at least not you.
Why may I not decide
who I am?  Whose child?
I kicked no yarn.
-There's no question about it.
Salla, I have raised you and
you can beg Laila's forgiveness.
No.  Certainly not.
You want to avoid me
when you are going to have a baby.
Salla!
Laila, eleven years is a lifetime for
a child.  We can't change that now.
I won't allow it.
Salla's our girl now.
I don't want to make life difficult for you,
but you've signed the papers.
But was I myself at the time?
Shouldn't Salla not decide for herself?
Hasn't she done so clearly?
I ask apologize for having
teased you with the others.
Believe me, it won't happen again.
Can you give this Salla?
I can't take it,
she hasn't earned it.
But it belongs to Salla.
-Laila, we mustn't confuse her.
You shouldn't meet with Salla anymore.
Stop nagging, they are legal.
-Safe ...
From Norway.
-Sure.  Here we go.
The skins are perfectly legal.
Salla!
Where have you been?
At the forest cabin.
-And you said nothing.
We were afraid of the worst.
-Sorry.
We raised the alarm and twenty men were
out in the wilds looking for you.
Sorry.
Don't go out in the wilds again.
You stay on the farm and go to
the school and village.
And Salla.
You'll get a snowmobile later on.
Understood?
That's it.
Sorry, but go away!
Look Salla...
I've always liked you for you are a
true forest person, not a chatterbox.
Why was Antti so upset about
Värrö's skins?  They were perfectly legal.
Ask Dad.
Aren't wolverines protected?
The skins came from Norway.
Aren't you underage?
Yet you're taught snowmobiling.
It's your dog too, but he drinks beer.
Isn't that animal cruelty?
You can be the police daughter as much as
you want, but don't start playing with us!
Simo!
Simo, get up!
You learned to spot wolves, right?
Had Simo scented the wolf on you,
he would have cut your throat.
You don't have to believe, but I saw them.
-What a liar! Where?
I don't lie.  Two, at Soaspää.
Soon there will be more since
the second was pregnant.
It's good that you told the
professionals about the wolves.
Soon you can sleep soundly
out there in Köngäs.
And soon they'll no longer disturb anyone.
Mom.  -Here.
This is my room, and my computer.
Mine crashed. I'm managing the
cabin reservations.
The room will be ready for Pietu soon. -You
snipe rudely. Be careful with your words.
I saw wolves and nobody believes
me though one did came by.
What? Came by where?
Nothing.  I told the idiot old
men I saw a wolf.
Now they'll be killed.
You did the right thing
if they were reindeer herders.
They should see to it that the wolves don't
do something bad.  -Nobody is allowed to kill them.
Sometimes I don't understand you.
Here, stupid.
Matias!
What?
Now don't believe something like that -
- that I would like to be with you -
but I need help.
You put me under pressure. Dad
would hang me if he knew.
How do you find them in the forest?
They must be found!
They must be chased away
so nobody can find them.
They must be somewhere here.
There's room out here for them
to hide.  -I'll find them.
Damn!  No track.
It was perhaps escaped huskies.
They always run home to dinner.
We won't find any wolves
there among the stones.
Not with snowmobiles.
What was it I said?
The Köngäs girl and Matias Laiti.
I think I know what they are looking for.
We'll follow along.
It is she who finds wolves.
Stay!
Fresh tracks!
There!
Go now!
We need to get in front of them!
We'll drive around, speed up!
No!
Watch it with your machine gun.
There are children around.
What? I saved them of course.
She would have been eaten
if I hadn't shot.
The wolf pretended to be dead
and would have attacked.
Pretended to be dead ...
Wolf ...
What did it do to you?
Laiti's snowmobile became scrap metal.
Your dad should be so happy.
We'll take you to the nearest house.
We'll see how we do in the morning.
But, guys, tonight
there will be hunting party.
I jumped down and
took the shot on reflex.
In fact, it was a neck shot.
It was dead.
She had driven over it.
Should she get the skin then?
For your home.
I don't want it. Take the whole animal.
Sorry.
Go away.
I want out of here.
Sorry, Dad.
I had to.  Absolutely had to.
You had to, so it can't be helped.
Venesmaa and the other wolf are in
Nillas cabin.
Where do you think we're coming from?
Take Salla directly home.
Your father is waiting.
Tomorrow you'll take the
snowmobile to Lompolo.
We need to talk about the consequences.
Mom! Do you spell it Po or Poo?
Salla. You have a visitor.
Salla Köngäs.
The reindeer team will reward you with
200 euros for a job well done.
Slaughter Money.  No thanks.
Salla, there's a scholarship.
As a thank you for having helped
save tens of reindeer.
Buy candy or get a moped.
Give it to Venesmaa.
I won't accept it.
I'll add it to her study funds.
We need a lot.
Very well. -Thank you.
Wait a minute.
Salla also won the nature competition
and she gets a prize ...
It is ... -A wolf-whip!
Shut it,
otherwise, I'll shut it!
What are the pure sapiens whining about?
Vellu would still like to sit next to mommy.
Thanks for your help.
You didn't need to.
In return.
What will you do on summer vacation?
Could we go somewhere together and...
And kiss?
No, I didn't mean that.
For a soda or something.
I like to be out in the mountains
and you sit at your computer.
It's true, but one never knows.
Is the cabin vacant?
Yes, so you?
I was going to go home,
the coffee is ready.
Therefore, I will too. -I'll have coffee.
Have you tried the sauna?
Not that one.
Help!
What is it?
-It's stuck.
I saw the wolf. It had two pups.
I killed one during the winter,
perhaps the father.
What could you do about it? All are
of course someone's pups.
Not me.
I do not know whose I am.
Laila did not mean something bad.
I don't want to talk about it.
In the forest it is such that those who
come last get the best places.
This place is ours.
Well, we can go.
Simo!
Get out, stay there!
Guys, up!
The wolf will tear up Simo!
What now?  -Wolf!
There!
Simo. -It is so bad to take
a dog in the house.
I'll take my revenge.
It's best that we go.
It's starting to go wrong.
Now they'll die.
If only it had taken cover.
-It can swim better than a dog.
Too far.
Pups stand no chance against them!
What do we do with them?
-We can't let Venesmaa get them!
Somewhere here?
There!
Here!
Venesmaa's gang is coming soon,
they saw me.
Go back a ways.
Backpacks, quickly!
They're nearby.
How did you know what to do?
-I didn't know.
The nest is fresh, a horrible stench,
but no one at home.
Yeah so there. Do they think the
Köngäs girl deserves a scholarship?
Shouldn't we talk to Antti?  It is
a police request, the wolf killed Simo.
It is probably best that we
take care of it ourselves.
I'm afraid Laiti's boy may go
into some damn animal protection.
I want the female.
Nobody comes here in summer.
They're staying overnight.
Couldn't they stay with you?
The house is full of reindeer dogs,
and wolves under the bed.
This is a good hiding place.
They drove past.
Salla! Wake up!
They have escaped!
They dug themselves out!
Salla! Where are you going?
You promised to clean the cabins!
Speed up!
They must be found!
Watch.  Unbelievable.
Don't look there. It's Venesmaa.
I'm going to the store.
Take the back road, catch the pups
and put them in a dustbin.
Now we have a track on the little ones.
They're decoys.
Come on and hunt wolves, girl,
the village men can't do it.
You know what I read in the newspaper?
The Italians are said to have a dog
which will match a bear.
Should I order one?
-A useful creature.
It scents wolf pups
in a safe four meters deep.
Don't forget this.
In a safe?
They followed you here!
-They know.  What do we do now?
Look out!
We don't have many choices.
Venesmaa is following you.
There is a place,
but you won't like it.
Thank you.
Laila has an empty cage in the shed.
The pups will be taken to the female
and rubbed with peat
so they don't smell strange.
Is that what Laila said?
-Yes.  She knows about animals.
But you didn't leave the box.
Well, it's a good box.
Does the young pair need a ride?
-No, thanks.
There will be an equipment inspection.
Say where they are!
Salla! Where were you? You were supposed
to clean the cabins, but ran off!
You can't be trusted.
-I'll clean up.
They are already cleaned.
Now help with serving instead.
We have a bus load of customers.
-Yes, yes!
From now on, you're staying at home!
-I'm sorry then!
I know what you're doing.
What do you want...
or do you just haunt
someone else's house?
You have a reputation that
draws attention.
Do you remember how you endangered
our children?
What do you know about them?
Beat it, you crazy bitch.
I leaving, maybe far away,
but I swear that I'll return if you
don't let Salla be.
It's best if you take care of yourself!
Hello, is Antti home?
Not now.
-He wasn't at the station either.
I intended to ask about licenses.
The shotgun came in yesterday.
I applied for it a month ago.
I don't know anything about it.
You better ask Antti.
Everything seems to take a
long time for me.
You're a sensitive person.
Thanks, Kirsti.
It was beautifully told.
Can I use the toilet?
Venesmaa came to our house!
We'll cross the river with the pups.
First thing in the morning.
Good.
Hunting Day.
Come to the cemetary in the morning
with all of the equipment.  Understood?
Did you get a tip?
-Failproof information.
Antero.
Wolves may well be useful.
They get blamed for everything.
I don't care about the benefits now.
I want to get the female.
Salla.
I want you to know...
that I didn't leave you out of malice.
I couldn't get back to you for a
long time because I was so sick.
Later on I didn't dare.
I was so ashamed.  Ashamed of what
I did to you.
Later on it seemed to be too late.
Why did you come?
Not to upset you.
I wanted you to know that I exist.
Thanks for your help.
Where did you find that?
It was lying there. Whose is it?
Some child's, certainly.
-Don't you know her?
Maybe.
Why don't I know?
I'm afraid I'll suddenly wake up and
find out that I'm somebody else.
Salla, you're Salla.
Everyone knows that, at least I do.
Can't you just be she?
Sorry, but go away
I should have guessed that they're here.
It would be best if we dig them out.
No, they're no longer here.
We'll follow them to the river.
We need to get there
before they cross.
Sorry, but Salla needs help.
Don't be offended, but I told you
that Salla should be left in peace.
She isn't home.
She's fishing with Matias Laiti.
They're not fishing.
What is that?
How could they have known the route?
We'll never make it across the river.
Through the rocks. An all-terrain vehicle
won't make it through.
I didn't realize that Venesmaa
came to us for Salla's sake.
It's for wolves.
-Wolves ...
In the spring, Antti became fed up with
Salla for the wolves' sake. -Pups, two.
They're also kids themselves.
What were you thinking?
Now I feel nothing anymore.
Now I won't leave Salla in the lurch.
There they are!
Hurry up, boys!
After them! Up there!
Excuse me.
-What? What?
His wife asked me to say
they went to the mountains.
Why did a pregnant woman go there?
Perhaps her daughter
had gone astray.
Excuse me.
His wife asked me to watch his house...
Törmänen! Come back!
We need to get to the river. It will
be difficult, but I've done it.
With a wolf on your back?
What will happen now?
If I could meet her
and know something of Salla.
I meant that the road ends,
and I have my queasy stomache.
They went down to the river.
Lompolo, run along the ridge
and down to the river.
We'll go here and
surround them.
There are hiding somewhere.
How will we cross? -Farther along
there's a bend.  That will work.
Watch out.
We must trudge on.
-Stay.
Certainly not.  -You can't
run here, you're pregnant.
We don't have time if you must
stop to catch your breath.
Why did we come here?
-I don't where they are ...
I, I, I!
You're a bloody idiot!
Antero, they're heading to the bend.
They won't cross without a boat.
We'd better not hunt children.
Wait here.  I'll look around.
Who do we have here?
Isn't it Salla Köngäs?
I see it's Salla.
What is it that
looking out of the backpacks?
Now it has come to this, girl.
Ask Laiti's boy over here.
Jump in!
I've done it before!
My God, what are they doing?
Are you crazy?
Don't kill yourselves!
Antero, put away the gun!
Laila, I shot accidentally.
-Laila, ignore that.
You didn't believe me,
though I warned you.
The blame is always on Antero;
no matter how hard I try to do right.
Well, the skins were my fault
and the reindeer was my fault, but ...
the wolf tore up my dog.
and Paulus tried to help me,
but to no avail.  -What do you say?
Sorry.
How could you do that with the snowmobile?
-I saw it on TV.
You said you had done it.
-No.
And on TV the sled sank.
You are definitely crazy.
Yes, I am.
Salla.
I don't like
that you stay overnight.
Dad, it's exactly 952 meters home.
I've measured.
You could phone if you miss me.
Oh count on it...
Here I am.
There you are.
Subtitles by HungryHippo