Centuries ago during the times of feudal Japan,
armies would fight over
control of the failing empire
And The Shogun ruled!
His personal assassins
were known as shadow warriors
and they were the most lethal of killers
We still exist today
But now it's a global market
Assassins by trade,
we only target
men of corrupt and evil ways
We are always successful on our missions
and we never leave our targets breathing
We are the best in our field
We are the Shadow Syndicate
What are you barking at'?
Go check!
I'm not gonna miss next time
It's okay. Use the whole mag this time.
Last time I failed because of you
I shouldn't have missed
Hey you!
Hey come out
Something must be wrong
They're over there. Go!
Shoot!
Stop!
Where are you going? Come back!
Don't leave me here!
Good job 9W5
Let's torch this place and move out
My father wants to meet you all,
one on one
You called me here Tatsuo?
I am passing over the business to my son
With all due respect Tatsuo,
There is no question
that Ken is the best assassin
But he has plans for the Shadow Syndicate...
well,
that are less than honorable
Please reconsider
Now times have changed
My time is over
Now please leave
So what do you think
about Ken being the new boss?
It's the perfect choice.
He's the best assassin by far.
You know he wants us
to target the whole family.
I mean that's something
we haven't done before.
If you want, you have the guy,
I'll take the kid and wife.
We move out at nightfall.
Hey hey you! You can't stay here!
You have to leave.
I seem to be having trouble with my boat
Do you mind giving me a hand?
Hey whoa! Whoa whoa mate. My boat -
It's not starting. I don't know
if it's the battery or what or the engine,
Can you get a jumper lead
or something, you know I...
Get down on the floor
Get down
Get down!
Who are you?
Hey!
Sam!
Don't start the party without me
Where's the wife and kid?
I took care of them already
Good on you!
I knew you were one of the boys.
Oh please don't!
- Come here
- Please
Daddy
- Daddy
- No no please don't
What! You said you took care of them!
No!
You! Traitor!
I'll take care of you later
Calm down Butch, calm-
You gotta leave
You gotta disappear
Thank you
There will be others
C'mon, let's go
May I help you?
Sorry, I don't mean to disturb you
You are welcome. Please come in.
What is your name?
My name is Sam, and you?
Ca“ me Phra Mam
Be calm, don't be so tense.
Make yourself comfortable
Put your right hand over your left
Breathe in
What happened?
This man was attacked by a tiger
What's this?
With this herb, I can help him
No, don't touch!
This sword has spirit
Phra Ajarn spoke about how long time ago,
during the Lanna period,
there was a great warrior
In a battle to protect his kingdom,
opposing soldiers overpowered him,
and took his life
He was so revered by the people
that he was immediately cremated
so an ancient ritual could be performed
to keep his spirit with them
From his ashes they forged a blade
that would protect them
and could not do harm
to the ones he loved
Phra Ajarn,
thank you for all that you have done
We welcome all
who look for peace
How can I ever know peace.
I've done such dark things.
To find peace,
you must look within
Thank you
Thank you, see you later
Oh sorry
Oh, sorry
You speak English
Yes I am
Wait!
You're the girl that was in the dance earlier
Yes, did you like it?
Oh yeah it was beautiful
Thank you
Your first time around here?
Yeah, it's the first time
Do you like it?
It's great, yeah I like it
Would you like some drink?
Sure
One more milk please
Thank you
- Thank you
- It's alright
Come, I show you around
- My name is Malee
- My name is Sam
- Nice to meet you
Look over there,
they have something interesting to show you
Yeah, go over there
Come
Sam, there is something I want to tell you
What's that?
I'm pregnant, 3 months
What'? Really?
WOW!
That's great, what should we name him?
If it's a girl, we call her Suree?
And if it's a boy,
then we'll name him Shiro
Q Kay
Yeah
Yeah! Woo!
How did you learn to do that?
Watching my uncle when I was a boy.
He was a blacksmith.
Good
Memee
- Hi Memee
- Hi
I've finished this
Looks beautiful
I cut it like this,
is it okay?
It's okay, looks nice
It's very beautiful
- Thank you
What a beauty
You think you can
just disappear from us, huh?
Did you think you could run away'?
Shire, you have 10 be a good boy, okay'?
Sam!
Stay here, don't go away, okay?
Stay here, I love you Shiro
And this is for Butch
Enough
See you in hell
Sam! Sam!
Sam!
Stop it
Come here!
Leave me alone
Is this you girl?
Leave her alone!
Sam!
Sam
No!
Let's go
Shiro
Malee
The jungle is dark
And my enemy tall
It's left me feeling weak
and naked and terribly small
So I cling to the life
That came from her death
I walk til I'm weary way passed
feeling weary not stopping to rest
And I won't settle
Just to settle the score
There's nothing left
if there is nothing worth fighting for
I cut with the sword
Made of spirit and flame
Tearing through the terror the darkness
getting nearer protecting my name
And I won't settle
Just to settle the score
There's nothing left
if there is nothing worth fighting for
I've got nothing left
if I've got nothing worth fighting for
The Shadow Syndicate
receives their assignments
from a satellite signal that can be accessed
from tall buildings
and a set of computer codes
Together, they're invincible
So I will hunt them down, one by one
I will show them no mercy
and I will slaughter them all
I prepared false passports for Shiro and I
I cannot leave Shiro with Phra Ajarn
The Shadow Syndicate
can find anyone, anywhere
So the safest place for him,
is with me
Hey Joseph!
Hey Sam!
Oh my god, my old friend
- Good to see you my old friend
- Yeah, good to see you too
Hey, that's a cute little boy you got there
This is Shire
Nice to meet you Shiro,
please come have a seat
Alright, you're my guest
Futoma, bring the tea please
Just a minute
Can you take Shiro to the back
to play with the other kids?
Yah, my sister will take care of Shiro
She's got like a hundred-
I'll be gone for a few days
I'll be back as soon as possible, okay?
What kind of trouble
did you get yourself into this time?
So, has everything been arranged?
Nevermind, I don't want to know
Everything has been arranged
Here's the tickets,
and you leave 6 o'clock local time
And this, is for you
After what you did for me,
If something happens to me,
give this to my boy okay?
Q Kay
Take care
I'll be back in a few days
I couldn't take Shiro with me
The desert elements
would've been too hard on him
And so, I must go it alone
My first target, is Red
He was a mercenary before being
employed by the Shadow Syndicate
And since Ken took over the business,
they will work for anyone
who pays a premium
Even if it's terrorists
Huh! We used to kill terrorists
C'mon, come here, c'mon
Are you getting everything ready?
C'mon, I told you, I told you.
Everything was-
Yah I'm trying boss,
I just talked to them
Just take care of it, okay?
Tomorrow we have training exercises
Okay boss, I'll take care of everything
Hey you get m work!
Get to work, get to work
What the?
No, please! No!
Who are you?!
Sam!
But you're...
dead?
So this is
what the Shadow Syndicates do in these days?
Training terrorists,
killing innocent people?
Killing's our business
and Ken has opened our market
We are making more money
than ever before
And my wife?
You know what happens
when you cross the Syndicate
Then you're gonna find out
what happens when you cross me!
I go to Cage's hideout
An environment only
he's tough enough to survive in
Not even the rats stay here
Cage was born on the streets, he was raised on the streets,
and he rules the streets
And tonight, he'll die on the streets
How you doing my boy, huh?
I'll be right back, okay?
I won't be long, I promise
Cage!
What do you want?
You know what I want
C'mon!
You think you can kill me'?
You piece of shit!
To find Yo, I go to his home
and walk the winding streets of the slum
Many here look up to Yo
A deadly killer with lots of money
To them, he's a hero,
a modern day Robin Hood
To me, he's a soon-to-be-dead punk
C'mon, baby, fight!
That's right!
I'm betting 2:1
Bring it on! Take your try!
See? See?
Let them know what you've got
Bite! Bite!
Woah! the tail's loose!
Hey pal, what are you doing here baby
Hey you, I'll take care of your child
He's dead meat
How dare he step on our ground
Who does he think he is?
What do you say boss?
Just look at him
I didn't think you would get here so soon
Not soon enough!
You know I don't like weapons
but if you want we can do that
Get him
- Hey you!
- Hey no need, I'll take care of him
Watch
Let's go Shiro
My next target is Yak
More of a monster than a man
People in his homeland believed
he was a tree ghost
He's not a ghost
But when I'm through with him,
he will be
Sh, sh, R's okay Shire, daddy's here
Hush little baby, don't say a word
Daddy's gonna buy you a mocking bird
Sh, sh, go to sleep Shiro
Before my showdown with Ken
I must leave Shiro
with one of the few people I trust
Ry o-san
He is a swordmaker,
and he lives the old ways of the samurai
When I was a little boy,
my parents died in an accident
and I was left alone
My uncle arrived
and took me to live with him
He taught me how to fight,
how to survive,
and how to live off the land
But he was a tormented soul
Haunted by his demons,
he couldn't take care of me
So he sent me on an old fishing boat,
to a distant land
to find a person he thought could
When I arrived, I walked and I walked
until I couldn't walk anymore
And that's when Ryo-san found me
That meet, gave me shelter
and he honed my skills
And that's when Tatsuo recruited me
Ry o-san
Sam
- I'm happy to see you Ryo-san
- Yeah
This is my son, Shiro
Very lovely
I have to ask if I can
leave him here with you for a while
There's something important I must do
and you're the only person I trust
Can I leave him with you?
Okay, I'll take care of him. Okay.
Here you go
It's okay, cry
Shiro, I'll be back as soon as possible
I love you
Of all the assassins on my hit list,
Ken is the one that I'm most worried of
This is why
I've decided to meet him face to face
No surprises, no ambush
So I sent him a message
I arranged the date, and the location
Despite the risks involved,
I wanted to meet him on his own turf
I want him to know
the seriousness of my intentions
that no place is safe for him
Not even his own backyard
Sam, you managed to kill my whole team
I'm impressed
I didn't come here to talk
You know you won't leave here alive
So what do you think Sam?
Maybe I'll just cut off your limbs
So you can spend the rest of your days
in guilt
It's you who caused
your wife's death
whose only crime is
that she loved the wrong man
Maybe I'll visit your son,
when I'm done with you
C'mon
So it seems that in the end,
it is you who'll have the happy ending
Soon you'll join
your wife on the other side
That is, of course, if she will have you,
if she can forgive you for
what you have done
So at last Shiro and I can live in peace
Still, because of my former life,
we must lay low
I miss Malee
And Shiro, he misses his mom
Try, throw me the ball, c'mon
C'mon
Oh, good throw, c'mon
C'mon, over here, c'mon
Okay, woah! What a kick!
Q Kay
Shiro!
Shiro
Tatsuo
let him go
I take your son,
like you took my son
Ken wasn't as honorable as you
He had no boundaries
and he killed my wife
Please,
I'm begging You
Let him go, you can take my life
As you wish!
Sam
Use the blade
You okay?
I saw your mommy here with us today
C'mon
I realize now that
she's always with us
She's in the wind, she's in the trees
She's in the earth and in the sky
She's everywhere
You okay my son? Yeah?
Let's go home now
- Daddy go home
- Yeah