There you are.
Go now!
GIRLS GIRLS
Are you going to Traunstein?
No, farther, to Bergen.
Quite a drag, huh?
Why don't you get off
at the next station
and take the bus to Neumarkt?
You'll get to Bergen one hour earlier.
Good idea.
Bye.
Where's the bus to Bergen leaving?
Back there,
but not until half an hour.
- What, no sooner than that?
- Yes, unfortunately.
Hello, are you going
in this direction?
Yeah, hop on.
Give me that.
Where are you headed?
To my parents, in Bergen.
- To Bergen?
- I meant to go there by bus,
but it's leaving much later.
I'm not going to Bergen though.
Yes, I know.
- Did you visit your boyfriend?
- No.
I'm coming from the reformatory.
Watch it, you beast!
Here. A little tranquilizer.
Thanks.
I want to get off.
Stop it, I want to get off.
What's the matter? I bet one
of those guys is going to Bergen!
Stop!
Station.
Over there. One of them
will surely give you a lift.
Give it to me,
I know these parts.
Thanks a lot, too!
Hey!
You're Andrea, aren't you?
Wait up!
Where are you going?
I recognized you right away.
Won't you slow down a bit?
I need to talk to you.
I'm Junior.
I know that.
Where is he?
Who?
He hasn't returned yet?
He left a little later.
- When is he coming back?
- I don't know. In a couple of days.
- Is that why you're here?
- I'm not here.
Come with me.
Don't you want to know
how he's doing?
Are you coming?
I don't think we can talk here.
Would you mind if we went up
to the house?
- We can leave that here.
- I don't know.
Actually, I meant to go to Bergen.
Are you longing so badly for Bergen?
You surely don't want somebody
to see you, right?
- I don't care.
- Come.
A young sow is standing
in front of a socket.
It grunts and says:
Come on out, you chicken!
Look who I brought along.
Very proper.
It's beautiful here, isn't it?
- So, what about him?
- Did you come because of him?
I was discharged today.
Got a lift on a silo truck.
- After all, I couldn't know...
- You want to start this all over?
- Are you nuts?
- Besides...
You can report him once again.
Sorry.
I completely forgot that you're not
dependent anymore.
Leave me alone.
I had nothing to do with it.
- My parents did...
- Did they sleep with him, or did you?
You must've told them.
And since you had to tell them
you could've also stopped them
from running to the police right away.
I couldn't have known.
- If he hadn't been so arrogant...
- Come on!
You just wanted to profit.
They would've liked him
as son-in-law, huh?
- That's not true.
- You're nothing but a slut.
You're lying.
You know you're lying.
Don't make such a fuss.
I'm sorry.
- Are you?
- Junior!
Junior! Lunch's ready!
Anna, lay the table for two.
How do you do?
She seems to like you.
- She's always been jealous.
- Nonsense!
"Buchental, Schlamoni,"
"Degerndorf, Taurick."
Sit here.
Or am I taking your seat?
I liked him very much.
And now?
Do you still love him?
A lot happened since then.
It's been a long time.
I don't mean to say that
I've got something against him.
Besides, I hardly think
that he wants to see me again.
I don't think he...
I believe
it's over.
They were jealous.
He would take me on Sundays.
- To parties or the theater.
- Is that a crime?
He gave me presents.
A watch.
Then they noticed.
They shook me down
until I admitted it.
You wanted to take him in.
That's not true.
I even told the judge
that it had been my fault.
- That I wanted it.
- But you didn't mind the fact
- that he was nearly your father's age.
- No.
Well, he's not that old after all.
Sometimes you could mistake us for brothers.
- He used to say so, too.
- Say, didn't your parents pick you up?
No.
Hey, fancy that:
My mother visited me just once
in those 17 months.
- Mean, isn't it?
- Listen, I need to go to the factory.
Will you wait for me?
I'll be right back.
You can go to my cabin,
up by the pit. I'll meet you there.
You'll wait, won't you?
I'll make it quick.
I won't go up there.
I'm sorry.
It took a little longer.
Ever since he left, I had to
run the company all by myself,
without knowing much about it, really.
I thought you were waiting
for me at the house?
I used to come up here more often,
in my holidays.
I can't stand Switzerland.
I could've seen you, but he didn't
want me to go to the factory.
I sometimes watched you from the window.
Once, you crashed his sports car
against the rain barrel.
You were terrified,
but he just laughed.
What did you do in the garage?
I simply felt like sitting in a posh car.
- Come.
- I can get up by myself.
Come on, I'm in a hurry.
They need me before they call it a day.
- So, what about the garage?
- Oh, nothing.
Do you know that I was never allowed
to go inside when you were there?
That pissed you off, didn't it?
Wait! Catch me!
Did you hurt yourself?
No.
- Come on, I need to hurry.
- Just a moment.
Soon we won't find anyone in the office.
Say, can you ask them if someone
is going to Bergen?
Anything else, Schiller?
No. Just the detonation tomorrow, Junior.
Alright.
- Hey, you said you'd ask!
- Just a moment.
Have a good trip, Schorsch!
Okay!
Well then?
Don't you want to stay for the night?
Marble, stone and iron break,
but our Io ve will not.
Your parents won't know
that you were coming today.
Besides, it's already late.
You'll have trouble finding someone
who'll take you to Bergen today.
You can sleep in mother's room.
No, that won't work.
Your parents will be aware of the fact
that you've been discharged in the morning.
They'll wonder where you've been all day.
I'll think of something.
You'll definitely be better off
if you come home in the morning.
I don't know.
... but our Io ve will not.
I can't stay for the night like that.
Checkmate.
You could win once in a while,
don't you think?
I've had enough.
I'm going to bed now.
Wait a second.
What about the kiss?
Alright, tomorrow at breakfast then.
It's nice that you've stayed.
- Good night.
- Shall I switch on your light?
- I know my way. Sleep well.
- Thanks, you too.
I could give you a lift home in my car.
But I guess you prefer not to come home
before lunchtime tomorrow, right?
Yes.
I think so, too.
See you tomorrow.
Everybody ready?
Go!
We took out quite a bit too much,
didn't we?
We still need to blast away
that head up there.
- Hey, you takin' shelter with me?
- Hands off me, grandpa.
Leave her!
Go back to your digger.
Hey!
- So, did you sleep well?
- Yes.
Have there ever been accidents
when you had an explosion?
No, I don't think so.
Are you afraid?
Shall I tell you something?
Is it funny?
It happened a couple
of weeks ago.
Next to that stone over there.
I was carving a stick.
Suddenly, I feel spied upon.
I turn around
- and there's a man behind me.
- Goodness gracious!
Your hand is so warm.
At first, I wanted to run away.
But since he didn't move,
I walked up to him.
Look, over there.
Come on, whoever gets in the
sunlight first!
I've won!
You're pretty.
How about now?
You've got pretty eyes.
He had the same eyes.
When I came closer, I noticed
that he wasn't wearing any shoes.
Was it too hot for him?
I like your hair.
What eyes he had!
Suddenly, I realized:
he's not standing, he's hanging!
Even your nose is beautiful.
Who was that man?
Don't!
Who he was?
A pest exterminator.
Very funny.
Why... did he hang himself?
Because...
Because all of those bugs had gone
over his head.
What if somebody comes?
In America, they cover them in gold.
Do they feel the pain?
They die at once.
What will you do
when he comes back?
He isn't back yet.
- I'm scared.
- You're telling me?
You're going away,
but I'm his son.
See that furnace there?
We built it, while father was gone.
Yeah, it's great.
She really had the nerve
to come back.
Her?
She dares to do plenty of
other things, too.
Is that so?
Sometimes I'd like to know
what you're doing over there,
in that house.
Hey!
Gone mad, old buck?
Don't get all worked up,
you hypocritical bitch!
I supervised the installation
and construction myself.
It's not finished yet.
Watch out!
If you fall down there
you're minced meat.
Anything left to do for today?
No, not today.
- Look!
- I'll show you something.
Gosh, the warden!
I thought she was calling
only after three days?
"My dear..."
"how did you like the three days
with your family?"
You know what?
I'll stay.
Awful!
Aren't you ashamed to lie
in bed with a stranger?
And you, with your father's girlfriend!
I don't find that funny at all.
Oh, you!
How could you be so shameless,
with someone so much older than you!
All I know is that you've slept
with somebody, who's twice your age!
And who knows with whom else.
Can't you say something?
You're a whore.
Are you buzzing off?
Beat it, but quickly!
400 sacks to Nuremberg and
50 to Neumarkt. Hurry up!
Else, try to get the driver of the
Stucka mine. He has to go to Zirndorf.
- Alright, see you later.
- And tell Mr. Schiller to see me.
Did you get your trailer fixed, Schorsch?
- Yeah, right there.
- Well, what're you waiting for?
Drive off, we hardly manage anyway,
and do it pronto, will you?
- This delivery is very important for us.
- Telephone!
Yes. What's up?
What?!
Else, where's the commission book?
Yes. Yes.
Yes.
Yes, that will be fine.
Alright, don't detonate yet,
I'm coming up.
And get that pump!
- You called for me. Something happened?
- I'll be back at once!
The car is in use right now.
Never mind!
- Has something happened?
- What do I know?
Don't you move.
Excuse me, can you tell me
how to find the Kopernikus Road?
Yes, of course I know.
Well, how do you get there?
Drive up over there,
around the memorial,
over the old bridge
and then onto the main road.
Thank you.
Where have you been?
I've been looking for you all day.
- You don't say.
- I need to talk to you.
- Your parents are out anyway.
- Do you always have to force me?
Please.
All right.
But not here.
Try to understand.
It won't work with us.
- Why not?
- I'll have to go home eventually.
- Hey, boss!
- I'd driven you home
if you'd wanted me to.
Another letter!
Come on, let's go.
And besides,
what about Ernst?
Damn it, I can't stand that "Ernst"!
All right, "your father".
Drive me home.
Let's go to Munich.
I'll change on the way.
"She's never been faster than today."
Hey, how are you doing?
Thanks!
New chick?
- Are you still mad at me for this morning?
- Never mind.
- Hey, you! Tommy's giving a party.
- Hi, Flo.
- Are you coming?
- I might, later.
Bring her with you!
She wouldn't be bad for a night, right?
- Yeah! She's nice, isn't she?
- Why don't you try her?
- Loser!
- Loser or not,
you'll always get it if you got
a fat sports car.
- Or a factory.
- Or something like that.
If that's his only way to make
an impression...
He'd even run off with your girlfriend.
What? Mine?
- Don't make me laugh!
- You'll see.
All the females in the office
are after him.
That's where he snacked
on that girl, too.
Now they're snacking on him.
And he... will be next.
Leave the boy alone!
I'm glad to have him around.
Morning, guys. What's up?
May I join in on the joke?
- Can I talk to you for a moment?
- Sure.
Do you actually know
who that girl is?
- Why?
- Well, I just thought...
Leave the thinking to me!
Well Schiller, I'll be off.
Else has my number in Hanover.
- Call me if anything happens.
- Very well, Mr. Ledebur.
"65 vouchers for Junior"
"Dear Mister Spieker,"
"...as far as the advisory board
is concerned."
"For the remainder of our hopefully
prosperous trading relationship,"
"I remain your devoted friend
von Vorstetten."
"Dear Elisabeth...
LIME KILN von VORSTETTEN & SON
Former STEINBRENNER & SON
"The boy is in a difficult
stage of development."
"I hope that my sweet mob is
not bothering you too much."
"Sincerely, your friend."
- Checked us out a little, haven't we?
- I was looking for something.
Well? Did you find it?
One morning, she was gone.
She took her suitcase
and walked down the street.
I've never saw her again.
Later, we put her things
into boxes
and then a delivery truck came
and picked up all the stuff.
Why did she run off?
Country life proved too dull for mylady.
He was traveling all the time
and left her alone by herself.
He looked like Junior back then.
How long have you been here, Anna?
Nearly eleven years.
I was 23 when I started here.
Back then, they kept the big house.
One cook, one domestic servant
and two maids.
When she left,
they were all sacked.
And you?
Me?
I lived alone with him, here.
Junior had been sent
to a boarding school.
Wasn't there too much work?
For two people?
Back then, I didn't look so bad.
You should've seen me.
When I went to the factory,
they dropped their work.
Oh well.
In any case, I didn't do badly.
See?
That's no business of mine.
Looking for your boyfriend?
He's in the woods.
What are you doing?
Want to have a look?
Getting a kick out of this, huh?
- I thought you were at the factory?
- As you see, I'm here. What do you want?
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
Tell me,
did Anna ever have a thing
with your father?
- Nonsense!
- I don't know.
With Ernst, I wouldn't be surprised.
Ernst, Ernst, Ernst! Dammit,
how many times have I told you
that I don't want you to call him
Ernst all the time?!
Say, why are you in such a bad mood, hm?
Because of the workers.
Just what I needed.
They just pull off their usual show.
- Shall we go?
- Come on.
I don't feel like it.
Take me with you!
Junior, are you there? Come out,
we want to ask you something!
Beloved Anna, where has that
famous Junior hidden?
Probably at the factory.
Come on in!
- If that ain't an offer!
- Let's go inside!
Junior has a new girlfriend!
- You don't say. Whose are you?
- Nobody's.
You don't need to wait.
- His girlfriend is much more beautiful.
- What does she look like?
She's got big green eyes!
- Do you know where they are?
- In a castle up in the woods.
Can you do me a favor?
Go there and tell them
that we are here, will you?
How stupid,
you sound like a child.
There they are!
Let's go after them!
Come on!
- Come on, this way!
- Yeah.
They are up there!
Go, go!
Come on!
We'll get you in the end!
Hurry up!
Go, go!
Hey!
Come on.
- Come on in.
- No!
It's really warm.
Shall I?
Jump, frog!
Look at yourselves!
- Where are the others?
- They wanted to get booze
but I think they got stuck.
Come.
What are you doing here?
Is that all you can say?
So it's true after all.
- What's true?
- About your new girlfriend.
Don't do that.
Love?
Wait for me downstairs.
Are you coming to the Schlosscafé, too?
- Wait, I'll be right down.
- Okay, but hurry up.
Are you ready yet?
Who was that?
- Bang!
- Are you coming?
- Listen, can you do me a favor?
- Sure, Junior.
Fetch the blonde and
take her with you, all right?
Okay, she gets cleaned and buried.
Who's the other one?
- A gift from heaven.
- Oh yes, from daddy.
- Well then.
- Are you coming?
Why ask him?
Ask her.
Come here.
Siggi, Willi, Richard, Joe,
and that's the lovely Monika.
I think we'd better leave.
- I think so, too.
- What about you?
What did I say? Love!
- Who's giving me a ride?
- Come on, let's beat it.
I'll stop by again,
before the holidays are over.
- Are you going back to Lausanne?
- Hey, take me with you!
They got a great club over there.
Hey, what about me?
Don't leave me!
Are you going back to Lausanne?
- Why don't you come with me?
- What do I do there?
Listen, I'll talk to...
No, that won't work.
I can study in Munich. You could
come visit me every Sunday.
- What were you going to say?
- Just an idiotic idea.
I definitely won't go back
to Lausanne.
- What's your old man doing?
- Why?
He's fighting for his pension.
War injury, but they don't accept it.
So that's where he got to
practice with the law.
Paragraph 174 isn't so well known.
I thought we agreed
to skip this topic.
It's an interesting topic.
The police talked him into
using that paragraph.
All right, your father
is completely innocent.
You're not at the factory?
It's funny, watching you in your sleep.
You've got no idea
how ugly you are!
That's unfair.
Watch me, you look like this:
Besides, you talk in your sleep.
- You're lying!
- So, what about Johanna?
You're lying!
If you don't admit at once
that you're lying,
- I'll kill you!
- "Late night edition!"
"Vice scandal at cement factory!"
"Lover strangles son and takes
father to jail!"
- As you wish! So you suffocate!
- Push harder!
Look here.
You need to go back home today.
If your parents are suspicious,
I'll talk to them.
- What's the matter?
- Dad may come back any moment.
- Something has to happen.
- Won't he send a telegram first?
Sure, and he might not
come back today.
But as soon as he's here,
I'll talk to him. About us, I mean.
- If you want, you can work here again.
- I don't want to work here anymore.
Even the caretaker's little daughter
knows about us.
All that stupid gossip.
I neither want to live
with my parents.
Be honest, you're just afraid
that father and you will reconcile.
Nonsense!
Don't be childish.
You think he's coming back,
and everything goes on,
as if nothing happened?
You think running away helps?
All right, I'll drive you home.
When he's here, I'll talk to him.
We'll sort everything out.
Okay.
You're discharged.
Hey.
Come here.
I need to tell you something.
Now, go to the factory.
Well, Anna?
What are your workers doing?
Oh, you!
Come, come!
- It's not my fault! I didn't do anything.
- It's never your fault.
- I'm fed up with this!
- Stupid excuses.
Hi Junior. We'll tear open the hill now.
You should come over.
Sorry about yesterday, Schiller.
I've been an idiot.
- I'm the one who's sorry.
- Let's forget about it. Any news?
Yes. The general manager's
left for Hanover.
The trade fair, I know.
Pammer, do me a favor:
Leave Anna alone, will you?
- What did he say?
- That he will shut you up.
Shut me up?
He'd better watch for his girl,
so that I won't make it with her!
- What's the matter?
- Oh, that horny dame!
Horny dame? Who? Anna?
She used to complain to the senior,
and now, it's the boy who's bothering me.
Charming!
Hello Anna.
You look so dressed.
You'll be rid of me soon.
- Well, bon voyage then.
- Need a hand?
No!
As you want.
Oh, Anna?
I'll stay for lunch though.
Well, if we cut up here,
it won't fit anymore.
How much is it?
About fifty marks.
Keep the change.
Thanks.
The old man's back.
Go down and tell Schiller.
Listen, the old man's back.
The old man's back.
Hey, the Senior has returned.
Have you heard?
The boss is back.
Hey chubby, the old man's back.
Hey you, your supreme boss is back.
- Girls, he's back!
- And just in time, too.
Cheers.
- Thanks.
- Cheers.
Just a moment.
Hey!
Bring a crate of beer!
- I'm paying for the round.
- Okay, Junior.
Is it your birthday?
Thanks.
There you go. Cheers!
It's a nice day, isn't it?
Cheers!
To your health!
Come with me.
I need to tell you something.
- The old man's back.
- What?
So, you cryin' already?
Your boss is back.
Look, over there!
- Hey!
Higher!
Thank you, Fritz!
Good bye!
Hey!
What are you doing here?
What are you here for?
How did you know
I'd get discharged today?
You...
I'm awfully happy to see you.
Come inside.
I'm glad.
You look sweet.
Have you seen my boy?
Where's he at?
Huh?
Well?
Come, sit over here.
Wine?
Junior!
Well, how are you?
- Are you happy that I'm back?
- Yes...
Have a seat first.
You're still panting.
There.
Drink.
Thanks.
- Well, how do you like her?
- You know, I...
Don't you like her?
Well, bon appétit!
Mmh, it's excellent.
That's something you have to
renounce every day in prison.
Not to speak of other things.
Well, finally one of you two
opens their mouth.
This isn't a funeral, is it?
When did you arrive?
An hour ago. I meant to call you first,
so you can pick me up,
but I just took a cab instead.
Why don't you say something?
That smells good. I would've preferred
to take you with me as my cook.
By the way, even inside,
I still made some money.
74 marks 30.
I spent half of it on the cab though.
- Is the new cauldron finished?
- Not yet.
In about two weeks.
We'll go up there later, huh?
Isn't he great?
He managed the factory all by himself.
Don't exaggerate.
Ledebur did most of the work.
Nothing against Ledebur, but without you,
it wouldn't have worked.
But that's over now.
You'll go straight back to university.
Say...
I've reconsidered.
About Lausanne, I mean.
Don't worry.
We'll talk about that later.
And you?
What are you doing?
Do you want to work for us again?
No.
I'll talk to your parents.
I've got some talking to do
with them anyway.
Junior will have to excuse us after lunch.
We can talk about it then.
And later, you and me
will go to the factory.
You haven't changed at all.
Where are you going?
Well, I can do it later.
Come on, let's go.
Come on.
And tonight, we'll have a little
game of chess, right?
Junior, have you seen Sabine?
- Is she with you?
- No.
There were some lumberjacks.
I don't trust those fellas.
- Come off it!
- If you see her,
tell her to come home at once!
Who is it?
It's me. I need to get something
from the desk.
- Does it have to be now?
- I'm sorry.
There you are!
I've been looking for you all over.
Let's go over.
I'm coming after you right away,
there's just something I forgot.
Did you tell him?
- I'll tell him then!
- Stay here!
I'll be back right away.
I'll give you a lift home then.
I must talk to you.
Right now?
Can't we do that later, in peace?
No, now!
It's very important.
Alright, is something with your car?
- No, I...
- Greetings, Mister baron!
Schiller! How's it going?
How are the wife and children,
is everything fine?
Yes, thank you.
The girl's going to high school now.
- Did you find her?
- I'll give her a big goodie-bag.
- After all, I'm her godfather.
- Thanks, that won't be necessary.
- She was in the woods.
- Schiller, go to the office
and get the books ready.
I want to check them later.
Yes. Right away.
He's acting as if we still lived
under the emperor.
- Hello, Otto!
- Hello!
Let me see.
Well done.
- Cheers!
- Back on the track, boss?
Go on laughing.
You'd rather like it.
If he knew.
- Hello!
- This is Schorsch, our new driver.
Hello.
I hope you like it with us.
I do, thanks.
- Good day everybody!
- Hello.
I didn't memorize you this pretty.
Did you dye your hair?
Hi there.
Nice decoration.
Who's using...
It smells like Cabochard.
Hello, brown-eye.
Well, where's Ledebur?
He's in Hanover, at the exhibition.
At the exhibition?
Very well.
Hello, Paul.
Is everything working out?
Listen a second, will you?
Come, let's go over there,
nobody will disturb us there.
Come.
You see?
That's why I'm wearing a helmet.
You know, Dad...
I see you've been making
nice progress with the building.
So, what were you going to tell me?
Watch out!
Quite deep.
Why haven't you fixed this yet?
So, what were you going to tell me?
It wasn't easy,
building the kettle.
You've done very well.
I'm proud of you.
Oh, one thing I meant to tell you:
I'd like to study in Munich.
All of a sudden?
Don't you like Lausanne anymore?
- I do, but...
- Then why the change?
- Well, I just thought...
- I'd like to check the books first.
- Well, kids, you know...
- Watch out!
Alright, my beauties,
show me the cashier books.
Let's see how badly you cheated.
I'm keeping the book now.
Didn't Junior tell you?
Give it to me.
Junior? He's got something
entirely else on his mind.
Why?
What do you mean?
Huh?
Come on!
Spill the beans.
- She's gone.
- Gone?
Where?
- With her suitcase.
- With her suitcase?
Anna, will you make us
roast hare tonight?
I'm sure Ernst will be delighted.
Where am I supposed
to get a hare at this hour?
- How'd you like pork leg tonight?
- I hope there's enough left.
- Where's the boy?
- It'll be enough for you two.
- Why two?
- She's gone.
- Gone?
- Yes.
Half an hour ago.
Would you like pork leg for tonight?
Great.
- And a game of chess afterwards?
- Why not?
Maybe we should accept the offer
from Habelburger Zement after all.
What do you think?