He has signed it so well.
You are still so young and already doing forgery!
You have signed for three people.
They cried to me that they have failed
they will receive a thrashing at the house.
So?
Will you sign for them? Stupid!
Sir! Sir!
Henceforth, I will not do it.
It is hurting, sir.
Rascal! Give me his card.
He must have signed this too.
You are a meritorious student.
If you do anything wrong now, your life will be ruined. Rascal!
Go and get your father right away.
Till then, don't permit him into the class.
Don't stand in front of me. Go.
Why are you standing? Go!
Go!
Mother!
Karthik has come. Go fast.
Where is my shirt? - It is lying on the floor.
Hey! Didn't you know that he will come early?
You should have told me.
I had no idea. I thought, he'd only come in the evening.
Bye. - Okay.
Don't tell father that Mr. Venkatesan had come.
I will get you whatever you ask for.
Where is our son? Did he eat?
He said that he doesn't want to eat and has gone out to play.
Why do you allow him to play at this time?
You should have slapped him and asked him to study.
Come here. Won't you listen to your mother?
You are sassing me! From where did you learn to do this?
Just question me!
Don't question her if she makes a mistake.
What has happened?
I am asking you. What happened?
Tell me. What has happened?
When I came in this afternoon
Mr. Venkatesan and mother were together.
I did not believe even when the neighbors told me about it.
What are you going to say now? You dog!
If you utter one more word, you will lose respect!
I work hard to take care of your needs. - Really!
If that was the case, why would have I gone to another person?
Are you arguing with me?
Yes, what will you do?
Go, do whatever you can. Go!
Dear!
What will I do?
Someone, please come!
You have left me and gone!
You went leaving us behind!
You! What brings you here at this hour?
I am going to Madurai. I'll be back only after two days.
So, I wanted to meet you. - Speak softly. Karthik is sleeping.
Come inside without making any noise.
The house is on fire! Open the door! - Open the door!
Somebody, open the door! - Save us! - Oh! - The house is on fire!
Somebody, open the door! - Please open the door!
Save us! - Save us!
'I'
"Superior to everything in the world"
"is a man's small heart."
"It holds many thoughts."
"But what will happen in real life?"
"In the direction you point out"
"rivers don't flow."
"In the path it flows"
"you run."
"That which troubles you.."
"There may be hundreds of sorrows."
"Cross all the hurdles"
"and fight."
"Superior to everything in the world"
"is a man's small heart."
"You are a drop in the ocean."
"Why are you worried?"
"Join the waves and play."
"Life is yours."
"Why do you need relations now?"
"The world is there for you."
"Stones which bear the pain"
"become statues."
"Only those boats which cross the waves"
"reach the shore."
"Only clothes which are pricked by needles"
"become dresses worthy of wearing."
"From darkness, light takes birth."
"Always!"
"Superior to everything in the world"
"is a man's small heart."
"It holds many thoughts."
"But what will happen in real life?"
"In the direction you point out"
"rivers don't flow."
"In the path it flows"
"you run."
"That which troubles you.."
"There may be hundreds of sorrows."
"Cross all the hurdles"
"and fight."
"Superior to everything in the world"
"is a man's small heart."
"It holds many thoughts."
"But what will happen in real life?"
Come, Karthik.
Sit down.
You are getting released today, right?
So, I called you as I wanted to see you.
You are very studious.
Normally, boys who come here, don't show any interest in academics.
Only education can do us good.
Don't worry about the past, think about the future.
Okay, sir. - I've pinned lots of hopes on you.
The next time, I see you, you should be a changed person.
Okay, sir.
There are few dresses in this. - Thanks, sir.
Keep this money for your expenses. - Okay, sir.
This is all I can afford for now.
I have spoken to your uncle.
Go and see him.
If you need any help, don't hesitate to ask me.
Madi, I had asked for coffee.
I'm getting it. Do I have 10 hands?
Aunt, are you fine? - Yes, I'm fine.
Hello, brother. - Hey, stop playing.
Go inside and study.
Always after me!
Come inside for a moment.
Karthik, have your coffee.
Why has your nephew come here?
Who else does he have?
Are you a fool?
Did you think about our children?
Both of them are young.
If you allow that murderer to stay here
they will get spoilt.
Why are you talking like this?
Then, leave us.
We will go somewhere.
Allow your nephew to stay here and pamper him.
Did you raise him all these years?
Is he a small kid?
Let me know, if you can't tell him. I will go and tell him.
I'll call you in the morning. Okay, bye. - Where had you been?
You're completely drenched.
'Chennai, Chennai.. Next, it will stop only in Tambaram.'
'Chennai, Chennai.. Go inside.'
'Chennai, Chennai.'
'The next stop is Tambaram.'
'Chennai, Chennai..'
'Show me your ticket.'
'Go inside and sit.'
Sir, the window seat is mine.
Okay. - Thanks.
Do you remember whatever I said?
Yes, mother. - Go carefully. - Okay, mother.
Call me without fail.
'Oh, no! What has happened!'
'Dear, where are you? - Oh, God!'
'I lost my son. - Oh, my God!'
Mister..
'Please, get up!'
Mister.. - 'Please get up!'
'Oh, God!' - 'Please carry him.'
Mister..
Mister.. Mister..
'Come here!'
Sir.. - It's hurting. - Sir, please help me.
I've hurt my hand. Please, sir.
'Come on. Hold his hand.'
I need a room.
How did you get hurt?
Bus accident, sir.
Where are you coming from? - Ramanathapuram.
Where do you work?
I have come here in search of a job.
Can I get a room? - We don't have a single room.
There's a triple cot room. Will you share?
Okay, sir.
Monthly, it will come to Rs.1,500.
Give me your address.
Sir, this is your room. - Okay, sir.
"Even I have a place."
"By the grace of God."
Salim. My name is Kumar.
I am looking at your mark sheet.
You will definitely get a medical seat.
You have got very good marks.
By the way, Salim, I have kept your suitcases there.
That is your cot.
Out of curiosity, I saw your certificates.
Are you from Ramanathapuram?
Very good. Even I am from Tirunelveli.
But I married a girl from your place.
Near Paramakudi.
I've relatives near Ramanathapuram.
I visit them quite often.
All that is fine.
Why is your hand bandaged?
I am vacating the room. - Sign here.
Thank you, sir.
You have to give the rent by the 2nd of every month.
Okay, sir. - Else, I will open the room
and throw your things out. - Okay, sir.
What do you do?
I have come to study at the college.
"All wrong deeds are not wrong."
"All right things are not right."
"If you do the wrong things rightly"
"it is not wrong, it is not wrong."
"Open the doors, let me show you something."
"You gotta call me. My name is Salim."
"Every day that I keep hunting. Let me go on, let me go strong."
"If Gandhi and Buddha"
"did something wrong and then, reform.."
"Move it, move it, move it, always."
"Every day, I believe that I will be fine."
"Someone good in the future, I think, I will be fine."
"All wrong deeds are not wrong."
"All right things are not right."
"If you do the wrong things rightly"
"it is not wrong, it is not wrong."
"Open the doors, let me show you something."
"You gotta call me. My name is Salim."
"Every day that I keep hunting. Let me go on, let me go strong."
"Since snakes are poisonous"
"we get scared and stand far."
"But poor goats.."
"We cook them on the fire."
"When you speak what's right"
"they will call you a coward."
"If you have a knife in your hand"
"they will call you a leader."
"Whenever you tell lies"
"they will say, there's no one like you in the world."
"When you tell the truth"
"they will say, there's not a fool like you in the world."
"All wrong deeds are not wrong."
"All right things are not right."
"If you do the wrong things rightly"
"it is not wrong, it is not wrong."
"Open the doors, let me show you something."
"You gotta call me. My name is Salim."
"Every day that I keep hunting. Let me go on, let me go strong."
"Life is a struggle."
"Life is a business."
"If you fall down"
"even the grass will laugh."
"Whichever direction you go in"
"you will be shunned."
"You will be deceived."
"Your heart will break."
"The world"
"wags its tail for money."
"It will encourage the lies."
"It will destroy the truth."
"Let your yearnings abandon you today."
"Let the joys increase."
"Let the curses run away."
"All wrong deeds are not wrong."
"All right things are not right."
"If you do the wrong things rightly"
"it is not wrong, it is not wrong."
"Open the doors, let me show you something."
"You gotta call me. My name is Salim."
"Every day that I keep hunting. Let me go on, let me go strong."
"If Gandhi and Buddha"
"did something wrong and then, reform.."
"Move it, move it, move it, always."
"Every day, I believe that I will be fine."
"Someone good in the future, I think, I will be fine."
Hello.
Not you. You, come here.
What is your name? - Why are you asking?
My hobby is to ask the names of beautiful girls.
Didn't you get it? I am ragging.
Which year are you in?
What is this? You are questioning me constantly.
Don't get scared.
Uma.
'3RD year, M.B.B.S, Bio Chemistry.'
Sir, what is your name?
Sorry, just for fun.
I thought, you were in the first year. Sorry.
If you come late to my class, I will not allow you inside.
May I come in, sir?
Are you late on the first day itself? What is your name?
Ashok. - Come in.
Since it is the first day, I am allowing you inside.
Henceforth, if you are late, you need not come to my class.
Sorry, sir. - What have you worn?
Don't you know, you shouldn't come to the class
wearing casuals and jeans? - Really sorry, sir.
I forgot as I was in a hurry. - Go.
Sir, have I come to a different class?
Is it the first year?
Yes. It is the first year.
Then, have you come to a different class?
The moment I saw you, I thought you to be a senior.
I've come after completing B.Sc. This is my second degree.
Good. So, you must be really studious. I am Ashok.
Salim. - Is there any problem?
Nothing, sir.
Good evening, sir. - Good evening.
My name is Salim, first year student.
I have come from Ramanathapuram. - Okay.
Can I get hostel accommodation? - Is it so?
Have you submitted an application? - Yes, I have.
Late admission? - Yes, sir.
All the rooms are full.
After three months
the PG students will vacate after their semester exams.
You can come and enquire then. - Please, sir.
Okay. - Thank you, sir. - Okay.
Punctured.
Brother, this is Ashok speaking.
I've got a flat tire.
I am in college. Will it take an hour?
Please try to come early.
I have to reform him first.
Do you have a spare tire and the necessary tools?
Do you know how to change a car's tire?
Yes, I do.
Are you Ashok?
What! Do you think yourself to be great? - Me?
It has been just two days since you came to college.
How dare you rag a senior girl!
I teased a senior girl?
Sorry, sir. I guess, you've misunderstood.
You are Ashok, aren't you?
Ashok! Who me?
Hey, are you Ashok?
Are you Ashok? You told me, you are Salim.
What is it? Arrogance?
What are you staring at me for?
Being sarcastic!
Hey, who is Ashok between the two of you?
Sorry, sir.
He did it unknowingly.
It was a mistake indeed. Forgive him.
Forgive him! Are you both playing the fool?
I'll hit you!
I did apologize. Then, why?
You have raised your hand at me!
I will teach you a lesson.
I will not spare you.
Bye, Ashok. See you in the morning.
Hey, where are you going? Get in the car. I will drop you.
It is okay, Ashok. I will take the bus.
The person who went now, may come back with his men.
Why do you want to get caught? Get in.
Senthil, this is not good.
You haven't paid rent for the last two months.
Am I running a charitable institution here?
Salim!
Please come here.
You came in, but the moment you saw me, you're making an exit.
Sorry, sir. Somebody is waiting outside.
What did I tell you when you came here?
You said that I must pay the rent by the 2nd of every month.
Do you remember? - Yes.
You are studying medicine. I thought, you will be punctual.
Tomorrow is the eighth.
Sorry, sir.
I will give it to you in a week. - Salim..
Don't make me angry.
I won't wait for a week.
Within two days, if I don't get the rent
I will throw your bags away.
Don't feel sorry at that time.
Okay, sir. I will give it to you.
I have told the manager. Vacate immediately.
He said somebody is waiting outside, but he is going upstairs.
'Within two days if I don't get the rent'
'I will throw your bags away.'
Salim..
Hang on, I'll be back soon.
There's one guy coming here. What is it? Ragging again?
You ran away when I asked your name.
Temerity, is it?
Did I misbehave with you?
I felt like talking to you as you are beautiful.
Will you send your men to hit me for that?
Do you think I will get scared?
What are you saying? Did I send men to hit you?
Actually, I.. - Hey! Who is that man?
Is he your friend or boyfriend?
He is talking about Satish.
Why did he go to him?
Hello, look at me and talk.
I never complained about anything to anybody.
If somebody came and fought with you because of me
I am sorry. Okay?
If you say sorry, will it be set right?
What else do you want me to do?
Offer coffee.
Thanks.
You are very bold. What is your name?
Ashok.
You are proposing a senior without any fear.
You are telling me that I am beautiful.
I am telling the truth.
We have something personal to speak. You..
Then, you drop her.
Rekha, wait, I am also coming with you.
Ashok, are you kidding?
If she goes, I'll have to walk back.
Too good. Let her go. I will drop you.
That's not required. Give that bag. It is getting late.
Okay, I am not kidding. I am serious.
If you accept my friendship, come with me.
Otherwise, take this.
You can say goodbye right away and leave.
Bye, Salim. See you later.
Bye, Ashok.
It's not even been a month since you joined
and you already need an advance?
I'm in need of it, sir.
Attend to that corner table.
Good evening, sir. - Good evening.
Salim, do you work here? - Yes, sir.
It's a part time job.
There are some problems at home.
So, I've decided to take care of my expenses.
You can do a job which is related to your studies.
If there is any such job, let me know, sir. I will do it.
Good. Senior students are helping me in my research.
You may have to refer to books. Come along.
Thank you, sir. - Welcome.
Thank you.
Hello. Hi, Salim, tell me. - Ashok, Salim speaking.
You have to do me a small favor.
Tell me. - I have to pay the rent.
I will return it to you as soon as I get my salary.
How much? - Rs.2000.
Come to my house tomorrow evening. Okay?
Thanks. Thanks, Ashok. Thanks.
"You the hot type"
"I'm the rock type."
"You that fly type"
"I'm that right type."
"Okay."
"When the bass drops"
"you know what to do."
"When the beat drops"
"Holla holla baby holla at this thug"
"Holla holla baby holla at this thing"
"Teenage never hesitates."
"They don't mind any hindrance in their way."
"Our legs are not on the floor now."
"No, no, no!"
"No shyness while alone."
"No use in standing alone."
"Nothing is a burden on the air."
"It's never wrong to cross the border line."
"Sleepless nights.."
"Nonstop fun till dawn."
"Our colorful dreams don't diminish."
"They never diminish."
"Yesterday has passed."
"Tomorrow is a dream."
"Today is ours."
"It is ours."
"If our friends get together"
"it gives rise to joy."
"Crores of desires"
"will knock the door."
"It's like the way your body moves I got to tell you what's up. What's up."
"I got the top type of Hustler's want to step in this club.."
"It's not some juvenile kids actually glow Wi-Fi."
"We gotta move your dollar bills baby, certified!"
"You know, you got me say I'm really bad like Michael Jackson."
"Designer suits, premier, proper like in action."
"Haul like a guy's thing."
"High like a vulture."
"Fly like a superman."
"Fly on departure."
"Friendship knows no time."
"Conversation never stops, once begun."
"No intervals here."
"Not at all."
"Don't hide anything within you."
"You don't get another chance."
"It's only one life, don't forget."
"Don't forget."
"Lying on friend's shoulder"
"will heal all the problems."
"In bad and good times"
"friendship can handle all problems."
Are you done with the work you'd come here for?
Did anything spill over you? - No. - Dude..
I spilled everything here only. - He is telling it so proudly!
Suresh.
Suresh, I'd asked for a servant. What happened?
Only if something like this happens
will you remember about the servant.
I'm enquiring for one. I haven't got anyone yet.
Sundar has lost control. Drop him home.
I have to drop them too. Can he walk?
Look, he is coming.
Dude..
Is the party over?
See you. - Bye.
He is drunk.
Do you have something left?
Yes, there's your vomit. Take it if you want.
Happy birthday.
Brother, happy birthday. - Take him.
Hey, will you not get liquor tomorrow?
Why do you hold me and walk?
How did you come?
By bus.
It is late. You will not get any bus now.
Stay back and leave in the morning.
Okay. - Nice to meet you, Salim.
Wait here, I will be back.
Salim.
Did you clean all this up? - Yes, Ashok. I was waiting for you to wake up.
You were saying, you don't have a servant.
I was feeling bored too.
So, I decided to do it myself.
Thanks. Leave everything. You come.
It is done, Ashok.
Did you wake up just now? - Yes.
Good morning, Salim. - Good morning.
Rupa, can you see any difference?
Difference?
I can see the effect of Salim's stay.
Salim, why don't you stay here with Ashok?
What do you say, Ashok?
Yeah.
Salim, vacate the mansion and come here.
Silence means he has agreed.
Okay.
Let's go this way.
Ashok!
I will go by bus.
Are you kidding me?
Wait, I will come.
Ashok
I want to talk to you.
Why are you avoiding me?
I have expressed myself quite clearly.
There's nothing left to talk.
You came to me on your own.
You said, you liked me.
Now, all of a sudden, why don't you like me?
I didn't like it when you said, you loved me.
It is true that I liked you and mingled with you.
But that does not mean that I love you.
I was just being friendly
but I never expected you to take it so seriously.
No, you are confusing me with your talk.
If I've done anything wrong.. - Uma, you are confused.
Understand. Think of our age.
Don't tell anyone that you love me the way you told me.
They will laugh at you. Leave it at this stage.
Has she left?
Yes, she has. - She is mad.
Come fast. Let's escape.
I thought, she will give me company for roaming around
but she says, she loves me.
In that case, I'll have to love every girl in this city.
Brother, do you know a boy named Salim who studies in first year?
No, sir, I don't know.
Salim, if anybody asks for me, tell them, I am in the bathroom.
It must be my dad.
Sir..
I am Ashok's friend, Salim speaking.
Ashok is in the bathroom, sir.
His cell phone must have got switched off due to lack of charge.
Okay, sir.
Okay, I will tell him, sir. Thank you.
Was it dad? - Yes.
'I am going to Singapore, I won't have the time to come home.'
'Ask him to come to the airport', Right?
He has told that 10 times since morning.
He is coming tomorrow afternoon.
Tomorrow?
What about the farmhouse plan?
We can manage.
Rupa, I forgot to tell you.
We are going to Suresh's farmhouse tomorrow evening.
You are also coming. - Leave me. I am not coming.
When I reached home late after your birthday party
I got scolded thoroughly.
Now, the farmhouse? No chance!
Come on, Rupa. It's just for two days.
Are you kidding me?
Please, Ashok. Try to understand. Please!
Please!
Okay, it is time. I'm getting a call from home.
Are you sure, you are not coming to the farmhouse?
No.
Okay, Salim. Bye.
Bye. - Bye, Suresh. See you. - Bye.
Salim, wash this too.
Hey, if Rupa is not coming
shall we take Roseline and Meera?
Salim? - Forget about him.
Salim, we are going to Pondicherry this weekend. Are you coming?
No, Ashok, I have some work. You all go.
Salim..
Somebody has come to see you.
Salim's father. - Please come inside.
Salim, are you fine?
Salim, you look petrified!
Are you shocked? - No, dad.
I just did not expect you now.
So.. Sorry, Ashok.
I wasn't informed of his arrival either.
So what? Please sit down.
I am Ashok. - Hi!
This is Suresh. - Hi!
I am Salim's dad.
Ashok, I will go out with dad for some time.
Wait here. I will change and come.
All original teakwood?
Yeah.
Suresh, does this AC work? - Yes.
Let's go.
I will be back soon.
Suresh, next time, we will talk over dinner.
Bye, Suresh.
Bye, Ashok. - Bye.
See you, bye!
Looks like a complicated family!
He's coming from so far.
Would he come without even informing?
Why did you come now?
Why are you asking like this, Salim?
Even though it is an act, it will be set right only when I show up.
Come on, you don't know anything.
I will hack you to death.
What do you want?
Not much. Just give me Rs.5000.
I will never approach you hereafter.
Are you not drinking?
I don't have money.
Drink fast and leave.
I should not see you here again.
How can you say that?
If you don't have the money, arrange it from somewhere else.
In that big house, you.. - In college..
You show that heroism here.
Did you think, by pointing the screwdriver at my stomach
you have become a great person?
Why are you staring?
Just because I went away silently as it was college premises
you thought, I got scared?
You raise your hand at me!
I won't do it anymore, Salim. Please..
Don't stab me. Both of us study in the same college.
Please, Salim. Please.
Salim, please. Salim, please.
Henceforth, I will not do this, Salim.
Let's run away. - What has he done to me?
Salim, dad will question us like a police officer.
Manage him somehow. - Okay, Ashok.
Hi! - Hi, dad! Mom, how are you?
I am fine. How are you?
I am fine, mom.
Dad, this is Salim.
Hello, sir. - Hello. - How are you? - Fine.
Hello. - Hello. How is the college?
It is nice, mom.
College will be nice. Ask him, how his studies are going on?
It's going on smoothly, dad. Shall we go?
Give it to me, sir. I will carry it. - Give me the bag, mom.
Thank you, Salim. - You have become so thin!
I've always been like this, mom. - Okay.
How is this boy, Salim?
He is a very good boy.
Okay. Don't allow anybody else to stay in the house. Okay?
Do you even study or just roam around?
Nothing like that, sir. We do study.
We provide everything so that our children don't suffer.
If you study, good for you.
After your sister delivers the baby, on my way back
I will stay with you for a week.
Okay, mom. - How does your father make a living?
He owns a medical shop.
Good.
What? Are you done with your conversation? - What do you mean?
I told him that we will come a day early and stay with him.
He nodded his head, but now
we are in a hurry to leave.
Okay, don't start again.
We will see while returning.
There is still 1 hour left before the flight arrives.
Let's eat something.
Ashok has to go urgently. He has some important work.
Salim will be here. Only I have to go.
Why are you troubling that boy? We will manage, Ashok.
No problem, ma'am. I will be here.
Ashok, do you want some money? - I have it, dad.
Convey my regards to Lakshmi and her husband.
I will take leave. - Okay, go carefully.
Bye, mom. Bye, dad. - Take care of your health. - Okay.
Take care.
Come, let's talk as we have something. - Okay, sir.
Come.
Have you come, Salim?
What did dad say? - He said, he will call you
after reaching Singapore.
Did he ask, why I am leaving early?
No.
Thanks, Salim. - Ashok..
I am ready. Shall we go?
Bye, Salim. - Bye.
I will come tomorrow evening. - See you tomorrow.
Get in.
Don't worry if there is no space. You can sit on my lap.
It is hot. Be careful.
Thank you.
Why didn't he take you along?
I have to meet my professor tomorrow.
That is why, I told him that I will not come.
Ashok didn't tell me anything about going there with girls.
Ashok didn't know that Suresh would be coming there with girls.
In fact, when you refused to go, Ashok did not want to go with him.
Suresh compelled and took him along.
I've no problems with him going out with girls.
But why did he have to hide it from me?
He has switched off his phone too.
I have never hidden anything from Ashok.
Even he should do the same.
But, he does not understand that
and takes everything lightly.
Even this morning, Ashok was talking about you.
In short
he does not have a life without you.
Everything is fine, Salim
but I'm unable to take this matter so lightly.
Certain things that I feel are wrong
he doesn't feel that they're wrong.
This quality of Ashok disturbs me.
Rupa, I can understand you.
You love Ashok deeply.
You are always thinking about him.
That is why, such things disturb you a lot.
Possessiveness is bound to be there in love
but it will become a problem if it becomes intense.
You get angry even when his phone is switched off.
Ashok may commit small mistakes.
Don't magnify it.
Nobody is 100 percent perfect here.
Your coffee will go cold. Have it.
'Currently switched off.'
'The number you have called is currently switched off.'
'Please call again.'
I will be back, Rupa.
'Hi, Rupa.'
'It is a mistake that I came here without informing you.'
'I am really sorry.'
'Henceforth, I will not do anything against your wish.'
'I'll see you tomorrow. Bye.'
You can smile a bit.
Thank you.
You perform mimicry?
It started as a game for me during my childhood.
I did not know how to console you. That is why.
After talking to you, I feel so relieved.
Ashok need not know whatever I spoke to you about him.
Sure.
I will withdraw the money and then, we can leave.
Hey, Karthik, are you fine?
Karthik?
My name is Salim. You've mistaken me
for someone else.
Are you Salim? What are you saying?
Don't you recognize me? - No, I don't.
You hail from Ramanathapuram, right?
What's wrong, Salim?
Yes. - Which school?
The Islam Higher Secondary School.
I have seen you in Ramanathapuram secondary school.
How can I go wrong? You are committing a crime, Karthik.
Sir, what crime have I committed?
You came on your own.
You said, I am Karthik.
Now, you say that I'm committing a crime.
Please leave, without torturing me any further.
Sir, take him along.
Ashok, we are getting late for college.
You are Karthik!
Salim, leave him.
If you speak again.. - Salim, leave him.
I will not even give respect to your age.
Salim, let's go.
Take him. - Go, Salim. - Come on.
I know it very well that he is Karthik.
Karthik, you can deceive me. But it is not for your good.
Father, you've retired. Why do you bother about others?
Keep quiet and come.
No. Why should he say, he is Salim and cheat others?
Let him do whatever he wants. Why should we bother?
Come without creating a problem. It is getting late.
Hundred years, Salim!
Ashok.
I was expecting you.
Will you believe if he says so?
Ashok, please.
That day
it was just you, me, and Suresh, who had gone to the farmhouse, right?
Rupa is not believing me. You tell her.
Ashok, I believe you.
You three had gone to the farmhouse. Okay?
Leave it.
Was it a mistake that I questioned you?
Sorry, Salim. We were just talking. Nothing else.
Nothing!
A while ago, you were asking questions
as if you knew everything. What happened now?
You did not believe me
but if he tells, you will believe. - Please stop it, Ashok.
Shall I tell the truth?
When you and Suresh had gone to the farmhouse
I called you both. Your mobiles were switched off.
After that, I came here and spoke to Salim.
So, tell lies, it is not wrong.
But for that purpose, don't make a fool out of others.
At least, try to be true to yourself.
Sorry, Salim.
Sorry, Ashok.
I don't have any intention to hurt you.
If what I did was wrong, was what you did right?
You asked him about what I was doing, behind my back
and then, both of you hid it from me. What do you call that?
Ashok. Don't you know about Rupa?
It is all his doing.
You are shouting at her instead of shouting at him.
Will you keep quiet?
Ashok, I did not say anything about you.. - Shut up!
Ashok! What is wrong with you?
Why did you slap him?
You both were wrong.
Why do you find fault with others to hide it?
Sorry, Salim. All this happened because of me.
I am really very sorry.
This will not work out. Find yourself another place.
Next time, if you tell anything about me to Rupa
or to any other girl, that's all.
Ashok, I did not tell anything about you to Rupa.
Why didn't you tell me that she had come here?
You're surviving on my favors
and you misled my girlfriend..
Now, are you putting up an act of being a noble person?
Are you not ashamed?
Why are you giving him time?
I had warned you earlier itself
that he is not a good person and not to let him stay with you.
But you defended him.
Did you see what happened?
Will you shut up?
You are responsible for all this.
Okay, buddy. You are angry now.
I will come and see you later.
'It's gonna be here, can't throw too far away.'
'Oh, look! He's going to try the summersault in it too.'
'Not good enough. Oh, no!'
'He got it!'
'And standing!'
Ashok.
Professor asked about you.
He asked me to tell you that if you don't have full attendance
you cannot write the examination.
Then..
'He's gone at the right.'
'He's gonna go way up and toss it up!'
I have found another place to stay.
Tomorrow, I am vacating from here.
'He gets him, all I can say is that he's just brilliant!'
'Wow! It is the second last dive of the summer, takes the breather.'
'That's not just brilliant, that's extraordinary. - He is a genius.'
'Never seen anything like that in my life.'
'Oh, my! Just see the smile on his face.'
'Haven't seen anything like this either. He's gone..'
What are you doing, Ashok?
What are you doing here, Ashok?
The person in this photo is you, right?
Who are these people with you?
Ashok, give it to me.
No, I will not. Answer my question.
Ashok, please. Give it to me.
Who was that who had come in search of you the other day?
Ashok, that's none of your business. Give that photo, Ashok.
You told, you've completed B.Sc., right?
Show me those certificates, I will believe you.
Why bring it up now? I have seen another house.
Give that photograph. I will leave right away.
The way you're asking for it, I can make out that you're a wrong person.
Yesterday, you fought with a person in front of the ATM..
He was right. Your name is Karthik.
You are cheating everyone here by saying that you are Salim.
Am I right? - I don't need to prove to you that I am Salim.
Ashok, give me that photo.
Why?
You are committing a big crime. When you get caught
even I will get caught for letting you stay here.
I am telling you. I'll be leaving right away.
I will not come to you ever again.
I cannot leave you like that.
Answer my question straightforwardly.
I won't. What will you do?
You won't tell me. I'll see what you say, when the police questions you.
Ashok, listen.. - Will you raise your hand at me?
Hit me! Let me see how you hit me!
Sorry, Ashok. Sorry, Ashok.
Sorry, Ashok. Sorry, Ashok. I did not intend to hit you.
Forgive me, Ashok. - You fraud!
You cheat! You're cheating everybody, you fraud!
Are you cheating everybody?
Ashok.. Ashok..
Ashok..
Ashok.. Ashok!
Ashok, get up.
Hey, Ashok..
Ashok! Get up. Get up!
Did I hit you? Ashok, you were the one who hit me.
Get up, Ashok. Get up. Get up.
Ashok..
Get up.
Did I kill you?
Jackie, come here.
What happened? Why is he barking?
I don't know. He is barking, looking at the neighbor's house.
Those boys must have done something.
Jackie, go inside.
Hello, Ashok.
Can you hear me? - Yes, dad.
What happened to your voice? Do you have a cold? - Yes.
Take tablets.
By the way, the doctor has given
the 6th of next month, as the delivery date for Lakshmi.
How is mom? - She is fine.
Wait, talk to her.
Ashok, are you okay?
We got Lakshmi's scan done. The baby is healthy.
There's no problem. The doctor has told that she will have a normal delivery.
Okay, mom. How are you?
We are fine. We felt like talking to you.
Hence, called you up. Nothing else.
Eat on time. Take care of your health. Okay?
Shall I hang up? - Okay, mom.
Hi. - Hi.
What happened? You have come at this hour.
Come inside.
I haven't spoken to Ashok since the last two days.
I am finding it really hard, Salim.
I wanted to see him. So..
Even I am at fault.
In your presence
I should not have spoken to Ashok in that manner.
Even you had told me.
I gave it a thought.
Instead of waiting for him to come and talk to me
I felt, I should break this silence myself. I came immediately.
Even today, we were talking about you.
He is still angry with you.
I don't think, this is the right time to talk.
Think about it.
He would have forgotten about the fight that day itself.
He must be angry now
because I didn't call him for two days.
We've never been without seeing or talking to each other before.
More than me, he must have found it hard.
He never questioned me, irrespective of whatever I did.
Only I..
He must be upstairs, right? He's lying down after
complaining of a headache. I was going to get tablets for him.
Why don't you come and see him in the morning?
Salim, I won't be able to stay
without seeing him or talking to him any longer.
Please, I'll see him and leave.
You go and come back soon.
I will be back in 10 minutes. Lock the door. - Okay.
Ashok.
Ashok! Please open the door.
What I did was wrong.
I am sorry, if I've spoken out of turn.
I spoke to you in that manner
out of my possessiveness for you.
I did not doubt you. Definitely not.
Please, Ashok. Open the door.
Please!
Tell me. What should I do to subside your anger?
You are hurting me a lot, Ashok.
I know, I haven't done anything wrong.
Still, if I have come at this hour and am requesting you
it is because I love you so much, Ashok.
Why don't you understand that?
I am leaving now, not out of anger
but out of fear that again
I might say something which may hurt you.
Salim, come here.
Yes, sir.
Go to the college office and see Mr. Sundaram.
I have recommended a scholarship for you.
You just study well.
I will take care of the other things.
Thank you, sir.
Hello. - Hi, Salim, how are you?
Fine, sir. - Is Ashok there?
Ashok is inside. I will call him, sir.
Yes, dad.
Hey, dad.
Hi, dad.
Yes, dad. - My friend, Mohandas has come from Dubai.
You go and meet him.
Dad, I have to study.
Come on, Ashok! This is also important.
He will give you a file. Keep it with you.
I will collect it when I come to Chennai.
Has he seen me? - He had seen you as a child.
He may not remember you now.
Meet him at a decent hour. He has come with his family.
Okay, dad. When should I go?
I have given him your cell number.
Keep your phone switched on. He will call you.
How are Lakshmi and mom?
All are fine. You take care of your health.
I will call you at night. Okay?
Bye, dad. - Bye, Ashok.
"Open the door, I want to show you something."
"You gotta call me. My name is Salim."
"Every day that I keep hunting."
"Let me go on, let me go strong."
Hi! - Hi.
Ashok has grown up, hasn't he?
Yeah.
Hi, Ashok. Though I am seeing you after a long time
I could recognize you at once because of your eyes.
How are you? - I am fine, Mr. Mohandas.
How are you all?
This is my daughter, Priya.
Hi! - Hi.
What will you have?
Priya has joined here in SAM.
Is it so?
Computer engineering.
Answer the call.
It's dad calling. He wanted to speak to you.
Hello, Mohandas speaking. How are you?
Yeah, no problem.
I will give the file to Ashok before going. Is that all?
Okay. Okay. That is not a problem.
No, no, no, we will tackle.
Mom, one minute.
My college friends are here.
I'll be right back. - Okay.
One minute, I will just be back.
Why don't you ask him to sign?
Okay. Agreed. Then, let's do this.
When you come here, we will meet and discuss.
Don't worry about it. Oh..
Excuse me, ma'am. I want to use the restroom.
Yeah. - I will do something about it.
Hello, ma'am. - Hello. - Hello, sir. - Hello.
How are you? - Sit down. - Fine. Take a seat.
Where is Ashok? - He has gone to the restroom.
Okay, Priya, I'll see you later. - See you.
Okay. - Bye, ma'am. - Take care. - Bye, sir.
Okay. - Bye.
Hi, Rupa. What are you doing here?
You're here?
Did Ashok call you and ask you to come too?
No, I'm here with my friends.
I came to know that Ashok has come here only after coming here.
Where is Ashok? - He has gone to smoke.
How does Ashok know Priya's family?
Has he told you anything about it?
A friend of Ashok's father has come from Dubai.
He has come to meet him.
If you take a right there and then, a left
you'll find the smoking area.
He must have gone there.
Don't worry, Rupa. Everything will fall in place like before.
I am also speaking to him. Give it some time.
Okay, Salim. Thank you. - No problem.
See you later. - Okay, Rupa.
Bye. - Bye.
You have got two calls, Ashok.
First, place the order and then, talk.
Is it an important call?
Sir, I had forgotten that I'd called a senior home
to clarify some doubts.
He is waiting outside the house. Sorry, sir, I am leaving.
We will be here for another two days.
I have told your dad that I'll give him some details.
Will you come and collect it later? - Okay, sir.
At least drink soup before leaving. - No, sir.
Next time, I will definitely dine with you.
I'll give a call before coming to collect the papers. Bye, ma'am.
Bye, Ashok. - Bye, Priya. - Bye.
'The Airtel number you are trying to reach'
'is currently busy.'
Buddy, where are you?
I have come to meet my father's friend.
Just now, I saw your number. What is the matter?
I got to know. Rupa told me everything. I was just talking to her.
You know it, right? Then, why are you asking?
Okay, leave it. I am waiting outside your house.
When will you come? - It will take time. I will see you tomorrow.
Henceforth, give me a call before coming.
Tell me how long will it take. I will wait.
It will take two to three hours. Why? What is the matter?
Dude, I have brought a good brand.
Just make some excuse and come.
On your way, pick something up to eat along with it.
I can come only after dropping them at the hotel.
I will be late. Let's meet up tomorrow.
Now, leave the place without pestering me any further.
What's wrong with you?
I've been observing
that you have been behaving differently since the last few days.
You have also fought with Rupa. She is very upset.
I have called you so many times.
Every time, I get the response that your phone's switched off.
Even when you talk, you make excuses and give
some or the other reasons. What is your problem?
Have we not met late in the night before?
You are talking differently.
We are meeting today, irrespective of whenever you come.
Why don't you understand?
Okay. Let's do this.
Tomorrow at 7:30 p.m.
Come alone. Let's meet at the pub.
Remember, come alone. Rupa should not come.
Don't you think, this is too much?
Why are you saying, Rupa shouldn't come?
Listen to me. If I tell you not to bring her, don't.
Come alone. Instead, if you bring her, I will go away. Bye.
Hey, Ashok! Why are you getting angry?
Come in. - Good afternoon, sir.
Sit down.
Is there any problem with your friend, Ashok?
No, sir. - A complaint has gone from the college to his parents.
No reply. Do you know his dad's cell number or email id?
I don't know, sir. - Why is he wasting
his medical seat like this?
If he is not interested, why is he studying?
Let him take a TC and leave.
He should not attend class without seeing me.
Inform him. - Okay, sir.
Are you searching for Ashok? - Yes.
I told you, he is angry with you and has asked you not to meet him.
Why did you come here then?
What? Are you guys playing a prank on me?
Salim called me up and asked me to come here
whereas you are asking me, why I have come.
What's my mistake, for Ashok to get so angry at me?
Did Salim ask you to come here?
Why are you listening to that idiot?
I had said earlier itself, not to let him inside the house.
Ashok did not heed to my words. - What has he done?
He asked me to come here to solve our problem.
He's not at fault.
Yes, we are the ones at fault.
Why is Ashok avoiding me if he isn't at fault?
He will be here. Ask him yourself.
It's him calling.
Why has Rupa come here? - I did not ask her to come.
You did not listen, in spite of my telling you several times.
That fool, Salim has asked her to come.
Okay, I am leaving. - Hello.. Hello!
Ashok!
What happened, Suresh?
'The number you have called is currently switched off.'
What's the matter? What happened, Suresh?
Hi! - Hi.
Rupa! What a surprise!
Who is he? Your boyfriend?
Not at all, just a friend.
Have you come alone?
No, a family friend has told me, he'll meet me here.
The other day, he was there at the restaurant with me, Mr. Ashok..
Oh! Sorry, you did not meet him that day, right?
Oh, yeah.
"Because of you, I'm flying high."
Okay, bye. See you later.
Catch you later. - Thanks.
"You wanna want it.."
Okay, Rupa, I am leaving. Ashok has come and gone.
I have understood everything, Suresh.
Ashok had come to the hotel the other day to meet her family.
Even now, he has only asked her to come here.
That is why, the moment he saw me here
he ran away as he could not face me.
Is that why, he is avoiding you every time?
I know how to catch hold of him.
You leave, Rupa. It is a waste, waiting here. He will not come.
She is waiting. Shall we also wait for some time?
We will be waiting unnecessarily. He will not come.
Come, let's go.
Bye.
Hi. - Hi.
Surprise. How do you know my address?
Did you forget, Ashok? This was our house.
We sold it to uncle before leaving for Dubai.
Is it so? I don't know. Come in.
Dad has asked you to hand over this file to your dad.
Do you know, I waited in the pub for such a long time that day?
Did you forget that you had asked me to come there?
Even your phone was switched off.
Sorry, Priya. Suddenly, I'd to attend to some urgent work.
I got held up. Also, my phone had no charge.
Oh! - That is why..
If you are free now, shall we go out somewhere?
Dinner?
Sure.
Your eyes are watery. Has dust got into your eyes?
It is nothing. It is slightly irritating.
Wait, I will help you. - It is okay. Thanks.
Wait for some time. I will change and come.
Hi, is Ashok there?
You? - Suresh, Ashok's friend.
The other day, we had met in the pub.
Yes, come in.
Sorry, I asked without knowing that you are Ashok's friend.
I am Priya. - No problem. Where is Ashok?
He is changing his dress.
Ashok, are you ready? - Yes, Priya. Two minutes.
Sorry, I forgot. What did you say your name was?
Suresh. Is Ashok in that room? - Yes.
Actually, Rupa is my college mate.
She had come with you to the pub that day, right?
Rupa, my classmate. - Yes, Rupa told me.
Hi, Ashok.
Hey!
Priya, you go for now. I will call you later.
Why? What happened? What happened, Ashok?
Sorry, Priya, don't ask me anything now.
Suresh is your friend, isn't he? - Yes.
Then, why are you tensed? - There's a minor problem between us.
It has to be solved today itself. That is why, he has come.
I will wait upstairs. We can go after you finish talking.
Sorry, Priya, It will take some time.
I will call you tomorrow. We will definitely go.
Bye, Priya. - Bye.
Okay, tomorrow for sure? - Sure.
Bye. - Bye.
Who is that who's visiting you, thinking you to be Ashok?
I was wondering, why your looks and activities seemed so different.
Nothing seemed to be right. I'd a doubt, something is wrong.
Only now, I've come to understand. Where is Ashok?
These are Ashok's clothes, right?
Does Ashok know about this?
So, had she come to see you in the pub yesterday?
Even at the restaurant, you have met Priya's family, as Ashok.
Hey, what are you doing?
Is he alive or have you done something to him?
"Every day, I am dying."
"Living in fear."
"Going through the pain."
"Seeing only darkness."
"Where do I go"
"to cure my illness?"
"I want to know the path"
"to that place."
"Where do I go"
"to get some sleep?"
"I want to lead a life"
"in that place."
"Every day, I am dying."
"Living in fear."
"Going through the pain."
"Seeing only darkness."
Ashok.
Ashok is not here. He has gone out. What is it, sir?
You? - Salim, Ashok's friend.
Classmate. I stay here.
Why are you asking, sir?
Can we talk inside?
Which place do you belong to? - Ramanathapuram, sir.
Do you know when will Ashok come?
I don't know, sir.
Sir, if you could tell me what's the problem..
Does Ashok have a friend named Suresh?
Yes, sir. - He has been murdered two days ago.
When did Ashok go out?
Salim!
How, sir? - He was hit on the neck and was buried.
We came to know, only after the owner of the land informed us.
When did Ashok go out?
Yesterday, I saw him before leaving for college.
Haven't you seen him after that? - No, sir.
Do you know, when Suresh came here last?
The day before yesterday, no.. The evening on the day before that..
When I was going out, Ashok told me, he was waiting for Suresh.
After that, when did you see Ashok?
I already told you, I saw him last morning.
Does Ashok often stay out at night?
Yes, sir. If Suresh is free, both of them usually stay out.
What do you know about Ashok and Suresh's friendship?
Very close friends, sir.
I got to know Suresh through Ashok. But..
I searched the whole house, sir. There's no one.
You were saying something.
Actually, sir, since last few days
it looked like both of them were not in good terms.
What do you mean? Could you elaborate?
I think, it had got something to do with girls.
I don't know who it is. Both of them didn't speak to me about it.
Do they both have girlfriends?
Ashok has a girlfriend named Rupa.
Suresh roams around with many girls.
Did they have a problem because of Rupa?
I don't think so, sir.
She is a very nice girl.
Because of Suresh's company, Ashok used to roam around
with other girls without Rupa's knowledge.
I guess, this was the problem between them, sir.
Since how many days do you know Ashok?
I know him from 11th standard.
Knowing means.. Were you lovers? - Yeah.
Did Ashok and Suresh have a tiff recently?
No. Just a small misunderstanding.
Because of that, Ashok started avoiding
Suresh and me since quite some time now.
How is Ashok? - He will not study.
He will not allow the others to study as well.
I am glad that the other students are not spoiled because of him.
Has Ashok had any fight or a problem
with anybody else in the college?
It's nothing as serious as you're assuming it to be.
Did I make you aware of my assumptions?
It's nothing like that, sir. What I meant was..
Since Ashok teased Uma
I just questioned him about it but did not do any ragging.
What is the problem between Ashok and you?
No problem, sir.
What type of relationship existed between you both?
No relationship as such.
For few days, he was after me saying that he loved me.
Chasing girls is a time pass for him.
Since I knew that, I didn't accept his proposal.
How is Ashok's roommate, Salim? - Good friends.
Salim, a meritorious student.
You can make out that as he doesn't want to trouble his parents
he is doing a part time job along with his studies.
I have seen him with Ashok. But I have not mingled with him.
Both of them are close friends, sir.
When I was enquiring Ashok about Uma
he was the one who came forward to hit me in Ashok's support.
Even then, I did not do anything.
When did you last see Ashok?
It must have been around one week, sir.
It has been 15 days since he last attended the class.
I don't remember, sir.
What is your full name?
Mohammed Salim, sir.
Your father's name? - Mohammed Ansari, sir.
What does he do? - He owns a medical shop in Ramanathapuram.
That day, when you were going to college
what did Ashok tell you?
He said, he had to speak and solve certain things with Suresh
and so, he is not coming to college.
When you returned, was Ashok there?
No, sir. I saw Ashok only the next day.
Nobody, except you, has seen Ashok for the last one week.
You are the one to see him for the last time.
Sorry, sir. I forgot to tell you.
Ashok's family friend's daughter
is studying here in SAM.
Her name is Priya.
Ashok was friendly with that girl for some time.
Rupa does not know about this.
She had told that she will also be coming that day.
Family friends...
I met him that day at the restaurant
when he had come to meet my dad.
When did you meet after that?
After that, dad asked me to hand over a file.
I'd been to Ashok's house to give that. I met Suresh there.
After that, I did not see Ashok at all.
Sir. - What is it? Are you diabetic?
How many times will you go? Control and sit there.
Sir had asked about you. Tell me.
Do you know, why Ashok panicked when he saw Suresh?
He said, there was a minor problem between them
and so, Suresh had come to solve that.
Nowadays, minor problems make them commit big crimes.
What happened after that?
Ashok changed the dinner plan
and sent me out in a hurry.
Can you say with conviction
that Ashok panicked only after he saw Suresh?
I am absolutely sure.
He was the one to suggest to go out for dinner just before Suresh came.
If required, you may have to come again.
Okay, sir. Thank you.
Hello, this is Satish speaking. - Which Satish?
Your senior, Satish. Okay, I need the address of Ashok's residence.
Stupid, ask him only. - Hey, I am in great tension.
Hello, hello..
Hello. - Rupa.
Ashok!
Please listen to me, Rupa. I've committed a grave mistake.
Ashok! - There was a misunderstanding
between Suresh and me.
When we were talking about it
we had an argument and I hit him.
He fell down and died.
Without knowing what to do, I disposed the body, out of fear
Ashok! What are you saying?
I am getting really scared.
Wait, I am coming home.
No, Rupa, I don't have the courage to face anyone.
I've not been true to you and to my parents.
Till now, I've been doing only wrong things.
Most importantly, I have troubled you a lot. Forgive me.
Ashok! - I am sorry, Rupa, forgive me.
Forgive me, Rupa.
Why are you talking like this, Ashok?
If you tell the truth to the police..
No, Rupa. That's not needed. I have decided.
Because of this, neither me nor the others are happy.
Poor Salim! They are suspecting him for my wrong doings.
Tell him as well.
Before going, I wanted to talk to you for the last time.
I don't have the courage to live and so, I have decided to end my life.
Ashok, please! Listen to me.
Thanks for everything, Rupa. - Ashok, please!
Ashok!
Ashok.
'Due to a small problem, I hit Suresh and he died.'
'Not knowing what to do, I buried his body.'
'Since the time, the police have come to know of it, I am on the run.'
'I am scared, I might get into trouble if someone saw me.'
'I am not true to my lover or to my parents.'
'Since I don't have the courage to live, I have decided to die.'
'Nobody is responsible for my death.'
'Please don't punish anybody for this.'
How did you get this?
I had been to the police station.
They suspected me and enquired. I came back just now.
The house was open. This letter was lying on the table.
Was Ashok not here when you came?
No.
I searched the whole house.
He is not there. Did he contact you?
The police thinks that I am hiding something
despite knowing everything about Ashok.
They have asked me not to leave Chennai.
Rupa, we have to stop him
before he does something as per his letter.
Ashok is not a foolish person to commit suicide.
You speak like Ashok, don't you?
Wait, I will get the candle.
Rupa.
I told you, I am getting a candle.
Did you get hurt?
You speak like Ashok, don't you?
Rupa, I am not in the mood to joke now.
Even I am not joking, Salim. I am asking you seriously.
You speak like him, don't you?
Oh! I spoke to you that day to make you happy.
Are you doubting on me now, because of that?
Okay, I will speak like Ashok.
Then, who has written this letter in his handwriting?
Rupa! Somebody is standing behind you.
Looks like Ashok.
He was here all this while.
You be here. I will check and be back.
Salim.
Salim!
Salim! Salim, open the door.
Rupa, I am not Salim. I am Ashok.
Ashok. Where's Rupa, Ashok? - Ashok.
I told you, I don't have the courage to face you.
Then, why did you come, Rupa? - Ashok!
Ashok, what are you doing?
Salim, leave me!
Ashok, listen to me. The police is suspecting me.
You say, you did not do it. Don't stop me.
Listen to me. Ashok!
Salim! Ashok!
Listen to me, Ashok!
Ashok, don't fight, please! - Think about Rupa and your parents. Listen to me, Ashok.
That is why, I want to die. Leave me! - Ashok!
Salim, if you don't allow me to go, I will kill you as well.
Ashok!
Salim! What happened?
Who hit you?
Why did you do this? - What are you saying?
You sent your men to hit me just as you had told.
Who hit you? I did not send anybody.
I have nothing to do with that problem.
The police will be here. They will take care of everything.
What! The police? Why are you doing this?
I came to apologize. Don't tell the police.
Oh!
They are coming again.
Ashok.. Ashok...
Ashok.. - What happened, Salim? - Ashok.
Ashok! - Who is inside? - Please open the door!
Hold him. - Ashok.. Ashok..
Salim! - What happened to Ashok?
Somebody, open the door!
Ashok. Ashok..
Ashok.. Ashok..
Ashok hit me..
Sorry, Rupa. It was Ashok..
Hello. - Hello, Ashok.
I am K4 police station's inspector, Duraipandiyan speaking.
Sir, I am Ashok's father, Ravindran speaking.
Please come to Chennai immediately.
The wounds are superficial. There's nothing to worry.
Thank you, Doctor.
Come, sir. Are you fine?
Salim, what did the doctor say?
I'm very sorry. - I did not have your cell number.
Otherwise, I would have called you earlier.
I had not expected, all this would happen.
I tried a lot to stop him.
Sir, they are Ashok's parents.
Yesterday, when you had called, I was the one who spoke to you
Inspector Duraipandiyan. Did your son contact you?
Sir, will you come aside for a minute?
Anything that you hide will put your son in danger.
Last evening, he had called me
saying that he was going to commit suicide.
We enquired about your son.
When he was in the 10th standard in Coimbatore
he had hit a boy and broke his chin for some girl.
It had become a police case. As he was given a TC
you were getting him educated here, in Chennai. Right?
That happened long ago, when he was very young.
It is not right to deal with this case by taking it up now.
I can understand your anger.
From our enquiry, it is very clear
that Ashok has committed this murder.
Not just that
your son has himself written
that he has murdered Suresh.
Please see if this is his handwriting.
It is his handwriting indeed.
Till your son is caught, we will not close this case.
If he contacts you, please inform us.
Do you suspect him?
It's because, when we enquired about him
we found that everyone has a good opinion of him.
That is why, I am asking you. - No, sir.
Sir.
Sir, the groom's side are coming to see my daughter in the evening.
I have to buy few things before going home.
I had informed you in the morning itself.
That's fine, Kathamuthu. On your way, go to this address
and check whether it is the same person in the house
and give a report in the morning, tomorrow, okay?
Okay, sir.
She is too much!
Yeah, tell me. Tomato, eggplant..
Couldn't you have told it before? Simply nagging!
Keep the phone. I will come.
Who do you want to see, sir? - Is anyone home?
Dad is there. Come inside.
Sit down, sir.
Sir, dad is calling. - Go ahead.
Two minutes, sir. - No problem.
Isn't your mom home?
No, sir. She is no more.
Nothing. I came here for a verification.
I will leave. - Okay, sir.
My life is your son, Salim's gift.
After Salim's death
you must have thought that his education and wishes
have died along with him.
I took this life
which would have otherwise gone waste.
I am not saying, what I did was correct.
I didn't have any other way out that day.
I want to live as Salim. If you permit
I will live as your son and look after you.
If you don't like it
I will stop this education, and let go of this identity.
One thing is for sure.
As long as I am alive, I will take care of you.
I want my life to be useful to someone.
Dad, sleep for some time.
To be continued..