Roberte
Roberte!
Leave me alone.
- Close the window.
It’s cold.
- You can't miss the
first migration of the year.
Go by yourself.
- A flock of ducks
before the equinox, that's rare.
- Oh, the equinox! For 40 years,
it’s all you ever think about.
- But it's you who wanted to
go hunting this morning.
I don't want to anymore.
How much is that?
3 shots
That’s not 3 shots.
-3, I swear.
Look again.
I’ll go downstairs
to prepare the rifles.
Hurry up.
Horrible Milan
I can't see a thing. Why
did you wake me so early?
- Don’t move.
Look.
I love that.
It’s like a girl undressing.
Milan!
It’s beautiful.
- Yes. Very beautiful.
It’s a jay.
But that’s not game.
It is. People eat them.
You aimed well.
It was flying quite high.
You’re a good shot.
It’s the male.
The female must be worried.
Look!
We can shoot it from
under the trees.
Hey!
No.
We should’ve shot the female.
It would’ve been more humane.
- It's true, I’m like a woman
from those realist songs.
Yes. A drunk!
One day I’ll find you, sitting on the
sidewalk with two litres of red wine.
That’s how I’ll end up.
What is it?
Do you see that tree?
Yeah, why?
- The pigeons settle in it.
- Oh let me go!
- They sleep on the
large branches.
You have to shoot
almost straight up.
The pigeons are in your dreams.
You told me...
You told me:
"I found a new love,..
".. and I’m leaving you. "
I begged you to stay,
but you left anyway.
I hate you.
Of course.
Me, for years
I dreamed..
.. I entered
a night club,..
.. and I found you there
with a man,..
.. and you told me:
"This is my new lover.
And you left
with him, laughing.
- Do you still have
that dream?
No.
Of course.
Hey!
Shit!
- There! You have
to know what you’re doing.
If you hunt ducks,
you can’t shoot pigeons.
-4 shots won’t wake every
duck in the neighbourhood.
- You can’t hunt with
a woman who isn’t serious.
You always end up
embarrassing me.
That pigeon was fast.
Of course it was.
- They call them "rowers"
because they row..
.. with their large wings,
silently like champions.
Ducks can’t row.
They make noise
like amateurs.
The pigeon passed by
like a ghost ship
I adore you.
Me too.
What a country! You can’t hunt
in a country if there’s no game.
It isn't duck season yet.
- so what, they shoot hares
on opening day.
This winter, we’ll go to the river.
We'll make such a massacre
that you will be disgusted
and with wild geese,
the most beautiful game.
Sure. Say,..
.. why don’t we go
to the casino tonight?
No.
- We should! I’m better
at roulette than at hunting.
- We’d lose what we spend
here in a month.
- We can leave a month early.
- No.
You’re a bastard.
Of course.
But it’s true!
You’re overacting!
Ah! You brought it along.
I’ve done well, haven’t I?
- You've had a drink, huh?
Sitting by yourself just now.
Just 2 swigs.
Shall we go on?
I’m tired.
She’s a bold one.
She has a tender look.
Well that doesn't mean anything.
- Hello, Madame Milan.
- Hello, Radiguette.
Hello.
So?
- Oh, nothing.
A thrush and a jay.
- We can open
a bird museum soon.
- You’re funny hunters.
Did you have a good time?
He scolds me for it.
- You lead a comfortable life.
You do as you please.
- But with Milan.
- He isn’t difficult to live with.
- For a foreigner, he has settled down well.
- That’s what you said.
How are things
with your husband?
- We don't have the time
to bother one other.
Does he chase girls?
- He needs a young one
from time to time.
How do you feel about it?
- When he's caught,
he's nicer to me.
Say, you’re clever.
Are you coming?
Radiguette will never
take us seriously.
She knows all about life.
So do I.
Perhaps.
Where were you?
- Le Mans, in '56.
The first time I drove for Jaguar.
- You say it
as if you were scared?
- It’s hard to find the right
word for the feeling.
Especially at the start
of the race.
Yet, you broke
the record that day.
- It’s funny,
I can’t remember it very well.
All I can remember is
the dress you were wearing.
A blue spot, on the left,
as I approached the straightaway.
The one you bought for me in Rome.
Yes.
- And while I tried it on, you made
a date with the salesgirl.
One of life's little pleasures.
- Aren't you getting a little
fed up with this small village?
Here or elsewhere...
- Don't mind me.
- Good evening, Madame Milan.
Hello everyone!
- How are you?
- I’m bored. It’s unbelievable.
- It’s not funny.
- It’s the way you said it.
Where is Mr. Milan?
- He’s working.
- He isn't bored?
- You'd like if he
came for you.
Who's that?
That's the new teacher.
Good evening.
Good evening, Madame.
- Well, just in town and you're already
at the pub. We'll be great friends.
I live here.
- Do you want a drink?
- No, thanks.
- You've got principles.
- No. I’m just not thirsty.
- You have a pretty laugh.
Jacqueline, my pastis!
You have a minute!
Have a seat.
Yes
I’m bored, you see.
- I understand, you are used to
having strong emotions.
You already know?
It's the first thing Jacqueline told me.
What did you say?
- When a man like Milan
settles here...
- Jacqueline!
- Sorry.
- I already knew
who your husband was.
Do you like racing?
- At home, we watch it on TV
I saw you once.
Oh yeah?
- It was a day
when Mr. Milan had won.
You were crying with joy.
I wish I had been in your place.
I'd like to see you there!
- It must be difficult to live
with a man like that. I couldn’t.
Surely not.
Hello.
Good evening.
- So champ,
already at your post?
Our veterinarian, Miss...
- Hйlиne Morel.
- Hello.
The new teacher.
Jacqueline, a Ricard.
2 Ricards.
20 under the mark like usual?
- No 40.
I have to get used to it
I'll leave you to it.
- Not going to play?
- No.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, Madam.
- Say. Join us for dinner
tomorrow evening.
Thanks.
Milan adores young girls.
No it was the year where Collins
wiped out at the chicane.
Milan got there
just behind
Monte Carlo, 2 years ago.
Oh yeah, 2 years already.
The next day we
had a sacred feast
Colins wanted to beat me.
He wanted to skin you!
Don’t you remember?
At the bar?
They sat next to us.
I told you: They’re scheming.
"They will have you in the chicane"
No luck for him, that year.
Behra was having trouble
with his tires.
I passed him.
He pulled a long face.
It was over for him.
Were you going fast?
- The Casino corner,
you enter it doing 120.
No one has come out alive
at more than 180.
Wow how could you see Behra’s face?
- I was going 180, him 175.
Like 2 trains at the same speed
I'm silly!
I was at the top..
.. of the chicane
with Luigi. He groaned.
That Milan has no respect...
They arrived at the bottom.
Moss entered too fast and wiped out.
Collins caught Moss' wheel
and went out as well.
A pole from the chicane..
.. fell onto the road.
Milan arrives.
Makes two controlled slides
and he passes through.
You must have been scared.
We’re always scared.
What a life!
- My father bought me
my first car when I was 18.
I wanted to be
a race car driver..
and I especially wanted
to be a writer.
But writing is much harder.
At first I wrote about racing.
It was a compromise.
And later on I raced.
That’s Monza, isn’t it?
- Yes.
My first 1000 miles.
I wasn't a driver yet.
I was reporting for a paper.
Octave Zabo took me on
as a teammate.
You guys look happy.
- I got a taste for it.
It started with him.
He was great.
- Yes, but above all
he was my best friend.
He died.
Some brandy?
- Of course.
She's already talking like you.
How?
Nothing.
Is this your first assignment?
- Yes. I finished school
at the end of May.
You aren't bored in the village?
- Not yet. I'm preparing
for a new exam.
I want to be a travelling teacher.
Why are you smiling?
Does that sound funny?
No, but I don't quite understand.
- It's for those who've
finished junior college.
We have more freedom.
A bit of home economics
and we take care of their leisure time.
3 hours a week in each village per district.
We'll go by car.
I'll start with a 2CV.
It's a more enjoyable life.
More independant as well.
- Independence matters
a lot to you.
It's the reason I work.
When I was your age,..
.. I thought the meaning of independence,..
.. was not having to work.
Your parents were rich.
My parents?
I never knew my father. And...
.. my mother was
supported by a friend.
We spent our vacations
in his chateau.
2 shots.
In Scotland.
He was an Englishman,
my mother's friend.
- The situation didn't bother you?
- No.
He taught me English,
and good manners.
In exchange, I taught him
the subtleties of slang.
We were very good friends.
And when my mother
wanted me to work.
I laughed in her face.
And when she threatened to
cut me off,..
.. I said that I would hit up..
.. "Uncle", my mom's friend.
She relented?
She had to.
She could have chased you.
- A mother doesn't call the police
to bring her daughter home...
How do you say it?
I would say: "domestic issue".
That's it! I'm not looking for you.
Of course not my dear.
- You still think your
mother was wrong?
More than ever!
Doing a job that you hate, is like
sleeping with a disgusting man.
I love my work.
You are a kid.
When is your new exam?
Is it soon?
- I've known Milan for 10 years.
- In the middle of May.
-10 years!
It's even worse than
if I depended on my mother.
and you?
- Me?
- Yes, you.
Who do you sleep with?
Oh!
You're 20.
I hope you aren't still a virgin.
Roberte! I beg you.
- My fiancй and I,
we often...
Do you love him?
- Yes, otherwise
I wouldn't go out with him.
She is pure.
- Your fiancй
lives in the region?
- He's doing his military service
not far from here.
What's he going to do afterwards?
He's an aeronautical engineer
Is he your first?
Yes
Will you receive him at the inn?
I'm a teacher.
I can't afford the gossip.
He's stuck in the trenches,
at night at the end of the dance.
In the country?
The lack of comfort increases the risk.
Afterwards you can sort it out.
But the first time,
is always tragic for girls.
What about girls from Paris?
Oh... It happened to me...
.. 12 or 13 times, I don't know.
He doesn't either.
But it's not that bad.
Leave her alone!
- For the moment of course,
but you quickly forget.
They'll all tell you the same thing.
What are you looking to do?
To spoil your evening.
Come, I'll see you home.
Come back to see us.
Don't be a stranger.
Yes
- It's never easy
to live as two.
- How come you don't
race anymore?
I think I'm afraid.
You?
It was after Octave died.
When I learned of the accident,
I had a feeling, a kind of change
I'll drop you off here,
since you value your reputation
Goodnight
See you soon.
If it happens, I'll manage.
What?
You aren't going to
tell me anyways...
All women sort it out.
I forbid you to see those people.
- You don't know them.
- A woman who drinks...
- She's not like the others.
- Fortunately!
It's not that simple.
- If he had guts he
wouldn't have retired at 40.
I already explained that.
- If all race drivers gave up after
the death of a friend.
He's a coward!
- I'm sure he hasn't
had his last word.
and you defend him!
Oh, you are stupid!
*- Like every Sunday,
from 14:30 till 17:15,..
*.. On this broadcast
Raymond Marcillac will present to us..
*.. the pleasure of sports
and varieties
*The guest of the day
will be Andrй Dasari.
*The programme is
produced by Vicky Liberez.
*- Greetings everyone.
*I am happy to see you..
*.. for a TV Sunday
with 4 sports segments.
- That's the Milans. Come.
I will introduce you. Yes. Come.
*- The 1st segment
will be devoted to boxing.
Tomorrow, Monday March 13, the championship
will be held in Miami Beach...
Hello
Good evening
- This is Duval, my fiancй.
Madame Milan.
Hello
- Please to meet you.
- and Mr. Milan.
Hello
Hйlиne has told us a lot
about you. Have a seat.
You're an engineer?
Right now a Sergeant-mechanic.
A good use of skills
Cigarette?
No thanks.
He's good looking, eh?
He is especially nice.
He looks serious
It has been 2 years.
You want a drink?
- No thanks.
On the Ferrari?
- On the engine, cooling
follows 2 principals.
- He's staying with you?
- He must return to the barracks by 8pm.
- We could spend
the evening at the casino.
Does Mr. Milan want to?
Ask him.
I wouldn't dare.
Hold on.
Let's go out tonight?
No.
Hйlиne would love to come out with us.
Where?
- To the casino?
I've never been.
You're still a minor.
I don't look it.
- They'll ask for your ID,
and you have to get up early for class.
Already!
Already what?
A husband!
There!
- How old are you now?
- I was born in '39.
Very good.
39. 9 and 3 is 12. But that's
one of my numbers! Go, hurry!
I'll never know!
You aren't forced to play.
Thank you.
3,000 on number 12.
- Why does she favor certain
numbers over others?
- She's the same with numbers and people.
She tries to possess them.
and she wins?
at gambling, sometimes.
on 29!
and with people?
- We won't know until the final
ball has been played.
No more bets!
27 Red, odd, high
6-1 Horse
What's your method?
I lose.
When I lose,
I go for a drink at the bar.
Hey!
Thank you.
Can you bring me a scotch?
- The 6-1.
What are you playing now?
What is the table maximum?
-10,000 francs,
Madame.
The maximum on 12.
- It's rare for a number
to hit 2 times
- We take a risk...
In gambling, like in love!
18-21.
No more bets, please.
He will lose.
-100000.
- No more.
No more bets!
12 Red, even.
- How did you know
that he would lose?
- Him there?
Because he looked unhappy.
Tonight, I'm happy.
And when you're happy,
you win on all fronts. No?
-210,000, Madame.
- Thank you.
It's wonderful
Gentlemen, place your bets.
Place your bets.
- Here
Milan thought of you
Thank you.
Go there.
Try your luck
- I don't know
I dare not.
No more bets.
29!
29 Black, odd, high.
A suede jacket
A record player.
- Why not a grand
teaching text?
- A sheepskin
lined coat.
- Some records waiting for
the record player?
No. A record player
Milan!
Michиle!
- Ah success
in the country.
- Hйlиne Morel,
my niece.
Nice to meet you, miss.
Roberte is playing
You gave her permission?
Will you dance with me?
Don't corrupt his niece.
Incorruptible!
What room is Madame Milan in?
Come, I'll show you.
The third and final, 3.
Hi!
Back from retirement?
For one night.
- Nobody in Paris can understand
your dissapearance.
- Me? I'm with Milan,
for better or for worse.
-32 Red, loses.
- You make me lose
We are at the bar.
- I'll come when I
break the bank.
- You can't force a woman like Roberte
to live on a farm with pigs.
You think she looks after pigs?
Have you known her for long?
She was the most talented of all,
the most beautiful.
The craziest, the most true.
- You think she's changed?
- When Milan was sad,
she drank with him.
They lead the lives of monks.
But she loves him.
- When he went to see other women,
she was the most elegant.
Now he's become a misanthrope,
and she sees nobody.
- She reproaches him.
- Yes, but she stays.
On 4.
No more.
13 Black, odd.
- My numbers aren't coming out.
Did you win?
No.
Can you give me some money?
You forgot our rules.
Come on.
No.
- Roberte!
- Have they left?
Yes. Here.
I'm sure with this,
your luck will return.
I'll pay you back soon.
I like her.
Oh yeah?
- I've never seen
her like that.
She burns.
Come.
Look.
She's burning
Roberte is a flame. She's lit up,
she burns.
Games, alcohol, love
are only excuses for her to burn.
Just how you like her!
- It's what makes me
so fascinated by her.
No more bets.
29 Black, odd, and high.
Just our number.
- The game is over.
It will resume tommorow at 3pm.
Good night, gentlemen.
Roberte.
Roberte!
I have to go home.
Come, we'll have a drink!
Give me 3 shots.
Make it 4.
Stay here!
Good night
Good night, Hйlиne.
Good morning
Good morning.
Sleep well?
How's Roberte?
She wanted to stay at home.
- I was just going to
she how she's doing.
Wait for me.
I'd love to.
What are you doing?
- You got a flat tire just
when you passed me.
But that's absurd!
Yes?
Hello
Oh, it's you!
Wipe yourself off.
You'll catch a cold like that.
- We were running, but the
rain caught us by surprise.
Oh yeah?
You didn't ride your bike, today?
I got a flat..
.. just as
I ran into Mr. Milan.
Hйlиne,..
.. stay like that.
Does she remind you of anything?
We had walked for hours.
You told me about your job.
I didn't dare ask you to
go to a hotel.
It was raining.
But you didn't mind
It was in Paris.
- Then when you finished
drying your hair,..
.. I went to the window.
Hйlиne, please.
Why?
- Please, humor me.
Go over to the window.
I stayed there for a moment
watching the Seine.
And then I turned around.
You were lying on the bed
smoking a cigarette.
You reached your hands out to me
Ant...
.. you took me by the wrists
and sat me down.
I was happy.
I was so happy that day.
And you told me,
that you loved me.
That was 10 years ago.
- What he'd give
to get rid of me!
How can you say that?
- You think you know
him better than me?
- If you knew how he loves you,
how he speaks of you.
Yeah
He also loved Octave.
Octave?
Did he tell you?
What?
Octave committed suicide.
He was mad at me.
Just before the Italian Grand Prix,..
.. He called home.
I wasn't there.
He begged Milan to tell
me that he could no longer,..
.. that I had to choose between them.
and if I didn't join him
the morning before he left for Monza,..
.. he would crash out in the first turn.
That's what he did.
Milan never told me anything.
That's a crime
A cowardly crime!
No!
- An adventurer,
a bastard!
- He was really in love
with Roberte.
Great excuse!
- and you, are you
capable of killing for love?
Certainly not!
and if he continues corrupting you,
I'll smash his face!
- You'd be too afraid of the consequences
- That's the least of my concerns.
You?
- I was a bit drunk.
Forgive me.
Of course.
- It makes me crazy when
I feel you walking away.
Anger really suits you.
I've never loved you so much.
- It's my pleasure
to be angry for you.
I love you.
- Don't you lovers
ever get bored!
- She irritates me!
I can't listen to her anymore!
- You'll hear it from her.
and the whole country too.
I do what I want.
- We'll say that
I'm your lover.
- What do we do in the barn?
- That's not the same thing.
- It's over. I won't go
to the barn with you.
I will make love
in my bed like everyone!
Hйlиne is right.
She's free.
We knew they were dating.
So why hide it?
You never see the bad in anything.
Where are you going?
- To get some air.
I don't feel right.
- You're surprised?
- Why?
- You're always like that
when you have a new love in mind.
So, sleep with her
so we can have some peace!
Give her a kiss for me!
Mr. Milan is not here.
I'm here to see Madame Milan.
- Oh! Just in time.
You can help me.
You alright?
Yes.
There!
It will be good for Milan
to work there by the fire.
Are you always going to keep
your hair up like that?
But it doesn't matter.
Look.
Look how beautiful you are.
I can't teach like that.
- You won't be teaching
your whole life.
Something is missing
there in the middle.
I've got a table upstairs.
Come with me.
Have a look in the bathroom
You'll see better.
You can put some on.
What's the point?
Let me do it.
Why?
Because it amuses me.
It's silky.
I washed it this morning.
Milan is nervous right now.
- The high wind puts
everyone on edge.
Yeah
It's also...
lack of sex.
When you live together a
long time, you no longer want to.
I already thought of that
Duval and I,
we've thought about it.
Beware of it becoming a habit.
Yeah.
Oh, Milan, for him,
it's a habit, it's...
It's only prostitutes.
He doesn't hide anything.
He likes to tell me his exploits.
He's probably
more discreet with you.
For me, the real whores,
don't bother me.
But...
.. but I couldn't tolerate Juliette.
Juliette?
Yes. She was my best friend.
All the time at home.
She found me...
.. beautiful, intelligent,..
.. elegant.
So, the day I discovered that...
.. she and him...
It didn't last long.
I assure you.
What do you say?
And Juliette?
- One night, at a friend's place,
he left with her.
And didn't return
until the next day at noon
She had the audacity to
come over a few days later.
Everyone was there.
We had many guests then.
And then, I cursed her at the door,..
.. with a pair of slaps
in front of everyone.
Maybe she really loved him.
So what?
Sure, I can't prevent him
from chasing girls.
But I can't allow someone
to take my husband.
- What did Milan do
when you slapped her?
- He yelled a little,
for appearances.
To save face.
What's become of her?
Oh, probably a whore.
She was talented for that.
And if she really loved him?
- But you don't love
the husband of another woman.
Has Milan seen her?
I don't think so.
But it would not surprise me
if he still wants more
I'm going to fix your eyebrows.
- No.
Yes. I want you to be beautiful.
You can look now.
How do you find yourself?
I'm a little bit frightened.
- More than ever you have the
deadly gaze of confidence.
Why do you drink so much?
- Do you have something
better to offer me than this?
- I don't want you
to be unhappy.
I want to see you in an evening gown.
I'm not unhappy, you know.
Here.
Look at this one.
Its beautiful!
Well, try it on.
Try it on!
Careful of your hair!
You have beautiful breasts.
You must show them.
Milan said they are glorious.
Look at yourself!
Go on the bed,
you'll see better.
You are beautiful.
You are awkward.
You are charming.
Here. That's all I killed.
It's a dirty beast.
It looks like the birds
in my nightmares.
Good evening
I taught her to be beautiful.
Are you angry?
I thought you
really liked that dress.
and take your dirty bird!
- I'll leave you the feathers
to dress the kid.
But what's the matter?
- I don't know.
He's nervous.
I told you.
I must go.
You won't stay?
I have assignments to correct.
How do I take all this off?
Do you want some coffee?
I asked if you wanted some coffee.
You can't stay angry at me, you know.
I won't give you that pleasure.
So?
You took the pretext
to go hunting..
.. to go by Hйlиne's place
and tell her to come here.
You could have
hooked up with her,..
.. instead of going
to kill a raven,..
.. to make me believe
that she came here by chance.
Spend your life at her place
if that amuses you.
It's your tricks that I dislike.
I don't want her to
take me for a fool
Why do you hide?
Why should I hide anything?
Because you are a liar.
I also wonder why you're a liar.
It's your evil nature.
- It's true
I lie to you often.
You admit it.
I lie to you out of pity.
You don't know what I think of you
- You have pity? But no.
You are mean
like all weaklings
- That's also true
I'm afraid of you.
You're the only one
I'm afraid of.
You are afraid to admit the truth.
- I'm afraid of you like I was
afraid of Hell when I was 13.
You control me like a confessor.
You're sick!
I've made my life with a sicko.
And you don't have the courage
to admit that you went to Hйlиne's..
.. to tell her to come here.
- Roberte, shut up!
Admit the truth.
- How unhappy you'll be
the day I stop lying!
Anger! That's all you are
able to provoke from me.
Admit what!
I hope you die.
One day, I'll kill you.
Good night
Good morning
- I've decided to
pick my pears.
What is that?
A lobster who grew up too fast.
It has a velvet claw.
It won't damage the fruit.
Even a primitive machine helps man.
- You must have a gentle hand
else the fruit will escape.
Fall to the ground and
become overripe.
I'm afraid of being too clumsy.
- You look rather embarassed
by this tool.
- Come help me tame it.
- If you want.
Leave one for me.
There
- I told you I was clumsy.
Go on. Taste them.
- They aren't ripe yet.
Leave them in the granary for 3 weeks.
This one.
This one instead.
You're right.
31.
32.
They'll be good in 3 weeks.
Let's hope
I must go home
Did you love Juliette?
Roberte told you the story
Did you love her?
I think so.
and she?
I think she loved me.
And you never saw her again?
No.
She had to suffer
I imagine she suffered.
You never tried to see her again?
- Cowardice is one aspect
of married life.
Why are you married?
- When we got married,
we were no longer in love.
But she was helpless.
I didn't want to save myself
for a bourgeois marriage.
- She should've refused the marraige.
It wasn't her line of safety.
- She has no job. In love,
security comes with age.
- Sometimes the two of you say
some monstrous things.
And Octave?
Octave?
Yeah. The telephone call.
It's true.
I didn't believe it.
Passion has no morals.
I love you.
Good evening, Madame Milan.
Unload the car.
Be careful of the bottles.
I'm late.
There were many of cars
on the highway!
Here.
I wasn't able to find parking
in the prefecture.
Look.
It's a new boy from Paris
It's not bad.
Ah! You know
what I brought back?
A case of scotch. A change from
Radiguette's brandy.
Bargain.
Looks like it came
from a boutique.
You're making a face!
Heartache?
Yes?
Italy? Did you call Italy?
- Yes. I did.
- Thank you Miss, we did.
I called Luigi.
- You called your manager
while on vacation...
My vacation is over.
Is it true?
- I was lucky, a place opened at Ferrari
I was offered a contract.
What position?
The last.
- You can't accept.
They'll pass you off a spare car.
Training starts next week.
At Modena?
Yes.
I do like Modena.
Who says I'm taking you?
- You'll be unhappy
if you have no one to torture.
We'll celebrate.
I almost suspected it:
Because I bought lots of food.
- All preserved food!
You two eat poorly.
It makes up for our drinking.
In fact you don't have to worry
anymore, we're leaving.
Where are you going?
- Milan is back in action,
we're leaving for Italy
- I knew you'd go.
You guys need your fun.
Hйlиne is what worries me.
Why?
- It wouldn't surprise me
if she has a crush on Milan.
You haven't noticed?
When he's not busy with her,
she's ready to cry.
- She's always around
Your stories go straight to her head.
It will pass.
- Yes, but for kids
of that age, it can be serious.
I don't want her
to do something foolish.
What's going on?
We never see you anymore.
- I have work
My exam is approaching.
You're not upset with Milan?
Why?
- Don't blame him.
It's his 40 year equinox.
But what a number with his raven!
I forgot all about it.
You coming for dinner?
- No. Duvel might be coming.
Another time.
- Don't delay if you want
to say goodbye to Milan.
Goodbye?
- You haven't heard the news?
The press had nothing to say?
He's resuming training at Ferrari.
- So we won't see him anymore
around here?
- He's going to race in all the Grand Prix
January in Buenos Aires,..
.. March, Mexico,
April, Monaco.
are you leaving too?
- Like usual, trailing from behind.
To chase away the reporters.
and to handle the hero's
bad moods.
Luigi is coming to sign his contract.
Are you not coming?
Yes I'm coming.
You're sure, you don't regret anything?
Absolutely sure.
You care so much for this girl?
Enough to know what I'm doing.
- And you've never slept with her?
- No.
I love her innocent gaze, her sincerity.
All that wouldn't last
living with me.
One year of crazy love
and 10 years like Roberte and I had
What do you know?
- It's inevitable. I've had
10 years to understand it.
Here!
You're never late!
Dear Roberte!
The country suits you.
- Did you have a good trip?
- I drove all night.
- There's not one minute to lose, is there.
Hйlиne, come!
This is Luigi, the sporting
director of Ferrari.
Hйlиne Morel, our friend.
A pleasure.
- You're going to have dinner with us
and discuss the contract.
But it's been signed.
You took advantage of my absence!
When Milan trusts
someone, he'll sign anything.
But Luigi is a bandit.
- Milan knew very well what he wanted.
I couldn't say a thing.
- You've become a businessman?
- Anything can happen.
When do we leave?
Milan has to be there tomorrow.
I'll go pack quickly
Have you booked our rooms?
- Milan prefers to stay at the factory.
No. They'll talk shop all the time.
He will live alone.
What?
It's in the contract.
And me?
You stay.
Are you kidding?
- Every month, we'll send
you a third of his salary.
You're taking her?
No.
I don't want to start over with her
what we've already done so well.
Get in. I'll take you back.
Take the wheel.
He's gone.
What are you going to do now?
Nothing.
I'll never have the time
to live a great love.
But I love you.
Me too.
You coming?
It's time for dinner.
- It will take a moment.
It won't move. This is troubling.
Maybe we should go there.
Where exactly?
It's on the high road.
It's far.
What's happening?
- He said he saw flames.
- A car that's stuck.
- They won't make it out alone
- Let's go.
We'd better go look Auguste.
Start dinner without me.
We should see the headlights.
- They must have wanted
to save their battery.
They were stuck right here.
They got out alone.
- They had to turn around.
- No the tracks continue.
Where does this path lead?
- It ends abruptly at
the edge of the pond.
But that's the car of...
We must inform Milan.
Where can we place a call to Modena?
Hey, Milan!
Hi, how are you?
You weren't made for the country.
The country is good.
Tell me a little, and Roberte?
Roberte is staying in the village.
Ah?