[Mob talking]
[Mob talking continuing]
[Weeping]
All of you move out.
Go out...
The safe locker looks broken...
thief might have intruded to rob.
How did it happen?
He came home night at 9:30 pm.
He slept without partaking dinner.
When I came in the morning to serve him coffee...
he was lying like this, sir.
Must have been murdered him
by slitting his throat, when he was sleeping.
Only two of you stay in the flat, right?
Didn’t you hear any noise,
when he was fighting for his life.
No sir, I didn’t hear any sounds...
Does your husband have a wrangle with anyone?
As far as I know, there is no one, sir.
He is very friendly and decent.
Yesterday night, didn’t two of you share the same bed?
Sorry...
Don’t feel bad.
In the course of an investigation...
it becomes inevitable to ask such questions.
Generally, a wife and husband sleep on the same bed.
That’s the reason I asked you the question.
He indicated yesternight, that he is not feeling well.
Hence, I went and slept in another room.
He spoke to me yesterday too, sir.
I interacted with him here, at the lawn.
Who are you?
-My name is Madhan, sir.
Watchman???
No sir.
Ok.
On the other side also, there is an entrance gate.
Is that CC camera in working mode?
Yes sir, it is working.
Alright.
I want the entire footage of that cc camera.
Ok sir.
I want both of you to give honest replies to my questions.
If you give fallacious answers, I will not spare you.
-I don’t have any compulsion to state falsehood, sir.
We will tell truth of the matter.
-We will tell you what we know.
Do you know Aravind?
On which floor, do you reside?
On third floor, sir.
Do you know Aravind,
who resides in your apartment, died?
Yes, I know sir.
Did you hear any sounds at 2 O’clock in the night?
We were in stupor at that time.
-We didn’t hear any sounds, sir.
Did Aravind have any arch foes?
No, he doesn’t have any adversaries,
as for my understanding, sir.
Did he have good relations with all.
-Yeah.. He has cordial ties with all.
You don’t worry about your safety.
Tell me the truth.
We have told you what we know.
-We told the whole truth, sir.
No problem will befall on you.
Ok sir.
-Ok sir.
If I come to know that you have lied,
then consequences will be drastic.
How long have you been working in their house?
Working in their house for past 3 months.
What type of person is Aravind?
He is a decent person.
How does he behave with you?
He behaves in courteous manner.
Where are you from?
Vizag.
Vizag?
How many years elapsed from the
time you came from Vizag?
Sir, Sir...
One year completed, sir.
Where did you work the initial 9 months?
Worked in another house.
Ok. Now tell me what happened
without hiding anything?
I don’t understand what you are alluding to, sir?
I know you understand everything...
Why did you kill Aravind???
I didn’t kill, sir.
If you didn’t kill, then what forced you
to hide this knife?
You killed Aravind and to escape from being
apprehended, you concealed the knife.
Yes or No.
No, sir. I didn’t kill.
Will you tell or shall I make you revel,
using my style of interrogation.
No. I will tell, sir.
Tell...
What transpired on that day, was...
Hey Jyothi...
what is this...?
See how it is...clean here...
Hey see here...
when did you last clean it...
Daily, I am cleaning sir.
Clean now...
If you do like this again,
I will have to inform madam. Leave me...
Hello SI sir, how are you?
Nothing...Lost a gold chain in our house.
Only me and my wife stay in the house...
but a maid regularly visits and leaves the house after work.
she is an honest servant,
but....
No, sir.... No, sir.
Ok... I’ll search my house once again...
then report you.
Please don’t tell sir.
If I it is found, ok sir.
Otherwise please come and investigate...
Thank you, sir. Thank you so much.
No... No...
Don’t...
-No...
No...
Don’t tell...
-No...
No.
He used to intimidate me with that video...
and exploit me daily.
Unable to bear his repeated sexual abuse...
I reported the whole matter to my husband.
Let’s relocate to some other place, dear.
I committed larceny...
taking advantage of it, he started ravishing me...
I’ll butcher that debaucher into pieces...
I'll kill that bastard.
No dear, let’s not commit any felony...
we will go to our village.
We will go...
after killing that bastard, we will proceed to our village.
No dear... stop.
dear...No...
Dear... stop...
No...
It is in my hands.
Why should I worry, when you are here, bro.
Ok... Ok...
What Sekhar, I asked you to summon a plumber....
What happened???
We will talk about it... Don’t worry about it.
Your work will be over, bro.
Fearing you will suspect my husband
upon seeing that knife, I dumped it.
Oh... because he couldn’t kill in the noon...
he committed it at night.
No, sir.
the whole night my hubby was with me.
There is no possibility that
he could have killed.
Ok...
you have to report whenever I summon you.
Alright sir.
Ok. Now you may leave.
Did receive the cc tv footage.
Yes. We received it sir.
You seem to be going somewhere?
I have some urgent work to attend...
that’s why I am leaving.
Going out to settle account???
A murder took place in an apartment, below yours.
Yet you appear to be unflustered and happy.
Do you any enmity towards him?
No.
we are actually good friends.
The whole of yesterday, we were in shock.
Today an emergency arose, so I am going out.
To windup things expeditiously.
So, that no problem befalls on you.
I am not able to comprehend
what you are talking.
Will understand...
slowly you will understand.
My husband doesn’t know anything about it, sir.
I didn’t ask him anything.
Why are you trying to explain that your
husband doesn’t know anything about it?
You are pointing an accusing finger at us and speaking.
See, initially everyone will say they don’t know anything.
Later they will state that it happened inadvertently.
This is the footage from cc tv camera
located outside your apartment.
Do you think that Police will believe whatever you tell,
at the face value and leave without investigating?
Tell me now.
what happened?
My husband didn’t do harm to him, sir.
He only threatened my husband
that he will murder him.
Contemplating that he may murder your hubby,
have you forestalled and finished him off?
Sir, how many times should I tell you, sir. I didn’t murder him.
What happened?
I will tell you the whole story from the beginning.
Wow...
Oh... be careful...
This is very heavy.
I will bring it. Come on.
No problem. I will carry it.
No. its heavy. Lemme do it.
It's ok. Thank you. I can carry.
Not at all. Let me give bring it.
Thank you.
Most welcome.
I haven’t seen you around in this building.
We are new to this place.
Came yesterday.
Nice. Which floor?
1st floor.
Oh... nice..
We stay on 2nd floor.
Thank you
Most welcome.
-Thank you so much.
Coffee is good.
Hai darling.
-Hi baby.
Meet my husband.
She is Priya. Newly shifted to our apartment.
Is it? You have already become friends!
You already know her.
Did she become your acquaintance already?
Not like that.
When they were shifting the other day, the suitcase
she was carrying was heavy... I lent a helping hand.
You guys carry on. I will freshen up and join you.
So.
-So...
Tell me.
-Everything is going good.
Super cool.
Archana, please don’t disturb me.
Hey, what's your problem..?
Let me work. It’s very important.
If you have guts... let’s see.
You are completely crazy.
Hello...
Archana...
-Yaa, Priya...
my system is hanging up.
If you know anyone,
could you send someone please.
I will send my hubby. He will solve the problem.
Ok..?
-Ok.
Don’t worry.
Thank you.
Bye Priya
-Bye.
Listen Baby...
Priya has some computer problem, go and solve, please.
Ouch... you go and solve it.
Darling... please...
Hey come on...
I have to attend to our household problems...
now I have to even solve other’s household problems too.
What is this!
-Just go.
Just one minute... I’ll call you back.
Hi...
It seems you have complained about some system problem.
It was working in the morning...
but I don’t know... suddenly encountered some problem.
Is it?
-Yeah...
Come... let’s look at it.
-Please come.
Did you update any anti-virus program in this system?
Yeah... very recently, it did it.
Now, it’s working... problem solved.
Oh... great!!! Thank you so much.
Four..!
What???
From the time we met to till now,
you have thanked me four times.
Ok... God!!!
Ok. I will take leave.
Thank you.
Count is Five.
Ok.
Play... will you drop the card tomorrow or what?
Why are you shouting? First play your game.
These women take lot of time to play.
I am drop.
Play.
Go and bring some tea.
Priya, today you are going to partake lunch with us.
I am preparing chicken fry.
Fix it slightly to your right.
Will you please give that item?
Oh sure.
Take this.
It will look better here.
Aravind...
this system is always posing problems.
But you don’t care about it.
How many times should seek this gentleman’s help?
I can’t handle this.
Can you change it.
There is no need to change, bro.
There was some minor OS problem.
I solved it now.
Now your computer doesn’t have any problem.
It's working fine.
Oh... You said you were working
on some venture?
How far it has come?
It’s almost in the finishing stage.
Very soon it will be done.
Ok. I will make a move.
-Thank you.
Bye bro, see you.
-Okay.. bye.
Okay.
I am going to Jubilee hills to give applications.
Can you come with me?
Oh Baby! I told you yesterday that
I have a lot work scheduled for today.
See, I am getting calls relentlessly.
Will you come with me?
It’s just a matter of just 4 to 5 hours.
Sorry baby. I have a lot of work on hand.
I have to create a web page.
Sorry.
Ok. Then I will go all alone myself. Bye.
Bye.
Does he meet you daily?
Does he come the moment I get out?
Is that why you preferred this flat?
Does he perform better than me?
Sorry dear...
It happened unwittingly.
You...
Sorry dear...
Please... No...
I will not do it again.
Hey Aravind how are you?
Hey, what is this? What are you doing?
Your husband is cohabiting my wife...
You too copulate with me.
Aravind, leave her alone.
What are you doing, rascal?
What are you doing?
You are enjoying with my wife. Aren’t you?
Your wife fell for me and seduced me.
Then send your wife to make love to me.
Hey, I'll kill him.
Stop it.
Tell me.
Did you finish your dinner?
What is your wife doing?
Is she awake or sleeping?
Thinking of paying a visit.
You scoundrel...
You have enjoyed my wife...
If I enjoy your wife, then it will get even.
You are exceeding the limits...
Will you go first or shall I make a move on your wife.
I’ll kill you scumbag,
if you talk another word about my wife.
Kill me???
Yes, I’ll kill you.
I’ll see.
Shall I come now.
Disconnect the phone you rascal.
Shall I come tomorrow for your wife.
Is tomorrow ok for you.
Your game is finished.
You have meddled with me.
I’ll kill you, if you call me again...
Bastard!
Will you fornicate with your wife first
or will you allow me?
I’ll kill you, you bastard.
Aye ... put it down.
Someday, you are going to die in my hands.
This is what has happened sir.
Ok.
Let’s meet again...
Did Aravind had any enemies?
To narrate about his living.... He is a big sadist.
He is a womaniser.
He doesn’t spare a single lady within his reach.
But recently...
I witnessed him wrangle with Arjun,
an employ in his organization, 2-3 times.
Arjun.
Your name?
What did you study?
Engineering.
How long have you been working with Aravind?
For the past two years I am working with him.
Your boss was murdered?
Did you know that.
Why did you kill your boss?
I didn’t kill him.
We have evidences to prove that you
had twice attempted to murder him.
Why did you kill?
Speak out everything.
I believed him very much.
But he...
I...
I feel in love with a girl named Stella,
who works in our office.
We both even decided to get married.
Arjun, did you inform to your people at home?
Informed... Daddy agreed.
If you somehow manage to impress
my mother, then she will also agree.
After that marriage only, right?
-Wow...!
Later honeymoon.
We both have our jobs.
We can settle in our life happily.
Yeah true.
Love you baby.
Love you.
He used intermittently state that
he will perform our marriage.
But instead that trickster...
Hi Sir.
Ok uncle, I will call you later...
I will guarantee you a hike in your pay...
and promotion for sure.
Thank you.
I am sorry Arjun, please...
Arjun...I am sorry...
Don’t come near me. Go away.
How did you think of deceiving me?
How much did I Love?
Arjun, please Arjun...
intentionally I didn’t do it, Arjun.
He trapped me Arjun.
If he trapped, didn’t you comprehend...
didn’t you feel our love?
You loved me.
I placed my head in your lap and professed my love.
but you stabbed here, in my heart.
You asked me to take permission of my Father
and my mother, they okayed it.
Now what should I do?
Finally, you made me a fool.
You are still able to stand before me
because of the fact that I love you.
Otherwise I would have killed you.
Leave me.
Go away.
I told you, your work will be over, right bro.
You come it will be over.
How much I believed you? Why ditch me?
How much I trusted you.
In the name of hike and increase in salary,
why did you trap my lover?
Hey, get lost.
Hey fool... If you interfere in my dealings
once more, I’ll kill you.
I will not leave you...
I’ll kill you.
This is what happened sir.
But I didn’t harm Aravind in any way, sir.
How long have you been working in the office?
One year.
Apart from Arjun, does Aravind has
squabbles with any other person?
To tell the truth... yes, he has...
Three people wanted to kill him...
who would have killed him?
The whole night my husband was with me.
But that bugger...
doesn’t spare a single lady within his reach.
He's very friendly and decent.
I did not harm Arvind.
My husband didn't harm him, Sir.
One...
Two...
Three...
Did forensic reports come?
Yes sir, they have come.
Hey, you are a vey smart person.
Hey constable, go inside and check.
-Okay Sir.
Hello... hello... what is this?
-I will tell.
We know you have murdered Aravind
prudently and freaking out.
What is this? I didn’t murder him.
Is it?
Then how come you finger prints and
foot prints clearly matched with those at the crime site.
My finger prints?
-Yes, yours only.
What happened Vikram?
Your husband committed murder
and created false alibi.
Found this knife under the mattress, sir.
Perpetrated murder and concealed
the knife in the house, Huh??
Sir, I am not aware how it got into my possession.
Your acting superbly, man.
-Please believe me, sir.
Please listen sir, I don’t know.
-Let’s go to station, we will discuss it there.
Baby...
Yeah.
You getting married... I getting married...
Having babies...
you having a husband .... Me possessing another...
this all will not work out.
I have an idea.
What?
My plan is... you marry a rich person...
I too will wed a wealthy person...
Later on, I will murder my wealthy husband and incriminate your
husband in the crime, so that he will be incarcerated.
Thereafter we will inherit their complete wealth and will be free.
We can together enjoy our life... It will be bindaas.
This is my plan.
Your plan is superb.
Lovely baby.
We are new to this place.
Came yesterday.
Oh..! Which floor?
1st floor.
Your husband is not a mug.
He is very smart.
He is just trying to seduce me.
Within a week, he will come in our line.
Yes.
Yes!
Perpetrated murder and concealed
the knife in the house?
Babies...
I have proved beyond doubt that
your husband killed her husband.
Fingerprints are also in our favor.
Now, one can prove and apprehend either of you.
This is the best deal in my life.
2 crores of money...
and 2 super figures on either side.
Cheers...
There are more truths we do not know...
behind the facts we know.