Timing and Subtitles by 🌬 My Accidentall Besties 🦄  @viki.com
Hi, everyone, my name is Hong An.
I am eight years old.
Like any other child, I'm being taken to "school" every morning by my dad.
Concentrate on your driving! What are you looking at?
- Mom.
- What?
- Everyone stops at traffic lights.
Why isn't he looking at the traffic light but at me?
We are in the car lane.
Oh, is this the car lane?
I've never driven a car. How would I know?
To be honest, I don't have a dad.
This is my mom.
I consider her to be my dad.
That's right. My mom is quite strict,
but she really loves me.
Mom, I told you before. We need to fill up the motorbike with gasoline. Why are you so forgetful?
Stop nagging! Everyone makes mistakes.
But you always make mistakes, Mom. You're raising me all wrong!
This is my biggest dream.
As you know, I go to "school" everyday.
But not for studying... I go there to buy banh mi*.
(*Vietnamese bread)
- Mom.
- What?
When can I go to school?
You're only eight years old! You don't need to go to school. When you're nine, you can go.
But all of my friends have gone to school since they were six years old.
Why do children nowadays start going to school so early?
I didn't go to school until I was about fourteen or fifteen years old.
Mom!
D*mn...
I am sorry.
Shame on you! How dare you hit her car?
Maybe you don't know who she is, right?
[Accidentally Dad]
Since you are sick like this, don't call me, okay?
I-If you die, don't even look for me!
- Stop!
- Run after your dad!
- Remember, don't call me!
Daddy, be careful. Don't fall!
He fell, but he's all right.
Keep enjoying your coffee.
Continue enjoying your coffee, okay?
- Mom!
- What is it?
He left.
Oh my gosh! I almost coughed up my throat.
Mom, was it ketchup or chilly sauce?
I mixed them together.
That's gross!
What are we celebrating?
Let me think about it. Great acting!
Let's get fried chicken across the street.
Okay, make sure to remove the skin for me.
Oh my, she's on a diet!
To be honest, she didn't want to be this way,
but she needs money for her business.
As you know, though, doing business has its ups and downs.
In case of a down, I don't get to eat fried chicken.
- Is it tasty?
- What are you doing?
We don't even have food to eat, yet you're feeding the dog?
I pitied Mun. She hasn't eaten all day!
What about me?
You eat this.
Here, this is for you.
- You eat it.
- What about you?
- I'll eat "Mun's meat."
- No!
Mun, you have to go down.
- Let's eat so we can go to work this evening.
- I'm going to eat.
Yes.
The way of living is like this.
We eat when we are hungry and laugh when we are happy. It's a shame we don't have a dad.
If we did, we would be so happy.
[Five, ten, fifteen... forty]
If we get another great "deal" like this, we will be awesome tomorrow.
- As usual?
- Yes.
Let's go big this time and make their jaws drop!
- Okay. All right.
- N-Not yet!
- Be careful, do you hear?
- Okay.
- Mommy!
- Oh my God! My baby!
Roll back.
Oh, Lord, help me, please!
- He hit my child.
- Help me!
Are you all right?
Maybe my ribs are broken!
Lord, I have no money to take her to the hospital. This could cost ₫5,000,000!
Oh my God!
Hey! H-Hey!
- What are you doing?
- Come here. What are you doing?
- Are you asking me what I'm doing?
- You hit a person, and now you want to run? What are you up to?
- Where did you get hurt, Baby?
- Mom, my lungs are probably damaged.
Damaged lungs?
Gosh, that would cost ₫10,000,000!
Give me fifteen and a half million dong. I'll take her to the hospital.
- How the h*ll is it ₫500,000 extra?
- It's for the taxi! Do you think the taxi is free?
- Are you going to give me the money?
- It hurts!
Everybody, come and see this!
You, stop screaming!
Here, take this!
- How much are you compensating?
- Only this much for you and your daughter... Take it or leave it!
- You don't care about her life!
- What else do you want?
- What do you want? Will you give me the money or not?
- You...
- I'm in so much pain!
- What compensation?
- Run if you can! What's your plate number?
- Six, seven, eight... God of Fortune!*
- What are you doing?
(Asians like to pray to this god for more money.)
- I dare you to run!
- H-Hey!
You hit my daughter and now you want to leave?
Go ahead and hit me as well.
- I want to die!
- It hurts!
I'm so worthless!
Mom, my hand is broken too.
Where is she? Where is my daughter?
Are you planning to kidnap her? Are you a kidnapper too, now?
Go away. Get away. Hey...
What are you doing? Where are we going?
I'm taking the two of you to withdraw money, all right?
All right, but make sure it's ₫15,500,000, or I won't get out of the car.
Hey, why don't you take us to the bank to get money? Why are you bringing us to the hospital?
Oh my God. My heavens!
Hey, do you hear me?
Hey, you, put her down! Put my daughter down!
- Child, lie still, okay?
- What are you doing?
Hey, what are you doing?
Are you going to give us the money or not? Give money to my child!
- What are you doing? Keep silent!
- Why did you bring us here?
Everyone, come and see! He hit my daughter and now he wants to run.
- Give me the money!
- Stop screaming.
Stop, your *ss.
Give me the money. Give it!
Give me the money right now!
Security! Security, take him!
Arrest him, not me!
- Lady, be calm, all right?
- Give me the money!
Be quiet. Keep her still.
Are you going to give me the money or not?
Why did you bring my child here?
Are you going to be quiet?
- How is she, Nurse?
- She's fine, no serious injuries.
Hey, why the h*ll do you answer him? He's not a doctor.
I am her mom. She was seriously injured.
This is Doctor Tung Son.
- Son Tung* what?
- Doctor Tung Son.
(*singer)
He is the head of this hospital's emergency department.
There shouldn't be a problem now.
- Everyone, go back to work.
- All right.
You, too.
It hurts! I'm hurting!
I'm hurt. It hurts.
Hey, Sweetie, where does it hurt?
Tell me.
My ribs are hurting. Here...
- Here?
- Yes.
This is your belly, not your rib cage.
All right, your ribs are up here.
Do a better job acting next time, or else it'll get awkward.
- I am hungry.
- My child is hungry.
Why did you fall in front of this uncle's car?
Put on your slippers, quickly.
Thank you, Doctor.
Hey.
I'm not in pain anymore.
No pain!
What a dream!
- This is for you.
- Mom...
- No, I won't take it.
- Hey,
this is for you.
- When you are hungry, get something to eat, okay?
- All right.
Promise me you won't do this again.
- It's bad.
- Okay.
Good girl.
- Go home.
- Okay. Mom, here.
He gave it to you so you keep it. Keep it safe.
Remember his face. Make sure to say thank you whenever we see him again.
All right.
It would be best not to see each other again.
Mom, why aren't you eating?
Are you skipping a meal cause you lost in gambling?
Do you like it? Here...
Ladies and Gentlemen,
as per our previous meeting's report,
we are looking for a person to fill the deputy director position of our hospital.
Doctor Thanh is going to retire by the end of this year.
In front of you is the list with our candidates.
Please take a look.
As you see, the results show that only Doctor Tung Son is left on the list.
Yes.
You have one month to get ready for the assignment and to present it in front of hospital directors.
For transparency,
I am going to invite some professors and PhDs from the Ministry of Health to join this event.
Madam, please take just one pill.
Then I will take you to every corner of this hospital.
Please just take one. Please...
Just this one pill, please...
Doctor.
Tell me why you don't want to take your medication.
- I want to eat sticky rice with sugar.
- It's really sweet.
If we eat that, the sugar level in our bodies will increase.
Then our bodies will get tired, won't they?
How about this? Let's have sticky rice with chicken. Let's eat that instead.
It's better with drumsticks!
- Here we are.
- Here it is.
This is your sticky rice with drumsticks. No, no, no.
- Now give me my medicine!
- Medicine.
- Here.
- Here it is.
Here you are.
All right, well done!
All done.
- Let's have some rest.
- Sticky rice with chicken drumsticks!
Sticky rice with chicken drumsticks...
But they don't have chicken drumsticks. Is it okay with shredded chicken instead?
I know they are shredded from the chicken drumsticks.
Right... Yes.
- "A Ty, A Ty."
- What?
It's me. She means "Nurse."
Nurse, please hide it for "A Tun", my son.
Don't let A Tun see it.
Let me tell you,
he's a grown-up. He won't eat this.
There's plenty of sticky rice out there. He can buy it whenever he wants.
The thing is, he is not going to visit you. Do you understand?
I mean, he is busy all the time. He doesn't have time to come here and visit you.
He's really busy at work. Yes, he's very busy.
Have some rest, Madam. He will visit you tonight. Get some rest.
Put it down.
Why?
You're not allowed to drink this coffee.
Is there something inside?
There are three "things."
First of all, drinking coffee during lunch, before eating, will cause your stomach to hurt.
Secondly, it contains more caffeine than milk.
It's going to affect your brain.
Then who would take care of your patients,
and of me?
Firstly, I already ate.
Secondly, I ordered a strong coffee for myself
because I was exhausted from working on the assignment last night. So this morning,
I need to take in enough caffeine to stay awake.
You argue with me whenever I say anything.
That's because what you said was wrong.
How about the third one?
When someone cares about a friend,
even though it's embarrassing,
you should pretend that you're touched by the fact that I care.
Understood?
Stop talking nonsense. This is way too much.
What would you like to eat? It's my treat!
Are you on the menu?
It would be boring if you weren't!
I'm sorry.
Will you be able to work at the hospital tomorrow if you drink this much?
I drink a lot. Did you bring enough money?
Baby, I have nothing but money. Feel free.
Good! Wait for me.
Hey... Hey!
You are soon going to live abroad.
Leave her alone, or else Karma is going to find you!
I don't care. Having that hot woman would be great karma anyway.
Whatever...
Here.
Cheers!
Drink!
- Hey, let's go.
- Whereto?
Where is Cong?
I can't believe you are that kind of man!
You are about to move abroad, and now you go to the club to find yourself some women!
No, I only went there with my brothers.
- I'm going to die to show you.
- Don't...
- Don't worry. I'm coming home now. Don't die.
- I'm going to kill myself.
I'm going to die right now!
Hey, Son...
My friend...
"Design" somewhere for me to vomit.
Do whatever you want in my room. Good stuff is waiting for you in there too.
This way...
Not this way...
How come she looks so sexy?
No, Karma will find me.
No, no, no...
- Hey you!
- I am here.
Watch you sleep?
Let me do it.
Only watching...
Don't...
Go to sleep.
I am tired.
Do you remember?
Hey!
Who are you? Are you trying to run away?
I'm sorry.
I was so drunk yesterday that I don't remember anything.
Yesterday, your friends tried to get me drunk.
Where's Cong? Where's Cong?
- He's sleeping.
- Where?
At home... He went home yesterday.
Or should I call him here to talk with you?
Tell me! Do you want to run away?
I have no idea who you are!
What is your name? Where are you from? Who is your family?
What if something happens? What the h*ll would I do?
It would be best not to  see each other again.
Would you like me to remind you about last time?
There's no need.
As you tell the story,
I feel terrible just thinking about it.
What do you want?
I want you to make up for what my child and I went through during the past seven years.
You're still "aggressive," like before.
What are you talking about? I don't understand.
We played an "adult game." Having a child is normal.
What?
The girl you crashed into...
She is your daughter.
How fortunate is that... right?
Since the heavens have given it, enjoy it.
The heavens or just a game?
What are you doing?
The game has just started.
Oh my God! You are crazy!
Are you out of your mind? At that time, my wife told me to go home.
I haven't even touched her yet!
Oh my God, I was drunk as h*ll! How should I remember?
Right, this lady seems to be a scammer.
It was my mistake. What if she belongs to someone else?
Stupid!
You are so stupid.
What is a DNA test for?
Come on! You are a doctor. You should know about that.
Think about it. That night, you may not have "eaten" her,
but you must have done something.
That's bullsh*t!
A DNA test is very easy.
But what if my colleagues and Thuy Linh find out about it?
Moreover, I have my study abroad program.
I don't care what others think of you, but you've been watching me bathe for way too long now.
Mom,
what are you calculating?
How much did we spend, the past seven years?
That would be a huge amount! You lose it every day during gambling.
She always says inauspicious things!
Not that one?
Do you want to have a dad?
Yes, I want one,
but he has to be an awesome mafioso!
No, why would he? He only needs to have money.
You would spend all the money on gambling anyway.
Stop cursing at me!
I told Chaien and Seiko I have a Mafia dad.
- You really want a dad, don't you?
- Yes.
Let me see. Your handwriting is a disaster!
Whatever! Having money is enough.
Hey, Doctor, are you free? Come calculate the last seven years with me!
Are you deaf? I'm calling you. Hey!
What are you doing now?
What are you doing? Don't touch me! What do you want?
Why are you here?
I told you to give me some time to find out what happened that night, and then I'd come to find you.
How much longer will it take? Another seven years?
- What?
- Do you know how difficult it is to raise a child for seven years?
Do you know how hard it is to raise her alone? Do you understand?
How do I know if that child is mine? How do I know if you aren't lying?
You "eat" it or throw it away! That's your business. Nobody cares.
I am her mom. I surely know who her dad is!
I want Hong An to have a dad.
Do you only want to make money out of this?
Do I want to make money out of this?
Let's see. How much did I spend these past seven years?
Take a DNA test, and you will know.
Okay, do you want money? I will give you money.
But on the condition that you  give me time to think about this situation.
Who are Hong An's parents?
Please hurry to the security office.
Hello, Dad.
How much more time do you need to think?
Take her home. I'll see you tonight.
Okay, tonight or else...
I don't know what will happen tomorrow!
- What are you doing?
- I'm checking your leg for you.
Why? My head hurts.
I am sorry.
Don't do this anymore, okay?
- That's immoral.
- You're right.
I am sorry. I will focus more.
I'm talking about your personal issue.
That is immoral!
- Do you know?
- Of course I know.
What is done at night will eventually appear in the daytime.
It's a big problem anyway.
Auntie, this one is very important to me.
I hope you won't tell anyone.
It's hard for me, but I pity you so I won't.
Now you have to make sure that I won't.
How do you want me to do that?
Between now and this afternoon, bring me chicken sticky rice,
but with drumsticks, okay?
Just chicken?
Make sure I get it before 4 p.m.
Otherwise, I will tell every single person in this hospital,
you...
took my chicken that day.
Don't be like this anymore, Doctor. That is "immoral."
Ch-Chicken...
I have a headache.
I have a headache, too. Have some rest, okay?
I'll take a look at you later.
- You're here. Where is your mom?
- I am here.
And you...
Hey, where are you going?
- Oh my God!
- It's so beautiful.
What a beautiful house!
It's just a rental home. Don't bring things out of order.
I don't care as long as it's pretty.
What are you doing? Where are you going?
I'm going to look in which room we'll be staying, and clean up.
- What?
You said you were going to let me know tonight.
Why did you tell me you would take me to see my dad?
We are just meeting. Why did you bring your baggage?
We can't afford to pay the rent so the landlord kicked us out.
Oh my God!
Sooner or later, you have to admit it so we'd better just move in here in advance.
Is he my dad?
Your dad? You'd wish!
Nice, I like it.
- What?
- Get out of my house.
No.
Son, are you home?
- Do you have someone else here tonight?
- No way!
This is my sister. She just came to the village.
What is your name?
Well, I am Thuy Linh.
- My daughter's name is Hong An.
- Yes.
You probably know me, right?
No, not yet.
My name is Phuong.
You are here. Your daughter is here. Where is your husband?
He passed away.
I am so sorry to hear that.
I am a single mom,
such a pity for my daughter.
She never met her dad.
You know, he was the "have fun and run" type of man.
Exactly the same... Their children are totally "like father, like son."
Look at this mole!
Luckily, she looks like her uncle.
Her dad doesn't have it.
How lucky you are!
We often wanted to remove it,
but it cost ₫10,000,000 so we didn't.
- Indeed, don't remove it. It's a waste of money.
- You're right!
It brings good luck.
That's right. That one helps us make some money.
I...
gradually make money.
Poor you and your daughter...
Sister, after visiting me, you're going back home, right?
No way!
No, my daughter is sick. May we stay here so she can be cared for?
At least she still has an uncle here.
If that's the case, you should stay here.
That's right.
- Hey, Baby.
- What?
We have a dinner reservation tonight. We may be late.
I forgot. Let's go, Darling.
We're going out for dinner. Help yourself at home.
Child, go to sleep early, okay?
- Let's go, Darling.
- Mom, I am starving.
Then... would you like to come with us?
Hong An!
- Hong An, come over here!
- All right.
Mom, what's going on?
- That hurts.
- Sit here!
This is a fancy restaurant. I can't afford to pay for your mess.
That's fine. We will take care of it.
- It's okay.
- She's going to kill them all.
My daughter is so naughty.
We should wait outside so you can enjoy your dinner.
No, it is totally fine. If you go, we won't feel comfortable.
- Right, Honey?
- Yes.
We're going to become family members anyway, aren't we?
You're right! It looks like you guys are about to get married.
He seems like a good man. Grab him while you can.
Would you like to order? Otherwise, they will close their kitchen.
- What do you want to eat?
- I want French fries.
No, we should order lobster here.
No, I want French fries first!
- Lobster.
- No.
Don't push her if she doesn't like to eat that, right, Honey?
- Enjoy your dinner.
- Thank you.
Thank you so much. Eat!
Don't be shy.
Here,
enjoy your food, Honey.
That much? How could we eat all of that?
Why not? There are four of us.
Correct, don't worry, "Uncle." We also have Mun.
Oh, yes.
Come on. Let's eat.
- Eat, Honey.
- Okay.
What is this?
Hong An has been sick and hasn't had any appetite lately,
but today she really enjoys the food.
I'm going to take it out so she can have it for breakfast tomorrow.
Lobster for breakfast?
We eat whatever we have. I can't make requests.
What if she can't finish it?
It's all right, Honey. We hardly have dinner together like this.
- Check, please.
- I already asked for it, Honey.
No, you can't do that.
If you'd pay, I would feel so bad!
Yes, I feel bad, too.
- All right, let me pay this bill.
- Okay, go ahead.
He's joking. I already did.
Let's go home.
I knew it. Thank you!
Come here and let's talk.
What?
You're full, aren't you? What else do you want?
I already told you. I want my child to have a dad.
Don't I keep telling you?
I need more time.
During this time, I have a lot of things to take care of. I just can't—
What for? How much more time?
Because of that Linh?
Tell me what else you have to do? Let me help you out.
It's personal.
All right, what now—
What?
A new place?
Okay, I know.
Do you have money? Lend me some.
You'd wish!
Let's see.
Dad, I am hungry.
I am hungry.
Tell your mom.
Dad, read this.
What the h*ll is going on so early in the morning?
I took some money for my business trip. I'll be back tomorrow.
Thank you.
She won't pick up the phone.
When will she pick up?
When she goes broke, Dad.
What? Again...
[Gia An]
Make sure you remember what I told you.
When someone asks you who you are, what do you tell them?
I'll say, "I am a daughter of my mom."
"My mom is Uncle Nam's daughter,"
"a niece of Eighth Auntie, sister of Grandpa Tam,"
"from Uncle Ba and Auntie Sau's side."
Yes. What about me? Who am I?
- Daddy.
- No.
I am your "Uncle Ba," understand?
Why do I have to lie?
"Grown-ups" said children should not lie!
This is not a lie.
It's just a little bit off from the truth.
As long as it's not going to hurt anyone, it's fine, okay?
So what do you want to say?
I want that someday,
you will tell everybody in the hospital that
I am your daughter...
or not.
I'll be late.
Don't be scared. Nobody's here.
What if someone suddenly shows up?
Oh my goodness, someone appeared!
- Good morning, Doctor!
- Good morning.
Who left a little girl here?
Is she your niece, Doctor?
I am the daughter of my mom.
My mom is Uncle Nam's daughter,
a niece of Eighth Auntie...
Oh my God, I forgot.
She is Sixth Aunt's grandchild. She is my niece.
On my, what a sweetie!
- Next time, just say you are his niece.
- Okay.
One look, and I knew you were related.
Look at this mole! Just the same as the one you have, Doctor.
But why is yours bigger?
You're hilarious!
You two look like father and daughter.
Really, do you think so?
So do I.
No way, not like father and daughter.
This little girl is a hundred times prettier than the doctor!
Here you go again.
We're here. Say goodbye, Baby.
Goodbye.
Stop being sarcastic. I know who I am. That's why I don't have a husband!
- You're "too much."
- Whatever!
- Apparently, we are here.
- We're supposed to be on this floor!
Why do we keep fighting like this?
Oh my, Doctor Son's niece is so smart!
Miss Van never listens to anyone, but today she listened to her and took her medicine.
If I had a daughter like her, I could raise a hundred children like Au Co.
- Are you talking about my niece?
- Yes, your niece! Who else?
My nieces are so bad. Like h*ll, I just want to slap their butts a few times.
D-Doctor...
One day, I will bring Mun here to play with you all.
She is very smart. She understands everything.
All right, you must keep your promise, okay?
We will soon have "dog meat" to "enjoy."
Hey, come here. Let them all rest. Come with me.
Okay.
Let's go. Say goodbye to them.
Goodbye, Madam.
That hurts!
What did I tell you?
Don't go anywhere, and don't tell any nonsense.
Why did you go there, talking with them and not letting them rest?
No, I played with them.
And I didn't tell any "nonsense."
Are you arguing with me? Like who?
Same as you!
Hey...
Stop retorting, okay?
Nobody taught you how to communicate right. The way you are talking is very rude.
As you know,
I don't have a dad so nobody taught me.
Doctor, Doctor, come with me! The patient in room nine has gone into shock.
Okay.
Stay here nicely.
"Uncle Ba" will be back, okay?
- Let's go.
- All right.
Fine! You bring me here and now you leave me.
Where are you, Hong An?
Hong An!
Child, you stay here! You're such a crafty child!
You're this little, yet you know how to steal other people's wallets! You have no manners!
- No, I didn't steal your wallet.
- If not you, then who did?
My wallet obviously was inside my bag!
- You're denying it!
- Hey, Miss, what are you doing?
Oh, Lord! This girl tried to steal my wallet!
- Who are you?
- I am her uncle.
Her uncle? How come you let her do this? Take her home and teach her, please!
She's only this small, but she already knows how to pick pockets!
I'm sorry, Miss.
Sweetie,
- say sorry and give it back to her.
- Why? I didn't steal her wallet.
- Say sorry and give it back to her right now.
- I didn't do it!
What? Admit it! Stop lying.
I did not do this!
- D*mn it!
- Miss, what are you doing?
She did not admit it! Obviously, I went to go shopping!
What made my purse open up, causing my wallet to fall on the ground?
If not her, then who did it?
- Is this one yours?
- Of course it's mine!
Double-check if you are missing anything, please.
Thank God, nothing is missing, or else I would drag your a*s to the police!
Hey, Miss, how did you know my niece did it?
Hey, Young Brother and everybody here witnessed it. Isn't that right?
Isn't it?
Really? This guy... is a drug addict!
- For sure, he tried to steal the wallet!
- Catch him!
Oh, no, why did we blame this poor little girl?
I am sorry.
Please forgive me.
I am so sorry.
I kept telling you, but you didn't trust me.
I said, I was sorry.
Please don't cry.
I just wanted to help her pick up that wallet. I did not do anything wrong.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry. Forgive me, please.
Please, don't cry. Don't cry.
All right, here you go.
How much...
Bet some more.
Put some more in.
Put some more in!
Hands up.
- All right, let's bet ₫100,000.
- Okay.
Be careful while dealing.
- Really?
- Pull.
- Slowly.
- Oh my God!
There are so many toys for you here.
Why are you still upset with me, Sweetie?
I am sorry, Baby. I told you I didn't mean it.
My mom only takes money from the rich, from the bad, to give to the poor.
She never takes anything from the poor or the elderly.
Then...
This morning she took it from me.
Do you mean she thinks I am a bad person?
Really, did she take your money this morning?
Yes.
Then she is wrong.
This one sounds acceptable.
What? Don't you eat mushrooms?
- No, I am scared mushrooms make my belly hurt.
- So am I.
If I eat it, I will get a stomachache.
- They're terrible!
- Yes, they are.
Anyway, we're still friends now, aren't we?
No.
Come on, what else do you want?
- Do you really want to be friends with me again?
- Yes.
Come here, and I'll whisper it in your ear.
- Hey.
- Hey, Handsome, come in.
This is my dad, my dad!
- Your dad?
- Daddy.
All right, do you remember?
But I am not your dad. I can't say that.
Don't worry. Saying this won't hurt anyone, right?
You said that before, remember?
But...
Do it for me, please.
Chaien and Seiko both have dads.
Only I don't have a dad. They are always teasing me.
Daddy, sit here.
- Why does your face look like that?
- Your place looks scary.
Don't be scared, Daddy. They look bad, but deep down, they are kind.
You wretched woman! Stop right there! I'm going to beat you right now.
Stop right there!
Who are you beating?
Oh my heavens!
Should we call the police?
Don't worry. They usually fight on the street, not inside the home.
It's safest inside the house.
D*mn it!
Hey, Child, what are you looking at?
Keep going! I don't dare to have an opinion.
- Is he finished?
- He finished a long time ago.
Can I go home?
Stay here with me, Daddy. I will protect you!
- It's scary.
- Hong An!
Hong An, who is that?
Hong An, where have you been lately?
I have not seen you for a while.
And who is this man?
- He is my dad.
- What?
How come you don't look like him?
What?
Who said I don't? My dad is an "authentic" mafioso.
An "authentic" mafioso... Mafia...
Yes, I am an authentic mafioso.
- Which area do you handle?
- The emergency room.
Hey, hospital, hospital, hospital...
I handle the hospital area.
I mean, I take care of the hospital, the gas station, the morgue and so on.
Even the morgue!
Really? That is so creepy!
Not just that...
Every day, people die in my area.
Death is nothing to me.
Are you scared?
Murderer!
I'm joking. I'm a doctor.
- I give injections to the patients.
- Yes, indeed.
- Oh, I know.
- Good.
Do you give injections to the dogs?
- Yes, you're right.
- No, it's not like that.
For animals, doctors are called "veterinarians."
But I'm a doctor. Someone who saves people is called a "doctor." Do you understand?
But you can give injections to dogs as well, can't you?
No, I can't—
He can give injections to pigs, dogs, chickens, and all types.
Hong An's father...
He is a "whatever mafioso!"
Chaien, Seiko, come home now!
All right!
See you later, Mr. Whatever-mafia.
Whatever-mafia...
Who are they?
They are my friends.
Your friends?
That's why!
Are you okay?
- Such a harmful pizza!
- Dad!
I remember I didn't eat mushrooms.
Here you are. Take this to refresh yourself.
Is it better, Dad?
Better... but my tummy is still a bit hurt.
Drink some water, Dad.
Thank you.
What is it?
What is inside? The taste is weird and sour.
- That is the water from the well.
- How can you drink this?
Let me drink. It's good.
- Seriously?
- It's totally normal water.
Oh, my goodness, it's hot.
Is there no fan here?
No, we don't have one.
My mom said we need to save money to buy a house,
not a fan.
Before... Isn't this...
So this is not your house.
No. No, we're just renting this place.
But where did you live before?
- Me? On the street.
- What?
Because mom lives in the casino so I live on the street.
On the street, I could play whenever I wanted to. It was so much fun!
Don't you go to school?
My mom said I'm too young to go to school.
I can go when I get older.
Doctor, Chaien's dad has passed out! Please help him.
Take me there right now.
Move. Please move.
- Stay away, please.
- Make way! He's a doctor!
- Wake up, Daddy!
- Give me something for his head.
Give me something, please. Thanks, Miss...
- Calm down, Chaien!
- But this is my dad!
- But my dad can help your dad.
- What happened with Dad, Mother?
His heart stopped. Call the ambulance, please!
Daddy!
He's conscious!
- Mr. Mole, what is your name?
- I am Tung Son.
- Are you a doctor?
- Yes, I am.
Thank you, Doctor Tung Son.
Thanks to him, this fatty man came back to life.
Daddy, how did you know how to save Chaien's father?
Since I am a doctor, that was "easy-peasy."
You are awesome, Dad!
See?
You were out this afternoon. Now you have a sunstroke!
- Let me adjust the temperature.
- No, it's okay, Dad.
- All right.
- Okay.
- Daddy, can I borrow your hand?
- What?
- Your hand...
- Why?
- Give it to me. Then you'll know.
- It smells dirty!
- Does it smell dirty?
It's smelly, but I love it!
- You're such a weird one!
- I don't mind.
Whenever I am with you, I'm so happy.
Here's some porridge.
Here, open your mouth.
Good girl.
Son speaking.
I was wrong.
Forgive me, Mr. Ma.
I promise I will give you your money back.
Help me, please.
They're going to cut off my hand because I can't pay him back!
Shut up! What a big mouth! Be careful, or I'll cut your tongue.
Son, did you bring all the money?
I'm still missing some.
I am sorry.
What do you mean? Can't you even withdraw ₫50,000,000 without some of it still missing? Are you joking with me?
I'm telling you the truth. When I was at the bank this morning to withdraw the money, it was very busy.
I had to go to the ATM to withdraw the money.
I was able to withdraw the ₫30,000,000 left on my card.
Oh, God, how is that enough?
All right, leave her hand.
- Cut two fingers and feed them to the dogs.
- Okay!
Wait! Don't cut! Please...
These fingers are used to deal cards.
Are you still thinking about gambling? Cut her entire hand off for me!
I will sew them for her later, free of charge!
Wait! He's not your grandfather. Why are you listening to him?
Hey, don't you think you've gone too far?
Think about the seven years I raised your daughter!
That does not relate to this. It has not yet been defined she's my child!
Cut it now! Cut the entire hand!
I will stitch them up later!
On the way to the hospital, take this for a paternity test.
- Did you just threaten me?
- Yes!
- Go ahead!
- Cut them!
- Cut!
- Cut now!
- Cut.
- You cut it for me. Cut now!
Cut so she can get rid of her habit! She's gambling all the time!
- It doesn't matter how sick your daughter is at home!
- Cut it!
Cut it! Cut them!
- Is she your cousin?
- Yes.
Why have I never heard about her before?
Why would I have to tell you?
Her story is her husband doesn't believe her daughter is his "real" daughter.
She wants to prove he's wrong by having him take a paternity test.
Why doesn't her husband trust her?
Do we still have such men on Earth?
Yes, of course.
I am out of luck so I met an a*shole.
He is a "have fun and run" man.
Again, are there still men like that on Earth?
It got even worse when he said to me,
"It would be best not to see each other again."
I cannot forget this.
That phrase sticks in my mind like a clue.
- Really?
- Yes.
So a man like that got  her pregnant and ran away?
He has such bad eyes!
If I were him, I would "run to you."
Yes, he did "hit" me.
- That sounds good.
- But still he refused to accept his daughter.
Why?
For now, I wish for my daughter to have a dad,
even if I'd die trying.
I sympathize with you. I will help you.
That man should not have been born in this world!
- Betrayer!
- Buffoon!
He lives without morality!
- If he had a child, that child would...
- Hey,
don't talk about people who are not here.
Yes, you're right. He's not here. We shouldn't talk behind his back.
Did he pass away?
Sorry, I'll let it slip.
Are you crazy? He is still alive!
Doctor, we have the result of the paternity test.
Okay, I'm coming back now.
What is it? Hey, what is it?
- Why did you come home so late?
- I had to go to work.
Today is your daughter's birthday! Why did you come home this late?
I wasn't aware of that.
Don't you remember your daughter's birthday?
I could forget my own birthday, but absolutely not those of my children!
Here... Not just my children's, I even remember his birthday.
Stop it. You're being weird. Don't be so loud, or else she will hear us.
- Give him the birthday hat.
- Okay.
Go. Go in.
Hong An, Children, come down here.
Okay.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, happy birthday, happy birthday, Hong An! ♪
Happy birthday to you, Baby!
Here, Hong An,
this is your birthday cake.
Don't give it to her! Take it to the table so she can blow out the candles.
Come here, Baby. Here...
Yes, lower it a bit. Here...
Okay, blow them out.
Wait!
First of all, make a wish.
- Blow.
- What did you wish for?
- Maybe she wished for her mom to have more money.
No, she wished for her mom to become God of Fortune.
Stop! Don't talk like that.
- Yes.
- No.
No.
No, I wish for my parents to always stay here with me.
That is so typical!
See, your parents are always here with you.
- Isn't that right, Dad?
- Yes.
Okay, that's not important. What's important is that there are gifts!
This... this is for you!
That's from me. I'm giving it to you, Hong An!
All right. All right, now.
Thank you. Do you even have a gift for me, Seiko?
- My sponsor?
- Thank you so much!
How about Mr. Mole?
His gift...
This is our gift for you.
Thank you so much.
Everybody, let's enjoy dinner!
- Bye.
- Bye bye.
Goodbye, Mr. Mole.
Take care on your way home.
Mom, where is Mun?
- I don't know. Go look for her.
- Okay.
Mun!
Hey,
what's wrong with you tonight? It's your daughter's birthday! Why did you put on a poker face all night?
Hey, hey, I'm talking to you. Where are you going?
- Have you had enough?
- No.
Not yet, I paid ₫300,000 for the taxi.
And this was the first time in my life I arranged a birthday party for her.
- It's not that expensive—
- I want to know if the both of you have had enough.
As you know, life is full of ups and downs.
At the moment, it's not exactly enough.
I think this is enough.
Take your bags and leave my house, please.
To be honest, I don't want her to know.
She would be sad.
What are you talking about?
Why are you showing me this attitude?
I did this for your daughter!
For her joy, whose else? This was her first birthday party!
The two persons above are not blood relatives: Father and Daughter.
No way!
How could the result be like this?
This is impossible.
Why?
With a woman like you...
I might not be a good mother,
but...
I'm trying to do what's best for her, whatever it may take.
I just want her to have a father!
Aren't you just craving money?
Yes, I'm always in need of money,
but, although I've lied to you now and then,
I wouldn't sell my daughter!
I would never sell my daughter.
To be honest, I really did like her.
For the last time, how much do you want?
This is the last time I'm going to give you money.
I don't need your money.
I want the both of us to take the paternity test again.
I want to get the results myself!
What are you doing?
Now I understand.
You are a doctor.
All of your colleagues work at the hospital.
They'd help you achieve whatever you want.
You could have changed the result! You changed it, didn't you?
You can say whatever you want,
but don't talk about my medical etiquette!
So who else could be her father?
- Who else could be her father?
- I don't know.
To be honest, I don't even want to know.
You are her mother. You should know it.
It's clearly written on this result.
You don't know it at all!
You should know...
who you slept with.
Don't you know?
Or are you just pretending you don't remember?
Let me tell you,
in your eyes, I might be dirty and cheap,
but I'm not a prostitute.
And even if I were prostitute...
I would still know who my child's father would be!
I would definitely know.
I am sorry, though.
I am not her dad.
But this result...
Let's go, Mom.
Dad,
am I really not your daughter?
No.
Dad.
Dad!
- This is for you.
- Thank you, Dad.
Dad!
My daughter, come over to Daddy!
I missed you so much!
Everything will be fine.
He will just stay mad at you for a few days, and then it will be over.
He's just like my dad, who punished me because I didn't listen to him.
Yet, that evening, he brought me ice-cream anyway.
- Are you trying to call him again?
- I miss him so badly, Mom.
- Let me call him.
- I told you so many times,
stop calling him! He's not your father!
You are lying!
Stop being stubborn! He is a bad person. Don't ever call him again!
I don't want to listen to you. You're lying!
He is not your father! Don't you understand?
- You're lying!
- Am I lying?
Stay away from me! I hate you!
Stay away from me!
I hate you!
I want to see my dad.
I miss him!
I hate you!
I miss him a lot! I miss him, Mom.
Darling.
Darling,
- what's wrong? Doesn't it taste good?
- That's not it.
- Why don't you eat?
- I will. You go ahead.
Mun, I have a question for you.
Do you think me and Daddy Son look alike?
See, even you say "yes."
How come Daddy Son said I am not his daughter?
Anyway, forget it. You can't even talk.
You're just like me.
We don't have a dad.
He left you, too.
Why do adults always lie?
Why did he lie to me?
I miss him so much.
Hello... I know. I understand.
I am coming right now. Why are you rushing me?
Mom,
are you going to see my dad?
Why would I be going to see him? I'm going to make some money.
Mom, let me go see him. I miss him.
I repeat, don't ever mention him again.
Mentioning him is bad luck. I didn't gamble, yet I can already see myself lose.
Go to sleep!
Why is your temperature so high?
You will feel better after sleeping, okay? I left some food for you in there, in case you're hungry.
Mom, come back home early, please.
I know. I'll be back soon. Stop nagging. Go to sleep.
"Lucky at cards, unlucky in love" is a true saying.
Every day should be like this.
Hong An, wake up. I have noodles for you,
very tasty noodles.
Get up, Hong An.
Why is your temperature so high? Hong An...
Hong An,
why is your temperature so high, Sweetie?
Hong An, Hong An,
Hong An, Hong An!
Help me!
Help!
Help me, please!
Help my daughter, please!
Hong An!
Based on this result and her symptoms,
she might have blood cancer.
Before we can say for sure, we need to take some more tests.
Did you say blood cancer, Doctor?
She is normal and healthy, Doctor.
Your family was probably too busy to notice she had those symptoms.
Symptoms such as fever, persistent fatigue,
and skin rash.
She's been having them for a while now.
Hey, did you call her son A Tun?
I've tried to call him so many times,
but the one who picked up the phone was never him.
What are you doing?
- From morning until now...
- A Tun?
How could you take money from your mother?
Your mother spent all day begging, for only a few dollars. Now you are going to take them. Are you even human?
- No.
- So what's it to you?
Hey, stop!
- What?
- Take it easy. Why are you fighting with the elders?
You dogs, it's none of your business. You'd better get away from here!
Come here!
Catch him!
Stop running!
Sister Thuy is  his mother.
He hit her until she was like this.
Hey!
Why don't you go see your mother for the last time?
I am tired.
Are you tired? Is it acceptable for you to say that?
When she was still alive,
you forced her to become a beggar so that there was enough money for you to take drugs.
Now that she has passed away,
I ask you to come and see her for the last time.
Did you say you were tired?
Did you know she kept asking to see you every single day?
My mom was in good health until she came here!
Her death, it's your fault.
Are you here to lecture me?
Are you human?
What?
I'm asking you if you are human or just an animal?
What did you say I am?
You're an unfilial and ungrateful child!
Doctor Son!
Doctor Hung is calling you.
Mind your words. Watch out for me next time!
Daddy, this is for you.
- Thank you, Sweetie.
- Don't open it yet.
Whenever you miss me, you can open it.
["You're My Hero" by Your Daughter]
My dad is going to become a super hero.
He will come on a sunny day.
He will kill all the bad people and take back the world,
and protect me.
I used to brag about that to my friends,
but till I met you,
I believed that this superhero was real.
My dad was an "authentic" superhero!
The way you saved Chaien's dad,
the way you help the patients,
and the way you treat me...
I'm truly happy to be your daughter.
Hong An loves you very much.
You're a bad person. Get out of here, please!
Dad, someone is causing disturbance here.
Who is it?
Here... Here, Dad!
- Where?
- Here, Dad!
Hey, Doctor Son!
- Do you know where they went?
- Haven't you heard?
Hong An is sick. She's been in the hospital for the past few days.
Dad...
- Have some rest.
- No, I want to sit with you, Dad.
- Dad!
- All right, okay,
take it easy.
Dad,
I miss you so badly.
I know. It's okay.
I miss you badly.
Be good.
Tell me,
how do you feel?
I don't know.
Before, it recovered by itself.
But not this time.
Dad...
Daddy, promise me you will stay here with me.
Please don't leave me anymore. Please...
Please, Daddy...
I promise.
Daddy...
- Don't cry.
- Daddy!
Don't leave me alone, please.
It hurts so much, Daddy.
- Mom.
- What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
I heard she was sick.
She is not your daughter.
You don't have any responsibility toward her.
I know you're still very mad at me but–
But what?
Did you come here to give her hope, and then leave again like before?
She's sick because she misses you.
What more does it take for you to be satisfied?
Daddy!
I am so sorry.
Her blood cancer has come to stage two.
We need to start using chemotherapy.
I hope your bone marrow matches hers.
M-Mom!
- Mom!
- I'm here. I'm here.
Mom, it hurts so much!
I know. I know. Hold on, okay?
It hurts so much!
I know. I know, Baby.
I never had this much pain in my life!
I know. You can't touch that. It will hurt.
I know. Hong An, don't touch it, or else it will start bleeding.
You have to keep it in to help you recover, okay?
- No, I hate it!
- I do, too.
I want to go home.
I want to go home, too. We will go home when you get better.
It's going to hurt, Baby.
Daddy!
I miss Daddy!
Tell him to come here, Mom!
Unfortunately, your bone marrow doesn't match hers.
I think we need to try to find other sources.
All you can do is look for your relatives.
Hopefully, we can find a match to help her.
Her condition is getting worse by the day.
Hong An...
Can you please...
save my daughter?
Hong An,
Hong An...
An!
Your "Uncle Ba" is here.
I am here for you, all right?
I am here. Don't be afraid.
Be strong, Sweetie.
Get well soon.
I will do anything for you, all right?
Mun...
- What?
- I want...
Do you want me to bring Mun over?
I promise I will.
I promise.
Thank you for agreeing to the bone marrow test.
It's not a big deal. I do love her.
Hopefully, my bone marrow will match hers.
So...
I am so sorry...
about what happened on her birthday.
Your apology makes me feel embarrassed.
I should be the one to say sorry.
I tried to force you to take care of her, making up so many stupid things.
I've caused you trouble.
I messed up...
everything.
But everything I did...
was only for my daughter,
hoping she'd get to have a dad.
That is her biggest wish in life.
But during those years, why didn't you look for her "real" dad?
Who said I didn't?
I've searched for him in every corner.
I don't know his name.
I don't have his address.
How could I find him in a sea of people?
There was no clue.
You don't understand how much I struggled.
I was a girl with a bright future ahead,
but then I got pregnant.
I got kicked out of school.
My dad is extremely strict.
It made him feel so embarrassed
toward his friends, relatives, and neighbors.
He kicked me out.
I tried to have an abortion many times.
[Obstetrics]
Who is Miss Phuong?
Miss Phuong?
I really wanted to do it, but somehow I couldn't.
My heart didn't give me permission.
Now I realize...
my daughter is just like me.
Everybody runs away from us,
dismisses us.
It's a pity.
Should I have...
abandoned her, too?
Darling,
is there something you'd like to tell me?
Why are you acting strange today?
Otherwise, tell me next time.
Today I am tired, too.
Go help Hong An.
She is your daughter.
What do you mean?
I...
How do you know she is my daughter?
It was me.
I changed your paternity result.
Are you crazy? Why did you do that? Why?
Because I didn't want to lose you!
- You are obviously very selfish!
- Yes,
I am selfish. So what? I wanted him to belong to me!
There's nothing wrong with what I did!
Son and I are obviously the perfect couple.
He loves me and always takes care of me.
He would have been mine!
Until the both of you came and messed everything up.
That's all your fault, both yours and your daughter's!
You're out of your mind!
She is just a child.
If she is your daughter, you won't be selected for the study abroad program.
Everything you built up will be gone!
I wanted to wait until you came back.
I would have told you the truth,
but I hadn't expected...
I never would have thought An would be sick!
Daddy!
She is dying.
I am so sorry. I was wrong!
If you are Father and Daughter,
the universe will make it happen for you to be together.
I can't do anything to interfere!
She is my daughter.
Honey, Darling,
I know what I did was wrong. I love her, too.
I didn't mean to hurt her!
Darling, Son, please don't leave me.
Honey...
Son, Son!
Right now, her condition is getting worse.
We need to process the surgery immediately.
I don't think she could live past tomorrow.
Please go ahead.
I will do anything to save my daughter.
Get ready.
We will start tomorrow morning, otherwise I think it will be too late.
All right.
Mom!
Mom, you promised to get me chicken sticky rice.
Why did you buy beans sticky rice?
Son, I'm sorry.
I did go to your favorite shop, but they were closed.
I will buy it for you tomorrow.
No, you eat this. I won't eat it!
- I want to eat chicken sticky rice!
- Son!
Son, Son!
Mom! Mom!
Mom, don't leave me!
- Mom!
- Poor lady.
Somebody, call an ambulance, please.
She's going to be fine.
Be strong, Sweetie.
Get well soon.
I will do anything for you, all right?
Mun...
- What?
- I want...
Do you want me to bring Mun over?
Mom, don't worry.
No matter what, I will save your grandchild.
- I'm begging you. Please, I will give it to you tomorrow.
- Get away from me.
- No, no!
- I promise, tomorrow.
- So many times...
- Especially the dog...
- Bring me the money, then we'll talk.
- Go away.
Hello, are you coming? Why are you not here yet?
All right.
It's always you.
This time I'm going to kill you.
Promise me you will keep her alive. We miss Hong An so much!
I know. Don't worry.
Don't forget, please!
Chaien, Seiko, come home to eat!
Doctor, Doctor!
The patient went into a coma. Let's resuscitate her right away.
Have you tried calling Doctor Son?
If he's not coming, I'm afraid it will be too late.
Call him again, please.
Hey!
I want that someday, you will tell everybody in the hospital that
I am your daughter...
Are you okay? Are you all right?
♫  Daddy wants to tell the world  ♫
♫  Daddy's baby is the lovely  ♫
♫  And awesome one  ♫
♫  Your baby wants to tell the world  ♫
♫  My Daddy is the best person  ♫
♫  Daddy will always want to do everything to make you happy  ♫
♫  I love how your eyes brighten  ♫
♫  Daddy, you are the pride of me  ♫
♫  Daddy's life was absent of laughter  ♫
♫  If my baby is not there in the morning  ♫
Where are you?
♫  Since you came into my world  ♫
♫  I know what happiness is  ♫
♫  Daddy hug me, hold me close to your heart  ♫
♫  Kiss me, my baby. Do you know I love you so much?  ♫
♫  You are my joy  ♫
♫  Daddy, promise to protect me for the rest of my life  ♫
♫  Never leave me in the dark  ♫
♫  No matter how far apart, just need to call out  ♫
♫  Daddy will always be by your side  ♫
Hong An...
♫  Even if you are an adult, you will always be Daddy's baby  ♫
♫  I will forever be Daddy's baby  ♫
♫  You will always be young and innocent in Daddy's eyes  ♫
♫  And Daddy will do anything for you  ♫
My baby Hong An is awake.
Where do you want to go? Where are you going?
Where is Daddy, Mom?
He went for his study abroad program.
He told you to take care of yourself.
When will he get home?
It's an important trip.
When...
He will come back when you are better.
It's fine.
I'll buy you a wig tomorrow.
The wig will be better than my hair. It'll be all right.
Yes.
Hong An!
- Hong An!
- Daddy!
Daddy,
it's me.
Daddy!
Daddy, Daddy!
Daddy! Daddy!
Daddy!
Dad! Daddy, Daddy!
What is going on?
Daddy...
Nurse, I saw my dad die!
No way! I'll take you to see your daddy when you are better.
I'm doing great right now.
Please take me to see my dad.
Please...
Daddy!
What happened to you, Dad?
- Daddy!
- Hong An, Hong An...
Hong An, Hong An, Hong An, let him rest!
Don't shake him like that. Let him sleep.
What happened to him, Mom?
- What happened to him, Mom?
- Be good.
Wake up, Daddy!
Daddy, stop joking, please.
I don't understand you now.
Daddy,
wake up, please!
Mom, wake him up!
I promise I will be a good girl.
Don't cry.
Daddy,
do you remember what you promised me?
You promised to take me out to eat,
to tell me stories,
to take me back to the countryside,
and to tell everyone in the hospital one day that
I am your daughter.
Don't lie to me, Daddy!
Wake up, please. Don't lie to me!
Hong An, I'm asking you, Baby.
Please, you are not allowed to lie!
- Daddy.
- I'm asking you, Baby, don't be like this.
- Daddy!
- Please, Baby...
Listen to me, Hong An.
Daddy!
- Hong An...
- Wake up, please!
Don't be like this, Daddy!
- Don't lie to me!
- Listen to me, Hong An.
Hong An, Hong An...
Daddy! Daddy!
You're not lying, right?
Right, Daddy?
You're a smart girl.
Even if I want to, I don't dare to.
I knew that you were not lying.
Promise me not to  leave me ever again.
Sister,
I am sorry.
Because of me, she almost...
It's okay. Forget it. It's over now.
If God wants us to circle a few times, we just do it.
We cannot change it.
- Are you still angry with me?
- Of course I am.
But I'm more angry with myself.
I was too careless to know my daughter was sick.
I have a part in this happening.
I am glad that you forgive me.
Have you visited Son lately?
Why?
After all this, I feel like I don't deserve to be with Son.
He should be with someone better than me.
You mean...
I think you are.
And Hong An needs a family, too.
Oh my God, it was just a one night stand.
You? How many nights...
Maybe not...
No, what I mean is that you had more time with Son than I did.
You know him better than I do.
I feel you fit him. He will...
Gosh, I have no chance!
Me neither...
No, open your door, and he will "jump" into you.
I did, but he doesn't want to come in.
I "expanded" my door. He won't even crawl in.
Oh, Lord, you two want to destroy the door!
From now on, I only have one person in my heart.
It is...
Baby Hong An!
- Let's go play. Let's go.
- No, wait, Dad.
You have to do what you promised.
What?
Remember? That promise...
- Right now?
- Yes, please.
Please...
Now?
Don't be shy.
You can do it!
I am Tung Son.
- Hong An is my daughter.
- Hey, of course, I knew that one.
She wants me to say it out loud.
- Speak louder.
- I can't.
- Why?
- My wound stitches would break.
Don't worry. This doctor will sew them back up for you.
I am Doctor Son!
Hong An is my daughter!
Thanks to our channel manager kamkaj!
Chief Segmenter: valneijr
Chief Editor: mirjam_465
General Editor: damiechan
Translation Editor: trangxlnguyen_197
Thanks to our other language moderators!
Today I'm taking you to school. Are you happy?
- Yes, I am.
- That's good.
The air is so fresh, Dad.
- So fresh!
- Yes, fresh!
Timing and Subtitles by 🌬 My Accidentall Besties 🦄  @viki.com
Look at how pitiful he is.
Who said it was bad luck for him to hit us with his car?
Now he drives me to school.
Thinking back, thanks to that accident,
I have Dad and he drives me to school.
Do you think my dad is handsome?
After seeing me in school, I just know you'd all love to hit his car.
Dad, is something wrong?
What the heck!
- What is going on?
- I don't know.
The first day of going to school is not good at all.
We have run out of gasoline.
Why didn't you refill?
I thought your Mom had done it for me.
She has never had that habit.
But where is your car?
I gave it to her to refill the gasoline.
What? Really?
You are doomed.
You got tricked.
Hey...
She's changed and she isn't like before.
Don't judge her that way, do you hear?
- If you don't believe it, call her!
- Don't you believe me? I'll prove it to you.
Let me prove it to you. I'll call her.
Okay, put her on speaker.
Your mom is calling right now.
- Does An's mom...
- Hello?
Sorry, this phone is...
She pawned this phone.
- Has this phone been pawned?
- Yes,
- and the white car, too.
- What?
- My car has been pawned!
- Wow, she's a "badass" this time. She even pawned the car!
Dad, Dad!
- What are you doing?
- I'm calling the police to arrest your mom.
- Police station speaking.
- Sir, my car got stolen.
See, my mom never changes.
Only my dad always falls for her trap.
Que Phuong!
[The End]