Like most black mothers,
mine was consumed
by the presentation of her child.
I was a reflection of her as a mother.
It was an ever-present source of anxiety
to prove that I was just as well-groomed
as any white child.
They would play, hair uncombed, no shoes,
traces of everything they'd eaten
smeared on their faces,
completely happy and oblivious
to any possible defects
to their appearance.
I, on the other hand, had to be fixed.
wash, conditioner, and hot comb,
until my hair was straight enough
to run her fingers through it
without one snap, crackle, or pop.
Ow!
That's your outside voice, Violet.
- But you're burning my head off.
- No one likes a complainer.
- Only then was I perfect.
- Hey, baby girl.
You deserve the world,
and one day, you're gonna find a man
who'll give it to you.
Like my daddy.
No, Vi. There's not a man in the world
who can give your mommy what she wants.
But for an 11-year-old,
perfection was no fun.
Violet, get away from that pool.
You scared of the water?
I bet I could hold my breath longer.
Vi, I'm warning you.
Violet! Violet Jones!
Violet Jones!
What the hell happened to your hair?
You look like a Chia Pet.
To my mom,
appearance was everything.
- We always had to be perfectly groomed.
- Violet! Violet Jones!
Because no fairy tale ever ended
with the words...
"Nappily Ever After."
What are you doing here?
It's 5:00 a.m.
How could I sleep on such a special day?
It's just... Where is it, where is it?
- Shh, Mom! Shh!
- Sorry, sorry, sorry.
It seems like we've been
preparing for this moment forever.
I told you one day your prince would come.
You just missed
a couple of carriages, that's all.
Dad is coming tonight.
- Why?
- It's my birthday party, Mom.
He's supposed to be there.
He lost that privilege
when he lost his mind.
He didn't lose his mind.
He quit selling insurance
to become a male model.
Is that not insane?
And I mean,
what is he gonna model anyway? Depends?
If he had not left,
I would have kicked him out.
Will you please,
please be civil? For me?
- I'll try.
- Thank you.
So, does Clint still think
the party's a surprise?
He's been calling my office,
asking April for help...
...so I've been able to plan everything.
All right.
What do you think?
Oh...
Mm...
Morning, baby.
Happy birthday, beautiful.
Mm.
Hmm.
I've got a little gift for you.
Oh, not that little.
Oh!
- I wanna get on top.
- Yeah?
I wanna get on top.
I wanna get on top. Yeah.
Oh, one of the big orthopedic guys,
he's gonna take me to lunch.
- He's opening up a new sports clinic.
- Oh?
And I think he might ask me to join him
after my residency.
That's excellent, Clint.
Right? And then, of course,
I am going to be taking
my beautiful birthday girl
out for a very special evening.
Sounds perfect.
In two weeks, you are going to be looking
at the hottest doctor in town.
- Mm-hmm.
- Mm, it is time to make moves.
Yes, it is.
Mm.
Violet Jones' office.
- Morning, April.
- Good morning, Violet.
- Happy birthday.
- Thank you.
Doctor Conroy called to ask
what your favorite flowers are.
I told him violets, and gave him
the number to A Blooming Business.
- Good girl. What's the forecast?
- Mainly sunny.
Highs in the mid-70s,
seven percent relative humidity,
and a five percent chance
of precipitation.
Perfect. Tell the girls,
lunch on the patio is on.
Okay.
We start with our woman.
She's a pretty girl.
She doesn't love what she sees.
We cut to her date,
waiting in the next room.
He has front row tickets to a show,
and according to his Rolex, they're late.
But our woman has found the answer:
Long Live Red by Essential.
She stands in the doorway,
looking beautiful. She is perfect.
Great lips, great night.
Great pitch.
Well done, well done.
So, wait. If I'm not 90 pounds
with injected lips,
- I don't get a hot guy to ask me out?
- Not going on a lot of dates, huh?
Well, I loved it, Violet. I loved it.
But tomorrow, add some more details
about your projected use of ad space.
- Okay?
- Got it.
All right. Good job.
Oh, are we calling it? I love it.
No, but seriously, Vi,
they got you in a little box.
You got it dressed up so pretty,
you think it's a condo.
Does that look like a rain cloud?
Look, you should be doing
some of them pimp spots, like Budweiser.
You know, Home Depot.
- Viagra.
- You would say that.
When a black couple walks into your office
to buy a house,
who does your boss trot out to greet them?
Oh!
See, I... I don't... I don't trot.
It's a brisk strut.
Listen, I am very good at selling
to the female market,
and if it ain't broke...
- Are you sure that's not a rain cloud?
- The weather report said no rain.
I checked twice.
Anyway, after tonight...
my career is gonna take a back seat...
because the doctor is about to be in.
- Gotta get ready.
- I know. I gotta find something to wear.
Oh, look at them! So cute!
- I can't wait.
- I can.
Hey, don't spray me!
Mom? Call me back.
I... I can't get into my normal salon.
I need help.
Call me as soon as you get this.
He is not proposing to you
because of your hair.
Violet, he loves you for who you are.
Does your husband know
about your Jewfro?
Because I have plenty of pictures
of the two of us in college.
Mom, I just called you at home.
- Call me back. Where are you?
- All right, all right, look.
I'm going to call my hairstylist
and see if she can fit you in.
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Okay?
Uh, offer money.
- All right, how much?
- Fifty. One hundred.
Two hundred dollars
to whoever has the next appointment.
- Okay. Just breathe.
- Yeah.
Okay.
Hey, Lalisa, girl!
What was I thinking?
You talked me into this.
This is your fault.
My fault?
You want to blame me
for making you look damn good,
I'll take it. But this...
This is all God's work.
But brothers love long hair.
What brothers want...
is a woman who's real.
You know, it's rude to stare.
Pay me five dollars, and I'll stop.
Excuse me?
You just paid Jackie $200
not to get her hair done.
Sorry, no deal.
You know, you can sponsor, like,
six kids from Uganda
with that money you're spending for hair.
I'm sorry, where is your mother?
Zoe, are you bothering my clients again?
Make yourself useful.
Go get Crystal some conditioner, okay?
Girl, she does whatever flies
into her head.
My mama would have popped me good
for running my mouth
- and having hair looking that crazy.
- Mm-hmm.
Come on, let's get you washed up.
You okay?
I'm fine.
Uh, excuse me, I need to be rinsed.
You have seven more minutes to condition.
Now, please!
Oh, God, thank you.
Lalisa?
- What?
- Uh-uh!
Oh, my goodness.
Oh, shit.
What?
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
Okay, all right. Vi, calm down.
All right, it's really not that bad,
you know. We could comb it over.
- What happened?
- I... I just washed and conditioned her.
- You used relaxer.
- What?
I used what Zoe handed me.
You!
You did this!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! Mistakes happen.
- This was no mistake!
- Where the hell is her mother?
- Her mother's not around.
She's my daughter,
I take responsibility.
That's your daughter?
With that mop on her head?
I am sorry this happened,
but don't talk
about my daughter like that.
But? No, no, no, no, no.
There is no "but."
You can think whatever you want
about me right now,
but in a few hours,
my man will be proposing to me,
so I suggest you go
to one of those thousand hair supplies
on this block
and buy me the best hair money can buy,
and figure out a way
to attach it to my head!
Surprise!
I am surprised
you're still doing her hair.
- Oh!
- She looks gorgeous.
Oh, that's just one
of our little things we do.
You're lucky, Vi.
Your grandmother hated doing
your mom's hair.
She used to just send her outside
with this... afro.
The boys on the block
used to call her Willie Mays.
Really?
Mom!
Well, now they'll be calling me
the mother-in-law of a doctor.
Well, happy birthday, Vi.
Thanks, Dad. Wait, you're not leaving.
Clint's going to, um...
uh, make a toast,
and I really want you here.
Well, I have an early call tomorrow.
a big photo shoot.
Oh, excellent!
This is all still a little weird for me.
Hey, enjoy your party.
- Thanks, Dad.
- Love you.
I love you.
Good night, Richard.
You okay?
Never better.
Good.
Ladies and gentlemen,
if I could just have your attention
for one minute, please.
So, I've been asking myself,
what do you get the perfect woman?
You are as beautiful
waking up in the morning
- as you are at night.
- No, I'm not.
It's unnatural how perfect.
So, I kept coming back
to that sense of... family.
Oh!
Oh, Clint.
Oh, this is the happiest moment
of my life.
Oh!
Oh, my.
What's this?
This might help.
- Oh!
Mm-hmm.
Meet Lola.
That's cool.
- Our first pet together.
- Oh.
And one that won't make a mess.
A dog?
He got me a dog.
What's wrong with me?
Oh, Vi.
There's nothing wrong with you.
Clint didn't propose tonight, but he will.
Soon.
Now freshen up, pick up that mutt,
and go back out there
with a smile on your face.
You don't like the dog.
What's not to like?
Did something happen at the party?
No, absolutely nothing happened
at the party.
What's that supposed to mean?
I was expecting a ring, Clint.
A ring?
Like an engagement ring?
Yes!
Why would you... would you think that?
Why? We've been together two years.
You said tonight I'm perfect.
Yeah, I did.
But that doesn't mean
we're ready to get married.
Yes, it does.
I... I want a husband,
not a boyfriend.
And a child, not a Chihuahua.
I'm not even a dog person.
Exactly.
What is that supposed to mean?
You know, I had to ask your assistant
what your favorite flowers were.
Your favorite wine. Your favorite music.
So?
So? You're talking about getting married.
I don't even know you.
Of course you do!
No. I know you're beautiful.
I know you're smart,
and you dress right, you act right,
you always say the perfect thing,
but you never let your hair down.
We go to a party, you don't dance.
You don't drink.
We've never just got buck wild
in the shower,
or just acted silly together.
You never take a chance, Vi,
because you've always gotta be perfect.
But 24/7 perfection is...
It's like being on a two-year first date.
Oh, my God.
You're never gonna marry me,
are you, Clint?
Babe, come on, that's...
That's not what I said.
I think you need to leave.
Are you being serious right now?
I think we need to stop wasting
each other's time.
So, because I won't marry you
at this moment,
you're saying it's over?
The first date has to end sometime.
Come on, go.
Go to the bathroom!
Don't you have to go?
Lola, I have to go to work.
Lola, go... to the bathroom!
Yay!
Hey.
Ugh.
Good morning, Violet.
Okay, so, um...
- Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Is, uh, everything ready
in the conference room?
Uh, Violet?
Oh, God.
And we... Then we go to our woman,
and she has on lipstick.
Uh, she has to put the lipstick on first,
of course.
She puts on Long Live Red.
Um...
Yeah, Long Live Red,
and, um, then she comes out...
Shit!
She comes out.
You know already.
She's beautiful, and, um...
...he's happy about it.
So... so what we're saying is
all women are pretty,
but you won't be perfect
until you wear Long Live Red?
Yes.
No.
Did I say perfect?
'Cause that wouldn't be nice,
or even fair, to call her perfect.
I mean, she's beautiful,
but she's much more than that.
Much, much more than that.
Fine. Then she's in Phi Beta Kappa
as well.
- Right?
- No, no, no, no, Bill.
I don't...
I don't think you're really seeing her.
She is, um, way, way, way, way more
than that.
Still, we all want to fuck her,
and that's really the point of the ad.
Right, Violet?
Yeah, mm-hmm.
Tyson loves your campaign.
He... just doesn't want you
on the account.
Alicia's gonna take over.
I want you to take a few days, okay?
Get your head straight.
I don't think that'll go very well
with the turquoise dress.
Oh, it's you. I guess you're right.
- Ow!
- Trust me, handcuffs would hurt worse.
Now, take the dress out of your backpack
and put it on the counter.
All the clothes have security tags.
You would have been caught at the door.
No, you wait for somebody else
to set off the alarm first,
then you walk through.
Oh, so clearly you've done this before.
I heard. Anyway, it was
a birthday present from my mom.
For. For your mom.
And that doesn't make it right. Come on.
Now, say thank you
to the nice security guard.
- Uh, wait a minute.
- Say it!
No!
Ma'am, could you stop, please?
So lucky I don't believe
in putting my hands on you,
or you'd be laid out on this sidewalk.
- I'm sorry!
- Sorry doesn't cut it, Zoe!
How did you even get here?
- The bus.
- The bus?
What gets you more excited, huh?
Being arrested or being kidnapped?
- Answer me when I'm talking to you!
- Look, I know what she did was wrong,
but maybe it was a cry for help.
- What the hell is she crying about?
- I don't know.
All right, then, stay out of it.
Excuse me, I was put in it
the moment I was strip-searched
by that security guard.
I've earned the right to tell you,
you don't know what's going on with her.
And in what world would I take advice
about my daughter from you?
Let's go. Move it.
Please! We are in public.
Stop it!
Quit tickling me!
Wow.
Wow?
Or "wow!"?
- Just...
- Wow.
Yeah.
I think it's hot.
I mean, I don't really know if it's you.
You know, maybe you just
want to keep it simple?
- Yeah, just be yourself.
- Yeah.
And what would that be?
The Anal-Compulsive Miss Perfect cut,
or the...
The Not Fun, Never Spontaneous Weave?
I mean, I liked the weave.
It was cute.
Violet, I think you're being
too hard on yourself.
This is me.
This is called "fuck you" hair.
Says so right on the box.
I just wasted two years of my life
on that asshole...
...so we are gonna go out,
and I am gonna get myself right.
- It's not really a "fuck you" outfit.
- No.
I mean, if you're really gonna do this,
the carpet's gonna
have to match the drapes.
Mm.
I want to do this, I just don't know how.
- Just go with how you feel.
- Yeah.
I feel like I should be on a pole,
and Floyd Mayweather's making it rain.
Okay, well, go with...
- Oh, shit.
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- Oh, my God.
- I think even God's laughing.
- Up. Come on. There you go.
- There you go.
All right.
If you leave now,
I know you're just gonna feel stupid
the rest of the night,
but if you stay here, I promise you,
I'll make you laugh a little bit.
Take as much time with her as you need.
- Vi, we gonna hit the dance floor, girl.
- You're leaving me?
Yeah, girl, you better have some fun! Oh!
- You're good?
- Yes.
- You're funny!
- You had a lot to drink.
- I did!
- I'm so funny?
Oh!
Wow!
Ooh, impressive!
You're impressive.
Ooh!
Mm!
Just slap me if that was too fast.
See, I was right about you.
Your hair told me everything
that I needed to know.
You're not afraid of anything.
No, I'm not.
You love to take a chance.
- Yes, I do.
- Yeah.
Oh, shit.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- No.
No, I liked it.
- You liked it?
- Yeah.
You are a wild one, aren't you?
- Oh, shit.
- Shock me, baby. Shock me.
- Shock you? Okay.
- Shock me.
- Yeah.
Mm!
No, no. Hold up. Safety cap there.
- Yeah, you gotta open it. Mm-hmm.
- There you go.
Okay. Yeah, okay.
Oh, yeah, that's... that's hot.
- Oh!
- Ooh!
Ow!
- Ow!
- Oh, no, it's... it's... erotic. It's fine.
- You're bleeding. You're bleeding!
- Oh, no, just...
Let me just sit up here for a second.
Ah, no, it's fine. It's fine.
This is terrible.
Uh, no, no, it's, uh... No, it's, uh...
What was I saying?
I gotta... I gotta go.
You don't have to run off!
I'm barely even bleeding now.
So, maybe he was just using me
to get through his residency. I mean,
it's obvious he was gonna
have me waiting on him forever.
I had to move on with my life.
That's it?
I mean, he didn't cheat on you?
He didn't hit you nor nothin' like that?
No.
But he hurt my feelings.
I mean, he... he broke my heart.
He hurt your feelings.
- Now you want to put a gun to his head?
- Yeah.
"Marry me or else."
Now, you know, men and women,
they're kind of like, uh, puzzle pieces.
No two pieces alike,
come in all different sizes,
different shapes, in this puzzle, and...
But, when a piece does fit, well,
when one piece goes into the other,
the search is over.
And you can even take 'em apart,
but they still gonna fit.
Mm-hmm. You can believe that.
A fit is a fit is a fit.
Can you take me
to Emory University Hospital?
For what?
I have to put the puzzle back together.
Ow, shit!
Violet, what... What are you doing here?
Nothing. Forget you ever saw me.
Hey, no, wait. Hey, come on.
What's... What's going on?
What did you do to your hair?
It's called "fuck you" hair. You like it?
- Wow.
- Your nurse needs you.
Kandi's a doctor. I don't know
what you're thinking, but she's...
You slept with her, Clint!
Glad to see
I meant so much to you.
You're the one who asked me to leave, Vi.
And you did, without even hesitating.
Doctor, my ass.
Hmm.
Ooh...
Ow!
Coming!
Oh, hey, baby.
You know, I found something
- that I think is...
- Mom.
- What?
What?
Mommy.
Mom?
Mom!
- Ah!
- Mom!
- Oh!
- Oh, my God.
How is she?
She's fine, same as always.
Course, she's convinced you're a lesbian,
by the way, so be prepared.
Thanks for coming.
Vi, you really shouldn't be calling me
for things like this anymore.
Come on, Dad, do you even remember
what you were angry at her about?
Yes.
Well, what if I need you?
Look at me.
It just shows off more
of your pretty face.
I've worked so hard
to be everything he wanted.
And it still wasn't enough.
I'm so tired.
Of course you're tired, baby girl.
Look, you think...
that this is just something
you did on a whim?
I think you've been building up to it.
Now, I understand what you're going
through probably better than anyone.
And you know what?
You gonna be okay.
We'll get this cleaned up.
You've just gotta soldier on.
And, look, you've got the head for it.
Sorry, but I...
I really need to get in there.
Can you just use...
Can you just use the men's room, please?
I'd really prefer not to.
Look, there are six women to every man
waiting to use a public restroom,
so there's an excellent chance
that it will be empty.
Just leave me the hell alone.
Sorry! Sorry, no, this isn't your fault.
No. I apologize. I...
I was incredibly rude.
I'm sorry.
That's a pretty scarf.
Thanks.
I am just so emotional lately.
Well, if it means anything, I...
I thought I was gonna be engaged...
last week.
And I'm supposed to be at work today,
and all I want to do is curl up
under the covers.
So do it.
I can't.
Hey,
you should really come to my group.
Oh, no, I'm not one to tell
my personal business to strangers.
Well, I'm a stranger,
and you're talking to me.
No, what can it hurt, right?
There you go.
- Thanks.
- Yeah.
He said that
he couldn't handle us anymore.
Handle it.
He's in the middle of dumping me,
and at the same time,
he's scared about how I'm gonna react.
Am I gonna lose it,
find a bridge, jump off?
I say, "Baby, please, I've lost my job,
I've lost my hair,
I've lost my $1,200 implants
in my left breast.
If I can get over cancer,
then I can get over your simple ass."
You don't have to do that.
Sneak out.
I'm Erika.
You're new,
but you have a right to speak up.
No, I... I really don't.
- Violet, it's okay.
- No, it's... it's... it's not.
I... um...
My boyfriend didn't give me a ring,
and so, uh... I shaved my hair off.
You guys are incredible, to be dealing
with everything you're dealing with
and still to have the courage
to... to not feel sorry for yourselves.
I am so sorry for the misunderstanding.
The first thing I asked my doctor when
he told me I was gonna have to have chemo
was, "Am I gonna lose my hair?"
- Right?
- Mm-hmm.
So, let's see.
Shit!
You walk around like that,
of course you're gonna get ignored.
You gotta own it, girl.
Own it.
All right.
- Wow!
- You go, girl.
In my six years here,
I've got every account I've gone after.
And, despite what happened,
that includes Essential.
I deserve a shot.
Yeah, Violet, you're my go-to girl
for beauty accounts.
I mean, that's your thing.
And you were g... You are great at it.
Well, let me prove I can be great
at something else.
I want Amber Lite.
Well, no offense, dear, but this is...
That's the granddaddy.
You know,
when I said to get your head right,
this isn't really what I had in mind.
Are you sure that
you don't need more time?
Bill, I am fine.
I just don't want anything that
has to do with beauty right now.
Please.
Fine.
Okay. I will give you this shot.
But if I am not blown away
by what you come up with,
then we go back to the old Violet.
All the way back.
- Deal?
- Deal.
All right.
So soft!
Oh, my gosh.
Vi, I thought Common made bald sexy,
but he ain't got nothin' on you.
- You like it?
- Yes, you look so good!
- You look bomb.
- Really?
- Beautiful.
- Mm-hmm.
So, what's it like?
Waking up in the morning
and not having to worry about your hair.
Yes.
I am so used to looking
at myself in the mirror all the time,
and now I never do.
It's only when I catch somebody's reaction
that it all comes back.
But we are not here to talk about hair.
Y'all are here to help me
come up with a beer commercial.
Okay.
Now, look around.
What do you see?
Uh... Guys drinking.
Go! Go!
- Yay!
- Yeah.
Yeah, guys screaming at the TV.
Latent homosexuality.
You know, I hate beer commercials,
to be honest.
I mean, they're so sexist.
Do something different, Vi.
Yes. Hear, hear.
Right?
Hmm...
Hello, Zoe.
Is that my fault too?
'Cause it doesn't look bad. I mean...
you don't have any dents or nothin'.
No.
I brought you a birthday present.
My birthday isn't for two weeks.
Okay. Never mind. I'll just return it.
I actually have the receipt.
Wait.
Why would you get this for me?
'Cause I felt like it.
Try it on.
Zoe, you look beautiful.
Yeah, right,
except for my body and my hair.
Why would you say that?
You did.
Zoe, don't ever let someone's negative
opinion of you become your reality.
You are a beautiful girl.
You just need a few tips.
My dad won't let me perm my hair.
He says the chemicals
go right to your brain.
You don't need to do that.
Now, just walk across the porch.
Okay, stop.
See how your right foot is angled out?
Try to walk with your feet straighter.
Stand up straighter.
Hold your head up.
Look at that, you just grew two inches!
Wow.
Could I ask you for something?
Mm-hmm.
Could this be from my mom,
for my birthday?
"From"?
Sometimes she forgets,
and my dad just gets all sad for me.
Sure.
I always wanted braids
when I was younger.
But my mom never let me.
Maybe I could draw some on your head.
Ha.
What's going on?
And, again, I am...
- ...sorry for just stopping by.
- No, no, no.
It's... quite all right. I'm glad you did.
I haven't heard Zoe laugh
like that in a long time.
She's a funny kid.
- Yeah.
- Sweet, too.
Thanks.
I owe you an apology.
I kind of went at you the last time,
and you were just trying to help,
I don't want you to think
I'm an asshole.
I wasn't exactly in top form
the first time we met, either.
So you do think I'm an asshole.
So stay, for dinner.
I'm making my famous pineapple chili.
Maybe that will change your opinion.
Thanks, but, um,
I have a lot of work to do.
Oh, come on,
you can't work on an empty stomach.
And I'm sure Zoe would love it.
You know, but, honestly, real talk...
Didn't the hum of the clippers...
sound like Harriet Tubman calling you
to freedom?
Yeah, but she lost her voice
when I woke up.
So, what are...
What are all these plants for?
They're my dad's.
Really?
Yeah. I use 'em
to make shampoos and stuff.
Oh?
You see, most women, they tell you that
they get their hair relaxed
because it's more manageable.
But anybody's hair is manageable
if you got the right products.
Now, my products,
they take away those excuses.
Excuses?
Yeah. I mean, look.
What, we make up 12%
of the population, right?
But yet,
we buy 70% of all wigs and weaves.
What does that say?
Mm... We hate our hair?
You hate your hair.
Ever since your mamas
drug you into the shop,
kicking and screaming, to get a perm.
You know, I swear,
I feel like a vet putting down an animal.
You know, you hate to do it,
but it's part of the job.
I'm just trying to change the world
one head at a time.
Starting with that one.
You know,
I tell her every day she's beautiful.
You know, but I'm battling TV,
commercials, magazines,
telling her that long, straight hair
is what makes you beautiful.
Well, I make some of those commercials,
and you can't just put the blame on us.
I mean, we're just reflecting society.
Hell, anybody can reflect society.
How about reflecting
what society should be?
I have to please my clients,
just like you.
I didn't make the social rules,
I just live by 'em.
Till now.
Are you guys arguing again?
Again?
Again.
Yes, actually.
Oh...
Do we really have to listen to this?
I mean, I got my own problems.
Why do I need to hear...?
Hey, quiet down, young 'un.
Okay? When you're feeling low,
songs like this send you to church.
- Amen.
So, what do you got on your playlist?
My playlist?
Yeah.
Beyoncé.
Uh, "1+1."
- Mm. Facts.
- Uh...
- Fugees.
- Yeah, which one?
- "Killing Me Softly."
- Must.
Uh, "Black Mermaid," Esthero.
I don't know that one.
Let me hear it.
Let me find it.
No, just sing it.
What? No.
Yeah, come on, sing it.
I don't even know the lyrics.
- Uh, yes, you do.
- Yes, you do.
You wanna talk about sad? That's my voice.
Really sad.
Okay, you don't have to...
You don't have to sing.
Just... just say the words.
You know what? We won't even watch you.
We won't even watch.
Uh, what?
- Hello?
- Okay, okay, okay, okay.
I'm a black mermaid,
nothing rarer you will find.
I am here for you to love me.
I've been here for all of time.
Mm.
Damn, that's a sad-ass song.
And you really can't sing.
What?
I see you doin' the math.
What math?
Okay, let's see.
He's got a bunch of plants,
plus he makes his own shampoos.
Plus he's a hairdresser, but...
he's got a daughter.
And I see him flirting
with all the women in the shop.
So, what does it add up to?
So, what's the answer?
Let me take you out this weekend.
Someplace special.
Oh, my God. Violet.
Oh!
Have you seen this?
- What?
- Oh, my God...
This.
Oh... my... God.
I mean, it's not enough that he leaves me,
he's got to embarrass me too?
How?
He... looks nice.
He looks like a geriatric porn star.
I mean, people are gonna think that I've
been subjected to that all these years?
I mean, what are they gonna say?
That you're a very lucky woman.
Watch your mouth, Violet.
This craziness has just got to stop.
Maybe it's just a... a midlife thing.
It's been going on for three months.
Where are you going?
To dinner.
Are you and Clint back?
No.
Oh. I guess you made sure of that.
Look, I have to meet at 6:00,
and it's 5:30, so...
You're meeting this man?
Violet, it is a man, right?
- Mom.
- Well, doesn't he have a car?
I'm sure he has a car.
I just want to keep it casual.
And anyway, it's more about his daughter
needing a female role model.
He has a daughter?
I have to finish getting ready.
No.
Oh, my God.
I am so overdressed.
No, no, no, no, don't worry about it.
You look great.
Thanks for coming.
I'll be right back.
What? Where you goin'?
Violet, you... you look great.
I thought it was a plain T-shirt.
There's no such thing
as a plain T-shirt anymore.
Well, don't get any ideas.
Oh, when you take a girl out,
you really take her out.
Thought it'd be nice to do something easy,
take the pressure off.
What can I get you guys?
Um...
I'll have the garden salad, please.
I'll have a Mo' Better Burger with cheese,
uh, some French fries,
and a chocolate banana shake.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
Wait. I'm sorry.
Can I get what he's getting?
Yeah, sure. $27.50.
- Keep the change.
- Thanks.
You know, good call.
I don't like to share my food.
Mm-hmm.
So, weren't you about to get hitched?
Wow, what a way to keep the pressure off.
You can't get to know a person
unless you ask questions.
He didn't want to marry me.
Why? What's wrong with you?
Apparently nothing.
He said I was too perfect.
Ah. Clearly, he hasn't seen you lose it
in the beauty parlor.
You know the thing he said
that hurt the most?
What's that?
That being with me was like
being on a two-year first date.
Maybe you just weren't,
you know, comfortable with the dude.
So, where's Zoe's mom?
Good redirect.
Zoe's mom, how can I put this? Um...
She thought being a mom
was gonna be like a Huggies commercial.
And when it didn't turn out that way,
she broke out.
Does Zoe ever see her?
She gets birthday cards, a present,
when her mom remembers.
You're doing a great job with her.
Except for the hair terrorist act.
And the shoplifting.
We laugh, but that was a real eye-opener.
I like to think that I'm enough,
you know, as a dad...
But Zoe, she...
She really misses having a mom.
Well, she has a good heart.
She just spends a lot of energy
trying to hide it.
Sounds kind of familiar.
Just saying.
This is where I like to come.
This is so beautiful.
Isn't it?
Look at that.
Wow.
Hey, I got something for you.
For the woman who wears it short and sexy.
It's my passion flower scalp rub.
- Aw.
- Here.
Try it and tell me your honest opinion.
Come here.
Come.
Ah.
Oh, that smells so good.
It's au naturel.
In fact, you could eat the stuff.
Show me.
Mm.
Mmm...
- Girl, you better hold on.
- I do?
- No, no, no.
- What?
- There.
- Oh, look! Look!
I won again!
Okay, a little bit.
If you overwater them, they die.
Really?
Don't kill our plants.
I'm proud of you, girl.
But you should have got some by now.
I mean, I can't believe y'all
are still just hanging out.
It's not like that.
- We're taking it slow.
- Mm-hmm.
I'm actually bringing him
to my mother's Fourth of July party
tomorrow.
Ooh!
Not at all the same.
And your mama needs to stop calling that
a Fourth of July barbecue,
because I have not once
seen a wing or a rib.
Okay, are we really talking about
a straight male hairdresser?
I know. Crazy, right?
- But he makes me... He makes me feel good.
- Oh!
It'll actually be a welcome distraction
because this will be the first time
in 35 years that my dad won't be there.
Mm! I saw the ad.
A girl at my job had it
hanging up at her desk.
Both pages.
- So, is it really this big?
- Please stop!
Yes, like Daddy.
- Stop! Please stop! Please stop!
- Ooh, yes, Daddy. Give it to me, Daddy.
This is how y'all do it
on the other side of the train track?
And you're worried
I ain't gon' pass the mama test.
Well, you do keep saying "ain't."
Oh, it's like that now, is it?
I'm good.
I'm good. Hit that bell.
Ooh, it is about time.
The guests are eating the decorative nuts
on my Independence Day collage.
Sorry. Mom, this is Will.
How do you do, Mrs. Jones?
You didn't tell me
you were bringing a guest.
Will brought these for you.
It's from my garden.
- Your garden.
- Yes, ma'am.
How unusual.
- Hi, Violet!
- Hey.
Oh, Gerard!
I want you to meet my... my daughter,
Violet.
Oh. Hi.
I'm sorry. I was just... I was looking
at, you know, your old photos.
Gerard is a lawyer.
I'm actually working
in Senate these days,
but law will always be my true love.
Hey, how you doin', man? Will Wright.
How you doing? Oh!
That's quite a handshake you got there.
You must work with your hands.
Violet, would... would you go
and fix Gerard a drink, please?
What, his hand's broke?
- That's very funny.
- Mm-hmm.
Are you a comedian?
Well, what is it that you do do?
- I own...
- Will owns his own business.
My own business.
Oh, really?
And how did the two of you meet?
- We met...
- We met professionally.
Well, owning your own business,
that does beat working for the Man.
Ain't that the truth?
Isn't it, though?
And isn't it wonderful to be successful?
Yeah, that's right.
So, anytime any of you need a cut,
come on into my shop.
I just might take you up on that.
Think I could do one of those frohawks?
- Mm-mm.
- You own a hair shop?
Mom, it's a great salon.
No, no, no. Shop is fine.
And, yes, I do, Miss Jones,
just like my mama before me.
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I gotta go pick up my daughter.
So this is the date with no car.
Wow.
Will.
I was serious about the frohawk.
Will!
Will, please wait a minute!
I embarrass you now?
- No!
- So what was that?
You know, you're a cool sister,
you really are, but...
I don't know. I thought we had something.
So do I!
But you seem to be mixed up
about who I am and who you are,
and a bunch of other important things.
And seeing as how I have a daughter,
I'm trying real hard not to fuck up.
I'm not in a position to be taking chances
while you figure it all out.
Just get yourself sorted.
Have a happy Fourth.
Think, Violet, think.
Something different.
Hey, Violet,
they're moving to the conference room.
Okay.
It's really great.
Thanks.
"Girls' Night Out."
We're at Philips Arena.
Hawks are playing the Cavs,
and we push into four crazy loud,
annoying guys in Cavs jerseys.
They're surrounded by rows of women
in Hawks gear.
Cavs are winning,
and our four guys are standing up,
cheering and annoying the hell out of
a female fan sitting in front of 'em.
Then, an Amber Lite vendor approaches,
and the annoyed girl calls him over,
orders four Amber Lites,
and hands 'em to the guys behind her.
They're shocked.
They sit down, clink their bottles,
and enjoy the rest of the game silently.
The girl in front smiles,
turns to her friend,
gives her a pound,
and turns back to the game.
A cut to a little later,
our boys are depressed.
Their bottles are empty.
They look at each other
and smile mischievously.
They stand up all at once
and start screaming.
This time, every girl around them
starts waving over the Amber Lite vendor.
It Does You Right."
Good pitch.
And, um, these friends,
how do you see them?
Uh... Real women, no models.
I want each and every one of them
to have their own unique vibe.
Okay.
It's not the typical way
to sell the product,
but it is funny, and effective,
and I think it could appeal
to the male audience.
- Thank you, Violet, thank you.
- Good job.
All right, Rich, you're up.
What do you got?
We're on a cruise ship,
and it's going down.
All the life rafts are full,
but there's still two guys left
on the boat.
One is a stud.
The other is some corny-looking dude.
But then these two gorgeous women,
long blonde hair,
big breasts, they float up in a life raft,
and they call out
that they can hold one more.
And of course, the stud grins,
and he pulls his shirt off,
and he's got the pecs and the six-pack.
But, to his shock,
they point to the cornball.
The cornball
is holding a six-pack of Amber Lite.
We cut to later, and he's laying
in the raft with the girls,
all three drinking an Amber Lite,
watching the stud go down with the ship.
Thanks, Rich, nice.
Well.
Okay.
Um...
I'm gonna go with Rich.
- What?
- But what's fresh about that?
We've heard that pitch a thousand times.
If it ain't broke, right?
I guess it depends
on your perspective.
I quit.
Violet.
Come on,
you can't be serious.
Violet, one pitch. It's one pitch.
Actually, I've been thinking about it
for a while now.
I think it's time for me
to step outside the box.
Violet.
Hi, Lola.
Hi.
Hey.
What are you doing here?
I'm sorry, I... But, wow, that was... Wow.
Shut up.
You didn't see that.
I saw nothing. I... Wait, wait. No, wait.
Yep, there it is.
Even better in slow motion.
Why have I never seen that?
Why are you here?
And what is that smell?
Uh...
So, I came round
to get the rest of my stuff,
and Lola is really excited to see me.
That, or very protective.
So, yeah, I need to take a shower,
'cause I have just been here packing,
and smelling of dog pee.
Be my guest.
Take a shower.
Thank you.
I'm sorry if I ever made you feel
like something was wrong with you.
Maybe...
I just tried to find the fault in you
because I was afraid that
I was never gonna be enough for you.
There's nothing wrong with you, Vi.
And I should have fought for you.
Right.
Gonna take that shower.
Hey.
Okay, so one of the things that I realized
these past few months
is how much you took care of me.
Sit.
Now, enjoy your time.
Oh...
Well, thank you.
You know what the funny thing is?
I've gained so much time
not having to think about my hair.
I mean, it was like a second job.
It's been really nice.
Does that mean you're
not gonna grow it back?
I don't know.
I mean, I certainly don't
like being dismissed or ignored, but...
it's kind of forced me
to give up my vanity...
and focus on other parts of myself.
So, what happens when
I walk through that door?
I... I don't... I don't know.
Hey.
We'll figure this out.
Don't cry.
Oh, no. No, Violet.
This is... This is the onion.
So crazy.
Violet Jones.
Will you marry me?
Will you?
- Oh, my gosh!
- Amazing!
Okay, so how long
do we have to lose weight?
- Three months.
- Girl, what?
Wait, hold on, guys, hold on.
Hello?
Finally! I'm so happy!
Hi, Mom.
- Vi!
- Aw.
Does your dad help you with that?
How'd you know?
Sir!
Nice work!
Oh. Thank you.
May I top you off?
Yes, please.
So. Let's talk about this wedding.
What's it gonna cost me?
You know, um, my engagement party
is tomorrow night.
Oh.
And, for some reason,
I'm feeling a little nervous,
maybe because I'm meeting Clint's parents.
You think you could come?
You'd have to get dressed up,
do hair, makeup, the whole works.
- I'll take that as a yes.
- Yes, yes, yes! Yes!
Shit!
Let me.
It's going to be fine.
Just need everything
to be perfect tonight, you know?
Well, as long as you don't get
any more surprise dogs, it'll be great.
- We good?
- Mm-hmm.
That's it.
- Vi?
- Mm-hmm?
Just wondering if you could do
something with your hair tonight.
Like what?
I don't know. Like, make it straight.
Why?
Well, I think it looks great.
I mean, you know that.
Women do different things
with their hair all the time,
so it's not, like, a big ask, right?
I'm sorry, I just... I just need everything
to be perfect tonight.
Okay.
- Hello, darling.
- Mom.
Dad.
This is Violet.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
Would you like a drink?
Hello.
Ooh. Hmm.
Hmm...
What? So, who do you belong to?
Who are you?
I'm the one paying for the bread
you have in your hands.
And you can keep this one, you touched it.
I'm Zoe. I'm Violet's friend.
Really? Well, nice to meet you, Zoe.
What a pretty dress.
And your hair.
It's so unusual.
Does "unusual" mean "good"?
'Cause I know I look dope.
Yes, you do.
Violet had the idea for the flower,
but my dad did the rest.
He's a hairdresser.
- Well, aren't you lucky?
- Mm-hmm.
These? So good. Try one.
No, thanks.
Oh, come on, I know you want some!
Excuse me,
you're using your outside voice.
Excuse me, but we are outside.
So, why don't you just get a soda
to... wash all that down?
- Mm-hmm.
- And please don't... Oh, my Lord.
I don't believe you.
You invited the hairdresser's daughter?
I mean, does Clint know
about you and her father?
- There's nothing to know.
- Shh.
Beautiful ladies.
Ready to sit?
Sure, um, can you give me a minute?
Yeah, sure.
Shall we?
Ooh.
...marvelous together.
Have you seen Violet?
No.
Okay.
I'll be back.
Excuse me a moment.
Violet.
Hey.
You okay?
I can't put these heels back on.
I can't be in them another moment.
But if I don't put them on,
I won't be perfect, so I'm stuck here.
Isn't that sad?
Zoe would just go out there barefoot.
Ten years old, and she already
has the guts to just be who she is.
But I don't.
Violet.
Stop being dramatic.
Now, there are people out there
waiting for you.
So you're okay with that,
for me to just go out there any which way?
What is your point?
When I was ten,
we went to some company picnic
for Dad at some... park...
and I jumped into the pool.
Do you remember that?
Oh, Lord, I...
My hair turned into a little fist,
and all the kids were laughing at me.
You yanked me out of the pool,
shoved me into the car, and we left.
And?
I wonder who I would be
if you had just hugged me
and told me I was still beautiful.
You wouldn't be marrying Clint.
That's right. That's right.
You taught me how to be
the girl the guy wants,
but not the girl I want.
Uh... What does that mean?
It means...
I want to go for a swim.
- Violet.
- A what?
A swim? Violet! Violet!
Violet.
Violet, don't you dare.
Ah!
Come in, everybody, the water is fine!
Mm.
Zoe!
What the hell.
I'm flashing like a stop light.
You know, Margaret, I don't believe
I've been in a pool in 50 years!
- Hey!
- Richard, what the hell are you doing? No.
Get off of me. No. Oh, my God. No!
What is the matter with you?
What the hell are you thinking?
I think you have never
looked so beautiful.
After everything you put me through?
No.
In the past couple years,
there's been a huge cultural shift
towards what's natural and real.
We've seen it in the growth
of natural foods,
the demand for eco-friendly cars,
to just about any product you can imagine.
Will wants women to change the way
we are thinking about our hair.
He wants us to know that there
is beauty in our natural hair,
regardless of what type of hair we have.
And his product line, YOU,
helps us bring out that natural beauty.
But why would I push a product
that totally undercuts
what I'm already selling?
Listen, women can wear weaves
if they want to.
They can straighten their hair
It's a choice.
There's nothing wrong with that.
But we also need them to know that
there is beauty in their natural hair.
Large grocery store chains
didn't ignore the health food craze,
they integrated it
and kept their customers.
The shift has already begun
with hair and beauty,
and women of color are one
of the biggest markets there is for hair.
Let us be the first to offer them
something that protects,
rather than destroys, their hair.
You were great in there.
- Thank you. Your passion is an easy sell.
- Not gonna lie, though.
I didn't know what to expect, you know,
with all your personal shit.
Wow.
I guess that's fair.
But I keep my personal out of my business.
I try to,
but it doesn't always work like that.
I'm still salty at you,
so I kind of feel like I'm using you.
I'm using you, too.
But you can't be salty at me forever.
Change the world?
One head at a time.