- Carson.
- Hello, Sergio.
- I'm so glad you came.
- I heard about Clarissa.
- Please, my friend.
Before we begin.
- I thought we
trusted each other.
- Always new rules, my friend.
This I must take.
- How did she die?
- What would you like?
- A beer.
A good one please.
- You got it, darling.
- It's for your next target.
- Not this shit again.
- After such success
with the Amante job,
you cannot be surprised
that the Patron wants more.
Our enemies were terrified.
Embrace your future.
- I kill clean.
They don't even
know they're dead.
I don't kill like this.
- Patron no longer wants death.
He wants horror.
- Sergio, I won't do it.
- Patron will be very
disappointed in you.
You wanted to know
about Clarissa.
Patron had Lance
deliver on their fear.
Does this bother you?
- Is the Patron
listening right now?
I imagine he'd wanna hear me die
after drinking that shit.
He shouldn't have killed her.
- My apologies my
friend but you,
you need to drink
your beer or die.
For your own good.
- No.
Hello, Patron.
You should not
have tortured her.
Now we'll both have to live
with the consequences.
- You there, Alice?
- I'm here, Paul.
And it's 5:05 in the
afternoon which means
I am off duty.
- Yeah, but I got this call
about some disturbance
at Hatchery Lake.
- Paul, I'm off,
have Dave do it.
- Dave is working an
accident up at 101.
So you're up.
. Okay-
Gimme the address.
- Hey, John, how's life?
- Where have you been, mom?
Dad said you had news for me.
- Listen, I'm gonna have
to call you later, sorry.
- Is something going on
between you and Da...
- Paul, I'm at the driveway.
Going to check things out.
- 10-4 Alice.
Call if you find anything.
- Shelton Police, anyone there?
We have received a
report of a disturbance.
I'll need to enter the premises.
- Alice, is that you?
Wanna get me a report?
Alice, you okay out there?
Come on, Alice.
Answer the radio.
- My name is Carson Empman.
By now you will have heard of
me and the things I've done.
And if you have found this
letter then I have died
a contented man.
I am being hunted by the
Chutro drug cartel.
If their assassins find
me alive, they will bring
something far worse than death.
They will bring the serum.
I have at most three
days to take my revenge.
Then I will end my
life on my terms.
For what I let
happen to Clarissa,
I deserve nothing less.
- You there, Paul?
- Here, Alice.
Why weren't you answering?
- Who was it that gave you
the tip on this place?
- He wouldn't give me his name.
But he had a Spanish accent,
not from around here.
Seemed convinced there's
some foul play out there.
- Do me a favor, call the
man named Bob Sistek,
he's with the FBI.
Have him run a trace on the tip
that we got on this place.
- The FBI?
Jesus, what do you
think you found?
- For my entire career
with the cartel
I was a ghost.
No one had seen my face.
To find my jobs I just
needed four words.
The key.
It was untraceable.
But then came the offer
that ruined everything.
They wanted to meet.
Do I wish now I
had turned around
never to work for
the cartel again?
Never to have met Clarissa?
No.
I'd do it all again.
- Good day, sir.
You must be Carson, yes?
Welcome to the Aguilamonte.
I believe it's the most beautiful
winery outside of Spain.
I am Sergio the winemaker.
I am very honored to finally
meet you, my friend.
- You pay a lot of
money for the chance.
I hope it's worth it.
- Our new Patron
certainly thinks so.
He has much faith
in your talents.
- New Patron?
- You must learn to keep up
with current events, compadre.
Come, let us meet
your new family.
Those you must trust
now and forever more.
- Well.
As long as that means
until this job is through
we see eye to eye.
- It's your new family.
To the left we have Anton.
On your right is Lance.
And the beautiful lady
in front is Clarissa.
- Please, call me Doctor.
- Doctor of what, exactly?
- Yes, yes, yes!
You are here for your
distinctive abilities.
And to focus
solely on the task at hand.
As ordered by the Patron himself
you are to share
nothing about yourself
or your past with the others.
- Unless one is to guess
correctly, of course.
You see, I have a
particular talent.
Sort of a sixth sense,
I seem to be able
to guess people's worst fears.
Take Anton for example.
He seems to have a
particular aversion
to being burned alive.
- Shut your goddamn mouth.
- It's roasted actually.
Stuffed within a cowhide,
strung over a smoldering fire.
Suffocating while his flesh
melts knowing full well
that only the pain
will kill him.
- Say another word and you die.
- And that word will be to
the Patron, wouldn't it?
- Boys.
Let's get to work.
- Excellent idea.
Let's get started.
You all follow me please.
- Washington Herald.
- Hello, ma'am, I'm
calling for Wendy Ludlow.
I have a story for her.
- One moment please.
- Thank you ma'am.
- This is Wendy Ludlow.
Who is this?
- Miss Ludlow, I'm calling
to tell you the whereabouts
of Senator Enrique
Parker's son Jared.
He disappeared on
September 20th 2011.
- Yeah, and that
case has been closed
for three years.
- You can find him 50 meters
north of the 17th green
at Rock Creek golf course.
Bring the police and
an excavation unit.
If I see the story in
tomorrow's online edition
I will give you the
story of your career.
- Buddy, this will be
the story of my career
if you weren't full of shit.
- It might be time to
raise your standards.
I'll call you at five p.m.
tomorrow at your time.
Wear running shoes.
- But how do I know
this isn't a prank?
- San Antonio Post.
- Mitch Verplank please.
- Alice?
- Yeah?
- Got a hold of
your friend Sistek.
You didn't tell me he's
the guy who hired you.
- Yeah well he is,
so did he help you?
- He said the call came
from a switchboard
station in Vegas.
They can't trace it beyond that.
He was also very interested
in why you were asking
and wants you to call him back.
- Okay, will do.
So who owns this cabin?
- I looked that up.
Aaron Mickowitz.
All paid for.
Taxes are up to date.
- Mind tracking him down?
- Sure thing.
- Family, our challenge
is a simple one.
Mayor Morgan Amante
will soon be taking
drastic measures
against the Cartel.
Beginning with the
press conference,
it'll be from Tuesday.
Now leveraging your
unique talents,
we will intercept him as
he emerges from City Hall
on his way to the event.
And the Patron wants
to make it very clear
that a simple abduction is
not the desired option.
. Okay-
So a sniper bullet to the
head then we go have drinks.
- So.
The Patron wishes to
use this opportunity
to test out the
finest innovation
by the cartel in its
entire history.
Team, I present
to you the serum.
Lance here has developed this
from very particular
toxins from the world's
most notorious
jellyfish and spiders.
- Excuse me.
What does it do?
- The question is,
what does it allow?
Unlike conventional
paralytic elements,
this formula leaves
the sympathetic
nervous system unaffected.
- What the hell is
he talking about?
- Your heart, lungs,
anything automatic.
- Leaving the patient
fully paralyzed
and yet entirely
sensory capable.
They can even target a
particular vertebrae
and you can still talk.
Or scream if needed.
- What's the point?
- The effect is what matters.
The Patron wishes
to send a message.
One that cannot be ignored.
- Hey Alice.
That VIN you gave me is
from a truck in California
that was reported
missing two weeks ago.
- Did you get Mr. Mickowitz?
- Nope.
No one has heard from
him in two years.
He was last seen driving a
shipment of wine into Canada.
Then he just disappeared.
- Interesting.
- So can you tell me what
you found out there?
- Nothing.
I guess I just needed some time
to think about the
San Francisco job.
- Yeah, and about
leaving us behind.
- If I could do their level
of narco work here, I would.
But I can't.
And I need it.
- But John needs you.
Is taking off to
fight drug cartels
really more important?
Well, whatever you're
doing, our anonymous tip
called back asking
about your progress.
- What did you say?
- I said we don't comment
on open investigations
and he got pretty angry at that.
How do you want me
to deal with him?
- Send him to me next time.
- Hello, Carson Empman.
- How do you know my name?
- I know everything
about this team.
Names, history, sexual
preferences, everything.
- I don't know much
about this new Patron
but this seems like a good
way to get on his bad side.
- Aren't you even curious?
- No.
- Hmm.
Anton Delacroix has beheaded
over 200 individuals.
He also feels no pain
which means he can take
a substantial beating,
comes in handy.
Lance Vitoros, the Doctor.
Pre-eminent monster
in the cartel
second only to the new Patron.
He likes to say he
earned his Doctorate
by studying Nazi
experimentation on the Jews.
And then there's you.
Carson Empman, the ghost.
Seven years contracting
for the cartel.
And yet not a single body found.
- What else do you
know about me?
- Enough.
You left me to die.
- Look at him.
- This is Wendy.
- Hello, Wendy.
- Hello, mystery man.
- You work fast, well done.
- Thank you.
You wouldn't believe the
questions that I'm getting.
- Hear from the FBI, no
doubt, don't answer them.
- And ATF.
- You have eight minutes to
get to the bank of payphones
at the southeast corner
of President's Park, go.
- What, in heels, I can't.
- I told you to
wear running shoes.
- I am not in that
kind of shape.
- Get used to it.
The Feds are tracking
your phone calls.
This gives us time to chat.
Here's the game you
and I will play.
I do something for you, and
you do something for me.
I gave you a body, so in
exchange, you will add
a set of information
on the web article
that first published
Parker's disappearance.
- Strange request.
- Yeah, maybe you.
Are you ready?
Write this down.
Cayman America's
Bank Georgetown.
Hendricks.
Lance Vitoros.
12854196.
- Got it.
- You likely know I'm working
with other reporters.
You are all in a competition.
Whoever serves me best,
gets the grand prize.
If you fail, I will replace you.
If you betray me,
I pay you a visit
and someone finds your
body in six years.
- Don't try and sweet talk me.
What's the prize?
- Has anyone found who killed.
Sacramento mayor Morgan Amante?
- You were a part of that?
You could identify the killers?
- Nice chatting with you, Wendy.
- Alice, you gotta tell
me what's going on.
Why haven't you told John
about San Francisco?
I'm sure he could tell you
why there's no point to it.
- Goddammit Paul, he's
not changing my mind.
- I know you want revenge
for what happened to him.
But,
- But what?
- But he sold drugs for Chutro
and he got caught.
It was his choice not
to take the plea deal.
- Yeah, but they got to him.
They threatened him.
And now he's hard.
He's lost.
It ruined him, Paul.
- That's why he needs you.
So talk to him,
Alice, all right?
See what he has to say
about all of this.
- You know, that's a good idea.
- Okay, let's do a round
of contingencies.
- Jesus, Sergio.
I think we got it by now.
- A plan, Anton.
A plan is nothing more
than a beautiful dream.
Preparation is facing
your nightmares.
Let's see how we do when
things go wrong, okay?
All right.
Presence of additional
police units.
- Escalate the hostility
and create urgency.
- Good.
And who evaluates
effectiveness of this?
- I do.
On approach, I call Lance.
- Excellent.
And if the subterfuge is
still not successful?
Anton!
- I detonate the explosives
in the trash bin.
Jesus, man, why is this
shit so complicated?
Why can't we just kill
the motherfucker'?
- Even in here, Anton.
I can smell the vines
and the barells.
This is heaven!
The Patron told me
personally on his deathbed
that if we succeed, this
is once again all mine.
But if we fail,
oh Anton, if we fail.
Lance, would you like
to explain to the team
what you told me?
- Ah, of course.
Sergio has two daughters
that he loves very much
but he hasn't seen
in quite a while.
You'd be tied to a table,
blindfolded and gagged.
Your precious little angels
wouldn't be able to hear you.
They'll be stuffed
in a burlap sack
and we pour in starving rats.
Now these rats, they
would eat ravenously.
Tearing at the nubile
flesh of your daughters.
And when their cries
became whimpers,
they would nibble till
there was nothing left.
- Okay, that's.
So you can see
that if you succeed you
have everything made.
But if we fail, Anton.
It's all light with
you, we go again?
- Can't you pick
any place closer?
- No, there aren't many
banks of payphones left.
And I kinda like making you run.
- I enjoy the exercise.
So, what happens next?
- You're staying on schedule
so you get another body.
Her name's Catherine Gronberg.
She's in Connecticut.
Died July 12, 2011.
- Wait a minute, Gronberg.
Wasn't she that bitchy
wine magazine editor?
- Wow, Wendy, you
really know your stuff.
Yeah.
She's in the northeast corner
of Ashton Park in Brighton.
- Northeast corner of
Ashton Park Brighton.
Got it, you'll see it
in tomorrow's edition.
- Thank you, Wendy.
- Hey mom.
- Hi John, you got a second?
- Yeah, on a smoke break.
- Yeah I forgot that you,
- Better than
shooting heroin, mom.
Yeah Greg, I'll be right there.
So, you finally gonna
tell me what's going on?
- Look, I need your help.
Do you remember a story in
the news a few weeks back
about a hitman that was
confessing his kills?
- Why the hell are you
calling me about this?
- That guy was trying to
take down the Chutro cartel
and I'm trying to figure
out how he was doing it.
- Jesus, mom.
Do you know what
would happen to me
if the cartel found out I
was talking to the police?
Don't ever call me about this.
- Dammit.
- Alice.
- Yeah?
- That same guy called again.
Asked for the same update.
- Why didn't you send him to me?
- Because he
threatened you, Alice.
Said that two men would arrive
before dark and kill you
if you didn't report
what you found.
So you wanna tell me what
the hell is going on?
- Okay, it's probably,
- I called Sistek.
He sounded angry with you.
He wants to know what
you're doing out there.
So since he's your new
boss, you better call.
- Okay, don't worry, I got it.
- Mind if I sit?
- Help yourself.
- You're a bit more
agreeable to my presence.
- You're a part of the team.
Guess a rather well
informed part.
- I was sent from
Bogota to review
as well as assist
in the operation.
- Bogota?
So you have the ear
of the Patron?
- Something like that.
Care for a glass?
- No thanks.
- Wine too nuanced
a taste for you?
- No, it's a.
It's the insult.
- The insult?
- May I?
Take a look at these two.
The wine has been so
carefully cultivated,
crafted, blended and
aged all to achieve
this particular taste that we
are supposed to celebrate.
For 800 bucks a bottle, no less.
- 1200 actually, but go on.
- And you have this beer.
Made well and with
care, but not,
as many would say, special.
- And?
- And then I shoot
them both in the head.
People see the wine as a tragedy
while the beer, the beer
is an afterthought.
I have one glass of beer
a day and I savor it.
And there it is on the ground.
Lost.
It's the effect we have on
the world that matters.
Whether you're the
wine or the beer.
And then to savor
what suits us best.
- Hello.
- Good morning, sunshine.
- How did you get
my home number?
And why are you calling me?
Jesus, you know I'm an evening
edition woman, right?
- Get your computer.
- Bossy and rude.
Wait, you wanna do a
video conference?
- Just accept.
- Why can't I see you?
- That's not part of the deal.
Post the next batch
of terms on the story
printed the day after
Catherine went missing.
- You didn't need to see
me to tell me that.
- No, but to trust you I
need to be able to look you
in the eye.
- Does this mean I get the key?
- The key to what?
- To your apartment.
To this matrix dummy.
I've seen criminal organizations
use this method before.
- All in good time.
- You better hurry.
The Chutro cartel is
scouring the earth for you.
- Yeah, I expected that.
- So what happens?
Why did you turn?
- I didn't turn.
They killed a woman
who needed my help.
We did the Amante job, split up.
The next thing I hear,
so I am responding.
- I love a romantic.
- Just get back to work.
Who is it?
I know why Anton and
Lance are here.
What makes you special?
- Sometimes a kill is a
matter of sleight of hand.
- I don't follow.
- I'm the distraction
while my partner
finishes the job.
- What does that make me?
- Do you wanna find out?
- I think you better leave.
- Sheriff Dreyer.
- Hello, Alice.
- Bob, is that you?
- I see that our calls
to your husband
have been ineffective.
- Who is this?
- Alice, this is the Patron.
I know you have
found Carson Empman
and have seen the punishment
inflicted on him.
So why have you not reported
anything to this effect?
- I'm sorry but I...
- You have one thing to do.
Call Rachel Sovich at
the Associated Press,
identify yourself and tell
her what you have found.
You understand?
- What will you do if I don't?
- Alice, do not risk hell
for a ghost.
- What?
Really?
Where?
No fucking way.
Shoots through the ribs.
- Very good.
Okay Clarissa, you're up.
- No, me next.
Not yet convinced.
. Okay-
Good luck.
- You'll need it.
- Ready, gentlemen?
- Ready.
- Okay then, go forward.
- Anton.
Anton!
Anton, goddammit!
- Just as I thought.
- Thought what?
- Asshole.
- Right cheek, actually.
- Good work.
Lance, you are paralyzed.
Okay, let's go get some lunch.
- Wait.
I think I finally figured
you out, Clarissa.
- Lance, do not tell her.
- You wanna be free.
Confinement.
That's your fear.
I wouldn't touch a
hair on your head.
We'd wrap you in carpet,
duct tape it tight
and give you air and an IV,
shove you in a box and
bury you underground.
- Lance, enough!
- You would try to
stay calm at first.
Then you would panic and
fight to move even an inch.
Then you would
pass out exhausted
just to wake to the true
nightmare of no escape again
and again and again.
- I'll remember that.
- Federal Bureau
of Investigation.
Special Agent Sistek.
- Bob, it's Alice.
Both Paul and I have
received very disturbing
death threats from
an anonymous caller.
Is there anything you can
do to track down this guy?
- Alice, it's about
time you contacted me.
What the hell do you think
you're doing out there?
- I don't know.
- What's funny is
I got a call too.
A source of mine says you
found a cartel hitman.
The cartel hitman, is that true?
- I don't know what I found.
John?
- Hey, sorry about before.
Hearing the word Chutro
just makes me angry.
- I know.
And I'm sorry.
- I checked up on
the hitman for you.
This guy's plan was incredible.
- What was he trying to do?
- He was sharing the
financial information
of the team that assassinated
that mayor Amante.
Reporters have published
their names, bank accounts,
routing numbers,
transaction IDs.
But in unconnected pieces.
- Did it work?
- No, he didn't provide a key.
- Key, what do you mean?
- The key is how you
connect everything.
It's how drug agents
communicate anonymously.
Four random words
they search for
that returns one page that
links it all together.
- What would you use
to make the key?
- I think he was using
the names of those
in the hit squad.
But he only published three.
Empman, Vitoros and Delacroix.
If someone could find
that fourth name,
they might be able to
finish what he started.
Just be careful, okay?
- I Will.
Thanks for your help.
Four words.
- Fuck him.
- Who was the woman?
- I was married once.
- So you have a heart after all.
- Not anymore.
- I'm sorry, it's
none of my business.
- Her name was Abby.
We were out in the backcountry.
Hunting, we've been drinking.
I was drunk.
My gun went off.
Caught her right in the gut.
I couldn't stop the bleeding.
I left camp.
By the time I got back,
it was too late.
Her face all contorted
from the pain.
What I wish is,
I wish I would have
just gone back,
snuck back in and put a bullet
in the back of her head.
She never would have known
and she never would
have suffered.
Killing people quickly
is the closest thing
to good I know how to do.
Can I help you?
- Yeah, you own this place?
- My uncle does.
- That's funny.
We've been by here a few times
and we've never seen anybody
check up on it before.
- Well here I am.
- So we don't think
you own this place.
And we need it.
We'd rather not kill you.
Gunshots attract the
kind of attention
that we don't need right now.
Look.
We just need a place to lay
low for a couple days.
If it's all the same to you,
how about that gun of yours?
- John, you won't believe
what I figured out.
- Mom, I looked
into this some more
and you can be in some trouble.
- He's not looking to
expose the hit squad.
He's looking to
expose everything.
- I need you to think
about your safety.
They could be listening
to you right now!
- Every kill he confessed to is
related to wine in some way.
He's giving us a map to how
the entire system worked.
Distributors, politicians,
even goddamn wine reviewers.
' System?
What system?
- The Aguilamonte winery is
a gigantic money launderer.
And through the other
contract killers,
he's tying together the entire.
Chutro financial organization.
- Mom, stop.
I need you to be quiet
and forget everything
you just said.
- John, this is huge, I,
- Mom!
Didn't you hear
about what happened
to those newspaper reporters
that Empman was working with?
- No, I didn't.
- You don't know how
bad these people are.
- Washington Herald.
- Hey, Wendy Ludlow please.
- Oh Jesus.
- Ma'am is everything all right?
- She's, Miss Ludlow is missing.
- What are you talking about?
- Are you the man she
was working with?
- Where's Wendy?
- They told me to read you this.
Carson, give up if you
want to save her life.
Or wait and have
both of you suffer.
- Oh shit.
- This is a police recording.
If you have information
on the whereabouts
of Mitch Verplank,
please contact the Dallas F...
- Sacramento 'Times.
- Manuel Cortez please.
- This is Special Agent Sistek.
Who am I speaking with, please?
- I need to speak with
Manuel Cortez now.
- So, you must be Carson.
Looks like the Patron
got ahead of your game.
- Is he alive?
- That's very hard to say.
This newspaper received
a video this morning
showing staff reporter
Manuel Cortez
being wrapped in cowhide
and strung up over a fire.
You spoke with this man
yesterday, correct?
- Yes.
- Well the video
continued to show.
Mr. Cortez being roasted
alive for over three hours.
I think it's about time
for you to help us out.
- What are they doing with him?
- It's one of our lab rats.
- I thought the
serum was finished.
- They want to get
the dosage light.
- Who is he?
- Someone who didn't
successfully curry
the Patron's favor,
I would guess.
Tell me about you and Clarissa.
- Has your sixth sense
figured me out yet?
- Not yet, but soon.
Has Sergio given
you his pitch yet?
- Pitch? No.
- I imagine that you'll accept.
You have a talent for
suffering I think
that you've yet to appreciate.
It was years ago, there
was a method I heard of
that I thought was
quite brilliant.
Takes just one bullet.
You hit a precise
spot in the abdomen.
Severs the intercostal nerve.
It's excruciating pain,
a slow bleed out.
But the mastery was
in the performance.
You staged it as an accident.
You told her you were
gonna go get help
but you gave her hope so
that she would endure
for as long as possible,
as long as her strength
would hold out.
Then you came back
at the last moment
just to laugh at her
before she dies.
Suffering is such a
complex emotion.
There's so many shapes, colors.
It's beautiful really.
You should embrace
this talent of yours.
- Office of the mayor.
- Margaret Amante please.
- May I ask who's calling?
- I am the man who
murdered her husband.
- It's him.
- Connect me in 30 seconds.
If she wants me caught,
I only speak to her.
- She will speak to you.
Call back in 15 minutes.
- Exactly 15.
- Your radios and
cellphones for tomorrow.
All ready, my friends.
Carson, please, sit.
We have one more piece
of business to discuss.
I have made an offer to
the rest of the team
and they have all accepted.
I'm about to make the
same offer to you.
- Another job like this?
I don't think so.
- Not a job, my
friend, a career.
Your contract rate
would increase
to one million dollars
per assignment.
Complete four jobs in a year
and you receive a four
million dollar bonus.
- What changes?
- A certain degree of.
- Torture?
- Penance.
That was the word that
I was looking for.
And don't worry, my friend.
We can offer you all
the training you need.
We need good men
like you, Carson.
Consider it.
- Do not miss out on this
opportunity, Carson.
The Patron would
be most grateful.
- You get to be my understudy.
- I don't torture people.
- You'd learn to like it.
- You still don't know, do you?
- Oh I think I'm getting close.
- How about I just tell you?
I'd hate for you
to get it wrong.
Take me somewhere remote
where I may never be found.
Slice off my fingertips,
peel the skin
off of my tattoos.
Pour acid on my face,
burning out my eyes.
Leave me completely
unrecognizable.
Then rip out my teeth
and tear out my tongue
and as I died, I know that
even when I was found
they would never know who I was.
I would leave no legacy
except my own excruciating hell.
- Strange how someone
that prizes anonymity
would fear that of all things.
- Yes.
Strange.
I'll think about it.
I am beginning to believe
that I will not succeed.
Whoever you are, share this
letter with the world.
They will want to know.
Just put the following
words in sequence
in whatever you say.
Do that and the
cartel will fall.
- Who is Clarissa, Carson?
- Hello, Alice.
- Hello, Patron.
- You have not made the call to Mrs.
Sovich.
- No.
- Why you make such a mistake?
- Because you want
the world to know
what you'll do to anyone
who gets in your way.
- Alice, I know how hard it was
for you to see your son
in prison three years.
But he knew that
whatever he faced inside
was nothing compared to
the price of betrayal.
Do you wish for him to
suffer now because of you?
- Okay Patron, I understand.
I understand completely.
I'll call Sovich right now.
- Because we can take him
from his garage in Olympia
whenever we want.
Do you understand?
- Yes, goddammit, I understand.
- Don't make me come for you.
- They won't turn
me into a monster.
- That's why they
brought you here.
Well what now?
- I'll do the job and disappear.
- They'll find you.
Let's leave.
Now.
I wanna be done with the cartel.
- Good luck tomorrow.
- Goddamn you.
- Is this a prank?
- Hello, Margaret, no it is not.
- Then why are you calling me?
- To give you vengeance.
- I don't,
I don't want vengeance.
- I am sorry but I need you.
I had four reporters that
were gonna do your job.
- Do you know what is
happening to them?
They are being tortured every
day until you are found.
- Yes.
Yes I do.
And we can help them.
- Tell me how.
- Alice, what you got for me?
- They're threatening my son.
I need you to send someone to
his garage to protect him.
- Try and calm down.
Who's threatening him?
- The Chutro drug cartel.
- All right, listen
carefully, Alice.
If you want this job
in San Francisco,
you hang up and do what
they asked you to do.
- I am begging you Bob, please.
Protect my son.
- All right, we have
men on the way.
- To watch my son?
- To you, Alice.
Now do what the Patron asks.
- Associated Press.
- Rachel Sovich please.
- If I do nothing,
you're dead anyway.
What could I
possibly give to you
that is in my interest?
- A public announcement.
- Go on.
- I want to destroy Chutro.
But to do that I need a war
between all the cartels.
If they all have access
to the same information
at the same time, they will
all go after Chutro at once.
Anything short of that
means nothing will happen.
- What do you need me to do?
- You will announce that the
man who murdered your husband
is giving himself up.
- He is?
- Schedule a press conference,
get on the five o'clock news,
put the microphone
up to the speaker
and I will give everything up.
- Five p.m. tonight.
Pacific time.
Call me then.
- Thank you, Margaret.
- I've been anxiously
awaiting your call,
Sheriff Dreyer.
This will be headline news
across the country tomorrow.
You are going to be famous.
- Are you working
with him, the Patron?
- I'm just doing
my job, Sheriff.
So I hear you have some
gory details for me.
Tell me about the body.
- Got what appears
to be a homicide.
Male victim,
deceased a few days.
Fingertips, patches of skin and
the scalp have been removed.
Face, teeth, tongue removed.
- Now I have sources
that indicate
a letter was found?
- You are working with
them, you little shit.
Yes, I found a letter.
- So, did he really
suffer all that
just for a woman?
- The woman.
John, don't hang up.
The hit on Amante, there
was a woman on the team.
Who was she?
- Mom, no one knows.
- This was a big target.
They would have used
their best people.
Any idea who she could be?
- The cartel hires dozens
of contract killers,
men and women.
- Anyone named Clarissa?
- So you agreed to the deal?
- Never had much of a
choice now, did we?
- You could have said no.
- I don't know what kind
of life you've lived,
but all my choices have been
either to live a nightmare
or be the nightmare.
Either way, the nightmare
just keeps getting worse.
But shit, it don't
even matter then now.
Probably won't live long enough
for it to be an issue.
- What does that mean?
- I mean you and Clarissa.
Man, how could you be so stupid?
- That is over.
We're through.
- We're a team, man.
We're family.
We succeed together,
we betray together.
- Betray?
Who did I betray?
- Well at least Clarissa would
suffer just as bad, huh?
Or maybe even worse.
What, I guess you're
just gonna hope
she keeps her mouth shut?
- Anton, what the fuck
are you talking about?
- Your little affair
was with Clarissa
Annabelle Chutro.
She's the new Patron's wife.
- Perhaps I had it wrong.
Perhaps I'm writing to
someone else entirely.
Maybe the person
holding this letter
is the one sent to torture me.
Maybe you were too late.
Together with Margaret Amante
we will show the world
how to take down
Chutro and the Patron.
And my penance will be complete.
- John, one more thing.
- No mom, stop trying
to figure this out.
Just let it be.
- There was going to
be a press conference
and Empman was calling in.
Amante's wife Margaret
was putting it on.
- No, there wasn't.
- Empman was going to
admit to everything.
Why was it cancelled?
- Mom, there never was gonna
be a press conference.
She set that up to
track his cellphone.
Looked like it worked.
- Yeah.
On it.
You are welcome at any time.
- I'm just saying I
think that we could try
and reschedule the one meeting.
- Well, can we just,
for this one can we
just keep the questions
to half an hour?
- You're declaring
that you will end
bribery and corruption
in the city.
There are going to be
a lot of questions.
- I'm just really nervous.
- Well, you're gonna piss off
some very dangerous people.
- Excuse me sir, may I help you?
- He's coming down the steps.
20 seconds.
- I need that script.
If I say too little,
this thing can blow up.
And if I say too much
of the wrong thing,
I can go to prison.
- Or worse.
- Sweety, you will be fine.
Short concise answers.
- 10 seconds, keep going.
- Sir, you're going
to have to leave.
- Don't over-explain.
- Five seconds, get ready.
- This is my last warning!
- Just try and stick
to the talking points
that we discussed.
- Do it now.
Do it now, make a count.
- That's it, out!
- Excuse me.
- What is she doing?
- Just let the staff handle it.
- That's the problem.
We can't have headlines of a,
of a beating on,
- Morgan, are you all right?
- He's all yours.
- Hello, Carson.
- It hurts.
- Morgan?
Somebody help me.
- I'm a Doctor, what's wrong?
- Stop right there.
- Look, I'm from St. Michaels.
Now please let me through.
And somebody call 911.
- Let him through.
- Is he gonna be all right?
- I don't know, dammit.
It could be an obstruction.
The Patron says, hello, Mayor.
And he thanks you
for your betrayal.
And in return, your
family will now watch
as you suffer the
most exquisite death.
Welcome to hell.
- Carson, my amigo.
- Hello, Patron.
They told me you were dead.
That you'd been tortured.
- Yeah, that was my doing.
I let the Patron believe
that you loved me
so he wanted you dead.
So I convinced him to let me
set the trap with Sergio.
- So you wanted me dead.
- I hadn't decided yet.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm the distraction.
- I've waited a long
time for this, Carson.
- As you now realize,
this was all for you.
You now are a monster like us.
I will call on you
again soon, compadre.
- You've been injected
with a paralytic serum
with a careful dose of acid.
And you shall die in
the next eight hours.
But do not worry.
We found a replacement for you.
Someone to keep things
just the way they were.
That should stabilize him.
And where's that damn ambulance?
- You were so
close, weren't you?
You ready?
- Congratulations, Alice.
You completed your
fist assignment.
You just let the world
know what happens
when you try to
cross the Patron.
And for a moment I think
you had it in you
to follow orders.
- So was that enough for you?
' Yes.
Thanks Alice,
you've done enough.
I look forward to having
you down here on the team.
- Go to hell.
- Clarissa, step aside.
- Does this scare you, Lance?
- And why would it?
- Because this sure as
hell isn't my worst fear.
- Your turn, Lance.
- If you are reading
this then I'm dead.
You must finish
what I've started.
With the information
provided here
you now possess the map to
seven hundred million dollars
of the Chutro cartel's assets.
Use it to destroy them.
Do whatever is necessary.
I'm counting on you.
If you fail me, then
know even in my death
that a ghost will
soon pay you a visit.
- Sheriff Dreyer.
- Alice, you were just in time.
- Will my son be left alone?
- Well, for now.
But we will keep an eye on him.
Now I wonder why you took
such risks for a dead man.
Perhaps you will
tell me when you are
in San Francisco.
- Perhaps not.
I might not have what it takes.
- Then until we meet
again, Sheriff Dreyer.
- Patron.