NORWAY DECLARES NEUTRALITY
WHEN WORLD WAR II BREAKS OUT
SWEDEN DELIVERS 85% OF THE IRON ORE
USED BY THE GERMAN WEAPONS INDUSTRY
THE ORE IS TRANSPORTED BY TRAIN ACROSS
THE BORDER AND SHIPPED OUT FROM NARVIK
GREAT BRITAIN CONSIDERS STOPPING THE ORE
TO BE OF THE UTMOST IMPORTANCE
ON APRIL 81940, THE BRITISH MARINE FORCE
MINE NORWEGIAN WATERS
BRITISH AND NAZIS
LOAD ORE IN NORWAY SIDE BY SIDE
BATTLE FOR IRON ORE
HECTIC DAYS AT PORT OF NARVIK
THAT DAY, A TROOP OF NORWEGIAN SOLDIERS
ARE SENT TO NARVIK AS NEUTRALITY GUARDS
THEY ARE UNAWARE THAT NORWAY'S
NEUTRALITY HAS ALREADY BEEN BREACHED
Do you smell that?
Yes, now I got it!
- Got what?
- The smell.
Saltwater?
There's something more.
You don't smell it?
Nope.
Then you're not a local.
It's ore. Iron ore.
The smell of money.
Soldiers, listen up.
All leave is cancelled.
Captain?
It's my son's birthday.
Everyone must go to the camp.
Corporal, be back by midnight.
Thank you, major.
Take this.
How did you manage that?
- I'm not a donkey.
- Don't make me order you.
Give Bjorg my best.
Bjorg?
Do you know who you are?
I'm coming!
Our ore...
contains more iron than any other.
That's why
it is sought after, all over the world.
Today, when we present the plans
for our new ore wharf,
you can see for yourselves,
that there is enough room for you all.
I can guarantee it.
German and English industry
have one thing in common
with us here in little Narvik.
You all profit
greatly from the peace
- and security of our harbour.
- Security of
our harbour.
- And we are happy about that.
- And...
But unfortunately,
it has come to my attention
that several ships,
both German and English,
have been sunk
- ...after leaving port.
- Excuse me.
This affects all of us.
Since there are representatives
from both English and German
authorities here today,
I would ask you
to speak with your governments
about an agreement
which guarantees safe passage
for all ships
of all nations.
...so that the ore
makes it safely to its destination.
Well...
Your mayor thinks too highly of me.
Consul Wussow.
- Cheers!
- Let me refill your drink.
To Narvik!
Consul Ross.
Cheers.
To Narvik!
- To Narvik!
Hansen says, "Hi!"
Say, "Hi!" back.
You're finished now, right?
Soon.
We were transferred to the town today.
Did they say why?
So I can be close to you, of course.
Hello! We have to serve.
Yes.
Someone is going to be happy to see you.
Yes? Where is he?
Outside, with your dad.
Ingrid?
I have to be back by midnight.
You can't leave until I finish work.
So hurry.
Are you ready?
And one more.
Look who's coming.
Daddy!
Hey. You...
- You're as heavy as a five-year old.
- I'm six.
Are you six?
Then this must be for you.
A locomotive!
A locomotive.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Let me see.
Is it nice?
So Gunnar is back?
Only for tonight.
So I came to ask if I could...
Reuters has been informed
from authoritative sources in London
that the mining in Norwegian waters
was completed in one hour,
without involvement from any others,
it has said.
Thank God we have the English.
During the afternoon and night,
there have been reports of the torpedoing
of three German ships
off the Norwegian coast.
Both warring parties have...
Someone has to put a stop to that Hitler.
This was the news.
He wanted to finish building.
I didn't have the heart to...
I'll take Ole and go to bed.
Thank you.
- Good night.
Good night.
By the way, as I told Ingrid,
I'm happy to make up a bunkbed.
Good night, Dad.
- Good night.
Hey.
I have to leave
- in half an hour.
- I know.
I know. We have time.
He's the one talking about the bunkbed.
Gunnar?
- Did you hear that?
- No.
No. You have no idea
how much trouble I'm in.
I should have been back there
over four hours ago.
You can blame me.
- When are you back?
- Tonight.
Unless I'm arrested.
I love you.
Take care of yourself.
Colonel, sir.
Why aren't you armed?
I've...
I've been on leave.
I'm supposed to defend the town with this?
Our ships
have been sunk.
Marines scattered all over the harbor.
German warships passed
the Oslofjord fortress tonight
after engaging
with the fortress' batteries,
and continued onwards.
German warships have also,
while battling the fortress,
entered Bergen, which is now occupied.
One ship has entered Narvik,
most likely after a battle
with Norwegian vessels,
and landed a smaller force.
No further details.
Has a ship really been sunk?
- Magne? Where's my equipment?
- What?
Where's my equipment?
Back at camp.
In position and awaiting your order.
Withdraw!
Or we will shoot!
That is not going to happen!
- What are you doing?
- I'm coming with.
No! I'm doing this alone.
Pull yourself together.
So many dead.
Was that really necessary?
We warned the ships.
They refused to surrender.
We have control over every town in Norway.
You don't stand a chance.
I thought that you...
had accepted an agreement.
Or did I misunderstand?
I got it.
I can't believe it.
Pull back!
Colonel, this is in violation of...
I can't have the town blown
to pieces.
Are we not going to fight?
Are we letting them just take it?
Where we going now?
Okay. Let's take a left here, boys.
Are we not going back to camp?
Not a cat in hell's chance.
Are we not?
What's going on?
I'm going home.
Where are you going?
You know what the Germans to do POWs?
They shoot them.
Magne!
What are you doing?
You're a soldier, damn it.
That one, too! Put him with the others!
Down!
To the reception desk!
Keep moving!
- Get out!
- Come on, hurry!
This way.
Get down, down!
- Give me the Englishman's keys!
- Come on, hurry up!
- Down, down! To the reception desk.
- One moment.
One second! I need this young lady.
As a translator.
Mrs. Tofte, could you help us?
ROYAL HOTEL
We urgently need the key to room 503.
They want Ross' key.
We don't give out guests' keys.
I'm sorry,
there is only one key for each room.
Yes. And one that fits everywhere.
The master key.
- The key! Now!
- No.
No, no. We come here as friends.
To protect Norway from the English.
So please be careful with your weapon.
I understand.
You do? Good.
But my husband is a soldier.
Down at the harbor?
No.
The Norwegian Army
has laid down their arms.
That means he's safe.
Thank you.
Walter, You're coming with me.
Alright, we'd like
to take over all the rooms.
He wants all the rooms.
What about the guests?
The guests who need to move out
will be compensated, of course.
One...
Two...
That should be enough for now.
And you will get a pay raise.
No. No, thanks.
- That's not necessary.
- Of course it is.
I need someone who
appreciates the value of cooperation
and who speaks German.
Excuse me.
Go help Bjorg in the kitchen,
people need breakfast.
Did I do something wrong?
No, you didn't. They were taking
the keys no matter what,
and we cannot control this conflict.
We have a hotel to run.
Halt! Stop there!
Keep marching.
What is going on, soldier?
You're not allowed to leave town.
Why?
You have to turn around
and go back to the barracks.
You are not allowed to march here.
Yes.
We march.
Let them through?
I'm ready. Should I shoot?
Eyes forward.
What should we do?
The Germans are out back.
Open the door at once!
Open up!
Hello?
Open the door right now!
We know you're in there!
There you go. Did you not hear us?
Move.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
Please follow me.
The coffee is ready.
Milk or sugar?
Milk, please.
For me too.
- Soldiers!
- Come.
Everyone gather...
I didn't know what to say.
What about the hunting cabin?
In the mountains?
We have to leave town.
Should I bring my boots?
Bring your boots.
Have you heard what happened?
What about Gunnar?
He's left already.
No.
The Norwegian soldiers
are here, in Narvik.
They've surrendered.
There's a company
on its way along the tracks.
And Gunnar is among them?
You think Gunnar would surrender?
You didn't make it back to camp yesterday?
He was too busy driving the toy train.
The ferry is closed. Go back home.
We're just standing here
gawking like idiots.
Do you think he's Norwegian?
Grandpa told me that they're from
the Norwegian ships sunk by the Germans.
What's happening?
The ferry is closed for civilians.
No one is allowed to leave the town.
If the Germans think
they can close off the city,
they'll get a surprise.
Ole.
Come.
Don't look.
Did you get more?
Corporal Tofte.
The major wants to see you.
Straight to jail.
It must be written somewhere.
Yes, it must.
We might be missing a page.
Corporal Tofte reporting.
Yes.
I understand you've worked
on the Ofoten line?
Yes, I have.
- When I don't have neutrality duty, sir.
- We are no longer neutral.
According to this plan, there
should be some dynamite here. Where is it?
I don't know, sir.
This bridge was made
to be able to be blown up,
so there must be dynamite here.
Tofte! Telephone for you.
Tofte.
Dad?
Can we speak freely?
I can speak freely.
Where are you, Gunnar?
Do you know of any dynamite
stored here by the Nordal Bridge?
There's a stash
in the tunnel facing Sweden.
In the tunnel on this side?
Yes. The chamber is in the third pillar.
You'll need...
three, four sticks in each chamber.
I know, Dad.
Gunnar, listen.
There's a train coming up the tracks.
And Ole and Ingrid are on it...
So you are competent with explosives?
Yes, major.
Bring your team, plant the dynamite,
and detonate immediately.
Shouldn't we let the train pass first?
Do you understand
why we're blowing up this bridge?
To keep the iron ore
from reaching Narvik, sir.
The only reason the Germans are here,
is so they can use that ore
for their armored steel.
- I understand.
- Yes.
Then you know we can't risk the train
having German alpine troops onboard.
EXPLOSIVES - DANGER
Right.
Is this enough?
That's all there was, major.
Movement in the tunnel!
Positions! Blast it right away.
To cover. Cover.
The chamber
is at the bottom of the third pillar!
Fire on my command!
They're civilians.
Yes.
Don't shoot!
Daddy!
Stay there, Grethe!
Get the civilians over the bridge.
Over here. Quick!
Get off the bridge! Come on!
Quick!
- Ole!
- Daddy!
Get off the bridge. It's gonna blow.
What happened to the train?
The Germans stopped it,
in Hundalen.
Where are they now?
I don't know.
They stayed at the station when we left.
In the tunnel.
Get in the tunnel.
Just follow the tracks.
You're almost in Sweden after that tunnel.
What happens to you?
Corporal! We've got to blast it.
- Yes, major.
- Now!
Run, Ole!
We're right behind.
- Are you?
- Yes!
Fire on my command!
I told you to use the chambers.
Those?
There's no point.
Then we don't have enough dynamite.
What else can we do?
We need a charge up there.
- Attach the rest to the other side.
- Yes.
Come.
I don't want to, I want to wait for daddy.
You heard what daddy said,
he's right behind us.
Ole!
- Ole!
- Yes.
Corporal, hurry up!
Shoot!
Don't think. Aim.
Blow it now!
Magne, catch!
Bring those two.
Run!
Gunnar, get off the bridge!
The fuse is lit!
Pull back!
Go, go! Across the bridge!
Go! Move it! Get over the bridge!
After them!
Is daddy coming now?
Are you alone?
Yes, we're alone.
Come with us.
You miserable saboteurs.
You'll regret this.
Move along!
Damn Norwegian pig.
What's happening to them?
They're prisoners of war.
They'll get their punishment.
They blew up the bridge.
Stop gawking.
What are you gawking at? Eyes forward.
Keep going, please.
- Grandpa!
- Ole!
Seeing you has made Grandpa happy.
What happened?
Daddy blew up the bridge
so it's all crooked.
Did the bridge get all crooked and weird?
Stay right here. Understood?
Is daddy okay?
- Yes.
- Mrs. Tofte?
Consul Wussow wants to see you.
Yes.
Mrs. Tofte. Thank you for coming.
We're having trouble with the mayor.
We need to evacuate.
- Evacuate?
- Yes.
We are here to protect you.
Oh, to protect us?
But many Norwegians are dead!
Your men had the opportunity
to surrender, and they chose not to.
What... Ingrid, he might understand
what I'm saying, but not what I mean.
- We need to evacuate.
- Yes.
Mr. Mayor, let's start from the top again.
You tried to send a telegraph?
What did you want to achieve by it?
You tried to telegraph, and...
they want to know
- what you want to achieve.
- Yes.
I've already told you,
I wanted to warn the British.
He wanted to warn the British.
Warn them.
- About what?
The town is full of civilians.
That the town is full of civilians.
Yes.
Which Englishman did he talk to?
He asks who you were in contact with.
No one, I didn't get that far.
None.
Yes. If you refuse to let us evacuate,
we'll be forced to use
the pedestrian tunnel as a shelter.
We have a long tunnel that the mayor
wants to use as an air-raid shelter.
The English aren't coming.
Ok. Then why do we need your protection?
Then why do you want to protect us?
The English won't come
because we are here.
as long as the Germans are here.
For the good of your people,
we should cooperate.
Oh, cooperate?
Our neutrality has been violated!
I'm not done with you yet.
No. You can tell him
I have another errand.
We need the mayor
to keep the town running.
May I try again?
One more thing.
He's temperamental,
but can be reasoned with.
Get the man under control.
We need 50 skilled workers.
See to it.
Go home and try to get some rest.
Yes.
Everything okay?
My husband was captured
on the Nordal Bridge.
Yes.
I... I fear for his life.
You have the wrong idea about us,
Mrs. Tofte.
We aren't like that.
But...
he was one of those
who blew up the bridge
I see.
I will ask General Dietl about it.
Thank you.
Would you do that?
Of course.
I will emphasize
how important your work is to us.
His name is
Gunnar Tofte.
Okay.
Thank you.
That's it.
It's Bjorg.
- Oh!
- It's moving!
Go on in.
Wait.
Sorry to intrude.
It's our friends from room 503.
They've asked you to visit.
- What do they want?
- For you to bring this.
Why can't you do it?
They insisted on you,
and that it had to be today.
No, they'll be fine without tobacco.
If you don't help, it becomes my problem.
You're the one who told me
to walk them to the cabin.
You can't just dump everything on me.
Good morning, General Dietl.
Your car is ready.
Drive me down to the pier,
I'm meeting with Admiral Bontar.
Yes, sir.
The attaché is here already.
General.
Put it over here.
But when it has been restored
and the trains are running again,
we're faced with the next problem:
the harbor, mines and line
need to be operational.
There are volunteers.
See to it,
use all your channels.
People must know that
everything will keep going like before.
Everything will keep going as usual.
People should go to work.
Nothing has changed,
everything goes on as normal.
Thank you.
English war ships are in the fjord!
They're attacking, General.
I thought the German fleet
had everything under control?
Why weren't we warned?
Aslak! Basement!
Are the English bad too?
No.
They've come to help us.
- Come on, Dag!
- Down to the basement.
All men to the dock!
All together! Now go!
All together!
Come on!
Faster!
Ole, come here.
There.
I have to pee.
Pee?
I don't want to pee.
It's perfectly normal to pee.
If you get really scared, you have
to hurry or you'll pee your pants.
Are the Germans peeing their pants now?
I'm sure they are.
Hitler too.
Hitler he cheated
He peed in his pants
If I know Polly,
she's readied the rooms
for the English already.
Is Daddy coming too?
Yes, but maybe not right away.
Oh, okay.
Is it the English?
No, they haven't come ashore yet,
and I don't understand why.
They've sunk all the German ships.
Ingrid, we need help out here.
Okay.
Stop helping the Germans.
This is my job, Aslak.
It's best if you go home
and wait for the English.
You go ahead, I'll come later.
Yes, like that.
He's got severe burns,
so clean the wounds please,
apply some ointment and bandages.
- Yes. We must clean it and apply bandages.
- Okay.
And it's the same for him.
Could your colleague take care of it?
It's mainly up here.
I've got cars to take them
to the military hospital.
Good. We'll take
the most seriously injured first.
Okay.
I need all their names.
Mrs. Tofte, could the rest of them
spend the night here?
Have you spoken to General Dietl?
No. I'm afraid he's not here.
When will he be back?
You need to be careful.
The general is under a lot of pressure.
What does that mean?
It's the wrong time
to tell him that your husband was there
when they blew up the bridge.
I understand.
Polly!
I'll get more blankets.
Stop complaining.
Halt!
You know there's a curfew?
- I... I have to get home.
- May I see your papers?
Yes.
Uh, one moment.
There.
Everything's in order. Go on.
Thank you.
Direct hit!
Everyone out of the building!
Put out the fire!
Pray for your lives!
Ole!
No!
Aslak!
Ole!
- Ole!
- Yes...
Mommy.
I'm bleeding.
Hey.
ROASME, 4 WEEKS LATER
THE GERMANS HAVE ESTABLISHED
AN IRON RING AROUND NARVIK
FRENCH AND POLISH TROOPS HAVE DISEMBARKED
TO ATTACK FROM THE NORTH AND SOUTH
FIRST THE NORWEGIANS MUST NEUTRALIZE
THE GERMAN POSITIONS IN THE MOUNTAINS.
Don't fall behind!
Get him back up, damn it!
We have to keep going!
Get up.
Get him up!
Pathetic Norwegians.
Come on.
If you can't get him up...
Think about that girl you love.
...I'll shoot him.
At the hotel.
- Bjorg has forgotten about me.
- Don't be silly.
- She remembers you.
- Magne, Bjorg is in love with you.
Ingrid told me.
Come on!
Move!
What else did she say?
Bjørg talks about you,
every day.
She's waiting for you.
For you to come home.
Shut up.
- Thank you.
- He already had some.
It gets worse if you stare.
What's going to happen to us?
Move it!
BOFORS MORTARS
Look what we are carrying.
Bofors ammunition.
How many dead Norwegians
in this box, you think?
Grenades!
Get ready to leave!
Get the wounded!
The wounded to HQ!
Get up, come on.
Faster!
Go! Faster!
Where are we going?
To HQ, by the railway line.
Why is this taking so long?
To your position!
Go!
There!
Yes, to the side.
Be careful.
How careful do you think
the Germans are with us?
How did that
story go again?
That guy who got his head smashed in
while the grandkid watched.
The one from Narvik?
- Tollefsen.
- No, Tofte.
How careful do you think
the Germans were with his head?
Tofte, you said?
Gunnar.
Go!
Go, go! To our positions!
Get the injured out, quickly!
Get out! Go!
Go, go, go! Hurry up!
Go, faster!
Get in here.
What happened to the kid?
- Tofte. Is the grandkid alive?
- I don't know.
Get up!
Stop!
Gunnar!
Stop right there!
It's okay, come on.
Come on, guys. Let's go.
Gunnar, we have to leave.
Let's run.
Look out!
Come on, Goddamn it. Come on...
Shit.
Here.
Let's go.
- Look out!
- they're coming from the left
Machine gun!
To the left.
To the right.
It's Pierre!
It's okay, guys.
- Who's he?
- It's okay.
He's with us.
Ah, thank you.
Well done. Pierre.
- Gunnar.
- You're welcome.
Come, let's go. We have to go.
Why the hell are you here?
Norwegian?
Are you injured?
No.
- Bring it down right away.
- Yes.
The Germans have fled the mountain.
Major.
Something to report?
Two dead Germans at the machine gun post.
Both shot by Corporal Tofte.
Yes.
The guy who told you that story,
is he here?
No.
I didn't know it was your father,
my condolences.
Corporal?
This was very well done.
- I must get to Narvik.
- Yes.
You'll be there soon fighting like that.
How long?
When we've emptied
the mountains of Germans.
Might be fast now that we have
the French helping,
and even the Poles from the south.
I need to go home now.
Yes. Then we must fight.
Corporal.
Did you have a little kid as well?
I don't know if he's alive.
You need to believe.
Believe that we'll soon
be standing in Narvik.
Then you can look your kid in the eye
and know he'll be growing up
in a free fatherland.
Come on.
Here you go, up.
This is what we're fighting for.
We're Norwegians,
and we fight for each other.
- Yes!
NARVIK, 1 WEEK LATER
CIVILIANS ARE CAUGHT IN THE CROSSFIRE
BETWEEN THE GERMAN AND BRITISH SHIPS
Does it hurt?
Yes.
Hold it.
Hey. We talked about this.
There.
Ingrid, I have to talk to you.
- What is it?
- It's the Germans.
They're going door to door,
asking who's hiding the English.
Have you told anyone?
No,
but now they're asking for you.
- As an interpreter.
- I don't know.
You have to go.
I'll watch Ole.
My superiors
want to ration the food further.
They want to cut the rations.
No.
People are starving. I can't do it.
The people are starving.
- We need food.
- I know.
It's only until
they find the British consul.
Those who are helping the English now
are putting everyone else in danger.
Do you understand?
They... He says it's only until
they find the consul and it's just...
I don't know where the consul is.
Consul Wussow, I must ask you
to follow me to the basement.
Yes.
They say go to the basement.
I don't want to go to the basement
with these Germans.
They have lost their homes
and their families.
Your people suffer the most
under the British air raids.
He says it's us,
the people of Narvik, who suffer
the most from the British shelling.
- Where is Consul Ross?
- I don't know.
If had I known,
I probably wouldn't have told them.
I can give you one more day,
then you must tell us who it is that's
providing the English with intelligence.
Otherwise you will be charged
with high treason.
They'll charge you with treason
if they don't show up tomorrow.
It's dangerous outside.
You should stay the night here
at the hotel.
I have to go to my son.
For his sake,
you should think of your own safety.
ROYAL HOTEL
He has nightmares because of the bombs.
I see.
I only have nightmares during the day.
And the days keep getting longer.
A few more weeks,
and there will be no more nights.
How did it go?
Hi, honey.
When did you last speak to the English?
Yesterday.
Are they gonna obliterate the entire town
before they come ashore?
They'll come soon.
Soon?
Yes.
Mommy?
I'm bleeding.
I've looked. He's not bleeding.
I know.
It's his nightmares.
Ole!
No!
I'm sorry, Consul.
She insisted.
Get the doctor.
Mrs. Tofte.
- Right away, please.
- What happened?
His wound is badly infected.
We have countless
seriously injured soldiers.
And the doctor is under orders
to take care of them first.
I am sorry.
But I work for you.
I know.
He is all I have. Please!
But you don't understand. I can't
go over the heads of the commanders.
It is a military issue.
I know where the consul is.
Pardon?
I know where the Englishmen are.
Ingrid?
- Is Ingrid here?
- Please wait in the lobby.
But it's really important.
Ingrid?
What's going on?
Is he sick?
He'll be okay.
Can I talk to you?
- Not now.
- That's enough.
I can't wait.
They've been caught.
How do you know?
There were German soldiers at the cabin.
Did they see you?
You have to do it carefully.
Make sure he's completely still.
How were you able to get a doctor here?
Bjorg, look at me.
I didn't say you helped hide them.
Look. Two millimeters to the right,
and it would have hit his lung.
Small blessings.
ROMBAKEN FJORD, 2 WEEKS LATER
NORWEGIAN AND FRENCH SOLDIERS HAVE WAITED
FOR THE GO-AHEAD FOR THE BATTLE OF NARVIK
Grenade!
How are the blasting caps?
They'll work, sir.
Yes?
Here.
As soon as they've fired,
they move the cannon back into
the tunnel so it's completely hidden.
Do you see the five machine gun positions?
Yes.
Once the French have taken it out,
you'll get a signal from there,
then go full speed into the tunnel
and take out the cannons.
This is the last hill before Narvik.
Remember that!
Come on!
I don't see any signal.
Keep going.
Hansen!
Gunnar?
Am I dying?
It's not your blood.
Run!
Do you want to die?
Halt!
Goddamn cowards!
If anyone takes another step,
I'll shoot them!
Get back up!
Major, MS Cairo has been hit.
We have to take out that cannon!
Come on.
Come on!
Come on, guys! Let's follow him.
Let's go, follow him!
It's no use!
We can't give up here, Gunnar.
We have to get up.
There's another way.
Another way?
We can't do it alone.
French?
Come on, Praestnes!
Yes.
Everything alright?
Everything under control?
Say something!
Shoot!
Shoot them dead!
Don't shoot!
Hi. Don't shoot!
Major!
Major! The cannon has been taken out!
Roger.
Forward!
Here, you got that?
- What about this one?
- Burn it.
Here's more.
Go in and get the one from the stairs.
- You asked for me?
- Yes.
Wussow here
insisted on talking with you
before he leaves.
So you're doing better?
That's nice to see.
Thank you.
I should thank you.
You were a great help to me and
to Narvik.
ROYAL HOTEL
- Are you leaving?
- Yes.
Sadly.
Would you consider
accompanying me to Berlin?
Ole, can you talk to Polly?
I'll be there soon.
Ole, come with me.
There...
Why?
Do you like chocolates?
I am not one of you.
But you'll all soon be a part of us.
The world is changing right now.
And very quickly.
Hitler is victorious everywhere.
But not here.
There will be brutal
German air raids on Narvik.
I don't want you to be here all alone
when this happens.
Alone?
I'm not alone.
Mrs. Tofte.
Your husband's name
is Gunnar Tofte, correct?
Yes.
His name has been removed from our lists.
Removed?
What does that mean?
I'm afraid that's bad news.
I am sorry.
May I see the list?
MOUNTAIN DIVISION, NORWEGIAN
I just didn't know how to tell you.
Your son was so ill at the time.
- What are you doing?
- Folding.
You're so good.
Did you know?
What?
About Gunnar?
Did you know?
I can't do this.
Ingrid, you have to be strong.
For Ole's sake.
You have to get out of town.
You can't stay here, people are talking.
Who?
You know how people are.
They need someone to be angry at.
Especially with the Germans leaving.
Here's your pay, Ingrid.
Don't you have family further north?
You should go there, far away from Narvik.
This is your money, take Ole and go.
You can do it. You have Ole.
Ole, come.
What about you?
How will people look at you?
I only have myself to worry about.
I don't have a little...
prince like you do.
I'll be fine.
Hip hip!
It's a long way to southern Norway
It's a long way
- To go
We shall win, we shall prevail
When we all together go
The weapons, hear them calling
We will chase the Germans home
It's a far, far way to southern Norway
But we'll leave right away
And the French!
It's a long way to southern Norway
It's a long way to go
The town is yours now.
Cheers!
Is that his wife?
She's beautiful.
Congratulations!
Go back home.
Your city is yours now.
Here they come!
Our boys are coming!
NARVIK, 28 MAY 1940
Hooray!
Welcome home!
Isn't Ingrid here?
I don't know.
It's probably not easy for her,
as much as she's dealt with the Germans.
What do you mean?
Ole?
Look what I found.
They said you were dead.
Who did?
Hi, Ole.
Aren't you going to say, "Hi" to daddy?
Hi. Hi, you.
Hi.
Nice flag.
Thank you.
Should we celebrate outside?
I'm not allowed.
Of course you are!
Why not?
Polly said we have to leave town.
Yeah, we have to leave.
I ran into Bjorg.
Do you know what she's talking about?
I can... I can explain, but not now.
- Why not?
- Please, Gunnar.
Should we bring the train?
What did you do with the Germans?
I did what I had to.
What?
He was dying.
Can you show daddy your scar?
- No. Ole, you don't have to show anything.
- See.
Have you been with a German?
No.
Then why are you running away? Answer!
Because I informed on some Englishmen.
That's not true.
It is.
They're on our side.
They weren't on my side.
I wouldn't be standing here
if it were not for them.
Then look where you are standing!
Ole almost died from an English shell,
and that same goddamn shell
killed your dad...
That must have been an accident.
That's not a reason to switch sides.
You don't understand.
What, Ingrid? That you're a traitor!?
Who have I betrayed?
Us!
Us who defended you.
Who was defending Ole?
While you were out waging war?
Should I have let him die?
Ingrid, this is war.
People die!
It would have been better
if you never came back!
Ole, are you ready?
Come.
I'm bleeding, I'm bleeding!
No, you're not bleeding.
Hey.
You have to listen.
Now you see how the Germans
thank you for helping.
Praestnes, get down!
Gunnar?
Listen.
It's too late.
He's dead.
Gone.
Why didn't we return fire?
The English are defending the airspace.
There are no English ships in the fjord.
If the English have left,
it's to defend their homeland.
Is it true that Hitler has taken France?
Fight for everything you hold dear,
and die if you must.
Private Praestnes did just that.
He died for everything he held dear,
and that's a sacrifice he made
for all of us standing here.
Because we are Norwegians,
and we fight for each other.
And now more than ever,
we need those of you who are willing
to sacrifice themselves.
Who are willing to sacrifice everything
for what they hold dear.
Yes.
Where is the camp?
Up the road to the right.
Where can I find a weapon?
The camp's in the woods.
German planes!
Planes!
Come onboard!
Don't stand there and drink!
Come on.
Move away.
Should throw her into the sea.
Come on. Hurry.
Where can I get weapons?
You must help her.
Get some Germans to help you.
LOCAL FISHING BOATS SUCCEEDED
IN EVACUATING THE REMAINING CIVILIANS
BEFORE GERMAN BOMBERS
LEFT THE CITY IN RUINS
THE RECAPTURE OF NARVIK IS CONSIDERED
HITLER'S FIRST DEFEAT IN WORLD WAR II
BUT THE VICTORY WAS BRIEF
WITHOUT INFORMING NORWAY, GREAT BRITAIN
AND FRANCE ORDERED A FULL WITHDRAWAL
NORWEGIAN FORCES WERE ALONE AND HAD TO
LAY DOWN THEIR WEAPONS ON JUNE 8TH 1940
THE BATTLE OF NARVIK
IS THE LARGEST BATTLE ON NORWEGIAN SOIL
Subtitle translation by:
Richard. Ngaburi Ngaburi