sub2srt by BAUM
Lee Sung Jae
Kim Ji Hoon
Park Hyun Jin
Kim Ki Yeon
Produced by Kang Sung Wook(PGK)
Written and directed by Ju Kyung Joong
Natali
Oh, is that you, Ma'am?
Yes, it is.
- I'II Iet you know.
- Yes, give me a call.
- Have a safe trip.
- Yes.
- Mr. Han.
- Congratulations.
Thank you. PIease be kind on the review.
Mr Han, Get home safely.
It was unbelievably successful.
Everything is sold.
AII of them except Natali.
You were fabulous today.
Oh, and that guy called again.
He said he was in your class
in college. CIass of '97, he said.
I told him that if he wanted to see you
so much, he should just come by sometime.
- Should I tell him not to come?
- No, Iet him.
Are you going to sell Natali?
The journalists are wondering
who Natali's real model is.
Hello. My name is Jang Min Woo.
Hello.
I'm here to see professor Hwang.
Is he here?
What is it about?
Hum. I think I have told you that
I would Iike to purchase Natali.
I'm sorryto say, but I don't
think that will happen.
Why not?
Why do you want her so badly?
- Because I also have a secret my own.
- What secret?
The exhibition is over.
- Professor Hwang Jun-hyuk?
- Yes, I am.
Hello. I'm Jang Min-woo.
I was moved by your work. Wait, wait.
Would you Iet me write
a review on your work?
You want to write about my work?
I don't even know you.
No, wait. Professor,
I was one of your students.
In art school, class of '97
Natali.
I would Iike to hear
more about Natali.
Don't you dare touch it.
What do you want to
hear about Natali?
I can feel her spirit.
It's as if she's alive.
And it seems she
is waiting for someone.
Who the hell are you?
Tell me about her.
The real person.
Who is the real Natali?
Are you asking the difference
between reality and art?
I'm asking about the real
model of Natali.
Hey, this work of art and the model
have nothing in common.
Are you saying that Natali
was created on its own?
I am not sure if you have
a theme of this review.
My theme is on Natali.
Just have some tea.
Here.
Don't even dream about
writing about my work.
We actually don't need permission
from anyone to write art reviews.
Jang Min-woo, or Jung Min-woo.
Whatever your name is.
My name is Jang Min-woo.
Mr. Jang, you put down of other
people's work to make a Iiving.
So, you want me to give you
something to gossip about?
People Iike you don't deserve
to exist in this world.
Stop threatening other people,
and do something more creative.
I agree on that, but
who will write about your great
work of creation then?
If it wasn't for me, those rocks...
Did you just say rocks?
No, I meant your work
would be valued simply by
its weight but nothing else.
Don't be surprised. This is just
a piece of rock, just Iike you said.
In your eyes, what does it Iook Iike?
A turtle or an elephant?
Do you know the difference between
a sculptor and a stonecutter?
If he thinks as he cuts,
he's a sculptor.
On the other side, a stonemaker
cut for work and not for art.
What about the one who made Inscriptions
on your ancestor's headstones?
Is he a sculptor or a stonecutter?
Well.
Do you think you know what art is?
Can you Iook at
the nature of objects?
No.
But Professor, I don't think you can
see the nature of women either.
Ah. Are we talking
about curator Park?
What? Did she criticize me?
Are you afraid of other
people's criticism?
No. Whatever she says
is not important to me.
Why is that?
Because she is in Iove with me.
Well.
What do you know about
me and curator Park?
Well, if she Ioved you, she wouldn't
call you such as a sex fiend.
Young man.
One poet once said that
Iove is a bitch.
Do you want to sleep with her?
The world consists of two parts:
men and women.
It's Iike yin and yang, so to speak.
She Ioved my work at first, then
she got attached physically but.
I just know once having
her in my bed.
She's just a bit angry at me
because she can't have me.
She knows there's another
woman in my heart.
A well known, but madly
ill-mannered sculptor
and a curator who needs his work.
She could have been
faking an orgasm.
Yeah?
Anyways, she forgets
while we have sex.
When the sex is over,
she is angry again.
Do you have sex
with only one woman?
Talk to me.
I'm curious about you.
Are you married?
You must be married.
You must Iove your wife very much.
How would you know all that?
You wouldn't even cheat.
You don't Iook Iike the type.
Stop it. Do you think I am an idiot?
No. You Iook too serious.
In fact, disgustingly sincere.
Not all men have to
fool around Iike you do.
Come on! That's a given
in this country.
Motels outnumber churches
Do you know how the motel
owners make a Iiving?
Yes, honey.
I'm at the office.
Huh? It's just a headache.
Gotta go for a meeting.
Talk to you Iater.
A married woman sends her husband
to work in the morning as usual.
Have you ever had sex with a woman
at 1 1AM overlooking the river?
Do you believe in monogamy?
What you see isn't all truth.
It's becoming a world of polygamy.
Adultery is simply
a word from the past.
Is your wife at home as she says?
Or is she with another man in a bed?
Don't you want to know the truth?
PIease, don't apply your experience
to everyone else's.
There are many people in this world
who Iive with Iove and truth.
Why was it that a King had 3000
concubines in his palace back then?
Do you want to be a king?
I'm just a sculptor.
Ten years ago,
after your Iast exhibition.
Didn't you say that you won't create
or release any more work?
I did say that.
What made you change your mind?
I don't ask you to understand
a fickle minded artist.
What is the reason that
you released to the press
your ten year old work, Natali?
It's the gallery's marketing planning.
That's what they do.
I know someone who'd Iike to
purchase Natali at the highest price.
- I'm just not.
- And why is that?
Just don't want to.
I'II buy it.
I doubt you can afford it.
Yes, I know very well.
Kan Yakumari was $10,000.
149 Sitalie was $20,000.
Kali was $30,000.
Gauri, the goddess that nurtures
all Iands was priced at $50,000.
Oh, that's impressive.
You're smarter than Curator Park.
So, how much are you
going to sell Natalie for?
I'm afraid this is not a grocery market
where you can buy anything.
Of course not, I value
your work. I will pay.
- Can you afford it?
- Yes. I have enough.
I don't think you have earned
enough yet at your age.
Did you inherit a Iot?
Just give me the price.
It's impossible to
estimate its value.
And your other work can?
In that sense,
I feel bad for them.
Anyway, I won't sell Natali.
There's a special
story behind Natali.
OK, then.
It really is hard dealing
with a stubborn artist.
Thank you for taking your time.
You!
Why are you so obsessed
with Natali, anyway?
You didn't come in here
for an art review, did you?
Do you know Natali?
Tell me! Do you know
who Natali is? Huh?
Before I answer this,
tell me who you think Natali is.
I'II tell you who Natali is.
Natali is me.
It's me, Hyo-rim Park.
Curator Park,
do you really think that it is you?
You can never be Natali.
Then,
you played with me to
make this piece of metal?
You son of a bitch.
What you're holding
is the woman I Iove.
I wanted to create the most
beautiful woman in the world.
I'II get ready.
Curator Park was also
part of my inspiration.
But nothing or nobody
could truly help me.
They were all just useless
and obvious imitations.
Days turned into months.
I simply couldn't do anything.
Stunning body movements
mixed with mortal seduction.
Right after that moment,
she invaded my Iife completely.
Until now, in various art works,
sculptures and construction projects,
have been used in various ways.
Even the Egyptian pyramids
were built using this
golden proportion.
Especially symbols and figures.
She excited me to recreate
her through my hands.
'Art and our desire towards it'
Because human beings
can't exist forever,
we Iive with the dilemma
we dream of eternity.
So we desire to capture
the beauty at the peak of it.
We always desire to
be more beautiful.
I believe that every art
piece begins from this.
Do you understand?
- OK, that's all.
- Thank you.
- You have a nice vacation too.
- Professor, please get married this year.
- Professor?
- Yes?
Would you sign this to celebrate
the end of the semester?
Autograph? Sure.
- What's your name?
- Don't you know my name?
Pardon?
- It's Mi-ran. Oh Mi-ran.
- AIright, Mi-ran.
What should I write for you?
I want you.
What?
Write, "I want you."
OK, then.
I want to be your model.
That's ridiculous.
You're telling me that
she seduced you first?
Yes, it was seduction.
A seduction nobody could refuse.
The Mi-ran I know
is not that type of girl.
I decided to be bold
with her seduction.
If you're ready,
shall we get started?
Yes.
You don't have to
take off the skirt.
Would you go up
there and sit down?
Wait.
Try to be steady.
Just relax.
Hold on a second.
The more we did
the bolder she became.
That's how our Iove started becoming
stronger than anyone else's in this world.
She made me excited
over and over.
We made Iove again and again.
We didn't want to stop,
I could have died with her.
When I made Iove to her.
Don't Iie to me.
Stop interrupting.
That makes no sense at all!
Every moment with her
is still vivid to me.
PIease.
Why did you break up
with her then?
Why didn't you just marry her?
We didn't break up.
We swore that we would
Iove each other forever.
We truly wanted our
Iove to be eternal.
If you Iove someone, do you
have to marry that person?
You're making all this up.
The Mi-ran I know isn't
some easy woman!
To me, she's pure and mysterious,
as if she came from a mythical tale.
She's a creation who Iooks as
if she jumped out of a painting.
Human beings will have to
face death eventually.
we Iive with the dilemma
that we dream of eternity.
So we desire to capture
the beauty at the peak of it.
We always desire to
be more beautiful.
Every art piece begins from this.
That's all for this semester.
Good work everyone.
Hey, excuse me!
- Excuse me!
- Me?
- You're in a dance major, right?
- Yes, what's up?
I saw you dancing before.
Okay.
I want to draw you dancing.
Why would you want to draw me?
Because you're special.
Special?
That sounds nice. Wait.
- Professor.
- Yes?
Would you sign this to celebrate
the end of the semester?
Sure.
What's your name?
Mi-ran. Oh Mi-ran, right?
Yes.
- Here.
- Thank you.
"I want you."
Can we talk? Just for a minute.
I was just wondering
if you'd be my model.
- It's nothing too difficult.
- Could you hold on a second?
It won't take too Iong.
You took her away
in the dirtiest way.
You put her in the corner
with a dirty trick.
You destroyed her with this
disgusting excuse you call 'art'.
Why don't you just
write a novel? Huh?
You are distorting the past
in order to beautify your work.
I think you are the one who is
twisted out of the memories.
That's not true.
Well, I can relate to you.
You Ioved Mi-ran but
couldn't have her all.
The jealousy towards me
with the desire for her.
Your memories could
be completely twisted.
You can say whatever you want.
But you can't avoid the fact.
So you fooled her completely
for your own good.
Shut up!
If you Ioved her to the death,
how could you Ieave her?
I said I didn't Ieave her!
Was she too much to handle
since she was too young?
Or you slept with
a young student impulsively.
But felt sorryfor her suddenly?
Professor.
Did you do well on your exam?
- Yes.
- Hello, Professor
- Just a minute.
- I missed you.
Should we go get
something to eat?
I was worried didn't
get the Ietters yet.
- When did you Ieave it there?
- About a week ago.
Why aren't you saying
anything else?
You agree with me, don't you?
I won't deny what you're saying.
But that wasn't the problem.
Age wasn't a problem
for us either.
As time went by, we only
sought physical pleasure.
Professor,
aren't you getting married?
A son and a daughter.
They Iook happy.
Why do you think people get
married and have babies?
That's because a man has met
an overly determined woman.
When a man marries,
it's because he's met the most cruel
and spiteful woman on earth.
No way,
then is your mother one of them?
How about we just Iive together?
We don't need marriage.
I don't want to crawl
into a grave of Iove
because of traditions
and any convenience.
Well, Mi-ran, it may not be easy
for you to understand now.
The Iust for a woman
reborn through my work,
I naturally fall in Iove
with the woman.
But on the other hand, I couldn't see
the passion in my work.
It started to diminish.
I got addicted to her continuously
and so did she.
How's Natali?
Ten years Iater, I would
compare myself to Natali.
She promised me
she would come back
ten years Iater and Ieft me.
I blamed myself for not being
able to hold her back.
So, you ended up Ieaving Mi-ran.
Are you expecting her to appear
today Iooking Iike an angel?
Then, why isn't she here?
Your Iove just Iingers
in your fantasy.
You are irresponsible immature person
who can't break into reality.
Mi-ran might have forgotten you.
Love might just end before
it reaches a decade.
Don't interpret it for
your own convenience.
You.
Why are you still obsessed with
your one-sided Iove from the past?
I probably think I was the only hope
for miserable Mi-ran after you Ieft her.
I couldn't see Mi-ran even
when she completely came to me.
Do you think you know
her better than I do?
I know her very well.
Since she is my wife.
What?
A wife!
I've been Iooking for
you since Iast week.
What's going on with you?
Do you Iove me?
Yes.
Really?
Min-woo.
Even though someone else is in
my heart, can you still Iove me?
Yes.
Forever?
Yes, forever.
She promised eternal Iove.
This is ridiculous.
When I was at a Ioss in sorrow.
She did eat, sleep and
have sex with you.
Why the hell did you come to me?
Why did you?
If you didn't come,
I would have been missing
her for the rest of my Iife.
Did she send you or did she
ask you to bring Natali?
Get out of my face now.
Give Natali to me.
No.
- I can't do that.
- She's my wife.
Natali is just one of the easy women
that I have spent a night with.
Does it make you feel better to objectify
Natali in a cheap and shameful way?
Yes, I should give away that
meaningless steel to someone
That's enough!
Tell your wife,
that my past, my work, my promises,
I take it all back and I regret everything.
- I wouldn't be able to.
- Go and tell her.
Don't Ieave out a single word.
Natali is a dirty and cheap whore.
- You hear me?
- That's enough!
I won't deliver a single
word you said.
Why? Why won't you?
Why! Why! Why!
Because...
Mi-ran...
is gone.
Mi-ran, Oh Mi-ran!
How could you say that?
Oh Mi-ran.
No, this is my first baby.
I'm going to have it.
This would kill you.
Honey, please...
No, I can't Iet you.
If I don't have you, I'II die.
We can always have
another baby.
Who's going to die?
I won't.
Mi-ran wanted to have Ye-rim.
I will be fine.
If we didn't have her,
Mi-ran could've Iived.
In the end, as Mi-ran wanted,
we stopped Chemo treatment.
And we were able to have
our healthy daughter, Ye-rim.
Are you all right?
Yeah.
Come here, Ye-rim.
Mi-ran had ovarian cancer.
Ye-rim.
After she had Ye-rim,
the cancer spread all over her body
so we couldn't do nothing about it.
But I think Mi-ran was not afraid.
Are you awake, baby?
I'm fine.
Hold me tight.
You know, the doctor said
I can have sex.
I'm sorry. Honey.
Honey.
I Iove you.
What?
I said I Iove you.
Me too. I Iove you, too.
I had no idea.
Natali
must be meaningful than
any of your work for you.
Can you forgive me? PIease.
Forgive me. PIease.
Mi-ran
tried to keep her words
until the end.
She waited for you
until the very Iast moment.
Right before she passed away
I found this out by accident.
Why, why did you do this? Why!
She missed you.
Until the Iast moment.
This is the Ietter she Ieft for you.
We have to see each other.
I don't think I can keep my promise
seeing you after ten years from now.
If I could see you just once.
I want to say this to you.
Do you know what she
was going to tell me?
No, I am curious too.
That's why I came to see you.
You said you have a daughter.
Will you bring her sometime?
I missed you.
It doesn't matter what
she was going to say.
In the way as I always wanted to.
I will Iove you Mi-ran.
Even though it will
take an eternity,
I will come to you.
Hope this mail box will
take me to you Mi-ran.