Every year in the Democratic
Republic of Congo,
almost 500000 young people sit the
equivalent of the baccalaureate.
The stakes are very high for them,
their future depends on it.
Athénée Royal - Kisangani
Democratic Republic of Congo
Royal High School?
Royal Junk Yard, more like!
To think we still have another
7,000 francs to pay...
No, 21,000.
NATIONAL DIPLOMA
Since my parents passed away,
it's hard for me to
pay for my studies.
Especially now, at
the end of the year,
when we're thrown out
because of teachers' fees.
I live at my aunt's.
She helps me to get by.
But I have to find a way
to pay the teachers' fees.
I'm at the market
morning and evening.
I have to unpack and pack goods,
then take them to the warehouse.
At this rate, I'm worried I
won't get my National Diploma
and remain a market
porter all my life.
That's why I'm here to see you.
I want you to help
me to succeed.
Help me get my National Diploma
so my life won't be wasted.
I really need your help.
Don't worry, we're
going to help you.
Get the plants that
fight bad luck.
Crush them and mix
them with water.
Come back regularly until
the day before the exam.
I have other plants for
you to put on your face.
Today is just a beginning.
Fetch that chair.
He has to climb onto this chair
and purify his body
with this water.
And, while he purifies himself,
he must talk to the ancestors
about his problem.
Give him the chair and
follow him to the shower.
You don't have to undress
during the ceremony.
All my projects...
must succeed.
The National Diploma...
I mustn't fail...
Say it all one more time.
All my projects...
must meet with success, with
success, with success...
Insist on the Diploma.
I want to get my
National Diploma.
"People of Congo... Reject
Evil, think of Good,
work hard and all will go well."
"The leader is a
superior among equals.
A democratic leader
makes work easier."
- Are you on time?
- No, I...
If you say no, you
think you aren't late!
I apologize.
- Has this one been done?
- Yes.
- This one too?
- Yes, we started here.
Excuse us...
Take that vest off.
Thank you. Sit down.
Yesterday, we said we'd exclude
those who haven't paid the fee.
Here we are?
The bursar is here.
He has to throw out
those who haven't paid.
We've waited a long time
but there's no money.
We have to pay the teachers.
They're hungry.
They have to live too.
- Yes, OK...
- All right, thank you.
Come up when I call your names.
Alice, come up here.
Djafari, come up here.
Lohoka, come up here.
Gandi, come up here.
Gently! No need to jostle me.
Explain to him we're
in the final year.
- The principal said he'd accept us.
- Not to me, he didn't.
- At the assembly...
- He has to talk to the teachers first.
At the assembly, he
told us to wait.
He told us we could
study until Saturday.
Go downstairs!
If you don't leave, the
teachers won't come in.
Then what do we do?
He told us that himself!
Let's see the principal.
It'll be a lot simpler.
Let's see him.
Sir, we're in the final year.
The principal...
You talk too much. You're
winding everyone up.
We want democracy!
Democracy isn't disorder.
The principal told us we could
study until Saturday...
- He said so at the assembly...
- Go downstairs!
What's your problem?
We haven't studied for weeks now
because of the
teachers' strikes.
The teachers have just
started work again.
Let us stay one more week...
When was the third
instalment due to be paid?
After the Easter holiday.
True or false?
Did you respect that?
If you'd paid at least 15,000
francs, we'd let you stay
I told you clearly: pay on time!
We'll pay, Papa, we'll pay.
Yes, that's what I'm saying.
The teacher threw you out.
Go home now
and come back tomorrow
But if you can't pay by
Saturday, don't come back.
For now, just go home.
- Yes, my girl.
- Mum...
- She gave you the money?
- Yes.
How much?
- 20,000 francs.
- No.
I'm not taking it.
Listen...
We're the leaders of our class.
We have to launch our
"maquis" plan fast.
That said,
we quickly need to
find a house to rent.
We need to react fast
to be ready for the
National Exam.
We'd already spotted a
few unfinished houses
that we could use as a "maquis".
But since we had
no money for rent,
we had to forget it.
We have to hurry...
We're running out of time!
Can we find one in the
musicians' district?
There are a lot there.
A lot, yes, but we have to pay.
Here's what I think:
as leaders, it's up to us
to find a way of paying at
least part of the rent.
We mustn't wait for the
whole class to chip in
if we want to move fast.
Let's say each student
has to pay $25.
Before the 15th of next month.
I know students who
are ready to pay...
Let me finish, please!
As I was saying,
$25 to take part
and we begin on June 15th.
We also accept small
down payments
as long as the sum is
reached by the 15th.
That's what we'll tell everyone.
Move it, pal.
Gangway!
Watch out.
We're here in this room for
the mock National Exam.
No excuses today.
It was clearly stated that only
students who have paid in full
will be allowed
to sit this exam.
When we throw you out, we'll
take the papers. Too bad.
If you haven't paid, you're
disqualified from the exam.
Let's start checking.
If you haven't paid,
give us your paper.
Or if you have the
money, come and pay.
Let's start here.
Fandama.
You haven't paid!
Take her exam paper.
Calm down, OK.
You got thrown out too?
What do you think?
Let's see the principal.
Forget it.
Let's see him. He might
listen this time.
Forget it, I said.
You know what he's going to say.
Let's see him.
You're looking for
trouble for no reason...
This time, all you'll
get is a slap.
He won't slap anyone if
there's a lot of us.
Go without us!
If it works, too bad for you.
Guys, let's see the principal.
Come on, we'll apologize to him.
Let's wait. He's busy.
You haven't paid either?
Would I be here if I had?
It's like we've played hooky all
year without meaning to, huh?
I don't tell my parents about
these exclusions anymore.
I already know what they'll say.
I've stopped telling mine too.
I swear it's no use!
They know we have to
pay to attend school
but always act as if they don't.
I asked them for the fees
three times this week.
But they don't react.
Mr. Chairman, take the floor.
We've all gathered here
because we only have two
months left to get ready.
You know what's
happening at school.
We haven't studied properly all
year because of absent teachers.
The lessons have resumed now
but we're excluded
because of the fees.
Whatever happens,
exclusion or not,
we'll never be able to
finish the year's programme.
There's no sense in complaining.
We have to find
our own solution.
Because if we manage
to get our diplomas,
they won't be diplomas for
the principal or head.
They'll be our diplomas.
Let's pool our energy
to attain our goal.
“Misfortune leads to good
fortune, ° they say.
And so we've decided that we
need to quickly find a house
where we can prepare for the
National Exam in peace.
Here's how you can join...
The full cost
is $25 each.
Of the $25,
each person has to
pay $10 in advance.
It's the deposit on the house.
It's too much!
You're exaggerating!
One person at a time.
Our families don't
have a lot of money...
Don't forget that!
I'm funding myself.
I can't afford $25.
Make it a bit less, please.
Let's make a list of the
people who want to come
and we'll know how
many are interested.
Then we can set a reasonable
amount for each one to pay.
A list won't be any use.
People make promises but
then they don't pay.
We may as well carry on
debating this issue.
No.
We can't keep talking
indefinitely.
We need a final decision here.
It's an individual choice.
Those who don't agree
can stay at home.
Those who want to
follow us have to pay.
I have a big pirogue
for you two.
Only 3,500 francs.
We'll take the public
pirogue for 200.
I can take you for 2,000.
- We'll take the public one.
- With a camera?
We have no money.
I'll take you across for 2,000.
No, I'll take the
public pirogue.
- With that crowd?
- Yes, for 200.
My friends and I have decided
to find a house where we
can prepare for the Exam.
There'll be a lot of us there.
Not so many at first but
a lot more at the end.
There might be problems.
When you live with
strangers for two months,
a lot of things can happen.
That's why
I want to be under your protection
so nothing happens to me.
Give him the money.
You know how much it is?
It hasn't changed.
Put it on the ground.
Follow me.
Got a hammer?
He's a burglar!
Don't try this at home.
Mind the electric wiring.
This can be a bedroom.
That's up to you. But
mind the wiring.
We just need a place to
spread out our mattresses.
We won't touch the wiring.
We just want to sleep at
night and study all day.
This is for the shower.
Question: calculate
the inverse function.
Here we have the equation.
We need to find the inverse.
For the inverse of any equation,
we just need to change
these two values.
Because they are two
different values.
We do what we call
a permutation.
That gives us:
X minus one
equals Y minus one.
Congratulations.
I'd like a kiss.
You'll get one tomorrow
We're going to pray now.
Girls, put your headscarves on.
Dearly beloved!
We're here to study but
we're nothing without God.
The devil won't let
us succeed easily.
That's why we'll fight him
and neutralize him
with our prayers.
In the name of Jesus
Christ, let us pray!
Jesus, do something.
Do something...
Lord, you give us
intelligence...
Give me a diploma...
Help me to succeed...
Can we come in?
Here's our papa!
This papa isn't mean.
The skilled director!
Papa is good!
A kind papa!
No male-female equality?
- There isn't a mum...
- They're inside.
- They're cooking?
- Yes.
They're here. They'll
join us soon.
Have a seat!
So, tell us what
you're doing here.
First off,
we've come here...
to study.
Our lesson plan is up there.
The timetable is there too.
Above it, the house rules.
- Where's the timetable?
- On that piece of card.
- With the rules above?
- Yes.
On listening to you, the first
point is what struck us.
You're here to study.
That's a good answer.
Carry on like that. Stick
to your timetable...
And get ready.
Every day,
the National Exam
gets a little closer.
I nearly forgot...
Some students haven't
finished paying the fees yet.
Why do you put spokes in
our wheels like that?
You've crippled us.
Your teachers do a bad
job because of that.
We have lists for each class...
Some students haven't
paid anything at all.
Omeleke, for instance, Osisemo...
To name just two.
It means you've
studied for free!
- Can I say something?
- Yes.
We want to give our opinion.
Let's take a subject
like Philosophy.
This year, we only studied
three philosophers.
Three philosophers.
All the others, the second
part of the course...
we never studied them.
How can we revise?
If the exam': on
them, what do we do?
Pedagogy. same thing.
The optional classes...
- Biology too - Don't
mention Biology.
History, English, French...
We've had it in all
those subjects.
In the whole year, only one
teacher finished his course,
the Didactics teacher.
All the others... a disaster!
We're trying to get the
textbooks from friends.
Honestly,
we don't know how to
explain to each other
things that we don't understand!
To address that key question,
I think that each time I
came to your classes,
I kept telling you:
when there's a problem,
come to the office.
The way I run things,
I've always asked teachers
to complete the programme.
After all, the programme
is the basis for the exam.
But there are mercenaries.
They're teachers of course
but mercenaries too.
A mercenary is someone
with a personal goal.
He doesn't see the
interest of what you do.
- He sees his own interest.
- His personal interest.
Calm down!
The desire to succeed is yours.
70% of the effort needed
to succeed comes from you.
And it's a good thing to have left
your homes to come and live here.
Thank you.
I'd like to tell you, as
the school authorities...
Really... We've been
sacrificed this year.
But do something for
future classes.
Help them, please!
We're going to have a
reading from Proverbs 8,
verse 14.
"Success belongs to me...
Intelligence is mine...
Strength is mine." Amen.
That's why I take an interest in
youngsters sitting the National Exam.
When I read that verse
for the first time,
I told myself,
"Yes, young people must
understand that verse
if they want to succeed."
Many who haven't
understood that verse
waste their time looking here
and there for intelligence.
Some spend their
nights in cemeteries,
other consult marabouts...
And others still, with their
parents, follow all kinds of paths
to find success!
Yet the only place to
go in order to succeed
is the church!
I'm going to ask you
to bring me your pens.
I'll pray for that.
You know, a pen
is what allows you to put in uniting
what you have in your mind.
God can give you intelligence
but if you can't put it down
on paper, you won't succeed.
That's why we want to
work on these pens
with powerful prayers
before returning them to you.
When you go to sit the
Exam with these pens,
you'll be able to
reproduce exactly
what God will put in your minds.
Write your name on a piece of
paper and slip it inside the pen.
That will avoid any confusion.
Those who are ready
may come forward now.
Thank you for welcoming us here.
We tried to come sooner
but we couldn't.
There's too much to do these
days at the university.
As a former student,
I can tell you
no one can pass the National
Exam without cheating.
My friend and I were
top of our class
throughout high school.
I regularly had the top place.
But on the 1st day of the
exam, out of 20 questions,
I only had one correct answer.
I couldn't believe it!
Just think! The best
student in the class...
Only one correct answer...
If I didn't cheat what
would become of me?
Even so, I'd been top of the
class since primary school.
That's just to show you how
complicated this exam is.
The people who set it know that.
So they allow the
answers to leak out.
That's how my friend got 70 %.
I got 63 %. Others,
more than 70 %...
if you haven't found anyone
to help you on that level,
we're ready to do it.
It's like a legacy.
This year, we're
going to help you.
Next year, it'll be your
turn to help your brothers.
It was the same in our day... Our
elders helped us to succeed.
Yesterday it was us, today it's you,
tomorrow, it will be your brothers...
And so on.
If you agree, we're
ready to help you.
Hi, is Modé here?
No, he's gone out.
I'm selling this phone.
How much do you want?
How much are you offering?
- You're the seller...
- Give me $8.
That's a lot.
- Phone for sale, boss.
- Not interested.
- How much is it?
- $10.
That's a lot.
Hello, Auntie.
I've made 5,000 francs.
I've sold my phone.
I need another 6,000 francs
to pay the exam fees.
I haven't sold anything yet.
You haven't sold anything?
How will I pay my fees?
Look at all this... There
aren't many customers today.
"The righteous will
live by faith."
Living God,
I entrust these young
people to Your hands.
They're not here for me.
They have come to You who
hands out diplomas...
My God!
Lord! I've done my share...
It's Your turn to act now...
I'm talking to the demon that
has taken over this brain.
Out with you!
Out!
Hold her!
Receive the fire!
Leave her mind!
Out!
Who are you?
Who is inside this body?
Many of us!
- Who are you?
- Men.
What are you doing in this body?
We don't want her
to get her diploma.
Where are you from?
From her family...
Listen!
She has found refuge with the
One who created intelligence.
You can no longer influence her.
I render void and ineffective
all the decisions
that you have made
about her life.
I destroy all your plans...
All your schemes...
That's it.
Everyone is ready.
They're waiting for you.
Quiet, please!
Everyone has a piece of paper?
Get out your pens.
I'm about to do
something very risky.
I'm doing it for the
good of everyone here.
So be quiet or I'll stop.
No! We'll be quiet... Go on!
Series number 1...
Question 2...
First president.
Series 1, question 2.
Reference: first president.
Four... One... Two...
Series 2...
Reference: second president.
Six... Five...
To know the number
of your series,
the first thing to do on
getting the questionnaire,
is to find these clues...
If you find "1st president",
you have series 1.
"2nd president" is series 2.
"3rd president"... And so on.
My brothers, we're
here for a reason.
You want to succeed, he wants
to, him over there too...
Everyone here wants to make
it to help his or her family.
So, please! Let's not look
for problems among us!
Don't be in a hurry to
use these bits of paper.
You have to be very
careful in the exam room.
If a supervisor catches you
with your piece of paper,
all you can do is swallow it.
No one will open up your stomach
to go looking for it inside.
If he won't back down, get
angry, threaten him...
Do all you can to scare him...
But if you get caught
with the evidence...
that will be your problem.
I'll deny everything.
So be careful.
Let's not put our
lives in danger.
Lycée Mapendano National
Diploma Exam Centre 1
The number of exam
exercise books is limited.
We have 351 candidates
and exactly 351 exam books.
If you damage yours,
that's your problem.
You've all learned how to
fill out the electronic grid.
If you damage your book,
that's your problem.
Today's exam only
lasts two hours.
You've seen that on the schedule
that I put up yesterday.
Therefore, no toilet
breaks today.
Relieve yourselves
before going in.
Once you're in, you stay!
Inside, do not speak
to the supervisor!
Inside, give the supervisor
eight sheets of paper.
We weren't told about that!
National Diploma Exam Centre 2
My respects, Excellency!
- How are you?
- Hello, Excellency.
Hello.
How are you?
Very nice strongboxes. Are
they like this every year?
We've improved them...
to improve exam security.
- Enter the code now.
- You have it?
Good security!
This is...
That's the exam for
the short cycle.
So this is what I give
to Madam Minister.
Thank you.
His Excellency the Provincial
Governor authorizes
the head of this centre
to lead the students
to their exam rooms.
The exam went badly for me...
They'll refund my money.
Don't say that... It's
all your fault...
You took our phones
and forced us
to work with no one but
your crook of a friend.
You killed us!
You're going to give
us our money back!
Our telephones too...
I was so confident this morning.
Luckily for me, I had a
back-up plan, otherwise...
I had wagered everything on
their shitty bit of paper...
They'll refund my money.
That gang of crooks is
going to hear from us!
- It's getting off to a bad start!
- I swear...
Take your pieces of paper...
And give us back our money.
Here's the real leak.
Unfortunately, I got it too late...
You were already in the exam.
We want to hear your
crooked friend, not you.
I'll call him...
He won't have all the money.
- Shako, did we give him his money?
- No.
You're playing with
people's lives.
The whole city had the
real leak, except us.
- We've been swindled!
- Let me explain...
They stepped up the
security measures...
Each code series was inverted.
Everything was messed
up because of that.
We didn't realize until
it was too late.
I tried to get a message to
you but it was impossible.
But you told us your source
was the most reliable one.
So what happened?
We want our money,
not explanations.
Give us back our money!
This is theft!
My brothers...
Listen to me, please.
We all know...
that today's exam...
didn't go well.
You've done a lot
of talking today.
It was unbearable!
Yes, it happened. But
it wasn't my fault.
It didn't just happen to us.
Everywhere...
You didn't try asking
other students.
You preferred to yell at me.
If you had, you'd have
understood what happened.
Anyone who wants...
to get their $5 back
can come to see me after
the exam tomorrow
No, now.
- I said tomorrow after the exam.
- No, today.
The most important thing now,
is...
the next exam.
It's an optional course
with 30 questions.
We need to find 30
correct answers
to make up for today's disaster.
Tonight, there have been
many leaks like yesterday.
But, yesterday, our haste
caused us to make mistakes.
This time, trust me.
There won't be any problem.
Let's start with the leaks
that are doing the rounds
before I give you mine.
We've already copied
all the other leaks.
- You have them?
- Yes.
Give us your version now.
It's already late.
S3...
Q2...
Touch...
Like on the board.
Series 3, question 2...
Touch...
Five...
Two...
Four...
Three...
Two...
It worked!
We have to celebrate!
You're a real leader!
You did a great job, Chairman!
You're the best.
Two months later
I Passed!
I'm happy! I have my diploma!
God helped me...
It's over... I got 80%!
- Well, Joel?
- I haven't had my results yet.
- I'm confident...
- Keep me posted.
Check your phone. The
results have been released.
Here we go...
I've sent a text message.
The answer...
What percentage did he get?
57... 57... 57 %!
What percentage?
What did I get?
59 “A.
Help me to check mine.
You've got it!
Give me the last
figure of your code.
I've sent a text message.
Nothing.
Chin up... There's no news yet.
Chin up, Joël...
Honoré, your turn.
The answer...
All the people working here have
had to give up their studies.
But you keep going.
This failure isn't the
end of your life.
You're young, you
have to resist...
If you give up, you'll
be stuck here forever.
Pull yourself together...
Next year, you'll
sit the exam again.
Take heart, my friend...
That's life.
Take up your studies again.
To my parents
NATIONAL DIPLOMA