How much is this?
4:30.
12:40... What about this?
6:35.
Its 7:30.
Mommy!
You're struggling to solve
such simple problems!
The clock has just two hands,
The hour hand and the minute hand,
How are you getting them mixed up?
Go on, write it again.
Lakshmi...
She's just a little girl!
She'll learn eventually...
You stay quiet and let me teach her, or do
you want to take up this responsibility?
Hey! Look, she ran away...
Sitara! Wait... Sitara!
You're my princess dear, wait up!
Wait!
I cant catch up to your speed... Wait!
Ill teach you a lesson once I catch you,
just wait!
Sitara!...Sitara!
Sitara!
My greetings to the media and respected
people who are here on this occasion.
I thank everyone for being a part of
the Inaugration of this Dance academy.
Sir,
why is this village called 'Naatyam'?
It means Dance, right?
Theres a huge story behind it.
In those days...
The Britishers took away our Historical
texts, Books, Sculptures related to Dance.
In the course, they even destroyed
all the scriptures, books, sculptures...
...and even temples.
They made sure the word 'Classical dance'
was wiped out from entire India.
Classical dance which existed since
thousands of years shouldn't be wiped out.
So the heads of the village orchestrated
a huge Yajna (RITUAL) in the temple.
Vedic Scholars and priests were
conducting the Homa (RITUAL)
While the Dance Scholars were
inscribing the Science of Dance.
The britishers who got wind of this,
came there, broke down the doors.
Shot everyone there and
threw them into the fire.
Unable to bear the bloodshed,
The Goddess emerged as
a form of destruction.
She incinerated the
Britishers there whilst,
The rest cowered and closed the Temple
gates to prevent her from getting out.
A British Commanding Officer Francis,
permanently sealed the temple gates.
Even after India became independent
from the British rule,
We still couldn't learn dance.
While all the artists were
grieved about the loss of dance...
One day...
They opened the gates of that temple only
to see that the goddess is still there.
Her eyes filled with rage and anger.
Upon performing the peace prayer,
She was calmed down and handed
the Historical Dance scriptures...
To educate the upcoming generations
in the Art of Dance...
...then transformed herself into a statue.
Many artists from around the country came
to this village to learn the Art of Dance.
They then settled into this place, turned
this village into a stage for dancing,
...and that's how the village got its name,
'Natyam'.
From then on, we started praying to
the Goddess as 'The Goddess of Dance'.
Due to her immense glory,
we named this Dance school after her.
Till now this campus was
given to our Guru temporarily.
But him along with his wife,
Transformed this into a School
of Dance and earned many laurels.
Which is why,
I have decided to give this
campus permanently to him.
Hey! You ran off from the ritual again,
haven't you?
Hey! Sitara...
My God! Its Mom!
From today onward, you will bear the
responsibility of the keys to this place.
Guru! Have you come across our kid?
No, I haven't.
She is such a brat.
Dont know where she runs off to...
This campus belongs to Mr. Francis. The one
who shut the gates of the temple that day,
What's surprising is that,
while leaving for England,
He wrote a will assigning
this bungalow and the car...
...to be used only for
the welfare of Dance.
"Even if this life ends
as a sacrifice for my art."
"This love has shed blood
as devotion towards my art."
- Its like this!
- OK!
Shalini, We have to provide a new part.
Prepare the stage right now.
Now dance with alapadmalu.
When will Shalini maam come?
When will she begin the dance?
Hey! Come here.
What are you up to?
Im writing a story.
Aren't we supposed to dance?
Both are one and the same!
How? Can you explain clearly?
Just like we listen to stories, when
they come to life in front of our eyes,
...we call it as a Dance.
Dancing means, to present a
story in the most beautiful form.
Oh...
So they tell stories through dancing?
Yes, indeed.
We can also change someones thoughts
and beliefs through dancing.
That's the power of Dance!
So, what story are you writing?
'Kaadambari Katha' (STORY)?
What story is that? Will you tell me?
Yes. I will.
Guru ji! The story is very nice.
I liked it! I will also do it.
What are you doing?
I am Kaadambari.
You keep narrating the story,
I will dance to it.
[LAUGHING]
Why are you laughing?
Come, teach me how to dance!
It doesn't work like that.
Kaadambari is an artist.
To tell her story,
you need to learn the art of dancing.
Learn!
I will give you that story
for your debut performance.
So you'd definitely give me that
story for my debut performance?
- Promise?
- Promise.
Guru ji! Shalini maam has been
bitten by a snake near the well!
Huh?
This has happened because of that
'Kaadambari katha'.
Yes, true.
'Kadambari Katha' brings ill fate.
It is said that whoever
performs it will get cursed!
DANCE
Can you call the next contestant please?
Rohith, from Barefoot Dance Company.
[RAP]
"Dreams glide in me"?
"Thoughts cloud my mind"?
"Crossing all hurdles"?
"Let me touch the stars"?
"Life is a one way journey"?
"Theres no rewind button to it"?
"Future is a huge mess"?
"Right now fly high with me"?
"My heart flies so high"?
"Sprinkles and leaps to the sky,
as I fly"?
"It flies across the sky"?
"Doesnt wanna stay still on ground"?
"It sprinkles and leaps to the sky,
as I fly"?
The energy in your dance is very good.
But, I couldn't see any concept behind it.
Aggressively jumping around
doing gymnastics isnt dance.
Make sure you conceptualize well,
the next time around.
Will you accept the request...
If given a chance, we will try something.
OK... you will go.
OK Ma'am...
Madam! Excuse me, please.
Madam, dance isnt just some
time-pass or hobby for me...
Im very passionate about dancing,
I feel like Im connected to my soul.
See, I can understand.
But, If you want to represent India
all the way across, in America,
Your performance needs to be much better.
Give me one chance madam!
Well somehow manage to
get a great concept.
Then,
is it possible to get a wild card entry?
Right now, we don't have any.
But our group will sit
together and brainstorm...
If you want to do something new,
you'll have to learn something new.
Do one thing.
Theres a village called "Natyam"?
The speciality of the village is that
everyone there are classical dancers.
For them,
dancing is a form of conveying a story.
Its an art of storytelling.
Why don't you go there?
You might find some inspiration there.
OK... OK...
Ill do it! I got it.
Ill come back to you
with an amazing concept.
You go there and show me a concept.
Then Ill think about your wild card entry.
OK!
Thank you maam.
Sir. Can you tell us about
the glory of this goddess?
Dance was thought to be extinct,
during the britishers rule.
The Historical Texts given by the goddess,
rejuvenated the art form.
Can you please show it to
the media people, priest.
See this, here...
The goddess preserved these texts under
her feet and transformed into a statue.
The eternal glory of this temple,
the goddess and the entire village.
Deserves to get more fame
and recognition and...
All of you must promote it world-wide,
that is my wish.
Greetings to one and all!
Todays program is about to
start in a few minutes...
Shall we go?
Nrutyaalaya Naatya Kalabrundham's.
'Ardhanaareeshwara' dance drama show.
[CONCH BLOWN]
[MEN CHANTING]
"Champeya gowradha sareerakayai."?
"Karpoora gourardha sareerakaya."?
"Dhamilakayai cha jatadaraya,"?
"Namashivayai cha namashivaya."?
"Kasthurika kumkuma charchithayai."?
"ChithaRaja puncha vicharchithayai."?
"Kruthasmarayai vikrutha smaraya."?
"Nama shivayai cha namashivaya."?
"Jhanath kvanath kankana noopurayai."?
"Padabja Rajat phani noopuraya."?
"Hemangadhayai bhujangangadhaya."?
"Nama Shivayai cha Namashiva."?
"Visala nilothphala lochanayai."?
"Vikasi pangeruha lochanaya."?
"Samekshanayai vishamekhanaya."?
"Nama shivayai cha namashivaya."?
"Mandhara mala kalithalakayai."?
"Kapalamalankitha kandharaya."?
"Divyambarayai cha digambaraya."?
"Nama shivayai cha namashivaya."?
"Ambhodara syamala kunthalayai."?
"Thadithprabha thamara jatadharaya."?
"Nireeswarayai nikhileeswaraya."?
"Namashivayai cha namashivaya."?
"Prapancha srushtyun muka lasyakayai."?
"Samastha samharaka thandavaya."?
"Jagat jananyai jagatheka pithre"?
"Nama shivayai cha namashivaya."
"Ethath pateth astaka mistatham yo."?
"Puranmaha pannaga bhushanaya."?
"Shivayai cha namashivaya."?
"Nama shivayai cha namashivaya."?
"Ethath pateth astaka mistathamyo."?
"Bhaktyaa sa maanyo bhuvi deerghajeevi."?
"Praapnothi saubhagyam ananthakaalm."?
"Bhooyaath sadha thasya
samastha sidhdhi."?
"Om Namashivaya..."?
"Namashivaya."
It's nice...
It is very nice!
Your contribution.
Very well done.
You depicted the holiness of Lord
Shiva and Parvati astonishingly.
Shall we leave, Shastri ji?
Get up!
Hey! Dancer!
You are Sitara, right?
You put on a hell of a show there...
I'll speak with my brother and
fix your spot in the upcoming fair.
Who is he?
He's the brother of our MLA.
My name is Veerabhadra.
I couldn't get into
studies at all as a kid...
But, I'm still very popular in this town.
Hey!
Yes, Brother.
Keep it.
It's OK, keep it.
I'll take it...
You just wait, there...
Take it!
So long then.
Come boys!
Move...
Hi Sitara!
You danced very well. It was superb!
I need to speak with you once.
Hey...
You danced very well!
Hey Sitara! I need to speak with you.
Hey, I need to talk with that girl.
Let's go...
Go! Hey, Ganesha! Don't send them...
Swami...
Sir, You're right on time.
Look after this for a couple of minutes,
I'll be back in a moment.
Hey! You wait, you wait.
Thanks!
Wait... wait...
Who's this girl?
How is it now?
Show it...
It's okay...
Is it painful?
You danced instead of me at
such short notice, Thanks.
It's I who should thank you!
Why?
I was waiting for the right opportunity to
show Guruji that I was ready for my debut.
Thanks to you, I was able to do that!
Vaishnavi.
- How are you feeling now?
- It's much better.
Sitara.
You performed very well...
Have I truly done well?
Yes. But, you haven't
learned that bit right?
How were you able to do it?
I used to observe while you and
Vaishnavi were practicing...
That's how I learnt it!
It takes years of practice to
get these postures right...
It's amazing that you learnt
them just through observation!
You're very special, Sitara!
You'll be part of all our
performances from now onward.
Oh thank you!
I'll take care of it...
I'll personally teach you
everything you need to know.
Hmm...
Hari sir! You need to clear
this up with Guru ji...
Hey! Hey! Hey! Stop! Stop! Stop!
- [SITARA SCREAMS]
- Stop! Don't shout!
Hey! Listen!
Hey! Please, Please, Please...
OK... OK. Just listen to me once.
My name is Rohit.
I came from Hyderabad.
I saw classical dance for
the first time in my life.
It's brilliant!
You did extremely good!
I felt awestruck by your performance!
I just coudn't take my eyes off you...
Hey! Shut your mouth.
How dare you peep in to gawk at
us while we're changing clothes!
Shame on you idiot!
Excuse me, Madam.
If I really were an Idiot,
I would've been behind the stand.
And not confronted you directly!
We have a lot to talk about.
Where have you come from?
Where did you learn dancing?
- I really need to know about your dance...
- Hey, stop it.
Can you just shut up.
If you really want to know about dance,
go and talk to our guru ji
in the dance school.
Now, get out!
Just for two minutes...
Hey! I'll go...
Guru ji.
How long will you just sit here
and mourn Shalini?
Leave that.
I heard that yesterday's performance
went really well! Is it true?
Yes...
It seems that Vaishnavi and
Hari put on a great show!
But, Guru ji, it was me who danced!
I know, dear... I read it on the papers.
'The performance that lit up the sky'
Hari and Sitara's outstanding performance
garnering all the praise!'
Does this mean I'm ready for my Debut?
Why not!
You look more than ready for it...
Of course! I've been dreaming about
my debut since I was a child...
I'll be wearing a white saree.
The jewelry should also be white!
I don't want flowers on the stage...
We'll decorate the stage
with diyas all over!
On the invitation,
we'll have the photo that we took!
The one with you, me and shalini...
But, Guru ji...
I have already decided the bit
I'm going to perform.
Wow! You have decided that as well!
What is it?
Have you forgotten?
You promised me right here,
when I was a child.
'Kaadambari Katha'
No, Sitara.
Don't perform 'Kaadambari Katha'?
What happened, Guru ji?
You do like Kaadambari Katha' right?
Why are you asking me not to do it?
Sitara... That story is ominous to us.
Whoever does it,
gets cursed in one way or another...
That is the reason Shalini lost her life!
What's the connection between Shalini
dying and 'Kaadambari Katha'?
Look here. I'm your Guru.
You must do as I say.
That's how it is done.
But, the debut is mine.
Every dancer has the right
to choose the bit they want!
Why don't I get that?
I will only do Kaadambari Katha' Guru ji!
I don't believe in curses and such.
What's up with these people dude?
Man this place look amazing!
Hey!
How's that girl doing?
How's he teaching...
Hi!
Have you recognized me?
What? Don't tell me you forgot!
It was you right, who told me
to come to the dance school!
Gangadhar!
Tell me ma'am.
Ask this man what he needs.
What's with this girl?
Doesn't she know how to smile?
It's time for the
Grand Master to arrive...
She's worried whether she would get
selected to perform her debut performance.
What's a debut performance?
How do I say it...
Yeah! It's similar to how you
get called up on stage...
...and receive a certificate
upon completing your studies.
Uh... A Convocation?
Yes. Kind of like that...
That is referred to as a Debut
Performance in our culture.
Yeah, but why worry about it?
I'm sure she'll pass with flying colors.
No doubt!
Your training starts from tomorrow,
You can leave for the day.
Please sir!
Give us one opportunity sir!
See, dance is something you learn
with discipline, which you lack.
Please leave.
Greetings, Guru ji!
Greetings...
Please sit...
Father, these 10 specimen are
unable to learn how to dance...
They are of no use, beyond hindering
the reputation of our school.
Which is why I've decided
to send them back home.
Hmm... What else?
If you'd let us know who is up
for their Debut Performance,
we'll take care of the arrangements.
This time.
Give it to Vaishnavi...
Guru ji!
You said it would be my turn this time?
Not now.
Maybe later.
Can you tell me
where I'm lagging, at least?
It doesn't make any sense...
Sitara...
you're very impatient.
Great things take time to happen...
You still have a lot to learn.
What? It was you who said
I learn everything perfectly!
Performing is just a part of it,
you should also be able to teach
people how to dance.
Can you teach them how to dance?
OK, guruji... I'll teach them
and prove myself.
Shiva Shivaaya...
Excuse me.
Sitara!
Sitara! You don't need to worry at all!
I'm telling you, you're the best
dancer among everyone here!
Look, I'm very frustrated.
Don't annoy me...
You're such a short-tempered person...
Hey!
Why can't youtry being calm for a change?
First of all, why do I even
need to speak with you?
You're not my friend,
neither are you a relative of mine...
You're not even a student here...
Yes...
I came here to join the dance school.
What? You.
Uh... No him...
Not me... this guy.
Yeah... him!
Yes. Me. I want to join here, sitara.
You guys are so confused...
Just leave this place
if you're not serious.
It's not like that Sitara...
What's happening here?
These people are bothering sitara,
in the name of the dance school.
You have to approach me
to learn dance, not her.
Uh... you guys just assigned
her to teach a batch right!
If we learn along with them,
it'll be easier for all of us.
It's not acceptable. Please leave.
Sir! What happened?
You're thinking about the easier
way out even before getting in...
You don't have the right to learn dance.
Sir, stop being so defensive about it.
It's just dance, right?
I'll try to learn whatever I can...
How much fee do you charge?
I'll pay you in advance!
You ignorant fool! Get out!
Hari.
Calm down.
What happened?
Namaste sir!
My name's Rohit.
I came from Hyderabad.
I want to learn dance from you, sir.
OK, learn.
Dad, if we just let random people learn,
the value of this craft
will be diminished.
If they learn well, the value of
the art will increase tenfold,
But no matter what,
the art will never go to waste.
Sitara, tomorrow's an auspicious day...
Arrange the necessary items
to perform the pooja.
Thank you sir.
Hey, Sitara.
Can we at least talk now?
Gangadhar,
check what items we need for the pooja.
Go and get your own items tomorrow.
I got all the items you asked for.
Oh...
It's very nice right?
Early morning,
at such an awesome location...
Talking to you peacefully...
"Let it go, Let it go...
Let you life flow..."
Can you sing as well?
Let's begin our first step.
Everyone, open your legs...
Sit in 'The Aramandi' posture.
Chin up.
A wide smile...
Ready...
[SINGING RYTHMIC PATTERNS]
One.
Two...
Three...
Four
[SINGING RYTHMIC PATTERNS]
Litle smile.
Teacher!
- I got it.
- Good.
Practice this step for a week.
A week?
Oh, do you need more time?
I guess a week is enough, thank you...
He thinks this is easy.
How do you do a single
step for a whole week?
I know it... she's doing it on purpose.
It's true though... We have to
practice a single step for one week.
What? For real?
Yup...
How long have you been here?
It's been 2 months...
So... you learn about 8 steps right?
No bro... Just 6 because...
They made me do that one step.
For 3 weeks because I couldn't
get it right to save my life...
3 weeks is a very long
time for a single step...
Hey!
Monitor the class.
OK sister.
Do you remember what we have to discuss?
Salutations sir.
Greetings...
Let's consider everyone's opinion
before taking the decision.
Everyone please maintain silence.
This gathering is to decide who takes
up the responsibility to organise...
The krishnashtami festival
that is coming up...
After we've all discussed...
We've decided to hand over the
responsibility to Guru Ji.
This is unfair! The rest
of us deserve a chance...
The same old dance for
the past fifteen years.
The audience are really
fed up of watching...
Guru ji! If you perform something new,
by all means do it,
Or give the rest of us a chance!
Will you do It?
No need to ask him...
I've been seeing those dances since
my brother was a ward member!
He went on to become a
sarpanch and is now the MLA!
States are being divided and
even the government is changing...
But there's no change to be
found yet in his dance!
There's truth to what he said...
Would you consider doing
something new this time?
I apologise.
I can only do what im capable of...
I don't mind if you don't like it...
Let them have it if they wish...
Stop right there.
Greetings sir!
Guru ji is mourning the death of his wife,
Let him have this satisfaction at least.
Not just that, till he's alive...
He'll be doing it!
This...
Is my decision!
Even this time, we'll be doing the
Main performance thiskrishnashtami...
The entire responsibility
of that is now yours.
I'm on it, Dad.
Your performance needs to be much better.
You go there and show me a concept.
Then I'll think about
your wild card entry.
Guru ji!
I need a small help...
There's a competition
I have to win at all costs!
So, if you give me a cassette
from your collection...
I'll transform it to a western style!
It'll surely be a big hit!
Alright.
Dad what is this?
You allowed him to learn...
not to alter it!
You're mistaking me!
I won't spoil its essence.
Just give it a makeover.
Who the hell do you think you are?
How dare you disrespect our
culture and look down on us?
What gives you the right?
Why are you obsessed with these rights?
Why do we need to have these rights?
You do need it! For everything...
You need to be well
accomplished or well learnt...
To have the right to speak about it!
Have you even attended
a single class properly?
OK, so what? I have to learn
the classes properly... right?
Not just learning... Mastering it!
Okay. I'll do it.
Will you give me then?
If you have what it takes,
you will obtain what you work for.
Go...
OK, Guru ji...
Let's give him a chance.
Sitara...
Take a look at this
casette and divide it...
OK
Sitara...
I've been observing you since many days,
you look a little gloomy.
Is it about your debut performance?
Sitara, don't worry.
In the upcoming performance...
Of Radha Gopala,
I'll give you the lead role.
Make sure you mesmerize everyone!
Dad will definitely change his mind.
Thank you very much for
understanding my position!
I'll definitely work hard and
make you and guru ji proud!
One more thing... Sitara...
Did I say something wrong about Rohit?
No. What you said was correct.
He lacks the discipline
and commitment to learn.
At-least you understood me well.
Those cassette's shouldn't
fall in Rohit's hands...
For that...
Can you not complete his training?
Sit like this...
1... 2...
1... 2... 3...
Hey! How many times do I have to tell you?
What do you think of yourself?
What are you doing?
What are you both doing?
Hand me that stick over there...
Hey... 1... 2... 3...
Stand erect.
Lift your leg up, like this...
Hey!
You can't even get one step right!
Hey... Hey...
Stop! What is this?
You overgrown manchild!
This looks more like
you're sweeping roads!
Are you drunk?
I've been seeing you from 4 days...
There's absolutely no improvement in you.
Do it all over again!
Gangadhar!
Where is everyone?
Over there... they're playing something.
Hey...
What's all this?
Do you have sense?
Why aren't you ready for your exam yet?
Guru ji will arrive at any moment now!
Because of you, I might lose my chance!
Do the Wall-Chair position.
Count to 50 without moving.
Sitara...
If you move, it goes up to a 100.
What's with these punishments, Sitara?
I don't need to explain it to you.
Don't try to give me
suggestions in everything.
Where are your anklets?
I was in a hurry and it slipped my mind.
How are you so careless, Rohit?
I'm not able to understand.
Why are you getting so worked up
over such a small thing, Sitara?
OK, give me your anklets.
Give me my anklets.
One should maintain their
own set of anklets.
Are you serious?
Does each set sound different
or something?
Shut up!
The sound of these anklets
is like a weapon...
You must always be armed with it.
Similarly each person
should have their own pair.
You go and get your anklets first.
Go!
Greetings, Guru ji!
Please sit.
Begin...
Everyone sit in "Aramandi' position."
1... 2... 3...4
Four of you, come forward!
Good.
1... 2... 3...4
It's nice.
I'm very pleased.
Everyone did a great job!
You've learn't well.
Well done.
If you perform in front of 10 people,
it stops there.
But, if you prepare 10 performers,
the art reaches many more souls.
You taught them very well!
Guru ji!
I taught them as I promised.
Will you let me perform for
'Kaadambari Katha' now?
Sitara, please stop this.
Don't halt your debut performance.
You're not performing for
'Kaadambari katha'.
Even if this life ends.
As a sacrifice for my art.
This love has shed blood.
What are you up to, Sitara?
I have already told you,
not to perform the 'Kaadambari Katha'!
Even if this life ends.
As a sacrifice for my art.
"This love has shed blood.."
I'm insisting you not to do it.
Why are you being so adamant?
As a child, you had promised me
I'd get to do "Kaadambari katha'"
as my debut performance.
Wasn't that why I had learn
dance in the first place?
How can I just do some other story?
You were a child when I told you.
But, now I don't even remember the story!
I lost the book too.
I remember it, Guru ji!
I can visualize every
single bit of that story!
I'll tell it.
You just provide the requirements.
Sitara!
Listen to me.
- Leave it.
- Leave it?
You can't leave something
that's chosen you.
Please think about it once.
How did you come across
the diary in the first place?
Why did you tell me?
Why am I not able to forget it?
There must be a reason behind this.
Think about it, Guru ji!
Kaadambari wants her story
to be told through us!
Today, if we are dancing...
It is because of Kaadambari.
Guru ji has arrived.
- The dance troupe is also here.
Greetings, Guru ji!
Come inside.
This is a very special programme.
They conduct it every year!
Who does all these arrangements?
The arrangements are done right?
That dancer girl is here, dude!
Yeah, brother!
Designs are so great.
Hey dancer!
Dancer girl, O dancer girl...
Will you dance with me?
You make me feel alive, I just
need to have you for myself!
Shall I?
You look like a loaded gun when angry!
Make it fast!
Sister, she's ready!
I hope hari is ready...
Sitara!
Everything fine?
Yes... everything is ready...
Call them when they're ready.
It's getting late.
OK.
Sitara.
I was afraid to let you
do the kaadambari katha,
Because I was afraid it might harm you!
But, we can't stop now...
People deserve to know
the Kaadambari Katha.
People need to know the truth!
I've decided we'll complete
the tale together.
After today's performance,
I'll announce your debut on stange!
Shubham.
Thank you very much!
Let's do her debut performance
on this stage as well!
Sitara... Make sure I get that contract!
Sir! The photo with you
and her was amazing!
You're the talk of the
town right now, trust me!
Really! Thanks to the almighty...
They're telling the Kaadambari katha,
again?
Kaadambari katha?
It's been 20 years so,
they might've forgotten about it.
Veerabhadra...
I don't know what you're going to do.
This performance needs to be stopped
and Guru ji needs to suffer for it!
Leave all this aside...
Kill that Sitara.
Come on.
Yes!
See that. You got what you wanted
because you listened to me.
But, this is still not enough...
There's a lot more to do.
The debut performance
should be more than perfect,
because it's not just about you...
It's about me as well.
I'm responsible for you guys, after all.
OK. OK... carry on.
You did good.
Moving him away from the exam.
He's like a leech among us...
Very dangerous.
Especially for you.
Hey!
Guru ji is about to announce
my debut performance!
Congratulations, Sitara!
Yes, he'll announce it
after this performance...
Yeah, give me a minute.
I'm getting my chance!
Congratulations teacher.
Take this.
Rohit.
Aren't you happy for me?
Trampling on my efforts
and succeeding alone...
Isn't real success!
Hey!
How dare you talk to me like that?
This is how I talk.
What are you, my friend?
A relative?
Or my dance teacher?
Sitara...
You can't accept your own mistakes,
and you're blaming it one me?
Lacking dedication and discipline
is your mistake, not mine.
Coming to class on time is
different from having dedication.
Listen...
How can I stay here the whole month,
without any dedication?
Hey, you've just been here a month!
We've been here for years!
Do you know why I got the opportunity?
Because I followed the rules properly!
Hey, girls!
Have I ever been late to the class?
No, sister!
That's my discipline.
I've followed the footsteps of guru ji,
without straying from the path!
That's my dedication.
I've practised each step
for about 50,000 times.
That's my hard work.
Because I was able to walk on this path,
while obeying the rules.
Now, I feel satisfied!
Sister! Hari sir is about to arrive,
let's practice till then.
Come sister.
Hey!
OK.
You do the dance you've practised...
I'll do what I do best.
Let's see whose performance is better.
No way am I dancing next to you.
What? Oh, you're scared?
- Gangadhar!
- Sister!
Take Natuuvangam.
Let's begin.
Brundhavanilo yamuna thatilo
Nandanandnudi nagumomunakai.
Kshama sundaruni sangatyamukai.
Alasina Kanulatho.
Solisina thanuvutho.
Virhasokamuna Hrudayam munigi.
Vechivunna I radhani chusi.
Vanakusumale Vagachina vela.
Vennela nisilo kalichin vela.
Kilakila guvvalu kalavarapadutu.
Vishada cgayalu alimina vela.
Won't you look at me Madhava?
Why are you indifferent?
Why aren't you responding?
Won't you come nearer and nearer to me?
Enough of your mischief... naughty Krishna
I will show you the wonders of
this village, will you come?
I was the one who showcased this
entire universe in my mouth.
If I offer you my cute girlish
beauty, will you come?
Brindavan is filled with
beauties which can outdo you.
It's enough, don't look down on me.
I am the girl who associated willingly.
Why all these antics of
yours in my company?
You won't be able to reach
this magician, Madhava anymore.
Won't you look at me Madhava?
Why are you indifferent?
Why aren't you responding?
Won't you come nearer and nearer to me?
Enough of your mischief... naughty Krishna.
Come, come Krishna... Radha Krishna.
The milk, butter and
everything is yours dear.
Get away Radha... all these
cows are owned by me.
Gopala! Shall I rhythmically
dance with you?
I make the heaven and earth dance to
my tunes, you and I needn't dance.
Gopala! I will build a dazzling,
shimmery temple for you.
I am the one who lifted Govardhana
hill, I don't need temples.
Won't you look at me Madhava?
Why are you indifferent?
Why aren't you responding?
Won't you come nearer and nearer to me?
Enough of your mischief... naughty Krishna.
Enough is enough then, don't come
near me, you will be insulted.
It is because of you that
this girl's heart is wounded.
Don't try to trap me your
naughty naughty acts of magic.
Don't push this innocent
Radha away from you.
Enough is enough then, don't come
near me, you will be insulted.
The direction for me
is the banks of Yamuna.
Enough is enough then, don't come
near me, you will be insulted.
You will never have Radha heart of love.
There is no Madhava without Radha.
Can he stay without Radha.
Radha is the symbol of selfless love.
This Krishna is always...
...a slave of such love.
This Krishna is always
a slave of such love.
Oh my god...
Wow!
Absolutely amazing!
I expected to see something new,
But what I've seen here is pure!
Hey, what are you doing here?
It's not how you think it is, sir.
We're practising for the dance program.
What's happening here?
Oh Lord!
This girl took the
opportunity when you left...
and kissed some other guy.
You need to be more careful, am I right?
Oh God! I never thought
I'd humiliate you all!
Just leave it, priest...
Being upset won't change
things in any way.
You portrayed dance
in such a horrible way!
More than you, I need to blame
your guru who taught you all this!
Look! Guru ji has nothing to do
with this... leave him out of this!
He didn't do it personally...
but made these people do it!
Such a clever fox, he is!
What's all this?
What happened?
Shastri ji! Look what's happening here...
They're altering the
history and portraying.
Lord krishna in a disrespectful manner!
We won't tolerate any
insult upon our lord!
We'll kill them!
Yes...
You dorn the attire of Radha, and
behave so shamelessly?
Are you even a lady?
Stop... Stop.
Let's not squabble amongst ourselves...
It's better we halt this performance.
Sire... I've invested a lot on this event!
If you halt the event...
I'll be in a huge loss...
You're concerned about your
personal monetary gain,
while I'm thinking about the
reputation of this village!
Hey! Stop all this...
Stop everything.
Sir... Sir...
Guru ji!
Please do something and make it happen!
Let's go and talk to Shastri ji once...
Finally, you got what you wanted!
What are you ogling at!
Drag her out of there!
Go... Go!
Send the rest away! Fast!
Let us talk first.
Hey!
If he denies, we'll leave respectfully.
Who the hell are you to come in between?
Hey! This matter concerns
the reputation of the village!
You already heard the man,
why are you still here?
Send them away!
Remove all.
I'll sort this out right away...
if you give me that kiss.
Saw that?
Have you?
I just asked her,
what made you insult the village and...
She hit me!
Such people...
They need to be taught a proper lesson!
Yes... Yes.
You are the reason for this.
Please understand...
Please listen to me!
Wait... Please wait.
Hey!
Let's go Sitara!
Come on.
Let's go.
Stop right there!
Shastri ji!
You need to understand,
why I'm telling this.
They have broken the stage...
Hey! Catch those buggers!
Sitara, Come!
Catch them over there.
Sitara, let's go...
take care.
Sitara, come fast!
Don't just stand there, they'll kill us!
Come fast!
Damn!
I'll take care of them the next
time they set foot on this land.
See that.
That's what happens when you
mess with people's beliefs...
A man doesn't submit to god...
but to the belief of god!
And even god himself can't
take it away from them...
let alone, your dance!
Rohit.
Anu, please...
You need to be the one comforting her...
Which is why I brought her here.
Sitara.
Don't worry.
Wear a fresh pair of clothes...
Here... take these.
That room, over there.
Take a right here...
Stop it here...
If I take her back now,
I'm afraid someone would harm her.
Uncle, have some tea.
- Aunty...
- Thank you, dear...
What are you studying?
I'm pursuing my MBA in the
same college as Rohit.
See, if you had listened to us,
you would've been studying like them.
It's not the end of the world, uncle!
She can study even now...
We can't even take her to our village,
how will she do her MBA?
It's not a problem aunty!
Actually, join her in our college!
However, the admission
are open in two weeks...
Till then, she can stay with me.
That's actually a good idea.
Sitara, you've pursued
what you wanted till now...
It's time you listen to us.
Stay here and study MBA.
We'll send you all your
certificates and clothes.
OK?
- Give it to her.
- OK, aunty.
I'll call you as soon as I reach there.
Greetings, guru ji.
Yes, greetings.
- How is Sitara?
- She's doing good.
She's staying at a friend of Revanth's.
Good for her...
It's better she stays there for a while.
We can bring her back once
things get sorted out.
No, sir.
She agreed to pursue MBA
and let go of dance.
Leaving dance?
How have you agreed to it?
She became a laughing stock because
of her passion towards dance.
Leave her now...
Sitara was born to dance!
She is too gifted to just let go of it...
Let me talk to her once...
Please wait! Don't call her.
You have lost your wife
because of this haste...
Pardon me.
We can't change what's happened...
We are trying to give her
the best life she can have.
Please don't call her
till she's done with her studies.
OK madam.
Sitara.
Instead of staying cooped up in this room,
come join us in the dance class.
Hey, Dinakar.
- Hi, bro.
- How are you?
All good.
Hey.
OK, Anu.
You both carry on.
I'll quickly change and come.
Come!
Dude, you'll fall!
Hey guys!
Hey! Hi!
So, she's Sitara.
Oh... Sitara!
By the way, nice hairstyle!
But, you just have one tuft.
While I've got 4 of them!
I'll cut them off, if you don't shut up.
Anyway, she's also a dancer.
Like... Classical.
Superb!
Wow! A Classical Dancer!
I'm a classical dancer as well!
Baby... Classical dance doesn't mean...
All of that!
It's very classy!
Oh my God, you're dress is so nice!
You're earrings are so pretty, so long!
You look so traditional!
By the way, have you done
your debut performance?
No!
I don't know how to dance!
Sitara!
What happened back there?
Rohit, I'm not able to do this...
I don't like it here...
I'll go back to my village.
I can understand what
you're going through.
But, look at the bright side...
Your parents have accepted it.
You're about to pursue your MBA.
You're starting a whole new life!
Have I asked for this new life?
I want my old one back...
I had a world where I belonged...
My dance...
OK, do that dance over here.
Here?
Without my guru ji, my dance school...
how can I do it?
Dance isn't confined
between those 4 walls,
It's within you.
It'll always be with you.
Come here.
Hey Ganapati! Get your
anklets ringing taitaitai
I will give you a good rhythm,
dance to that ditamditai.
Diditarigida Diditarigida
Diditarigida diditai
[SINGING RYTHMIC PATTERNS]
Won't the air that doesn't flow
through a flute have music?
Won't the irregularly drizzled
raindrops have dance in them?
For once, visualise from
a source called heart.
Remove those veils of the
heart and come beyond.
Won't the streams flowing
towards lowlands have grace?
Won't the structure less
lightninghave a beauty?
Hey Ganapati! Get your
anklets ringing taitaitai
I will give you a good rhythm,
dance to that ditamditai
[SINGING RYTHMIC PATTERNS]
Won't the air that doesn't flow
through a flute have music?
Won't the irregularly drizzled
raindrops have dance in them?
For once, visualise from
a source called heart.
Remove those veils of the
heart and come beyond.
Won't the streams flowing
towards lowlands have grace?
Won't the structure less
lightning have a beauty?
Is the peacock dancing for
someone's appreciation?
Do flowers bloom for the
sake of a single person?
The bird which flew high won't stop,
assuming the dark of sky to be a limit.
Now! Stop restricting this art that
is flowing from within the heart.
Even a tiny anklet's bell that falls
down, will ring breaking the silence.
Don't stop your step.
Can't you arrive, erasing?
Even the dwindling feet of a
child can teach dancelessons.
If you realise that, won't every
move of your body become a posture?
Just like the infinite sea,
all your hidden talents.
Imbibe them into every cell of
yours and do a joyous dance.
If the moon, assuming that the world
lies behind the clouds in the sky,
And sleeps, then won't all its
moonlight end in darkness?
Being mistaken that the art lies
behind the pillars of buildings.
Don't stop your steps and
dance beyond boundaries.
Hey Ganapati! Get your
anklets ringing taitaitai
I will give you a good rhythm,
dance to that ditamditai
[SINGING RYTHMIC PATTERNS]
Guys! This dance competition
is my last chance...
If I miss this opportunity,
I would have to stop pursuing dance.
I'll always be reminded
of what a failure I am...
Don't say that, Rohit.
You have so many people to support you!
I will also help you.
What? You?
But, you don't know
western dance, right?
So?
I can help him with my classical dance.
- Classical dance?
- Hmm!
Actually... Guys...
That's actually a good idea!
Instead of the usual Hip-hop,
jazz and salsa...
Let's hit them with a fusion of
classical dance and western dance!
It'll be very fresh!
I'll do one thing, Rohit.
First, I'll teach you all the
basics of classical dance...
No! No! No!
Please, my lady, don't!
Guys an Idea.
I designed a crazy costume.
Completely classical on the bottom.
Top western jacket.
If we do in this way no one
will give chance to us.
Not like this.
I'll play some music...
let's start dancing!
Let's see... We might get some new ideas!
What are you doing, Sitara?
We are dancing much better than you!
If I had a troupe of classical dancers...
I would've been better at this!
Sitara, don't worry...
I'll take care of it, trust me.
Start.
1... 2... 3... 4
Sitara!
Classical dancers.
She's Lakshmi. Senior.
Really!
Whoooo!
Superb, Rohit!
Guys! We absolutely loved the fusion
between western and classical dance!
But, what about the concept?
What do we do now?
Conducting festivals in this temple
each year, has been our tradition!
Only Popular dance schools
can perform this year...
Ayyappa, please read out the list
of school performing this year.
First one, 'Kalabhaarati'
Second, 'Naatyalayam'
Third, 'Saraswati Dance Academy'
Fourth, 'Naatya Bharatiya Dance School'
Five, 'Shakti Academy'
I hope you all co-operate
with us for this.
Forgive me,
but can I know why our school's
name isn't included in the list?
The whole village hasn't forgotten the
humiliation your school has caused!
They probably don't want
that to be repeated!
Holding the entire school responsible
for one dancer's actions is unfair!
You have brought shame upon our village's
reputation with a single performance,
is that fair?
What reputation are you talking about?
All these years, we held up the
reputation of this village.
Stop this squabble!
We don't need to debate amongst ourselves.
Hari babu, we have noticed a lack
of novelty in your performances.
We've decided to give a
chance to fresh faces!
If novelty is what you want,
I'll give it to you.
I'll boost the reputation
of not just our college...
But the whole village!
Hey.
[MOBILE BUSY NOTIFICATION]
- What's up?
If everything were normal, I would've
had my debut performance by now.
I would have performed
'Kaadambari Katha' as well...
Yeah...
What's this about 'Kaadambari Katha'...
What's the story behind it?
OK, I'll tell you the 'Kaadambari Katha'.
During the British rule, there was a
dancer by the name of Kaadambari.
She fell in love with a british
officer, named Francis...
Awesome.
The story is superb, Sitara.
Why don't we choose this concept
for the US Dance competition?
Are you serious? The Kaadambari Katha?
For the American competition?
Yeah...
Rohit... I actually started
dancing to help you out.
But, in this journey, I'm able to
look at my dance in a new light!
You were right, Rohit.
Even though the form of dance is
different, the soul is the same!
With that soul instilled in the Kaadambari
Katha, we'll complete our journeys!
Instead of everything in a
single raaga, let's split it up...
Swarakalpanas come after Charanas...
Oh god!
This dress isn't comfortable
while dancing.
We need some sculptures on this pillar.
OK...
There needs to be this much distance
between the Garbha-gudi and the Main door.
This way.
Attack!
The labour charges have gone up
drastically over these years...
Hello Mr.Prakash.
Welcome, sir, Welcome.
How is our performance?
Shall I be honest?
Yes, please.
It's not that great...
What's not working?
The subject or the dance?
Nothing like that...
The grandeur we witnessed when you
performed with Sitara is missing...
Just leave her...
I'm enduring all this because of her...
Be careful, hari sir.
You don't want to repeat the
mistake you made the last time.
What is she troubling you?
I'll talk, this time.
No, hari.
Don't be hasty.
She did no wrong willingly.
A mistake just... happened.
Sitara is like our own family.
She might also be regretting it...
It's not that dad.
Not on the phone...
Meet her in person and try to talk to her.
[VEHICLES HONKING]
[INDISTINCT CHATTER]
Hello.
Hello. Sitara!
This is Anushree speaking.
I'm Sitara's roommate.
Can you pass the phone to her?
Actually she isn't here right now
and her phone is with me.
Oh, I just arrived here to meet Sitara.
OK, you do one thing.
I'll send you the address of a coffee shop.
You wait there, she'll be coming over.
OK...
is it OK...
OK
You can meet her.
OK bye.
Sure.
Dude, how much longer?
Sitara and all will be here, anytime!
Why can't you people get
things done on time!
Make it quick.
Stay on hold.
Hey, you're hari right?
Yeah, how do you know?
I was the one you spoke with on phone.
I sent you the address, right?
Yeah, that part's fine,
but how do you know me by my name?
Come on yaar! Nobody from here
dresses up so traditionally!
OK, but where is Sitara?
You're right on time! Come.
Is the cake ready?
Please make it fast.
Guys, Guys, Guys.
They'll be here any minute!
Give it here.
Everybody, stick to the plan!
No one should forget.
They're here, now go! Hide somewhere.
Hari! Hide! Get down.
Quickly! Come come come.
Shh! We're giving a surprise to Sitara!
She's coming.
Where are we going?
I'll tell you, wait.
You'll see for yourself.
Surprise!
Happy birthday!
Woohoo!
Happy birthday to you!
Thank you.
Happy birthday.
Happy birthday to you, Sitara!
Hari sir?
How come, you're here?
It's your birthday, right?
That's why he came!
OK, guys. Come.
Let's have the cake. Come on.
Come on. Come.
Woohoo.
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday, Dear Sitara!
Happy birthday, Dear Sitara! Woohoo.
Hair sir.
Thank you so much for coming to visit.
I had some work here... just wanted
to drop by and see how you're doing.
Guys, I have some good news.
The judge really liked the video we sent.
We're selected for the US Competition!
We're flying to New York!
Woohoo!
Yes!
We did it!
Guys!
Rohit, we must tell this to hari sir!
Guru ji will be very pleased
to know about this!
Yeah. Our team got selected
for the US Dance competition.
We're flying to America!
Downtown!
Front page in the New York Magazine!
We're gonna rock!
Do you know, we're taking your Kaadambari
Katha to the International level!
Guess who did the choreography?
Sitara!
Is the date fixed?
Yeah bro. 10th of the next month.
Cool bro.
Really?
We don't have enough time!
No problem, we'll rock!
Sitara, I'll be leaving.
I have some work.
Thank you very much for visiting,
Hari sir.
I'm feeling very happy.
I want to come back to our village
and apologize to Guru ji...
You need to help me...
Don't worry. I'll take care of it.
Nobody's liking my performances,
but Sitara's taking her dance to America.
According to the calendar,
the most auspicious date
to conduct the festival...
in our temple is, 10th and
16th of the next month.
Which date among them should we fix?
10th seems to be very less time to
prepare all the arrangements...
I guess,
we should go for 16th as the date.
Not 16th, let's do it on 10th!
Let's conduct the festival
on the 10th of next month.
Because that was the day, the
temple gates were reopened...
and we got our sacred texts back!
Hopefully, we'll get our god's
blessings if we do it on that day.
Auspicious!
That's nice to hear.
So, it's settled then.
We'll also get the favour of gods!
OK, let's plan accordingly.
Shubham!
Yeah... that's fine...
Sitara!
Pack this.
Hari sir!
Sitara... I've found a way
to get you back here.
- Really?
- Yes, Sitara.
You coming to our village, Guru ji
forgiving you... Everything will happen.
But how, hari sir?
I'll be performing during this
year's temple festivities.
Instead of doing something I want,
I thought we'd do the 'Kadambari Katha'.
I'll safely escort you till the stage,
don't worry.
Once the performance begins,
nobody would stop us.
You can fascinate everyone
out there with your dance...
and prove them wrong about you.
I'll stand with you.
I'll make sure everyone forgives you.
I'm very excited upon
hearing this from you.
This day, is not too far from now, Sitara.
We're conducting our festivities,
on the 10th of next month.
10th?
Yes, what's wrong?
I'll be going to America
on that day sir...
This is your last chance at redemption,
we can't do much if you let it slip.
What? Are you lost for words
because of how grateful you are?
Rohit stood by me when
everyone let me down...
I can't just leave him when he needs me.
Please forgive me.
You're so stubborn! Your wish.
Hey. What happened?
- Nothing.
- Everything all right?
Sure?
Hey, did you know this?
Sitara will be performing in the US.
Entirely choreographed by her!
Really great, right?
Performing in the US.
Entirely choreographed by her!
Do I do it again?
You'll have to do it the
third time as well.
Third time as well?
OK
What happened, hari sir?
Nothing... you continue.
Guys, look here.
We got the passports.
Woohoo!
Today is the 10th.
Sitara will be on her way to America.
I have to dance in the temple festivities.
If something goes wrong and
the people dislike it...
It would've been nice
to have Sitara here...
I still have time.
I need to get her back!
It's getting late, make it fast.
[MOBILE RINGING]
Catch these. Someone is calling me.
Careful.
Oh God! I still have to pack all these...
Hey, Sitara!
I should've been more patient, I'm sorry.
So, when are you leaving today?
3:00 a.m. early morning.
You were truly blessed!
Our performance is at 7:00.
If you leave as soon as the performance
is finished, you can make it on time.
I'll personally see
you off to the airport.
Really?
I've been waiting since forever
for Guru ji's blessing!
I'll definitely come!
OK.
[CHUCKLES] Rohit!
What?
I'm going to go back to
the village and perform!
OK...
That's... That's great. But how?
How did this miracle happen?
- Guru ji?
- No, Hari sir.
Hari?
Yes.
The temple festivities happen every year!
He planned for us to do
a performance together!
He'll even send a video!
I Just have to go in,
do the performance and come back!
Rohit, the people there,
Guru ji, will accept me right?
What acceptance?
Have you forgotten what happened?
Pack this.
Please understand.
I'll do the performance and come!
Please...
OK, when is this?
Tonight, 7 p.m.
What?
What? Today?
Yes...
Have you completely lost it?
How can you even think that
when we have a flight tonight?
Have you lost your mind?
Erasing Borders... New York. Contract?
Have I told you I won't come?
The program is at 7...
I'll come back on time
to catch the flight!
Yeah, because the people there
will welcome you with open arms,
and let you leave whenever you please!
Hell no. They'll kill you
right then and there.
Please, let me go!
Enough, Sitara!
Stop this now.
I'll not allow you to go back, that's it.
Sitara...
Do you really need to go?
How can you be so selfish?
Who is being selfish here?
I always think about the both of us.
But you're the one just
thinking about yourself.
I'll be on time, don't worry.
Guys, I don't know how...
At any circumstance,
we're going to the US.
- OK?
- OK...
Shreya. If Sitara isn't coming,
you'll be replacing her.
OK, I'll do it.
OK, guys. Let's finish the packing.
Mom!
Yes, dear...
Have you finished all the
arrangements to go to America?
No, mom.
I'm coming to the village.
To perform at the temple festivities.
What? Coming to the village?
These people will kill you on sight!
Nothing will happen, mom.
Hari sir told me he'd
take care of everything.
Don't be crazy, Sitara!
I can't explain it to you, mum.
I'll talk to you later, bye.
Sitara!
Nobody saw you, right?
Nobody did. But why did
you make me come here?
Everyone would be alert,
if you came right into the village.
Nothing will go wrong, right sir?
Most importantly, I have to
reach the airport on time.
Sitara. I'll take care of it,
you don't have to worry.
Everyone, step outside for a moment.
Sitara.
See, I've kept my word.
Can anyone else do this?
I'll reach the airport on time, right?
Sitara... Concentrate on
the performance first.
OK.
Yes, OK.
Greetings guruji.
Hari sir! Guru ji is here!
Sitara, get ready to change your life!
The people, Guru ji!
They'll immerse you in praise.
You always wanted to play
the role of a host, right?
Yes.
Will you play my host?
Well, of course! If guru ji
will accept me, then surely!
Sitara. I don't think you
understand what I mean...
Will you be my host!
Not just my host, but my life-partner.
I want to marry you.
Hari sir, please forgive me.
I never thought of you like that.
Then who will be more suited? That Rohit?
I'm over her risking it all for you,
while you're thinking about that guy?
Isn't it because of him,
that all of this happened?
It's not his fault, sir.
Whatever he did, was for me.
What did he do?
He destroyed the only dream
you grew up to achieve.
He insulted guru ji!
Brought shame upon all of us!
Despite all that, I risked my
life to get you all the way here!
Tell me now! Me or him?
Forgive me.
Sitara! Wait a minute.
I lost myself there,
let's focus on the performance first.
The announcement is already
done, don't overthink it.
We enjoyed 'Natya Mayuri Kala Brundham's
amazing performance.
Up next, we have Vidyalaya Natya
Kala Brundham's performance.
Their performances are always
magical and captivating!
But, this year, Guru ji's son, Hari, is
on a quest to carry his father's legacy!
Let's see what they have
choreographed for us!
We hope this performance
will be beyond expectations!
Let's welcome them on stage.
How dare you reject me...
I'll make sure you'll never set
foot in this village again.
Catch her now!
Sitara... what are you doing here?
Our performance is in due time...
See, everyone's waiting.
Please get down from the stage, Sitara.
Where can you go? Look at them,
waiting to gobble you up.
You won't even cross this village,
let alone reach the airport.
Sitara,
I'm telling you... Please go!
I won't leave this stage
untill Guru ji forgives me!
See that!
That's what I've been
trying to tell you all...
One dancer's mistake shouldn't hinder
the whole school's reputation...
Look at her now, she wants to perform
on behalf of our school and...
earn laurels!
Tell me! What should I do?
Leave, Sitara!
Get down!
Sitara, get down.
These aren't good men.
You have infected this
village like a plague!
Why have you come back?
To insult us further?
Leave!
Hey, it's OK. It's me, Rohit.
Rohit!
Nothing will happen to you...
I'm here now.
It's OK, Sitara.
Sorry.
I'm here, now.
Hey! Sitara...
- Sorry...
- It's OK!
You tried to warn me,
but I didn't listen...
It's OK...
Wipe your tears.
What is it you want?
You seek Guru ji's forgiveness, right?
OK. Sitara... Listen to me.
It's time to prove yourself.
OK?
To these people, this guy and everyone.
Perform the 'Kadambari Katha',
right here... right now!
Let's go Sitara!
Come on!
Let's go guys.
Wait... Just listen to me.
Through our dance, we'll be
showcasing the story of your village!
Are you thinking, what do
we know about your village?
There's one story,
which none of you knows.
This is 'Kadambari Katha'
This is the Tale of Kaadambari.
The story of dance itself.
Just like Blossoming smiles
tuning into Swaras.
Just the way steps are
rhythmically tuned to Tala.
Just like bouncing waves.
The rhythm of heart beat has risen.
Piece of heart beat has sprinkled.
Sitdown everybody.
Sitdown.
Their strength is their
tradition and culture!
Their art unites them.
We need to destroy their
art, to establish our rule!
Let's appoint Francis to crush them!
British Honk attention.
Are these villagers jobless? They
are always into singing and dancing.
This is a mistake.
Here after, dance is banned.
Go and tell them in a way they understand.
I'm great Francis.
I work for country
I'll even sacrifice my life
I'll ravage the enemies.
There might be many countries
in this world.
But none of them can
compete with the Bristish.
It's an empire where the sun never sets.
The entire world is under us.
Warning...
Your tantrums will no
longer be entertained.
It's a crime to dance henceforth.
They burnt them all! How cruel!
Shut down this temple forever.
So sad...
Yes.
Why shouldn't I become a path to them?
I shall restore dance, its past glory.
I will write the future of dance.
It was written by Kaadambari.
Yes...
Yes... It was written by Kaadambari.
We thaught it was written God
but it was wrriten by Kaadhambari.
Yes...
This dance starts.
It's an offering to god.
The match is set between pitch and Dance.
For ultimate art begins here.
The earth itself has become the stage.
The sculptures have come forward as guests.
Mixing tempo in every step.
Feet is moving now.
The nature is blushing standing here.
It's a joy uttered by rhythm
who are you?
My name is Kaadambari.
Don't you know that dance
is illegal and shameful!
Do you know how pure dance is?
How dare you go against the law?
How dare you destroy our culture?
When the feet are dancing.
Will this nature not get delighted?
When she is tuning into our moves.
Our great culture and
tradition are prayer worthy.
If you watch it with your
heart, it'll touch your hearts.
Yes! That's what dance means. Amazing!
Super...
Francis was surprised to watch
to kadambari's dance greatness.
He realized that it was unfair on his part
and his countrymen's part to destroy dance
stood along with Kadambari to support her.
In that process, Francis
became close to Kadambari
and eventually fell in love with her.
Come with me, I'll show you a new world.
Come with me, I'll make you
the queen of the world.
Let's fly through the sky,
and glimpse the holy heaven.
Let's touch the summit of happiness,
and twirl around the world.
Come with me, as the world awaits us.
Leave this world and let's journey love.
Come with me, I'll show you
the wonders of this world.
Let's explore vivid natures
of dance around the world
and feast your eyes over many more visuals.
Come with me, as the universe awaits us.
Leave this world and let's journey love.
Come with me, as the universe awaits us
leave this world and let's journey love.
How can you tolerate such obscenity!
Do something! Stop this!
Since Kaadambari agreed
to his love proposal,
Francis wanted to marry her
and take her to England.
But, Kaadambari told she
wouldn't leave the temple
until she completes
writing the sacred texts
Francis respected her resolve and
asked to marry her in this temple.
All of this is false!
Absolutely fabricated!
Veerabhadra. Go and help Hari.
Kaadambari arrived at the temple in hopes
of getting married starting a new life.
But, the Britishers came to know of this,
surrounded the temple to end her life.
Veerabhadra!
Guru ji! You're crossing your limits.
Stop it!
Enough of your deception.
You changed the story of
our village to suit your need.
Kaadambari sacrificed for us all!
It's not just an act.
But an effort to bring out the truth!
See there!
Kaadambari! Come.
They came to know about us.
We need to leave at once!
Stop!
If we leave,
these texts will be destroyed.
And I won't let that happen.
It's OK, we can write it in England.
There is no assurance to my
Art in your country, Francis.
But, here. They'll stay safe inside the
temple no matter how many years pass.
You life is worth more than those texts!
My life will cease to have any
meaning if I fail to protect them.
Kaadambari, please try to understand me!
How can I protect you!
Francis, there's no one to
protect these texts, but me.
Francis. There's only one way out of this.
My death.
Kill me, Francis.
What are you saying, Kaadambari?
Yes.
If you kill me, you won't be suspected.
And they'll trust you.
Before they discover these texts,
distract them and close the temple gates!
Only then, can these texts
be protected till eternity.
I must sacrifice myself,
for the sake of dance.
Even if this life ends.
As a sacrifice for my art.
This love has shed blood.
As devotion towards my art.
At every corner of my heart
I've held you as my breath.
Even for greater good.
Love needs to collapse.
How can I burn my heart in this fire
and bury my hopes with it?
On the scars of my broken heart.
The chariot of hopes need to move on.
Give art a reason to live
and bless it like a Samaritan.
Let my wish turn into poison
and grant me demise.
I'm like a dove with a broken wing.
So how can I fly to my destination?
And now my shattered heart, in rebirth
I vow to dedicate it to you
[SHOT FIRED]
I sealed the gates of the temple,
to protect those scriptures
and give meaning to
Kaadambari's sacrifice.
I fabricated the story of
the Goddess for people
to be afraid to set
foot inside the temple.
If I told the truth, there won't
be any safety for those texts.
But, if I never told the truth, people
won't come to know about her sacrifice!
Which is why, I'm writing this
diary before leaving to England.
In hopes that, one day, people are aware
of the unsung warrior that is, Kaadambari.
Till date, we believed that those
texts were written by a goddess.
But that is totally false!
It was written by Kaadambari.
This diary is the proof for it.
Everyone know it's the work of the
goddess, who are you to deny it?
Not a goddess, but Kaadambari!
The glory of this temple is that
story and what we all believe in!
It's not belief, but a superstition.
Stop it! We can't tolerate you,
smearing the name of our goddess.
Oh no! What if the goddess
is angered by this?
Trustee sir.
It is our responsibility
to bring forth the tale
of kaadambari like we did
with her sacred texts!
See that.
The number of devotees keep
increasing day-by-day.
They believe that these texts were
given by the goddess herself.
Let it be belief or superstition.
But, it draws a lot of
people towards this temple
and with more people, I get more profits.
But, if people come to know
that it wasn't a goddess,
But a mere human who
wrote these scriptures.
Who would visit this temple?
What will the goddess be reduced to?
And the money would stop pooling for me.
Therefore,
let this tale be left unspoken.
I will tell people the truth
and put an end to this!
Really? How do plan on convincing
everyone with just this book.
How will you prove it?
People like you need proofs and evidence,
but for me, my dance will do the talking!
My dance, is your downfall.
'You'll give me the "Kaadambari Katha
for my debut performance, right?'"
'Surely, I will.'
'Guru ji!'
'Shalini ma'am has been bitten
by a snake near the well!'
How unfortunate!
People are believing that since your
wife disrespected the goddess herself,
she decided to punish her
in the form of a snake...
Do you believe in that?
Or maybe someone...
You wanted to bury the
superstition with your dance...
All you can do is bury your wife...
You performance was fabulous, dear.
You made us all teary eyed, wonderful!
You were my inspiration, right
from my childhood, Guru ji!
I wanted to be your host
and orchestrate new
dances, after shalini
ma'am passed away.
But, all I did was smear your name...
Please forgive me!
Why are you apologizing?
Look at your success!
You brought out the truth,
with your dance!
What about my debut performance?
A Debut performance better than this?
You told the 'Kadambari Katha'
with your dance!
Perhaps even I wouldn't have
told it so magnificently!
Sitara, it's time to leave.
Have a safe journey.
OK sir...
Kaadambari!
Please forgive me for calling you names!
You portrayal of kaadambari is life-like!
What are you saying? She's
Kaadambari herself, re-incarnated!
Kaadambari!