Cherry, Why did you bring me here?
Shit! I'm scared
wait and see
I will do triple loop jump
Ah... go ahead
Why did you bring cell phone?
Incase someone call
Who?
Is it Tum?
Have you ever felt, you didn't
want to pick up?
But want to know, is it him?
I did erase his name from my list
So I will forget he calls
You start again
This disease is an uncureable,
it always come and go
But this time is different
Why? you don't want to go
I did not say I did not want to go
Just ask beach again
It means you don't want to go
Do you know you have change?
First time I saw Noon
Noon did not act like this
What did I act?
Now, what do I do?
Before Noon can take care yourself
you can go anywhere alone
Later you stick to me like twin
Noon will go where ever I go
Noon wants to go some place,
Noon will make me go too
Noon, do you still remember
two circles story?
I think Noon cross the line
If you feel that way,
we should brake-up
It may be better that way
You think the string will tear down
Afraid
So you're not afraid
But if we can do the scariest thing
We don't have to scare anything forever
Noon, you talk like Plato with me
I want to go work, save money
and sightseeing abroad
My aunt lives in London
I did call, she should be able
to help
About your college
Don't worry, we will know
when the time come
You want to go with me
How can we live?
I don't know
I think we will have fun
Once in a life time
London, Paris
Vanice, Big Ben
Eiffel Tower, Stone Hedge
Gondola
Pizza Tower
We will not let other down, right
Go
DEAR GALILEO
Dad, Why Angoon not come to help you?
Ngoon
Angoon
I will help you, Dad
Why don't you use washing machine?
It cleaner with my hand wash
Machine can't complete
Tell me, you don't know how to use
You don't have to help me
Just go eat, food is on the table
Dad...
I was suspended one year from college
I want to go work, save money
and sightseeing Europe with Noon
I don't know how long but it
should be several months
How about your college?
If I have an opportunity,
I will stay longer
How come dad don't understand me?
Stop talking
Have you ever think?
I and mom worry about you, think
I know dad worry but
I go with Cherry
That why I worry
Just two girls, how can you survive
Dad
No
Dad, dad, do you belive me?
Don't say it
I won't harm myself
Anyway I will go
Your broading gate is E2
Go straight, turn right pass immigration
Thank you
Your welcome
Good luck
I did not dead yet, Kink
I don't know, I don't want you to go
Wait here I will be right back
Midnight,You should broad the plane
Dad, I have to say goodbye
Hey... Ngoon
Dad, you don't have to worry
When time come Noon will bring her back
Don't stick too much to your friend
Learn to buddy with dad
Don't play video game
all the time, understand
Cherry, I get inside first
Dad bye, Ngoon bye
You guys, I leave now
Come back soon, bye, bye
Bye, bye
I leave now, Dad
I can not call often
Leave now
This is dad
This time you go long time
Dad...
I have something to give you
I want to tell you
Becareful you might get sick
Go someplace, dress warm clothes
When you sleep, use warm blanket
Take care Noon
Take good care yourself
Don't think too much
Come Ngoon, take picture with me
You want too
No, not really
Not true
Cherry's grade report - F
You don't think it over
punishment, teacher
Just only the pass to use design room
If you did not come
Anyone can sign the pass
Anyway I will be allow
to use the room
That is not the point
use or not use the room
But you fake my signature
Don't you understand
If you're not here,
it's not your fault
But it's my fault
You told Pee Jai the right date, right
Yes
You told her Thai time or
English time
Just go by ourself
How to go?
Cherry, you don't feel ashame
Nobody know you
Can we just ask?
Guide book tell us
For safety
We should not let anyone know we lost
The way you do
No one will know
31.. 32.. 33
34 almost 37
Where is number 37?
Pee Jai
It's you... Cherry
What happen to you?
I have to go home now
Where are you going?
Pee Jai... how about us
On the board, look for it
Taxi, Heathrow airport
Pee Jai left her will to us
Thai restaurant is here, here
Wow.. many restaurants
Howard will collect the rent
on last sunday, Good luck... Pee Jai
Why we have to turn off the light
before use microwave?
London, here we come
me too
5 days a week
from 3 pm to 11 pm
Yes
You will off Monday and Tuesday
30 pounds a day, no tip
I will give you dinner box everyday
Yes
Start tomorrow
you can replace Jai, is it ok?
ok, yes
Jai told me only one need work
I just hire another one yesterday
Noon, you take the job
I will find new job
Thai Best is not hiring, this one too
Where is Oriental Corner?
Thai Wave closed
Thai Caf accept only male
This is the only restaurant
What is the name?
Mister, Mister
Do you know thai restaurant, called The Thai?
Yes, just around the corner
We're going there, now
Really, Yes
Hey... good luck,
they will go there too
Sawadee
looking for job
We can talk down there
Late, deduct money
Forget sawadee, deduct money
Spill water, deduct money
Broke the dish, deduct money
Not smile, deduct money
Do you want the job?
Yes
Home down
What are you doing, let go, go?
Are you ok?
Don't just stand there?
you will get caught
Are you new, right?
Just fill application
I will start in two days
Not work here, why did you run?
Uncle told me to run
Hey, hey, call me Pee, Pee (brother)
All restaurant workers,
we are brother and sister
Pee... Pee Tom
What is happening?
Home down
What does it mean?
Home is an immigration officer
Remember the word "Home Down"
You don't think, just run only
Home Down
Like this
ok... water, water
Tom Yum Koong, table 5
Fried pork table 10
Glass of water table 4
Thai chow fun table 15
You know what I find, Ngoon
Oh... don't know to say sawadee
Ah... saawadee, how is dad?
He is fine
He complaint since you're gone
He didn't wash clothes for you
hmm...
Still irritate me
How are you?
About the same, Sis
When you will come back?
Don't forget to buy Liverpool
shirt as a gift?
Why do you want?
It cost several thousand baht, right
Come on, number 9, Torres ok
For now, let me think about
take car dad too
Don't tell dad, I call
Cherry
what is that?
Oh... It dry faster
But.. it's not look nice
How come...
Everyone do this way
Tell me who did it
Stop complaint
You want to eat with me,
I can cook more
ok
I have a day off tomorrow,
go tour with me
No, I don't want
Come on
No, I don't have money
I will pay for you
Cherry
This is call poo stick
Noon
Throw stick into the water
If your stick reach the bank first
you win
Idiot
No imagination
No, won't play
Have to play
we are here at hundred acres forest
If you don't play,
it means you're never been here
Hurry, count to two, ok
one, two
You win
Sure, I have a lighter stick
it will run faster
You think Tum still miss me
I don't know
but I know, you still miss him
Bull..
ok, do this
these two stone
hit water at the same time,
mean he still miss you
if not the same time, mean
he's already forget you
you can find a new boyfriend
Stone is diferent size
how can it hit the ground same time?
In theory, it should
Who told you?
Galileo told me
If you drop same material
from same height
even different weight
it will hit the ground same time
if not bad luck, the wind blow
come on, count to two
1... 2
not the same time, mean
he's already forget you
I'm not really care that much
it true
Dear Galileo
last night the sound...
Cherry pass gas, right
1... 2
you pass gas
Dear Galileo
last night, Noon cry
home sick again
1... 2
Seeee, Galileo said it's not true
Dear Galileo
Cherry will not bad mouth in this life
1... 2
How come you do this?
You can't do this,
You can't cancel
How rude!
I'm the customer, remember
you did order it,
you have to eat
Well..
I need to please you
but I'm not pay for it
Bitch,
Cherry
Sorry Madam,
I will take care of it
Thank you very much
Go to the back
Pee Nuan,
looks at her, Now
you work here only one month
you want quarrel the customer
it's already cook,
she cancel it, sis
you are waitress
don't quarrel customer
I told you since the first day
stupid customer,
I should quarrel with her
If you want to work here
do not quarrel the customer
Do you want to do?
if you want to work, you have
to accept or work somewhere else
Oh... no..
What have you done here?
look at these,
look at my good
All these mess,
everyday same thing
I don't like it at all,
I will call the police now
It's all dirty, Woo...
don't shout don't shout
It's not a big deal
I do it, I do it
Salt, give me salt
I will do it, unterstand, bullshit
sorry, sorry, no, no
give to me, I will do it, calm down
everyday, everyday,
forget it, I will cal the police
brush, brush, pan too
I'm doing right now
What, What are you doing?
look, what you guy doing
calm down
calm down calm down, what?
you can't make me calm down
seee, it clean, ok ok
What did I see?
no... I'm not ok
Thank you, Pee
never mind
Next time becareful, ok
get inside
What are you doing in Chumporn?
What can I do,
except palm oil tree?
Waht do you think to come here?
If palm oil price is good
Why should I come here?
just gambling, it better
than stay home do nothing
same thing
I stay home and have nothing to do
Let me tell you
stay here have lot of money
but not feel like our home
look, I have many police
friends around my house
I live here saw police
I run as fast as I can
look at me, when I collect
the money I need
I will call the police to lock me
Let go
write address to my dad
The mail cost more than money inside
Hey... This is first time
I have a job and money
Hey... your dad can smile like that too
just two time in my life
First time, I passed
college entrance exam
Another time, I win an award
your dad has a lovely smile
Hey... take picture, take picture
Could you take photo for me?
I'm not an photographer
push shutter, push shutter
count it too, count it
3... 2... Yea...
It's blur... Yea...
Hey, What
what, what
Excuse me
Hello, Hello, Hi
It's really nice t-shirt,
where did you get it from?
I painted it by myself
you made it yourself,
Oh... ok cool
Can I get one anywhere?
no, no it's only one
No, ok, ok, what a shame
We have to get off this station
we off, ok, thank you
Noon... get off
fast,
Hey... hey.. Wait..
you want to swap
your shirt with my shirt
Your shirt... yes, yes
It confuse
Definitely
Here we go, It's your
Hey... Oh...
Thank you
I got it
Ah... 3 more hours
before catch the train home
What should we do?
wow... very beautiful
Thank you
church
I did not see you painted at all
I don't have any pen
We will go back to work, right
Yes, but I want to tour first
Pee Nuan, complaint without reason
It should ok not go to work for one day
you fire me
You did not work for a week
If I didn't do anything,
someone will blame me
Cherry
It's ok. I'll give you a farewell party.
If it's late, you will have to carry me
You can have some in a minute.
It's hard to find in Paris, you know!
Here's my e-mail.
What e-mail, don't know how to use
It's ok... One day you know so we can chat
ok
follow me, ok
fast, fast
The next song
Please welcome Noon
come and sing with us
No, I can not sing
Don't shy
Tomorrow, we won't see you
come on
Are you sure?
Noon wants SaoThungKhe song
Home Down
Pee Tom, where are you?
What are you doing
No, No, Nothing
let me see!
ok, just a minute
how many day have you been here?
Look!
3,165 days
We report from Thai restaurant
Where police has unchemical
investigate has raid the area
After the newer compliant about
toxic smell come out from the restaurant
We can not safely announce
that smell nothing more than
a chef try new fried chili receipt
How ever one immigrant
worker was found?
now will safely deport
back to his own country
This news reported by Del Tayor,
thank you
you're good, Pee Tom
The package address to Ngoon
go to Paris, ok
overnight at Hotel, ok
almost there, almost
only one night, we will not broke
almost there
Youth Home sign, Paris
How are you, beautiful?
or sleep at Hotel
It's too late
We want to go out with me tonight
Bullshit
Don, I think I like her
perfect
Hey...
don't worry, I'm engaged
Cherry.. waits, what wrong with you
Are you angry at me?
No, just hungry
go find something to eat
Shit... lost money bag
Are you look here and there?
My money... our money
our money too
anything else, how about passport
Sh...
Hey
Sawadee
Are you Pee Chat?
from Pee Tom, you just call, right
Yes
Come in
take sofa outside
make room for this dining table
leave small storage over there
keep this corner for large storage for goods
and the clock put here
bed against the wall
will have more space
yeah.. my dear designer
cherry
housewarming gift
thank
How are you.. guys?
We can do the serving.
Aah.. I can speak French too.
Hello... How are you?
Eiffel Tower... Champs Elise
I love you.
Pretty good.. Keep cutting>
Here money
Your pay
And.. here.
For the house.
Thank.
Hey... quiet ok
I'm so sorry
I'm sorry. What do you want?
No cat here, Do you know?
complaint often, will tell Pee Chat
tomorrow day off, what should we do
I think you should pack your things
You can build the whole house
only this room, How come
you can't pack it?
have to wash the clothes
Delicious, next time cook
it again
The day after today is your birthday,
how can we celebrate?
You still remember
never remember before
What should we celebrate?
Big party, ok
What is it "big party"?
Don't forget we are poor?
Ok, do it this way
Tomorrow we walk at night in Paris
and save money too
Let me count down
I will sing happy birthday for you
I want to go home
Why go.. it's fun here.
What's fun!... Working all day?
Not even sight seeing.
You see.. Working all day,
my hands get rotten.
At the end, have to eat
this expired pork.
Should we go home?
I've got the tickets.
But I don't have any,
mine is a one way.
What made it a one way?
Since we went get it together.
I exchanged it later.
Then.. Why won't you say something?
I tried to tell you but I can't
find any right moment.
What right time?
How long have we been together?
It' been 3 months, you know?
You can't find the right time or
you don't want me to know?
Why I don't want you to know?
Then, why don't you tell?
What is the different?
I didn't take your ticket and sold it.
That ticket is mine.
It's not your business if i go or not.
Why do you care?
Of course... I care.
Why do you lie?
We came here together.
And you want me to back alone.
It's my business too
It was you
You gave my address to Tum
I know you will not remember
my bithday
What is this?
You want to doublecross me again
Tell me everything
Hey... It's too much
I did not double cross you
Tum wants to be your friend
Why are you so angry?
But I did not want to be his friend
It true
Why are you watching this video? Why?
Why not, used to be friend
broke up then you hate him
Tum did not want to be your
boy friend
But he wants to be your friend,
what wrong?
You did wrong and won't accept
wrong doing
You act like that, that
why you've to be here
how about you, like straight talk
when straight talk, can't accept it
you just right that,
Tum can't tolerate you
Can you talk like human?
Today I can not,
I hurry to be back home
It's rush hour
and the station was closed
Yes... Can it be tomorrow?
ok, ok, yes ok
Becareful
Are you Thai?
Green light, we can cross now
You're not follow me anymore
What is your name... I'm Noon
I'm Tum
What is your real name?
Pisit
Pisit...
you are here, Uh...
Come here to study!
Used to study, not now
How about you?
Sightseeing
come alone
with friend
how about your friend
How do you know, I am Thai?
Don't care traffic light,
look on right side
only Thai has these two thing in one
Pisit, you are clever
It's not about clever
Nothing about clever,
This is an observation
Where are you going?
Go home
Oh..
What, just meet you
ask me to go to your house
I did not ask you
If I ask you, I will say come with me
I only ask you don't want to follow me
You mean I follow you by myself
Have I ever said that?
Come with me, I ask you now
All are my roommate, come in
Say... Noon
Hi, Noon
Hi
Nice to meet you
France
Hey... What up man?
Good
This is Noon
Hi
Roberto from Columbia
Nice to meet you
where is Lee Lander?
Sleep
Lee Lander
Lee Lander, wake up
Sleeping again
Nothing better to do, man
Say Hi to Noon
Hey, how you doing, honey?
Hi
Lee Ander from United State
This is Noon
Here Junko, Japanese American
No japanese, no english
only France
Wait here!
Water
ok
Hot or cold
Cold
Wait until it cool down
No water.. No electricity...
How you guys live!
It sounds impossible to the one
who never try.
But when it is time,
any one can live here.
How much is the rent?
It's free.
Umm.. Is the owner fine with it?
The owner is the French's government.
No complaint
Once in a while,
They come to check and fine.
When they come... You guys just
hide in the jar... Just like that?
Why run away, just pay the fine
Fine, How much?
2,000 euro
Ha..
Why do you pay?
sneak in and live here
It's right that they fine us.
With 2,000 euro you can rent
a nice house for several month.
I like living here.
What are they doing?
They are preparing for the presentation,
next month is the time to pay the fine.
Party, beer, ticket and art show
I'm set up exhibition
want more labor
yes, want more
Where have you been?
I ask you, where have you been?
not your business
I did not sleep all night
Do you remember?
Come back or not, it's my life
nothing to do with you
no, no, don't, don't police will lock me
Hey
Noon
I want medicine, you know
Medicine
Fever
you know
Cough
Uh..
5 doses
prescription
please
Please
Fuck you, fuck you, fuck you
medicine... you know
Fever... you know
Cough, cough
you know
why all has cold heart
I will tell Pee Chat to throw
the cat out, wait and see
what do you want?
Here it is
Taste good
Not at all
You..
How are you right now?
It's ok
How about you?
Fine.
Let me have straight talk
Sh... So-o-o lonely.
Same here.
Let's do this.
From now on, we will not mad at
each other more than a day. All right?
And you.. You can talk straight to me.
And I will not complain
anything... not washing the plates,
not clean up the room..
even drying the cloth on the heater.
I'll try.
Hey.. Are you pick on me?
Umm... Can I ask you something?
The thing that you complained
the day before
You said...
Did it really my fault?
Yes.
Hey... What?
Tomorrow you will not mad at me anymore?
Cher... ry!
You... You...
Are you fish for your food?
It's not easy to buy
It's easy but just eat
What your fishing reason!
I did fishing fish
The outcome is the same... eating fish.
It's all you can think. That's it.
Nowadays people think more
about the outcome than how to.
But for some people, all they
want is the hard old way.
Just because they think
it is elegant.
Some people just think easy
until get used to it
At the end, become negligent
He is strange like you said.
Yeah... Pisit
Is this her who got kick out?
Yeah... This is Cherry.
Just one night, he already
knows everything.
How about you Pisit,
what are you studying?
I told you, I'm not in school.
Then, what are you doing?
Just live
What are you doing with your life?
It's tough enough to just live.
What else you want me to do?
You don't want to work.
Sometimes when the money's gone.
That's what I am asking,
what kind of work?
restaurant
That's our job too.
I don't like this beard man
He's so irritate.
Take it easy.
He's just a little strange.
but straight forward.
Do you have free time today?
It's our day off.
We come to help.
Cherry come to help too
So what can we help?
What can you do?
Many things
Anything need to be done?
Quite a few.
pack, clean up and some paint.
Can you paint?
sure.
The boat is go here, ok
Listen, no, no, listen
Stop.. Stop..
What's up?, what?
Oh.. Why don't you move the stage?
near by the piano and interesting wall.
This boat should be move to over there
cause there enough space for and
This installation
is not to high, not to big
Should move to around here
and up there
So many people can walk
thru this way
Isn't it?
What do you think?
Boys, you're good
Yeah... She said she
study Architecture
You should bring your work
here to enjoy us
What you think?
I will think about it
Tonight I plan to help Roberto
set up, you want to go too?
I will
How is it? Good?
No.. No. I didn't..
You just get it wrong.
It's them, the girl come with us
Don't lie, I have the proof.
When I count to three,
just run to the train.
1.. 2.. 3
Cherry, What should we do if
the police gets us?
Hey, can not get caught.
I'm sorry. I'll never
do it again.
If I get away this time,
I'll never do it again. Sorry.. Sorry..
Let's get off on the next one.
Unbelievable!
Yeah.. It is..
We almost get caught this time.
If I get caught, They will
send me home, right
You act like you're not care about me
Both of you wrong
Why did you point finger to someone else?
Why did you blame on ome?
It's not true
If we didn't want to do,
no one can control us
you follow what she did,
you have the same quilty
you're never sneak into the train
No, never
What about,
you did not have money?
just walk
walk, walk and look at scenery,
very enjoy
Have you tour Paris yet?
act like you did not agree
Because I have to work
cut vegetable, cut pork
Thailand has no job like this
Strange... other want to come
here but have no opportunity
You are here but stay in kitchen
How about, I escort
you for one day
without map
go where evere we want
ok
You often wake up early
Only the day,
I want to wake up early
I ask you very often
not really
today, I don't
why are you wake up?
not beautiful
It's beautiful
You want to race
Let you run first
Wait for you, I have short legs
not a dog, ok
Taste good
I cook
Why did you make funny face?
It's very dry
Thristy
want water
Here
I want cold drink
Very cold right, sure...
ok... it cold now
If I want warm drink
warm, warm
Sure it warms
It's hot, can it be warm?
you want go anywhere else
You want to take me there
Who said local people hardly
smile, raise your hand
who has home sick, clap your hand
This type of weather should have
someone to hug, who agree raise your hand
You want this
I want
to eat
right in your mouth
Bird, bird
Have you ask a wish from Galileo?
Never
Do this, push your hans forward
and make a wish
if the rock fall down
the same time
It means your wish will come true
I make a wish, first
1.. 2.. 3
What is your wish?
Can not tell
Let me make a wish
ok
make a wish first, right
Yeah
Ready 1.. 2.. 3
What is your wish?
can not tell
Noon, Bus stop sign is over there
enough
We did not come to Paris
to stay in the kitchen, ok
Cherry
We will not work in the kitchen
You think about light job
Good money
less labor
use our womanize
may be show little bid body
But I think it worth
Cherry, that table said
she is your friend
Err.. Hey
Mue, why are you here?
How are you... Sawadee Noon
Sawadee
This is Pee Yuth from work,
for training
Sawadee Pee Yuth, These are
Mue's friend, Cherry and Noon
Everyone asks about you.
Yeah!
You've got a job?
How is Fon?
She works at 123 creation.
How about Belle?
She works at SB.
Ging?
Works at Land&House.
Nan works at Expo.
Deer's at Index.
Nat skips to TV career.
Ex, Pol, and Tim are in school in USA.
But you are the best.
From architecture to dancer.
I didn't recognize
you at the first place.
This May
you have to fininsh your college's admission,
don't just have fun dancing around.
Cherry, Pee Chaat called
I have to go.
Now?
Yeah... Bye Bye
Hello
Dad.. It's me.
You have not called for a while.
How are you?
Fine. It starts getting cold.
Is it cold there?
Cold
wear something to keep you warm
and cover up at night.
Umm.
What is it?
Umm.. Next time don't send me any money.
I have enough.
Umm
Have you fought with Noon?
No.
A- ngoon always talks about you.
Dad.. I get to go.
Is it leaning just like the
Leaning Tower of Pizza?
Yes
You're good too.
I know.
Have you been there?
No
One day I will go there
What to go for?
Just for a make believe picture
that you 're carrying the tower?
Like this?
Go left.. a bit more.. Like this?
Just to see why it doesn't fall.
Right.. a bit more
Up, up, ok
a bit, a bit, up
Umm... ok
You should go finish your school.
Admit your mistake and start again.
it's a waste.
I am not wrong. Why admit?
What's not wrong?
fraud teacher's signature?
wrong for sure
I understand that is a harsh punishment.
But wrong is wrong.
one day people will know
that I am not wrong.
It will take time to proof yourself.
Like Galileo
He said Earth is not
the center of the universe
They put him in jail. And now
Every one knows Galileo is right.
But you... are wrong.
Make a mistake.. accept it
That's common rule
common rule...
What is his common rule?
Let's go to Pizza in April.
Why April?
for Song-graan festival?
I want to celebrate your
birthday with Galileo.
Let's go Pizza!
Juseppe
Tum
How ar you?
Fine, and you?
Good, good
You like it?
I love it
Is it your work?
This is Cherry.
Cherry.. This is jusepe
Jusepe.. this is Cherry.
I like your work very much
Do you think?
It really can be build
Of course
But the real one won't collapse
There be strong foundation
It might be risky
But the beauty is worth to risk
Isn't it?
I like you
Do you want to work with me?
I have a company in Milan.
Not big but I have a job
for you if you want
But I don't have a degree
But you have talent
I don't have work permit also
Don't worry. I will take
care of that for you too
You can start training in January.
If I work with you
Can you allow me to use your drafting room?
Sure, Why not..
Do I need permission from
you to use it?
No, you don't
You can use it at any
time that you want
really?
ok, ok
Can I borrow your mobile phone?
Hello
Hello Dad I get a job
as an architecture
Architecture.. not a waitress
He did accept me
Can you trust him?
Yes. He's a freind of a freind.
He is a nice guy.
I will start in January.
And I can use the drafting room too.
He will take care of my work permit.
You don't have to worry about me.
I've got a job.
I am happy for you.
Um.. I get to go
I'll call you later
When will you go?
soon
How soon?
won't tell
You afraid that I will see you off?
I'm afraid of changing my mind.
Aunty, I'm leaving
You guys almost miss the train.
I'll wait for inside the train
You know that when the train leave
We may never see each other again.
Then we will not... address...
phone number...
Tum.. noonnitta@hotmail. com
double "O", double "T", ok
I don't really like him.
but he's ok.
Hello
May I speak to Naruemon?
Mom went shopping.
It's been a while.. How is it?
Where on earth are you?
In Italy, dad
What do you think if I go back to Paris?
You're sure about it?
You think, is it gonna work?
How can I know!
If you want to know, you should
try to know him more.
How about you? You will
not go back to finish your school?
Don't worry about me.
So.. when will you go to Paris?
May be after New Year, Just want
to spend time going around with you.
And leave you at Milan
Then you go to work,
I'll go to Paris
On April 29...
We'll meet at Pizza.
Chau
Where are you from?
Thailand
Thai people are very nice
Tom Yum Gung.. very good.
I love Thailander
Are you tourists?
Yes, we'll be here for a week.
And then might go to Florence.
Very rich people
Ah.. cheap trip, back packing
we've only eat once a day.
It's ok,
once in a life time anyway
You want to work
Here?
Yes, this is my restaurant
But we can't speak Italian.
Very easy
Chau, chau
Glacier, Glacier
That all.. you speak Italian now
Only thing you have to do
is just, uh.. uh..
that's all
This one for Pasta
This is for Pizza.
They are 200 plates
and will be enough for one day
Ok
And now welcome to Fabricio!
We have to sell fresh food every day.
So we start from 200
Here we have 50
150, you're sold out 150,
4 euro each
It's 600 euro
You gave me 580
so the different is 20 euro
I have to take it from your money
Please just one mistake
It'll never happen again.
I'm sorry. These are the rule.
It's not that beautiful.
I didn't buy for you.
What you're gonna do?
If the com stop working.
Use the phone
Would you like a Gondola trip?
Yes but it is so expensive.
I have a way.
We go buy the same kind of box.
Then use our boxes to sell
That is cheating.
We won't do that many.
May be 10 a day
Fabricio won't get poor.
This is the last time that
we will spend time together
You cheated at the subway
station before
It is not the same.
That... We don't know who we
cheat but here... it's Fabricio.
You really can do it?
Nothing happen in the past.
Don't think too much.
It's not about getting away,
It's about right or wrong.
Then... I'll do it.
Tomorrow you switch to sell
the ice cream.
That would be weird.
What do you want? You don't want to do it.
And you won't let me do it.
ok? Just one last time.
Only this time
You have to promise
not to cheat again.
I promise.
I'm sorry
Cherry
It's not you
Out
she's my friend
Cherry.. Jusepe..
Help
I will talk to the police,
and see what they can do
Wait for me here,
Ok
What'd they say
They won't send her to prison
But they will send her home
within 24 hours
Can I see her again
Don't
Or you're getting in trouble too
I'm sorry
Fabricio
Now it is 11.18 pm in Thailand.
Today is Christmas
It is 117 days
From the beginning of this trip
Today
I am so lonely.
damn.. lonely
Today
We should be together
Because of me
I destroy it all
Noon, I am sorry
I am sorry
I'm sorry that I use to talk
bad to you.
I am sorry that I make you mad.
I am sorry that I am coward
I am sorry that I leave you.
I am sorry.
That I can not keep my words
April 28
Tom Thipmanee, I can use it.
Are you still mad at me?
sms to Cherry, Who has a home sick?
What are you doing?
Everyone does it
What do you think what is Pisit doing?
Dear Galileo,
Will Noon come back to Paris?
yes
Galileo said no
I say yes
I am glad that I'm with you.
you are sweet talking.
Just try to be nice.
Who's miss friend, raise your hand?