Fixed & Synced by bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick
Live long and happy lives!
My blessings are with you!
- Greetings.
Four plates of special Biryani.
Yes.
Here you are.
- I've seen 'Anand' seven times.
- Really?
That too at the theaters.
I remember every
dialogue from that film.
- Wow... bless you my 'mureed'.
- Who is 'mureed.' my name is Neerja.
Oho! Mureed means fan. Fan.
Just like I am a fan of Dilip Kumar.
And I am Rajesh Khanna's.
May God bless you with a long life.
Life should be big, not long.
Well said! Goodbye.
Hi!
- Yes.
- Will you have some?
Sister's here!
- Sister's here!
- Go get ready.
- Hi Laado (DARLING)!
- Hi brother.
Thank God you are here.
It's a very boring party.
- Hi my 3D.
- So sorry I'm late.
Daddy's darling daughter!
Hi daddy!
Why are you so late?
Everyone has been
asking "Where is Neerja?"
Why are you eating samosas?
Are you hungry?
Did you eat the fruit
I packed for you?
- Yes.
- I had packed flat bread for you.
She must have eaten nothing!
See! She didn't eat?
Look at her.
Look.
Good evening everybody!
Today, the boys and
girls of Navjeevan society...
are going to dance...
to our favourite superstar
Rajesh Khanna's song!
Everyone's favorite superstar
or YOUR favorite superstar!
- Mine too.
- mama not fair!
My favorite! Everyone's favorite!
Rajesh Khanna the super star's song!
Look at your son!
Sweet!
"Bye-bye!"
"Bye-bye miss, goodnight.
We'll meet again tomorrow."
"The day was colorful,
the dazzling night has arrived."
"Bye-bye miss, goodnight.
We'll meet again tomorrow."
Those were the kids!
For Navjeevan society!
That was amazing!
And now a special
performance by my parents!
They are going to sing!
They want you to sing, not me!
You haven't clicked
a single good snap of me!
Click their snap!
"My heart has been crazy since childhood."
"Love is the reason for life."
"The flowers didn't impress me,
I never enjoyed a nap in a hammock."
"I found solace
in the softness of your tresses."
"Bye-bye miss, goodnight."
- OK, dad. That's it! Enough flirting!
And now...
a special act!
Our society's Robot-boy!
"Bye-bye miss, goodnight.
We'll meet again tomorrow."
"Bye-bye!"
- "Bye-bye!"
He is here.
- He is here.
Go down.
- Hello!
Quickly!
Put it on the table.
Good evening.
She loves posing for snaps!
Don't bother.
Everyone kept waiting
for you to liven up the party.
Hold it carefully.
Careful.
Did you see mama dancing today?
- She was having great fun!
- You mimic!
I had to compete with you, right?
She's perfected the dance step.
Go to bed now.
- Please wake me up in a while.
- Go get some sleep. Don't you get tired?
Oh, Nikki!
Why don't you take sick leave?
I can't...
Shanti is also on sick leave...
and this is my first
flight as Head Purser.
Wow!
I'm not giving you this.
I'll read it on the flight.
Read it when you come back.
You won't die if you don't read it.
You're so mean.
Papa, I never got back
the last magazine I gave her.
Look Laado,
they're showing your commercial.
Which one?
You look like an aunty!
These are 4 AK47s,
8 grenades and bullets.
Safarini will wear the explosives belt.
Fahad and Mansoor,
be careful with the grenades.
And these clothes are for you.
Rama!
It's 1 o'clock.
If you let her sleep some
more then she'll get late.
I have to complete this article.
You wake her up.
Laado!
- It's 1 o'clock.
- Let me sleep.
Okay sleep, dear.
You still have some time.
Your modeling career
is going so well...
do you have to work so hard?
Why don't you quit
your job as an air hostess?
I like my job.
That's the problem.
You know...
when your plane takes off...
so does my blood pressure.
My blood pressure comes
down only when your plane lands.
You ate three samosas yesterday...
that's why your
blood pressure's high.
Don't blame my plane.
Oh my baby!
- By the way...
- Huh?
Did you tell Karim bhai to
pick you for the airport?
Jaideep's coming.
Okay.
I've switched on
the water heater, dear.
Come on.
Pack the guns.
We will work hard.
We are prepared.
We will do anything to
succeed in our mission.
We will definitely emerge victorious.
- One more...
- mom.
- Just a little more...
- ma, please.
Only a little.
- Where's your ring?
- Don't know. Can't find it.
What do you mean you can't find it?
Mom, I looked everywhere.
I told you never
to take that ring off.
Did you look under the pillow?
I promise I searched the entire room.
It's not there.
- Check the bathroom.
- mom... I've checked everywhere.
It's not here either.
You keep flitting
around like a busy bee.
You get so many things done in a day...
but you can't take
care of a single ring.
I got it specially
made for your safety.
My sweet mom.
If this happened
then that wouldn't happen.
If that happened
then this wouldn't.
Eventually what has to happen
will happen. Understood?
Wow!
What film is this dialogue from?
My child!
It's an original dialogue.
Stop spoiling her.
Wait, Laado.
I've made rolls!
Don't give all of it away.
Keep some for yourself too.
Okay.
Bye, mom!
Oh... my vanity case.
Okay, bye.
Laado... your birthday's on the 7th.
You won't be here!
I'll celebrate in Frankfurt!
But don't forget to
get my birthday present.
Tell me what you want!
You remember to yell
at me but you forgot this?
- I want that yellow dress.
- Yes, of course.
I remember now.
I'll definitely get that dress, dear.
- Bye!
Aunty, you take good care of uncle.
I made a big mistake.
Jaideep is the right boy for Laado.
I wonder why I got her
married to Naresh.
Will Mansoor and Fahad
be able to do their jobs?
- Yes, they have been properly trained.
- They're both good.
We will hijack the
plane and meet in Cyprus.
In exchange for the passengers...
we will get our
brothers out of jail.
May God protect you.
- Good bye!
May God protect you!
See you in Cyprus!
"Oh my dream girl, when will you come?"
"The weather is so fine,
when will you come?"
I'm being really honest...
when you're not here...
I miss your voice the most.
But you don't like my voice, do you?
I listen to your voice with my heart,
not my ears!
Oh really!
I really miss you.
"Gently.. gently.."
You can also say,
"Jaideep, I also miss you".
"The gentle breeze.."
"I miss you... mademoiselle."
"my persona began to soar."
"Oh fragrant.. mesmerizing love.."
"Deep, immersive love."
"I'll wrap myself in these thoughts."
"I'll connect to those memories."
"Oh fragrant.. mesmerizing love.."
"Deep, immersive love."
Now slow down... stop here!
Hey I'm a good boy.
I don't like where this is going.
Please don't waste time,
just look at that.
What do you think?
Who's that?
Can't you see?
That's you?
No it's someone else.
That can't be you.
Very funny.
The photographer must
have worked some magic.
I thought...
since I am not here on my birthday...
if you missed me...
you could come here.
But you look really
nice with makeup.
Thanks. Fine, let's go. Forget it.
- Take me to the airport.
- Listen...
- I have to report at 2.30...
- Listen!
What?
You look beautiful as a bride,
mademoiselle.
"Gently.. gently.."
"the gentle breeze.."
You look beautiful as a bride,
mademoiselle.
It's 2:27am... 3 more minutes to go.
What do you need 3 minutes for?
These 3 minutes are
very important for me.
Okay.
Your idol Rajesh Khanna is
going to do me a huge favor.
In three minutes?
Okay.
- What's this?
- Your birthday present.
I'm opening it.
- Not yet...
- Why?
- Open it on your birthday.
- No, I'll open it now.
No! For my sake!
- And..
- Hi, Jaideep.
- Hello...
- HI.
Tina, unfortunately..
only we have to deal with
grouchy company drivers.
You're right.
I wish our pickup was as cute.
- Okay, guys, come on let's go.
- And he's blushing by the way.
Let's go.
- Sorry, bye.
- Bye.
Bye, Jaideep!
Bye, Jaideep! See you!
Jaideep is so cute!
I think you should marry him.
Marry him,
or else she'll steal him from you.
She has the hugest crush on Jaideep.
Excuse me, sir.
Excuse me, sir. Sorry.
Let go of the past.
That was an arranged marriage.
He loves you.
You should consider giving
life another chance.
Jaideep!
I'll miss you.
I'll miss you too.
Bye.
I'll open this on my birthday.
If they stop us,
do as you've been told.
ID, Sir?
He's a diplomat from Libya.
We are here to see him off.
Sorry sir.
Come on...
Okay Sir.
Let them through!
Are all systems checked
and serviceable?
Checked and serviceable.
Hi, Zone 4. All equipments
checked and serviceable.
Thank you so much.
Debina, I'm going up to
the pilots to let them know.
- Debrief?
- Yes.
- Hi, Samarth. All okay?
- Yes Neerja, everything is fine.
Hello.
Good morning, Captains.
I'm Neerja Bhanot.
I'm your Head Purser today.
- Good morning.
- Hey Neerja. How are you?
Very well, Captain.
I haven't learnt my French yet.
We flew last weekend
to Paris together.
Okay, you know each other.
I'm Capt. Snipes.
Very nice to meet you, Captain.
This is my first
flight as Head Purser.
- Wow! Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Let us know if you need anything.
Captain, this is for you.
Great. That's your staff list.
And we'd just love it if you could...
get some tea up here
once we're in the air.
Sure.
Indian habits, huh!
- See you.
- Bye.
We're ready to board.
Hi, we're ready to board.
- Hi, Neerja.
- Yes.
These are the Unaccompanied
minors traveling to Frankfurt.
Hello.
- Hi.
- Hi, how are you doing?
Careful, careful.
He's scared of flying.
Really? Why?
Because I've seen on television...
that sometimes planes crash.
I thought I'll introduce
you to the pilot...
- but, since you're scared...
- No... I'll meet the pilot.
I won't be scared.
Fine.
Mom, I will sit with my dad.
Emergency Exit Lights.
- Auto.
Oxygen masks.
Normal.
- What's your name, dear?
- Tina!
Debina.
- Both of you look really beautiful.
- Thank you.
- This is my grandson Rahul.
- Yes.
- Hello.
- Are you married?
- No, not yet.
- Grandma, please.
I'll talk to you later.
17D and 17E. Here.
Right here.
Thank you.
May I see your boarding
passes, please.
- Come on.
- Let me speak.
- I want a blanket.
- We're not sitting in a bus, dear.
I want a blanket.
Maintain some discipline, dear.
May I help you sir?
30... 30...
- 31. Your seat.
- Yeah okay, thank you.
- May I help you sir?
- Thank you.
Please let me know.
Put on your seat belts.
Hello.
- Hello.
- Mr. Malone. 13J.
- I'll lead you to your seat.
- Oh, that's so...
Mr. Malone.
Oh look honey, I think it's her.
Hello, Mr. and Mrs. Goldstein.
I'm Neerja Bhanot.
I'm the Head Purser today.
If you need anything,
please let me know.
- May I ask you something?
- Sir?
- Is this you?
- Yes, sir.
- That's a beautiful picture.
- You are very beautiful.
Thank you.
Sir your blanket.
Thanks.
You are flying with
us till Frankfurt, is it?
Yes, we are going
to see you in Frankfurt.
Perhaps. Great enjoy your flight.
I don't have patience
like your mother. Hold this.
Since you are seated at the emergency
exit, it's important to brief you.
Please do not open the
door till the orders are given.
- Is everyone aboard?
- All passengers on board.
- Have a safe flight Neerja.
- Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Welcome aboard Pan Am 73 to
New York, via Karachi and Frankfurt.
But you know I always love
being back here in India...
Sir, please keep your seat upright.
in fact, I'm in the middle of an
intensive course in Hindi lessons.
So... here goes.
Hello, Ladies and Gentlemen.
My name's Capt. Jack Snipes.
It's now 4 a.m.
And we should be arriving in Karachi
in about an hour and 20 minutes.
One small favor.
By the time we reach Frankfurt,
if you could let me know...
how my Hindi is.
He likes to talk a lot in Hindi.
Have a good flight.
What's this?
Love letter?
Did Jaideep give you this?
Jaideep has asked me to
open it on my birthday.
Open it.
How will he know that
you opened it on your birthday or not?
- No!
- Show Na!
It's a matter of principle.
I don't want to open it.
Why is everything a matter
of principle for you?
- How many principles can one have?
- Stop it.
He's looking at us.
Give it back.
No chance,
I don't have a magazine.
I need some reading material.
Please.
Fine, I'll open it.
I'll be the first one to read it.
Don't be mean, please give it back.
Okay... one condition.
Promise me you'll marry Jaideep.
Thank God you left Naresh.
Is your mother like this too?
Does she make your father
order take-outs all the time?
No, my mother's a good cook.
I see... she's a good cook!
You could've learnt something
from her before marriage.
Or maybe in trying
to make you independent...
she didn't teach you anything.
I'll learn everything soon,
don't worry.
No, I'm not worried.
You know what the problem is Neerja?
We don't get paid to look pretty.
We have to work hard.
Do you know what "hard work" is?
And... look! How my hard-earned money...
is being wasted!
But don't worry.
Give me your hand.
What's the amount on the bill?
45 Riyal.
45 Riyal. Hold this. Eat it.
Eat it.
I'll recover this 45 Riyal
from your darling Daddy.
Oh yes, you're vegetarian.
Throw it.
Where are you going?
To serve your friends.
You stay here.
Don't come out, understand?
Who is going to clean all this?
Me?
Should I call someone else?
Then do it.
Good for nothing...
Dad, I don't think I can make it.
It's taking me some
time to adjust here.
So I think if I stay and
spend some time here...
without coming back,
then I might adjust better.
Did anyone at home
say something to you?
Should I have a word with Naresh?
No! Please don't talk to Naresh.
He knows. He suggested that...
actually,
we both took a joint decision...
that I should stop modeling.
Look, dear...
remember what I've been teaching
you since you were a kid.
Listen to me.
First of all, stay strong.
Stay strong... it solves every problem.
Yes.
And second...
don't ever do or
tolerate anything wrong.
And third...
Yes... remember the first two statements.
You have to be a brave girl.
Now come on tell me...
Who is my brave girl?
Once more.
Do it properly.
Khalil!
Why are your hands shaking? Coward!
- Don't be scared.
You just need to follow the plan.
That's all.
Come on, try again.
Be brave.
You have trained hard for this day.
Good morning, Ladies and Gentlemen.
We will be landing at Karachi
International Airport shortly.
Please make sure your tray tables
and seats are in the upright position.
Also make sure your seat
belts are correctly fastened.
- Sir... please put your seat belt on.
- Thank you.
Quick!
The plane is landing.
- Are you ready?
- Ready.
Ready.
Fahad, Mansoor, both of
you will enter from the rear gate.
Khalil, you've to control the cockpit.
It's time.
I know.
Good morning, we have arrived
at Karachi International Airport.
Passengers flying en-route to Frankfurt
and New York, please remain seated.
All those deboarding in Karachi,
thank you for flying Pan Am.
- This is for you.
- Thanks.
How are you Mr. Imran?
Sign on this.
All fine?
All good.
And I have a special gift for you.
As always.
Thank you.
I'll go see the pilots.
How are you?
May I come in, sir!
- Who's there?
- Sir, Imran Ali. Radio Engineer.
- Good morning, Pilot.
- Good morning.
- Sir, any interference in the radio?
- No. Everything is good.
Okay, sir. Have a nice journey, sir.
Thanks.
- Fahad.
- Shoot! Now! Come on!
- What's wrong?
- Rajesh Khanna again?
I like Amitabh Bachchan more.
How many times...
Shoot!
Fast, fast, fast!
Come on, fast!
Close the door!
Close the door, Debina!
Hold on, Grandma.
Hey move back!
Move! Move!
Come on! Move!
- Down! Down!
- move it! Move it!
Shut up!
Sit down! Sit down!
Down! Down!
No one moving!
No one!
- Everyone keep quiet!
- Hello.
- Hijack.
What?
Hijack.
Phone down.
She said hijack?
There is no cockpit in the front!
What?
Cockpit?
- Cockpit?
- Upstairs. Upstairs.
- Let me go and check.
- No, no, wait.
We will follow protocol.
Open the door.
- What about the passengers?
- We don't have time.
We cannot leave them.
Captain!
Open the door.
Open the door!
Move it.
Open it!
It can only be opened from the inside.
It is the right thing to do,
because it's protocol.
- But the passengers...
- That is an order.
Open the door!
How did they escape? Huh?
- I don't know.
- Did you signal them? Huh!
They are all going
to die because of you.
Get up!
Get up! Everyone, go down.
Go down!
Hurry up.
Move!
Move! Move!
The pilots escaped.
How did they escape?
They escaped from the cockpit.
Where? How?
We were standing down here!
Even you didn't know
that the cockpit was upstairs.
So don't blame me for this.
What were you doing?
This is hijack!
- Get up.
No one moving.
This is a hijack!
You... hands up!
Hands up.
Everyone hands up!
What happened?
Pilots have escaped from the plane!
What should we do now?
- The pilots will come back!
Bring everyone to the middle section!
Come on! Do it now!
Move! Move!
- Hurry up! Move!
Come on! Move!
Move ahead!
Move! Move!
- Move it!
- Move up!
Come here!
Back! Back!
Go back!
Get up!
Move! Move! Move!
Move! Move!
Sit.
- Okay.
- Down!
Move! Move!
- Sit!
You. Sit.
Sit! Sit! Sit!
- Move! Move inside!
Come on!
Shut up!
Hands up!
I'll get back to you with the details.
- Yes, Captain.
- Hijack. My plane's been hijacked.
Hijacked? Saad, clear this crowd.
Please sit down.
Please come into my cabin,
let's talk there.
Please, this way.
This side.
Please come.
Rehman, re-route
all planes via Lahore.
- Yes sir.
- This side.
- Excuse me sir, please don't hurt her.
- Sit down!
Rahul, sit down.
- One second!
Sit down.
Sir please sir.
Who do you think I am?
- Sorry! Sorry!
- Who do you think I am?
- Look at me!
- I said sorry!
Look at me!
I am an American!
I'll show you my passport!
Stay there!
How will we reach Cyprus?
- If the plane doesn't take
off they are no good to us.
- Brother!
- Shut up!
- Let's kill all of them here
if we can't reach Cyprus.
- Their dead bodies will
get our brothers released from jail.
Kill them all!
We have to keep these
passengers alive.
That's the only way to get the pilots.
Sit.
Sit here.
- So did you leave the engine running?
- Yes.
Yes, we followed protocol,
so we left the engine running.
- Great!
- We evacuated the cockpit.
My passengers are on board.
There's over 300 passengers.
What do we do now?
You, get up.
Announcement!
- Announcement!
- I... I... I'll make the announcement.
I'll make the announcement.
- I...
- Sit here!
Announce!
Everyone... silent.
Silent... otherwise kill everyone.
I am Neerja Bhanot.
I'm the Head Purser on this flight.
Our pilots are not
in the cockpit right now.
We do not have any pilots.
Everyone please stay calm
and cooperate with them...
and I promise nothing
will happen to you.
They have no enmity with any of you.
- Please... lower your hands.
- No!
No hands down!
- Hands up!
- Up. All up!
I am trying to help you.
If they stay calm and cooperate...
and if they are reassured,
then it'll make things easier for you.
Please understand.
Please.
Let the passengers lower their hands.
Please... please put your hands down.
Hands down! Hands down, everyone.
Sir, there are
approximately 44 Pakistanis...
Did I ask you how many
Pakistanis are on board?
What do you want me to do?
Go up there, check their passports.
Save the Pakistanis...
and offer my regrets to the rest?
Sorry, sir.
Give me that!
Arrange for a van
to go to the tarmac.
Okay, sir.
- And...
- Yes, sir.
I want a camera on the roof.
I want photographs of the hijackers.
Sit up.
My name is Inzamam.
I'm coming to help you out.
Are you hearing me?
We should ask for pilots...
Otherwise we'll shoot the passengers.
Whatever your demand..
I will try to fulfill your demand.
Shutter down! Shutter down!
You shutter down!
Shutter down! Down!
Quickly!
Come on!
Let the ladies and children go.
- Brother! How will we talk to them?
- We shouldn't open the door.
- We need a radio operator
to talk to people at the ATC.
Go... announcement!
Radio operator... plane.
Radio operator.
Announce!
Is there a radio engineer
on our flight?
Radio engineer.
Fast!
Is there a radio engineer
on our flight?
Radio engineer!
I'm coming to help you out.
Is there a radio engineer
on our flight?
Radio engineer?
Do we have a radio
engineer on our flight?
Radio engineer?
There is no radio
engineer on our flight.
Until you talk to me..
how will I know what your demands are?
- Name...
- Sir... I...
I'm an American. I'm not an Indian.
I'll show you my passport.
One second.
American!
Yeah, one second. I'll show you.
Sir, sir, sir...
Don't hit him!
Sir, sir, sir... wait.
Don't hit her. Don't hit her, sir.
- Brother!
Take me instead.
Sit there! Sit there!
- Otherwise I will kill you.
Sit straight.
Kill me.
American.
- Shut up.
- Kill me. Kill me.
Kill me.
Let him go.
Pilot...!
We are unarmed!
- No arms!
- Pilot...!
Kill!
Send the pilot.
I will convey your
demands to my authorities.
Pilot...!
- The pilots will come.
- No! We have to talk to him.
- Be patient.
Please stay calm!
30 minutes!
Pilot no...
- Kill!
- 30 minutes are less, brother!
I'll speak to the
authorities on your behalf.
I'm sure they'll
agree to your demands.
30 minutes!
- Just a little more time.
- 30.
Give us a little longer, brother.
One passenger... kill!
- I'm here to help you.
- 30!
No pilot... kill!
- Kill everyone!
- They are innocent.
They are not at fault.
- I kill! Everyone! 30 minutes!
- I am getting your demands processed.
Give me a little time.
Please be patient.
Stair... Van... move...
I'll get it moved.
There's...
some news that...
some flight has been hijacked.
Hijack?
Pan Am flight.
Which flight was she on?
Pan Am 73, but...
You know what...
Are you sure...
I'll call our guy Ismail,
and confirm this...
and check what's going on.
I mean...
let's not speculate.
Give me five minutes, okay.
And I'll get back to you.
Just five minutes, you relax.
Sit down.
I'll be back in five minutes.
How can you not send me the pilots?
Sir, Karachi Airport
is your responsibility.
See what is the best
you can do, but...
Pan Am can't risk
any of it's crew, sir.
And what about the air hostesses?
They are also a part of Pan Am.
What about them?
What can I say!
That's our policy.
Sorry. Excuse me.
- Hello.
- Hello, Harish.
I'm glad you called.
I've been getting this
strange sinking feeling.
Well... actually...
Laado's plane which had
gone to Karachi...
has been hijacked.
And... Neerja?
Neerja's... on board the flight.
We... we...
Mushtaq just informed me.
Rama, don't worry.
I... I...
I mean...
I'm still at the office.
- Just look after yourself, I...
- Everything will be okay.
Nothing will happen to our Laado.
- Don't worry.
- I... I'll call you...
- What if the pilots don't come?
- Wait.
Open.
Open!
Shut up! Shut up!
- Please...
- Shut up, sit down!
Sit down! Sit down!
Pilots! Pilots!
My team is trying to get you pilots.
- Sit down! Sit down!
- Please be patient.
30 minutes...
30 minutes... over!
Brother, they're almost here.
30 minutes!
No pilots! 30 minutes!
Violence won't serve any purpose.
We'll solve the problem together.
Please be patient.
Pilots!
I'm here to help you.
Shoot!
The longer you take,
more people will die!
Move it!
Sit down!
- Down!
Open door!
Neerja... come on baby.
Neerja...
Neerja!
Will you call your father again?
Once again
Naresh is the bad guy, huh!
Who do you think you are?
I've been keeping count.
Been writing down every detail.
Every phone call... every food delivery,
I'll make your father pay for everything.
Get it?
You just come out.
Come out Neerja!
Come out!
Open the door.
Stay strong... it solves every problem.
And secondly...
Don't ever do or tolerate
something that's wrong.
Who's my brave girl?
Me.
Open the door.
Or I shoot!
Why move?
I tell you to move?
We shot the wrong man.
Should've shot her.
Tina! Debina!
What?
Water.
Go back.
No water. No water.
Sir, please.
No water!
Sir, I am only doing my job.
I'm performing my duty,
just like you are.
Do it fast.
Brother...
Tough times, Inzamam.
Yes.
Have you sealed the airport?
Yes, the airport has been sealed.
Sir... the terrorists are from ANO.
- Abu Nidal Organization?
- Yes.
Sir, they will keep
the passengers hostage...
until their jailed comrades
in Cyprus are freed.
You'll have to stall them
for 2-3 hours till I get there.
I'm trying my best.
But they sound very
restless and nervous.
Thankfully the pilots
managed to escape.
All thanks to that Purser...
Neerja Bhanot...
who gave them the Hijack
code at the right time.
- Brother.
They are taking too long.
Let's kill another hostage.
Let's kill her. She is trouble.
No! She is not an American, plus she
is the only one who is able to function.
Get all the passports
from the passengers.
First American passports, then others.
- Okay?
Hey... come here.
Make... Uhhh...
Brother!
What's the word for 'Elaan'?
- Announcement.
Make announcement.
Passports... of... all the passengers..
Collect.
Quickly.
We need your passports.
We want your passports.
Please keep your
passports ready with you.
- Keep your passports with you.
- Passports!
- Shut up! Shut up!
- We will come and collect them.
Only the cabin crew will come
and collect them.
Only the cabin crew
will take your passports.
- Shut up!
- Please calm down.
You'll be safe
if you cooperate with us.
Please keep calm and cooperate
with us. Nothing will happen to you.
Please listen to me.
Please leave us!
- No clever.
- For passports.
No American passports.
No taking American passports.
No American passports?
All passports!
Passports!
Sir passports!
Sir.
Ma'am, passport.
Thank you.
Will you return it?
Move!
- Shut up!
- Do as they say.
Your passport.
Fast!
Passports?
Passports!
Where passport?
Passports?
I'll get it.
Move!
- Brother!
Yes.
Hello, Rama.
The government is negotiating
with the terrorists.
You know, when she returned
from her hijack training...
I made it very clear.
Forget your training and all that...
if you're in danger,
just run for your life.
But she never listens to me.
- Rama, I hope Laado...
- I hope!
What do you mean I hope?
Laado's going to be fine.
She's absolutely fine.
Absolutely... Absolutely...
Harish... we had two sons...
yet I kept praying for a daughter.
- Isn't it?
- Yes.
At the time of her birth...
there was a threat to her life,
and mine too.
But... she didn't give
up and neither did I.
So... God finally had
to answer our prayers.
- Yeah..
- So... who can snatch her from us now?
Don't worry.
- Absolutely...
- 100 percent...
- Okay.
- She'll come back...
Just watch.
She wants that yellow
dress on her birthday.
I'll go get that.
Okay?
She will definitely come back.
Don't you worry.
- What did papa say?
- Wait.
- Where are you going?
- They have no news yet.
Actually... I...
I just need to go to the market.
Why do you need to
go to the market now, mom?
I have to buy that
yellow dress for Laado.
- She wants to wear that.
- I am coming too.
Aneesh, stay close to the phone.
If papa calls tell him
we'll be back in half an hour.
- There are no American passports!
- No American passports?
- No American.
Hey... come here.
Quickly... quickly... quickly.
- No Americans?
- Sir, I don't know sir.
- Huh?
- I don't know, sir.
- No Americans?
- I don't know.
Brother! What are you doing?
I was checking whether she's
hiding the American passports.
Get all UK passports.
- Fast!
Ronnie Heston!
- Ronnie Heston!
- Ronnie Heston?
- No!
Kill all English passengers.
- Ronnie?
- Ronnie Heston!
Who's Heston Ronnie?
Ronnie Heston!
- I am Ronnie Heston!
- Get up!
- Please...
Move!
Shoot you!
Shoot you! Shoot all of you!
Move!
Shut up!
Wonderful!
English, huh!
- Let's kill him, so that
they send us the pilots sooner.
We have to keep the passengers alive.
It's been more than 8 hours.
The negotiator is stalling us.
Let's kill this Englishman.
Be patient.
No time for patience... we must
open the door right now...
- and kill this Englishman.
- Brother! Stop!
I say kill the Englishman.
Look he's back.
Are you hearing me?
Because we had sealed the airport
it's taking time for the pilots to reach.
Keep your mouth shut!
Where are the pilots?
- Pilot!
- How much time?
There's a radio engineer
present on the plane.
Radio!
Now you can communicate with
us through him on the radio.
- Name?
- His name is Imran Ali!
- Imran...
- Imran Ali.
Imran Ali.
Now you can communicate with
us through him on the radio.
- Imran Ali!
- Who Imran Ali?
Imran Ali!
- Imran Ali!
You won't tell me?
I'll shoot him!
I...I am Imran Ali.
Why did you keep quiet earlier!
Imran!
Sir...
Sir... he...
Shut up!
Sir, please...
- Shut up!
He can help you.
Please don't hit him!
How will he help us?
Help?
Sir, he was very scared, sir.
Come on.
Come...
Sir he can help you sir!
I announced!
- Announcement!
- Sir, he can help you.
- Sir, he can help you!
No American!
Announcement... radio engineer!
You wait...
- Mansoor... I'm taking him upstairs.
- You keep an eye on the Englishman!
Sir please...
Sit! Sit!
Shut up!
Sit. Sit.
I am going.
Come. Go on.
Khalil, control the passengers!
Come on.
Windows... shut them.
Let me talk to them.
Yes, speak.
Fast... time!
The French crew pilots
will be here soon.
How much longer?
They're asking how
much longer will it take.
Like I said,
Imran, they will be here soon.
I have only one request.
Please let the women and children go.
No women... no children!
Pilot! Pilot!
The pilots are on their way,
please be patient.
Tell him! Pilot! Pilot! Pilot!
At least give me enough time...
to get information from Imran.
Please hurry up.
Five minutes.
- Five minutes.
- Okay, brother.
I'll let you know in a while.
- Be patient.
Why you not tell? Imran Ali?
Huh!
Why?
Come here. Come.
Hero, huh!
Sing.
Last song... sing.
Sing for them.
Sing.
Sing loud!
Sing the song.
I don't want to sing.
- You don't want to sing?
- No, I don't want to sing.
Sing!
Please...
Down!
Sing!
- Okay, don't sing.
- Okay, okay, I'll sing.
Sing!
- Sing!
- I'll sing!
Sing then!
"When will you come,
Oh the woman of my dreams!"
"It's a fine day, when will you come?"
- Louder...
- "Come, Oh dear.."
Loud, loud...
"Oh the woman of my dreams!"
For everyone.
"When will you come.."
"It's a fine day,
when will you come?"
"Come, Oh dear.."
Sing louder, or I'll shoot this one.
I want my mom.
"When will you come,
Oh the woman of my dreams!"
"It's a fine day.."
Go sit. Hero.
Go!
Go, go, go.
'Laado!'
"Teach me to walk again,
lift me in your arms, mom!"
"Wipe my face with your shawl,
wherever you spot some dirt."
"When life stares down at me."
"I remember your words.."
"You're the one who scolded me
for my mistakes!"
"Why isn't the whole world like you,
mom?"
"I want to complain about everybody,
they trouble me, mom."
"Give me shelter, call me to you,
my heart is with you."
'Laado!'
He needs to use the washroom urgently.
Your plane... country...
Hey! What are you saying?
- Stand up!
Hey!
Go back.
- He needs to use the washroom.
- Go back.
- He's just a kid, let him go.
- Go back!
- He needs to go to the bathroom.
- Go back.
Let them go.
I'll keep a watch.
What do you mean let them go?
- He's just a kid...
- Is he your kid?
Brother, he's just a small kid.
That's the least we can do.
Please control your anger.
Control my anger?
Are you trying to teach me?
Yes.
Yes? You are trying to teach me?
Khalil! What are you doing?
- What's going on here?
What's going on here? Why?
- Why?
- He...
If we fight with each other
the passengers will overpower us!
- Where's your head?
I'm sorry, aunty.
It's okay. It's okay.
Stop it!
Shhh. Come, come, come.
Move!
Go!
It's okay.
Open!
Little time?
Little time!
- You need more time.
- This is not a Pakistani airline.
So the pilots are taking
longer to get here.
Tell him!
How much longer?
More time? 5 minutes.
10 minutes.
20... 30...
You're letting them fool you.
What are you doing here?
- Go down now.
- Are you hearing me?
Khalil.
Khalil!
The devil is playing with us.
Go down now.
Now!
I know what to do.
Brother.
Brother?
- Yes.
- Imran's no more.
If the pilots don't get here...
then each and every one...
- Keep talking to them.
- Sit. Sit!
- You killed?
Yeah, I killed him.
You next? You next?
Sit down!
Where's the radio engineer?
Where?
Oh... dead.
He's dead!
- I want my mother.
- me too.
We'll all go home soon, okay.
Eat something.
Here.
Mom, I am not hungry.
I made this specially for you,
you must eat one.
I've a sore throat, so it hurts.
What do you feel like eating?
I don't want anything.
Seriously, I don't want anything.
It'll get wasted.
How about we ask Sharma aunty...
to teach us how to make chowmein.
If you learn to cook a few things...
you'll have fewer
problems when you go back.
I feel if Laado can mould herself...
then things will be better.
I don't mean that she isn't trying...
Who said she is going back?
Instead of making her understand,
you are encouraging her.
Girls always have to be
the ones to adjust.
Can we discuss it some other time?
Let's talk about this later.
Will things get better
by brushing this under the carpet?
There are differences
in every marriage.
You can't give up
on your marriage, dear.
- You don't know everything...
- Then tell me.
What happened?
Let's first finish..
Laado! Laado!
What's that?
Naresh wrote letters to papa.
"Dear sir, I don't like that...
you keep calling up
your daughter so often."
"No respectable father will
ever let his daughter model..."
"If you call Neerja to Mumbai again..."
"then don't bother sending her back."
"Even a poor man sends his daughter
with gifts when she gets married."
"You sent Neerja empty-handed."
"Harish... your daughter doesn't
know basic chores... even cleaning."
"She is of no use to me"
mummy, I swear, I
tried to do everything.
I swept and mopped the floors...
washed clothes, cleaned the utensils.
When I came back home,
the wound on my head...
wasn't because I slipped and fell.
I am sorry, papa.
No, dear.
I couldn't be your brave girl.
I ran away.
No, dear.
I don't want to die before
I am actually dead, mom.
I won't send my Laado anywhere.
I'll be right back.
What?
I'll give everyone something to eat.
- Aren't you hungry?
- Go!
I need help to
distribute refreshments.
Let's just give food
to everybody, okay.
Neerja, do something... please...
Some more.
- Hey... move back!
Back!
- Give!
Please read this.
On my signal,
you have to open the emergency exit.
Get water. Go!
Move!
Back!
Hello!
Come on.
- Sir.
- Yes.
379 people are trapped on that plane.
Don't you think this can
be quite humiliating for Pakistan?
Why should it be
humiliating for Pakistan?
The terrorists are not from Pakistan.
The passengers' safety is our
priority. We're doing the best we can.
- Sir...
- Yeah.
What are the demands of these people?
We're trying to talk to them.
As soon as we come to know,
we'll let you know.
Sir... if we can't fulfill their demands...
then what will the
government's stance be?
Do you think that the Pakistani
government is sitting idle?
You two will cover this section.
Yes sir!
Water.
"Neerja..."
"I have been eagerly
waiting for your birthday."
"I've re-written
this letter 15 times."
"But I finally found the courage
to give it to you today."
"Neerja I know that you're afraid."
"Your fear is completely justified."
"Fear eventually gives us courage."
"Your past will try to stop
you from moving on in life."
"But even with that fear, move
one step forward for my sake."
"marry me, mademoiselle."
"You are the one who believes
that life should be big, not long."
"Let's live a big and grand life."
"Please say yes."
"By the way which film is that
dialogue from? Safar right?"
Anand you idiot.
Good evening.
This is All India Radio.
You're listening to the
news with Vandana Mehta.
In the headlines.
Due to the hijacking
of Pan Am flight 73 in Karachi...
the situation
continues to be tense.
Even after 15 hours of negotiations...
things are at an impasse.
It's being said
that these terrorists...
belong to Palestine's
Abu Nidal Group.
There are more than 100 Indian
passengers and flight crew on the plane.
Three men are in airport
security uniforms. - Yes.
This guy is wearing a pathani suit.
Look at him carefully.
He is their leader.
We have 4 entry points.
These two in the front.
- The five of you will go in first...
- Yes sir.
from this entry point.
Yes, sir!
Please protect my daughter!
Sir. The target has opened
the 2A window shutter.
What's the order, sir?
Don't shoot until you
see all four targets.
Sir, the plane lights are off!
- The auxiliary power's run out.
- Let's go.
- Military has cut the power for the plane!
- They are going to enter the plane!
The military won't enter!
Only the light has gone off sir!
- The military won't come inside.
- Sir... the battery is down sir!
That will put the
passengers in danger.
The time has come!
Everything will be over now!
Fahad! Mansoor! Fahad!
Kill them!
It's time.
It's just the emergency lights!
Shut up!
Sir the auxiliary power has run out.
Sit down!
Shut up!
Come on, come on! Let's go out!
Come on, get out!
Come on, slide down!
Out! Out!
Sanjana, come quickly.
Let's go.
Come.
Come on, move!
Come on, move quickly!
Slide down!
Please open the door, sir.
I'll help you.
Come on.
Let's go!
Out! Come out!
Come out! Sir, come out!
Mansoor!
No, Fahad. If you throw
the grenade we'll all die!
We're already dead, Mansoor!
We can survive Fahad!
Let's go son.
Leave her, come with us.
We can still escape, Fahad!
- Neerja, come on.
- You go, I'm just coming.
Ma'am come!
Leave us.
Mama come.
Come, come.
- Samar, carefully!
- Jump, jump!
Neerja, get down!
Neerja, let's go!
Sir, come on, sir.
Mama! I want my mama!
Neerja aunty, save us!
We want our mama.
Please save us! Please!
Help me please!
Come, come on.
We have to go down this slide.
Come on. Come with me.
Jatin... get down.
Go down.
No, no, no... do you have any
idea what we're going through.
I want to know the status
of purser Neerja Bhanot.
No, I will not hold the line anymore.
I'm tired of holding the line!
Hello.
Why are you crying, son?
Why are you crying?
Your sister will be fine.
Be quiet. Come here.
She will be fine.
Why is he crying?
This is bad,
you shouldn't cry like this.
Don't cry. It brings bad luck.
Mr. Harish...
but there's a lot of
confusion here.
It's difficult to get
any information.
Give me some time...
I'll call you as soon as
I find out anything.
Can you hear me? Hello.
- Yes... thank you.
- Bye.
Rama.
Let's go. Come on.
Shall we go?
Come, son. Let's go.
Hello. Welcome home!
Look...
on your birthday.
Mama remembers, darling.
Neerja's mom.
She sent a message for you.
- What?
- 'Pushpa, I hate tears.'
Neerja is no more.
It's been over a year...
It's hard to believe.
So cheerful... so full of life...
so... happy-go-lucky.
And she...
passed away on her 23rd birthday.
At first, it really hurt that...
she sacrificed her
life for her passengers.
She didn't even think
about her mama once?
Everyone asks me...
what kind of upbringing
did you give your daughter...
that she grew up to
be as brave as a soldier...
that the guns didn't scare her.
I didn't even know that...
my daughter was so brave...
and such a good hearted child.
In fact,
I would keep nagging her.
"Don't work so hard."
"Lower your eyes while walking."
"mind your own business."
"Think about your own honor
and life, when in danger."
Isn't that what we
teach our daughters?
We consider our brothers
to be the brave ones.
Sisters expect their
brothers to protect them.
No one ever asks
a sister for protection.
That's how I raised
Neerja as well.
You could share a laugh with her...
make her recite any
of Rajesh Khanna's dialogues.
But I wonder how this child...
turned out to be
so completely different.
Her horoscope said...
that she was destined
to be a shining light.
But when you lose your
23 year old daughter like this...
that pain is impossible
to describe.
There can be no bigger pain
in the world than losing one's child.
At times, I felt like dying too.
People tell me that Neerja isn't
dead, she has become immortal.
I console myself...
that my Laado's become immortal.
But what about the haunting thought...
that I'll never
see my daughter again.
The night she was leaving
for her last flight...
I kept nagging her repeatedly.
"Do this... don't forget this... do that..."
And she left.
I wish I had taken
her in my arms just once...
and hugged her tight.
Just once.
When Neerja received the highest
honor for bravery, the Ashok Chakra...
President Gyani
Zail Singh consoled me.
He said...
that there is no other
mother in the country like you.
You should hold your
head high with pride.
You should be proud.
"By sacrificing her life while
trying to save the passengers..."
"ms. Neerja, displayed exceptional
bravery under unusual circumstances."
Harish and I must have
good karma...
that Neerja was our daughter.
Even as she was breathing her last...
she taught me how to live.
There was a small child on the plane,
she told him...
"Tell my mama..."
Neerja's mom.
She sent a message for you.
That...
"Pushpa..."
"I hate tears!"
"This fleeting moment coaxes you
to think beyond yourself.."
"Go on living.. go on living.."
"Forget the sorrow of strangers.."
"Let the sun shine through your window."
"Go on living.. go on living.."
"Beneath the feet is cold.."
"the earth which beckons us to sprint."
"A lively fragrance in the chest of time,
it leaves everything behind."
"Let the sands of the past slip
through your fingers."
"Allow yourself to be
in the here and the now."
"This fleeting moment coaxes you
to think beyond yourself.."
"Go on living.. go on living.."
"A slice of laughter for taste.."
"A twig of life for keeps.."
"Go on living.. go on living.."
"Overcome the hiccups and hesitations.."
"This is the plea of time."
"Why die when you can live?"
"Drink the drops,
it's the rain of your dreams.."
"Let the streams pave the paths."
"Let yourself go beyond the light."
"This fleeting moment coaxes you
to think beyond yourself.."
"Go on living.. go on living.."
"This fleeting moment coaxes you
to think beyond yourself.."
"Go on living.. go on living.."
"We'll look fear in the eyes."
"We'll pass through the path of danger."
"We've set out with passion.."
"We'll look fear in the eyes."
"When it rains from people's eyes.."
"it marks the arrival of a new season."
"my dreams taught me to live."
"The night of life has passed.."
"Bright and shiny is the morning!"
"To hell with you, fear.."
"Your time's up, fear.."
"Let's get straight buddy,
fear is nobody."
"Open your eyes, no shut.
Tell fear to get lost!"
"Tell fear to get lost!"
"We'll look fear in the eyes."
"We'll pass through the path of danger."
"We've set out with passion.."
"We'll look fear in the eyes."