♪Translated
resynced by♪  XQ2☻
NEITHER SEEN NOR RECOGNIZED
CALMEST TOWN IN FRANCE
Gentlemen, as long as I'm alive
nothing will trouble...
the tranquillity of our little city!
Since the founding of Montpaillard*,
[*Smutty mountain]
revolutions have come and gone in France.
Thrones have crumbled,
without ever troubling
our little city.
That's why these regrettable incidents
which daily ridicule our authority...
Blaireau* again?
[*Badger]
Yeah, but I'll get him.
- Oh, yeah!
- I'll get him!
- Oh, sure!
Authority, respected by all,☻
is the most praiseworthy endeavour...
What happened to poor Parju?
Blaireau struck again, judge. It's been 20 years.
These incidents must cease!
Already, there are whispers,
The monster Calumny
glares at us with it's greedy eye!
M. Bluette*, how many detainees in your prison? [*blueberry]
About a dozen. Great bunch of guys, very calm.
Even the delinquents are calm.
This town's asleep.
I'd rather see my town burnt to ashes
than prey to disorder.
Oh, that's very good.
Since Henri IV...
Yes.
- Mr. Mayor.
-Hello, Parju. What's new?
Nothing, Mr. Mayor.
Well done, see that it stays that way.
- Mayor, I wanted to tell you...
-What?
That's Blaireau's doing for sure!
- Yes, Mayor.
When will you collar him, Parju.
I'd love to, but he's a cunning devil.
If he was Game Warden, he'd have
nabbed you already, Parju!
- Yeah, for sure!
- Come on, Parju!
Eyes sharp! Step lively!
Vive Montpaillard!
At ease!
TOWN HALL
Hello.
- Hello, Mayor.
- Hello.
- Hello, monsieur.
- Madame.
Bluette , come on, it's time for bridge.
Mr. & Mrs. Chaville are waiting.
- 47.
- 48.
- 47!
Amédée...
Amédée, have a go.
44.
Remember our secret bridge code?
-Yes, yes.
2 of clubs means I have a diamond.
- Yes.
- And 3 of hearts?
5 of spades.
- Hello, Mayor.
- Hello Chaville! Madame.
- Oh!
- Oh mon Dieu!
Hello papa, hello mama, hello gentlemen!
Arabella, my little girl!
Come in, M. Bluette .
She's got the devil in her,
your girl.
Better marry her off on the double.
At a gallop, my dear fellow.
- Hup!
- Oh, Mademoiselle!
So, my dear Dubenoit*, what's new?
[*sanctimonious ]
The pheasant, Madame... Pardon.
The pheasant, Madame,
roasted or à l'orange?
- Blaireau! You too, naturally!
- Hunting season's closed.
- No Blaireau, no game!
- Who's this Blaireau?
Blaireau... is... well...
Blaireau is Blaireau.
Come here, Pissoff.
I see. A sort of rural Bohemian.
A poacher! There's no room
in Montpaillard for outlaws!
- Hello, Countess.
-Hello, M. Fléchard. Arabella's waiting for you.
Thank you, Countess.
♪♪ (jazz)
What's this?
"A man loves you from the shadows."
Yes?
- Mademoiselle.
- Look who's here, little Chopin.
Mademoiselle, I brought you a Schumann waltz "I'm All Yours".
- Whose?
- "Yours", mademoiselle.
Well let's go, old man.
Work it, mademoiselle.
Fingers like little hammers.
♪♪
One, two three, four...
Fingers like little hammers!
Oh, pardon.
A little bit for Pissoff,
and a bit for Lucienne.
There.
Have a snort, huh?
Well, when you gotta go,
you gotta go, hey, Lucienne?
- That's beautiful, Blaireau.
- (That's beautiful, Blaireau.)
Voilà, voilà.
You're beautiful, Blaireau.
OK, you already said that.
Very beautiful,Blaireau.
Ah... thanks.
Very beautiful, Blaireau.
Ah, good.
Beautiful, Blaireau.
Yes, old man, that'll do.
- Beautiful, Blaireau.
- Hm, I get the message.
Beautiful, Blaireau!
Yes, alright, what... what is it? ... Ah!
Thank you, Lucienne.
Parju, come here, Parju!
Allez, Parju!
Come here!
Parju, Parju.
Come, bon appétit, Parju!
Huh? It's all for little Parju.
The king of the piggies.
Et fais bien grâce à Madame*.
Ay, ay, ay!
Listen, listen...
...you this way, me that way...
Come, Pissoff.
Come here, Pissoff.
It's Blaireau!
Ah!
Hm... There you are!
Always chasing the girls, huh?
Ah, Parju! Let him pass.
Yes. Hm...
Dunno what's with him these days.
I can't hold him back.
I'll get you, Blaireau.
Ooh, Look, a little fly.
Oh, pardon!
♪♪
"Love devours me.
Three times a week,
I suffer a bit less..."
It's idiotic.
Arabella, my love...
All the young men in town are weiners.
- You refused little Colibert.
- A weiner!
- And Rissol's son, from the polytechnic.
- Bernard de Montripier...
- Him? A plateful of weiners!
Montpaillard lacks men.
-Are you talking about me?
-About the whole Municipal council!
Counselor Guilloche,
that's the sort of opinion
you print in your rag,
"L'Eveil* de Montpaillard".
[*The Awakening]
It's the organ of those who
don't want their town asleep.
The organ of a young ambitious man.
- Better ambition than incompetence!
- Monsieur you better specify!
- I'm specifying!
- I'm listening!
-One word will suffice!
-Say it!
Blaireau!
Blaireau!...
Indeed, Monsieur!
For 20 years, Blaireau...
(indistinct)...
...Municipalité!
Blaireau will knuckle under!
Or else, prison!
Mealwhile, Messieurs,
as you snore under your * this year...
he dévastates our woods and our rivers...
accumulating unpunished crimes.
Oh!
Parju!
Yoo-hoo, Parju!
Ow! Ow!
A garter snake! Ay!
Get'em fresh! Get'em fresh!
Champipi, champignon mushrooms!
Come see my champipi, ladies!
I got lovely chanterelles!
Who wants my champipi?
My champipi  mushrooms...
Champignons.
Ah, hello Mme Baquet.
- How many?
- The usual.
Thank you.
Champipi, champignons!
Look at my chanterelles, ladies!
Who'll take'em? Who'll take'em?
Champipi, champignons!
Look at my lovely chanterelle, madame!
Who'll take'em? Who'll take'em?
Look at my champipi...
Voilà a champignon.
Who'll take'em? Who'll buy'em?
A champipi...
Voilà two champignons.
Who wants a lovely chanterelle?
Who wants'em? Who'll buy'em?
Voilà two, three...
four.
Badaboom... Boom!
Boom!
Ah...
Champipi,
champipi...
Look at my chanterelles!
Look at my champipi!
Looking for mushrooms, Parju?
Aquatic mushrooms!
- Looking for something?
- Where are the trouts?
Trouts?
Oh!
Ah!
- Trouts!
- But fishing season's over.
They call that representing
law and order.
I'll get you, Blaireau! I'll get you.
Who wants mushrooms,
champipi, champignons?
Not only are you incapable of
maintaining order, but you
actively create disorder, huh?
Ah, Arabella, how's your papa?
He's a blast.
-And your mother?
-She's a blast, too.
Come on! Don't just stand there!
- The "Noir" serials came in.
- I know, thanks.
I read that one, I read this...
Ah! "You Can Run",
I didn't read this one.
-Hold on, I'll check the others.
- Hello, M.Fléchard* [*wishy washy]
- Hello, M. Fléchard.
- Hello, ... uh...
- What would you like?
- "The Two of Us".
No more "Two of Us".
"Don't Shoot the Piano Player",
I won't take it today.
-I'll put it back.
- Oh!
- What do I owe you?
- 220.
- Has the "Paris Match" arrived?
- It's out front.
M. Fléchard, see you later for my lesson.
- Very well.
Some roses and ...
everlasting daisies, for mama.
Oh, my note!
Hey, Tarzan?
Let's get to work, mademoiselle
Today we'll tackle the
Allegretto Amoroso.
♪♪
More intensity, mademoiselle.
More passion.
-What are you thinking of?
- Oh, whatever.
Think of, I dunno, let's say...
the man you love.
That's not likely to happen soon.
I couldn't love anyone, but
a man of action.
Someone like me. And in Montpaillard,
there are only wieners!
Thank you, mademoiselle.
So I'm a wiener.
- You're from Dijon!
- That's easy to say.
What's wrong with him?
Ah, women!
Gentlemen, it's thanks to a woman
that I began my carreer
in administration.
She threw money out the window,
and I watched it drop.
That's so Parisian!
At the time,
I was a minister's cousin.
You're no longer his cousin?
He's no longer minister.
He barely had time to
post me to Montpaillard.
And not a moment too soon.
My alternatives were...
become a wardenn, or go to prison myself.
Another trout?
I can be tempted.
Yes, I haven't had trout...
since the close of the fishing season.
In fact, fishing opens tomorrow.
Léontine!
- Monsieur?
- It's Blaireau, naturally?
- I thought it'd please you Monsieur.
- Miserable! Shameless! Go!
And take that with you!
Oh! I had a thought, messieurs!
We've got that rascal! Red handed.
What's the penalty?
- Maximum, 6 months.
- Scandalous, but better than nothing.
In the clink, you rotter!
In the clink!
6 months for poaching and
3 for receiving poached goods
Great! We'll make a clean sweep!
Receivers of poached goods are
those who eat Blaireau's trouts.
OPENING OF FISHING SEASON
GRAND CONTEST
Public notice: tomorrow at the
opening of the fishing season,
"The Independant Gaul Foundation"
of Montpaillard, has organised
a grand fishing contest.
First prize: 5000 francs.
Second prize: 1500 francs.
Third prize: 500 francs.
Fourth prize:
a superb 'objet d'art'.
Parju, tout petit...
You can register at the Café Botineau!
- Hello!
- Hello Blaireau.
- I'll register tomorrow...
- I'll collect mudworms.
- You guys make me laugh.
- What bait would you use, Blaireau?
Contests are for choirboys!
- Your turn, Blaireau!
- Not for me, for my dog.
Well trimmed at the back.
The ears like always.
Messieurs!
- Mr. Mayor!
What? Mr. Mayor, you're in the contest?
Counselor Guilloche,
I never neglect an occasion
to get close to my constituents.
If you were in touch with
your constituents.
you wouldn't need to
get close to them.
-Give me some N° 4 fish-hooks.
-Number 4?! They're for whales!
"Each angler is allowed
a single line: floating,
"handheld, having only one hook,
"and fixed securely a rod,
"or red rubber."
Shall I sign you up?
- Yes.
Gentlemen, I drink to fishing...
a democratic sport...
symbol of liberty and independence
Long live fishing!
Last year I caught 7 bottom
feeding roaches as big as my hand.
- Bleaks!
- No, bottom roaches!
In 1913, I caught a 18 pound Koi!
Like Auguste's pike!
Exactly, a pike this big!
A monster!
How big was your pike?
- Like that.
- Eh...
Like that.
Cut it out Blaireau. It's easy to
catch fish when the season's closed.
In a fair contest, you're no
cleverer than the rest.
In a fair contest,
I can take all of you!
Parju!
Parju, sign me up for the contest.
A miscreant like you? Never!
Watch it, Parju, or I'll
shut you up for good.
You're threatening a
representative of the law?!
Game Warden, register Blaireau!
In the name of the Declaration
of Human Rights,
I charge you to register Blaireau!
♪♪ (fanfare)
♪♪
(March)
FISHING CONTEST
- 52.
- Trouteau!
53.
Monsieur Dubenoît!
-Mr. Mayor.
-Hello.
Here's your paper bag, Mayor.
- 54!
Well, Parju, 54.
Blaireau!
Blaireau?!
Me next to Blaireau, never!
Ah, Mr. Mayor, the random draw
must be respected,
or the contest is invalid.
After you, Mayor.
Each fish must be put
in the paper bag.
Shh, oh!
Attention! Attention!
The contest is about to start!
At the first gunshot, you can
throw in your bait!
Come on, Parju.
Contestants must loudly call out
their number, after each catch!
At the 2nd gunshot, cast your lines!
(Oh, ah...)
What's going on?
(Oh!)
Parju, I can't work this.
Excuse the incident!
It's coming, it's coming!
♪♪
(The Trout - Franz Schubert)
54!
54.
- 54!
- 54.
- 54...
54!
OH! Again?
-Look at that!
-Lovely.
- 26!
- 27!
Wait.
- 54!
- 54...
54!
A beauty.
No, I think this one's mine.
Ah no, pardon, it's mine.
54!
12!
54.
54!
-53!
-Aaah!
And it's a beauty!
- And he's back!
- 54.
BLAIREAU THE WINNNER
Oh, well!
Hello, gentlemen.
I say, Counselor Guilloche,
great joke you played on the mayor!
That's no joke, it's information.
Gosh darned bugger!
-I've got him!
- Who?
-Blaireau.
-No! -Yes!
- Where?
- The room next door!
-You taking the piss, Parju?
-No, I have him!
The dog will lead me to Blaireau!
Dog or no dog,
stick Blaireau in the slammer!
Trot along!
(♪♪)
Galloping, mademoiselle!
(♪#)
No, no, I can't listen
to it anymore! Enough.
M. Fléchard, you're so hard on me!
-Too bad!
-No, good!
I like it when you're mean.
You're a man.
Non, I'm an wiener, you're a wiener,
we're all wieners! Get out!
- No, I'll go tell mama!
- That's it, you tell your mama. Good!
Arabella, you want action?
I'll give you action!
"Mademoiselle,
"...the desperate man who
loves you from the shadows...
"...waits for you at midnight...
"...by the wine press.
Signed: An earthworm in love with a star."
♪
Pissoff, come here, doggy.!
Come here! Pissoff!
Hmm, bugger you, fat pig!
You'll pay for this. Dearly!
Go on, go, find'im!
Find'im!
Woah! Red-handed! I got'im!
Take it to your master!
Where's Blaireau?
Well, doggie?
Go, take it to him.
Bring him the lovely rabbit.
Take it to him.
Ah! There he is!
Flagrant délit!
I'll catch you red-handed!
Just you wait, my little piggy.
Just you wait.
I've got him! I've got him!
Oh... Oh... Oh no!
Come, come here!
Come here, my little choux.
I'll get you, Blaireau,
I'll get you!
Voilà.
C'mon!
See ya around, Parju!
I'll get you, Blaireau!
Ow, ow!
Wha...?
Blaireau!
Don't be an ass!
Parju, What's this get up?
Blaireau, Mr. Mayor.
-Bloody hell...!
-Shh, sh...
Will you let people sleep!
-What's this racket!
-...commotion, what!
I missed him by a hair, Mr Mayor.
Get dressed, Parju!
Keep your eyes open!
Do your daily rounds!
Above all your nightly rounds!
I'll start right now
And don't let me see you again
without Blaireau in handcuffs!
- Yes, Mayor.
- Fall out! Shh!
"at midnight by the wine press."
We shall see.
Ah, gotcha!
Ow, ouh!...!
My badge!
M. Parju, a game warden
without his badge,
is like a regiment
that has lost its standard!
- Yes, Mayor.
Nail Blaireau, ASAP!
It was dark.
I couldn't swear it was him.
Only Blaireau could have done it.
- But, I swear...
Aah! Am I mayor of Montpaillard
or are you, Parju?
You're the mayor, Mr. Mayor.
- I'll take care of the rest.
Hello. Notify the Prefecture,
to send me reinforcements!
- What's happening?
- Seems they're arresting Blaireau.
Ah, they'll have
a hell of a time doing that!
They sure went all out
at the Prefecture!
Voilà, reinforcements, Mr. Mayor.
Section, halt!
Say, are those planes with you?
No, it's general manoeuvres.
Ah, general man...
Yes, I thought as much.
Gentlemen, we'll attack
at 11:12, local time!
Forward!
Mount... up!
Oh là là...
Oh sweety guess what?
Last night, Blaireau
broke into our property,
he broke a cold frame
and knocked out the game warden!
Oh! It was Blaireau?
- Everything ready?
- Yes sir.
Perfct, shh!
♪♪ hmm hm...
♪ Je vais faire un petit café
♪
Ah! Wha...!
Pécades, pécades...!*
I'm innocent!
Calm down, Blaireau!
Parju, do you recognize this man?
- He can't, the blasted blockhead!
- Silence, Blaireau!
Parju, do you recognize this man?
Oui, Juge.
Parju!
Parju, come on!
Gendarmes, would you...
Blaireau, call off your dog goldarnit!
♪
He'll be quiet now, Mr. president.
Blaireau: the Game Warden
having formally recogniz...
He can't, I was in my bed.
I have an alibi!
Honest people don't need alibis.
Do you have a witness?
- Certainly!
Pissoff, was I in my bed?
Woof!
Haha ha!
Enough joking.
Counselor, you have the floor.
Few words will suffice for my plea:
Indulgence or pardon,
pardon or indulgence.
Very good!
The tribunal,...
after due deliberation,
condemns Blaireau to one month in prison.
I'm innocent!
Even if you weren't guilty,
all your unpunished misdeeds,
over 20 years...
Misdeeds?!
I did misdeeds? Me?
My dear Blaireau, it won't do you
any good to tell me stories.
Me, who for 20 years bought wild
game from you during the off season.
Guards, take him away.
-I'm innocent!
-Woof, woof!
Coming!
Ah! There he is!
My dear Blaireau, glad to meet you!
I heard so much.
It's fine, leave us.
- After you, Blaireau.
- But, Mr. Director!
Please, you're a guest in my home,
I mean, 'your' home.
- May I?
- I'm overwhelmed!
My pleasure.
I hope, dear Blaireau, that
during these few weeks
which the government of the Republic
has confided you in my care,
we'll have an excellent rapport.
Mr. Director,
I'm very easy to live with.
Bravo!
So, tell me my friend, it seems
someone beat up the game warden?
That's real funny.
Yes, but what's less funny
is that I'm innocent.
Ah, not that old miscarriage of
justice stuff! You cease to be interesting.
♪ Les rendez-vous de noble compagnie
♪ Se donnent tous
en ce charmant séjour
♪ Et doucement, on y passe la vie...
- Morning, kids!
- Morning, Director.
- How's your tonsils?
- I gargled this morning.
Let's see. Swelling's down,
keep up the treatment.
-Good news from your wife?
-Yes, thank God, director.
Very good. Back to work.
As you see, Blaireau,
my penal system's very simple.
After you.
I occupy my men with the work
they used to do
before they took a bad turn.
- Hello, director.
- Hello, Grégory!
Our latest addition.
- Hello, monsieur.
- An excellent pedicurist.
- Ah!
- Eh, watch it!
'Was', an excellent pedicurist.
Hello, Antoine.
- Mr. Directeur.
Our tailor.
My dear Blaireau,
I don't have much
available, at the moment,
but I'll show you around, and
you can choose your own room.
You're too kind, Director.
There! Number 14.
Good exposure, but a bit warm
during this season.
You've got nothing better?
Wait, I have just the thing.
Little number 4.
Ah, my dear Blaireau,
may I present Victor,
our Head Guard.
- Enchanté.
- Welcome.
It matters to me that you feel...
ah, how can I put it...
that you're in a home-style prison.
Victor, number 4.
My dear Blaireau, see you later,
I'll let you get settled.
Thank you, Mr. Director.
Ah, I wanted to ask,
your morning coffee; black or with milk?
Spiked with liqueur.
Always the same thing when
he tries to marry her off.
Doesn't seem she's convinced.
You want me to marry?
- Yes.
As fast as possible?
- Yes!
Fine, I found one.
-Finally!
A man who's proved himself!
- Perfect!
She'll only marry the man of her dreams;
her ideal, her prince charming.
She wants to marry Blaireau!
PRISON REGULATIONS
Animals are forbidden to enter
on prison grounds.
I'll say it was already torn.
Come on, come.
Oh, my puppy!
I'm so happy to see my big bow-wow!
Oh, my little bow-wow...
It's not him! It's not him!
Mr. President...
I'm innocent.
No! No!
Arabella!
Here I am. Mmmwah!
What are you doing, sweety?
A package for my fiancé, papa.
What?
Hold this, papa.
Thank you, papa.
No, not the clock.
LATUDE OR
THIRTY-FIVE YEARS OF CAPTIVITY
"Don't let them beat you down.
Care Packages for Detainees
♪ Les rendez-vous
de noble compagnie
♪ Se donnent tous
en ce charmant séjour
♪ Les rendez-vous de noble compagnie
♪ Se donnent tous en hm, hmm...
So, Parju, what's new?
Nothing, Mayor. Not anymore.
You seem bored, my dear Parju.
A bit, Mr. Mayor.
You miss Blaireau, huh?
So, Counselor Guilloche,
- Blaireau's finished.
- Bravo, Mr. Mayor.
The town's never been so calm.
A real nest of slugs.
-Perfect!
That's how I like it!
So Monsieur * how's business?
Calm. Very calm.
Perfect, perfect.
- Chef!
- Voilà.
So, chef...
- Three poached crayfish.
- No more crayfish, monsieur.
- Then, terrine of hare.
- No more hares, monsieur.
Three woodcocks flambées, then.
No more woodcocks flambées,
Nothing for eight days, since...
Yes?
- Oh, M. Bluette !
- Not disturbing you, am I?
Ah, no, here...
- a little cigar.
- Gladly.
Hmm, el Papero!
They take good care of you.
Naturally, I'm innocent.
Come, come, let's be serious.
Tell me, what did you do
before your conviction?
Odd jobs.
Good, perfect,
you can continue with that.
In a prison, there's always
something to occupy a handyman.
Follow me, Blaireau.
Good morning, Director.
Good morning, kids.
Come, my dear Blaireau.
Well... Huh?
M. Bluette , do you like crayfish?
Do I ever?
Shall I rig something up?
Rig away, my friend, rig away!
What about me?
Blaireau, package for you!
Again?
One per day!
"Care Packages for Detainees"
really know how to things!
Oh, no way!
Mm... a star... a what?
"From a star to an earthworm"?!
No.
For M. Blaireau.
Oh well!
Oooh!
Oh! Aaah!
Blaireau, another package for you!
- Two in one day?
- Oooh!
"Protection of the Innocent".
See that, I'm innocent?
You know, so are we!
Oh là là...
- Oh I say!
- Oh là là!
Ask him, I say.
- No.
- Old 'pops Bluette ' is a pal.
I couldn't ask him that.
He did it for a guy, once.
For his daughter's first communion.
What's up, dear Blaireau?
Ask him, go on.
M. Bluette , tonight's a new moon.
And?
And, I've set 300 snares,
and with this weather,
we're on Easy Street.
Oh, yeah? Oh, I see you coming.
No, Blaireau. No!
You'll be back at midnight.
Hm, swear?
M. Bluette , I swear.
Blaireau...
won't you take me with you?
But... M. Bluette ...
Are you serious?
It'd make me so happy!
I shouldn't, but...
- Look.
- Oooh...
- it's marvellous!
- Shh!
That way.
Oh...
Oh, lovely animal!
- Shh!
HUNTING RESERVE
-Oh, marvellous!
- Shh.
Oh... Oh...
This is not good...
not good at all.
I'm having visions.
46°!  (114.8°F)
Oh I say!
Don't tell me...
- Yes.
No, no, M. Bluette.
No, no.
♪
- Well! Good evening, Bluette..
- Good evening, Mayor.
So, I hope you've crushed,
that damned Blaireau?
You've no idea how much...!
Never forget the
tranquillity of Montpaillard
is in your hands.
Absolu... You know me, hm?
A h-hand in a g-glove...
Exactly, let's not treat that
scoundrel like a 1st class passenger!
Ohlala, imagine that!
I make life hard for him.
-Good evening, Bluette.
-Goodbye, Mr. Mayor.
- Bless you.
- Thank you, Mr. Mayor.
- Right, we need to get in.
- OK, let's go.
Watch out!
Well, Victor?
Director! Good evening.
What's the meaning of this?
I took the liberty of
taking them to the cinema.
- Are you mad?!
- But, under cover of dark.
I see, well no big deal,
open up.
Yes, Director.
- I'll be...
- Don't tell me that...
- Yes.
- Ah no!
Good thing you've got yours, Director.
That's just it...
Allow me.
- Bravo.
- A handyman's skill.
Tell me, what did you see
at the cinéma?
"Arsène Lupin".
Imagine how happy they were!
Oh, you're much better.
I told you: a 3 week diet.
I could sure eat something.
By all means...
You need to regain your strength, now.
Blaireau gets out of prison tomorrow.
Blaireau?!
If it's any consolation,
he's as sick as you are.
How are you, Blaireau?
Oh, my liver, ugh... enormous.
With me, it's my stomach.
Good thing I get out tomorrow.
Oh no, oh no.
Oh no.
- Aaah!
BRAKES CAN SLIP
INSURANCE STICKS
A PACKAGE FOR BLAIREAU?
Why?
It's my secret.
Arabella, I want the truth.
You're drunk, Mr Fléchard!
But, Arabella. Mademoiselle!
And Blaireau accepted your package?
Yes, papa!
-Jams, fruits?
-Yes!
The ...?
Murderous demons of the speed!
-Blaireau is innocent.
- That's a lie!
I smacked Parju!
- You? Come on!
- Here's the proof!
- I don't believe you.
- The man who loves you from the shadows
- You've read my letters!
- I wrote them.
- You?
- Yes.
- But why?
- Because I love you!
- What?
- I love you!
I LOVE YOU!
You did that?... You?
Yes.
What's he done?
-That's really marvellous.
-Yes, Arabella!
-You'll be sent to prison.
-Yes... what?
And I thought you were insipid,
idiotic, insignificant!
But if you're in prison,
I'll be crazy about you.
In prison? I'm going.
- You'd do that for me?
- Yes, Arabella.
Right away?
I'm going! I'm going!
Fléchard! Fléchard!
Where are you going?
To a Court of the Republic
to admit to my crime.
There is no crime in Montpaillard!
I beat up Parju.
Blaireau's innocent.
- What are you babbling about?
- I'm not babbling,
I'm expiating.
It's a miscarriage of justice.
There are no judicial errors
in Montpaillard!
It's a frightful scandal.
There are no scandals in Montpaillard!
Oh, there'll be one,
I garantee it.
No, no, no...
You don't just up and confess
at vacation time!
Mr. Prosecutor,
remorse doesn't choose the day.
Remorse!
Delaying my vacation doesn't
cause you any remorse?
My children's health
is of little import to you?
When do I go to prison?
And you want to go to prison,
to boot? It's crowded there!
I want to sleep in prison tonight.
Nossir, you will not sleep
in prison tonight.
When then?
We'll notify you in writing!
FOR ARMAND FLECHARD
- Who is this package for?
- For my fiancé.
- He just got out of prison.
- No, he's just going in.
G-going in? Who?
My new fiancé, papa.
No! No! No!
-...La!
-Voila!
So, that's it? I'm free?
Yes. Goodbye, my old Blaireau.
Send me news.
I'll bring you some game.
- Oh, come on!
It won't cost much, for you or me.
You still intend to poach?
We can't all be functionaries,
Mr Director.
- See ya, M. Bluette.
- Goodbye, Blaireau.
What's this?
- Goodbye, Victor.
- Goodbye, Blaireau.
Come back, one second!
My pleasure, Directeur!
It's incredible!
The real culprit gave a complete confession,
and turned himself in to justice
Ah, Blaireau. What would you say
if I told you
you were innocent?
- That I already knew it.
- You were right, Blaireau.
I just received a letter
from the public prosecutor.
-You're innocent.
-Who did it?
Fléchard, the piano teacher.
Even professors are getting
involved, now?
Here's exactly what's in the letter.
"After the indispensable formalities,
Blaireau will be set at liberty
as soon as possible."
Now, I'm free.
Woah there, "as soon as possible"!
-How's that, "as soon as possible"?
-Blaireau, I'll handle that.
- I'm going, now.
- No!
What, "no"?!
You served your time
as a guilty man, alright.
But...
we learned today, you were innocent.
We find ourselves
presented with new
formalities to fulfill.
So, because I'm innocent
I have to stay in prison?!
The law is the law!
To be imprisoned, it's not
absolutely necessary
that you be guilty,
On the other hand,
to be set free, it's not
always enough to be innocent.
But I...
Poor Blaireau, go.
Bonbon?
Yes, come in!
Ah, here you are, Fléchard!
My compliments, eh!
What would you like?
- I came to turn myself in to prison.
- Do you have papers?
- No, Mr. Director.
- A word, a letter, from the prosecutor?
No, nothing at all.
And you imagine I'll throw you in
the slammer just like that? For kicks?
You astonish me, upon my word!
You need a recommendation
to go to prison?
Certainly!
It's still the old favoritism!
- Yes!
Mr. Director.
What, now?
I don't mean to reproach, Mr. Director,
but I think you're taking
your time to release me.
Impossible, not before receiving
the prosecutor's order!
So, not only did I serve
my time while being innocent
but you won't turn me loose!
Don't that beat all!
I can beat that, I'm guilty
but they won't arrest me!
If we put every guilty person
in prison, it'd never end!
Pretty neat! Justice!
- No.
- Will you shut up!
- No, I won't shut up. I want out!
- I want in!
- I want out!
ENOUGH!
- Victor! -Director?
- Throw Blaireau in the clink.
As for you, M. Fléchard, out!
M. Bluette, I have to get in prison.
No!
I'll complain to the government!
You're charming, but no!
Look here...
No!
No, no!
I'm innocent!
Oh, when I get out,
this is gonna get ugly!
I'm innocent!
SCANDAL IN MONTPAILLARD
grave judicial error
Watch your ass, Dubenoit!
Go ahead!
- L'Eveil! L'Eveil!
- Read all about it!
I knew he was innocent!
I knew it!
(Mégaphone)
Innocent man rots in prison!
We, the sons of Saint Louis,
thirst for justice,
We did not storm
the Bastille for nothing!
Our newspaper,
l'Eveil de Montpaillard,
will obtain Blaireau's liberty!
Let us shout our indignation!
Liberate Blaireau!
Fustigate all decadent public powers!
Let us feast Blaireau's
new found innocence,
tomorrow in front of the prison!
Ah, poor Parju,
Montpaillard is no longer
the calmest town of Francee.
LIBERATE BLAIREAU, LIBERATE BLAIREAU ...
BLAIREAU! BLAIREAU! BLAIREAU!
♪♪
BLAIREAU! BLAIREAU! BLAIREAU!...
My fellow citizens,
I'm too emotional
to speak for long.
Your newspaper,
l'Eveil de Montpaillard,
has asked you to be here.
And all Montpaillard is here,
manifesting its sympathy
with an innocent martyr,
and its reprobation
for municipal tyranny!
But...
let's put aside, on this beautiful day,
our passions and hatreds,
and let us repeat these words,
which illustrate the
sentiment that unites us all:
"Pardon us, Blaireau"!
PARDON US, BLAIREAU!
Long live Blaireau!
LONG LIVE BLAIREAU!
♪♪
This feast is for you, Blaireau.
You shouldn't have, it's too much!
- There!
- All that's for me?
TO YOUR HEALTH, BLAIREAU!
- I'm overwhelmed.
- Oh, no.
Come on guys, it's my round!
VIVE BLAIREAU! VIVE BLAIREAU!
Nice to share in the glory, eh?
- You, here, Mr. Mayor?!
I'm greatly amused.
Instead of shouting "Guilloche"
they're shouting "Vive Blaireau"
That's normal,
- I'm not the victim, here.
- Oh, but that'll come!
Montpaillard's next mayor will be
neither Dubenoit nor Guilloche.
It'll be Blaireau!
Well done, Counselor!
Guilloche, the wine bill.
And now the Cycling Grand Prix
of Montpaillard!
Director, Counselor Guilloche.
...the Cycling Grand Prix...
and firing the starting pistol:
Blaireau!
Ready!
Hold on, you.
Right! Mustn't play around
with these things.
I'll get you, Blaireau!
Start on 3.
1...
2...
2 and a half!
3!
Arabella, I tried everything.
- Perfect. Are you in prison?
- No.
Why not?
They don't want me.
In that case I don't want you either.
But I love you, Arabella.
Prove it.
Nice, party, Judge!
My dear Blaireau, you're the
hero of Montpaillard,
And thanks to whom?...
Thanks to me.
Pardon?
But of course.
If you hadn't been found guilty, first,
you couldn't have been
declared innocent, later.
And nobody would care about you.
That's oddly true.
I hope you don't hold
a grudge against me?
Come now, why would I?
Everyone has his specialty.
You found me guilty,
because you're a judge.
If you'd been a lawyer,
you'd have found me innocent.
To each his specialty, eh.
Come have a drink with me,
you'll feel better.
Delighted.
Dunno what's wrong with me today.
So, we're playing soldiers?
Damned Dubenoit!
Love, a great deal of love.
Are you a fakir?
During my off hours.
Aah!
Eh, drink a toast with us, Mayor!
What an honor for me, Blaireau!
Come on, Guilloche,
Come drink a glass with us!
But not too much!
To justice!
-To innocence!
Well Parju, what do you say?
Feel like having a drink with
the big shots of Montpaillard eh?
Parju.
Let's shake hands, old pal.
Such popularity!
Blaireau will owe you one,
when he's elected.
Elected? You're messing with me!
Blaireau, at the finish line,
gives out the Grand Prize!
Voilà!
Mme de Chaville,
Would you do me the honor
and the privilege
of stomping out
the next song with me?
Oh, how rustic!
I'll stomp, my friend, I'll stomp!
So, Guilloche, how's it hanging?
- So, Counselor, "how's it hanging?"
- Entertaining, that Blaireau, isn't he?
Laugh, gentlemen.
I admit I made a mistake.
Youth, dear fellow!
Of course, the people...
-are courageous,
- Yes!
hard-working,
but...
very ungrateful.
- Oh, la-la!
Eh, Fléchard!
If the real culprit leaves,
the feast is over!
Voila!
No prison, no marriage.
You go down there...
and I'll arrange everything.
♪♪ (waltz)
Not one word, or I'll shoot!
- M. Blaireau!
- Hands up!
So, you like terrorisers,
scarfaces, gangsters?
Come kiss your great big thug, hm!
No, no, not me, him.
Well, I see I'm not needed, anymore.
Arabella, you'll see
how happy we'll be.
-After I get out of prison...
-I don't want you in prison anymore.
I'll go all the same! Arabella...
- No.
Starting tonight,
I make the decisions.
Yes, my love.
Understood?
-Yes, my love.
- Good!
Fine, I won't go to prison.
No!
Allow me, gentlemen,
to stand by your side.
Henceforth, we'll fight together
against the cataclysm which
will engulf our nation's government
at the hands of Blaireau.
♪♪
Fléchard?!
Arabella? It's marvellous!
I must announce the good news
to her father! Léon!
But, papa...
Léon! M. Blaireau just told me!
I know!
Never!
And I'll take care of you!
Léon!
Well, I'll take care of him.
M. Lerechigneux, a word...
Is Fléchard guilty?
Without a doubt.
Could you do me a favour.
Throw him in the can, ASAP.
Pouah! What rotgut!
- My wine, rotgut?!
- It's cat's peepee.
- My wine, cat's peepee?!
- Taste it yourself.
Taste it yourself.
It's excellent, this wine!
Taste it properly.
- Scrapes the throat, huh?
- A bit young, maybe.
I know. Taste this one,
it's famous.
- It's very mediocre.
- Now taste yours, again.
- This one's excellent.
- OK, and this one.
- Lacks body.
- We agree.
This one...
Now yours.
Excellent, wine!
If you were a nice guy...
Listen... call me Léon.
If you were a nice guy, Léon...
I'm always a nice guy, Blaireau.
Alright, if Léon were a nice guy...
Yes.
you'd give me...
your daughter's hand
Oh, I'll give it to you, Blaireau.
Fine!
But, not for me.
Ah, not for you?
- No.
For Fléchard
It's for Fléchard?
Whatever you do...
is well done my... Blaireau.
Arrh!
I'll call Fléchard.
Fléchard!
- Ho!
-Fléchard!
*
Hey, Blaireau!
Hey! You coming for a drink,
Blaireau?
Voilà, they're so charming!
M. Bluette, Counselor Guilloche,
Parju, Mme de Chaville, Mlle Rose.
Let's see, M. Blaireau, M. Chaville
Judge, Mr. Mayor... Perfect!
Attention! Don't move!
You sure got me drunk last night
hey, you swine?
Not without difficulty.
- Smile!
Perfect! Don't move!
One...
two...
three!
Monsieur, you wanted to go to prison?
Right then, let's go!
-But I'm getting married!
- Voila!
You to prison and me on vacation.
Oh, no, come on!
Aw, will you look at that!
M. Bluette!
No, no, no!
- M. Bluette!
- No. No!
M. Bluette!
No!
You're not gonna leave this little
lady outside on her wedding night!
But... regulations!
Voila!
You'da never thought of that?
Yeah.
But, no one must know.
No one. No-one!
Come in, dear madam.
- M. Blaireau...
- Yes, go, go.
Shh!
IT'S DONE !
LONG LIVE THE NEWLYWEDS!
♪♪ (Fanfare)
CALMEST TOWN IN FRANCE
HAPPIEST TOWN IN FRANCE
There! For you.
I'm overwhelmed.
Yes.
- For me?
- Yes, for you.
Gotcha, Blaireau! I got you!
♪Translated
resynced by♪  XQ2☻