Kousi!
Hey, Kousi.
Come here.
I've told you several times...
What if you'd been bitten by the dog?
Come!
- What happened?
- I don't know. It's not starting!
We only have 15 minutes left.
Leave it here for now.
Let me see if we can get a ride.
- We're headed there too. Get in.
- Thank you!
Let's go.
[Motivational M.G.R. Song playing on radio]
You look familiar.
What do you do?
Hey...
Hey!
Your phone is ringing.
We've reached.
Get down.
I'm talking to you.
Get out!
Sir, can I get down
after this song finishes?
'With your heart, For the Truth,
Rise and Charge'
'Few Months Ago'
Ramu, working on a festival holiday?
Where are you off to?
- Medical shops doesn't have festivals!
- Fair enough.
Sir, I'll pay the rent tomorrow.
I don't have any money on me.
Did I ask you for the rent?
You can pay when
you have the money, okay?
Okay, sir.
Can you drop me at the medical shop?
What happened to your vehicle?
My brothers took it three days back
for shoot. They're not back.
You give your brothers everything!
Hold this.
Give it to me
Ramu...
Don't get me wrong.
You're spoiling those boys.
You give all your
earnings to them,
and now you're struggling
to even pay the rent!
They are poor things.
We grew up together
at the orphanage.
After I got a job and moved out,
they had no one to take care of them.
Even I have no one besides them.
I want to support them
till they settle down.
But that is why you took a bank loan
and educated them.
What are they doing, though?
They're going around with a camera
for some YouTube channel!
I'm working in a medical shop
though I don't like it.
Atleast let them do
something they love.
Whatever you say.
It's all about money.
The moment you run out of money,
they will just desert you.
- Sir, let's go through the park.
- The park?
Why?
The boys are there.
I want to hand the house keys.
The boys?
When I called them this morning,
they said they are in Trichy.
They must have pranked you!
Put that helmet on me.
I'm coming, too.
I'll sort them out!
Wow, balloons!
You buffalo!
Stop here.
There they are!
- Brother is here.
- Hello!
Why do you give our phone numbers
to random people?
The house owner called for rent
and sucked the life out of us.
Don't say that...
Just because it's his house,
he will ask for rent?
You know something?
He should pay us rent
for living in that house!
Him and his ugly mug.
His very sight irks me.
I'm sparing him for his wife's sake.
You are sparing me
for my wife's sake?
Welcome, sir.
When did you come?
When did I come?
You didn't know it was me
riding this vehicle?
We didn't know!
You don't know this vehicle
belongs to me?
We don't know!
You didn't know this helmet
belongs to me?
We swear, we didn't know.
But you know my wife very well?
We do, sir!
This ends today!
[Chanting prayer]
- I should pray in whose name?
- God's name.
Which God?
Who else? The Gods that
are rocking Tamil Nadu.
Gods Siva and Viki.
'What you gonna do now?'
'Yo yo, let's go!'
'Let's go!'
"Our hearts are guileless,
Our antics are boundless, we're fearless."
"Our memes are countless,
We troll everyone, we point out mistakes."
"Honour, dignity, pride - what's all that?
Love, friendship, affection - that's everything."
"Never hesitated to borrow some money;
Never missed an opportunity to show-off."
"We pay bribes for money;
We're the internet boys!"
"We shed tears over comments;
"We pull pranks and scam you;
We're the internet boys!"
"We salute those who share our posts;
"Internet boys, internet boys;
We are the internet boys!"
"1, 2, 3, 4... so many movies;
Our undaunted hearts watch it all."
"The superb kind and the sloppy kind;
We have it in us to binge on everything."
"The internet boys!"
"What you gonna do now?"
"Law and order have all but died;
Fairness and justice are in shortage."
"Facebook and Twitter buzzing with our posts;
Has made wrong-doers think about their acts."
"When we asked the question;
It prompted the government to action."
"What you gonna do now?"
"Though they tried to shackle us;
We fought and won Jallikattu."
"What you gonna do now?"
"This is not idle work;
It's ideal work."
"Even when they say it's The End;
We can make it trend."
"We score instant wins;
We're the internet boys!"
"Our hearts are guileless,
Our antics are boundless, we're fearless."
"Our memes are countless,
We troll everyone, we point out mistakes."
"Honour, dignity, pride - what's all that?
Love, friendship, affection - that's everything."
"Never hesitated to borrow some money;
Never missed an opportunity to show-off."
"We pay bribes for money;
We're the internet boys!"
"We shed tears over comments;
"We pull pranks and scam you;
We're the internet boys!"
"We salute those who share our posts;
"Internet boys, internet boys;
We are the internet boys!"
"What you gonna do now?"
Just the sight of that guy irks me.
I'm sparing him for his wife's sake.
Enough of cleaning the fan.
Don't go to the
house downstairs anymore.
I shouldn't go down?
Why, dear?
Don't ask me questions.
Just do as I say!
Then who will teach me yoga
in the mornings?
Who is teaching you yoga?
Master Viki.
That fat rat
is your yoga master?
If you ever go there
to do yoga or anything other crap...
You've been saying that for days!
Go and grab his stuff!
- Sir, don't...
- Stop it!
Where have you come from?
You dare take stuff from my tenants?
Who are you guys?
- What do you want?
- Don't shout at me...
If he just repays the loan he borrowed,
I'll be on my way.
- How much?
- 1500 rupees.
You created this ruckus
for 1500 rupees?
- Sir, you don't...
- It's okay!
Here.
Get going.
Pay it on time
next month.
Of course.
Buzz off now.
Go back to your homes.
Don't just crowd for everything.
Go away!
Ramu, you could have told me!
Saw the scene he created
for 1500 rupees?
- It's not that, sir...
- It's not what?
You give all your earnings
to your brothers.
Also, if someone begs for money,
you buy them food!
You're 34 years old!
Stop living for others.
Live a little for yourself.
You go to a few places...
Have you got money
in your pocket?
Do you have atleast 10 bucks?
Sir...
Sir, that is...
Well, it is...
Brother?
Oh, good. I was worried his yelling
would make you pay up.
You are the best, brother!
What are they
taking the money for?
Are they going to pay
the school fees of orphaned children?
Or pay for an old person's
medical expenses?
Or donate food for the poor?
Where are they taking
that damn money?
- Hey...
- Sir?
Why do you look tense?
Nothing, sir.
I am normal.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
You have any idea who he is?
I'm warning you,
leave him alone...
- I will--
- Calm down! Stop yelling.
- You came to kill this man, right?
- What? Me?
Why are you getting agitated?
- You're going to make me stab him.
- You're doing one mistake after another...
Shut up.
Everyone, please listen
to what I am going to say.
If any of you...
He makes me hold an old man
and he grabs that gorgeous girl?
Just let him go.
Or, I'll kill her.
Why would you kill me
for that man?
Shut up,
I'll bite your ears off.
You want to play it that way?
If you kill her,
I will kill this man.
Sir, please!
I don't even know
who this man is.
Sir, let me go.
Please! Please! Please!
Quit nagging.
Take your hand off her waist.
Why? You can hold his waist
if you'd like!
Just take your hands
off her waist.
I won't!
Don't cheat, buddy!
Get your hands off.
Don't talk unnecessarily...
Sir, please I beg you.
Let me go.
Sir, please!
Sir?
Please! Please!
- Please, sir!
- Hello?
She is your co-hostage, isn't she?
Look how she is begging for her life.
Why are you just standing there
like it's a college viva.
I saw the camera.
Camera?
Impossible!
Our cameraman...
Sarath?
Yes, sir?
- What are you doing?
- I am hiding, sir!
- Come again?
- I'm hiding, brother.
- No one saw you, right?
- Not at all!
- Let's roll the camera?
- Sure! Rolling, action!
I'll whack you!
Sir, we were doing it for kicks!
Be a sport and
say, 'We're doing fun!'
It's a prank, sir.
'We're doing fun?'
You dare play a prank?
You--!
What were you thinking?
What do we look like to you?
When you put a knife to our necks,
we're supposed to get scared.
Finally when you say it's a prank,
we're supposed to smile for the camera?
A reporter?
If I call the cops, they'll lock you up
under public nuisance for 5 years.
I'll call them?
No, please don't.
The next time I see you in Chennai
with a camera, you're done for!
Rascals.
Tell them to disperse.
Get going, everyone.
Leave!
Boys...
You're one of those people
who make videos for YouTube?
Yes, sir.
You're putting a knife to my neck
in front of such a big crowd...
What if someone from the crowd
stepped forward and beat you up?
Sir, don't humour me.
Who would dare come close
when I hold a knife to your neck?
Even that girl was scared
when she had that knife to her neck.
Only after she knew it was a prank
did she slap my friend.
So...
In front of such a large crowd...
A girl just slapped you.
You didn't feel like slapping her back?
Oh, right.
If I slap her back
in return...
She'd slap me again.
I'll hit her back.
Is this what revenge is?
The courage she gathered to slap me...
I need to break that courage.
She should only feel fear
when she tries to hit me again.
Instilling that fear is true revenge.
Wow!
- Oh yes...
- Sir!
Sir! Sir!
Aren't you 'Prank Star' Siva?
Sir, I'm your biggest fan.
During the Gaja Cyclone,
you helped the Delta Region people...
and raised money
by donating both your kidneys!
You're god, sir.
- I'll fall at your feet.
- To handle any potential problems...
we set-up these men and...
- Sir?
- Go!
Sir, during the Jallikattu protests...
Get out.
You take so much risk in public,
set-up these men too...
why do you go through
all this pain?
Sir, we need to make money.
We want to make solid cash...
in lakhs and crores!
What will you do by making
lakhs and crores?
Sir, he is...
Don't.
No, dude.
It's the time to speak up.
Sir, his name is Viki.
He is my friend.
He fainted a couple
of days back.
After we rushed him to the hospital,
we found out...
He has brain tumour.
Sorry.
When we went to treat it,
we found out...
He has a hole in his heart.
A hole in your heart?
I'm sorry.
When we opened him up
to plug that hole, we found out...
his body is missing lungs.
What, then?
Why do we need reasons
to make money?
The reason is money itself!
It was nice and cool in there...
now, we're sweating.
Money!
The tomatoes we eat
is sold on the streets...
and our footwear
is sold in air-conditioned rooms.
Money, money, money.
Money is everything.
How do you survive in our country
without this basic general knowledge!
Do you have a visiting card?
Sir!
- This card is...
- Sir, one moment.
Got a pen?
Okay!
By the by,
this is my visiting card.
You can contact us anytime
to sponsor our videos.
But get in touch with us quickly
because we have a lot of sponsors waiting.
Sir, step aside please.
Dude, that guy who wanted to
sponsor 20 crores...
He backed out.
- He slippered us!
- He is gone too?
Oh, that's funny!
Who would dare come close
when I hold a knife to your neck?
The courage she gathered to slap me...
I need to break that courage.
Instilling that fear is true revenge.
Money, money, money.
Money is everything.
You said there's this guy Ram
who helps the beggars at the beach...
I don't see him here.
I wanted to interview him today.
The next time I see you in Chennai
with a camera, you're done for!
How come I've never seen you here before?
You want to sit up here?
- Careful.
- Watch it.
- Are you doing well?
- Yes.
- Have you two eaten?
- We have.
My name is Ram.
What's yours?
- My name is Kuppan...
- What about grandma?
My name is Azhagi!
These are my brothers,
Siva and Viki.
- Hi, darling.
- Yes, darling?
What a English!
How long have you been here?
We've been here for 30 years.
We beg here.
We live here.
We sleep here.
Where were you
before 30 years?
Thirty years back,
when grandma was cooking...
The stove exploded and she got
injuries on her hands and neck.
We went to the hospital.
Our children asked us to place our fingerprint
on a document to pay the hospital bills.
We were waiting and waiting
for them to return.
But they never came.
We left the hospital
and came here.
You came here?
How did you come here
with the burn injuries?
It was Kuppan who looked after me.
It took 3 years to heal.
You call your husband by name?
Why not?
I'll hit you!
I can't use my hands to eat.
Kuppan feeds me.
He fed you for 3 whole years?
No, Kuppan has been feeding me
for 30 years.
"Day after day, we run and run for ourselves;
This selfish life is a burden on the soul."
"Look for God in someone's smile;
For God lives in the heart of a loved one."
You've been feeding someone
for 30 years?
I'd even feed my beauty Azhagi
for another 40 years!
- What do you care?
- Look at him!
Getting all worked up.
Does grandpa lose his temper often?
Oh, yes.
When he gets angry,
he won't talk to me for 3 days.
Darling, do you really have to live with
such a short tempered man?
Why don't you come with me?
I will take such good care of you.
Yes, darling. I'm bored of
living with this man.
Why are you talking to that guy?
Darling, he feels possessive.
Let's irritate him?
Give me your hand.
Very good.
Come! Kiss me, darling.
Hey, don't kiss him!
- I will.
- Don't!
I will!
Grandpa, I'll build a hut for you
by the railway station.
You can live there and sell
vegetables from a cart.
- Okay?
- Okay...
- We need to pay rent, right?
- Come on, darling...
We will take care of that.
- Do you really mean it?
- Of course we do.
So my Azhagi is going
to sleep under a roof from now?
"The way of love is a higher state of mind;
Yes, it is a higher state of mind."
"There is no lock to contain love."
Sir?
Sir...
You're going a great deed.
I feel so happy.
Thanks.
Sir, my name is Nisha.
I work as a reporter at News7 Channel.
I actually came looking for you.
Can you give us an interview?
I'm not important enough
to give an interview.
I do these things
because it makes me happy.
If I give an interview,
the whole purpose changes.
Please don't mistake me.
Sorry.
Oh, okay sir.
But if you ever feel like
giving an interview...
call this number.
You dare ask him
for an interview?
- Brother, you know who she is?
- Who is she?
She is 'that' girl!
Yes, brother.
We've had a YouTube channel for years
and even we haven't asked him.
She thinks she'd get one
if she says 'Sir, interview sir?'
No interview.
Go away, woman!
Sir, it's okay if you
don't give us an interview...
but don't give it
to their channel!
Even 10 people won't watch.
What did you say, woman?
Hey, don't shout
Tell her
Don't mistake them.
That's just how they are.
Rip that card an throw it
at her face.
I'll rip it apart!
See, I'm taking that card...
I'm tearing it to pieces...
ripping it to shreds,
and throwing it away!
What?
Slip it inside.
I can see it!
Tuck it in properly.
Can't see it now.
Disgusting.
Dude...
- Look there.
- You traitor!
Look there!
You recognize him?
Isn't he the PA
of that tunic man from the mall?
Why is he all suited up
and drinking witch-grass juice?
He is following us.
What are you saying?
Yes, he was there
at the restaurant yesterday.
Dude...
something is happening
around us.
- We need to be careful.
- You are scaring me!
No need to be scared...
We will handle it.
Come
Actually Indian economy heavily depends
on agriculture and farming.
Yes, Mr. Viki...
But no one is taking
care of them.
Yeah...
During this crisis period,
youngsters should be taking care--
Was it the PA?
You, too?
What was your dream?
We were walking,
he rammed his car into us...
and shot us with a gun.
- What about you?
- Well...
[Singing a romantic song]
Viki!
Hi!
Viki...
Tell me,
what was your dream?
It was the same accident!
The same dream.
He rammed his car into us
and shot us with a gun.
Hi!
- Let's go.
- Take your hands off, perv!
Don't you have brothers?
Turn that AC on, please.
We need to make some serious money,
buy a house like this...
and rent it to our house owner.
You fool!
Why would you buy such a big house
and rent it out to our house owner?
It should be his wife!
Come on!
Oh, yes.
What is it?
What is it, dear?
What are you doing?
You sanction the liquor shops...
and then you protest against it too?
When did I protest against it?
You brainless moron!
If we build factories in all the farming lands,
what would you do for food?
I didn't build any factories.
I didn't build any either!
People don't even have water to drink,
but you want it to make cool drinks?
You stupid fool.
Why are you asking me all this?
Then whom do I ask?
There is a tunic clad man inside.
Go ask him!
Who was that guy?
Maybe that tunic man's
younger brother?
Could be!
They do look alike.
Why did you concede Katchatheevu?
Who are you, man?
Where did you come from?
You fool--
Why did you concede it?
Why, why, why?
- Please forgive him, please.
- Why didn't you come sooner?
Please don't take it the wrong way.
The boss is inside.
Come on.
Take that stick away from him.
Dude...
Hello, sir.
Sit.
That's okay, sir.
We can't sit in front of you.
Enough with the act.
Just sit.
He figured.
Sir, do you know how to play
the piano?
What would you do
if I said I didn't know?
All the rich people have it in their homes.
But I've never seen anyone playing it!
Do you know
why I asked you to come?
Of course!
Your daughter went missing
a couple of months back...
You couldn't find her anywhere.
It will damage your reputation if you
went to the police...
so you've called us.
- What are you blabbering?
- Then what?
How could we possibly know
why you called us?
You need to tell us!
This respectable man has all his
workers standing while he is seated...
is this the way you talk to him?
Sorry, sir.
You tell us...
That big mouth!
Make it smaller.
Fine...
I'll tell you
why I called you.
Money, money, money.
You were crazy about it.
What sort of money
would make you happy?
Write it down.
Sir, you don't know us!
We would write an exorbitant amount!
Take it back.
Then write an exorbitant amount.
He's talking too much...
ask him for 10 grand!
Keep your mouth shut!
Ones, ten, hundred...
lakh, lakh and lakh...
We don't know if he has
that much money!
million, billion, and trillion!
That's our amount, sir.
I'll give you that amount
with a couple of extra zeros.
Will you do as I say?
Sir?
By 'giving', you mean,
you're actually giving it?
Sir, pardon sir...
Will you actually
give us the money?
Yes.
Wow, sir! Tell us...
what do we have to do?
- Well... - Sir, just say the word...
we will do it for you!
- You guys--
- We really want to do something for you!
Why are you still silent?
Just tell us what we need to do!
Let me speak.
Point, sir.
Tell us, sir.
I'll give you three tasks.
If you complete
all three tasks successfully...
I'll give you the money
you asked for.
But I have some conditions.
Condition 1 - The task could be anything.
You can't ask me any questions.
Condition 2 - Only after you
finish the first task will...
...I even tell you what the next task is.
Condition 3 - this is the
most important one.
If you complete the first two tasks
and give up at the final task...
you won't even get a single rupee.
The third task is very difficult.
Till you complete these tasks,
you need to stay where I tell you to.
You use the numbers I give you.
I'll take care of all the expenses
to complete these tasks.
If you agree to all these conditions...
sign on this agreement.
What are you thinking?
Are you scared?
No, sir...
The amount is okay.
It's just the tasks... 10 to 15
would have suited our level...
just three?
Only three!
Don't get cocky.
- The agreement...
- Here you go!
You're still playful...
The tasks will be extreme.
We're extreme people.
Tell us the task!
There are 22 news channels
in Tamil Nadu.
All 22 channels should carry
the same breaking news at the same time.
You should be in that breaking news.
I need to see your faces there.
You must get all the channels
to talk about you.
All the opinions and debates that day...
every single thing should be about you.
From the evening newspapers
to the next day papers,
all the headlines
should be about you.
All the FM radio channels
should talk about you.
In this huge screen here,
when I watch all 22 channels...
every one of them
should show your faces!
I need to watch it from here
and enjoy it.
I want to watch and enjoy it.
You are an anti-Indian.
His name is not Vignesh.
It is actually Joseph Vignesh.
I've got a Xerox copy
of his identity card.
High Court?
High Court can go to--
Today, we are going to review the movie
'With your heart, for the truth, rise and charge'.
You may use the first couple of words
of an old song as a movie title.
You don't use an entire song
as the title!
Funny, funny, funny!
Dude...
It's a little difficult for us
to make breaking news.
A little difficult is something,
impossible is something else.
Come on, man.
You've been trying to call
Sun Music for six years!
Did you even get
your call through?
No.
That's the clout
we have in media.
Understand?
We can't even ask anyone for help.
We have problems with everyone in town!
Minister Nellore Gaja...
is meeting ISRO scientists today
in Sriharikota.
We expect a breakthrough in science
following this meeting.
Come what may,
we are not going to her!
Right, right, right.
Even if we die penniless,
we are not asking her for help.
Correct, correct, correct.
I'm too cool.
Not her, of all people.
Are you idiots?
Wants to feature on breaking news!
Do you always come up
with twisted ideas like these?
Nisha, Nisha, Nisha, Nisha!
Please, Nisha!
Help us somehow.
Please!
Please?
First tell me why you want
to be in breaking news?
Don't ask us that!
If you give us a good idea, we will
find a way to make it to breaking news.
You don't get it?
Do you know what breaking news means?
News is generally scheduled ahead of time.
But we put all that aside,
and break some important news.
How will you ever fit in there?
If you dare touch my phone,
I'll cuss at you real bad.
Why are you touching my phone
without my permission?
Fat cupcake!
You can't keep your hands to yourself?
This is an important business meeting.
Stop fidgeting.
Fat cupcake!
Forget him, Nisha.
Please do something.
Anything!
We will do exactly as you say.
Help us in some way.
Please, Nisha.
Fine...
You have a camera, right?
Take it and roam around the city.
Try to get some good footage
that can be breaking news.
Everyday at 6,
my friend reports 100 different news.
I can ask her to include yours
as one among them.
I'm doing this not for you,
but for your brother.
Nisha, the boss called for you.
Damn.
Fat cupcake!
Forget it.
She says she will cover us
if we get her something.
She has a porn movie in her mobile
Wait, what?!
I'm sure she does! That's why
she isn't allowing me to touch it.
Really?
Yes, dude.
The stuff they watch
is something else.
Not like us.
She has a pattern lock.
Oh no! She has a pattern lock?
Her name is Nisha.
The pattern should be N!
Give it.
A disgrace to pattern locks!
See, it's open!
Oh! So these girls fall in love
with men who get kisses from grannies.
Come on!
Just one kiss.
You still haven't left?
The very sight of your faces annoy me.
Such weirdos.
It's you I'm scolding.
Why are you grinning?
Did you take my phone?
I've got a pattern lock!
Yeah, like it's a
really secure pattern!
Look how secure it is.
Sir, come here.
Her name is Nisha,
and this is her phone.
She has a pattern.
Open it.
If her name is Nisha,
it should be N, right?
There you go!
"My fingers yearn to touch you,
Come, give me a kiss!"
"My fingers long to feel you,
Come, let's start the war."
- Are you going to sing a duet?
- Why do you ask?
We have lots of work.
Holy shit!
Coming back to work, Mr. Siva...
did you get any idea
for breaking news?
Let me tell one idea.
Yes, please!
A man sticks his head into the mouth
of a crocodile that entered the city - Vignesh!
Traitor!
The man who decided to jump
head first from the LIC building... Siva!
A man dances naked
in Mount Road... Vignesh!
A lone man cleans up
Marina Beach... Siva!
Take it!
That sounds like a good idea.
What are you saying?
You're going to clean
the beach single-handedly?
Then why are we still thinking?
Hello, put that down!
Go away.
Dude, look here...
I did this only yesterday morning!
Fat pancake!
Nothing we shot so far has worked.
Didn't I tell you,
this is not for us.
Coming on breaking news
isn't a simple thing.
We're acting like lunatics.
I know we are acting like lunatics.
you think I don't get that?
But think about it.
No one else here would have
got a chance like we have.
Even we won't get another chance
like this in our lives again.
So I want to make use of it.
Just think about it,
what do we have to lose?
Let's try to give it our best shot.
You're blabbering.
Brother, please don't...
Just drink it, girl.
- I want to go home.
- Here, drink it.
Open your mouth!
Drink up...
Pour it in her mouth.
Dude, pour it
Something wrong is happening.
What do we do now?
Come here.
Roll the camera.
Frame it with them on one half
and me on the other.
- Okay?
- Action!
Four rich boys here are harassing
two public school girls.
Such injustices continue happening
all over Tamil Nadu.
To prevent such incidents,
we must stop them in the act.
Viki will now show you
how to stop such incidents.
Viki, my foot!
Why don't you go and save them?
All of them are big and bulky.
You'd be a good match.
For your kind information Mr. Siva,
I am the cameraman.
I work the camera,
you save the girls.
If everyone minds their own job,
someone has to go save them!
You could be that someone!
Go ahead.
- Try to be socially conscious...
- If you are just going to talk...
someone will--
They're gone!
What?
Why won't he blink?
You're committing all the mistakes.
I've been watching you.
Such an irresponsible Indian citizen.
- Who, me?
- Yes, you!
Wretched man.
We've missed the
only proper content we got.
Happy?
Good content...
Did you think about this?
We tried to do good things.
But not one person was interested.
But when something bad happens,
we give it all our attention.
So?
We shouldn't do good things anymore.
Only bad things.
What do you mean?
We shall become suicide bombers
We didn't know any other way.
All the press and media from Tamil Nadu
need to be here in the next 5 minutes.
Or I'll press the remote I'm holding,
and explode these bombs.
Three...
Two...
- One...
- Bro!
Bro, aren't you from that
YouTube channel?
Bro, the prank you played
at the park was so funny.
What are you doing here?
What's this TV remote?
- Who is this guy?
- No idea!
Oh, so you were doing a prank here?
Bro, judging by everyone's scared faces,
I'm sure this prank will be a big hit.
Superb, bro. Bye!
All the best!
We'll throw ourselves
in front of the CM's convoy.
All hail Tamil Nadu's permanent
Chief Minister!
The leader of our future!
Dude...
If you've got any dirt on
your moustache, clean it!
When we rise,
the press is going to be all over us.
Did all these people come here
to feature in some breaking news?
'Two youth desperate to feature
in breaking news face untimely death.'
I'm telling you...finally that's going to be
the breaking news.
Why don't you answer the damn phone?
Why are you rejecting her calls?
Let it go.
That girl loves you.
You know that, right?
I know...
that's why she is going
out of her way to help us.
You love that girl, too.
You know that, right?
What's that look?
Don't pretend!
I've been noticing you.
Yes...
I like her too.
- But...
- But what?
If you are into this crap,
just say it out loud.
I like her, yes!
Are we in any place
to ask a girl out?
Let's complete these 3 tasks first...
then I'll tell her in person.
There is a big difference between
telling her now and telling her later.
Complete 3 tasks, then love, and marriage.
Must tell that girl
to find some other man!
He's dead meat.
Actually I'm answering your calls.
But see, it's getting rejected!
- What are you doing here?
- We are...
- Breaking news...
- Are you mad?
Do you know what you're doing?
Who are you?
Who the hell are you?
Are you a politician?
Or a celebrity?
Who are you?
Are you Kamal Haasan or Kareena Kapoor
to make it to news when you have a fever?
Understand one thing.
These days, breaking news don't happen.
It's being created.
Come with me.
The MP is on a hunger
protest with his son-
-to close down the liquor
shop next to the school.
The liquor shop has been there for 4 years.
He didn't mind it these 4 years,
why is he suddenly concerned now?
Now all the media have come here
with our mics to cover this.
Sir!
My daughter wouldn't have done
such a thing.
Two school girls got drunk and jumped into
the pond, committing suicide.
I think they had relationship problems.
Their parents are weeping.
Saying, 'Our girls don't drink..
they were really good girls.'
'Please don't put this in the papers
and tarnish their names.'
But then parents really don't know
if their kids drink.
The liquor shop CCTV has recorded
the two girls buying booze there.
That's the case here.
But over there...
the MP's men won't allow the bodies to be
removed till the liquor shop is sealed shut
This is the news for the next 3 days.
We will run behind these people.
For the media to come after you,
you need to be a politician or a rich person.
You can't do it.
Let's get that straight.
My daughter doesn't drink.
She doesn't.
Please give my girl back to me.
My little one!
My little girl.
Sir, you can't go in.
Sir, please.
It's important.
Two young girls have died due to
liquor consumption today.
I need to go in!
Get out of here.
Who is the reason for this?
Is it the girls?
Or their parents?
- We can't raise our voice against them.
- Listen...
Not at all.
We are the reason.
Every youth in this country is responsible.
Sir, so your son is also responsible?
Brother...
What did you say?
You said every youth was responsible.
I asked if your son is included, too.
A young man has been waiting a long time
to talk about this.
Let us know how deeply
you care for his opinion?
Ask him to come.
Let's talk.
Superb, sir!
Siva.
The MP says that every youth
is responsible for this misfortune.
Do you wish to comment on that?
I'm going to tell you something
more important.
Do you know how
those two girls actually died?
Stick to the stuff
you wanted to speak about.
Don't digress from the topic.
Okay?
One moment, sir.
Let me say what I have to say.
Tell me...
Do you think those two girls
committed suicide?
How did they die, then?
Someone could have threatened them
to go to the liquor shop.
And the girls could have bought liquor
out of fear.
Then they could have been forced
to drink that liquor and then killed.
The boy's father, fearing
for his son's future,
could divert everyone by
organising this protest.
It could be anything.
What do you mean?
Based on what you're saying...
the MP is the one on a hunger protest.
Are you accusing his son
of killing the girls?
What's all this nonsense?
Just because you have a mic
you'd say anything you want?
Do you know it's a crime to accuse someone
without any evidence?
Do you have any evidence?
Do you have any evidence at all?
Show us the proof!
Tell us, sir...
do you have any evidence?
Our media friends are asking you!
Answer them.
- Any evidence?
- Tell them!
- Do you have the evidence?
- I have evidence.
Then quit talking
and show us the evidence.
- Show us, sir.
- Show it!
Don't just talk. Show us the evidence.
Buddy, someone is killing it here.
He is showing a video of the MP's son
harassing those girls as evidence.
- Really?
- I'll send a live feed...
you tell the people there
and break the news.
Right away!
We have some great news.
Inform our boss.
'There is a witness against to
Central Minister's son'
Had I been there,
I'd have chopped them down like vegetables.
I'd shave off their ears
along with the beard.
'Will police arrest minister's son?'
Slow.
What's the point in being on
all the major breaking news?
We're still scared of that mad-man.
I have a feeling that mad-man
is out here somewhere...
watching us.
Shut your mouth.
Why did you kill Gandhi?
Gandhi is dead?
Oh, no.
The monkey got away.
What's an African doing in Tamil Nadu?
I'm from Africa?
You saw that?
Don't speak.
Sir!
Hello, sir.
You're both on every breaking news.
In all 22 channels.
Very good!
How? How did you do it?
I really don't understand...
How did you manage it?
Tell me.
Oh, it's nothing.
Ever since childhood--
You said no one other than you
knew this number?
I am getting so many threats by call.
It's scary.
I'm here for you, dear.
I'll handle it.
Thanks, sir.
Sir, about the second task...
What was that sound?
I bit him!
What?
Yeah, man.
Look, sir. Either he stays in this house
or I stay.
The choice is yours.
But you don't even live in this house.
Only he lives here.
What does it matter who lives where?
Ask him what the task is,
let's get it over with.
Mani...
His name is Mani.
- He is a little...
- I know!
I know, sir.
I know.
- If you hand him a stick--
- I know!
I know, sir.
I know.
Make him an MLA
in the upcoming by-elections.
Mr. Siva, take good care of your health.
Eat your meals on time.
Don't go sleepless because of the task.
Be wise with your money.
- Come on, man.
- What, then?
If it were possible,
we could become MLAs instead of him.
He is mad.
And this man is mad
for setting us this task.
What are you looking at?
You have all this money.
Why don't 'you' make him an MLA?
Like we don't have enough geniuses
for politicians in our country.
This won't work.
Be quiet.
We will talk it out.
Sir...
Please don't joke around.
Really...?
Is this the task?
This is the second task.
You must make him an MLA
in the by-elections.
I will take care of all the expenses.
He never fails to say this line,
no matter what.
- Buddy...
- Get lost, man.
Listen up, man.
We can handle this.
Don't tell me we're
going to do this task.
What we did earlier was tough.
This is very easy.
What? Making this mad man
a politician is easy?
Oh...
He did agree to foot all the expenses.
Politicians are just criminals.
Now we need to find the
most criminal of the criminals.
We need to find someone whose mind,
body and soul is seeped in corruption.
If we give him the money,
he will make him an MLA.
You mean a political criminal?
Yes.
Keep it shut.
Sit down.
So it's you?
You said you are willing to
spend as much as needed to make an MLA?
Yes, sir.
That's me.
What do you mean,
Spend as much as needed?
We can spend as much as needed, sir.
Who wants to become an MLA?
You?
No, sir.
Him.
You have a lot of money?
If yes, tell me.
I'll make both of you MLAs.
Dear, there can only be one MLA
in one constituency.
What's wrong with that?
Aren't there states
with two chief ministers?
Let two people rather than one person
do good for the constituency.
Okay, son.
You can discuss money matters
with my Baby here.
We'll meet at the party office tomorrow.
Wait, dear.
You forgot our little brother.
Oh, thank god.
I forgot to mention.
I will introduce you to someone
very important.
This is my sister's son.
His name is Little Face.
Since his childhood, he has to sneeze
before I leave home.
If he sneezes, I will have
a good day.
But he needs to feel like sneezing
at that moment, right?
Oh, we will make him feel it.
- Do it.
- Okay, leader.
That's done.
This endeavour will be successful.
You have won!
He looks so weird.
What if the people are unhappy
when we let him contest?
People?
Who are these people?
You mean those who speak
indignantly all year...
and at election time take thousand or two
thousand rupees for votes?
You mean those who
participate in protests...
but when a 20-20 cricket match is on,
shamelessly go to watch the game?
When our farmers were protesting
semi-naked for 100 days in New Delhi...
those who sat in their homes and voted for
reality TV contestants Aarav and Oviya?
Who are the people? Huh?
Who are they?
Have we not cheated them in the past?
Have they not been cheated
by us in the past?
Worst case, what can they do?
They'll spit on us?
If they spit
We shall wipe it.
This girl?
Why is she jumping over
this compound wall?
Who knows who this little mouse
is playing hide-n-seek with?
Girl, I'll get you.
When we said we're featuring in
breaking news, you called us crazy.
And now you're secretly
making plans with him?
Tell me, how much
is he paying you?
I thought you were something else.
But you're doing such a thing
just for money?
Tell me, what were you doing in Bombay?
Shut up.
Don't keep yelling like a fool.
I am his daughter.
His daughter?
You mean you're his daughter?
Yes, moron.
He is my father.
The outside world doesn't know.
I work as a reporter
and observe the happenings...
get Intel on news channels
and their stance, find allies...
and I pass on this information.
With this knowledge,
he works in politics and wins.
What is your problem?
You wretch!
Disgusting.
You know what will happen
if word got out?
What? They'll spit on me?
If they spit, I'll wipe it off.
Get lost.
What's she doing here?
Buddy, that man's mistaken her
for us and is taking her away.
Yeah!
'NASA Munnetra Kazhagam
[NASA Progressive Conference]'
Why are they shouting?
What are you looking at?
Shush!
What are you fighting over?
- To end the farmers' crisis?
- No, sir.
- To tackle the river water shortage?
- To put an end to black money?
- No, sir.
Then what were you fighting over?
Sir, we think Nayantara
should campaign for the by-elections.
"People all around you
got dumbfounded"
Sir, we think it should be Keerthi Suresh.
"I love you sincerely
You are my fiancee truly"
Why are you standing separately?
Leader, if you don't bring Ramya Krishnan
none of us will come for the campaigns.
"Is it a play
or procession, you tell?"
Always listen to your elders.
[Humming raunchy Tamil song]
Stop that!
Go away.
As discussed, for the U.K Nagar
by-elections...
we are nominating Mani
as our candidate.
- For the campaign--
- Leader!
I am a senior member in this party.
You have roped him in
unnecessarily.
The public will...
Bijli, 'Bijili' Ramesh is for M.G.R Nagar.
For U.K Nagar, it's Mani.
Stay quiet.
You know very well...
because of a small rift
within the party...
the party symbol has been
temporarily repealed.
Nominee Mani will unveil the symbol
we're going to use henceforth.
Take it off.
Go on, man.
Will you just sit
and eat savouries?
Answer!
Will you steal river sand?
Will you?
Will you shoot the peaceful protesters?
Will you, now?
Answer me!
Why should I read another language
when my mother tongue is Tamil?
Easy for you to say.
You're crazy.
You'll say anything.
But we can't be like you.
Why did you concede Katchatheevu?
Why did you?
Why did you do that?
I'll do as I please.
What are you doing here?
Let's go inside.
What is it?
- Please.
- Why?
No
We must hide somewhere.
Get lost!
What's going on?
Sir, that's just how he is.
He cannot be controlled
when he's handed a stick.
You've chosen that as his emblem.
How can we control him now?
That's it?
It's over now?
He can never be made to win?
Son...
"Yesterday we met each other, you see"
"Forgot ourselves in our meeting duly"
"The wind..."
"...blows the cool breeze"
"Dance, you bet"
"Will rock & roll"
"Everywhere around here
filled the folklore, you hear"
"A novel song"
Drop the stick.
"A group has joined together"
So let's start our campaign, then?
"We plead for seats, we beg for votes;
We post a tweet and pin it on the admin."
"Twenty bucks a house
all it takes to win;"
"Float thermocol on rivers
to prevent evaporation."
"If they spit...
I will wipe it off."
Look at that!
Dude, I have to tell you something.
Tell me, dude.
Promise me you won't
hurt yourself if I tell you?
Fool! Tell me.
It's not like you think.
I can't even say it!
'We shall end disparity
of caste and creed;'
'But we split our potential
voters by caste.'
'If a haughty independent candidate loses;
We shall split the fruit with him.'
"Roar for a lion, flowers for the CM;
Money for votes, I just don't get it."
"Our land shall prosper,
the people are Gods;"
"Is there even a count to the lies?"
"If they spit...
I will wipe it off."
Look at that!
"If they spit...
I will wipe it off."
Look at that!
He is the true leader!
Judging by his wit and charm,
I'm sure he went to Oxford.
If I had a daughter,
I'd get her married to Mani.
Actually, even I--
"If they spit...
I will wipe it off."
[Speaking incorrect Hindi]
Our country has vaccine drops.
[Translating in incorrect Tamil]
We have urine drops.
'If they spit...
I will wipe it off.'
Look at that!
No, I can't say it.
You better tell me.
- I said, tell me!
- Nisha is a tease.
Yes. She's with that M.P.
Slapping me won't
change the truth, Mr. Siva!
- The other day--
- She's his daughter.
Daughter?
You mean, daughter?
Yes.
"You are bringing happiness to me
and making my heart colorful, I believe"
"You are stretching pot full of affection
and sharing it with millions of drizzles"
"If they spit...
I will wipe it off."
"I will wipe it off."
- Have you seen Mani or Viki?
- No.
- No, I haven't.
- Mani?
- I don't know.
- Have you seen them?
- Check downstairs?
What's wrong?
- Mani is missing.
- He must have left with the trainer.
Trainer?
2000, 4000, 6000, 8000...
Have you seen Mani?
He was with you!
Why do you ask me?
I just got here.
Did you ask Viki?
I called him, he didn't answ--
Who is it?
- It's Viki.
- Answer it.
- Hello?
- Dude.
Guess where I am?
Where the hell are you?
Mani is missing.
Mani, Nisha and I are all
at her channel's office.
Mani is about to give an interview.
Brainless oaf!
He will blabber something inappropriate.
Who asked you to interfere
in all this?
Don't get worked up!
There are no sticks
in the surrounding perimeter.
Besides, I'm right here.
Okay, call me after the show.
I will sit in the edit
and choose what can be aired.
Only then can it be broadcast.
Superb, man.
Perfect.
But all that's not possible
in a live show.
Hello, viewers.
We have Tamil Nadu's greatest sensation
here with us today.
The man who has earned titles like
The Inquirer...
and the Aggressive Revolutionary.
Greetings, Mani.
Mani, the questions you have raised
have stirred up the people.
Will your actions be
as vigorous as your questions?
I have been asking questions...
but you're just doing
some--thing.
Do you have answers
to the questions you have asked?
- Why did you give away Katchatheevu?
- I didn't, sir!
Will you open the Cauvery water?
- Will you?
- I will.
- Will you extract methane?
- I won't. I swear I won't!
'Candidate Mani manhandles the reporter'
Is he even a leader? [Spits]
It's about what the people need--
He is a mad man!
That rascal!
Had I trusted him with a daughter,
he would have beat her to death.
If you have read Osho's books,
you would know
All the answers are in the books.
He is a mad man!
Sir!
But he is a mad man!
Who are you calling a mad man?
U.K. Nagar by-elections have ended
in a peaceful manner.
75% of the people have voted.
The much awaited counting of votes
is to begin tomorrow morning at 10.
Oh, no!
Dude, wake up.
- Wake up!
- Yes, Nisha.
Yes, I love you too.
Siva is not such a nice guy
like you think.
You can hit me,
but I won't change my mind, Nisha.
The count is taking place.
The ruling party's candidate Mani is behind
the opposition party's Thangadurai...
by 2200 votes at the
end of the first round.
It's over.
We're doomed.
We've lost.
NASA party has never lost
at U.K Nagar till now.
I told you this won't work out.
You won't get a single rupee.
Complete 3 tasks, then love, and marriage.
Must tell that girl
to find some other man!
Everyone come here
Boss has come
Sir, the counting is about to be done.
What do we do?
Sir?
Can we call somebody,
do something?
Sir?
Sir...
We trusted you and spent so much money.
But now they're leading.
Sir?
Sir...
Tell me your three favourite numbers.
Three what?
Come on, tell me your
three favourite numbers.
7, 3 and 4.
Why do you ask?
Sir?
Go downstairs
and see for yourself.
- Sir?
- Go downstairs and see.
U.K. Nagar by-election vote counting
has come to an end.
With a margin of 734 votes,
ruling party's Mani has won over the
opposition candidate Thangadurai.
Money, money, money.
I've told you about people.
Now let me tell you about money.
The man who picked pockets
to fill his belly is locked up in prison.
The man who trampled over starving bellies
and made money, is in power.
Money.
The man who brews illegal liquor
is given honorary doctorate.
The man who aspired to
be a doctor...
all his life ends his life unable
to attend coaching.
Money.
If you have money, you can get drunk
and run over homeless people on sidewalks.
If you have money, you can destroy forests
and erect statues for yourself.
If you have money,
you can do anything.
Money.
Everyone bribed the voters with money.
I think different.
I bribed the vote counter with money.
Everybody knows.
I got this far in politics
only with money.
What can they do?
Worst case, they will spit on me.
- If they spit--
- We shall wipe it off, sir!
You're God!
Dude, we won!
We won!
'Our beloved brother Mani'
Finally, you've turned him
into a politician too!
Siva, Viki! How are you?
Let's take a picture.
You should stay for the meal.
What's all this?
Oh, so you're the reason?
Oh, no.
Him and his stupid face.
Move it.
Long live... MLA Mani.
Dude, we completed both the tasks!
Oh, yeah.
If we finish the third task as well
and collect all the money...
Meets the VJ here
Sir, there's a problem.
What is it?
A man is troubling me
asking for a recharge of 30 lakhs.
Dammit!
What's the problem?
Why hasn't the train left?
Two men are causing a ruckus
insisting on buying the train.
What? Someone wants to buy off
the government train?
Grandma, why are you running?
Two men are harassing me asking me
to cook 'vadais' on the moon.
They're coming!
Hello, NASA.
No, we don't sell rockets.
What? Sparkle firecrackers?
Flower pot?
Bull shit.
Siva and Viki have shocked the nation...
by meeting Donald Trump
at the White House...
and asking to buy off America.
Sir, we have completed
both the tasks assigned by you.
If you tell us about that
difficult third task...
we'll quickly get it done, collect
our payment and be on our way.
I understand.
For our calibre, it's hard to come up
with a task difficult enough.
But tell us whatever you had in mind.
We'll handle it.
This coming Wednesday morning at 7:30...
there will be an attempt to kill a girl
at Kodambakkam Railway Station.
You must prevent that murder.
Sir, stop kidding.
What's our task?
Let me finish.
You don't know the identity
of the murderer.
of the victim either.
Most importantly, you may not
carry any weapons.
When he pulls out his knife to attack her,
you can use anything you
find there to hit him.
In front of everyone,
you must prevent the murder.
Do we look like idiots to you?
What?
Dude, this man is fooling us.
He wants us to prevent a murder.
That too, without any weapons.
You think you and I
can do this?
When we get close,
the knife could be on our throats.
What will you do?
What if I die stopping it?
What if you die?
Or if we lose a limb?
What then?
We have been fooled.
This man is cheating us.
I told you in the very beginning,
the tasks could be anything.
You did agree to it.
You said it could be anything,
but not that we could die.
I don't want this.
Give us half the money.
We'll be on our way.
You have these huge men
standing outside your doors.
Use them for this task.
Let us go.
If you don't complete this task,
you won't get a single paisa.
For the past five months,
we've done nothing but slog on your tasks.
Now you have the gall to tell us
you won't pay a single paisa?
Okay, forget about the money.
Won't you do this for me?
For you?
Who are you?
Why should I do this for you?
You don't care if we die there.
Why should we do this for you?
Fine, let that go.
We've done so much.
Have you ever told us why?
Why make it to breaking news?
Why get a mad man elected as MLA?
Why prevent this murder?
How do you know it's about to take place?
You won't tell us any of this
but we should die for you?
I have no need for that.
Either, you tell us why.
Or you pay us half the agreed amount.
If not, we know how to get our hands
on that money.
We'll handle it.
Let's go.
Dad...
How are you?
It's been so many days
since you spoke properly to me, you know?
Ever since I became a reporter,
you've stopped talking to me.
You keep telling me to work with you
on your business...
but I don't like business, dad.
I want to become a great journalist, dad.
Want to cover many news items.
One day, I shall uncover
a major news...
that will be the breaking
news in all channels.
In our big screen TV at home,
I want to be on all 22 channels we surf.
And you should sit back on the sofa
and watch it like a king.
You should watch it like a king, dad.
We won't get any of
this in business, dad.
That's why I went against your word
and joined as a reporter, dad.
I've always wanted to tell you
these things in person.
But you've never had the time
to even lend me a ear.
I wished to buy you a gift
with my first month's salary.
That's why I've told you everything
in the form of this gift.
Dad, on your birthday...
I only ask for one thing.
Will you hug me just one time?
My son.
His name was Anbu.
He would always say, 'I want to
be a reporter, feature in breaking news.'
I would always scold him saying,
What money could possibly be there in it?
But he was adamant
and became a reporter.
I was so angry,
I stopped talking to him.
I thought, if I didn't talk to him,
he would work in the business.
Business, business, business.
I knew nothing else.
When he gave me this gift...
that was the last time I saw him.
Dad...
What? Tell me, I'm running late.
Dad, it's your birthday.
So I got you this gift.
What gift?
A cell phone?
Dad...
What does it cost?
6,000? Or 8,000?
Do you know how much my cell phone costs?
Do you know who uses this?
- Ramasamy!
- Boss?
Keep doing such jobs and these are
the kind of gifts you can buy me.
You better come and join my business.
Then I left to my office.
I got a call from my son
a little while later.
Dad, I'm going to feature
in a breaking news.
What?
You're featuring in a breaking news?
Stop blabbering.
I'm in a meeting, don't disturb me.
- Dad, dad, dad...
- Calm down and talk!
Listen to me, dad!
Someone has murdered a man
under the bridge!
Murdered?
- Where are you?
- Listen to me!
I went closer to see his face,
but he had covered it with a kerchief.
So I've come to his house
following him.
You went to his house?
You shouldn't be there.
Get out of there right away.
We'll inform the police.
Get out of there.
No, dad. I overheard
everything they were talking.
There is a verdict in the court
on December 26th.
The very next day,
they are going to murder a girl
in Kodambakkam Railway Station.
Murder?
They're going to murder?
Son, you shouldn't be there.
They will kill you.
Tell me where you are.
Tell me.
Didn't I always say I wanted
to be on the breaking news?
This is the perfect chance.
I'll get to the railway
station with reporters...
and cameramen when
they come to murder.
Just when they are about to murder,
I will intervene and prevent it.
I will get captured on every camera,
won't I?
I will definitely be on breaking news,
Fool of a son!
Don't talk like an idiot.
None of what you say will happen.
Not a single soul will come
when you call them.
- Get out of there.
- No, I can't.
This will work.
I will be on the breaking news.
I will never get another chance.
Fool! You fool!
Tell me where you are.
Daddy will come and--
This number can't be reached
I looked everywhere.
I got a call three hours later.
That my son is lying dead
in the railway station.
I went and looked.
They had slashed him
in twelve places.
Some random guy went and surrendered
claiming to have committed the murder.
But everyone knows he didn't do it.
I searched everywhere
for the murderer.
Two days later, we caught the driver
of the murderer.
Do you know why they killed my son?
Can you hear anything?
You can't?
It does seem like you can hear.
Maybe you can hear a little bit?
- Hey...
- Yes, boss?
- Go inside and talk.
- Okay.
Quick.
Boss? Can you hear me?
I can hear.
Oh, shucks.
It can be heard.
Come on, dear.
Run along.
Come on!
How long have you been
eavesdropping on us?
Who are you?
How did you get in?
Tell me.
It was a mistake.
You followed us here, didn't you?
We've become friends now.
Tell me.
You followed us here, didn't you?
So, under that bridge...
Boss, his ID card.
Oh, you're a reporter?
You never mentioned.
So, you were eavesdropping on us.
What were we talking inside?
I couldn't hear.
Tell me, dude!
Tell me, tell me, tell me.
Tell me.
The court verdict is on December 26th.
Yes, it is.
The next day, you're going to
Kodambakkam Railway station and...
Going to the railway station and...?
Murder a girl...
Me? Murder a girl?
Oh, God!
Okay, what will you do
with all this knowledge?
You'll go to the police?
You'll write an article?
What will you do?
You'll do nothing.
You're scared?
Get back! Back!
Tell me.
Don't be afraid, okay?
Yes!
How could I not be afraid?
It's your house.
Your men are surrounding me.
Of course I'm afraid.
Are you some brave man?
You're the guy that hides behind a kerchief
and murders someone under a bridge.
Let me see you try to stand alone
and murder someone in public.
Oh... what if I do it?
That's it.
The public would destroy you.
Like hell they will.
When I pull out a knife in public,
everyone will scatter away in fear.
They'd stand around and watch.
Standing around and watching
is a thing of the past.
People have changed now.
They've changed?
Haven't you seen those
murder videos on YouTube?
Not one soul will come forward.
That's who they are.
Their maximum courage is to record
a video on their mobiles.
Ask the man recording the video
to take one step forward?
He won't come.
No, he will definitely come.
- He won't come.
- He will.
Only one person needs
to step forward.
Then everyone will follow.
Now you're talking.
When one person steps forward,
others will follow.
But such a person doesn't exist.
- He will come.
- He won't come.
- He will come!
- God, what's with you?
Fine...
Let's do three things.
One: Let's kill you.
Two: I've never murdered anyone
in a railway station before.
So I'll do a demo round with you.
Three: This is the most important point.
You challenged me saying
someone will come?
I will prove to you
that no one will come.
It's time!
The college boys would be there.
Let's get going.
My glasses!
Play some music?
Okay, boss.
"The jasmine flower on the creeper..."
"...scents so fragrant, my dear"
"Shall I take and offer it to you?"
"I am very much eager, my sweetie pie"
"Provokes me to pluck it at once"
"...this vast jasmine garden"
"But stops me to reach it..."
"...by the shyness inside my heart"
"Which direction to take to fly?"
"This bird doesn't know anything"
"Pity, do not know of its kith and kin"
I will ask you one last time.
Will that someone step forward or not?
He will.
"The jasmine flower on the creeper..."
"...scents so fragrant, my sweetheart"
"Shall I say 'yes' to accept
or 'no' to refuse...?"
"I am very much confused"
Oh, I'm out of breath.
I am panting.
Is this spot okay?
It's crowded.
It's more crowded over there.
This is a good crowd.
So?
When I brandish my knife,
these people will step forward?
See? Didn't I tell you?
Didn't I tell you these people are useless,
that they won't come?
Standing by and watching
is a thing of the past?
A thing of the past?
Someone from the public will step forward
and destroy me?
Die!
Public...
For a second there,
even I got scared hearing your words.
I thought someone might come forward.
He is a mad man.
A mad man.
Mad man!
Who are you?
Where did you come from?
This was unnecessary...
Ten seconds before you die...
I wish to tell you something.
I want you to die
while listening to it.
There's a pulse.
There is, there is.
It's dropping!
It's dropping, man.
That someone you mentioned...
he never did come.
Till the very end, my son believed
that the people will step forward.
He didn't know reality,
that no one will come.
He died.
He died watching that crowd.
But think about it, what my son said
was correct.
At least one person
should have stepped forward that day.
We have grown up wrong.
The crowd that stood and watched
was a selfish crowd.
They only care about their daily meal.
They don't care if others starve.
Ask him who is his area's MLA?
He won't know.
A mad man is enough to rule them.
And I have made it happen.
Mani, the MLA.
In our country, no one will help
even if someone is murdered in public.
With that confidence, they are going to
murder a girl tomorrow.
This time, I won't let that happen.
That one person my son needed
shall be there to step forward.
I will tell him
that the man he needed has arrived.
My son would be watching, wouldn't he?
He would be happy, wouldn't he?
That's why I asked you to go there.
Do you know why I chose you both?
When I found out who murdered my son...
I came to the mall determined
to chop his head off his body.
He was sitting in the table
next to mine.
If you had placed that knife on my throat
two seconds later...
that man would have been headless.
You brought my son back
right before my eyes.
That's when I began to understand.
When you told me what it meant
to exact revenge...
I realised how foolish I have been
all this time.
I know you weren't
serious about anything.
But you were right.
If I had killed him then and there,
no one would have stepped forward.
My son would have lost
all over again.
I wanted to complete this task with
the men who made me understand this.
Tell me now.
Will you prevent that murder tomorrow?
We can't, sir.
You can't?
Sir...
Everything you say is fair.
We do feel sorry for your son.
Based on what you've said...
Sounds like the murderer
is a big-shot.
If I go there,
I will definitely die.
Think about it practically.
What's your final decision?
We...
don't want to go.
Let's not talk about the money now.
We'll take leave now.
I confided all this in you
because I considered you my sons.
What if this were to happen
to one of you?
Would you still refuse?
Get out.
Get out of my sight.
Get lost!
That poor boy.
Why are you constantly thinking about it.
Let it go.
What do you think
was the cause of his death?
The murderer?
No.
The fear of the onlookers.
Not one person there thought
the way that mad-man did.
Just let it go, man.
It's Nisha.
I wonder what he would have thought
right before he died?
Dude, let it go.
You're whining non-stop.
As if we don't have enough on our plates,
you're bothering us, too?
We're discussing something important.
And look what you're doing.
Come on.
At least he won't hit us back.
Why are you messing with 'it'?
Wait, man.
Where are you from?
Did someone cheat you also after promising
to give you crores for completing tasks?
Stop beating yourself.
I know you have
something to say to the world.
Tell me, I'll make sure you're heard.
Tell me, tell me, tell me.
Siva, Siva, Siva...
It's your name 'Siva' that he's muttering.
It's you.
They are good boys.
After I got a job and moved out,
they had no one to take care of them.
Even I have no one besides them.
Brother! My brother Ram!
How did you become like this?
Oh! Why should this happen to you?
He's bleeding!
Come on, man.
Somebody! Please help.
It's my brother...
He's my brother!
Brother!
Siva, come on.
Come on, man.
Hello!
- Hello, brother?
- Who is this?
It's me, Siva.
Bloody hell! You're still alive?
Where were you gone
all these days?
Bro...?
Because of you both, your brother
has become a mad-man, out on the streets.
You got an MP's son
caught in the news, right?
His men came looking for you
at your home.
When they realised you weren't home,
they beat the hell out of your brother.
Even when he was lying unconscious
in the hospital...
he kept calling out your name.
Suddenly, he went missing one day.
We just couldn't find him.
I told him not to trust you dogs.
Where are you now?
Did you go after some man
who promised you money?
I wouldn't be surprised.
You'd do anything for money, you--
Siva!
Why are you avoiding me?
I shouldn't have taken Mani to
the channel office without telling you.
But you won't even look at my face?
We've never had fun together.
We have never gone out on dates.
But we both know
we're in love with each other.
Fine, Siva.
I'll say it.
I love you.
You could scold me.
You could hate me.
But I will always love you.
Siva!
What happened?
Why are you crying?
Say something!
What happened?
I have lost.
I have lost everything.
What do I want? What do I like?
I have lived selfishly.
But there were people around me...
I never gave them a thought.
Six months back, when hunger struck,
I would remember about my brother Ram.
But these past six months, maybe because
I had food even before I got hungry...
I didn't even remember him.
To prove to me that there is a life
beyond money, here he was...
right here.
He's been loafing around
as a mad man here.
I've been passing by this road
for one month now.
I don't know how many times
he saw me here.
I feel terrible seeing him
in flesh and blood this way...
think of the two school girls?
They just died.
To everyone else, that was a death.
But to me, that was just news.
I was right there moments before
the two girls died.
Right before my eyes,
a man pinched her waist.
And another man poured her a drink.
But I...
I was just holding a camera.
If I'd put the camera down,
I could have saved them.
Those two girls
would still be alive.
My happiness, my money...
that's all I thought about.
But not anymore.
Now...
that man who is setting out
to murder a girl in public with no fear...
I will stand up to him.
Are you stupid?
If you stand up to him--
I will die.
Because I don't know how to fight.
You think if you stand up,
everyone else will step forward?
They won't.
Not one of them.
I don't need anyone.
- But I will stand tall.
- Siva...
Whether or not I survive tomorrow...
I won't let that girl die.
What happened?
"Let me kill you, yaar"
I see a car approaching.
Let me see if we can get a ride.
"Shall I finish you off, you tell?"
"Let me kill you, yaar"
Sir, we need to go to
the railway station urgently.
Can you help us?
"Let me kill you, yaar"
"Shall I finish you off, you tell?"
'Attention to the passengers'
'Next train to Chennai beach
will arrive shortly on platform # 3'
Dude...
If we step up,
others will follow, right?
They may come, or they may not.
I'm going.
Dude, listen.
It's very difficult for the two of us
to stop the murderer.
Do something.
Stand a little away.
When I intervene,
he will it me.
You come and save me.
When he hits you,
I will save you.
But here's the thing...
the both of us must not get
trapped by him.
I am still very scared.
I am scared, too.
But we're here now.
Let's do this.
Siva...
one last time.
"With your heart, for the truth;
Rise and charge!"
"Your time will come;
Wait and watch!"
"You've cowered in fear for too long;
Not anymore!"
"Like a dam breaking loose;
Rise and charge!"
"What use is the blood
in the body of a slave?"
"What use is a home for
coward living in fear?"
"What use is the blood
in the body of a slave?"
"What use is a home for
coward living in fear?"
"What is the need to fear torment?"
"You were born with nothing;
Rise and charge!"
"You can, you can!
Believe in yourself, take the plunge."
"What's a world without you?
Let go of your worries."
"You can, you can!
Believe in yourself, take the plunge."
"What's a world without you?
Let go of your worries."
"It ends one way or the other;
Stand tall and face it."
"Justice shall reward you;
With pomp and fanfare."
"With your heart, for the truth;
Rise and charge!"
"Your time will come;
Wait and watch!"
"You've cowered in fear for too long;
Not anymore!"
"Like a dam breaking loose;
Rise and charge!"
Only one man needs to step forward.
Everyone else will follow.
But such a person doesn't exist.
He will come.
He will definitely come.
No, it's fine.
Brother, thank you so much.
Thank you?
- Who are you?
- Who am I?
It's me you were fighting for
all this time, brother.
"With your heart, for the truth;
Rise and charge!"
"Your time will come;
Wait and watch!"
"You've cowered in fear for too long;
Not anymore!"
"Like a dam breaking loose;
Rise and charge!"
"What use is the blood
in the body of a slave?"
"What use is a home for
coward living in fear?"
"What use is the blood
in the body of a slave?"
"What use is a home for
coward living in fear?"
"What is the need to fear torment?"
"You were born with nothing;
Rise and charge!"