NOBODY COM BS ME
AS WELL AS THE WIND
How did it go ?
Someone else got the job.
Good. I don't want you waking up
when it's dark.
I might have a job pumping gas.
- Need money ?
- No, I still have some.
You shouldn't have quit dental school.
Not again...
I can provide for you
for a few more years.
Want more coffee ?
No, I'm going to sleep.
Whafll you do ?
The sea is choppy today.
South-west wind. ..
There was a dead boy
on the beach today.
Probably another fucking junkie.
You didn't get along
with grandma either.
Me ? Not true, we talk every day.
Now you do, but not before.
You never invited her for Christmas.
Gea, sorry but I need to concentrate now,
I have an interview soon
and don't even remember what to ask.
My stomach doesn't feel well.
ln Milan they called her
"the poor man's doctor",
because she took care of people
in the worst neighborhoods.
She draped her tall, slender body
in a black suit;
a red scan' wrapped around her neck
accentuating her spindly,
almost abstract shape.
- Good morning l
- Morning l
My daughter's with me because
we're going to Grosseto after.
I'll let you in.
Leave him in the car,
we won't be long.
No, I'll take him for a walk.
Usually l wake up early,
have a quick breakfast,
go buy the newspapers,
then I sit down and work.
Well, l intend to but often
l just sit staring at a blank page
without writing a word,
all I want to do is run away.
From what ?
A spider I saw on the wall.
Arachnophobia.
What do you do for the rest of the day ?
I read, go to the supermarket.
Nothing.
- At night?
- At night... I go to sleep.
Do you have any recurring dreams ?
Yes, I've often dreamt that it's raining
and my house is flooded with water
and I'm running around like a madwoman
trying to stop the leaks
but there's always a new leak so...
Ado l
ls he yours ?
A few days ago in Paris, your husband
announced his return to politics.
Yes, so I read.
After the scandal,
you came back to live in Italy.
Has your relationship
with your husband changed ?
We haven't spoken in years.
During interviews, your husband
expressed great respect for you.
And affection.
Are we done ?
Yes, I'll get my daughter and we'll go.
I'm sorry if I seemed invasive,
but my editor would've skinned me alive
if I hadn't asked at least
one question about your husband.
EX.
- I'm done, we can go.
- Already ?
Yes, we have a long drive ahead of us.
Can we wait a bit?
Wait for what ?
I just told you I finished.
But I'm hungry.
Gea is a whiz in Italian.
She got an A on her last test.
- That's not true, I got a B.
- Well, a B is good.
Yes, but I'm at the bottom of the class
in other subjects.
It's a tough class, and you're not
at the bottom of the class.
- What was the essay about?
- The hand.
The hand, how interesting.
She even wrote some poetic things.
l recall one phrase: "The hand takes
but at times it asks as well".
How did you come up with that ?
Can I stay here a few days ?
- Here ?
- What did you just say ?
Why on earth
would you ask such a thing ?
I'm not going to grandma's.
I have a plane to catch for work.
- I was to spend Easter with dad.
- He had a change of plans.
- Now where are you going ?
- To the bathroom.
I'm sorry, I'm mortified.
I don't know how to handle her anymore.
Whatever I say is wrong,
whatever I do is irritating.
What's her relationship like
with her dad ?
She nearly set fire to his bathroom
last time.
So I should be worried ?
She wanted to see if alcohol
catches fire,
but I think unconsciously
she did it on purpose because
she's jealous of the daughter...
of her father's lady friend.
- Has she seen a specialist?
- Of course.
But she won't utter a word.
One night she went out alone,
she said the heat was bothering her.
We found her sleeping with her dog
on the banks of the river.
Can you imagine ?
What would you do ?
I don't have kids.
- Are you done ?
- I'm not coming out.
You're behaving childishly, Gea.
I'm really sorry.
Hello, Tullio ? I'm having
a problem with your daughter.
I'm at a writer's home,
I came to interview her.
Gea refuses
to come out of the bathroom.
I don't know what to do.
She doesn't want to go to grandma's,
I don't know why.
- Want to speak to your dad ?
- No.
Great, she said no.
I have a plane to catch tonight...
How's everything in there ?
I locked myself in the bathroom
when I was a kid too.
Once because
my father gave my cousin a doll
and I got nothing,
to me it seemed
like an unbearable insult.
Why can't I stay here ?
You're worried because my mom
told you I burned dad's bathroom ?
I didn't do it on purpose,
it was an accident.
Let me stay.
You don't know me, I'm a stranger.
My grandma's a stranger too.
- She's not even my real grandma.
- How so ?
This is embarrassing...
Tullio says he can come pick her up...
but tomorrow. What shall I do ?
How can I ever thank you ?
There's a conference in Bombay
on the state of women,
Rocca was supposed to go
since it's her field
but she broke a leg
so the paper decided to send me.
This is Gea's backpack,
her clothes and homework are in here.
This is surreal, I'm practically
abandoning my daughter...
Tullio said he'll call
before picking her up.
But we'll be in touch.
She'll tell you she's adopted,
her teacher told me she wrote
an essay about it, but it's not true.
Here you go... this is your room.
So, do you like it?
- Can Ado stay in here with me ?
- What?
- Can my dog stay with me ?
- No, he stays in the yard.
- Even at night?
- Yes.
I'm not used to keeping animals
in my house.
- I'm going out.
- Where ?
To the square, I don't want him
to poop inside out of spite.
My mom says you're very intelligent.
Being intelligent doesn't mean
understanding more.
What does it mean ?
Understanding less ?
At times, yes.
- Did you really live in Paris ?
- Yes.
- Did you speak in French ?
- Yes, of course.
So why did you come here ?
I like the sound of the sea.
- Aren't you afraid to be alone ?
- No, l like being alone.
I like being alone too.
At your age, you're never alone:
you have school, friends...
I have no friends.
Why not?
Dunno... nobody likes me.
Today a reporter with her daughter
came by,
supposedly to write about me
and my work,
but she really wanted
to know about Michel.
Her daughter suddenly asked
if she could stay with me.
An insane request, to which
I gave an even more insane reply.
What are you writing ?
A book.
- About what ?
- A woman.
Are you annoyed I'm here ?
No. Why, do I seem annoyed ?
- Did you get the job ?
- No.
There may be a job
in the supermarket stock room.
I'll go inquire today.
- ls 150 enough for the week ?
- I told you I don't need money.
How is that possible ?
- It's possible.
- How do you manage ?
I help out a friend,
we clean out clubs.
Your father called.
He said the snow
caused some car trouble
so he can't come today,
he'll probably come tomorrow.
- Does my mom know ?
- No, she didn't call yet.
- What do you think of my mom ?
- I don't know her...
- She's stressed about her daughter.
- My mom's always stressed.
Maybe it's partially your fault ?
I'll make breakfast.
Erica's not my real mom,
I was adopted.
What's that ?
It's true, I was adopted.
Your mom told you ?
No, she pretends it's not true.
- Then how do you know ?
- I remember.
- How old were you ?
- Probably two.
You can't remember anything
when you're two.
- I do remember.
- What?
We were outside, in a truck.
It was night.
There were lots of kids
and a dead horse.
- And then ?
- That's it.
Musfve been a dream.
There was also a gypsy
hitting us with a cane.
He did this to me.
Maybe you just fell.
Hi, Yuri. How much did you rake in ?
- Surplus ?
- 8 grams of hash.
Here, it's 500.
150 for you.
Next assignment:
25 grams of Moroccan,
10 of Afghan,
and 5 of blow for the old dude.
- But he wants that other stuff.
- There's a war going on...
you can't ask for off-market goods.
They take it as is, furniture and all.
I can't take it with me.
They can burn it after
for all I care.
Memories ? Memories of what ?
When I could still get it up...
that's a real memory.
Well, what have you brought me ?
- The black bud ?
- Next time.
Good, better than last time.
Why are you looking at me
like that, Hamlet?
My name's Yuri.
Do I provoke disgust?
- Pity?
- Nothing.
Nothing. I wish that were the case...
But you're too young to understand.
Do you like boats ?
I had a boat once,
I went all over the place with it.
Then one day I stopped,
captivated by an Indian girl,
a teenager,
as beautiful as a goddess.
I married her, or rather I bought her.
Then I sank the ship.
And her as well.
And then I came here.
To bury myself.
I have to go.
- You're pale, Hamlet.
- My name's Yuri.
You're named Yuri,
but you're Hamlet inside.
A prince without a kingdom, like me.
- What are you drawing ?
- Spiders.
Don't tell me you like spiders ?
- It's my favorite animal.
- What's so nice about them ?
Nice ? Nothing.
Then why do you like them ?
Because they're ugly and scary.
What have you got?
Afghan.
Those guys are waiting for you.
Sweet l
- I'm going for a stroll with the dog.
- Okay.
Don't wander off too far.
- Nothing for me ?
- No, because you're a bitch.
Go on, smoke.
Who's she ?
What do you want? Who's she ?
- Dunno, never seen her.
- Hey kid, get lost.
What's the problem ?
I don't like buzzkills,
and I don't want to be stared at.
I'm off.
Me too, I'm hungry.
Are you gonna hit on her?
Go to bed, Gea,
your dad's coming tomorrow.
"I'll light the fire
because it's cold".
"Light the fire"
is that cause or effect ?
If the action occurs first it's cause,
if after it's effect.
It occurs after.
- What comes before ?
- An urge to scream.
Then scream.
Not in front of you.
I'll go.
- ls she staying with us too ?
- Just for a few days.
Good morning.
I'm Tullio, her father.
Arianna, nice to meet you.
Sorry I'm late, the roads were icy.
- Where'
she sleep ?
- In your room with you.
No way l
Don't start acting up.
Not in my room,
you said she scares you too.
I never said that.
I just said she's an odd girl.
Odd ? She's got eyes like a witch.
- Goodbye, thanks.
- Goodbye.
Want me to carry your backpack ?
- Hi.
- Hi, Gea.
Hello.
- So who's hungry?
- I am.
I'm not.
Go on ahead.
Look Gea, isn't this nice ?
I need to talk to you.
I have to tell you...
there's been a bit of a hitch,
we can't go home.
I don't have the keys,
it's a long story.
But don't tell your mom about this...
We'll stay with Ginevra for a few days.
Just a few days,
Ginevra loves you.
And Marta thinks you're great.
- What would you like ?
- A hamburger and fries.
A salad.
- You ?
- Nothing, I already ate.
- Could I have plain boiled rice ?
- I'll ask the chef.
Thanks.
- Are you still ill?
- No.
After I had colic, Erica told me
to be more careful.
Right, Gea ?
I'll take Ado for a walk.
Don't leave the parking lot.
- I told her.
- How'd it go ?
Fine, she seems okay with it.
Marta would rather not have her
in her room.
Where'
we put her then ?
On the sofa bed.
All right.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- Could I have some oil?
- Sure.
Where's Gea ?
I'll go see.
Gea !
- Thanks.
- Bye.
What happened ?
I don't want to stay at her house.
- Weren't you to stay at your dad's ?
- His house was seized...
because of his unlicensed
bed & breakfast.
I'll get an umbrella.
- Where are we going ?
- To the police.
But I haven't finished eating.
Yes, speaking.
Maybe she's dead.
Maybe it's best she stays with me
a few more days.
How kind of you,
but I wouldn't want to impose...
It's not a problem.
I don't know if Erica would approve,
you know ?
I'll send her a text.
Sure.
That's a good idea.
Hold on a second...
Gea went to Arianna's,
she said she could stay a few days,
what do you think ?
- No need to think it over!
- I was just informing you...
Okay, if it's no problem for you,
it's fine for us.
What did Gea say ?
He wants to speak to you.
Hi.
Yes, I have everything,
even my backpack.
You don't need to come here.
Look how hot I am l
- You look like a ragdoll.
- Looks who's talking...
- Look at her and America l
- What a couple l
Someone's bitter...
Smile l
Knock it off.
Come on.
She's back.
Of all places, why come here
and bust our balls ?
America, you caught her eye.
- Why's she killing our buzz ?
- Maybe she's lonely.
America, ask her to show it to you.
She's a kid, you asshole.
Only a kid would ever show it to him l
You're disgusting.
- Hi.
Cute dog, what's its name ?
- Ado.
- What kind of dog ?
He's a bastard.
Hear that, America ?
He's your relative.
- Come inside, please l
- It's about time.
You didn't tell me you were going out.
I was just in the square, no big deal.
I don't want you out there
with those kids.
Why ?
They vandalized the benches.
- You saw them do it ?
- No, but I know it was them.
Every night they ruin something,
and the next morning
the square is full of trash.
Enough with the noise, please l
The square's not yours, lady l
Nor yours, learn how
to be considerate of others.
- What a bitch !
- What did you say ?
Let's go.
- And let her win ?
- Mazinga is right though.
She's not in charge here.
Do you think I was too harsh
with those kids ?
You're right... poor things.
I should feel pity, not rage for them.
- I don't feel pity for them.
- What do you feel, fondness ?
They didn't do anything wrong.
So who vandalized the benches ?
You didn't see them.
But I see how they go around,
and how they talk.
They barely know how
to properly string two words together.
How odd, there are no pipes here.
The heating pipes
are on the other side.
So what is that stain ?
Maybe the leak is elsewhere
and just spread here.
Water takes
the strangest routes at times.
- I'm going out to the square.
- Don't wander off.
- This is Paco.
- Hi.
This isn't a late onset maternal urge,
she's just here for a few days.
She checks my phone,
I have to explain my every move.
All women are a threat.
At first I tried to reassure her,
but things just got worse.
I'm afraid she'll take it out
on our son.
Never.
- How do you know ?
- I know, I lived through that.
It's been three years,
seems like yesterday.
I feel like I messed everything up.
Don't mess up anymore.
Keep an eye on that stain,
and let me know.
Gea l What are you doing there ?
Nothing, just watching.
Don't wander off without telling me.
I didn't wander off, I'm right here.
Come here now.
Why do you like those kids so much ?
- Because they're free.
- Free from what ?
Free.
I want to show you something.
See this woman ?
Her name was Anna Kuliscioff.
She was born in Russia
to a very rich family.
She left it all to come to Italy
and join a group of revolutionaries.
She was a free woman.
They're back again l
Will you knock it off ?
People are trying to sleep l
Don't bust our balls, lady l
I've had enough l
Every single night...
What do you expect me to do then ?
They're not childish pranks l
I'm telling you, they vandalized
the benches in the square.
Fine, thanks.
Who did you call?
Guess.
- The police.
- Bingo.
- What did they say ?
- They're on their way.
Guys, the police l
What are you doing ?
Now we can finally get some sleep.
Good night.
Let's beat it l
You don't want the cookies ?
What's up, are you mad at me ?
Hello, mom ?
Everythings fine.
I'll be waiting outside,
when you're done we'll go run errands.
Okay... she's a bit snooty.
BETTER WATCH OUT, BITCH
Can you believe
what those hooligans did ?
Who says they did it?
Are you kidding me ?
You provoked them.
I just asked them not to make noise
outside my house at night.
Does that seem unreasonable ?
- You called the police too.
- So what ?
Didn't you hear them call me a bitch ?
Did you hear them or not?
Answer me l
Yes.
Then let's go.
Did you actually see them doing it?
Of course not, I was sleeping.
Well if you didn't see them,
you can't file a report
against them personally.
Same goes for the benches, I imagine.
Ma'am, there is no proof.
Who else could it be ?
I'm certain it was them.
Plus, they even insulted me.
How so ?
They called me a bitch.
- Well...
- Well what ?
If we had to intervene every time
someone says "bitch"...
Do you think that's normal?
Well...
- What do you think ?
- Never mind her.
Did you hear them ?
No.
You didn't hear them insult me ?
- Why did you lie ?
- I didn't lie.
You said one thing to me,
and the opposite to the cop.
- I'm not a rat.
- This is about telling the truth.
- I did tell the truth.
- Right, like about you being adopted.
What ?
Your mom says it's a lie
that you tell people for attention.
Will you please knock it off ?
It's not night.
It's not night
but you're disturbing the peace.
You can't just do as you please.
I told the police about that lovely
graffiti you left for me too l
What graffiti ?
Will you please stop that ?
She really did it l
You two are such assholes.
What did you do ?
I asked them to leave.
Why did you lift up your skirt ?
They said they'd leave
if I showed them my panties.
- So you did ?
- Yes.
Do you realize what you've done ?
- What?
- They wanted to humiliate you...
you put yourself
in a position of weakness l
- You're in a position of weakness.
- Me ? Why ?
Because you're afraid of them.
Oh, really ?
Hey you, hold on l
Hold on l
The ﬁrst days of her arrest
in Florence were agonizing.
She was locked in a small cell
that faced a courtyard.
She was denied any type of contact,
with her family
and with other inmates.
She was even forbidden
to write down her thoughts.
And for her,
this was most unbearable.
- Your grandma's pissed off...
- She's not my grandma.
- Come with us.
- Where ?
To a place
where nobody busts our balls.
Get on.
Look who's here l
- Hey.
- Hi.
Why's she here ?
She was walking all alone
and asked me if she could come.
Sit down.
- What's your name ?
- Gea.
- ls that a dog's name ?
- No, it means "Earth".
- Ever smoked before ?
- No.
How old are you ?
11, I mean 13.
- Quit bullshitting us.
- Where do you live ?
- In Rome.
- And you never smoked a joint ?
Ignore him, he's an idiot.
Can I try ?
Not like that,
you have to inhale and hold it.
She can't take her eyes off you.
Come here,
I want to show you something.
Good girl.
Do you have a boyfriend ?
- No.
- So wanna date me ?
Quit fucking laughing l
- Not you.
- Why, you don't like me ?
- Wanna try something good ?
- What?
Drink this.
- What's the big deal ?
- Just wait and see.
Gea !
Why don't you want to date me ?
Are you crying ?
Of course she is, you sicken her.
Do I really sicken you ?
Say it.
No.
Can you French kiss ?
Want to touch my thingie ?
But thanks for asking.
Where have you been ?
I searched everywhere.
- Out.
- With who, those kids ?
No, alone.
Ado ran off when I unleashed him
on the beach.
Come on.
- How's everything ?
- Fine.
I called your father.
Did you tell him to come get me ?
He wants to talk to you.
Now ?
Yes, now.
- What happened ?
- Nothing, Ado ran away.
Arianna searched for you for hours.
- Where are you ?
- In the hospital, for colic.
I can't come right away.
But I can send Ginevra
to pick you up at the station.
I don't want to leave.
Look what was in my gall bladder.
Three centimeters. Crazy, huh ?
You asleep ?
I don't want to be pushy
but tell me what happened.
You were with those kids, weren't you ?
I already told you, Ado ran away.
You don't believe me.
I don't know.
Leave the door open.
All right.
Gea disappeared for hours today.
I found her walking,
dazed and alone on the highway.
l suspect she was with those kids
and that something bad happened,
but she denies it.
l should've pushed harder,
taken her to the hospital for an exam,
alarmed her parents.
Instead l did nothing.
To be discreet 7?
I'm afraid not.
Good morning.
Hi.
- Home so early?
- I did some shopping.
- Coffee ?
- I already had some.
We need to talk.
Go ahead.
Sit down.
I met a guy at the club,
a salesman from the north.
His wife died a few years ago.
He asked me to live with him.
- And you ?
- I said I need to think it over.
- And talk to you about it.
- Why?
Because you're my son.
I think you should do what you want.
You can come live with us.
He has a huge house in Varese.
There's nothing for me in Varese.
Plus, I found a steady job here.
Really? Where ?
In the supermarket stock room.
I start next week.
Why aren't you eating ?
I'm not hungry.
What would you like to do today ?
Did you do your homework ?
I know you want me to leave...
I didn't say anything.
I don't know where she went
or what happened.
Sorry, she wouldn't tell me.
What ?
Yes, I did tell your husband that...
But now there's a different issue:
I can't handle her anymore
and don't want to.
When could you come ?
That's fine by me.
No, it's best you tell her.
All right, thanks.
Goodbye, thanks.
Hi, mom.
Why so soon ?
But I didn't do anything.
I don't want to leave.
- Hi.
- Arianna isn't home.
- Will you tell her I came by?
- Yes.
Hi!
- How's the stain ?
- It hasn't come back yet.
I've been staying at my brother's,
I haven't seen my son in three days.
- I spoke to a psychiatrist.
- What did he say ?
That I need to convince her
to get help, but she'll never agree.
It would be easier for you
if there were a name for her condition,
but women's disorders
are more mysterious than men's.
They're not that easy to define.
Will you hug me ?
It's just a minor lapse, it'll pass.
Thanks.
Bye.
Shall we go ? It's getting cold.
Can't we stay a bit longer?
It's the last day.
Seems the gang has split up.
- He's not in the gang.
- He's always in the square with them.
- He doesn't like being with others.
- No ?
How do you know ?
I just know.
That boy must be in love with me.
Perhaps.
Have you ever been in love ?
Lots of times when I was a kid.
Then when I grew up, just once,
when I met my husband.
Did you talk to him ?
Of course, how else
would I have fallen in love with him ?
I don't think you need to talk
to fall in love.
True, it's not essential,
but it is preferable
so you can avoid nasty surprises.
You fall in love with someone
because you know him.
You don't know him by talking
but by looking,
one look and you know everything.
That never happened to me.
Maybe that's why I faced
some nasty surprises.
Good night.
Know where I'm taking you ?
Yes, I do.
And you're not afraid ?
No.
Hey, you're still in bed ?
Get dressed,
your mom will be here soon.
I had a dream.
ls that so ? A good or bad dream ?
A good dream, but I died in the end.
- Where is she ?
- In her room getting ready.
Do have any idea
what might have happened ?
- I thought I did.
- What did you think ?
You know,
last night Gea started dancing.
Okay. .-
When you asked where she'd been,
what did she say ?
- Out with the dog.
- For four hours ?
I'm sorry, it's my fault,
I'm not used to dealing with kids.
I don't understand them.
It's not your fault,
Gea is an odd kid.
You're her mom, she might tell you.
Perhaps, but I doubt it.
Thanks for everything, goodbye.
Goodbye.
It's time for us to say goodbye.
If that boy asks about me,
tell him I've left but I'll be back.
Okay, if he asks I'll tell him.
- I'm almost done.
- Take your time.
No need to rush.
She's always scurrying l
Your mom says
you dropped out of school.
Looking for work ?
Not really,
l take whatever comes along.
I have a small farm equipment company.
Nothing big,
but it involves lots of traveling,
even abroad,
and meeting lots of people.
Let me know if you're interested.
Thanks, but I don't like traveling.
How strange, at your age
most kids can't sit still l
- Want more coffee ?
- Yes, sure.
Thanks.
I have a son too.
I rarely see him, he lives in Belgium,
his name's Fabio.
All set.
I'll load the car.
Have Yuri give you hand,
I'll grab a few more things.
No need, I'll do it.
It was a pleasure to meet you.
Hope to see you soon. Bye.
- What do you think of him ?
- Dunno, we didn't talk much.
- Will you be okay alone ?
- Of course, I'm not a baby.
It's a just a vacation,
I'll be back here in a week.
Or sooner if I get bored.
Your pants are in the washer,
make sure to hang them out.
Okay, don't worry.
There are steaks in the freezer.
I've got a surprise for the old dude...
first and last time.
Hello l
Will you set them up ?
The mirror's on the table.
Know it ?
He's a legend, a traveler
who knew the world.
An untranslatable title:
"Os Cus de Judas".
In Italian it was translated as:
"Butt Fuck Nowhere".
Want to read it?
Oh right, you have no use
for reading, Hamlet.
You go to the School of Hard Knocks.
Good.
Found it.
The king of all drugs.
Just this time, never again.
This will be my last time.
I'm leaving, changing scenery.
Where to ?
I'm going to start traveling
like I used to.
Wouldn't you like to leave ?
Changing location won't change
who we are deep inside.
You've become a philosopher, Hamlet.
My name's Yuri.
We're nothing deep inside,
we're just full of ghosts
who've set up their lairs.
She thought about those distant years
and it seemed that life
did not belong to her
but to someone else, with a different
name, a different destiny.
Hey.
Did you see the waves ?
Not going out?
Not today.
The others ?
Haven't heard from Mazinga in days
and Dora is missing.
- They're never in the square.
- They got scared shitless.
Speed it up,
you have another one waiting.
All right, see you.
Why'd you come looking for me ?
I was just passing by.
See you tonight ?
No, I've got stuff to do.
Hi, done with History homework ?
Yes, I just need to review.
- Hello ?
- Have you seen that boy ?
No.
- He hasn't been in the square ?
- I don't think so.
Remember,
if you see him tell him I left.
Of course.
- Bye.
- Good night.
Hello.
Subtitles:
Laser S. Film s.r.l. - Rome