I
Fifth Lady
Master wants you to go to Sixth Lady's room
What for?
I don't know
Sure, we will go right away
Yes
Could Hsi-men found out what we were planning
Don't think too much of it
Hurry up
Remember what I said
Tell Wu-Song no to come back
Ten I shall leave
Sister, we must be careful
I will be careful
Master. Master
You are all here
I feel really happy today
So I would like to chat with you all
I, Hsi-men Ching
These three words mean "bad boy”
Because except good things I can not do
I have done all the bad stuffs
Such as rape
Murder
Anything that benefits me
I will do it
Some people don't like me
They curse behind my back
Said I did too much bad
And I won't get a son
I was afraid in the beginning
But now
I don't have to any more
Because Vase is pregnant
Vase started for you guys
You should work more harder
Who can give me a healthy son
I will give her one thousand dollars
And she will get a portion of my property
But, if nothing happens at all
Don't blame me for not being fair
Moon Lady, Vase has to eat more from now on
Make her healthy
Give birth to a healthy baby for me
Go in yourself
I wait for you outside
Let go in
Get them out of here
Get out...
Hurry out... Get out
Hurry up...
Hey, hurry up...
Get out, everyone
Hurry...
Get out
Lord, what happened?
Nothing will happen in this county
Go
What?
Hsi-men Ching
It's you master Kao
Long time no see, how's going?
Not bad
It's just I miss you so much I could not sleep
Master Kao
It was a misunderstanding that day
People who didn't mean it is not guilty
Hope master Kao would forgive me
Don't worry
I won't kill you
I just want justice
Master, is something going to happen?
Nothing will happen
You guys go first, go
No need to hurry
Let her stay and watch
Maids can go if they want
You go, go...
Don't worry, nothing will happen
Young master Kao
I will admit what I have done
I will take the blame myself
You have to take the blame no matter what
Master Kao
Please don't say it in front of my wives
Can't they go first
Please, master Kao
I can't hear suddenly
Can you speak louder
Please
Good, let them go
Master
Wait for me outside
Nothing will happen, hurry, go
Go
Hurry
OK
You can say anything now
I was wrong, master Kao
You are so kind
Don't mind my mistakes
I didn't know who you were then
Please forgive me
Hsi-men Ching
I thought you are a man
You too are scared of death
Of course I do
Only stupid people don't
Master Kao, let me go
I can give you women or money
I am very rich
And have five beautiful wives
I can share them with you
To repay your kindness
Hsi-men Ching, you are wrong
I came to this place
Not for your money
About women
I don't have a shortage of them either
I just want revenge
I don't want nothing except for this
Master Kao
If only you let me live
You can do anything to me
I don't like to bully others
But I don't like others to bully me
I get then I repay
Of course...You mean
If I didn't remember wrong
Someone wants me to drink yellow soup
Who?
It's me
What about now
I'll drink, but where?
Master Kao
What do you say
Hurry
Hsi-men brother
I am sorry
I can only pee on shoe
I have to tell everyone to pee
Come on...
Come...more...
Thanks for not killing me
Let's go
Are you OK, master
I'm alright
Take me bake
Be careful
Don't tell anyone about today
Vase knows
I won't let you go easy if you say it
Yes
Be careful
Do I look like I've been bully at?
No
But you walk strange
Strange my ass
Don't say anything when we go in
Yes
Hey, open up
coming...
Master
You are so slow
Master, you are back
Of course
Yin said you were taken away by those bad guy
I was worried for you
What's there to worry about
Who dares do anything to me in this county
Then it OK
Because Yin said they are not from this county
And they are big-time
It's just a little misunderstanding
They were so polite to me
after they know who I am
Master, I will let kitchen
prepare something to eat for you
Eat what, I don't want to eat
Go get me a doctor
Eat...all you know is eat
Doctor
Master
Your pulse is not regular
You have kidney sickness
But nothing serious
You will get better after a few days rest
But, Lord
Don't get too close with women these days
I heard that saying for years
Every doctor says the same thing
It's like those women
has done something bad to you
I don't want you to tell me how to stay fit
I just ate something
wrong and felt like puking
Just get me some stomach medicine
Right
I smell something weird from your breath
Master, what did you eat wrong
Don't ask too much
What I ate is none of your business
Yes...
Did you want to know who
I slept with last night also?
Damn you...
Lord...
Look, listen, ask and touch are
the four important things for doctors
If I don't ask,
it might affect your health
OK, OK...you can go...
Yes
Come in
Master
What?
Chin was caught and
sent back by the court
This little bastard
He can't run away from me
Where is Picture of Grace
Don't know, we just caught Chin
It's OK
Once we have Chin
We will get her soon
Speak
Where is Picture of Grace
Chin
I treated you nice
If you tell the truth, I will let you go
Why take the blame
I---
I shall speak, but I have a request
What?
I want to see the Fifth Lady
If I don't see her,
I won't say anything
Sure
Fifth Lady,
master wants you to go to the lobby
What happened now?
Chin was caught
Master wants to see you
OK, tell master
I will be there shortly
Yes, Fifth Lady
Who?
It's Plum Blossom
Fifth Lady,
why are you holding a pair of scissors
Chin was caught
He must can stand the beat
He probably told everything
This idiot, I told him to run far and away
How could he got caught
Plum Blossom
Thank god
I send Chen Ching-chi go rescue uncle
I have fulfill my only wish
If 1 die, I could die peacefully
Fifth Lady, just do it step by step
I think chin
Probably won't tell anything
Master
Chin, now that fifth Lady is here
Tell the truth
Stupid servant
Where is Picture of Grace
Fifth Lady...
am sorry to you
I did something I shouldn't do to you
It ruined your reputation
Chin is wrong, please forgive me
Quit the nonsense
Speak
Where is that bitch
I killed her
Body
Is in the old well back in the garden
What, you killed Picture of Grace?
Yes, I killed her
I hate her,
because she wants to frame Fifth Lady
Because she ruined everything of mine
I hate her...
Men
Master
Feed his body to the dogs
Yes
Come in
Fifth Lady
What made you so happy
Did you know Hsi-men Ching is in bad luck
Is that so
I never heard any one mention it
Of course no one dares say it
He was forced to eat shit
Who dares made him eat shit
This is called one
mountain is higher than another
He did something to Minister kao's son
This you master is so special
He didn't hit him and swear at him
He just forced him to eat a pile of shit
No wonder
he kept eating stomach medicine these days
Everyone knows this in Chin-he County
Jung even mad a song about it
Fate will decide everything
I think good luck is giving Hsi-men up
Bye the way, sister
I've great news for you
What is it?
Do you know
Tomorrow is Emperor's
mother's seventieth birthday
Emperor will set everything free
Your uncle might be free,
you will see each other
really, great
But...
What,
you don't want uncle to be free?
It's good that he is free
But I don't want him back
Why?
Think about it
What can he do after he is back
Ask him to take me away?
Why not?
Unless he doesn't love you
No
You won't understand
He is a real man
So he won't do anything
that would make people laugh at him
If he is a real man
He should know how to pay back
Rescue you from here
Besides, this is about you two
What's people got to say about it?
I know
This is impossible
And I don't wish him to do this
I can't do this, I can't
It's better he never comes back
OK, don't cry
Wu-Song, someone is looking for you
Sir, go get something to drink
Hurry
OK...
Brother Wu
You are...
These are shoe Fifth Lady made for you
And these cakes
Does
she has anything to say to me
She...
She... she is dead
Dead?
What did you say?
She is dead
How did she die?
Brother Wu, let me go first
Let me tell you everything
Speak, are you lying to me
She won't die this easy
Speak
Hurry up
Let me tell you the truth, Brother Wu
She is not dead
But she wants me to tell you she is
She doesn't want you to go back
She doesn't want me to go back
What has happened to her?
After you committed murder
Caught by the court
She wants to rescue you
So she sold herself
to Hsi-men Ching for two hundred dollars
Now
she is the Fifth Lady of Hsi-men
You understand now
Why
she doesn't want you back
Brother Wu
Although I don't know your past
But I know
Fifth Lady treats you truly
Although Hsi-men loves her
But I stayed there for a long period of time
I've never seen her laugh
She loves no one but you
Sister-in-law
Brother Wu
Don't run brother Wu
Don't run
Freeze
After him
Uncle
Sister-in-law
What are you thinking
You are back uncle
Have you met Chen Ching-chi
You tell me
Why marry Hsi-men Ching
Why...
I...I want to rescue you
If I don't bribe the court,
you will get killed
I rather die
Then you marry that bastard
You should know it
Sister-in-law
Golden Lotus
What's wrong
It's a dream
I just dream a dream
You were killed in it
It really scared me
You cry so sadly
In fact
You do love me a little
Master you should know
If you are not here
My life will be a living hell,
of course I am sad
Golden Lotus, don't worry
I am still in good health
Not that easy to die
Infect, if something do happen to me
I've taken care of everything for you
If you are real to me
I won't let you suffer
I have no one here in Ching-he County
Who can I depend on but you
How can't I be real to you
It's great you think this way
We haven't done it for a long time
I'll tell Plum Blossom do some cooking
We should drink Happily today
By the way,
what was that you gave me last time
taste sweet, not bad
Master,
isn't your health not great these days
A little
But it's OK
I haven't had fun for a long time
I am almost sick
I almost forgot
I have something good for you
What is it?
See
Master,
where did you get these
It from a relative of Ying
He got it from Japan
He said just do it according to the picture
You will feel so great
I don't...
Master, the wine is warm now
Plum Blossom, let's drink it together
Here, have some too, Plum Blossom
Sure
Golden Lotus, you too
I drink one
Master, don't drink too much
You are like a tiger every time you drink
Then we will suffer from you
Cheers
Master
I am a tiger now
Don't run, come
Don't run...
Master...
Come...
Master! Are you alright?
Master, you are not in great health these days
rest more, don't play too much
I know myself
You don't have to tell me
Come in
Master, First Lady, doctor is here
Lord Hsi-men
Madam
What, it's not doctor Chen
Doctor Chen went back to his home town
This female doctor is from Lo-yang city
She is famous
This is the first time
I heard about a female doctor
Mrs. Hsi-men
I learned my medication from my ancestors
In my family
I am the only daughter
But the name of Lo-yang Wong family
Won't fade away because I am a girl
No matter what
A male doctor is better
Since you think this way
Then I won't do anything
Please get another doctor
Don't go
I didn't say you can't do it
How about this
Show me what you've got
If you are for real
I won't treat you unfairly
Good
That me take a look at you
Please take your clothes off
Your pulse is strong
But it is not smooth
It seems like
You had stomach problems
You hurt your stomach
You might bleed
Not bad, you have something
Doctor, is that a big problem
If it's just stomach problems
It's not a big deal
Just adjust your eating behavior
Then you should be OK
Doctor,
does he has any other problems
Problems
He has every other men's problem
To be honest
He drinks and has too much women
He has to change it
I can't change it
If you want me to change
I rather die
Maybe it's not that serious
If you know how to take care of yourself
This problem of yours won't harm you
This is great
Moon Lady
Go get some money
Thank this doctor well
Yes
Lord Hsi-men
Let me get you some medicine
Doctor
The treatment of my problem
Can you teach me
Lord, you really want to learn
If you teach me yourself
I don't care how expensive it is
We'll talk about it some other day
OK
It's a deal
Doctor
Mrs. Hsi-men
Cook this medicine
Take it three days in a row
Don’t eat too much fried foods
This is for you
Thank you
Come
Lord Hsi-men, Mrs. Hsi-men
Good bye
Take this
This is a real doctor
You have a new target
I've played many women
But I've never touched a female doctor
Coming
Brother
I am back
Hui-lan, did you see Hsi-men Ching
Yes, I did
Is he doubting you
I did everything the way you taught me
Not just he didn’t doubt me
He said I am a good doctor
He will fall into our trap
Hsi-men is a really ruthless guy
He will do anything
I don't think you should take this risk
Brother
Other then this
You tell me
how can we deal with this guy
Do we have to give up
If he found out you are not for real
The cruel way
he treats women is very famous
Beside,
you have to lose your chastity for me
Does it worth it?
Your face, brother
Was burnt by that guy
He ruined your life
No matter how much I sacrifice
I want him to pay back
Hui-lan, I... I am worried
Brother, don't say it any more
I have made my mind
Have you got everything I need
This is a scab of the death sore
It's from a dead body
make it into powder
Leave it on Hsi-men's wound
If it contacts blood
Hsi-men will get the sore in three days
But you have to be careful
Don't touch it yourself
There are no cure for it
Hsi-men Ching
I want you to suffer
Who is it?
It me, Chen Ching-chi
Chin-chi, you are back
Fifth Lady
Have you met my uncle
Yes
How was he
He looks health
But he looks a little stupid
Like a idiot
All he know is eat the cakes
you made him
Like he has starved for a long time
But,
I thought I saw tears in his eyes
Chin-chi
Did you tell him what I want to say
I told everything
I even said it twice
Told me not to come back
Good, he should never come back
Never
Fifth Lady
Don't be sad
He is a clumsy guy
He doesn't understand your heart
Don't be sad, because
Chen Ching-chi
Fifth Lady, this is not our first time
Don't pretend
This is the only time and the last time
I won't promise you another
Fifth Lady...
I go every where for you
You have to thank me
No, no matter what you say
Fifth Lady, pity me
I think ill of you
Let me go...
Chen Chin-chi, let go of me
Move
Chen Ching-chi
Golden Lotus
Don't forget I rescue you ones
Come
OK
Chen Ching-chi
You are crazy
Don't pull me.
Let her go, Chen Ching-chi
Chen Ching-chi, what are you doing
Father-in-law, I...
Master, he is harassing me...
If it's not for Fifth Lady...
Bastard, loser, get out of here
Yes
Master, her is like a maniac
Men gets crazy when they need women
Haven't you see those dogs on heat?
If female dogs don't let them,
they get crazy
Master, I am so scared
You're still talking
That loser is pretty pitiful actually
I say you should satisfy him, Plum Blossom
No, I am yours, how can I do that?
You are loyal to me
By the way
I need you guys to do me a favor
Master, why are you so polite
It's this
My health has a little problem
I need a total treatment
But it's inconvenient at First Lady's place
So I want to come here
You can do anything at home
What's so in convenient?
You liked that doctor
So you want to do it here
You are quick
You all understand me?
Master, don't worry, we know what to do
Plum Blossom
Bring her here tomorrow then
You have to act well
I shall leave now
And have a good sleep
So I can handle that doctor tomorrow
Plum Blossom
How can we help Hsi-men do this?
You over did it
Fifth Lady, don't angry
I am not helping Hsi-men actually
What?
Just what and see
He will get his deserved fate
Hsi-men
See how I am going treat you
Brother
Hui-lan, you have
to be careful not to touch that stuff
Understand
Don't worry, I remember
I'm leaving, brother
OK
Don't come out
Lord Hsi-men's house is big
So what?
It only makes people feel lonely
Lord Hsi-men. you aren't joking
You have four or five wives, you sill lonely?
It's not this
There are enough people
But we don’t have someone like you
It's too bad
You are joking again, lord Hsi-men
Please
Come
this is fifth Lady's room
It's so neat
Where is Fifth Lady
She went to the temple
I thought she wants me to take a look too
That was an excuse
I wanted you to come
I want to teach me the special treatment
You liar
You said to learn the treatment,
you need a quiet and clean place
Isn't this place quiet and clean
This place is good enough
but it the person who
needs it the most, can you do it
I can
No problem
This treatment is a kind of inner strength
we have to be naked with no other thoughts
Can you do it?
I look like a playboy,
but actually I am a nice guy
I won't have any other thoughts towards you
Good
I will teach you the treatment here
Thanks
Let's take our clothes off
Remember, no other thoughts
Of course, I understand
You...don't, lord
Doctor, I am in trouble, help me
No...
Lord, you are great
You almost killed me
I never knew you are so wild
See
It looks like I tattooed my back
It's bleeding, how?
Turn over
I have some medicine
Let me put some on you
No need, it's just a scratch
This medicine is very helpful
There will be no scars
Don you feel better now?
Better
But it's itchy
I scratched you too
Here, let me put some on you
No...No need...Don't move
No...
Hui-lan, you are back
Some thing wrong?
My scratch...
Some powder got on it...
How come you are so careless
I told you before
This kind of death sore
Is very poisonous
It won't let you die
But it will make you suffer your whole life
Stop it
So what
If 1 die with Hsi-men Ching
Brother
Is there a cure
Rub your whole body with grapefruit leaves
If nothing happens in three days,
you will be alright
Whole body
Lord, I dream a dream
I dream about a little boy
in red ran into my stomach
It scared me
I am thinking
The baby
Will look like Buddha's servant
Looks like this baby will be special
Lord
Are you listening to me, it's almost noon
I don't feel well
There are so many mosquitoes
So itch
Lord, what happened to your face?
What about it?
I hate it
Tell Hui-lan to come here
See what's wrong with me
Master
Doctor Chen is here
Lord Hsi-men
I told you to get Hui-lan, you didn't hear me?
Master, she is not home
No one knows where she is
Female doctor
We have a female doctor is this county?
Yes
From Lo-yang
You never heard?
No
don't care about her now
Look at me first
What are this things on my face?
It's so itchy
Please have a seat
Thank you
Lord Hsi-men
Have you been to any place lately
No
Strange
It looks like smallpox, but it isn't
In the past few years
Smallpox has never appear in this county
What, I got smallpox?
This...
am not sure
But it could be
Damn you
You didn't say anything yet
Is it a big deal, doctor?
Madam, to tell you the truth
If this is smallpox,
you might just become pockmarked face
But I haven't seen anything like this
Let me go home and check, and come back late
You are saying this
disease is worse then smallpox?
It might be what my teacher told me before...
Bastard
Don't think I will give
you more money by scaring me
Get lost...
I don't want to see you ever
Yes
Get em Hui-lan
Didn’t Yin just said she is not here
She can't go far
Go find her
If you can't find her, I will kill you
Yes
Why this?
Bastard
Is this ghost that did this?
Brother
Hui-lan
Hui-lan. Brother
Hui-lan...what happened
Brother
It looks like I've got the death sore
I told you don't deal with Hsi-men
He is a living monster
I don't regret it
Even if I die with him
I won't regret
Hui-lan
I heard Hsi-men is looking for you
Before he found out everything
Leave This place
If he found out, we will die
No
I got this disease
I have nothing to be afraid of
Hui-lan
This is not a deadly disease
I will find a cure
Leave with me
Brother, don’t lie anymore
This is a deadly disease
When you are sick, you feel itchy everywhere
Itch till the bone
Death is a better treatment
Or I won't use it on Hsi-men
Hui-lan
A worthful death is
better than a worthless life
Leave will have a better chance of surviving
Let's leave
OK
Can you leave me for a moment
I want to change
No I still look good
But I will be ugly in two days
Hui-lan
Hsi-men Ching
Master
Bad news
What?
We found Hui-lan
But she is dead
Dead?
How?
Suicide
And died in Jung's house
People said she is Jung's sister
Even if she is Jung's sister
She doesn't have to commit suicide
Unless...
Master, doctor Chen is here
Lord Hsi-men
I found it
Found it?
The disease
So?
This is called Death Sore
This is a rare disease
Deadly
No, it's not
But it's worse then death
It makes you itchy everywhere
Even inside you
People who can't stand it scratch
themselves till blood comes out
Sometimes get crazy
Any cure?
No
People who got it, eight out of ten dies
Why do you tell me this?
Let's do some studying
Study my ass, you are joking me
The did this to me
Jung
When I got you, I will chop you into pieces
Man
Master
Tell this to everyone
Who every catches Jung
gets one thousand dollars reward
That blind man can't go far
Yes, master
Jung
Fifth Lady...
Why are you here
Do you know Hsi-men Ching is looking for you?
Yes
This is why I hide here
They will never know
I hide at Hsi-men's home
What are your plans
We'll see
When they don't want me that bad,
I will get away
Fifth Lady
Can you find a hideout for me?
Let me see...
Fifth Lady, don't worry
I won't get you in trouble
I know you hate Hsi-men too
We are on the same team
Fifth Lady, pity me
Spare my life
OK, Jung, come with me
Come
Please hide in this well
I will give you something to eat everyday
When everything is OK, you can come out
Fifth Lady, thank you, you will get good luck
So itchy
Lord
Itchy
Lord, hold it in
Give it to me
Let me suck on it more. No, lord
You suck on it seven times today
Doctor said you cant suck on it too much
Or you will harm yourself
Shut up, give it to me, hurry
Wine
Good...
You are the hero Wu-Song
Never let go of any good wine
Brother, Mrs.Sun
I received the letter from Liang-San
We heard you were in trouble
but you got away with it
We prepared some wine when we got the news
Thank you
what do you want to do from now on, brother
I am going to Ching-he County
Brother Wu
You have no relative there, why go back?
Come to Laing San with me
Everyone at Liang San misses you
Master
Congratulations, master
Sixth Lady gave birth
Really?
Really
A boy or a girl
Master, it's a boy
Excellent
Vase, where is my son
Where is my son. Here, my lord
It looks exactly like you
So cute
Don't touch him, lord
You are sick, lord
OK, I won't touch him
I can look at him, right
Leave some distance
OK
He looks like me
Of course
If he doesn't look like you, who else
Yea
I won't be afraid of nothing since I have him
I could die peacefully
He is a boy
Who dares say Hsi-men family
will get bad fate from now on
Who dares say I won't have a son
Lord, he doesn't have a name yet
I came up with lots of names
Non of it fits
But this is no problem
When he is one month old
I will invite all the smart people here
Everyone
Let them pick a nice name for my son
Congratulations
Thanks
First Lady, look at it
Look how cocky Vase is
She though she is the First Lady
It's OK, let her be happy for one night
Right
We can fix her some other chance
Hsi-men Ching won't live long
See how cocky she can be
Forget about it, Plum Blossom
We are all unfortunate people, why blame him
You forgot everything
You forgot it
She treated you so bad these days
Master Hsi-men
The whole Ching-he County is happy
Why?
It's easy
We haven't had a honored
person for a long time
According to my calculation
Your son was born at a perfect time
This county will be famous
Our hopes are on your son
Really?
Of course
Master Hsi-men
Though I haven't met your son yet
But I bet
He must be really handsome
You are joking,
you haven't even seen the kid yet
Just look at his daddy and mommy
Handsome parents have handsome kids
Right
By the way
Where is your son?
He is drinking milk,
when he is full, he will come out
Right
Please have some tea inside
I have some other guests. Sure...go ahead
Please...
Go in first
Inside...
Please go inside
Master, and Sixth Lady
Bad news
What?
When the nurse wants to feed young master
A man took young master away
Where did they go
In the garden
Son of a bitch
Man
come with me
Move it
Don't rush
Slow down
I won't run
I was waiting
Jung
It's me
Hsi-men Ching
I am here to congratulate you
Men, arrest him
Yes
Who dares to come forward
I will throw the kid down, back off
Jung
Don't do it
We can talk
Jung, I did something bad to you
But this kid knows nothing
Don't kill him
Vase, you are right
Your kid did nothing wrong
But what did Wu-Da do wrong?
What did I do wrong?
Besides
People who die because of Hsi-men
What did they do wrong?
They don't even know why they die
Jung
It's us adult's fault
You want to revenge, revenge on us
Give the kid back, please
Jung
If you let the kid go
I won't do anything to you
I will give you money to open a new store
Hsi-men Ching
I am not a three years old kid
I came here today
Never thought of going out alive
I want to see you get your fate
I don't care if I die
Jung, please
Don't revenge on my kid
You can hit me
You can kill me
But don't harm my kid, please
No need to kneel down
I am not here for you
Lord, you kneel down too
Lord
Jung
No all the family member
is kneeling right in front of you
Please let go of him
Hsi-men Ching
I won't let you go this easy
Unless I get my revenge
Or I won't give you back your kid
Good
What do you want me to do
No I want to tell everyone
What you have done in the past years
If you lie
I will throw the kid down
Don't. don't, don't...
Then tell him to speak
Lord, speak, hurry
OK, I speak
Listen
I
Have a bad temper
I swear everyone
I hit everyone
Sometimes I see beautiful women
I will look at her
Hsi-men Chine
I think you don't want your son to live
Don't...
I want to start from small stuffs
But you are so impatient
Then I will start from the big events
I took Wong’s land
Burnt his house
I raped Ho's wife
And I said she seduced me
She...
She killed herself
I bribed the government
Import wine
Sell fake medicine
I killed a lot...
Let me ask you, Hsi-men
Did you killed Hua
Yes...
Say it
Yes
Wu-Da
Did you poisoned him?
You wants his wife
So you poisoned him
And lied
Let Wu-Song take the blame
Hsi-men Ching
Don't think no one can do anything to you
You better die early
So when Wu-Song Comes back,
you won't die in his hands
Enough
Jung, I had enough of you
Stop or I won't be polite to you
Good, let's see what you can do
You dare, I will kill you
Son...
Hsi-men Ching
No that you don't have a son
I just want to see you get your desired fate
I see it now
I can die
Jung
You bastard
Give back my son
Give back my son, you bastard
Son...
Give back my son, give if back
Bastard, give back my son
Lord
Bastard
Give back my son
Lord
Lord...Sixth Lady
Hsi-men Ching, give back my life
Give back my life
His-men Ching
Give back my life...
Lord, you are dreaming, take some medicine
I won't drink it
There must be poison in it
You want to drug me
Lord, who dares to drug you
When I was sleeping, I heard you said
I heard someone wants to kill me
And eat me
Master, Mistress, here come Second Uncle
Let him in. Get lost
Lord
Why is he here this moment
He comes here this time
He want to eat me too
Lord, stop the nonsense
He is here to see you
You people aren't this good
I am not stupid
I rather feed myself to the dogs then you
Lord
Brother-in-law, where are you
What's wrong with he, sister
He...he is crazy
Sister
You are his first wife
This is your house from now on
But be careful of betrayal
Because when he dies
People would want his property
So I want you do give me some ideas
Sister, you are right
Don't worry, I know what to do