Our next story is about love.
"LOVE" is an exhibition by the young
but established artist
Ugljesa Rackovic.
His latest display in the
Center for Cultural Decontamination
triggered heated
reactions in Belgrade.
My guest is
the National Museum curator,
and the Presidential Adviser
on Culture, Mr. Kosovac.
I haven 't seen the exhibition,
but I see that the media
cover this event
rather vulgarly.
This is not art.
This is political pamphletism.
I  don 't understand...
You see, everyone rushes to defend
his freedom of speech.
And I don't dispute that, but...
What about defending
religious freedoms?
Yes, but...
No one defends the religious feelings
of the great majority of Serbs
who feel offended by the blasphemous
works of this so-called artist.
The people simply do not want
this exhibition in their city.
Hey, lovebirds.
-Good morning, teacher.
-Hello.
Excuse me, teacher!
Teacher?
Can you please tell me,
will you be asking questions
about the WWII today?
-Because others said...
-Didn't you get an 'A' last week, Dobrica?
Hello.
-Hi.
Where is Srba?
Dinkic, Tadija?
Teacher, Tadija said he'd be late.
They'll come.
OK. I'll wait 'till
the end of the lesson.
Who will take an oral exam?
Sofija, you can answer
when I finish the lecture.
My favorite question:
What was 27th of March St.
named after?
You mean, The International Crisis,
Battle for the Yugoslav Region,
and the culmination of the crisis
in the events of 25th and 2 7th of March?
Title of the lecture.
In exact words!
Shoot.
-Please, start.
-From where?
-From the beginning.
-Which chapter?
Sofija, you don't divide
history into chapters.
We strive to understand the causes
of an event in order to...
-Sorry we are late.
-Just sit down.
You won't admit it?
So, what happened on March 27, 1941?
Coup d'etat by a group of
Yugoslav Army officers.
-Yes. What was the cause?
-The British propaganda.
The British felt that the Serbs
can forgive their rulers
everything, except treason.
-Same as today!
-So, the MI6
plotted to declare
Prince Paul a traitor.
Because they saw that he
was useless to them.
Wait, where did you get that?
Quiet, please!
-A read Harold Temperley's...
-Let's take it easy now.
Do you think that
Prince Paul was a patriot?
He was a member of the
Karadjordjevic dynasty.
He was the Regent...
I can see that you've studied,
But I'm interested in your opinion:
Was his pact with the Nazis
an act of patriotism?
Of course! To protect the people
from German invasion.
Matija, I'm not asking you,
I'm asking Sofija. Quiet, please!
Teacher, I don't understand
what do you want from me?
Prince Paul was rehabilitated.
Guys! Wait a minute.
Don't forget about the school trip
tomorrow! After the classes.
-What grade did I get?
-A strong 'B'.
Communist bitch.
Of course he's lying!
-What?
-So, you're lying, eh?
-Don't be such a cunt!
-C'mon, say it!
What's going on here?
-He's a pathological lair, they all are.
-Shut up, Matija!
Is it true?
What the fuck, man?
-Did you hear what I asked?
-What's wrong with you?
This is where they'd sleep.
Downstairs is the workshop,
with a small stage.
It looks great, right?
It would mean a world to them.
Svetlana, you don't get
to see them in class.
Apathetic, distant...
We have to fight for them.
Ms Olivera, I...
I really don't know
what do you want from me?
They've already been
on a school excursion.
Szentendre, Budapest and Prague.
And who would pay for it?
Their parents?
The owner is a friend of my husband.
It's an art colony.
I arranged free transportation.
The parents agreed, it's a Saturday,
I don't see the problem?
It's not a Saturday.
It's a working Saturday.
Surprised you forgot.
And, besides...
I cannot... the school
cannot approve.
Why not?
I know it's a working Saturday.
We'd go after the classes.
May I ask you a favor?
Can you show me...
How do you switch off
the ringing on this phone?
I want it to be on,
but I don't want to hear it ring.
Just press and hold this button.
Oh, I see...
-How do I turn it back on?
-The same way.
Svetlana, we're losing them.
Soon, we won't even speak
the same language.
High school kids utilize
less than 800 words...
And that's from a Canadian study!
We can't even compare...
Ms Olja, this is not a kindergarten.
You are not their nanny.
This is a high school.
And what you said about them,
well, that's the parents' fault.
They've reached the age when
nothing more can be done.
-Did you hear this hippie crap?
-Yes.
Insisting on
a first-name basis with me!
Her kind wanted to see the end
of us when Milosevic fell.
-You know that Ivana got fired?
-Really?
They are moving the marketing
department to Slovenia.
-She'll get a severance pay.
-Well, better than nothing.
No way! I haven't been there
since high school.
Good night, teacher.
...heard about that exhibition?
Horrible.
I've just heard, this morning.
And nobody's doing anything about it!
-What the fuck? Again?
-Third child.
Where do they get the money?
No money.
She's always on maternity leave.
And he's, like, working.
Part time.
They say the first kid costs a fortune,
the others just inherit stuff.
-Yeah, right.
-What?
What about you?
You're married, after all.
Please. Imagine me as a mom?
Imagine Ugljesa as a dad?
Someone's going to kill Ugljesa
because of this exhibition.
-Aren't you scared?
-Why?
Why would anyone kill him?
Nationalists are going crazy.
-You've seen the tweets?
-Actually, the Twitter's fine,
compared to the forums!
They're hammering him.
But they never go to exhibitions.
I mean, who does?
Same 200 people as always,
that's it.
But, still...
His painting called ''Love''...
The Patriarch? Really?
That's a bit too much. Even for me.
Come on, let's go!
No way I'm going inside,
it's full of children.
-That's what I'm telling you!
-No way.
Three shots of Jaegermeister.
-Isidora?!
-Good evening, teacher.
-You work here?
-Yes.
You said,
three shots of Jaegermeister?
Two.
-Keep the change.
-Thank you.
-I look forward to the field trip!
-Me, too.
Who's there?
Come on!
It's not blood. It's paint.
What happened?
-Olja!
-What?
-Tell me what happened!
-I'm alright!
And we could've been in New York...
Never again going through
shit like this.
What would I do in New York?
What would you do?
I dunno.
You could Rollerblade
in Central Park.
Or go shopping.
Hang on Left-wing blogs and troll
the nationalist forums, more likely.
Beats getting soaked with paint
by a bunch of morons.
Maybe.
Fuck.
I have to take the kids
to Tesa's place tonight.
I have to organize the transport,
to send an invoice...
Are you out of your mind?
I don't know anymore, really.
Half of all Serbian Jews were killed
at Sajmiste concentration camp.
But, also, thousands
of Roma people, communists...
The communists don't count!
They were traitors!
Matija...
Of 200.000 people that were killed
during the WWII in Serbia,
67.000 were Partisans.
FC 'Partisan'!
I'm talking about death camps
and you find that funny?!
No, you're imposing
your ideology in the classroom.
Couldn't you talk about something more
cheerful on the field trip day?
Really!
She is trying to do her job.
Okay, seniors.
What would you like to talk about?
About the Champions League!
About love!
-No way!
-That's great!
By the end of the school day, I want
you to write an essay about love.
We want the death camps back!
-Really.
-No, no. This is great.
-What does love mean to you?
-Nothing.
Whom do you love?
Who loves you?
And, we are gonna talk about your
essays during the trip.
People!
Do you realize that
most of the other teachers
say that you're the worst
generation ever?
Yeah, great!
They say that you have no empathy.
That you're cold, alienated...
-Thank you.
-Well, I don't share their opinion.
Maybe it's because
I'm stupid or naive,
or maybe it's because I've been
your age, not so long ago.
And it's great that
you mentioned love.
I'd really like to hear
your opinions about it.
Excuse me,
what's that got to do with history?
Everything.
-I won't take part in this.
-Me neither.
Radovan! Really!
Give me that cell phone.
Right now.
Who's there?
Who did this?
What?
One of you did this.
-Who?
-What?
Since you refuse to tell me
who did this,
I’ll assume that all of you
are responsible.
I'm taking this cell phone
straight to the police.
Who did what?
-You don't know, do you?!
-No, I don't.
-So, it wasn't you, then?
-No.
You neither, right?
Now listen carefully!
I'll give you a chance to tell
me who did this.
The one who did it
will face the consequences.
But if that person
hasn't got the guts to admit it,
I will hold all of you responsible!
In that case
I will no longer be
your teacher.
Because,
this...
There is a name for this in the aw.
And there is a street name for it, too.
And in both cases,
you know the procedure.
Was I clear?!
Yes...
Was I clear, Tadija?
Why allways me?
Am I clear?
Yes.
Now you'll hand over
your cell phone to me.
Here it is.
In fact, all of you will hand over
your cell phones.
-No, really!
-Come on!
You know that I couldn't have done it.
I don't care, Sandra!
My Mom has to call me.
You're taking away
our personal property.
You'll get it back once we discover
who attacked me,
who filmed it,
and who uploaded it.
Theese will remain locked in the
school vault until I get the answers.
-Man...
-She'll be back in a minute.
Poor teacher.
-She's really lost it.
-Right.
-What a retard.
-I've never seen her like this.
For real?
Why the fuck did you have to watch
the video in the first place?
Wait, are you fucking serious?
-Why?
-I'm not the one who uploaded it.
-She gonna give them back?
-What else?
-I need a cigarette.
-Me too.
Of all the things,
she had to take away the phones.
-Wow, it's the end of the world!
-Well, I'm not happy about it.
Punishing the whole class because
couple of retards...
She had no right!
Shut up!
You watched it too, didn't you?
You could've just gone back
to your place!
Don't blame it on me.
You have morons like that everywhere.
I'll kill myself if we end up
not going to the school trip.
After this? No way.
Hey!!
Fallout Girl is taking control.
Take care of wour personal hygiene first!
Let's speak one at a time, OK?
I got the video from
something-whore@yahoo.com
I didn't open it.
You?
-I got it from the same address.
-Just like all of us.
-I didn't get it!
-So, the address is the same.
This means that we can
easily find out...
What? She wants to figure out
who uploaded it?
No, she wants to know
who filmed it.
-Why would any of us do it?
-Right, she's got no proof.
She can't prove a thing,
the bitch is tripping.
How can she know it was one of us?
Dude... dude!
The video was viewed just 9 times,
and it already reached us.
So, it must've been uploaded
by someone here.
-Maybe it was you?
-Maybe it was Dobrica.
-I didn't!
-That's not the problem.
It will take a minute for the cops
to trace the IP address.
I could do that,
I just need a computer.
You could do it my ass!
Face the blackboard!
Keep quiet, they'll kill us...
Morons... I just can't stand
stupid people...
Yo, nerd!
Who's a moron?
I'm telling you, the cops can trace
the IP address...
Again with the cops?
Keep facing the blackboard!
You're pathetic!
Olja won't call the cops
if we tell her who did it.
Why wouldn't she?
See you after school, pretty boy.
-Olja is a commie.
-Fuck you.
Stutter-mouth, you're loud.
Maybe you're the one?
-I'm not.
-''I'm not''.
Stuttering retard.
Just like you don't go around telling
people I'm a fag, right?
I was just stating facts.
So you told them to
kick my ass?
They're unbelievable! She busted
her ass for us...
Why?
Because I don't believe you.
Because I'm not daft.
Chill out, jock.
Wait.
Let me handle this.
Not daft, eh?
He can go on for hours, like...
Then don't assume anything
about me, bro. Get it?
Is that it?
That's it.
Okay.
...they have no fucking idea what she
went through to...
He thinks he's a stud
if he fucked that whore.
Fucking jocks.
What's your problem?
-Just shut up for a while!
-Fuck you!
..and nobody gives a shit
about how she felt...
People, one at a time!
-Let's speak one at a time.
-That's what I said three minutes ago.
So, nobody will admit?
Isn't it obvious?
Then, let's tell that to Olja.
If none of us did it,
why would we be afraid of cops?
OK, why not. Strahinja,
what's your problem?
Maybe we could write
those essays, after all.
After that, we could all
take responsibility...
I don't want to take responsibility!
I don't give a fuck!
-Sit down!
-I haven't done a thing!
It runs in the family.
I didn't either,
but I feel ashamed!
She broke her balls to find
the money for the trip,
the school didn't give her a cent!
Are we going to that trip at all?
Can't you see that we're going
to be questioned by the police?
I don't give a fuck!
I'm not gonna let some moron
stop me from going...
Please, just go and write
that fashion blog of yours.
You could read it sometimes!
Junkie skank! Just look at you.
Don't talk back!
Fuck off!
You're really hot in these
pants, sweetheart!
This one is off to confess,
right?
Yeah, right, he'll confess
everything.
-Chill out, Jelena!
-She started it!
-She provoked me!
-Just behave!
-Little slut.
-And mind the language!
Will you stop arguing!?
Just write the stupid essays!
I'll go crazy!
Okay. Just take it easy.
I freaked out. So what?
Love. Amore...
Love is when stupid jocks
fuck the hot cheerleaders.
Who gives a fuck
about the rest of us.
Love is the meaning of life, Miksa!
You know that, right?
Are we really going
to write this shit?
Write it down.
-I don't know what.
-Cut the crap.
-Just scribble anything.
-What?
-Hey...
-Give me the pen, please.
I'm sorry for being
such a bitch.
Dawson's Creek, dude?
Never heard of it.
You haven't written a word.
...it ran for some 10.000 seasons.
The guy who made Dawson's Creek
made The Vampire Diaries.
Dawson goes through changes.
In the final season,
he looks like our Dobrica.
-Please, write something for me.
-You two are morons.
Nina...
Nina... Nina...
Please, ask her to write just
two lines for us, nothing more.
-Okay?
-Yeah. Please, write something.
-She retarded?
-Just do it.
Look at them,
they are really into it.
''My dear classmates''...
You dated Dinkic, you know them.
Really think they could've...
-Absolutely.
-But, still, something like this?
Well, it wasn't my Granny...
I guess not.
Shut up, you two!
-What's wrong with her?
-I don't know.
Gross.
Just ignore them.
Crazy biatchez.
-I can see that.
-What did you write about?
I drew myself at the stadium,
that's true love.
Yes, but for the wrong club.
Why don't you write
something about Lazar?
-I know you find him cute.
-Just leave it, will you?
Strale!
Strahinja...
Hey, this is me,
sitting next to you.
I see.
You saw that message
on Facebook, too!
-''Seen at 21 :05''.
-So?
So, you could write something back.
It pisses me off.
You're liking all those stupid
basketball jocks on Facebook all day,
but when I ask you a serious question,
you never answer.
So what?
Being bitchy again?
No, sweetie. Really.
Forget it.
But, I had to choose myself.
What's wrong with you?
-What?
Did you see that?
What a slut!
Look at this.
I don't like it.
Just look at him.
-Who wrote this?
-The Midget.
Really?
Nice handwriting.
Yeah, like a little girl.
Wait...
You’ll soon turn 18,
you know?
-Who do you play against?
-''Rad'', their field.
Retards are still waiting
for the school trip. Nice.
If my Lilith is in Capricorn,
and his in Scorpio...
Then the two of you
are sex maniacs!
We're locked in the school.
-What do you mean?
-alll the doors are locked.
-Really?
-For real?
-She's full of shit.
-Maybe the door just got stuck?
Olivera locked us!
She completely lost it.
-Like, really-really?
-I swear.
Where is Mile the janitor?
His room is empty.
What about the teacher's room?
-Icy, seriously?
-Yup.
Now what?
Locked us in to call the cops?
No way, man.
Why would she do that?
Maybe because they fucked up?
Let's see what's going on.
Where are they going?
The Baboons are off to save us.
Final Destination 3.
-Did you try the back door?
-Yes.
What if she really...?
The phones.
She took our phones!!
Right, you're the smart
one. Go ahead, open it.
Fucktard!
-Won't budge!
-Because you're a moron.
She really locked us in.
Now what?
What do you mean, take it easy?
I never turn off my phone!
If Granny calls, she'll freak out!
-She'll think something happened...
-Granny will die.
-Do they know about the school trip?
-Yes.
They'll think you're out of town,
no signal, and that's it.
Someone will contact her.
How will they contact her?
By smoke signals?
Does anyone have a second phone?
I've got three in my bag.
She'd die without a witty remark.
-Got something on you?
-Just one shitty XTC.
Hey, there's a landline
in the school, too!
-Wow, you're right!
-Smartass.
-Shit, the party's over now!
-We'll use the landlline.
What?
The landlline phone is dead.
No shit!
No internet, either.
The router's dead.
-What's dead?
-The router.
He doesn't know what a router is.
Unbelievable.
There has to be a phone
in the Principal's office.
-Let's go there.
-It's locked.
We'll break the door. Easier
than the front one.
Tadija, take it easy,
we’ll end up in jail.
Who'll send us to jail?
Olja, who else? She locked
us in, she took our phones.
She killed the... router.
She's coming back with the cops.
We'll just say that we're locked
inside without fucking phones!
-It's not that.
-What, then?
You're talking about
your dealing drugs?
-Olja doesn't know about that.
-What a retard.
Hey, you've got that other phone.
-I don't.
-The ''business'' one.
-I threw it away.
-What?
I threw the sim card. Drop it.
Can't we find it?
Hey, dude... if anyone's got...
another sim card... here it is.
-No way you threw the card.
-No, I'll use it to call the cops.
-Dude, I don't believe...
-What?!
-We could've called someone.
-Who?
Your old man, maybe?
What's he gotta do with this?
He probably knows the Chief of Police.
They are in the same Party.
First of all, my Dad is not
in that Party anymore.
You know, the old boy's club.
Can he say that we
didn't upload the video?
But we didn't.
-Shut your mouth.
-Shut up!
So it was us, after all?
Ask the cameraman.
Hey, dude!
I was behind the lens,
you can't see me on the video.
That because you're a cunt.
That's what you get
when you want to play the lead.
Now, what?
-Shut your mouth.
-Shut up!
I told you so.
Didn't I?
It's official:
we're in deep shit.
-Really? I don't see no shit.
-What happened?
We can't use the landlline!
-She pulled out the cable!
-No joke.
That psycho pulled out the cable
and took it away.
Way to go!
-She pulled out what?
-Sit down, please.
And I said she's a psycho!
Dude, thanks for sticking your neck
out for me yesterday.
-No problem. What?
-Seriously?
Yeah, she pulled it out.
What a moron!
What kind of a person
could do that?
could think of that?
Breakfast Club. The movie.
Kids get locked in school?
-What are we gonna do?
-Nothing.
You don't believe all of this
happened by accident?
Anything can happen
when the shit hits the fan.
What did they expect?
-Don't panic now.
-''Love is hard''...
And when should I panic?
When we get slaughtered?
Cool down!
We can shout through the window!
Or, you can jump? But, all of
the first floor windows have bars.
-Hey, Matija can jump!
C'mon, take a jump for
the holy Serbian land!
What's the point of all this?
Shit, no Wi-Fi, no Facebook.
How can you defend Kosovo now?
-Can we really shout from the window?
-Who would hear us?
You'd have to shout over
the hamburger takeaway.
Wait, maybe Aunt Ruza is still there.
Aunt Ruza!
The hamburger takeout
is closed on Saturdays.
Can you please stop doing that!
-She could send smoke signals...
-With her tits.
-Or we could tie the curtains...
-The curtains!
If something happens to Granny,
I’ll sue Olja!
alll alone. Finally...
Is it really so funny that
we're locked??
Wow, we're locked in!
Let's panic!
-Alll those condoms...
-Wait, he's right...
Maybe she just went
somewhere and she'll be back.
For three hours now?
The worst thing that can happen to us
is to stay here until morning.
It's warm, we have food,
someone will open
the door tomorrow and that's it.
Way to go, Strale!
What's your problem?
I'm serious.
You're a god among retards!
You're actually making sense.
And you wonder why half of the
school wants to kill you?
Back off, man.
Jelena... Jelena!
There she goes.
Running after him like...
Strale... Strale!
Strahinja, stop!
Where the fuck are you running?
Nowhere.
Can I go with you?
Whatever.
When was the last time the three
of us hung out together?
I can't remember.
Strahinja is a cool dude.
Cool? I hope he dies from prostate
cancer... like, tomorrow.
What did they write?
Terrible things.
-What now?
-Let's see...
We can do drugs!
That would be so like us.
Or...
-GeForce!
-GeForce! Let's go!
-What?
-Get up!
Take my picture.
Blow the smoke.
Hey, Sofija...
what's that you're reading?
Wow... history.
Tadija's getting an education.
Never dug that shit.
We just do the uppers
in my 'hood$.
A faggot, and a junkie.
Fantastic.
Hey! You, Nazi-boy,
did you say something?
Looking, eh...?
-No, thanks.
-Ever tried it?
Once, on my hometown,
but it didn't hit me.
No wonder. Try again.
-No, thanks.
-Look. I'm Tadija!
Wait.
-Got some water?
-No.
-What?
-Trying to get her hooked?
Now it's free,
later you profit.
The evil dealer... plus a Croat!
Don't just stand there!
Bite!
I wasn't talking to you.
Because I'm a faggot?
The school's big enough.
No, wait! Is it because we're faggots,
or because we're Croats?
Wait. You look stronger to me.
What is it?
Hitting the gym?
You look taller.
You got some special workout for that?
Hey, bro... tell me something.
Why don't you call sometimes?
No, really, we could go
to a movie or something.
Or a nice dinner?
Come on, don't treat me
just like a sex object,
I'm a human being too, you know?
I don't know what you're talking
about, you sick freak.
''Just stating facts''.
No, you're staging an incident so you
could say that I bully you,
that's exactly why people
hate your kind.
Instead of treating
your illness in private,
you parade it like it's a virtue.
And what do you parade?
Greater Serbia? Smaller dick?
The fact that I'm a Serbian patriot
and an Orthodox Christian...
Okay, forget it.
You know what I think?
I don't want to know.
I think that those ultra-nationalist
so-called patriot opinions,
are just one big sexual
frustration, you know?
-Come on!
-I'm talking to my bro here.
-By the way, do you get laid at all?
-Get your filthy hands off me.
Sex is not filthy, man.
Just get yourself a nice girl,
a real Serbian...
Leave me alone.
And how can I do that?
How?
The minute I do it, you start
telling everybody that I'm gay.
Wanna know when will
I leave you alone?
When I find a really sweet
girl for you to fuck.
You can't wank off to holy relics
for the rest of your life!
Believe me... once
you fuck a living being,
you'll wanna vote for Obama
in the elections!
Hey, biathcez, wait for me!
Any luck?
-Just 5 more cm.
-Size of your package!
Can you please explain
what are you trying to do?
I just want to see if it works.
Okay. Do that.
That ugly bitch Isidora is right,
we'd better stay here.
Better for you, maybe.
If we split, that will
make us prime suspects.
What the fuck is this?!
It must be those nerds!
How do you turn this off?
This is a magical night.
Strange creatures are leaving
their crypts
...and caves.
And anything is possible.
-This is your goth bitch.
-Fuck you.
-Turn the freak off!
-Turn her off!
Tonight, just for you,
DJ Mary Shelley.
I still don't get it.
That's because you're slow!
Let's connect these and play.
You can't even pay Prince of Persia 1
on that piece of shit.
This is junk, man!
286 processor...
Why did you do that?
You didn't mind the music
last Thursday!
Remember last Thursday?
Not really.
This is Prof. Greaseball's sweater.
We started going out?
We wanna be cool?
-Tell Kosta what happened.
-What?
You know what.
Embarrassed?
-No.
-Then tell him.
-With whom?
-With what.
-With a girl.
-Don't get carried away.
Well, if it was a girl...
She blew you off!
That's not the point.
Kosta, you can't imagine...
I got laid, and you didn't.
End of story.
More like Ursula from The Little
Mermaid gave you a BJ in the toilet.
Gross... Look at this.
Just watch.
I draw a line here...
And an 'F' turns into an 'A'.
And GeForce gets bought by parents!
That's what I call art.
You could've just erase that 'F'.
How? Scratch it away?
Acetonitrile.
Where do I get acetonitrile,
you troglodyte?
-Chemistry cabinet.
-What are you doing?!
Well... we are redefining the results
of science research.
We thought you were
tweaking the grades.
-Is this the Principal’s office?
-No, her assistant’s.
I remember when I was here
with my parents...
Because of that clip?
''Pierced chick sucks it all
the way''? A masterpiece.
-You're pathetic.
-I'm her true fan!
Hey, dude.
Awesome, man!
Am I bothering you?
No, no. Come in.
I can't find a place to study.
This dreadful music roars
all over the school.
We can turn it down.
There's a switch.
Thank you.
Unfortunately, I cannot mute the lost
Serbian kids raised by turbo-folk.
I could literally feel this song
chewing my brain.
Idiots.
I didn't get stoned like this
since grade school.
-Hey, stop smoking, will you?
-Why?
We left the classroom because
you turned it into a gas chamber.
Then you came here.
Can't you be somewhere else?
Way to go.
You're great.
Strale...
Come on.
Strahinja!
-Strahinja...
-What?
That's it.
-It's over.
-Really?
You're done playing.
Strahinja...
-I'll be going now.
-See you.
Could you keep
the noise down?
What's the problem now?
All I asked was if you could
be a little quieter.
This is a library, there is a sign
in Serbian alphabet,
you should know how to read it,
since you live in Serbia.
A library. Not an opium den.
Or the office of the Liberal Party.
You could at least open the window.
No, it's cold.
Let them go somewhere else.
Why don't you go?
Really?!
Just as we Serbs left Croatia
after Operation Storm?
Just as I left the classroom?
No! This is where I draw the line.
Don't be such a primitive, Matija.
What does getting high
has to do with Operation Storm?
So, let them play Croat
nationalist songs here?
This was not a nationalist song.
Cut the crap, Matija?
I'm just stating facts.
In 1941, they slaughtered
my grandfather.
In 1995, they killed my uncle while
we fled from the Croat offensive.
I won't stand this shit anymore!
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
Hey, man.
You missed the target here.
The Croat nationalists killed
3 members of my family in WWII.
Don't explain yourself to him,
he's obviously insane.
Right. Whenever you lack arguments,
I'm ''insane''.
Let's go, Ana.
Hey, Matija...
can I see your ID?
-Why?
-I want to see something.
-Why do you want my ID?
-Just to check something.
No way.
Operation Storm, Croat nationalists...
he's full of bullshit!
He's a Scorpio, meaning
he was born in November,
after the Croat offensive.
That's why he didn't want me
to see his ID.
Hoes! You're shitface drunk!
-What's this?
-Dinkic's passing grade in Latin.
How could've anyone listened
to the music coming from this?
I'd make a sweater from this tape!
Imagine a sweater?
Or leggings.
Yeah right.
Leggings and a crop top.
Like you'd actually prefer this
to an mp3 payer? Boring.
Right. Everything's boring now.
You used to wait all day
to buy one Iron Maiden album,
and now you download their compete
works in a few seconds,
and when they ask you
about the Maidens,
you're, like,
''Yeah, the Maidens are okay''.
What's a ''Maiden''?
That bar uptown, don't be basic.
Let's go. What are you doing
with these retards, anyway?
After we drink this.
Where have you been?
Dude, what's this?
I don't know.
I don't want to know.
In the gym? You're lying!
What?
On the wrestling mat?
I knew it!
Three times.
The first time it was all
gentle and cuddly and kisses...
-And then...
-And then?
Yes!
He totally rocked!
-You didn't miss his balls?
-Shut up.
I'll tell you about it later.
No problem, just ignore us.
Radovan, sweetie...
Don't you owe me some money
for this sexual education?
What do you mean?
Ever since junior year
I keep talking, and talking,
and still, nothing.
You just wank off to my stories,
and I get nothing.
You really are a wacko.
Like you're normal?
You and these...
You're listening to some music
nobody's ever heard of,
you play Counters all day long
and you never get laid. That's normal?
-First of all, we don't pay Counters.
-Counter Strike is for the plebs.
-What do you play, then?
-Warcraft.
Twelve passes, level 89
in Mists of Pandaria.
Mists of Pandaria is crap,
switch to Diablo III.
See?
You guys are morons.
And what the fuck are you?
Kim Kardashian?
You'd still fuck me. In a reality
show, if only you could.
But I'd rather
fuck that bottle, thank you.
Jelena, chill out, really!
-They are our friends!
-You're full of crap, Sandra.
Everyone is your friend
when you get drunk!
Where could you even meet geeks like
them, if it wasn't for school?
Just look at them. Straight from
The Big Bang Theory.
We're sorry if we all can't have
a perfect boyfriend like you.
Jealous?
-Why would I be jealous?
-I don't know.
Maybe because Strahinja
blew you off in junior year?
Who told you that?
Strahinja.
What a stud.
Did he tell you that
he couldn't get it up?
I bet he did?
His prostate, man.
Go, Strale, go!
Go, Strale!
Strale's the Man!
-You got a problem?
-Dude, just do your thing.
Like I'm not here.
Seriously, drop it, man.
I'm not in the mood.
Mood for what?
I didn't say a thing.
That's a cool...
Coo tracksuit.
Where did you buy it?
What's with these
fucking gay jokes?
No joke, bro.
Let's play ball!
I am not gonna fuck you,
I swear.
Hey!
What? Wanna beat me up?
Don't go all Tadija on me,
I'm just messing with you.
We're locked in the school.
Don't get all worked up.
I'm not worked up,
you're just pushing it.
You're afraid I'll kill you
in one-on-one?
-Where now, dude?
-To kick your ass, dude.
Man, we're in real shit.
Yeah, she really lost it.
-What's this?
-You'll see.
The Don's office?
This is where the devil sleeps.
Like she'd call the cops
because of red paint?
Let her call them!
We'll fuck them, too!
Who are you gonna fuck, shorty?
That faggot already got your ass!
Don't laugh, your dad will get it!
At east he's better looking
than your mom!
Ready for some time travel?
This is what I call a spa!
No really, Lazar kicked your ass.
He's full of those boxing tricks.
That was a sucker punch.
He won't get me next time,
now I know the catch!
Maybe he's not a queer,
but he's a pussy.
I'll get him next time.
If he was a faggot, he wouldn't
go around fighting people.
No way, man.
That dude showed that
he's got balls, and that's it.
Did you expect him
to say something like,
''My hands are lethal weapons''?
And why wouldn't a boxer be gay?
Gimme a break.
You think Mike Tyson
gets it in the ass?
Go back to your time machine!
But really? Know any gays?
Not one.
How can you know a gay?
That's what I'm saying.
Maybe some boxers are gay.
Those bastards are sick,
they're everywhere.
Really sick, man.
With so many hot babes around,
they still fuck their asses?
Really? You told everybody
you fucked Sandra in the ass.
-That's not the same.
-No?
He's right.
The ass rules.
I mean, it's tighter than the pussy.
Can you believe this?
Come on, do Wendy for us!
What's this hillbilly shit?
Submit to the power of Goth,
slaves!
Switch it off!
No, really.
This folk music is killing me.
Oh yeah? I can see
that you're bummed out.
Playing Spin the Bottle?
-Just fooling around.
-I want in!
Are you sure? If I start telling
people that Mary Shelley played...
There are no survivors
if you play with her.
So, what does the next one do?
The next person, if it's a female,
will kiss Miksa!
French kiss him, actually!
-If it's a male?
-No way.
-I don't believe this.
-Don't be scared.
What do you want from me?
Come on Sandra, stop pretending.
You've been fucking around
with him all night!
Come on, it's a game! Kiss him!
I mean, if you're not embarrassed.
These are your friends, maybe
they can get a hard-on for you.
Miksa, you're a real stud!
Way to go, man!
Wow. You're such a whore, Sandra.
In that clip at least you sucked
a football player's cock,
but now, this nerd?
What did you say?
-It was a joke!
-No, it wasn't.
How can you say that to me?
-You didn't know?
-Her?
Everybody knows you posted
that clip online yourself.
-I posted it?
-Everybody knows.
-Are you sure I posted it?
-I'm sure.
Are you also sure
you live uptown?
Or maybe in the Ripanj village?
What?
You parade the outfits I gave
you in the village?
You never gave me a thing,
we swapped.
Yeah, Benetton shorts for
a Chinese T-shirt.
I wouldn't be caught dead
in that crap!
Plus, you spend days at my place,
and I've never been in your house.
-Nonsense.
-Ever saw Jelena's place?
No, because she's redneck
who's granny keeps
chickens in the yard.
Why don't you put that on your blog?
Because you're ashamed!
-You're drunk.
-Yes.
But I'm not trailer-trash,
and you are.
I don't believe you, I mean,
I don't get it.
First of all,
why does it matter if I...
Of course it fucking doesn't matter!
You're my friend! I don't
give a shit where you live!
But I'm sick of hearing
lies about your home,
your family, about Veselin...
-How do you know of Veselin?
I know, 'coz you didn't log off
when you used my laptop!
I didn't tell anybody because
I thought you were my friend!
So, why say it now?! Fuck.
How could you call me a whore?!
Do you fucking realize...
-Sandra, wait...
-You're a piece of shit!
I don't believe this.
I was born during the war.
My parents had to...
Whatever. When we came here,
they had no personal documents.
That's why it says here
that I was born in Belgrade.
I didn't want to show this to Ana.
None of her business.
-Right.
-But it made me look like a retard.
Sometimes I say dumb shit like that.
Why? You were right.
Maybe you were wrong
about that song, but...
But when you talked about your family...
I really didn't know.
I can only imagine how does it feel
to be expelled from your home.
My Granny told me...
The communists took away everything
from us after the WWII.
My family was true nobility
before the war.
And our history teacher never mentions
the crimes against families like yours.
Because she's a daughter of
a communist officer...
Really?
She gave me a 'B',
did you see that?
She didn't blink.
And I studied.
I studied hard, precisely to avoid
her communist provocations.
I studied to get an 'A'.
-I deserved an 'A'.
-You did.
''Do you think
that Prince Paul was a patriot?''
Prince Paul Karadjordjevic,
who left that magnificent collection
to the Museum?
And I have to defend him
from a woman whose husband smears
the Serbs and calls that ''art''.
-What?
-You don't know?
-You heard about ''Love''?
-The essay we did?
No. That new exhibition!
I would’ve shown you his filth
if I only had my cell phone.
-The Patriarch and Novak Djokovic...
-I know about that. What of it?
The ''artist'' is Olja's husband.
Her husband, can you believe it?
They do whatever they want.
And then she's surprised when
someone spills paint over her.
They should have
tarred and feathered her.
Now she pays a victim for getting
splashed a bit with her commie color.
Her husband uses the same color
for his sick paintings.
I didn't know that he was
her husband.
What else can surprise you?
The fact that she keeps
us locked in here?
Keeps all of us here,
to be accurate.
Not just the ones who did it.
And who did it?
She can ask her husband.
I didn't do it, that's for sure.
I just informed Tadija
about the exhibition.
But it was
in all the papers, anyhow.
OK, who's next?
Give it to me!
You can take my share.
That's all?
I thought that Dule brought
some more stuff for the excursion.
Dude, I ordered two...
I ordered two grams, and Tadija brought
just a half. Threw away the rest.
So?
-What now?
-I've got no idea.
Ask your daddy?
That's funny. My dad, again?
You could think of something else.
It's not my fault
your old man's on welfare.
What did you say?
I said, it's not my...
I'll fucking kill you!
Tadija, bro!
I'm not your brother,
you rich cunt!
That's our Dule, Tadija!
Fuck you, and Dule!
Don't you ever
talk about my dad! Ever!
Did you see that?
He keeps talking shit
about my dad!
And then? When I mention
his dad, he wants to fight!
The Olja action was all his idea,
so what does he want now?
I just said that Dule should film it,
everything else
was Tadija's idea, right?
That's right.
Where are you going?
I'm going to fuck myself.
You should go back to Tadija.
-They made that video, you know?
-I knew it.
I heard them the other day.
When Sofija got a 'B'.
You should tell someone.
No, dude.
You can tell whoever you want.
I won't have anything
to do with it.
I just beat those bastards up.
-Got a T-shirt?
-What?
A T-shirt?
Yeah, I got it.
You knocked him out like a pro
yesterday.
-You train something?
-Boxing.
It shows.
Motherfucker!
Too cold?
Where do you think you're going?
-It's okay.
-Get out of here!
Just stay cool...
Get out of here,
fucking faggot! Out!
Jelena, open the door,
I know you're in there.
What do you want from me now?!
Nothing. Just to see
that you're okay.
Okay?
Do you want me
to call Strahinja?
I'm okay, Isidora!
Just don't call anyone!
Okay.
Then I'll stay here
until you get out.
Strahinja, my ass!
I mean, I never...
We never...
I'm a fucking virgin!
Want a sandwich?
Thanks.
Matija, what are you doing?
Sofija, I'm sorry, I...
I just...
I just thought that...
What?
You and I...
Fuck, dude.
I mean, it's gonna be okay.
Like hell it will.
It's not like it's the
end of the world, right?
Yes, it is.
I don't give a fuck!
You're my only true friend
in this world.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Come on, tell me what
the fuck is wrong?
You never called me
to go with you.
Go where?
-To action.
-What action?
The teacher, the red paint action.
You're one fucking moron.
Fuck, man.
I told that jerk to call you, but...
No, you haven't.
I overheard you talking to him.
You said that I'm retarded and
that I'll rat on you, 1 00%.
When it's just the two of us, it's
cool, but when someone else is there,
I'm a retard, I'm a rat,
I go to the time machine.
''I go to the time machine''.
''Because Tadija doesn't love me''.
Are you out of your mind,
little faggot?
Why can't you at east speak
like a normal person?
Why can't you be normal
for once in your life?!
Of course I didn't call you!
Just look at you,
so miserable and ugly.
Who would call you?
I'm sorry.
Did you see this?
That story in the papers
Matija talked about?
It's all true, you know?
That was me.
Before I came here, I went to school
in another part of town.
There was a crew there,
bunch of morons.
I thought to myself,
if I act, if I blend in,
no one will notice anything.
I'm a jock, the chicks dig me...
I watch out for my every move,
not to look too femme.
Tops.
Just like in grade school.
And then one day,
this girl, she was my best friend,
she took my phone, she said
she was looking for a song,
but she really
wanted to browse.
She browsed, all right.
She found some messages
and some pictures.
With some guy from Grindr.
What did she do?
Print screen
and straight to Facebook.
Fuck, man...
In 30 minutes...
In 30 fucking minutes...
The whole school was, like...
''Faggot!''
''Homo!''
''Butt rider!'' Hell, man.
One guy threw shit on my head.
He actually crapped in a plastic bag
and spilled it over my head.
Literally.
Each day I go to school, I throw up.
Every morning.
I can't tell my Mom,
I don't know how.
I lost track of
how many times I got beaten up.
Until one day,
I go to school
and I run into this bully, Ruzic.
One of those Serb nationalists.
He comes to me
and spits in my face.
I smack him over the face.
So, after school, three of them...
Dude...
three of then, and I'm alone.
And they start to pound,
and pound, and hammer.
They kick me, they don't stop,
and all in the head.
The blood's all over me,
I don't know if I'm alive or dead...
I look up, one of them says,
''You like to suck cock, do you?
You like to suck cock?''
''You really love sucking it, right?''
That's the last thing I remember.
I fell into a coma.
For three days.
Skull fracture,
three broken ribs,
and that knife. Missed by
a couple of millimeters.
After that, I came out to my mom.
We managed to survive that.
Then, I started to work out.
I train every day,
like my life depends on it.
They can wonder
if I'm top or bottom.
But if anyone touches me,
I'll beat the shit out of him.
I really don't know what love is.
I mean...I can give you
a textbook definition, but
you’re not looking for that.
I'm sorry I read your essays.
I  shouldn 't have.
Those are your private thoughts.
But just for a second, I wanted to see
how does it feel...
not being me.
You've got friends.
You love each other, hate each other,
fight and make up,
and you think
that's the end of the world.
You've got no idea how lucky you are.
I  know that the problems of all those
Jelenas, Tadijas, Strahinjas
Dinkics, Srbas,
and even Miksas, Rasas or Anas
will always be bigger and more
important than my problems.
That's okay.
I think that it's always been
that way, and it always will be.
I only know that...
If I died today
most of you wouldn't
even remember my name.
Teacher?
Teacher!
Subtitle rip and timing:
sofiaguy™, 2017